[Panther]
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
POLYGRAM FILMED ENTERTAINMENT
WE SHALL OVERCOME
WE SHALL OVERCOME...
Malcolm X:
THERE IS NOTHING MORE DANGEROUS
THAN TO BUILD A SOCIETY
WITH A LARGE SEGMENT
OF PEOPLE IN THAT SOCIETY
WHO FEEL THEY HAVE
NO STAKE IN IT,
NOTHING TO LOSE.
PEOPLE WHO HAVE STAKE
IN THEIR SOCIETY
PROTECT THAT SOCIETY,
BUT WHEN
THEY DON'T HAVE IT,
THEY UNCONSCIOUSLY
WANT TO DESTROY IT.
[CHANTING]
WE WANT KING!
King: I AM CONVINCED
THE MOST POTENT WEAPON
AVAILABLE TO OPPRESSED PEOPLE
AS THEY STRUGGLE
FOR FREEDOM AND JUSTICE
IS THE WEAPON
OF NONVIOLENCE.
WE ARE NONVIOLENT
WITH PEOPLE
WHO ARE
NONVIOLENT WITH US.
BUT WE ARE
NOT NONVIOLENT
WITH ANYONE WHO IS
VIOLENT WITH US.
THIS IS AN UNLAWFUL
ASSEMBLY.
YOU ARE ORDERED
TO DISPERSE.
GO HOME
OR GO TO YOUR CHURCH.
THIS MARCH
WILL NOT CONTINUE!
NEXT WEEK, I SHALL ASK
THE CONGRESS
OF THE UNITED STATES TO ACT,
TO MAKE A COMMITMENT
IT HAS NOT FULLY MADE
IN THIS CENTURY
TO THE PROPOSITION
THAT RACE HAS NO PLACE
IN AMERICAN LIFE OR LAW.
[GUNSHOT]
Malcolm X: WELL, ANYTIME
YOU LIVE IN A SOCIETY
SUPPOSEDLY BASED UPON LAW,
AND IT DOESN'T
ENFORCE ITS OWN LAW
BECAUSE THE COLOR
OF A MAN'S SKIN IS WRONG,
THEN THOSE PEOPLE
ARE JUSTIFIED
TO RESORT
TO ANY MEANS NECESSARY
TO BRING ABOUT JUSTICE
WHERE THE GOVERNMENT
CAN'T GIVE THEM JUSTICE.
[GUN COCKS]
[GUNSHOT]
Judge:
THE BLACK PANTHERS.
PEOPLE STILL ASK ME
HOW IT ALL STARTED,
HOW THINGS WENT SO FAR.
AND LIKE A LOT OF QUESTIONS
ABOUT THE PANTHERS,
THERE ARE DIFFERENT ANSWERS,
DIFFERENT BEGINNINGS.
WHAT BECAME THE BLACK PANTHER
PARTY FOR SELF DEFENSE
REALLY STARTED WITH 2 GUYS,
BOBBY SEALE AND HUEY NEWTON,
SAYING 2 WORDS--
"DEFEND YOURSELVES."
STORY HAS IT THAT THEY
HOOKED UP AT SOME COFFEEHOUSE
WHERE BOBBY WAS
RUNNING DOWN A RHYME.
OH, YEAH.
IT'S EASY TO SEE...
RIGHT ON YOUR
BLACK AND WHITE TV.
BLACK MAN. BLUE COP.
RED BLOOD.
BROTHERS WATCHING
OTHER BROTHERS DIE.
OH, MY.
THAT'S THE AMERICAN WAY.
WHAT YOU DOING?
HEY, GET HIM
OFF ME.
SETTLE DOWN,
BLACK BOY.
Judge: THE POLICE
THREW THEM BOTH IN JAIL.
YOU KNOW,
THE MAN IS CONVINCED
HIS FOOT IS AN INTEGRAL
PART OF OUR ASS.
YEAH.
BUT FUCK THAT.
DIG IT.
FUCK THAT.
Judge: THERE THEY STARTED
TALKING ABOUT BLACK FOLKS
OUGHT TO START
STANDING UP FOR THEMSELVES.
NO MASTER PLAN.
NO POT TO PISS IN.
NOTHING LIKE THAT.
JUST 2 FED-UP BROTHERS.
NEXT THING YOU KNOW,
BAM.
YOU GOT THE BLACK PANTHER
PARTY FOR SELF DEFENSE.
ONE OF THE FIRST
MEMBERS TO JOIN
WAS LITTLE BOBBY HUTTON.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
AND THAT GOT THE BALL
ROLLING.
[SIREN]
WHOA!
I FEEL GOOD
I KNEW THAT I WOULD, NOW...
Judge: BUT FOR ME,
IT STARTED DIFFERENTLY.
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
SO GOOD
I GOT YOU
WHOA!
BERNADETTE
PEOPLE ARE
SEARCHING FOR
THE KIND OF LOVE
THAT WE POSSESS
SOME GO ON
SEARCHING
THEIR WHOLE LIFE THROUGH
AND NEVER FIND THE LOVE
I FOUND IN YOU
OOH
AND WHEN I SPEAK
OF YOU
I SEE ENVY
IN OTHER MEN'S EYES...
[GASPS]
LOOK AT YOU LOOKING.
WHAT YOU LOOKING AT
IS ALMOST 30 YEARS OLD,
BUT THIS HAT
IS BRAND-NEW.
GET YOURSELF
ON TO SCHOOL, BOY.
YES, MA'AM.
I SHOULD TELL
YOUR MAMA ON YOU.
LITTLE CUTIE PIE.
HEY, LUTHER, MAN, HE
WAS MESSING AROUND
WITH THAT OLD
WHITE WOMAN.
I'M GOING TO POUR
SOME OUT FOR LUTHER.
FUCK LUTHER, MAN.
HE OWE ME $30.
YOU AIN'T GOING TO
GET THAT MONEY NOW.
WHEN I SEE HIS MOTHER,
I'LL GET MY MONEY.
SHE AIN'T GOT
NO MONEY.
CHECK IT OUT.
I GOT THE PERFECT GIFT
FOR THAT SOPHISTICATED LADY.
LIGHT UP HER FLAME
WITH SOLID GOLD.
ACT NOW, THE SECOND ONE
HALF-PRICE.
LOOK AT THIS.
WHY YOU STILL TRYING
TO SELL THESE?
HEY, I DON'T
KNOW HIM.
MAN, GET YOUR ONE-EYED ASS
OUT OF HERE.
SHUT UP,
YOU TALL MIDGET,
AND PAY ME FOR
THIS FAKE LIGHTER.
TINY, YOU GET
TO SCHOOL.
YOU MAD 'CAUSE YOU CAN
ONLY SEE HALF THE LIGHTER.
HI, TINY.
GET TO SCHOOL
ON TIME.
MMM. MMM.
FINE YOUNG MAN.
GOD DAMN YOU!
HOW COULD YOU
DO THAT?
WHAT ARE YOU
DOING OVER HERE?
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
Judge: LIKE I SAID,
FOR ME IT STARTED
A LOT DIFFERENTLY.
YEAH.
I GUESS YOU COULD SAY
FOR ME
THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY...
STARTED IN
MY MOM'S FRONT YARD.
YOU BETTER SHOOT.
OH, MAN!
UH!
WHAT YOU DO IN VIETNAM?
YOU SHOOT HOOPS?
I SHOT EVERYTHING
IN NAM, BABY.
MAN, HE AIN'T
IN THE GAME.
DON'T YOU FINE
BLACK MEN
GOT ANYTHING
BETTER TO DO?
SURE. BUT YOUR SISTER
AIN'T HOME.
TAKE IT.
THOUGHT SOME
RIGHTEOUS BROTHERS
MIGHT BE ABLE
TO HELP US OUT,
BUT I GUESS
THAT AIN'T YOU.
HELP WHO
WITH WHAT?
WITH YOUR COMMUNITY,
THAT'S WHO.
MAYBE YOU AIN'T KNOW,
BUT ANOTHER KID DIED TODAY.
THAT'S 3 THIS YEAR.
THE SAME SPOT.
DAMN STRAIGHT.
AND OLD REVEREND SLOCUM,
HE'S HAVING ANOTHER VIGIL
TO PUT A STOPLIGHT
AT THAT CORNER.
I'M ASKING YOU
ABLE BLACK ASSES
TO COME DOWN
AND BE OBSERVERS
ON THEM COPS.
TAKE DOWN SOME
BADGE NUMBERS.
THEY DON'T PULL
A LOT OF SHIT
WHEN TOO MANY EYES
ARE ON THEM.
Y'ALL CAN HELP
NOT BY PRAYING
BUT BY WATCHING.
YOU THINK THE POLICE CARE
ABOUT BLACK PEOPLE PRAYING?
THE COMMUNITY
HAS BEEN TRYING
TO GET THIS STOPLIGHT
PUT IN
SINCE BEFORE MY MOTHER
WAS A VIRGIN.
YOU THINK CITY HALL
REALLY CARES
ABOUT A BUNCH OF
BLACK PEOPLE
HAVING ANOTHER PRAYER VIGIL
AT SOME GODDAMN CHURCH?
THEY AIN'T GOING
TO HAVE IT AT CHURCH.
THEY GOING TO MARCH
TO THE INTERSECTION,
A PEACEFUL PROTEST.
I AIN'T FUCKING
WITH NO COPS.
THEY DON'T LIKE US
GETTING INVOLVED
WITH NO POLITICAL SHIT.
SOME OF US FEEL
WE SHOULDN'T EVEN INTERACT
WITH THE WHITE MAN.
WE ARE AFRICAN, BROTHER.
MOTHER AFRICA'S
THE ONLY SALVATION.
LOOK, YOU PHONY-ASS
BOOJY NIGGER.
WE AIN'T IN AFRICA.
WE IN OAKLAND.
IN OAKLAND WE GOT
POLICE BRUTALITY.
WE GOT THE WHITE MAN
INTERACTING HIS BILLY CLUB
UPSIDE THE BLACK MAN'S
HEAD.
IF THAT SHIT
DON'T BOTHER YOU,
TAKE YOUR SKIRT-WEARIN' ASS
BACK TO AFRICA.
NOW COME ON.
HEY, COME ON.
WE DON'T WANT TO GO.
OK? GO.
WHAT ABOUT YOU?
YOU WERE BOTH THERE.
YOU SAW THAT KID.
YEAH, I SAW, BUT...
BUT WHAT? YOU DO LIVE
HERE, DON'T YOU?
YEAH, I DO LIVE HERE.
THEN ACT LIKE IT,
MAN.
COME ON. THIS'LL TAKE
A SECOND. I PROMISE.
YOU YOUNG NIGGERS
CRAZY.
THE MAN AIN'T GOING
TO LET Y'ALL
HAVE NO SAY-SO IN SHIT.
HE GOING TO COME DOWN
ON Y'ALL
LIKE A TON OF BRICKS
JUST LIKE THIS
RIGHT HERE.
DON'T LET THE COPS
PROVOKE YOU.
WE'RE JUST TAKING DOWN
BADGE NUMBERS.
WHO'S WE, MAN?
WHERE YOU BEEN?
WE THE BLACK
PANTHER PARTY
FOR SELF DEFENSE.
Y'ALL SOME KIND
OF GANG?
WE AIN'T NO
GANGSTERS.
WE'RE REVOLUTIONARIES.
CAN YOU DIG IT?
HE'S ONLY 16.
WE MADE HIM GET HIS MA'S
PERMISSION BEFORE HE JOINED.
16? HE'S JUST
A KID, MAN.
COPS KICK THE SHIT
OUT OF KIDS, TOO.
WE'RE FIGHTING
FOR OUR FREEDOM...
Judge: THE BLACK COMMUNITY
WAS A FAMILY,
A STRONG FORCE
TO BE RECKONED WITH.
THE GHETTO
WAS NEVER HEAVEN.
WE HAD OUR CROOKS
AND DRUNKS
AND THE ESTABLISHMENT
EXPLOITING US.
AS LONG AS WE
SUFFERED IN SILENCE,
THE AUTHORITIES
LEFT US ALONE.
WE SHALL NOT
BE MOVED...
BUT...
THAT SILENT-SUFFERING SHIT
WAS ABOUT TO CHANGE.
YOU SAID ALL THE PANTHERS
WOULD BE HERE.
WHAT YOU SEE IS WHAT YOU GET.
THAT'S BOBBY SEALE.
AND THAT--
THAT'S HUEY.
SHIT, AIN'T TOO MANY OF YOU
MOTHERFUCKERS OUT THERE.
HEY, MAN, IT ONLY TAKES
A SINGLE GRAIN OF SAND
TO MOVE THE WORLD.
WE SHALL NOT
BE MOVED...
WHAT THE SAM HILL
IS THIS?
A VIGIL FOR
SOME PICKANINNY
GOT HIT HERE.
START TAKING DOWN
BADGE NUMBERS, Y'ALL.
Cop: VIGIL, MY ASS.
NOW LISTEN UP.
YOU'VE GOT 30 SECONDS
TO DISPERSE
AND RETURN TO YOUR HOMES.
FAILURE TO DO SO
WILL RESULT
IN YOUR IMMEDIATE ARREST.
WE SHALL NOT
BE MOVED
WE SHALL NOT BE MOVED
JUST LIKE A TREE
THAT'S PLANTED
BY THE WATER
YOU ARE RESISTING
ARREST.
WE SHALL NOT BE MOVED
WE SHALL NOT--
GO.
GET THEIR BADGE
NUMBERS.
HEY, Y'ALL, THE COPS
COVERING THEIR BADGES.
THEY CAN'T DO THAT!
MOM!
GET A NUMBER, MAN.
GET A NUMBER
ON THAT COP!
MOM!
HEY, LOOK, THIS OBSERVER
STUFF AIN'T WORKING.
THE COPS COVER THEIR BADGES,
AND EVEN IF WE DO REPORT IT,
DON'T NOTHING HAPPEN.
I KNOW WE NEED
TO STAY DISCIPLINED.
BUT I AIN'T JOINED
THIS MOTHERFUCKER
JUST TO GET
MY ASS KICKED.
YEAH!
DIG IT!
WE MUST TURN
THE OTHER CHEEK, BROTHERS.
OH, MAN.
TCH.
REMEMBER, THE MEEK
SHALL INHERIT THE EARTH.
WAIT, WAIT, HOLD.
LOOK, FELLAS,
WHAT WE NEED TO DO...
IS PRAY
FOR THEIR FORGIVENESS.
THEY KNOW NOT
WHAT THEY DO.
HEY, NO OFFENSE,
REVEREND,
BUT THEY BEEN
PRACTICING ON US
FOR 400 YEARS.
THEY KNOW EXACTLY
WHAT THEY DOING.
BROTHER MALCOLM SAID
WE NEED TO STOP SINGING
AND START SWINGING.
Y'ALL CAN RANT AND RAVE,
BUT IT'S THE POLICE
WHO GOT THE GUN.
SHIT, IF BLACK FOLKS
HAD GUNS,
WE'D PROBABLY SHOOT
EACH OTHER WITH THEM.
AW!
TCH!
LORD, WHY DON'T THEY
SHOW US NO RESPECT?
BECAUSE THEY DON'T
HAVE TO.
THEY THINK THEY CAN
BRUTALIZE US AND LOCK US UP
WITHOUT A JURY
OF OUR PEERS
'CAUSE WE'RE IGNORANT
TO THE LAWS.
WE NEED TO ORGANIZE,
KEEP OUR SHIT CORRECT,
AND EXERCISE OUR
CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHT
AS CITIZENS
TO DEFEND OURSELVES
AND ARM OURSELVES.
THEN IF THEY TRY
TO BRUTALIZE US
OR VIOLATE OUR RIGHTS,
WE GOT A RIGHT AND MEANS
TO DEFEND OURSELVES.
WHAT THE HELL
THE BOY SAYING?
THE MAN SAID
WE CAN CARRY GUNS.
IT'S LEGAL.
THAT'S RIGHT.
Y'ALL GOING TO
GET GUNS AND SHOOT COPS?
NO, IT AIN'T ABOUT
SHOOTING COPS.
IT'S ABOUT GETTING
THE MAN'S ATTENTION
AND SHOWING
OUR COMMUNITY
THAT WE AIN'T GOT TO
TAKE THIS SHIT NO MORE.
THE ESTABLISHMENT,
IT DON'T LISTEN
WHEN WE SING, PRAY, OR BEG.
BUT THEY SEE SOME DISCIPLINED
BROTHERS WITH GUNS,
THEY'LL KNOW THE BLACK PANTHER
PARTY FOR SELF DEFENSE
IS SERIOUS ABOUT DEFENDING
THE RIGHTS OF OUR PEOPLE.
ALL POWER
TO THE PEOPLE.
ALL POWER TO THE PEOPLE!
[LAUGHTER]
FREE AT LAST,
MY BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
GOD HAS DELIVERED US
FROM THE LION'S DEN.
REVEREND, WE BLACK
WHERE WE STARTED.
WE STILL AIN'T GOT
A STOPLIGHT.
AS THE REVEREND SAYS,
GOD HELPS THOSE
THAT HELP THEMSELVES.
WE'LL BE OUR OWN
STOPLIGHT.
Y'ALL NEED A HOT MEAL
AND A HOT BATH.
HOW'S MOM?
WE LEARN THROUGH OBSERVATION
AND PARTICIPATION.
YES!
HEY. HEY!
WHAT YOU DOING THERE?
IS THERE A PROBLEM?
THAT'S BEAUTIFUL, MAN.
THEY BEING THEIR OWN
STOPLIGHT.
CY, WHAT IS THAT
GOING TO DO, MAN?
COME ON, JUDGE. WE GOT
TO START SOMEWHERE.
I'M GOING TO START
BY GETTING ON MY FEET.
WORKING ON THINGS
FROM INSIDE THE SYSTEM.
THAT'S WHY
I VOLUNTEERED FOR NAM--
TO GET THE G.I. BILL.
THAT'S BULLSHIT.
YOU VOLUNTEERED
TO BEAT
THAT JOYRIDING RAP.
MAN, INSIDE
AIN'T IN THE SYSTEM.
IT'S RIGHT THERE
INSIDE OF YOU.
YOU KNOW WHAT?
I'M JOINING, MAN.
YOU WHAT?
I'M GOING TO JOIN
THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY.
CY, MAN,
YOU DON'T NEED TO--
Martin Luther King:
...IN VIETNAM
AND CHALLENGE THEM
WITH THE ALTERNATIVE...
YOU BE CAREFUL,
ALL RIGHT?
OF CONSCIENTIOUS
OBJECTION.
AND I SAY THIS MORNING
THAT IT IS MY...
MY GOD.
MOM, WHEN DID THEY
LET YOU OUT?
COUPLE OF HOURS AGO.
YOU OK?
I'M ALL RIGHT.
HOW ABOUT YOU?
YOU DON'T LOOK
ALL RIGHT.
WHIPPING UP ON THAT COP
LIKE YOU WAS CRAZY.
THAT COP WAS TRYING
TO HIT MY MAMA.
I CAN'T HAVE THAT.
YOU KNOW.
COME HERE.
Martin Luther King:
NO MATTER WHAT YOU THINK
OF MR. MUHAMMAD ALI'S
RELIGION...
WHAT WOULD
YOUR DADDY SAY?
BOTH OF US LOCKED UP
IN PRISON
LIKE 2 JAILBIRDS.
I DON'T KNOW.
THOSE YOUR
ROUGHNECK FRIENDS
YOU MET IN JAIL
OVER THERE?
MOM, IT'S NOT
LIKE YOU THINK.
THOSE FELLAS...
THEY ALL RIGHT.
THEY WAS OUT THERE
TRYING TO DO SOMETHING.
WELL, THOSE FELLAS,
THOSE BLACK PANTHERS,
I HEAR THEY'RE
COMMUNIST.
THEY DON'T EVEN
BELIEVE IN GOD.
MA, BLACK FOLKS BEEN PRAYING
TO GOD FOR 400 YEARS.
MAYBE IT'S TIME
WE TRIED SOMETHING ELSE.
YOU BELIEVE THAT?
I DON'T KNOW.
I REALLY DON'T.
I TELL YOU ONE THING.
THEM BOYS KEEP ON
THE WAY THEY KEEPING ON,
IT'S GOING TO BE A LOT
OF TROUBLE AROUND HERE.
THOSE THINGS DON'T WORK,
BELIEVE ME.
DON'T I KNOW IT.
COME ON IN,
AGENT RODGERS.
ALWAYS A PLEASURE
TO SEE YOU.
WHAT CAN I DO
TO BE OF HELP?
WELL, IT SEEMS
THE BAY AREA
HAS BECOME A REAL HORNET'S NEST
FOR SUBVERSIVE ACTIVITIES.
MR. HOOVER WOULD
JUST LIKE TO REITERATE
THAT THE FBI IS WILLING
TO HELP THE AUTHORITIES
IN ANY WAY THEY CAN,
STRICTLY ON AN ADVISORY
BASIS, OF COURSE.
OF COURSE. WELL,
I APPRECIATE YOUR HELP,
BUT I THINK
WE HAVE THINGS
PRETTY WELL
UNDER CONTROL.
JUST THE USUAL
BUNCH OF KOOKS
THAT YOU GUYS HAVE
HAD UNDER SURVEILLANCE.
THEY'RE STILL MAKING
NOISE AND SMOKING POT,
BUT NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT.
AND WHAT CAN YOU
TELL ME ABOUT
THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY
FOR SELF DEFENSE?
THEY'RE JUST A BUNCH
OF SHINES
RUNNING AROUND
SHAKING THEIR FISTS
ABOUT SOME STREETLIGHT.
THEY'RE LOUD, BUT
THEY'RE NOT DANGEROUS.
IS IT POSSIBLE WE CAN
MAKE A DEAL WITH THEM?
NO...THEY'RE--
THEY'RE KIDS, MOSTLY.
IDEALISTS.
THEY THINK, ACTUALLY,
THEY'RE FOR REAL.
YOU WANT ME
TO PUT A MAN ON IT?
I THINK THAT'D BE
A GOOD IDEA.
TAKE CARE
OF THAT STOMACH.
OH, YEAH,
BY THE WAY,
I WOULD APPRECIATE IT
IF THAT MAN OF YOURS
WOULD KEEP
A LOW PROFILE.
[MUSIC PLAYS]
2 BETS.
2 BETS WITH ME.
WHOO.
HEY, HEY, HEY!
HEY, WHAT'S UP?
WHAT Y'ALL WANT? PANAMA RED?
I WAS WONDERING...
DO YOU HAVE ANY COCAINE?
SOME COCAINE?
I CAN GET YOU
SOME COCAINE,
BUT YOU CAN'T
DO IT HERE.
GIVE ME $20 AND MEET ME
BACK HERE IN A HOUR.
DON'T FUCK AROUND,
WHITE BOY,
'CAUSE THIS SOME
SERIOUS SHIT.
YOU'LL MEET ME HERE
IN AN HOUR?
I SAID I'LL MEET YOU HERE.
GET OUT OF HERE, MAN.
MOTHERFUCKER!
THAT'S A STUPID
MOTHERFUCKER.
SABU, MAN, WE CAN'T HAVE YOU
PUSHING POISON ON THE STREET.
WHITEBREAD
WANTED SOME COKE,
SO I JUST TOOK
HIS MONEY.
IT'S A HUSTLE.
I'M OUT TO GET PAID,
BROTHER.
I UNDERSTAND,
BUT YOU GOTTA UNDERSTAND
WHAT THE PANTHERS
ARE SAYING.
YOU GOT TO BE PART OF
THE SOLUTION, NOT THE PROBLEM.
YEAH, WHATEVER.
ALL THAT'S COOL,
BUT LET ME GET MY MONEY
THING STRAIGHT FIRST.
MOTHERFUCKING PANTHERS.
Y'ALL ARE WORSER
THAN THE POLICE.
OHH.
HEY, BABY,
WHY DON'T YOU JOIN
THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY?
BETTER YET,
JOIN ME FOR DINNER.
LOOK AT THAT!
BROWN SUGAR!
NO, THANK YOU.
GIRL, YOU MAKE ME WANT TO
SOP YOU WITH SOME GRAVY!
HEY, LOOK WHAT
YOU MADE ME DO!
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
JIVIN' AROUND,
LOOKING AT
THE YOUNG GIRL LIKE THAT?
YOU SUPPOSED TO BE
DIRECTING TRAFFIC.
I KNOW.
LOOKIE HERE,
LOOKIE HERE!
HOW YOU DOING,
CASPER?
GO AWAY.
YOU LOST OR SOMETHING?
WE WON'T HURT YOU.
OH!
OH, MAN!
OH,
YOU POLICE.
HE THE FUZZ, MAN.
YOU COULDN'T BE
JUST A PLAIN OLD
WHITE MAN.
TAKE US WITH YOU.
COME ON, MAN.
WASH THE CAR, MAN.
COME ON, MAN!
HEY.
YEAH, SO, UH,
SHE ARRIVE NEXT MONTH.
SO IF YOU BROTHERS
INTERESTED...
INTERESTED?
WE'RE TRYING TO PRACTICE
WHAT BROTHER MALCOLM
PREACHED.
WHERE'S BOBBY SEALE?
I DON'T KNOW.
I'M LOOKING AT
THAT FINE SISTER.
MAN, CHECK THIS OUT.
YOU GOING TO LOVE IT.
WE GOT A DECISION
TO MAKE.
THOSE BROTHERS IN SAN FRAN
CALL THEMSELVES
BLACK PANTHERS, TOO.
THEM BROTHERS THAT
DON'T DO NOTHING
BUT PUT UP PAPER SAYING
BLACK IS BEAUTIFUL?
HE'S ONE OF THEM,
AND THEY'RE BRINGING IN
SISTER BETTY SHABAZZ NEXT MONTH
TO SPEAK AT A RALLY AND DO
AN INTERVIEW FOR RAMPARTS.
THEY WANT US TO HELP
WITH SECURITY.
ANYBODY'S GOING TO
PROTECT MALCOLM'S LEGACY,
IT BETTER BE US.
LET'S GO CHECK IT OUT.
COOK ME UP
A BURGER OR SOMETHING.
GREETINGS, AFRICAN BROTHERS
FROM ACROSS THE BAY.
WE UNDERSTAND
YOU WOULD LIKE TO ASSIST US
WITH SISTER BETTY SHABAZZ'S
SECURITY.
THAT'S RIGHT.
WE'D BE PROUD
TO PROVIDE ESCORT
FOR SISTER SHABAZZ.
HOW MANY MEN, HOW
MANY GUNS YOU GOT?
[CHUCKLING]
GET THE BROTHERS
SOME LIBATION.
ME, TOO,
WHILE YOU AT IT.
MEN...BROTHER DEWEY?
HUEY.
NO, THANK YOU, SISTER.
YEAH. LOUIE.
YOU KNOW WHAT
I'M SAYING, BROTHER.
WE, AS A REVOLUTIONARY
VANGUARD,
ARE SERIOUS
WITH OUR SHIT.
I ASSURE YOU
THAT BROTHER LOMBARD HERE
AND OUR OTHER BROTHERS
WILL RISE TO THE OCCASION
IN FULL EFFECT.
JUST BE ON TIME.
WE'LL BE PREPARED.
RIGHT, BROTHER LOMBARD?
UHURU...WAMBASA...SIMBA.
FREEDOM AND WORK...LION.
UMOJA, BROTHERS.
THOSE ORANGUTAN-LOOKING
ARMCHAIR REVOLUTIONARIES
AIN'T FIT FOR THE NAME
PANTHERS.
WE NEED TO BE READY TO
PROTECT BETTY SHABAZZ,
BECAUSE THEM BROTHERS
SURE AS HELL CAN'T.
WE NEED SOME GUNS.
WE NEED SOME MONEY
FIRST.
WE ONLY GOT
2 PISTOLS.
WHERE WE GOING TO GET
THE MONEY TO BUY GUNS
YOU TOLD THEM WE HAD?
YOU'RE THE CHAIRMAN.
I'M MINSTER
OF DEFENSE.
YOU FIGURE IT OUT.
I ALREADY DID.
THAT'S WHAT I WAS
TRYING TO TELL YOU.
HERE WE GO.
CHECK IT OUT.
BOUGHT EVERY COPY
IN CHINATOWN.
GOT A DISCOUNT, TOO.
30 CENT APIECE.
BOBBY, QUOTATIONS
FROM CHAIRMAN MAYO?
MAO, BROTHER, MAO.
MAN, THESE ARE
BOOKS, MAN.
THAT'S RIGHT.
GOING TO SELL THEM
FOR A DOLLAR.
MAN, THIS WHAT
YOU DID WITH MY MONEY?
ONLY A DOLLAR.
GET THE LOWDOWN HERE.
YOU WANT TO GET IT
FROM ME.
IF YOU'RE AFRAID
OF SOCIALISM,
YOU'RE AFRAID
OF YOURSELF.
GET THE LOWDOWN
RIGHT THERE.
MAO TSE-TUNG
RIGHT HERE.
ONLY $1.00.
ONLY A DOLLAR.
HUEY! HEY, HUEY.
THESE GUYS RIGHT HERE
WANT TO JOIN.
SORRY, GUYS.
THE PARTY FEELS
IT'S IMPORTANT
FOR BLACK PEOPLE
TO DO IT FOR THEMSELVES,
SO WE'RE NOT SIGNING UP
ANY WHITE FOLKS.
IF YOU'RE DOWN FOR WHAT
WE'RE DOING, WE APPRECIATE IT.
ORGANIZE SOME RIGHTEOUS
WHITE FOLKS.
I GOT A FEELING WE'RE
GOING TO NEED EACH OTHER.
STOP, CHILDREN,
WHAT'S THAT SOUND?
EVERYBODY, LOOK
WHAT'S GOIN' DOWN...
I READ THROUGH IT
ABOUT 5 TIMES.
ONLY A DOLLAR.
GET YOUR RED BOOK.
OH, THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
BE HIP TO THE STRUGGLE.
ONLY A DOLLAR.
HEY, BOY, THIS WHAT
THEY GOT YOU DOING NOW?
PARTY NEEDS THE BREAD.
BE HIP TO THE STRUGGLE.
A DOLLAR?
IS THAT AUTHENTIC?
THIS HERE IS
THE REAL DEAL.
STRAIGHT FROM
REVOLUTION HQ.
FAR OUT.
THANK YOU.
LONG LIVE
THE REVOLUTION, BROTHER.
ALL RIGHT, NOW.
THE MONEY'S COOL,
BUT WHAT THE PARTY
NEED EVEN MORE
IS BROTHERS
LIKE YOU.
HEY, JUDGE, MAN,
WE NEED YOU, MAN.
LOOK AT ALL THESE--
ALL THESE WORDS.
I DON'T EVEN KNOW
HALF OF THEM.
I'LL TIGHTEN YOU UP
ON THE WORDS, MAN.
BUT I GOT TO PASS
ON THE REVOLUTION.
I GOT CLASS. LET'S HIT
CLOUD NINE LATER.
COME ON DOWN
TO THE OFFICE.
YOU REALLY INTO
THIS PANTHER THING.
HEY, FAR OUT, MAN.
YOU KNOW WHAT, MAN?
YOU SHOULD COME DOWN,
HEAR WHAT HUEY AND BOBBY
GOT TO SAY TONIGHT.
YEAH, MAYBE.
MAYBE.
HEY, MAN, FUCK MAYBE.
BE THERE.
LIKE I SAID,
MAYBE, MAN.
MAYBE BROTHER
GOT AN AFRO ON.
MAYBE HE GOT A PROCESS.
MAYBE SISTER'S
HAIR IS STRAIGHTENED.
MAYBE IT'S NATURAL.
MAYBE A BROTHER
GOT A DASHIKI ON
OR MAYBE
A SHARP PIMP SUIT.
MAYBE SHE'S
PROSTITUTING HERSELF.
MAYBE SHE'S TEACHING KIDS
TO READ.
THE PIG WILL MURDER,
BRUTALIZE AND KILL YOU
BECAUSE YOU'RE BLACK,
NO MATTER WHAT KIND OF BAG
YOU IN.
WE, THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY
FOR SELF DEFENSE,
WE'RE NOT ANARCHISTS.
THE GOVERNMENT'S SUPPOSED
TO SERVE THE PEOPLE.
THE GOVERNMENT SHOULD SERVE
THE BLACK COMMUNITY.
BLACK COPS
FOR BLACK PEOPLE.
NOT THE ARMY THAT'S
OCCUPYING OUR COMMUNITY NOW.
ARMY, YOU SAY.
HOLD ON.
HEY, BROTHER--
THIS AIN'T VIETNAM.
[SIREN]
THE ARMY'S RIGHT OUTSIDE
YOUR DOOR. THEY'RE COPS.
THE PIGS. THEY'RE SUPPOSED
TO PROTECT AND SERVE.
THEY DON'T DO NOTHING
BUT PATROL AND CONTROL.
WE CALL THEM PIGS
BECAUSE IT'S LEGAL.
YOU CURSE. YOU CALL A PIG
A DIRTY MOTHER-WHATEVER,
HE GOT AN EXCUSE
TO ARREST YOU.
DON'T GIVE HIM NO EXCUSE.
TO BECOME A MEMBER
OF THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY
FOR SELF DEFENSE,
YOU MUST KNOW NOT ONLY
THE OPPRESSOR'S LAWS.
YOU HAVE TO KNOW OURS.
FOR INSTANCE...
NO GETTING HIGH
ON PANTHER PREMISES
OR WHILE CARRYING OUT
PANTHER DUTIES.
WHEN AM I GOING
TO GET A GUN?
WE DON'T HAVE NONE YET.
NO ONE GETS ONE FROM US
UNTIL THEY'VE GONE THROUGH
THE PROPER TRAINING.
THAT INCLUDES KNOWING
THE 10-POINT PROGRAM.
Bobby:
WE GOT TO EDUCATE OURSELVES,
KNOW OUR OWN HISTORY.
MAN, I HAD HISTORY
IN SCHOOL.
NOT THAT COLONIAL SLAVERY
BULL THEY WANT YOU TO KNOW.
I'M TALKING ABOUT
THE REAL HISTORY--FROM MAO
TO FANON TO MALCOLM X.
AND IF YOU GOT TROUBLE
READING, WE'LL HELP YOU.
THAT'S RIGHT.
MAN,
I'M OUT OF HERE.
YOU NIGGERS...
CRAZY.
YOU GOT NO GUNS.
ALL THOSE INTERESTED
IN JOINING THE PANTHERS,
SIGN THIS PAPER HERE.
CLEAN THIS SHIT UP.
THEM WHITE BOYS GOING
TO KICK ALL YOUR ASSES.
YOU NEED TO CUT
SOME OF THAT HASSLE
TO PUT THEM IN THEIR
MOTHERFUCKING COFFINS.
Huey:
BROTHER, SIGN THIS SHEET.
I KNOW
YOU COMING BACK.
YOU COMING BACK,
AIN'T YOU?
ALL RIGHT NOW.
WHAT YOU GOT?
LET ME SEE.
THAT'S THE ONE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WHY DO YOU THINK
THAT IS?
WHAT IS?
EVERY TIME A BLACK MAN
GOES TO LIFT HIS HEAD,
THERE'S ANOTHER BLACK MAN
THERE TO CALL HIM CRAZY.
YOU'RE CY'S VIETNAM
BUDDY, RIGHT?           YEAH.
SO YOU KNOW SOMETHING
ABOUT FIREPOWER.
IT'S A BUSTED FIRING PIN.
YOU WANT ONLY
THE LEGAL STUFF, RIGHT?
YEAH,
JUST THE LEGIT STUFF.
NOTHING WRONG
WITH THAT PISTOL.
THE SERIAL NUMBER'S
BEEN FILED.
COP CATCHES YOU
WITH THIS,
HE'LL SAY
YOU EITHER STOLE IT
OR OFFED SOMEBODY
WITH IT.
Mr. Yang: I DON'T WANT
NO COPS COMING TO ME.
YOU GOT A PERMIT TO SELL.
WE GOT CASH. ALL LEGAL.
THEY'RE WORTH
A LOT MORE.
I THOUGHT YOU WERE
A REVOLUTIONARY.
WE CAN'T AFFORD IT
UNLESS YOU CUT US SOME SLACK.
YOU TREAT US RIGHT,
WE BE DOING
A WHOLE LOT OF BUSINESS.
ALL RIGHT?
COME ON NOW.
THAT'S IT?
LET'S GO.
Judge: THE GHETTO
BEING THE GHETTO,
THE PANTHERS HAD
2 OBSTACLES TO OVERCOME--
IGNORANCE AND INERTIA.
THE BIG Is
AS THEY CALLED THEM.
MY BROTHER,
TAKE A PEEK.
TAKE THE PARTY PROGRAM,
MAN.
EXPRESS YOURSELF
[SIREN WAILING]
I HOPE YOU SEE
WHAT YOU'RE DOING.
I SEE YOU WITH HALF A BRA
ON YOUR FACE.
LOOKING LIKE
A FUCKING PIRATE!
ALL YOU GOT TO DO NOW
IS EXPRESS YOURSELF
LOOK, BROTHER,
ONLY A DOLLAR!
REMBRANDT WITH A FRO.
ALL RIGHT.
WHATEVER YOU DO
DO IT GOOD
DO DO
DO-DOO DO-DOO
DO IT GOOD
YEAH
IT'S NOT
WHAT YOU LOOK LIKE
WHEN YOU'RE DOIN'
WHAT YOU'RE DOIN'
IT'S WHEN YOU'RE DOIN',
WHEN YOU'RE DOIN'
WHAT YOU LOOK LIKE
YOU'RE DOIN'
EXPRESS YOURSELF...
Bobby: THAT'S WHAT WE CALL
THE PANTHER PATROL.
WE SEE A BROTHER
GETTING BUSTED,
WE CHECK IT OUT,
MAKE SURE THE PIGS
DON'T BEAT ON HIM.
WE GET HIM A LAWYER, BAIL.
IT'S LIKE WE'RE
POLICING THE POLICE.
DAMN STRAIGHT.
PIGS DON'T LIKE IT.
IT MESSES UP
THEIR CUT
OF THE DRUG TRADE.
DIG IT.
EVERY DAY
THERE'S SOMETHIN' NEW
YOU PULL OUT
YOUR BAG...
AAH!
[CHOKING]
[COCKING GUNS]
HEY! IT'S THE POLICE
AND SOME BROTHERS WITH GUNS.
GET SOME BACKUP!
[GROANING]
GET THE HELL
OUT OF HERE.
GET OUT OF HERE.
Cop: SO, HUEY, WHAT'S
YOUR TELEPHONE NUMBER?
I CONFIRMED MY ADDRESS.
THAT'S ALL I'M REQUIRED
BY CALIFORNIA LAW TO DO.
WE AIN'T BROKEN NO LAW.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
WITH THAT GUN?
WITH YOURS?
LET ME SEE THAT RIFLE.
NO! IT'S PRIVATE PROPERTY.
ACCORDING TO CALIFORNIA LAW,
WE GOT A CONSTITUTIONAL
RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS.
MOVE ALONG. GO ON
ABOUT YOUR BUSINESS!
WAIT! WAIT!
YOU AIN'T GOT
TO GO NOWHERE!
THIS IS YOUR BUSINESS!
STAY RIGHT HERE!
THE LAW SAYS, YOU STAY
AT A REASONABLE DISTANCE--
THAT'S 8 TO 10 FEET--
YOU GOT A RIGHT
TO OBSERVE THE POLICE
CARRYING OUT THEIR DUTIES!
AND YOU'RE STANDING 22 FEET
AWAY FROM THIS...
MAN!
THERE AIN'T NO LAW
BEING BROKEN!
RIGHT.
STAY WHERE YOU ARE.
YOU AIN'T GOT TO GO NOWHERE!
TAKE PART IN THE PROTEST.
LEARN ABOUT
THE BLACK PANTHERS.
IS THAT GUN
LOADED, BOY?
THE FISH AND GAME LAW
CLEARLY STATES
IT'S UNLAWFUL TO CARRY
A LIVE ROUND OF AMMUNITION
IN THE CHAMBER
OF A SHOTGUN OR A RIFLE
IN A VEHICLE...PIG!
[MURMURING]
REFER TO HIM
AS OFFICER.
THEN DON'T REFER
TO HIM AS BOY.
WELL, IS IT LOADED?
IT WASN'T, OFFICER.
BUT NOW IT IS.
[COCKING GUNS]
Man: WHOA, THAT'S
A BAD-ASS NIGGER!
WHAT DO THOSE GUNS
MEAN?
THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY
DECLARES
YOU TRY TO BRUTALIZE OUR
COMMUNITY OR TAKE OUR WEAPONS,
WE'LL SHOOT YOU.
GET BACK!
Woman: JESUS, I THINK
I DONE DIED AND GONE TO HEAVEN!
Man:
HALLELUJAH!
ALL RIGHT.
HOLD IT.
PUT IT THERE.
THE BROTHER HAD
HIS RIFLE UP LIKE THIS.
CALLED THE POLICE A PIG.
THE POLICE
COULDN'T DO NOTHING.
THE BROTHER WAS SPEAKING
ALL KIND OF LAW SHIT.
THIS HERE'S
OUR 10-POINT PROGRAM.
THESE BROTHERS
WASN'T SCARED OF SHIT!
THE POLICE COULDN'T DO
A DAMN THING!
YOU AIN'T NEVER SEEN
NOTHING LIKE IT.
"POINT 1--WE WANT FREEDOM.
"WE WANT THE POWER
TO DETERMINE THE DESTINY
"OF OUR BLACK COMMUNITY.
"2--WE WANT FULL EMPLOYMENT
FOR OUR PEOPLE.
"3--WE WANT AN END
TO THE ROBBERY
BY CAPITALISTS
OF OUR BLACK COMMUNITY."
CHRIST, THEY'RE ASKING
FOR REPARATIONS.
THEY COULDN'T HAVE
THOUGHT THIS UP THEMSELVES.
YEAH, SOUNDS LIKE
THE CONSTITUTION,
MAYBE SOME BILL OF RIGHTS
THROWN IN.
INSPECTOR BRIMMER,
THIS IS NO JOKE.
DURING YOUR SURVEILLANCE,
DID YOU SEE ANY COMMUNISTS
OR OUTSIDE AGITATORS?
I SAW COLORED PEOPLE
HANDING OUT FOOD,
HAVING MEETINGS,
PAINTING,
AND PATROLLING
THE NEIGHBORHOOD
AND HAVING MORE MEETINGS.
THEY ARE UNDERMINING
THE UNITED STATES OF AMERICA!
AND YOU, INSPECTOR, ARE NOT
TAKING YOUR JOB SERIOUSLY.
NOW, COME ON, RODGERS.
NOW, DORSETT,
IF THE BLACK PANTHERS
REMAIN IN YOUR JURISDICTION,
FUNDAMENTAL CHANGES
HAVE TO BE MADE.
LIKE WHAT?
LIKE YOU,
INSPECTOR BRIMMER,
ARE NOT SITTING
IN YOUR CAR ANYMORE.
I THINK IT'S TIME
YOU TOOK A LITTLE MORE
ACTIVE INVOLVEMENT.
[TIRES SCREECH]
ANOTHER BUSY DAY
KEEPING THE STREETS SAFE?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING
OUT SO LATE?
I LIKE TO WATCH OVER
MY CLIENT'S INVESTMENTS.
WE REALLY SHOULD ADDRESS
THAT BUSINESS EXPANSION.
LOOK, I DON'T THINK--
THAT'S A NICE CAR.
IT'S NICE.
YOU REMEMBER WHO
PAID FOR IT, RIGHT?
WE'LL TALK AGAIN...
SOON.
[CY SIGHS]
DID YOU SEE US
ON GROVE STREET
ALL UP ON THE COPS
WITH THAT LAW SHIT?
MAN, IT WAS PERFECT!
IT WAS ALL RIGHT.
GIVE ME A LIFT, MAN?
YOU GOT IT.
BERKELEY CAMPUS?
MAN...NO.
LET'S GO TO
PANTHER HEADQUARTERS.
WE COULD HANG OUT
MORE LIKE WE USED TO.
HA HA! MY BROTHER!
OHH!
I GOT TO TAKE CARE
OF YOU, KID.
GOING TO BE DOWN NOW,
HUH?
AM I DOWN?
I'M DOWN LIKE 4 FLATS
ON A DUMP TRUCK.
SEE, I'M P-D HO.
THAT'S SHORT FOR
"PIMP DOWN HOME."
I SAW YOU PANTHERS
ON GROVE STREET.
EVERYBODY KNOW
Y'ALL GOT THE FINEST PUSSY.
SO SIGN A NIGGER UP.
AS LONG AS
I CAN KEEP MY JOB,
AND KEEP PUTTING FOOD
ON THE TABLE,
I WANT TO BE A PANTHER.
WHITEY DROPS NAPALM
ON THE YELLOW MAN,
SLAUGHTERS AND BETRAYS
THE RED MAN,
ENSLAVES AND MUTILATES
THE BLACK MAN,
AND FUCKS WITH ANYBODY ELSE
HE CAN.
I GOT IT.
YOU GOT THIS
UNDER CONTROL?
ALL RIGHT.
THANKS, BROTHER.
WE'LL BE IN TOUCH.
JUDGE IS JOINING US.
GLAD TO HAVE YOU.
Bobby: CONGRATULATIONS,
MY BROTHER.
THIS MAKES IT OFFICIAL.
COME IN CLEAN, SOBER,
AND READY TO WORK.
COMMUNITY'S
THE FOCAL POINT.
I GOT THAT.
10-POINT PROGRAM.
HUEY WANTS
TO SEE YOU.
ME?
YEAH, YOU.
SAID HE THOUGHT
YOU'D BE COMING BY.
TV Reporter:
IN OTHER NATIONAL NEWS,
PRESIDENT JOHNSON'S
PRESS SECRETARY
HAS EMPHATICALLY DENIED
THE RUMOR THAT THE WHITE HOUSE
IS CONSIDERING ORDERING
THE BOMBING OF CAMBODIA
BY OUR STRATEGIC BOMBERS.
THE VIETCONG HAVE
FURTHER ATTACKED...
WELCOME.
BROTHER JUDGE, HAVE YOU DECIDED
TO GET DOWN WITH US?
[CLEARING THROAT]
YEAH, I'M DOWN.
YOU WERE VERY HELPFUL
WITH THOSE GUNS.
YOUR SOLDIER SHIT--
BAD ASS.
I'D HOPED TO BE DONE
WITH ALL THAT.
YOU'RE LUCKY
TO BE BACK.
MOST BROTHERS DIE
ON THE FRONT LINES.
SEEMS LIKE THAT'S WHAT
THEY'RE THERE FOR.
MIND IF I ASK YOU
A QUESTION?
WHERE'D YOU GET THE MONEY
TO GO TO SCHOOL?
G.I. BILL,
PLUS I GOT SOME
SHRAPNEL IN MY LEG.
IT'S NO PROBLEM
ANYMORE,
BUT I STILL GET MY
DISABILITY CHECKS.
WE HIT A LAND MINE.
I THOUGHT A LAND MINE
WAS SUPPOSED TO BE FATAL.
IT WAS FOR THE 2
GUYS IN FRONT OF ME.
OH, YOU VOLUNTEERED
OR SOMETHING?
REFORM SCHOOL.
THE COURT SAID THAT
OR THE MILITARY.
[SIREN WAILING]
IF I'D STAYED HERE,
I'D END UP DRUNK
OR DEAD.
WHY ALL THE QUESTIONS,
MAN?
SECURITY.
SECURITY
FOR SISTER BETTY SHABAZZ
HAS GOT TO BE TIGHT.
P.A: ARRIVING PASSENGER
MRS. CRANE,
PLEASE SEE
THE TICKET AGENT
AT THE AIRLINE
RESERVATION COUNTER.
MRS. CRANE,
PLEASE SEE
THE TICKET AGENT
AT THE AIRLINE
RESERVATION COUNTER.
BOBBY, TAKE HIM
AND GO INSIDE.
NOW!
WHAT WOULD YOU TELL YOUNG
BROTHERS AND SISTERS TO DO
IN FOLLOWING
BROTHER MALCOLM'S FOOTSTEPS?
WELL,
I WOULD SAY THAT...
MALCOLM LIVES
IN EACH OF US,
AND WE MUST
ALL WORK TOGETHER
FOR THE COMMUNITY,
LIKE THOSE BROTHERS
OUT THERE ARE DOING.
SISTER SHABAZZ, WE THANK YOU.
WE'RE HONORED THAT YOU'VE
CHOSEN SAN FRANCISCO
FOR YOUR FIRST
PUBLIC APPEARANCE
SINCE THE MARTYRDOM
OF MALCOLM.
DO YOU FEEL THE FERVOR
OF THE MOVEMENT WAS LOST
WITH THE DEATH OF MALCOLM?
NO. THE THIRST FOR FREEDOM
WASN'T EXTINGUISHED
WITH HIS MURDER.
THE DESIRE FOR LIBERTY
IS MANIFESTED DAILY...
THE POLICE IS
PULLING UP OUTSIDE.
FALL IN.
LET'S GO, LITTLE BOBBY.
BROTHER HUEY,
NO PICTURES, PLEASE.
YES, MA'AM.
THANK YOU.
I'M NOT GOING.
LET'S PUT THIS GUN AWAY.
I AIN'T GOING TO JAIL.
Reporter:
THERE SHE IS.
HEY, HEY, HEY.
MISS SHABAZZ,
DO YOU FEAR FOR YOUR LIFE?
NO PICTURES TODAY.
BACK UP!
WHO SHOT MALCOLM?
DO YOU THINK
THE FBI WAS LINKED--
NO STATEMENT.
DO YOU THINK FARRAKHAN
WAS INVOLVED?
MOVE BACK! YOU'RE
BLOCKING HER PATH!
BACK UP!
[SIRENS WAILING]
HEY, HEY, BACK UP.
GET AWAY FROM THIS CAR!
LEAVE
THE SISTER ALONE!
MISS SHABAZZ,
A STATEMENT, PLEASE!
SIR, FOR THE LAST TIME,
WILL YOU BACK UP?
I JUST WANT TO ASK
A QUESTION. MISS SHABAZZ,
DO YOU KNOW WHO KILLED
YOUR HUSBAND?
HE ASSAULTED ME!
ARREST HIM!
IF I'M GONNA ARREST ANYONE,
IT'S GONNA BE YOU.
NOT TODAY.
HUEY, COME ON, MAN.
LOWER THE GUNS.
WE DON'T WANT TROUBLE.
RIGHT.
PUT THE GUNS AWAY.
BE A SMART NIGGER
LIKE YOUR FRIEND.
WE AIN'T BROKEN NO LAW.
YOU TRY TO VIOLATE OUR
CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHTS,
WE WILL
DEFEND OURSELVES, PIG!
AREN'T YOU GOING
TO DO ANYTHING?
THEY'RE NOT BREAKING
ANY LAWS, ASSHOLE.
OH.
ALL RIGHT. STEP OUT!
STEP BACK, FOLKS.
STEP BACK.
WE'LL GO AHEAD
AND CALL IT IN.
Reporter: WHAT WAS
MISS SHABAZZ DOING HERE?
IS IT TRUE THE PANTHERS
ARE DEDICATED
TO MALCOLM X?
[ALL SHOUTING QUESTIONS]
AH!
WHOO!
Bobby: DID Y'ALL SEE
THAT JIVE PUNK PANTHER?
[LAUGHING]
HE DOVE UNDER HIS DESK
SO FAST,
HE DROPPED HIS GUN.
DID YOU SEE? DAMN SAD.
IT SURPRISED ME
THEY EVEN SHOWED
UP WITH GUNS.
DIG IT.
THEY AIN'T FIT FOR
THE NAME PANTHERS.
WHOO!
WHAT IT BE, JUDGE?
NOBODY GOT HURT.
SISTER BETTY'S SAFE.
TODAY WAS A GOOD DAY.
CHEER UP.
THAT TALL
PUNK PANTHER'S GUN...
IT WASN'T LOADED.
I BET THE REST
WEREN'T EITHER.
SHIT!
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S FIND OUT.
YOU GOTTA SAY, YEAH
'CAUSE
NO MATTER WHAT...
BROTHER, A LEADER MUST
HAVE COURAGE OF SIMBA.
LION, HMM?
THIS IS ONLY
THE BEGINNING.
REFRESHMENTS,
BROTHER BAKAR?
NO. NO.
BROTHER BAKAR, YOU
SHOULD HAVE BEEN THERE.
THE PIGS LAID DOWN
TO US.
WE'RE FINALLY
GETTING RESPECT,
JUST LIKE
YOU PROPHESIED.
SISTER ALMA.
MORE LIBATION,
PLEASE.
YES, BROTHER.
LIKE I SAID,
BROTHER,
WE ARE THE VANGUARD.
ONCE CLEAVER'S STORY
COMES OUT, THEN YOU'LL SEE--
HEY, MAN, WHAT THE FUCK
ARE YOU DOING?
MALCOLM X's WIDOW'S LIFE
WAS ON THE LINE TODAY,
AND YOUR GUNS
WEREN'T LOADED.
A GUN'S A GUN.
IT DOESN'T NEED TO BE LOADED.
TELL THAT TO THE PIGS.
TELL THAT TO MALCOLM.
WAIT, BROTHER!
NO, YOU WAIT!
YOU AND YOUR
PUNK PANTHERS
ARE
COUNTERREVOLUTIONARY!
YOU GOT 3 CHOICES--
1--MERGE WITH US,
FOLLOW OUR RULES,
2--CHANGE YOUR NAME,
OR 3--WE ANNIHILATE
YOUR ASS--
YOU LISTEN,
PRETTY GHETTO BOY!
YOU'RE A LONG WAY
FROM OAKLAND.
AND YOU'RE NOT MALCOLM.
FUCK YOU!
Huey: YOU'RE THE KIND
OF BROTHER WE DON'T NEED!
YOU GET
OTHER BROTHERS KILLED!
YOU GOING
TO CHANGE YOUR NAME?
BAKAR, TELL HIM
YOU'LL DO IT.
TELL HIM YOU'LL DO IT.
OH. OK...
BUT ONLY FOR
THE REVOLUTION.
UHH!
HELP ME UP.
MOVE OUT!
Lombard:
YOU OK, BROTHER BAKAR?
Bakar: SEE? THIS IS
COUNTERREVOLUTIONARY.
LIKE CRABS IN A BARREL,
PULLING EACH OTHER DOWN.
Lombard:
BROTHER JAMAL,
WHERE YOU GOING, MAN?
Bakar:
FORGET HIM.
BROTHER JAMAL?
[MUSIC PLAYS]
YEAH!
I NEED YOU TO DO
SOMETHING FOR US.
STAYING ALIVE
MIGHT DEPEND ON IT.
WE'RE GOING TO LET
THE PIGS INFILTRATE US.
THEIR SPY IS GOING
TO BE OUR SPY, TOO.
ME?
YOU GOT A BUNCH
OF PEOPLE SIGNING UP.
MEAN NIGGERS
LIKE TYRONE HERE.
WHY ME?
YOU FIT THE PROFILE,
BROTHER.
YOU'RE EXACTLY
THE TYPE OF NIGGER
THEY THINK
THEY CAN TRUST.
[CLINKS BOTTLES]
1--WE WANT FREEDOM AND POWER
TO DETERMINE THE DESTINY
OF OUR BLACK COMMUNITY.
2--WE WANT FULL EMPLOYMENT
FOR OUR PEOPLE.
3--WE WANT AN END TO
THE ROBBERY BY WHITE MEN
OF OUR BLACK COMMUNITY.
4--WE WANT DECENT HOUSING
FIT FOR SHELTER
OF HUMAN BEINGS...
EVERYBODY TALKS ABOUT
WHAT NEEDS TO BE DONE
TO UPLIFT THE RACE.
YOU BROTHERS ARE DOING
SOMETHING ABOUT THAT...
I WANT TO DO IT WITH YOU...
IF YOU'LL HAVE ME.
ALMA...
UH...
I DON'T THINK--
WHAT YOU MEAN?
I'M BLACK, AIN'T I?
I CARE ABOUT IMPROVING
THE PLIGHT OF MY PEOPLE
JUST LIKE YOU, DON'T I?
OR YOU FIGURE OPPRESSION
STOPS WITH THAT THING
DANGLING BETWEEN YOUR LEGS?
HEY, I'M WITH YOU,
SISTER, BUT, UH--
BUT NOTHING.
WE WANT FULL-FLEDGED MEMBERSHIP
IN THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY.
AND NONE OF THAT
"OK, SUGAR,
"AS LONG AS YOU PLAY
THE BACKGROUND,
GETTING MY BEER
AND RUBBING MY FEET"
BULLSHIT EITHER. YOU DIG?
MY BEAUTIFUL
BLACK SISTERS,
AS LONG AS YOU'RE DOWN
WITH THE 10-POINT PROGRAM...
SIGN UP.
Judge:
LIKE MA ALWAYS SAID,
"THE LORD MAY NOT COME
WHEN YOU CALL HIM,
BUT HE'S ALWAYS
RIGHT ON TIME."
Black panther:
6--WE WANT ALL BLACK MEN
TO BE EXEMPT
FROM MILITARY SERVICE.
7--WE WANT
AN IMMEDIATE END...
ALL POWER...
TO THE PEOPLE!
RIGHT NOW!
ALL POWER!
Bobby:
WE WANT THE GOVERNMENT'S POWER
IN THE HANDS OF THE PEOPLE,
WHICH MEANS YOU AND I.
THAT'S WHY WE'RE SAYING
ALL POWER TO THE PEOPLE.
ALL OF US EQUALLY UNITED.
ALL RACES. ALL COLORS.
WHITE POWER TO WHITE PEOPLE.
RED POWER TO RED PEOPLE.
BROWN POWER TO BROWN PEOPLE.
YELLOW POWER
TO YELLOW PEOPLE.
BLACK POWER TO BLACK PEOPLE.
SEE?
ALL POWER TO THE PEOPLE.
Y'ALL DIG?
REPEAT AFTER ME--
ALL POWER TO THE PEOPLE.
NOW, PUT YOUR FIST UP.
THERE YOU GO.
YEAH, I LIKE THIS.
Black panther:
9--WE WANT ALL BLACK PEOPLE
BROUGHT TO TRIAL TO BE
TRIED IN ACCORDANCE...
Judge:
THE BLACK COMMUNITY
WAS STARTING TO SEE THINGS
THE PANTHERS' WAY.
SLOWLY IT WAS BEGINNING
TO SOLIDIFY BEHIND US.
BLACK WAS BEAUTIFUL, MAN.
FAST,
CLASSY,
ASS-KICKIN',
AND NAME-TAKIN', TOO.
Black panther: AS OUR MAIN
POLITICAL OBJECTIVE,
A UNITED NATIONS-SUPERVISED
PLEBISCITE
HELD THROUGHOUT
THE BLACK COLONY
IN WHICH ONLY
BLACK COLONIAL SUBJECTS
WILL BE ALLOWED
TO PARTICIPATE
FOR THE PURPOSE OF DETERMINING
THE WILL OF BLACK PEOPLE
AS TO THEIR
NATIONAL DESTINY.
GO!
WE GOT TO GET MORE POWER
TO THE PEOPLE
FOR GOD'S SAKE
WHY DON'T YOU GET
MORE POWER
TO THE PEOPLE?
5-6-7, OPEN UP
THE PEARLY GATES
WELL, THERE AIN'T NO TIME
TO WONDER WHY
WHOOPEE! WE'RE ALL
GOIN' TO DIE...
ONLY A DOLLAR.
10 DIMES. GET THEM.
THEY'RE GOING FAST.
YOU'RE JUDGE, RIGHT?
I'M BRIMMER.
WE NEED TO TALK--
OFF THE RECORD.
I GOT NOTHING TO SAY TO YOU
ON OR OFF ANY RECORD.
YEAH, YOU DO.
WE CAN TALK HERE
OR GO DOWNTOWN.
DIDN'T YOUR MOTHER
ASSAULT A POLICE OFFICER
AT 55th AND MARKET
NOT LONG AGO?
OF COURSE,
UH, JUDGE,
THIS IS ALL
JUST CONJECTURE.
LET'S WALK AND TALK.
COME ON.
HERE'S THE DEAL.
YOU HELP ME OUT
SOMETIMES,
AND I'LL MAKE SURE
EVERYTHING STAYS CLEAN.
YOU CAN BE A BIG HELP
TO YOUR COUNTRY.
WE BOTH FOUGHT FOR
AMERICA--KOREA, NAM.
WE BOTH KNOW AMERICA'S
GOT PROBLEMS.
IT'S STILL THE LAND
OF OPPORTUNITY.
EQUAL OPPORTUNITY.
I KNOW WHAT I'M
TALKING ABOUT, JUDGE.
MY FOLKS WERE
IMMIGRANTS, DIRT POOR.
THEY PULLED THEMSELVES
UP BY THE BOOTSTRAPS.
YOU BELIEVE ALL THAT,
DON'T YOU?
I WOULDN'T BE A COP
IF I DIDN'T.
SOLDIER, WITHOUT
LAW AND ORDER,
THESE STREETS
WOULD JUST BE CHAOS,
AND YOU KNOW IT.
NOW, LOOK HERE, JUDGE,
WE DON'T ASK SOMETHING
FOR NOTHING.
WE KNOW THAT COLLEGE
IS EXPENSIVE THESE DAYS.
WE'D LIKE TO HELP OUT.
WHAT DO YOU SAY?
[SOFTLY]
I'M LISTENING.
PARDON?
YOU DO MORE
THAN LISTEN.
YOU CALL ME
BY WEDNESDAY,
ALL RIGHT?
THAT NUMBER.
OK?
A COUPLE OF BUCKS
IN IT FOR YOU.
ALL RIGHT.
SEE YOU, JUDGE.
Children:
GOOD MORNING, MR. ALLAN.
POWER TO THE PEOPLE.
OK, TYRONE.
THEY TRIED TO RECRUIT ME
JUST LIKE YOU SAID.
YEAH.
PROBABLY NOT THE ONLY
ONE THEY CAME AFTER.
STALL A LITTLE SO THEY
THINK YOU'RE FOR REAL.
EAT UP YOUR FOOD.
GET SOME NUTRITION.
TYRONE, YOU THINK
FEEDING OUR CHILDREN
WILL MAKE THE MAN JUMPY?
I DON'T KNOW.
SEEMS TO ME BLACK FOLKS
IS GETTING MIGHTY UPPITY--
FEEDING THEIR KIDS
BREAKFAST,
TRYING TO TAKE THEIR DESTINY
IN THEIR OWN HANDS.
MAKES ME WONDER WHAT
THIS WORLD'S COMING TO.
OFFICER, NO!
DON'T SHOOT!
FREEZE, DAMN IT!
I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING!
TURN AROUND NOW!
[GUNSHOTS]
THE POLICE LIED.
THEY SAID HE WAS TRYING
TO STEAL A CAR.
MY BABY
WOULDN'T STEAL NO CAR.
MAMA...
MAMA, THESE BROTHERS HERE
ARE FROM THE BLACK PANTHER
PARTY FOR SELF DEFENSE.
I ASKED THEM OVER
FROM OAKLAND.
I THANK Y'ALL FOR COMING
TO GRIEVE WITH US.
POLICE WON'T TELL US
NOTHING.
THEY BEEN SHOOTING
BLACK MEN AROUND HERE
LIKE WE GOING
OUT OF STYLE.
LORD HAVE MERCY.
MY BOY DIDN'T DO NOTHING.
CAN'T SOMEBODY
DO SOMETHING?
YES, MA'AM. WE CAME
TO DO SOMETHING.
WHAT DO WE WANT?
JUSTICE!
ALL POWER
TO THE PEOPLE!
ALL POWER TO THE PEOPLE!
ALL POWER
TO THE PEOPLE!
THE POLICE SAY
BROTHER DENZIL DOWELL
WAS TRYING TO STEAL A CAR.
[MURMURING]
THAT HE LEAPED A FENCE
AND RAN THROUGH A FIELD
OF BROKEN GLASS AND OIL,
BUT WHEN WE CHECKED,
THE BOTTOM OF HIS SHOES
WERE CLEAN.
IF ANY OF Y'ALL KNEW DENZIL,
YOU KNEW
HE WAS IN A CAR ACCIDENT,
THAT HE WALKED WITH A LIMP.
HE COULDN'T HAVE HOPPED
ANY FENCE.
THE POLICE REPORT
SAYS QUITE CLEARLY
DENZIL WAS SHOT 3 TIMES,
BUT THE CORONER'S
REPORT SAYS
DENZIL DOWELL WAS SHOT
6 TIMES.
2 OF THOSE SHOTS
WERE IN HIS ARMPITS,
BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
YOU KNOW WHY THAT IS?
BROTHER DENZIL
HAD HIS HANDS UP.
WHAT DO WE WANT?
JUSTICE!
WE NEED MORE PROGRAMS.
THEY'RE IN THE CAR.
AMEN, BROTHERS AND SISTERS.
LET US BOW OUR HEADS
AND PRAY.
I MISSED
YOUR PHONE CALL.
SHOULD HAVE TOLD ME
ABOUT THIS.
DON'T WORRY.
I'M JUST PLAYING
ROUGH COP
SO YOUR
SOUL BROTHERS
WON'T KNOW
WE'RE PARTNERS.
JUSTICE!
WHAT DO WE WANT?
COME ON, MAN.
NO. IT'S JUST HARASSMENT.
WE GOT MOMENTUM,
BROTHER.
Crowd:
ALL POWER TO THE PEOPLE.
YOU'RE NOT COMING
IN HERE WITH NO GUN.
THE FIREARM
IS IN PLAIN VIEW,
THEREFORE, IT'S LEGAL
BY CALIFORNIA STATUTE.
THIS IS PUBLIC PROPERTY
PAID FOR BY THE PEOPLE.
OVER MY DEAD BODY.
THAT'S YOUR CALL,
PIG.
WE DIDN'T COME
FOR BLOODSHED.
WE COME FOR JUSTICE,
BUT DON'T BE PUSHING US
TOO FAR.
BOYS, PLEASE.
[CHEERING]
Huey: IF THE POLICE DEPARTMENT
HAS NOTHING TO HIDE,
WHY COULDN'T THE DOWELL
FAMILY OBSERVE THE BODY?
IF HE BLED TO DEATH,
WHY DOES
THE CORONER'S REPORT SAY
HE WAS SHOT TO DEATH?
WE DEMAND A GRAND JURY
INVESTIGATION
INTO DENZIL DOWELL'S DEATH
AND THE PATTERN
OF BRUTALITY
AGAINST THE BLACK
CITIZENS OF RICHMOND.
THE POLICE DEPARTMENT
HAS CONDUCTED
ITS OWN INQUEST
AND CONCLUDED
THAT NO MISCONDUCT
OCCURRED.
AS FAR AS A PATTERN
OF BRUTALITY,
THE CHARGE
IS RIDICULOUS.
WHAT DO YOU CALL 4 DEAD
BLACK MEN IN 6 MONTHS?
I CALL IT THE POLICE
DOING THEIR DUTY
UNDER THE LAW.
YOU GOT A PROBLEM
WITH ANY LAW,
YOU TAKE IT
TO THE LEGISLATURE.
I THINK THE PIG
MIGHT HAVE A POINT.
GET THE HELL OUT
OF MY OFFICE!
Brimmer: LOOK HERE,
THE LAW'S CHANGING.
YOU WON'T BE ABLE TO CARRY
THEM GUNS MUCH LONGER.
WE UNDERSTAND
EACH OTHER, JUDGE?
Judge: YEAH.
ALL RIGHT. I EXPECT
TO HEAR FROM YOU REAL SOON.
HUEY NEWTON TAKES A CRAP,
I WANT TO KNOW ABOUT IT.
OTHERWISE, I'M GOING
TO COME LOOKING FOR YOU.
I WON'T BE NEAR AS FRIENDLY
AS I WAS TODAY.
JUDGE, YOU GOT TO
REMEMBER SOMETHING--
YOU GOT A LOT AT STAKE
HERE.
LOOK, THE PANTHERS
ARE GOING TO LOSE.
THE ONLY QUESTION IS
ARE YOU GOING TO LOSE
ALONG WITH THEM?
YOU'RE GOING TO LOSE
YOUR FUTURE,
YOUR MOTHER, YOUR LIFE.
NOW THINK ABOUT IT.
ALL RIGHT, SOLDIER,
GO ON. GET OUT OF HERE.
GO ON.
Bobby: HOW Y'ALL DOING
OUT THERE?
ALL RIGHT!
YOU KNOW,
IT'S INTERESTING.
JUST AS BLACK PEOPLE
START TO EXERCISE
THEIR RIGHT TO BEAR ARMS,
THE PIGS
WANT TO CHANGE THE LAW.
WE AIN'T GOING
TO MAKE IT EASY FOR THEM
TO HAVE NO UNARMED TARGETS,
ARE WE?
HAVE A GOOD TIME
AND ENJOY YOURSELVES
'CAUSE THIS HERE
IS YOUR COMMUNITY.
IT'S OUR COMMUNITY.
IT'S A BEAUTIFUL THING.
THAT'S RIGHT.
JUST DO ME ONE FAVOR.
SAVE ME SOME OF THAT
BARBECUE OUT THERE.
ALL RIGHT,
LISTEN TO THE BAND,
HAVE A GOOD TIME.
LOVE YA.
OH-HO OH-HO
STAND, IN THE END
YOU'LL STILL BE YOU
ONE THAT'S DONE
ALL THE THINGS
YOU SET OUT TO DO
STAND
THERE'S A CROSS
FOR YOU TO BEAR
THINGS TO GO THROUGH
IF YOU'RE GOIN'
ANYWHERE
OOH
STAND...
WONDERFUL PICNIC.
WHAT A DAY.
WE JUST NEED THEM 10 EXTRA
GUNS, WE'LL BE STRAIGHT.
FOR THE 10 BROTHERS
COMING LATER.
ALL RIGHT. SOLID.
RIGHT ON.
HUEY, WE GOT
29 PANTHERS GOING,
INCLUDING THAT REPORTER
FROM, UH, RAMPARTS, CLEAVER.
THAT'S 30.
THIS IS GOING TO BE
A COLOSSAL EVENT.
WE'RE GOING TO TURN
THE CAPITAL OUT.
FAR OUT, BABY.
FAR OUT.
COOL IT BOBBY, MAN.
WHAT IT BE, BROTHER?
YOU AIN'T GOING
WITH US, HUEY.
WE'RE THE LEADERSHIP,
YOU AND ME.
THERE AIN'T ENOUGH
OF US AS IT IS.
THE PIGS DON'T KNOW
HOW MANY PANTHERS THERE ARE.
IF BOTH OF US SHOW UP,
THEY MIGHT PUT 2 AND 2 TOGETHER.
WE AIN'T EVEN 100 STRONG,
BUT WE GOT THEM GUESSING
THOUSANDS.
OK.
I'LL GO, YOU STAY.
OH, NO.
WE TOOK A VOTE.
YOU'RE TOO RISKY.
IT'S DECIDED. YOU STAY.
GO ON AND MOW YOUR MAMA'S
LAWN LIKE YOU PROMISED.
ALL RIGHT.
ALL RIGHT,
I'LL STAY. YOU GO.
JUDGE...
WANT A BEER?
HEY, JUDGE,
WHERE YOU BEEN, MAN?
I SAW THE PIGS
ROUSTING YOU. YOU OK?
YEAH, MAN.
IT WAS JUST HARASSMENT.
MY DRIVER'S LICENSE
EXPIRED.
PIGS, MAN, THEY BE
GRABBING AT ANYTHING.
SO WHAT'S THE PIG'S NAME?
BRIMMER.
YOU GOT TO STAY COOL
ON THIS,
ICY-GODDAMN-COOL.
YOU JUST BECAME
THE STRONGEST WEAPON WE GOT.
LET ME GUESS. THAT PIG
WANTS YOU TO CALL HIM
AND TELL HIM
WHAT WE'RE DOING.
YEP.
YOU'RE GOING TO DO
JUST THAT,
BUT I'M GOING TO TELL YOU
WHAT TO FEED THE PIG.
YOU ALL RIGHT
WITH THIS?
YEAH, YEAH, I GUESS.
HEY, MAN, DO ANY OF
THE OTHER BROTHERS
KNOW ABOUT THIS?
SHIT'S GETTING
PRETTY THICK, HUEY.
IT'S GOING TO GET
A WHOLE LOT THICKER...
FOR ALL OF US.
WELL, ISN'T THAT NICE.
WHAT EXACTLY
IS YOUR NAME?
GOVERNOR, ARE YOU RUNNING
FOR THE NATIONAL TICKET?
ARE YOU KIDS
ALL FROM THE SAME AREA?
GOVERNOR,
WHAT ABOUT THE MULFORD ACT?
I'D SAY THE SAME THING
I SAY TO ALL THE YOUTH.
REMEMBER THE 3 Rs--
READING, WRITING,
ARITHMETIC--
AND YOU CAN BECOME
LAWYERS, DOCTORS.
THAT'S WHAT AMERICA'S
ALL ABOUT.
COME ON, LET'S GO.
IS THIS
A MILITANT ACTION?
ARE THE PANTHERS
STORMING THE CAPITOL?
ABSOLUTELY NOT. WE'RE
HERE TO SEND A MESSAGE.
BLACK PANTHER PARTY
CALLS UPON AMERICANS
TO TAKE CAREFUL NOTE
OF THE RACIST
CALIFORNIA LEGISLATURE
NOW CONSIDERING
THE MULFORD ACT,
AIMED TO KEEP BLACK PEOPLE
DISARMED AND POWERLESS
WHILE THE RACIST
POLICE AGENCIES
THROUGHOUT THIS COUNTRY
INTENSIFY THE TERROR,
BRUTALITY, MURDER,
OPPRESSION
OF BLACK PEOPLE.
NOW I GOT A QUESTION
FOR YOU.
WHICH WAY IS
THE STATE ASSEMBLY?
RIGHT UP THERE
ON THE SECOND FLOOR, SIR.
GOOD MAN. ALL POWER
TO THE PEOPLE.
CALL THE POLICE.
CALL THE POLICE NOW.
YOU GUYS CAN'T...
WAIT A MINUTE, GUYS.
YOU CAN'T COME IN HERE.
WE'RE HERE TO OBSERVE
THE ASSEMBLY.
YOU TRYING TO DENY US
OUR CONSTITUTIONAL RIGHTS?
MY GOD!
CALL SECURITY.
DON'T SHOOT US.
Radio: 29 ARMED NEGROES
STORMED INTO
THE STATE CAPITOL TODAY.
BOBBY SEALE,
THE BLACK PANTHER LEADER,
CALLED THE NEW
ANTIGUN PROPOSAL RACIST.
GOVERNOR REAGAN
HAD THIS TO SAY.
Reagan: THE BLACK PANTHERS
ARE A MILITANT FRINGE GROUP
WHO ARE USING FEAR
AND INTIMIDATION
AGAINST THE OAKLAND
POLICE DEPARTMENT.
Reporter: THE BLACK PANTHER
PARTY MADE A WRONG TURN
AND ACCIDENTALLY WALKED
ONTO THE ASSEMBLY FLOOR
INSTEAD OF
THE VISITORS GALLERY.
THE BLACK PANTHERS
ARE NOT ANTIWHITE.
WE ANTIOPPRESSION.
YOU CAN'T FIGHT RACISM
WITH RACISM.
Reporter: THE LAW
THE PANTHERS BROKE
IS DISTURBING
THE ASSEMBLY.
26 BLACK PANTHERS HAVE BEEN
ARRESTED IN SACRAMENTO.
Judge: WE LOST BOBBY.
HE SERVED 6 MONTHS
FOR TAKING
THAT WRONG TURN.
THE MULFORD ACT
EVENTUALLY PASSED,
SO WE LOST THE RIGHT
TO CARRY GUNS.
ONE THING WE DID GET
WAS WORLDWIDE ATTENTION.
YEAH, DISCIPLINED NIGGERS
MARCHING WITH GUNS,
THAT GOT
EVERYBODY'S ATTENTION.
THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY
FOR SELF DEFENSE
CLAIMS TO BE THE VOICE
OF THE BLACK COMMUNITY.
HOWEVER, ANALYSIS
OF OUR FIELD REPORT
REVEALS A HIGH LEVEL
OF ORGANIZATIONAL SKILLS.
WE'VE BEEN DOWN
THIS ROAD BEFORE.
WHAT WE HAVE HERE
IS A CLASSIC EXAMPLE
OF OUTSIDE AGITATION.
BLACK TERRORISTS
ON THE FLOOR
OF A STATE CAPITOL?
I WON'T HAVE IT.
THIS IS OBVIOUSLY
AN ORGANIZATION
FUNDED AND MASTERMINDED
BY SOME COMMUNIST POWER
HOSTILE
TO THE UNITED STATES.
THE ONLY QUESTION IS
WHICH ONE?
BEFORE WE CRUSH
THESE UNGRATEFUL COONS,
FIND OUT
WHO THEIR REAL BOSS IS.
YES, SIR.
GENTLEMEN.
WE'RE GOING FOR A RIDE.
GET IN THE BACK SEAT.
WE AIN'T GOT ALL DAY.
WHY DIDN'T YOU TELL ME
ABOUT THIS PARTY
YOU BOYS WERE PLANNING
AT THE CAPITOL?
THE SHIT WAS SPONTANEOUS.
YOU TOLD THE PRESS.
YOU DIDN'T TELL ME.
REMEMBER
WHO YOU'RE WORKING FOR.
WHATEVER YOU SAY,
MAN.
YOU SASSING ME?
YOU LITTLE PIECE
OF SHIT!
I'LL GET YOUR BLACK ASS.
SASS ME, WILL YOU?
GET OUT OF
THE FUCKING CAR!
"WHATEVER YOU SAY,
INSPECTOR BRIMMER."
YOU'RE FUCKING RIGHT,
WHATEVER I SAY.
I'M GOING TO MAKE SURE
YOUR WIRY HEAD'S
SCREWED ON STRAIGHT.
GET UP HERE.
YOU KNOW HOW EASY
IT WOULD BE
FOR YOU TO DISAPPEAR?
ALL THESE DRIVERS SEE
IS A WHITE COP
AND A BLACK CONVICT
IN HANDCUFFS.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
YEAH, WHAT
DO YOU WANT, MAN?
I WANT YOU TO GET YOUR ASS
OUT OF NEUTRAL.
SET THE PANTHERS
ON A PLATE FOR ME.
SET THEM UP
FOR ARMED ROBBERY.
THE PANTHERS
DON'T ROB NOBODY.
THEY DON'T OPERATE
LIKE THAT.
YOU JUST DO IT.
LIKE YOUR MAN SAYS,
"BY ANY MEANS
NECESSARY."
OK! ALL RIGHT!
ALL RIGHT!
ALL RIGHT.
SOMETHING
FOR YOUR TUITION.
GET BACK
IN THE FUCKING CAR.
WHAT'S HAPPENING, BRO?
WHERE'S JUDGE? I AIN'T
SEEN HIM AROUND LATELY.
BETWEEN SCHOOL, HIS JOB,
AND THE PANTHERS,
HE'S BEEN RUNNING
KIND OF RAW.
I GOT TO TAKE A LEAK.
HEY!
I KNOW THIS FOOL AIN'T SELLING
DRUGS IN OUR NEIGHBORHOOD.
GO ON. USE MY PAD.
LET ME HANDLE THIS.
I'VE BEEN KICKING HIS
ASS SINCE HIGH SCHOOL.
I'LL SEE YOU OUT AT
THE MEETING, ALL RIGHT?
WHAT DO YOU GOT
TO SELL?
EVERY BLACK MAN
AIN'T A DOPE DEALER.
WHAT DID HE MEAN
BY THAT?
I TOLD YOU FOR THE LAST
TIME, STOP PUSHING
THAT FUCKING POISON
IN THE NEIGHBORHOOD!
YOU'RE POISONING
YOUR OWN PEOPLE, FOOL!
FUCK THAT
BLACK POWER SHIT!
I'M DOWN WITH GREEN
POWER AND FUCK YOU!
FUCK YOU, ALL RIGHT?
DON'T MAKE ME COME
BACK HERE, ALL RIGHT?
ALL RIGHT?
LET'S STRAIGHTEN IT OUT
OOH
LET'S STRAIGHTEN
IT OUT...
CY, IS THAT YOU?
I'LL BE OUT
IN A MINUTE, MAN.
HEY, HEY, HEY.
OFFICER, I WAS--
I WASN'T DOING NOTHING.
COME HERE. COME HERE.
PANTHERS TURNED INTO SOME
REAL SHITHEELS, AIN'T THEY?
YES, SIR. THEY'RE GETTING
ALL HIGH AND MIGHTY.
IF THIS
WAS MY NEIGHBORHOOD,
I'D STAND UP
FOR MYSELF,
IF YOU KNOW
WHAT I MEAN.
YES, SIR.
SAW THE PIGS ROUSTING
YOU, MAN. YOU OK?
Judge: YEAH, MAN.
IT WAS JUST HARASSMENT.
MY DRIVER'S LICENSE
EXPIRED.
YEAH, RIGHT.
Huey: ALL RIGHT, Y'ALL,
LOOK AROUND YOU.
WE GOT NEW MEMBERS
JOINING EVERY DAY.
NEWLY APPOINTED MEMBERS
FROM OUR NEWARK CHAPTER
VISITING FROM THE EAST,
STAND.
I'D LIKE TO INTRODUCE
ANOTHER NEW MEMBER TO YOU--
THE AUTHOR OF SOUL ON ICE
AND A RESPECTED JOURNALIST.
I'M PROUD TO INTRODUCE
OUR NEW MINISTER OF INFORMATION,
ELDRIDGE CLEAVER.
YOU'RE ALL WELL AWARE
OF THE CHAINS
THAT WE AS A PEOPLE BEAR--
THE CHAINS OF SLAVERY,
OF SECOND-CLASS CITIZENSHIP.
BUT THERE ARE OTHER
MORE INVISIBLE CHAINS--
CHAINS OF NOT
SPEAKING YOUR MIND,
CHAINS OF ALL THE WORDS
LEFT UNSAID
OUT OF FEAR OF REPRISAL
BY THE MAN,
THE SILENCING
OF OUR BLACK VOICES.
I'M HERE TO TELL YOU
WE HAVE A VOICE, DIG IT?
THAT'S RIGHT.
I'D LIKE
TO PROVE IT TO YOU.
EVERYBODY
REPEAT AFTER ME.
FUCK RONALD REAGAN.
I'M SERIOUS.
FEEL GOOD, DON'T IT?
YEAH.
ALL RIGHT.
AMAZING HOW SPEAKING YOUR MIND
CAN FREE YOUR SOUL.
THANK YOU,
BROTHER ELDRIDGE,
MINISTER OF INFORMATION.
SISTER, HEY.
WAS YOU PAYING
ATTENTION?
THE PIGS MUST HAVE
PLANTED HER
SO THEY COULD
BUST US.
I'LL HANDLE THIS.
I'M OK.
I'LL BE ALL RIGHT.
COME ON, SISTER,
LET'S GO.
AND REPORT
TO YOUR CADRE LEADER.
DON'T FORGET WE GOT
OUR RED BOOK HERE ON SALE.
EACH ONE TEACH ONE.
WE'VE GOT TO REACH OUT
TO OUR BROTHERS ON THE STREET.
THAT'S WHAT THE 10-POINT
PROGRAM IS ALL ABOUT.
BROTHER HUEY,
CAN I TALK TO YOU?
YEAH, CERTAINLY.
ALONE.
NOT RIGHT NOW,
BROTHER.
I'M TALKING
SOME BUSINESS
WITH THE MINISTER
OF INFORMATION.
TOMORROW. TOMORROW.
OK, SO, I DON'T KNOW
IF IT'S EXACTLY...
CAN'T YOU SEE YOU'RE
JEOPARDIZING THE MOVEMENT?
THE PIGS ARE LOOKING FOR ANY
EXCUSE TO COME DOWN ON US.
I DON'T WANT MY BABY
TO BE NO JUNKIE.
I WANT MY BABY
TO BE FREE.
THAT'S WHAT WE ALL WANT.
YOU AIN'T GOING
TO HURT ME, IS YOU?
YOU'RE HURTING YOURSELF
AND THAT BABY, TOO.
SISTER, YOU GOT
TO STOP KILLING US.
YOU GOT TO STOP
KILLING THAT CHILD.
Huey: JUDGE,
YOUR INFORMATION
IS VITAL TO US, MAN.
HOW VITAL
COULD IT BE, MAN?
WE GOT CHAPTERS
ALL OVER NOW.
THIS IS PANTHER
INTERNATIONAL HEADQUARTERS.
THE POLICE WILL START
RUNNING GAMES HERE FIRST.
WHO'LL STRAIGHTEN OUT
THE OTHER BROTHERS
WHEN THEY GET ON MY ASS?
LIKE THE MANUAL
SAYS,
"INFORMATION
IS DISSEMINATED...
ON A NEED-TO-KNOW
BASIS."
HERE'S ANOTHER DONATION
FROM THE PIGS.
IF THE PIGS KNEW
THEY WERE SUBSIDIZING
THE PANTHERS...
THEY WANT A LOT
FOR THEIR MONEY, MAN.
THEY WANT A FELONY
WITH VIOLENT INTENT.
IF THEY DON'T GET IT,
THEY'LL KILL ME.
IF THEY DO,
THE PANTHERS WILL KILL ME.
MAN, I HEAR THAT.
BUT I WOULD RATHER
DIE ON MY FEET
THAN LIVE
ON MY KNEES.
COME HERE.
PIG FUCKING
INFILTRATOR!
EASE UP, SISTER!
SELL OUT!
WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU TRYING TO PROVE?
THIS BOOT-LICKING
HOUSE NIGGER
SIGNED UP
ABOUT A MONTH AGO.
SAYS HIS NAME'S MATTY.
I CALL HIM SPY.
OH!
MOTHERFUCKER GAVE THE PIGS
THE LICENSE NUMBER
OF EVERY PANTHER CAR!
NO!
SHOW US SOME JUSTICE,
TYRONE.
PIG.
IS THIS THE FINGER
YOU RATTED ON US
TO THE PIGS WITH?
CUT ME SOME SLACK.
AAH!
FUCKER!
GET THE FUCK DOWN!
WHERE YOU GOING?
YOU DON'T LIKE TO SEE
A TRAITOR GET HURT?
I WONDER WHY THAT IS.
YOU GOT SOMETHING
TO SAY, YOU SAY IT.
IF ANYTHING HAPPENS
TO HUEY--
BROTHER JUDGE, IT'S CY,
MAN, HE'S BEEN SHOT.
WHO DID THIS
TO YOU, CY?
WHO DID IT
TELL ME.
WHO?
WHO, BROTHER, WHO?
TALK TO ME.
FIGHT NOW! FIGHT!
NOW FIGHT! FIGHT, BROTHER!
I'M WITH YOU!
I'M RIGHT HERE!
I'M HERE!
WHO DID IT TO YOU?
WHO DID IT TO YOU, CY?
WHO, BABY?
I'LL GET
AN AMBULANCE!
TELL ME, CY!
JUST TELL ME WHO!
JUST TELL ME!
NO! NO! NO! NO!
NO! NO!
NO! CY, NO!
I'M SORRY!
INSPECTOR BRIMMER.
Judge:
YEAH, IT'S ME.
JUDGE, HOLD ON.
IS YOUR PHONE SAFE?
WHO FUCKING CARES, MAN?
YOU COPS KILLED CY.
BEFORE YOU BASTARDS
KILL ANYBODY ELSE,
I'LL GIVE YOU YOUR FUCKING
SETUP, ALL RIGHT?
THAT MAKE YOU HAPPY?
JUDGE.
JUDGE NOTHING. YOU SHUT UP,
AND YOU LISTEN.
I'M WORKING WITH YOU.
THAT'S WHAT YOU WANTED.
YOU GOT ME NOW.
ALL RIGHT.
LISTEN UP. IT'S GOING DOWN
RIGHT ON TIME.
WHAT'S UP WITH YOU,
MAN?
NOTHING, MAN.
I ASKED YOU
A QUESTION.
SOMETHING ON
YOUR MIND, BROTHER?
MY BEST FRIEND
IS STONE-DEAD, BROTHER.
I'M SORRY.
HEY, I'M SORRY, TOO.
I GOT TO TAKE A LEAK.
BOBBY, PULL OVER
AT THIS GAS STATION HERE.
IF YOU WANT GAS,
MY NEPHEW WILL BE BACK
IN ABOUT 10 MINUTES,
AS USUAL.
WHERE'S YOUR BATHROOM?
IT'S OUT BACK.
OPEN THE REGISTER
AND GIVE ME THE MONEY.
DON'T HURT ME.
I'M NOT FUCKING AROUND,
MAN. MOVE.
I DON'T WANT TO HURT YOU.
MOVE!
[SIREN]
HOW LONG
CAN A PISS TAKE?
WHAT THE FUCK?
PIGS, MAN!
OUT OF THE CAR.
JUST TAKE IT EASY.
TAKE IT EASY!
NOW! I SAID NOW.
EVERYONE, STOP.
WE AIN'T BROKEN
NO LAWS.
DON'T HIM THEM
IN THE FACES!
I WANT THEM
RECOGNIZABLE.
EASY, BOY.
I'LL BLOW YOU AWAY.
WE DIDN'T DO NOTHING!
YOU FASCIST PIGS,
STOP HARASSING US!
YOU STUCK UP
THIS FILLING STATION.
WE GOT A WITNESS.
WHAT KIND OF BULLSHIT
IS THAT?
CUFF HIM.
I'LL GET HIM.
JUDGE! JUDGE!
JUDGE, IT'S ME, BRIMMER.
GET OUT OF HERE!
HOW DARE YOU?
GET BACK THERE!
TODAY'S ARREST EXPOSES
THE BLACK PANTHERS
FOR WHAT
THEY TRULY ARE--
COMMON CRIMINALS.
YES, WE HAVE A GROUP
OF SO-CALLED
REVOLUTIONARIES IN CUSTODY,
CAUGHT RED-HANDED ROBBING
A LOCAL BUSINESS.
AS SOON AS OUR WITNESS
GIVES US
A POSITIVE IDENTIFICATION,
WE'LL BE FILING CHARGES
OF ARMED ROBBERY
WITH INTENT TO KILL.
SIR, WAS ANYONE HURT?
I HAVE
NO FURTHER COMMENTS.
JUST SOME SHINES, HUH?
NOW THEY GOT
THEIR OWN NEWSPAPER.
HOLY MOTHER OF GOD.
WHEN'D
THEY START THIS?
THAT COMES OUT
NEXT WEEK.
A YEAR AGO,
THEY DIDN'T EXIST.
NOW THEY GOT CHAPTERS
ALL OVER THE COUNTRY.
HOOVER'S LOOKING INTO
REACTIVATING
THE INTERNMENT CAMPS.
HE'S NOT GOING TO LET
THIS PEACE MOVEMENT
AND THIS BLACK POWER THING
GET OUT OF--
YEAH.
FOLLOW ME.
Man: IT'S HIS NEPHEW'S
GAS STATION.
Second man:
YOU KIDDING ME?
HE STANDS IN FOR THE SAME
15 MINUTES EVERY MORNING.
Man: NUMBER ONE,
TAKE YOUR HAT OFF.
HEY. IS HE SERIOUS?
AHEM...
BOSS,
THE MAN'S BLIND.
HE CAN'T SEE
ANYTHING.
WHAT ARE YOU
TELLING ME?
BLIND AS A BAT, SIR.
COULDN'T I.D.
HIS OWN MOTHER.
HE JUST STANDS IN
FOR HIS NEPHEW
DURING BREAK PERIODS.
RETIRE.
Man: ALL RIGHT, BOYS,
TURN TO YOUR LEFT.
MOVE ON OUT. BACK
TO THE HOLDING TANK.
Reporter: GOVERNOR REAGAN ADDED
THAT SUCH ACTS OF LAWLESSNESS
WILL NOT BE TOLERATED.
Reagan: I WANT TO
APPLAUD THE EFFORTS
OF THE LOCAL
POLICE AUTHORITIES
TO SUPPRESS
THE VIOLENCE...
WHOA, WHOA.
WHOA, SOLDIER BOY, WHOA.
HOLD ON NOW.
...ALL IN THE NAME
OF PEACE.
LOOK AT THAT--
BEATING THE SHIT OUT OF
THEIR OWN YOUNG FOLK.
YOU NEED
SOME OF THIS.
TO CALM DOWN.
NO. I'M ALL RIGHT.
WHAT'S WRONG?
Reporter: BLACK PANTHER PARTY
MEMBERS WERE FREED...
PANTHERS
DONE GOT OUT.
FOR LACK OF WITNESSES
IN THAT
FILLING STATION ROBBERY.
THOSE YOUR PEOPLE,
RIGHT?
THIS TAKE THE HEAT
OF YOU ANY?
I'M NOT SURE,
BUT I'LL FIND OUT.
FREEDOM NOW!
I GOT TO GO.
I'LL CATCH YOU.
HEY, JUDGE.
JUDGE, JUDGE,
JUDGE.
MAN, I SHOULD'VE
TOLD YOU THIS BEFORE,
BUT, YOU KNOW...
FUCK IT.
WHAT?
MAN, IT WAS...
IT WAS SABU
WHO KILLED CY.
THERE'S YOUR 3
RIGHT THERE.
YOU GOT TO BE
A CARD-CARRYING MEMBER
OF THE STUPID REVOLUTION.
STAY THE FUCK
AWAY FROM ME.
I TOLD YOUR ASS.
WHERE IS HE?
I DON'T KNOW, MAN.
FROM WHAT I HEAR,
HE DONE PACKED UP HIS BAGS
AND WENT OUT OF TOWN.
WHY DIDN'T
YOU TELL ME?
I DIDN'T WANT NOBODY
TO THINK I WAS NO SNITCH.
HOW WOULD THAT
LOOK ON ME?
KNOW WHAT I'M SAYING?
YEAH, MAN, I KNOW.
STAY GOOD, MAN.
YOU BE GOOD, TOO,
BABY.
WHERE THE HELL
IS JUDGE?
BROTHER JUDGE NEEDS
OUR SUPPORT RIGHT NOW,
NOT OUR SUSPICION.
OH, THIS IS BEAUTIFUL.
FOLKS AIN'T NEVER SEEN
NO TRUTH LIKE THIS.
HUEY, CHECK THIS OUT.
WHAT'S WITH ALL
THIS, ELDRIDGE?
WHITE MEDIA HAS
CONTROLLED OUR IMAGE.
WE GOT TO LET
THE BROTHERS KNOW
WHAT WE'RE ABOUT
OURSELVES.
THAT'S WHAT
OUR NEWSPAPER WILL DO.
A LOT OF BROTHERS
DON'T READ. DIG?
WE GOT TO GIVE THEM
A STRONGER IMAGE.
TYRONE, GET YOUR ASS
IN HERE.
THIS PICTURE WILL BE
WORTH A THOUSAND WORDS.
THOUGHT ABOUT THAT PEACE
AND FREEDOM PARTY THING?
THEY REALLY WANT
TO HOOK UP WITH US.
WE'VE BEEN INVITED
TO THEIR RALLY.
WHAT DOES
BROTHER JAMAL THINK?
I THINK POOR BLACK FOLKS
ARE FIGHTING FOR THEIR HUMANITY
AND POOR WHITE FOLKS ARE
FIGHTING FOR MORE MONEY.
WHITE BOYS CAN GET A HAIRCUT
AND JOIN THE ESTABLISHMENT,
BUT US--
WE'RE BLACK FOREVER.
SISTER ALMA,
SHARE YOUR THOUGHTS.
THE FBI's LEANING
ON OUR PRINTER
LOOKING FOR AN EXCUSE
TO CANCEL THE CONTRACT.
DEADLINE FOR THE NEXT ISSUE
OF THE PAPER IS TOMORROW.
CIRCULATION IS UP--
125,000 AND RISING.
WE'RE SEIZING THE TIME.
THE TIME IS WHAT
SARTRE CALLED
THE MOMENT THE MATCH
IS PUT TO THE FUSE.
NOW, IS THE HAND
HOLDING THE MATCH
BLACK OR WHITE?
ALL RIGHT.
NO FULL-FLEDGED ALLIANCE,
BUT WE WILL ACCEPT
THE RALLY INVITATION.
RIGHT ON.
BROTHER ELDRIDGE,
SET IT UP.
LOOK LIKE A WARRIOR.
HELL, NO! WE WON'T GO!
A FEW DAYS AGO,
WE CAME TO THESE STEPS
TO PROTEST.
WE WERE 4,000 THEN,
AND THE COPS
BEAT US DOWN.
[BOOING]
TODAY...
WE ARE 10,000!
[CHEERING]
10,000 DIFFERENT VOICES
IN UNISON
SAYING ONE THING...
[TIRES SCREECH]
THAT YOU CANNOT HAVE
AN IMPERIALISTIC WAR ABROAD
AND SOCIAL PEACE AT HOME.
SUSPECT JUMPED
THE BACKYARD FENCE,
HEADING EAST
ON MARKET STREET.
IN PURSUIT.
SO IT IS WITH THIS UNITY,
THIS PURPOSE, IN MIND,
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN...
HE'S CUTTING
THROUGH THE PARK.
DEFENSE MINISTER
OF THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY--
HUEY NEWTON.
HUEY! HUEY!
THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY'S
PROUD TO BE HERE TODAY.
[CROWD CHEERS]
NOT FAR FROM HERE,
BROTHER BOBBY SEALE'S
LOCKED DOWN...
[CROWD BOOS]
A VICTIM OF THE TYRANNY
WE FEEL HERE AT HOME.
THAT SAME TYRANNY
IS AT WORK
MANY THOUSANDS OF MILES
FROM HERE IN VIETNAM.
THANKS A LOT,
ASSHOLE.
THAT "BLIND MAN"
THING WAS REAL CUTE.
THE ONLY QUESTION
YOU CAN ASK IS...
I GOT HIM.
THANK YOU, GUYS.
WHY SHOULD THE BLACK MAN
GO FIGHT THE YELLOW MAN
FOR THE WHITE MAN?
THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY
IS OPPOSED TO THE WAR
IN VIETNAM.
WE KNOW OUR WAR
IS HERE AT HOME
AGAINST HARD DRUGS
IN THE COMMUNITY,
AGAINST UNEMPLOYMENT.
THAT, BROTHERS AND SISTERS,
IS OUR WAR.
POWER TO THE PEOPLE!
HELL, NO!
WE WON'T GO!
WHAT THE HELL'S THIS?
INSPECTOR BRIMMER,
COULD YOU COME
IN HERE A MINUTE?
WHAT'S GOING ON, CHARLIE?
THE FEDS--
THEY'RE MOVING IN.
OH, LORD.
COME ON, GUYS,
LET'S GO.
HAVE A SEAT, INSPECTOR,
PLEASE.
GENTLEMEN,
THIS IS PRUITT.
HE'LL BE WORKING WITH US
FROM HERE ON IN.
BUT--BUT ISN'T HE...
SPECIAL PEOPLE
FOR SPECIAL PROBLEMS.
I DIDN'T KNOW
THE FBI HAD--
THERE ARE MANY THINGS
YOU DON'T KNOW.
SHALL WE GET
TO THE POINT?
THE BLACK PANTHERS
HAVE UNITED
WITH OTHER ORGANIZATIONS
SPONSORED BY THE COMMUNISTS
TO UNDERMINE OUR EFFORTS
IN VIETNAM.
IN THE OPINION
OF MR. HOOVER,
THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY
IS PUBLIC ENEMY NUMBER ONE.
THEY HAVE, QUITE SIMPLY,
GUARANTEED
THEIR OWN EXTINCTION.
JESUS.
I DON'T EVEN
NEED TO SAY
YOUR DEPARTMENT'S HANDLING
OF THE BLACK PANTHERS--
IN PARTICULAR,
INSPECTOR BRIMMER'S
SO-CALLED
UNDERCOVER OPERATION--
HAS BEEN
A COMPLETE TRAVESTY.
MEMO FROM
THE COMMISSIONER, ET CETERA,
BACKING
MR. HOOVER'S DECISION
TO PLACE
THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY
AND THEIR
SUBVERSIVE ACTIVITIES
UNDER THE FULL JURISDICTION
OF THE BUREAU.
MOVE IT!
MOVE! MOVE!
Kathleen Cleaver: THIS PATTERN
OF HARASSMENT
IS GOING ON AGAINST
THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY
ACROSS THE COUNTRY.
ON FRIDAY, THE WATTS OFFICE
OF THE BLACK PANTHER PARTY
WAS BOMBED
AND DEMOLISHED.
LAST WEEK, THE DES MOINES
OFFICE WAS BOMBED.
THIS WEEK THEY RAIDED
THE SAN FRANCISCO OFFICE.
THEY SHOOT US,
SHOOT TEAR GAS
IN OUR OFFICE,
AND DRAG PEOPLE
OFF TO JAIL.
PHYSICALLY
YOU LOOK BLACK,
BUT YOU DON'T KNOW
WHO YOU ARE.
YOU DON'T KNOW
WHERE YOU'RE FROM.
YOU'VE BEEN GIVEN A SLAVE NAME
AND A SLAVE MENTALITY.
A SLAVE HATES HISSELF,
HATES HIS SKIN.
A SLAVE HATES
HIS NATURAL KINKY HAIR.
GIVE A GUN TO A SLAVE,
HE'LL KILL HIS BROTHER.
HOW LONG ARE YOU
GOING TO CRY
AND BLAME
YOUR OPPRESSOR
BEFORE YOU GET UP
OFF YOUR KNEES
AND DO IT
YOUR GODDAMN SELF?
KNOW THE 10 POINTS.
IF YOU DON'T,
YOU DO NOT KNOW
WHAT YOU'RE LIVING
AND DYING FOR.
Fred Hampton: YOU GOT
TO MAKE A DECISION,
STAND UP AGAINST THE PIGS.
THAT'S WHAT
THE PANTHERS ARE DOING HERE,
THEY CAN DO ANYTHING
THEY WANT TO TO US.
I AM...
A REVOLUTIONARY.
AFTER THAT GOOD DOCTOR
IS GONE,
THERE'LL NEVER BE
ANOTHER BLACK MESSIAH
UNLESS WE CREATE HIM.
WHAT'S
YOUR NAME, BOY?
5.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
WHAT'S YOUR NAME,
PUNK?
I SAID, 5.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME?
WHAT'S WITH
THE NAME?
I KEEP SAYING 5,
LIKE THE FIFTH AMENDMENT,
AND THIS COP'S
GETTING PISSED.
THERE AIN'T MUCH
HE CAN DO TO ME
SO HE GIVE ME
A TICKET FOR LITTERING
ON ACCOUNT OF THE PAPER
HE RIPPED OUT OF MY HAND.
THEY CAN'T DO TOO MUCH
WITH THAT MANY EYES ON THEM.
THEY AIN'T NOTHING
BUT RACIST COPS.
[SIREN]
SHIT.
WELL, WELL, WELL.
IF IT ISN'T THE GREAT
HUEY P. NEWTON.
LICENSE
AND REGISTRATION.
GET OUT OF THE CAR.
CALIFORNIA LAW DOES NOT
REQUIRE A DRIVER
TO LEAVE A VEHICLE.
OUT OF THE FUCKING CAR!
YOU GOT A PROBLEM
WITH ENGLISH, BOY?
YOU, TOO.
WHAT'S THE PROBLEM,
OFFICER?
I'M NOT
RESISTING ARREST,
NOR AM I ARMED.
ANY USE OF FORCE
ON YOUR PART IS ILLEGAL.
LET'S GO
FOR A WALK.
AM I UNDER ARREST?
[GUNSHOTS]
HUEY!
OH, MY GOD!
SON OF A--
[MOANING]
THIS DOCTOR IS ALL
PREPARED FOR SURGERY.
HE HAS INTERNAL BLEEDING.
OK, WHAT HAVE
WE GOT HERE?
GUNSHOTS--
MULTIPLE.
GET OUT OF THE WAY!
BACK OFF!
THAT'S A COP KILLER.
YOU KILLED A COP, BOY!
[ANGRY SHOUTING]
[PAINFUL SCREAMING]
GET THEM
OUT OF HERE!
GET BACK!
[CHANTING MUSLIM PRAYER]
ALL RIGHT.
MOVE IT NOW.
COME ON.
STAY STRONG,
MY BROTHER.
POWER TO THE PEOPLE,
BOBBY.
RIGHT ON, MAN.
ALL RIGHT, MAN,
DON'T LET THEM
BREAK YOU.
WHERE'S THE LAWYER?
RIGHT DOWN THERE.
CAN HE FREE HUEY?
IF ANYBODY CAN,
HE'S THE MAN.
WHERE'S HE AT?
IT'S GOING TO WORK.
JUST MAKE SURE THE FOCUS
STAYS ON FREEING HUEY.
WE CAN'T MAKE ENOUGH
OF THESE THINGS.
WE GOT MOVIE STARS
CALLING UP TO HELP.
BROTHERS AND SISTERS,
IT'S NATION TIME.
I WISH WE DIDN'T
NEED THESE BUTTONS.
I WISH
HUEY WAS HERE.
ME, TOO.
YOU SURE ABOUT THAT,
MY BROTHER?
LOOK AT THIS.
Judge: YOU COULD JAIL
A REVOLUTIONARY,
BUT YOU COULDN'T
JAIL THE REVOLUTION.
DESPITE THE PIGS
AND THE FBI,
OUR POWER BASE
IN THE BLACK COMMUNITY
CONTINUED TO GROW.
EVEN MOM CAME AROUND.
WELL?
SERIOUS NOW.
I COME OUT
OF THAT WIG.
ELDRIDGE,
COME MEET MY MOTHER.
MA, THIS
IS ELDRIDGE CLEAVER.
ELDRIDGE CLEAVER,
THIS IS MY MOTHER.
HERE'S THE GUY
I TOLD YOU ABOUT.
BE PROUD
OF YOUR SON.
SAY IT LOUD--
I'M BLACK,
AND I'M PROUD.
Judge: EVERYTHING IN HERE--
BUTTER, SALT, GREASE--
YOU ARE
THE MALNUTRITION PANTHER,
THAT'S WHAT YOU ARE.
Y'ALL NEED
TO BE EATING MORE.
RUNNING AROUND HERE
LIKE SCARECROWS.
YOU DON'T EAT,
YOU DON'T SLEEP.
TAKE THIS HAT OFF
AT THE TABLE.
AIN'T NO WAY TO LIVE.
IT'S GOOD
TO BE SKINNY--
EASIER TO RUN
FROM FAT PIGS.
TV: WE BRING YOU
THE FOLLOWING SPECIAL REPORT.
MARTIN LUTHER KING JR.
WAS KILLED TONIGHT IN MEMPHIS,
SHOT IN THE FACE
AS HE STOOD ALONE
ON THE BALCONY
OF HIS HOTEL ROOM.
HE DIED IN A HOSPITAL
AN HOUR LATER.
LAST NIGHT,
HE SAID THIS...
King: I JUST WANT
TO DO GOD'S WILL.
HE NEVER
HURT NOBODY.
HE HAS ALLOWED ME TO GO
UP TO THE MOUNTAIN,
AND I'VE LOOKED OVER
AND I'VE SEEN
THE PROMISED LAND.
I MAY NOT
GET THERE WITH YOU,
BUT I WANT YOU
TO KNOW TONIGHT
THAT WE AS A PEOPLE
WILL GET
TO THE PROMISED LAND.
[CHEERING]
SO I AM HAPPY TONIGHT.
I'M NOT WORRIED
ABOUT ANYTHING.
I'M NOT FEARING ANY MAN.
MINE EYES
HAVE SEEN THE GLORY
OF THE COMING
OF THE LORD.
HEY, JOE
A-WHERE YOU GOIN'
WITH THAT GUN
IN YOUR HAND?
Judge: WHEN KING'S MESSAGE
OF NONVIOLENCE
ENDED
IN HIS VIOLENT DEATH,
FOLKS FINALLY REALIZED
THAT THEY COULDN'T
PRAY THEIR WAY TO FREEDOM--
JUST WHAT THE PANTHERS
HAD SAID ALL ALONG.
AMERICA WAS BURNING.
NATIONWIDE, OUR ENROLLMENT
DOUBLED IN 2 WEEKS.
NO, NO.
NO MORE WORDS!
NO MORE WORDS.
NO MORE SITTING.
NO MORE PRAYING,
WAITING FOR THE PIGS
TO KILL US.
LATER FOR LYING DOWN,
WAITING TO GET SHOT
LIKE DOGS.
NONVIOLENCE DIED IN MEMPHIS
WITH DR. KING.
WE MUST RETALIATE.
WE GOT THE FUCKING GUNS.
IT'S TIME
TO USE THEM.
HOLD ON,
MOTHERFUCKER!
BROTHER, I HEAR YOU,
BUT I DISAGREE.
AND WE BOTH KNOW
HUEY DISAGREES.
YEAH, WE GOT GUNS,
BUT THE PIG
HAS GOT MORE GUNS.
THE PIG HAS GOT
THE NATIONAL GUARD.
I AIN'T AFRAID TO FIGHT,
BUT WE AIN'T STUPID EITHER.
THIS HERE IS A TIME
TO BE SMART.
NO. LATER FOR THAT.
NO, LATER FOR YOU.
NOW LISTEN UP, MAN.
WHAT, WE GOING TO FORGET
ABOUT HUEY AND HIS TRIAL?
START KILLING PIGS?
START THE REVOLUTION NOW
WITH ONE OF OUR
LEADERS IN JAIL?        YEAH.
MAN, IF WE DO THAT,
HUEY'S A DEAD MAN.
WE'RE ALL DEAD.
NO, MAN. WE STAY COOL.
OH, WHAT?
YOU GIVING ME
ORDERS NOW?
I'M JUST TELLING YOU
WHAT IT IS.
LATER FOR THAT.
IT IS TIME TO INTENSIFY
THE STRUGGLE.
THAT'S WHAT IT IS.
GOT TO GO.
BOB--
DAMN.
OH, MAN.
Huey: WE MUST
STAY DISCIPLINED.
TO ACT WITHOUT A PLAN
IS COUNTERREVOLUTIONARY.
WE MUST STOP ELDRIDGE.
EL RAGE IS EL RAGE.
YOU KNOW HIM.
HE GOT TO RECOGNIZE
YOU'RE PARTY LEADER.
IT AIN'T EASY
RUNNING AROUND LECTURING
TRYING TO RAISE BREAD
TO DEFEND YOUR ASS.
YOU ALWAYS COULD
TALK YOUR BUTT OFF.
HEY. DON'T WORRY
ABOUT ME.
DON'T WORRY
ABOUT YOU?
IT AIN'T THE SAME
WITHOUT YOU, HUEY.
ALL POWER TO THE PEOPLE.
ALL POWER
TO THE PEOPLE.
YOU GOT TO SIT
ON ELDRIDGE.
HERE YOU GO.
KEEP PASSING
IT DOWN.
HERE YOU GO.
ALL RIGHT.
SHELLS.
GIVE ME
MORE SHELLS.
PIGS BE HERE
ANY MINUTE.
WE READY
FOR THEM.
THIS IS
FOR BROTHER MALCOLM...
BROTHER MARTIN...
AND BEING
A MOTHERFUCKING PIG.
[SIREN APPROACHING]
NOW!
GO! GO! GO!
OUT! OUT! OUT!
THERE THEY ARE!
COME ON,
GET UP!
GET UP.
COME ON!
COME ON.
LET'S GO!
COME ON, MAN.
GET INSIDE.
STAY DOWN!
AAH!
OH, NO!
STOP THEM!
HELP! HELP! HELP!
AH!
AAH!
HOLD YOUR FIRE!
STAY DOWN,
LITTLE BOBBY.
[CRYING]
GET US OUT.
GO!
P.A.: COME OUT
WITH YOUR HANDS UP!
UHH!
LOOK OUT!
YOU HURT?
THROW DOWN YOUR WEAPONS
AND COME OUT
WITH YOUR HANDS UP!
I'M OK.
YOU HAVE 5 SECONDS.
TAKE YOUR CLOTHES OFF.
WHAT?
THE PIGS AIN'T GOING
TO SHOOT YOU
IF YOU'RE NAKED
AND UNARMED.
3...
JUST DO IT!
KEEP YOUR HANDS UP.
KEEP YOUR HANDS UP,
BOBBY.
DON'T TRY ANYTHING!
I'M NOT
RESISTING ARREST!
PUT YOUR HANDS
ON THE CAR!
AAH!
NO! NO!
MOTHERFUCKERS!
HE WAS GOING FOR THIS.
AND I SAY
TO THE FAMILY AND FRIENDS
THAT I STAND HERE
WITH THIS STRANGE
FEELING OF JOY
AND THANKSGIVING,
KNOWING
THAT OUR YOUNG BROTHER
DID NOT DIE IN VAIN.
HE DIED FOR THE PEOPLE.
AND, OUT OF HIS DEATH,
WE MUST GO BACK
TO OUR COMMUNITY
WITH THIS NEW SENSE
OF LIFE FORCE
FOR LIBERATION.
HE SAID IT WELL,
"POWER TO THE PEOPLE."
HE WAS JUST A KID.
BROWN POWER
FOR BROWN PEOPLE,
RED POWER
FOR RED PEOPLE...
THEY HURTING US,
BABY.
HUEY'S
LOCKED UP.
WHITE POWER
FOR WHITE PEOPLE...
BOBBY RUNNING ALL
OVER THE COUNTRY
AND TRYING TO HOLD
THINGS TOGETHER.
CY'S DEAD,
AND LITTLE BOBBY.
I DON'T EVEN
RECOGNIZE
HALF THE FACES
AT THE MEETINGS...
EXCEPT HIS.
NOW, LOOK, I GOT
TO GO GET ON A PLANE,
GO RAISE MONEY
FOR HUEY'S TRIAL.
I WANT YOU ALL
TO MAKE SURE
THERE'S A STRONG
PANTHER PRESENCE THERE.
HEAR ME?
YES, SIR.
ALL RIGHT.
WHAT ABOUT
ELDRIDGE?
YOU DID GET HIM
OUT ON BAIL?
YEAH,
BUT THINGS
GETTING TOO HOT.
ELDRIDGE IS...
IS GOING TO DISAPPEAR.
THE FREE HUEY THING'S
BECOME
A BIT OF A RALLYING CRY
FOR THE LEFT,
ESPECIALLY WITH
BOBBY SEALE RUNNING AROUND
FANNING THE FLAMES.
RALLYING CRY!
THAT'S INSURRECTION!
SIR, THE PANTHERS HAVE
BECOME VERY RESOURCEFUL.
I'M AFRAID
WE'VE UNDERESTIMATED
THEIR SUPPORT
IN THE BLACK COMMUNITY.
THAT'S THEIR POWER BASE.
THEY SAY A BLACK PANTHER
IS BORN EVERY MINUTE
IN THE GHETTO.
TELL HIM I WANT THAT
POWER BASE NEUTRALIZED!
MR. HOOVER WISHES THE ULTIMATE
CONTINGENCY IMPLEMENTED.
YOU MEAN...
THAT'S EXACTLY
WHAT I MEAN!
AND AGENT RODGERS, THIS
CONVERSATION NEVER OCCURRED.
Dorsett: RODGERS,
THIS IS NO GOOD.
Rodgers: CUT THE COMEDY.
YOU'VE BEEN TAKING
MONEY FROM THE MOB
FOR YEARS.
GENTLEMEN, FORGIVE ME
FOR KEEPING YOU.
AHH, DORSETT, NO MATTER
HOW WE DENY IT,
WE ALWAYS END UP ON
THE SAME SIDE OF THE COIN.
IT'S ALMOST FUNNY.
HONESTLY,
IT TURNS MY STOMACH.
NEITHER YOUR STOMACH
NOR YOUR OPINION
MATTERS HERE, DORSETT.
WHAT MATTERS IS THAT
MR. TYNAN'S CLIENTS
AND THE BUREAU HAVE
COME UP WITH A SOLUTION
TO OUR PANTHER PROBLEM.
THE FINAL SOLUTION,
YOU MIGHT SAY.
OUR CLIENTS, OF COURSE,
ARE VERY PLEASED
MR. HOOVER DECIDED TO TAKE
OUR SUGGESTION TO HEART.
BY THE WAY, WHY DID
HE CHANGE HIS MIND?
WOMAN'S INTUITION.
ARE YOU SURE YOU CAN
CONTROL THE PRODUCT?
CAN YOU ASSURE US
THAT THIS WILL NOT
GET OUT OF HAND?
OF COURSE.
OUR CLIENTS HAVE
VAST EXPERIENCE
IN THESE COMMUNITIES.
IT'S JUST A MATTER
OF DEGREES.
YOU GIVE US FREE REIGN
IN THE GHETTO,
WE SOLVE YOUR PROBLEMS.
I'LL ASSURE YOU
OF ONE THING.
THE PACIFYING QUALITIES
OF HEROIN ARE FORMIDABLE.
A JUNKIE'S POLITICS
ARE NOT LIKE YOURS AND MINE.
I'LL EVEN READ
THE FUTURE FOR YOU--
VERY SOON,
THE JIGABOOS--
NO OFFENSE--
THE JIGABOOS WILL BE
WANTING THE STUFF SO BAD--
TRYING TO GET,
TO SELL--
THEY'LL BE BLOWING
EACH OTHER'S BRAINS OUT.
IT'S NOT A RACIAL ISSUE.
IT'S A MATTER
OF LAW AND ORDER.
OF COURSE.
AT ANY RATE,
WE JUST SET THEM UP
AND STEP BACK.
WHEN CAN YOU GET IT
OUT IN THE STREETS?
AS QUICK AS POSSIBLE.
WE'LL MANUFACTURE AND
DISTRIBUTE FROM A WAREHOUSE.
DORSETT KNOWS THE LOCALE.
I REITERATE.
WE NEED ASSURANCES
ON CONTAINMENT...
THAT IT STAYS STRICTLY
WITHIN THE PROBLEM AREA.
I WANT YOU TO PUT
SOMEBODY ON THIS.
KEEP TABS
ON THE NEW OPERATION.
NO OFFENSE.
YOU TALK AS IF
THIS THING'S BEEN DECIDED.
IT HAS BEEN.
PIGS FIND HIM YET?
NO, THEY HAVEN'T.
THEY DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHO WAS IN THE CAR
WITH YOU.
GOOD LUCK, HUEY.
WHY ARE YOU HERE?
FREE HUEY!
ALL POWER TO THE PEOPLE!
POWER TO THE PEOPLE!
BROTHERS AND SISTERS,
STOKELY CARMICHAEL!
YOU SAY THAT HUEY P. NEWTON
IS A PRISONER OF WAR.
NOW, MANY PEOPLE SAY
THAT THAT'S NOT TRUE
OR THAT THE PARTY
IS EXAGGERATING.
NO!
BUT I THINK IT'S CLEAR--
IT'S CRYSTAL CLEAR
THE UNITED STATES HAS
DECLARED WAR ON BLACK PEOPLE.
[SHOUTING]
NOW, SHE DID THAT
WHEN SHE TOOK THE FIRST
BLACK MAN FROM AFRICA.
AH, SHE NEVER CAME OUT
AND SAID THE WORDS--
"I DECLARE WAR
ON BLACK PEOPLE."
NO, SHE DIDN'T DO THAT.
BUT LET US STUDY
OUR HISTORY.
TO THIS DAY,
THE UNITED STATES
HAS NOT DECLARED WAR
ON VIETNAM,
BUT THERE IS VIETNAM.
AND THEY DID NOT
DECLARE WAR IN NORTH KOREA,
BUT THEY SURE FOUGHT
IN NORTH KOREA.
AND THEY DID NOT DECLARE WAR
ON THE INDIANS.
THEY JUST WIPED THEM OUT.
RIGHT ON!
THEY WIPED THEM OUT!
THAT'S RIGHT!
SO...
WE MUST DEFINE
OUR POSITION.
WE ARE AT WAR.
HUEY P. NEWTON,
MINISTER OF DEFENSE,
IS A PRISONER OF WAR.
THAT'S RIGHT!
WE MUST GET HIM OUT
BY ANY MEANS NECESSARY!
FREE HUEY!
SO?
WE KNOW FOR SURE
THERE WAS A PASSENGER.
WE JUST DON'T KNOW WHO.
YOU CAN'T HELP BUT ADMIRE
THOSE YOUNG BROTHERS.
THEY DO A LOT OF GOOD
IN THEIR COMMUNITIES.
YOU EVER HEARD
ABOUT THE COMMON GOOD?
THE UNITED STATES
OF AMERICA IS MORE
THAN A SIMPLE COLLECTION
OF GHETTOS.
THIS COUNTRY WAS BUILT
ON CAPITALISM
AND DEMOCRACY.
IN A DEMOCRACY,
THE MAJORITY RULES.
WE ARE A MINORITY UNLESS
WE INTEGRATE FULLY.
WHOSE SIDE
ARE YOU ON, BROTHER?
NO. WHOSE SIDE
ARE YOU ON, OFFICER?
NOW, YOU SAY
THAT HUEY NEWTON
OPENED FIRE THAT NIGHT
WITHOUT ANY PROVOCATION.
WHAT MAKES YOU SO SURE?
IT WAS A DARK NIGHT.
THERE WAS
LOTS OF CONFUSION.
WELL, SIR,
I WAS THERE.
THAT'S RIGHT, YOU WERE.
HE WAS THERE.
HE SAW EVERYTHING.
AND HE IS NOT ON TRIAL.
HE DOES NOT NEED TO LIE
TO SAVE HIS OWN LIFE.
YOUR WITNESS.
THANK YOU.
NO QUESTIONS,
YOUR HONOR.
WELL, YOU MAY STEP DOWN.
BUT IF IT PLEASE
THE COURT,
I WOULD LIKE TO INTRODUCE
TESTIMONY AT THIS TIME
FROM A NEW WITNESS,
ONE WHO, UH, IS NOT
ON TRIAL FOR HIS LIFE,
BUT ONE WHO WAS
ALSO THERE.
I CALL...
GENE McKINNEY
TO THE STAND.
I OBJECT,
YOUR HONOR!
WHO IS THIS MAN?
THIS IS AN EYEWITNESS,
YOUR HONOR--
THE PASSENGER
IN HUEY NEWTON'S CAR.
Judge: OVERRULED.
MR. GARRY, YOU MAY
EXAMINE YOUR WITNESS.
Bailiff: DO YOU SWEAR
TO TELL THE WHOLE TRUTH,
NOTHING BUT THE TRUTH
SO HELP YOU GOD?
I DO.
MR. McKINNEY,
WERE YOU A PASSENGER
IN THE CAR THAT NIGHT,
OCTOBER 28, 1967?
I KEEP SAYING 5,
LIKE THE FIFTH AMENDMENT.
YES. YES, SIR, I WAS.
AND DID YOU WITNESS
THE SHOOTOUT?
[GUNSHOTS]
YES, SIR, I DID.
[CROWD TALKING]
ORDER. ORDER.
FROM WHAT YOU SAW...
DID HUEY NEWTON
START THE SHOOTING?
LOOK, AM I
UNDER ARREST?
'CAUSE ACCORDING
TO CALIFORNIA--
TAKE THAT LAW BOOK AND SHOVE
IT UP YOUR ASS, NIGGER!
NO! HUEY!
HUEY!
NO, SIR, HE DID NOT.
ORDER!
FREE HUEY!
Judge: ORDER!
ORDER!
WELL, THEN...
DID SOMEONE ELSE
START
THE SHOOTING?
I REFUSE TO ANSWER
THAT QUESTION
ON THE GROUNDS THAT
IT MIGHT INCRIMINATE ME.
[CROWD TALKING]
Judge: ORDER!
ORDER!
DID YOU SHOOT THE
OFFICERS IN QUESTION?
AGAIN I WILL TAKE THE FIFTH
AMENDMENT ON THAT QUESTION
ON THE GROUNDS THAT
IT MIGHT INCRIMINATE ME.
Judge: ORDER!
ORDER!
FREE HUEY!
Reporter:
THIS JUST IN.
GENE McKINNEY PLEADED
THE FIFTH AMENDMENT,
AND IN DOING SO,
DREW SUSPICION FROM
HUEY P. NEWTON TO HIMSELF.
IF NEWTON DID NOT
INITIATE THE SHOOTING,
CHARGES AGAINST HIM
COULD BE GREATLY REDUCED.
HOWEVER, HAVING BEEN
GRANTED IMMUNITY
IN EXCHANGE FOR TESTIFYING,
McKINNEY HIMSELF
CANNOT BE PROSECUTED.
FREE HUEY!
REVOLUTION HAS COME
Huey: YOU FIT
THE PROFILE, BROTHER.
YOU EXACTLY THE TYPE OF NIGGER
THEY THINK THEY CAN TRUST.
NO!
Eldridge: NOW
WE MUST RETALIATE.
WE GOT
THE FUCKING GUNS.
IT IS TIME
TO USE THEM!
YOU DON'T LIKE TO SEE
A TRAITOR GET HURT?
ANYTHING HAPPEN TO HUEY,
I'M GOING TO FUCK YOU UP.
Brimmer: THE PANTHERS
ARE GOING TO LOSE.
ARE YOU GOING TO LOSE
ALONG WITH THEM?
LOSE YOUR FUTURE,
YOUR MOTHER, YOUR LIFE.
JUDGE, OPEN UP!
IT'S ME--BRIMMER!
COME ON!
OPEN THE DOOR!
JUDGE, WAKE UP.
WE GOT
TO GET OUT OF HERE.
GET OUT OF HERE?
COME ON.
WE'RE ON THE MOVE.
I DONE SOME FUCKED-UP THINGS
ON THE FORCE,
BUT NOTHING
LIKE THIS.
DORSETT ORDERED ME
TO BABYSIT SOME DOPE DEALERS.
COME ON, GET OUT.
LET'S GO.
RUN.
GET OUT OF HERE.
SO YOU CAN SHOOT ME
IN THE BACK
AND CALL IT
RESISTING ARREST?
I AIN'T GOING
TO SHOOT YOU.
JUST GET OUT
OF HERE.
IT'S OVER.
GET OUT.
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
YOU FUCKED UP, MAN.
THIS WHOLE FUCKING
COUNTRY'S FUCKED UP!
THEY'RE GOING
TO FLOOD THE GHETTO
WITH CHEAP DOPE.
THEY'RE GOING
TO STORE IT
IN THAT WAREHOUSE
I TOOK YOU.
I JUST DON'T KNOW
WHAT'S GOING ON.
THIS THING, IT'S BIGGER
THAN YOU AND ME.
THE PANTHERS
ARE DEAD.
THEY KILLED YOU!
YOU JUST
DON'T KNOW IT.
IT'S OVER.
FUCK THAT.
AIN'T NOTHING OVER.
Judge, Judge.
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
LISTEN.
WHAT I GOT
TO TELL YOU RIGHT NOW
IS JUST BETWEEN
ME AND YOU
AND THESE RATS
AND ROACHES.
NOW, LISTEN.
SABU'S BACK.
MOTHERFUCKER.
WAIT.
HOLD ON. HOLD ON.
HOLD ON THERE, BABY.
SABU GOT JUICE NOW.
YOU KNOW
HOW HE LEFT--
HE LEFT HERE
ON HIS ASS.
HE CAME BACK HERE,
AND HE'S TALKING LARGE,
LIVING EVEN LARGER.
YOU TAKE CARE
OF YOURSELF.
OF YOURSELF, MAN.
OK.
ALL RIGHT.
THE PIGS ARE
GOING TO LET THE MOB
FLOOD THE COMMUNITY
WITH DOPE.
WE'VE ALWAYS HAD DRUGS.
NO, NOT LIKE THAT.
A WHOLE 'NOTHER
LEVEL.
HUEY, THEY'RE OUT
TO NEUTRALIZE US.
WE GOT TO STOP THIS NOW.
I'M ON IT.
POWER TO THE PEOPLE.
POWER TO THE PEOPLE,
BROTHER.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
YEAH, BLACK PANTHER PARTY
FOR SELF DEFENSE.
CONGRATULATIONS,
ASSHOLE. HUEY GOT OFF,
BUT WE GOT YOUR BOY
BOBBY SEALE.
WHAT THE HELL
YOU TALKING ABOUT?
BOBBY'S AT A WEDDING.
GET YOUR HANDS
OFF ME, GOD DAMN IT!
NOT ANYMORE,
HE'S NOT.
[SNAPPING FINGERS]
WE'RE TAKING HIM TO
CHICAGO ON CONSPIRACY,
CONSPIRACY?
WHO THE FUCK IS THIS?
IT'S THE TOOTH FAIRY.
OH, BY THE WAY,
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
LIKE TO KNOW
WHO GAVE US BOBBY.
HIS NAME IS JUDGE.
HEY, WHAT'S
HAPPENING, MAN?
WHAT'S UP, ROSE?
HOW YOU DOING?
IT'S GOOD
TO SEE YOU.
SEEN STAY, MAN?
STAY WHO?
STAY THE FUCK
OUT OF MY BUSINESS.
[WHIMPERS]
[DOG YELPS]
[TYPING]
IS CHAIRMAN BOBBY
BACK FROM THE WEDDING?
I NEED TO SPEAK
WITH HIM.
WHAT THE FUCK
ABOUT, PIG?
NOW AIN'T THE TIME
FOR THAT SHIT, MAN.
IF YOU WANT IT,
PICK IT UP.
I CAN'T BELIEVE
THAT RAT BASTARD
ISN'T GETTING THE CHAIR.
THAT NEWTON TURD
OUGHT TO BE SHOT.
HOW ABOUT A LITTLE
TARGET PRACTICE, HUH?
YEAH.
GET DOWN!
STAY DOWN!
[LAUGHING]
YOU CHICKENSHIT!
WHAT? YOU BRING
YOUR BUDDIES?
NO! LISTEN!
WE GOT TO MOVE!
THEY GOT A WAREHOUSE
FULL OF DRUGS!
YOU SET BOBBY SEALE UP
TO GET KIDNAPPED!
HOW MUCH DID THE PIGS
PAY YOU FOR THAT ONE?
AAH!
DROP YOUR PIECE,
MOTHERFUCKER!
DROP IT!
YOU BETTER KILL ME,
ALMA, RIGHT NOW!
WHAT ARE YOU SAYING?
THE PIGS ARE GOING
TO FLOOD US WITH DOPE!
BULLSHIT!
TYRONE, HOLD ON.
LET'S GO WITH JUDGE
AND CHECK IT OUT.
THIS MOTHERFUCKER
IS JUST LYING AGAIN.
WE GOT TO TAKE
THIS WAREHOUSE DOWN!
ALL RIGHT. WE'LL GO
CHECK IT OUT.
NO FUCKING AROUND.
THEM SURE AIN'T
NO PIGS, TY.
WAIT.
THAT'S SHORTY.
MAN, THAT BIG FOOL
USED TO RUN WITH SABU
BACK IN DETROIT.
SABU IS IN THERE
WITH THE DOPE, MAN.
YOU BELIEVE ME NOW.
[CLICK]
Sabu: I NEED FOR YOU
TO GET THIS OUT OF HERE.
NEXT 2 WEEKS,
I GOT A BIG SALE COMING.
I NEED FOR YOU
TO GET THIS,
THESE 2 BOXES,
AND THOSE OUT.
THE DUDE CALLED.
HE'LL BRING MONEY AT 12:00.
BE DOWN THERE
WITH THE SHIT.
LET YOUR PEOPLE KNOW
THAT I'M THE MAN.
IF THEY WANT TO GET RID
OF THEIR STUFF,
I'M THE ONE THEY GO TO.
I MAKE ALL THESE CUSTOMERS.
WE'RE DOING IT HERE.
LOOK AT THIS.
THIS IS MY SPECIALTY.
SHORTY, MOVE THEM BOXES
ON THE OTHER SIDE.
THERE'S HARD WORK
IN HERE, BABY.
EVERYBODY'S WORKING.
ALL YOU DO IS
BRING YOUR STUFF TO ME.
MOTHERFUCKER!
[GUNSHOTS]
HEY, YOU BUM!
GIVE ME DORSETT.
WE'VE GOT A PROBLEM.
HELP THE MAN!
NO! TY!
AAH!
MOTHERFUCKER!
[CLICK]
COME ON, BABY.
I'M GOING TO DROP IT.
I'M GOING TO LET IT GO.
I AIN'T GOT NOTHING.
NO GUN, NO EAR,
NO NOTHING, BABY.
I'M THROUGH WITH IT.
TALK TO ME.
I KNOW WHO YOU ARE.
YOU LIKE THE PIG'S MONEY
AS MUCH AS I DO.
WE CAN BOTH GET PAID.
BOTH OF US.
I GOT EVERYTHING.
LOOK AT THIS.
I GOT THE COCAINE,
THE HEROIN.
WHATEVER YOU NEED.
IT'S ME AND YOU.
WE DON'T NEED TO KILL
EACH OTHER, BLACK MAN.
THE BLACK PANTHERS
IS OVER, BABY.
IT'S OVER.
TODAY IS A NEW DAY.
[GUNSHOT]
OHH.
TYRONE.
[MOANING]
[CRYING]
OH, GOD.
JUDGE, HELP.
HE'S GOING
TO BE ALL RIGHT.
WE GOT TO GET HIM UP
AND OUT OF HERE.
COME ON.
[SIRENS]
WE GOT TO GET YOU
OUT OF HERE RIGHT NOW.
I AIN'T GOING
TO MAKE IT.
YES, YOU ARE.
I GOT YOU.
I'LL DISTRACT THE PIGS.
GIVE ME THE LIGHTER.
[SIRENS]
[CAR DOORS OPEN AND CLOSE]
I LOVE YOU, ALMA.
NOW GET THE HELL
OUT OF HERE.
[POLICE SHOUTING]
COME ON, SISTER.
WE GOT TO GO.
WE GOT TO MOVE.
LET'S GO.
COME ON.
[GUNS COCKING]
Cop: COME ON!
WE KNOW YOU'RE IN THERE!
Loudspeaker:
THIS IS THE POLICE!
YOU HAVE 5 SECONDS
TO COME OUT
WITH YOUR HANDS UP.
I REPEAT. YOU ARE ORDERED
TO COME OUT
WITH YOUR HANDS UP!
YOU THERE, IN THE DOORWAY!
YOU HAVE 5 SECONDS
TO COME OUT
WITH YOUR HANDS UP!
5...4...
3...2...
ONE!
Judge: WELL, WE FINALLY
GOT THAT STOPLIGHT.
THEY PUMPED IN THE DOPE
TO NEUTRALIZE
THE BLACK COMMUNITY
AND DESTROY
THE PANTHER POWER BASE,
BUT DRUGS OVERFLOWED
THE BORDERS OF THE GHETTO
AND ENDED UP ON ALL
AMERICA'S DOORSTEP.
LOOK AT THAT!
DESPITE ONGOING PERSECUTION
BY THE AUTHORITIES,
THE PANTHERS CONTINUED TO
PROVIDE BREAKFAST PROGRAMS,
SICKLE CELL ANEMIA TESTING,
EVEN SCHOOLS
FOR THE COMMUNITY.
BEFORE THEY WERE
EVENTUALLY CRUSHED,
THE PANTHERS HAD CHAPTERS
IN ALMOST EVERY STATE
OF THE UNION
AND SEVERAL
FOREIGN COUNTRIES.
IT CAME OUT LATER
THAT HOOVER AND THE FBI
USED ILLEGAL TACTICS
TO DESTROY THE PANTHERS.
SEVERAL PANTHERS ARE STILL
BEING HELD IN PRISON
ON TRUMPED-UP CHARGES.
HUEY WAS KILLED IN 1989
IN A DRUG DEAL.
BOBBY LIVES
IN PENNSYLVANIA.
HE TEACHES AND LECTURES.
THE WAY I SEE IT,
THE STRUGGLE CONTINUES.
NOW IS THE TIME TO FREE
YOUR MIND AND YOUR SOUL
Y'ALL
OFF THE STORY
I'VE NEVER BEEN TOLD
LADIES, WE GOT TO DEMAND
WHAT WE WANT
AND WHAT WE WANT
IS RESPECT, RIGHT?
COME AND TAKE
A WALK WITH ME
A CLOSER WALK WITH THEE
SEE WHAT ONLY
I CAN SEE
BROTHERS AND SISTERS,
CHECK THIS, WATCH THIS
TO THE BEAT
OF FREEDOM
FREEDOM
TURN US LOOSE,
SET US FREE
FROM ALL THE CHAINS
THAT BIND ME
LET US RUN
IN OUR OWN DIRECTION
LET US GO
SET US FREE
FROM ALL THIS PROPAGANDA
AND LIES THAT YOUR PEOPLE
TRY TO TEACH US
I KNOW WHY YOU WOULD
LIKE TO BRING US DOWN
BECAUSE WE HAVE ALL
THE GOODS ON YOU
YOU TRY TO TELL US THAT
OUR LIVES
DON'T MEAN A DAMN
BUT WE KNOW
SO MUCH BETTER
SO IT'S GOIN' TO TAKE
FREEDOM
FREE--FREE--
FREE--FREEDOM
FREEDOM, OH
OH, YEAH
FREEDOM TO THE BEAT
FREE--FREE-
FREEDOM
FREEDOM I'LL TAKE
FOR MY MIND
YEAH, FREEDOM
FOR MY SPIRIT
FREE--FREE--
FREE--FREEDOM
FREEDOM
OHH
YEAH, YEAH
FREE--FREE--
FREE--FREEDOM
WHEN I THINK
BACK IN TIME
NOT VERY LONG AGO
OF HOW FAR WE'VE COME
AND HOW FAR
WE HAVE TO GO
I REMEMBER HEARING
SOMEONE SAY
THAT LOVE'S IN NEED
OF LOVE TODAY
BUT NO ONE SEEMS TO CARE
BUT STILL I KNOW
WHEN YOU'VE
TAKEN ALL
WHEN YOU'VE TAKEN ALL
THAT YOU CAN TAKE
AND YOUR HEART
BEGINS TO BEND
AND IT FEELS LIKE IT'S
ABOUT TO BREAK
THAT'S WHEN
YOU
YOU'VE GOT TO STAND
STAND, STAND
WHEN YOU FEEL LIKE YOU WON'T
MAKE IT THROUGH, STAND
STAND
AND THE THINGS
YOU HOPED FOR
HAVEN'T TURNED OUT
QUITE THE WAY YOU PLANNED
WHEN YOU'VE DONE
ALL THAT YOU CAN
YOU'VE GOT TO STAND
OH OH OH
HELP ME SING IT.
OH
OHH OH OH OH
OHH OH
OH OHH
YOU'VE GOT TO STAND,
YOU'VE GOT TO STAND
YOU'VE GOT
TO STAND
HEY
YOU'VE GOT TO,
YOU'VE GOT TO
YOU'VE GOT TO STAND
STAND
OH, YEAH
WHEN YOU FEEL LIKE YOU
WON'T MAKE IT THROUGH
JUST STAND
STAND
AND THE THINGS
YOU HOPED FOR
HAVEN'T TURNED OUT QUITE
THE WAY YOU PLANNED...
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
POLYGRAM FILMED ENTERTAINMENT
CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.
PUBLIC PERFORMANCE OF CAPTIONS
PROHIBITED WITHOUT PERMISSION OF
NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE