Hey.
You know, I, uh, I got
a piece of advice.
I'd feel really selfish
if I didn't share it.
Okay.
You're supposed to picture 'em
naked when you're on the stand.
If you're nervous.
Oh.
I would, but, um,
it's my dad, so...
Yeah, okay...
Right.
I'm Truitt, by the way.
Tamyra.
Everyone calls me Spider.
Well, the world would be taken
over by mosquitoes and flies
if it weren't
for spiders, so...
Good point.
Did he do that?
How did you know that?
I don't even know you,
but... that makes me
really want to kick
someone's ass on your behalf.
Thanks.
So, why are you here?
Someone said I did something I didn't do.
Oh.
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
So, listen, if things go well
today and-and I'm a free man
and the criminal justice
system doesn't fail me...
do you want to hang out?
Tamyra?
They're ready for you.
You're gonna be great.
Be strong.
Yes! Let's hang out.
My name and info's on a sticker
inside the front cover,
and... it was nice
meeting you.
Maybe it was good luck
or something.
Hey!
Hey.
What, are you guys leaving
for a long lunch?
We know you?
Kate Carley.
Lawyer for DHS.
You guys dcold jobs, right?
Yeah.
Detectives Rush, Miller.
So back in '98, I represented
a teenager named Tamyra Borden,
who was suing her piece-of-scum
father for emancipation.
Scum like how?
Drunk.
Good old Sly liked
to beat his little girl,
put out his cigarettes on her.
So I lose.
Jerk judge said
daughter's testimony wasn't
evidence enough of abuse.
Three months later
Tamyra was killed.
Skull crushed in.
They put the dad away?
No, they did not.
And now, dad's brought up
on charges for his stepdaughter.
Beating her, too?
Three-year-old's in a coma.
I've been talking
to the assigned DA.
Doing some research,
this is what I find.
What is it?
Social Security checks for Tamyra
Borden 'cause her mother's dead.
Checks were stolen and cashed
by dear old Dad for six months
after her death, until Uncle
Sam stopped sending them.
We'll look into it.
I was just outta law school.
Me and her could've shared
a wardrobe, ya know?
Case got away from me.
Got it.
Just get the guy, so I
can live with myself.
???
??? the Kensington and Allegheny
overpass, August '98.
Well, blunt-force trauma
to the skull's what killed her.
ME speculates
a hammer's the murder weapon.
Original theory
was, neighborhood
like that, Tamyra's looking for
drugs, turning tricks, maybe.
Interviewed family, neighbors.
No one knew what she was doing that day, who she
might've been with.
What about friends?
None in here.
Sounds like Tamyra was a loner.
Mother died in Vegas in '92.
She and her dad were split by then.
Sly Borden- three counts
of public intoxication.
Second conviction
for drunk driving in '01.
He said he hadn't
seen Tamyra
in a week before she died.
New info on
the Social Security checks,
maybe her dad'll be
more cooperative.
Why is it that I'm in a
crap cell with no cable hookup?
Ain't that the way?
Beat your baby girl
half to death and get treated
like a scumbag.
Don't come at me
with that bullcrap.
You ever heard of
"innocent until guilty"?
We're here to talk about
Tamyra.
Where were you the night she
was killed?
In the privacy of my own home,
sleepin' off a bad day.
I had no idea my little girl
was gettin' murdered.
And you were just crippled
with grief
when you spent her Social
Security checks at the track.
I was just trying to get by.
Tamyra woulda wanted that.
The daughter you
physically abused?
I'll bet she hated
your guts.
That why you finished
her off, Sly?
Couldn't stand the way
she looked at you?
I hadn't seen the girl in a week
when I heard she died.
And by the way, now she is dead,
everybody talks
like she's some angel.
You got another
version?
Took after her mother.
Kind of a ho.
That's nice of you.
I'm sayin' it wasn't me
that got her into trouble.
It was herself
and her ho-ish habits.
Dinner's ready.
Don't yell.
Here, Dad.
Dinner.
You can just set it on your lap.
So... when you were little
and Grandpa Ed
had the department store,
where was that?
I don't know.
Downtown.
I told you this a million times.
Did you ever work there?
No.
By the time I was old enough
to get a job,
the store was closing.
No customers.
Sorry.
Sorry?!
We went from being
"Hello, Mr. Borden"
to havin' our hand out
like the Mexican bums
that took over our neighborhood,
and there was nothin' that I
could do to get us back on top.
Just...
Okay, Dad.
You just...
love bringing up
stuff like this.
I'm a failure?!
I'm sorry.
You're the failure.
What do you do around here, anyway? Huh?
Nothing.
Like a mouse.
You're out?
Go sit down on the couch.
Who the hell are you?
I said sit down on the couch,
'cause her and I are gonna walk
out of here
and you're just gonna watch us
leave, okay, old man?
Tamyra, go wait outside.
Spider?
It's okay. Wait outside.
If you ever try to see
her again, I'll make sure
you fall down those stairs
and don't get up.
Last time I saw her.
Good riddance.
Spider?
What's his real name?
Hell if I know.
But Tamyra was writing letters
to some prisoner-
number blah-blah-blah-
for a few months
before he graced us
with his visit.
And you keep this in
for ten years?
Certain people could view me
in a bad light after that story.
You get a look at where he was
locked up with those letters?
No.
You see his car
that night?
Oh, yeah.
Jerk drove a Nissan Altima.
That was Tamyra's slap
in my face.
Havin' a boyfriend
with a Jap car.
Uh-huh.
Can't really say you dug
yourself out here, Sly.
But thanks for seeing us.
We'll be sure to stop by again.
Who's the clown?
Never seen him before.
Friend of yours?
That's the problem
with this job.
People know
where you work.
Who is he?
Deadbeat from
my undercover days.
Ex-banger, dealer,
just got outta prison.
Came looking for a second date?
Kidding.
You don't date.
Don't think you know so much
more about things than I do.
That woman just tolerates you.
Toni can handle a real man.
Not every woman can.
We got a list from DMV-
who owned a '94
Nissan Altima in '98.
Don't suppose any of 'em put
down Spider as their first name?
No, but one guy might fit the bill.
Lil and Scotty are with him now.
No, I'm not Spider.
That guy's real name
is Truitt Leland.
And he drove a car
registered to you
the night he went to
Tamyra Borden's house?
He used to borrow
my car, yes.
I used to hang out with him
when I was young and stupid.
You don't keep up?
Have you met him?
The moment I graduated from angry young man-dom,
I
stopped spending time with him.
What do
you know about Tamyra?
She dated Spider.
Stayed at his mom's house
with us for a few weeks.
Look, do I need a lawyer?
I swear, I'm nothing like that guy.
Why are you protesting
so much, Elliot?
God knows what he's done that I don't want to be
associated with.
He have anything to do
with Tamyra's death?
When did she die?
I mean, she stopped coming
around, but I just figured...
What?
That it was because of what
was going on with us... with Spider.
Which was what, Elliot?
Look, my parents had
a bad divorce and I had "dad" issues,
which made me vulnerable
to Spider.
Again...
stupid kid.
Truitt wrote me
all these letters,
and I don't know.
It was nice
to get something in the mail.
My mom- she used
to send postcards or whatever, but...
Yeah, Truitt's a good writer.
That's my son.
And he can talk his way
out of anything, too.
Hope he warned you
we're boring over here.
We don't drink or
smoke or anything.
No, that's great.
Want some milk?
Okay.
Tamyra, if you
ever want a place to stay.
We have an
extra room.
I left my dad, moved in here.
We're her orphans.
Trust me, there's
no better mother.
Take this downstairs.
It's "No Mom Allowed. "
The values that we're taught
are important to us,
don't mean
anything anymore.
I mean, go to school.
You can't afford college.
Work hard. Well, some illegal aliens
get my job.
Be honest.
Go to church.
Well, I'd like to. But my preacher
and my government
are lying to me about what kind of people
they really are.
But it's not like things have ever been better.
Or easier.
It's the same old struggles our parents had.
What about our grandparents?
My grandfather comesack
from World War II
and goes to any college
he wants to on the government.
I come back from Kuwait, I'm on my own.
Something's gone wrong between that generation and this one.
Big time.
I think we know what it is.
It's the government's
liberal agenda.
They serve the blacks,
the Jews, the Mexicans,
and the homosexuals.
The white race is under attack.
You were skinheads.
Like I said,
I was lonely and lost,
so I hung out with Spider
and tolerated all that talk.
But he was
the true believer.
Tamyra's boyfriend
was a neo-Nazi
and she winds up
with her skull bashed in.
I wonder if Spider and his steel-toed boots
know anything about that.
Truitt Leland, summer of '98,
he spends two months
at the house of corrections for
trashing a convenience store.
Owned by a Vietnamese couple.
Only two months?
Court called it vandalism.
Not ethnic-motivated.
He up to his old tricks?
Recent as '06,
cops got called to break apart a scuffle
at a White Pride rally he organized.
No charges pressed.
Speaking of which.
Guess my invite
got lost in the mail.
Can I help you?
This is a Neighborhood Freedom Coalition meeting.
Freedom from what, exactly?
Philly PD.
We've got a legal right to congregate here.
What's your issue?
Tamyra Borden.
You know anything about
her gettin' her head bashed in...
Spider?
It's Truitt.
And no, I don't.
Is this your normal
potluck accessory... Spider?
Again, I've got a legal right,
I have a permit.
That sets my mind at ease.
Neo-Nazi roaming the streets
with a concealed weapon.
Unbelievable. The bigotry.
You should know better than anyone.
Just because we're organized
and proud of our race
doesn't mean we go around
committing murder.
Tamyra was your girlfriend
when she was killed.
And you've got a history of violence.
What we had was
pure and innoct.
That girl was an Aryan goddess.
Is that a compliment?
Oh, so you didn't get
slap-happy on her
when she decided she wasn't
into the swastika thing?
What makes you think
she wasn't into it?
Hey.
Why are you up?
I couldn't sleep.
Why not?
Because I was worried
you couldn't sleep.
You barely talked
to me tonight.
Do you believe
in, like, the Holocaust?
That it was right?
No.
I'm confused.
Why did you talk to me
that day
at the courthouse?
Why did you write to me?
You're the most beautiful
girl I've ever seen.
That's ridiculous.
I hate the way
that swastika looks.
It's hate.
And I just don't think you are like that.
The swastika is
an ancient symbol for strength.
I mean to the sun, good luck.
That's everything I want for you.
For our people.
When my dad lost his job...
that's when he started drinking.
Who'd he lose it to?
An illegal alien, right?
Yeah.
He just... he felt so useless,
you know.
I could tell.
I just wish things could have
been better for him.
It doesn't have
to be that way.
Are you gonna help me?
Are you gonna be brave?
Why'd Tamyra have
to be brave?
What did you
get her into?
Nothing other than
defending our beliefs.
And how do you do that?
We abide by the law.
You cops protect us so well,
how could we not
want to play nice?
Nice.
You remember prison.
How would you like that
for the rest of your life?
Unless you're going to press charges,
I'm not going anywhere with you.
You know you have
no grounds to do that.
Plus, I have a First Amendment
right to congregate here
and that's what
I plan on doing.
See ya.
Hey, Spider,
where'd you get that nickname from?
Wouldn't happen to do
with the skinhead tattoo
you get when you kill
a black person, would it?
It's 'cause I'm nocturnal.
He was taunting us, boss.
Jackass thinks he can hide,but he's wrong.
These are all the crime reports from the summer of '98.
When Spider ask Tamyra to swear her allegiance to him,
said he needed her to be brave.
These types can't resist staking a claim.
There's got to be a signature in there.
A week before Tamyra's murder there were
broken windows at a temple in South Philly.
The same at a mosque.
Racist graffiti on an African-American family home--
standard curse word stuff,
nothing distinctive.
Oh, I've got something.
It was flagged as ethnic intimidation
'cause it's a Honduran lady.
This car belonged
to Nora Mariposa,
went missing
August 17, 1998.
The day
before Tamyra was killed.
There's graffiti
on the door.
That a skinhead tag?
I've been reading up on the crap
these white supremacists use
to justify their beliefs.
That's real educational.
Oh, the Internet's
overflowing with stuff.
They're everywhere.
The one thing they can all agree on is this book
The Lightning and The Sun.
It's got a loving dedication to Hitler himself.
Isn't that sweet?
That book's about using violence to cleanse society.
And this tag is the lightning and the sun.
Nora Mariposa never turned up?
But we got a witness.
Nora's four-year-old son was in the car.
You were four years old,Miguel,
when your mother went missing?
Yeah.
They found me in the car,
but I didn't remember anything.
You remember this?
Did you see someone do this?
Sorry.
Can we show you some other pictures?
Was, uh, this guy there that night?
I don't know. Sorry.
Him and her.
These two?
They were there that night?
Ponche de goma.
Flat tire.
Hola, chica.
What did they do when they got out of the truck?
Miguel?
They hurt her.
My mother.
What are you doing?
Remember I told you to be brave?
ecesitas ayuda?
Si.
Gracias.
I cannot change tire.
You guys gotta get down here.
It's going to get explosive.
Spider.
Your father,a white man,
lost his job because people like this
are willing to work for nothing!
Leeches!
Wait.You'll kill her!
No. You will.
Hey, hey, look at me
I know that you're scared, okay?
This is what it looks like
when you're fighting
to get your life back, okay?
Trust me. I love you.
She shot Nora.
????
So far, none of them
match Nora Mariposa.
Must have hid the body.
Rush and Will
are in with the girl.
Neck tat girl?
She was capable of beating
Nora Mariposa to death.
Could have done it to Tamyra.
Stillman.
The not-so-nice lady told you to get lost, homes.
I know she did,
but she needs to talk to me.
How about I talk to you, sport?
Man, I just need to see my kid.
Your kid?
Veronica.
My daughter.
I got it.
I said I got it.
I told you...
we're done talking about this.
I'm not the same
person as I was.
No drugs,
no playing around.
I got my act together
on the inside.
Good for you.
She even know about me?
What should I say?
Dad's in prison.
Ex-banger thug?
Kat, you act like
you're better than me.
You forgot how we met?
I was doing my job.
Oh. That's what
you tell yourself, huh?
I've made a life for me and her,
and it works.
We got it down.
That's all she needs.
You sure about that?
I leave Philly in a week.
Get away from all the elements.
Make sure I stay on track.
Before I go... I'd like
to meet my daughter.
I said no.
And don't come
back here again
or I'll have your sorry ass
thrown back in jail.
Those your kids screaming
like banshees out there?
ADD. Yeah.
I guess you weren't
a diehard skinhead, huh?
Love is blind.
And another of those kids
has got Spider as a dad.
So? You can't tell me
who to have my babies with.
Four years back child support.
What is he,
ashamed of you guys?
He's a frickin' dirtbag
is what he is.
And after you did
everything for him.
Helped him kill a woman.
Huh
Nora Mariposa.
We got a witness puts you as coconspirator to murder,
beating that woman as she lay on the ground.
A witness?
That's impossible.
It was frickin' pitch-dark.
Um... You've just put yourself
at the scene
of the murder, Lindsay.
So, that means
you're going away.
But I didn't do it.
Who did, Lindsay?
Was it Tamyra?
You've got one option
if you want to save yourself,
and that's tell us
what happened.
It's them...
or you.
Spider trusted Tamyra
that night...
which was a huge mistake.
No. No.
Oh, my God.
What happened?
We killed the bitch.
Roadkill.
Why?
No. Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Why are you
freaking out on me?
Why did you do that?
Why?
Spider...
you never said
we'd do this.
What did I say,
Elliot, huh?
What did I say?!
I said this was war!
What do soldiers do?!
What do they do, Elliot?!
I thought, I thought
it was about ideas or the...
Ideas?
What did you think
we were doing?
We have to call
an ambulance!
You stupid bitch.
She's dead.
How can you be my girl
when you're acting
like this right now?
Stop!
Here's an idea.
Why don't you help me
clean this up?
Help me.
Teamwork.
Give me a T.
Wait, I told what
you wanted to know.
You said it was me or them.
We meant you and them.
Tell us where Spider is.
-With his bitch wife.
-They took off.
Do you know where
Spider might hide out?
Can't you give me a break?
I was kind of stupid back then.
Still are, Lindsay.
Think you guys are going
in the wrong direction.
What? This ain't the swap meet?
You're gonna want
to put that weapon
on the ground, right now. Now!
Put your weapon down,
sweetheart.
What did you do
with Nora Mariposa's body?
You're going away
for life for that, Spider.
Don't care.
Movement's strong inside.
Good. You got somebody
to pray for you
when you get the needle.
No way.
Double murder--
Nora and Tamyra.
I didn't do Tamyra.
She was gonna turn you in.
She was a traitor ??
Something had to be done,
and you were the guy to do it.
Not with her.
She was just
a little freaked out,
but she would've come around.
Deep down, she was with me.
Hoping she'd be
your Aryan bride?
Not everybody saw
my future like that.
Tamyra?
You guys were out late last night.
Are you looking for something?
No. It's okay.
Honey, what's wrong?
Sweetheart,
please let me help.
Is it your father?
No.
Please let me out.
I need to go to the police.
Is someone hurt?
She's dead.
We killed her.
Who?
A woman, a Latin woman.
We shot her.
Please, let me out.
Do you know what those
spic mud people niggers do
to white women like us?
Ravage us.
And you don't hear
about it on the news,
and the cops won't help.
All we have is men
like my son to protect us.
No, but this woman
didn't do anything wrong.
We are at war
with those people.
You are either with us,
or you're against us.
You can't do this.
We are.
It's happening
with or without you.
Your mother killed
Tamyra Borden?
Why are you surprised?
She raised me.
My mother...
is the ultimate believer.
You ever heard those stories about
somebody who raises a pit bull?
eds them gunpowder and
kicks them to make them mean?
One day the dog turns on 'em, attacks.
That's what
happened to you.
Your little psychopath Spider
told us what you did to
his girlfriend Tamyra.
He straight-cold sold you out.
What did I do? I talked to her.
Tried to reason with her.
And when that didn't work, you killed her.
I would never lay my hands on that girl.
She was going to send
Spider back to jail.
Your baby boy.
You wouldn't
let that happen.
Do you think I'm stupid?
We think you had someone else
do your dirty work for you.
Somehow Tamyra got out and was
beat to death a mile from your house.
Somehow.
Hey.
Why aren't you upstairs
eating dinner?
Elliot.
Yeah?
We ran away
from our parents, and...
here we are again.
We're prisoners...
living with
another crazy man.
Yeah. Spider's not
what I thought.
If I could go back to the night
that he came to get me,
instead of getting in that car,
I'd run away.
I'd get on the
first bus out,
and when I got out,
I'd change my name.
I'd try to always be happy.
Elliot, what
are you doing?
They'll kill you.
You need to go.
Go now. Please.
Come with me.
Come!
Don't be scared.
I'm sorry I didn't
tell you to leave.
When you first came.
Go.
He went after her.
Ten minutes later.
With a hammer.
And you just let him go?
You can't stop young men
on a mission.
Elliot went after her
on your mission.
You put him up
to it, Rayanne.
How'd you make him do it?
Elliot didn't
believe in killing.
You don't know Elliot.
He's not who he pretends to be.
He's much weaker.
Did you talk to Spider?
Everything all right?
Tamyra wasn't just some girl
you met a few times.
You helped her escape from Spider.
You both knew Spider
killed Nora Mariposa.
And Rayanne
says that's
what you did to Tamyra.
What? Well, Rayanne is a trailer trash lunatic.
What is it you teach?
Economics.
So this is for pleasure?
Ah, Lightning and the Sun.
You fooled us, Elliot.
You look normal enough.
And Nordic mythology.
Ben Klassen.
History of the Illuminati.
Mein Kampf.
You didn't stop
hanging out with Spider
because of
his beliefs.
'Cause you two
got that in common.
Do those college
kids' parents know
the kind of sewage
they're paying you
to teach their kids?
You don't think
economics and race
belong in the same classroom?
This is all about money.
9/11. The Jews bringing
do the towers.
The war we're fighting
right now with our white males.
It's all to protect Israel?
You really drank the Kool-Aid,
didn't you?
Does it nag at you, Detective,
that you only got your job
because the liberal elite
pities your race?
You guys believe
in alien probes, too?
The tide is turning, Detective.
We are on the Internet.
We are funded and organized.
And politicians agree:
it's time to make
our neighborhoods safe,
protect our borders.
The courts agree affirmative action is reverse racism.
You wrap it up like it ain't narrow-minded,
paranoid bullcrap, but it is.
Well, what's really
crazy, Elliot, is
that you can say all this...
but you're Jewish.
No, I'm not.
No. Your mother's
Jewish, Elliot.
Makes you the most self-hating
son of a bitch I ever seen.
I'm not that.
Not anymore.
It's 'cause of your mother
you have this way about you.
It's weak.
People see it.
That's why it is.
How it is.
How?
Nobody respecting you.
It's that sick thing in you.
I don't even live
with my mother.
I don't even like her.
It's only half.
Feels like more than that.
It's not.
You've gotta burn it out.
How'd you burn
it out, Elliot?
Killing Tamyra for the cause?
Rayanne convinced you.
You're not gonna leave here
and say that thing
you said, are you?
Because that would be slander.
I'm a white American.
Nothing less.
Take her
somewhere else.
Wait till you're far from here.
Our esteemed president Theodore Roosevelt said it
and I don't know why people can't grasp this
"We have room for but one sole loyalty
and that is loyalty to the American people."
Okay.
I'll handle it.
Tamyra was American.
Your logic doesn't work.
I'm talking about
the ordinary American.
Your mailman, college student,
fireman.
They've been wronged,
and now they're mad.
I didn't write the rules of war.
They've existed since the dawn of time.
Blood is spilled and it wipes us clean.
Why'd you need
to be clean, Elliot?
You could've left with her.
No. She was a race traitor.
Like you.
And I was a soldier.
It's what the true soldiers do.
And when the race war starts,
everyone who ever laughed at me and deserted me
will say, "He knew.
He knew all along."
I had to.
To be clean.