(PEOPLE YELLING)
(HORN HONKING)
MAN: Yo, man,
come on!
WOMAN 1: Eighteen to party,
21 to drink.
Have your IDs ready.
WOMAN 2: Eighteen to party,
21 to drink.
Have your IDs ready,
ladies.
Eighteen to party,
21 to drink.
(BOUNCERS CONTINUE CHECKING)
(HIP-HOP SONG PLAYING)
DJ: Oh, my God.
Goddamn,
I say I love my job!
Come on now,
let's go!
Now where are all
my sexy Sagittarian
ladies at?
Man, where your dollars?
Where your dollars at?
Man, she doin' it,
y'all.
Chill, chill.
Watchu' come here for?
DANCER: Oh, come on, baby,
I'm not going to bite.
Sorry,
excuse me, sorry.
DJ: Come on now,
let's go.
Yeah,
it's your girl K-Sty.
You know you're rocking
with your girl K-Sty.
We're live
at the Catnip Lounge.
Give it up
for your girl Maine.
Maine's in the building.
Come on,
we're late.
Huh?
I gotta go.
Hold on a minute.
Why you trippin'?
What?
I gotta go.
Why are you trippin'?
I'm gonna get in trouble.
Let me dance
with shortie right quick
and then I'll be ready.
What?
Stop pulling
on my clothes, yo.
Sorry.
How many numbers
you get? One?
I could've gotten more,
but your moms
was holdin' me up.
(LAUGHING)
That's messed up.
How many you get?
Oh. Let me see.
Tonya, Denise,
Shelley...
Oh, wait,
that's an old one,
I could delete that one.
So, Tonya...
Hold up. Liar.
Ain't Shelley that chick
from your math class?
Give me!
Denise?
Yo, hold up,
these are your damn
study group numbers, yo.
Why you frontin', huh?
I don't see you
with no list of numbers.
I'm not the one looking
for a girlfriend, man.
You the one
still a virgin!
Trying to help your ass,
you know what I'm saying?
I don't know what you
waitin' on. Shit.
Still kickin'
that quiet shit from
sixth grade, nigga.
I don't need to press,
I gets plenty.
You feel me?
Wah-wah.
Look, I get more pussy
than your daddy, nigga.
(ALIKE LAUGHING)
What?
Okay, you got me
with that one.
You got me
Yeah, I know. I know.
You need to pop
that damn cherry, yo.
Shut up.
That's what
you need to do.
(DINGS)
Quit playing.
Your stop.
Huh?
Time to get off.
Nah, I'm gonna roll
with you a few more
stops, a'ight?
Why are you gonna
go all the way up
to come back down?
Make sure
you get home safe.
I don't need
your protection.
You ain't big, nigga,
get off.
Hey, yo!
That's a'ight, man.
Yo, yo, yo.
Next stop.
A'ight?
Would you
get off the bus?
Yo, what you
pushin' me for?
Why're you beastin'?
I'm not beastin'.
Just get off!
Tsk.
(DOOR OPENS)
You got a problem.
Yo, call me.
I'll call you. Bye.
You're late.
Be quiet.
Where you been
this late?
Movies.
Movies ended
at midnight.
Shut up.
Don't push me.
I know what stays open
past midnight.
Good for you.
Go to sleep.
Goodnight, Lee.
AUDREY: Lee?
Nice to know
you still live here.
What are you doing home
so late, anyway?
Lost track of time.
You know what time
your curfew is.
Where were you?
Movies.
The movie ended
at midnight
and your curfew's
at 12:30.
I lost track of time.
Well, at least
you were cute.
I like that shirt.
Where'd you get
that from?
Angel.
It's old.
Really compliments
your figure.
You know, maybe
we can go shopping.
I saw one just like it...
Goodnight, Ma.
You know what?
I don't like
that young lady
that you run around with.
Yeah, okay!
And tie up your head.
It's your head.
And wash
your face, too!
I don't have makeup on.
Wash your face,
anyway!
Mom, I'm seventeen years old.
Can you please...
You need to
watch your tone!
It's your skin.
(BELL RINGING)
TEACHER: All right,
as I promised, people,
these will be graded
on a curve.
So, you're not going
to get a whole lot
of help unfortunately
because the highest score
on the test was a 98.
Very good job.
STUDENT: This wasn't even
in the study guide...
Guys, I gave you
all the answers
and the questions
on the review sheets.
It was on the test.
I didn't say that.
(BELL RINGING)
Y'all have a good lunch.
I'll see y'all tomorrow.
Study, people.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
Hey, girl.
Hi.
How you doing?
Talk to me.
You eat that shit?
I do.
I don't know about
what you eatin'.
Tastes good.
You should try it.
Yeah, listen, hummus
will keep me alive
longer than that.
(LAUGHING)
So, where's
the new stuff?
Here you go.
Hmm.
Do you see the one
in the back?
I'm gonna...
I'll probably do
that in class.
Hmm.
So?
So what?
So what'd you think?
Yeah, they're okay.
Okay?
Well, they're lovely.
I mean, of course
your descriptiveness
and your use of alliteration
are beautiful and all, but
you know that.
But I don't know,
is it your best?
No.
I thought it was good.
They're okay.
Not great.
I think you can
go deeper.
ALIKE: (ON VOICEMAIL)
I'm not able to
take your call.
Please leave a message
at the sound of the tone.
Peace.
(HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
Hey, this is Lee,
I'm not able to
take your call...
How's it coming?
It's good.
(LOWERING VOLUME)
Let me know
if you need me.
I don't see why
we can't just
watch TV like usual.
ALIKE: Shut up.
You shut up!
AUDREY: Girls!
(PHONE RINGING)
I was expecting a call.
ARTHUR: Hello?
Yeah.
It's your father's
night off.
Straighten up.
(SIGHS)
SHARONDA: So,
Homecoming got
moved up this year.
It's actually going to
be in September
instead of October.
AUDREY: Really?
Yeah, which means
that I can actually
go to the Autumn Ball
and the Homecoming Dance.
Who're you going
to go with?
I don't know, uh,
maybe Derek,
if he asks me.
Or maybe Parrish.
But I know for Homecoming
that I definitely want to
go with Craig.
And who are you going
to go with, Lee?
I'm not going.
AUDREY: What do you mean,
you're not going?
It's your junior year!
Leave her alone,
Audrey.
If she doesn't want to go,
she doesn't have to go.
But she's a junior.
She's not going to
have any memories!
I don't like
all those boys
buzzing around
my daughters anyway.
Nobody's buzzing around Alike.
ARTHUR: That's right,
and it better
stay that way.
Matter of fact,
I'm not sure if
I'm gonna let you go.
SHARONDA: Dad!
Shut up!
(LAUGHING)
So what are
your memories, Mother?
I got plenty
of memories.
Like?
I'm just saying,
share with us.
SHARONDA:
Did you go to prom?
Yes, I went to prom.
Who'd you go with?
Are you comfortable
with this?
I'm fine.
She asked you.
Did you have sex
at prom?
ARTHUR: Hey, hey, hey!
(ALIKE LAUGHS)
ARTHUR: Relax.
SHARONDA: I'm definitely
having sex at prom.
ALIKE: Oh, my God!
ARTHUR: No,
you're definitely
not going to prom.
You're not having sex
for 10 more years, so...
SHARONDA: Ten years?
At least.
That's like 25!
Exactly.
That's early for me.
That's an
inappropriate
question.
SHARONDA: Is that
how old you were
when you first had sex?
That's how old you'll be
when you find out.
AUDREY: This isn't
dinner conversation.
(ALIKE LAUGHING)
Okay.
AUDREY: Guys...
Oh. Oh, my God.
(LAUGHING)
That's just
embarrassing, girl.
ALIKE: You ain't got
no range either!
Well, at least I hit
the backboard, damn.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Help!
I'm getting mugged!
Girl. Come on,
what's the score?
One up.
One?
Yup.
Girl, I got at least three.
Definitely three, come on.
You trying to
cheat me, too?
Help me!
(WOMEN SPEAKING)
Hey! Hey, hey.
Mind if I sit here?
Sure, go ahead.
Help yourself.
Oh, thank you.
What you got there?
You been shopping?
Mmm-mmm.
Just some yogurt.
Some vanilla yogurt.
No, I mean in the bag.
What do you got
in the bag?
That big red thing?
Oh...
I don't know
where my mind is.
(CHUCKLES)
That's okay.
Um...
Yeah, let me...
Let me show it to you.
Okay.
Can I get your opinion?
Oh.
That's really nice.
Isn't that cute?
Yeah! Is that
for your daughter?
Yeah, yeah.
It's for Alike.
Oh, the youngest one.
No, the oldest one.
Oh, the other one.
Oh. Okay. Yeah.
Why, you think
it's too young?
Oh, no!
For some reason
the youngest one
just popped
into my head first,
that's all.
Oh, but I think
it'll be fine.
Oh, it's really nice.
Thank you.
Yeah.
And you know what,
it'll compliment
her figure.
You see,
that's what I thought.
Yeah.
For some reason,
Lee just doesn't like
anything I pick out
for her anymore.
Oh, girl, please.
My oldest has banned me
from buying her
any more clothes.
I just get her
gift cards now.
Trust me,
we're both happier for it.
WOMAN: She needs to
go on a diet. Anyway...
Hey, Brenda!
Hey!
Audrey, you got
me a present!
No, I didn't.
What y'all in here
talking about?
None of your
damn business.
Let me know
how it goes, okay?
Okay, I will.
Hey, Bren...
This is the article
I was telling you about.
Oh, no.
Is that her?
I told you!
Look how big
she done got!
Oh, my gosh,
that's a shame!
Isn't that crazy?
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
GIRL 1: So, it was,
like, seven of us.
Me, Khalil, Misha,
Tamara...
GIRL 2: Tamara Marks?
Hell, no.
Fat Tamara.
Oh, I was about to say.
Tamara Marks is a...
Uh, I can't stand her.
Anyway, it was all of us,
and oh, Laura.
You know that girl
from the restaurant?
She was there with
one of her friends.
The gay chick?
Y'all be hanging out
like that?
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
GIRL 1: Anyway,
there's a couple of them.
She's mad cool though,
so she come out with us
every now and...
Man, y'all be doing it
big on the weekends.
Let me know!
GIRL 2: I told
your butt to come.
GIRL 1: But anyway...
Yo, some of them AGs
are kinda cute.
I'm not saying I would,
but I'll holla.
GIRL 2: I don't know
about all that.
Yo, isn't that one
of them over there?
What's her name?
Amika? Alisha?
GIRL 2: Alike.
Yeah, Alike.
She's cute, too.
GIRL 2: I don't be looking
at them like that.
Look, I'm not gay,
but if I was gay,
I might talk to her!
She's in the middle
anyway.
Yeah, I know,
if she was just
a little bit harder...
BOY: 'Sup, ladies.
Oh, hey. (LAUGHING)
Hey, what's up?
What's going on?
Hey.
BOY: What's good?
What's good with
that party?
What's good
with this hat?
(GIRLS LAUGHING)
BOY: Don't play me.
GIRL 1: Yo!
Oh, Mika,
you act like you
bi or something.
I like girls.
I love boys.
GIRL 2: I can't tell!
MIKA: Whatever!
So what do you think?
Watch out,
it's slippery.
I already told you
what I think.
But you know her.
I know of her,
but I don't
"know her" know her.
Okay,
you know her friend.
Can you hook us up?
Yo, put that stack
over there.
Um...
Yo, pass me
that rice.
Are you listening?
Yeah, I'm listening, man!
All I'm saying is
that I don't think
you should be
putting yourself
out there like that.
Especially
if you don't know
she like you like that.
She does.
She does?
How do you know
she does?
I just know she does.
Hmm. We'll see.
What are you doing?
Thought I felt a drop
of pig shit.
Shut...
Shut the fuck up!
All I know is
I've been trying
to get you
to talk to chicks
for the longest
in the club.
I don't want to
holla at girls
at the club.
Obviously.
So, why are you
so pressed
about this one?
I wanted to ask you
something else, too.
What?
I need you to get
something for me.
What?
Just for my image.
You trying
to strap, yo?
Oh, my God, yo!
What are you
going through?
By next Friday, please.
Next Friday?
Please.
All right.
Okay, whatever.
I mean...
Oh, my God, yo!
She better be cute
for this, yo.
That's all I know,
she better be cute.
LAURA: I think
it looks natural.
(SIGHS)
I'm serious, I mean,
it doesn't look that bad.
I can't believe you.
What?
Laura, this looks stupid!
It doesn't look right!
Well, first of all,
it's not supposed
to be over your
underwear like that.
I'm not
putting this thing
next to my skin.
It already pinches!
It's supposed to
fit like that.
They didn't
have brown?
I didn't have time
for all of that!
And plus the brown ones
are too big for you anyway.
It's not funny!
Here, you gotta
take it back.
I can't take it back.
No, here's the receipt!
Yo, I'm not
going back in there.
One time was
embarrassing enough. No.
You grown!
So what?
What if someone
see me in there?
No, I'm not going back!
Then where's
my change?
Lee, where'd you
put my makeup.
Ooh, I'm telling.
Hey! Hey, get off of me!
Stop! Stop!
Get off of me
with that thing, geez!
Be quiet!
Okay. Be quiet!
I'm telling
you got that!
You can't tell.
I'm telling!
Shut up!
Gosh, it looks nasty!
See, I told you so!
Yeah, whatever.
Where's my makeup case?
I know you've got it.
I just borrowed it.
Okay, well,
give it back!
Take it.
Promise you won't tell.
Just give it back!
All right! All right,
all right, all right.
All right,
I won't tell. Okay?
Geez.
I'm still telling.
Telling what?
She took
my makeup again!
Lee, please stop
with the...
Oh, hello, Laura.
I didn't see you
standing over there.
Hello, Mrs. Freeman.
How's your mother?
I haven't spoken
to her in a while.
She's fine.
I hope so.
And I was glad to hear
that your sister finally
got back on her feet.
Mom! Mom!
She's good,
she's good.
No, I don't think so.
We leave
this door open.
Let a little fresh air
circulate in here.
I was just about to
leave anyway, so...
SHARONDA: Mom?
Just try it.
(DOOR CLOSES)
LAURA: Chill,
you just got to
get used to it.
Stop touching it
like that,
people gonna think
you got something.
The string hurts.
I'm going to
take it off.
You're not going
to take it off.
I'm going to take it off.
Where you gonna
take it off at?
In the bathroom.
Then where are
you going to put it?
You going to walk
around the club with
a dick in your hand?
I mean, chill, man,
you're straight
blowing me right now, yo.
Then I'm out.
No, you're not!
You're about to
go through with this.
You're the one that
wanted to meet her,
not me.
Okay, then come on then,
let's go.
All right,
man, chill.
GIRL: Hey.
DJ: Where are my AGs at?
Where are my butches at?
Throw your hands
in the air.
Let's get it.
(HIP-HOP SONG PLAYING)
You all right?
Yeah, um, I think there's
a spring in the cushion
or something.
You wanna
switch seats?
Nah, I'm good.
MIKA: And you don't
wanna dance?
Hey, yo, we gonna
go dance, a'ight?
Nah, I'm not
really feeling
the music.
Well, look,
you don't mind, right,
if I go dance
with somebody else?
Nah, do your thing.
If you change
your mind, we...
Nah, it's cool.
(HIP-HOP SONG PLAYING ON TV)
AUDREY:
Turn that mess off!
Sharonda!
(TURNS DOWN VOLUME)
Sharonda,
stop lollygagging!
Lee! Are you ready?
Yup.
I said off.
(TURNS OFF TV)
And I thought you said
you were ready?
I am ready.
You're not going
to church in that!
What's wrong
with this?
Where's that blouse
I bought you?
What's wrong with this?
Dad!
Do what your mom says.
Are you hungry?
Here, let me heat
this up for you.
That's okay.
Oh, it tastes
so much better.
Just leave it.
ALIKE: Dad...
Lee!
Leave me out of it.
Now go get changed.
Dad, what's wrong
with this outfit?
Nothing.
ALIKE: See.
I'm not going to
argue with you.
Do what she says.
Dad!
(SPEAKING SWAHILl)
And put on a skirt!
Give me a beer, please.
It's Sunday morning.
It goes with
the spaghetti.
Too much lip gloss.
Did you talk to her?
Sharonda's fine.
I'm talking
about Lee.
Alike.
And I don't see that
there's a problem.
I'm tired of
this whole tomboy thing
she's been doing.
And Laura.
You said that
you were going
to handle it.
Mmm-hmm.
She needs
a male point of view!
I said okay, damn it.
Do you have
to work tonight?
To put food on the table
and clothes on our backs, no.
To go out to restaurants
and keep designer sneakers
in the closet, yes.
Are you forever
gonna be mad?
gonna be happy?
You made that decision
a long time ago.
We both made sacrifices.
You look beautiful, baby.
(CHUCKLING)
Tuck your blouse in.
This isn't me.
AUDREY: Tuck it in.
Leave it out.
I think it's fine out.
Are you coming with us?
Nope. Sleep.
We could do
a later service.
Maybe the one o'clock.
I said no!
SHARONDA: I'm ready!
Sharonda, Alike,
you look beautiful.
Everybody looks
beautiful, okay?
Well, fine then.
Stop hitting me.
Put this one in then.
"God's love"?
I don't think so.
Put it in.
Stop!
Put in that one.
Audrey, hey!
Hi!
How're you
doing, girl?
All right.
I'm not touching you.
Stop!
I'm not touching you!
Sharonda, stop!
Ouch!
Lee, there's somebody
I want you to meet.
That's just mean.
Huh?
Here's somebody
I want you to meet.
Oh, hi.
Get down out of the car
and come speak!
What's wrong
with you?
All right, Mom.
You'll have to
excuse my daughter,
she's been
feeling rude lately.
Oh, don't worry
about it.
I understand
how it is.
Hormones, you know.
It's just a phase.
Alike, this is
Mrs. Singletary,
one of my coworkers,
and her daughter Bina.
Hi.
And that's my youngest
daughter Sharonda.
BINA: Hey.
MRS. SINGLETARY: Hi, there.
Nice to meet you.
(CHUCKLES)
Lee, Bina goes
to your school.
ALIKE: Cool.
Yeah, I think
I've seen you around,
um, Mrs. Alvarado's class?
AP English?
Yup.
Well, now that
we're all acquainted
with one another,
let's not be strangers.
Oh, no, no, we won't.
Right, honey?
Bina, you know,
I think you two
even go to school
the same way.
MRS. SINGLETARY: Oh! Well,
you know,
there's something
to be said about
safety in numbers, right?
AUDREY: Yup.
Yeah.
MRS. SINGLETARY: Well,
you know, we need
to be pushing off.
I'll call you about
the VBS workbooks.
All righty. All righty.
Take care.
All right?
Great.
Come on, honey.
Bye!
MRS. SINGLETARY: So,
where you wanna go?
Um, I want to
get those pancakes.
(SIGHS)
Oops.
You're funny.
I don't know
what your problem is.
SHARONDA: Mom, can you
put this in please?
I don't know
what you think this
is going to change.
I know God doesn't
make mistakes.
I know that.
Now, you may not
like Bina,
but you're going
to be spending
a whole lot less time
with that Laura
person.
Mom, can you
just put this in?
I can guarantee you that.
No, shh, be quiet,
I'm not putting
anything in.
I'm going to listen
to what I want to
listen to for a change.
(UPBEAT SONG PLAYING)
Look, I just
don't like lying
to my mother, that's all.
So then don't,
she doesn't
have to know.
Yes, she does,
she asks me every day!
So, then,
tell her yeah.
No! I don't want
to lie just to
cover for you.
So don't!
Look, Alike, or Lee
or whatever it is
you want to be called,
I'm really not
trying to hang out
with you either, okay,
but I'm not about
to take an L for it.
So just stop
dodging me!
Let's just go
to school together
and then...
Then it's over with,
we don't have to hang out
with each other after that.
You know what,
whatever!
She asks me again
I'm gonna tell her,
and then she's gonna
tell your mother,
and then it's
whatever for you.
Hey!
Hey, look, I'm sorry!
Look, I'm sorry!
Hello,
I said I'm sorry!
Yeah, you sorry
your mother's about
to bug out.
No, for real,
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean
to be that way,
it's just...
Okay, look,
I am concerned
my mom will find out,
but it's...
But...
It's not like that,
it's just that she's...
Look, if you
knew my mother,
you'd understand.
She's...
Overprotective?
Yeah.
Yeah, I know,
I've seen her.
I see what she's like,
but lots of people's
parents are like that.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Yeah, but
not like mine.
Anyway...
Anyway, like I said,
let's just walk.
Thank you so much
for bringing that.
No problem.
You done studying yet?
No.
Did you start
studying yet?
I'm on chapter nine.
Now, stop.
Get them fucking cards
out of here.
No, we gonna
study these words.
I ain't studying.
We can play
'em like Tonk.
We can play Spades with
these vocabulary cards.
Get outta here, yo.
I'm about to
deal you in.
I'm gonna deal you in.
So, listen, I'm gonna
work some more hours
so we could...
"Listless, apathetic,
having no interest
in anything." That's yours.
Listen!
I have a job.
I'll work
some more hours.
I don't need school.
"Clandestine, secret,
hidden, undercover."
Not you.
Annoying,
you annoying me.
Like, really.
"Turbulent, violently
disturbed...
Come on, yo.
"...agitated, unruly."
That's yours.
Anyway, how much
we paid him last time?
Six twenty-five.
So, that's
another 275 for
the rest of the month.
Electric?
Half.
Phone?
Let it ride.
Gas?
How much is it?
Eighty-five.
Half.
No, mmm-mmm.
Let it ride.
I could get
some more hours.
No.
You know
what you need to do.
Nah, Candy,
I can't just dip out
on you like that, man.
Please, I was
doing just fine before
you moved in, remember?
You working was
only supposed to
be temporary.
Remember that?
I'm only gonna work
for a little bit.
Ma would've wanted you
to be done with...
Who?
Yo, don't even...
Just... Just stop.
Mom would have
wanted you to be
done by now.
Look, I'll get
the money orders
in the morning.
I'll look into it.
The next test is
coming up soon.
I said
I'll look into it.
Without them and
their courageous efforts,
we wouldn't
have been able
to pull this off.
(CONTINUES SPEAKING ON TV)
Look, it's on again.
Check it out, Free.
Channel Five
and Channel Two.
(MACK LAUGHING)
Look who's big time.
Oh, yeah,
but my brother
looked clean though.
Yeah, you look like,
you look like, uh,
that guy on TV.
(ALL LAUGHING)
MACK: Oh, yeah...
There's been
more of that
since they opened up
that new club
'cross the way.
Excuse me, Miss?
Miss?
On certain Fridays
they got this,
you know...
Special party
going on.
Miss?
Or should I say, "Sir"?
Sir?
Hello?
Chill out, Sock.
Hey, my man,
you hear me
talking to you?
Hey.
ARTHUR:
Mind your business.
Hey!
And a pack of Kool.
Say, I've been trying
to get your attention.
Do you go by
sir or miss?
Will that be all, ma'am?
Yeah.
Look, I just had
a simple question
I wanted to ask.
MACK: $67.05.
See, I just wanna know,
how does pussy taste?
You know, I just
want to know if
you go with women
for the taste,
or is it because
you too dry,
crusty, and ugly,
so don't no
man want you?
(LAUGHING)
I can't lie.
The pussy do
taste good.
Oh, yeah?
Maybe you should
try it sometime.
Or better yet,
ask your wife
how much she like me.
Fuckin' bulldagger!
He-she dyke!
Yeah.
(LAUGHING)
Hey, ask yo' wife!
She told you.
She ain't
tell me shit!
What the fuck y'all
niggas are laughing for!
Oh, shut up, man,
your big mouth
got you in trouble
as usual.
Thought you was
my friend, Mack.
Oh, man!
But I guess I didn't
expect you to
defend me, Free.
Way your daughter's running
around here bull-dyke.
Say what?
Hey! Hey, hey,
hey, hey, hey!
Come on,
he don't mean nothin'.
What?
He don't know
what he talking about, man.
He ain't moved
outside of a
two mile radius
of where
he crawled out
his mama's pussy.
He don't know shit!
I been to Poughkeepsie!
Yeah, well, get your
Poughkeepsie ass
out my store!
Fuck y'all!
I should arrest
your ass.
Man, fuck y'all!
Come, come on, Free.
Don't pay him no mind,
he just talking trash.
...had you all mad.
ALIKE: I wasn't mad.
Yes, you was.
Yo, Candy,
I'm home yo.
Getting all crazy.
Damn, this
your color, man.
So what's the deal,
incog-negro?
Ma has me
hemmed up.
Your phone ain't broke.
You coulda
called a nigga.
My bad.
She's got me
hanging out
with this
chick from church.
It's crazy.
Well, is she
making you?
I mean, you a
grown-ass
woman, bruh!
Here,
put these on.
So I guess
the piers is out
for this Saturday, huh?
Uh... I don't know
if that's me anymore.
That's hot, yo,
you should rock that.
I was thinking
maybe we could do
something different.
Different like what?
I don't know.
Like, maybe
check out
an open mic
or something.
Open mic? Nah, man,
there's plenty of
chicks at the piers.
You just gotta be
more confident.
I mean I haven't
even wore this,
you could rock that.
If you want.
But I understand
if you got
better things to do.
No. I'm down.
I don't want you
getting all hemmed up.
No, seriously...
I'm down for
whatever.
Real?
Promise.
A'ight.
I'ma take Saturday
off at work,
it's going to be on
and poppin',
you feel me?
It's gonna be
mad tight.
We goin' get
that punani, yo.
Feel me?
ALIKE: They look fake.
AUDREY: No, I think
they're happy.
Now, that looks fake.
You should wear
your hair down
more often.
Your father
likes it up.
It looks
nice down.
Maybe.
Give this back
to Bina's mom
when you go over there
tomorrow night.
Saturday night?
We talked about this.
No, we didn't!
Lee.
I had plans
this weekend!
Well, you don't have
to go to Bina's.
You can stay here
with me on
Saturday night.
God!
Come on.
So you like Destiny's Kids?
Mmm-mmm.
JP?
Nope.
What about Fiddy?
No, I don't like
any of that
commercial bullshit.
Okay, so who
do you like?
Just some underground stuff.
None of that crap
they play on the radio.
Okay, like who?
You know,
people you probably
never heard of.
Conscious stuff.
Okay, like who?
Like Trees,
Black Circle,
Far Front.
Far Front?
Girl, I know
Far Front.
Really?
Yeah!
What about, um,
Trade, or BRawls?
Or what about,
um, Mama Dobia?
Uh-oh. What do you know
about Mama Bodia?
Let me find out.
(PHONE RINGING)
See. You don't
even know me.
MRS. SINGLETARY:
Oh, hi, Audrey.
Yes, she's here.
Yeah, yeah.
No, no, I understand.
Sure.
Not a problem.
What about rock?
It's cool.
All right, I'm out.
Wait, oh, hey,
wait, hey.
You gotta
check this out.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Wow.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
Hello!
Hey.
You look nice.
Oh, um,
is Lee home?
No, she's not,
she's out
with a friend.
Oh, do you know
what time she'll be back?
She won't be back.
She's out with a friend
the entire evening.
Oh, 'cause,
we was gonna...
You take care.
Goodnight.
(SINGING) The love is gone
but the memory lingers...
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Yo, this shit is hot.
Oh, don't you
gotta go?
It's cool, I'll...
I'll cover for you.
Nah, I wanna stay.
Hey, this is Lee,
I'm not able
to take your call.
Please leave a message
at the sound
of the tone. Peace.
Hey, yo,
where you at, Lee?
Yo, hit me up
when you
get here, a'ight?
A'ight?
Come on, man,
let's go, man.
A'ight, yo.
What happened?
She didn't fucking
show up, man.
Well, you stressing
that shit too much.
(HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
Uh, Mrs. Alvarado's trying
to get me to check out
one of these places.
Oh, hell, no.
This is for
old people.
You know what,
I'll write down
some places for you.
And maybe you can read
some of my stuff, too?
Definitely.
Yo, y'all remember
when we used to
come out here
all night?
Shit, used to.
You staying
with your sister
now, huh?
Yeah.
Lucky as hell, man.
Think?
My sister be home by six,
so, you gotta be out by then.
A'ight,
good-looking.
Yeah, there's some
lunch meat in the fridge
if you want some.
I appreciate you.
Yeah.
Okay, easy, easy.
Watch the
right hand side,
watch the right.
I am!
Okay.
Oh, careful of the curb!
All right.
Okay.
Good, good.
See.
I did it.
Can I drive
back home? Please?
Uh, I don't know
about all that girl.
You're shaky.
Please?
Here, here,
get us some chips and
we'll think about it.
Come...
Give me some time
to consider.
Careful.
Hey, Mack!
Hey there.
Hey, Mr. Ferguson.
How you doing?
I'm good,
how you doing?
I'm all right,
I'm all right.
Thanks.
MACK: Yeah, I see where
Alike been running
you around again, huh?
Oh, little bit,
little bit,
but you know,
I still got it,
though.
Yeah, I remember
that crossover
you used to have.
You got to come out
there with us
so I can show her
what it's like
in the fifties.
(STORE DOOR OPENING)
Get in the car.
Wait, I'm driving!
You said I could...
Get in the car.
(INAUDIBLE)
(SIGHS)
Look, um...
You know you're
daddy's girl, right?
ALIKE: "A butterfly,
briefly suffocated
"on the mucus
of its own change,
"imprisoned by the
membranous chaff
"of its own
underdeveloped wings
"and cramped
in the darkness
"of the too tight cocoon
of its own creation,
"pauses, thinking
death inevitable,
"prepares to die
in the absolute solitude
of swollen husk.
"A crack appears,
"a thin, jagged light
connecting the inner
to the outer world,
"a butterfly,
briefly paralyzed by
the imminence of death,
"discovers life
is possible."
MRS. ALVARADO:
Comments? Critiques?
Julie, tell me
what you think.
I like how
she described
the butterfly.
I could almost
see her...
I liked
your story though,
it was tight.
Yeah, which one?
The one about
the...
Karma.
About how things
come back to you.
That one,
it was tight.
For real? Thanks.
Yeah.
I wasn't gonna
say anything, but...
I liked yours, too.
Why?
Why wasn't
I gonna say anything,
or why did I like it?
No, why did you like it?
I don't know,
it just...
It felt real.
Okay.
Didn't you have
a different shirt
on earlier?
What?
Nothin'.
No, say what you're
gonna say.
Nothin'.
Yeah, I had on
a different shirt.
That's cool.
So how come you weren't
going to say
anything about it?
About your shirt?
About the poem.
'Cause you're moody.
Moody?
And quiet.
I'm not moody!
Yeah, right!
What?
This is me.
Hey, it's not so bad
when there's
a little conversation!
You wanna come up?
Who gave you this?
The bear?
My dad.
No, this.
Girl, my stupid
ex-boyfriend
gave me that.
Oh, cute.
Not really.
But I guess it was
at the time.
So this is the artist
I was telling you about.
Her stuff is like...
I don't know, dense.
Yeah, this is straight.
You burn me a copy?
Yeah. Yeah,
yeah, yeah.
Good. Thanks.
I got some other stuff
for you, too.
Cool.
So who do you
hang out with?
'Cause I never really
see you with anybody.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean for it
to come out like that.
I was just curious 'cause
I don't really like
anybody that
goes there either.
No, my, my friend Laura
used to go there.
Not now,
but she's
coming back.
Cool.
'Cause I was gonna say,
I'm going to
this house party
and, you know,
you can come
if you want to.
They play like
this kind of music.
Sure.
How am I
supposed to dress?
You don't gotta dress,
you just come however.
Come as you are.
Okay.
Can I see?
It's... It's mostly
old stuff, though.
Oh, this is the one
that you did earlier.
Yeah.
It's nice.
Here you go.
Take it.
You play too much!
Just take it.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
So, what's so private?
Nothing.
It's just
my writings.
Why'd you
do that for?
I'm sorry.
I thought...
No, I'm sorry,
I just gotta go.
But I thought that...
I'm sorry.
We gonna get y'all
on the board,
God damn it!
Okay.
Let's play, keep it rolling,
keep it rolling!
GIRL 1: Ain't giving you
no stupid-ass hand.
(KNOCKING AT DOOR)
You gonna get that?
Yeah, I got it.
There you go.
Cut that!
Come on,
bring it out,
bring it out.
GIRL 2: Ooh!
We went in
the hole one time.
GIRL 1:
Y'all went in the hole twice!
Yo, wassup.
LAURA:
Yo, whaddup, Lee!
Yo, what you got, Ty?
Pick 'em up! Nasty!
(ALL CLAMORING)
Oh! We goin' to eight!
We goin' to eight!
Uh, can I talk to you
for a second?
Yo, I'm busy right now,
I'm doing something.
Holdup, holdup!
That was my jack!
I cut! I cut!
Laura, I really need
to talk to you.
Laura, I really need...
Yo, man.
I told you
I'm fucking busy!
Shit!
Nah. Nah, nah.
I'm busy.
GIRL 1: Goodnight.
GIRL 2: Get home safe!
Yo...
I thought that
was your girl.
Mind yo business!
I'm her girl!
Exactly. Exactly.
This will...
You go ahead.
That's what
I'm talking about.
Y'all niggas don't know.
You know, boo.
Get the fuck
outta here, yo!
Dad!
Come on, now,
you know that's
not what I want.
That's not what
I'm saying!
Lis... Listen to me.
Are you going
to listen to me?
ALIKE: Dad?
Listen, I gotta go.
I gotta go,
my daughter's...
My daughter's up!
Dad?
Talk to you later, bye.
Who was that?
What you doing up?
Just wanted to talk.
Dad, the plate!
Don't trash the plate.
Aren't you hungry?
No.
Ate already.
You ate at work?
Grabbed some takeout.
Oh, where?
Why you asking me so many
goddamn questions, girl?
What's wrong with you?
You don't question me.
Sorry.
Hold up, Alike.
Come on back. Look.
I got patties.
Beef?
And chicken.
Come on.
Listen, um...
Your mom was worried
that uh...
She's been wanting me
to ask you,
that, uh...
How's school?
Straight As?
Probably.
That's right.
Wanna sip?
I said a sip! A sip!
What's on your mind?
Nothin'.
What if...
What if say...
Somebody liked you?
They like you?
Or they "like you"
like you?
They "like you"
like you.
Uh-huh.
They haven't said
anything yet but...
But what if...
All right, what if the person
is kind of
like a friend,
but you know
they like you
more than that?
Well, I think
that's the best way,
to start as friends.
What if...
What if the person is...
What if the person...
What's his name?
What grade is he in?
I'm gonna look
his ass up in the system.
Wait till I tell
your mama.
She'll be
so goddamn happy.
Yeah.
Say, uh...
There's this new, uh,
women's club
up there
by the liquor store.
Do you...
Have you...
You haven't heard
anything about it, right?
Called the Kitty Litter,
Cat Box,
something like that?
Nah, never even
heard of it.
Good.
'Cause it's a...
That's a
rough neighborhood.
You know that, right?
I had a case
over there.
You wanna be careful.
Stay away
from that element.
In case it ever
comes up.
I'll be careful.
Good.
I know you will.
Dad, when you were
on the phone earlier...
Uh-huh.
It sounded like...
I mean...
I guess you're headed
back to work, huh?
Yup.
Your mama still up?
Probably.
Tell her I had to work.
Love you.
Hey.
I'm real sorry about
the other day.
It's cool.
Things have been crazy.
But look,
I'm really sorry
I bugged out.
It's just, I didn't know
that you...
I wasn't expecting that.
First kiss? (CHUCKLES)
It's cool.
You still comin'
to the party?
Um... I don't know.
I need to try to
catch up with Laura.
Oh, okay.
No, but I do wanna hang,
but I mean,
maybe we could do both.
Cool.
Uh, do you want to
spend the night?
You know, maybe avoid
that whole curfew thing?
Oh, you're home?
Hey.
I must have
dozed off.
How long you been in?
Hour.
Did you see the plate
over there?
This is fine.
Why don't you come
sit over here?
There's room.
You could see
the TV better.
This is fine.
Thank you.
Just alike.
Say what?
You and your daughter.
Did you talk to Lee yet?
I told you she's still...
I talked to Alike.
You did?
Everything's fine,
like I told you.
Matter of fact,
she's got a boyfriend.
A boyfriend?
Just give her some space.
Space?
She's never around as it is.
And you're just like her!
Creeping in all hours
of the night.
Running around
like you got
something to hide.
Both of you!
And acting like
I'm the big bad witch!
What about me, huh?
I'm here alone
by myself
all the time.
And Sharonda's
getting older and she's
starting to go out,
and pretty soon...
I don't have
anything to hide.
Look, I told you,
I talked to Alike.
Everything's fine.
Did you ask her?
No, because
I don't have to.
Besides,
I would know, okay?
I know my daughter
better than anyone else.
"Your daughter."
So all of a sudden
now she's your daughter?
And I'm telling you,
she's fine.
Well, I guess then
I just shouldn't say
anything else about this!
That's your damn problem.
You're too much of
a damn worrywart.
Well, let's hope
you're right, detective.
Will you
shut the fuck up?
An hour? Really?
I'm not your
damn dumb floozy
on the street
and you will not
talk to me like that!
ARTHUR: Dammit, Audrey,
you're making a scene!
I'm not making a scene.
You're the one
making a scene!
You're all
paranoid and sick!
You're never here!
(ARGUMENT CONTINUES)
I know you're
not scared.
I'm not.
Lee...
Hmm?
I hope you know
it doesn't matter
to me.
I know.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(SINGING)
And she ran like blood
Through the corridors
of your mind
Into a brand new future
One without the
likes of you
BINA: You are mad fun
to hang out with,
I have to say.
ALIKE: Are you serious?
BINA: Yeah! (LAUGHING)
Whatever!
I'm just playing.
About... About
six months ago.
What's good?
What's up?
How you doing?
Good.
So what do you think?
She's cool, right?
She's hot, right?
I told you!
Right? I told you!
It was so...
Yo, I'm right here.
Oh, my bad!
I thought you were
right beside me.
No. Anyway,
I was thinking
next weekend,
the three of us,
we could,
you know, go out.
I'm sorry about
all the drama.
Nah, it's cool.
I mean, I should have...
No.
You know.
What I'm saying is,
I probably overreacted.
I mean...
But then, I don't know,
seeing the
two of you together...
I'm glad you're finally
happy though.
Come on, man,
you know you're
my best friend.
I'm not, no one's ever...
You don't have to say
anything, yo.
I just want to
get this off my chest,
all right?
I'm glad she
makes you happy.
I'm happy for you.
A'ight?
'Cause I love you.
Hey.
Hey!
MIKA: Come on,
let's get out of here.
BINA: So...
Wait! Laura.
Come on, let's go,
I know some...
Laura!
LAURA: What up, boo?
Come on,
let's go.
I'm not sleeping.
Yes, you are.
Are there any more
brownies left?
Nope.
What?
Nothing.
Nothing!
What's wrong?
This is...
I never...
I'm sorry,
I'm trippin'.
It's okay.
We don't have to.
(PAPER TEARING)
(KNOCKING AT THE DOOR)
Oh.
I thought you
went out for something.
How you been?
You know me and Candy
doing real good.
We might even get
a bigger place.
She workin'
at the hospital now.
You'd be real proud.
She might even
get her RN.
How's...
How's pops?
You look good.
You look real good.
You know, we miss you
and everything.
I don't, I don't want
to take too much
of your time
or anything like that.
I just...
I got my...
I'm getting my stuff
together, too.
You know?
So I did it.
I got my GED.
Nah, nah, I did it!
I got my GED!
Good morning.
Hey.
You're up already.
Actually, it's after
one o'clock.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I'm just trying
to clean up,
that's all.
Okay, let me help you then.
No, it's all right,
I got it.
What's wrong?
Nothing!
Look, um,
last night was...
It was amazing,
and thank you.
Last night was just
playing around, all right?
Look, we can
slow things down.
People don't
have to know
that we're together.
Together?
Whoa.
No, uh-uh.
Look, if you don't want
to call it that,
that's fine,
but don't act
like nothing happened.
I'm not like "gay" gay,
I'm just...
You know,
I'm just doing my thing,
that's all.
I'm just, I'm not ready
for all of this, okay?
Excuse me.
Hey, Lee, Lee!
Hold up.
What?
You don't have to
tell anybody, okay?
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(SCREAMING)
Where in the hell
have you been?
You hear me
talking to you?
You left Bina
hours ago!
I am not Dad!
I'm not your husband,
so stop coming
at me like I am!
I'm not your companion
and I'm not
your friend!
You made that
abundantly clear!
I'm your daughter!
And I have my own shit
to deal with!
You must have
lost your damn mind!
You wait
till your father
gets home!
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(SOBBING)
ARTHUR: I would be
something else
if it wasn't for you!
I'd be a lawyer maybe!
AUDREY: Oh, you
wouldn't be shit because
I made you!
You couldn't even
get a damn B...
Always thinking
about yourself!
...on a test until
I helped you!
We'd have more money!
We'd have a damn
brownstone instead of living
in the basement of one!
You the one who's
making a scene!
Doing all this paranoid shit!
You're never here!
I'm not paranoid.
I can't take
this shit anymore!
Will you stop
saying that!
It's the truth!
Audrey, stop it!
Alike, go back
to bed.
You have a slut
on the side!
Nothing's going on!
I'm not paranoid!
I can't take
this shit anymore!
You are paranoid!
Alike, baby,
go back to
your room!
SHARONDA: Lee, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no.
ALIKE: Go upstairs.
Don't leave me,
please! No, No!
Go in my room
and lock the door.
Keep me company, please?
Do not come
out the room!
Go upstairs in my room
and lock the door.
Please!
AUDREY:
I'm not paranoid!
You are paranoid!
All you do is break!
When do I see you?
When do the kids see you?
I just need to
get outta here!
You don't want to
face the facts!
You don't wanna
No dammit, that's not true!
It is true!
Look, would you
stop saying that?
It is true!
Audrey, stop it!
Alike go back to bed.
Your daughter is
turning into a damn man
right before your eyes
and you can't even see it!
No, you take that back!
Shut the fuck up
about that, Audrey!
Mom, Dad, stop! Please!
Tell him!
Tell him where
you hang out!
Tell him about your
butch-ass girlfriend!
Laura is not my girlfriend!
What the hell are you
talking about?
Alike, please,
just go back
to your room, baby.
Tell him! Tell him!
Tell me what?
Tell him you're a
nasty ass dyke!
No! No! No!
Alike, you tell your mama
that's not true!
Baby, tell her!
You see! You see!
Will you shut the hell up?
You tell her.
Dad.
You tell your mother
that's not true.
You already know.
No, I don't know.
You tell your mama
it's just a phase.
It's not a phase!
AUDREY: See, you should
have done something!
You should have
done something!
What's wrong with you?
There's nothing
wrong with me!
This is your fault!
Shut the hell up!
Lemme talk!
If you had been here!
(SHOUTING) Yeah. I'm gay!
You say it again.
Say it again!
I'm a lesbian!
Yeah, I'm a dyke!
Audrey! Audrey!
Get off! Get off!
(ALL SHOUTING)
Audrey!
No, you're not!
You get off of me!
Come on!
You cheater!
You get off me!
AUDREY: Get off of me!
ARTHUR: Come on,
we gotta go!
(ALIKE SOBBING)
(SNIFFLING)
Okay.
Would you care
to say grace?
Heavenly Father,
we thank you
for this food.
We pray for your
continued blessing.
We pray...
We thank...
Amen.
This food should
be delicious.
I got the recipe
from a magazine.
And I made
your green beans
that you like so much.
Sharonda, could you
pass me the green beans?
This is yummy.
Dad, you know
where she is.
(WRITING)
LAURA: Yo, Lee.
(EXHALES)
Where's Mom?
She...
Your mother
couldn't make it.
You remember
our old place?
Way out in Queens?
It was our first apartment.
We were so proud.
It had all those trees
around it.
In October,
the whole block would
be covered with leaves.
You remember?
Couldn't have been
more than two years old.
When that wind would blow,
those leaves would
come rushing
down the street at us.
You thought
they were alive.
You'd get so scared.
You'd cry and scream
and beg for us
to pick you up.
I would try and tell you,
"They're only leaves, baby,"
and make you stay
on the ground,
but your mother
would always pick you up.
She always
picked you up.
Remember how we used
to race to the phone
when it rang?
I've been accepted
into an early
college program.
It starts in the spring.
It's in Berkeley.
It's a 10-week
writing workshop.
Boot camp,
then I could start
summer semester.
We can talk
about that, okay?
I need you to meet
with my guidance counselor,
so you could
sign the paperwork,
so I can graduate early.
I'm sorry, all right?
I'm sorry
I let her hurt you.
I just need to know if
you'll sign the paperwork.
Yes or no?
Can you forgive me?
You can always
come back home.
Things are going to
be different,
I promise you.
Dad...
I'm not runnin'.
I'm choosin'.
I'm not
going back home.
I know.
And you could tell Mom
she was right.
God doesn't
make mistakes.
You should
tell her yourself.
ALIKE: Mom.
Lee.
Alike.
How have you been?
Fine.
Did Dad tell you?
Yeah. He told me.
How you been?
I sure hope you've
been keeping
yourself safe.
I love you, Mom.
I said I love you.
I'll be praying for you.
ALIKE: "Heartbreak opens
onto the sunrise
"For even breaking
is opening
"And I am broken
"I am open
"Broken to the new light
without pushing in
"Open to the possibilities
within pushing out
"See the love shine in
through my cracks
"See the light shine out
through me
"I am broken
"I am open
"I am broken open
Be careful.
ALIKE: "See the love light
shining through me
"Shining through
my cracks
"Through the gaps
"My spirit takes journey
"My spirit takes flight
You just better
fuckin' call, man.
ALIKE: "Could not have
risen otherwise
"And I am not running
"I am choosing
"Running is not a choice
from the breaking
"Breaking is freeing
"Broken is freedom
"I am not broken
"I am free"
(SNIFFLING)
Yeah.
MRS. ALVARADO: Yeah.