PASSING FANCY
"A geisha says she loves her client"
and he lies saying he'll come again
I fell for your honesty at first sight
I was so shy!
It's a shame to miss the main attraction
Story-telling for a kid is stupid
"Geisha Takao will come next month
Takao, in March"
Look at the barber
Forget your business, old man
"That was the true love of Takao
a geisha"
"Men yearn for love
Love is an emotional boat"
It's a wise remark
I hate girl-trouble
I hate money-trouble, but
welcome girl-trouble
Love is so elusive
Trust me and get married just once
You'll enjoy it
Have the bill charged to me
You must have been beautiful before
And now?
I can't be frank when I owe you money
Stop being curious, old man
Anywhere here I can stay?
Of course
I have a child, but no wife
Mind your son!
Homeless when you're so young?
I was at a spinning mill until yesterday
Fired?
No relatives?
That's an old trick, huh?
Young men have no pity
What are you going to do?
She can stay here
Will that be any trouble?
If so, I'll handle it
Dad! Your work!
Don't nag your father
Always be filial to your parents
Don't your teachers tell you that?
Did you know why a hand
has five fingers?
With only four
it wouldn't fit into a glove
Very funny
Thanks for last night
I spoke to her and decided
she'll work here
I was drunk. Did I force her on you?
She's very nice
I'm a good judge of people
Sorry, but I choose only people I like
Everyone is so kind to me
You hear that? How sweet!
What grade are you in?
My name's Tomio Kimur
I'm in third grade
My son Tomio is very intelligent
With better manners
he'd top his class
Yes! He's too good
for a dumb father like you
I'm not as dumb a father as they say
Doesn't Tomio need lunch?
The school feeds him
He's a "stupid" without lunch
You'd be a "dunce" without lunch
How can I go to grade school with kids?
He'd be the school's prize dunce
I forgot to ask your name
It's Harue
What was that?
Harue
She reminds me...
I mean Harue
She looks exactly like her
Who? The woman who jilted you?
No, not her
Who? That little slut?
Act your age
Age doesn't matter
I'll get an advance from him
I want to buy a gift for her
Don't ask too often
If he refuses, so what?
How stupid he is!
Where did you find the girl?
She's like my daughter
You're one to protect your treasures
How could you keep her?
Anyone who harms her dies
You understand?
For whom does she powder her face?
Ah, how very sweet!
It's a terrible waste!
Let's get going
No, not today
I have a stomachache
Drop the act!
No one appreciates your play
I forgot it
My safety charm
I don't dare go anywhere without it
May he get to the factory in a hurry
My stomach hurts so
I prayed for recovery
I'd better be going now
You're dressed up, Kihachi
Where's the funeral?
You think I'm going to a funeral?
How ominous!
Not going to work?
I bought it for you
Keep it a secret
She gets jealous
Do you like me?
You're so very kind to me, uncle
Don't call me uncle
Do you prefer me to Jiro?
He sort of scares me
But he's nice when you know him
On second thoughts I'm even better
This one really costs a lot
But the world is highly complicated
May I have this?
Do you like soldiers?
High ranking ones?
Let's go to Jiro's place
It was messy, so...
How kind you are!
Don't act so friendly, huh?
No more photos of you in uniform?
She wants some
You're shrewd
You made the kid say sweet words
My friend is at your shop
Go back quickly
You won't return evil for good
will you?
I'm not jealous
but don't ridicule the man next door
He has a reputation, too
I'm not so mean a woman
He's so kind to me that
I regard him as my uncle
Why not regard him as a husband?
You'll never be able to know
...the way I feel
I'm afraid I don't have time
for guessing games
"But now, ever since the accident..."
Come to the restaurant
The madam hasn't seen you
for a long time
I don't want to be with that Harue
I want to talk about her, do you mind?
Talk, I'm listening
I'll come to your place later. Wait for me
You look quite modern recently
It's the times
Do I look twice as handsome
as I used to?
Go somewhere and play
I'm busy studying now
Don't interrupt me
Just go out and play, will you?
It's a kind of filialness
Waiting is torture
There was no need for a gift
We can be informal
Actually, it's about Harue
She's so nice. I feel as if
she's one of the family
For that reason
I must think about her age
It's a pity to leave a girl her age alone...
With grown men like Jiro around
I'd be pleased if Jiro decided
to marry her
Did he make love to her?
I don't know
But be keeps away from her
She's too good for him
It's natural
I was wrong
She's too young for me
Did you fancy her as your wife?
Things like that can happen
It's so hot
I'm asking you, for old times sake
to convince him
You have my trust. Please try
Whatever you may think
I'm picky about my woman
Oh? Frankly, she's too good for you
Then you marry her
It's good luck to be loved
by a young girl
I must have let down my guard with her
You sure are stubborn!
But then, so am I
I'll match you, that's for sure!
However, to Kihachi
this is a great tragedy
Why brood? Why not tell a story?
Young man
You call me young?
Do I really look so young?
Don't flatter me
I've got news! This boy's dad is stupid
No, he's not."
He can't even read, can he?
He just looks at cartoons
He doesn't go to the factory
Only to restaurants
Who did it?
I did. Me
I always tell the truth
George Washington cut down
a cherry tree
You cheat by saying what I don't know
Even the truth can't make you
a magician
You can't re-create the tree
What a dumb!
You don't work, you're always drunk
You trying to lecture your dad?
Drunk or sober, I'm still your dad
You're so dumb!
You can't even read, huh?
Newspapers you sell to junkmen
Son!
Forgive me, son
Something is wrong with me
I'm a dumb old dad, but don't hate me
"Then, the following morning..."
That matter... how is it?
Don't be so hasty. Just leave it to me
Behave yourself at school
and be attentive
Be patient and study
and you'll get an education
I'm patient and go to the factory
So it pays me
50 sen
Buy whatever you want
How funny!
You can't live as a pauper's son
Examine it well. It's milled
You can polish your nails
Very funny
How extravagant today!
I haven't taken care of him properly
I want to act like a good father
50 sen is a lot to a boy his age
Like 10 yen to us
Not ten. You mean a thousand!
I want him to feel as if he's rich
just once in his life
About Jiro...
It's time you accept, Jiro
It's time you quit nagging me
You're to go home. Your son is ill
My son can't possibly be ill
But he could get hurt
Why did you get sick so suddenly?
He ate his fill in one go
You spent it all?
It's difficult for a poor man's kid
You did it. You gave him too much
Nurse him carefully
A mere stomachache
Have a drink and go to sleep
This wine is very mellow
I was worried. I left work early
It's serious. So do something
Don't shock me
He's my son. He can't die so easily
Have a doctor examine him
Get ready, old man
Then, 48 hours later
We'll try our best
This charm is very effective
It's terrible
We may have to hold a funeral
I'm glad I have formal summer wear
Don't tempt Fate
Don't worry. Your son won't die
You say that because he's not your son
I'm sorry, but I have to go now
I'll leave Harue
If she can help, just ask her
Your son's teacher is here
I can't talk to a teacher
Will you greet him for me?
You must be very worried
You have the ball game?
We beat Class Three's team
What's the problem?
50 sen's worth of candy all at once
Orange pop, jelly...
...cookies, fried cake...
...toffee and watermelon...
I guess it was all my fault, huh?
I gave him cold wine, too
Not only that, he ate bananas
What's his illness called?
An acute intestinal catarrh
Your pals want you to get well
and return to school
Tomio's a bright boy
He'll be a great man some day
Be a good boy and get well
Hear what he said?
He's very kind
So now you must get well
I have only you
So don't die before I do
Do you know why a hand
has five fingers?
I'll never forget that one
Can't even make 5 yen
It's a shame to be uneducated
I made my son ill and can't pay the bill
The factory won't give me an advance
I can't get money
I have a bad habit of
spending every penny
Don't do that, old man
The doctor wants to talk to you
What's the big problem?
How can I pay the hospital?
How much money do you need?
Maybe forty or fifty yen
I'll raise the money
I'm sure I can
Now is the time I can
repay your kindness
What a wonderful girl!
Such a young girl trying to save a man!
Hearing your works
I could even lose Tomio
He would gladly die, too
I'll bring the money soon
Don't be so proud!
I may be poor
but I won't depend on you
Hurry up and go to the hospital
I want to talk with her for a while
Stay put in your place
Do you think you can shame
the two of us?
But this is my chance to
pay back his kindness
That's an excuse. People would think
we made you sacrifice
What happens to a young person
who tries to raise lots of money?
Who cares what happens to me?
Who cares about me?
I'll raise the money
Haven't you any idea how I feel?
Don't say anything. Just obey me
I know a place where I can get money
Why do you need so much money?
I can't tell you. Just lend it to me
We're old friends. Please
I know you'll pay me back, but
When will you repay me?
"Hokkaido Needs Men!"
After I get to Hokkaido
I was only kidding
Thanks to warm-hearted people...
Know why sea water is salty?
To salt salmon with
Very funny
Give me another fifty sen and try
Don't pester people. You should've died
Wanted to eat funeral cake, did you?
You told me a lie
This water is salty
but there's no salmon. Why?
Suddenly Jiro is going to repay me
All this brat does is cause trouble
It's not goodbye forever. Don't cry
When you finally understand me
we must part
I don't think I'll ever be happy
Don't be pessimistic
Be patient for a while
I'm going willingly
I hate sad farewells
I'll come back, I promise
Are you going to Hokkaido?
I've no right to complain
but you might have told me
Let me go to Hokkaido
You have Tomio, old man
Kids don't need parents
Tomio will flourish without care
You have a great future, Jiro
People will be relying on you
I leave at ten. Don't stop me
I didn't mean to
Don't hate me
I'm going there
Take care of Tomio
I can give up the money knowing
it saved the boy's life
You needn't go so far away
leaving your son behind
Your sincerity moves me. It's enough
Accept his kindness
You can work and repay him
We must help one another
The barber talks like a saint
It's nice to live long
I've never felt any better
Remember to obey
your teachers at school
Don't eat too much candy
Will you be back?
What a silly question!
I'm taking a vacation
Know why a hand has five fingers?
If we had only four
it wouldn't fit a glove
What's that land?
America?
We've just left the port
My son is a bright boy at school
With better manners, he'd be top
No! No!
Won't this boat stop?
Is that land linked with Tokyo?
Of course it is
I'm sorry, but I'll go home
Why is sea water salty?
To salt salmon with
Very funny