Good morning, Miss Lanier.
If you're this early, you'll
have to take the local.
Alright, Phil.
20th floor Executive, Miss Lanier.
─ Thank you, Phil.
Good morning, Miss Lanier.
─ Good morning, Martha.
I couldn't find a cab anywhere.
─ Such a lovely day, though.
40th Floor Executive. Ramsey
& Company. Miss Stevens.
I'm sorry sir, our switchboard
doesn't open until nine.
You will be able to reach
him shortly thereafter
Ann.
That's correct, sir.
Mr Staples begins with
the company today.
I'll leave your message on his desk.
Ann, would you put this on
Mr Staples's desk, please.
Yes, ma'am.
Mr Staples will be in Mr Quinn's
old office, Executive Corridor.
Yes, I know.
I said deliver it, not read it.
─ Yes, ma'am.
Executive. 40th Floor. Miss Stevens.
Morning.
─ Hi.
Good morning, madam.
What did Margie say?
She's to go to work next door?
Oh no.
Well I'm glad I don't.
─ Not there.
Well, they really fixed up a new
Exec's office for him, didn't they.
Very nice.
A new man.
Right next door to your boss.
And awfully close to Mr Ramsey.
It so happens that the new man.
What's his name?
Staples?
─ Uhuh.
Will be working with Mr Briggs.
They try to have adjoining offices.
Marjorie baby, you're awfully defensive.
I guess that's because you're
worried about your Mr Briggs.
Run along, will you.
May I have some more cream, please?
Next car, please. Next car.
Next car, please. Okay.
Next car.
Harry, Charlie, Joe. Express down.
No stops. We're jammed.
Next car, please. Next car. Next car.
Good morning, Mr Ramsey.
Next car, please.
Thank you, Lenny.
─ Yes, sir.
"Miss Lanier. We've seen him."
"He's here."
─ Thank you, Martha.
Chief operator, please.
Miss Phillips, you can put those three
long-distance calls through to Mr Ramsey.
Portland, Dallas, St Louis offices.
Good morning, Mr Ramsey.
─ Good morning, Miss Lanier.
Any messages?
You have calls place for our
Portland, Dallas and St Louis offices.
Nothing else important, sir.
Martin Tool & Die.
You said you'd wired him.
Yes, you'll find a copy in my briefcase.
You are right as usual.
Nothing important.
I have the Portland
report in my briefcase.
I want it teletyped this
morning to Seattle.
Have someone there drive over to Portland
and get it to Johnson before lunch.
Then run off 20 copies,
confidential mimeographing.
Have them ready in time
for the board meeting.
I want it on the agenda.
Has Mr Staples arrived yet?
─ Not yet, sir.
Delay the meeting until
ten this morning.
To give you time to get the
report mimeo'd and distributed.
I want it read, and carefully.
Get word underground
to the secretaries ..
That no-one can count on making
any early luncheon appointments.
And make a note.
Staples is to sit one down
from Vandeventer on my left.
Yes sir.
Let me know as soon
as Mr Staples arrives.
Yes, Mr Ramsey.
Well, Fred .. here we are.
Yeah, here we are.
A little different
to Mansfield, isn't it.
Now I know what a mother feels when her
child goes to school for the first time.
Well, goodbye, mother.
It looks big, doesn't it.
Well, give me a chance, honey.
Maybe I can cut it down to my size.
And I'm a little late.
─ Shall I call you when I ..
No, no, no. You go on home
after you've finished shopping.
And find a garage somewhere
around mid-town to park the car.
I'll phone you on what
train I'll be on. Bye bye.
Goodbye, darling.
Ramsey & Company, the board room ..
Yes, sir. Executive or Administrative?
The Executive. Mr Ramsey.
─ 40th floor, sir.
Morning. Morning.
Oh, you want the tower, sir.
The tower elevator, sir.
It will be down in a minute.
─ Oh.
Sorry. Thank you.
─ My pleasure, sir.
Good morning, Ed. Good morning.
─ Good morning.
Good morning. Good morning.
Good morning, Jamie.
─ Good morning, Bill.
Morning, Marge. How was the weekend?
─ Fine.
Letters are on your desk. The
coffee cart is here any minute.
I can use some coffee.
─ Didn't you get any rest at all?
Couldn't even take my kind to the
double-header.   ─ What a shame.
That planning report is going
to be a real job, Marge.
This will be a big week for
you too, with that thing.
I believe we'll try a rough first draft.
─ Long?
No longer than the telephone directory.
Phew!
Marge.
Has Mr Staples come in yet, Marge?
No, sir.
Mr Staples?
─ Yes.
I'm Margaret Lanier,
Mr Ramsey's secretary.
Oh, how do you do.
Mr Ramsey would be here to welcome you
himself but he has a long distance call.
May I take you back to your office?
Why, thank you very much.
And on our way, I might show you
some of our other departments.
Have you met Miss Stevens?
I introduced myself, Miss Lanier.
─ Fine.
And may I bid you my
own personal welcome.
We are very glad to see you.
Well, that's very nice
of you. Thank you.
Now if you'll just come
with me, Mr Staples.
Miss Stevens.
Marketing and Sales are below here.
We have our own research
department on the 40th floor.
Perhaps you'd like to see that later?
This is the Executive Corridor.
Mr Ramsey's office is that
one down at the end.
Then Mr Jameson, head of purchasing.
Mr Briggs. You'll be working
closely with Mr Briggs.
Mr Vandeventer, Chief Engineer.
And this is your office.
Isn't it nice?
I hope you like it.
Mr Ramsey was told by your office that
you're especially fond of this period.
Wasn't your office in Mansfield
furnished in early American?
My furniture consisted
of two filing cabinets ..
And a surplus metal desk
off of a destroyer escort.
No, it's ..
It's really very attractive. Very.
I appreciate it very much indeed.
Excuse me, Miss Lanier.
Ann said you wanted to see me.
Oh yes, Marge.
Mr Staples, this is Miss Fleming.
How do you do.
─ How do you do.
Marge, see that Mr Staples has all he
needs in the way of office equipment.
It was arranged for this morning
at Mr Briggs' suggestion.
I must rush now, Mr Staples.
Again, a most cordial welcome.
Thank you very much.
And Marge, will you stop by at my
desk when you've finished here please?
Yes, Miss Lanier.
I think I'd better explain the
phone system, Mr Staples.
There are four lines.
One, is your private
line direct to outside.
Two is for conference calls.
Three is for inter-office.
And Four, this button,
is for your secretary.
Oh I'm sorry. May I?
─ Oh. Yes, thank you.
Yes, I think I have that.
Let me see.
Outside, inter-office ..
Conference and ..
Yes, that's ..
That's fine.
Thank heavens this isn't early American.
Busy?
No .. not at all.
Well, you must be ..?
─ Bill Briggs, your next-door neighbor.
Yes, of course. Well I'm
certainly glad to meet you, sir.
I think Mr Ramsey told me
you'd been sick, didn't he?
Oh, did he?
Actually, it's just a .. just a pesky
stomach that's been acting up on me.
You just in from Mansfield?
Yes, they took a house for us.
Oh, sit down, Mr Briggs.
Settled already? Good.
I'm not trying to set myself
up as a real New Yorker.
Altoona, Pennsylvania.
That's where I came from.
My first trip home, I was wearing spats.
I remember my father not
being able to get over it.
He says "Bill".
"Bill" he says ..
"You went to New York to see the sights,
and instead you've became one of them."
We just got here Friday afternoon.
So this morning, Nancy
insisted .. my wife.
Insisted on driving me to
work on the first morning.
Well, you know the way women are.
You know, you come out
of a .. small-town plant.
You feel a little lost
in a place like this.
Well, as I was saying, you know. We
walked into a house Friday afternoon.
And we'd never laid eyes on
the place before, you know.
And there it was furnished
like a magazine.
Milk in the icebox,
bourbon on the shelf.
I don't know. You got to hand it to 'em
the way they do things round here.
Yes, Miss Lanier handles
all that. Does a fine job.
That feeling that I got driving
into town this morning.
I got to admit it's just ..
It's just a little overwhelming.
Yes. And it's a pretty wonderful
thing to be as young as you are.
And see it all spread out
in front of you like a ..
Like a Christmas tree.
You know .. you think of ..
You think of big business.
You always think of it as being ..
Very impersonal .. you know ..?
But ..
It's really not true
with your Mr Ramsey.
I know what you mean.
How much time did you put in Mansfield?
Almost six years.
You must have blown a bugle in Ramsey's
ear in Ohio. He got you here in a hurry.
Well actually, I wasn't at all sure I
wanted to come to New York, but ..
This Ramsey is a pretty dynamic man.
Yes .. I know.
You see, you've been with the
firm some time now, haven't you?
Oh, maybe forty years or so.
I seem to recall Mr Ramsey talking
about you as a production man.
You're an engineer, aren't you?
Yes, but ..
From what he told me, I guess I'll
be a little of everything around here.
Mostly, in industrial relations.
Industrial relations?
As a matter of fact, it's
been one of my specialities.
We ..
We ought to get along
pretty well together.
I'm sure we will.
Excuse me.
Mr Ramsey has called a meeting in
the conference room, Mr Briggs.
Oh?
Well Fred, it's been a real
pleasure meeting you.
Thank you.
Mr Ramsey is expecting Mr Staples, too.
Oh.
Well then, I'll .. I'll go in
with you if you don't mind?
Not at all.
I just hope Mr Ramsey
remembers hiring me.
Mr Ramsey rarely forgets anything.
After you.
─ Thank you.
Staples?
─ Yes.           ─ Hello.
Fred, this is Harvey Jameson,
head of purchasing.
Hello. How are you?
So they finally finished it.
What?
Fred, your office. On Friday the
painters were here. It was a madhouse.
Hey Bill, are you taking
along Ramsey's breakdown?
No. I forgot that. A couple
of other things I forgot, too.
Jamie, you and Fred go in together.
I'll be a few minutes.          ─ Fine.
I suppose Lanier has
given you the Cook's tour?
What? Oh yes.
Did she show you the conference room?
Oh yes, on the other side. Yes.
Mr Briggs.
What is it, Marge?
I don't know.
Mr Briggs, I think I ought to resign.
Resign? What are you talking about?
What happened? What is it, Marge?
Mr Briggs, I've just been ordered to go
over to Mr Staples as his new secretary.
Temporarily.
─ No, I don't think so.
Who gave this order?
─ Miss Lanier.
When?
─ About five minutes ago.
You are supposed to
break in your new secretary.
They've picked a new secretary for me?
─ Yes, I think so.
Out of the question for you to resign,
Marge. To even think of resigning.
You're a fine, wonderful
woman, and a great secretary.
That's the reason they want
you over with Staples.
He'll need someone like you as he's new.
They want him to get into harness fast.
Who can tell, Marge?
One of these days ..
That .. stomach of mine
is a pretty perverse organ.
And .. I'm tired.
You know, as it must to all men.
Mr Briggs.
Have you any idea who your successor is?
Yes. They've chose Sylvia Trammel.
Miss Trammel?
─ Hmm.
It is so ordained. So be it.
She's new, but she supposed
to be very good at dictation.
Well, we'll give her
a chance to prove it.
Mr Briggs.
If I could only tell you what
this job has meant to me.
What working with you has meant to me ..
Alright, kid.
Wash up, get your money
and get out of here.
And give Mr Staples all the
best you've got in you.
I know you will. That's the
only way you operate.
I like they guy.
I have a feeling he's going to
carve out a career around here.
Yes, sir.
Everybody seems to think so.
Sorry to keep you waiting, gentlemen.
Mr Ramsey will be with us in a moment.
Been away, have you?
─ Good to see you.
Sorry, Fred. I was held
up for a few minutes.
See you later, Fred.
Where are we going to sit you?
Oh, here's an empty chair.
I guess you can sit right here.
Mr Staples, will you sit over there,
please? Right next to Mr Vandeventer.
One down from Mr Ramsey.
Welcome back, Bill. Feeling better?
Much, thank you. A little stomach upset.
Good .. I'm glad it's cleared up.
John, don't forget that contract.
Can we get it through tomorrow?
First gentlemen, I'd like you to look
over the mimeo'd sheet on top.
Haverford Mutual had some doctors look
into the matter of executive diets.
Their findings showed
incredible deficiencies.
They've gotten up some food
tables. I'll have them mimeo'd
I'd like you to look them over.
As you know, it's been my feeling that
a healthy executive is an efficient one.
I think it not amiss now to introduce
the newest member of our team.
Mr Fred Staples.
He's from Mansfield, Ohio.
As you know, he was General Manager of
Queen Tool & Die until we took it over.
His record there was a brilliant one.
He's a production engineer by training.
And an industrial
relations man by instinct.
I expect good things from him.
You've probably met everyone, but ..
Just for the record,
reading from left to right.
Mr Jameson, Head of Purchasing.
─ Yeah, we've met.
Mr Grannigan, Controller.
Mr Gordon, Head of Sales.
Mr Latham, Head of Service.
Mr Portier, Chief of Operations.
How do you do, sir.
─ Nice to know you.
And Mr Vandeventer, Chief Engineer.
How are you? Nice to see you.
─ Pleasure.
Oh, and of course you've met Mr Briggs.
Oh yes.
He's our Vice President and
Assistant General manager.
In charge of everything that everybody
else forgets to be in charge of.
Now gentlemen, you
all have before you a ..
Copy of the Williamston
Plant purchase prospectus.
Mr Jameson, did you attach a supplement?
It's right there, Mr Ramsey.
Page 17r, under "Process Equipment".
Mr Grannigan, the stock purchase plan
I outlined. I have your comments here?
You do, Mr Ramsey.
Feasible, is it?
─ Very much so, in my opinion.
Good.
Well.
That about winds it up, unless there
are any .. further points to be made.
I do think, Mr Ramsey, if we could keep
the transaction under wraps for a bit.
At least during the preliminaries.
You know what happens to the stock quote
if it leaks that we agreed the purchase.
I've arranged it this way.
The stock quotation as
of yesterday morning.
You seem to be straining at the
leash, Mr Briggs. Or am I mistaken?
You mention here that probable time of
purchase will be some time in June.
Now, the plant is to be in
receivership until then?
That seems to be what it says.
That means six months with improper
maintenance of equipment.
Oh, I doubt it, Bill.
I've had two of my best men
out there for the last six weeks.
We had a varying voltage problem,
but that was taken care of.
No, maintenance-wise, I doubt if there
will be $1,000 worth of deterioration.
How about goodwill?
─ What about it?
The plant employs 900 men. That's
half the working force of the village.
So?
What do we do with the men?
Cover them in Cosmoline and put them
in a drawer until we resume production?
I thought your concern
was for the plant.
What good is the plant without men?
You chop a village payroll in half for
six months and you may not have a plant.
Because you might not have a village.
Mr Briggs, if we may be permitted
to disregard for the moment ..
The considerations that
you have brought up.
What about the rest of the plan?
I'd say it was adequate.
Adequate?
That gentlemen, is the
kiss of death. Believe me.
I've known Mr Briggs for a long time.
When he says something is adequate, what
he means is, it is entirely inadequate.
I must admit to feeling concern over 900
men suddenly deprived of a livelihood.
Mr Briggs, do me the goodness ..
To look at what I consider to be a
fairly elementary business principle.
By putting 900 men out
of work temporarily.
We may ultimately employ twice
that number in the same town.
By cutting production costs as a result.
We will then be able to compete
more favorably in the market.
Thus we'll be able to sell more goods.
We're not going to ruin that town.
We're going to make it.
I should think Mr Briggs,
that after thirty years ..
You'd be able to think beyond
the tongue-clucking stage ..
And come up with something
resembling an analytical point of view.
I'm under the impression
I gave you a point of view.
I saw none!
I've perceived what amounts
to a rather emotional little titbit.
That was decidedly more
charitable than coöperative.
And by no means thought through.
I asked I believe, for an objective
view of a business venture.
From you I got and I seem to
be constantly to be getting ..
A very negative response, if any at all.
"Adequate", I believe you said.
Well, Mr Briggs. This move will save us
conservatively half a million dollars.
Which we'll be able to
put back into the business.
I must say you take a
liberal view of adequacy.
I didn't intend to make a
central issue out of this.
But I did feel it important
enough to air in this meeting.
Well, you have aired it in this meeting.
And I think it's a good thing you did.
But I think Bill, we're pretty
much of one mind about it now.
And we may assume the
matter is closed now?
Mr Briggs?
How about you, Mr Staples?
Do you have an opinion?
No .. no, I think not, Mr Ramsey.
Why not?
Well frankly, it's a little out
of my grasp at the moment.
I don't know anything
about the firm, its ..
Corporate set up.
Its reasons for bankruptcy.
Or for that matter, its product.
I'm afraid I'll have to pass.
Good answer.
I respect thoughtful
judgement, Mr Staples.
Congratulations.
We'll adjourn now until 2 o'clock.
I'm sorry we got started
so late this morning.
But I wanted this analysis
mimeo'd for your inspection.
After lunch, we'll take up the Portland
report which you have before you.
Mr Grannigan attended the stockholder's
meeting there on Tuesday.
And we'll begin our
discussion with his report.
That's all.
─ Alright, sir.
Oh, Bill.
What about coming to have some lunch?
─ No, thank you.
Oh Bill, wasn't there something you
wanted to speak to me about before?
Nothing important.
─ Fine.
Your tummy is alright, eh?
─ Cast iron. Couldn't be better.
Good. Keep it up.
Oh, Staples.
See you later.
─ You bet.
Good to have you with us, Staples.
─ Thank you.
The arrangements satisfactory?
Yes, just perfect. I'm sure you'll hear
from my wife very soon about that.
It's a beautiful house.
It's beautiful country up there.
I'm sure you'll love it.
Oh ..
See you later, Bill?
Oh Fred.
Briggs is working on a project now.
A comprehensive planning report.
The point is that it's very important.
Most important indeed
for our future program.
And it is far too big a job for Briggs.
Or for any one man to handle.
Now what I want you to
do is get your finger in.
Certainly.
What I mean is .. more
than just your finger in.
You understand?
Yes, Mr Ramsey. You
make that quite clear.
Oh, could I see you a
minute, Miss Fleming.
Yes, sir?
Oh, I wonder if you can check for me,
please, as to who's to be my secretary.
I need some notes typed up.
I'm to be your secretary, Mr Staples.
But I thought Mr Briggs ..
It was arranged for.
Just before the meeting, Mr Staples.
I take it you would rather
remain with Mr Briggs?
I was Mr Briggs' secretary
for seven years, Mr Staples.
Well in that case I see no reason why
I shouldn't be able to get someone else.
It was Mr Ramsey's idea.
Do you want to give me those notes now?
No .. why don't you have
your lunch first, Miss Fleming.
We'll take care of these
when you come back.
Mr Briggs.
There are some notes here that ..
Later, Marge.
I'll do it later.
Darling, you didn't say anything about
my new hairdo. Do you like it?
Yeah, it's lovely.
I wish you could see the new dresses
I bought. They're just beautiful.
Where are they?
Oh, they're still at the store
having little things done to them.
Come to the kitchen, I'll make a drink.
Not the kitchen.
The library.
Oh.
I hoped they'd have the dresses ready.
I'd have them sent over to
your office this afternoon.
I spoke to your secretary
about it when I called.
It's funny. She didn't mention it.
They didn't get the job done in time.
She had a nice voice. What's she like?
Who?
Your secretary.
Oh ..
What you might expect.
You know.
What's her name?
Now to tell you the truth,
I didn't get her name.
Only her dimensions.
Ha. Alright.
No .. her name is "Fleming".
It so happens you don't have a
thing in the world to worry about.
She doesn't like me worth a bit.
Why?
Well, I guess she prefers
working for her former boss.
Well then, why doesn't she?
I don't know. Some kind of ..
Strategy at the top, I guess.
Sounds funny.
Yeah.
Her ex-boss happens to be only
one of the Vice Presidents ..
My superior, and a
very nice guy to boot.
Could that perhaps be a good sign?
You figure it out. It left
me a little up in the air.
You know Nancy, running a ..
Plant in Ohio is beginning
to take on all the ..
Aspects of a ..
Nice simple uncomplicated gravy train.
What happened today?
Oh, nothing really.
Just ..
An impression, I guess.
Sort of ..
Queer undercurrents.
Tensions.
Good luck.
Mr Ramsey.
Good morning, Mr Ramsey.
─ Miss Stevens.
Fine. Thanks, Jerry.
Let me see that breakdown again.
─ Oh, sure.
Miss Fleming, will you
step in for a minute?
Yes, Mr Staples.
No, that's not the one.
─ I'm sorry.
I'll see to this.
Here it is. Yeah.
This is the only one I've cross indexed
for division, so don't let him keep it.
I want Billy to take my letter
from Henry Jacobsen with him.
Oh. Yes.
Now look, Billy.
Henry is a nice, sincere guy, you know.
Made out of Bessemer steel.
He hasn't been off of his duff
since he learned how to walk.
He started out stoking coke
furnaces when he was 14.
Mill foreman at 20 ..
And ended up buying the whole plant
for his own 40th birthday present. So ..
Know what I mean? Watch out.
─ Sure will.
And give him that report and
then remember what he says.
Make stenographic notes when
you can. When you can't ..
Put it on paper as soon
as you get out of his office.
No approximations.
Make it as ..
─ Fred, I've got to go.
I must know what they think.
I want to know how they feel
about every paragraph they read.
I just hope they'll open up more
to you than they did to me.
I'll be down there sometime
next week for their decision.
Mention that to them will you.
─ Yes sir, I will.
Hello?
Ah .. hold it please. Just a second.
Have a nice trip, Billy. And be
sure and call me Sunday night.
I will. Thanks very much.
Thanks, Marge.
Yes, put him on. Don't go
away Miss Fleming, please.
Hello?
Judd.
Look, sorry. I meant
to call you right back.
It's about that Atlantic States nitrate
meeting set up for October the 3rd.
I'd like a delay on that.
Well, I want to walk in there
sure of my ground and ..
October is not going to
give me any ground at all.
Yeah, could you do that?
That would be a help.
November 7th.
Fine.
Look, I'll see you in the dining room.
Okay, good.
Put that on my calendar, please.
Now then ..
Did you get those wires off?
─ Yes, sir.
Right after lunch I want you
to set up a conference call ..
With Ramsey, Jameson and myself
with Frank Derring in Denver.
You got a minute, Fred?
Sorry, Marge. This is urgent.
It's about that NLRB vote in Portland.
─ What about it?
Ramsey's grumbling about it.
He thinks it's premature.
Premature? What's he talking about?
He's had that plant running on
wishful thinking for 19 months now.
We've got a labor problem out there
all primed to explode in our faces.
Look Bill, you'd better walk into his
office with a great big neon sign:
"Strike", you know .. then tell him
I've got a little estimate worked out ..
That it will cost us, conservatively,
$4,000 a day if that plant goes out.
You know how it will hit him.
You go and dig up the ground.
I'll follow you with a bulldozer
and we'll plow him under.
We've got 800 lumberjacks out there and
if they go it will do us big, you know.
This won't be any one-week picket.
This thing could go on for
a year with no strain at all.
You walk in there, set the charge,
and I'll be in to light the fuse.
Fine.
I'll have to call you back.
Is 2:30 convenient for your
call to Denver, Mr Staples?
Anything else?
I've another problem here
if you can spare a minute.
Oh Paul. How are you, partner?
Mr Staples, that gun.
Ah, you got it. You like it?
You try it out yet?
Try it yet?
Thirty seconds after he saw "Winchester"
on the box, he was sighting it.
Well, how about going out for a little
skeet shooting on Sunday? Give it try?
Wonderful. Can I Dad?
He's all yours, Fred. It's a
little too strenuous for me.
Mr Staples doesn't get
tired like you do, Dad.
I don't get tired.
He was an All-American.
It was just terrific so I had
to stop by and thank you.
Forget it.
Well, so long. I'll see you outside.
Real thoughtful of you, Fred.
It's my pleasure, Bill.
Hello, Mr Ramsey.
How are you, Paul?
Still taking your vitamins, are you?
I guess so, sir.
─ Fine, fine. Keep it up.
Excuse me, Mr Briggs.
Oh man, I'm tired.
I've arranged for your call to Denver,
Mr Staples. I must go over a paragraph.
No, I think I'll knock that off after
lunch if you don't mind, Miss Fleming.
Alright, Mr Staples.
No. Drink it here. Relax a minute.
Thank you.
I will.
Would you like some of mine?
Yes, thank you.
As a matter of fact, I would.
No, that's fine, thank you.
Where did you play your
football, Mr Staples?
Oh, Ohio State. But don't ask
me the years. I won't tell you.
I won't ask you.
Anyway, I feel about three times
older than when I first came here.
They've kept you busy?
Yes, they sure have.
You've done very well.
You've fitted in quickly.
Thank you.
You know, that's the first out-and-out
friendly thing you've said to me.
I think you resent me a little,
don't you, Miss Fleming?
I don't know why you should ..
─ Well, it's just ..
A feeling that I've
gotten from time to time.
If you work with a man for
a long time, a fine man.
You become part of him.
You identify yourself with him.
Then along comes a new man.
I like Bill Briggs. I like him a lot.
I have from the first.
If I have done or said anything ..
─ No, no. Of course not.
Because I must say
you've been very fair.
But seven years isn't a day.
I owe a lot to Mr Briggs.
Mr Briggs is the last of the
original bunch around here.
The people who really
started this business.
And it's not easy to be the
last of the original bunch.
I know.
He's not well. He has a bad heart.
And an ulcer.
I guess that's just about par for
the executive course, isn't it.
Well, I guess I've always
been a field man.
I haven't been an executive long
enough to find that out for myself.
You're a good one.
I think you're a very good executive.
You admit mistakes.
You don't pass the buck.
You're a lot like Mr Briggs that way.
I take that as a very nice compliment.
─ I mean it.
Mr Briggs only trouble is that
he could never be a yes-man.
Not even to Mr Ramsey himself.
He always has to speak his mind.
You see Mr Ramsey .. doesn't
like his judgement questioned.
You either go along.
Or you get off.
Bill Briggs never got off.
No. He never did.
But maybe he's about to be pushed.
They drew up in the next round and then
Howard went by him with a 60 foot putt.
I ask you. 7 birdies and he sunk an 80
foot putt on the last hole for an eagle.
Well, hello my dear.
You know, that's some golf.
Got everything you need?
─ Yes, indeed.
That coffee will be ready
in just a little while.
Fine.
You know, my ..
My father's recipe for coffee ..
Was to mix salt and
chocolate with the grounds.
And cook them all up together.
He'd never drink anything else.
Sounds wonderful.
They ..
They serve it in a small down-town
restaurant I eat at occasionally.
I must remember to mention it to Fred.
You said he was a
confirmed coffee drinker?
Dedicated.
─ Fine.
He's quite a young man,
this husband of yours.
Have you had a chance to
read much of the report?
Of course it isn't finished yet.
Thank you for letting me see this much.
Not according to the protocol,
I suppose, of a dinner party.
It makes me extremely
proud of my judgement.
I'm so happy.
He's been worried about it.
Nancy.
Would you excuse me?
A Wonderful party, you two.
Makes me think I should get married.
Don't do anything as drastic as that.
It's been wonderful having
you, Ed. Come again soon.
You try keeping me away.
I'll see you at the office tomorrow.
─ Yes. Bright and early. Goodnight.
Ah Jamie, you don't have to
go yet. Stick around a while.
Of course, I'd like to stay
all night, however ..
We're going home. I can't
get him out of here, Nancy.
At these office parties,
eating all the canapés is bad.
I thought everybody behaved very well.
Is that so?
I give you credit for that.
─ Night, again.
I was beginning to like all of them.
Will you come over and see us?
─ Certainly.
During the day?
─ Love to.
You know, holidays.
Jamie never gets home at all.
I think we wives ought to form a union.
─ You're right.
Goodnight, dear.
─ Bye bye.       ─ Goodnight.
I wonder what happened
to Bill Briggs tonight.
Oh darling, I forgot to
tell you. He phoned earlier.
He said he wanted to come
but he just didn't feel up to it.
Oh, I wish you'd have
called me to the phone.
I wanted to talk to him anyway.
─ Darling, you were busy.
Well, I know, but I ..
What about Ramsey? Is he
planning to spend the night?
No .. he just gravitated towards the
library and made himself cozy.
That sounds a little like
artificial gravitation to me.
You didn't have anything to do
with it, of course?        ─ Well ..
He's really an amazing person.
You know, I expected
a real tycoon, but ..
He's so simple. Almost childlike.
Baby, I just hope by mistake
you never wander into a jungle.
Goodnight, Jeff.
─ Goodnight. Wonderful time.
The most interesting
reading matter here, Fred.
Very interesting reading.
I took the liberty of taking your wife's
invitation to look over your report.
Oh really?
Good, heady stuff.
Good solid thinking.
And some of it is better than good.
Of course, I can't say that I agree
with all your conclusions, but ..
I listen to arguments.
It will be good to hear
arguments for a change.
Good arguments.
I can't tell you what a relief that is.
We really sweated that one out.
Fred, I like a man to show initiative.
I like a man who's not afraid
to think a new thought.
To take a different kind
of step on his own.
With your permission, I'll ..
Borrow this extra copy of
your report just overnight.
But for now, I can say ..
I'm very impressed.
Of course we haven't finished it yet,
but Bill and I, after another week we ..
Bill?
You mean Briggs?
Yes, sir. Well, we worked
together on this.
Oh come now, Staples.
I pride myself on my sense for style.
I can link what I see with what I know
to be peculiar to a certain individual.
And I know Bill Briggs' work.
I've been exposed to it
since I was of voting age.
This ..
This isn't his style.
It isn't his brand of thinking.
Well, I don't know what Nancy has
told you, but Bill and I worked ..
Fred. Learn to accept success.
It's tougher sometimes than
learning to accept failure.
Don't take half of your
accomplishment and ..
And hand it out gratuitously
to the man on your left.
Who hasn't the stuff
to do it on his own.
That is charitable. Humane.
It makes you feel good.
But it's not business.
Mr Ramsey, I'd like
to clear up one point.
There will be a meeting
on Tuesday, Fred.
We can discuss the report then.
I assure you I don't
want any undue credit.
I never extend undue credit.
Ask anybody! Ask your friend, Briggs.
You think I'm tough on him, don't you.
I am tough on him.
And I think Bill is ..
I think he's a good man.
He was.
And grandfather clocks were good clocks.
And Stanley Steamers
were good automobiles.
But you can't run them
in competition today.
I must say that I like some
of his ideas very much.
Very much indeed.
So do I.
Some of them.
Not many.
Still, a man with ..
Bill's experience and ..
I don't know. I think he'd
be hard to replace.
I'll see if that coffee is ready yet.
─ Are you serious, Fred?
Briggs would be hard to replace?
Do you honestly think that?
And why do you think I brought you down
here from Mansfield on short notice?
Do you think that was a whim?
Is that what you think?
Fred, you're Briggs' replacement.
I thought you understood that.
I'm ..
Expecting his resignation.
I don't like to prolong
these things. They are ..
Unpleasant and personal,
no matter what tack you use.
And under no circumstances
could I, or ..
Would I, undertake to fire him.
Coffee is in the living room. I thought
you'd like to go in there? Quiet.
Look at the time. I really must go.
It's been a wonderful evening.
Sorry you have to leave so soon.
I really must.
My .. coat, I think is in the bedroom.
Oh yes of course. I will get it for you.
May I make a suggestion?
Mr Ramsey, I don't want
to seem ungrateful.
I'm not looking for gratitude.
You can't run a business
on thank-you notes.
That's Briggs' trouble.
And, God forgive me that
was my father's trouble, too.
This.
The incredible conception of an industry
being run like a soup kitchen, like a ..
Like a welfare comfort station.
I know what the old-timers think of me.
I've grown up getting stared at ..
By a lot of tongue-clucking
old fogeys who find me ruthless.
The kind of people who represent all ..
That might have kept our business from
growing to anything like its present size.
This .. this stupid black and white idea
that honesty and profit are incompatible.
I just happen to feel.
That the atmosphere
of a large corporation.
Cannot be constantly cathedral-like.
Thank you, Mrs Staples.
And .. again, thanks for
a wonderful evening.
I'll see you in the morning, Fred.
You didn't steal that promotion.
You won it.
Remember that.
Goodnight, Mr Ramsey.
I hope you'll come again.
Thank you Nancy, and I hope
I'll be able to. Goodnight.
Goodnight.
What .. what was that all about?
I'm Bill Briggs' replacement.
A Vice Presidency?
You must have really spread it on him.
Listen.
A little rare roast beef and ..
Wifely pride don't get you
that kind of a promotion.
Yeah, it takes something a little more.
A little misrepresentation
for one thing.
A little switch in
authorship for another.
You told him I'd written that report.
I did not! I told him
Bill had helped you.
But Nancy, this is Bill's basic idea.
They're the same set of ideas that he's
had for years. I gathered that much
You gave it life, you made it work.
You made it practical.
Even so Nancy, I don't
want any part of it.
Fred, I happen to know what
you contributed to this.
I also know that you
can't stand winning.
If you have even a nodding
acquaintance with the loser.
I don't like stepping on another human
being to get to a capital gains bracket.
Ramsey stalking that
poor guy like an animal.
He'll whip him to death if he
can, to make him resign.
I didn't hear you tell Mr
Ramsey he was mistaken.
I didn't hear any clear-cut
defence of Mr Briggs.
If you don't want to be successful.
Go tell that to Mr Ramsey.
─ Look, Nancy.
Will you please ..
Then you check in every
night, but don't tell me ..
I don't want to argue about it!
─ Nor do I .. I want you to answer me.
Did you tell him that
your wife was mistaken?
Did you tell him that you were taking
bows for something that you did not do?
No.
No, I didn't.
Why not, Fred?
Why not?
Because I wanted the job.
Thank you.
For a straight and honest answer.
Now I think we can both sleep tonight.
Hi.
─ Good morning, Paul.
Where is Cora?
─ She's late, I guess.
Aren't you going to be late for school?
It's only 8:10.
I've still got six minutes.
You've got it figured out to
a science, haven't you.
I've just got it figured to
how far I have to go.
And how long it'll take me.
Well, if you've found that out,
you've found out a lot.
Thanks for breakfast.
You worked late again last night.
Yeah. No rest for the weary.
You haven't got it down to a
science yet, have you dad.
What?
How far you have to go and ..
How long it will take you.
What's the matter, Paul?
Here. Here's last night's double-header.
The one we were going to see.
Oh, I forgot all about it, Paul. I'm ..
I'm sorry.
We didn't miss much.
I watched it on television.
A crummy double-header. The Braves
took both of them. You're lucky.
The Yanks are playing
tonight, aren't they?
Yeah. They play the Red Sox.
Let's start all over again.
You meet me at the office. We'll have
dinner and then go to the game together.
Sounds good.
─ It's a date.
You're on.
So long, Dad. Have a good day and ..
Uh ..
If you can't make it tonight.
Would you give me a call at school?
I've raised the world's worst pessimist.
At eight in the morning you work out the
worst thing that could happen tonight.
Upstairs in my room, I've ..
I've got a drawer full of tickets
to ballgames we've never seen.
Because of that stuff.
But ..
Call me if you can, Dad. It's important.
I'll make it this time, son.
Can't you have another
glass of milk and ..
Maybe tell me about last
night's double-header?
I'll be late. I wish I could.
So long, Dad. Take it easy.
Sure.
Good evening, Mr Staples.
Good evening, Sally.
Paul?
Hi, Bill.
Hi, Fred.
I thought it was my son.
He's going to pick me up.
You got time for a cigarette?
Sure.
What are you doing here? I thought
you were going to the ballgame.
I've had a miserable
headache since dinner.
So I sent Paul on to see the game alone.
He's going to pick me up.
How long have you been here?
A couple of hours, I guess.
Can I get you an aspirin or something?
─ No .. no.
I'm much better now.
Anyway.
It gave me a chance to look over the
supplements you did for the report.
I think Ramsey's right, Fred.
You may be an engineer
by diploma, but you're ..
A crackerjack industrial planner
by instinct or something.
Coming from you Bill,
that sounds real good.
No question about it.
Some of your suggestions
were great, Fred.
Really great.
I've incorporated them verbatim.
I like your approach, Fred.
You think of people in
terms of the human factor.
Not just logistically.
Something I've never been able
to make Ramsey understand.
Anyway.
Now he can't complain I turn
in the same report every year.
He won't be able to say that this year.
Join me, Fred?
No thanks, Bill. I've got to ..
Take Nancy out for supper and ..
And that long drive home, you know.
I don't know.
Maybe I'm just getting old.
I used to be pretty tough.
I'm still tough, I guess.
But every now and then I get .. tired.
Tired of arguments.
Tired of battling. Tired of the
whole bloody mess with all this ..
Fancy organization as super-finagling.
Oh I know it's legal and
modern and all that.
It's what they call a "trend" isn't it?
In the old days things
were a lot simpler.
Businesses grow, Bill.
─ This business didn't grow.
Not since old man Ramsey passed on.
It's been added to.
That's not growth.
Just plain acquisition of business
and stock transfers and bank loans.
Manipulated by hired shysters
and a sharp-shooting accountant.
And organized and controlled by
a barracuda like Walter Ramsey.
You sure you won't have a snifter, Fred?
I wish you would.
─ No.
Look, times change, Bill. You know that.
But do they always
change for the better?
Old Ramsey could walk down a production
line and call any man by his first name.
And get called by his
first name in return.
Yeah, I know that feeling, believe me.
He didn't need public relations experts.
Honor was enough. Character.
And he never sold a share of
stock in this company either.
Not until the depression came along and
then he had to raise cash or go under.
And do you know why?
Because he would not
lay off one single man.
That's the kind of man Jim Ramsey was.
Now I sit in that fancy conference
room with Jim Ramsey's son.
I sit there and I see all
the old man's principles ..
All his beliefs.
Every single thing holy to him.
Jobbed off by this spindly
little financial wizard.
This wall-eyed,
ice-coated little rooster.
Who knows more about debentures
than about the human heart.
Bill.
─ I'm alright.
Take it easy.
You're beginning to work yourself up.
─ I'm alright.
Sit down, Fred.
Sit down quietly and be a nice,
sympathetic friend and associate.
I wonder if you're as good a human being
as you are an industrial relations man.
He doesn't like you, does he.
No.
Bill.
Has it ever occurred to you to resign?
─ Pah!
Of course it has .. a thousand times.
Why don't you?
What?
Resign.
You can't take the chance
of letting this man fire you.
On our level you don't
get fired. You know that.
After 30 years productive work they can't
say to a man like me "alright, get out".
They just can't do that.
So what do they do?
They create a situation.
A situation you can't work in
and finally that you can't live in.
With this tension .. abuse.
Small humiliations.
It all starts out on a scale
so subtle, so microscopic.
That at first you can't really
believe it's happening at all.
Gradually, the thing
begins to take shape.
Pieces fit together.
All the little bits.
And it becomes unmistakable.
They chip away at your
pride, your security.
Until you begin to have .. doubts.
Then .. fears.
Ramsey.
He wants me to resign.
He wants me to get my craw so full, I'll
be miserable enough to do just that.
But you'd take it?
─ Yes, I'd take it.
Why?
The bigger the job, the more desperately
you hang on to it.              ─ Why?
Why?
Why do you take it?
Why don't you quit?
Quit?
Yes, Quit. Get out of it, chuck it.
You'd have your pension,
your peace of mind.
No!
You know Ramsey is going to go on
hounding you until he makes you quit.
Never!
He'll never make me quit!
Bill, I ..
I wish I could understand
why you go on taking it.
Because I'm weak, I guess.
Because I'm sixty-two years old and
I don't think I could get another job.
How does that strike you?
How do you think?
Once in a while I have a dream.
I dream I'm sitting in that conference
room and he starts working me over.
I'm just smiling, see.
I'm perfectly calm and I'm taking it.
I don't show the slightest resentment.
And then.
And then without any change of
expression, I get up out of my chair.
And I walk over to him.
And I say .. "Ramsey".
─ Bill.
Ramsey!
─ Bill.           ─ Ramsey, I say!
And then I smash him, and then
I smash him again.     ─ Bill.
Get hold of yourself.
─ I hit him again!
And he starts to fall and I hold him up.
Bill!
Ramsey, I say: I'm not through yet!
─ Bill!
[ Whistling ]
It's the kid.
He's coming to pick me up.
Fred .. I don't want him
to see me. Not like this.
You're alright, Bill. Just sit down now.
─ No, he can't see me like this.
Fred, help me, help me.
─ Alright, I'll take care of him.
You just lay low for a bit.
I'll see he gets home.
Tell him I left early to get ..
─ Bill, be quiet .. be quiet!
Please Fred, hurry.
─ Be quiet.
[ Whistling ]
It's me, Paul.
Oh hi, Mr Staples.
Man, what a place by night.
Where do they keep the caskets?
How you doing, partner?
Dad said I should drop
in and pick him up.
Oh. Well he went on home.
He needed a little rest.
Oh .. good.
He's under orders not to work late.
He can't seem to keep away lately.
Always working, always worrying.
No wonder he's Number 2 man.
Suppose I drop you off
at Grand Central, huh?
Swell. Thanks, Mr Staples.
Ever since I can remember he's
been married to this place.
Mom used to say the same thing.
They were great together,
Mr Staples. Mum and Dad.
They used to yell and
argue and carry on.
He was a fighter.
Thank you, Mark.
More?
There's another bundle on the truck.
Mr Staples. You left your
hat in Mr Briggs' office.
Fred, I've the Stanley contract made up.
─ Later, please.
A bad night.
Yes, Mr Staples?
Now this is the proposals report.
Give that to Miss Lanier for
confidential mimeo-ing.
Tell her that Mr Briggs has the
only carbon. Is he in yet?
No, sir.
Mr Staples.
─ Yes?
It's not signed.
How would you like the
names? In what order?
First yours, or first Mr Briggs?
─ I don't care. It makes no difference.
But a joint project, sir?
I really don't think it's too important.
Put Mr Briggs name first if you like.
Just give it to Miss Lanier, right away.
I'd like this thing printed
by afternoon if possible.
That's all, Marge.
Yes Marge, what is it?
Proposals report. Will you
sign it so it can be printed?
Would you ..?
Just a moment, please.
Marge, would you please take it in to
Mr Ramsey. He asked to see it first.
Hello?
Oh yes, good morning.
Is that the report?
─ Yes, sir.
Miss Lanier said you wanted to see it.
─ Yes, I do.
Who signed this?
I wrote the title page.
Mr Staples suggested I sign it.
Print it.
I'm sure that if Mr Staples knew ..
─ Print it, Miss Fleming.
I can sign that report now, Marge.
Now we meet with Ramsey in 20 minutes.
Under the conditions and the time we've
got, it's the best plan I can devise.
It's the only one ready, so you
fellows have got to go along.
Marge, I can sign that report now.
Thank you, Marge.
The major projects during the
period aforementioned ..
Being the Huber Petroleum Refinery.
The Sterling Carstairs Refinery.
The Chatham Nichols Smelter Company.
The Henderson Valley Dam.
The Swincarbon Steam Plant.
And the New England Canadian
natural gas pipeline.
A good report, Van.
I get a real feeling of
activity doing your reading.
The next item of business is
the projects proposal report.
Clearly, of the the greatest single
importance on our docket this morning.
I must say, and I'm
sure you all agree ..
That I am not given to enthusiasms
at the drop of a submission.
But of this, I'm impelled to say that it
is unique in effort, genius and thought.
To Mr Staples of our organization goes
my heartfelt thanks and congratulations.
Besides being our newest member,
he is shaping up as our most astute.
This set of proposals is ingenious
comprehensive and fresh.
Congratulations.
Your success is a reaffirmation of my
own judgement.         ─ Mr Ramsey.
My own good judgement, I may add.
─ Mr Ramsey.
I prefer not to be drenched
in modesty Mr Staples.
This is not modesty, just the
extension of credit where it's due.
Bill is as responsible as ..
─ Mr Briggs.
Is your name about to be used in vain?
I don't think Fred would
use my name in vain.
It is refreshing to find someone
not suffering from over-modesty.
What I was trying to say is, that we
worked on this project together.
It was a combined effort.
I'm sure it was.
Well as long as that's understood.
Oh it is. It is.
It's just that I feel ..
Reasonably competent to assess
the individual performances.
And to single out those that
I feel should be singled out.
With all due regard for Mr Staples'
concern for his fellow man.
Now then, if Mr Briggs' ego
has been sufficiently nourished ..
I don't think Fred brought
this up to feed my ego.
Oh, well whatever it was that prompted
his precipitate dash to your defense.
There was no dash to my defense.
─ Why not drop the thing, Mr Briggs?
I hate becoming entangled in
absurd little personality conflicts.
I'll put a star by your name on the
front cover if that will make you happy.
My name is no longer on the front cover.
─ Mr Briggs.
You're twisting the thing to make it
seem I'm grubbing for some recognition.
Mr Briggs.
I find it unfair, Mr Ramsey.
─ We have a full agenda.
If you feel so bruised that you must
persist in prolonging this discussion.
Mr Ramsey!
Let me finish Mr Staples, if I may.
We have only one purpose here. To work.
We cannot hope to accomplish this if we
must be continually subjected to the ..
To these singularly unbecoming
strains and tensions.
These childish claims
and counter-claims.
Mr Briggs, I asked
you a simple question.
Is it or is not within my province to
credit a man with a job well done?
Of course it is.
─ Then may we drop it now?
Only if it's clearly understood ..
That I do not submit to these calculated
discolorations of a man's worth.
As to a man's worth, Mr Briggs, I think
I have proven myself a competent judge.
I ask you to recall I built the business
from a scratch-pile of used lumber ..
And a few machines into a giant.
And I made few mistakes in doing it.
Few mistakes in business and
few mistakes in judging men.
You've made one here, this report ..
I refuse to engage in a running fight ..
Because a supposedly responsible
official of this company ..
Persists in wasting time
haggling over credit.
That is not fair.
─ I was not haggling over credit.
This is a joint report we worked on.
Don't tell me what is true
and what is not true.
What am I, some kind of idiot? That I
can't recognize another man's thinking?
Whatever your abilities
in the past, Mr Briggs.
Your work hasn't shown this stamp of
originality and talent in ten years.
A man slips, clutches.
He loses his grip.
He tries to hand on by someone else's.
You have no right to say that.
Bill, will you please speak up.
Do by all means, Mr Briggs.
You think I'm mistaken, do you?
Can I go through 150 pages ..
And point out to you line by line, where
another man has taken over for you?
Has had to take over for you.
And I can point out sections of this
report that I never had to touch.
Had to, Mr Staples? Of course you can.
Let me show them to you. I've seen
them submitted, year after year.
"Principles and precepts
for better business."
Mr Briggs' yearly platitudes.
But you translated his unworkable
well-intentioned philosophy.
Into tough business procedures.
You make it work.
Ramsey!
Mr Briggs, I will not tolerate
insubordination on any level.
And if anyone here
finds that intolerable ..
He has the God-given right
to offer his resignation.
Bill.
Please.
Mister Ramsey.
I had no intention of
seeming insubordinate.
Meeting is adjourned.
Mr Briggs.
Miss Lanier! Miss Lanier!
Bill.
Bill, can you hear me?
A little ..
A little .. bottle of pills.
In my coat .. in the office.
Get some water.
─ Yes, sir.
Grannigan, get an ambulance.
And call Dr Fletcher.
Don't move him.
Fred.
Bill .. still giving .. audits.
Do me a favor, Fred.
What, Bill?
Tell him ..
Go to ..
[ Telephone ]
Hello?
Thank you, Mr Staples.
Five minutes ago.
We just had word from the hospital.
He died five minutes ago.
Thank you, Mr Grannigan.
Nancy?
What are you doing here?
I called your office.
And there wasn't any
train, so I drove here.
How did you know where to find me?
They told me at the hospital.
Does Paul know?
Yes, he's with ..
Bill's sister. He's alright.
You care for something, Miss?
Have you had anything to eat?
Huh?
Have you eaten anything?
Fred.
What happened?
Nothing.
Not a thing.
Except a murder.
There were witnesses, too. Plenty of us.
And no-one lifted a finger to stop it.
─ Oh, Fred.
Nancy, I know. I didn't lift a finger.
─ You don't know.
I'm not going to have you going
around in sackcloth and ashes ..
For something that you did
everything in your power to stop.
You begged him to resign. You know that.
What more could you have done?
What more could anyone have done?
Nancy, I think you had better go home.
Would you check this please?
Are you coming?
─ Nope.
Then I won't go.
I want you to go home and start packing.
Where are we going?
I don't know. Somewhere. Anywhere.
Just away.
There's an awful stink in this town
and we're going to get away from it.
Come on, I'll put you in the car.
─ No, I'm not going to leave you alone.
Nancy, I want you to go home, please.
─ No, I'm not going tonight.
Tomorrow, I'll do anything you ask.
I'll pack, I'll go anywhere you ask. But
not tonight, not in the state you're in.
Look. There's something I've got to do.
─ Fine.
Then we'll do it together.
Bill was meant to go to Lansing tomorrow
morning for a meeting with Phillips.
You'll have to take his place.
I believe I've already mentioned that.
Yeah. You mentioned it.
You'll leave on flight number 116.
8:32 from LaGuärdia.
Miss Lanier will meet you at the
airport with your reservation ..
And all the memoranda and correspondence
pertaining to the negotiations.
You'll have three uninterrupted
hours in the air ..
To familiarize yourself
with all the details.
I have no interest whatever
in the Phillips matter.
What was that?
I'm telling you that I don't
want the job. I'm through.
I'm quitting. I resign as of now.
Why?
Because I hate your guts.
You used Bill Briggs for a whipping boy.
You made him knuckle under
and then you beat him to death.
You wouldn't try anything like that
with me because I'd kill you first.
I'm not a nice human being. What else?
You're nothing but a freak!
You drive your people to peak efficiency
if they make it or a grave if they can't.
Because Bill lacked the strength ..
─ And the perspicacity.
He was second in command.
He'd a lot of responsibility
to hold and he cracked.
It was his business, too.
─ It's no-one's business.
It belongs only to the best.
To those who can control it, sustain it,
nurture it, keep it growing.
Right now it belongs to us
because we're producing.
But in the future it belongs
to whoever has the brains ..
The nerve and the skill
to take it away from us.
Well, they can have my share of it right
now, as I don't want any part of it.
What do you want from me? Apologies?
I don't apologize!
What else?
A nice, unsullied conscience?
Do you walk out of there with a
halo because you spoke your mind?
What do you do then?
Go to work for some nickel and
dime outfit run by "nice" people?
Who won't challenge you
and prod you and goad you.
And drive you to a height
you never even dreamed of.
A company where there is nothing
to fight for, because you are the best.
Where there is no competition.
Where everything is handed to you.
And nothing is worth fighting for.
I want you to stay.
I don't think you understand, Ramsey.
I don't like you.
I don't like anything about you.
I didn't hire you to like me.
Alright. I'm not a nice
person in your eyes.
But whatever I am, you'll learn
more, grow more and do more ..
Here with me than
anywhere else on earth.
I want you to stay because
I need help on my level.
And you're the only one
who's able to function there.
Be a conscience for me if you want.
Be anything you like.
And if it's something I don't like
you'll know about it soon enough.
I think you're strong enough to take it.
And if not, I think you're
strong enough to get out.
Name your terms!
All terms are negotiable.
I don't think so.
Not mine.
Alright.
I'd just as soon not waste
any time doing trading.
As of now, your salary is doubled.
Your stock option is doubled
right down the line.
Your expense account is
whatever you make it.
Add to that a new title: Vice President.
I want a lot more than that.
You're not taking me on as just another
Vice President you can just push around.
You'll take me as someone who
hates you down to the bare nerves.
Nothing in the world
will ever change that.
I'll argue with you, contradict you,
fight you in every way I know how.
I'll do everything in my power to push
you out and take your place myself.
Go ahead and try.
Mr Staples.
You have yourself a deal.
Have it drawn up.
No reservations now?
Yes. One.
Bill had one pitiful little dream.
That someday he'd walk in
here and break your jaw.
I reserve the right to
have that wish for myself.
I'll have it drawn into to the contract.
With a little rider giving
me the same privilege.
Oh .. Staples.
You'll be pleased to know that Bill
Briggs' boy is being taken care of.
Well, that lets you
sleep better tonight.
It begins, huh?
It begins .. fair enough?
Fair enough.
Do we pack?
No .. we stay.
On whose terms?
─ Mine.
And his.
Are you satisfied?
─ Yes.
Oh, Fred.
You know it's easy enough to chuck
something you thiñk is wrong.
I don't know. This way
maybe there's a çhance.
I'm so happy.
Well, we'll see.
I've got to go to Lansing.
The morning plane.
When will you be back?
─ Tomorrow night.
I'll be late.
Aren't you always?
T-G