Get photo?
Yes, please
No problem
Excuse me, takeaway?
Who ordered takeaway?
Brother Cheong, you ordered
Me?
Oh, yes!
It has been too long that I almost forgot
I am sorry, I couldn't get a bus
Whatever, here
$283, please
What the hell is that?
The noodle gets fatter?
Got radiated?
Well... it got bigger...
then can be shared with more people?
Right, then let's share your lollipop
Hey, don't make trouble at my place!
Yes... boss... Go to hell!
Hey!
What? It's not your business
You son of a bitch!
Why your boss hasn't shown up yet?
Asshole, call him now!
Call him!
I told you to call your boss!
What? Stay there! You wanna get beaten?
That's enough, you are gonna kill him
You are nothing to me
What's happened? Why so noisy?
Why so drunk
Brother Ghost! It's so
hard to get you in touch
Come on, let's have a chat
What you guys are staring?
Is it an entertainment show?
Move this jerk aside
Quick, clear things up
You'd better leave first
I haven't got my money
I'll get it for you. I'll give you tomorrow
$283
Thank You
Ghost, I want to do some business with you
What business I can do with you?
This location is great
I can get you more customers
Girls are not a problem
I've already got the coke and K
What you have to do is
to provide this place,
you and I are going to make some money
We share what we earn
I know you don't like this stuff,
how about this, sell me the place
Give me a number,
I will absolutely fulfill
you, how about that?
Those real estate guys,
they've almost bought the entire Hong Kong
why don't they leave some space
for people to sing?
Bill, you have made so much money
all these years
it's time for you to do some good
one more thing,
don't you ever to cause trouble
at my place again
Uncle Two, Brother B, Boss!
Leung, are you alright?
I am fine, just a dozen stitches
Damn it
A dozen stitches? Cheong that asshole,
If I didn't hurt my hand,
I am gonna make him to pay back
Yeah right
Don't make fun of me Boss
Brother B,
Everyone Knows you can fight
against 8 people at a time
You are the toughest among Hung Hing
Of course I am!
30 years ago?
Don't make fun of me ok?
Anyway, be careful when you take shower
Uggh, uggh... Ouch, ouch...
Boss, what Bill talked with you?
What thing can we talk?
He just wants my Karaoke
He has talked with me for a lot of times,
I am done with it
But anyway,
we really need to think about it seriously,
any other business,
Karaoke is out, tough to do
Last time we talked
about running a coffin shop,
why no follow up?
Not no follow up, we already checked,
The source of coffins
is controlled by 2 families,
it's difficult to get supply
Hong Kong style teahouse?
Ask B, he ran one before
It's been ages,
teahouses are much more
than grocery stores now
It won't work
But recently even a Hong
Kong style teahouse
plans to get listed
on the Stock Market
Keep thinking, keep thinking,
let's do some research
Think... think...
Think again?
Any suggestion else? Any sure win plan?
What if we lose money? How do we explain?
Brother Ghost!
Damn it, why she knows I am here?
Damn!
Who said that you are not here?
It's so difficult to find you
Oh, you got tired to find me?
Yes!
How about having someone
to give you a massage?
Good idea, you!
Where?
Is it ok?
Yes, that's right
Do you know?
Japanese ramen restaurant
is very popular these days
That one in Causeway Bay,
people queue up day and night
I have an idea,
let's also sell yoghurt
and pearl milk tea here
Little Girl
We only have 2 chefs,
they are already very busy
and you want them to do more things?
Do you think they can handle it?
They have to...
You sound like your father
We have to...
Uncle Kwan, here you go
OK, thank you
Come! Take it to your father
before it gets cold
OK
Hey, what are you doing?
I am making an "instant soup pack"
So my father can have hot soup anytime
even in the hospital
Hey, why don't you have a taste?
No, have your father taste it, go!
Fine
Ok, ok, don't you touch my stuff!
Ok, ok, I won't touch your stuff
Hi!
Your money
I didn't expect that you are accountable
How's your head?
I am fine
Want to eat?
Sure
Have a seat
What do you want to eat?
How about macaroni soup
with a fried egg and ham?
Add $1 to change to toast?
- Ok
- What do you want to drink?
Iced milk tea
Uncle Kwan, Meal A with iced milk tea!
COPY
Hey, your father is waiting, get going!
Yes, yes
I got to go first
Hey, your phone! Quick, quick, quick...
Password?
don't show your password
to others that easily next time
Bye-bye
Sorry that I forgot to thank you
for saving my life
I am going to the hospital
to visit my father,
he is very sick
Bless your dad
I am Mei
What? Our place got messed up?
Yes! They mix grasshoppers with shit
and threw into our shop
ls Boss with you?
No, He said he has a place
to go this morning,
Ok, I Will find him
Hey, clean up the place
Yes, I will
OK, I go find him now
Boss, why didn't you answer your phone?
Our Karaoke got messed up by someone
Who did it?
Still checking...
Boss, are you alright?
My mother wouldn't see me
she has been in nursing
home for many years,
she refuses to see me
every time I go visit her
Boss, it has been so long,
it's not that you don't go visiting her,
it's she doesn't want to see you
when I was a kid,
the environment was tough,
we had no food, no toys,
the best way-out is either be a policeman
or to be a thug
I was just in time,
couldn't say if I am lucky or not,
that I didn't have a
chance to do bad things
now we are old,
Hung Hing is collapsing,
My mother still doesn't want to see me,
Boss, I'll go visit her tomorrow,
I'll buy her some good food
anything you want to say to her,
I'll tell her for you
she always talks about you
No, she is gone
don't worry, we have
worked here for so long,
you have our full support
we are going to hang in here...
until you decide to quit,
to sell it No worries
Uncle Kwan, I know you love me,
but what about you guys?
If I couldn't hang in anymore
and sell the shop?
Don't say things like this
Be confident, especially at this moment
We will be with you even we don't get paid
Everyone agrees?
You have the final say?
You don't stand for us,
we are the main support in our families
Yes, we are old, who will hire us?
If no one hires you?
Then go back to your home village
and grow something
I don't have any farm
land in my home village,
so where can I grow?
Grow in your field?
Hey, you don't have to say that
So what?
Stop it, I didn't say that I will quit
Ghost, did you hear what the priest said?
He said believe in God
will get an eternal life
Your mother believed in God,
which means she didn't die
So don't be sad, right?
Then Brother Two,
you'd better hurry up to believe in God too
Are you cursing me?
No, as you are terrified by death,
believe in God as quick as possible,
then you will not die
Jerk!
Don't curse me, God forgives people
That's true,
but his mother is the one
who believed in God, not me
So I don't forgive
Stop it
I go buy you a cup of milk tea later
Boss, where are you going?
Everyone sits, let's order
Have a seat
What do you want?
Milk tea
Iced lemon tea, no sweet
OK, iced lemon...
Coffee with tea
OK, coffee with...
Did you lose a bet? Why pull a long face
Hey, Brother Two,
this toast is just like your face
I didn't want to raise my voice
as I am a educated man,
but this is outrageous
I am sorry and I will change it for you
Make it quick!
Damn it, is it $500 a lemon?
Is it free?
I am sorry, I am sorry
That's absurd
Hey, if you don't like
the food, then don't pay
Why the scene?
Because you are triad
and you can do anything you want?
What did you say, bitch?
Sorry, sorry
She is in a bad mood
because her father just passed away
That's why she is like
this, please forgive her
My Boss's mother just passed away too
He is in a bad mood too!
I am sorry,
We just finished with the
funeral arrangements,
that's why everyone is in a bad mood
I am sorry about that
What?
My condolences
You too
Check
Hey,
it's for you
It's salted mandarin drink,
my father said you will feel better
after drinking it
Thank you
I have been busy
with boss mother's funeral arragement,
didn't have the time to call you
I am sorry for your loss, cheer up
Take good care of yourself
Brother Ghost! Brother Ghost!
Who?
It's Boobies
Which one?
The bigger one
- Brother Ghost!
- You are good!
I have been looking for you!
Where have you been?
Why are you looking for me?
We are going to a concert tonight!
Really? A concert?
I promised you?
Yes, it is difficult to get the tickets
- But I am really sleepy
- Brother Ghost! Brother Ghost!
Who is this again?
Boogie, the small one
Brother Ghost, it's time to go
To where?
To the concert, don't you remember?
Concert again?
Why everyone wants to go to the concert?
Hurry UP!
Wait...
Why don't you two go with them?
Oh no, not today Boss, I am exhausted
Just want to go home and get some sleep
You want to sleep too?
Yes!
Hey, hey
I am really sleepy today, tired too,
just want to get home earlier,
You are sleepy...
why don't I go to your
place and sleep with you
Um...
SQ?
Then“.
Why don't us three go
home and sleep together?
Together?
You want to?
Are you insane?
Jerk!
Hey... just sleeping together,
what's wrong with that?
Come on, let's sleep
together, don't leave me
I am really tired, I
head back to home first
Ok, see you Boss
Hey, give me one pack of Mild Seven
$50
Thanks!
You want to eat?
No,
The kitchen is closed
No, I didn't come here for food
I had dinner
Just passing by,
and see it's still open,
why are you getting them off?
These are all the dishes that I create,
but no customers want to try
And we only have one chef left,
cannot do it
Hot Red Lips Curry? Really?
What is it?
I don't know either
Let me help you
Oh... thanks
I am sorry for the other day,
let me take these off for you
Sorry
Thank you
Let me write for you! I can do it
What do you want me to write?
How about double eggs luncheon meat noodle?
Double eggs luncheon meat noodle, ok
What are you doing?
Double eggs luncheon meat...
this is an egg...
Don't draw! Who knows what you are drawing?
Write the words!
It's better to read from a picture
Write! Write!
Fine, I write, double eggs
luncheon meat noodle, right? Luncheon...
Your handwriting is pretty nice
No...
Yes, it is...
L...u... n... c... h... e... o... n...
M... e... a... t...
Hey... no...
- This is "Meet"
- Meet!
- No, not this word, it's "meat"!
- Whatever,
people go to Hong Kong style teahouse
don't read
Hey, what's the name of your group?
Technically, it starts with letter "H"
Besides killing each other,
hitting people's heads,
What else do you guys do?
Hitting people's head?
When did I hit someone's head?
Last time in the Karaoke... l saw it
Karaoke? You were there?
Yes, I saw you hitting a man's head
Oh... that was an special case
Normally, we don't hit people's heads
We talk more than we act,
There is no future for triad now
You need to compensate
for hitting someone's head
We are businessmen actually
Really?
You have so many brothers with you
the other day,
but there is a woman
The day at the teahouse?
That is a guy,
I'll explain to you later
This is me
Here?
Um
Nice, which floor you live?
I'll tell you later,
seems like you are much better
Thanks for that drink
You are much better too
Yes, because I drink a lot of it,
do you like it?
Yes, but it was too sweet
I cannot have too much sugar at my age
No, you look young
Oh, really?
How can you tell?
From the side? Or from the back?
L am going
Bye-bye
I am Mei
Mei! I am Ghost
Little Ghost, Little Ghost
Bye-bye
- Bye
- Bye-bye
Come on, give me a hug! Don't be so rude
See which floor the light
is on then I know where she lives
Wow... it's easy to climb up and get there
"Thank you, how's going lately?
Come to have breakfast if you have time"
Don't cry... don't cry...
I am scared...
Don't be afraid... bastards,
lam gonna kill them,
Did you see anyone suspicious?
Where were you when it happened?
Stop crying, it's fine now,
Tell me everything you know!
Get some tea
If I know then we wouldn't got messed up!
Right?
- Uncle Two!
- Boss!
Right! This is Ghost's place, you ask him
Let's have tea!
B, let's go have tea!
Go!
Ghost, what's happened?
You are in bad luck this year?
Every place of yours got messed up?
I want to ask you too,
Wounding, criminal intimidation,
criminal damage...
The triad is so arrogant these days,
you tell me how we can run business, sir?
Come here for a second
What?
I am on the street everyday,
don't you think that I don't know things
between you and Bill
If you are on the street everyday,
then you would know what he is doing!
You think he wants to
take care of my place?
He wants to takeover my place!
He wants us evicted! Real estate guy!
Anyway, I don't want any troubles,
I'll catch you people
Things already happened,
why don't you go catch some people?
We are civilians, we depend on policemen
Go and catch some criminals!
Mr Ng, do you any further information?
We will notify you
for the identification parade
Boss, Nine said he recognized
some of them are Bill's men
Whatever happens in the
future, call the police
Call the police?
It costs money to call backup,
emergency call is free!
Hey, closed?
Yes... you are passing by... again?
No, just had dinner around
I see
Why only you? Let me help
No, thank you
You can't sweep like this,
take off your gloves
Really?
Are you sure?
Of course!
OK...
when I was a kid, I swept everyday
Why?
Punished by my father...
When you sweep,
you need to start from the inside,
Not like this,
Yes right, you really know how to sweep
Of course!
Bruce Lee once said that...
keep your waist
and horse stance straight in a line
Ha-ha... even for sweeping?
Of course! Bruce Lee swept too,
Once done, you don't have
to come out from the inside,
It won't get the floor dirty, right!
Yes...
Do you need to get anything?
Oh...
Ok now!
Let me buy you a drink
NOW?
Or tomorrow?
It's too late...
How late?
I swept the floor for you,
I think it's fair that
you have a drink with me, ok?
Um... ok then
Turn off the light
OK
Thank you
One, one, one, two, two
Two... one... one... two...
Drink!
That quick... it's me again...
I can't drink anymore, I am full
Full? I thought you are gonna throw up
Why am I so dumb,
I can't play this or that
not that you are dumb, I am just too good
No, my father always said I am dumb
But, he said...
no matter how dumb I am,
he would support me,
like a tree
Now he is gone, no one supports me anymore
He spent his whole life for this teahouse
Now the employees want to leave
Neither I have to do it nor not to do it,
Even if I keep doing it
but I really don't know how
Ok! I know how to do it!
I know how to do it!
You do?
You keep doing it then you can do it!
Bullshit! I know that!
No, no bullshit, just keep doing it
If you don't want to do it, then don't
If you want to do it, then do it,
I will support you
You support me? Everyone says so!
So what do you want me to do? Say it!
I want you to be like my father
Oh no!
- You mean it? Really?
- Be my tree
Oh... be your tree...
I thought you want me
to like your father... dead,
- How am I gonna support you?
- No, no more talking about death,
Oh, ok, ok, no more death
talking, I won't die
I will be your tree
I will plant a tree, let me plant a tree
Look! It's growing, ok?
Be my tree...
Sure... ok... l will be your tree
No... but...
Ok... Cheers!
Be your tree, ok?
Be your tree, why it sounds so weird?
- Ha-ha!
- Be your tree,
good, I will be your tree, cheers!
Hey... Hey... it's not good
Excuse me Sir...
What do you want to drink?
Iced Lemon tea
0k!
Why are you here?
Good Morning
It's for you
Why giving me flowers?
Nothing... you were drunk last night,
and you said your father was like a tree
and support you,
I have been thinking of it
for a whole night, I think...
I think I can be your tree to support you
Oh! Why did I tell you this,
it's so embarrassing
People do have consciousness
even if they are blackout drunk
Come on, take it first
What a cliché
- No, they are the best
- I cannot have them
There is chocolate too,
I cannot have them...
I bought them, not stole it
The saleslady said this is the best,
No more arguments,
I'll have them put in a vase
everyone buys it
Thank... thank you
Boss!
Hey, come here!
Let me introduce to you,
this is Leung, my brother This is Mei
I go back to work
OK!
What do you think about her?
She can be a girlfriend,
I can feel it, I feel it
Boss! You had me here
and just ask me this question?
No, I had you here
to talk about some real business
Didn't you suggest to run a teahouse?
I asked you here
to take a look of this teahouse,
also take a look of her
I found a new direction in my life
Your choice is so unexpected
No, I always like this type
Oh really?
Look at her, she is really interesting
I want to go to the Disneyland with her
Really?
Really
What is the price of Gei Wai Shrimp?
$80 per kilo
That's expensive, cheaper please!
My father used to buy from you very often
It's already very cheap
how about giving you for free?
Well, that's not necessary
Hey, what are you doing?
You tried to rob? What?
Brother Ghost!
Hey, how much?
You and I don't talk about money!
Shrimp, crab or fish,
take anything you want!
Hey, take anything you want!
Hey, what's wrong? Hey...
She is throwing a temper
Hey, no, it's not free,
just because I helped them
What exactly do you guys want?
Either you give them back to me,
Or you have them brought
back to the teahouse?
The chefs are waiting
Yes sister! I will have them brought
to them in 3 minutes
- Don't worry! Let's go!
- Hey!
OK!
What sister, who is your sister!
Stop following me
Hey! Hey! Hey!
I feel like selling Cocaine now!
Look at you, you must be used to...
- No! I don't do this!
- Really? I don't buy it
I do women, I don't do this stuff
Boss! You have been running for an hour,
That's enough, take a break!
You are very keen on it,
Gym in the morning,
football in the afternoon
And running at night,
You may even try Wing Chun and Thai boxing!
Anything else?
Bungee jump
Keep going, anything else?
Water rafting! That's exciting!
Really there are more...
You are quite talky among people your age
Why didn't I see you these days?
Where have you been?
I am always around,
just that you only care for girls
Speaking of which, how's the progress?
I am about to ask you,
what do you think about Mei?
- She is nice
- Really?
Better than the rest of yours!
That's good, I want to talk to you
about something
I have thought about it,
I want to invest in Mei's teahouse
Either business or personal,
I do think I should give her a hand. Right?
Um...
Why are you still thinking?
It is your idea to run a teahouse
Yes, but we haven't done it before
Brother, it is your idea
Barack Obama hasn't been
a president before,
but he is doing quite well now
Alright! Either business or personal,
it's your call!
Great! You say yes and so it is!
I will run for 2 more laps
Again?
Here... smoking...
Smoking...
Yes, smoking...
Jackass.
- Bastard
- It kills!
- You are going to die badly!
You keep running and I... l am dying!
Hey, the delivery guy that you hired
is not good,
He left for more than an hour
and still haven't come back
No sense of direction, just like you
I really don't know what he is thinking
Hey! What's the matter with you?
Why does it take so long
to deliver a breakfast?
I got tired and these are just feet
So is it a time management issue?
Is it you are not happy?
If you are not happy, then quit
What do you mean? Are you threatening me?
Are you threatening me?
Kiddo, do you know who you are talking to?
Who? Wow... so many people,
Then I'll leave!
Leave? Apologize to my sister first
Who is your sister?
This is my sister
I am not your sister!
She is not your sister,
who actually is your sister?
Huh!
All of them are!
Sorry sisters,
It's my problem, I'll... I'll leave
Hey!
The money!
I forgot...
I am going
Don't waste time on these schmucks
Leung! Find someone else to replace him!
- Hey! Let's go!
- Let's get to work
Hey, I got something to say to you
What's wrong?
Want to share some secrets with me?
Why your brothers keep calling me sister?
I don't know, I didn't
ask them to say that,
It's totally their ideas
Anyway, I don't want to hear them
calling me sister again
But, there is something that
I have been wanting to talk to you
for a long time
I have been observing for long
I found that, your teahouse,
is lack of one thing
What?
Manpower
It is no need to observe,
it's very obvious!
Right, that's mean you agree with me
I don't have much,
what I do have is a lot of brothers
All my brothers have nothing to do
With or without experience in catering,
I will have them helped here
I want to, but I cannot afford to hire
that many staff
Just your approval is enough,
you don't need to hire them
It's free
We will discuss later
when we make some money
Consider that as my investment
in your teahouse,
what do you think?
Let's do it! Let's get some helps here
Uncle Kwan!
Look, Uncle Kwan agrees too!
Sister Mei, it's done
It's done, here the money
It's absolutely their ideas, not mine
But you can stop them!
I cannot
Stop calling me sister!
Yes, sister
Hey!
See, couldn't stop them
Hello everyone,
I am the representative of the developer,
we are very interested in buying your shop
I come here today to
discuss a deal with you
We are not moving,
also the lease has not run out yet
If you want to talk, find the landlord
It's no use to come here
Understood! That's why I want
to talk to Brother Ghost
The lease has not run out yet
and the tenant doesn't want to move,
what else can we talk?
You are the landlord?
It doesn't matter if I
am the landlord or not
I absolutely understand
what landlords think,
it's all about money
If you accept the price, then sell it
Even though I am the landlord,
but rule is rule,
we don't just care about the money
We care about loyalty and morality too
To compare with thugs who just care
about money but not morality,
there is a huge difference
I would sell it if I were you
who care very much about loyalty
You can give the money to your brothers
and everyone can start a new life
It's better than making your own decision,
and have others suffered
Go to hell! Who you are saying
that got others suffered?
You or me?
We are all educated people
and don't say the F-word
I don't think we can have anything
concluded today, think it through again,
I will be waiting for your call,
sorry for the disturb
You save it Bill,
I would rather burn my shop down,
than selling it to you
Well said!
Take it easy... take it easy
- Give them a lesson
- Ok
Hey, you are the landlord?
Why don't I know it?
Why don't you tell me?
Why do I have to tell you?
Why do you need to know?
It doesn't matter if I
am the landlord or not
I didn't raise the rent
No, I am just worried if he comes again
No, my brothers will be here every day
They won't come, what they can do?
Just bluffing, don't worry
One, two, three... Here is your uniform
Outside you are a staff of this teahouse,
but inside...
inside, you are also just a staff
of this teahouse
Ok, that's all I wanted to say
We are family now,
Uncle Kwan will help you guys,
he will tell everyone
what his job is later,
Ok! Uncle Kwan, we are fine!
Sister, just feel free to order us,
lam Shing
This is my one last time to tell you guys,
Stop calling me sister!
Sorry!
But you are truly our sister,
what else we can call you?
What are you saying?
O...Ok... everyone just stops it
Let's get working
Here... come here... l
tell you how to place them
Haven't I told you?
I already told them, but
they just can't stop I
Hey... hey... don't be mad,
Just a name, don't be so serious
It's right to call her sister, isn't it?
Wow, Brother Two, so many firemen
Yeah, only those little dirty thugs,
do it this way
Speaking of taking possession of property,
Bill that prick,
would exactly do it this
way, son of a bitch
Thanks, sweetie, thanks
Uncle Two, no smoking, please do not smoke!
Yes, I see it
Hey, who want to have a taste?
I do
I can't eat anymore
Come on, have a bite
Wow...
Which dish is the most delicious one
in our teahouse?
It's totally different from other teahouses
Ramen, vegetable meat bun, dumpling,
they are irrelevant to
Hong Kong style teahouse
Yes you are right, that's weird
Pineapple bun, egg tart, these are
the specialty of Hong Kong style teahouse
That's what a teahouse is
Who are going to make pineapple bun
and egg tart?
It's so troublesome and
has no profit to make
How can you call it a teahouse,
without these kinds of food?
Hung, you got experience,
think about it
0k!
It's fresh and hot! Fresh and hot!
Wow...
Boss, have a bit,
what is it?
Pineapple bun!
It looks rather like a pastry
Brother Two made it
You taught me how to do it
A Japanese cuisine,
like a fried pineapple! Weird?
SQ?
- It's awful...
- Damn it!
You said you have done it before? Bragger
I truly did, for 2 months,
then it closed, that makes sense?
Chef, You have to tell me honestly,
what is your secrets of
making pineapple bun?
Yes, why the buns you make are so big,
but mine are so small?
Because they are not fully puffed up
And our pastries,
why they collapse in the middle?
Because they are over puffed up
Don't you lie to me,
what's the secret? Spill it!
You should brush 2 layers of custard,
after putting in the oven,
you have to keep checking
it from time to time,
- once the pastry turns lightly brown,
- The color changes! The color changes!
Lower the heat!
This time should be ok
Everyone, here are the fresh
and hot pineapple buns
It looks right this time...
- it's still very hot,
- It's very hot,
- good stuff
- Be careful, very hot
- How is it? How is it?
- Is that ok?
Good! That's right!
Really?
That's the taste!
Let's try the scramble egg then,
Ming cooked it with Uncle
Two's secret recipe
Come on, let's try...
It works this time, doesn't it?
Why don't you guys wait for me?
Taste it...
B, where have you been?
I haven't seen you whole day
Every teahouse has a
spirit, what a spirit is?
A cup of milk tea!
We specially went for Giant today,
asked him to tell us the secret
of making a cup of milk tea
He also promised us,
to share the tea leaf with us
Wow, we are impeccable,
We now can make a good cup of milk tea
Milk tea, scramble egg, pineapple bun
From now on, these will be our specialties
We are coming back!
Yes, better than Chow Kee next door
Wait... wait... we are
in a pretty good shape,
but seems like we are still
lack of something special
I actually have a thought,
I always have a question,
why a pineapple bun has no pineapple in it,
but still calls a pineapple bun?
I am thinking that our pineapple buns
should have pineapple in it
Again?
No, I agree!
There is cocktail in a cocktail bun,
mexican in a mexican bun, right?
Boss, you really do agree to everything
Have a think about it
It's worth a try
We can put pineapple on
top of a pineapple bun
Yes, we can
pineapple toasties
What are you up to lately?
Hello, Park's teahouse
Mei please, thank you
I am Mei
Hello Mei, this is Ghost's ex-wife,
I would like to invite
you for a dinner, ok?
O..ok, when?
Hey, where are you? Are you here?
Yes, I'll be there soon
Where are you?
Turn around!
You scared me, what did you buy?
Let's hang up first
What did you buy?
Cake, watch, same old same old
Watch again? Who asked you to buy a watch?
You did
Did I? Ten years ago?
Wow, that's expensive!
I bought her a car, I bought her a house,
I shouldn't have bought her anything else!
- Fine, let's go.
- Huh...
Boss, here you go, I'll leave
Let's go together!
- No
- Let's go together!
Quick, I need you there!
Go!
Boss, what's the matter with you?
I am nervous!
Why are you nervous? Press it!
I asked that witch to have Mei invited
Hey, you press it
Hi, happy birthday! You
are beautiful tonight!
Oh, what a coincidence
I invited Mei
Have a seat
I go to the kitchen
0k!
L 90 help her!
OK
What are you doing? Sit!
Do you need some help?
No, thanks
I can't cook
how about I wash the vegetables
that I can do
I already washed them
Oh...
Hey, Boss, why are you standing here? Sit!
Leave me alone
Hey, do I have a double chin?
You look great, have a seat!
Mei, why don't you ask me,
don't you want to know why I invited you?
I guess I know...
Ghost asked me to, he wants me to test you
I told him bluntly,
he is way older than you,
you are not going to be with him right?
He is crazy!
Well... age is not a problem actually
I understand, they might be evil-looking
but actually they are just like kids,
I am like a mother to them,
have to teach and take
care of them one by one
They are not really that bad,
sometimes they are quite funny
Huh, they may be funny now,
but when I was young,
we argued everyday!
He would rather spent the whole night
with his gangs,
but not coming back home
I was young too, so we got divorced
But we get along now, he
takes good care of me
he bought this house for me
Wow... this house... then
he must be very rich
Well, it's been a long time ago,
but the situation now is...
karaoke, night clubs and saunas,
even those old men they
all go for young girls
but they do have principles,
those things that are monstrous,
they don't do
They are all afraid of retribution
They know where the bottom line is
And they are not far from the bottom!
Try? I have spent a lot of hours on it,
- Wow, it smells good!
- It's good
Try it
Um...
How is it?
Delicious!
- Really?
'Yes, very good!
Hey Mei, take the dishes out
OK
Hey, what did she say? What did she say?
What is it? Is it a yes or no?
No!
Why? You sure? Are you sure?
I am sure!
Why so sure?
If you don't believe me, ask her yourself?
If I can ask her myself,
then I don't need your help!
You asked her one more time!
Why didn't you ask me in the past?
Why are you saying this now?
I don't say this, then what should I say?
Didn't I ask you?
Deep throat smoked pork... what it is...
Hey... what are you talking about...
let's eat!
Yes, yes, let's eat
Leung, come here!
Dinner time!
It smells good!
Why here? This seat is better?
Wait! Wait! Let me get my phone
Let's take a picture first!
Oh... ok
How to turn it on?
Let me take a picture first! Ready?
Let me take a picture first!
Is it this chicken's birthday?
Sorry! Sorry! Let's have a picture
- Picture with the phoenix!
- Let me have the phone,
- let me have the phone!
- Come on, smiles!
You don't take a picture?
Hey together! C..H..E..E..R..S
one... two... three... ok
It's your turn, your turn
You take a picture for us,
come, take a picture for us
You stand in the middle, ok,
here we go, one... two... three...
- Is it ok?
- OK, ok.
The food is getting cold, let's eat
OK, we took the most
important one, let's eat
Hey Ghost, have a mushroom
this is your favorite, here you go!
My favorite food is
chicken, you don't know me
Leung, have some mushrooms, here
I'll have the mushrooms, I love mushrooms
I love mushrooms too...
Isn't your favorite food chicken?
I've just changed it, I love mushrooms
Good?
Yes, very good!
You have one too, here, here
Here, here, don't be so fussy
Fine, quick quick quick!
Right Mei, how long have you known Ghost?
Around a month
Oh... a month...
Here, have some more
Again?
Keep going... please please
OK...0k...
Right Mei, what do you think about Ghost?
Very funny
Um... right? Very funny?
Hey... get some more
More again? Huh...
This is your birthday! Eat more
Sigh...
You two are...
Excuse me,
Sister Pui, I don't mean to upset you
on your birthday
But let me be clear about this,
Brother Ghost, I think you are
a very good person, funny too,
but, I don't like you,
I like someone else
Sigh... everything is clear now
I go get a bottle of wine, let's drink
I 90 help you
You drink as much as you want tonight,
let's get drunk!
I want to get off!
Boss, I go first
What?
Boss, I have something to say
Fine, I got it...
She already said it, go find her
You shouldn't keep a woman waiting
Hello...
Hey... where are you now?
Why?
I come to you
I'll wait at the bridge
that you just got off,
I'll be there very soon
"Hurry Up, are you here yet?"
What's wrong? What's wrong?
He is gonna be fine
What are you doing? Out!
Get out! Get the hell out!
- You get out!
- Sir, please calm down
Screw you! You are just a kid,
are you up to this?
Do you know how to save a life?
If you don't know, then
go get someone else!
- Go away!
- Sir, please calm down
Calm down? I told you to find someone else!
How can I calm down?
Sir, please calm down, the victim is dead
What the hell are you saying?
I am speaking to you! Dead?
Find someone else! Find someone else!
He is inexperienced,
he doesn't know what he is doing,
Look at him, such a freaking nerd
Bring someone else, bring someone else!
Take it easy, let's the doctor handles it
My condolences
Fine, I don't need your condolences
Go get someone, arrest someone
I know who did it, it's Bill! Go get him
You just calm down first,
we will investigate
What to investigate? Go get him!
I told you to calm down!
Boss!
- Ghost, how's things?
- Damn it!
Ghost, are you alright?
How's Leung? You calm down first
Once I heard that something happened,
I get here immediately
to check you guys out
We are cousins,
- why would I kill Leung?
- Damn it!
You bastard!
- Are you done?
- Relax!
Relax!
Leave if you are done! Now!
No, I have to say something,
I said, I need to say something
You are dead to me! You are dead to me!
I am telling you, you are dead to me
Fine... fine... fine...
Let's go!
Sorry sir
I told you to leave
Fine... fine... fine...
You are going to pay for this
Watch out
I am speechless...
You see that? It's criminal intimidation,
go get them!
Don't you mess with me, go!
Damn it
Go!
Yes
B, where are you going to?
Hey, what are you going to do?
It's Bill that son of a
bitch who killed Leung!
I am gonna get him and cut him in pieces!
By what? Just the two of you?
You don't even know where he is right now,
cut him in pieces?
Cut what? Pineapple? Watermelon?
He is going to pay for it, but not now
If we have money, we will have more people
If we have more people,
then we will be stronger
Ghost, why don't we sell this teahouse?
Then we have the fund
Leung would not approve
if we sell the teahouse
That's true, so what do you think?
Let's not do anything at this moment,
just focus on the teahouse first
Why don't you sell it?
I don't want to do it anymore
Then what do you want to do?
I know nothing and I am not good
at running a teahouse
I can't do it!
But your father spent his whole life
to build this
It is yours now, if it is not you,
I wouldn't invest, you have to keep it
I can't do it
You must do it even if you can't do it!
Everyone is just like a kid
Do we have enough bread?
Should be ok
Mei is back
Uncle Kwan
Back?
Getting any better after taking 3 days off?
A drink of tangerine and honey,
I made it, cheer up!
SQ?
Thanks
I haven't been here for a long time
yet still full of crowd
Ghost, I flied almost
24 hours to come back,
don't give me this look, ok?
No worries, I am here for you, relax
Brother T a“!
Bill!
It's been ages, how are you?
- I am good, thank you
- When did you come back?
I came back last night
Why don't you give me a call to get you!
Say hello to Brother Tai!
Brother T a“!
What brings you back?
I wouldn't come back if it is not for Ghost
It has been ages, let's have a drink
Ok, here, cheers!
You two cousins, don't hang out together?
It's Ghost who doesn't go out!
Hey, I got to go first
Oh?
Why? There is something between you two?
No, that's who Ghost is
Personality determines
one's destiny, that's it
Hahaha... you are in Peru,
it takes a long flight to be back,
you miss Hong Kong so much?
There are some clients of Ghost's
that want to cooperate with me,
that's why I am back
Ghost touches this stuff
Oh come on Bill, he doesn't?
I have been making some
money because of him!
That's great, come on, cheers!
How are you recently?
Find me some girls
and I will show you how I am lately
Cool! Let's go to my new place later
Hey sweetie, come and
accompany Brother Tai!
Come, come, come... Five, five
Fifteen
Fifteen, fifteen
Hey Brother Cheong!
Please have a sit
Ghost, he is here...
then we don't talk
No, we need to talk,
please sit down first, come, come
I have you two came here today
to discuss something
We all know that in the last few decades,
The real estate business
is getting bigger and bigger,
and our business is getting
smaller and smaller
So what I want to do today is
to discuss with you two,
how we can have our business...
strike back
What's your opinion Brother Cheong?
No?
Then Brother Fu?
Yes or No?
Hey come on, brothers, please say something
Next month is my birthday,
how about go to travelling together?
I havn't been on a vacation for so long
Boss!
Go!
There were two groups of people that went
to Ghost's teahouse for a talk
That bastard is calling people,
seems like there is something up
Go to the teahouse
and find out what's going on?
I'll go tomorrow
You go? Why you? I am a taxpayer
PHleave
You can leave too, we want to talk
Brother Two
Yes
There is something wrong
What's wrong?
It's Ghost
Ghost?
Yes, there is something different
He doesn't tell us what he is doing
Leung just died and he
is probably just upset
He never tells us what he plans to do
All these years, has he ever harmed you?
No...
That's right, brothers
have to trust each other
Brother Two, a new night
club just opens in Shen Zhen,
let's go some day
Who is the boss?
Me, I am in charge, what's the matter?
Police, ID card, thank you
Here is the warrant,
we have information saying
that there are drugs in this teahouse,
So we need to search this place,
please cooperate
- Sir, ID card
- It doesn't make any sense
Hey, how we gonna do business
with you people interrupting here
Please cooperate with the Police
I can help you to get
Bill charged with murder
Dare to work with me?
Sir, we found nothing
Give them back the ID cards, dismiss!
Sorry for the interruption
Hey, next time my treat.
Sorry
What are you doing lately?
We never touch this stuff,
you have to tell us honestly,
We are good brothers
Regardless if you are right or wrong,
B and I will fully support you
What the hell is going on?
You have said that Triad is already out
and it's time to do some real business,
Now the teahouse is getting on track
and you want to go back?
You are not young anymore,
you should think of yourself,
also think of your brothers too
Now you are having us all
involved, so tell me,
what the heck are you doing?
Hey?
Ghost!
Hey!
- Ghost!
- Hey! Hey! Hey!
"I give my property (2) to Lee Lai Mei"
"I give my property (3) to Chan Yi"
"I give my property (4) to Wong Chi Hung"
I have made you some tangerines
and it should be enoug
That huge?
It should be enough for years, enjoy
Please sign here
"Wong Kam Kwei"
Mr. Wong, your will is good now
Miss Lee will have the rest done
Ok, thank you
"Receipt: Self Portrait with frame - Paid"
Hello
Get photo?
The number you have dialed
is not available...
Uncle Two, Ghost took a funeral picture!
I couldn't reach him,
I am afraid something will happen to him
A funeral picture? Oh no
Detective Cheung! Detective Cheung!
Ghost might be in danger
We couldn't find him,
You really have to help us this time
Call the police if you have any problems!
Detective Cheung! It can't wait!
We are in an operation, get out of my way
Call the police and they will help you
Hey, you are just shirking us
You have to deal with this first
Detective Cheung,
we never get you in any troubles,
but this time, I am begging you,
you really need to help us
Get in the car! Get in the car!
We don't have time!
Detective Cheung, Ghost arrives
Copy!
Detective Cheung! Detective Cheung!
What's going on?
Ghost is here
What is he doing? Will he be ok?
I can help you to get
Bill charged with murder
If we are lucky, it would be the evidence
of him killing Leung
If not, that would be the evidence
of him killing me
Dare to work with me?
Don't worry! We have so many
policemen here, it will be fine
Detective Cheung, Bill arrives
Everyone stands by!
Brother Ghost, am I surprising you?
Nope, just right on time
I am always punctual,
no wonder why I offer you that much money
and you still refuse to sell me the shop
There you are with so
much stuff, by the way,
does your buyer trade in cash with you?
I have no idea that you
are really that greedy
Brother Ghost, it is just human nature,
I won't lie to myself
and I don't need your company
Ah!
Hey! Detective Cheung,
why don't you go catch them?
Someone is gonna get killed
You son of a bitch! Am I something now?
Hitting my head?
Hey! We ask you here to help,
not to watch a live show
Detective Cheung,
are you going to let my Boss dies?
Everyone calm down,
- I don't need you to
tell me how to do my job
- Are you out of your mind?
He will die if you don't take action now
lam warning you!
If you don't go out and rescue him
I will complain you and sue your ass
Let's go out
We have our plan, if we get him now,
It's just a serious assault
and he will only in jail for 12 years top
Bill hasn't started
We are cousins, why do
we have to be like this?
Why you have to put me
in such a difficult position?
We could be good if you could
just simply sell me the shop
WW gang up on me
for such tiny misunderstanding
What you policemen are thinking?
Hold hold hold, someone is dying
B, go!
Wait!
Get me off!
Hey!
Sir, are we going to stop them?
Hold it, hold it. Don't be reckless!
Why?
Give me the knife
This one is good
Hey! Are you ok?
Of course not! They outnumber us
Pick the most hideous one to kill!
0k!
Come here! Come here! Come here!
Get here! Don't you dare to get here!
You move, I kill!
You never change! You got my stuff dirty
You son of a bitch! Killing your brother
Did you kill Leung?
You jerk, yes I killed Leung,
I can kill you too!
Yes, I killed Leung,
what are you going to do with me?
Action!
I am gonna kill you too
Don't Move!
Police! Drop your weapons!
How you holding up? You
lost a lot of blood!
Don't die!
Who taught you
to hit someone's head with a bottle?
You
Me? Did I?
Hang on!
Ghost, hang on, the medic is coming
I am arresting you
for a murder of Ng Ka Leung,
You are not obliged to say
anything unless you...
What?
Why don't you arresst him?
He is trafficking drug!
Jackass, it's just flour!
I am just ask Brother Tai back for vacation
Get him out of here!
Ghost! Ghost! Are you ok?
Luckily I am fat, I am ok
You scared me to death
I really need to run more,
- Of course you have to!
- I am out of breath!
Boss, it's ok now
B, didn't expect that you can still fight!
Yea...
Don't risk it another time
Still another time?
Are you out of your mind!
Hey, let's get him up
Where is the ambulance? Still not here?
On the way, on the way
Go check where the ambulance is!
Fresh and hot, $8 each
- Pineapple bun with pineapple
- Thank you, one?
Fresh out of oven! Fresh out of oven!
Excuse me...
- Good?
- Good
Of course, yes?
- Yes!
- Yes but why are you shaking you head?
It definitely would work!
And I am counting on you
We care a lot about the
spirit of cooperation,
I'll reserve the best bunch of eggs for you
If you open another shop,
remember to get the stock from us
But I hear that the powder
is getting very limited in the US,
Remember to save me some!
I am gonna to save you the best
bunch of flour! Definitely!
We have a deal!
Of course
As we are brothers, then no need to pay!
That's another issue
Hey Brother Ty, not going back to Peru?
No
Have a seat!
Even I have been backed
for just a few weeks,
but I am already loving it
Really? That's great
I am thinking to ask my
wife to come back too
Hey, let's have some food, ok?
- Ok...
- What do you want to eat?
I miss my egg tarts
Egg tart it is, right away
Hey, get Brother Tai an egg tart!
Got it Boss!
Thank you! Thank you!
Take your time,
we have plenty of egg tarts, no hurry
Thank you!
Take your time,
we have plenty of egg tarts, no hurry
Pineapple bun with pineapple
Thank you! Thank you!