Do not render in vain your charity
by grandiosity or injury
or you shall resemble dust
on a smooth rock,
washed away by torrents of rain.
hate lies. Don't fucking lie to me.
Why would lie to you?
Yes? - Your documents please.
What do you want?
None of your business.
It's not here.
Don't behave like an idiot
in front of others.
Others? In this wilderness?
It all makes me want to puke!
You hit me?
Dumbfuck sack of shit!
Madam. - What?
Where are you coming from?
From a graveyard,
and we're going back to one!
Shut up. He's just asking.
Swear, she's made my life hell.
She's shat on my life. - Speak calmly.
I'm talking to her, not to you.
He's crazy sir, ignore him.
Where are you coming from? - Tehran.
She's full of shit! She's lying!
Told you to shut up.
Never a straight word.
If she says it's day
you can be sure it's night.
Answer my question.
He won't let me. Can't you see?
Answer you? You want to hear lies?
Try and speak calmly, please.
Do you want me to whisper?
Just ignore him.
This is how you've made me!
Don't scream fuckhead!
Look, she shattered my arm.
Take a breath, salute the prophet.
A breath?
She's been on my nerves for 500 km.
"She did this for us,
he did that for us." So what?
They did it for a reason.
They owed your parents.
You do the math officer.
It's a 500 km journey.
Your phone. - don't give a shit.
What if it's her? - Fuck her!
What are you doing? Psycho!
Because I'm a psycho!
You threw it in the snow.
I'm really sorry officer - Oh, eat shit!
Call the mobile so can find it.
So that stupid woman can bug me more?
Sir, can you call my mobile 0912?
Let me see your license first.
She doesn't have one.
It's not on me, Officer.
He has it, and he won't give it back.
You never had a driver's license!
Didn't ? - No, you didn't.
How come I've been driving
for 500 km?
My point exactly.
He has your license? - Yes.
Have it?
If have it; search me.
Get back in the car.
She says have it, right?
Then search me.
Stay where you are!
Here it is.
Get in the car, you clown.
Soheila, yes, we're doing it.
Sir, do your job.
Just shoot me.
Shoot me in the head
so can be free of her.
I'll call you.
Do you have a light?
What?
Matches, a lighter?
Get in the car.
Go get in the car.
Can't take it any more, Leila.
Can't stand you, or this life.
I'm staying here.
What's your problem brother?
His problem is money. - Money?
We're all a bunch of beggars.
Go get in the car
and stop blocking the road.
This is God's earth,
I'm God's subject.
Who's to say can't sit here?
This is a restricted area. Get up.
Wait a minute.
Wait. I'll fix it.
I'll fix his problem.
Here, divide this amongst yourselves.
What is this? - You think care?
I'll throw some myself.
What's this money?
Was this your problem?
Was this money fucking up your life?
Done! Let's go!
Take it buddy. Have fun.
It's legit.
Stop!
Abdollahi, stop them!
Taraneh Alidoosti
Mani Haghighi
MODEST RECEPTION
Saeed Changizian
Esmail Khalaj
Saber Abar
Mohammad Aghebati
Danial Fathi
Himan Dehghani
Naghi Seiflamali
Nader Fallah
Vahid Aghapoor
Mohammad Reza Najafi
Ghorban Najafi
Screenplay:
Mani Haghighi &Amir Reza Koohestani
Sound Design:
Amir Hossein Ghasemi
Music:
Feuermusik
Costume Design:
Negar Nemati
Set Design:
Amir Hossein Ghodsi
Editor:
Haideh Safiyari
Director of Photography:
Houman Behmanesh
Produced & Directed by:
Mani Haghighi
He was stumped.
Are they following us?
God no. They'll be counting
notes until midnight.
Did it record anything?
Must have. Where does it save the films?
The sunflower icon. - Here it is.
You were brilliant!
When you threw the mobile,
totally thought you'd lost your mind!
It felt right to throw it, so threw it.
But he was about to shoot.
No he wasn't.
Got scared. thought he'd shoot.
He has to give a warning first,
say something like 'Halt'.
The film isn't very good.
It looks alright. - We have to be in it.
You brag about 12 megapixels
and this is it?
Us not being in it
has nothing to do with pixels.
Is there a problem with clarity?
It's not clear, and we're not in it.
It's no use.
You can hear us,
and you can see the bags. It's fine.
I'm taking the bag, right here.
Took mine from the same place.
No, you took it from the other side.
You threw two bags, right?
Threw one. Or was it two?
Made sure to throw two.
Number 23 and 24.
No, we gave 23
to the rooster guy last night.
So threw 24 and 25?
So you must have thrown 26 and 27.
But 27 is still here.
It's a real mess back here.
Maybe we threw 3 bags.
2 for the soldiers
and 1 for the truck driver.
The driver had someone with him.
Was careful there'd be 4.
Right here, when we drive off,
you can see there are four bags.
We're cool.
Let me see...
They'll never come after us.
They'll have to report the money first.
What if we bump into them again?
It's charity.
It's helping the poor.
They might ask
why do it like crazy idiots.
Why not do it right?
Anyone who's unhappy can go complain
that we gave them money by force.
If we see them again,
they'll never mention it.
But we mustn't attract attention
among the locals.
They'll come after us like genies
with AK47s.
Genies don't carry guns.
Leila, this is on photo mode.
Down on the right,
there's a button for filming.
Got it? - think so.
Hello, Haji. - Hello. Welcome.
What's this?
Are you getting this?
Haji, sit right here.
Wave for the camera.
Is that OK?
Say thank you to the lady.
Say thanks, hope you get better soon.
May God heal all the sick.
Thank you Haji,
you've been very kind.
Miss, what's all this?
What's all what? - These.
Told you, it's a gift.
Gift? This is cash.
Yes, a gift of cash.
Are you from the Relief Center?
Where are we from?
Are we from the Relief Center?
No, we work for ourselves.
Don't need this.
You don't need it?
What earn here is enough.
Give this to someone needy.
Here we go again. You take it from here.
Hey Lady, where are you going?
Don't worry about others, OK?
We've brought enough for everyone.
Divide this between them as well,
so they get a bigger share.
Sir, you don't need to teach us
how to do our job.
There's a method to this.
See the numbers on the bags?
Yours is bag number 30.
You received, we filmed, you thanked.
If you give it back now
our books will get all messed up.
Kaveh what's this guy talking about?
Why are you getting angry?
Someone who's being charitable
doesn't get angry.
You don't return a gift, right?
You respect people's alms.
Just take the gift, say a prayer,
and enjoy yourself, right?
Am right?
Alright, don't want to offend you.
I'll take one of these as a keepsake.
That's enough for me.
What?
Offend me?
Why would be offended...
See? Now he's doing me a favor!
Look, can see you're not materialistic.
You're the spiritual type, right?
Fine, then spend the money
and change these plastic sheets.
They're filthy.
Fix the poles so they don't fall
on you if you fart.
What did you do that for?
You were lucky brought it down
a light breeze and you'd be done for.
What are you doing?
He doesn't want the money!
He's straight out of the Book of Saints.
Free cash is below him.
We'll find someone needy.
Where?
He's the only guy in this hellhole!
He's needy?
Why won't he take it then?
Why won't you take it?
Look, I'm really sorry.
Why are you sorry?
I'm giving alms to the poor,
Why apologize?
Take it, take it, needy prick!
Get in the car and stay there.
Move!
Apologize.
Can't help you because of my arm.
Sit for a minute.
Do you have a light?
I'm sorry if she upset you.
I'm not upset.
Don't know why she got angry.
Don't know what to do with her.
She's driving me crazy.
You'll be fine,
this kind of thing happens
to married couples.
She's my sister.
A sister is even closer than a wife.
They're after her.
She's committed a serious crime.
We're here to send her across the border
She drowned her baby
in my swimming pool.
Left the hospital at noon
with her one day old baby,
killed her before the day was out.
Then she broke my arm with a rod.
If her husband drops
the case for execution,
she'll end up in an asylum.
Which is worse.
Got all my money together
so could pay the traffickers.
Now it turns out
they take all your money
and abandon you
in the middle of nowhere.
So, with all this money,
we are in a lot of danger.
Without the money
we're just unlucky suckers
like everyone else.
We thought we'd give it away to people.
But we've been driving for 3 hours now,
the only person we've seen is you.
And you are so obstinate.
If you'd taken the money,
we'd be on our way.
It's not that simple.
It's a big responsibility.
OK then.
Leave these with you for safekeeping.
Leave the money here, cross over,
deliver her to friends,
and return tonight.
Tonight, I'll take all of it back, OK?
Don't say no. I'm in a bind.
How am supposed to look
after all this money?
You tell me what to do.
Take this Qoran with you.
Come back quickly.
I'll be waiting!
Done.
Hey, you have customers.
They're city types!
How do you do this?
There's a trick to it.
What's the trick?
I'm the trick.
What if you're not around?
I'll always be around, don't worry.
Give it to me.
Want to do it myself.
You can't, give it to me.
Welcome.
Should we call her?
You do it, I'm not in the mood.
She'll call herself.
Then you'll have to talk to her
and she'll piss you off.
What do you have?
Only offal today.
Bring whatever you have.
Dude, can you score Hash here?
What do you want Hash for?
Want to smoke some.
No we don't have that
kind of thing here.
How do you make ends meet, then?
With tea and waterpipes?
We have offal, too.
Trying to sound like a tough guy?
Want to smoke hash,
is there a problem?
What did the old man say
to make you such a shit now?
Nothing. I'm a shit by birth.
Organically, right from the word go.
Do you want yogurt?
Yes.
This guy's out of control.
You should talk to him.
We're not in Tehran.
He was just kidding.
Whatever. You won't see
another coffeehouse for miles around.
Either the owner has fled
for fear of his life,
or he got involved in this type of filth
and they closed him down.
He was wrong, shouldn't have said that.
Have a seat, kids.
Look at the twigs.
We looked everywhere,
here it was, right under our noses.
Guess where found them?
Near the old man's shack.
Small world, eh?
So you take these for your uncle?
Our uncle's car has broken down,
he can't take our gas capsule to refill.
How much do you charge for each load?
We don't sell these.
You burn this wood?
Do you know the wood you burn
can save human lives?
This is medicine.
Do you know what medicine is?
What do you want here?
An ashtray.
There are some inside.
There weren't any.
Will you take it in?
Want to use the toilet. Is it this way?
It's a bit muddy.
There's mud everywhere.
Give that to the kids,
make another one for us.
And don't charge me for it.
They have money now, they can pay.
Miss! You left your bag.
It's not mine.
It's full of bank notes.
It's a lot of money.
And who's that guy, your husband,
or boyfriend, he's distributing money.
Is it alms or something?
Yeah.
God bless. - Thanks.
Is this all mine now?
My husband will probably
give some to the others too.
So he's your husband?
Is he your husband or a husband?
Bet this money, you're not his wife.
So what if I'm not?
He's not your type.
He's your guide, right?
He was here with someone
else last month,
to take them across.
If you want to cross, can take you.
Told you, we're giving gifts,
you have it in your hand.
Don't trust just anyone.
You're from the city, you're loaded.
They'll take your money
and dump you somewhere.
Then there's the border guards.
They have their own system.
You need someone who knows the ways.
The guy you're with is a bullshitter.
We have no money left,
we gave it all away.
Don't be fooled by his looks.
He'll steal your car in a heartbeat.
Then you'll have to come
and be a guest at my house tonight!
But you won't come, will you?
Look,
they just arrived last night,
latest fashion.
There's no need, it was a gift.
Wear it to a party one night,
back in Tehran, and think of me...
That guy... That place...
What's this you're wearing?
You'll look pretty in this.
Prettier!
Thanks a lot.
And your car has lots
of takers around here.
It's a honey.
Just like yourself.
5 million in each bag.
Times 4, that's how much?
4 times 5, is 20.
And how many bags do you have?
Have one. - Altogether how many?
Can say? - No, let him say.
4 plus 1 comes to what?
7.
Good boy.
Take another prize.
No, it comes to 5.
Shut up and mind your own business.
So what does it add up to now?
7.
You're so clever.
No, it comes to 6.
No, he's right, it's 7.
Don't listen to him,
he doesn't know anything.
Here's your prize.
But it comes to 6. - Do a count.
See? - It's 7 now.
If you talk too much,
I'll take them back.
Off you go. Run along.
You are a troubled person.
It was a pothole, can't you see?
Why can't we get rid of this cash?
That pile looks the same as before.
There were 200 bags, only 32 have gone.
In two days.
A day and a half. 32 divided by 2 is?
16.
Let's say 20. At this rate we have to
keep going for another 8 days.
8 and a half.
You should have given
the coffeehouse owner's bag to that guy.
We said one bag for each person.
It's still pretty good we unloaded 3.
8. One for the guy, 7 for the kids.
You gave the kids 7 bags?
Why?
What does this mean?
Felt like being extra charitable.
The deal was one bag per person.
That was my judgment.
Was putting 100 kilos
of firewood on the roof
also your judgment?
Waited for an hour for you outside
the coffeehouse.
Was bored. What's the big deal?
The Wood's up there.
It can breathe the fresh air.
You could've dumped them
when got back. bought them.
You can't dump something
you've just bought.
The kids don't need such games.
You say hello, how are you,
take this money go give it to your mom.
You take the photo and it's done.
You can't buy stuff from someone
and then throw it away
in front of them.
Why not?
They'll think you're a moron.
It's like walking into a gas station,
putting your ration card in the machine
and telling the guy
to pour 60 liters on the ground.
He'll think you're a moron.
No, he'll discover that you're a moron.
First of all, those kids explained
that it's cold up there,
they burn the twigs
so they don't die of cold.
Secondly, so what if
they think you're a moron?
They're just kids.
Didn't that border guard
think you're a moron
for throwing 20 million at him?
That was different.
What's the difference?
These were kids.
So you were worried that
they'd grow up traumatized
because you gave them
money for nothing?
No, I'm serious,
were you trying not
to hurt their feelings?
Didn't want to confuse them.
These kid are confused by birth!
If they dodge the bombs,
and not step on mines,
they'll be shepherds, or cowherds...
'Confused' cowherds at most, so what?
Look, I'm hungry.
Help me understand,
then we'll have lunch.
Understand what?
What are you obsessing about now?
Want to know why
there is 100 kg of twigs
on my roof.
I'm sorry, pull aside
and I'll take them off
so you can relax.
Am relaxed.
They can stay there
for another 100 years.
Want to know why
you put them there
in the first place.
I'm not worried about the car,
want to know what's
going on in your brain.
There's nothing in my brain
because my brain is hungry,
and the offal is now cold.
No, there's a difference in your brain
between that old man
who had to take all my crap,
and the kids you treated so well.
Yes there is a difference. - And?
One person may
have been a contender
before a bomb exploded
his life to bits
another one might have
always been a leach,
a liar, a beggar, don't know.
And you judge blind
who deserves better and who doesn't?
So the deal that we give one bag
to each person in need is off?
Now you say
we should assess the needy.
So the oppressed
of the world can come
and sit a test of merit.
And if they fail your TOEFL of misery,
we can just shit on them?
Turn around, I'll find those kids,
take my money back,
and shove the twigs...
Shit, her morphine's worn off again.
Hi Mom!
Wait, have no reception.
Can't hear you, wait a minute.
Don't understand what you're saying.
Let me find a good spot.
Everything is OK here.
Same as California, but with snow.
What signatures?
You said either film or photographs.
Now suddenly you want signatures?
Internet in this hellhole?
Do you know where am right now?
There's nobody here.
What you saw on TV has changed now.
People were still around then.
They've disappeared down
some shithole now.
Wait a minute.
I'll call you, have to go now.
Kaveh this guy has what we want.
What is it we want? - Beverages.
It's someone ease’s order.
What are we buying exactly?
We're good customers.
I've already sold this load.
My mule slipped and fell down.
Where are you?
I'm close to the graveyard.
Honk your horn
so can tell how far you are.
You're far off. Drive fast.
What about the mule?
Have to finish her off.
Why?
When a horse breaks a leg,
they shoot it,
in order to kill it.
Hey, I'm the vet here,
and it's a mule, not a horse.
Same thing. It's over for her.
Undo her packsaddle.
Smuggling booze is not my real job.
My land never yielded
after the rocket attack.
Sir, asked you to undo her packsaddle.
What for? She's finished.
Are you a vet or what?
Put the gun away and come here.
It's not her stomach,
her leg's broken.
She's pregnant.
Stop fooling around Miss,
let me do my job.
I'm telling you,
she's pregnant.
She's a mule.
She's 11 weeks gone.
She must have been
at it behind your back!
It's moving.
Kaveh come and touch, it's kicking.
Mules don't get pregnant.
So what's this kicking in here?
How do know? A fart?
This lady is a vet.
She knows the difference.
Her leg's broken.
have to finish her off.
Kill her off for a broken leg?
This guy's arm's broken too,
should finish him off as well?
You bind a broken leg.
No big deal.
It would be great
if it could be fixed
with a scarf, but it's broken.
This is my job, you know.
Listen to what the doctor says.
Even if you bind it,
she won't be able to walk.
She'll be stuck here tonight
and freeze to death.
You just want to kill her so you can go.
This mule and have walked
these mountains for years.
She's like a friend, and she's in pain.
And I'm asking you to sell her to me.
She just keeps at it no matter what say.
I'll pay for the foal as well
so you'll believe she's pregnant.
Name your price.
It depends. don't know.
How much is a foal?
Wouldn't sell a foal.
The profit's in selling it as an adult.
Told you these scumbags are greedy.
He was whining a minute ago,
now he's playing hardball.
It's not the way you put it.
It's always the way
YOU guys put it.
Let's go.
Ignore him.
I'll buy the foal
the same price as an adult.
Don't know...
Who knows what'll happen?
What if the foal is lame,
or blind, or twins?
It's an unknown quantity.
What if God doesn't want
this beast dead,
and she gets up and walks?
These people won't deal with you
until you show them cash.
Take it!
This is too much. - Don't worry.
I'll take everything.
The foal, the mule,
the whisky and the gun.
Why the gun?
You want to take our cash,
come back and finish her off?
Give me the gun.
What's this?
It gets cold here at night.
Why didn't you bring it all?
If they arrest us
it's smuggling, one bottle
is for personal use,
only 80 lashes.
The bastard was going to come back
and shoot the mule.
Why are we still here?
Let's wait until he's far away.
He took his money and he's gone.
Is the sound really loud?
Will he hear the shot?
You have to finish off the mule.
He was right,
she won't last the night.
But you said she'd get better.
He was about to do it himself,
why didn't you let him?
How would we give him the money then?
We were supposed to buy the mule,
pay and leave.
He'd go back and finish her off.
But then you decided
to take his gun as well.
You want me to shoot with this hand?
Do it with your other hand.
You want me to kill the mule?
She'll die eventually anyway.
Maybe she'll get better.
Did he see me?
He'll never find it.
Were you digging a grave?
You said he shouldn't find it quickly.
Not my fault he's decided
to dig on the other side.
This is stupid, why not just say:
"Here is some money. It's yours."
You saw what happened
when we did that yesterday.
They stare at you, then walk off.
Let's go where people are still living,
put a bag at the door,
ring the bell, hide.
When they find it,
we take a picture and go.
Why ring the bell?
It's quicker.
We won't have to hang around.
They'll think it's lost,
and try to find the owner.
Bullshit.
1 in a million chance.
If it's considered chance.
If you don't ring, they'll think
someone's lost the money
and start putting notices around:
"Money found".
Like they do outside shops.
Why do you think everyone's
as crazy as you are?
Imagine you're walking
around downtown Tehran,
and two weirdies come over
with a bag of money.
You wouldn't take it, would you?
It's different
when you ring someone's bell.
He really went out of his way
to find the owners, didn't he?
Let's go. don't want to spend
another night in the car.
Sir...
Have you seen a bag around here?
Hi.
Have you seen a plastic bag this size?
No Miss.
Left it around here near a rock.
No rocks here.
They put the gravel
down here a long time ago.
Was here this morning,
there was no gravel.
It's a few days now.
What's he saying?
He says the gravel's
been here for a few days.
If it was, he wouldn't be able to dig.
It'd be frozen.
The sun melts the ice on top
in the mornings.
But underneath, it's frozen hard.
Have a look.
Didn't say you took it.
There were no rocks here, it was frozen.
He's not so stupid to admit
he's seen all that money.
I'm a guard here,
look after people's property.
If I'd seen anything would tell you.
Listen, we're taking our child over
the border for surgery.
He's in the car right now.
It's his hospital money.
We were driving past,
stopped to wash my hands,
they dropped a bomb or something,
got scared and let': the bag behind.
If don't find the bag
my child will die right here.
May God heal your child.
Would pay for him myself
if could.
If I'd seen any money,
would say so.
I'm not lying.
Is this where you sleep?
Yes.
Do you mind if have a look inside?
What for? - Nothing, just a quick look.
There's someone in there. - What?
There's family in there.
You have a wife and kids here?
He's lying, what family?
Don't go in,
my wife's inside.
Just want to have a look.
Can go where your wife is, right?
He's lying, there's no one in there.
Miss, Miss, Hello.
Is your wife deaf?
You've scared her.
Who are you trying to fool?
He's not lying.
Won't bother her.
Just want to see her.
Said no.
What's your problem?
Told you not to go in.
Leave it Kaveh, let's go.
You started it. You finish it.
Go inside. Ignore him!
Our child is dying in the car.
Why hide such a pretty
girl in this tent?
Take her somewhere better,
now that you have money.
Are you in pain?
It's nothing.
Do you want an Advil?
No use.
Let's get rid of the rest and get back.
I'm suffocating.
Can't wait.
Slow down. The truck.
Turn around.
It won't stop.
Said turn around!
Hurry!
Use your beamer.
Pull aside. - What for?
Just do it, OK?
Don't act crazy again.
Stay in the car if you can't take it.
Where are you running to?
Get down.
Do you have any ID? - What?
ID. Identification!
What for?
Have to deliver this load, I'm late.
Don't care if you're late,
need to see your ID.
We're not Afghans,
we're from here.
Have a license to drive a truck.
I've done nothing wrong.
Swear on my mother's grave...
Get down here for a minute.
Haven't got my papers on me.
What? - My license is in the camp.
Have to deliver this lime. - Camp?
It's in my tent in the camp.
You're driving a truck
without your license?
If they arrest you in this mess
how will you prove anything?
What's there to prove?
He's my brother,
everyone knows us along this route.
We've been working here for 3 years.
Why do you keep on about work?
Can see you work here.
Want to know who you are.
I'm Morteza Kerendi.
I've been working here 3 years.
Know you're Morteza Kerendi.
And this is your brother, right?
Yes sir.
We've been looking for you for a week.
Why? go to work all day.
I've never even hurt an ant.
I've asked everyone your whereabouts.
You've no phone, no address...
even asked the police,
no one knows where you are.
Miss Radmanesh, we found him.
Bring the receipt forms.
Receipt for what?
You're a winner my friend.
You've hit Jackpot!
Won what?
Bring the money too.
I'll tell you in a minute.
What did you tell them?
She's my colleague.
This is ten million. Two fives.
Sit and count it at your leisure.
This money is all mine?
And sign this receipt.
What's wrong with you?
Sign the receipt.
What's this for?
There was a lottery in Tehran.
Your name was pulled out.
Can take it back
if you don't want it.
Do you have a bag?
The plastic tears easily.
There's a sack in the cabin.
What lottery?
You can't trust
your own brother with money.
This one is making plans already.
Thanks a lot.
My duty to say.
Now he can get married.
Is he such an idiot?
He's been engaged for four months.
He was stuck for money.
You're engaged? - Yes.
What's her name?
Sepideh. Miss Sepideh.
Is she pretty?
Oh, for god's sake...
I'm just asking.
If she isn't,
don't waste the money on her.
Wait, you'll find someone better.
Is she any good?
She's good.
It took him a year
to persuade her father.
Wish you all the best.
It's the beginning of his end!
Come to the site with us
for a cup of tea.
It's just 5 minutes down the road.
The road's a bit muddy,
but it's near.
You want to go to work?
I'll be careful with the money.
I'll put it under my
seat, it'll be safe.
Don't care where you put it,e
I'm asking if you're going to work now?
We're workers.
Just gave you 10 million cash.
Looked for you in
all the holes on this road.
The boss has been waiting
for this load for 2 days
Fuck the boss!
You're the jewel in his crown!
There's a shortage of trucks.
The project has to end
by the end of the...
Give it back.
You want the money?
Give it to me or I'll call the cops.
Kaveh?
What did say?
You work, you have a salary.
You don't need money.
Why? He didn't say anything.
You mind your own business.
You want to go to work
and you have no ID.
Do, have a birth certificate.
It's in the camp.
You tell him Mostafa...
What good is that to me?
Want to know who you are.
Been looking in this shithole
for a week asking for Morteza Kerendi.
Was it Morteza or Mostafa?
Morteza.
What?
Mostafa.
Everyone tells a different story,
he's gone to Toutsari, Ghaderabad,
gone away...
I'm Mostafa.
Do you want Morteza or Mostafa?
Mostafa Kerendi.
You said Morteza.
Are you Mostafa or Morteza?
I'm Morteza.
Are you going to work too?
No, swear I won't.
Give him the money.
But you said Morteza.
What's the difference?
My money is your money.
No it isn't. Come here.
Where there's a Qoran,
there's no need for ID.
Swear you won't give any
of the money to your brother.
Can't, he's my brother.
Swear Mostafa.
Put your hand on the book
and repeat after me:
What should say?
Swear on this Qoran...
won't give any of this money...
Under any circumstances... - What?
Under any circumstances...
'to my brother Morteza Kerendi.
Louder!
Done.
You're not going to work are you?
No, swear to God I'm not! - God bless.
What will you do with that load?
Are you going to deliver it? - No.
Dump it.
What?
Where?
Don't care. Just be quick, I'm late.
You're going the wrong way.
You're going back to the coffeehouse.
I'm talking to you,
you're going back to Tehran.
Know where I'm going.
You want to go back to Tehran?
Yes.
We're running out of gas,
where do you think you're going?
What about these?
What does this mean?
We go back and say we failed. We failed!
You forget why we came here.
How will we go on living? - We won't.
If you can take from one man
and give to another,
can say I'm tired and I'm going back.
There were two of them threw
two bags, what's the big deal?
Stop being a jerk! You just took away
10 million from some guy.
You took it away!
Took my own money, not his.
You saw what he said.
He said he wanted to go to work.
Everyone goes to work.
Fuck his work!
You're here to deliver and leave,
their lives are not your business.
He didn't get it!
He wanted to be a slave!
And now he's got it?
Pull aside.
Answer my question!
Pull aside or I'll smash your face in.
No won't.
Thank you very much, I'll get off here.
Get out, I'm driving.
What's the matter with you?
You can't drive with that arm.
Is that your child?
My daughter.
The ground's frozen solid, isn't it?
That's right.
Was she your only child?
What?
Did you only have the one?
No, have three sons.
Asked god for a daughter,
he gave her
and took her the next day.
She was only a day old?
But it's better when they go early, no?
When they get older,
you get used to them; it's harder.
God rest her soul.
This way you can go make another one.
What are you doing exactly?
You can't dig this soil, it's frozen.
Have to bury her.
Sure, in the right conditions.
The ground is rock hard right now.
We bury them for our own benefit.
Makes no difference to the dead.
What is it? understand;
she was your daughter.
But she is no more. Gone.
Dead. Who knows where she is now?
This corpse isn't your kid,
it's 2kg of meat.
Let's say you dig a hole
and bury these four bits of meat
so you won't see her disintergrate.
A corpse eaten by worms
is a hundred times worse
than one eaten by wolves.
If you don't want to see her,
just leave her here
in 30 minutes the dogs
won't even leave the bones.
She doesn't care if she's eaten
by worms or wolves.
And what about the wolves?
Should they starve
in the cold because she's your kid?
Leave it for them,
it's just a tiny morsel.
Do you know what you're saying?
I'm going to...
Stop right there!
It's God's earth and I'm God's subject,
feel like sitting right here.
You don't want to talk,
fine, why pick a fight?
Go dig your hole.
Dig till you drop dead.
I'm burying my daughter. - Bury her.
If digging was possible
you'd have reached oil by now.
YOU People!
How many kids
did you say you have? - Three.
With your wife, you're five.
Do you make enough?
Do you have enough to eat?
What does that mean?
You either have enough or you don't.
What do you do? - I'm a teacher.
I'll pay you for that?
Pay for what?
The corpse.
I'll buy it.
Mean well.
Just say the price.
1 million current notes of the country.
That makes 333,000 per kilo...
don't know, don't have scales with me.
How much does meat cost these days?
What? Count it.
I'm giving you 1 million
so you won't have to dig any more.
That's not a bad thing.
Easy legit money.
You want more?
Just say so.
3 million, 1 million per kilo.
What for?
What difference does it make
to you if bury her or not?
Told you, want the animals
to have something to eat too.
That poor thing is dead,
but those beasts are still alive.
Just take the money,
never mind why.
Are you haggling?
Take it,
4 million.
Do we have a deal?
Or shall take all this money and go?
There's nothing left here,
everyone's gone!
Shall take the kid?
I'm talking to you.
What are you doing? Let's go.
This is for those 3 poor kids.
8 million,
that's 2 each
for the kids and your wife.
Nothing for you, because
you're not a man.
If you were, you'd have taken the money
and gone without looking back.
You don't want it? Fine.
Stay and bury the dead.
Try and dig the frozen rock.
But don't think don't know how you feel.
Know what it's like to lose a child.
Did she have a name?
Yes.
A one day old had a name?
She's called Banafsheh.
The other 3 kids also have names,
your wife also has a name.
You'll regret it when they starve,
and won't be here to help you.
Who'll know why gave you this money?
This kid will never speak,
only you and know.
Don't you touch me again.
You want to set fire to your life?
It's easy.
How much do you earn in a week?
100,000 max?
Here blows one week's pay, idiot.
Two weeks.
Keep digging and it'll be three weeks.
Three weeks.
Keep digging, soon it'll be spring
and the earth will breathe again
and a hole will finally appear
in front of you.
4 weeks.
5 weeks.
Half a million cash down the toilet.
Can you hear me?
Mister!
Why are you sitting here?
Are you waiting for us? - What happened?
Didn't you cross?
Your brother said he was going
to take you across. What happened?
My brother's on the other side
of the world.
Let's go, I'll give you a ride.
So who was the man you were with?
He told you he was my brother? - Yes.
He lied so you'd take the money.
He said he'd come back for it.
He won't come.
You have to leave.
Where's your brother?
What brother? He's not my brother.
Whoever. Where is he?
He won't be coming.
You must go.
No, promised. He said he'd come back.
Why don't you listen to sense?
He won't come back.
He let': the money for you;
take it.
Or leave it right here.
I'll wait. He left it for safekeeping.
Safekeeping?
We wanted to give it you.
You wouldn't take it! Remember?
Please. - Don't you come near me!
OK I'll say it from here.
You have to leave, you'll catch cold.
No need for you to worry about me.
Your brother told me everything.
If you cared, you wouldn't do
what you did to your baby.
What baby?
Don't have a baby.
Know. God rest her soul.
Whose?
What did that bastard tell you?
We came to give you the money.
Maybe you killed your brother too.
Why don't you listen?
God forgive you, Miss.
Who are they?
Good evening.
Don't you remember me?
Said good evening.
Good evening.
Where's your boyfriend?
He's around. - Where?
Needed something from that shack.
There's always something missing.
There's still so much left.
What are you going to do?
Money will move.
Yeah but don't you want to go back?
No hurry.
But it takes time and it's dark.
It's work.
You pay others but never get paid.
What kind of work is that?
It's not our money.
We're entrusted with it.
And you leave it in
the toilet and leave.
That's right.
Giving alms looks easy,
but it's hard work.
Can ask you to give some of it
to these guys?
OK.
Why not give it all, so you can be done?
There's a system. We have to give
a certain amount to everyone.
What if we took it by force? Can't we?
You can.
Will you be upset?
You want to give it to everyone;
they're everyone.
Will you be upset?
No, not at all.
Shall call them?
Flash your light.
Do what?
Use your beamer.
They all left
and nobody offered me a ride.
So you'll have to drop me off.
Where?
What?
Where do you want to go?
You want to take me?
Isn't he waiting for you?
Is it far?
Told you, across the border.
Will you come?
No, not across the border.
Right.
Get out. I'll drive on my own.
It's no big deal, I'll drive myself.
It's going to rain.
Forgot.
What? - Hashish.
Your boyfriend wanted some.
I'm not into it,
but the guys say it's good stuff.
Get away, get lost.
Hey! Let's go.
I'm talking to you.
Kaveh...
Come help me bury this corpse.
We'll do that later. Let's go.
We can't leave it; the
dogs will eat her.
What's your problem?
Leila you tell them.
We'll bring equipment.
We won't leave the kid lying around.
Can't you see the dogs?
I'll stay here 'til they come back.
You'll disappear again.
Are these animals your problem?
What are you doing?
You killed them!
Leave me alone you fucking psychopaths!
Breakfast.
Come in.
Thanks.
Can come in for a moment?
Kaveh,
get UP-
He wants to talk to us.
They've found your car
in the next village, near the border.
Last night was asleep,
there was a report of a murder.
Apparently they stabbed the guy
and took the money.
But they didn't take the car.
Abdollahi sent the body
to the coroners;
he had the sense
not to mention the car.
This way there's no mention
of the money,
the gun or the burial.
But you have to leave...
Not right now, have your tea.
And you have to take this.
If they find it here,
we'll be in trouble.
But for god's sake, be careful.
Sorry have nothing to offer
but these biscuits.
What if your commander finds out?
Don't know.
He'll hit us with extra service time.
He's a tough guy.-
If he found out tell him this:
Our mother is from around here.
She's old and ill, but very rich.
She's asked us to give away
some of her money in this area.
Tell him, their money was clean,
and their intention was good.
And the rest is my own business.