Papa.
Every thing is fine.
Papa, tell me about it again.
It's very different this new country.
A very peculiar land.
- Yes, but tell me again.
How I won't believe my eyes.
They put raisins in the pork roast.
And butter on your bread.
At least half an inch thick layer.
The brandy is cheaper
than water.
But strong enough to
knock kill an ox.
But your father can
handle it, Pelle.
Because he's hard.
And children are free all day?
- Yes, yes.
Tell me about it again.
Wages are so incredibly high,
that kids don't have to work.
They don't work?
And they can play all day?
Yes.
Don't worry.
Over there.
They won't fool me.
Shouldn't take the first offer.
Over there.
Your papers, your papers.
Here.
He's my son.
Is your wife with you?
- She's dead.
We're from Tommelilla.
Lasse Karlsson from Tommelilla.
I'm offering you my services.
That one looks like he'd
be kind to children.
Hello.
Lasse Karlsson from Tommelilla.
I'm offering you my services.
You should have stayed
in Sweden, you' re too old.
Hello.
I'm Lasse Karlsson from
Tommelilla, I'm offering...
I'm not gonna take the first offer.
Lasse Karlsson from Tommelilla.
I'm offering my services.
You're too old, and the
boy is too young.
Pelle, I'm not gonna
take the first offer.
No.
You're too late.
You were on the boat from Sweden?
Where are your parents?
Hello, Lasse Karlsson
from Tomelilla.
I'm offering my...
- Let me see your papers.
I'll pay you 100 crowns a year.
Including the boy, your son.
Dear sweet Jesus!
You'll sleep in there.
Any questions ask me
or my assistance.
Stop doing that!
Come back here!
Stupid animals!
You'll get me in trouble!
You won't get away from me.
You dumb beast!
Do what I tell you!
That's it. Move it!
You gotta learn how to treat them.
Hit them on their teats.
The teats or their hind legs.
Hit them!
Keep moving, I said, keep moving!
Stupid cows.
- Keep moving.
If you help me with the cows...
...and teach me danish...
...I' II share my food with you.
Always carry a stone.
If a cow runs away,
you throw it at her.
You take a good stone.
You throw it and you call her name.
Then, she'll come back.
She'll know who's boss.
- What's your name?
Rud.
Rut?
Rud. With the tongue.
Rud, Rud.
If you put your head
between your legs...
...and the sub is above the trees...
...it's time to give them water.
The larks' song will tell you too.
Rut!
That's my mother.
She can't say Rud either.
Rut!
Here's the food I promised.
Stablehand!
Why's that cow standing there?
Why's Gabriella there?
The girls can't find their cows,
when you move them around.
Aspasia, can't you read?
Just as it's written.
As-pe-sia.
You're saying there's a difference...
...where the cows stand?
Kongstrup is back.
Erik!
Why haven't you unharnessed
the horses?
Because I want to eat
my food first.
What do you say?
I say you unharness those
horses right now.
Come on!
Those horses are more
important than your stomach.
Do you know the punishment
for stealing milk?
You could be whipped for it.
I won't report you this time.
Hey Pelle... I've been thinking.
I like you.
So I'll say you a secret.
I know where you can find
a lot of gold coins.
But you got to keep it secret.
A real secret. You promise?
Come in here, Pelle, very quietly.
The raven can be
dangerous if it hears us.
Come.
Where are you?
Sir!
Are you here?
Jump!
Jump, you stinking Swede!
You dirty bastard!
Do you like it?
- Help!
That's enough!
I'll turn you both in
to the authorities!
I said that's enough!
You, son of a bitch!
- Help!
Erik! I'm warning you!
I'll turn you in!
Get out of here fast.
You're lucky I was
here to save you.
Get going.
He'll be punished. You can be sure.
On my word of honor.
I promise you I'II...
- Kill him!
Kill that filthy bastard.
You really gonna do it?
- I' ve given you my word.
How?
- How?
How are you gonna kill him?
With a hammer, I think.
Knock out his brains?
- Yes.
You'll really do it?
He's just good as dead.
But who'll read
the cows' names then?
You're right.
Yes.
We'd better settle for a whipping.
Then he can still read for us.
But it'll be a proper whipping,
that he'll never forgot.
Yarn for the boy's grey socks.
The patch was for...
What did she say?
The Sunday sweater.
Your mother said...
...the sleeves should be let down.
And...
Your mother was...
She was so worried before she died.
She didn't think I could
take care of you.
Don't let him wear the socks too long
Don't let him wear them through.
Lasse!
It's him.
Where are you, you Swedish bumpkin?
Are you going to do it now?
Yes, yes.
Sir, I want to protest
what you did to my son.
I want to protest...
- Why...
...don't you answer when I call?
Sir, I want...
I want to protest about
the way Pelle...
...was...
- You want trouble?
I can report you to the manager.
Aspasia is not going out
to pasture tomorrow.
Is she going to calve?
- That's right!
Did you think she was foaling?
You can lie there and cry.
But if one can't read
Aspasia's name...
...one ought to show a little respect
I know where's Aspasia.
She's the third one from the door.
You promised, papa!
Knowing that she's the third
one from the door...
Is not at all the same as
reading her name!
You fool!
I'm your father you should
show some respect for me!
Lasse is old and poor.
What's left?
No respect.
They can do what they
want with you.
You're short of breath.
You worry about your heart
and your blood pressure.
That's what getting old is like but...
...you're young, Pelle.
You can still conquer the whole world
Look at that! I nearly forgot,
Look here, Pelle.
Look, look what I have.
See, Pelle.
I forgot.
I brought this from Sweden.
From Tommelilla.
Well.
If we're lucky, we'll get
wild strawberries.
Just think, Pelle.
Real swedish strawberries.
Nils, get some water for your father
Nils, how about that water?
Keep out over there!
Just what do you think you are, Nils?
Where have you been?
Your father's been looking for you.
The missus sent me to the store.
Let's see what you've got
in your jacket Pelle?
She said no one was to know.
You're a good lad, Pelle, come.
If you give me the package,
I'll give it to my wife.
No one else will see it.
Cognac.
It's mine.
I won't move... until
you give it to me.
You bastard, Kongstrup!
I said give me that bottle.
You, Satan! Devil! Pelle...
...go and tell them all
how he bullies me.
How wicked he is, tell them...
...how he's ruining my life!
- It's all a lie!
You'll keep it.
God who keeps his children near.
Look at me who's kneeling here.
My happiness is in God's hands.
Whatever are the world's demands.
Papa.
What?
Tomorrow is the day
after tomorrow?
And the day after
tomorrow is tomorrow?
My birthday.
Yes, yes.
Pelle, was it the real
thing he threw out...
...really cognac?
He poured into the flower pot?
Happiness comes, happiness goes.
My happiness is in God's hands...
...whatever are the world's
demands.
You ought to start moving.
Put your clothes on.
Pants, Pelle, pans first.
But...
...what about your pocket?
There's something in your pocket!
You weren't out stealing
eggs last night, were you?
I'll be very surprised if
that egg isn't broken.
It's only paper.
Why do you stuff your pockets?
It's your day.
Your birthday,
God bless you, son.
Thank you.
It's just a simple gift from
a poor man, Pelle.
Look.
Well, a real beauty!
It's a birthday present.
I should have guessed.
You look like someone
who's having a birthday.
Congratulations.
Happy birthday. It's your day.
They say...
...that you plan to run
away to America.
What?
Run away!
Do I look like an idiot?
You think I'd risk losing
all my savings...
...and be lawless?
No.
I want to be free.
A free man.
That's what I'm waiting for.
That's what I want.
To be free.
Pelle.
I'll show you something.
It's here.
Here.
This is the boat to America.
I've got two years left to
work on this damn farm.
That's all, two years.
Then I'll have enough
money for the ticket.
As soon as the manager pays me...
...I'll go out and conquer the world.
Over the great ocean.
First to America.
China, Spain, Australia.
It's out there, it'll be
mine to conquer.
It's all out there just waiting
to be conquered.
A man can actually live!
It's out there waiting for us.
Take me with you.
Yes!
Because today is your birthday!
Remember. In two years,
when the snow begins to melt...
...we two will sail to America.
You and me will sail to conquer...
...that great wonderful world.
Open.
Surprise!
We've eaten wild strawberries
on all your birthdays.
Just think, real Swedish strawberries
How far is it to America, papa?
America?
It's a long way. You have
to cross an ocean, Pelle.
Erik said that he wants to sail there
He told me it's the strongest
thing there is.
It's soft but it can
hold up anything.
Yes.
- I wonder...
...America and...
...China...
...are they made
something like a boat?
It seems impossible.
Are those countries drifting?
Or are they anchored
to the bottom?
They are anchored.
Kongstrup!
Come out, Kongstrup.
I want to talk to you!
Your son is hungry!
- The sow...
...and the cabbagehead.
Kongstrup, your bastard
son needs money for food.
What do you think is going your
cabbagehead to talk about his father?
Come out and say hello to
your bastard son. He's hungry.
That lecher, he has kids
all over the place.
Kongstrup!
Except with his missus.
Your son is hungry!
- They say she is a witch.
The monthly allowance for your son.
Do yo have so many, you forgot?
- Get out!
Get out, sow!
- You'll never take care of us!
Get out!
- He never see his father!
Get out, you disgusting sow!
Kongstrup has to pay his due!
Kongstrup!
- Get out!
You'll never get rid about!
Kongstrup!
Take good care of your
slate now, Pelle.
And stay out of the way of the big
boys, until you can handle them.
But if you won't leave you alone...
...you have to be
the one that hits first.
But when you hit, hit hard.
Listen to everything the teacher says
And don't make trouble.
When you blow your nose,
use your handkerchief.
Do not use your fingers.
But...
...if you're sure that
no one's looking...
...then you can save
on the handkerchief.
Take care of your sweater,
now that I've mended it.
If the teacher's wife invites
you to coffee...
...take only one piece of cake.
She's not gonna do it.
Why not?
Because the teacher hasn't got a wife
That's the better.
Go on.
B-A says BA.
B-E says BE.
B-A...
...says BA.
B-E...
...says BE.
B-I says BI.
B-O says BO.
B-U says BU.
B-Y says BY.
B-A says BAH!
You miserable brats.
Stop it at once I tell you!
I'll teach each and every
one of you a lesson!
Silence! Silence in the classroom!
Silence! Bunch of barbarians!
He have here a new boy.
We must welcome him.
Stand up.
Tell us your name.
Pelle Karlsson.
And what are you good at?
I can make a cow obey me
just by throwing stones at her.
What an ass is he!
And I can make my cows stand...
...still by buzzing like a wasp.
- Swedish.
I can tell time by using the sun.
- Can you read?
No, that's why I've come here.
I don't care for your
insolence and sarcasm.
B-A says BA.
B-E says BE.
B-I says BI.
This one, here.
You told me but I forgot.
What did you call it?
Have you already forgotten?
I remembered after seeing it once.
It's an F.
That's what it is.
What's wrong with my head today?
F, F.
What do you think it's used for?
It's the first letter in f-ternoon.
F-ternoon, papa.
That's right.
But your didn't figure that out alone
The teacher must have told you.
- No.
I figured it out myself.
You did you're getting clever, Pelle.
There's no end to what a boy with
so much book learning can do.
Maybe we'll get roast pork
with raisins, Pelle.
Or with apples.
They also make it with
apples instead of with raisins.
We'll see.
Get out. I don't want any
more trouble with you!
Herring on Christmas Eve!
I didn't expect that given from you!
If you don't like the food,
then find some other place.
It will be a pleasure
to lose sight of you.
Herring, herring
every single day!
Couldn't we have had
roast pork for Christmas?
A real Christmas dinner?
- Damn you, always complaining!
If you don't like it in this country,
go back to Sweden!
You're so damn stingy!
Don't you think we work hard enough?
And you of all people say that to me!
Go to your quarters!
Go to hell!
Go to hell with you!
Go to hell with your farm!
Go to hell with you and your farm!
Go to hell!
Any other complaints here?
What are you doing here?
Why don't you go back
to where you came from?
Yellow-belly!
Why don't you stay with your own kind
Get lost, Pelle. You might
fall in the icy water.
Go home, Pelle!
You are a yellow-belly!
- So quit following us around.
Go home to your mama!
I can't my mama is dead!
Can you prove you're not
a yellow-belly?
Yes, I'll jump into that water.
You must be crazy...
...jumping into the water like...
...some love sick woman!
Just a show those kids!
A good beating is
what you deserve, Pelle.
If you had drowned...
...I'd have given you such a beating
you'd had sit down for a month.
Because if you had done it,
it would have been your fault.
Doctor...
...you could...
...you could use this if you
want to take some blood.
Drink this.
It will help your cold.
Don't be afraid, Pelle.
I'm not a witch.
Just very...
...Ionely at times.
Oh dear God!
You don't even have a mother.
Do yo?
It's three years since mama died.
She's lying in the lefthand side
of the church cemetery.
Do you miss her much?
Lasse mends my clothes.
She was a good mother, wasn't she?
She was so ill and grouchy at the end
And she used to be so happy.
But he'll marry again soon.
If Lasse can find a woman.
And then you'll go away.
The workers all hate it here.
It's as we were God forsaken.
As if we were cursed.
The earth is bloody.
Is that what they say?
Yes.
And what do they say about me?
That missus has a pact with the devil
And turns into a werewolf at night.
It's the price you pay...
...giving your heart to
the wrong man.
If he knew the anguish...
...the suffering that he
causes with his lechery.
He's in town again.
Why does he do this to me?
I married him, made him a proprietor.
Gave him my love.
The best I have, I've given him.
If he could have given me a child.
- I really have to go.
Now you're afraid of me again.
You're a good boy, Pelle.
If I had a son...
...he would be like you.
Come.
And this is where we keep the cows.
Papa, it's the missus.
It's the missus
with the young lady.
My God!
Pelle, go forward.
Pelle, where's your father?
This is our cattleman, Lasse
Karlsson and his son Pelle.
Hello.
This is Miss Signe,
my niece from Copenhagen.
She will be staying with us now.
Hello.
I've forgotten what 2 times 2 are.
May be I'm a bit rusty
on the subject...
...but I think the answer is
the same as in addition.
2 and 2 are 5.
What's lighter? A ton
of feathers or a ton of lead?
Now you!
- Sit down.
If you don't mind I'd like to hear
that question again, Pelle.
Repeat, please.
Which is lighter? A ton of
feathers or a ton of lead?
Well, what have we here?
Where is the herring?
I eat nothing but herring.
Do you know the difference
between you and a buttock?
No.
- No?
I don't know either.
Erik, did you hear what I asked?
I'm ask for a favour, Lasse.
Can you take my place
at the chaff-cutter tonight?
But it's saturday.
Yes, I wanna get
a bit of... you know. Will you?
Yes.
- No, not so fast.
He's got a way with women.
Like his papa.
It must be a hell of a long
time ago, Karlsson.
It's a real good idea, Karna.
Really.
You like Pelle.
You've always been good to the boy.
Why not move together.
We could be really happy.
You're too old, Lasse.
My man has to be dangerous.
You're not dangerous anymore.
I see.
So you're out fishing for young men.
Watch out you don't miss the boat.
Lasse, do us a favor.
Get us some brandy.
- What?
If you want brandy,
you can go and get it.
Just because someone is old!
That used to be respect!
"Lasse", the girls would say.
"I want Lasse Karlsson."
Eventhough you were married,
the girls were chasing you.
There was respect.
Papa!
I'm sorry.
I had hoped when we left Sweden...
...that there will be some
money that cover...
...enough to buy a little house.
And maybe find a woman,
who could take care of us.
Then, we could have coffee
in bed sunday mornings.
We could run away.
Run to somewhere, far.
¿Run away?
But think of the authorities. I don't
want to become an outlaw.
I know the way.
To América.
¡America!
- America, across the ocean.
They don't follow anybody that far.
We'll get away.
What are you doing?
Stealing eggs. I was hungry.
For God's sake,
don't tell anyone you saw me.
I know who the father is.
You've got to swear
that you tell no one.
His father...
If he found out I don't
know what he would...
To his father a Swedish woman...
...is only a worker.
For the love of God,
don't tell anyone.
I've got to hide in here
until my time comes.
Understand?
Pelle!
Come here!
What were you doing in the henhouse?
Stealing eggs.
Come.
Bend.
Pelle, can I have that coin?
My crown?
You're really out of your head.
I need it for when I go to America.
I'll pay you 10 crown
when I get grown.
You'll not grow.
Your body is unnatural.
I could be an attraction
in a circus at carnival.
At carnival?
Yes, as a monster,
I coud be rich.
What about of letting you
beat me 100 times with nettles.
A 100 good ones. How would that be?
Me beat you?
¿ What do you say?
You couldn't take it.
- Is it a deal?
Are you ready?
No more! No more!
You don't want I get pay!
You hit too hard!
Make up your mind.
The money first.
Can you tell us anything about
Adam and Eve and the serpent?
Well, we're all waiting.
Have you never heard of Adam
and Eve and the serpent?
Haven't you been listening in class?
What did the serpent
promise Adam and Eve...
...if they disobeyed God and ate of
the forbidden fruit?
You don't know what
the serpent promised them?
The snake in the garden
convinced them that they would...
...would indeed be
equal to almightly God.
I don't see how can we let you
continue with the class...
...when the children don't
understand the basic tenets.
Are his parents here?
His parents are not in attendance.
You may take you seat.
Next.
Pelle.
Perhaps you can tell us
what God said to the serpent?
And God said that...
That...
God said that the serpent
must crawl on its belly.
They shall crawl on their belly.
And does it still do so?
Yes. It hasn't any limbs.
And can you tell me what a limb is?
A limb is...
...a hand, for example.
Very good.
What distinguishes a limb...
...from other parts of the body?
A limb moves...
...independently of
the rest of the body.
Can you provide the others in
the class with an example?
Ears.
Can you move your ears?
- Yes.
I should really like to see that.
So your ears saved you.
I always told you to use your ears.
Rud!
Rud! You idiot! Come back!
You'll never get a heaven!
You'll never see your
grandma in heaven!
You can have my slate
if you come back.
You can't do that to me!
No! No!
Don't touch that stone!
The child is laying there.
In the bloody earth under the stone.
Yes he is.
Ana killed the child and
now she is in prison!
The crime is on my soul.
I murdered the child.
Natural fathers wouldn't do that.
Lasse would never
have done that to me.
Why don't you go and leave me alone?
I see in the night!
A bonfire you can see from miles!
Its soul burns on the rocks at night.
You musn't say that.
You must not lie before God.
The boy is lying up in the church...
...in consecrated earth.
- Its soul is under the rocks.
I've seen it burning on
the rocks at night!
And the reason is that he
was baptized too late.
God won't let him into heaven.
Nils!
Who has gone out there
into the arms of death?
It's Nils. He went out with the line.
Let's take him out!
Let's get him over there!
Your eyes are young.
Can you see Nils?
Blessed is the earth.
Blessed is our god in heaven...
The Angels...
He was a good son.
He was my everything.
He was... the fine boy.
He never spoke an evil
word to me. Not once.
Even though I denied him his love.
He was my son.
And my only one.
May he find peace now.
He had so little of it here on earth.
He sacrificed his life to save others
Perhaps now, in heaven...
...you'll be welcome.
Come on, Erik! Come on!
Two more inches and you've
won yourself a bottle of brandy.
He won the brandy!
When will you drink it?
The foreman says...
...you have to work tonight.
Tonight I don't work.
He'll do it without Erik.
I'll going out to found some fun.
No one is going to keep me in
when I am getting some fun.
Can I come with you?
No, not now, Pelle.
Not now.
In one year.
Across the ocean when
the snow starts to melt...
...then we'll go out
into the great world.
First America.
Then Australia.
And China.
Out there's the whole world, Pelle.
Where are you going you lazy dog?
You have work to do.
Erik!
You had to hear.
What do you call this?
I must have the flu.
My head is spinning like a tap.
That sounds serious.
Let's have a look at you.
Look at this, dressed up
in your sunday clothes.
What's this, your funeral clothes?
Were you going to buy
yourself a grave?
It's about time we get
you into the ground.
You're beginning to smell.
I'm not dead yet.
And I don't smell any worse
than some people.
You're nothing but a lazy
complaining trouble maker.
I'm sick of you!
Go ahead, do it again.
I'm sick of your belly aching.
- Come on, hit me again.
In front of all these witnesses.
We'll make a report
to the authorities.
Get up and go to work...
...or I'll show you the authorities.
The foreman wants you to be quiet.
You're making noise.
What did you say?
You're homely!
The foreman wants you...
- You must speak a little louder.
I can't hear what you're saying.
You're making too much noise.
Too much noise, little chicken?
You should help us
make too much noise.
Come on, sing us a little song.
I wonder if he sings like
a little chicken as well.
Run back and tell him
to run his own errands.
Skol!
Run!
Run to the fuck foreman!
I'm not dead yet.
Not yet.
Where are you going, Erik?
To rest.
What's that word?
Rest.
No, you can't rest now.
You'll get back in job.
You're after me again.
- After you?
What makes you think that?
The others are resting.
Yes, they are resting.
You get back in the job.
I'm always the one you pick on.
- You're feeling hurt!
That's because you're so clever.
For all the kind words
that you say...
...when my back is turned up.
What the hell do you think
your getting paid for?
Are you so stupid to think
you are on a paid vacation?
Get out to work right now!
You lousy bastard.
All right.
You can turn into the authorities.
And you won't get a single crown more
Not a crown, Erik.
You're all done.
Lasse! They're coming.
Good Lord.
They're going to do it.
Put him in the cellar.
You heard me, put him in the cellar!
The rest of you go back to work.
Come inside and get warm.
Thank you, it's a strong wind.
Then mama died.
And now she's in the cemetery
back home, in Tommelilla.
So your father is a widower?
That's the word.
The sea is hard. My husband
went to sea a year ago.
I've been like a widow since.
Has he drowned?
I can't say. I haven't
received an omen.
It's been a year that
she's living all alone?
That's what she said.
That's a long time.
A long time.
And you told her that your
mother was dead?
Yes, of course you did.
This is all we have left
of your mother.
It's all or nothing now.
Pelle, could you...
...visit Mrs. Olson tomorrow
after school...
...and you can say I send...
...my...
...my thanks for taking you in
and treating you so well?
I got an omen last night.
In fact you could call
it a kind of vision.
I dreamt there was a huge
dog standing next to my bed.
His coat was dripping wet.
I knew it was the shipdog with
a message for me.
I got out of bed.
And outside my window
I saw a ship go down.
I saw my husband rise to heaven.
He was dripping wet with saltwater.
I realized immediately...
...that the dog was
an omen from him.
Who's there?
Pelle's father. Lasse Karlsson.
You're Pelle's father?
He's very young your son.
Come, sit.
Pelle, was...
...a late-comer you might say.
But I can still do a man's work.
In every way.
Drink.
Thanks for the drink.
I must be on my way.
Eat.
That's how you get to know
something about a man.
You've walked a long way.
I just came by to thank
you for being kind to Pelle.
No, that's enough talk. Go ahead.
Please.
You must have been a
good wife to your husband.
Yes.
That's true enough.
Everything and anything he desired
when he was on dry land.
But he was ungrateful.
He became tired of that.
I don't think my wife would'nt
spoke on that way of me.
There is a lot to do in a house like
this, if there is a man to help.
Yes, yes.
There is only one cow.
That one could become two.
I'm only a poor person...
...but we have decent
clothes, both of us.
And I've a good pair of hands.
And you're not be afraid
to use them. Would you?
Not in the list.
I'm not afraid of...
...hot coffee in bed on
sunday morning either.
Can I think I should have a kiss?
Yes, you should.
We look for happiness and
blessings on the three of us.
You already like the boy.
You'd better stay for the night.
But I must be back
before the cows wake up.
And Pelle's all alone.
Pelle. ¿ What are you doing here?
Come on. Come on.
Everything is arranged.
We'll have a home and a woman
who'll take care of us.
Missus Olson. You'll be happy.
And may be we'll get coffee
in bed on sunday mornings.
Come, come.
Give us this day...
- Do you have the biblical stories?
And God...
- Does it have the one about the man...
...whose sons pulled down his pants?
Noah?
Yes, old man Noah.
What did he drink, old man Noah?
- Wine.
Wine! Then he must
have been a rich man.
Then there was the one...
...the man who was so devilish clever.
- Which was his name?
Laban.
- Laban!
Laban, of course.
It was Laban, Laban.
How is it go?
Could you have two wives then?
All right, I won't bother
you any more.
The great prophets. Let me see.
Let's see.
Isaiah and Daniel.
I remember them.
I remember, if you want to you can
test me about the prophets.
Let's hear them.
You better stop reading now.
Otherwise you may lose track.
There are only four great once.
Isaiah.
Come on, papa.
Well, first I need to concentrate.
There's Isaiah and Daniel...
I had them a minute ago,
where they have gone?
There's Isaiah...
...Daniel...
It's not working today, Pelle.
Isaiah...
- Think of how old I am.
Daniel...
Isaiah..., Daniel...
Jesus.
Not Jesus! Of course not, not him.
Isaiah, Daniel...
- They sure had devilish names.
You got tongued-tied.
- Try papa.
Isaiah.
- Isaiah.
Daniel.
- Daniel.
Ezequiel.
- Ezequiel.
And Jeremiah!
- Jeremiah!
Isaiah, Daniel, Ezequiel...
- Isaiah, Daniel, Ezequiel...
And Jeremiah.
- And Jeremiah.
Isaiah, Daniel, Ezequiel...
- Isaiah, Daniel, Ezequiel...
And Jeremiah.
- And Jeremiah.
Isaiah, Daniel, Ezequiel...
- Isaiah, Daniel, Ezequiel...
And Jeremiah.
- Jeremiah.
Will you never grow up?
Don't be afraid.
He wouldn't hurt a fly.
Are you going to the barber's then?
That's the last thing I'd do.
Erik are you coming?
Are you coming to the fair, Erik?
Come, Erik.
Come on.
Come on, Erik.
Isn't Erik coming?
He can't stay alone here
without the foreman.
He doesn't want to go.
Can't you go inside and get him?
You're the only one he listens to.
Come on, Erik!
Let's go.
We're going to the fair.
Isaiah, Daniel, Ezekiel, Jeremiah.
Isaiah, Daniel, Ezekiel, Jeremiah!
Those were the days.
Imagine, two wives.
One could make coffee and
the other could mend and sew.
Everything's for sale!
You can take four packages!
Pelle.
Hello.
What's going on here?
I'm leaving, aunt.
I need to go.
But Signe, is there a problem?
If so, I'm sure we can solve it.
It's the isolation from
all my friends.
I'm a city girl so...
...so I'm returning.
- But you...
...say nothing, Signe.
- I...
...I know that I must told you before
- I'm so disappointed.
I don't understand.
It's just time to leave
to Copenhagen.
But I thought...
...Kongstrup and I were sure
you were happy here.
Dear Signe.
I don't know what else to say.
I've made my decision.
So suddenly...
If you had mentioned it before
I could understand.
Sorry.
- Why didn't you...?
Is your reason why you don't look at
the eyes. Should I know something?
Signe?
How are you going to manage?
Well, you see...
- Who buy you a ticket?
Kongstrup takes me to the boat.
Thank God. I don't have to worry.
If only I could understand...
You will return here for a visit?
I'd hope you would take over
around the farm at an old age.
Kongstrup too wanted it.
Signe, dearest, don't cry!
It's not as serious as all that.
I want you to feel free...
...to visit us the times
that you want.
Kongstrup!
Come out and talk to me!
I'm here to collect
the money, Kongstrup!
Kongstrup!
Look who it is!
Let me say hello to you.
Are you too proud to
say hello to me?
Do you think that you're better?
Is it because you're leaving
to have your bastard son...
...on the other side of the sea,
while I had mine in a turnip patch?
But it was the same
old whoremonger.
The same whoremonger as ever!
Signe, Signe.
Signe.
Would you tell him that
I need the money?
Why do you leave evil eye?
I warned you!
Let me go! Let me go!
Kongstrup, come on and help
you're old sweetheart!
Let me go!
What do you stare?
If I've to search for you once more...
- Sorry madame.
It beats me.
I would have thought that only
dead could end such grief.
She must have an iron grip on herself
Wake up! Send the doctor, quick!
What is it papa?
Dear Jesus! It must be something bad.
What is it?
- It's so awful.
What? What did you say?
She cut...!
- What is it?
What happened?
- Kongstrup.
What?
- He's bleeding.
We should get some help.
- Really?
It's fun!
Mister Freeze, could you
tell us what this means?
Pelle is the young cuckoo
in missus Olson's nest.
Ins't she married to a seaman?
He's captain Olson's bride.
Your father doesn't care
about that, does he?
He's captain Olson's bride.
Your father doesn't care
about that, does he?
Watch out! Watch out!
Any girl would like to marry
a man like that.
What if her husband
comes back, Pelle?
Guess what Pelle?
This is for Captain Olson!
Just you wait Pelle,
we're gonna get you.
Pelle.
I've thinking a lot
about the situation.
You and I would be welcome
at missus Olson's.
We could move right in.
I mean...
It's against the law to
move in with a woman who's married.
But...
I want some comfort.
We could make it look like
the two of us are labourers.
She could sew you new clothes.
Wouldn't it be nice to
have new underwear?
lf...
...I did move in with missus Olson...
...you did move in with missus Olson?
It's a lot easier for you.
Is all ahead of you.
Your whole future to make
something happen.
I need someone to take care of me.
I'll run away if you move in.
You have to grow
old to say that to me.
Just look what you're doing?
Someone else will have
to fill in the holes.
So the foreman doesn't find you out.
Stop that right now.
I don't make acarving of you
and missus Olson in bed.
You're getting a little so far.
Come back here!
You'd better watch out I don't
send the foreman on you.
Pelle!
Could you go by missus Olson's...
...on your way back from school?
This is something she's
going to mend for us.
And be sure to tell her
I'll come by this evening.
Why don't you marry her, papa?
Pelle, I will.
But we've got to deal with
the country's authorities.
Missus Olson needs a dead
certificate from the government.
But soon we'll have coffee and bed.
It's missus Olson's young cuckoo!
Let's see how tough you are, Pelle.
To the sea with him!
Run cuckoo bird!
- Run!
Come on, let's see you dance!
Run cuckoo bird!
Come back to Sweden!
Go away, cuckoo bird!
Away, away, away, away!
Away, away, away!
Away, away, away. Come on!
Look! It's Captain Olson!
You're at home already.
Missus's Olson husband
has come home.
I will stay here forever...
...standing here like...
...a block of hay in the shed.
I was only looking for a home...
...to spend my old age.
I've found someone and I felt free.
Jesus!
Jesus, help!
What the hell is the point of crying?
I want you to meet my new sweetheart.
Here, Pelle.
I forgot...
...that you didn't this thing.
You're too fine.
It doesn't help going around...
...whimpering.
Papa!
It's sleepery.
This is a little devil.
You're crying?
If some do something to you...
...tell them that your father is
Lasse, from Tommelilla.
It's alright, your father is here.
And your father can stand
on his own two feet.
I'm going out to the big house.
Now the bastard is gonna...
...have to answer for all these years
We are going to have a
little talk with the missus.
I won't let you go out there!
Erik.
Spring is coming, that's
what papa says.
In the spring you'll be...
...a free man.
Think of it.
Then, we can leave this awful place.
And go out and conquer the world.
Pelle.
What is it they all talk about?
I wouldn't know.
You haven't heard anything?
Do you think I wanna go to class
so they can laugh at me some more?
I know I drink too much.
But it's difficult not to, when
you're heart is broken.
Pelle...
...if I promise you'll never again se
me the way I was yesterday...
...would you agree to go to school?
Tomorrow, Pelle?
Because if you don't...
...then they will force you.
There'll be a lot of trouble
with the authority.
Alright? Say yes.
10 times 10 is a hundred
100 times 10 is a thousand.
100 divided by 10 is 10.
1000 divided by 10 is 100.
Mister Freeze?
Mister Freeze.
He's asleep.
Mister Freeze, it's time.
Sir.
It's time to go home.
Pelle, where's your father?
Fooling around?
My father would be happy...
...to marry your father to captain
Olson's second wife.
Help papa! Help!
You scoundrel!
How dare you hit my son!
You're going to hear from
the authorities about this!
Pelle, Pelle, Pelle...
That was about the worst you
could do, hit the minister's son.
The town's minister.
He deserved it, I'm sure.
But still you shouldn't have done it.
What else did he do to you?
He said he could get you married
at boatsman Olson's second wife.
He did?
If I had him here,
I'd rip his innards out.
Do you feel revenged?
No, not really.
His father came and gave
what he deserved.
Revenge.
It's a bad situation.
And you don't intend to apologize?
No, no, you shouldn't.
Although maybe you should...
No, no.
You have to twist and turn...
...as the eel said in the frying pan.
We are very sorry to bother you...
We have no choice, but...
...to ask for your help.
Did you blow your nose properly?
We are very sorry to bother you, Sir.
I'm very sorry.
There's probably no one home.
- Let's go in.
We can't stand here all day.
Go first, if you think you
can handle this better.
Come in.
Good day.
It's like this...
I hope the proprietor
be angry with us.
He won't be angry.
You must forgive us for coming here...
...to talk about something which
has nothing to do with the farm.
But...
...when the father's sins...
...are visited upon his son.
Then...
- Why are you standing?
Sit down, please.
Thank you.
- Why you haven't...
...offered them a sit, dear?
Thank you.
- What is it?
You need money?
No, it's...
Is just like a...
It's just that...
I hope that you won't be angry but...
...it's...
It's the boy.
They're going to send him away.
Send him away?
- Yes.
¿ What have you done?
I beat up the minister's son.
And why you did you do that?
Because he said evil
things about Lasse.
What did he say?
He called me...
He called me Mrs. Olson's plaything.
You know, the kids...
I was...
...Mrs. Olson's sweetheart.
Because everyone thought
she was a widow.
And other day her husband
came home from the sea.
Here.
And the boy made Pelle furious.
- Yes, unfortunately.
That's how it is.
With poor wretches...
...they're only there to be pecked at
Well, I prefer the bird that pecks
back and defends his nest...
...regardless of the poor it is.
I'll do what I can.
Don't worry about it anymore.
Thank you.
By the way.
My husband and I decided...
...the young assistant to
our foreman will be leaving.
Maybe Pelle would like to
become his replacement.
Thank you.
Say thank you.
Almost as if she thought
it was her own idea?
She thought, she thought it herself.
Your recognized this?
They're a bit big, but
we'll stuff them with papers.
Try them on.
I'll get some boot wax,
and they'll be like new.
Now let's have a look.
Stand up straight. I want
you stand very straight.
Shoulders back and
chin a little forward.
Not like that. Lift you chin a little
Now a sharp look in the eye.
You must command respect for yourself
The way you stand and the look
in your eye. That's what does it.
Let the others labour.
You give the orders.
You can't take tonight off!
Clean now the cow down!
And Pelle...
Maybe you'll get to eat
sunday dinner with the proprietor.
And have a napkin-ring
with your name on it.
Pelle Karlsson.
And who knows, Pelle. Maybe
one day you'll be the foreman.
I could tell you the way she
was thinking it was perfect.
Erik!
Wait for me!
I don't want it.
We must leave here, papa.
Now.
It's Karna.
I get here in time.
I was afraid the foreman
and the missus would see me.
A gift for you.
It's a down quilt.
It'll keep you warm. No matter
where you end up in the world.
Bye, Gabriela.
Bye, Blanca.
You'll be a good girl.
Well, Aspasia.
Time to say goodbye to Pelle.
He is going up to see the world.
Papa.
What is it?
Can't we stay?
You'll have to go
without me, Pelle.
I don't have the strength anymore.
I'm too old. It's the reason.
Too old.
There's no future for an old man.
Do you understand that?
I'll make a bundle for you.
You can have 2 of
my shirts then you have 4.
Then one you're wearing is clean.
And remember: never wear
it more than two weeks...
...at a time, otherwise you
get bad name in town.
And change your socks
before they wear out.
Keep your clothes clean.
Keep your good name.
You save half the work and all shames
You can have my boots too.
They are a bit worn.
And here's the Bible.
Your mohter said
I was to give it to you...
...on the day she went
out to the world.
Next time we'll meet maybe
there'll be a proper home for you.
Say Karna goodbye.
Goodbye, papa.
Thank you.