I'm probably not going very far but
you're welcome to ride as
far as I'm going.
I bet this is one of the
roughest stretches
of hitch hiking you've
ever come across.
Yeah I've seen better.
There's two prisons right over the
horizon over there.
And folks around here are kind of
leery of hitch hikers.
Two prisons?
Yeah one for the ladies and one
for the gentlemen.
How'd you like to crawl in the back
and roll around with me for
a little while?
Beaver seven, Beaver
seven, come in Beaver seven.
This is Charlie one.
Beaver seven here
Charlie one come in.
Beaver seven I been trying
to contact you for over
half an hour.
What's your present
position Beaver seven?
Headed east on highway 12
just west of cove number two.
Good going you got two
customers waiting at cove two.
They'll be sitting in the
corner to the left.
Gotcha Charlie, talk to you later.
Well you know it's business
before pleasure.
And I'm sure you're a real pleasure.
Well this is where we part.
But I have a feeling you and I
will be meeting again someplace.
Hey hurry up with that damn beer.
You two put in a call
to Charlie one?
Hey Hymie you put in a call
Who the hell's Charlie one?
I don't know.
But he aught to have more sense than
to send a filthy whore like this.
Listen funky mama better get your
little butt out of my face
'cause me and Hymie we ain't about
to mess with no slut
just finished up with a
dirty nigger.
Just who in the hell do you desert
rats think you are?
You better get back on
those tricycles
and go play in the sand.
'Cause after having a real man
I'd probably puke having a
couple of boys.
Hey I don't want any
trouble in here.
Please get out of here, get out.
Stop that or I'll call the police.
Don't do that, be careful.
Please don't fight up my place.
Get out.
Go fight outside.
You can go kill yourself
just not on my time.
Oh my God please.
Come on damn man damn.
The lines gonna be moving to
count a few ticks man.
Hey Poin, check Cheese out.
He wants some of that new
stuff bad don't he?
Oh look who's talking fucker.
You ain't never talk lessen we set
the stuff up for you.
Aint this 'bout a bitch?
You the one always hanging round
for them sloppy seconds fool face.
You ain't talking to me.
Yeah I'm talking to you.
He ain't talking to me.
Not lessen he want a size 13 old man
cuffing up his ass he ain't.
Say man why don't y'all knock
the bullshit off?
Now this is business.
Here that nut go messing
with that new dude.
You got a match?
No man.
Get out the new dudes face sucker.
What's happening baby?
Awe man that's that old fool
Half Dead he's insane.
Go off like this every now
and then looking
for the dude he caught
with his old lady
the night he killed her.
Not this again.
Here he go in bed with his girl.
Gave him a scar, left
cheek of his ass
as the dude was going
out the window.
Oh man damn it.
How many times I gotta show
you my ass man?
Give me some slack Dead.
Hey Dead you wrong, Dead you wrong.
No man.
It's him.
It ain't him, it ain't him.
Man show him cheeks man.
That's him.
That's him man.
That's the one.
It ain't him Dead.
God damn it.
Okay.
Wait, wait wait wait.
Show him.
I'll show you.
Show him quick.
See look.
Look you crazy fool.
Do you see a cut?
Huh?
Shit.
This is one butt I could never cut.
The boy paid his dues.
Hey man let's talk.
Cut this chatter and go to chow.
Okay now get out of here.
Crazy man again huh Jonathon?
How many times are we gonna have to
play this God damn game?
See me after chow, get in that line.
Come on Pops.
Boston let's go into the chow hall.
I'm not hungry man.
You been playing the
game for how long?
You know it's gonna get
pretty tough for you.
When you get yourself
together come on down.
The guard will let you
out into the yard.
That's where everybody is, out in
the afternoon yard.
Come on guard hurry
up with the count.
I want to see Charlie's Angels.
Oh chump, you
are Charlie's Angel.
Hey cousin.
What?
You got any more of
them spit ball things?
Nah nigger.
Okay Jonathon
get over here.
Jonathon you on coal
furnace detail already.
The next step is the
hole for a month.
Don't push it.
Who the hell put you in my cell?
You just fall?
Been in the county jail six months.
Just got sentenced a few days ago.
What you down for?
Being in the wrong place at
the wrong time.
You box?
Not really.
Why?
Boxing tournament coming up.
Big fun.
Might bring some lady trustees
from across the way.
You aught to see them fools,
showing off for them slutty broads.
You box?
Hell no.
Half Dead don't box.
I kill.
But you got to keep yourself
in shape round here.
This place is full of fools.
If you don't handle the
fools they handle you.
Get my meaning?
That bad huh?
Some dudes get smart, get in
with big brother,
keep the hounds off.
God damn it.
Boy I'm gonna beat your ass.
Must have caught him
standing up peeing again.
I told you about that
standing up and peeing boy.
I'm sorry I forgot, I forgot.
Didn't I tell you huh, huh?
Sit down and pee, sit down and pee.
Check yourself the man's coming.
Come on.
What the hell's going on in here?
Break this shit up and sit down.
You mess with me the whole block
will be locked down for
six damn months.
You understand?
You want to watch TV sit down and be
quiet, cut the shit.
You know the day officer told me
you gave him a little
trouble already today.
He put you on the coal furnace
detail, among other things.
Watch your step Gordone.
Settle down and listen to TV
or I'll lock this whole block up.
What you want, what you want?
You got anymore Cracker Jacks?
Nah I ain't got no Cracker Jacks.
Bitch get all the money huh?
Man business is hard.
Look here Jesse I'm telling you
I can take this sissy by myself man.
I can feel it Jesse.
Ain't no bronc I can't bust Jesse.
I don't know Dead.
There's just something
about this dude
that tells me he ain't no push over.
Yeah Dead what if you
can't break him man?
You gonna blow the whole plan.
Look, relax Dead.
Wait a couple of days so we can set
the bootie up right.
Yeah man we can all
help break him in.
Ah man.
Alright look here Half Dead.
Are you sure you can bust
this young buck man?
Ah Jesse I don't even
know what all this
conversation is about man,
sure I can.
Jesse I'm the baddest in the
whole penitentiary.
Okay, okay okay I'll tell you what.
You try him out.
But if he backs off him,
you back off.
Hey Jesse, what does Dead know
about backing off man?
Shut up man.
You got anything you want Jesse.
But you watch in the morning.
Brother gonna ask for the
salt and pepper,
his voice gonna up five octaves.
Come on fellas enough of
this chomp chomp.
Amos you and the boys get
the line and wait.
I ain't got time for this shit.
Get in your cells it's count time.
I said move it.
Get the hell out of my way.
Get in your cells it's count time.
Move it Lightening.
Count time, in your
cell on your feet.
Count time.
Look here Gene.
I hate to have to do that shit I
had to do tonight.
But you bring all that
shit on yourself.
You can't stand up, I tell
you all the time.
And when you do shit like that
you bust my bubble and I
can't stand that.
You all I got Genie.
Hey man you want some Good Bar?
Hey man why don't you check
out one of these?
They'll get your shit long,
get some spirit.
What if Half Dead blows it?
Damn, can't you think
of nothing else?
It ain't that at all
but I hate to see
Half Dead blow a sale that we could
have easily handled.
Man be cool give Dead a chance.
We'll soon find out if he
blew it or not.
He just did it man.
Ride him Dead.
Ride him Dead, ride that old rascal.
Never heard Half Dead make no
sound like that before.
Me either man, I've heard Dead
make some weird sounds.
But I ain't never heard a
sound like that.
He's playing man.
Man that Dead done real
learned how to play.
I bet them yells is scaring that
yellow rascal crazy.
I'm gonna bust you.
You my stuff.
Bust you.
I'm gonna bust you.
You my stuff, you my stuff.
You mine sucker, you mine.
Bust you mother fucker,
I'ma bust your ass.
You still want to ride me?
Now you finished playing that
cowboy shit for the night?
If not I can keep whooping on your
ugly ass all night long.
I'm talking to you.
That ain't gonna help you sucker.
Sounds like Half Dead got
himself another one.
Aren't your boys good enough to
see how it was huh?
No.
You don't want to disappoint your
boys out there do you?
You're gonna say something.
Jesse.
Yeah Dead.
Run it to me right Dead
what's happening?
Say it.
Now.
The bronc, the bronc done
busted the buster.
Come on man.
Don't tell me that shit just run
it to me right Dead.
He's running it to you right.
This is Too Sweet talking.
And I'm riding your bronc
buster right now.
Now why don't you and your
boys just back off?
I told him.
Didn't I tell him?
Told him he was gonna
blow that stuff.
Told that nigger was gonna
burn that fine stuff.
I don't believe it.
Damn Dead.
What you laughing at sucker?
Get it fixed.
I said get it fixed.
Jesse I don't feel like.
Genie God damn it,
move it.
Mind if I squat?
It's a free prison isn't it?
But I happened to be
Jesse's property
as you gathered last night.
Property?
Is that what you think of yourself?
Somebody's property?
Ah come on you know
what's happening.
Everybody knows what's happening.
I been as they say tampered with.
Hey man that ain't my thing.
What five fingers can't get done,
don't get done.
The only thing these
fools know to do
with five fingers is make a fist.
And you saw what they can do
with it last night.
Come to think of it you put on quite
an exhibition yourself.
Hey.
Let me show you something.
You see?
You can make one too.
Now don't nobody have to be
nobody's property.
Keep going keep going, keep running.
Come on keep going keep going.
What was that all about?
Look Two Star or
whatever your name is
you been here a hot
second and already
you got your nose in
other folk's asses.
Well I ain't Half Dead boy.
I catch you bugging my
stuff one more time
I'm gonna send half your face
out of here on parole.
You got that?
Hey hey check it out.
A street fight on Big Jesse.
I'll kill you,
I'll kill you.
I'll kill you freak.
Bad man, that
new kid is bad.
14 days.
14 days in the hole.
That should have been enough
time for you men
to find yourself and get
your shit straight.
And your act better damn
well be together.
'Cause one more ruckus out of
either one of you
and I'm gonna forget
I'm a gentleman.
And you.
I can't get over you Amos.
I apparently gave you more damn
credit than you deserve.
I went out on the limb and invited
my brother-in-law up here this year
just to catch your
boxing tournament.
And if he likes you I don't
have to tell you
what a word from me and him can
for your ass with the parole board.
Anymore fighting outside of
that damn ring,
if you so much as look cross
eyed at each other,
you're next trip to the
hole is gonna be
preceded by a thorough, efficient,
and otherwise
consistent ass whipping.
Do you understand me Gordone?
Amos?
Alright let's get in to
current things.
Now there's been a few changes
in the past 14 days.
Hezzikia Jackson has
taken over your job
as the trainer while you were
down in the hole.
It's alright with me Lieutenant
the old man's good.
I thought he vowed to never
train fighters again?
He did he surprised the
hell out of us
but he's doing it and he's
doing a good job of it.
As a matter of fact
we're gonna ask him
to stay on the team
after you rejoin.
We already asked him once he said
he might under one consideration.
What's that?
Hezzikia want a key to
the front gate?
No he don't want no key to
the front gate.
He just said that Gordone here
in his estimation is one
of the fastest
talented young fighters
that he's ever seen.
And he'll stay on as trainer if
Gordone joins the team.
And Gordone in respect to
joining the team
you heard what I mentioned to
Amos a few minutes ago.
The fringe benefits my
brother-in-law and the parole board.
Same thing holds true for you if
you're interested.
Sir I'm no fighter.
You're no fighter?
What the hell do you call
what you been doing
since you came through
that front gate?
Well I fight to defend myself
but I'm no boxer.
You're no boxer?
Neither is Eugene Lawson.
But he surprised the hell out of us,
he's joined the team.
Genie, I mean Eugene Lawson's
singed up for what?
The boxing team Amos what else?
Awe Lieutenant that boy
ain't no fighter.
Sir I think I'll join up after all.
That's good Gordone, good,
real good.
Wouldn't it be something if you two
were in the same weight class?
I'd give anything to
see you up there
toe to toe whacking at each other.
Wouldn't that be something?
Alright look you can head back now.
But remember no more fighting.
By the way Gordone you're cell
has been changed for
obvious reasons.
You'll be locked in with Hezzikia
Jackson your trainer.
Where do I put my stuff?
Up your ass.
They put me in here.
Soon as the matches are over
I'll be happy to leave.
You a winner?
I try hard.
With me you're gonna do
more than try.
You're gonna win.
Now put your stuff down there
and bring your bunk
up from down the block and put
it against the wall.
Right on.
Don't talk to me by that
hippy dippy shit.
I'm a man, I'm no hippy dippy fool.
And let's get one thing
straight right now.
I keep my stuff clean and I expect
you to do the same.
And I don't want nobody in here.
You want to talk, you want to visit,
you visit them.
I don't want no fools in my home.
This is my home.
And keep your ass clean.
I know fighting gets you
a little funky.
But soap and water will take
care of all of that so
keep your ass clean.
Are you gonna hold
inspection too sir?
A wise guy?
A wise guy.
Just do like I tell you and
everything will be alright.
And oh, no sissies.
Wait wait man let me show you.
See get right here see, see.
Go ahead jab it.
Oh no wait a minute.
Joey come on show him.
Left left left see, that's
the way to do it.
Alright man I got it, I got it.
Work quickly.
Hold it.
Hold it, hold it, take five.
Take five.
I want all you fighters to move in
closer to ring side.
You fighters come over here.
Got a couple of things to say.
First of all the winner in each...
Well hell first things first.
Men I may as well tell you.
I've invited some lady trustees
from the woman's prison next door
to come here tonight to
cheer you guys on.
Anybody mess up this whole thing
can go down the drain like that.
I'm trying, but it's
not positive yet.
But I'm trying to work out one week
of connubial visits for the
winner in each event.
Connubial visits you jackasses means
that the winner of each event will
get to spend one night
in a trailer in the
yard with a woman.
I'll tell you what hold it.
If you don't have a woman we'll
supply one for you okay.
Hey Eugene why don't you let me
take your place man?
I mean after all what
are you gonna do
with one of the come
bugelie visits anyway?
Same thing you do with it sucker.
Hey.
Back off.
Yeah you fellas can throw it
out of your minds.
I'm fighting, I'm winning, and I'm
damn sure screwing.
Get up sucker get up.
What you chumps laughing at?
This is Half Dead.
Okay cut it out over there.
Eugene man, my name is Eugene Lawson
and I'm kicking ass tonight.
Eugene, Sue Gene, Flugene,
what the hell ever.
Man I know it's rough but you can
whoop this kid 'cause you tough.
Tony the Tiger
Now he's gonna kick your
ass you hear me?
That's just it you
ain't said nothing.
We all alone now baby.
Ain't that all that counts?
What you mean that's
all that counts?
What are doing in here?
If you didn't know what I
was doing in here
you'd be screaming at the top of
your voice by now.
Shit.
You expect me just to
drop my drawers
'cause you jumped out
the ceiling huh?
Now look baby.
Now we ain't got no time
for talk making.
I done been locked up
for a long time.
Me too, me too.
Hey wait a minute this is my fight.
This is my fight man come one.
This is my fight man.
God damn baby, ooh shit.
Hi sweetie.
Didn't hurt you did I?
Come on get up baby.
Get up, come on baby.
Break.
Boy you hit me again I'm
gonna kill you man.
Hey man I'm sorry.
I'm gonna kill you you
hit me again man.
Come on man, come on now.
Don't hit me no more.
Come on man.
Go on let's go.
Alright Genie, Genie you mean.
My name is Eugene man, Eugene.
Alright hey, Eugene then you mean.
I'm glad it wasn't no God
damn straight fight.
He would have killed my ass man.
Alright.
Hey.
May I have your attention?
Quiet!
Hey!
Hey man!
Watch your step over there.
You got another 'bout for
another row of teeth.
First of all I'd like to wish the
ladies from next door
a pleasant good evening tonight.
Well thank you very much sweetie.
Now bring on the boys baby.
Hey!
Quiet!
Right now let's give
both of these men
a big round of applause for
a hell of a fight.
And ladies and gentlemen I'd like to
announce the winner.
By unanimous decision
your man Eugene.
It's the guard.
Tell what's your name baby?
What's your name?
Peaches.
Come on Peaches, oh baby.
147, 148, 149, 150.
You're feeling mighty
frisky tonight man.
Yeah I feel like celebrating.
Break out the Mister Good Bar.
Mister Good Bar my ass.
You know how I feel about sweets
when you're in training.
You haven't won't the
tournament yet.
Shit Seldom I'm ready.
You know I'm ready.
I'ma kick plenty of butt
including yours old man
if you don't give me a Good Bar.
I want some Good Bar.
I want a Good Bar.
You don't know your strength.
I'm not about to get too old
to get a little bold
and knock one of you
chumps out cold.
Well you damn near did Seldom.
You wouldn't really
hurt me would you?
Back up.
I joke and I laugh but
I don't touch.
Sometimes I can be tough.
Sometimes I get mean.
Why you think they call
me Seldom Seen?
You a poet and don't know it.
But you promised me a Good Bar so
please will you show it?
Okay.
Go on get and the Good Bar.
But I hope you get the cramps and
get knocked on your ass.
Shit, Ali ain't got
nothing on the kid.
Hey looky here Gene.
Now you ain't got to put
yourself through this
'cause you ain't got nothing to
prove to these suckers.
You're right Jesse.
I don't have nothing to prove
to these suckers.
But I do have something to prove
to myself you know?
Hey Jesse?
Yeah man.
Tonight call me Eugene okay.
I'm Eugene tonight.
Hey Eugene I heard some
good news man.
Half Dead ain't gonna
be here tonight.
Better watch out man,
the mans coming.
Say that was a good fight
tonight Jared.
That put Plebes down.
Hezzikia come here please.
This is my brother-in-law
Sam Cunningham
the promoter I told you about.
Alright if you get a
chance call everybody
here in the house and
bring them together.
Hey everybody gather around.
This is the Lieutenant's
brother-in-law.
Sam Cunningham.
He's a big handler.
And he has a few words he
want to say to you.
I haven't really got much
to say except that
I've heard a lot of good
things about you men.
And I just want to let you know
that I'll be out there tonight
looking for potential champions.
By the way men I just go the word
from the Wardens office.
It's been okayed.
The winner of each
division will have
a day of connubial visits.
Winner by knock down, five seconds
in the first round.
Jesse Amos.
Say what?
You want something?
Damn boy you ain't
gonna get no pussy
with you laying on your back.
Oh man.
God damn Peaches.
Got to beat you with this shit.
Girl you almost got hurt.
Oh hurt me.
Oh 'cause you jumped out
of the ceiling
I'm supposed to drop my drawers huh?
For what I'm gonna just drop
it ain't necessary.
It isn't necessary at all.
Come on Eugene.
Slow down man.
Oh baby.
Do to me as you will.
Slow down.
See Half Dead is tricky man.
Jive sucker.
Done hit the man in a clinch.
Foul foul foul, foul foul foul.
Quiet.
Knock it off, I said quiet.
What is you lost your mind?
Take these dumb broads back
where they come from.
You ain't got good sense.
Get out to your own hood.
This is Half Dead.
I ain't going nowhere
till these sissies
give me some respect and
name me the winner.
That some bull dog, we
wouldn't have you anyway.
Now wait a minute baby you
speak for yourself.
I don't turn down nothing
but my collar.
He's okay. Seldom?
Yeah come on.
I mean, I lost?
Wait but I got knocked out huh?
Shit.
I got knocked out.
You see me, you see, I'm alright.
I got knocked out and
I'm still here.
I got knocked out.
Get it Muhammad baby, strut girl,
strut your stuff.
Eugene, Eugene, Eugene, Eugene,
Eugene.
Oh yeah, oh Peaches.
Shit.
I got knocked out tonight.
Kicked as one night.
Got knocked out the next.
Come on brother, I got your
mother for you.
Come on sucker.
Look boy I'm tired of hearing about
how you got knocked out and how
you did this and that.
Ya ya ya, let's get
something straight.
You still my bitch boy.
You'll always be that, on Mars,
on Pluto,
on Earth, Heaven, Hell you
still my bitch.
And I better not catch your ass
standing at no toilet peeing either.
And you can forget about that truce
I made with the Lieutenant.
And your boy Too Sweet,
he's washed up.
Boy you better get
yourself together...
Or what?
You're gonna threaten me?
You're gonna kill me?
You gonna beat me up?
If I didn't learn nothing else
out ofjumping my
crazy ass up in that ring like
some depraved animal
I did learn one thing.
That you, Dead, Latney, nobody
can take anything
from me that I ain't ready to give.
And you got to bring ass to get ass.
And I done already got
knocked out once
so that ain't nothing new.
And furthermore I kicked a
little ass too.
Why you?
That's the last time you ever gonna
hit me and get away with it.
Your ass gotta sleep and you got
to turn your back.
You ain't worth it.
You ain't worth it, get
away from me.
Get away from me!
Lights out,
quiet on the block.
Seldom man do you hear me?
I mean this ain't no Mister Good
Bar I'm talking about.
This is some real live, hot, steamy,
hairy pussy.
So man, you ain't human.
I mean I'm talking about pussy
and here you are reading a book.
You been locked up for God
knows how long.
35 years.
That's right.
35 long years.
And 15 before that.
That's right I been in the pen 50
of the 65 years I been
on this Earth.
And I damn sure ain't
about to get myself
all worked up over no pussy
for a week contest.
Do you hear where I'm coming from?
Survival,
that's my first concern.
I faced myself a long time ago.
I'm nothing and I faced it.
35 years and I've learned
to be content.
I just deal with the me
that's in here.
I just lay back and relax and
keep my mind together.
'Cause I now believe that
I'm the one's free.
the freest man in the world.
The rest of the world is locked up.
They are locked out.
And Too Sweet once I quit
believing that
I might as well push a bunk up
against the wall,
tie a sheet around my
neck and jump off.
Or I'd go completely crazy.
They call that
institutionalized Too Sweet.
Institutionalized, and I'm it.
So keep your far fetched
dreams to yourself.
And if the Lieutenant and
his brother-in-law
by some miracle can convince the
board to turn you lose,
or is some young lady will come up
and lay you with you
for a week don't tell me
when you going.
Don't tell me when you coming back.
Don't bring no fucking drawers in
here for me to sniff.
Don't tell me a God damn thing.
'Cause if I can't have it all
I don't any of it.
Now I'm for real Too Sweet.
Already Daddy here go your girl.
Don't hit me on my ear no more.
You hit me on my ear again boy
I'll kill your ass.
Think I'm bullshitting, I
ain't bullshitting.
How's that?
That looks the nose to me, no ear.
Yeah let me tell you something
I wasn't jiving you about my ear.
Hit me on my ear again boy
I'll kick your...
No bro just because you ugly
don't mean you bad.
Besides I want the other
ear than that.
Awe shit.
You done done it now sucker.
No you done done it now.
What I told your crazy ass?
I told your ass boy.
Don't say I didn't tell your ass.
Yeah you hit me on my God
damn ear again huh?
One, two, three.
five, six, seven, eight.
Don't turn your bootie on me sucker.
What you doing to me you homosexual?
Break it, break this shit up.
One.
You ain't gonna never leave the
penitentiary alive.
You dead sucker.
Come here mama.
Oh yeah.
Too Sweet, Too Sweet,
Too Sweet,
Too Sweet, Too Sweet, Too Sweet,
Too Sweet.
Jesse man take these things off.
Oh but look here you beat
the count man.
I don't give a shit man.
That's the only thing I'm gonna
beat tonight besides my meat.
I said you beat the count Magilla.
Man this ain't my element Jesse man.
I'm gonna kill that
bastard and it ain't
gonna be with no boxing gloves.
Now take these things off me man!
I ain't no damn boxer!
You sure the hell ain't baby!
You need to sit your ass down!
Nah Magilla I ain't taking them off.
I ain't taking them off.
You want a fight I'll take him.
We'll take him anytime you
give it to him.
You damn right.
Kill Magilla.
Kill Magilla, kill
Magilla, kill Magilla,
kill Magilla, kill Magilla,
kill Magilla.
Hey your mama ain't cute!
Forget all a y'all.
Too Sweet.
Too Sweet, Too Sweet,
Too Sweet,
Too Sweet, Too Sweet, Too Sweet,
The winner of the first
connubial visit, Martel Gordone.
And do I have a beauty
picked out for you.
Hey Linda?
Yes?
You don't know who I am do you?
Yes.
You know who I am?
Yes, you're Martel Gordone.
And I know why they call
you Too Sweet.
You remember picking me up
on the highway?
You remember me
fighting to save you?
You remember me looking for you
when I got railroaded, got
this time, huh?
Yes I remember all of that.
God I wish I could forget.
Then what happened?
Why'd you run?
What difference does it make?
It makes a hell of a lot
of difference.
Too Sweet we got to live now.
Oh don't give me that
bullshit Linda.
Here I am doing time and I
don't even know why.
Why?
'Cause you're a man that's why.
And you fought like a man.
Oh Jesus.
After those bikers hit you and
you were out cold,
oh God I was there all alone and...
But nothing I could do.
There wasn't anything but...
And you just let them set me up,
and ran away.
Too Sweet,
I did what I had to do.
Oh please forgive me I'm sorry.
I'm sorry Too Sweet.
Let me make it up.
Let me make it up Sweet.
Too Sweet please.
I'm begging you please here.
Please somebody.
This is Linda.
Tell the Lieutenant he can
send in another one.
He's a good man, gonna be
a good fighter.
Yeah we'll see.
This is our control center.
There's your man now.
Gordone I was just
talking about you.
Come on that little chippy out
there in the trailer
too much for you to handle huh?
Yeah something like that.
Yeah Gordone, damn good
showing the other night.
But me and Henry here
have been talking.
We feel that you need
another year or so
to kind of polish up your style.
Fine.
Gordone, Sam has decided to go
with Amos this year.
Now it's nothing you can't overcome.
Especially with a little more
time with Hezzikia.
Fine Lieutenant.
Okay.
You got those passes cleared?
Yeah they're all cleared.
Alright you men can go
back to your cell.
Now look any more trouble
with this set,
I got a technician coming up for the
third time this week.
I want him to fix it
and fix it right.
How about that third set?
It's working right.
The camera in the
yard working right?
Pretty boy's here.
He make me sick with that bullshit.
Hey man hey.
I'd like to make this
move with y'all.
Now I gonna blow this
damn road check.
You get my meaning?
Shit Jesse you ain't said nothing.
You know I been waiting for you
to take the wraps off a long time.
This chump dies tonight.
Hey Carlos?
You coming tonight.
Hold the gate,
hold the gate.
Coming across the yard.
You got yours?
Hey Too Sweet man how
was that broad?
I told you man this ain't me man
this ain't me at all.
Shut up nigger.
If you gonna chump out leave now.
Back already huh Gordone?
She must have kicked you out of bed.
You die mother fucker.
Too Sweet, Too Sweet, Too Sweet,
come on.
Let it go, you don't need that.
Okay.
That a boy.
Too Sweet.
Somebody get a doctor.
Will somebody get a damn doctor?
I'm sorry brother man.
I kind of let you down
No you haven't let me down.
You haven't let anybody down.
You've won Eugene.
Eugene you've won.
Eugene you can't...
Too Sweet I know what
you're thinking.
But you ain't thinking at all.
You got a chance to get out
of this insanity.
Don't blow it.
Use your head and fight no more.
You.
You set this whole thing up.
And then like the coward you
are you stood back
and let your crazy fools do
your dirty work.
Well now I'm gonna show
you where it's at.
Seldom you call the Lieutenant
and you tell him if he wants rumble
we'll give him rumble.
Yeah.
I'm gonna kill you.
I'm gonna break your neck boy.
He's 50 pounds heavier than you so
stay away from him.
Alright you cover up that
left rib you hear me.
If you don't get
the joker I will.
Get him Jesse.
Get his ass Jesse.
Get off me!
Man looks
like Big Jesse
is really working on Too
Sweet tonight.
Yeah looks like his
rib might be crushed.
Nah Seldom, this is
where you dig man.
Right on Too Sweet.
Too Sweet, Too Sweet,
Too Sweet, Too Sweet, Too Sweet,
Too Sweet,
Too Sweet.
You got it, you've worked for it.
Too Sweet, Too Sweet,
Too Sweet, Too Sweet, Too Sweet,
Too Sweet,
But I know you're gonna
be a champion.
Yeah baby you're the greatest,
you're the greatest.
Got to sign
for this money.
You got it my man.
I want to wish
you good luck man.
Good news Gordone.
I got a memo this morning
from the parole board
and it stated that if Jackson shows
a sincere desire to get out of here
and function in society he'll be
by your side training
you if he wants.
Hey Lieutenant that's really decent.
The way it should be.
Lieutenant.
Yeah.
Here's Jackson.
Okay.
Now look by the way I want you to
really whip ass for my
brother-in-law.
I want you to make him
a lot of money
so that he'll get my sister and his
ass out of my house.
I'll do best.
Don't let me down.
Now look I know you two
want to be together
so why don't you take a
couple of minutes
outside the gate here and say
your goodbyes, okay.
Guard open up the gate.
Okay it's all yours.
Now is there something you
want to see me about?
You know don't you?
You know I'm afraid?
I'm afraid of streets.
When I first went to jail TV was
just begun to be talked about.
The jet age wasn't even
thought about.
Now it just scares me to think about
going back out there and
being a nobody.
What can I do?
Who wants me?
Who even would pay attention to
an old out of date fool like me?
In here I am somebody.
I got my own TV, my own stereo,
my own home, three hots and a cot.
And more than that I mean
something in here.
I got respect.
There's only one thing wrong Seldom.
You ain't got no hope.
Seldom we could make out there man.
Me and you, we could do it.
You got to at least try.
Okay?
Okay.
Okay Gordone let's go.
What do we got to do get a writ
to get your ass out of this place?
No sir all you gotta do is
open up those gates.
Okay guard.
Seldom, I'll see you soon.
Bye Too.