Declare all valuables to Customs.
Items undeclared will be
confiscated plus a 1000% fine.
Fei-hung, declare the
ginseng to Customs.
Dad, we've to pay at least
a duty of 50 yuan.
- Here.
- Right.
Let's pass by hiding
it inside our pants.
They won't search him,
taking it for hernia only.
The idea...
- Outrageous, outrageous!
- It won't work.
You've got nothing but lousy ideas.
The Northern Army has imposed
heavy duties. That's most unfair.
Nothing in this world is fair.
One traveling must avoid
as much as possible.
Declare it.
- What's going on?
- Who's he?
Don't you know British
Consul is privileged?
You don't pay duties if
you become a Consul.
He's lucky.
- What the hell are you up to?
- He was knocked down.
Please, sir, I apologize.
Why have you given away
such a big ginseng?
To avoid tax!
I'll get it back in a minute.
- Let me have another fall then.
- What?
By putting everything in,
I don't have to pay tax.
What's wrong with him.
Epilepsy. Tso, get up!
File in!
- Dad, I'll pay tax in front.
- Take care.
Catch it, master.
Good, there they are.
Easy, easy.
Be careful. You'll crush everything.
That's good.
Hold it.
Fei-hung!
Fei-hung, don't chase him!
Fei-hung, remember what I've taught you.
You can't win over a local boy.
Don't chase a desperate
thief, understand?
But he's stole your money.
Forget it, as there's no loss.
Remember, the important
thing in life is...
Forgive while you can.
- Remember it.
- I forgot.
Checkmate!
Again.
A man shouldn't renege.
- How should I move now?
- Try it again.
Think, think it over.
Dad, look, many trees.
That tree's big!
Already gone.
Come on.
Can I concede the loss?
- Use your brains.
- What? Can't move now.
Ready? Catch!
Are you okay?
I'll take care of it.
I'm sorry, sir.
Young man, be careful in playing ball.
Thank you.
- Have you thought it over?
- Come on.
What's this?
It's called cheating.
Dad, you don't like this. Let me go
down to buy roast chicken for you.
Just wait. A vendor
will come in a minute.
No, we must go down to get
a nice roast chicken.
Right, right.
You yearn for a chance to move around.
Why make an excuse?
- Go then.
- Go, go.
Hey!
You two stay out of trouble!
Be sure to come right back!
God, do you believe
the smell of this place?
I think I'm gonna be sick.
Hey!
It's like another world.
I like it.
This is first class.
The number of foreigners speaks for it.
What are you doing?
Looking for a friend.
- Could you possibly have friends here?
- Yeah, yeah, we do.
Yes.
- You mustn't go in anyway.
- Can't we just have a look?
No. Go away!
One more time,
and you're off the train.
- Master, what now?
- I got an idea.
- Master, the next step?
- Just watch me.
Go!
They've gone wild!
Get him!
Sorry.
Hey!
I'm sure I saw him come this way.
Hey, stop!
Halt!
Wait. Why you hit--?
Traitor.
What?
Next time, I cut your throat.
Traitor.
Hey, don't run. Listen!
First, I'm not a traitor. Second...
- I've already conceded to you.
- Who cares? I won't lose.
You mule, what do you want?
Simple, just apologize to me.
Apologize to you?
How dare you call me a traitor.
Okay. Sorry.
And let me box you on the ear.
Ducking? Again.
You must be kidding me.
Let's make this fair.
- Ready?
- Ready!
Drunken boxing.
Sure, you think I'm getting dizzy?
OK, come on.
- Come on.
Come on.
Well, wait till you get sober first.
I show you! Tiger slash at bear!
What do you call that one?
It's called "Turtle holding wine barrel."
Fairies Littering Petals.
Eagle grabs the rabbit!
Drunk plays the flute?
And this one?
Nursing a hangover.
Okay.
Don't worry, stand up.
Your Kung Fu is pretty good.
Young man, you're not too bad yourself,
but that drunken boxing was...
faultless?
Basically, it's slow,
and you have no power.
It's pathetic.
What?
I can defeat any Kung Fu.
I show you power.
You're running out of time.
I'm young and strong.
I've lots of time.
The train's leaving.
Nice try, old man,
but now you're going to get it.
Come back here!
The train!
Wait for me!
Come on, give me your hand.
Thank you.
Get what you were after?
Ginseng?
Get up, all of you!
Gather your luggage for inspection.
Hurry up! Move!
Everyone, now. Come on.
You. Wake up.
Good morning.
What are you doing?
Something has been stolen,
so everyone has to be searched.
Guard.
Search them.
Open your luggage, be quick!
Hurry up.
- What's this?
- Lingtzu.
Bear gall.
What's that? Show me.
- Open that.
- This one?
What's that?
- Fried yak.
- Okay, next.
Now the other box. Come on.
That box...
Not that. That.
Let me see that one.
- Not that one.
- That box?
- Which one?
- On the seat between you.
Now!
He means the ginseng.
He wasn't hiding it.
Open it.
Open that box!
They're clearly physicians from Hunan.
Why don't you give them a break, huh?
Who are you?
Show me your papers.
Sir, my apologies.
He's with Counterintelligence.
He's with the central government.
Better not challenge his authority.
Check the next compartment.
- Search up there.
- Next car.
This young man's quite capable.
Fei-hung, follow his example.
Put aside the ginseng.
You said the jade seal's missing?
The Emperor's jade seal is like
the crown of England. Understand?
Everything combined here is not as valuable.
The British Empire's premier is my friend.
I promised to put the jade
seal symbolizing the power
of Chinese Emperor into
the London Museum of Art.
I don't care how you do it.
I want it back.
Sir, I know who's taken it.
Find him!
John,
The workers at the steel factory
refuse to work at night.
Anything you can do about it?
Don't worry.
I know just what to do in this situation.
I promise you'll have no more trouble.
Go then.
Ancestors be blessed.
All of a kind!
Thank you, Patriarch.
Let's go, let's go.
Come on, come on, pay up.
Quickly. We haven't got all day.
For treatment tell him
to see Luk-Ah-choi.
Come on.
My luck's beat you all.
One make leads to a series of others.
She wins every time.
Madam?
Master's back.
Good, why fuss?
Master's back!
Master.
What's taken you so long?
I didn't hear you from inside.
Master, you're back.
Any hardship on the journey?
No, no.
Mother, no mahjong?
Nonsense!
I told you repeatedly not
to treat when I am out.
Master, you preached a
doctor's parental love too.
I couldn't stand by doing
nothing about a dying person.
If I did, you'd blame me.
Have they lost much?
Yes.
Perhaps I should examine them.
It's a female problem.
I can handle it.
Fei Hung, would you
prepare my altar for me?
Wash your hands before you do it.
Don't laugh.
- Get a ladder for him to do it.
- Yes.
- Did you water the plants regularly?
- Yes, master.
Mother.
The chips.
Fei-hung.
- What was that?
- I didn't hear anything.
The altar.
Get up. Go now, go.
- This is mine.
- It's mine, it's on my chair!
What are you doing?
Behave yourself.
Remember to come again for treatment.
- Mr. Chan.
- Madam Wong.
- Is Master Wong back?
- Yes, he's inside.
Any news about my ginseng?
Did he get it?
He must've got it. This way, please.
Master, Mr. Chan's here to get the ginseng.
Mr. Chan, you've come...
To get the ginseng?
What are you doing?
- I'm going in to get the ginseng.
- Yes. Go quick.
Mr. Chan, I've bought you a big ginseng.
Sit a while. Let's chat
after I've serve incense.
Sorry for the trouble.
Mr. Chan, let me bring
you a cup of tea.
Good, thank you.
Where're you going?
If master knows the ginseng's lost,
I'll be finished.
- You won't.
- Fei Hung.
- What are you two doing?
- Step-mom, come here.
We're finished.
We're in such trouble.
The ginseng was replaced on the train.
Tso, you're finished.
Look. Step-mom, what shall we do now?
Do something.
Fei Hung!
Coming!
Go and get a cup
of tea for Mr. Chan.
- Go! I'll think of something.
- What? I'll leave it up to you two.
He gets the tea. What about me?
Okay, you see what's behind me?
- A staircase.
- And above the stairs?
- The medicine storehouse.
- And inside the storehouse?
- A box.
- And inside it?
Another ginseng. I can't believe it!
It's poison.
- What for?
- For you.
Oh, no, madam,
please don't tease me this way!
Who's teasing?
- I have your tea, Mr. Chan.
- Thank you.
Enjoy.
Father, you must be very hot.
Let me help you.
Mr. Chan.
- You...
- It's real.
A rare genus of super quality
appears only once in a blue moon.
Just put it in boiling water. After taking it,
you're assured of potency and youth.
Why have you brought a carrot?
What?
This is a carrot?
You mean it isn't ginseng?
No.
Of course it isn't ginseng.
What I meant to tell you was that
you should stay away from carrots,
especially big ones like this one,
while you're taking ginseng.
Don't take it within three months
after taking ginseng. Understand?
Excuse me.
Mr. Chan,
I'm glad she remembered
to tell you about that.
You know, most people don't realize
that when you use ginseng...
you should avoid the use of carrots,
because they're not a good mix.
Why doesn't it look like it?
- I didn't see it.
- Nor did I.
I didn't see it either.
Fei-hung, what are you doing?
- Good luck, now.
- Step-mom, does it look like it?
Oh, yeah, it looks just like it.
Where did you find it?
Father's bonsai tree.
What a great idea.
Just blame it on Tso.
Okay.
I'll try to keep your father distracted.
What do you think of this?
- Boy, that looks great.
- Of course.
Excuse me. May I have a word?
Just a second.
Of course.
- What is it, dear?
- Come on, come over.
- Why are you acting so furtively?
- I want to consult you on something.
Fei-hung's grown now,
he must be lonesome.
- What then?
- Do you feel that...
Mr. Chan, your ginseng.
Still wet?
Just unearthed, Mr. Chan.
My dad got it hard.
He said it's wild ginseng.
It's to be taken only after being put
in a rice container for three days.
- To bring him a small brother or sister?
- No hurry, let's talk about it later.
Why not? Your master Lu
Ah-choi's birthday is coming.
It's just passed.
He'll have his birthday
again next year.
- Honey, not now. Mr. Chan--
- No, no. We're not finished.
Okay. Roll it up tight to keep it nice
and fresh and close to your heart.
Remember what I told you.
And don't forget tomorrows
fund-raising assembly.
Master Wong.
- I must take my leave.
- Have you seen the ginseng?
Just fine. I'll keep it inside.
- Let me see you out.
- Let Fei Hung do it.
- Mrs. Wong, bye-bye.
- I can show you. Please, this way.
- Goodbye.
- Take care.
The Militia want you to be their coach.
They ask if you're interested.
- I've already given them my answer.
- I know you did.
Step-mom. Mr. Chan has left.
What do you want to tell me?
I need your advice.
Are we to ask for a 30-years
deposit in advance?
Forget it. You're tired.
Talk about it tomorrow.
- Yes, Father. Please go in and retire.
- How long am I going to live?
Frankly, if they do pay
you a 30-year deposit,
that's a good thing.
Hey, why do you make that look?
Because I'm afraid he'll find the tree.
Don't be silly. Throw the pot away.
- One more thing.
- What's it?
What happens when Mr. Chan drinks
the tea made from those roots?
Let's wait till he is sick.
Wish he could really
wait for three days.
All right, that's it for me.
See you tomorrow.
Deliver the coffee
before ringing the bell.
Fo Sang, my stove's going out. Stoke it.
Just a minute.
Stand back.
That was great. Thanks for the light.
It's almost quitting time.
After this, I ought to.
Off now.
Hey!
Get them back to work.
- But why?
- Go!
I'm the new foreman.
Now ring the bell.
Go on.
Hey, Fo Sang,
what the hell you doing now?
- Yeah, what are you, out of your mind?
- Yeah!
He is...
The new foreman told me to do it.
The new foreman?
Well,
we seem to have fallen
behind this month,
so everybody works the
night shift for one month.
What? One month?
Hey, guys, hold on.
So, let's say we work all
those overtime hours for you,
then we need overtime pay.
Quiet.
You give us no choice.
You either work the overtime,
or we close the steel mill down,
and you'll all be without jobs.
Now, you can take it or leave it.
Mr. Smith, you can't
blackmail us anymore.
We worked hard for you, and now
we've had enough! We quit!
Hey! Hold it!
Nobody is to leave.
You'll stay and work.
Do you understand that?
You can take my job,
but you can't run my life!
You think you can make us?
Who you think you are? Let's go!
- Don't move!
- You're in our way!
Back to work, you hear me?
That's enough!
Keung!
Everyone up! Back to work!
Henry, you're great!
You see? He's very persuasive.
They have to work.
You go on with practice.
It's bloody impossible
to sleep with all this noise.
Why don't we just buy it
and have it bulldozed?
The land is owned by Po Chi Lam gym.
He just won't sell.
Damn it! I must get rid of him!
Yes, sir.
Fun, are you tired working alone?
Why not let someone help you?
Don't you agree?
Getting help, huh?
No woman dares to kill snakes like I do.
And I can't afford to
pay wages to a man.
So I prefer to be alone.
Right you are.
But seriously now, Fun,
But a woman may suffer
without the care of a man.
Hey, Fun, why not let me teach you
Kung Fu to protect yourself?
How about drunken boxing?
What good is it? It can't fight.
Come to Sha Min tonight and I'll
teach you Tsai Li Fu boxing!
I prefer drunken boxing.
What you looking at?
Get back to work.
How much you want?
We've got customers waiting.
They need the help now.
Drunken boxing beat Tsai Li Fu?
Nonsense!
Hey, Master Tsang.
Wong Fei-hung?
A fillet of salmon and a
pound of fish maw, okay?
Which half?
Snake gall good for the eyes,
suits elderly persons best.
- Hey, Fun...
- boil snake soup...
Fei Hung! Hi!
Oh, it's getting away.
- Never mind. What can I get you?
- Three snake galls and one pheasant.
I've already reserved them for you.
Thank you.
Which half do you want?
It makes no difference.
Fei-hung, I hear your
drunken boxing is the best.
Thank you.
Would you be able to teach me?
Of course.
Hey!
I won't mince fish today.
I'll do it at home myself.
How about later with that?
We're discussing drunken boxing.
Fei Hung, when will you
teach me drunken boxing?
What good is drunken boxing?
It's so sissy.
Wong Fei-hung, you've spoken the truth.
Why don't you ask Tsan
to teach you Tsai Li Fu?
What good is your Tsai Li Fu?
At least it's better
than drunken boxing?
Never mind him, Fei-hung.
When will you teach
me drunken boxing?
Fun, don't you prefer
Tsai Li Fu to drunken boxing?
Pupils, don't you agree?
- Yes.
- Sure.
It depends on who's the master.
What do you say to
a challenge, then?
Out of my way.
Wong Fei-hung, if I lose, I'll pay for
the fish and fish head you bought today.
- Tsan, isn't that a deal?
- Yes, it's a deal!
Master Tsan, I'm afraid
I may hurt the passers-by.
Let them be the witness then.
Attention, everybody!
I, fishmonger Tsan, will have a fight
with Wong Fei-hung. Be our witness.
Come on.
Don't worry, just a token fight.
Go ahead.
Why don't you use drunken boxing?
Good! Great, Fei-hung, you've won.
No, I drew with Master Tsan.
I think Tsang Sang would agree.
It's not over yet!
Coming. Step-mom wants me.
Excuse me. My Step-mom wants me.
Fei Hung!
Your fish.
- What do I owe you?
- It my treat.
Thank you.
All right now. It's a draw.
Buy anything you want. Go.
Getting your food free?
Didn't you fight?
No.
You may get the hell from
dad again if you did.
How can we afford
to replace the ginseng?
Just sell my diamond
necklace from your dad.
- No way.
- Why not?
We'll be in big trouble if Mr. Chan
decides to brew that tree root.
- You would do that?
- Just remember, you owe me one.
He's the man we're looking for.
Stay close to him while I go
and get the boss, okay?
Yes, sir.
Wong Kei-ying sells his wife's
jewelry only in emergency.
- Try to cut down the price, understand?
- Look, I'm late already.
- I'll see you later.
-  Let's go, okay?
Is the drought so serious?
The province is known for infertility.
There's no harvest and no rainfall.
How can it not be serious?
My friend told me one whole family
there shares one pair of pants only.
Who wears it then?
If you have to go outside,
you wear the pants.
Hello. Sorry I'm late.
- It's all right. How are you?
- Good to see you.
Fei Hung, don't you think
we should be going?
Aren't you meeting my wife for tea?
Oh, no, not mahjongg again.
How can you say that?
It's our fund-raising meeting,
and you were supposed to remind me.
Oh, I forgot. I'll try to
get a donation from Tsan.
Go quick, don't keep them waiting.
- Of course. You're right.
- Nice talking to you.
Don't arouse trouble.
I won't.
Get the others.
It's been called to our attention
that Master Wong needs us
to lend him some money.
Good. This...
Since Po Chi Lam's in trouble, we must
answer Master Wong's request for donation.
Please don't misunderstand.
The donation is not for Po Chi Lam.
It's for the relief of draught victims.
The donation goes to whoever's in trouble.
We're all Chinese, right?
- Nothing right now.
- Okay.
You better not have said anything,
you understand?
- I won't say a word.
- I won't tell a soul.
- Besides, she's the one that talks a lot.
- Like you don't?
How dare you say that?
I only told my sister--
Chiu doesn't even know I came here.
Ladies, somebody has been talking.
They always lie to me.
Look at their faces.
- Now, that's enough.
- Can't we just take a look?
- Let's see.
- There.
It's beautiful!
Oh, don't handle it like that.
And I'm only borrowing the money.
You're going to have to give it back to me.
I know, I know. I understand.
Come on. Show it to us.
Here.
So did you get it?
No. I haven't actually seen it,
but I'm sure they have it.
Well, we can't waste any more time.
Grab the seal,
and we'll meet you out front.
Okay.
Okay, grab it, and I'll see you outside.
- Listen, don't wear it to show off.
- Don't worry, I'll enjoy it at home only.
- What's wrong?
- Thief!
You've got to learn to speak up.
Thief! Thief!
Wait here.
Leave it.
Fei-hung, over there.
You better run.
Fei-hung, great, you've got it back!
My dear son!
- Hey, Fei Hung.
- Fat, hello.
Great!
- What's this?
- You bumped me.
Sorry.
Sorry's not good enough.
- What do you want then?
- Kneel down and kowtow to say 'sorry'.
- What? You're crazy.
- Hold it!
You were in on it.
I saw the whole thing.
Mind your own business, bitch.
Who you calling bitch?
You couldn't escape our attention.
You exchanged eyes with that man.
You look wretched
even in a foreign suit.
Wait--!
Step-mom, are you all right?
I want this guy's ass!
Step-mom, you'll be okay.
She wants to fight?
We'll take on both of you.
What? You're going to start this again?
- What'd you say?
- I said, kick his ass!
- You want me to go kick--
- You will, or I will.
- What happened to your mouth?
- I'm all right.
The necklace is inside.
It's going to be ruined!
Fei Hung! Throw it over here!
Catch!
- Where'd he learn to do that?
- Oh, look at that!
Po Chi Lam.
- His drunken boxing is terrific.
- It's a superb!
How's drunken boxing? Show me.
Ask him!
All right.
Whatever you want. Fei Hung!
Fei-hung, teach them a
lesson with drunken boxing.
- What about Father?
- I'll take care of him.
Besides, it will be great
publicity for the school.
- Your dad will be happy.
- Okay.
Drunken boxing!
What the hell's wrong with you?
The four of you can't beat one man?
Get him!
- Is this drunken boxing?
- I think so.
- Not bad.
- Excellent!
- Not too powerful.
- Just so-so.
Hey, you don't understand.
Come on.
- Hold it quick!
- Take as much as you can carry.
Hey, who's going to pay for that?
- Charge it to Mrs. Wong's account.
- All right, then.
- They're fighting over there.
- Go over quick!
- Hey, where'd they go?
- Over there, I think.
- I'm going to call the police.
- Don't call the police.
Fei-hung, catch!
Dad won't let me drink!
I will. You're finished if you're
beaten and your gym ruined.
Here you go, white wine, red wine.
- Can your son drink it adult rated?
- why not? It adds to the strength.
Are you all right?
One more drink would be helpful.
A little bit. Give it to me. Catch!
Get up!
What the hell was that?
What does it mean when
there's a picture of a skull?
Good wine!
Lu Tung Pin, Drinking Gives
Herculean Strength.
Gripple Li, Elbow Whirl and Knees Hit.
Old Han, Holding Jar with Drunken gait.
White tiger washes face.
Fairies Serve Wine, Choking the Throat.
Get him!
Chang Kuo Lao, Drunken, Throwing cup
and kicking Continuously.
Lan Tsai Ho, Serving Wine on One Foot.
Grasping Wrist.
Attacking Chest,
Playing Flute Drunken.
This is Angel Ho.
Serving Wine with Swaying
Wait & Drunken Gait.
Twist, twist, I twist.
- And this one?
- Angel Pisses.
- It's called what?
- Just watch.
Uncle Tsao stirs the barrel.
Drinking Removes Myriads of Woes.
Come back!
- He can't even stand up straight!
- Find some more wine.
Of course.
- Doctor Wong!
- What's going on here?
Those men are attacking Fei Hung!
Hold this. Fei Hung!
- Fei Hung!
- God on Birthday Celebration!
Oh, no!
Have you been drinking?
You stop it right now!
- I'm your father!
- Father?
You have the cutest little nose.
Great father and son.
- How are you, Dad?
- Fighting again!
Fighting?
- What's going on?
- You should come earlier.
Fei-hung fought brilliantly.
The thugs snatched Fa's diamond
necklace from Mrs. Wong.
With the little money from you,
I couldn't buy it.
Why did you sell the diamond necklace?
Master, why hide Po Chi
Lam's financial trouble?
Why raise funds under
the pretext of relief?
Po Chi Lam doesn't need money.
You can take charge
of the funds we raised.
Stop drinking!
Mrs. Wong.
I said stop it!
- Master Wong, let's help him back.
- Step-mom, fetch me another bottle.
- Let me help you.
Why are you standing there?
- Go home.
- Yes, master.
- Do as he says. All right.
- Let's go.
See you.
Where's he going?
Go on. Follow him!
Losers.
You didn't do any better.
You meant to tell on me?
You meant to tarnish our image.
You brat! Now everybody thought I raise
money under the pretext of relief!
Are you broke?
You're even selling my jewelry.
Who's selling it?
I showed it to Fa as an example only
because she likes the pattern.
Don't lie to me!
Mr. Chiu's wife asked him
for money to buy it.
How much did you
lose playing mahjongg?
Fa could've lied to her
husband to get the money.
Besides, who are you going
to believe, them or me?
Step-mom, I believe you.
Be on your knees properly!
See how drunk you are! Kneel properly!
I told you not to drink, fight
or use drunken boxing.
You even fought with me!
I'll kill you.
Wait! Wait! Stop hitting him.
He was just defending me!
They tried to break my jaw.
I guess that's something
you don't care about.
Damn you, woman!
It was forbidden!
They could have killed him.
Don't you care about that?
Oh, sure. Like it matters.
You're beating him worse
than those guys ever did.
You're driving me insane!
I can't believe this!
What has happened to my
300-year-old bonsai?
Damn it! I forgot to throw it out!
Tso!
You're responsible.
Well...,
Why fuss over such a trifles?
Why get so excited?
I ruined the plant.
I sold the necklace because
I lost in gambling.
And I forced Fei-hung to use drunken boxing.
And I made him drink as he did.
Curse me! Kill me,
I asked for it! Oh well!
I've had enough, Ling.
I am so sick and tired
of your deception!
If you're going to hit me, just go on.
Don't think I daren't lay hands on you!
That's not gonna work this time!
You better hit me so I won't
cause you any more trouble.
You're driving me out of my mind!
Hit me then! Or better yet, kill me!
One body with two lives!
What?
Are you pregnant?
We're going to have a baby?
- Get up.
- No!
You told me to kneel.
So I kneel, kneel.
Well, I'm sorry, all my fault!
Great, I'm going to
have a small brother!
- Get up, come on!
- Leave me alone! Keep away!
- I crouch!
- Watch out!
Don't!
- Then put me down!
- Okay.
I hate you! I'll back-somersault!
- Don't!
- Put me down!
- It's all my fault!
- I'll spin one full circle.
Calm down, it was all my fault!
Tso, get a chair for madam!
I'm begging you, please sit down!
Sorry!
I'm so sorry.
- You tripped me.
- It was an accident.
You did it on purpose.
- Is the baby all right?
- Stop it!
- It's fine.
- Oh thank God!
Master Wong,
Mrs. Chan wants to see
you on urgent business.
I'll be right back.
Dad's OK, he's as sophisticated as ever.
Nonsense!
- Master Wong.
- Mrs. Chan, it's such a pleasure.
Master Wong, look.
This is not ginseng.
I showed it to another doctor
and he says it's poisonous.
Now, I'm not sure where you got it,
but you've surely been misled.
It has made my husband deathly ill.
Thank God he only brewed half of it.
You owe me, and you're going to have
to take the blame for this mess.
Now!
Forgive me. Uncle Ho,
get the snake extract.
I can assure you he will
recover if you give him this.
Master Wong, this is wonderful.
I promise I won't tell anyone.
- It must have been a mistake.
- You're kind.
Goodbye.
Who did it?!
What's this?
He did it!
Not my fault.
How could you do such a thing?
Are you out of your mind?
You are destroying my reputation!
Hey, Mother.
He dropped his bonsai tree.
I'll kill you!
Wait!
Just listen! He lost it on the
train and couldn't get it back!
Oh, shit. What am I saying?
He was trying to save you some tax.
He hid the ginseng in someone
else's luggage and it got lost.
To evade tax for me? Outrageous!
I may be poor, but I'm honest.
Dishonesty is worst than starvation.
How could I have raised
such a deceitful bastard!
You want to drink?
I'll let you drink it now.
Drink it, drink it like hell, come on!
Come on, drink!
Drink it like hell!
How dare you fight back?
I've brought you up for nothing.
Get out of my sight!
You're not my son!
Get out! Get out of here!
Stop it! That's enough!
You're going to kill him!
Fei-hung.
Fei Hung! Fei Hung!
- Get out! You're not my son!
- Stop it!
Master, stop it, please!
Master, don't.
Up! Get out of here!
That was self-defense!
He didn't mean to do it!
Get out!
Fei Hung!
Tso, after him!
Tso!
That way.
Catch.
- Boss, here you are.
- Thank you.
- Hello. Beer, please.
- Yes, sir. Very good, sir.
Fei-hung, your dad
wouldn't let you loose,
this is to protect the
image of Po Chi Lam.
I see a generation gap.
Let me toast dad.
Drink!
No way. That's it for tonight.
I'm cutting you off.
Excuse me, miss?
I want a song here.
Something I should sing?
"The Ocean's Crying,"
but I'll sing it myself.
The Ocean's Crying.
Okay.
I am so sad now.
I was so happy and now...
I'm all alone with no home...
What can I do?
If not for the wine...
I'd be hurting all the time
If only I could go home...
Father, listen to me now...
What can I do to make it up...
To make you proud...
A pity I never know...
I only tried to help...
Why did you--
- Why did you--
- Look, it's that guy.
He doesn't look so tough.
Oh, yes, his drunken boxing is terrific.
Well, let's just see about this.
I still love you... No matter what you--
Party's over. I suggest you go.
Hey! What are you doing?!
Stand back, or you'll regret it!
- The rest of you, leave!
- Come on.
Get out!
- Yeah. You gotta leave. Go on. Move!
- Keep away!
What happened to the music?
Are you the drunken boxer?
Dad won't let me fight.
He's just faking.
What's going on?
What's the matter with him?
Fei-hung?
- Out of my way! What are you doing?
- Hold it!
It's none of your business!
Get rid of him! Keep him away!
What's going on?
Is this some kind of joke?
No, no! He wasn't like that earlier.
He couldn't be stopped. Ask anyone.
Why you kick me?
Look at you.
Get up and fight me! Come on!
You call that drunken boxing?
Kill him! Go! Go on!
Wait.
There are too many witnesses,
just teach him a lesson.
"King of Drunken Boxing"?\N\N\N
- I know who that is.\N\N\N
- I know who that is.
- He's hurt bad.
Wong Fei-hung.\N\N\N
Master Wong, over here.\N\N\N
Fei Hung!
I hear his father is
a drunk as well.
What did you say?
Don't be ashamed. When we were children,
we ran around naked as well.
If I had found you sooner,
this might not have happened!
Young master, don't be sad.
I have some good news for you.
Every woman in town
wants to marry you.
Are you happy now?
Don't cry. Come on, wipe your face.
Father--
In the garden.
Fei-hung never forgets he once
won with drunken boxing.
I've my reason for not
letting him use it.
There's nothing wrong
with drunken boxing.
You have to drink for it to work,
and you may become too drunk.
Let alone fighting, you lose stability.
He get into trouble because of this.
Don't drink so much then.
No, he must drink a proper portion,
before it becomes effective.
He gets powerful but feels
no pain when beaten.
So it gives the illusion
of being powerful.
A drinker knows he can't stop drinking.
Is it worth being a
drunkard to use this style?
"Boats can float on water,"
or so it says,
"but they can sink in it, too."
Now, that's really profound...
but I have only a question.
What?
Whose boat are we talking about?
How much drink is a proper portion?
How do boats float on water,
but sink in it, too?
I won't drink any more.
I'm glad to see that you're okay now.
Come on, let's get up and thank your
friends here for helping you. Go on.
- How's the baby today?
- Don't touch him. He's asleep.
Yes, yes.
Come again for treatment tomorrow.
- Does Wong Fei-hung live here?
- What if he does?
- Is he here?
- He might be. What for?
I can't tell you.
Did those men send you here?
What was that for?
- Keep your distance.
- I want you to leave.
I'm warning you.
Have you had enough?
You dare hit my Step-mom?
Fei-hung, let me help you.
He attacked me.
Father, help!
Beat him!
- Fei Hung, are you hurt?
- I feigned only to make dad fight.
Fei Hung, who is that?
Hold it!
- Hey!
- We have you surrounded!
I'm talking to you.
He's talking to you.
Me? Okay.
I'm Wong Kei-Ying. And you?
You're the coach of the Militia.
I'm Fu Wen-chi.
Fu Wen-chi?
- Father knows him?
- It looks that way.
Our most decorated Manchu officer.
It's nice seeing you. It's an honor.
- Please.
- Okay.
I guess that man is someone important.
Trust me, if he was important,
he wouldn't be hitting women, would he?
Think about it.
What?
Such a mess.
Look in the parlor when you're done.
- Fei-hung, have you found it?
- No.
Where could it be?
Tso might know!
What are you doing?
It's hot tonight.
I'm keeping cool over here.
She's quite a handful.
- Where did you put it?
- What?
What's this?
I don't know.
- Is it the one I brought back?
- I don't know.
I've found it!
Hey, I'm not finished with that.
Mr. Fu, you came from Beijing to Canton,
and got back the jade seal.
Yes, the jade seal is a
Chinese Royal emblem.
Tell me something,
there must be a hundred
jade seals in our museums.
Why is this one so special?
If you tolerate the plunder
of a jade seal now,
tomorrow he may...
...pull down the Great Wall.
Then our children will have to go
aboard to see Chinese treasure.
Don't you know why the
Allies invaded Beijing?
To seize the large territory of China.
Would they restrain themselves
if you don't collect yourself?
It's but natural that might wins.
You won't win respect without spines.
Anyone gets bulled if he
bullies himself, understand?
I do. Thanks for your guidance, sir.
Drink.
It's awfully quiet all of a sudden.
Right. They left without saying a word.
Let me go and see if Tsan has come.
Where's everybody in the street?
Kill them!
- What do we do?
- Fei-hung, follow me.
I'll lead!
Get him!
Fei-hung, grasp it.
Let's go!
How's the situation?
No problem.
When you hire the Ax Gang,
you're sure to get the job done.
That's what we're paying for.
Fei Hung, here!
Fei Hung!
Oh, my God! No!
Undress.
Undress now!
Okay!
Catch!
Run!
- What's going on?
- Don't get involved.
- Get on out of here.
- Now. Go on.
Sir!
Fu Wen-chi!
- Sir!
Try to stop the bleeding.
Sir!
The jade seal...
- Don't worry, I'll get it back for you.
- We'll get it back for sure.
Forget it. You can't beat them.
I'll help you back to Po Chi Lam.
My dad will treat you.
Don't die. He'll help you for sure.
Master!
Master--
What are you thinking?
Nothing!
- Tsan?
- Fei Hung?
What are you doing here?
Same for you!
- So where's the seal?
- How should I know? Come
Here.
Hey, did you bring a light?
- Yes.
- Light it quick!
Welcome.
You want to get back this.
You really are too naive.
I've already taken photos of you.
Intrusion into a consulate
means invasion.
I can punish you any way I like.
Kill us if you've the guts.
Good.
Do you understand what I said?
Yes, sir.
Things have worked out rather well
now that we have the jade seal back
and a way to acquire Po Chi Lam.
Right.
Po Chi Lam has been in power
for too long. Now it's our turn.
Send someone to Po Chi Lam,
and tell him his son sneaked
into our consulate illegally...
and see what he says.
If he doesn't agrees to
sell the land to us cheap,
we'll execute the both of them.
Damn those boys!
Don't they understand
there's nothing we can do?
As an embassy,
they're exempt from the laws of China.
- Maybe we can reason with them. I'll go.
- Sit down!
You know what they want,
the rights to Po Chi Lam!
They just wanted to return the seal.
They aren't the criminals.
This is all your fault!
- You disowned him!
- You spoiled him!
You're impossible.
And you're his father.
We're running out of time.
We've got to do something.
- You're right.
- I refuse.
How can I?
You know this land has been
in our family for centuries.
There has always been a school here.
What would you do, just give it up?
I'll never do it.
Oh, really?
If you won't help your son,
I'll beg his mother to.
Sister, I need your wisdom
more than ever.
Please show me your divine powers.
Can you help us?
Release them.
You okay? Just go on.
Master Wong.
- Step-mom.
- Just look at you.
I'm gonna be all right.
- Auntie.
- Master, are you all right?
Some bruises, but I'll be fine.
- Master, where are we moving to?
- What do you mean?
Master Wong has sold
the school to the embassy.
He did what?!
What has dad done?
To help you, Master Wong did it.
He had to sell the land cheap to the
consulate or you'd both be dead.
Fei Hung, this fight is over.
We can't do this anymore.
I hope you know your father
has sacrificed everything.
I regret not having taken dad's advice.
It's not too late for you to repent now.
Life's changes are like a moving river.
What's here today is gone tomorrow...
and tomorrow brings a whole new journey.
Let's move forward and live.
So when will the ship be leaving?
In 10 days.
Have you completed production?
Yes, sir. Ready and waiting, sir.
Good. Close the factory for the
time being and lay off the workers.
After the shipment leaves,
find cheaper workers.
Yes.
First we work overtime!
We refuse, then they beat us!
And now they think they can
just fire all of us just like that!
So are you guys going to
let him get away with that?
What do you say, huh?
Tsan, what happened?
They closed the mill,
and you know what?
The English ambassador who had
us beaten is also the foreman.
Right.
Tsan, forget it.
The less trouble the better.
Oh, sure. You didn't lose your job.
Well, I'm not gonna
let them push us around.
Yeah. As soon as they
finished the last shipment,
they fired all the men.
How could the factory
have suddenly closed?
I've lately found they've
been acting furtively.
They must be up to no good.
Fei-hung, what now?
Well, we know they're up to something.
- Find a way into the factory.
- Okay.
Then we'll find a way to stop them.
- Come on!
- Right.
Looks valuable.
Why're these hidden
with the steel for shipment.
- I'll go and tell them.
- Go quick.
Go! Go!
Get out of here!
Get help!
Go now!
Madam, they're coming out.
All right, keep it down.
- Bye.
- Good, take care on the journey.
- Madam, we're leaving.
- Take care of the baby.
- I will.
Fei Hung?
- Yes, Father?
- Don't get up. Keep working.
- You know what to do.
- I'll remember what you said.
Make another one afterwards.
I'll make sure he does.
It's my responsibility.
Listen. He's not allowed to leave.
You understand me?
- Perfectly.
- All right, good.
I want to have a word with you.
If we were to have a boy,
he could be Wong Tei-Pau.
If it's a girl, Wong Pei.
Nice. Both names are fine.
But do we really
need to pick one now?
What if I'm early?
That should be alright if you
take it easy till I get back.
Good.
- Fei Hung?
- Yes?
Remember.
- Oh, I will!
- Master Wong, time to leave.
Coming.
- Take care.
- I'll rein Fei-hung in.
Take good care on the road.
Come back early.
Go! You may come out!
They are shipping Chinese treasure.
Wonder how Uncle Hing is.
I've got him involved.
Don't be silly.
No Chinese would tolerate seeing
treasures being shipped away.
Step-mom, what now?
Come with me.
Step-mom, where are you going?
To beat the bastard!
- Dad said...
- Madam, you're pregnant.
Only 4 months, nothing serious.
Auntie, we told Master Wong
nothing would happen to you.
You're right.
That son of the bitch is lucky.
I'll go get my students.
Meet me at the mill.
Right. I'll gather up the men.
See you at the bridgehead.
Fei-hung, let's go.
- We're leaving.
- Take care.
Right.
If anything happens to me,
take care of my dad.
Damn your dirty mouth!
One without ambitions
is not my worthy son!
I'm leaving.
Fei Hung!
Don't return if you get beaten.
Yes, Step-mom.
Protest unreasonable closure,
demand reasonable compensation!
Don't get carried away
What are you doing here? Go away!
Hand over the treasure
or we won't let you go.
Those antiques are not yours,
and we won't let them out of China!
You have no right to them.
Is that so?
Throw them out!
No! Don't shoot!
Fei Hung, rescue Uncle Hing!
Wait!
Fei Hung!
Don't.
Go and rescue Uncle Hing.
- I know where he is.
- Good. Keep an eye on him.
Wong Fei-hung is here!
Stop him!
Wait!
Do you realize what you're doing?
He's helping foreigners steal
China's treasure. Why help him?
State treasure?
What about our empty stomach?
- Others will do it if they don't.
- I won't let you do it.
And what are you
gonna do about it?
Listen here,
nothing's gonna stand in my way,
so why don't you just
go home to daddy?
I've heard enough.
Oh? Well, that makes two of us.
Enough talk. Just kill him already.
Do it.
Do it!
Finish him!
Come on!
Drunken boxing.
Just so-so.
Come on!
I also have a fist.
"A boat can float in water,
but also sink in it"?
You are beyond help!
Just perfect!
Damn you.