Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
The twilight embraced a rare foray
outside those kingly walls,
Upon Lady Jeon's request to visit
her abode in the Northern District.
So turbid was the mantle of mist
which there she found,
Dread engulfed her
every single hesitant step.
So sudden it was, the feeble sound
of footsteps haunting the shadows.
Taken aback,
she swiftly turned to behold,
As a manly contour crept
outside the nightly haze,
Her heart shivering in dread!
Verging upon her was
this menacing figure...
this menacing figure!
Let's get moving.
Verging upon her was
this menacing figure.
Piercing the nebulous brume,
His punishing blade beheaded Lady Jeon!
Demise brewing from the darkness,
one last time she beheld,
That man's visage and the
arcane secrets it concealed,
One last ominous sight before
eternal quiet graced the night.
My, what a tragic finale!
Ehh...
Everyone, stop!
May I ask you what is the matter?
Murderer Oh Suntak, submit immediately.
- WITH S2 Presents -
JOSEON X-Files: Secret Book
- Episode 5: The Sealed Tale -
Believe me.
All I did was narrating
right as it was written.
Every single thing you said
matches yesterday's murder.
Why did you slay that court lady?
I mean, if I truly
was behind that murder,
why would I boast of such a
heinous crime in everyone's presence?
Perhaps it is mere
vainglory on your part,
or else you and the actual murderer
might be conspiring together.
But it doesn't merely stop at this,
as three recent murders in the capital
perfectly match tales you recounted!
Officer Choi,
let's tame all that ferment.
Isn't there a possibility that
what he claims could be the truth?
But, still...
And you don't even have any tangible
evidence proving his culpability.
Yet, despite the lack of evidence,
all the clues at our disposal inevitably
discredit your claims of innocence.
Are you perchance aware that
anyone murdering a court official...
is sentenced to
death by dismemberment?
Actually,
there is someone who
provides me with such tales.
And who would that be?
I am neither aware of his
name nor where he might live.
How did you two meet?
He one day came looking for me,
allowed me to peruse his tales,
and told me I could use them
if I found them to my liking.
He displayed remarkable prose and
his tales were deeply intriguing,
so I thought he might have been a
scholar with a predilection for narrative.
Not to mention that he
asked for no remuneration, so...
So?
We meet twice per month,
during every full and new moon.
I do not know his name,
and after leaving his tales behind,
he disappears right as he came.
I never imagined the tales he
narrates were real occurrences.
You said you meet every full moon?
Aigoo... Come on in!
What is with all these
stories to tell, these days?!
This is the latest one.
Yesterday in Ayeong-Gol,
a Royal Court lady was murdered.
But what's peculiar is that there
were no traces of violation or burglary.
Not to mention that
she was even beheaded!
That would more than suffice.
But, tell me.
Why not write a short story,
while you're at it?
I will generously compensate you.
No interest?
*of a noble and commoner,
usually clan servants or gisaeng
Your prose is to be lauded,
but you remain an illegitimate son*,
so any court aspirations
would be rather far-fetched.
What are you going to do
with all that talent, anyhow?
Why?
Importuned by what I said?
Shall I let you in on something?
What?
Next year, on the first day of the
fifth month at the hour of the ram (1-3pm),
*by the Han River
you will ride a boat
headed for Gwang Port*.
I see a yellow flag
fluttering in the wind,
while someone carrying a huge load
comes on board in haste.
That happens exactly
as you are boarding the boat.
Hit by wayfarers passing by,
you lose your balance,
and end up thrown right under the ship,
where a big stone
covered by ropes is lying.
You will hit your head on
the stone and meet your demise.
What?!
You little...
What did you just say?
You little bastard...
How dare you belittle me
with such palaver!
You insolent son of a wench!
You insolent,
shameless son of a wench!
How dare you?
Aigoo, really...
I wonder If we should
have even bothered.
What are you referring to?
Getting involved in this case, that is.
He's being watched,
so he won't get away easily.
I didn't mean that...
I'm just saying, murders are for
the capital bureau to worry about,
but if we interfere and
something happens, then what?
Don't tell me...
Are we suddenly feeling scared?!
It's not that...
I just feel that we might have gotten
involved in something bigger than we think.
Why complicate things?
All we need to find out is why that
murderer would flaunt his crimes.
By the way, there is
a book I must peruse,
so I will spend some time
immersed in lectures,
just so you know.
What?
No!
Oh Gyeonghoon!
Stop there!
What's wrong with you?
Naeuri!
*in Korean shamanism, an intercessor
between humans and gods
A male mudang* is running
away in great haste,
As a man on his trail, sickle in hand,
Pierces his back with great fervor,
As howls of fear
are drenching the streets.
The prose is so accurate,
it feels almost as if he
jotted it down right as it happened.
How did he know something
like that would happen?
He's a mudang, all right.
No doubt.
I know from experience,
since my mother was one...
Then, why could he not predict
we would be on his trail?
That was likely...
not part of his vision.
Listen, he's a mudang.
Even my mother only chooses
to see whatever she wants to.
Wow... This is really...
quite something, isn't it?
Wow... Mudang.
- Magistrate Jang!
- Uh?
You didn't happen
to see my tablet, did you?
Tablet?!
Nah... Never mind.
Did the damned tablet
fly away or something?
Now that's peculiar.
I guess the capital bureau released him.
Ahh... You said the tablet
would be around here!
Is anything the matter?
Uh?! Is ever...
Pretend I'm not even around, will you?
*tavern owner
- Jumo*.
- Yes... Here you are.
- Have you been faring well?
- Yes.
- Is he inside?
- Yes, he is.
Gyeonghoon.
Here I am.
Hyung...
Let's go in.
Hyung!
- Come out at once!
- What's wrong with you people?
Are you all right?
My...
brother...
- My brother...
- Listen!
This...
"A blade is pointing..."
"at Inspector Kim's pate."
Then, this...
Hyeongdo!
Stop there!
The Office?!
Why would an Office inspector
be on that man's trail?
Judging by your garments
we seem to be fellow officials,
so may I ask you
the very same question?
Unless you want
to face an early demise,
I suggest you leave that man alone.
What?
Wow... If it weren't for this book,
you'd be on a trip to the Hades by now.
How did you know you'd be stabbed,
wearing this book on your belly?
Then, the man writing those tales
was your half-brother?
That's right.
Ever since the age of seven,
he endured all struggles known to man.
And your parents?
A chronic disease took away our father,
while my brother's mother
suddenly left our abode one day.
From that day onwards,
I've been raising him like a father...
So the same man who raised
his brother like a father...
was conspiring to hand him
to the authorities?
It's not that...
My brother...
is not like everyone else.
One day,
he suddenly started
claiming he was seeing things,
and that they'd ravage his mind
if he didn't write about them.
At first, I thought it
was only a fleeting condition...
But then?
Not long ago, he started suggesting
someone was on his trail.
Those men we saw earlier?
My brother would never be
capable of committing murder.
I know that.
All I was curious about was
how your brother could manage...
to record in such glaring detail
events which have not yet occurred.
His mother was a mudang.
So you're suggesting he might
have inherited her same attributes?
- It is the only logical...
- Give me a break.
Then, it should be the same for
everyone who had mudang parents.
Why isn't it working for me?
But, what is this book about?
I can't say, either.
He told me to take good care of it,
and the moment he had me conceal it
beneath my vestments, those men came in.
This is sealed.
Is that one of his...
It is likely one of his tales.
(Left) Mudang Baekyi's Love
(Right) Book of Prophecies
Mudang Baekyi graced us
with the following prophecies...
on the impending destiny
of our state matters.
In the fifteenth year
of Gwanghae's reign (1623),
*one of the major political factions of
mid-Joseon; pro-Ming and anti-Manchu (Qing)
the Westerners* will begin a restoration to
protest against the king's lack of virtue,
dethroning him, and helping the
grandson of the late King Seonjo,
*to be King Injo
Prince Neungyang*, to the throne.
- Book of Prophecies -
Naeuri.
Have a look at these.
They're records of people claiming
to have foreshadowed the future.
Why, anything of note in there?
But, is anything the matter?
Ahh... It's nothing.
No, I'm sure something is up.
I said it's nothing.
Everything is fine.
I spent the night immersed in
lectures, so I could not sleep.
Take a look at this.
The latest is about a mudang named Baekyi
who was recently ousted from the palace.
Baekyi?!
She read all the
court attendants' fortune,
and everything she claimed was true.
- As a result...
- So nothing of note, you're saying.
Isn't overwhelming people with
vague chicanery what they're best at?
After which people interpret that as
their own situation and experience shock.
- But this is not your usual...
- Never you mind.
No need to concern ourselves
with a mudang's vicissitudes.
Ahh, also.
This...
Have you read this?
It's just a book of tales,
as we expected.
Hardly out of the ordinary.
Nothing more than vulgar tripe
narrating of lascivious encounters.
Here...
You may choose your brushes now.
The Westerners will begin a restoration to
protest against the king's lack of virtue,
dethroning him, and helping the
grandson of the late King Seonjo,
Prince Neungyang, to the throne.
Hyung!
Gyeonghoon!
Gyeonghoon... Gyeonghoon!
Gyeonghoon? Are you all right?
Is everything fine?
Yes, Hyung...
And... And nobody was trailing you.
Hyung.
For the time being,
I think I should leave the capital.
Hyung, that book I entrusted...
Did that Office inspector...
He asked me to give you
this letter, in case I met you.
Gyeonghoon...
What on earth is happening?
Hyung.
Take care.
So long.
Hyung... Run!
Hyung!
- Hyung...
- Gyeonghoon, get out of here, now!
No... You must come with me!
I said go!
- Now!
- Hyung!
- Out of the way.
Hyung!!
I said move!
Hyung!
Get out of the way!
Hyung...
- Move!
- Hyung...
What brings you here?
I am Kim Hyeongdo from
the Office of Inspector-General.
Father.
Father...
I read that book of yours.
I trust you're well aware of what
nefarious consequences would...
befall the court,
if its content was revealed.
I suggest you keep it secret
and leave Hanyang immediately.
*gisaeng parlor
You will find a gibang* named
Soguk past Gwangtong Bridge,
so head there and tell them I sent you.
They will let you know
where you can find refuge.
And where is the body?
Over there.
What is going on here?
Where is the inspector?
Ahh... He's been prancing about
all day long... I have no idea.
Go find him right away.
I need to go somewhere.
As the gibang is sweltered
by a crimson tide,
Vice Minister of Personnel Choi
Geunyoung's lifeless body is found.
A ghastly shadow of
dread haunts all bystanders,
While Inspector Kim Hyeongdo
beholds this all, blade in hand.
It is not as an Office
inspector that I ask you,
but as a loyal subject with
the court's interests at heart.
I have no intention of bringing
personal fallacies to your attention,
so may you answer my
inquiries with utmost sincerity.
What you said is right.
I did indeed share an intimate
liaison with Court Lady Baekyi.
Then, Oh Gyeonghoon...
must be your son as well.
It brings shame to my noble legacy.
Baekyi was accused of being possessed,
as a result of which she
was ousted from the palace.
I thus suppose that your illicit
relationship with her...
stopped you from
being of any help to her.
But why did you resort to killing her?
What...
is that supposed to mean?
A certain Court Lady Jeon from His Majesty's
quarters was recently found dead,
not to mention the body of a palace
eunuch we discovered before that.
The other day, a male mudang...
entrusted with Baekyi's possession
ritual was murdered at the market.
All those murders were related
to Your Excellency's lover, Baekyi.
There... There is no way...
Are you suggesting
you weren't responsible?
What do I owe your visit to?
I'd like to ask you something.
Do you perchance know anything about
His Excellency the Vice Minister Choi Geunyoung?
Vice Minister Choi Geunyoung?
Someone foreshadowing the future
suggests he might be involved with this.
*Wa (Japan) invasion
of Joseon (1592-1598)
It's a record regarding the Imjin War*.
Why this...
It was written no less than
two years before the Imjin year (1592).
A mudang known as Baekyi wrote it.
She predicted the endless misery
the Wa invasion would bring us.
She was then ousted from the palace
because of her prophecies,
but people lost all traces of her
right before the Imjin year.
Everyone believed her dead.
However,
someone claims to
have recently seen her.
And what would that have
to do with Vice Minister Choi?
He and that mudang were
engaged in an illicit liaison.
I see.
If you'll excuse me, I'll get going.
Perchance...
Yes.
Did you find any kind of book on him?
It was nothing more than
a vulgar tale of illicit affairs.
Nothing else?
As it stands.
My best wishes, Your Excellency.
My gratitude.
Should you ever meet again,
convey my deep concerns to him.
Yes, certainly.
In truth, meeting him even once
would be of great comfort.
Do you really mean that?
Do you know where he might be?
- I can't speak with certainty, but...
- Never you mind.
I don't believe
that would even be necessary.
There is nothing I
have given him as his father,
so wishing to meet him only now
would be all the more selfish on my part.
If you'll excuse me.
May I ask you what brings you here?
That Office inspector...
Please...
Aww... My legs...
And the inspector?
Where on earth...
I looked everywhere,
but no trace of him?!
Then, any gibang he might frequent...
Aigoo...
That is surely not the
Kim Hyeongdo I know.
When it comes to judging character,
I'm as gifted as my mother.
You'll never see Inspector Kim
frequenting any such place.
Put a little powder on, and
he'll explode with nosebleeds...
All right, then.
Will you look for him one last time?
You haven't changed at all.
Thank you for coming to my aid.
But...
That fellow...
He fell asleep just now.
How have you been faring?
Did he come in alone?
Yes.
Those garments are all worn out...
- I can get you new ones right away...
- No need.
There is somewhere I must urgently go.
As the gibang is sweltered
by a crimson tide...
Inspector Kim Hyeongdo
beholds this all, blade in hand.
You're still here?
What is the matter?
Just thought I smelled a
gisaeng's powder on you...
What?!
What is that supposed to mean?
I wonder, what do we owe
this sudden departure to,
leaving work behind
as if in a lovelorn frenzy?
That, well...
I had my reasons, don't you mind.
Can I serve you a cup of tea?
Here.
A gibang, you said?
Indeed.
You could have dealt
with it right away, then.
- Why come to me?
- That Office inspector was with him.
When our nation's stability is at stake,
you show qualms about disposing
a mere Office inspector?
- However, as a court official...
- Indeed.
Aren't you a State Tribunal inspector?
Whatever the case,
you must get this done.
Get rid of those people
and bring me that book.
What are you waiting for?
All right.
Wait.
Gwangtong Bridge, you said?
His Excellency left in utmost urgency.
Did he mention where he was headed?
I did seem to hear near
Gwangtong Bridge, if I'm not mistaken...
Thank you.
You could say I help deal with any
quandaries of his, emotional or not.
Is there anything on my face?
Why...
can't you confess your feelings to him?
He is...
Aigoo... He's nowhere, no traces, none.
He's not... Ahh...
And what... What is this?
Stop staring and just unclasp me.
Ahh... Yes... But who...
Why... Who did this?
Can we just do this, please?
- Was Assistant Heo responsible?
- Or else who, me?
Ahh... Enough with this and just unclasp me!
That blade over there must have a use!
Yes... Yes.
Where did you hide that book?
I see...
I will be forced
to face the same destiny.
I thought I asked you something.
Did your relationship with
a mudang bring you such shame?
Silence!
And what would you possibly know?
- Give me that book at once.
- No.
I'm afraid I cannot.
You knave...
Do you even realize what kind
of book we're dealing with?
Naturally.
I do.
And do you think it ends at that?
I could easily write such a book myself!
Shall I prove my claims?
Shall I tell you what future
awaits our nation?
Shut your gob!
What kind of palaver is that?
Merely because noble blood
graces your veins,
you had no qualms about forsaking
your own flesh and blood!
But now that I might
expose your nefarious conduct,
you're eager to rid yourself of me?
I said speak no more!
One single utterance, and I shall
extirpate that viperous tongue of yours.
For am I nothing but a
lowly mudang's offspring,
why stop at that, when you
could easily cut off my hands?
No... Why not dismember me?!
- You knave, I ought to...
- Shall we put an end to this?
Vice Minister Choi Geunyoung.
I trust you're all aware of
what book is in my hands?!
I might not be aware of why you're
so frantically looking for this,
but if it's something
the world cannot learn of,
wouldn't burning it in
your presence solve all this?
Magistrate Jang!
Your Excellency has been deceived.
You might have been trying to erase any
evidence of your illicit liaison with Baekyi,
but that is not what
these people were after.
Don't... Stay away...
I'm going to set it on fire!
Stop there!
I will not hesitate to slay him.
Father...
Father!
Mudang Baekyi's Love...
Assistant Heo, Magistrate Jang.
Oh Gyeonghoon has finally
completed his first novel.
But what's with the flowers?
Naeuri...
Here.
And what is this?
From Buok.
And he would never frequent a gibang...
I didn't think
you'd be capable of that...
Looks like I was wrong.
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Main Translator and Timer: Anarchist
Timing QC: julier
Editor/QC: thunderbolt
Coordinators: mily2, ay_link
I feel ashamed to just mention it,
but meseems ghosts haunt my abode.
Don't tell me you
believe in such superstition...
Quite interesting, indeed.
I just went in,
and suddenly felt this presence...
But His Excellency was never caught.
Then, was it that Goryeo ghost?
His Excellency can't be behind this.
And who would be behind that, then?
What were you planning to do,
once everyone left?
Is this presence
evoking those phenomena,
or are those events only
happening during such phenomena?
What kind of place is this?
I suggest you leave.
Watch dramas legally at
dramafever.com | crunchyroll.com