He Hao Yi, you're my best friend.
Only friends?
He Hao Yi! Listen to me explain. It's not what you think!
Boss, could that A.I. stand for "artificial intelligence?"
That's right. I'm cold-hearted. I'm a machine.
Whether A.I. is human or a robot, we'll find out tomorrow.
Timing and subtitles brought to youby the Forever17 Team@ Viki
♫ What does it take to love you is a decision of my whole life. ♫
♫ If I lose, if I forget, I won't be searching numbly anymore. ♫
♫ It rains all night and I regret breaking your heart ♫
♫ I can’t have your tenderness. Quickly return to my bosom. ♫
♫ I want to approach you, but we are only friends now. ♫
♫ I can’t wake up from my beautiful memories. Why doubt? ♫
♫ Hug closer and closer, till we're unable to breathe the trace of our love. ♫
♫ The answer is you. ♫
♫ I miss you very much. I really miss you very much. ♫
♫ I can’t change myself in time. ♫
♫ I can’t resist. I can't resist anymore. (I don’t want to resist.) ♫
♫ I really want to love you. To persist until the end, ♫
♫ tell me how much courage it requires. ♫
♫ My only love. My only love. ♫
Love at Seventeen♫ My only love. Yeah. ♫
Okay. Can we start discussing now?
Without A.I., there is nothing I need to discuss with you.
She's here. She's already here.
I am the researcher, A.I., Ai Li Si.
Thirteen years.
I've imagined hundreds of ways of meeting Ai Li Si again.
However, I never imagined the way that's in front of my eyes.
Back then, if I had made another choice,
would you not look at me so coldly now?
Today at noon, I'll wait for you at the place we buried the time capsule.
I have to clear things up with you three.
In life, there are times where there will suddenly be a fork in the road.
Unfortunately, at that time, we thought the only path was the one in front of us .
Even if instinct tells you to choose,
and go see what the other path holds.
However, the more you think, the less inclined you are to go
because you don't have the courage.
Thirteen years ago,
I didn't have the courage to hear what Ai Li Si had to say.
I was afraid she would tell me, "I'm sorry."
"I truly don't like you."
I'm back.
Ah Di, Mom will be home late today so we ordered pizza.
- Come eat.  - Do you want some?
You guys didn't go see Ai Li Si?
We haven't talked in a long time. Why would we go?
Ever since the camping trip, did you really not talk to her?
Pretty much.
I thought you guys made up. Why didn't you go?
You didn't go either.
Are we going overboard?
You know my situation. We can talk after some time.
♫Why have your eyes avoided my eyes? ♫
Later, I realized,
timing
was crueler than time.
♫Is that because I’m losing you? ♫
Ai Li Si!
♫ The more I worry, the more I doubt, ♫
♫ the more I can’t bring your heart back. ♫
♫ Where did this love between us fall off? ♫
Time elapsed and made me lose my youth.
I missed the timing,
which left my youth filled with mystery and regrets.
I didn't pick the right time
to muster up the courage and choose another path.
The punishment I received was that
after that day, Ai Li Si transferred schools.
♫ Some people will let a person forget himself, but also remember himself. ♫
I never saw her again
until now.
♫ Only you can let me forget myself, ♫
♫ but also remember myself. ♫
Ai Li Si, this is the U.S.Capital's
Risk Management Advisor, Mr. He Hao Yi.
Mr. He, so your company believes our collaboration
has some risks, and therefore especially sent you to manage?
Every three months, you send some pictures of the experiment,
and ask for $200,000 USD in experiment funds.
The experiment completion time has not been set. There is only the signature of A.I. on the papers.
For such an investment, it took Capital a year before they sent me to understand the situation.
I'm actually quite surprised.
If the company has concerns,
then please ask any questions you may have.
We will answer fully.
Very good.
My first question is,
where is Ms. Ai residing?
What does this have to do with the experiment?
It's because I once had someone blamelessly disappear.
I definitely won't let that happen again.
Therefore, tell me now where you are residing,
your cell phone number,
your email, Live, Twitter, Facebook, Weibo, and PTT screen names.
I want them now.
[Researcher, Ai Li Si A.I.]
The experiment has entered the rat-testing stage.
The business card has my email.
If you need any information, you're welcome to request it.
CEO, Mr. He has arrived. You two can discuss the rest.
Boss, what plan number is this? Did we plan to ask all this?
You can continue with the CEO.
CEO, excuse me. I'm going out for a bit.
Ai Li Si.
Ai Li Si,
do you remember me?
I remember,
but this has no significance to me.
If you have any questions, please go through the CEO.
Naruto, volume 72.
It was you at the comic bookstore that day, right?
So what if it was?
What I want to ask most
is what happened to you these thirteen years?
Why have you changed this way?
Are you upset that I didn't meet you that day?
Ai Li Si.
Timing and subtitles brought to youby the Forever17 Team@ Viki
Dear, is someone bothering you?
Hello, I am Capital's Risk Management Advisor. My name is He Hao Yi.
I know. I didn't think
that I would meet you here.
You know me because you're in the same company as Ai Li Si, right?
I am JSUT's business manager. My name is Peter, Ai Li Si's closest colleague.
I think our lunch hour is over.
If you have anything to say, you can wait until you are stationed in the company.
Dear, let's go.
Wait.
Capital is your company's most important collaboration partner.
This means I can discuss with your company personnel.
Our discussion is over.
Then you don't have to waste more time.
Mr. He, let's talk another day.
Let's go.
Did you see
He Hao Yi's face when I called you "dear?" It turned green!
I think his head is full of questions now.
Are you upset?
Alright, I won't casually call you that next time.
I'm not upset. It's because you grabbed my hand,
so it's a little sore.
Did you receive the breakfast this morning?
Since you were out of the country this month, I received it everyday.
Thank you. You don't have to anymore.
Then is your stomach pain gone?
I told you, I have a way to treat your stomach pain.
I don't know how you lived before I entered the company.
Song Han Ming...
Hey,
you're not allowed to say thank you.
If we say that between the two of us, it'll ruin the friendship.
Are you alright?
Didn't I say my stomach pain was gone?
That's not it. You haven't seen He Hao Yi in so long.
Is here alright?
He's Capital's Risk Management Advisor. What can happen?
Before, all your feelings show on your face.
Now, you have a poker face. I can't tell anything.
I hope you're really fine.
Wait for me!
You're back?
I'm back.
What are you up to?
Taking pictures for spring make-up. Come over.
Come look. Come and look!
Look.
Before make-up. After make-up.
It's great, right?
Such a dedicated blog like mine
is really rare and tiring, you know?
Take your time.
Hey, it's hard on my own. Help me.
Hurry up!
Before and after make-up, okay?
Slow down.
Before make-up.
After make-up.
I pressed video recording.
What are you doing? Cut!
Why are you taking selfies?
What are you thinking? Work didn't go well today?
- Sis. - What?
Do you remember Ai Li Si?
Your college classmate?
Lei Lei's friend?
Your ex-girlfriend? Oh no, that was Amanda.
You're so annoying. You can't even take some photos.
Ai Li Si,
do you remember me?
I remember, but this has no significance to me.
If you have any questions, please go through the CEO.
It turns out,
this is what the reaction should be after hearing a high school classmate's name after thirteen years.
Ai Li Si saw me today just like how Sis heard her name.
Stranger. No meaning.
It turns out I'm the only one who still cares.
Ah Di, what's wrong with you?
Nothing. I haven't gotten over the jet lag.
I'm going to rest.
You should stop scaring people.
Please! I'm pretty, okay?
Scaring people? I'll scare you.
You said Ah Di came back?
Yeah.
I haven't seen him in so long.
After I get settled in my new job, I'll take him out.
It's her?
He's not bad.
Stop being noisy!
I'm Peter.
- Go away. - I'm returning this.
I'm not interested in you.
Looks like she didn't recognize me.
Could it be that he doesn't like girls?
I'm not the landlubber from back then, Song Han Ming.
Hang on.
Can you go up?
Hold on tight.
Does it still hurt?
How come you know how to treat cramps?
I'm familiar with the sport of swimming.
I think you are too, right?
I was on the swim team in high school.
However, in college, during a competition I hurt my left leg ligament.
From then on, I can't swim fast anymore.
So, everytime I see someone swim fast, I get envious.
Earlier, I wanted to catch up to you, but ended up like this.
What's your name?
Peter. My name is Peter.
My name is Bai Shu Lei. Hello.
So, do you regularly come here to exercise?
Yes. It's on the way home from work.
Oh, such a coincidence. My new company happens to be nearby.
What company?
Jsut Biotec. Have you heard of it?
I heard about it. That is a good company.
Then, I think we will bump into one another very often.
♫ I really want to love you. To persist until the end, ♫
♫ tell me how much courage it requires. My only love. My only love. ♫
That's right! Ms. Bai, have a good night.
Good night.
This guy didn't say he'll give me a ride home.
Does he actually like men or just playing cat and mouse with me?
It's okay, I will let you go this time.
I want to see next time, what trick you have up your sleeve.
(Jsut International Co. LTD)
Is there something?
What kind of relationship do you have with Mr. He?
He is a high school classmate that I haven't seen in 13 years.
Is that it?
Are you worried about my personal involvement with him?
Yes, I am worried you would care about your past friendship
and let it influence your decision.
You think of him as too important.
Capital arranged Mr. He to come.
It means that they are impatient and want to see some achievements.
I'm worried that at any time they will withdraw their support, so I need to find another way.
And, in fact, I need that complete copy of experiment results
in order to search for funding.
If you want to finish this earlier,
then don't have unrelated things bother me.
CEO, from tomorrow, He Hao Yi will represent the collaboration company
to oversee the ongoing process of the experiment in JSUT.
- Just follow the original plan. Don't let him suspect. - Yes.
Timing and subtitles brought to youby the Forever17 Team@ Viki
Advisor He, I will first guide you around every JSUT department.
I can tour around by myself. Have you arranged a cubicle for me in R&D?
Is there a problem?
I will take care of this immediately.
- Sweet deserts.- There are pineapple cakes.
- I have it, too.- I'll go buy what you want to eat.
Everyone just take some.
Look, you guys all became so skinny.
What a pity.
Please excuse me.
Advisor He, you came to supervise us so early.
Doing things at the right time could have double effectiveness,
and change crisis into turning points.
You are right.
Is it because Advisor He once missed a certain time in your life,
that lets you have such a deep realization?
If you really want to know my past,
I am always at the research and development department. You are welcome to come and find me anytime.
Jun Xiong, how to get to the marketing department?
Over here, Boss.
He's so quick.
Manager Bai, hello.
Are you are my special assistant, Ya Li?
Yes.
That's right.
If you can change your flats to high heels,
and hot chick short skirt to business skirt,
I think that you will look more professional.
My assistant is a representation of myself.
Yes.
Right now, I will go around to understand each department.
On the first day of work, I immediately want to be in the best mindset.
Let's go.
Hello, I am the research and development manager, Zhao Gu Yi.
During this period, Manager Zhao, sorry for disturbing.
No problem.
Juan Mao, help him arrange a seat.
- There's an empty seat next to me.  - Where does Ai Li Si sit?
Right there.
Okay.
Then, I'll sit here.
- Good morning everyone. - Peter, good morning.
Good morning.
Oh, it turns out that James Bond in JSUT
is the mystery person who gave Ai Li Si's 3-month supply of breakfast.
This.. This.. What happened?
I thought that only high schoolers sent breakfast.
To care about someone, one should be simple and straightforward to be effective.
Someone like you, a high school classmate whom she hasn't seen for a while
probably doesn't know the meaning of accompanying someone.
Ah, that's right. Where's Team Lead Ai?
She is most likely busy working in the lab.
Okay. Goodbye.
Manager Bai, this is our R&D lab.
All our products are researched and developed here.
Hi.
Looking at your outfit I can tell you are probably a researcher.
Then, is it okay if you give me a tour around the lab?
Bai Shu Lei?
Who are you?
Oh, I am the new marketing manager, Bai Shu Lei.
People from other departments who want to come into the research room need to register first.
Have you registered?
Today is my first day at work, so I haven't registered.
Then, you can't come in.
Miss, I just told you I am the new marketing manager.
Even if you are the chairman of the board, you still need to register.
Then, would you be responsible for the secrets that get leaked into the public?
Or do you think that you can use your position to force others?
I'm sorry that doesn't work here.
Miss, I am trying to talk to you nicely. Do you have to speak in this way?
Who do you think you are?
Are you okay, Bai Shu Lei?
How come it's you?
This is what I was going to ask you. Get up first.
Now, let's go back to your question you just asked.
I am the team leader of R&D, Ai Li Si.
♫ I really want to love you. To persist until the end, ♫
♫ tell me how much courage it requires. ♫
- Ah!- Are you alright, Bai Shu Lei?
How come it's you?
This is the same question I want to ask you.
Now, let's go back to your question you just asked.
I'm the team leader in R&D, Ai Li Si.
Lei Lei!
Manager Bai, are you alright?
Hi!
Peter.
Welcome to you both.
It seems like we all know each other.
You come here.
He Hao Yi, you already knew that Ai Li Si worked in our company. Didn't you?
I only knew that a day before you knew.
You didn't see what kind of attitude she had just now?
Did she already know that I was going to work here so that's why she is giving me trouble in public?
Moreover, it's in front of Peter.
It destroys my carefully planned debut completely.
I think she didn't do it against you.
How would you know?
She treats everyone with the same attitude.
Yesterday, I was going to chat with her to understand how she became like this.
At the end, Peter took her away.
Thus, she and Peter are close.
At least, I didn't see her giving Peter a dig.
Fine, I didn't give thorough thought to today's event.
I just want to make sure she's not against me and that will be okay.
From now on, I'll just treat her
as a stranger working in the same company.
Can we really treat Ai Li Si as a stranger?
Of course.
We were only classmates for two years.
If she hadn't said her name was Ai Li Si, I would have completely forgotten her a long time ago.
Ah Di,
I know you really mind that you didn't meet her at that time.
However, since she is so cold to you, why are you still warm to a cold shoulder?
Let bygones be bygones.
We both don't have a time machine. We can only look forward.
Understand?
I'll see.
You didn't hear what I said.
Ai Li Si! Ai Li Si!
Were you also surprised just now?
We never thought that we would bump into both of them here.
Now... Now should we have a
high school reunion in the company?
But I have to say what you just did was awesome.
What did I do?
Teach the Queen a lesson.
I was just teaching a newbie who didn't know about the regulations in R&D a lesson.
Who she is has no meaning to me.
So, should I really not have to worry about that incident?
Although I had promised you to forget the past and
had guaranteed not to mention it to anyone,
now with He Hao Yi and Bai Shu Lei appearing, I'm afraid that you...
How can a long forgotten incident affect me?
Why... Why am I here?
Are you going to the lab?
Then, okay. Let both of us go forward together.
Never look back. Okay?
Manager Zhao, I have something to discuss with you.
It happens that I also want to ask you something.
Did you already know Ai Li Si and Manager Bai before?
We were high school classmates. Only I don't know
why Ai Li Si became this way now.
Although everyone feels Ai Li Si is hard to get along with,
and doesn't see her having friends,
but I feel she is a good girl.
Especially, she works very hard.
She doesn't even take a break for lunch. Isn't it too much?
You didn't have lunch. You must be hungry; I'll take you out for tea this afternoon.
No.
But she takes a break at 3:15 pm everyday.
The time for making tea also has to be accurate so it's more flavorful.
Do you drink tea at this particular time everday? May I have a cup?
- No.- Hey.
Then what time does she usually take off?
She often works overtime and sleeps in the office,
but you're lucky today.
She will take off on time once per month.
Today is the day.
Would you like to have dinner together?
No.
Ah!
Timing and subtitles brought to youby the Forever17 Team@ Viki
Wow.
Excuse me. Sorry. Sorry.
What a coincidence!
Mister, please stop standing so close to me.
♫ I really want to love you. To persist until the end, ♫
♫ tell me how much courage it requires. ♫
Are you alright?
I'm sorry, all passengers. The bus is out of order.
Please take the next bus.
How come?
Are you in a hurry? Where are you going?
What does it have to do with you?
Why do I always chase after you?
Hey! Your purse.
♫ What does it take to love you is a decision of my whole life. ♫
♫ If I lose, if I forget, I won't be searching numbly anymore. ♫
♫ It rains all night and I regret breaking your heart ♫
Wow. What are you looking for?
♫ Quickly return to my bosom. ♫
Miss, is that pudding inside?
Then, where is the pudding truck?
There were cops so it left early.
Which direction did it go?
Hello. Ah. Thanks.
Hey!
I saw it.
That pudding truck turned.
♫ I miss you very much. I really miss you very much. ♫
♫ I can’t change myself in time. ♫
♫ I can’t resist. I can't resist anymore. (I don’t want to resist.) ♫
♫ I really want to love you. To persist until the end, ♫
♫ tell me how much courage it requires. ♫
♫ My only love. My only love. ♫
Wait a moment! Wait a moment! Wait a moment!
♫ My. My only love. ♫
She wants to buy some pudding.
You got off work on time just to buy this pudding. Is it good?
It's very good.
I want one, too.
Then why didn't you buy one earlier?
I forgot. Let me eat one.
Before we eat pudding, we should eat dinner.
I remember near here...
Ah! There's a good restaurant. Let's go.
Cheers.
He Hao Yi!
Ah Di!
It's been so long since I saw you.
How come you haven't changed at all?
People say that you speak the truth when you're drunk.
I finally see the Ai Li Si I remember.
How are you? Have you been well all these years?
Not good.
Not good at all.
Is that why you've become so cold?
Ah, okay. It's okay.
It's all in the past. I'm here.
Whatever was hard, tell me all.
So, so, so, so, so many hardships.
I'll pour for you.
Cheers!
Isn't it already enough?
Not yet. You're not drunk yet.
Your words haven't cleared it up yet.
Not okay.
I won't get drunk by drinking unless it's mixed liquor.
Let me tell you. Let me tell you.
Thirteen years ago, on the day that you texted me,
I really did go.
But I was late.
It was too late.
When I went, you weren't there anymore.
Later I called you,
but it didn't connect.
Didn't connect...
So what was our friendship?
After summer, I was going to see you at school like nothing was wrong,
but...
you transferred schools. I went to your house to look for you.
I really went to your house to look for you.
Ai Li Si,
if I apologize to you now,
would it be too late?
Sorry, there is no electricity. We will fix it right away.
Do you remember that in the comic bookstore,
there was also no electricity.
Oh, how did it happen again?
♫ If you catch me unaware ♫
What do you want?
Don't go.
I didn't plan to leave.
I only want to use my cellphone as a flashlight.
You're not allowed to go.
I won't allow you to disappear again.
I won't allow you to disappear anymore.
I won't allow you to leave anymore.
Understand?
Timing and subtitles brought to youby the Forever17 Team@ Viki
♫ I really want to love you. To persist until the end, ♫
♫ tell me how much courage it requires. ♫
We've eaten and drank.
Can I leave?
Wait a moment.
I almost forgot.
Your pudding.
To be honest, I wanted to make you drunk.
I didn't guess wrong. You had a motive.
But all that I've said so far was the truth.
Why?
Why did you want to get me drunk?
I was thinking that...
if I got you drunk, then you wouldn't avoid me,
then you would tell me
some real feelings.
What do you want to know?
Where did you go after you transferred?
What did you want to say on that day you made an appointment with us?
And you. What caused you to
become so... cool?
That's it?
A man and a woman. Eat, drink beer, talk.
Most people would consider this to be a date.
He Hao Yi, are you asking me to be your date?
I've missed you so much.
♫ Why have your eyes ♫
♫ avoided my eyes? ♫
The expiration date of pudding is only 3 days.
The expiration for an apology,
isn't as long as 13 years like what you thought.
Your apology to me... has expired long ago.
♫ I start to be unable to locate you. ♫
♫ The more I worry, the more I doubt, the more I can’t bring your heart back. ♫
Things from high school, I've forgotten most of them.
Your apology to me now isn't necessary.
If you want to use our history as high school classmates to get close to me,
to spend one night with me,
then I think that you should go to night club. It will be faster.
That way we won't be awkward when we see each other at work.
You don't have to pretend to care about me.
Isn't it nice to each other as strangers?
That's not what I meant.
It doesn't matter. I don't care at all.
I just don't want you to disappear anymore!
I ate dinner with you today to tell you that
no matter what you want to do later, let's end it here.
Don't bother me anymore.
Please come in.
Manager Bai, haven't you knocked off work yet?
My work is done. I should take care private matters now.
I think that you owe me an explanation.
You're right, I do owe you an explanation.
I can give you a chance to make it up.
Have dinner together tonight?
Today, I don't think I can.
Such a coincidence, I can't either tonight.
It seems that your business department is also quite busy.
But, for you I am willing to change tomorrow's schedule to have more time.
Then, I will see tomorrow's schedule,
if I have time, I'll call you.
Business card is for business.
Between us two, we don't need to be so foreign.
This is my screen name for Line. Tell me when you make your decision.
- Good night.- Good night.
Bai Shu Lei, I'm looking forward to the time when you realize I'm Song Han Ming.
♫ I want to go forward. I want to go backward. Oh~♫
♫ I really want to love you. To persist until the end, ♫
♫ tell me how much courage it requires. ♫
Hey! He Hao Yi!
You ran into Ai Li Si and didn't tell me! Lei Lei and I are shocked!
I did tell you, but you forgot her.
You both forgot everything.
Only I remembered.
Why did you shake pudding like this?
What happened to you?
Mom, weren't you coming today?
Our neighbor is injured?
I understand.
Then you can come next month.
Hmm. Bye bye.
And I especially bought your favorite pudding.
I really missed you.
Does missing the timing and apologizing too late
mean not being able to recover everything?
Morning!
I think it's not my illusion.
Since I met you, you always have it in for me.
Yes, I have it in for you.
I have asked Manager Zhao.
You've just started to work at the company for three months.
I think if you have it in for me because of AI Li Si,
first, you don't quite understand the situation.
Second, I think you don't have the right to get involved with my relationship to Ai Li Si.
I know you give much effort.
Not only you have asked Manager Zhao Ai Li Si's condition after she joins the company,
but also you followed her a whole day yesterday. Didn't you?
However, you still don't know anything.
If you want to know more about Ai Li Si, I know the answer.
This kind of bluffing and blasting negotiation doesn't work on me.
Then I'll clearly tell you,
I know why Ai Li Si transferred schools 13 years ago.
How would you know?
The reason ist very simple, but I won't tell you.
You know, there's something I really don't get.
Why does Ai Li Si treat you especially different?
Did you do something to Ai Li Si so she has to get along with you?
I can understand your feelings.
You have to give yourself a reason to make me the dark side
so you can accept the reason Ai Li Si is close to me is out of unwillingness. Right?
But He Hao Yi, saying it that way is way off.
The reason Ai Li Si accepts me
is because we are alike and friends.
That's because I have never given up on Ai Li Si,
and you still live in the past. There is no place for you here.
Now it's not that if you want to return, then you can return. I won't allow.
Ai Li Si won't accept you, either.
You don't have the right to make decisions for her.
I didn't make decisions for her. Neither did I prohibit her.
JSUT not only has cleansing masks,
but also have series for blackhead termination.
Right now, there's a big fight over cleansing masks. We will not only promote new products,
in addition to our new test,
with everyone's cooperation here,
I believe it will reach a win-win situation.
Manager Bai. please continue. I apologize.
We'll also present maintenance series this season,
the promotion of any combination of masks with buy 1 get 1 free.
It's mainly for...
Sorry.
Hello?
Okay, okay. I got it. I'll look into it.
It's nothing, it's nothing. Please, continue the meeting.
It's mainly for having all our delicate products..
with one plus one greater than two effectiveness..
Manager Bai.
Didn't I tell you that I'd look into it?
I also have something I need to say.
Please tell me after I finish talking to our distributors.
You should not continue this meeting.
I think you don't have the right to tell me what to do.
Fine. I'll just say it then.
There's a problem in the proposal.
The company's product packaging and ingredients,
in your presentation it didn't say that it can be used.
This is a big mistake.
Everyone, this product contains things that aren't good and has melanin.
It stimulates with other regular products.
Yin Mei's skin would be irritated and fragile.
It is not supposed to be allowed and the ingredients too.
Your mistake made the product worse. People would have a cognitive thinking of the product.
Before your presentation,
did you actually carefully look over our research lab's instruction manual and ingredients?
Thank you R&D's Team Leader Ai for reminding me,
I should look over the instruction manual more carefully.
But, when the product actually goes out for sale,
I will carefully look over the instruction manual.
- So... - Everyone, let me explain.
Our company has a very hardworking R&D team to help our products become better.
So, I believe that our product will have a special touch to it.
Also, using our company's research
professional tone will help promote our slogan.
How does that sound to everyone?
Yes, yes, yes.
Then, please come this way.
Come. Come. Come. Sorry, sorry.
Ai Li Si...
What's the matter?
Advisor He, you don't have to follow Ai Li Si's every step, do you?
If you haven't used your work as an excuse, it would seem like you're a stalker.
Team Leader Ai, Capital has some questions about your research. Do you have time tonight?
Timing and subtitles brought to youby the Forever17 Team@ Viki
I shouldn't have believed you 13 years ago.
Are you the Ai Li Si I've known?
In the past I wasn't capable to protect you, but I won't let you suffer now.
You like Ai Li Si, don't you?
Right, I like Ai Li Si.
Tumor?
The rate of a successful surgery is about 50%.
Because I want to know the feeling before I die.
Hey!
♫ I have been embraced, so I desire to be more together, every day. ♫
♫ I matured, so I seek for the happiness of simplicity. ♫
♫ At that time, dreams were so astound. ♫
♫ I hide at a corner of the world and yearn for the vastness of the world. ♫
♫ Later. Later, time as a thief, ♫
♫ city lights inundate the stars. ♫
♫ I want to go forward. I want to go backward. ♫
♫ Oh~ Unwilling awakened dream. ♫
♫ Naivety exchanges with maturity.
♫ A smile exchanges with a makeup face. ♫
♫ When I will really grow up, I will surprisingly lose my self. ♫
♫ Later. Later, time as a spell, ♫
♫ I assume there will be more happiness for tomorrow. ♫
♫ I pick up some while dropping some. ♫
♫ Which one is worth more to be owned? ♫
♫ Later. Later, time as a thief, ♫
♫ city lights inundate the stars. ♫
♫ I want to go forward. I want to go backward. ♫
♫ Oh~ Unwilling awakened dream. ♫