LITTLE WHITE LIES (2010)
I don't sting my nose.
You idiot.
I'm outta here.
That's for girls.
Use the men's room then.
You're tall.
I bone you yet?
My blow.
- All gone.
You fucker.
- It's all gone.
He's a total headcase.
Meet Ludo.
Ludo, this is Christine.
Not Christine. Christelle.
What?
Yours is mine and mine is mine.
That's not cool.
Cut it out.
You okay?
Hey, dude.
I called David.
He's on his way.
This is rocking.
We're gonna burn it up.
Say, why don't you ever call me?
You never call me.
Straight up.
Chill out, bro.
I'll be right back.
You're going?
- For a smoke.
Eric bounced?
You're splitting?
- I'm beat.
See you soon.
How are you?
Nearly missed it.
Hey.
Is Juliette coming?
I don't know.
I guess not.
What?
She won't come.
While I'm here.
Did she call? Did she...
Antoine, give us a break.
This is not the time.
Yeah, sorry.
I was just wondering...
I guess she'll come after I...
Where's Marie?
She said she'd be here but...
Pisses me off. She's always late.
Pain in the ass.
You mean me, doofus?
We can't all go in together.
Or stay too long.
Let's split into 2 groups.
Who's going first?
I will.
- Me too.
We'll wait then.
- I'll wait too.
You guys?
Wait till they give you masks.
Hold on, Eric.
They're really strict.
You been here long?
A half-hour.
I'm going for a smoke.
Did Juliette tell you if she'd come by today?
Ludo...
We're here, buddy.
We're all here.
You gave us a hell of a fright.
It's gonna be okay.
You're in good hands.
Hey there.
Hi.
You...
You've got a mask.
You too.
I'm getting out.
I'm getting out tomorrow.
You're...
You're all...
- Take it easy.
You're all dressed the same.
You're beautiful.
You too, you're beautiful.
Get some rest.
He'll be okay.
We leave him all alone a whole month?
Sabine'll be here. I called her.
As if she'd abandon her son.
But us...
We just go on vacation?
And leave him like that?
How can we help him, Marie?
We can't.
We can be there for him.
Or am I just being stupid?
You're right, it's...
- I agree.
It's mean of us...
I'm here another week.
I'll come by.
Hold on...
You all know,
Ludo's like a little brother to me.
Seeing him like that drives me crazy,
but what can we do? Not much.
Like the doc said,
he's in intensive care.
We can't even visit.
If anything happens,
like we said,
we fly right back.
It's one hour away.
Anyway, why'd anything go wrong?
I'll be away for 6 months afterwards.
I want to spend some time with him.
You can all go and I'll stay here.
Or we shorten the vacation.
Good idea. I agree.
We take 2 weeks while he recovers.
So when we get back,
he'll be fit enough to see us.
What do you say, Marie?
That's okay, isn't it?
It's a good compromise.
How about it? Let's do that.
Sounds good to me.
Get off that.
Damn it.
I have to go.
I'm putting it out.
- You quit.
I gotta run.
- Where?
The Opera. My rehearsal.
See you later. I'll call you.
Bye, everyone.
Lea's saying goodbye.
Deep breath.
That's good. And again.
Jeez, I love that.
It feels so good.
You're right, I was in agony.
You leave it till you're bent double.
I know. I should drop by.
But right now...
Quitting smoking,
the hotel expansion,
that idiot waiter suing me,
the recession and now Ludo's accident...
And you're hardly Mr. Laidback.
You said it.
C'mon, flip over.
You at the hotel tonight?
With Véro and her sister.
Never mind.
Why? What's up?
I wanted a talk.
I need your advice on something.
It's important.
- Join us for dinner.
Or you preferjust us guys?
Yeah, but I don't want to impose.
I'll talk to her.
I'd be glad.
Her sister's a pain.
C'mon, on your back.
I'm always scared
she'll tell Véro I banged her.
Véro knows.
She told me about it.
That's massive.
Why didn't she tell me?
I don't know.
Let go...
You're tense, buddy.
Okay, one...
Two...
Relax.
If it's one of your orgies,
count me out.
I can't fool around.
Whatever.
Just keep the cousin occupied.
In case she's a skank.
I texted her, you know.
I said, I know how you feel.
Get the double meaning?
Pretty smart, huh?
Poor kid's having a tough time.
It's hard for her too.
Maybe I put too much pressure on her...
Then again,
her text speaks for itself.
It means something.
I never understand her texts.
Too many idiot metaphors.
She's a walking dictionary.
She's been toying with you...
...for months while
she shags someone else.
In your bed.
How you doing?
And you?
What's your name again?
- Virginie.
Antoine...
Nice to meet you.
Where's your cousin?
Missed her train. All the more for me.
You ever done a double?
You know, a DP.
Where are you going?
Forget it.
I shocked him?
Vincent.
Come quickly.
Go on...
Tell Daddy what you just told me.
I'm tired from making love too much.
That's good, son.
How many girlfriends now?
Nine.
Nine girlfriends?
That's huge, honey.
You're a real ladies man.
It's only natural.
These guys are stupid.
As if the recession just happened.
They open the paper,
Oh, a recession.
Look...
See the maitre d'?
When I bought this place, 65 staff.
38 now, same profits.
I have some stories to tell.
But you...
You wanted to talk?
I wanted your advice.
Actually, no...
How can I put it?
I'm having this...
It's pretty weird.
I'm not sure how to deal with it.
A babe?
No, it's not that.
Look...
It's hard to talk about it,
so please,
hear me out, okay?
Wait till I'm done.
How can I say this?
It's just...
I love your hands.
What?
I don't know what's got into me,
but recently I get a strange feeling
when I see you.
Don't worry, I'm not gay or anything.
It's just you.
I mean...
It's only with you...
...that I get this feeling.
I'm trying to get a handle on it.
I mean, I've always admired you.
I like your personality.
The way you fight for things.
I even like your flaws.
You're there when I need to let off steam.
You're my friend, my confidant.
So now...
Now I love it when we hug to say goodbye,
or when we're watching a game...
...and we jump up in each other's arms.
Just that physical contact.
It's weird, I know,
but it gives me a thrill.
You're shitting me?
Max...
I was too young when I met Isa.
And now...
...she stifles me.
But when I'm with you,
I feel so good, relaxed.
Maybe I find your presence reassuring.
Honestly, I don't get it.
You've known me...
...15 years.
- Yeah.
In 15 years, I never felt this
for a guy. Not once.
You know me, right?
I know I'm not queer.
It's just...
I think I love you.
Straight up,
I don't wanna kiss you...
...or sleep with you.
Maybe one day but...
Are you nuts or what?
What the hell is this?
You must be out of your mind.
What's wrong with you?
I'm your son's godfather. Get real.
Are you guys having a joke?
Max, please...
Don't react like this.
It only makes it harder for me.
I need your support.
As my buddy.
Not just as a friend...
My buddy.
You understand?
I don't know what to say.
Don't say anything.
It's okay if you can't find the words.
Just don't be scared.
Whatever shit you're pulling,
if this is true...
Max...
Please.
What?
- Pardon me?
Who's gonna do it? Me?
Tomorrow?
Don't put off till tomorrow...
Do it right now.
I don't understand.
Do it.
Mr. Cantara?
Your friend got the check.
Should I take it?
1 new message. Eric.
Cbll me. Usgent.
I was in a movie not so long ago,
with this guy I know, Philippe.
A skin flick,
but I had a few lines.
That was my first...
What do you want?
Are you kidding?
You asked me to call you.
No way.
What's wrong?
When?
No way. Why do you always
call me to get you out of shit?
You're a maniac.
See ya.
I'm on my way. Bye.
I don't believe it.
What's wrong?
A friend crashed his scooter.
He's in ER.
- Shit. I'll come with you.
That's sweet but...
Too fucking right I'm coming.
I just need to pee. You pay.
Come on...
A complete psycho,
you should have seen her.
What a bailer.
What are you up to? A drink?
No, no drink.
Why not?
I'm expecting someone.
Expecting someone?
Who?
Bye bye.
Fess up. Do I know him?
No, you don't.
He doesn't matter then.
Blow him off and let's go out.
I can't. Too late.
You prefer a new-age schmuck to me?
I'm on my way and I'm hungry.
Don't let your oldest friend starve to death.
Goodnight.
- Shame on you.
Hey there...
I brought you flowers.
Thanks.
How are you?
Come in.
You okay?
- Not bad, actually.
A bit out of breath.
Can you get rid of that?
Sure, sorry.
What are you doing?
I thought we'd watch the movie together.
I'd rather see it alone.
I can dig that.
I prefer watching movies on my own.
I'll be off then.
'Night.
I'll see you out.
Sorry, it's not my thing.
I know, it's cool.
See you soon.
- Bye.
Don't butter me up the right way.
I know you architects.
Let's not waste our time.
Do the job or I'll find someone who can.
Think it over and we'll talk.
Yes, I'll need time to think.
That's what I said.
Goodbye, Mister...
Lother.
- Exactly.
Hey.
Look...
Can we forget all about last night?
I was dumb, blurting that out.
Sorry it unnerved you.
I had to say it,
that's all.
I promise.
I won't mention it again.
I mean, it's ridiculous...
You know I'm not queer.
I don't give a damn if you're queer.
Not so loud.
Sorry.
Try to understand.
You know what I'm like.
That's why
I want you to forget our conversation...
...before it wrecks our friendship.
I don't know why I said it.
So...
Please accept my apology.
And above all,
keep all this to yourself.
Max...
I don't want anyone to know.
Okay?
And lastly...
I'll understand if you say no...
Elliot, Isabelle and me...
Does your invitation stand?
Sure. Just cut out
the l-Iove-your-hands bullshit.
Get some help.
I already said I will.
I won't say another word, I promise.
I gotta go.
I need a new architect.
No one gives it to me up the ass.
Don't worry.
See you tonight?
Sure.
Jesus, she's out of order.
My birthday and not even a message.
She left you
because you were scared she would.
Now what are you scared of?
Here, a little extra gift.
What is it?
My ad man pal's mobile. Call him.
Shit, I'm so lame. Sorry.
I forgot all about it.
So did he.
Why would he give a damn?
It's for you. Call him.
As soon as I settle the Juliette issue, okay?
Don't tell her I'm in the shit, will you?
We don't discuss you, Antoine.
You don't?
Thanks.
Just what we need.
Those guys keep staring at me.
Those guys over there keep staring.
It's weird,
people keep recognizing me.
Chill, you've only done two TV movies.
Owned, my friend.
She's right.
I'm just teasing.
Truth hurts.
Hey, Marie.
You're back, I see.
Yeah, I got back a few days ago.
How was the Amazon?
I shuttle back and forth.
Sure.
Goodbye, miss.
I don't get it.
They eat pussy.
She's not 14 anymore. Get over it.
You didn't know?
Excuse me.
Do you live in a cave?
She's not the first.
Get off her case.
I need a leak too.
Stop that. It turns you on.
You bet it turns me on.
I'll do it for you at home.
Are you nuts.
- What's the problem?
Don't joke about that.
- Not so funny now?
When it's your girlfriend.
- Stop.
I'd never have thought it.
To love.
To Ludo.
Pace e salute.
Hi, Brigitte.
- You're pathetic.
A real pain in the butt.
Hi, Brigitte,
how are you?
Good to see you.
- Same here.
Fuck it.
What?
That really pisses me off.
What? What's wrong?
Hi, Brigitte.
- Hello, Mr. Max.
What the hell's going on?
I don't understand.
How are you, Marie?
Good, Brigitte.
You got it the last 2 years.
- Last year was Ludo.
And I sleep with the kids?
Sure.
The bedroom?
Okay, but if Juliette comes...
Don't start with that.
We agreed it was off limits.
If she does, I get the room.
Yeah, yeah.
- No. I get the room.
Yes.
I'm here 2 months a year.
What do I pay you for?
You remember how much I pay you?
572 euros. Per month.
You could do jack shit all year,
I'd never know.
But when you know I'm coming,
would it hurt to mow the lawn?
What?
Three days ago? Bullshit.
I know my lawn.
I don't give a rat's ass.
I arrive with my friends
and now what do I look like?
Okay, if it was only the lawn...
How many times have I told you
about the hose?
I knew it, yellow marks.
Listen to me, dipshit.
You can tell that other dipshit,
I want my lawn looking like Versailles,
or your company's going belly under.
Calm down.
It's just fine. I'll mow the lawn.
Where's the mower?
I have to pick up Véro and the kids
at the station.
Want me to come?
I won't be long.
Can we buy food?
Wait for Véro.
You know what she's like.
How are you?
Wow.
He's in a bad mood.
Véro? This is okay surely?
Fine, block up your arteries,
but not in my house.
And not in front of the kids.
And this for when we're rushed?
Rushed? We're on vacation.
You don't respect your bodies.
That's not chicken,
it's industrial.
Full of antibiotics.
Yeah, but it's cheaper.
Sure, of course.
Organic's more expensive, sure,
but you don't get sick.
Or boost
pharmaceutical companies' profits.
Anyway, when did we ask you
to pay for anything?
Very subtle.
Please.
Screw it, I'm buying it.
- Me too.
Can I take us into the beach?
- Sure.
I've been learning.
I pass my test in two days.
You can rent one then.
Jean-Louis.
Run it up here, Max.
We'll anchor it later.
Sure?
The tide's going out, I'll be marooned.
It's a neap tide, you'll be fine.
Eric, I can't see a thing.
His tide book's from 1983.
I'm doing the ladder. Chill.
How are you?
Alright, Antoine?
- I'm good.
Look at this.
You put it in reverse?
Just back it up.
Bye bye, Maxie.
Shit. I knew it.
It's a motorboat, Max.
Use the motors.
See you tonight.
Hello, Jeanne.
Welcome aboard.
Welcome on board...
Remember? He wrote that for you
when you were born.
Yes.
Jean-Louis wrote it for me
when I was a little baby, one year old.
Littler than that.
What can you say in Spanish?
She speaks to the au pair in Spanish.
Say something in Spanish.
Go on.
Marie never heard you speak Spanish.
Wonderful.
It's great here, Jean-Louis.
I think I'll buy you out and fire you.
You loser.
Getting speaking parts
has gone to his head.
Speaking parts.
Know what?
It's fantastic having you all here.
I miss my little Ludo but...
Yeah, it felt weird when we arrived earlier.
He was still living wild?
He was wired when he had the crash.
Marie and I keep saying
we should clean him up.
But do you do anything?
I don't snort that shit with him.
Hold on...
The crash was my fault?
He's saying we're all to blame.
He said I encourage him.
Don't be silly. He didn't say that.
He's just worried. We all are.
I'll get some crack for the kids.
Want a hit?
The Amazon? Your Indians?
Sorry, excuse me.
I spent all winter there.
It was great to go back.
I taped over 35 hours
of ceremonial laments,
sublime chants...
Didn't you get my photos?
Sure.
With you painted all over.
I love it there. It soothes me.
It has it all.
Except rosé.
So she knocks it back here.
Thanks.
Can I have a word?
What?
- It's really important.
I know it's off limits,
but I'm confused.
Don't tell anyone I showed you.
You left some of you with me.
You left something at hers?
She means I left a little bit of me behind.
I'm in her thoughts.
Alright, okay. So what?
So, do I reply?
Definitely not.
What? I don't even reply?
No, don't do anything.
You and Max fell out?
No, we're cool. Everything's fine.
Right.
Antoine, push. Come on.
I know it's off limits,
but look what she sent.
Don't tell anyone I showed you.
I don't reply, right?
Sure you should reply.
That's really sweet.
What do I say then?
You work it out.
Vincent?
I was looking for you.
I need some advice.
I'll just get some clothes.
- Stay.
I want to know what you think too.
Sit down a minute.
Just there.
I have something to ask you.
Go on, I'm listening.
Can you take a break?
I can't think straight.
Let's go...
It's really important.
I'd like to keep it between us three.
Okay?
- Sure.
The other evening,
after my birthday dinner...
I saw Juliette.
You'll need all the details
to form an opinion so...
Poker anyone?
- We're talking here.
Close the door, will you?
So, the night of my birthday,
after we said goodbye...
Is this your bag?
After we said goodbye in the street,
I went home.
Except I snuck out again to go see...
To go see Juliette.
Wanna play poker?
Plant 5 trees in the Amazon...
That's good.
- And 5 in Africa.
We'll party like this every night?
Hold on,
I'm trying to get cable on the TV.
Go say goodnight to your children.
And take a Lexomil on the way.
Jesus.
Costs me a fortune...
...and they cut me off
the only time of the year I use it.
What are you doing?
Listen.
What?
The weasels are back.
They must have heard you.
I thought they'd got rid of them.
The fuckers'll eat the insulation.
I'm jinxed right now.
You reap what you sow.
What?
Give out shit, you get it back.
It's only logical.
Send out more positive vibes.
What's up with Vincent?
What do you mean, what's up?
I don't know. You're not talking.
We do, we talk.
Really?
When you're alone maybe.
Everyone's asked me about it.
Don't bother knocking.
Fuck.
Eric, can we talk?
Sorry, I'm closed.
I've really screwed up.
I'm so in the shit.
I don't know what to do.
Let me explain...
I wanted to send her something,
a quick text, see?
No, I don't see.
I told you not to.
Yeah, but...
What did you send?
I was going to put...
I don't know how to express...
...how happy I am I left a bit of me with you.
Exactly. That's why...
I tried to delete it
and I accidentally sent 'I don't know'.
What was her text again?
You left a bit of you with me.
'You left a bit of you with me.'
'I don't know.'
What a numbskull, seriously.
Great move.
I told you not to reply.
Max, Vincent and Isa
said I should send something.
What did you just say?
What?
- You're taking the piss?
About what?
You bust my balls with top-secret texts,
then you go ask the others?
No, I didn't...
Know what, my friend?
Grow a pair. You're 35.
It's time to grow up.
Goodnight.
Yeah, goodnight.
Marie, can you tell Juliette.
I didn't mean to send her that and I...
You're kidding me.
Goodnight.
What are you doing?
Trying to work out
how the little bitches get in.
Who?
The weasels.
Listen.
Hear that?
Light on or off?
- Off.
They're asleep.
It's a pleasure to see you.
Great news, you all being here.
It'll bring much joy and happiness.
It's good to see you too.
Good morning, Max.
How are you?
Hi, Nassim.
- I'm overjoyed to see you.
How you doing?
- Fine.
Morning, Jeanne. Morning, Arthur.
What beautiful children.
I said to Véro,
it's marvelous you all being here.
We'll share some good times.
Coffee, Nassim?
No, thanks.
Vincent and I are going running.
He called me to say
he wanted to get some exercise.
Come along.
I'm going to the market with Véro.
Hey, Nassim.
Great to see you.
- You too.
Morning, Max.
How are you?
I was telling Véro and Max...
...the joy I feel seeing you all.
A real buzz.
That's nice to hear.
Congratulations on getting up
to go running.
It'll do you good.
Too right. Look at this gut.
Alright, ready?
- Let's go.
See you later.
- Enjoy your run.
Can you give me a hand?
Maybe we should wake them.
- At this time?
Comes a time you have to choose.
Bed or boat.
I don't decide the time of the tides.
After 10, it's too late.
We can go later.
What's the problem?
Why'd I buy the damn boat?
What's that?
- Nothing.
Do we need towels?
It's up to you. I took one.
We'll be on a boat.
There's water all around.
Stop it.
It bugs me.
All I do for you guys...
Stop being like this.
We're out ofjam.
Where's Véro?
- Waiting outside with the others.
Waiting for me?
I woke you 2 hours ago to take the boat out.
An hour ago tops.
- No. It's gone 2 p.m.
Lemme eat this, grab a shower,
and we'll go.
I'll just put some shorts on.
What's this?
- The hotel security cameras.
You're leaving that on?
Apparently,
music keeps weasels away.
We'll see how they like that.
Bitches.
Faster. Faster.
Awesome, Max.
Stop.
Slow down.
We can't hear you.
Fantastic.
You were great. Great roll.
I told you not to go so fast.
Bunch of assholes.
That's right, have a good laugh.
You okay, Marie?
Fine, you little shit.
Give me the ladder.
When you calm down,
we'll let you up.
I am calm. Give me the ladder.
Give me the fucking ladder.
Calm down.
I am calm. Give me the ladder.
You can come out when you calm down.
Calm down for real, please.
Stop laughing.
Give me the fucking...
No way I'm giving her the ladder.
She's on her own.
Assholes.
- I'll help you up.
Fuck you all.
Stop laughing.
That's right, enjoy it.
Take some photos.
I'll wipe the fucking smiles off your faces.
Thank you, miss.
She's gone.
I swear.
You've no idea how jealous he got.
You're putting me on.
Ludo? Why didn't he tell me?
You know what he's like.
You think he'd tell you that?
He gave me shit for months,
saying I had a thing for you.
Well? Did you?
To be honest,
if I wasn't with him...
I might have been tempted.
Sorry, Isa.
It's fine, no worries.
Amazing. I didn't notice.
I never picked up on it.
Too bad.
I'm going to bed.
Hold on, I didn't mean...
I meant,
if you hadn't been together.
I'm not upset. I'm glad, in fact.
But I need to sleep.
Okay.
Everything's fine, Marie.
You coming?
- I'll be there in 5.
Goodnight.
Goodnight. See you tomorrow.
Shit.
It's cool, don't worry.
He followed me one day.
I swear he did.
All the way to your house.
And?
You know when you sense
someone's there. I turned round...
...and he was there peeking round a corner,
like in a cartoon.
Incredible.
He'd lost it or what?
I totally busted him.
I bet he felt stupid.
No, it was cute...
Perfect.
Let's do one last maneuver.
Man overboard, starboard side,
north-westerly wind.
Excuse me...
I'm sorry.
Put that away right now.
Yes, but it's Juliette.
I don't care who it is. Slow down.
You're going too fast.
Shit.
What do I do?
It's really important.
I'm very sorry.
I'll be right back.
Not at all.
And you?
We take the boat out, go swimming...
Fun stuff you do by the sea.
Colt Silvers.
Can you pull over so I can buy some stuff?
Fine, I'll pick up some wine.
You guys put it away.
We'll buy our share.
It's not a problem. I was only saying.
Saying what exactly?
Holy shit.
I love that smell.
Marie, smell this.
I'll pass. I feel a bit sick.
Is something wrong?
It brings back so many memories.
I'm just so happy.
You need help.
And these, and that's it.
Hold on...
Then 3 grapefruit and 5 oranges.
Jeanne's a beautiful little girl.
Hasn't she grown?
Thanks, that's nice.
How about some plums?
I have a list.
I'll take care of it.
I'll wait in the car then.
Should I go back to Paris?
No, I just need time.
Right...
Okay.
Can you hear me?
They said I couldn't talk long,
so I'll be quick.
I just wanted to tell you
something very important.
Keep it in mind always.
You're a beautiful person.
You're a really beautiful person, Ludo.
There aren't many people like you.
Even if it was long ago...
...and even if...
...we caused each other a lot of pain...
I'm proud that I was your girl.
I also wanted you to know...
Although you must have noticed...
That...
I mess up with all the other guys too.
That's all.
Thank you.
Hey.
Feeling better?
- Yeah, I guess.
Still a bit pukey.
- Same here.
Lea's not with you?
She missed her flight.
Wasted journey.
Damn.
- Yeah, it sucks.
That's enough, cut it out.
You're nuts.
You'll wake everybody up.
Give it a rest.
I'll just put it away.
- Leave it. Put it away later.
I don't believe it.
Later, they'll be having breakfast.
Shit.
It's gonna leave marks.
You're taking the piss.
Stop that. Stop.
Speak French.
Did you forget Lea?
She's stuck at the Opera.
Rehearsals or something.
She won't be here today.
Max, what are you doing?
Working out where they get in.
They'll leave prints in the sand
and then I can...
Why not go for a run?
Come on, it clears your mind.
You feel great afterwards.
I'm not changed.
I'll keep you waiting.
You go ahead.
We'll wait for you.
We're in no hurry.
Go on, just for me.
Can I come too?
Vincent never lets me.
As if.
Of course, you're welcome to join us.
More people, more energy.
Great. I'll just get changed.
Core exercise is crucial.
Your muscles will thank you for it.
You're doing them a favor.
Take in only the air you need.
Keep your breathing in sync
with your stride pattern.
There you go.
Even better is not to think about it.
I wasn't thinking about it.
I'm not used to those skis.
I couldn't slalom.
What are you doing?
Vincent hasn't had a go.
It doesn't matter.
You wanted to.
- It's fine, forget it.
Let's get moving before the tide goes out.
Yeah, with Ericjust now,
it wasn't very deep.
We'll go out tomorrow.
- No problem.
After 2 hours,
2 minutes won't hurt.
I wanted a drink with you guys.
Let Jean-Louis drive your boat then.
Alright, come on.
Don't worry, it's cool.
I said I'd take you.
Go on, Vincent.
Go on, Dad.
Thanks, Max.
- Let's clear up ready to go.
What's going on?
Anything wrong?
Can you all move forward?
Watch out.
Careful, on your left.
We're going aground.
Right, Jean-Louis.
Now straight ahead.
Get a move on.
Or we'll end up on a sand bank.
Get behind me, in my wake.
Let me pick up the others.
No time, you'll end up high and dry.
C'mon, let's go.
Move it.
Not that way, Max.
What a jerk.
Wait a second.
You've run aground.
Can't you give me a tow?
Too late. I'll be stranded too.
Just sit tight for 6 hours...
...until the tide comes back in.
You did this on purpose.
- What?
We gotta go.
To get the kids back.
Hold on, I'm coming.
Don't jump in.
- Shut up.
Don't jump.
It's mud.
I'm not staying here 6 hours.
You're being ridiculous.
Don't do that.
Shit, I'm stuck.
Watch out, you'll sink in.
Listen to Jean-Louis,
he knows his mud.
Come on, cut the crap.
Give me your hand.
Stop.
What's wrong?
- I'm losing my shorts.
Let go of me.
Cute butt.
Towel.
Give me the towel.
You did this on purpose.
- What's wrong with you?
A week ago,
you say you love my hands.
Now you get us stranded overnight.
No more, okay.
How could I have planned this?
2 years ago, for my coccyx,
you didn't need to use your finger.
The time you stuck your finger in my ass.
There must've been another way.
Stop this now...
- Get away.
It wasn't my fault.
In the bow.
- He told you to stay behind him.
Get lost.
Why didn't we ever hook up?
Here we go again.
Go on, tell me.
Every time you get dumped...
Bullshit. I haven't been dumped.
You don't fool me.
Pull that with the others, not me.
I think they know anyway.
Don't you wanna talk?
We can talk it over.
I look like Ludo, that's why.
C'mon, why not me?
You fuck anybody but me.
What's with you?
It's dumb,
we've known each other for years.
Exactly. I like it that way.
If we 'fuck', what happens then?
Stop that.
We're best buddies, we get on great,
what's with you?
I'd get on your nerves.
You know me.
Okay, a blowjob if you want.
Thanks, we really appreciate it.
Goodnight.
You're back? How was it?
Okay? You weren't too bored?
It's non-stop.
You're right about the noise.
What are you doing with that?
Hello there.
Well?
That's right.
I don't know...
I'm at a loss.
He'll wake the kids too.
I'm sorry.
I'll talk to him.
That's not a good idea.
What's he doing?
- Busting the wall.
To catch one, I guess.
He hasn't slept all week.
It's therapeutic.
Sorry.
What do you say now?
Hello.
Not so noisy now, are you?
It's the landlord.
What's the story with Max?
Look at me.
Hold on, don't move.
I'll be right back.
I don't give a hoot.
You okay?
- No.
I can't sleep.
I feel just great.
I've decided to stop pressuring her...
...and play it cool,
like I have a life too, you know?
You're going to bed?
Is our age difference the problem?
You gave me a fright.
I need to borrow some shorts. Can I?
What for?
To play soccer.
Jesus.
Where is everybody?
At the beach. It's gone 4.
Nobody got any sleep.
Is Véro mad at me?
She'd like you to chill out.
Hold on, wait for me.
Sam. What the hell was that?
Go back to playing marbles.
Try running.
Tackle him.
Let's get some focus.
Game faces on.
You know what we gotta do.
Bunch of losers.
Where were you?
We're in shirts.
- I didn't see you.
Look.
- Mark the little guy.
Your waitress is here.
Follows me everywhere.
I shouldn't have banged her.
She was born in '87.
I was in 9th grade.
Sorry.
Cut that out or I'll clock you one.
My friends. Good evening to you.
Hi, beautiful.
I never saw you in shoes.
Very true.
What's going on?
Those feet.
You get shoes made to measure?
Morning, ma'am.
Flip-flops, size 76, please.
You idiots.
I went to see Ludo.
Go on, how is he?
I got a real shock.
I didn't think it was that bad.
He's out of it,
but the doctors are optimistic.
I doubt he recognized me.
You made the trip in a day?
Sure.
Let's drink to his health.
Sorry, I started without you.
Did he open his eyes at least?
A bit, but he's totally drugged up.
But are you sure...
He's gonna be okay.
Say, Marie...
Look at me. He'll be okay.
He'll pull through.
It'll be okay.
Here, eat this.
A wonderful place you have, Max.
Thank you for your generosity...
...and your hospitality.
Yeah, it's a killer house. Sick.
What did I say?
Words are important, you know.
They have real influence on things.
By calling things sick,
they become so...
...in the bad sense.
You see?
Sure.
Use words for what they mean.
And what they imply.
There's an amazing experiment
by a Japanese guy, Masaru Emoto.
He filled two jars with rice.
He labeled the first one I Love You...
...and the other one I Hate You.
He kept saying those words to them.
After a certain amount of time,
the l-Iove-you rice was still edible,
but the other rice was rotten.
I cooked some rice.
Let's try it. It's awesome.
That's why people talk to plants
or play them music?
Exactly.
- It's wonderful.
Amazing.
But rice isn't an actual plant.
- Sure it is.
It's not a living organism,
it's hard.
I never get on with new-age types.
That's why I like you.
A guy I know has driven from Paris
to see me. He'll be here soon.
I didn't ask him to come.
A guy? What guy?
What do I tell him when he shows up?
Tell him to fuck off. Simple.
Let the poor guy stay the night,
600 km to see you,
you can't let him camp out.
Where's he gonna sleep?
Up a hole. Sorry.
There's the laundry or the couch.
In my room.
A quick shag never hurts.
Especially as he's a very good shag.
Great, it'll do you good.
Your body will thank you for it.
You're doing it a favor.
He won't let that one go.
Yeah, I know.
I call him then?
- Sure.
Pisses me off.
And the temperature in winter?
12° a day.
12°?
- Every day.
Does it ever hail here?
- Of course.
Twice we had hail.
In '67, I think...
...1, 2, 3, sun's up.
It works like clairvoyance.
Animals use it a lot.
For example, in Hiroshima,
the rats left the city
before the bomb even dropped.
Like the tsunami.
Animals bailed before it hit.
Why didn't we feel the tsunami coming?
Humans don't listen
to their intuitions and premonitions.
You have to learn to listen.
Humanity lives by answering questions
it hasn't asked.
I'm lost.
I feel dumb and that drives me mad.
Your musical sex toy has arrived.
Hey. You want some help?
You enjoy scamming my kids?
You're way out of line.
You think I didn't notice, you cheat?
You say 1, 2, 3, sun's up.
Then you turn round.
You go 1, 2, turn round,
then 3, sun's up.
Cut it out.
No more bullshit tricks.
Bedroom. Now.
Bedroom.
Good evening.
He was cheating.
Are you out of your mind?
Do you realize what you just did?
He was cheating.
He's a child. 6 years old.
Your godson.
Look at me when I bawl you out.
I'm sick of it.
Sick of your long face,
your pathetic hang-ups.
Your weasels, your tide times.
Relax or go back to work.
Give us all a break.
Don't invite your friends
if it turns you into the great dictator.
Honestly,
you're acting like a real prick.
Even I begin to wonder...
It's simple.
Stop making our lives hell...
...or I'll go back to Paris with the kids.
Why am I like this?
Go and apologize.
You'll see, it won't hurt.
What are you doing?
Don't leave, it's ridiculous.
Can we talk?
Please, put that down.
What's with you guys?
I've no idea, honestly.
You ignore each other...
...and neither knows why?
I'm sorry,
he always gets his panties in a wad.
He went too far, yelling at Elliot.
It's better if we go.
I can afford our own vacation.
I don't need him.
He can be a pain in the ass,
but you know he's a great guy.
Something's bugging him
and he won't talk.
Can I talk to you?
Forget it.
Let's have a drink.
You're shitting me?
Is that all you can say?
It's not easy.
You started all over at the soccer game.
I can't read you and it freaks me out.
Try to understand,
I can't take any more.
I try to make it a great vacation.
I take care of everything...
...and, whatever I do,
I'm the pain in the ass.
I can't relax.
Stop it, Max.
Every year you say that,
then you invite us all again.
That's not the issue.
Look how you chewed out Elliot.
He's a kid.
Leave him out of all this.
Yes, I know.
I was a jerk.
I'm really sorry.
I'll watch what I say from now on.
C'mon...
Stay.
We'll start over from scratch.
I'm warning you...
It's the last time.
- I promise.
But, please, you cut it out too.
Okay.
What kind of musician?
Musician.
That's yourjob?
- Yes.
Like you do nothing else?
- No.
Awesome.
Yeah, I'm lucky.
That blows me away.
Franck.
Sorry to barge in.
- No problem.
Elliot, I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have talked that way.
I shouldn't have yelled at you, see?
I apologize.
Okay.
I'm on-edge right now.
I know it's not an excuse
and it's not your fault.
It won't happen again.
Definitely not.
Let's go, kiddo, bedtime.
Goodnight, sweetie.
Say goodnight.
Where's Jean-Louis?
- He went home.
Say goodnight to the kids.
I need a drink.
- Me too.
What kind of ax have you got?
A J-45.
Gibson.
You wanna play by any chance?
That must be unbelievable in concert.
Just acoustic, it was fabulous.
Don't you think?
How about another?
I don't know.
Just a quick one.
Encore. Encore.
They're nuts.
We want more.
Good, you moved the table in.
You didn't get soaked?
- No, we're fine.
It'll blow over with the tide.
Did you sleep well?
Yes, I slept fine.
What will it be, Franck?
Tea? Coffee?
Coffee'd be great.
Coffee for me too, please.
I know that.
I got a gift for Jean-Louis.
- Why?
For yesterday.
We could drop by for lunch.
I'll call him.
You wanna come?
I don't know.
It's amazingly beautiful.
You have to meet Jean-Louis.
Like I said,
I've known him for years.
My dad worked at a wholesale market...
...and every summer
he sent me to Jean-Louis's dad's...
...to work in the oyster farm.
At 5 every morning
I sailed past these beautiful houses,
and said to myself,
One day, I'll buy one.
I'll be going. I don't want
to get back to Paris too late.
Son of a bitch motherfucker.
Screw you, asshole.
Blow me, you degenerate bastard.
You stink, asswipe.
It's our...
Shit-stinking, motherfucking scumbag.
I like you.
I'll give you lots of hugs and kisses.
You okay?
I'm okay.
You can come to Jean-Louis's.
Thanks, but I'll be off.
It's up to you.
I shouldn't have rocked up like this.
I had to do all I could to find out.
And I found out.
I'm not mad at you.
I respect you totally.
Even if I really, really love
making love with you,
there's a time when I need more.
6 months we've been sleeping together,
when you're around...
I see now.
I can't share things with you.
It's no big deal.
What is, is.
But it's not for me.
Let's end it now.
I don't want to get hurt.
Or hurt you.
Your guitar.
It's yours.
I can't play.
It'll be a chance to learn.
Take care of yourself.
Say goodbye, Elliot.
It was great meeting you.
See you soon.
- You have real talent.
Have a good trip.
Drive safely.
Yeah, thanks.
He's really got something.
I'm no judge of music, but he's got
more than one string to his bone.
Stop, please. Stop it now.
We're just saying...
I don't need your opinion of him.
I don't want it.
That's off limits too now.
What do we have to do?
Blow things up? Block the roads?
It's crazy.
You haven't heard the last of this.
Yeah, right. Thanks.
Fucking asshole.
Everything okay?
Don't ask. Who wants a drink?
I've got something for you.
C'mon, it's time for his surprise.
Hold on, just a second...
You're nuts. I won't use that.
To reach your boat in the morning.
4-stroke...
My motor's right here.
The day I stop rowing, it's over.
Thanks anyway, Max.
Why'd you buy me that?
No reason.
Like your present?
When does Lea arrive?
She's got rehearsals.
She's dancing in the new show by...
Découflé.
He is just so talented.
You heard about Juliette?
What?
Any news?
This morning,
she said she'd call me in 5.
Sounds complicated,
Lea and her flight.
A real struggle.
Yeah...
No, I'm struggling.
I don't know why...
I just mess up.
I realize I have no faith in love.
I expect it to go wrong one way or another.
So it's reassuring to be the one to blame.
I worry less about it going wrong
and when it does,
I feel kind of vindicated.
But I never move forward.
Never.
I'm the same.
It's not my news to break but...
Let it go now.
It's over with Juliette.
She's marrying him.
You're kidding.
Am I laughing?
Is Starckos here?
All of July, but he had to go.
Too much work.
We need a night out.
Can we take your car to go to Bordeaux?
Sure, with pleasure. When?
Right now.
We're gonna change and go.
No problem.
Just let me get the shopping out of it.
No, take mine.
Jean-Louis will give us a ride
and I'll help you unload your car.
What?
Nothing, sweetheart.
That's great. And unexpected.
Are you sure?
Good luck.
You too.
See you later.
Lea, it's me.
It didn't work.
Stop, please. Go away.
Open up. I need to talk to you.
It's really important.
I'm taking the intercom off the hook.
Go away.
Don't, Lea. Open up.
It's me. How are you?
I'm downstairs.
I am.
I need to talk,
can you come down?
I know but I...
Hold on a second...
I just want you to hear me out.
It won't take long, I promise.
Surely you can do that.
It's me.
You don't answer,
so it's over, we're through?
Great.
Look at me at least.
I came to see you. Look at me.
I drove 500 km to see you.
Come to the damn window.
I love you.
I never did that stuff on purpose.
I didn't know it hurt you.
What do I do now?
What do I do without you?
I don't get it.
11 years down the pan
to marry a guy you know a year?
It's not about time.
What is it about?
And why keep sending me messages?
If you're getting married?
It means you're not sure about it.
Are you sure?
You know what marriage means?
Yes.
I was fooling myself.
I saw in you what I wanted to see.
I've changed, for Christ's sake.
Can't you see that?
Can't you see what I'm doing?
Don't you see I believe in myself?
In us.
I have to go.
You didn't answer me.
Why the messages
if you're getting married?
I don't like you being alone.
Don't do it, Juliette.
Your life is with me.
I'm gonna stay here.
You have all night to decide.
If you don't come out by 7,
you'll never see me again, it's over.
Okay?
So get out of the car now...
...and after you close the door,
just do one thing for me...
On the way to that door,
think of all we had together.
All we shared.
When you open that door,
ask yourself if you want it to end here.
Hey, everybody. How's it going?
You're all alone?
Who's got my car?
Antoine.
He scored a chick in Bordeaux.
Good for him, having some fun.
We had a totally crazy night.
You weren't bored being third wheel?
I hit the dance floor.
You know I love dancing.
I saw Ludo this morning.
He recognized me,
but he's still in bad shape.
He can't speak,
he's hardly fizzing.
You saw Ludo in Bordeaux?
No. Because I was in Paris.
She left me.
She left me because I'm a selfish bastard.
The only girl who loved me for what I am...
And I blew it 'cos I'm a stupid jerk.
Sure but...
She's right.
I didn't deserve her.
At 60, I'll end up chasing after 20-year-olds.
Now I never want to hear another word,
not another word about this, get it?
Do you get it?
Will you please say yes?
Please.
We taking the boat out later?
A glass of red'll do you good.
You okay?
It's just a scratch.
I thought you said it was wrecked.
Sorry.
We found it like that at the rest stop.
It stands out more in daylight.
Really?
We'll see tomorrow.
As Véro says, it's all immaterial.
Hey, how are you?
I didn't expect you to react so well.
The vacation's done me a world of good.
It's so relaxing here.
It's great to see you.
- You too.
How are you, babe?
- Yeah, fine.
Hey, beautiful.
I know this is pretty weird for you,
but it's weirder for me.
Let's just act normal.
I'm so happy to be here...
...and to see you all again.
We're glad to see you too.
He'll stop hassling us about texts.
What's he saying?
What texts? That's bullshit.
Careful, she'll believe you.
You bet. Did you really?
Would I? Course not.
This calls for champagne.
You putting the lid behind you.
What did you say?
We put the lid behind us.
I'll get you for that, asshole.
You okay?
Sure.
Let's party, take your mind off it.
Party anyone?
- Let's go dancing.
We haven't been clubbing yet.
I'm in.
- You haven't?
I'm out.
You go, if you want.
What about you?
I'll stay here.
Let's go get changed.
Eric, poker?
No, he's coming with us.
I'm okay. I don't feel like it.
I wanna win my money back.
Dream on, buddy.
I'll just grab a shower.
Won't be long.
Don't be long.
I'm pleased for you.
Yeah, I'm pleased too.
This is how it works.
You talk to each one every day.
We all do it.
It's not what I thought.
It's relaxing. Who knew I'd declare
undying love to some rice?
Is Marie still asleep?
I guess so. We left without her.
It was 4:30.
I'd no idea you got home so late.
What were you doing till then?
I danced, then I had a gangbang
with 3 surfers on a trampoline.
The surfer boys rode that wave.
You missed out.
I don't like you being like that.
Fuck.
How is she?
- She's in the toilet.
I'll go.
It's me.
Are you okay?
Coming all the way from Valras Beach,
barefoot,
she needs no introduction.
She's divine, she's...
Ludovine.
Careful, you'll hurt him.
Hands off Neptune's son.
Get off, for Christ's sake.
You're freezing cold.
You're getting sand in my face.
Lighten up, we're on vacation.
I'm cool,
but you got sand in my face.
I've got one for you, douchebag.
The Z.
That's not a Z.
- It's my Z.
Ludo, demonstrate for him.
Like no one's looking.
Let's go.
It's not nice, killing live animals.
You're the best, dude.
You're the best.
Check it out.
It's bleeding.
I’ll leave you to enjoy the night.
I'll be up tomorrow at sunrise.
It's idyllic.
You don't have that.
You’ll never know...
Morning's too much for you.
I'd love to be there with you.
If I weren't an actor, I'd farm oysters.
No kidding.
Remember?
I swear I’ll be
at Jean-Louis's oyster beds at 5:45.
You wanna grab a bite...
Maybe some ratatouille?
Look at the state of you.
There we go. He kept his word.
Our hero is aboard.
Nothing stands in his way.
Stop filming me.
Puke stew.
A tasty dish consisting mostly of corn...
...made by our friend Rico,
who looks like he's...
Give me a slug of beer.
No.
C'mon, you big faggot.
Shit, Eric. There are children.
Sorry.
What's a faggot?
Ask your dad, he knows.
Elliot, come here, son.
Faggot is a very bad word.
It means a homosexual and a homosexual...
...is a man who loves another man.
There's nothing wrong with that.
You just have to respect it.
Because it's still love.
Understand?
Come with me.
Kids...
Jeanne, Arthur, come with me.
Kids, wait here for me.
Don't move, I'll be right back.
Got something to say?
Say it.
Tell them.
- Stop.
Calm down.
Let go of me.
You prefer talking to my son?
What the hell is all this?
I don't get it.
- You don't get it?
You saw, didn't you?
Give me your teddy, please.
Lift your arm up.
You okay, pops?
Okay.
Calm down.
All my love.
We can do this another time.
Jean-Louis,
I guess the ban on oyster sales...
...with the big season coming up...
If you need any help financially,
just shout.
I can help, if you want.
I'll be fine.
Are you sure? Why?
I'd rather you offered in private
without people to impress.
It's not to impress...
I don't care about the money.
I don't care, get it?
Cut that out now.
Sorry, but I can't pretend...
No one's asking you to pretend.
No, but you all do.
What's eating you?
You've spent 2 weeks lying to each other.
What?
You earn your living from it.
You made it an art.
Easy now. What's got into you?
You guys have.
Right under my skin.
You show off to everybody,
especially your friends,
flaunting your success.
Where does it get you?
You don't enjoy it.
The biggest boat, the swankiest house,
the goldest gold card...
But your heart's like everyone else's.
You can't buy an upgrade.
Worst of all,
you lie to yourselves.
Every single one of you.
You buy into each other's lies.
Call yourselves friends?
What's friendship?
Leaving a pal in the hospital
'cos your vacation matters more?
Cut it out now.
What's your problem?
You bust our balls with your stupid texts,
but did you call the hospital
to see how he was?
He's dead.
Hear me?
He died this morning all alone.
I'm sorry, it's...
Vincent just called me.
If there's one man I believed in...
...it's Ludo.
I'd like to talk about his generosity.
He was...
You could go to see him anytime,
he was there for you.
To talk to you.
Even when he was down,
and he often was,
he was so generous that...
...he forgot to think of himself.
Since we met,
and in the last few years especially,
you kept telling me...
...that life is to be lived.
You gave me the strength...
...to live some extraordinary experiences.
You gave me the strength
to imagine us living together one day.
How could I have done it without you?
How will I keep going without you?
I always told you everything...
...and I have so much still to tell you.
I don't know what to expect...
...but I'm expecting a baby.
Have a great journey, Ludo.
I'll love you all my life.
Ludo...
Buddy-o...
My pal...
The fun we had. Damn.
We had some amazing times together.
I tried, I swear. I tried but...
I promised I wouldn't...
You gave us so much. All of us.
I didn't give you as much back.
I doubt I gave you as much but...
It was good being with you.
Being your friend.
Don't cry.
Look at me.