Phaedra!
Stravos!
Thank you, Thanos, here's to number 60.
Drink to 61, she's
already in construction.
Thank you.
Dime'.!
Everyone says she's a beauty.
Here's your present.
I be! It's a cigarette case.
How did you know?
A! Every baptism of a ship I design,
he gives me the same present,
a gold cigarette case.
That's not to break my luck.
Don't you like them?
I love them, but I keep
telling you I don't smoke.
Congratulations.
Thank you, Ariadne.
Uncle, is my present beautiful?
For you, only beautiful presents.
No, no, this one is for your mother.
Ariadne.
Thank you.
Here's yours, Ercy.
Mommy, may I open it now'?
Yes.
Andreas.
Thank you and congratulations, but, uh,
aren't you going too fast'?
Not fast enough.
I want to catch up with you.
Ah?
Then between the two of us,
we could destroy any monster
of the sea and elsewhere.
Are you proposing a merger?
I'm proposing a merger.
Well, suppose you catch up first.
Uncle Thanos!
Put it on me.
When I baptize my next ship,
maybe I'll name it after you.
Would you like that, hmm?
SS Ercy.
Mommy, did you hear?
. Hey!
Come on, they want a picture
of the old sea monster
and his sons-in-law.
Did you give Grandpa his present'?
The first one.
Come on, come on, it's time.
Come on.
Just a minute.
Phaedra.
Phaedra,
your present.
It's perfect.
Anna.
LOOK.
Open your bag.
Take these.
1 3333 rial I;'; Ilfl 'ii
I have the most beautiful
daughters in all of Athens
and my sons-in-law are the most powerful.
And you the strongest of us all.
Of course.
I christen this ship Phaedra.
May God bless her and all
those who sail with her.
1 3333 rial I;'; Ilfl 'ii.
Ercy, you look pretty tonight.
Thank you.
They are powerful.
They speak many languages
and they celebrate with fire in the sky.
Oh, no, it is I who open the dance.
1 3333 rial I;'; Ilfl 'ii.
Pardon.
Andreas, business during my party'?
Just a minute.
I'm sending someone a birthday telegram.
Ah, a birthday telegram.
Yes.
What time is it now in Brussels?
In Brussels?
Only an hour earlier than here.
Yes, of course.
Well, say happy birthday from me, too.
It's a lovely party, Mr. Karillis.
Thank you, your Highness.
If you decide to stay
in Greece for a while,
we'll have reason for another party.
Let's dance.
It's your night, Phaedra.
You look beautiful.
Mother is more jealous of you than ever.
. EFCY-
- Really, Phaedra, I know everything.
About what?
About how Uncle Thanos
was crazy about Mommy first,
and he divorced the English woman for her,
and then you came back from Switzerland,
and he fell madly in love with you,
and the son of the English woman hates you
instead of Mommy.
Will you dance with me, Ercy'?
You came just in time.
Take her away.
Phaedra, I'm going to do the same thing.
I'm going to lure all the
men away from their women.
That's Renee Felere.
He owns all those uranium mines.
Do you know any girl
who wants a uranium mine?
They accepted, all of them.
The prince, too'?
They're all on my payroll.
The power you have over people,
it must be exciting to you.
From time to time.
And the power you have over men,
is it exciting to you'?
From time to time.
Come with me.
She has everything she could want.
But so do you.
Of course.
Psst!
Listen, I'm going to disappear.
What HOW?
Brussels, something big.
Tonight?
Now.
I'll be back for lunch tomorrow.
Make it on the yacht and invite Andreas.
I want to see the expression on his face.
Will you never be satisfied?
No.
They're exploring (hose
other planets just for me.
I'm tired.
I'm worried.
Talk to me, Anna, talk to me.
All of Athens is at
your fee! And you're sad.
Anna.
What am I worried about?
Mr. Thanos?
I don't know.
It's Thanos!
How many helicopters does he own?
Even he doesn't know.
I said happy birthday in person.
Bravo.
Bravo, bravo.
You're beautiful, I love you!
Come on up,
we've already finished.
I'm not hungry, just throw me a grape.
I could take you to court.
The Belgians and I had a deal.
Did they sign?
We shook hands.
Maybe it was to say goodbye.
We shook hands on a deal.
We shook hands on a deal, too,
but after they signed.
Bravo.
You told me to catch up, didn't you?
Yes, bu! Not so fast!
Thanos, you're a pirate.
One day you'll be hung
by your own ambition.
I'm ambitious, my queen, only for you.
Why do men dedicate all
their crimes to women?
I can't anymore.
Congratulations, Phaedra,
your new cook is a wonder.
You steal her and there will
really be war in the family.
Come on up.
Thanos, but I've forgotten
to congratulate for your son, Alexis.
He didn't get married, did he'?
Didn't you see the Sunday Observer?
At an exhibition of young
painters he got very nice reviews.
That's worse than getting married.
But it can'! Be.
Alexis goes to the London
School of Economics.
We spent the weekend
in London 10 days ago.
He never said a word about painting.
I think they even
mentioned you, wait a minute.
Ercy, did you keep the
copy of the Observer?
It's in my cabin, but I remember it.
I was thrilled for you, Uncle Thanos.
It said, "if young Alexis
Karillis keeps working",
"he may well become lo painting"
"what is illustrious
father is to shipping."
Damn!
Tomorrow I'm going to London.
F' I
I've got to be in Rotterdam tomorrow.
Phaedra,
you'll go to London for me.
BM I...
You're going to Paris for your dresses,
you'll go by way of London.
Bring him to Paris, I'll meet you there.
But he's always refused to see me.
It's different now.
His mother remarried and he's grown up.
He'll like you.
Just get him away from London
and these young painters,
then between us, we'll
persuade him to spend
the wonderful summer in Greece.
You're very anxious to
have him here, aren't you?
I love my son, and you know it.
Of course,
but is that the only reason?
No,
it's not the only reason.
This time I buy every
dress in the collection.
Don't go, I had a bad dream.
Don't be ridiculous.
Don't pack that ring,
I wear it on the trip.
Anna, what's wrong?
Give it to me.
Anna.
I don't want you to go.
In my dream, two boys
were fighting with spears.
One was your son,
the other the son of the foreigner.
Why do you want to frighten me'?
Protect his fortune, he's only a child.
Your husband will put the
son of the English woman
in the shipping.
He's building an empire.
He needs a prince.
And my father, he sees everything.
He sees in the dark.
Do you think he let everything go
to the son of the foreigner?
All my dowry went into those ships.
I'm afraid.
I have a message
for you Mrs. Karillis.
Mr. Karillis is detained.
He would like you to pick
him up at the British Museum.
He will wait for you in the entry room.
Are you all right?
Yes, I'm sorry, I.
You're Alexis.
Mes,
and you're Phaedra.
Yes.
Never let them photograph you.
They'd make you look pretty,
and you're not pretty.
Your face is unique.
I never saw a face like yours.
Don't turn away.
We're here to know each
other, Father's orders.
Do you always obey your father's orders?
They are sacred.
Well, he commands you to
like me and me to like you.
And do you always obey his orders?
I write them.
Aphrodite, headless,
reclining on the lap of her mother.
Aphrodite.
I need some air.
Please, let's go.
Come on.
I don't call you Mother, do I'?
If you do, I'll kill you.
You know,
in London one can walk
and talk at the same time.
What should we talk about?
Me.
When did you being to paint?
A few years ago.
Does I! Mean a lot to you'?
I don't know yet.
And the London School of Economics?
Ah, I'm mad for it, I'm
glad you brought it up.
Must drop in one of these days,
I haven't set foot there
the whole semester.
Good morning?
Good evening?
Good.
Eyes?
Hands?
Uh,.
Bravo, and when I say
my body hurts,
that means in Greek my feet hurt.
I thought you liked walking.
Not in these shoes.
Well, come on, I'll buy you others.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
Goodbye, sir.
I look funny.
You look funny all right.
Sir,
don't stare at my mother.
I beg your pardon?
That means thank you in Greek.
Uh-huh, very welcome, sir.
Yes.
Didn't your father teach you any Greek?
No, Mother wouldn't let him.
She thinks all Greeks are savages.
Where is your mother now?
In Hong Kong, her new husband's there.
He's with the diplomatic corps.
You must love her very much
to hate me as much as you did.
Well, you know how kids are,
intolerant little puritans.
But now I know their marriage was wrong
and that you're the perfect
woman for my father.
Shall we talk about him now'?
We have serious things...
Later.
And you have lot of friends here?
Oh, yes, hundreds, nice friends.
Girls?
. One,
one beautiful, miraculous girl.
Well that may complicate things.
Your father doesn't know about her.
You're gonna tell him.
. Me?
Yes.
You're gonna meet her right now.
It's impossible.
Why'?
Not in these flat shoes.
Oh, she won't notice
the shoes, I swear it.
Please-.
Come meet my girl.
Stop, there she is.
There's my girl.
Excuse me, please.
I haven't kissed her today.
Make my father give her to me.
Tell him I'll give up painting.
Tell him I'll give up breathing.
He's half Greek, very impulsive.
It's his girl.
Now, we talk seriously.
You are my prisoner,
I'm taking you to Paris.
Your father wants to talk
to you about your future.
You are young.
Yes, Mommy.
I hate giving advice.
I'm not your mother, I...
You're my stepmother,
as wicked and ugly as
a fairytale stepmother,
and I adore you, and will
you tell him about the car?
You're a child.
Yes, Mommy.
Will you talk to him?
I will, and don't call me Mommy.
No, ma'am.
You like your father?
Uh, he's mad,
but maybe he's a great man,
I like him when I see him.
He wants to see more of you-.
He wants you to come to Greece-.
Greece, to stay'?
Forever?
Your father stays in no place forever.
He's a meteor.
Why didn't he ask me before?
Why now?
Probably because of me.
He knew you hated me.
Why are you helping him?
I was going to Paris
to buy some dresses.
He asked me to come by way of London
and give you the message.
I did.
. Please,
be forgiving.
I only hated you until I met you.
Now I'm crazy about you.
And now I'd like you to dance with me,
so that everyone will look
at me with dark jealousy.
Please?
I made up a poem for you.
Would you like to hear it?
Of course.
Do you like it?
Very much.
Let's stay here for a few minutes.
All right.
Driver?
Yes, sir?
We're gonna stay
here for a few minutes.
Just go around once and then pick us up.
Very good, sir.
Please come to Greece-.
At least come to Paris
to talk to your father.
I would like you to
want me to come to Greece,
because you would like
me to come to Greece.
I do, I wish it with all my heart.
LOOK.
In ancient Greece when they
wished something very hard,
they would make a sacrifice.
They used to carry a pig into the water
and offer it to the gods.
A pig'?
. A Pig,
but I have no pig.
Then sacrifice something else.
I could sacrifice this ring.
You could not.
Hey!
Hey.
Touch it.
Look at it.
It's beautiful, is it not'?
Yes, it's beautiful.
Now give it to me.
I wish that you come to Greece.
- Hey!
- You're crazy!
You're crazy!
7,000 pigs into the Thames!
Seven million pigs into the Thames!
For you.
For me.
Come on, you sluggard!
We're going to Paris!
P.
I missed you.
This time was the longest.
But you did well.
You brought me my da Vinci.
I never said I was da Vinci.
Can you become a da Vinci?
Well,
I'd say the odds are against it.
Then don't paint.
Stop.
I don't have to be da Vinci.
Sometimes little painters
can get as much satisfaction
as big ship owners.
Don't be so sure.
The bristles on your
paintbrush come from India,
could be one of my
ships that brought them.
This coffee from Brazil.
I have 22 ships that carry
trade from South America.
This wood from Sweden,
maybe on one of my ships.
Tell him if that give satisfaction.
My ships cross every ocean
and bring life lo the world.
And a fortune to you.
That's right, and I earn it.
I love this woman.
I'd like to stay with her tonight,
but in a few hours I be in the air.
ThHHOS.
Can't help it.
And tomorrow in New York.
Where's my beautiful ring?
I throw it into the Thames.
Don't be angry, my queen.
I've got to go.
Nico!
How are you going to travel?
Nico is driving me.
“In!
The car is ready, sir.
But if Nico goes?
Keep the house closed, go to a hotel.
I can still get a
plane for London tonight.
I have classes tomorrow.
All right.
Stay, don't go tonight.
Darling, it's impossible.
A million people are wailing for me.
Find an excuse, say you are ill.
Who would ever believe that'?
I've never been ill in my life.
It's raining.
And now, it's important for him, too.
Please-.
If I make this project
happen, it's an atom bomb.
Andreas will die.
Come on.
So long, da Vinci.
You made me very happy.
I promise you a wonderful summer.
See you soon.
So long.
See ya soon.
Ah, reservations, please.
Uh, hello, you still have a
flight for London tonight,
can you get me on?
Damn!
Excuse me.
Can you see about another line, please?
Alexis Karilliss at 12-23-18-.
Call me back as soon as you can, will you?
Thank you.
They're calling me back
about the plane.
There may still be a flight on Olympic.
You needn't wait.
You must be tired.
Please help me.
I'm sorry you hate me again.
I love you.
Thank you.
When I say I love you,
that means I'm in love with you.
I'm cold.
I'm a little cold.
You're my first love.
Wait, I have to pick up a
lady, I'll be out in a minute.
A lady'?
Out in a minute from Dior?
Please pay, I can't wait, I'm too old.
Ah!
I'm looking for Mrs. Karillis, please.
Right upstairs.
Thank you.
Phaedra?
Did you call me'?
No, no, uh.
I'm looking for Mrs. Karillis.
I'll show you.
She'll be right out.
Do you like it?
It's magnificent.
Wait, there are others.
Just a minute.
Come a little closer.
Closer.
We're leaving.
I want to make love to you now.
I'll give you two minutes.
Ah, just let me...
Not another step.
Not another second.
That's pretty.
Do you want to go out'?
Do you know for how many
days you haven't gone out?
What does that mean'?
My love.
Sounds funny.
Oh, no, it's pretty.
A happy word.
I'm happy,.
Can I have a kiss'?
Yes.
. New?
Well?
P
I like it.
What's it about'?
Like all Greek songs,
about love and death.
What's it say?
His beloved is watching in the doorway.
I give you milk and honey.
In return you give me poison.
He loves her cold nose.
Falcon of solitude.
Phaedra,
what are we gonna do'?
Not yet.
We have to talk.
Please, not yet-.
Yes.
YES.
J1 Da da da da da da da.
I1 Ba dada da da.
J1 da da.
J1 La la la la da da da.
I1 Ba da da da da dum da dum.
J1 Da da da da.
I1 Ba ba barn ha ba barn
flLa la la la la la la.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Don't touch me.
I don't recognize you.
I don't know you.
So much the better.
Phaedra, listen, whatever it is.
It's New York.
They announced the call
when you were in the shower.
Don't answer it.
Don't answer!
Hello, yes?
Yes, yes, I'll take it.
Don't.
Yes, Thanos.
Fine.
Yes, yes, I hear you well.
Congratulations.
What?
He went back to London.
The night you left.
He didn't say.
I know he promise, but he didn't say when.
No, I'm fine.
No, I didn't spend too much money.
When'?
All right.
I look forward to seeing you.
YES.
Goodbye, Thanos.
You're coming to London with me.
That's impossible.
Anything else is impossible.
Anything else is horrible!
Don't come to Greece.
Don't come to Greece!
Anything else is ugly!
Don't come to Greece.
What does that make me'?
What does that make you?
Don't come to Greece.
Welcome back, Mrs. Karillis,
I hope you had a good trip.
Very good, thank you.
Welcome, Mrs. Karillis.
Mr. Karillis asked me to meet you.
Thank you, Stravos.
Welcome back, Mrs. Karillis, good trip?
Very good trip, Anna, thank you.
May I congratulate you'?
Everyone says that Mr.
Karillis' conference in New York
will bring great results.
- Thank you.
- Do you want me to go
to go to the island
or stay in Athens?
Stay here.
If you give me your
passport and tickets,
I'll get your through quickly.
Thank you.
The others
waiting at the terminal.
Welcome, Mrs. Karillis!
Thank you.
Welcome back, Mrs. Karillis.
It's Mr. Karillis!
Phaedra!
Poor thing, she looks so tired.
Somethings wrong.
Oh, my present!
Give me your hand.
Thanos, it's so beautiful.
Thank you.
Such a pitiful little thank you.
Let me sleep, I'm so tired.
No.
I'm tired.
See you tomorrow.
I'm crazy about you.
Alexis.
My baby, what's wrong?
Give me a cigarette.
What's wrong?
I hurt.
Where?
Everywhere.
What is it?
Tell me.
Tell me like you always do, I help you.
I live only for you.
I don't wan! To live.
And your husband and your child,
only now in the cards I saw
a boy trampled by horses.
If you disappear,
the son of the foreigner
will take everything.
He will do evil to your son.
Quiet, quiet!
Don't talk like that about him ever, ever!
. Baby,
turn around.
Let me see your face.
LOOK.
I love him.
I love him!
No, I, I said I won't wait!
Get the number and get it now.
And don't talk to me that way.
I don't care what!
Well, well then, do your job!
You had enough time to get me Bombay.
Give me the Athens operator.
Phaedra!
Hello, hello, Operator?
I've been trying for, all
right, give me Chelsea,
one, two, one, eight-.
This time of morning should
get London in few minutes.
Don't argue with me.
Get the number.
What does this telegram mean?
The lakes of Scotland'?
He must have said something to you.
I'd rather vacation on
the lakes of Scotland.
What the hell kind of nonsense is that?
You kept him away.
Your father called you, didn't he?
Your father wants to
swallow the whole world.
All right!
He helped me in the beginning,
but I am not at the beginning anymore.
He doesn't want my son
in business with me,
and it's because of your son!
Isn't my son yours too'?
He is, and no one wants to hurt him,
but no more!
I don't want to hear anymore
Alexis dishonor the foreigner.
He's my son, and you'll
call him by that name,
and your father will
call him by that name!
My father knows nothing about it.
Alexis would just rather go to Scotland.
I said nonsense!
I need him.
I asked for you help.
Forgive me.
I wasn't able.
Ah,
I'm a bull, I make noise.
No, don't spoil my beautiful eyes.
I adore you.
If somebody talked to
you like I did just now,
I'd kill him.
Wouldn't I?
“Mm?
My queen, my beautiful.
Phaedra?
THBHOS!
Forgive me.
The next time I shout at you,
don't stop, just, just
scratch out my eyes.
Just let me rest!
Let me TESL.
Hello, yes?
Yes!
Phaedra.
Alexis, what the hell
does that telegram mean?
You promised, boy.
All the way from New York,
I kept saying to myself
that this summer Alexis will be with us.
More than I can tell you.
Sure, for
business, but more for you.
Are you crazy?
Wait, she wants to talk to you.
Please-.
Just a second, she's coming.
How are you, Alex'?
I'm all right.
Tell him how much we want him.
Please come-.
Please-.
Tell him I've ordered
his car, it's coming here.
Your car will be here,
your dream car.
Come quickly.
Alexis, ah, you see?
Yes, yes, you just call
Fergus at my office.
He'll take care of everything.
After the exams.
Wonderful!
Hurry, witch, tell me.
Mommy!
I see two whales and a spy submarine.
Poor little boy, and he's so amusing,
but I think I was condemned
to some punishment
before I was born.
I have no sense of being a mother.
You rememberl could never hold him,
afraid that his little hands would break'?
Maybe it's the mother
that's coming out now.
Oh, no, you found the one thing
I don't have to worry about.
I don't have to think that
when I'm 45 he'll be 35.
We, we last like this.
Oh, no, I'm not afraid of that.
He'll never see me old.
That's my girl.
Now I know you.
You're laughing again.
Yes, I'm laughing, laughing.
Quickly, quickly,
quickly.
Got here before he did, connections.
He'll be so happy-
You don't know how much he love that car.
Okay-
- Uh, Mr. Karillis?
What is it?
Don't you know, Cristo?
To me, it looks like a big coffin.
It's the fastest coffin you ever saw,
driven by hundreds of horses.
Horses?
Don't try to figure it out, Cristo,
just let me know when
my coffin is open, huh?
I love you.
Why did you make me come here?
How did you plan it?
How much time in my father's bed'?
How much time in mine?
You're ugly.
Hey!
. Hey!
You keep a promise.
I keep a promise.
Phaedra, what are you doing?
Go to hell!
Come on, girl.
Now we go.
(engine revs}.
That's a good girl.
I have got to admit.
You are both very amusing.
Come on, we're going out.
I arranged a little party.
We need company.
I've invited people.
' Who?
Surprise.
Darling, they're here!
Darling, I'm so happy to see you!
Uncle Thanos!
Ercy, this is my son, Alexis.
Oh, wonderful to have a handsome cousin.
Not your cousin, Ercy, but
I let you kiss him anyway.
Andreas.
Thanos, you look fine.
Arianda, you're beautiful.
This is my son Alexis.
Alexis.
You're looking well, Phaedra.
You, too, Ariadne.
Andreas.
Phaedra, Ercy.
Thanos, next lo me.
Alexis.
Ah, the young people together.
Good.
There you are, speak to Alexis.
You are your father's favorite subject.
More than ships?
He's not English, he's Greek!
Do you like the beach?
What I've seen so far is beautiful.
Now he's English.
Ercy, do you want to see the jukebox?
So then we have to go
all the way over there,
and everyone can hear.
Pick me!
After jukebox.
He's definitely English!
Come on.
Come on, Phaedra, dance with me.
Phaedra, will you dance with me'?
Half close your eyes
like this and look at them.
Why'?
Go ahead.
What do you see?
I half see the children.
And I half see us
when we were like them.
Instead of cruising around,
why don't you all come to
the house for a while, hmm?
Maybe.
Alexis,
dance with me.
He's delicious, I could eat him up.
Andreas, I'll buy you a cigar.
I got a cigar.
I'll buy you another one.
Come on.
The last time we danced,
you made up a poem.
Do you remember?
No.
I do, do you want to hear it?
Speaking of eating,
what do you think of the
appetite of our father-in-law?
. Big-
Separately, one by one,
he can swallow us whole,
but if we get together,
indigestible.
Phaedra,
please help me.
Let me go.
I can't.
Get in, come on.
Come on.
Hey!
I'm not gonna be blase,
it's exciting, tremendous.
Ah, this is only the repair yard.
. Hey!
Somebody told them I
get my feet pedicured.
I'll never live it down.
Hey, take your foot out of my sky!
To me, you used to be
a name in a newspaper,
but here I can see you and touch you.
That's a wonderful process.
You take an older ship
and cut off both ends,
then we make new ones, much larger,
and attach them to the middle.
The same ship is twice as big.
Extraordinary.
All this makes me feel very foolish
with my paint box and my exams.
I'm thinking of putting
this yard in your hands.
No, don't!
I, I mean, what would I do with it?
You'll build it, you'll make it bigger,
then you'll give I! To your son.
And when I'm old,
you'll name a little tanker after me.
Ercy, Emy!
Alexis, come on, we'll
be the last ones there.
- Ercy, Ercy!
- One moment!
One, one, one, two, three,
one, one, remember,
we don't hold hands when
we do the cha-cha-cha,
but always look in my eyes.
That's what makes it sexy.
Ercy,
I hear every word you say.
Mommy, you know who's
going to die of jealousy?
Who'?
Eleni, she asked me about Alexis.
I got very mysterious and said,
I don't tell you anything,
so naturally she thinks
we're at least engaged.
Alexis,
a girl named Eleni will be at the party.
She's old, about 24, and a man-eater.
Yeah, yeah.
Keep away from her.
Mommy, may I take some of your records?
Go ahead.
Thanks.
They're charming together.
What do you think of the idea of Thanos?
Which idea?
You know which one,
to marry the children.
What did you say?
You mean he didn't tell you?
Oh, the sly one.
What is it?
Nothing.
Why do they play that music so loud'?
Oh, let them play, they're young.
Well, what do you think?
It can't be, they're related.
Why'?
Alexis is not your son.
Ercy's a child.
You're mad, all of you.
She's ripe, Phaedra, she's ripe,
and it would make us
the most powerful family
in Greece.
Mommy, do you think
I should wear this'?
. L come up!
Anna, help me.
I'm losing my mind.
Put that boy out of your heart,
or everything will fall.
There will be no marriage.
Hi, Mommy.
Ah, I lost a buck.
I wouldn't be afraid
of Eleni if I were you.
Phaedra, he's a shark.
Come and bring me luck.
Soon, Thanos, soon.
That's no
way to dress for a party.
How do you think the
others will be dressed?
Come in.
Your father is planning
for you to marry Ercy.
I warn you.
I will not allow it.
I can just imagine
what Eleni will be wearing.
'If l_, ll .3:, 1»,
Phaedra,
I didn't hear what you said.
Say it again.
Clearly.
I said your father is planning
for you to marry Ercy.
I will not allow it.
Why'?
How long is Eleni staying?
Don't provoke me, Alexis.
I don't care if the
whole world burns down.
Please, may I stay another week?
I love you.
Remember the ring?
I'd sacrifice anything to kiss you.
Go on.
Kiss me now.
Here.
I'll kill ya.
Let me alone or I'll kill you.
I wouldn't be
afraid of Eleni if I were you.
Who said I was afraid?
Ercy, ready'?
Ready, Alexis.
I'll kill you.
Come on.
Phaedra.
He loves me, Anna.
I swear to you, he loves me.
He loves me.
Shh.
How did you know I was Eleni
even before we were introduced'?
Oh, you couldn't be anyone else.
You're the first
Englishman I ever liked.
Fee-fi-fo-fum.
What?
I'm a woman-eater.
' Change.
Do I know you well enough to kiss you'?
No.
Should I let that stop me'?
Yes.
Why do you want to kiss me'?
I want to kiss all the girls.
That's not very complimentary.
I mean, uh, I wanna kiss
you because you're beautiful.
' Change.
Too late.
I saw you kiss Eleni.
Do you like her?
I don't like you.
Then come closer.
Why don't you kiss me'?
Because you're different
and because you have a buck tooth.
Phaedra won't let me fix it.
She says it's charming.
It is charming.
You're a sweet, little girl.
I'm not sweet, I'm not a little girl,
and on night I'll come to
your room and seduce you
and don't laugh.
Hello.
Why are you drinking so much'?
Because, little cousin, I'm thirsty.
You want to get drunk'?
Mm-Hmm.
Please-.
Whiskey.
An Englishman is what he wears.
In those clothes you could be Greek.
I am Greek.
Throw it.
Form fair, throw feeble.
Let's try it in English.
Would you do this, please?
Would you?
I declare myself the winner.
A winner should get a reward.
I'm going down to the cabin.
Drink?
No.
DEUCE?
I see you and Eleni.
I see everything.
Little cousin, you don't own me.
Why does everybody think they own me'?
Nobody owns me.
I1 Ba dada da da
flDada
. em'-!
EN?!'-
- I don't want to see you again.
I don't want anyone to say
your name in my presence.
Don't worry.
I'll be going away soon.
The sooner the better.
I don't want you to go away.
Don't go away.
I make believe you were drunk and,
and you don't like Eleni better than me'?
No.
Kiss me-.
Try to fall in love with me.
Phaedra!
Don't call her.
Alexis.
Go on, go in now.
Go on!
Phaedra.
I don't have time to
talk to you now, Ercy.
I'm going to Athens.
Athens?
At this time of the...
Don't bother me now, Ercy.
Don't be angry with me.
It's the first time in my life
that I stayed out all night.
I love him.
I want him to love me.
Help me.
Tell me how to be attractive to him.
I know he can love me.
L can tell.
Don't touch my perfume!
I don't like my perfume on other people.
Please, the child wants
to sleep a little more.
It's still so early.
I said
wake him up.
Oh, Phaedra, such a surprise.
We don't see each other enough.
And the little Dimitri.
Give me a kiss.
Kiss your grandfather.
I don't like it here.
You see that child?
He doesn't like me.
He adores you.
Why don't you kiss your grandfather?
I don't like it here.
It's all right, all right.
What is it, Phaedra'?
ThHHOS.
That's funny.
I have a call in for him now.
He's ordered special new ships.
He needs capital.
. So'?
Give it to him-.
And why?
If you don't, Andreas will.
And what's wrong with that?
They want to make a marriage
between Ercy and Alexis.
What's wrong with that?
Everything would go to
the son of the foreigner.
What happens to him?
Dimitri?
I don't like it here, it's hot.
Next year, we put in air conditioning.
You know what air conditioning is?
That child never liked me!
Ah.
You have Mr. Karillis.
Thanos, did you change your name'?
Because a Mr., uh,
a Mr. Sarossa just bought a lot
of shares in Union Shipping.
I was interested in those shares.
Mr. Sarossa was acting for me.
You're nuts!
Of course, of course you can come in.
Just a minute, I get a pencil.
Americans have an expression.
If you can't lick them, join them!
Andreas, I'm formally
asking your daughter's hand
in marriage with my son.
Given.
Donny!
. Hey!
Call my house, tell
Alexis to go to my office!
Okay!
' Aye!
How many?
Of course.
Good, good.
What?
Bravo, bravo.
Phaedra, listen to me.
Andreas has just promised Ercy to Alexis.
And, Phaedra, I think it's a good thing.
Phaedra!
Take the boy home.
Phaedra, Phaedra!
Let him alone.
What he's building is very big.
It will fall,
everything.
Better come to the
office right away, Thanos.
One of our ships has been lost.
There are casualties.
Thanos, come by the back entrance.
The families of the crew
are coming from everywhere.
They are all over the building.
It's the SS Phaedra.
Tell me.
It was not far from the coast of Norway,
a violent squall.
She was dragged against a reef.
The whole crew was magnificent, but.
The list'?
Many friends.
It's terrible.
It was not for this I asked you to come.
It was for another reason,
a happy reason.
What did you tell the families?
What could I tell them?
They want to know about the missing.
We don't have any details yet.
We have no names yet.
We are waiting.
There was a terrible storm.
The crew without exception
showed a great courage.
As soon as we have the names,
we'll notify you at your home.
Please, go home.
Please-.
Oh, Mrs. Karillis, I
can'! Open this door.
Go next door to Mr.
Karillis' private office.
I want to see Mr. Karillis.
I don't think he can come now, I...
At once-.
There is no authority
for an investigation
outside of Greece.
She was sailing under a Greek flag.
The whole crew was Greek.
What the hell do I care about the press'?
Mrs. Karillis is here.
I can'! Now.
What, what repairs?
That ship was brand new.
She insists.
Damn!
Just a minute.
Alexis, please.
Tell him I want the bodies sent to Athens.
Mr. Karillis can't talk to you now.
Thanos, don't.
Of course he's emotional.
Wouldn't you be?
Listen, as soon as (he
bodies are recovered,
send them to Athens.
' BY Plane.
It's good of you to come, Phaedra,
but I can't talk to you now.
Only a minute.
I tell you it's impossible.
Thanos, the marriage
will not take place.
What marriage?
What the devil are you talking about?
The marriage between Ercy and Alexis.
Is that what you came to tell me now?
Now!
That's not all.
I love Alexis.
Alexis is my lover.
Since Paris.
'If l_, ll .3:, 1»,
You,
come in here and close the door.
Not you.
My son.
Explain to me how you
could live in my house,
how you can talk to me,
how you can look at me.
Explain to me how you can stand before me.
I let her go.
I didn't touch her.
Explain to me!
Why didn't you leave me where I was?
Why didn't you leave me in London'?
What do they matter to me, your ships?
And your finance?
And your business?
And your taxes'?
And your capital?
And your money'?
The ring, the ring, the ring.
My whole life,
my whole life,
you made my whole life dirty!
Gel out of Greece.
Carry my curse wherever you go.
I loved you.
Get out!
'If l_, ll .3:, 1»,
Goodbye, Phaedra.
You must take me with you.
I'll never look at your face again.
There's only one thing more terrible
than what we have done,
and that is to leave each other.
I want you to die.
I'm 24 years old,
that's all, just 24.
(engine revs}.
Anna.
Undress me.
Bring me a nightgown.
Go.
Close the shutters.
Anna,
is little Dimitri taking his siesta?
Soon.
Tell him to come and give me a kiss.
(engine revs}
. Go, girl, go!
(engine revs}.
That's my girl.
You do what I say, don't you'?
You want a little music?
Sure, ya do.
A little banishment music, Professor!
Hey, girl, nothing but the best for us.
Escorted out by Bach!
Oh, John Sebastian in person!
J1 La la la la la.
J1 La la la la la la.
Goodbye, Greek life!
It's true what they say about ya.
I hardly got to know ya.
Bye sea!
Let's face it, John,
she loved me!
She loved me like they
did in the good old days.
J1 Da da da da da da da.
Bye-yah, John Sebastian!
They're playing your music like crazy,
and I'm listening to I! In Greece.
What are ya doing here, old John?
Why aren't you home minding the children?
I at least had some business in Greece.
I had a father to kill,
didn't we, Phaedra?
Phaedra!
Anna.
Yes?
Give me my mask.
Anna,
you know everything.
You know what's good.
Don't let anyone disturb me.
Let me sleep.
Yes, baby.
We have the list.
L! Is long,
very few survived.
Menyadis...
Petrokulas,
Menyaris,
RUSSOS,
Meyonas,
Yuanis,
Evangaleo,
Vonrakus,
Bemadu,
Tervisus,
Effius,
Apatim,
Boris,
Anopolis,
Patrakus,
THGFOS,
Niram».
EVEOS.
Maris,
Denopolis,
Aliam,
Ageris,
Nikolopolous,
Atriatus,
Juan,
', 5 .~ >-|
Oanis,
Salakinos.