Hey!
Chief!
Why aren't you drinking?
I don't usually drink.
Why ordered then?
Drinking lemon tea every night is a bit suspicious.
Isn't not drinking even more suspicious?
There's problem between Rachel and me.
A fight?
We never fight.
Well, then that's a real problem.
It has to do with me.
Seeing another girl?
Don't tell me you've crossed to the other side?
For you.
Really?
Oh, Chief.
Thanks.
It's been five years.
Just to prove that I wasn't suited for her.
Hey, do you know how whiskey came to be?
Once upon a time, the alchemists thought
If you put something into a oven to burn it,
you can make something new.
They started with gold, silver, bronze, steel.
Afterwards they tried burning anything.
One day they tried burning barley,
and ended up with alcohol.
Did they drink it?
That's only ethanol.
They used it for disinfection at first.
But there wasn't that much to disinfect,
so they kept the leftover in barrels.
After storing it for a few years,
one day a person tried drinking it.
Whoa, it was sweet.
Since then they started to brew whiskey.
Did you need to go back that far?
That's to prevent any misunderstanding.
It's like investigating a homicide,
Each case has many possibilities.
It takes time to nail the real murderer.
In our line of work we need
to have a lot of patience.
Can we not treat our women the same?
Thanks... Chief.
What's so good about drinking alcohol anyway?
It's only good because it's hard to drink.
Hello, Merry Christmas.
Yes.
Got it.
Officer, I'm scared.
I can't stop talking when I'm scared.
Normally, I'm not like that.
Is the toi..toi..toilet leaking?
What?
Is the toilet lea..leaking?
Mr. Lai,
I'm Inspector Lau Ching Hei
from the Hong Kong Island Regional Crime Unit.
The police have evidence to suspect your
involvement in 3 homicide and rape cases.
You are now under arrest.
All you say will be submitted as evidence in court.
Inspector, I was just having a bit of fun.
Rachel died from blood loss.
The coroner said that she had an
abortion a few days prior to her death.
She didn't tell Bong. Nor anyone else.
In the following few days,
Bong would not say anything.
When he spoke again, his first words were:
When the person you love,
suddenly disappears from
this world without a sound.
It's absolutely terrifying.
So it was with Rachel And her child.
Afterwards,
Bong placed a resignation letter on my table.
When we met again,
He become a private investigator
and an alcoholic.
This is my father. This is my husband.
Call me Hei.
Sit down.
In the past,
it used to be about fighting
crime and protecting the public.
Now, the superiors only look at the crime rate,
not the number or cases solved.
So now, we are doing more publicity
than investigating crimes.
Feels like any other job.
That's good. It's safer that way.
I'm happy that my daughter marry you.
Cheers.
It must be hard for Bong to see Rachel die.
You better spend more time with him.
We see each other every week.
I even refer cases to him sometimes.
You said it's hard to find, so I asked Bong to.
He gave it to us for our wedding gift.
I've asked many people.
They all didn't want to sell theirs.
How did he manage to get it?
I've asked him to meet up with us tonight.
You can ask him then.
What are you guys up to?
Guess...
Thank you.
Both you and your father are strange,
You can stay silent for the whole night.
What is it?
Why keep it here?
It's precious.
I won it in a competition!
It's priceless.
The problem is that I don't like you
leaving the gun in the house.
Didn't you say that you were a journalist in Iraq?
How can you be scared of guns?
But there's no one fighting a war here.
I am ...
A terrorist!
Hahaha. Are you scared?
Two months ago,
I found ten or so people
with that model of camera.
So I went to ask them one by one,
Everyday I would go and harass them.
Eventually,
In the end, there was one named Kwan
agreed to sell me his camera.
Why was he willing to sell it?
He was in his 90's. It didn't matter to him.
Can you introduce him to me?
I want to take his pictures to thank him.
He died two weeks ago.
We plan to take the team out
for a banquet two weeks later.
Good. Let's get a few drinks to celebrate.
Beer girl. Come here!
Coming.
How many bottles?
Another round of whiskey, please.
No whiskey.
No?
What sort of attitude is that?
What company are you with?
Is this how you treat your customers?
The brand is right here.
Can't you see?
We all need friends in life.
You've called me over dozens of times.
Each time it's whiskey.
Don't you know what I'm selling?
No, it's just that when I drink beer, I'll ...
If I drink beer, I'll ...
Hey, what are you doing?
Afterwards, Bong continued
to investigate Rachel's suicide.
He spent several months
and spoke to many people.
Months later, he finally found out
on that Christmas eve,
Rachel had been in this bar for hours.
For three hours,
No one knew whom she's waiting for.
Only that she had 4 glasses of whiskey
and never spoke to anyone.
Then she went home and killed herself.
When things like this happen,
most people would choose to escape.
But I know Bong wouldn't.
He has to know the reason.
He won't quit until he finds out.
It might seem meaningless.
But to him, this is the only way out.
Excuse me, Miss?
Have you seen this woman
here?
Yes, two nights ago.
What?
Where?
Just before we got into bed together
two nights ago.
Susan.
I don't know what's with me,
I always seem to want to sleep.
'Cos you're happy.
Are you awake?
I've slept for the night.
Consider it rental for the room.
But you've slept for 3 nights.
You're right... I'm sorry.
Where you working tonight?
Taiping Road.
"Beer Bottle Bar"
The more they drink, the less they cheat.
I don't go to that area often.
What are you worried about?
I'm not asking you to come.
I'll call you.
What for?
Call me whenever you want.
We are buddies after all.
But...
I want to...
increase the price.
OK.
Buddies ought to be fair to each other.
Yeah, buddy.
Let's go, buddy.
Bong, I'm taking statement.
I'll call you back.
Go on.
Mr. Wong. Mr. Wong.
Help. Help.
You know what adultery is?
You call these pictures evidence?
What kind of detective are you?
Don't worry.
It's 99%
sure win at court.
Ask your Solicitor Lau if you don't trust me.
I want 100% sure.
I don't know how Solicitor Lau could've hired you.
You're fired.
Forget about the final payment.
Then,
the pictures where you're kissing Solicitor Lau.
should I give them to you or him?
Hello, Lau?
I'm coming to talk to you later.
How much do you want?
Just give me the remaining amount..
If you try anything,
I'll sue you till you lose your license.
Sue?
I never had one to begin with.
Put the bottle down.
Where's Chief?
There's something I want to see you about.
I want you to look into my father's case.
This one?
Looks like the police have
already closed the case.
I don't know either of them.
Neither did my dad.
I don't get it.
Man would never open the door to a strangers.
Before he would open the door for anyone,
he would ask my father first.
Could it be that these criminals knew Man.
Or Man opened the door
by mistake?
Even for my friends,
Man would get my father to have a look first.
Because of this, we argued many times.
I think the real murderer knows my dad.
These two are just scapegoats.
My mother died when I was four.
I never really got to know my dad.
I left home when I was 18.
It could be, I just wanted to know
exactly what sort of person my father was.
You'll help me, won't you?
Actually, I really want to help you.
But this is a homicide, a big case.
And I'm no longer a cop.
I thought you'd understand.
It's similar to why you always stay in this place?
Do I need to call an ambulance for you?
You're going to drink?
You must be asking for death?
You've agreed to help Susan?
What do you think?
How about you?
She raised a good point.
The one about Man not opening
the door to strangers?
You believe that there was
a third person involved?
I just feel that, a couple of adult men
being afraid to open the door to strangers,
is a bit strange.
Where will you start?
Who's in charge of this case?
Tsui the Bullshitter.
Tsui the Bullshitter?
Can't help it. I am a suspect myself.
Susan's dad left a lot of inheritance.
Then actually, did you do it?
Murder charge is not to be taken lightly,
Officer!
I'd like you to get me some information.
I also would like you to help me with something.
Susan's been acting weird lately.
Saying that she's being followed.
If she's not calling the police,
she's calling the complaints dept.
The doctor said that it's only a stress.
They started her on medication
but she won't take it.
Please help me to persuade her.
That's easy.
Drink and be happy.
The doctor said not to mix
alcohol with the medication.
Oh crap.
She drank the whole bottle that day.
You're kidding?
Sorry.
What's wrong?
Let's eat.
I want to move.
I'll talk to the management office.
Do you find me annoying?
I told you there's someone following me,
but you don't believe me.
I told you my dad died under suspicious situation,
and you also don't believe me.
Do you just think that I'm lying, or that I'm crazy?
Of course, I trust you.
You are my wife.
I hope you trust me too.
If there's no trust, then this family will be over.
I never had a family when I was young.
I don't want to lose this one.
Hello? Hello?
The things you've done,
be ready for the consequences.
This is the living room.
That night, Chow's body
was discovered here.
His butler, Man was found in the study.
The CSI team dusted the place
and took pictures under UV light.
Chow's left shoulder had knife wounds,
And there was repeated blunt trauma to his head.
It was the cause of death.
The murder weapon was a brass Buddha statue.
On the left side of Man's abdomen and face,
there were knife wounds.
His head also suffered blunt trauma.
And was also the case of death.
On the floor, 1 feet 10 inches from the
entrance had Man's bloodstains.
It appears that Man was the
one who opened the door.
The killers attacked immediately after entering.
That is the sequence of events
according to the report.
What's wrong, Man?
Accounting for the missing property
comes to about $3.87 Million.
It must have been a premeditated
murder and robbery.
These pictures were all taken in Macau?
Chow was from Macau,
and had a transport business there.
He migrated to Hong Kong afterwards.
It's Tsui the Bullshitter.
That's right, this is his case.
Why would he pass it on to you?
He has a mistress.
He wouldn't dare not to give it to me.
Mistress?
His wife Shirley is smart.
She's so clever, how could she not know?
Shirley is his mistress.
His wife emigrated to Australia in 1997.
Tsui, Bong is all yours.
Inspector Bullshit.
What's so funny?
How's the weather in Australia?
You find that funny? Listen up.
If I didn't pass this case to your buddy,
then you would have had nothing.
OK.
Stay away.
The lock is connected to the security company.
The alarm goes off if the code is not re-entered.
Hey, the alarm didn't go off that day.
So?
The code must have been
used after they entered.
So?
So the two killers knew Chow or Man.
Or the killers might have known the code.
Didn't you read my report?
It wasn't mentioned in your report.
How much does it cost to hire a butler?
$10,000 to $20,000 a month.
He treated the butler quite well.
Man has worked here for over 20 years.
This huge house was managed by him alone.
Sometimes he acted as the chauffeur too.
Occasionally,
a maid would come to clean the house.
It was actually the maid who found the bodies.
Initially I though that Man had it up to here,
couldn't take it any more and
committed a murder suicide.
That morning there was a jogger there,
Who saw 2 men running over there.
No one saw what car they took.
Want to see their hideout?
OK.
Sir Lau, the number you were asking about.
The call came from a convenience store.
Located in Bai Hua Street.
9:30 pm last night,
I wasn't on duty.
Are you investigating a case?
Just a theft case.
There's been a rise in pickpockets lately.
I see.
I was sure that I had $40 in my pocket yesterday.
Wong and Keung were both drug addicts.
Both have criminal records.
Just minor cases like thefts.
Wong rented the house.
He put poison in Keung's drink.
Keung noticed something
wrong after having a drink,
He pulled a knife and stabbed Wong.
The knife is 7 inches long,
the same one used on Chow.
In face of millions,
who could control themselves?
Did the cops bust the door open?
This door opens outwards,
how could we break it inwards?
You pull to open the door.
The door was locked.
And was just broken by you.
They locked themselves in to kill each other.
Do you understand, super detective?
Have you seen any suspicious
people pass through that day?
Yeah, going that way.
Back to the hilltop.
From the hilltop to Li Yu Men
is at least 1.5 hours with 3 changeovers.
You mean a third guy picked them up,
and after they did the murder,
returned them to the Li Yu Men,
and then killed them as well.
Perhaps they drove themselves.
So there's no third guy?
Keung stabbed Wong very precisely.
He didn't seem to be poisoned.
So you're saying that there
was a 3rd person then?
He could have just been lucky.
Or maybe, he really was good with knives.
So, you're saying that anything is possible?
That's possible.
Police said the door was locked from inside.
So after he killed them, how did he escape?
The air-conditioner.
Damn it.
A bit far-fetched?
Whiskey on rocks?
Do you have beer?
I thought that you don't drink beer.
I'm thirsty.
Hong Kong is so hot lately.
It's almost winter. Isn't it abnormal?
Besides, it's very polluted.
What's wrong?
Chief said that you shouldn't drink alcohol.
When talking about their own wives,
do all men make them sound
like crazy old women?
Oh, don't worry about him. Come.
Shirley? Haven't seen her for a while.
Trust me. I will introduce her to a good man.
How's our daughter?
What's next?
I'll start investigating the victims.
That's your dad and Man.
Hey Bong.
Go.
Hei has kept something important here.
Let me.
It's dangerous, get out quickly.
This is a very difficult matter,
I don't think it will be resolved easily.
How could it be so coincidental
that I ran into the suspect.
But I let him slip away.
You saw the suspect?
Yes.
Did you recognize him?
Of course not.
Sorry, I should have believed you.
I'm glad you're OK.
Bong,
are you OK?
I'm fine. You?
Why don't you take Susan home first!
I'll call you in a couple of days.
Let's go.
So actually, did you do it?
Murder charge is not to be taken lightly,
Officer.
Mister, did you want a beer?
Another 2 dozen for table 3.
Hey, come back. Sit down.
Sit down.
No. You might expose your identity.
Shit. Think you're an undercover?
Give him a glass of piss.
Come closer.
Cheers.
You can go now. Scram.
What? Go?
Go. Take your beer with you.
I'll call you.
What happened to your head?
What do you mean by what's wrong?
The customer got a bit over excited.
What's up? Did you come to see me?
No, I came to have a chat with my friend.
What time do you finish tonight?
What the hell's it to you?
A week before he died,
Man called this number.
Does it ring a bell?
No.
That's all?
How did you meet Chief?
Hasn't he ever told you?
I lost my camera at the mall once.
Hei found it for me.
After I invited him out for a dinner to thank him.
I discovered that we had many,
many things in common.
Before we met,
We had seen the same film in the same cinema,
ordered the same dish at the same restaurant,
even took the same flight to the same place.
Is Hei involved in this case?
No.
Just want to know how these things begin.
Never tried it before?
Can't remember.
Last time I went to the US,
he took me to the airport.
Then he proposed to me at
the Los Angeles airport.
I thought it was your idea.
I just helped him find a flight that
would get there earlier than you.
Let's have dinner.
Oh, you're here.
Just came to have a look. What's this?
It's soup.
Soup?
You take this. I'll get another one.
Oxtail soup, good for your kidneys.
She knows.
About what?
Susan knows that you put
medication into the soup.
She says nothing,
because she doesn't want you to worry.
Really?
I checked out Wong's family today.
He only has a 70 year old
mother with Alzheimer's.
She can't even hold up a bowl.
What about Keung?
How about dropping him home?
I checked Man's call record.
Before the attack,
there were 2 calls to his phone.
It's registered under Keung.
Here's the address.
What about this guy?
Let him sleep.
October 27, the day before the murder.
I've checked the call record.
The last number dialed was 23365195.
That's Chow's home number.
Keung was also from Macau.
Maybe he knew Chow.
Maybe.
I think there's a third guy.
Perhaps he's someone we both know?
No idea.
Bong.
No.
Police. Freeze.
Let go of him.
Bong, you all right?
Police.
Sorry.
So, there's really a third guy.
Why didn't he flee after the attack?
Why would he come back to his place?
What happened to your head?
No big deal.
The customer got a bit over excited.
Is this another one of your problems?
Do you want me to go over to help?
No need. It's just work.
What am I doing here?
We came out for a drink after dinner.
You collapsed after two rounds.
I can't remember a thing.
What happened to your head?
After you got drunk,
you smashed a bottle on me.
That bad ...
then, I'm really sorry.
Don't worry.
Check this license plate for me.
Might be a lead.
Thanks.
Let me buy you a drink.
- Beer girl.
- Coming!
The license plate has been tempered.
The real number is GG8165.
A phone was found.
The last number dialed was 23589991.
October 29 was not a special festival.
But someone donated $10,000 to the temple.
That's why I remembered.
Did you meet this donor?
No, he just left an envelope.
Who is this man Fu?
Ancestor.
Wai Shu was on duty that day.
She remembers that person.
Are you Wai Shu? Can you remember him?
Yes, he is a man.
How tall was he? How big?
Look?
If I could see clearly, then I would know.
My eyes are failing. Everyone knows.
I'm going blind, sir.
Chow's time of death is 5:30 am.
At 6:58 am
Keung called the temple.
At 7:10 am
a snapshot of Keung's speeding car
was taken on its way to the temple.
Keung reached the temple at 7:20 am,
stayed for 15 minutes and left.
The autopsy report is as follows:
Keung and Wong's time of death was
between 6 am to 9 am.
But the CCTV on the main road
shows that Keung leaving the temple
and crossing the road.
Across the road is a bus stop.
There is a bus that goes to Li Yu Men.
It takes 1 hour.
That means their time of death
should be around 8:30 am.
I knew from the start that
there was more to this case.
Follow it up, people.
What are you waiting for!
What's wrong with him?
He lost his handcuffs.
He can just buy another pair.
Out of stock.
Why do you think Keung would leave
Wong to go to the temple alone?
Why would he be so stupid to give
Wong the opportunity to poison him?
It's several million. If it were me,
I would split the money first.
Maybe some things are more
important than money.
I think I need to go to Macau.
Why are you here?
Looking for you.
What for?
Let's go to Macau.
Don't mess around.
I'll pay you.
Go to hell.
That's not what I meant.
What the hell do you want?
You want sex?
You want sex? Come on.
Is that what you want?
OK, come on.
Just do it right here.
Come on.
Come.
I've been thinking of you.
You only ... only ...
You only think of me when you get drunk?
I've been sober for the past few days,
and I'm still was thinking about you.
What about the next few days?
Can't I just have a conversation with you?
No ... I really want to talk to you
But I'm not sure if I can love you.
Can we?
Forget it.
What's wrong with you?
I still haven't asked you what you want to do.
You just like imagining things.
You don't know what you want.
I know.
Hey,
can you not give me money in the future?
I'm not...
I'm really not that sort of girl.
Stealing wine?
No.
Red wine OK?
You know why people like drinking alcohol?
Why?
Because it's hard to swallow.
Which moron said that?
I'm done with your father's case.
Keung didn't kill your dad for money.
He had other reasons.
When your dad was young,
he ran a transportation company in Macau.
Did you learn anything from going to Macau?
Good on you.
I already told Susan.
In Macau,
I found a homicide case from 25 years ago,
a man Fu and his entire family were murdered,
including his wife, mother and daughter.
On the day of the massacre,
several killers entered the home
and killed without mercy.
The entire family was dead.
The killers also burnt the place
to destroy the evidence.
Fu was an anti-narcotics cop.
He offended some people, and they took revenge.
Removing roots and all.
But they missed one person.
Fu's son, Keung.
The police eventually caught a ten or so people.
All of them had been investigated by Fu,
including Man and Chow.
Chow was in drug trafficking.
Man was Fu's colleague.
Chow bribed Man to pull strings for him.
Fu refused his bribe and exposed him.
Man quitted the force afterwards
and started working for Chow.
When Susan's mother died,
Chow retired and moved to Hong Kong.
The case turned cold.
At that time, Keung survived the tragedy.
Waited for 25 years, and finally got his revenge.
If you were him, what would you do?
If I had nothing to lose like him,
I would have done the same.
What you laughing at?
I like ...
I like you fighting for me.
Come on, go upstairs.
No, don't ...
Bye.
How cute.
You've moved back to the hilltop?
Susan's taken over her dad's fortune.
She said that's her home after all.
Chief,
remember we went to Keung's house?
That night when Tsui hit you?
I have been there by myself
before we did.
You thought I was a suspect?
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
I would have done the same if I were you.
According to Mr. Chow's will,
all the properties,
stocks, bonds and cash
will be inherited solely by Ms. Chow.
In principle, all of Mr. Chow's fortune
is now Ms. Chow's.
Hello? Speaking.
Broadband installation tomorrow night?
Please give me a call before you come.
What're you doing?
I'll tell you later.
Why so mysterious?
Don't look.
Let me.
I'll tell you later.
Sure you're not coming?
No. You go ahead.
Get changed.
After I'm changed, you take your medication.
Susan is not coming?
She is occupied.
I don't know how to break the news to Susan.
I got this from a fellow in Macau.
Chow got married in 1978
but Susan was born in 1976.
There's no father's name
on her birth certificate.
Chow is not Susan's real father.
Lose.
There was a gas explosion at your house.
A male body was found in the scene.
His name is Lai.
He was one the criminals you caught.
Looks like he came for revenge.
Mr. Lau, your wife suffered severe shock.
She is in a coma.
We've done everything we could.
The rest is up to her.
Mr. Lau, please wait outside.
2cc of 1:1000 adrenaline.
Yes.
CPR.
According to the weather report,
it will be sunny this week.
That's good.
Not like last week where it was raining every day.
Puts everyone in a bad mood.
The temperature will be warmer, 22 degrees.
It's been a while since you've been in the sun.
Once you're awake,
I'll take you for a stroll in the sun.
Thanks for your help.
No problem.
It's better than drinking all day, right?
Shut up.
Hang in there, Chief.
Susan will wake up.
Ask her to buy you new underwear.
I've torn some while washing, sorry.
Wait for me downstairs. Leave!
Leaving again?
Go.
Take the stairs.
Bye.
You've changed.
For better or worse?
Better.
When I was a cop,
I thought I could change the world.
I tried so hard but failed.
I didn't know what I was doing.
Now I know,
it's the world that's changing me.
Chief,
there's something that I've wanted to tell you.
Actually Rachel's baby wasn't mine.
I've always wanted to know who
she was waiting for that night.
Until one month ago,
Fung helped me find that person.
On the night that Rachel died,
he was on his way to meet her.
Unfortunately,
he had an accident and went into a coma.
I've always thought that once I found him,
I would bash the crap out of him
or kill him.
In the end I didn't.
Now, I go and see him every
week to give him a body wash.
I've become his carer.
Chief, don't be like this.
I'm fine.
I still want to have new underwear.
What would the world be when you wake up?
Pack some clothes.
Take the clothes to the hospital,
then wait for me at the HK-Macau pier.
Go.
Tsui, this is Bong.
Please check Sir Lau file for me.
In the past my master baked the
quail in the belly of the geese.
The goose was crispy, and the quails were sweet.
But it's hard to find now.
You're so fat.
That's true. 20 years ago, I wasn't this fat.
I was very slim, only 80 pounds.
Right, I heard that you were an athlete before
Yes. World Table Tennis champion. Undefeated.
How about the match in 1978?
1978...
Yeah, I did lose that match
but I still came runner up.
Do you remember the name
of the person who won?
It was a long time ago. I don't remember.
- All right.
- Thank you.
- Thanks a lot.
- You're welcome.
Thanks.
Let's go.
Captain Lau Ching Hei, line 3.
Have you waken up?
Did you marry me
in order to kill Dad?
Yes.
So why are you still here?
I don't want you to be hurt.
I want to see you wake up.
Have you ever loved me?
I have.
No, you haven't.
I'm fine.
Why did you get so drunk?
I just solved Susan's dad's case.
So I had a few to celebrate.
While I was boozing,
I thought about how Susan is at the moment,
I really don't know how to tell her.
So I kept thinking,
and drinking.
the more I thought, the more I drank.
The more I drank, the more I thought.
I went to Macau a few days ago.
You know where I went?
I went to Keung's primary school.
In 1978,
he won the inter-schools competition.
He took his new table tennis bat.
Carrying the new paddle,
And went home to show his dad,
Instead,
he saw his family
get killed by Man and Chow.
Keung was afraid and ran away.
He witnessed the entire sequence of events.
He ran to his father's workplace.
But he found that all of his father's friends
and colleagues were involved with the killers.
So he didn't dare report it to the police.
Because he knew
the killers would finish the job.
He became homeless and hid outside
a Sisters Covenant for a week.
A Sister found him
and took him into the Covenant's orphanage.
The Sister asked him his name,
Without hesitation, he said:
My name is Lau Ching Hei.
This name protected his life.
When he heard Chow moved to Hong Kong,
He followed him to Hong Kong.
Got into school.
After college, he became a cop.
Then he married Susan.
In the end, he killed Chow.
A bit far-fetched.
Isn't it, Keung?
You'll never understand.
Have you ever lost everything?
I have.
I lost everything in one day.
My home, my family,
even my own identity.
I want Chow to experience that.
I didn't think about revenge for a long time
Because there was no opportunity.
4 years ago in the police record,
I accidentally discovered
another person called Keung.
He's also from Macau, with no relatives.
The same ordinary name.
This was an opportunity sent by above.
What about Wong?
He said that for $50,000, he would kill for me.
who cares if someone like that dies.
And Susan?
She was part of my plan.
To get to Chow, I followed her
to the movies, and restaurants.
Even holidays.
After we married, we came back to Hong Kong.
I went to see Chow
and told him I was Fu's son.
Susan should not have died.
Should my family have died?
I always thought this was a perfect plan.
I did everything perfectly.
Then I saw Susan in the hospital.
I realized that it didn't matter whether
she was Chow's daughter or not,
She's my wife.
My family.
She was the same as my father,
mother, sister, and grandmother.
They're all my relatives.
Thank you.
- Cheers.
When I said that I loved you,
I was serious.
I know.
You once said that I should not
give you any money in the future.
You've got to keep your promise.
Of course.
No .. I meant ...
No way ...
That day I ...
But you know... for things around the home
could you give me just a little bit?
How much?
The more you pay, the better the service.
Boss.