1
00:00:03,786 --> 00:00:05,990
This is a district of São Paulo.

2
00:00:06,474 --> 00:00:08,546
A large latin American industrial city...

3
00:00:08,714 --> 00:00:12,194
...responsible for 60 to 70%...

4
00:00:12,362 --> 00:00:14,566
...of this country's gross
national product.

5
00:00:15,114 --> 00:00:17,830
Brazil has 120 million inhabitants...

6
00:00:17,994 --> 00:00:21,605
...of which, 50% are under 21
years of age.

7
00:00:21,962 --> 00:00:26,021
Of these, almost 28 million...

8
00:00:26,186 --> 00:00:29,666
...live in conditions below
the standards set forth...

9
00:00:29,834 --> 00:00:34,274
...in the lnternational Childrens
Rights prescribed by the U.N.

10
00:00:34,506 --> 00:00:37,987
There are also approximately
3 million homeless children...

11
00:00:38,153 --> 00:00:42,856
...who have no one and no defined
family of origin.

12
00:00:43,594 --> 00:00:45,863
The situation of these
children is more chaotic...

13
00:00:46,026 --> 00:00:53,031
...when one is aware that they
can't be prosecuted...

14
00:00:53,450 --> 00:00:58,665
...which permits the exploitation
of these minors by some adults.

15
00:00:58,826 --> 00:01:02,819
Forcing them to commit crimes
or acts of delinquency...

16
00:01:02,986 --> 00:01:04,480
...knowing they won't be prosecuted.

17
00:01:04,650 --> 00:01:06,984
At most they'll be sent
to reformatories...

18
00:01:07,146 --> 00:01:09,797
...where they will spend several
months; where the pressure...

19
00:01:09,962 --> 00:01:13,574
...and lack of space will cause
their immediate release.

20
00:01:13,738 --> 00:01:17,283
This district here, is one,
wherein live...

21
00:01:17,450 --> 00:01:20,931
...the families of workers from
large neighboring factories...

22
00:01:21,418 --> 00:01:26,055
...mom and dad who both work and
children who remain at home...

23
00:01:26,634 --> 00:01:31,555
...with care provided by an older
sibling or a paid neighbor.

24
00:01:31,722 --> 00:01:35,977
Fernando, who plays the main
character of "Pixote"...

25
00:01:36,138 --> 00:01:39,553
...lives with his mom and 9 other
siblings in this house.

26
00:01:39,786 --> 00:01:44,608
This film is acted by children
who belong to this social class.

27
00:01:58,218 --> 00:02:05,026
The Survival of the Weakest

28
00:03:37,738 --> 00:03:41,033
O.K. love, that's crazy!

29
00:03:41,513 --> 00:03:43,335
- I've been waiting an hour.
- Want me to give up the job?

30
00:03:43,498 --> 00:03:48,254
- Just a minute longer, please.

31
00:03:50,153 --> 00:03:52,968
I'll give you a call later on, okay? Bye.

32
00:03:53,129 --> 00:03:55,496
My son has been missing for over a month.

33
00:03:55,657 --> 00:03:57,545
That's another matter.

34
00:03:57,706 --> 00:04:00,553
Just give me his name for now.

35
00:04:00,713 --> 00:04:01,761
José Maria.

36
00:04:01,929 --> 00:04:04,613
- José Maria, what?
- José Maria Da Silva.

37
00:04:19,465 --> 00:04:21,538
Get moving, all of you!

38
00:04:47,178 --> 00:04:50,527
- What's up?
- They're rounding everyone up.

39
00:04:50,697 --> 00:04:53,153
Some old guy was killed,
they're pinning it on us.

40
00:04:53,961 --> 00:04:58,216
Pedro Socrates, 15 years old:
father, Julio; mother, Ambrosia.

41
00:04:58,377 --> 00:05:03,593
Diego Emanuel, 13, Marcelino
dos Anjos, Father; unknown.

42
00:05:03,754 --> 00:05:08,064
Joao Henrique, 10, Mother: Maria
Da Costa, 35; Father: unknown.

43
00:05:08,234 --> 00:05:11,397
- My father's dead!
- Father: unknown!

44
00:05:11,561 --> 00:05:14,212
Anastasio Pereira, 17 years old...

45
00:05:14,441 --> 00:05:16,897
...Father, Roberval ; Mother, Severina.

46
00:05:17,065 --> 00:05:21,506
José Altacilho: 16 years old.
Father, Fortunato; mother, Julia.

47
00:05:21,674 --> 00:05:28,297
Edmundo Pires, alias Marilyn,
Parents: Luis, Esmeralda... 17.

48
00:05:28,458 --> 00:05:31,491
Raimundo de Souza: Father, Pedro...

49
00:06:28,746 --> 00:06:31,910
What a mess. Everyone up.

50
00:06:33,673 --> 00:06:34,786
Get in line.

51
00:06:46,089 --> 00:06:49,831
Back again, eh? You know all
about what's going on.

52
00:06:50,058 --> 00:06:54,182
You don't get hit for no reason here.

53
00:06:57,226 --> 00:06:58,916
Let's have some order here!

54
00:07:04,585 --> 00:07:06,473
Inside you're a man, see?

55
00:07:09,706 --> 00:07:12,226
Any trouble, and you'll answer to me.

56
00:07:13,354 --> 00:07:17,031
- Any questions?
- No questions.

57
00:07:17,386 --> 00:07:19,393
Sunday is visiting day.

58
00:07:21,161 --> 00:07:24,325
No whores. Only family.

59
00:07:24,681 --> 00:07:26,688
Get them to the dormitory.

60
00:07:26,857 --> 00:07:29,126
Come on, quickly! Quick!

61
00:08:55,818 --> 00:08:57,061
Quiet!

62
00:09:01,961 --> 00:09:03,455
Keep quiet!

63
00:09:05,033 --> 00:09:07,815
It'll be O.K. if you keep quiet.

64
00:09:07,977 --> 00:09:08,643
What the...?

65
00:09:47,017 --> 00:09:49,537
I won't ask who's responsible!

66
00:09:49,897 --> 00:09:51,653
No one will own up!

67
00:09:52,585 --> 00:09:56,262
But hear this, I'm nobody's father!

68
00:09:56,425 --> 00:09:58,759
I don't put up with any bullshit!

69
00:09:59,561 --> 00:10:02,660
You want to kill each other,
do it outside!

70
00:10:03,081 --> 00:10:05,088
Not here or I take the rap.

71
00:10:06,025 --> 00:10:07,334
This is a respectable house.

72
00:10:08,201 --> 00:10:13,220
You tell me everything, or,
I'll smash your heads in!

73
00:10:17,674 --> 00:10:21,602
- Pixote, did you see who did it?
- Not me. I was asleep.

74
00:10:25,993 --> 00:10:29,735
Fucking hell! Get him to sick bay.

75
00:10:57,994 --> 00:10:59,554
You're gonna look pretty.

76
00:11:01,193 --> 00:11:02,437
Watch out for Lilica.

77
00:11:46,185 --> 00:11:49,219
Keep still! Got ants in your pants?

78
00:12:48,906 --> 00:12:51,109
Hey! You're afraid.

79
00:12:53,065 --> 00:12:54,887
Take a drag.

80
00:12:56,265 --> 00:12:58,916
Breathe in and hold it.

81
00:12:59,785 --> 00:13:01,727
Right on!

82
00:13:08,169 --> 00:13:10,503
The smoke that satisfies.

83
00:13:16,873 --> 00:13:18,564
Go again.

84
00:13:40,681 --> 00:13:44,162
Shit, man, I'm so hungry.

85
00:13:44,841 --> 00:13:46,401
I'm spaced out.

86
00:13:47,145 --> 00:13:50,691
It doesn't get to an old hand
like me so easily.

87
00:14:40,585 --> 00:14:42,014
Let's split.

88
00:14:47,433 --> 00:14:48,742
Pixote!

89
00:15:32,041 --> 00:15:34,758
Fucking sexy chick!

90
00:15:34,921 --> 00:15:38,020
My ass, she's a fag.

91
00:15:38,185 --> 00:15:39,876
Lilica.

92
00:15:40,681 --> 00:15:41,990
But I'd fuck it.

93
00:16:06,216 --> 00:16:07,907
How's your memory?

94
00:16:08,649 --> 00:16:10,209
That guy's Almir.

95
00:16:12,169 --> 00:16:14,438
Son of a bitch cop.

96
00:16:15,689 --> 00:16:19,813
You pushed an old guy under a
car the other day. He's dead!

97
00:16:20,233 --> 00:16:21,727
Did you need to do this...

98
00:16:23,240 --> 00:16:25,575
...just to rob his wallet!

99
00:16:27,721 --> 00:16:31,714
The guy was some judge.
Know what that means?

100
00:16:31,880 --> 00:16:34,215
We sure fucked up.

101
00:16:34,377 --> 00:16:36,515
How could we know he was important?

102
00:16:36,809 --> 00:16:39,013
The Commissioner's got the screws on me.

103
00:16:39,560 --> 00:16:42,856
The Chief Commissioner put the
screws on the commissioner.

104
00:16:49,416 --> 00:16:51,239
I want the names of who did it.

105
00:16:52,489 --> 00:16:54,115
Nothing will happen to you.

106
00:16:55,880 --> 00:16:58,531
Here, the law protects minors.

107
00:17:04,329 --> 00:17:07,645
You're untouchable.

108
00:17:08,041 --> 00:17:10,627
But I'm not taken in by this
minors' business.

109
00:17:17,385 --> 00:17:19,392
If you won't collaborate...

110
00:17:21,096 --> 00:17:25,025
I'll just finger one of you,
then where will you be?

111
00:17:28,265 --> 00:17:30,786
The old man died in lpiranga
and 24th, the 24th of May.

112
00:17:31,209 --> 00:17:32,834
Who hangs out there?

113
00:17:33,001 --> 00:17:36,034
The guy doesn't know anything.

114
00:17:36,200 --> 00:17:38,917
He died at the block,
not at the corner...

115
00:17:39,080 --> 00:17:41,863
...like this jerk just said.

116
00:17:44,840 --> 00:17:49,281
Talk faggot! Tell us!
Speak up, you whore!

117
00:17:51,241 --> 00:17:54,208
Your lips are sealed, eh?

118
00:17:54,505 --> 00:17:57,025
One good turn deserves another.

119
00:17:57,193 --> 00:18:00,990
When we get out of here
no one will stop us.

120
00:18:01,160 --> 00:18:03,681
- Got it, pal?
- Got it.

121
00:18:08,777 --> 00:18:13,284
Start scrubbing, you pigs.
Let's get this dirt off you.

122
00:18:13,513 --> 00:18:16,808
Get rid of the lice.

123
00:18:18,569 --> 00:18:20,325
And you, darling...

124
00:18:20,681 --> 00:18:23,779
...get your pussy nice and clean.

125
00:18:32,136 --> 00:18:34,209
What are you staring at?

126
00:18:35,081 --> 00:18:36,641
You like it?

127
00:18:38,281 --> 00:18:40,801
You want to touch it?

128
00:19:12,905 --> 00:19:14,399
Sit here.

129
00:19:14,953 --> 00:19:17,157
Are you new here?

130
00:19:24,297 --> 00:19:26,882
Boy, I coughed all night!

131
00:19:34,217 --> 00:19:36,486
Drink up, before it gets cold.

132
00:19:37,737 --> 00:19:39,111
You'd better.

133
00:19:39,273 --> 00:19:42,240
You'll only have to drink it tomorrow.

134
00:19:53,288 --> 00:19:56,288
You're gonna be nice and
strong when you grow up.

135
00:20:00,456 --> 00:20:01,504
The...

136
00:20:03,336 --> 00:20:04,765
...world...

137
00:20:05,960 --> 00:20:07,138
...is...

138
00:20:07,561 --> 00:20:10,976
...round...

139
00:20:13,129 --> 00:20:14,373
...like...

140
00:20:15,497 --> 00:20:16,741
...an...

141
00:20:18,121 --> 00:20:21,918
...orange.

142
00:20:27,336 --> 00:20:31,133
Have you written that?
Why aren't you writing?

143
00:20:32,904 --> 00:20:35,938
Open your book. Too tired to do it?

144
00:20:36,232 --> 00:20:40,291
Well, you must learn to write,
to know things.

145
00:20:40,457 --> 00:20:44,581
Come on, wake up, will you!

146
00:20:47,625 --> 00:20:49,119
Start writing.

147
00:21:52,009 --> 00:21:53,896
Fess up!

148
00:21:54,056 --> 00:21:55,617
I know nothing.

149
00:21:55,785 --> 00:21:57,279
Come clean, you son of a bitch!

150
00:21:57,449 --> 00:22:01,126
How can I tell you what
I don't know, shit?

151
00:22:01,289 --> 00:22:03,176
No swearing allowed here, asshole!

152
00:22:05,512 --> 00:22:07,138
You'd better talk.

153
00:22:08,329 --> 00:22:11,362
I can wait all day. I'm in no hurry.

154
00:22:11,849 --> 00:22:15,329
You'll tell us in the end,
anyway. So talk!

155
00:22:15,945 --> 00:22:20,320
Okay, okay, I'll talk. It's like this...

156
00:22:21,640 --> 00:22:23,975
...I met two guys on the street.

157
00:22:24,649 --> 00:22:27,682
They asked me for a cigarette,
and I gave 'em one.

158
00:22:29,320 --> 00:22:33,249
- Marijuana, right?
- No, just a plain cigarette.

159
00:22:34,376 --> 00:22:38,370
Then they asked me if I'd ever
been involved in a hold-up.

160
00:22:39,241 --> 00:22:45,864
I said, yes, and they gave me
a gun, and we went to the bank.

161
00:22:48,968 --> 00:22:51,107
There were two guys there...

162
00:22:52,552 --> 00:22:53,861
...taking money out.

163
00:23:02,793 --> 00:23:04,167
I'd like a loan.

164
00:23:04,328 --> 00:23:06,467
- How much do you want.
- 800.

165
00:23:19,944 --> 00:23:24,003
- Hand over the money!
- We need it.

166
00:23:24,169 --> 00:23:25,663
There isn't much. It's early.

167
00:23:25,833 --> 00:23:29,891
What do you care? It isn't
yours, hand it over.

168
00:23:30,056 --> 00:23:32,839
- Quick, before someone comes!
- Please, don't kill me!

169
00:23:33,001 --> 00:23:35,139
I'll blow you away!

170
00:23:35,304 --> 00:23:36,798
In the bag, quick!

171
00:23:40,040 --> 00:23:41,087
Stop, Dito!

172
00:23:41,832 --> 00:23:43,840
Shit I quit playing!

173
00:23:47,913 --> 00:23:51,208
Pixote screwed it all up.
He blurted out my name!

174
00:23:54,633 --> 00:23:57,284
Piss off!

175
00:24:03,080 --> 00:24:07,520
Cut it out. I've got something
more interesting for you.

176
00:24:08,840 --> 00:24:10,912
Naked women!

177
00:24:11,080 --> 00:24:17,060
Imagine taking down her panties
and putting it in her.

178
00:24:17,608 --> 00:24:18,786
Pixote's blushing.

179
00:24:18,952 --> 00:24:24,167
- Enough, that's not for kids.
- Shit, Lilica!

180
00:24:24,328 --> 00:24:26,084
It's already hard.

181
00:24:27,656 --> 00:24:30,373
There it is you jerk offs.

182
00:24:32,840 --> 00:24:35,687
You act like big men but
you have tiny weenies.

183
00:24:39,497 --> 00:24:43,807
You, who are still on mother's milk,
can do me a favor.

184
00:24:44,297 --> 00:24:48,607
Stop it, only big boys can do that.

185
00:24:51,464 --> 00:24:53,853
I need a little favor from you.

186
00:24:54,665 --> 00:24:58,527
On Sunday your folks might
bring me some...

187
00:25:01,288 --> 00:25:04,932
- Don't want much, do you?
- I don't want any trouble.

188
00:25:05,096 --> 00:25:08,358
It's easy for you, isn't it?

189
00:25:08,616 --> 00:25:13,253
- Don't ask me!
- I know I could bring it.

190
00:25:15,977 --> 00:25:18,824
But what's in it for me?

191
00:25:23,657 --> 00:25:27,453
No one will rape you, nor beat you up.

192
00:25:28,201 --> 00:25:30,535
We'll make sure of that.

193
00:25:31,528 --> 00:25:33,219
Could you want more?

194
00:25:41,320 --> 00:25:43,327
There's just one other thing.

195
00:25:45,672 --> 00:25:47,876
- I want cash.
- Bug off, fairy.

196
00:25:48,040 --> 00:25:49,218
Let's play soccer.

197
00:25:54,120 --> 00:25:57,469
Think about it, eh?

198
00:25:57,769 --> 00:26:00,998
I just told you I don't want trouble.

199
00:26:09,737 --> 00:26:13,795
If you want a copy of today's message...

200
00:26:13,960 --> 00:26:19,230
...ask for number 1,720
and for the theme...

201
00:26:19,400 --> 00:26:22,433
...Jesus, the king who bestows happiness.

202
00:26:55,176 --> 00:26:57,063
Go talk to the judge, mom.

203
00:26:57,608 --> 00:27:02,365
I will son, but I'm sure
he won't let you out.

204
00:27:02,536 --> 00:27:06,846
What for? So you can go back
on the streets again?

205
00:27:07,528 --> 00:27:10,757
If anything happens to me
in this hell hole...

206
00:27:10,920 --> 00:27:12,415
...it'll be your fault.

207
00:27:13,288 --> 00:27:15,492
What could happen?

208
00:27:18,280 --> 00:27:22,535
If your Grandpa turns up,
will you talk to him?

209
00:27:22,696 --> 00:27:26,373
- I sure hope he doesn't!
- Why?

210
00:27:27,176 --> 00:27:28,670
He pisses me off!

211
00:27:33,065 --> 00:27:34,952
Come here, Roberto.

212
00:27:38,440 --> 00:27:40,709
Today's my big day.

213
00:27:40,872 --> 00:27:42,116
See Fumaca's mother?

214
00:27:42,280 --> 00:27:46,623
Never misses a visit, you'd
think she likes it here.

215
00:27:47,209 --> 00:27:51,464
That's right. Ugly old bat.

216
00:27:51,624 --> 00:27:53,446
Looks like she brought him something.

217
00:27:53,608 --> 00:27:55,234
Maybe it's coconut pie.

218
00:27:55,400 --> 00:27:58,117
The last one she brought was great.

219
00:28:01,416 --> 00:28:05,988
Dito, your mom wants to see you, c'mon.

220
00:28:06,152 --> 00:28:07,462
I don't wanna see her!

221
00:28:07,625 --> 00:28:11,302
- She came all this way to see you.
- I didn't ask her to!

222
00:28:11,465 --> 00:28:14,182
C'mon, Sapato told me to get you.

223
00:28:14,345 --> 00:28:17,192
Tell that cow I want
nothing to do with her!

224
00:28:26,825 --> 00:28:30,621
You won't talk to your mom? lngrate.

225
00:28:30,792 --> 00:28:33,509
She sacrifices for you. Now go see her.

226
00:28:42,185 --> 00:28:45,032
- Can I go?
- Yeah, go on, Dito.

227
00:28:59,912 --> 00:29:01,341
When did he arrive?

228
00:29:02,345 --> 00:29:07,101
About 2 months ago, I guess.

229
00:29:08,744 --> 00:29:12,159
- Almost kicked him to death.
- Why don't you ever come home?

230
00:29:12,328 --> 00:29:16,256
- You don't turn me on anymore.
- I don't?

231
00:29:30,120 --> 00:29:32,324
Ever since I was a kid...

232
00:29:33,704 --> 00:29:36,803
...I did nothing but listen to you...

233
00:29:37,672 --> 00:29:40,639
...I followed your story...

234
00:29:41,896 --> 00:29:44,798
...I knew your glory...

235
00:29:45,672 --> 00:29:49,829
...I knew by heart...

236
00:29:50,472 --> 00:29:54,465
He's good. He really sounds
like Roberto Carlos.

237
00:29:54,952 --> 00:29:58,116
When he gets out he'll be a star.

238
00:29:59,496 --> 00:30:02,398
And what about you?

239
00:30:05,096 --> 00:30:07,715
Because I read...

240
00:30:09,288 --> 00:30:12,322
...in those star magazines...

241
00:30:13,320 --> 00:30:16,168
...that you had been...

242
00:30:17,480 --> 00:30:20,414
...a poor kid like me.

243
00:30:30,280 --> 00:30:31,774
But you know...

244
00:30:32,456 --> 00:30:34,911
...I didn't need to be told that...

245
00:30:35,528 --> 00:30:39,783
...because it was written
all over your face...

246
00:30:39,944 --> 00:30:42,978
...what you suffered, what
you went through...

247
00:30:44,616 --> 00:30:47,779
...and what you lost.

248
00:30:50,696 --> 00:30:54,493
Look, I'm in a jam. Can't you help me?

249
00:30:55,816 --> 00:30:56,864
What sort of jam?

250
00:30:57,032 --> 00:30:58,658
I need to get hold of a few joints.

251
00:30:59,528 --> 00:31:00,957
What do you mean "joints"?

252
00:31:01,128 --> 00:31:03,136
Just a few.

253
00:31:09,128 --> 00:31:12,739
I won't get you anything.
Don't make trouble.

254
00:31:13,736 --> 00:31:15,940
You watch out for yourself, son.

255
00:31:17,768 --> 00:31:19,775
I am...

256
00:31:20,648 --> 00:31:24,641
...the Roberto Carlos of the poor.

257
00:31:25,960 --> 00:31:32,255
I'm the boy who loved you and grew up...

258
00:31:34,216 --> 00:31:39,748
...I sing where you no longer can.

259
00:31:42,472 --> 00:31:49,149
That's the destiny life has given me.

260
00:31:50,344 --> 00:31:52,035
Why can't you be like him?

261
00:31:53,416 --> 00:31:55,172
I can't sing.

262
00:31:56,872 --> 00:31:58,759
Besides, you'd have to
get me out of here!

263
00:32:01,992 --> 00:32:06,247
It's even worse out there.
Now, let's watch the singer.

264
00:32:07,432 --> 00:32:10,977
Since you won't get me joints,
I'll look for my mom.

265
00:32:11,400 --> 00:32:14,848
If you find her before I do, let me know.

266
00:32:15,112 --> 00:32:17,894
In your footsteps...

267
00:32:18,888 --> 00:32:21,736
...where you passed by.

268
00:32:54,088 --> 00:32:56,990
- Keep still.
- Any other questions?

269
00:32:57,608 --> 00:33:02,048
- Why did you leave home?
- Granny nagged me, so I left.

270
00:33:03,048 --> 00:33:06,845
Look, I'm only trying to help you.

271
00:33:07,144 --> 00:33:10,690
But you have to trust me.
Tell me everything.

272
00:33:11,368 --> 00:33:14,532
If I do, you'll turn me over to the cops.

273
00:33:14,952 --> 00:33:18,629
I'm not a cop. I'm a doctor.

274
00:33:18,984 --> 00:33:20,871
Promise you won't tell the judge?

275
00:33:24,104 --> 00:33:27,584
I told you, I want you with the others.

276
00:33:28,904 --> 00:33:31,043
- What is it?
- Transfer.

277
00:33:31,208 --> 00:33:33,150
We don't have his evaluation yet.

278
00:33:33,384 --> 00:33:35,805
Not my problem. Let's go.

279
00:33:35,976 --> 00:33:38,464
I still haven't told her everything.

280
00:33:38,760 --> 00:33:42,622
If she doesn't know, how will
the judge let me out?

281
00:33:59,112 --> 00:34:00,541
There's another lady there.

282
00:34:01,864 --> 00:34:04,385
Everything you said is kept confidential.

283
00:34:04,551 --> 00:34:06,559
Go. Obey, Mr. Sapato.

284
00:34:19,528 --> 00:34:21,917
Almir, I don't want any trouble.

285
00:34:22,088 --> 00:34:23,844
I want those kids back in 3 days.

286
00:34:24,008 --> 00:34:26,975
Relax, I always bring them back.

287
00:34:27,144 --> 00:34:30,046
Sure, but some of your
colleagues haven't.

288
00:34:30,280 --> 00:34:34,076
- And I take the rap.
- Don't panic.

289
00:34:34,248 --> 00:34:37,925
If anyone asks, they're on vacation.

290
00:34:57,160 --> 00:35:00,007
What are you looking at? Get a move on.

291
00:35:01,320 --> 00:35:02,367
Hurry!

292
00:35:08,680 --> 00:35:09,923
Help!

293
00:35:10,087 --> 00:35:12,422
No! Help!

294
00:35:38,375 --> 00:35:41,724
I don't know. Could be any of them.

295
00:35:42,408 --> 00:35:46,336
I only remember he was a blond.

296
00:35:49,128 --> 00:35:52,095
They all look the same.
How can I be sure?

297
00:35:54,312 --> 00:35:57,792
You say he looked like that blond one?

298
00:35:58,408 --> 00:36:00,415
He's already committed a homicide.

299
00:36:00,584 --> 00:36:03,682
Could be, but I only saw him
for a second.

300
00:36:03,847 --> 00:36:04,895
I can't be certain.

301
00:36:05,063 --> 00:36:07,584
It's him all right. He's a wild one.

302
00:36:07,816 --> 00:36:10,980
You seem certain. I cannot be sure.

303
00:36:11,144 --> 00:36:14,046
Let's go. It won't bring father back.

304
00:36:14,216 --> 00:36:18,787
I know it's painful, but it's
still part of our job.

305
00:37:08,488 --> 00:37:10,430
What's your name, kid?

306
00:37:11,751 --> 00:37:13,245
I like it.

307
00:37:28,008 --> 00:37:31,172
Have you seen my son? You know him?

308
00:37:31,528 --> 00:37:32,772
Fumaca.

309
00:37:35,559 --> 00:37:36,934
Do you know where he is?

310
00:37:38,824 --> 00:37:40,133
Is he sick?

311
00:37:46,248 --> 00:37:48,190
Has something happened to him?

312
00:37:55,080 --> 00:37:56,935
They took away a bunch of guys...

313
00:37:57,096 --> 00:37:58,754
...and Fumaca hasn't returned yet.

314
00:37:58,920 --> 00:38:01,440
You'd better inquire further.

315
00:38:01,671 --> 00:38:05,283
Lady, better make yourself another son...

316
00:38:05,448 --> 00:38:07,139
...Cause that one's had it!

317
00:38:10,888 --> 00:38:17,565
The bodies of 2 boys, of about
14 to 15, have been found.

318
00:38:17,735 --> 00:38:22,372
The victims were riddled
with bulletholes.

319
00:38:22,535 --> 00:38:25,569
The authorities are at this moment...

320
00:38:25,735 --> 00:38:28,834
...going around to all city
reform schools...

321
00:38:28,999 --> 00:38:35,229
...the only clue was the drill
uniforms they are wearing.

322
00:38:37,639 --> 00:38:38,686
Let's go! Quick!

323
00:38:39,432 --> 00:38:41,570
Get dressed and out!

324
00:38:45,256 --> 00:38:48,933
We have visitors. Keep your traps
shut, or you're back here!

325
00:39:24,231 --> 00:39:26,598
This is the dormitory wing.

326
00:39:27,304 --> 00:39:29,693
We work miracles with our small budget.

327
00:39:29,864 --> 00:39:32,384
That explains the conditions.

328
00:39:33,639 --> 00:39:38,276
- Are the children locked up?
- No, it's not like that anymore.

329
00:39:42,983 --> 00:39:46,464
This is our chief supervisor,
he is dedicated to his boys.

330
00:39:46,631 --> 00:39:53,222
Excuse the mess, it is difficult
to clean all day long.

331
00:39:53,672 --> 00:39:55,101
And that boy?

332
00:39:57,256 --> 00:40:00,158
- Shouldn't he be in school?
- No, he is sick.

333
00:40:02,439 --> 00:40:04,261
Infectious Hepatitis.

334
00:40:07,560 --> 00:40:10,527
Son, how are you getting along here?

335
00:40:11,015 --> 00:40:13,055
The doctor comes twice a week.

336
00:40:16,519 --> 00:40:19,683
Did the mother see the boy
in the infirmary, or not?

337
00:40:19,848 --> 00:40:21,222
Sure she did.

338
00:40:21,383 --> 00:40:23,587
She said she'd been here Sunday.

339
00:40:23,751 --> 00:40:25,955
She was told the boy had run away.

340
00:40:26,119 --> 00:40:28,006
She doesn't know what she's
talking about.

341
00:40:28,167 --> 00:40:29,990
I took her to the infirmary myself.

342
00:40:30,152 --> 00:40:33,119
She was shocked, naturally...

343
00:40:33,288 --> 00:40:35,360
...considering the state he was in.

344
00:40:35,527 --> 00:40:40,742
She knew the police had been here
and had taken the boy away.

345
00:40:40,904 --> 00:40:42,594
But the police never returned.

346
00:40:42,759 --> 00:40:47,015
When boys fight, they are
worse than adults.

347
00:40:47,239 --> 00:40:51,679
Could one boy attack another
with such violence?

348
00:40:52,039 --> 00:40:54,428
Only if he was King Kong.

349
00:40:54,664 --> 00:40:57,381
When he's better, you can talk to him.

350
00:40:58,311 --> 00:41:02,173
We'd like the press to spend
some time here...

351
00:41:02,344 --> 00:41:05,061
...to acknowledge the valuable
work we do.

352
00:41:26,855 --> 00:41:32,256
Pixote, you're here! Where's Fumaca?

353
00:41:32,552 --> 00:41:36,349
They took us away somewhere
and worked him over.

354
00:41:36,583 --> 00:41:41,155
- They said, he'd killed that old man.
- His mother was here on Sunday.

355
00:41:41,448 --> 00:41:45,245
She blew up when she found out
they'd taken Fumaca away.

356
00:41:45,415 --> 00:41:48,066
She said she'd tell the papers.

357
00:41:48,231 --> 00:41:50,053
It's gonna get rough.

358
00:41:50,215 --> 00:41:51,906
So, Pixote, tell us everything.

359
00:41:52,519 --> 00:41:57,985
Almir, that son of a bitch, drove
off with some of the kids.

360
00:41:58,151 --> 00:42:01,119
Carlinhos and Mirandinha,
he killed them both.

361
00:42:02,695 --> 00:42:05,346
Then he took us to the police station...

362
00:42:06,087 --> 00:42:08,095
...and stuck us in solitary.

363
00:42:09,671 --> 00:42:13,086
We were there for a long time.
Sapato came and took me out...

364
00:42:13,255 --> 00:42:15,394
...and put me in fatigues.

365
00:42:17,735 --> 00:42:20,320
- I gotta get out of here.
- Me too.

366
00:42:20,487 --> 00:42:22,822
I saved a bit of glue for you.

367
00:42:23,559 --> 00:42:26,276
When you're through, get rid of the can.

368
00:42:26,439 --> 00:42:29,920
- Thanks.
- Let's split.

369
00:42:32,711 --> 00:42:34,205
Hang in there, O.K.?

370
00:44:43,271 --> 00:44:45,278
The boy is in fine shape.

371
00:44:45,831 --> 00:44:48,798
If he doesn't eat well,
he's gonna "kick it."

372
00:44:51,335 --> 00:44:55,525
- Isn't that how they talk?
- It is.

373
00:45:51,559 --> 00:45:55,552
Internal hemorrhage. It's what I feared.

374
00:45:56,295 --> 00:45:58,816
Weren't you caring for him?
How did this happen?

375
00:45:58,984 --> 00:46:01,700
As if... you give me this
boy all busted up.

376
00:46:03,655 --> 00:46:06,502
I did everything I could.

377
00:46:06,855 --> 00:46:08,994
Don't try to pin this on me!

378
00:46:10,695 --> 00:46:13,729
Cad! This will cost you
your job, I swear.

379
00:46:13,895 --> 00:46:14,942
Did you have to turn the boy over?

380
00:46:15,111 --> 00:46:17,380
I didn't turn him over.
The police came for him.

381
00:46:17,543 --> 00:46:20,707
Scream at them. I had no part in it.

382
00:46:20,935 --> 00:46:23,455
You accepted the boy in this condition?

383
00:46:24,263 --> 00:46:25,692
It was on my day off.

384
00:46:28,423 --> 00:46:32,220
- You accepted him, then?
- What should I have done?

385
00:46:32,455 --> 00:46:34,844
Nothing!

386
00:46:35,143 --> 00:46:38,558
What I want is for all of you
to go to hell!

387
00:46:38,727 --> 00:46:43,877
The press will come down on us
like a ton of bricks!

388
00:46:44,743 --> 00:46:46,947
God, this is the last thing we needed!

389
00:46:50,631 --> 00:46:55,846
- What's the kid doing here?
- He's out of it.

390
00:46:56,519 --> 00:46:58,854
He won't remember a thing.

391
00:46:59,015 --> 00:47:01,600
I won't be blamed!

392
00:47:01,767 --> 00:47:04,996
I will put the blame on you!

393
00:47:14,631 --> 00:47:19,901
Make your own bed. Everybody
has to pull together.

394
00:47:26,151 --> 00:47:27,744
Come on, get dressed.

395
00:47:28,199 --> 00:47:31,876
The doctor says you can go. Snap to it.

396
00:47:32,039 --> 00:47:34,112
Where's Fumaca? He was in that bed.

397
00:47:36,007 --> 00:47:40,131
That's nonsense, kid. I don't
know any Fumaca.

398
00:47:41,895 --> 00:47:42,943
Swallow this.

399
00:48:24,198 --> 00:48:28,322
...drawn up by President Figueiredo...

400
00:48:33,159 --> 00:48:36,771
In São Paulo, violence on
the streets increases daily...

401
00:48:36,935 --> 00:48:41,757
...at dawn the body of LCB was found.

402
00:48:41,927 --> 00:48:45,921
The Director of the lnstitute
explained to our reporters:

403
00:48:46,727 --> 00:48:49,891
Fights are frequent between
the children...

404
00:48:50,055 --> 00:48:52,444
...mostly due to their social
background...

405
00:48:52,807 --> 00:48:57,062
...as for the case of the minor
who was found dead.

406
00:48:58,247 --> 00:49:03,844
I have informed, that he had
been brutally beaten up...

407
00:49:04,007 --> 00:49:05,895
...by one of his colleagues...

408
00:49:06,695 --> 00:49:09,728
...and that the attacker
has been identified.

409
00:49:10,151 --> 00:49:14,908
His assailant, A.C., 17,
has a police record...

410
00:49:15,078 --> 00:49:17,926
...of armed robbery, assault,
and 1 homicide.

411
00:49:18,087 --> 00:49:20,738
A typical juvenile delinquent.

412
00:49:23,783 --> 00:49:28,605
I really don't know. I went
and he wasn't there.

413
00:49:29,478 --> 00:49:33,340
Then they told me he had run away.

414
00:49:34,278 --> 00:49:36,548
Then when I went to visit him...

415
00:49:36,903 --> 00:49:39,805
...they told me he was in the infirmary.

416
00:49:40,871 --> 00:49:47,745
Then a boy told me it was a lie;
that the police had got him.

417
00:49:49,191 --> 00:49:54,341
I don't know. I just want my son.

418
00:49:55,335 --> 00:49:59,459
I think this institution
is pretty mysterious.

419
00:50:00,263 --> 00:50:05,664
This reporter saw him in the
infirmary in a terrible state.

420
00:50:06,855 --> 00:50:09,637
He couldn't have taken a step.
So how could he have run away?

421
00:50:11,911 --> 00:50:15,075
Everyone get to bed.

422
00:50:15,239 --> 00:50:18,141
Shit, you want to destroy me?!

423
00:50:18,567 --> 00:50:20,258
But it won't be like that.!

424
00:50:20,935 --> 00:50:24,033
You scum, you think
you can get rid of me?!

425
00:50:24,198 --> 00:50:26,206
But you're wrong, you hear?!

426
00:50:26,503 --> 00:50:29,089
That's quite enough for today!

427
00:50:29,383 --> 00:50:32,678
Sapato, you son of a bitch,
I want to talk to you!

428
00:50:32,838 --> 00:50:34,333
Everyone to the dormitory!

429
00:50:35,399 --> 00:50:37,603
Everyone stay put!

430
00:50:40,967 --> 00:50:45,091
Come on, I'm gonna bust your gut!

431
00:50:45,959 --> 00:50:47,519
I'll cut you in pieces!

432
00:50:47,687 --> 00:50:51,942
Sapato, you swine, get your ass here!

433
00:50:52,103 --> 00:50:55,452
I didn't hurt Fumaca! He was my friend!

434
00:50:57,031 --> 00:50:59,748
It was you and your gang of friends!

435
00:50:59,911 --> 00:51:01,285
You are stoned.

436
00:51:01,447 --> 00:51:03,902
You want my hide!

437
00:51:04,070 --> 00:51:05,696
Don't get carried away.

438
00:51:06,567 --> 00:51:09,600
Even if you had done it,
nothing will happen to you.

439
00:51:10,727 --> 00:51:14,655
You'll be 18 soon and
everything will be fine.

440
00:51:16,038 --> 00:51:20,162
No one will bother you.
You don't even exist.

441
00:51:21,287 --> 00:51:24,004
There will be nothing on your record.

442
00:51:24,582 --> 00:51:27,135
I wasn't even on duty yesterday.

443
00:51:29,734 --> 00:51:32,451
Keep cool, and everything will work out.

444
00:51:34,855 --> 00:51:37,505
Now, everybody get to bed!

445
00:51:52,774 --> 00:51:57,990
- Why the rush?
- Let me go! You want my hide!

446
00:52:24,006 --> 00:52:25,949
What's going on? Who's there?

447
00:52:38,023 --> 00:52:43,238
What have they done to you?

448
00:52:44,743 --> 00:52:46,750
They got me, Lilica.

449
00:52:47,431 --> 00:52:49,057
They finished me off.

450
00:52:49,926 --> 00:52:52,196
They took me to the box.

451
00:52:53,447 --> 00:52:55,073
They let me have it.

452
00:52:57,031 --> 00:52:58,405
Really worked me over.

453
00:52:58,566 --> 00:53:01,915
Where are you hurt? Tell me, tell me.

454
00:53:02,150 --> 00:53:05,216
Tell me, where did they hit you?

455
00:53:05,351 --> 00:53:06,976
Everywhere.

456
00:53:14,311 --> 00:53:15,423
Help me, Lilica.

457
00:53:15,590 --> 00:53:19,965
I'll help you, I'm here beside you.

458
00:53:20,071 --> 00:53:23,104
I promise no one will lay
a hand on you again.

459
00:53:23,270 --> 00:53:25,092
No one will harm you.

460
00:53:25,255 --> 00:53:27,644
- He's dying.
- No he's not!

461
00:53:28,647 --> 00:53:32,957
You're my man. You're my love.
You're my life.

462
00:53:33,447 --> 00:53:37,637
I promise I'll always stay by your side.

463
00:53:37,799 --> 00:53:42,054
- He's dying!
- He's NOT dying!

464
00:53:43,623 --> 00:53:46,852
You're not dying.
You're gonna stay with me.

465
00:53:47,014 --> 00:53:49,731
I love you. I do.

466
00:54:10,118 --> 00:54:14,047
You'll pay for this you fucking swine!

467
00:54:14,343 --> 00:54:17,692
I'll kill all of you!

468
00:54:21,511 --> 00:54:24,806
I'll be the next one. Dito, let's split.

469
00:54:24,966 --> 00:54:26,657
Open this door!

470
00:54:27,783 --> 00:54:30,117
Let's destroy this shit hole.

471
00:54:36,167 --> 00:54:37,727
They want to kill me!

472
00:55:33,318 --> 00:55:36,165
Mr. Mario, I'm really very worried.

473
00:55:36,710 --> 00:55:38,084
How so?

474
00:55:39,078 --> 00:55:41,533
It was a kids rumble?

475
00:55:45,479 --> 00:55:49,156
- What was the dead kid into?
- Deviates.

476
00:55:51,239 --> 00:55:54,403
If there is no suspect, find one.

477
00:55:54,887 --> 00:56:00,157
This will blow the whole thing wide open.

478
00:56:21,830 --> 00:56:24,929
The 2nd death in less than 2 weeks.

479
00:56:25,095 --> 00:56:27,942
You can ask Almir about the first one.

480
00:56:29,127 --> 00:56:33,567
You know why, this country doesn't budge?

481
00:56:34,374 --> 00:56:36,382
Because it's full of idiots.

482
00:56:38,214 --> 00:56:41,378
The judge has just arrived.

483
00:56:42,694 --> 00:56:45,444
Well let's get it over with.

484
00:56:46,342 --> 00:56:50,019
Tonight, a boy was killed.

485
00:56:51,206 --> 00:56:55,397
Tell me everything you know,
as if telling your father.

486
00:56:56,327 --> 00:56:58,847
I'm here to help you.

487
00:56:59,655 --> 00:57:02,110
Why all the destruction?

488
00:57:03,110 --> 00:57:05,379
Isn't this your home?

489
00:57:05,990 --> 00:57:08,259
A home we all ought to take care of.

490
00:57:09,446 --> 00:57:14,978
Why all this crazy fighting,
even killing each other.

491
00:57:27,174 --> 00:57:33,219
You're here to reintegrate into
society as useful citizens.

492
00:57:34,215 --> 00:57:37,062
You're missing the chance of a lifetime.

493
00:57:38,055 --> 00:57:39,299
Why?

494
00:57:43,238 --> 00:57:45,180
Can anyone tell me?

495
00:57:48,678 --> 00:57:49,987
Can you?

496
00:57:57,767 --> 00:58:02,469
I'll only leave here
when I know the truth.

497
00:58:06,855 --> 00:58:10,150
Only God can give or take life away.

498
00:58:20,614 --> 00:58:23,516
They're all blind, deaf, and dumb.

499
00:58:28,550 --> 00:58:33,187
They're covering up because
they all feel guilty.

500
00:58:47,687 --> 00:58:49,956
You're almost 18, aren't you?

501
00:58:52,166 --> 00:58:54,501
You were a friend of the victim?

502
00:58:56,198 --> 00:58:57,954
I knew him.

503
00:58:58,951 --> 00:59:02,693
- Tell me about him.
- I have nothing to say.

504
00:59:03,430 --> 00:59:04,924
I know nothing.

505
00:59:06,054 --> 00:59:08,771
- Want to talk in private?
- What?

506
00:59:09,126 --> 00:59:12,159
You can talk. The judge will protect you.

507
00:59:13,126 --> 00:59:15,810
Why'd you do it? Did he betray you?

508
00:59:16,294 --> 00:59:18,050
Where you jealous?

509
00:59:18,726 --> 00:59:21,246
Go on, tell us!

510
00:59:22,438 --> 00:59:25,406
It's a lie! You're trying to frame me!

511
00:59:25,575 --> 00:59:29,884
Did you start it?
Queer stuff, right or wrong?

512
00:59:30,246 --> 00:59:34,621
He hit you and that's how
it happened, right?

513
00:59:34,790 --> 00:59:36,284
You animals!

514
00:59:36,454 --> 00:59:39,236
You killed him, you disgusting fairy!

515
00:59:39,398 --> 00:59:40,445
Stop!

516
00:59:41,766 --> 00:59:43,075
Leave!

517
00:59:43,878 --> 00:59:45,187
Get out!

518
00:59:47,334 --> 00:59:48,447
Go!

519
01:00:10,503 --> 01:00:15,456
You can tell me, son. Don't be afraid.

520
01:01:02,982 --> 01:01:04,543
My God!

521
01:01:26,278 --> 01:01:27,839
That's the window!

522
01:01:33,510 --> 01:01:35,845
Freedom's outside.

523
01:01:38,182 --> 01:01:39,360
Let's go.

524
01:01:50,534 --> 01:01:52,160
C'mon, let's go, man!

525
01:01:58,727 --> 01:02:00,614
It's worse out there for me.

526
01:02:03,334 --> 01:02:04,578
Idiot!

527
01:02:58,118 --> 01:02:59,940
Stop, thief!

528
01:04:19,334 --> 01:04:22,683
I love lying here in the sun.

529
01:04:26,566 --> 01:04:29,795
When I am with you, I feel so calm.

530
01:04:29,958 --> 01:04:31,135
And you?

531
01:04:34,502 --> 01:04:36,706
Imagine us in Copacabana.

532
01:04:36,870 --> 01:04:40,219
Beautiful beach, beautiful sun.

533
01:04:40,390 --> 01:04:43,554
Take all of us, Dito. Take us.

534
01:04:44,102 --> 01:04:48,739
I promise. When I make the big time...

535
01:04:48,902 --> 01:04:52,131
- ...all four of us will go.
- Awesome!

536
01:04:58,886 --> 01:05:02,945
I want to ask you something.

537
01:05:03,430 --> 01:05:04,608
Anything.

538
01:05:05,734 --> 01:05:09,083
- Do you like me?
- Of course I do.

539
01:05:09,702 --> 01:05:11,262
Then say...

540
01:05:11,430 --> 01:05:14,464
...Lilica, I love you.

541
01:05:15,014 --> 01:05:17,981
- Cut it out, Lilica!
- Say it, Dito.

542
01:05:20,454 --> 01:05:22,145
Don't fuck with me.

543
01:05:24,550 --> 01:05:26,622
Fuck with you, I will.

544
01:05:52,198 --> 01:05:53,758
Lilica.

545
01:06:20,102 --> 01:06:24,292
Awesome. Long time, no see.

546
01:06:24,453 --> 01:06:27,236
What a surprise, get in.

547
01:06:27,398 --> 01:06:29,285
I thought you had forgotten me!

548
01:06:29,446 --> 01:06:33,756
Forgotten you? How could I forget you.

549
01:06:57,286 --> 01:07:00,963
You took your time!
We've been here since 9.

550
01:07:13,094 --> 01:07:15,680
Go on, Lilica. Take it in.

551
01:07:20,198 --> 01:07:22,085
The peace pipe.

552
01:07:22,374 --> 01:07:26,432
- It's all yours, Dito.
- No, I don't do grass.

553
01:07:26,918 --> 01:07:29,122
Don't do grass?

554
01:07:30,246 --> 01:07:35,515
You only took a small hit.
I don't care for non-smokers.

555
01:07:36,006 --> 01:07:38,722
If you think you're gonna
sit here looking on...

556
01:07:41,062 --> 01:07:44,858
- I just don't feel like it.
- Don't feel like it, my ass.

557
01:07:45,478 --> 01:07:47,900
Show this crumb what it's all about.

558
01:07:48,294 --> 01:07:50,301
Suck in, man.

559
01:07:53,222 --> 01:07:56,768
Cristal, your car is really great.

560
01:07:58,533 --> 01:08:03,803
It is for me and my friends.

561
01:08:04,166 --> 01:08:06,053
But only my close ones.

562
01:09:05,029 --> 01:09:08,706
What do you think this is, man?
Lemon pledge time?

563
01:09:08,869 --> 01:09:12,415
- Leave the kid alone, Cristal.
- What are you thinking, queen?

564
01:09:12,582 --> 01:09:15,299
What are you thinking, eh?

565
01:09:15,462 --> 01:09:16,444
Sorry.

566
01:09:16,614 --> 01:09:20,672
Sorry my ass! You ain't
gonna watch anything!

567
01:09:21,222 --> 01:09:25,019
You come here, drink my whiskey...

568
01:09:25,189 --> 01:09:27,012
...mess the place up...

569
01:09:27,174 --> 01:09:28,930
...watch this shitty film...

570
01:09:29,094 --> 01:09:32,574
What do you think I am, a hostess?

571
01:09:32,742 --> 01:09:34,814
You've got it all wrong.

572
01:09:35,174 --> 01:09:38,021
Dito is just a kid.

573
01:09:38,181 --> 01:09:40,767
He doesn't know anything
about this sort of thing.

574
01:09:40,997 --> 01:09:43,964
- Give him a break.
- I won't even wish him luck.

575
01:09:44,326 --> 01:09:47,806
I'm wasting my time with these crumbs.

576
01:09:47,973 --> 01:09:52,032
You want to know something?
I won't make no deal.

577
01:09:52,198 --> 01:09:56,060
So you can't get out, now!

578
01:10:02,181 --> 01:10:06,753
You can't do this. Dito worked
his ass off to get the dough!

579
01:10:07,173 --> 01:10:10,850
That's not my problem. It's yours! Out!

580
01:10:11,013 --> 01:10:13,086
Just this favor.

581
01:10:13,254 --> 01:10:14,683
No, I won't.

582
01:10:24,774 --> 01:10:28,832
Let me talk to him for a while.

583
01:10:32,006 --> 01:10:33,893
Assholes!

584
01:10:40,710 --> 01:10:44,572
Some is missing. There's 5,000 or so.

585
01:10:44,742 --> 01:10:46,629
I soon as I sell the stuff, it'll be O.K.

586
01:10:46,789 --> 01:10:49,058
And where are you going to deal it?

587
01:10:49,221 --> 01:10:51,425
In Rio. I know the spots.

588
01:10:55,941 --> 01:10:58,210
I'm gonna save you some time.

589
01:10:58,374 --> 01:11:01,090
I don't do this for anyone,
but I like you.

590
01:11:01,382 --> 01:11:05,244
When you get there, see my friend Debora.

591
01:11:05,606 --> 01:11:08,323
A fine chick with a large clientele.

592
01:11:08,486 --> 01:11:12,926
Take the stuff to her. Rio's
a pretty bad place.

593
01:11:13,350 --> 01:11:17,343
If you can't find her look for
Raulzinho at the cowboy club.

594
01:11:18,150 --> 01:11:20,867
- You know the place, don't you?
- I know it.

595
01:11:21,030 --> 01:11:23,997
Get going then.

596
01:11:27,686 --> 01:11:29,824
And don't forget.

597
01:11:30,501 --> 01:11:32,541
You owe me 5 more grand.

598
01:11:34,341 --> 01:11:37,189
And no double-crossing.

599
01:11:37,350 --> 01:11:42,685
If you mess things up it'll cost double.

600
01:11:44,710 --> 01:11:48,638
This is your break. Either you deal...

601
01:11:51,557 --> 01:11:52,801
...or you'll get dealt!

602
01:12:11,846 --> 01:12:15,075
Boy, am I hungry!

603
01:12:15,173 --> 01:12:20,640
Just pretend you are eating
and you'll be O.K.

604
01:12:26,246 --> 01:12:29,409
Do you think we are on the wrong train?

605
01:12:29,573 --> 01:12:33,567
If we are, we'll get the right one.

606
01:12:33,734 --> 01:12:36,581
We'll get there sooner or later.

607
01:12:58,117 --> 01:13:02,492
When I get my share, I'm gonna
get a board like that.

608
01:13:05,414 --> 01:13:07,683
I'm not into that.

609
01:13:07,846 --> 01:13:11,708
I'd like a stream where
I can see the bottom.

610
01:13:11,878 --> 01:13:14,267
I spoke to the lady. She's nearby.

611
01:13:14,437 --> 01:13:17,023
Me and Lilica will go. You two stay here.

612
01:13:17,253 --> 01:13:22,010
Hey man, we're together.
Why can't we go too?

613
01:13:22,182 --> 01:13:25,859
Yeah, Dito. I want to see
the lady, if she's sexy.

614
01:13:26,022 --> 01:13:29,371
- O.K. Let's go.
- C'mon Pixote.

615
01:13:44,518 --> 01:13:47,551
It's good. I'll take it.

616
01:13:49,253 --> 01:13:52,450
- How did you get here?
- By train?

617
01:13:55,973 --> 01:14:00,032
What are you staring at?
Think I'm pretty?

618
01:14:00,197 --> 01:14:01,145
I think.

619
01:14:05,957 --> 01:14:11,870
Cristal is still kicking?
I thought he'd vanished.

620
01:14:13,189 --> 01:14:17,444
- Is this your first trip here?
- Yeah, the first.

621
01:14:19,269 --> 01:14:22,117
Okay, that'll be 13,000.

622
01:14:23,749 --> 01:14:25,636
Did she say she lived here?

623
01:14:28,613 --> 01:14:30,435
Where does she sleep?

624
01:14:33,093 --> 01:14:34,980
No telephone; no nothing. It's empty.

625
01:14:39,365 --> 01:14:43,391
- Why? You don't trust me?
- No, it's not that.

626
01:14:44,933 --> 01:14:47,072
Let's be friends.

627
01:14:47,237 --> 01:14:53,217
I'll take you home. I've
got a son about your age.

628
01:14:54,085 --> 01:14:55,711
Wouldn't you like to play with him?

629
01:14:59,781 --> 01:15:03,491
This is for food, and the
rest will come later.

630
01:15:04,454 --> 01:15:10,149
What? Don't you trust me?
You've got my number.

631
01:15:10,789 --> 01:15:12,033
It's very simple.

632
01:15:12,197 --> 01:15:14,139
I'll take the stuff,
take it to my friend...

633
01:15:14,310 --> 01:15:16,514
...he pays me, and I'll pay you.

634
01:15:19,045 --> 01:15:22,209
Or do you think I'd walk around
with all that money?

635
01:15:23,781 --> 01:15:25,854
We won't leave without the dough!

636
01:15:26,021 --> 01:15:28,672
- I'm the boss, Lilica!
- You're gonna get dealt.

637
01:15:28,837 --> 01:15:32,383
- Debora seems all right.
- Keep out of this, Pixote!

638
01:15:33,381 --> 01:15:35,520
Okay, you know best.

639
01:15:35,686 --> 01:15:40,704
This is the way I work, if
you don't want it, fine.

640
01:15:44,709 --> 01:15:47,098
How long would we have to wait?

641
01:15:47,269 --> 01:15:50,302
Jesus, I'll be back as soon as I can.

642
01:15:50,469 --> 01:15:53,503
But leave half the stuff for good faith.

643
01:16:10,502 --> 01:16:12,127
The water is great, Lilica.

644
01:16:12,293 --> 01:16:14,432
Don't splash, Chico.

645
01:16:19,525 --> 01:16:23,137
Didn't they teach you
any manners at home?

646
01:16:23,301 --> 01:16:25,308
What home, Lilica? The brothel?

647
01:16:26,949 --> 01:16:30,495
Watch your mouth. My home was no brothel!

648
01:16:30,662 --> 01:16:32,549
Will you two quit fighting!

649
01:16:35,525 --> 01:16:37,412
Shouldn't Debora be back by now?

650
01:16:37,574 --> 01:16:41,370
Maybe we'd better go back.
Dito will be pissed.

651
01:16:42,501 --> 01:16:46,811
We just got here.
Why do we have to go now?

652
01:16:46,982 --> 01:16:49,829
I want to know if Dito's got the dough.

653
01:16:49,989 --> 01:16:53,023
I saw some great threads today,
all embroidered.

654
01:16:54,341 --> 01:16:58,400
When I get my share, no one
will mess with me.

655
01:16:58,565 --> 01:17:04,860
- I won't die like Big Boy.
- Nobody knows the future.

656
01:17:05,541 --> 01:17:09,021
When I get my share
of the take, Lilica...

657
01:17:09,381 --> 01:17:13,821
...I'm gonna buy a nice black .38
and you know what I'll do?

658
01:17:15,077 --> 01:17:18,906
This is a hold up! Get 'em up,
you bastard.

659
01:17:24,037 --> 01:17:27,266
That's how I'll treat those ass kickers.

660
01:17:27,941 --> 01:17:31,684
Everyone will respect me.
Chico, the Trigger King.

661
01:17:36,517 --> 01:17:38,721
And know who'll be the first?

662
01:17:41,190 --> 01:17:45,445
The big-shot cop who beat me up
at the station...

663
01:17:45,733 --> 01:17:49,410
...and I didn't even know why
he was hitting me.

664
01:17:51,109 --> 01:17:53,181
But his day will come.

665
01:17:53,797 --> 01:17:56,961
That son of a bitch will pay.

666
01:18:00,646 --> 01:18:04,639
Roberto should be here with us.

667
01:18:06,917 --> 01:18:11,357
It'd be great if he were here.

668
01:18:11,525 --> 01:18:15,202
But he couldn't go in the water;
his leg would rust.

669
01:18:24,517 --> 01:18:28,314
- I'll be 18 next month.
- Getting old, eh? Lilica?

670
01:18:34,949 --> 01:18:39,521
Then the going will get rough.
I'll have to cool it.

671
01:18:40,133 --> 01:18:43,297
If I'm caught, I'll be beaten
and locked up forever.

672
01:18:44,933 --> 01:18:48,228
When I'm 18, I'll split.

673
01:18:49,541 --> 01:18:52,770
I'll see if Roberto will
let me join his band.

674
01:18:53,765 --> 01:18:55,456
For me, things will be the same.

675
01:18:56,773 --> 01:18:59,807
They'll always be on my back.

676
01:19:00,293 --> 01:19:02,748
They'll always find a way
of messing me up.

677
01:19:11,045 --> 01:19:13,500
What can a queen expect from life?

678
01:19:15,653 --> 01:19:17,475
Nothing, Lilica.

679
01:20:14,533 --> 01:20:17,250
I knew that whore was double-crossing us.

680
01:20:18,245 --> 01:20:19,805
Fuck!

681
01:20:20,997 --> 01:20:23,136
Son of a bitch!

682
01:20:24,837 --> 01:20:26,659
How did we ever get into this?

683
01:20:29,445 --> 01:20:31,584
You got us into this.

684
01:20:33,477 --> 01:20:36,128
Did I give her the stuff?

685
01:20:36,421 --> 01:20:38,625
Wake up, will you?

686
01:20:38,789 --> 01:20:42,718
Aren't you the lay of that
bastard, Cristal?

687
01:20:42,885 --> 01:20:44,511
How does Cristal come into this?

688
01:20:44,677 --> 01:20:47,841
Well, all you wanted was
to make it with him.

689
01:20:48,005 --> 01:20:50,077
You took us along to show off.

690
01:20:51,973 --> 01:20:54,046
Baby's jealous, isn't he?

691
01:20:58,053 --> 01:21:00,638
I didn't do it to show off.

692
01:21:02,533 --> 01:21:03,962
I did it for you.

693
01:21:04,453 --> 01:21:08,250
One thing I hate is people cheating me.

694
01:21:08,997 --> 01:21:10,491
Business is business.

695
01:21:10,725 --> 01:21:13,114
- Yes, or no?
- That depends.

696
01:21:14,053 --> 01:21:20,388
Some business requires a little cheating.

697
01:21:20,389 --> 01:21:24,447
Kiss off, Lilica! I never wanna
see your face again!

698
01:21:24,805 --> 01:21:28,100
What's wrong with you?
What's done is done.

699
01:21:29,669 --> 01:21:30,782
Just go!

700
01:21:32,485 --> 01:21:34,624
Really want me to go, Dito.

701
01:21:36,773 --> 01:21:41,115
Just repeat that and you
won't see me again.

702
01:21:42,341 --> 01:21:46,848
Go on, say it! Repeat it!

703
01:22:38,661 --> 01:22:40,155
Come here.

704
01:22:44,997 --> 01:22:47,714
It's okay. Raulzinho's waiting.

705
01:22:50,693 --> 01:22:54,238
Not me, I wouldn't feel safe.

706
01:22:56,645 --> 01:23:01,085
If they're caught they can say
they're begging, or something.

707
01:23:01,253 --> 01:23:02,911
I'll do it.

708
01:23:06,373 --> 01:23:09,853
Don't hand over the stuff
without getting the cash.

709
01:23:10,085 --> 01:23:11,459
No "laters."

710
01:24:12,165 --> 01:24:16,672
No, I must go to São Paulo, on business.

711
01:24:16,837 --> 01:24:19,554
I'll be back in two days.

712
01:24:20,293 --> 01:24:21,722
Who are you? What do you want?

713
01:24:21,893 --> 01:24:24,610
We called you up. Cristal sent us.

714
01:24:24,773 --> 01:24:26,267
Yes, I know.

715
01:24:26,821 --> 01:24:28,196
No, no, I'm here.

716
01:24:28,357 --> 01:24:29,469
Come in.

717
01:24:31,493 --> 01:24:32,987
No, I'll be back soon.

718
01:24:33,157 --> 01:24:34,651
Let me see the stuff.

719
01:24:39,108 --> 01:24:40,669
Put the shit over here!

720
01:24:44,933 --> 01:24:50,268
No, it's a private matter.
I'll tell you later.

721
01:24:50,821 --> 01:24:51,868
Hang on.

722
01:24:52,036 --> 01:24:54,622
- How much?
- 8,000 in cash.

723
01:24:54,789 --> 01:24:56,033
What the fu...?

724
01:24:57,285 --> 01:25:00,100
Okay, okay, hang on.

725
01:25:02,404 --> 01:25:05,700
Why the hell did you give it to him?

726
01:25:06,181 --> 01:25:09,410
Didn't you hear what Lilica said?

727
01:25:10,149 --> 01:25:12,800
What could I do?

728
01:25:13,605 --> 01:25:15,034
He asked for it.

729
01:25:15,205 --> 01:25:17,092
Just because he asked, you gave it?

730
01:25:17,317 --> 01:25:18,244
Hi there!

731
01:25:25,765 --> 01:25:28,612
See who's there? That cow Debora.

732
01:25:28,772 --> 01:25:29,885
Let's go call Dito.

733
01:25:30,053 --> 01:25:33,730
No way, well take care of her ourselves.

734
01:25:35,685 --> 01:25:38,849
- What about the stuff?
- We'll get it later.

735
01:25:39,013 --> 01:25:40,125
C'mon.

736
01:25:49,509 --> 01:25:51,647
- Everything O.K.
- Hi, boys.

737
01:26:00,708 --> 01:26:02,596
We came to get our money.

738
01:26:04,996 --> 01:26:07,004
We waited all day.

739
01:26:08,132 --> 01:26:10,849
I was held up in traffic.

740
01:26:11,845 --> 01:26:14,878
Glad you came. I've got the cash.

741
01:26:16,645 --> 01:26:21,085
You wait outside and after
the show I'll pay you.

742
01:26:21,445 --> 01:26:22,492
No way!

743
01:26:22,661 --> 01:26:26,851
We're not gonna fall for that twice.

744
01:26:27,013 --> 01:26:28,835
We want it now, okay.

745
01:26:29,125 --> 01:26:32,474
Piss off! Leave, or I'll call the police!

746
01:26:32,644 --> 01:26:34,073
Then your bag goes with us!

747
01:26:59,780 --> 01:27:01,090
Speak to me!

748
01:27:01,573 --> 01:27:03,777
Speak to me, for God's sake!

749
01:28:03,717 --> 01:28:08,802
This is Dito, this is Pixote,
all real nice people.

750
01:28:14,981 --> 01:28:19,039
Hey, take a look at that
dark one over there.

751
01:28:21,189 --> 01:28:25,498
- What do you think?
- I like it.

752
01:28:28,996 --> 01:28:32,030
She's a love machine, man.

753
01:28:32,196 --> 01:28:35,677
1,000 a day, at least.

754
01:28:36,292 --> 01:28:39,522
I'll hand her over to you,
because I'm going away.

755
01:28:39,876 --> 01:28:42,724
It's a bargain.

756
01:28:47,812 --> 01:28:49,023
Let's get to the point.

757
01:29:08,676 --> 01:29:10,367
Turn it off!

758
01:29:10,852 --> 01:29:13,373
We gotta talk.

759
01:29:13,668 --> 01:29:14,977
Close your eyes.

760
01:29:16,933 --> 01:29:18,820
You think I'm stupid?

761
01:29:19,557 --> 01:29:21,564
I was good to you, wasn't I?

762
01:29:21,733 --> 01:29:25,410
Sure, but you know I've got to cut out.

763
01:29:25,573 --> 01:29:27,460
Only for a while.

764
01:29:28,901 --> 01:29:34,171
They're O.K., What's more,
you said you'd agree with it.

765
01:29:35,044 --> 01:29:37,433
What am I gonna do with these kids?

766
01:29:37,861 --> 01:29:41,854
It's only for a while.
I'll come straight back.

767
01:29:44,325 --> 01:29:46,659
Don't want to make trouble,
do you, Sueli?

768
01:29:48,036 --> 01:29:51,898
Okay, forget it. Just let me rest.

769
01:29:56,228 --> 01:29:58,684
Hand over the 1,000, then...

770
01:30:08,388 --> 01:30:10,210
Easy, brother!

771
01:30:11,205 --> 01:30:14,107
This gun is great. It's brand new.

772
01:30:14,916 --> 01:30:16,804
You only need some bullets.

773
01:30:17,157 --> 01:30:20,506
Another 1,000 and it's yours,
you'll need it.

774
01:30:20,676 --> 01:30:22,105
I've got one.

775
01:30:27,717 --> 01:30:31,262
- Like it? Do you want it?
- Of course, I do.

776
01:30:32,644 --> 01:30:34,335
I'll take it for Pixote.

777
01:31:01,956 --> 01:31:03,647
What are you peeking at?

778
01:31:11,300 --> 01:31:12,729
You hurt?

779
01:31:16,292 --> 01:31:17,274
You sick?

780
01:31:18,724 --> 01:31:20,612
I may be.

781
01:31:27,108 --> 01:31:28,930
Why are you staring?

782
01:31:30,117 --> 01:31:33,150
- Should I have kept the baby?
- What baby?

783
01:31:35,300 --> 01:31:36,161
That one!

784
01:31:37,668 --> 01:31:41,727
What do you think that is? A steak?

785
01:31:46,245 --> 01:31:51,395
Didn't your mom tell you the facts
of life? Even looks like you.

786
01:31:51,556 --> 01:31:53,181
Look at him!

787
01:31:56,868 --> 01:31:58,940
Stop staring at me!

788
01:32:03,525 --> 01:32:08,096
Get out, or I'll stick you
like I stuck him! Go!

789
01:32:29,893 --> 01:32:32,031
This goddamned fever...

790
01:32:34,372 --> 01:32:36,707
...won't it ever go away?

791
01:32:42,436 --> 01:32:47,521
There's blood in the bathroom,
I think she's hurt.

792
01:32:48,260 --> 01:32:52,319
No, she's not hurt. She's menstruating.

793
01:32:53,189 --> 01:32:54,879
Didn't they ever tell you?

794
01:32:56,773 --> 01:32:58,398
Every woman has it.

795
01:32:59,140 --> 01:33:02,883
Quiet, Lilica. I don't
want fighting here.

796
01:33:09,444 --> 01:33:11,299
Why are you people so quiet?

797
01:33:12,836 --> 01:33:14,397
It's like a funeral.

798
01:33:17,956 --> 01:33:22,396
I'm sorry, but I'm not myself today.

799
01:33:39,332 --> 01:33:40,826
Anyone want some?

800
01:33:46,692 --> 01:33:48,896
I'll just give it to Lilica.

801
01:33:54,372 --> 01:33:57,023
You're of age now, right?

802
01:34:06,212 --> 01:34:08,416
Now I can see you better.

803
01:34:10,245 --> 01:34:12,700
If you know how, everything
will be swell.

804
01:34:13,444 --> 01:34:15,648
We'll divide the money in half.

805
01:34:16,132 --> 01:34:19,929
- In half!
- Shut up, will you?!

806
01:34:21,444 --> 01:34:23,005
You've got a deal!

807
01:34:23,429 --> 01:34:29,408
- This could put you in jail.
- Don't worry, we're minors.

808
01:34:30,596 --> 01:34:33,892
There won't be any trouble.

809
01:34:37,125 --> 01:34:38,499
Of course.

810
01:34:39,748 --> 01:34:42,269
So sure of yourself.

811
01:34:43,268 --> 01:34:45,789
Eh, darling?

812
01:34:47,492 --> 01:34:49,314
Who are you trying to fool?

813
01:34:50,180 --> 01:34:52,831
The macho number doesn't add up with me.

814
01:34:54,340 --> 01:34:57,308
My last left a souvenir in the bathroom.

815
01:34:58,564 --> 01:34:59,808
You saw it, didn't you?

816
01:35:06,436 --> 01:35:09,403
- What did you say your name was?
- Pixote.

817
01:35:12,004 --> 01:35:13,116
Pretty name.

818
01:35:15,716 --> 01:35:17,985
Don't be angry with me.

819
01:35:19,621 --> 01:35:23,417
I'm on the edge today.

820
01:35:26,596 --> 01:35:28,668
They told me you are nice people.

821
01:35:30,948 --> 01:35:35,258
Pixote could be the man
for me. How about it?

822
01:36:01,861 --> 01:36:04,828
Here we are.

823
01:36:06,020 --> 01:36:10,275
- Isn't it nice?
- What a flea bag!

824
01:36:10,884 --> 01:36:13,153
I didn't expect a place like this!

825
01:36:13,316 --> 01:36:15,258
It's cheap.

826
01:36:15,748 --> 01:36:20,385
Anyway, for making love,
it's the company that counts.

827
01:36:33,476 --> 01:36:36,825
What are you waiting for, pops?

828
01:36:38,532 --> 01:36:41,434
I thought you couldn't wait?

829
01:36:42,692 --> 01:36:46,750
Lean back. Let me help you
with your pants.

830
01:36:46,916 --> 01:36:48,858
Shall I put some talc on it?

831
01:36:49,604 --> 01:36:51,612
Gimme your whole repertoire.

832
01:37:19,044 --> 01:37:22,208
- You're terrific.
- So are you.

833
01:37:25,444 --> 01:37:28,095
Never seen anything nicer than you.

834
01:37:28,260 --> 01:37:30,203
I'm crazy about you.

835
01:37:40,036 --> 01:37:42,305
Okay, you motherfucker...

836
01:37:43,876 --> 01:37:46,658
- Hand over the money!
- Take the money...

837
01:37:46,948 --> 01:37:48,890
...but don't kill me, I have a family!

838
01:37:49,060 --> 01:37:50,554
See if this makes you cum!

839
01:37:52,068 --> 01:37:55,363
Take everything, but don't kill me.

840
01:38:05,380 --> 01:38:07,966
What did you think of our performance?

841
01:38:08,132 --> 01:38:11,099
It was really great.

842
01:38:11,780 --> 01:38:14,114
Give me your meat, if you don't want it.

843
01:38:14,276 --> 01:38:18,466
You're like pigs! Take it!

844
01:38:20,228 --> 01:38:21,657
She's pissed off?

845
01:38:29,508 --> 01:38:33,475
- They're queers, aren't they?
- Lilica likes cock...

846
01:38:33,476 --> 01:38:38,233
...but Dito doesn't. I know
him. I can assure you.

847
01:38:39,555 --> 01:38:43,352
Now, I'll have a big chocolate ice cream.

848
01:38:45,636 --> 01:38:47,010
What about you?

849
01:38:48,708 --> 01:38:51,042
Cognac and marshmallow.

850
01:39:04,964 --> 01:39:06,077
Enjoying it?

851
01:39:06,244 --> 01:39:09,146
Well worth the money, eh?

852
01:39:09,828 --> 01:39:11,518
How much is a car like this?

853
01:39:12,836 --> 01:39:14,527
You're rich, eh?

854
01:39:14,884 --> 01:39:16,640
I want one.

855
01:39:19,620 --> 01:39:21,508
I want a car like this.

856
01:39:21,668 --> 01:39:26,818
I want a car like this one.

857
01:39:37,540 --> 01:39:39,296
Easy now, or I'll blow your brains out!

858
01:39:40,612 --> 01:39:43,776
Quiet, or I'll cut your balls off!

859
01:39:44,708 --> 01:39:45,755
Nice and quiet.

860
01:39:50,020 --> 01:39:51,776
Go on, get in there!

861
01:39:55,651 --> 01:39:57,659
I think he shit in his pants.

862
01:40:11,715 --> 01:40:14,530
- Everything okay?
- Better and better.

863
01:40:24,068 --> 01:40:27,363
He beat me so hard, I ended up
in the hospital.

864
01:40:28,291 --> 01:40:31,074
I told him, "Shove your money
up your ass."

865
01:40:32,068 --> 01:40:35,548
"I'll have a house and a car all my own."

866
01:40:36,868 --> 01:40:39,388
Then I went to São Paulo, on my own.

867
01:40:40,388 --> 01:40:42,395
I worked in a nightclub.

868
01:40:43,588 --> 01:40:48,542
It was great. I felt like a queen.

869
01:40:49,028 --> 01:40:51,548
I would dance all night.

870
01:40:52,100 --> 01:40:54,434
Change the music.

871
01:41:04,708 --> 01:41:07,555
Hey, I was enjoying that!

872
01:41:07,716 --> 01:41:10,433
Sueli told me too. She's great, eh?

873
01:41:12,260 --> 01:41:14,267
That's all I needed.

874
01:41:17,251 --> 01:41:18,200
Like it?

875
01:41:29,604 --> 01:41:31,164
What did you do there?

876
01:41:31,332 --> 01:41:36,285
I was a go-go girl. I had
a bikini like this...

877
01:41:36,451 --> 01:41:37,826
...all covered with glitter.

878
01:41:37,988 --> 01:41:40,770
Smashing! Sort of heart shaped.

879
01:41:42,340 --> 01:41:44,609
I love dancing.

880
01:41:44,835 --> 01:41:49,724
I used to dance all night
on a stool like this.

881
01:42:18,308 --> 01:42:22,683
- Why did they throw you out?
- That's a long story.

882
01:42:47,747 --> 01:42:51,096
This car is much nicer than Cristal's.

883
01:42:54,019 --> 01:42:55,907
Think the guy in back is hungry?

884
01:42:56,068 --> 01:42:58,785
Just leave me alone!

885
01:43:00,164 --> 01:43:04,671
What's up with you today?
You're being so difficult.

886
01:43:04,964 --> 01:43:07,419
Nothing's the matter.

887
01:43:09,892 --> 01:43:11,801
I hate drunks!

888
01:43:11,940 --> 01:43:14,591
Look, she's drunk.

889
01:43:14,820 --> 01:43:16,642
No big deal.

890
01:43:17,380 --> 01:43:18,307
So what!

891
01:43:20,516 --> 01:43:24,771
- And stop talking trash!
- I just don't like it.

892
01:43:25,635 --> 01:43:27,642
So, give me some money, and I'll go.

893
01:43:27,940 --> 01:43:29,762
Drop dead, you silly fag!

894
01:43:29,924 --> 01:43:33,273
Don't treat me this way.

895
01:43:33,444 --> 01:43:34,688
I'm gonna split.

896
01:43:34,852 --> 01:43:38,267
No one's leaving.

897
01:43:39,587 --> 01:43:45,119
Don't you like it here? What's wrong?

898
01:43:48,739 --> 01:43:50,562
Something upset you?

899
01:43:56,804 --> 01:43:58,811
Don't break up the party.

900
01:44:15,684 --> 01:44:18,979
Ever give anyone a French kiss?

901
01:44:22,020 --> 01:44:24,093
God, she's gross!

902
01:44:41,283 --> 01:44:44,000
Anyone like to dance?

903
01:45:24,291 --> 01:45:27,008
Did he have to do that to me?

904
01:45:28,644 --> 01:45:31,677
Bar me from the door of the club...

905
01:45:33,956 --> 01:45:36,094
...with everyone looking.

906
01:45:40,932 --> 01:45:45,242
Whenever I recall that,
I can't control myself.

907
01:48:32,835 --> 01:48:33,631
Wake up.

908
01:48:34,307 --> 01:48:37,340
Where's Lilica?

909
01:48:38,147 --> 01:48:39,259
She split.

910
01:48:51,780 --> 01:48:54,944
Just as well, she was pissing me off.

911
01:48:57,923 --> 01:48:59,418
Don't talk about her that way.

912
01:49:00,803 --> 01:49:03,837
- She was nice.
- Go after her, then.

913
01:49:05,283 --> 01:49:08,632
- You'd make a lovely couple.
- She was cool.

914
01:49:08,867 --> 01:49:10,558
You're the son of a bitch!

915
01:49:12,195 --> 01:49:15,872
Look, if you don't like it, just get out!

916
01:49:16,035 --> 01:49:17,977
The fewer we are, the better.

917
01:49:18,148 --> 01:49:20,798
You can't say that This isn't your house!

918
01:49:20,963 --> 01:49:22,719
You're asking for it!

919
01:49:22,883 --> 01:49:26,495
We saw your mother giving
her ass to Sapato.

920
01:49:28,004 --> 01:49:29,116
You screwy bastard!

921
01:49:29,539 --> 01:49:33,216
- That goddamned whore!
- Think I didn't know?!

922
01:49:33,955 --> 01:49:36,344
I told you she'd be first on my list.

923
01:49:39,524 --> 01:49:42,873
So keep your nose out of
other people's business!

924
01:49:44,963 --> 01:49:46,392
Did you hear, you asshole?!

925
01:50:13,124 --> 01:50:14,367
What time is it?

926
01:50:25,795 --> 01:50:27,290
Up we go!

927
01:50:31,491 --> 01:50:34,808
Let's go make babies.

928
01:51:19,299 --> 01:51:23,423
Sit there gringo, We'll soon
finish you off.

929
01:51:25,443 --> 01:51:27,450
Let me kiss you.

930
01:51:31,907 --> 01:51:35,900
Fuckin' gringo, don't push me!

931
01:51:37,347 --> 01:51:39,235
Don't push me.

932
01:51:50,659 --> 01:51:54,336
Let me kiss you there, you scumbag!

933
01:52:06,275 --> 01:52:09,887
Keep still, creep, or you're dead!

934
01:52:13,380 --> 01:52:15,518
Get him, Dito! Get him!

935
01:52:15,683 --> 01:52:17,505
I told you never to say my name!

936
01:52:17,891 --> 01:52:19,996
Stop that! look out, Dito!

937
01:52:20,163 --> 01:52:21,821
Shoot!

938
01:53:04,771 --> 01:53:06,778
I'm leaving, Sueli.

939
01:53:15,715 --> 01:53:17,854
Dito was a nice guy.

940
01:53:18,531 --> 01:53:21,695
I know, don't talk about him anymore.

941
01:53:24,547 --> 01:53:25,976
Dito's dead.

942
01:53:46,147 --> 01:53:48,252
I was falling for Dito.

943
01:53:53,091 --> 01:53:56,058
Lilica was right to fall for him.

944
01:54:12,803 --> 01:54:14,876
All of my family is from Minas.

945
01:54:18,755 --> 01:54:21,144
We could go there.

946
01:54:26,435 --> 01:54:27,679
Come with me?

947
01:54:30,275 --> 01:54:32,860
Don't go away.

948
01:54:38,275 --> 01:54:43,032
I can't live all alone.

949
01:55:15,395 --> 01:55:17,086
What's wrong?

950
01:55:27,554 --> 01:55:29,758
It's over.

951
01:55:35,779 --> 01:55:39,041
Come with me, will you? What's wrong?

952
01:55:39,395 --> 01:55:41,282
Don't be like that.

953
01:55:41,827 --> 01:55:46,267
Calm down. Everything's okay.
Sueli's here.

954
01:55:49,187 --> 01:55:51,456
It's over now.

955
01:55:54,819 --> 01:55:55,866
Better now?

956
01:56:39,810 --> 01:56:41,633
Baby, suck it.

957
01:56:48,323 --> 01:56:50,265
Mommy's with you.

958
01:57:18,403 --> 01:57:20,345
Get off me, Pixote!

959
01:57:29,091 --> 01:57:31,546
Get off, Pixote! I don't want this!

960
01:57:36,899 --> 01:57:39,616
Take your dirty mouth off me!

961
01:57:41,891 --> 01:57:44,924
I'm not your mother! Do you hear?!

962
01:57:48,035 --> 01:57:50,042
I don't want a child!

963
01:57:51,043 --> 01:57:53,760
I hate children!

964
01:57:56,866 --> 01:58:00,663
Go live your own life!
We'll each get by on our own!

965
01:58:04,867 --> 01:58:06,044
Scram!

966
01:58:30,722 --> 01:58:31,704
Go.

