- Where are they?
- Still at it.
I hear they broke the bed!
They didn't mean to.
It could be true, anything's possible.
Got a light?
Don't tell anyone, they'll kill you.
Erbao's tractor was in a smash-up.
It was in Longwangkou.
The corpse is still lying there,
you know.
When was it?
Day before yesterday.
Now the Peasant Culture Group...
...from Fenyang will perform...
...Train Heading for Shaoshan.
"A southbound train...
"...races across the sunny land
"It's heading for Shaoshan!
"Chairman Mao's hometown!
"Look, here they come!"
Wheels flying, whistle blowing
Train heading for Shaoshan!
Over mountains, across rivers...
Towards the radiant sun
"Comrades, next stop Shaoshan
"Chairman Mao's hometown
"Really?
"Miss...
"How much longer to Shaoshan?
"Forty minutes, sir
"See, this gentleman
finds the train too slow
"Young folk, don't you know..."
Learn from Dazhai Commune
Where poor farmers
raised the red flag
They united in action
Fearless and practical,
they acted as one
Everyone on board?
Roll call.
- Li Hongyun?
- Yes.
Yao Eryong?
Yin Ruijuan?
Wen Xuefeng?
Zhang Jun?
- Where were you?
- Toilet.
Shangli Hongli?
Li Yang?
Yuan Fenglin?
Guo Xiaoyan?
Wu Jingming?
Cui Mingliang?
Lu Jinghuan?
Wang Xiaoling?
Zhang Xiaohong?
Zhong Ping?
Sun Lijuan?
Song Yongping?
- Cui Mingliang?
- In the toilet.
Slackers hog the toilet.
He's not a slacker!
Driver Xue, sound the horn.
- Zhang Jun, your trousers?
- Wearing them!
It's really cold!
- No, the other pair.
- Performance over?
Of course! I'm on the bus!
Are you?
- Aren't I?
- No discipline!
- Everyone was waiting!
- Are you in charge?
You understand collectivism?
Give me a break! I'm not that late.
- I didn't spoil the show.
- Didn't you?
You think you were okay?
- What do you think?
- I'm not bad.
What the hell were
those train sounds?
I don't know how a train sounds!
Never taken a train?
Even if you've never tasted pork,
you must have seen a pig!
I've only heard one!
Seen The Train Driver's Son?
Seen Railway Guerrillas?
I'm not a train driver's son.
Forget it, Mingliang.
Finished?
Let's move.
Ready yet, Mum?
Can't you make yourself useful?
More chores?
Have you asked Brother?
Who's older, you or him?
You should have had him first then.
Shouldn't have had you at all!
We're different!
I'm an art worker, I use my brain.
Really? Here, you follow orders.
Then I'll stop coming home.
Yes, society needs you, live outside!
- If you won't feed me, the Party will.
- Get out!
He slashed girls' trousers
with a razor.
He used to cut the girls too,
until he got more skilful.
Then the girls didn't notice...
...until they got home.
- Pretty bad.
- Your trousers, Zhang Jun.
The bottoms are so wide!
I could sweep the streets with them!
Didn't you see this boiling?
Where did you get those bellbottoms?
My Auntie got them in Guangzhou.
Your Auntie bought them for you?
They're trendy in the big cities,
you know.
Then you should go and live there!
I would if I could!
Mum, you should liberate
your thoughts!
You should try self-criticism!
Watch out they don't lock you all up.
Men need to let off steam!
No legwarmers? Catch your death, then.
Come on!
- Want a pair, Eryong?
- And get my legs cut?
Who'd want to do that, idiot?
Come on, help unload the logs.
Okay.
Your hat.
Hey!
- What are those trousers?
- Bellbottoms.
What?
Bellbottom trousers.
- Can you squat in them?
- Of course.
Show me.
Squat.
- See?
- Okay.
People can work in those trousers?
I'm an art worker, no manual work.
You sound more like
a capitalist roader.
I can't talk to you.
What's the time?
See, there they are.
Really?
Them? That Cui Mingliang
looks like a real idiot.
Why not teach him a lesson?
- Go on!
- I don't dare.
I do.
What time do you call this?
Sorry, my watch stopped.
Not smart enough?
Stupid!
- What are those trousers?
- Same as his.
Imitating others like a kid!
- They're in fashion.
- One good turn...
It's starting, it'll be sold out!
Buy the tickets!
Quick!
Go on!
I'm a rambler
A rambler's fate is sad
I won't disguise who I am
I'm a rambler
Yin Ruijuan of the Cultural Team!
Someone wants you outside!
Dad!
- Why are you here?
- I'm not with a crowd.
- Who are you with?
- Zhong Ping.
- Learn from good people!
- What do you mean?
Face the wall!
You're easily led,
always seeing foreign movies.
Cui Mingliang!
Sir.
You're seeing this film too.
Why have you come out?
- I have a report to write.
- Really?
I have to go.
You can write reports?
- Go back and watch it.
- No, I don't want to.
Then don't be late.
I don't believe him.
Wearing glasses
doesn't mean he can write!
He just blindly follows others!
Of course I'm judging by appearance!
I see hundreds at the station
every day.
I know a bad guy when I see one.
Coincidence!
No, I saw you.
I saw you too.
My father would too, let's go down.
Haven't you been with Zhong Ping?
Why should I have been?
Zhang Jun's family doesn't know yet?
They should by now.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
Zhong Ping's family
seems to like Zhang Jun.
He ate at their place last night.
Your father goes too far sometimes.
- What do you mean?
- He's like a KGB man.
Don't say that, he is my dad.
Since Mum died, he's worried about me.
But he's like a military dictator!
Don't say that.
- What are you doing tomorrow?
- Working.
Auntie wants me
to meet a man tomorrow.
A prospective husband?
They arrange the whole thing.
That's nice, to have it arranged.
Auntie says he's a dentist.
Great, a university graduate!
- Why are you so happy?
- Am I?
Where is Ulan Bator?
Capital of Outer Mongolia.
Where's Outer Mongolia?
Up north, past Inner Mongolia.
And further north?
USSR.
The sea, I guess.
And further north?
What the fuck are you on about?
Further north is here, Fenyang.
18, Wujia Lane... Zhang Jun's house.
So we're all north of the sea.
"Romance... romance...
"What is romance?
"My soul is like a willow in March
"Romance... romance...
"What is romance?
"Who loves not romance?
"My thoughts ripen like fruit
in autumn"
You use this ruler for fighting?
Comics? How old are you?
Camelia? What's this Camelia?
She sells camelias.
"Through Marguerite's sad demise,
the book reveals...
"...the ugly face of capitalism
and the fact of moral hypocrisy.
"Marguerite has humble origins.
"To survive, she prostitutes herself
on the streets of Paris..."
Paris! Prostitute!
Eat!
Let him be, don't look for him.
"Slightly out of focus...
Slightly out of focus..."
Are you crazy?
Losing your temper?
Thinking about that dentist?
We could beat him up!
Smash out his teeth so badly...
...even he couldn't fix them!
Good plan?
I've been looking for you!
I told you we'd get haircuts!
Not you... Cui, you should watch
TV this evening.
I'm waiting for a haircut.
I see, very impressive!
Yin Ruijuan!
Let's go.
- What's on?
- Daredevil Garrison, I think.
Daredevil Garrison?
- Supposed to be good.
- War film?
Come on, Zhang Jun.
You weren't asking me.
Shut up and come along.
Quick!
Come!
Cui Mingliang!
Come on, Eryong.
Are you sick?
Still taking the works bus home?
- Any plans tonight?
- Yes.
- You had a perm.
Looks good!
I'll be going, then.
- You go ahead!
- Okay.
Go on, Xu is waiting for us.
You were taking your time with her.
I had to let her finish.
Plenty to say to her, but not to me.
- We see each other every day!
- So?
Come on.
You're angry again.
No, I'm not.
What's upsetting you?
You are... all your socialising
with girls.
We all have pasts, you know.
Is that wrong?
Didn't someone say you should love
a person completely...
...including his past?
- Who said that?
- Who?
A friend... Pushkin.
He thinks I should love
that girl Han too?
Maybe you can leave that to me.
I'll beat you to death!
We'll meet again in twenty years
How beautiful
our great Motherland will be
The sky is new, the earth is new
City and village alike will glow
Young friends,
this spring will be yours
Yours and mine
The new generation of the 1980s!
We'll meet again in twenty years...
With 8 or 9 wives
and hordes of kids!
Settle down, everyone.
We need to talk.
Zhang Jun, stand up.
Sing us "Young Friends Gather".
I'm no vocalist.
Never mind, sing it.
Young friends gathering today
Rowing little boats
in the bright spring...
That's enough!
Quiet!
What were you singing in the truck?
I wasn't leading it.
No? I heard you!
You were the loudest.
What was it?
Is this a punishment?
Calm down, our priority is unity!
Unity?
I heard it was you.
- I don't know.
- Don't know?
- Who else then?
- Don't know.
Me.
You again?
Okay, sing it for us.
We'll meet again in twenty years
With 8 or 9 wives
and hordes of kids
Stop! What are you singing?
When is twenty years from now?
2000.
Where will our country be by then?
The 4 Modernisations: Industry,
Agriculture, Defence and Science.
And what are your goals?
Several wives, hordes of kids?
We practice monogamy.
Several wives?
Like landowners before Liberation?
You think you could handle that?
And hordes of kids?
We practice family planning...
heard of birth control?
It's just a song.
Where's your discipline?
Yes, there's the Open Door policy.
But reforms are still needed.
Think about it.
Okay, I'll reform.
"Long live birth control!
"One child's enough!
"One child's enough!"
Come on in.
- What's wrong?
- Forget it.
Don't want a perm after all?
It'll look good.
What if it doesn't?
It will! Do it for me!
Come on, if Han dares to...
- Say that again!
- No, no.
- Anybody there?
- No.
Boss, where are you from?
- The south.
- Where?
Wenzhou.
Far from Guangzhou?
Around 400 km.
That far!
You want to go south?
Yeah, my Auntie lives there.
- It's nice there.
- Really?
Can you turn it off now?
7 or 8 minutes more.
Be patient, perms take time.
- I don't want curls.
- It'll look great.
Really.
You'll look just like that poster.
Quiet!
The agenda is programme reform.
We'll introduce some pop music.
We've invited someone from town
to guide us.
Maybe some of you don't like it.
But it's been popular in the cities
for a while
and there have been
heated debates there.
My feeling is...
...pop music is relaxing and...
What?
Nothing.
I see Zhong Ping has a perm.
Very up-to-date.
She looks like a Spanish girl!
She could dance flamenco!
It would look great!
The 5th National Assembly
announces the rehabilitation...
...of Comrade Liu Shaoqi.
The Party resolves to return
to the bases of Mao Zedong Thought.
Under the flag
of Mao Zedong Thought,
onward to final victory!
Honour to Comrade Liu Shaoqi!
"Following the same trail,
leading to the tree...
"The morning sun lights my face
and the leafy branches
"Dear companion, dear tree!
"Spring stream on the border
"Clear and pure
"Songs of the border...
"...warm the heart...
"The harbour nights...
"...are so peaceful
"Waves gently rock the battleship"
Zhong Ping!
You know who's being charged?
- Who?
- Piggy.
- What did he get?
- Death penalty!
His mother must be sad.
Serves him right!
One less scumbag, who cares?
- Many watching?
- Lots.
It was packed.
I was just passing by.
Nearly finished?
- Too big?
- About right.
I taught you to cross-stitch!
It's too hard to do.
This is out of fashion, you know.
Never mind.
I'm always wrong.
Did you see him die?
No.
I don't know where they do it.
The police shoot them from behind.
Their brains must splash out...
Don't! It's gross!
Everyone watches.
What's up?
You're smoking?
- No thanks.
- Try one.
Won't your father be angry?
He's out at work.
- Okay?
- Fine.
Are you choking?
I think Lai has a crush on you.
Me? He fancies you!
No way!
Lai is very choosy.
Yes, but that post-office girl
dumped him.
Who dumped who?
She dumped him!
- I didn't know.
- Six months ago!
No-one's better than Zhang Jun.
Think so?
Then you can have him.
I wouldn't dare.
What do you think he's doing now?
Probably thinking of you.
Not necessarily.
I'm not thinking of him!
You have tears in your eyes!
That's smoke.
You've made up your eyebrows!
For Zhang Jun? It looks awful!
No it doesn't.
It's the latest style.
- Awful!
- No, it's not.
Don't do mine!
Stop it! It looks awful.
Shut up!
- Mine look awful?
- Yes!
Take care!
Will you shut up?
This will make you look
so fashionable.
Who cares? That's enough.
Don't move! Just a moment...
Hang on...
Wait till I've finished.
It hurts! Mind your cigarette!
Been with her all afternoon?
Just chatting.
About me?
A bit.
Saying what?
Good things.
That's fine.
Zhong Ping's been strange lately.
Why? Because of Zhang Jun?
Don't think so.
She'll be okay.
What do you know?
- What don't I know?
- You think you know it all.
Someone asked me yesterday...
...whether you're my girlfriend.
Are you?
Why are people so nosy?
I want to know too.
I don't know.
Oh, there's some post for you.
For me?
By the window.
Mingliang: The outside world
is great! Zhang Jun, in Guangzhou
We're so happy on vacation
in the countryside with friends
Light rain is falling...
I, Zhang Di, am always asked...
...if Taiwan girls are better than
Singapore girls
Mingliang!
Stop! Foreign devil!
- Doing well now?
- When did you get back?
This afternoon.
So soon?
You bought a tape player?
- Who's that?
- Zhang Di.
Who?
He's very popular.
More than Teresa Teng.
Let me see.
How's the big, wide world?
Pretty good.
Come on, tell me about it.
Everyone's busy all day.
Zhang Jun!
You're back!
How are you doing?
How's southern food?
Okay... the food here's better.
Zhong Ping!
Can I hear it?
How do you open it?
Careful, don't break it!
The sandstorm blows, but we sing on
We friends have no cares
in the world
Our cattle and horses are strong
We sit proud in the saddle
We warm the world with our light!
Gen... Gen... Genghis Khan
Nothing can stop me,
know where I'm going...
An electric alarm might be better.
It's not to keep out villains.
Who's a villain?
We had a thief once.
He must have been hungry,
he took two eggs.
It takes all sorts.
It's so hot!
Where is happiness?
Cui Mingliang, what's upset you?
Who says I'm upset?
Yin Ruijuan.
- What did she say?
- She says you're sick.
Why doesn't she tell me?
She doesn't dare.
- Why not?
- Because you're sick!
Can't you act normal?
I'm normal enough.
Calm down and talk to me!
Anyhow, she's a girl.
- It's useless.
- Idiot!
Talk to her then.
You've upset her, don't you care?
Hi, Uncle!
- Visiting?
- A washing machine?
- Just bought it.
- We'll bring our washing over!
Seize the moment, talk to her.
In all this time, I've never really
thought of you as my boyfriend.
I was taken aback
when you brought it up the other day.
You didn't notice.
I've been thinking...
I feel... we're not a good match.
And my dad doesn't like you.
I didn't dare to tell you before.
Of course,
Dad's not the main problem.
It's me who feels
we're not a good match.
Incompatible.
We can still see each other...
You're right,
but you know what's wrong?
You're saying it too late.
Cui Mingliang...
Bus 27 to Songjiachuan...
...is ready to depart.
Wen isn't stupid, is he?
He made his own TV in two days.
Why is ours taking so long?
No money this month,
I bought a guitar.
What's up?
Cui Wanlin, come inside!
What is it?
I'll say this in front of our sons.
You took that from my bag?
Who did you buy this for?
Erbo wants it for his wife.
You never buy anything for us
on your trips!
But you never forget that bitch!
Mum, let him explain.
I won't listen.
It's not your business.
Father, I'm 24,
I know as much as you do.
- Are you rebelling?
- What if I am?
I have a little secret
I want to tell you
It's something buried in my heart
Here it comes!
Don't miss!
Let's leave.
How can I face them?
Scared?
If you are, let's leave.
Let's talk it over with our parents.
Be serious.
Chief, you were stationed here?
That's right, I was here for years.
Close by, in a place
for all of us lot from the city.
It's not bad here.
Yes, quite prosperous,
you can tell from this hospital.
Thanks a lot, Dr Liang.
Too much trouble.
Don't say anything,
you're almost family.
So, we're ready.
Let's do it then.
What's wrong?
Don't give me a headache.
Chief, what do you think of
privatisation?
I'm not sure yet.
To be frank, it's very simple.
If you have money,
you can privatise.
Everything's yours:
the actors, the equipment...
Good business!
If I do it, you'll be mine!
Maybe not...
but are you considering it?
Most team members are.
Don't miss your chance.
Many have longed for this chance.
Mr Xu, your friend's girl says
she doesn't want it.
I'm scared.
Of course I'm scared.
No abortion.
I don't want it any more.
Then what do you want?
Go on in!
Fuck you!
To celebrate the 35th Anniversary of
the People's Republic of China...
...the armed forces will salute
Deng Xiaoping in march-past...
We must resolve
the privatisation issue today.
The terms on offer are attractive.
Better than many other communes,
you can check for yourselves.
The asking price isn't that high.
So what do you all think?
Li Hongyun! Just smoking?
This has been pending for months.
If you still hesitate,
what hope is there for reform?
My wife won't agree!
It's like the Sino-British Talks...
Your wife's become an Iron Lady?
Inflexible!
Don't criticise his wife! Li Yang,
what are your thoughts?
You're always harassing me about this.
Why are you so quiet now?
The key thing is the money.
I can't raise that much.
It's not all that much.
The commune knows you're not rich.
Chief, you're so keen
to get rid of us.
To sell us out!
How could I bear to do that?
I'm selling my own job here!
Okay, I'll help you out,
I'll accept the offer.
Really, Song?
What a relief!
Are you going to follow Song?
He'll be our leader.
And you'll be his advisor.
- Are you leaving?
- Aren't you?
No, my father is ill.
Zhang Jun, stop playing.
I'm staying.
I'm waiting for you!
I'd rather open a store.
Zhong Ping...
- I'll teach you mahjong.
- Don't.
- I'm playing for you.
- Stop!
Zhang Jun, stop playing!
Stop shouting, just play.
- What's with you?
- Mind your business.
Just play.
Your turn.
Nine!
Zhang Jun!
Very close...
...very far.
Just wait a bit.
We're almost done.
- Do me a favour.
- What is it?
I promised to say goodbye
but I can't.
Tell them not to wait for me.
Unload it all there.
Can you imitate a rooster's crow?
Just copy me, okay?
Zhang Jun, come and eat!
What is it?
Any water?
- Why?
- To wash my hands.
Really?
Sanming, water.
Thanks.
A bit more.
Me too.
Cousin...
I'm Sanming.
Sanming, I didn't recognise you!
You have a moustache now!
It's been a while!
I was about to go looking for you!
How's your mother?
I'll go see her after we've eaten.
Tell her we're coming, okay?
I'll eat first.
No, either the girl won't
have him...
...or we won't have her.
Sanming will have a hard life.
He'll need a good wife.
No-one stupid or handicapped.
He'll work in the coalmine.
Wenying is still studying.
That's good, but it costs too much.
And it's getting more expensive!
Sanming alone can't earn enough.
She'll have to come back, to work.
Pity, she's studied for 2 years.
Right... I'll keep going here
for as long as I can...
We'll save up to keep her there.
But if we fail,
she'll have to come home.
She's still young.
She should study.
The only work here is
in the fields and down the mine.
She'd do better in education.
But we're almost starving here.