Lascivia
As you arrive, you leave,
No time to nest
we must continue.
I feel that
who knows when,
come and see me
again.
A special welcome to
all of you tonight,
I hope that those who
are far from home
Do not feel too sad.
If there is anything I can do,
I will do it.
I have another piece of
sausage, do you like it?
Oh, yes, thank you.
Just a little bit.
I still can not believe I'm
sitting so close to you.
Really, all my friends
adore his style.
Do you know why they arrested you?
I think it was because
of my boyfriend,
Is in the resistance.
Oh.
I adore him,
His name is Maurice.
Is in the second year
of dental school.
Mine are here,
With relatives.
Oh, France, it's beautiful.
I love France.
Mme. Fénelon his music
is the soul of Paris.
Yes. Yes.
Thank you.
Someone said we will have to
pretend joy when they take us out.
Are you?
Where?
You have to.
I never meant anything to me.
about me.
You really should not eat so much.
Oh, I can not help it.
I never did until
I got arrested.
Since then I have been
hungry all the time.
Can you tell the address?
It's to the north.
Some think it will be Munich,
perhaps as workers on the farms.
Munich?
I'm not sure I can
work on a farm, might?
Have you lived in the country?
No, no, never. She was a student
in my house, my whole life.
He would care, sir.
Change?
He turned east.
To the East?
That can not be right, some
of us know this, Janet.
He cares if we can
stay together.
How old are you?
Twenty.
For real?
If you're so young.
I have to find the shithead.
Why do not you watch what you do?
Come with me.
It's changed.
I almost fainted.
I have to get to the shithead.
Outrageous.
Thank you.
Quiet.
No one is watching.
It was not your fault.
Mrs., Mrs., your husband.
Open the door!
There's a dead man in here.
Come, this is where our things
will be returned to us.
What did you say?
What if this is where our
things will be returned to us?
Take off your coat.
Take off your clothes.
Take off your clothes!
She can keep her hair.
Only shave the Jews.
Look how I look, you Jewish rat.
I'm not a Jewish
rat, I'm French.
For talking!
Where are the people
with whom we came,
The ones on the
Red Cross trucks?
Look...
The "cook".
Mariane, listen to me.
You have to be careful.
Why did they do that?
What do they get?
What is the purpose?
Neither boyfriend would allow me to enter the
resistance because it was too dangerous.
Is that why you did not?
I have been in resistance
for a long time.
There's a dead woman here.
The best at night
When we are alone,
Is to remember everything.
You have to take care of this.
There was once a prince,
Called John,
And was terribly vain.
And he married Princess Couchonet,
Which was very beautiful.
So one day, the prince sent
For her, because she wanted children.
So...
so
They had six children
and five daughters...
And every son had a horse,
And every daughter had a cow.
And when they grew up...
They always took care of each other.
Does anyone know how to sing Madama Butterfly?
Does anyone know how to
sing Madama Butterfly?
She... she can.
Bring it.
I'm Ethanine, I saw her once
in Paris at the Melodie,
My parents took me for
my 17th birthday.
I myself have started to play
professionally this year.
She was the one who
recognized it, it's Michou.
Yesterday I thought I saw
her coming out of her tent.
I begged our custodian
to give him an audition.
For whom is this?
For the officers, for us.
Laura, Laura, come and meet Mme.
Fénelon.
She is one of our
best interpreters.
You can make Brahms solos.
It is an honor for me to meet you.
Is there a Director?
Oh yeah, Mme. Alma Rosé.
His uncle was Gustav Mahler,
the great composer.
He is a fantastic talent, - but
not a warm heart, take care.
Are you Mlle. Fénelon?
Yes madam
Plays the piano?
Let me hear something
about Madama Butterfly.
Will he take it?
Yes, lady, her tones
are very good.
It's marvelous.
Do you know any German music?
Yes.
I am the Lagerfuhrerin Maria Amanda,
Commander of all the
women in this camp.
I...
I forgot to tell Mme. Rosé that...
I can not accept being
in the orchestra
Unless my friend
6W62 can also join
the orchestra.
It has a beautiful voice.
It's in tent B,
unless...
That she may enter,
I...
I must refuse, I'm sorry.
See that they are cleaned,
and sent to the warehouse.
Yes, Mrs. Lagerfuhrerin.
What size?
Number 9, Frau Lagerfuhrerin.
- Nine.
I want boots.
I'm afraid we do not have it.
- Find them!
It should be warm and comfortable
to take care of your voice.
Continue.
Sit down.
From the beginning.
Why so strident?
This is not band music,
We do not touch the wind.
Why can not they obey
my instructions?
Music is the most sacred
activity of humanity,
Must be devoted day and night,
You must listen to yourself,
Should be inspired to achieve some improvement.
They can not just keep
repeating the same stupidity.
Rest, Philharmonic.
I think you altered it.
Well, it's been so good.
Who suddenly realized
how we really sounded.
Well, it was a big crash.
Do not know why we can
not learn that number?
We have to do it as
she indicates it.
And you, you're making them worse.
I've only studied music for
six months in my entire life.
Surely it was not the worst
6 months you've ever spent.
It's not just that we can not mate,
But the teacher has also
gotten into this problem.
Why?
We were just a band of
marches when we started,
To touch the prisoners after
their work assignments
And allowed the band.
Our guards were excited.
Suddenly we found ourselves
playing Bach, Brahms,
Concerts for high metals.
He is a victim of his own pride,
And that's why we have problems now.
- Will they ever feed us?
The last soup will be
served at any time.
I do not want problems.
As soon as the big bosses
came and listened to us
They began to get bored of
hearing the same three numbers.
But we did not have any
other orchestration.
It's just that no composer ever wrote
anything for a group like this.
You happen to not make
instrumentations, do you?
We have performed the same concerts
so many times that the commanders...
Fania, you do not have to instrument,
But you're good at
all sorts of things.
I'll try, I think I can.
Yes
Well, it will not be very professional.
We must tell Madame.
Yes.
We thought you would like to know
Which Fania knows how to implement.
Leave us, leave us.
Tell me the truth Fania.
Yes, I can, I can
not see why not.
I must suppose that he
actually studied it.
Yes, in the conservatory of Paris.
Lucky!
How lucky for you to have Fania.
I've been under terrible pressure
to present something new.
That's what they told me.
You can start with...
I have a piano score
for "Carmen".
Good yes. I guess I
can do "Carmen".
Or something German,
For bone, that of the house.
I know,
But they have done
nothing but Von Suppé.
And we must try to please Fania.
Well, I think that's elementary.
I'd rather believe that
I'm saving my life.
Instead of trying to please S.S.
Do you think you can
do without the other?
Start immediately.
I will need some people
to copy the parts and
Some music paper.
It is not possible to get music paper.
It may not require some.
There is a war going on my dear.
Come on, I'll find some paper,
you draw the lines themselves.
What did he say?
Fania...
I can not help but strive for
the pursuit of perfection,
I was trained that way and
I can not change now.
He is hardly in a position
to criticize her, and
I'm also trying to please her.
Exactly,
But we are artists,
We can not get away from that.
There is nothing
to be ashamed of.
Please try to speed up the work,
You will see that they are
very temperamental with us.
Do it soon Fania.
Now.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
with your permission
A little bit of popular
music with our new member.
Why do you bother
stealing when you know
I can not bear to see you eat so much?
I was just looking for a little taste.
I told you that you could take it.
You should think it's
good to be a little girl,
When are you going to take
care of that situation?
You can not keep expecting
something fantastic to happen.
You have to accept that
this is where you are,
And it is much better
than most prisons.
I will not do it any more.
Is there anyone else you're
doing these things for?
If that's what you
want, then we're done.
Is seriously.
You are welcome to take
everything I have,
I hope you do the same
for me if I'm desperate.
Fania very well that we can
share everything we have.
I have refused to become an
animal for a gram of "something"
Or a piece of potato.
But will not you want to share
with the prebostes as well?
You can share with
those bitches, not me.
Well they are not all like that.
You, you also had a
pet, July, like Fania.
But you are an anti-Semite.
- No, I'm not.
We had many Jewish
friends in the theater.
I am not.
In my opinion Etalina
The public thinks that
you are going to be...
Oh, can you tell? Darling
spells G A S E A D O S.
The point is they want to feel
superior because they probably
Will have to return to their homes
at the end of the war being pagans.
They are more stupid than ever.
Well, then we should
try to educate them.
Fania, Fania,
Tell us about Paris again,
You wore those skirts.
Very elegant, very current,
I always liked flowers.
They are also very tall,
legs are terrible.
You can not wear stockings
because your legs are marked.
My mother would not let me use them.
And her hair, there were women
in a convoy the other day,
I think of Holland,
With loops on top of hair.
Oh yeah, rich girls,
All up.
Where are those women?
Oh, they must have burned them already.
And of songs, do you
know some new ones?
It's strong to say that.
Why not say it?
It is better to be prepared
for when our time comes.
Who sings any of the new songs?
Did you record any record in Paris?
Let's get up.
Fania.
You do not have to do that,
you're in the band now.
I would not want it to be seen
that it is not for prisoners.
I'm so hungry Fania.
What can I do?
Try to think of something else.
Can not you ask Alma something?
Do not be silly, because you
would give me something.
And what am I going to do?
We are all in the same problem.
Why do you expect
me to find food?
I'm not a magician.
Is that all you've done?
At that rate we will wait a hundred
years for you to give us another score.
You can stop annoying, instrument
It is a difficult job,
even for experts.
I have to talk to you.
Why do not you stop...?
Then you lied.
You can not instrument.
I'm very capable of doing
it, I'm sure I can.
What is it then?
One of the women...
this morning...
He spit on me
Yes?
I had not realized how
much they should hate us.
Yes, of course,
what did he expect?
Well, I...
I had not thought about it.
Perhaps you are too aware
of the orchestra's purpose.
No, no, I did not mean...
Do you want to go back to tent B?
Surely that can be fixed.
Master, please, I'm
not criticizing you.
It's just that I'm not used
to being hated this way.
Fania...
In this place there
is life or death.
There is no possibility for
anything else, whatever.
I'm trying to rehearse that piece tomorrow.
I want the parties early.
That, if you can.
You are?
Yes yes I am.
Eat it.
You must go hungry
working all night.
Will not you eat it?
Who gave you the right
to judge anyone?
I'm just trying to keep myself alive,
just like everyone else, just like you.
Or you?
You know what they think of us.
We are no better than the prostitutes
who entertain the murderers.
I know, I'm not judging you.
But if you do, I perceive it from you.
And you have no right.
Eat it.
Well, it does not matter.
Either way we'll live
until we get out of here.
What if we succeeded?
What if we really live?
Everything that means
to me, my dear, is
You try to die, and it's hard to see
that happen and keep your mouth shut.
I'm trying to survive.
Throwing yourself out.
You treat yourself like
a rotten piece of meat.
Shut up.
Do not do that.
What?
Turn around.
You have to look and see everything.
So I can tell when I'm done.
Who?
But I am not a believer.
Why did you choose me?
I always know who to choose.
Live.
Would you let me?
I just want to ask
you about an issue.
What do you know about her?
I see them talking
together sometimes.
Well, she's a militant communist,
She is also engaged to get married.
It's that kind, since we're here
you have plans to survive, why?
I do not know.
It's just... it looks so
different from the others.
So full of courage.
She says the same thing about you.
She... She's talked about me.
Rachel too.
Spatially admire your value,
And your beauty.
She is... she is so beautiful.
Do not you think so?
I love his smile.
It would be all faster if you tell
me what you do not like about it.
I do not understand what's
happening to me, Fania.
I think about her all day.
I just adore everything
she says and does.
Oh, you're in love with her.
Do you think that...
Why not?
They are very young.
When you are so young,
only love matters.
I feel like...
I do not know what it is.
Oh, the human race.
You are laughing at me?
No, for the pure,
everything is purity.
Do not despise yourself.
In this place feeling
something can be a blessing.
Have you ever had
feelings like that Fania?
Never.
Never. With nobody.
Go, let me get some sleep.
What a correct young lady
you should have been.
Had I ever heard anything
more moving, Herr Commander?
Very good, very good, but the
musical opinion of Dr. Méngüele
Are much more expert, of course.
I've really been
totally touched.
You must thank the doctor, Fania.
Thank you Doctor.
I must tell you Fénelon that
I originally objected...
Excuse me Herr commander.
I must tell you that my
name is not really Fénelon,
My mother's last name was Fénelon,
My father's was Goldstein.
I'm Fania Goldstein.
Excuse me, I did not intend
to interrupt, Herr Commander.
You must learn to
sing German songs.
I'll see you begin learning them
immediately, Herr Commander.
As I was saying, I was
opposed to this idea,
On the orchestra.
But now I must say
That a song like that
It is a comfort that nourishes
the spirit and strengthens us
For our difficult work.
Very good.
Fräulein Goldstein,
Is there anything you need especially?
Good...
toothbrush?
Send it to Canada
for some things.
With my congratulations.
To Canada?
Ah the things of the Franchute.
Very clean.
Welcome to Canada.
There you have your filth, stupid.
You got a toothbrush,
can I see it?
Oh, it looks almost new.
Nothing like having something
imported from France, right?
Hey what's up?
What have you got against me?
Nothing.
It's just that I think
that's not the way
Correct to act with a superior.
But when they are the
owners of this place.
You expect me to congratulate
you on some of the things
What are you doing these days
What I am doing?
Oh, let's forget it.
- All right.
I personally feel much safer
Now that Mandel is
so hot with you.
Scared, but I'm grateful,
Otherwise I would not envy anyone
That would wake up so close
to that arrogant Nazi.
There is no danger of that.
You never know.
Life does not always leave a
girl a lot to choose from.
You were not given any alternative
Considering the companies
you've been maintaining.
Listen to this skin and bones.
Well, maybe I am but
I'll wake up near Mandel
Sooner than many of you girls.
That was disgusting, Etalina.
Mandel is just a killer.
Even so it's beautiful,
I'm sorry to bother you.
If you had an ounce of Jewish pride
You could not call such
a monster beautiful.
Do not try to make her look ugly.
Is beautiful.
It is human.
What bothers me is
That a woman
That is so beautiful
Can be doing such things.
We are of the same species.
That's exactly what makes the
whole situation so black.
No, there is still hope.
Because when this war is over,
Europe will be a communist.
And for that, I want to live.
No, we'll try to go to Palestine.
To raise Jewish children in Palestine.
You do not have any Fania identity.
And that's why you can call such
a human and beautiful monster.
I envy you both.
They will not believe that they have solved the problem?
What problem ?, I do not see a problem.
She is human.
Like you, like me.
Do not you think that's a problem?
What does it matter to you?
Your hair comes out lighter.
Go to bed, Maria.
Well that happens, one of us
was a doctor from Vienna,
He just went to check it out.
And I thought we would
never menstruate again.
Why?
Because of this fear,
every day and night.
And the food can be sterilized.
Maria
You know, it's so weird, but I think
Maybe you can control your hunger.
If you could share what you get with
Some other woman, anyone.
You know, sometimes a person
Needs the strength that comes
from giving something.
Fania...
about
To endure.
Understand me.
Is a musician.
Tell them that... it should not be sacrificed.
To hospital.
We need it very much.
Well, do you understand me or not?
Wait, wait.
Excuse me, Herr Oberstand fuhrer.
With your permission.
I could instruct these men that
this woman should not be hurt.
It's our cellist, you
should go to the hospital.
High fever, perhaps typhus.
I do not know what language they speak.
He speaks Italian, Spanish,
Russian, Romanian,
Is not she fantastic?
It is very insistent.
Yes, that is Mala the
head of interpreters.
She's Jewish, but
she's intimidated.
How is that possible?
Mala has been here
longer than anyone else,
Since the field was built.
She was supposed to be gassed,
But escaped with
five other girls.
Did he actually get out?
Yes, it started by opening
a ventilation duct,
Already had managed to pass
the house of the commander,
When he saw them out on the road.
Guess what Mala did
then, demanded clothes.
When they spoke, they realized that
She practically spoke
all languages.
He is very high in the Belgian resistance.
He even has a lover here.
No, you have to be kidding.
Is not true.
They save people.
A few, anyway.
And help others.
Fania.
Come, we must work
on Schubert's song.
You have to practice
the "HRU" sound again,
Dr. Mengele has a sensitive
ear for language.
He has required it.
I hope she's never stupid
enough to cover up a language.
Well, from the beginning.
Excuse me Madam, meet Mala.
Yes very good.
How did you manage to
make yourself respected?
Well, it's extremely
useful, of course.
Speak fluently 9
or 10 languages,
And with so many
nationalities in the camp
Makes it possible to communicate.
Is that all?
It even seems...
That overwhelms them.
Is incredible.
Mala is one of those people
whose superiority is clear.
Even for the ignorant.
Bad is...
Miraculous
Raising a shield among
those kind of people,
Like the cloth around
the precious seeds.
It is everyone's hope here.
Even those Nazis perceive
that kind of glory in it.
She is a miracle.
Are you trying to destroy us?
That was a high octave.
Do you know what is tall or not?
I asked if you know what the
octaves are tall or not?
They should try harder.
As things stand, Dr. Mengele
hardly bears listening to us,
If we come down from a certain
level, anything can happen.
He is a vile and variable man.
The truth is...
If it were not for my reputation
They would have roasted them long ago.
My father was the first violin
of the Vienna Philharmonic,
His string quartet played
all over the world.
My own "Viennese Waltzing Girls"
They played in most of Europe.
I know that.
For I am a Rosé and I am directing...
A group of prisoners.
So, why do they resent me?
You are professional,
Knows that strict
discipline is required,
The director must be respected.
I think it can also be loved.
He can not love what
is not respected!
It is perfectly traditional,
In Austria, in Germany,
when a musician is
Repeatedly wrong...
- Slapping?
Yes of course.
Furtwängler did it very often but
his orchestras idolized him.
I need your support, Fania.
I realize that they respect her,
Must support what they claim to them.
We must constantly raise the
level of our execution,
Or, I really do not know how
long they will bear us.
Will you help me?
It will?
I'm going to tell you the truth,
I really do not know how
long I can bear this.
I'm trying the best I can.
And I'll keep trying.
But sometimes I get the impression
Of which parts of
me are collapsing.
And believe me,
I recognize that it is about
their strength, probably,
That our lives depend on.
So why do they resent me?
I do not know.
I guess... maybe...
It is simply that
When a monster keeps
something in reserve,
We can not, we can not really
dedicate ourselves to please them.
But he has to want
to please them,
And with all his heart.
You are an artist who can only
propose to give the best of herself.
But when you look
through the window...
That's why I told you not
to look out the window.
Fania was wrong,
Seems to believe that I have stopped seeing.
I refused to look.
Before they brought me here,
Had begun to love,
To a young man,
Come as me
He is now a soldier in the Wehrmacht.
The three best months of my life...
The three best months of my life.
Oh. He wanted me, like a coat.
Then I was arrested for being a Jewess.
It still surprises me.
Why is she also German?
Yes, I am, German.
In this place Fania,
You will have to be an artist,
And only artist.
You will have to concentrate
on one thing only,
And it is the creation of all the
beauty that it is capable of creating.
Excuse me.
Attention!
Get Aligned!
Jews on the left.
Aririos on the right.
She and I are only half.
Half what?
Middle Jews.
Our mothers were Aryan,
Mestizos are not meant to
be gassed, Frau Schmidt.
I am completely sure.
Why, if I may ask,
is this selection?
You belong to the Jews.
Get ready to sing.
Nobody wants to end
their lives this time.
Move!
Half Jews, follow me.
In that case they are allowed to
cut the top half of the star.
Was that proposal correct?
It is disgusting to cut the
star of David in half.
Why not?
If we can avoid the gas.
Disgusting are you.
Jewish nationalists,
Since when they are custodians
of the principles...
Do not you dare get
into your traps.
Your discomfort does not impress me,
Because you accepted even
greater humiliation,
Without a gesture.
We are just a convenience.
The blood of innocent Jews
cries out for their betrayal.
Why do not they just shut up?
I'm sick of Jews and heathens,
The Westerners, the Orientals,
The Germans, the non-Germans,
The French, the non-French,
I'm tired, I'm tired...
I'm sick
I am a woman, not a tribe.
And I have been humiliated,
That's all I know.
You're all just jealous,
Anyway they also educated
us as Catholics,
After all, our mothers
were Catholic.
What are you doing that for?
Fania...
I do not know.
I'm doing.
That's right, I'm doing it.
Fania.
In front of you, up at the door.
Thank you.
Fania, they are gassing
12,000 every day now.
12,000 angels,
Flying above.
Every day.
Why do you keep telling
me these things?
What do you want from me?
Look over your eyes,
The air is full of angels.
Two more cigarettes,
You took more time this time.
I'm broken, I'll give
it to you next time.
At least share some of
what you get with others.
For your own good,
So that you do not end up
becoming a complete animal.
Jealous?
All present, Herr Captain.
Do you know who Mala is?
Bad, not very good,
I have seen her, of course,
she has accompanied me with
With the commander, Herr Captain,
As an interpreter.
He has not had any contact
with his musicians.
No, Herr Captain,
She has visited the
barracks for not recently.
Attention!
Mala escaped.
And he helped two.
They got SS uniforms,
Somehow and flew.
What a romance!
Imagine, the two together.
I saw him once, he
is a good fighter,
Blond with beautiful white teeth.
She is Belgian, like me.
What a Belgian, she is
Jewish like all of us.
Eric is Polish, and they are going to
tell the world what is going on here.
Imagine, they could have
exploded that chimney.
Listen, listen, let's
play something for them.
Oh yeah.
Allies land France.
Silence now,
I have corrections.
Paulette, on page 5, letter B, you
will do it in D sharp instead of...
Etalin...
Those are not Jews, they are Poles.
Hitler said he was going
to kill all the Poles
To make room for
the Germans there.
But there must be thousands, they
would never kill so many Aryans.
What are they going to do with them?
I think they're going to
put them in these stalls.
Ladislaus,
Ladislaus...
It's not beautiful?
What happens to them?
Is nothing.
Frau Lagerfuhrerin.
There is a rumor that these Polish Aryans
were going to put them in our barracks.
No way, Madame.
In fact I can tell you that there will
be no more selections in our field.
Of course, there is no
room for newcomers,
There will be other instances.
Oh, look here.
Check it out.
And now...
Let's get you a nice
new suit, some shoes
And a sweet little friend.
Come with me.
Work hard now.
So he's a human
being, after all.
Is she? But where is the mother?
Even so, in a way,
I want to say that at least
he adores the child.
What is going on here?
Everything she said...
What was that he say?
And suddenly it is human.
What is going on here?
From the beginning.
Come on.
We are going to...
Attention!
The officers have decided to keep the piano
in their club for the use of its members.
Can you handle it without him?
Yes, of course, Herr commander.
It was just a little extra
sound, but it's not mandatory.
What is Greta, the Dutch girl?
In front!
Open your mouth.
Do you have any illness?
No, no, Herr Commander.
Dr. Mengele told me that he
is not a very good musician.
No, not very good, but
not very bad either.
But he works very hard...
But could it be handled without it?
Why?
Yes, of course, Herr commander.
My wife needs someone to look
after our little daughters.
You are coming with me.
He will play in the hospital for
the sick and the mental patients,
You will have ready to Beethoven.
Yes, Herr Commander,
I must ask for your tolerance, if I may.
Our cellist has typhus,
And now without the piano too, we may sound
rather deficient in the bass records.
I'll send one of the men's
orchestra cellists,
Have several from the Berlin Philharmonic.
He can train one of his
violinists for Sunday.
Well... of course Herr commander
I'm sure she can teach one
of the girls for Sunday.
Yes.
It will be very interesting Madame, Dr.
Mengele.
Wants to observe the effect
of music on the insane.
Ahh. We will really do our best.
And how have you been these days?
I'm quite well.
Of course, we, all of us
have been very hungry,
most of the time.
And that makes it very difficult.
I offered to send two additional rations, but
Mme. Rosé believed that
you had to win them,
As a reward.
Would not you agree?
It's not me who has to agree or
not, without being the director.
Close the door.
How dare he make such a comment?
I do not understand, I just
told him we were hungry.
When they can interpret a simple piece
Without making a mistake, I will
recommend the extra ration,
But I'll decide that,
you understand?
There can not be two leaders.
Do you agree or not?
Are you upset?
We're hungry, that's
what I was saying.
In this situation we
lose human feelings,
She asked and I told her.
I think we understand
each other.
That's all for now.
Yes, whats up?
Nothing.
I'm really trying to
decide if I should leave.
Oh, come on, Fania, nobody lets
himself die if he can help it.
You should try to be more
honest with yourself.
Go away.
It's here.
The cellist of the male orchestra.
Paulette! Paulette!
Good to see you.
Do you want to say something? What is it?
You're going to play on Sunday...
- At the hospital.
You do not look good...
- Silence.
They have planned...
Gassing... all patients,
After the concert.
How did you know that?
One of the women of the SS
She warned me, I met her once.
I used to be a
waitress in our house.
So I left.
Paulette, welcome.
We were desperate for you.
We do Beethoven's
fifth on Sunday.
Mme. He could lie down for a while.
Do not.
I... I... I can.
Let's start.
From the beginning.
I believe...
that I...
I saw my mother yesterday
My three sisters and my father.
What? Where?
What are you talking about?
Yesterday...
The last convoy of Bucharest...
The mirror, when we played outside,
A train arrived,
Look...
And... I was not...
I was not sure.
But what could you do?
Does it bother you to wash?
Thank you,
Fania, I am tormented,
About whether I should have
warned the other patients
About what was going to happen to them.
What you think?
Except that he would
let them know.
I no longer have any anxiety Paulette,
I live from minute to minute,
My heart beats, so I'm alive,
But I'm filling up with dust.
Go to sleep.
American people.
Hope for you Fania.
Maybe it's too late for the
whole human race, Varya.
So after all it will end.
Everyone comes to tell you
their problems, does not it?
I do not know why they tell me.
You're someone to trust, Fania.
Maybe it's because you
have no ideology,
And you are satisfied with being a person.
There is so much feeling in you.
It was that way, yes.
But you can not cross my
hands with my fingernails,
To be able to face me with
such strong material.
That's the truth.
I'm dying to pieces.
I know. Very well, I seem
to be, too, too, too...
It's making it harder
for me to eat anything.
I am one of the most successful
actresses in Poland,
My father was an earl,
I was born in a castle.
I have a husband and...
Narok, my son is 9 years old.
I do not know what will happen to us,
Fania, you know, before the end.
I just want a Jewish
woman to understand...
When they first brought me here,
I was sure that the Pope
and the Christian leaders
Who did not know.
When they found out they were
going to send planes to bomb
The incinerators and the trains
that bring them here every day.
But the trains kept coming and
the incinerators burning.
Do you understand?
Perhaps there is something more important to them.
So that we are here, in any way,
A group of women who can
not even menstruate
Innocent people who frighten men.
Oh, Fania, please forgive me.
Your...
Why?
What did you do to me?
Were you in the resistance?
Did you try to fight
against this?
Why do you have to feel guilty?
Confide it, or it will destroy us.
If you survive you feel that you are innocent.
Everything is a joke,
You do not see it.
Has no sense.
I'm afraid nothing you would have
done would have changed that.
I almost feel more sorrow for
people like you than for us,
And you, you will survive.
All those around you
will be in sin,
From one end to the other.
And those with whom you
can never speak again.
My memory falls to pieces,
- Did We Go?
Were we Russian last night?
Did we go?
You dropped the milk, Yakovska.
Was mine.
But still.
Our farm is 10
kilometers from here.
They bring it to me.
My sister.
But still.
To throw it that way...
Are you saying it's not my milk?
Do not worry.
You read too many books.
They drive you crazy.
Fania.
I leave for "Baselhauser" on Sunday.
They send me on a tour
to play for the troops.
I wanted you to be
the first to know.
I'm going to be released, Fania.
Can you imagine?
I will touch what I like,
and how I like it.
They say that a musician of my
talent should not be wasted here.
What is the problem?
I thought he would be happy for me.
Well, yes, I am.
Of course.
But, while he is playing, he will continue to
fight because he does not enslave us. It will?
But that's not the point.
I'll be playing for soldiers, Fania.
And what about us?
Will we continue? Will we?
I intend to suggest
that you replace me.
Oh well...
I hope that soon we will follow...
before ..
Why are you trying to
ruin my happiness?
I will be playing
for honorable men.
Not for murderers
like these here.
Soldiers risk their lives.
Why do you need my
approval if you are happy?
Enjoy your happiness.
Not all Germans are Nazis.
You're just a racist
if you think so.
I agree.
It is an extraordinary honor,
The only Jew who will play the
violin for the Germans in the army,
my head is going to explode!
Frau Schmidt
Only for...
Just to extend my
congratulations.
I just heard the big news.
Thank you.
Thank you, Frau Schmidt.
It is very touching for
me, coming from you.
Well, I've never been known
to hide my feelings.
He'll join us for
dinner tonight.
It's a farewell
dinner in his honor.
I'm overwhelmed, Frau
Schmidt, of course.
In short, "in a shoe minister"
In my rooms, yes.
- I will be there. Thank you.
Thank you, Frau Schmidt.
Do not you realize?, really...
That woman, that woman...
He has tried everything to
be transferred from here.
Yeah, she's desperate to get out of here.
And he has the kindness to come
to wish me well in my departure.
Well, that's certainly something I
would never have expected from her.
It is amazing what is
in the human heart.
You judge people, Fania,
You are terribly strict.
Beware of that charm, maybe
they are losing the war.
So... - Why does everything
have to have war inside?
Why can not you accept
the little hope in life?
I'm all confused.
That Schmidt wants it to go
well is really inconceivable.
Alma, she's getting rich
in the black market,
Has stolen every woman
who has come here.
His hand is in everything
that moves in this place.
I'm going there Fania.
If I do not have another chance, I
would like to thank you for your help.
It is totally wrong about
practically everything,
I must say that you
probably saved our lives,
So I thank you from the bottom of my heart.
You can thank him that I
refused to despair, Fania.
That's true, is not it?
What happened?
Schmidt poisoned her, at dinner.
But you can not know?
She was shot this morning.
Schmidt?
No one was going to leave here
unless she could, especially a Jew.
You mean I wanted her dead?
She wrote her epitaph, Why not?
No no no.
Order, order
Tanya, what are you rehearsing for?
Now, move.
No, I'm not leaving.
- Let me stop the rehearsal.
Come on.
Mariane,
Do not touch it like that.
Now, listen to me.
Now I am the director and ordered
you to stop interfering.
Fania, Fania...
With the executioner?
Did he kill Mala and Edic?
You know that?
Well, if he did not, someone else
would have, you can be sure of that.
I want to tell you that there is something...
On which side do you think they are?
Because if someone is not sure, they
are on the side of the executioners.
Come out, ask any
prisoners in this camp.
They will be happy to tell you.
So you know where exactly
you can put your comments.
You should not have let
him do that, Fania.
I answered but nobody
heard what I said.
But he is right,
And I also think it's a serious thing.
I'm not on your side.
I'm just trying to
survive for Jerusalem.
All right.
What do you mean, Fania?
I mean, this is fine.
If you can get away from
what war is, so clean.
But we are not
responsible for this.
No, of course not.
Nothing here is our fault.
What I mean is this,
maybe we are innocent,
But we have changed.
I want to say that we know something
more about the human race,
Which we did not know before.
And not good news.
How can you still call them humans?
And what are they?
I do not like the way you
connect such monsters with us.
Mengele.
Would Herr doctor like to
hear any particular music?
"Kapo"
Doctor.
These are the bracelet and the
posthumous flag of its director.
They must remain undisturbed.
In memoriam.
If the Herr Doctor allows me to.
The orchestra is determined to
Interpret with our greater capacity
In the memory of our
beloved director.
I can assure you, Dr.
We are ready
To devote all the necessary time
To perfect the way we play.
We believe that our late leader
would have wanted us to continue.
Let us move forward,
She has inspired us.
... rehearse and rehearse and rehearse,
We must not touch until
we can do it right.
Yes, we should not
do that again...
You should not have...
I had never been... Fania...
Oh, Mandel.
You can play Mme Butterfly,
You and the others.
We are ready to begin,
Frau Lagerfuhrerin
We are ready to begin.
Is it something that
happened to the boy?
It has always been said that
the greatness of the people,
Depends on the sacrifices
they are willing to make.
I gave him back.
Let's go now,
Touch for me.
Play for me.
Musicians, we'll start the rehearsal.
I order you to rehearse.
It is the Russian artillery,
I am in charge, and I have not given
permission to suspend trials.
Stupid, it's all over.
You do not get it!
It's the Russians
out there, Olga.
And we probably "gas"
Before they can get here.
Relax, we can not
rehearse in the dark.
She can in any case
carry the baton.
Stop grilling potatoes,
What are you thinking?
I order you to come with me.
Stop.
Sit down.
The Germans leave tonight.
I do not see why.
We'll be released, silly.
We survived.
He's trying to get an
orchestra to direct,
But the war must end.
I was supposed to be free, or something.
I believe that...
I should applaud...
he...
I believe that...
Have you seen him?
Do not.
I want you to have this,
It's my diary.
I can not do this.
I know you'll live, Fania, I know.
I assure you that I want to live,
I feel something
terrible is happening.
Where are we going?
Where are they taking us?
Sonya!
Fania, I can not go on.
How is every soldier doing?
Can you tell me
where they lead us?
Because wherever it is
It's like making a guy
forget his problems.
Where do we go?
Who knows?
- Truly?
I think it's so they do not fall
into the hands of the Russians.
They would tell them what they did to them.
Are they going to kill us?
Do not ask me.
I make you "Kappo", keep them together,
Follow that path and take care of the bombs,
The commanders will
be in charge later.
Fania!
Where are you?
Fania...
Try to keep your eyes
Open if you can.
You have to live Fania.
Could it be possible for you
to say something to the press?
It is very important to me.
Let us march, children of the country,
That the day of glory has arrived
We have faced tyranny,
Our bloody flag
Es ized.
Do you understand me comrades?
When you reach men be soldiers
They will fall into our arms,
To kill, to kill completely!
To arms, comrades!
Form brigades!
On the go, on the go,
Do not be afraid.
For a much higher ideal.