Daeng.
I'm going to buy some cigarettes,
do you want anything?
- No, thanks.
"Noy" tel. 081-6828965
They seem pretty drunk eh?
Hello there.
Could I borrow a lighter?
Could I get a cigarette too?
How does it work?
What kind of music do you listen to?
- I listen to all kinds...
- But, not very often.
Your hands look like a musicians.
Do you like "Job"?
- Who?
Do you like "Job Bunjob?'
- I never heard of him.
- How old are you?
I'll be 19 tomorrow...
Why do you ask?
I listen to old music, is that it?
- No, but it doesn't fit your age.
I don't listen to "pop"
it's retarded.
- what do you mean, 'retarded'?
coffee please.
- make it two.
- What are you doing sitting here
at 5:30 in the morning?
Waiting for my Mom,
we are meeting here.
- Your from Bangkok, huh?
No.
I live in Phuket.
But Mom will be here at 10:30.
- So your Mom lives in Bangkok?
Nope.
Stockholm.
- Ah Germany...
Sweden!
What about you? You live in Bangkok?
- No, I'm from Phuket,
but I went to America more
than 10 years ago.
And your just getting back now or what?
- I came back for a funeral.
Why do you have to stay in a hotel?
- I don't have a house in Bangkok.
Hey...hey.
Why don't you go freshen up in my room,
there's time to take a nap.
Your mom isn't going to be here until 10.
coming?
Check please.
- Why don't you bring your boyfriend, too?
What makes you think this guy
is my boyfriend?
Hello.
What's your name?
- My name is Wit.
My name is Ploy.
- Nice to meet you.
Hey.
Are you Wit's girlfriend?
- Wife.
Hello.
- Hi.
Go on in.
If I had know we were having a party,
I would have put something else on.
- We met down at the bar.
She is waiting for her mom
and they are meeting in the lobby at 10.
- 10:30.
oh yeah 10:30.
Her Mom is from Germany.
- Sweden, Wit.
I meant Sweden.
- From Stockholm.
Ploy is from Phuket, like us.
Oh, really?
What happened to your eye?
Mind if I go to the bathroom?
- No...
Make yourself comfortable.
What is this Wit?
You decide to have a party
without telling me?
It's 6 o'clock in the morning!
- What party?
She's just a little girl.
She was waiting for her mom all alone.
for like, 4 hours already.
Well I'm going to sleep understand?
Sleep!
- Go to sleep then!
How can I sleep with some
stranger in the room.
- Well don't worry about it.
We've been on a plane for 20 hours Wit!!
And I'm tired, understand? Tired!
Can't I just get some sleep for 4-5
hours, without some guest here?
- You don't have to entertain.
Feel better?
When she is done in the bathroom,
get her out of this room.
- Where do you want her to go?
That's not our problem, Wit.
- You don't care about
other peoples problems?
What's wrong with her?
- She's waiting for her Mom.
That's not your problem.
That's between her and her mom.
If it's a problem, how is she
going to solve it here?
- OK, it's not our problem.
I just invited her up to freshen up
and get a little sleep.
Sleep here?
- I told her she could rest here
before her mom comes.
So what, this is an orphanage now right?
- No its not, Daeng.
This room is only big enough
for the two of us.
What are you going to do,
why didn't you ask me first?
Wit?
Get that girl out of here, now.
- Where is she now?
In the shower.
- You want me to just burst in?
Yes.
If you don't tell her..
then I'll tell her myself.
- You wouldn't do that.
How do you know?
- You won't.
Is that a challenge?
- No, but I know you won't do it.
- You're going to worry yourself
to death.
Did I wake you?
- No.
You don't have to pick that up,
I'll do it.
Shouldn't you finish in there?
- I'm all finished.
Thank you.
I know your not asleep.
Someone in the room is a thief!
- What's missing?
You like her don't you?
Wit?
- What?
Why aren't you answering?
- You know why I'm not answering.
- I think you should take the medicine
the doctor gave you, and go to sleep.
Yes, I'll go to sleep and then
you will go to that girl.
- That girl could be my daughter!
Thats even better, right?
I thought this would be more comfortable.
- Thank you, sis.
Is this Wit's room?
- And you are?
I'm Noy.
- Oh.
Do you know me?
- I know you, I'm not sure
if Wit's awake or not.
Where did you go?
- I gave her a pillow.
I need to talk to you.
- About?
About us.
- OK, what.
How can we talk, if your reading that book.
- Alright, What is it?
Do you love me?
- Why are you asking?
- Yes.
How come I don't feel like you love me?
- What do you want me to do about it?
I don't want you to do anything!
I want you to love me,
I want to know, you love me.
- If I didn't love you, why did I
marry you?
- If I didn't love you, why would
I stay for 8 years?
7 years.
We don't have time with each other.
- Were together, all day, everyday.
That's not what I meant.
- Well what do you mean then?
Like the two of us, going out to eat.
- What? We have a restaurant why
would we go eat at someone else's?
To hang out, go to a movie, anything!
- I work everyday...
when the restaurant closes
I just want to rest.
What rest, you go to your friends house
and watch football all night!
- So you want me to stop seeing my friends?
I don't want you to stop anything.
I just need to know that you want me too.
- We are human, if we want, we want,
if we don't, then we don't.
Are you saying you don't need me?
- That's not what I said.
Do you remember when we were first together?
You just told me, for no reason
that you loved me, everyday.
- It's been 8 years, Daeng.
Seven years.
- So you want me to have said, "I love you, I love
you, I love you", everyday all this time?
Why not? Don't you love me?
- So like a parrot, Myna Bird or something?
So what, I make you feel like
a Bird in a cage?
- Ok, I love you, I love you,
I love you.
I don't want you to just say it,
I want you to mean it!
- are you having your period or something?
Why do you ask that every time we talk?
- Your so shaky all the time.
What do you care, if I have my period or not?
We haven't slept with each other for a year.
- That's my fault then?
I don't know.
- I haven't been with my wife in 2 years!
It's not like I've been with anyone else.
- And you think I have?
Yes I do.
- Who?
A woman named Noy.
- Who?!
Noy.
I want to know if you have anything
going on with a woman named Noy?
- What are you a psychic,
or palm reader now?
Don't try to change the subject.
- Did you go through my stuff?
No, I was looking for a key
to open the luggage.
It was in the pocket of your shirt.
- Did you check my cellphone too?
- Should I be more careful of my things,
since we live together?
Tell me who she is.
- Don't change the subject.
Who is she?
- If you don't tell me why you
were looking through my stuff,
then I wont tell you anything.
That's a totally different subject!
- That's the same thing, its has to do
with trust!
If were going to live like this maybe
we shouldn't live together.
Daeng.
Where are you going?
I forgot where I put my necklace.
- It's not in the bathroom?
No it's not.
Where did your girlfriend go?
- Probably walking around downstairs.
You guys were arguing, huh?
Because of me right?
- No.
- We were arguing because we didn't
have anything else to do.
- We have been together for a long time. Sometimes
the argument is to prove we are still close.
- Arguing to confirm closeness.
- The worse the argument..
- But it also brings us closer.
Why don't you hug? It's easier.
Hugging, kissing, having sex.
- We've been together 8 years.
What? It has an expiration date?
- Yes.
Like canned food or something!
- That's not the same.
- A can of food tells you
when it will expire.
- This doesn't tell you when it goes bad.
Your Wife is a real beauty.
- She used to be in movies.
Really?
- A long time ago.
She seemed familiar.
How did you meet?
- I was working at a restaurant in America.
- She came in with her husband.
- That's how we met.
Do you two have any children?
- No.
- Daeng has a son with her ex-husband,
and I have a daughter with my ex-girlfriend.
Did they break up because of you?
- That was part of it.
- But I think they broke up,
because their relationship expired.
What about you and your ex?
Did your relationship expire too?
- No, she died.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Are you reading this?
- Go ahead.
- Excuse me, your Jiranan right?
I'm Tiranan, yes.
- Oh Tiranan.
- That paper is 3 days old.
- Someone wants to talk to you.
Who is it?
- It's one of your fans.
Hello?
Yes.
Really?
Thank you.
But I don't act anymore.
I've been living in America.
It's been about 10 years.
I came back for my grandmothers funeral.
I came back by myself.
What?
Lover?
I don't have one, I'm single.
Thank you.
- No problem.
- Please excuse me.
Your a lonely person aren't you.
- Isn't everyone lonely?
- A lot of times, people don't know
they are lonely.
- Since they have things to keep them busy.
That's true, is your wife lonely too?
- Lonely and drunk.
What?
- Nothing.
I had a really gross dream.
- What?
Do you remember the maid
we passed in the hallway?
I dreamt that she was doing
something with the bartender.
- What was it?
They were having sex.
- Did it turn you on?
Jerk!
Go ahead.
Doy?
Doy!
Go ahead.
DOY!
It seems my girlfriend went to go shopping.
It's dark huh?
Come this way.
- You live here?
Yes my condo is also a showroom,
and warehouse.
It's like "three in one".
Are you OK?
- I'm not sure.
- Is this your collection?
I sell, rent it, and collect it too.
"Three in one".
Have a seat.
Want some Vodka?
- Can I use your phone?
- I need to call a friend.
Go ahead.
It's on the table on the corner.
It's next to the hand.
Room 603 please.
His name is Wit Waitiyakun.
What?
He's out?
How long ago?
Your sure?
He left with a girl?
Get a hold of your friend?
- No
Drink up.
- Can I have one on the rocks?
Hello.
Daeng?
Cold water?
- Move over a little.
Warm enough?
- Just move over a little.
- Your wife wouldn't like it.
I don't have a wife.
- Who did I talk to on the phone earlier then?
That was my sister.
- You guys are all the same aren't they.
It really was my sister.
- Don't.
- Don't!
Think you can just kick me for no reason?
Kicking my balls.. that's unacceptable.
You don't have to worry.
I'll use a condom.
Daeng.
Daeng?
Don't leave me.
I'm sorry.
Daeng?
I'm not going to do it again!
I'm sorry.
Love...
you float in the wind....
confident... passionate...
affectionate...
Iove...is it really from the heart...
isn't it funny... we always protect it...
even though it can't be seen...
it provokes and chases our heart...
my heart can sympathize....
somewhat...
hope you don't get...Hurt by love...
and hurt again..
annoying pain of love...
tears flow...
If there are both...
I might have to die
Shall we go?
- Let's go.
Daeng?
I love you.
- The girl from this morning...
- She was kinda cute.
English translation by: BuccKeao.
Subbed by: Jan de Uitvreter.