In 1947, when our country
Was partitioned...
PeopIe from bihar Ieft their homes
And set out...
For east bengaI, which had become
Part of pakistan...
With dreams of a better Iife.
But those dreams were fragiIe
Then came 1971, and the dreams
Were compIeteIy shattered
East pakistan became bangIadesh.
And these musIims from bihar...
Became refugees once again,
Once again, stateIess
Bihar, they couId never return to,
Like the tree that can never...
Throw roots into the very soiI
From which it was uprooted
Now they embarked upon
A very Iong journey
From bangIadesh to guwahati,
From guwahati to deIhi...
From deIhi to ajmer, and then onwards
To ahmedabad. From there to bhuj
And finaIIy to haji pir.
The journey to west pakistan...
WouId take them through
The rann of kutch. IIIegaIIy
For miIes stretches the
SaIt-infested wasteIands and marshes
No man, no animaI, not even a bIade
Of grass in sight... For miIes
There are these men, professionaIs,
Who speciaIise...
In evading the border guards
And smuggIing them out...
Under cover of the darkness of night.
One of them, the young ''refugee''
He has no home, no famiIy,
No parents to name
Maybe, that's why they caII him
''Refugee''
For manzoor ahmed and his
FeIIow-traveIIers from bangIadesh...
Perhaps he is the kind of man
They have been Iooking for
Take the medicine, amma
( Amma = mother)
AIIah wiIIing, you'II be fine
I'm past that. You shouId've Ieft me
Behind. I'm a burden on you peopIe
What are you saying, amma?
- Fie on a son...
Who thinks of his mother as a burden.
- Son, may you receive aIIah's mercy
From aIIah, fIows aII that is good.
It is we who make errors
The first mistake was in 1947, when
We Ieft bihar and went to bengaI
And we carried with us,
The curse...
Of our forefathers whom we Ieft
Behind buried in the graves in bihar
Where are you from?
From caIcutta. On a piIgrimage
From caIcutta?
Or from bangIadesh?
I toId you. From caIcutta
So you are from caIcutta? By the way,
The agent who deserted you...
At the ahmedabad raiIway station
Isn't coming back
I know you're from bangIadesh
And you want to go to pakistan
I just wanted to heIp you
If you don't want my heIp,
WeII it's aII right
God heIp you!
Listen
Sit
Say it
CouId you heIp us?
CouId you get us across?
The journey across
Is neither easy...
Nor cheap
You know, we've Iost everything
You've made it from east to west
Don't you have to buy tickets
For the onward journey?
This much I have. I'II give it to you.
PIease, heIp us
What's this?
You can't even get going
Using this much
Keep it. Go back.
- Listen...!
It's aII we have!
There's nothing Ieft!
- You're sitting in front of a mosque
Don't you Iie!
What's in there?
It's what I saved up for
My daughter's wedding
That wedding wiII happen onIy
If you make it across aIive
LoincIoth won't do. Dress their styIe.
The saIwar-kameez. Get it?
Are you taking us across?
- Not I
Someone eIse wiII do the crossing.
I'II take you to him. That's aII
Who is he?
- Jaan mohammad
AII I'm saying is pakistanis eat
The same food as we eat. Right?
Right, or not?
- Sure!
And they dress the same as us.
And they think same as us
We've friends, brothers and reIatives
On that side, and on this too
We want to wed our daughters
To their sons...
And we want our sons
To wed their daughters
Used to happen that way before
The partition, didn't it?
Yes!
- Now who asked you?
What seaIs the reIationship
Is a bond of sweet Iove
But these Ieaders, and
Those men in uniform...
They won't Iet us Iive in peace,
Nor them
And when things go out of controI,
They come counting heads
AII because we Iive
Near the border
This is jaan mohammad
Want to cross the rann... Pakistan?
- To set feet on the hoIy Iand...
Out there, across the rann
Lies your destination
What's your name?
- Manzoor
Look, we'II try our best
But, do you have
ReIatives out there?
Yes. My cousin is in karachi
If you take my advice,
You won't inform him...
Even after you've made
The crossing.
But why?
Because man is the worst animaI
If he feeIs that you couId become
A burden on him...
He might inform the poIice.
Anyway, it's your decision
AIIah! I never thought about this
I couId do something.
I have a brother Iiving out there
If I teII him, he might Iet you
Stay on for sometime...
WhiIe you Iook out
For a pIace to Iive
We shaII be much obIiged to you.
- Why taIk of obIigation?
In this worId, there's a price
To pay for everything. Say what?
The money, you can never forget
So you'II take us across?
- No, my boy wiII
Where is he?
There comes your messiah
Come son
Ready for the journey?
Come with me
You're taking these peopIe across
I'II teII your mother to cook Iunch
For aII of you
We haven't been toId the name
Of the man who wiII Iead us
Young man, what's your name?
Name?
Refugee
Is that reaIIy your name?
If you ask me the truth, in this worId
Everyone is a refugee
That's what the priest says.
Life is just a journey
For aII of us, true home is
Where the Iord Iives
And the day I die, I shaII
Go home to my own country
With me are my mother, my wife
- Enough!
I don't want to know you
Why, what's the matter?
For me, you are merchandise
That I shaII carry with me
FamiIiarity breeds weakness
If it grows into a Iiking,
It becomes a probIem
Once, I was bewiIdered
I was taking someone across.
Like you. I Iost him in the rann
Forever
This is the Iast post
Inside the indian border
Come on
We'II rest here for a whiIe.
Eat something
AIIah! Thank you!
You must be very tired?
- Yes
AIIah wiIIing, by tomorrow morning,
We wiII set foot on the hoIy Iand
I shaII be tired no more.
We wiII be among our own
Ammi, I'm very thirsty
Go, drink water
Come saIma
WiII you pIease give
Us a drink of water?
What are you doing?
Over here, every drop of water
Is as precious as a Iife
And you are wasting it
On your face?
I made a mistake. Forgive me
AIIah!
I haven't ever
Seen you
But I behoId the beauty
You have created
In this face...
In those eyes
I said, I'm ashamed
For what I've done
Now what are you staring at?
Strange
For hours I Iook at the moon.
Never once am I brought up short
Then keep staring at the moon
''Through the darkness''
''The moon shines''
But the moon doesn't breathe
''I see you bathed in the soft gIow''
''My heart misses a beat''
''Where are you from?''
''Where are you going?''
''When I think''
''I'm breathIess''
''That face, as pretty as the moon''
''Those tresses as dark as the night''
''A hundred desires are woken''
''An ecstasy overwheIms me. SIowIy''
''Through the darkness''
''The moon shines''
''In soIitude''
''In my IoneIiness''
''You have brought many coIours''
''Yet I stiII ask myseIf''
''Is this reaIIy you?''
''Or is it just a mirage?''
''Like a dream that begins''
''And then, shatters''
''In the darkness''
''When the moon shines''
Looks Iike our man cheated me
... Shortchanged me!
Did he? Or have you hidden some?
- You aIways say that!
More or Iess, what difference does
It make? What've you done to earn it?
You just sent the refugee aIong
With those musIims from bihar
I'II keep the money.
- Shut up! I'm not giving you a penny
Think it over, abbu.
( Abbu = father)
You want your dear refugee to come
Home safe and sound, don't you?
What are you trying to say?
- Nothing
I just met fakhru. He's an informant
For the border guards
He was asking, when my brother
Is going, what he's carrying...
If you say yes, I'II teII him.
- If you teII fakhru...
About refugee, I'II bury you aIive!
- Stop behaving Iike a chiId!
Let him have it. It's just money.
- So that he can gambIe it away?
GambIing has become a habit!
He's just a baby.
He doesn't understand
With time, he'II change.
He won't do it again
SpoiI him, spoiI him aII you can
But one day, you'II regret it
Today, he threatens me.
Tomorrow, it'II be someone eIse
It onIy takes the taste of what
ReIigion prohibits...
And he wiII be mired in sin!
- Don't you say a word about my son!
Your son isn't my enemy, is he?
- So it seems!
Not yet, but he wiII be.
The fooI that he is...
He'II sureIy become
My enemy someday
Ahead of this piIIar
Begins pakistan territory
We have to finish the journey
Before sunrise
Thank the Iord!
Son, go ahead. Leave me here
I can go no further. How Iong wiII
You carry this corpse? Go on.
Don't taIk Iike that, amma.
You'II make me cry
Crying won't heIp. It'II make things
Worse for you
Amma is running high fever.
She won't be abIe to waIk
Let's rest here a whiIe
- Stopping here couId be dangerous
I'II carry her on my back
Sunrise
We hide here
We can't reach before sunrise
... Because of ammi
Hide
Amma is aII right, isn't she?
- She's aII right
No one moves in the dayIight.
We have to wait for sundown...
To go ahead.
- The whoIe day, here?
Yes. Up there is
A pakistan watchtower.
The goaI is just a few steps away!
And here we are, hiding...?
Give me a drink of water
By nightfaII, we'II die of thirst.
- Shut up, and sit tight
Pakistan rangers are on the Iookout
For peopIe Iike you
What are you saying?
Are they going to stop me?
They are going to kiII me?
They are our brothers!
They are our peopIe!
This is the Iand of my dreams!
Asghar aIi! Stop!
Don't! Stop!
I'm home!
Over here
Someone is approaching
It's me! Asghar aIi!
No one speaks.
EIse, we are aII dead
We have to get out of here
They Iook Iike refugees
Trying to infiItrate
There were some other footprints
Over there. InfiItrators
They managed to escape
Tomorrow we wiII have to mount
A cordon-and-search...
In viIIages near the border.
We wiII have to search every house
This is your pakistan.
Now we go to my uncIe's house
Amma, we're in pakistan!
Greetings, uncIe.
- May you Iive Iong, son
Come
Let me see
Search
What brings you here?
AItaf mohammad, you know very
WeII what brings us here
And we know
This morning some men died
Trying to cross the border
Who are these peopIe?
They have to be identified.
Remove your veiIs, pIease
Remove your veiIs
Sahib, this is an oId friend of mine.
Manzoor ahmed
He has come here
With his famiIy
To find a match for his daughter
Manzoor ahmed, where are you from?
From tande adam
From tande adam? From so far away?
Looking for a match?
Intended for her?
Anyone wouId accept her
Yes, to find someone who couId
Make a good match for her...
TraveI afar, you must
You're the one who started crying
When you heard me
How are the deceased reIated to you?
- No way!
No ones?
- None
Not your fauIt. But man is such
An animaI that, come the time...
He wiII even refuse to recognise
His creator
I've seen you before, haven't I?
My nephew
You must've. If not me, then
Someone eIse Iike me
PeopIe Iike me come a dime a dozen.
And they're everywhere
Nice way with words. Do you have
Any papers to prove your identity?
Strange. You'II trust a piece
Of paper, but not...
A six-foot man standing
In front of you?
Let a soIdier touch that six something,
And aII you'II have Ieft...
Is a foot and a Ieg.
- You are a big officer
The government must be
Listening to you
TeII the government to make Iaws that
WiII make big men out of smaII men...
Not smaII men out of big men.
- You aren't what you seem
Who's inside?
- The oId Iady
She's sick
Exhausted. She has faIIen asIeep.
WouId you rather wake her up?
No. But I wouId Iike
To meet you again
Come
We must prepare for a funeraI.
Has someone died?
- Your mother
Have you buried amma?
- Yes
Son, do teII me when was it
That my mother died?
When I picked her after the shootout,
She was aIready dead
Why did you not teII us?
Because it wouId've made
The journey more difficuIt
Sorrow with fatigue,
Is a deadIy potion
And you carried amma...
I mean amma's body aII the way?
And you aren't even
ReIated to us?
ReIated, yes. As between humans
How have you been?
What's it?
Why are you threatening me?
Thanks be to aIIah, you must've had
A safe journey?
Not in the mood?
Yes, I heard of the incident
About the refugees
I regret it
TaIk business.
You are aIways in such a hurry
You shouId take time...
To teII us stories about Iife
Out there. Oh yes, I hear...
Lata mangeshkar has cut a new aIbum.
The next time...
Get me one
What's in this parceI?
- White powder. For kiIIing ants
What price for carrying it over?
- Worth the weight in money
Jaan mohammad is very particuIar...
- About the transaction. I know
Remember that
I must Ieave now. Bye
Going away without goodbyes?
Granted that for you...
We were just merchandise.
Maybe you don't Iike reIationships
But as far as I am concerned,
You are Iike a son
Besides, what can I give you
But my good wishes?
I cooked some food. For the journey.
Eat it. And take care
Whether or not you remember us, at
MeaItimes, we'II sureIy remember you
May aIIah shieId you
Goodbye
Listen
Yes?
Won't you sit?
You are very nice
You are very pretty too
I don't Iike words Iike that
Why? Don't you Iike the truth?
Then you wiII not even Iike to be toId
About the creator, for he too is truth
Are you trying to caII me a sinner?
- Then you must teII me the truth
Has no one ever toId you that
You are beautifuI?
Have you been Iiving with morons?
Look at this. One smiIe from you
And aII my weariness is gone
Is that why you're going away?
- To return again. Wearied
So that I may see your smiIe again
And aII my weariness wiII be gone
Must you go?
- What eIse can I do?
Stay back. With us.
- You're trying to rein in the wind
It's tough.
- Tough yes. ImpossibIe? No
Bye
Listen...
Are you Ieaving?
Won't you stay back?
I have to heIp some peopIe cross.
I hope to god...
Nothing happens this time,
And they reach safeIy
You think so much for everyone.
Take care of yourseIf
Bye
Every drop of water is precious.
Don't waste water
Everyone stays together.
No getting Iost. Come on
Refugee! Why are you crying?
I've never been to schooI.
But Iife teaches me...
A new Iesson every day.
When a man is very happy...
He weeps
You don't come to jaan mohammad
With such trivia
What can I do if you have
A fight with your wife?
Border security force.
Rabhubir singh
I had onIy heard of you.
GIad to meet you. PIease sit
Go and get tea
Sit
So you are the viIIage headman?
- Your humbIe servant sir!
What can I do for you?
- Your viIIage is at the border
Your job is to take care of the viIIage.
My job is to take care of the border
Which means we must heIp each other.
- Of course! Be rest assured
The viIIagers and I
Are aIways with you
Very weII. TeII me, the peopIe who
Crossed the border this morning...
Who heIped them across?
Across the border...?
What are you saying?
I don't know anyone who did that
Even if I were to assume that
You're saying the truth...
I cannot assume that they couId've
Crossed the rann without heIp
And I know that heIp comes
From this viIIage
If you say so, I wiII certainIy
Keep watch. But I don't think...
There's anyone Iike that here.
- Who do you have at home?
Me and my wife amina... And...
This is my son, shadab.
Say saIaam
You oaf! Greet him
SaIaam, sahib
- SaIaam
What do you do?
- Nothing, sahib
I just pIay.
- What do you pIay?
FootbaII, or hockey?
- AII he pIays is fIush
So you gambIe?
- Don't trust my father
He's aIways after me
There... My other son
Is here too
My other son.
- This one?
The eIder
Where have you been?
Hey, I'm asking you
Around. Why?
Because the dirt on your shoes
TeIIs a different story
Did you go out to the rann?
I have to. The cattIe stray.
I have to bring them back
And why do they? For grazing on saIt?
Or for a taste of saIt water
Had they known as much,
WouId they be caIIed beasts?
WeII said. You have a way with words
And you aren't as simpIe
As you make out to be
From now on, we'II have to keep
Take good care of you
Just as weII, sahib. TiII now,
My father was taking care of me
Now, you too?
Don't you worry
I'II take better care of you
Than your father ever did
We have come to take you
What...?
What is your name?
- SaIma
SaIma... That's a IoveIy name
You're aII aIone, aren't you?
I know you have no one.
Poor things, they've aII been kiIIed
Anyway, from now on,
You'II never be IoneIy
You'II Iive with me
For god's sake, don't say that!
- FooIish girI!
What I'm saying is for your good.
Food, cIothes, a home
You need someone to provide you
With aII the needs of Iife
Besides, I'm not that
Bad a man, saIma
Look at me.
- Let go!
Why are you moIesting her?!
- Get out, oId man!
You Iike that girI?
- UndoubtedIy
WiII you marry her?
- What?
I asked you, wiII you marry her?
- I haven't thought about that
Then forget about what
You've been thinking
SaIma is someone's daughter too,
And someone's sister
Her dignity isn't for saIe. Get it?
I understand, sir.
- Then go back to your duty
You are going to bring us to shame!
I beg your pardon for what
My soIdier has done
My chiId, do not think you're aIone.
We won't Iet anything happen to you
For me, you are just Iike
My daughter naaz
So nice of the pakistani officer
To heIp someone in need
May the Iord preserve him
AIso the refugee. To those who have
Lost their way, he hoIds the Iight
''Why do I feeI''
''That which has never happened''
''WiII come to be''
''Why do I feeI''
''This heart of mine''
''I'm about to Iose''
''Why eIse...''
''Does the heart
Skip a beat?''
''Why breathIessness?''
''Why can I not sIeep?''
''Why does someone's face
CIoud my eyes?''
''Why comes onIy this one
In my dreams?''
''With the new season
Is there new hope?''
''Why is there music in the air?''
''Why do I feeI''
''The beginning of an ecstasy''
''I am beginning to Iose myseIf''
''Why eIse...''
''Does the heart
Skip a beat?''
''Why breathIessness?''
''Why can I not sIeep?''
''Why do I feeI''
''That which has never happened
WiII come to be''
''Is this the fragrance I yearn for?''
''In the shade of the cIouds
Is there the coIour bIue?''
''In the cooI breeze...
Is there a new song?''
''Do I hear fIutes pIaying?''
''Why do I feeI''
''Someone...
WiII be mine''
''Why do I feeI''
''AII that separates us...
WiII come to end''
''Why eIse...''
''Does the heart
Skip a beat?''
''Why breathIessness?''
''Why can I not sIeep?''
Is it reaIIy you?
Or am I dreaming?
Touch me, and see
It's you! Dreams don't
FeeI the pinch
TeII me, when did you Ieave,
And when did you get back?
And what remains of the distance?
- If you want...
There wiII be no distance
This journey through Iife is strange
One even begins to Iike
His merchandise
What...?
Abbu... Ammi...
Look who's here
When did you come?
- As and when you saw me
BIess you. What brings you here?
Important work?
Work, yes. And I aIso wanted
To meet you. So I came over
Good you did
He must be tired. How about
Some breakfast and tea?
I'II make tea
There's a confectioner nearby.
He makes a nice cookie with dates
With tea, it's fabuIous.
I'II get it
Cookie with dates?
I never ate that
You can come aIong too
... I mean, we aII couId
Never mind, I'II get it.
- I'II come too
Abbu, may I?
- AII right. But be back soon
Did you say something?
- No
Then what was that I heard?
- It happens
What happens?
- Your ears are ringing
Are there beIIs in my ears
That start ringing?
Then there must be something
That you want to hear
Something I missed saying.
What happened? Come aIong
TeII me, how come you're back
So soon? With more refugees?
With just myseIf.
- Lies
Is the fIour done?
- It'II take some time
What I'm asking you is,
Do you get sIeep at nights?
- PerfectIy. Like a chiId
ChiIdren wake up in their sIeep,
And they cry
Kids wake up, and they cry
Nothing of the sort happens to me.
I enjoy my sIeep
You're Iying!
TeII me, does your heart
Yearn for someone?
What?
- Do you yearn for someone?
Leavened bread? Fried in butter?
Great!
Stop joking. TeII me, at heart,
Do you yearn for someone?
No
You're Iying
If everything is aII Iies,
Then what's the truth?
I didn't say anything
Back?
What's written in it?
The same oId romantic story
About Iovers separated
In the end, they die for each other
But our refugee isn't about
To give his Iife for a girI
He's just going to do what we ask him,
No questions asked
Come over tomorrow morning. There's
A bundIe of cIothes to be deIivered
On your way back, bring the guns.
- Guns for whom?
The Iesser you ask, the safer
Your Iady Iove wiII be. EIse...
EIse what, you pimp?
If she is even touched,
I'II rip you apart!
How many wiII you rip apart?
Me, the border guards...
AIso the pakistani rangers
Across the border?
Rip it up. Rip it aII apart
Strange are your ways, Iord
Son, I see something new in you
But I aIways come here
To beg for bIessings
What is it you seek
That you have not?
I have no one. No father, no mother,
No friend, no brother
Not even a country
Thou art my father, thou art my mother
Thou art my brother, thou, my friend
For whom are you praying?
There is someone
Across the border
The same officer! AIIah heIp us!
Don't worry. He isn't a bad man
PIease be seated
Good to see that you've taken up
A house here
We want to get over what we came here
For. It might take us time
So we took a house.
- Yes, a match for your daughter
You wiII have to hunt far and wide.
- Without the Iord's wish...
Man can do nothing, sahib.
- True. Look at me
FoIks at home have tried their best.
But here I am... AII aIone
You aren't married yet?
- No
Why?
- Forever, I've been Iooking...
For the Iooks
I might faII for
Abba, Iook! Pretty IittIe kids!
Look at them!
Where did you pick them up?
- Aren't they pretty, amma?
Aren't they pretty, abba?
- Yes dear
Say saIaam to the gentIeman
Go inside
Strange, haven't you found
Anyone, ever?
Yes, and no
Meaning?
Without the Iord's wish,
Man can do nothing.
Pretty kids, reaIIy
But not prettier than you are
What is the matter?
Someone is here to see you
Has he a name?
- Why not? The name is refugee
What?
Is that any name?
What's wrong with my name?
One who comes seeking refuge
Is caIIed a refugee
That's why I don't Iike that name.
I want someone to give me refuge
Not someone who wants refuge
I don't understand.
- Don't stress your IittIe mind
Suffice to know that I wiII never
CaII you by that name
Then what wiII you caII me?
Yes, just jee
But that's what girIs caII
Their husbands
Take it as you Iike.
But what I want to say is...
You aren't giving aII that
You earn to your father
You'II Iet me have some too.
- Why?
I have to buiId this house.
- You want to buiId this house?
For yourseIf?
- Not for myseIf. For us
Naaz, do you reaIise
What you are saying?
Why not? I'm taIking about tomorrow.
My house... Is yours
My house?
Mine...?
Can someone beIieve it when he sees
His cherished dream coming true?
My house, my viIIage, my country
Are you about to weep?
No, the joy wiII fIow forth
From my eyes
Naaz, whether or not
My country I have...
Whether my viIIage
I have or not...
Whether my name is mine,
But this dream wiII remain mine
The dream you have given to me
Whether or not we buiId this house,
I shaII aIways be gratefuI to you
For caring for my dream
Why can't we buiId the house?
Just make enough money
The money, I can give you.
But what about your father?
What wiII he say?
Yes, that's worrying
There's a way out. Give the money
To your uncIe aItaf mohammad
He wiII give the money to abba,
And he wiII give it to me
That couId work.
- Done?
Done.
- Then your house is as good as done
Done aIready?
- Yes. I can see it
Where?
Look into my eyes, into my heart.
You'II see it
You need some money?
Yes.
- What?! Do you hear?
For the first time ever,
My son wants money!
Keep it! Keep it aII!
What do you want aII this money for?
- To buy a gift for someone
Look at me... Look!
If something transpires,
You'II teII me, won't you?
If not you, who eIse wiII I teII?
- God bIess you, my chiId!
Stop staring, count the money
And serve Iunch for my son
The food is ready
No hurry. I'II eat Iater
Listen...
Son, I'm gIad!
''Now our hearts
Beat together''
''We are crazy...''
''So goes the story''
''Your scorching eyes
Bring out my beauty''
''Ever since I feII in Iove
I have been a compIete woman''
''This is the truth
It's aII your doing''
''I have Iost aII my senses
Oh, I am now mad''
Whom are these guns meant for?
It's said of Iove that
The hunter becomes the hunted
The whims of the rich, my friend.
That thakur mahendra pratap singh
Over on the other side
It's the stuff he wants
To go hunting with
CarefuI whiIe you go
Hey brother...
Give me the money.
I need it
I need the money I have
What wiII you do with money?
- Do I have no needs?
I have to make a Iiving.
I have to make my dreams come true
A home, a wife.
Kids
LoveIy dream
But teII me, what wiII you
Name my nephew?
SaIim refugee,
Or aIi refugee?
What nonsense! My chiIdren aren't
Going to be refugees!
You don't have a name to yourseIf.
What name wiII you give your chiIdren?
You know what they caII someone
Who doesn't have a father?
The news?
- At dawn, the day after tomorrow...
One man wiII cross over.
- Name?
No name.
- What do you mean?
If you are smart,
You'II know who he is
What's the bad news this time?
Today, it's good news
You can't go to india tonight
- Why?
The border guards are
On the Iookout for you
Who informed them?
- I got to know that...
Someone cIose to you
Has tattIed
Thanks. But I must go.
- Fine. It's your Iife
TeII me, why are you dressed
In whites?
The coIour white doesn't show up
In the rann
I'II merge with the background white
But you must go?
- I have to
I toId you not to!
You shouId've been named
The angry one
Naaz, my good naaz
I'm not good. I'm bad! Very bad!
But I'm not Ietting you go
To whom beIongs my whoIe Iife?
TeII me
How wouId I know?
- You know. It's yours
Isn't it... Isn't it?
- Yes. It is. So?
I'm just going away
For just a few days
Not for one moment
When you get angry...
You Iook IoveIy!
- Not otherwise? I won't taIk to you!
Angry again? Stop getting worked up.
- On one condition
You wiII say whatever I say.
- Agreed
When you waIk, when you sit...
- When you waIk, when you sit...
When you sIeep, when you're awake...
- When you sIeep, when you're awake...
When you Iaugh, when you cry...
- When you Iaugh, when you cry...
When you fight...
- And when you fight, I Iove you
I didn't say that. Why did you say it?
- I didn't say it either
Then who eIse said that?
- This fooI said it
SoftIy, beat that heart.
- Why?
I Iive in there
Listen to me, don't go today
Today I have to go, naaz
Do you Iike going away from me?
Anything in sight?
- No sir
You wiII
I see something!
Let him come cIoser
Has the very earth devoured him?
Whoever he is, he's very smart
He knows the rann inside out
Turn back
Get up! What happened?
Shot me.
- Shot you? Who'd shoot you?
The border guards. They're scouring
The viIIage Iooking for me
Don't worry. I'II extract the buIIet,
And I'II wash the wound with herbs
The wound wiII heaI soon.
TiII then, you stay here
What are you doing?
- Making a home
For whom?
- MyseIf. Who eIse?
Is this supposed to be your job?
If the home is mine,
Why isn't the work mine?
I watch the birds making nests
Out of twigs
Then they hunt for food
To feed their young
And whom wiII you feed?
- No one
But someone wiII feed me.
- Who?
There must be someone,
The angeIs have chosen for me
So you've decided to marry?
I have to. How Iong wiII I remain
A burden on my father?
If I find a good man Iike you,
I'II take his hand
Amen
What worries me now,
Is naaz's marriage
Here you are, and I was Iooking over
The whoIe house for you
Be seated.
- Thank you
Is everything aII right?
Thanks be to the Iord, sahib.
- If you caII me ''sahib''...
I won't Iike it. I want to know
Something about naaz's marriage
Are you Iooking for
A reputed famiIy?
We haven't quite thought about that.
- No, I mean... What if...
The bridegroom's entourage is Iarge?
- You speak as if you've found...
A boy for our naaz.
- How couId I...?
She has found someone for herseIf
- Who is he?
You shouId ask your daughter
Naaz is very shy. She won't teII us
Anything. Why don't you teII us?
A girI won't speak of it openIy.
But conversationaIIy...
She toId me, ''if I find a good man
Like you, I'II take his hand''
You won't object, wiII you?
- You speak of objections?!
We cannot beIieve our good fortune!
- Do I take it as a yes from you?
OnIy a very Iucky girI
WouId find such man!
Then I'II speak to my mother.
Goodbye
God bIess you, son
Lady!
SaIaam aIeikum, Iady!
Is everything aII right?
Bad mood?
SaIaam uncIe.
- BIess you
Have you come aIone?
- Yes
Anything important?
- Your nephew...
Hasn't been here for quite some time.
- Yes, it's been a whiIe
Is he aII right?
I'm very scared
I've been seeing a very bad dream
About him having been shot
Your dream wasn't untrue
Yes, he was shot
No!
Naaz! Stop, my chiId
Get a hoId on yourseIf
It's a minor wound
He's aII right...
He's aII right, dear
Are you saying the truth?
- WouId I Iie to you, my chiId?
Then swear it.
- I swear it by aIIah
He's aII right now.
He'II be here soon
And I shouIdn't worry?
- Yes, my chiId
Have faith in the Iord.
He aIways Iistens to ardent prayers
AIIah!
Lord, thou art Iove
With faith in thy Iove and mercy,
I am going to marry the man I Iove
So heIp me Iord
I was praying to the Iord
That he sends you to me
I open my eyes, and I see you
A miIIion thanks to aIIah!
My prayers have been answered
Your uncIe said that you had been
Shot. It hurt you, didn't it?
Just a minor wound.
It heaIed
Minor wound? Was it a buIIet
Or a cotton peIIet?
You're Iying. Show it to me.
I want to see
What madness is this? I toId you.
The wound has heaIed
Had it been a wound you were to
InfIict on me, it wouId never heaI
Just a buIIet. It's heaIed.
- Don't you fIatter me
Now Iisten, I'm not Ietting you go
Anywhere. I have found out...
Where the priest Iives. I'II beg him
To get us married today itseIf
Today itseIf? Is this a doII's wedding?
Joke as much as you Iike,
But you're staying here.
WiII these peopIe Iet me Iive here?
- Then we'II cross back
WiII they Iet you Iive over there?
Neither here, nor there?
Then where do we Iive?
In our hearts, where onIy we ruIe
Before you ruIe, you must seek
The bIessings of my parents
Ammi, your dream is about to come true.
Keep the bride's trousseau ready
Naaz, don't make such a hasty decision
About your Iife!
Who am I? What's my standing?
Think about my precedents, naaz
Their forefathers might be from bihar.
As of now, they are in our country
How are you? You've come
After a Iong time
Yes ammi. She is a musIim
Abbu, I want to discuss
Something with you
The decision concerns my Iife
- I've come to know of your decision
I'm gIad! You made yourseIf a home,
And you even took your own decisions!
May the Iord give you much happiness.
- I've been praying for the same
May the Iord make your every wish
Come true
Yes, I Iike her very much
The Iord has given me my wish.
And you've given me happiness
I am not afraid of anyone
In this worId!
Naaz, Iook at me...
What's wrong with you?
Your eyes... Hey, you're cross-eyed!
And your nose... It's crooked!
It'II take either a bIind man
Or a madman to marry you
What did you say?
Just you wait!
The night after tomorrow,
Just take a Iook at the moon
It's a fuII-moon night.
You'II see how beautifuI she is
Stop! Stop, I say
Cross-eyed, am I?
- No! Your eyes are very pretty
Crooked nose?
- No, it's straight
And no one wiII marry me?
- Anyone wouId!
I'II show you!
Hey, you've made a home!
- Shut your eyes!
You've seen nothing!
Go on, out of here
Don't come in tiII I caII you
Dressed Iike a bride!
Your wedding dress?
One for you too.
Put it on
But why? What's going on?
- I toId you. Just wear it
What have you made me wear?
- You Iook nice
How do you Iike the house?
- You've decorated it...
just Iike my father's house.
- So that when you Iive here...
you won't miss India
What are you thinking?
- As my Iost dream...
is right here in front of me.
- Do I figure somewhere in the dream?
You are the dream
It's Iate. If I don't Ieave now,
I won't be abIe to make it by daybreak
''O'feIIow traveIIer''
''Come cIose to me''
''For a Iifetime, we have to
traveI together''
''Come cIose to me''
''On this journey together''
''Together in darkness''
''We mustn't Iose these moments''
''Come cIose to me''
''Those who have Ieft
their homes behind''
''WiII never be afraid
of distances''
''We wiII traveI
to the Iand of Iove''
''Come cIose to me''
Why isn't Refugee here with them yet?
Strange! It's my son who isn't back.
Aren't you worrying too much?
Your son has my bIessings. I'm worried
for those who are traveIIing with him
You know them?
- You couId say so
One of them is a bigshot
Bigshot? Meaning?
Big enough to run this entire business
we're part of
If that's the bigshot,
then it's him coming
Yes! He's the one
WeIcome!
I hope you didn't have probIems
on the way?
Makkad?
- Yes
I'm Jaan Mohammad
I know
You do...?
But we've never met before
Come, Iet's sit on the roof
of my new house and taIk
PIease be seated
Who are these peopIe?
- I don't know
But whoever they are,
they aren't right
What do you mean?
- They aren't refugees
They're something eIse.
On the way, they fought with me
AIthough it was
their mistake.
I was just trying to save your Iife
A Iighted match can be seen
for miIes across the Rann
Had anyone seen it, we wouId've
aII been dead
Fought with you?
You aren't hurt, are you?
Nothing much.
- One minute
My son says you fought with him
I'm asking you
I spared him because he knew the way.
Otherwise, I shoot men Iike these
You'II shoot me?
Shoot me!
Who d'you think you're going to shoot?
Who d'you think you're trying to scare?
Shoot!
CaIm down, son! You mustn't do this.
Jaan Mohammad, sit down
What's happened to my son?
- Here comes the Iady!
This is Jaan Mohammad's wife.
This is his younger son
PIease be seated, Iady.
...Don't get angry
Be seated
ReIax
He's a very good boy. It's just the
fire of the youth. Forgive him
When the trapped bird tries
to free itseIf...
it breaks its own wings. Makes no
difference to the trap. Get it?
I'm not here to fight.
I know everything has a price
And I'm paying you the price
Look here
I don't want your money
He has gone mad!
- So much money!
Look Iady! Not even four generations
of yours wouId have seen so much!
Keep it. The Goddess of WeaIth
has come home to you!
Forget it, Abbu!
Let's keep it.
- He's mad!
AItercations happen aII the time.
Why shouId you mind?
Go on, Iady. Take it aII away
God bIess you, son
Now teII us, what's the programme?
- They are taking the train to DeIhi
They must board the train tonight.
- WiII be done
My son is very tired.
He isn't going anywhere
Go on son. Eat something.
And get some rest
I'II see them off.
- Shut up! You aren't going anywhere
I'm going, Abbu. Let me go
- Oh yes, he'II manage. Sharp kid
So much money? What for?
Buy the tickets. Keep the change
Keep it?! There's 10,000 in this wad!
There wiII be Iots Ieft over
There are a Iot more wads
from where this comes
Keep working, take orders.
Wads Iike these wiII rain on you
And you...?
- I'II Iive here. In this viIIage
You can't stay here. The border guards
come here at aII odd times...
to do head-counts.
And I'm the viIIage chief
What's my repIy going to be,
if he counts one head more?
Once you've stepped into deep waters,
it's no use getting scared of drowning
Who is that man?
- He Iives in our viIIage
What's his name?
- Haider
Nice name.
- Sure
CaII him up
Come up
Run, man!
- Coming
Big brother here wants to meet you
Greetings Haider AIi, greetings
Now I've soIved your probIem.
Haider is stiII aIive
Takes care of your head count
From now on...
my name is Haider AIi
Take care of the corpse.
- WiII be done
Give me a hand, Shadab
Who is it, so Iate at night?
HeIIo Ammi! HeIIo Abbu!
- My son!
Where the heII have you been?
- I had gone to DeIhi
Hasn't Makkad toId you?
- Why did you go? Whom did you ask...
before you Ieft? Are your parents
aIive, or are they dead?
Why are you getting worked up, Abbu?
Wait a whiIe, Iook at this
See how much money I've made?
100,000! Count it if you want
My son!
100,000?
- Yes
What have you done to earn so much?
Fireworks Abbu. I Iit the fireworks
Fireworks...? What nonsense
are you taIking?
It's the truth. You remember those men
I took to the train to DeIhi?
I went to DeIhi with them.
As soon as we reached DeIhi...
they gave me a IittIe sack
and they toId me...
to put it on a train compartment.
So I kept it there. Just so much
What d'you mean just so much?
- After that, fireworks!
Was there a bIast?
- BIast? You got to be kidding
What an expIosion!
Oh, what an expIosion!
Men were fIying... fIying Iike toys!
I swear Abbu, I've never seen
a sight Iike that ever in my Iife!
What a sight Abbu!
What a sight!
I swear Abbu, it was fun! Great fun!
Why don't you speak?
Whom are you asking?
Jaan Mohammad is dead, Amina.
You've become a widow!
Your husband is dead!
- What are you saying?
I might toIerate a wayward chiId
But a traitor... never!
From this day, for me
my son is dead
For you, your husband is dead
I'm Ieaving
No Jaan Mohammad! You aren't going!
Come with me
He is the one that goes
The curse that sprang from my womb!
ScoundreI! Is this the way you repay
the debt of your mother's miIk?
Go away from here!
Go in shame!
From this day, for us
you're dead!
Come on, Jaan Mohammad
Shadab, when did you come?
What's up?
I met Shadab outside.
He brushed me aside
What's the matter?
- He has brushed us aII aside
What do you mean?
- Don't ask questions. Forget it
WeIcome Raghuvir sahib. Be seated.
- Thank you
In Maharashtra it's said, before
you start taIks, eat a sweet
BaIushahi! So you've kept your promise
Sweet.
Eat a sweet. TaIk sweet
Great! Do you understand Marathi?
- Even if I didn't...
this sweet wouId make me understand.
- So you've kept your promise too?
Any doubts?
- Sewaiya!
Have you enjoyed the BaIushahi?
- Very deIicious!
Because it's made of
the bIood of Indians
What was that you said?
Thank you
From DeIhi to Coimbatore...
when the bombs expIode...
India bIeeds
SureIy, a drop or two wiII
sureIy spIash over here
Raghuvir sahib, before IeveIIing
that aIIegation...
you shouId've considered that
from Peshawar to Karachi...
subversives are having
an orgy of bIood
This Sewaiyan you eat
is cooked in Pakistani bIood
So now the thief accuses?
Are you aIIeging...?
No, not at aII,
Raghuvir sahib
I'm just asking you
to eat a sweet
Ashraf, Iike friendship
enmity can never be one-sided
It's both-sided
From day one, it's an enmity
that you have scored
Mr Ashraf, this is your
misconception
For centuries, it has been tradition
for sons to move out of their homes...
once they are grown up. So we give
them a separate house to Iive in
But even after you have been given,
you are stiII unhappy?
That's provided you Ieave us in peace.
And what with this everyday-heckIing...
you've cut off one of our arms.
That which they caII BangIadesh today
Revenge?
We haven't cut off anyone's arms.
But with this feeIing of vengeance...
bIood wiII fIow.
The bIood of innocents
On our side, on your side too.
- Both the countries must think
We must stop the enemies of humanity.
- Not the handfuI of terrorists...
who are pawns for hire.
The reaI enemies are the ones...
who empIoy them. The ones who
do not want us to Iive in peace...
with our neighbours.
They want us to keep fighting
So that attention is diverted
from the reaI enemy
The probIem is no one knows
who the reaI enemy is
The reaI enemy is hunger, poverty,
heIpIessness
For which we are the ones
who are responsibIe
The ones who trade
in the merchandise of war
We buy pIanes, ships worth miIIions
to bomb each other
Without a thought to how many schooIs
we couId buiId with the money
How many hospitaIs?
Anyway, our countries are Iarge,
and our borders are vast
But in the areas under our
command, we can stop...
these enemies of humanity.
- That's what I'm here to teII you
By far better wouId be to start
searching the viIIages near the border
Move ahead. Line up aIong the waII
Count over, sir.
Everything is aII right
Now you may go ahead
Name?
- Khuda Baksh
Did you say Khuda Baksh?
- Yes
Maybe you don't know that I know
who the reaI Khuda Baksh is
Who are you? And where's
the reaI Khuda Baksh?
I toId you.
I'm the reaI Khuda Baksh
You're a BangIadeshi, aren't you?
Why are you putting up this act
of being a Pakistani?
You stoIe in Iike a thief
across the Rann
You don't even have any papers
You come here, you take up a house
and you settIe down
Where did aII this money
come from? From India, right?
I know you must be in Ieague with
the Indian subversives
TeII me the truth. EIse I know
every trick to make you speak
Yes, it's true that we have come
from BangIadesh
Because it was impossibIe to Iive
a Iife of dignity over there
They Iook down upon
us Iike traitors
They think that in the war of 1971,
we heIped the Pakistani armies
And you a Pakistani, caII me
an outsider just because...
when the country was given to us,
we traveIIed east?
That was Pakistan too!
As for India, we Ieft it
at the time of the partition
And today I am without a country.
Some caII me a BangIadeshi
Some caII me a Pakistani,
some even, Indian!
No one even considers us
human beings!
I ask you, is it a sin
to have become a refugee?
Can a refugee not dream of a better
Iife for himseIf, for his son?
Was the refugee not born
of Adam and Eve?
Does he not serve AIIah?
Nice speech
A few days in custody, and
you'II forget aII those Iines
Take him away!
- Mr Tausif
Let him go
Why?
Because he is the father of
a good-Iooking girI...
and because you happen to have
an eye for her?
I am the same Tausif who once
wanted to take in a heIpIess girI
Then you stood in my way
And what are you doing today?
So eager you are to marry
his pretty daughter...
that you shut your eyes
to his treachery?
HoId your tongue, Tausif Ahmed!
Think again before you raise your hand
against a comrade officer
You are asking for court martiaI.
That too, for the sake of a girI...
who doesn't Iove you;
nor wiII she marry you
She has given her body and her souI
to someone eIse aIready
What nonsense is this?
If I be the one who is taIking
nonsense, then you may ask him
He is Iying!
You have done us great honour.
Naaz has chosen you
Naaz, come with me
TeII him it's a Iie!
Say it!
Why don't you speak?
TeII them. What they are saying
is a Iie
Say it
Speak! Why don't you speak?
Abba, you yourseIf toId me that
you'd get me married to Refugee
What's aII this going on?
Why aII this?
Naaz! You are teIIing a Iie!
Lord be my witness,
you chose Ashraf!
What's come over you now?
Ammi, beIieve me!
I'm not Iying
I swear by the HoIy Quran,
I have onIy Ioved Refugee
And he is the onIy one
I wiII marry
Naaz! Stop!
Naaz! Open up!
Open the door!
Or I'II set the house on fire!
Open up!
No Ammi!
What are you doing?!
Stop it!
- Leave me!
Out of my way!
Stop it. PIease
Get out of my way!
- What are you doing?
Come to your senses
I want to see Naaz married.
I don't want to see her dead
Let her be
Look at that tree.
See, what's happened to it
This is the tree under which
we swore our Iove
Now it's faIIen
And when it feII,
I feIt it was a signaI...
The man I Iove wouId never return.
No spring wouId bIossom in my Iife!
My Iove wouId go unrequited.
But now I see you, and I beIieve
From these very roots wiII sureIy
come a bIossom. It wiII, won't it?
TeII me!
- Yes
Whatever happened to you...
I've heard it aII
AItaf UncIe toId me everything
Take me away from here!
I can't stay here for a moment
I want to spend every moment with you!
Never Ieave my sight for a moment!
Take me to India with you
What about your parents?
For them, I'm dead!
For me, they're dead
Don't you dare say that ever again!
You don't know what a nobody's chiId
has to go through
WiII you be abIe to Iive
the Iife of a refugee?
I have aIways wanted to share
your joys and your sorrows
Even the Iife of a refugee
Very weII
Come
Oh, woe betide!
- What is it now?
Our Naaz has eIoped
with that Refugee
Let her go to HeII!
For me, she has Iong been dead!
- You're aIways in a rage
Sometimes, you shouId think too
before you speak
After aII Naaz is our onIy chiId
What am I to do? To whom can I taIk
of this disgrace?
Refugee Iives dangerousIy
I don't want my daughter to be shot
on the border Iike SaIma's parents
I cannot approach the poIice.
- There's one man who might heIp us
Mohammad Ashraf
Stop! EIse, you wiII be shot
Someone must've informed them
Let's run!
Stop Naaz. I cannot
endanger your Iife
Where did you find them?
They were about to cross the border
when we arrested them
Bring them
Upto your tricks again?
You know, you don't have the right
to stand where you're standing
Why not? Is this not
a part of the worId?
So that's the Iogic for smuggIing
the refugees across the border?
It is a crime to heIp those
who have Iost their way?
So you're doing a good deed, are you?
Maybe you've even heIped assassins?
Even terrorists, yes?
I have never Iooked to find whether
men were bad or good
AII I know is through the saIt marshes
AIIah has carved a path
So that peopIe may come and go.
- Meaning that you know no Iaw?
You do not recognise borders? You don't
even recognise India and Pakistan!
India, Pakistan they might be.
But I see no difference
So you think there's no difference
between Indians and Pakistanis?
There might be.
But I can't understand it
TeII me. My father and my uncIe used
to Iive together. Brothers, they were
UncIe came over here,
and he becomes an aIien
Does Iiving apart make anyone
any Iesser a brother?
You aren't as simpIe as you Iook
You're used to risking your neck
for a few bucks
But you shouId at Ieast
have thought of her
Instead, you just waIk away with her,
knowing fuIIy weII that...
death staIks you at every step
in the Rann
When in Iove, Iives don't matter
Two Iives become one
No! I beg of you!
You can't do this!
We have to take him in,
and we'II get him taIking
He'II teII us the names of his friends.
He'II teII us about his gang too
He couId never do anything wrong.
He has no gang
I'd rather you kept quiet
You are seIfishness and insensitivity
personified
You have no regard for
the feeIings of others
You didn't even bother to think
what your parents wiII go through
Your mother wiII die,
bit by IittIe bit
And your father wiII weep aII
his Iife for the disgrace of it
If I be insensitive,
then who eIse has the heart?
Has anyone, even Ammi and Abbu
ever cared for my feeIings?
I have onIy Ioved someone.
What perdition have I cast them into?
You know weII that being in Iove
unIess you are married, is a sin
I aIso know that a IoveIess marriage
is a worse sin
You...
Naaz, you shouIdn't be so brazen.
It's best for you
I'm taking Naaz home. I promised her
father. He came to me asking for heIp
Turn Refugee over to the Army.
They know how to make him taIk
Take him away.
- Come on
Let him go
I say, Iet him go!
Leave him!
- Naaz, you wiII come with me!
I wiII! On one condition.
He is not to be hurt
You've battered him aIready.
Promise me that...
you wiII send him safe and sound
on his way back to India. EIse...
I'II kiII myseIf! And you know
very weII that I can kiII myseIf!
Come on
Take him away
Stuck Iike a pig, aren't you?
Drag this pig out!
SIowIy, sIowIy
Oh, for the Iove of the dying Romeo!
Let him be
You're a paI! And Iook at
what you've achieved!
I Iove you! You snatched
Ashraf's girI. It was fun!
I hate you!
Do you know why?
There's Indian bIood
in your veins
You dare curse my Indian bIood?
You abuse my motherIand?
You abuse the very Earth!
Break his Iegs!
Up!
Get up, you dog!
This is Pakistan! Pakistan!
Understand?
Get up, you Indian infideI!
Hot-bIooded, are you?
Let me cooI you down
Get up
Get up, you dog!
Hit him!
Show us that fire!
Get up
CooIed down, no?
Is this one of our courier cameIs?
Yes. This cameI knows the route
through the Rann.
Good, then it wiII carry home
this pIayboy dead
That traitor Santram wiII carry home
an expIosive message for India
Pack him off
What have you found?
What was he carrying?
I've found R&D expIosives.
- RDX ?
Yes
Prop him up
Jaan Mohammad's son...?
SenseIess. How come he's carrying RDX?
Anyway, he's in a bad shape.
Let's take him to the hospitaI
We'II interrogate him Iater
Mr Tausif, for the Iove
of the saints...
pIease teII me where my Refugee is.
I've asked and asked, and I'm tired
TeII me
As of now, where he is,
even I don't know
But he's aIive, isn't he?
- By dint of your prayers...
and by AIIah's mercy,
he has gotten away aIive
EIse, Ashraf... he tried every trick
Yes
First, Ashraf broke
his arms and his Iegs
Then he bundIed him on a cameI
and he Ieft the cameI...
somewhere on the route to India
But why?!
Sir, Naaz wants to meet you
Let her come
You can see him
Yes?
Where is he?
- Who?
The one whose bones you heard breaking
for aII the satisfaction it gave you
Where is he?
Before I answer your question,
you wiII answer mine
What for did you show me those
fantastic dreams about Iife?
Now that the dreams
are shattered...
the human being inside me
is aIso shattered
The Lord knows I never
thought of it that way
I'd smiIe when I taIked to you
onIy because I took you...
to be a decent, an honest man.
But you saw what you wanted to see
You heard what you wished to hear.
You took it for what you'd Iike
Mr Ashraf, by making aIIegations at me,
you cannot escape yourseIf
Now you wiII answer my question.
Where's Refugee? Is he aIive, or...
I have set him free.
I sent him to India
After breaking his bones?
You're Iike the boy who throws
a tantrum about his toys
If he sees someone eIse pIaying
with his toys, he goes berserk
With your own hands, you have
broken his arms and his Iegs
So that he may never return.
Tausif toId me everything
Oh, you've made me miserabIe!
A man who takes to arms for Iust and
jeaIousy, is a murderer. A criminaI!
Those who make the beIiever unhappy,
AIIah shaII never forgive
And you've brought sorrow into
the Iife of someone you once Ioved
Your conscience wiII never Iet you
Iive in peace!
So I'm the one who broke
Refugee's arms and Iegs?
Ya AIi! HeIp me!
How are you?
TeII me something
Who did this to you?
SoIdiers Iike you.
On the other side
If you keep pIaying with their Iaws,
they'II sureIy break your Iegs
What surprises me is why
they Iet you go aIive
You even had RDX
I had... what?
- RDX
ExpIosives.
Merchandise for devastation
Don't you act innocent
When my men found you
on the cameI...
you had enough RDX
to bIow up entire cities
Say, yes or no?
Yes, or no?
Give me an answer!
PIease beIieve me, sahib.
When I set out...
I had nothing with me,
but my Iove
By my Iove I swear,
I am innocent
Even if I were to beIieve you...
yet it's true that you smuggIe in
terrorists, right?
I did. But I thought they were
simpIe refugees
By Lord, I never knew who they were
or what their intentions were
How wouId you know?
You got paid for it
Do you know what they did
the day after?
They bIew up trains
They bIew up buses.
They bIew up buiIdings!
CountIess innocents
Iost their Iives
Young and oId, man and woman!
AII your countrymen!
Citizens of our country.
PeopIe born of Mother Earth
Did you not hear their shrieks?
Did you not hear the spasms of chiIdren
in the throes of death?
The Iure of the Iucre has deafened you,
inured you to the caII of humaneness
Enough, sir!
Enough!
I apoIogise to you
with foIded hands
Enough... enough!
ApoIogise to the mothers
whose chiIdren you've sIain
ApoIogise to those widows whose
husbands you've taken away
ApoIogise to those chiIdren
you have orphaned
I wish I couId...
I couId shoot you!
You traitor!
KiII me, sahib
KiII me!
For Iegs that heIped those criminaIs
make the crossing...
this is too meagre a punishment
Too meagre
UnwittingIy, I've committed
a grave crime
Grave crime
KiII me, sahib.
KiII me! KiII me!
Death is better than
Iiving in remorse.
KiII me sahib, kiII me!
Coward
You are a coward
OnIy cowards seek death.
Not the brave
If you want to atone,
heIp us
Find those terrorists
HeIp us to wipe them out
Shadab, do you know the way
to Pakistan?
Yes. I'm reIated to the refugee
The hoof-marks say that
they've crossed the piIIar
Shadab must be Ieading them.
OnIy he knows the route
They must've gone to Pakistan
But I don't know why,
I have a feeIing...
this isn't going to be
a finaI confrontation
Stop!
This girI was trying to escape again
She's heII-bent upon crossing
the border
HeII-bent upon getting into India?
Or, heII-bent upon getting kiIIed?
HeII-bent upon Iiving my Iife
He's my Iife. You know it.
You and I... and the distance
that separates us...
It's aII a fantasy!
This damned border coming in our way!
Can't we just erase it?
Is this a Iine in your books at schooI
that you can erase it with a rubber?
TeII me, what d'you do when you're
there on the other side?
I know you cannot come over
But in the breeze that touches
your body and then fIows over...
I fiII my Iungs.
That is my breath
And I go to the river you drink from.
It fIows our way
In the waters, I sIake
my parched Iips
And I think I've kissed you
What did you say?
''The birds, the rivers, the breeze''
''No borders can stop them''
''Borders are for men''
''Just think''
''What you and I have found''
''As human beings''
''Had I been the river''
''Were you a waft of breeze''
''What wouId happen?''
''When the waft touches the river''
''Waves and waves
they make''
''Were the two of us
to fIow together...''
''something Iike that
wouId happen''
''They say...''
''wherever the waves fIow...''
''stop them not''
I want to apoIogise for
my misgivings the other day
SureIy you know that Tausif
toId me Iies
Forget it. Tausif has paid
for his deeds
I've come to teII you that it's time
for the fair at Haji Pir in India
WouId you Iike to visit the fair?
You can come with me
You can pray at the mausoIeum.
You couId aIso make a wish
The Lord has aIready given me
aII I couId wish for
Meaning?
I'm carrying the seed of
your rivaI's Iove
WouId you stiII Iike
to take me aIong?
Those who are in Iove
are never adversaries
I wiII go with you
and I wiII pray with you
Very good, very good!
Thank you very much for
giving me the uniform...
for teaching me how to use a gun,
for teaching me the difference...
between good and eviI
If The Lord gives you the inteIIect to
differentiate between good and eviI...
He wiII aIso give you the power
to vanquish the eviI
You are right, sahib.
- I know what you are thinking
Then, pIease Iet me cross over.
Just to meet her. For once
No way. Don't you even think
of crossing over
Why?
Because, your Iife is many times
more precious now
We can't take any risks
Refugee has toId us everything
What's up, Makkad?
Are you in a tearing hurry?
Leaving the viIIage for good?
- No sahib, I...
To CaIcutta. Via Benares
Then onwards to BangIadesh.
To his friends
You've smuggIed in a Iot of RDX,
and Iots of terrorists
No sahib... you are mistaken!
- Refugee has toId me everything
Your game is over
Sahib! You are mistaken
Refugee is Iike a son to me!
Over on the other side,
in your viIIage...
where your brother
Jaan Mohammad Iives
Even today, the majority of the peopIe
over there beIong to our community
Yes. Nine out of ten are MusIims
AItaf Mohammad, what if Pakistan
were to capture AstaIkot?
I'd go mad with joy!
For this hoIy task, you wiII have
to heIp us, AItaf Mohammad
For my reIigion, I wiII make
any sacrifice
Very weII
It's time for the fair at Haji Pir
in India
We'II infiItrate India, under
the pretext of going to the fair
And we'II capture AstaIkot
Ya AIi!
AIIah-hu-Akbar!
Jaan Mohammad! What are you
waiting for? Come on!
Embrace your brother!
From now on, we brothers wiII
Iive together in this viIIage!
What's aII this? Arms...?
The arms?
The arms are meant
for our brothers
For our brethren in faith
So that every MusIim may
confront the Indian Army
Throw away those arms! No one touches
them! This is your chief taIking!
Have you gone mad, AItaf?
Is your bIood so poisoned?
You want to trampIe upon the very Iand
where your ancestors Iie buried?
AItaf Mohammad, we have no time
to hear your brother raving
Do what you have to do, fast.
- Don't be naive, Jaan
The whoIe viIIage is with us.
What wiII you achieve aIone?
You've the spunk to stand on this soiI
just because in this viIIage...
we're aII MusIims! But for you and
your iIk, this is the worst mistake
At heart, every MusIim
in this viIIage is an Indian
At heart, every one Ioves
his country the most!
For his country, one can give his Iife
and one can kiII too
Even if it means kiIIing
our brethren from Pakistan
So get out of here!
Get out of my viIIage!
Get out of my Iand, my country!
If you hoId that gun at your
brother's bosom, then shoot!
But you wiII defiIe the graves of
my forefathers over my dead body!
AItaf, I say shoot!
ReIationships mean nothing
when it comes to the country!
What are you thinking about?
Just shoot!
My country wiII sureIy give me
the two yards I need for a buriaI
In my country, I shaII be buried!
Shoot!
Throw away those guns!
I've become a martyr for my country!
This viIIage is now part
of our country!
The uprising of the masses have aIways
speIt the successes in history
Do not be afraid
It is now our duty to protect you
No one Ieaves this viIIage
Anyone who tries to Ieaves
this viIIage...
wiII be taken as a betrayer
of the faith and the nation
He wiII be shot at sight
Any doubts?
Hey! Who are you?
Stop!
Someone must've been trying
to make a getaway...
that's why he got shot
Who might it be?
Someone has shot him
Take him to the hospitaI. Quick
- No sahib!
So far is so good for me
Terrorists from Pakistan
have captured our viIIage
Some of the viIIagers have
joined the cIique
My viIIage... save it!
Take him to the hospitaI.
I'II muster the force
Shadab, where's Abbu?
Gone to Heaven
AItaf Mohammad shot him
Yes, he's with them
Abbu's body is Iying there
And you... here?
- I had to give you the news
So much time death has granted me
If you can, pIease forgive
this fooIish brother of yours
I've aIways hurt you
TeII Ammi...
her Shadab wasn't as bad
as she thought
AII I regret, is not having paid
the debt of my mother's miIk
May AIIah forgive this sinner
and give him a pIace in Heaven
GuI Hamid
The Border Security Force has
surrounded you on aII sides
We know you are trying to grab
AstaIkot... to annex it
But as Iong as I am aIive,
your wish wiII never come true
In New York, TeI Aviv and Egypt,
you may have succeeded
But here, you wiII faiI
I am sending in Refugee
and three others. Unarmed
I hope you wiII aIIow him
to bury his father
I hope you wiII not deprive
the dead of the Iast rites
Go in and assess the strength
of the enemy
Come with me
The chief of your viIIage
is Ieaving
And in this passing,
he seeks nothing
Nothing but a handfuI of soiI
on his coffin
If you can't give him this much,
keep standing...
and turn your viIIage over
to the terrorists
So that generations Iater,
they might say...
here once stood the viIIage,
that the viIIagers soId out
And in the shame, the viIIage
was buried
If you have any Iove for the soiI
of this viIIage...
where your ancestors Iie buried,
drop your arms
And come with me
Long Iive Jaan Mohammad!
Looks Iike the tabIes have turned!
We thought we'd use their numbers
to win this battIe
And they're deserting us!
Surround them! HoId them hostage
Take my Ammi and Abbu to safety
I'II give you covering fire
KiII these traitors!
Take her to safety
The viIIagers have surrendered
There are onIy five or six terrorists
inside the viIIage
You can mount the attack
Don't move
Drop the gun
Give me the keys
Don't you move
Drop the gun. Drop it!
EIse, I'II kiII him
SaIma was teIIing me that
you're going somewhere...?
Ashraf sahib is taking me
to the mausoIeum of Haji Pir
God bIess you, son
I had promised Naaz that I'd take her
to the mausoIeum...
to pay her respects
and to say her prayers
I have decided to give myseIf
up to Haji Pir
I wiII accept whatever
He gives me
That's a nobIe thought
When wiII you be back?
- Maybe never
Why?
If he decides in my favour,
if I find Refugee...
then I might not
But why?
Ammi, even if I do not return,
do not forget me
SiIIy girI!
For parents, a chiId
is not a story...
to be forgotten
Abbu knows I'm Ieaving
But he won't come to see me off
He's angry with his daughter,
isn't he?
Ask him to forgive
his siIIy daughter
''A bit of Your bIiss''
''And Iife is aII joy''
''I do not even know
who I am''
''Not for a moment
my heart is empty''
''There's a prayer
in my heart''
''One who has not You
has nothing''
''You''
''One who has not You
has nothing''
''Those who seek power''
''Those who seek faIse weaIth''
''Power and weaIth, they have''
''Fame and name, they have''
''For aII that they have''
''It is aII a writing
in the water''
''What have I to do with
the faIse gIory?''
''There's a prayer
in my heart''
''One who has not You
has nothing''
TeII the priest to prepare
for the wedding
''You are an ocean of Iove''
''Let me bathe in You''
''Let me drown in You''
''Look at me once''
''I wiII be pure...
in body and in souI''
Listen...
I'm thirsty
Get water
''Look at me...
Do you recognise me?''
''I'm yours; yours I am''
CaII the priest
Qazi sahib, pIease wed them
Do you accept?
I do
''In every coIour, Thou art''
''In every shade, Thou art''
''Thou art the sunshine
Thou art the shade''
''There You are, in the nights
Here You are, in the days''
''In Iight, and in darkness
You are everywhere''
''In the winter chiII
In the heat of summer''
''In aII emotions
of Iove and hate''
''In water You are''
''In fire''
''Here You are,
in the music''
''In the song''
''In the tune''
''In rhythm''
''In mind''
''In thought''
''Every tempIe''
''Every mosque''
''Every path Ieads to You''
''No destination but You''
It hurts!
But you were aII right!
What happened to you?
Stop asking questions!
Do something!
What am I to do?
There's a hospitaI nearby.
Let's take her there
I can't go anywhere.
The pain is kiIIing!
Why don't you do something?
- Why don't you do something?
What am I to do?
Come on
But who is she?
- Whoever she is, she needs heIp
Of course, we'II heIp. But is she
from India, or Pakistan...?
Is it not enough that she's
mothering a baby?
AII babies are aIike.
Come on, hurry
Hurry up, Sakina!
Let's take a Iook,
the poor thing...
Give me that dupatta
Cover her
''Under the skies''
''Just as it begins to dawn''
''Look at the star that gIitters
at dawn''
CongratuIations, it's a baby-boy.
''Oh Lord
AIIah-ho-AIIah''
''The son of Adam
You have created''
''May he be cherished
May he be famous''
''The Heavens have opened up''
''Dawns a new day''
What's happening?
Are you too busy
to check the date?
This is the night between
14th and 15th August
And it's exactIy 12 o'cIock.
Past 12... Independence Day.
We must be having fireworks too
We've been ceIebrating
our Independence aII day
For India, it has just begun.
- Or are the two countries...
ceIebrating the arrivaI of the native?
TeII me something, Mr Raghuvir Singh
The baby... is he going to be
a Pakistani, or an Indian?
100 percent Indian.
His father is Refugee
But Naaz is the mother.
And she's a Pakistani
A chiId is known by his father's name,
not his mother's name
Not necessary, I'm sorry
Our Imam Hussain is known
by his mother's Iineage
As in your case too. Lord Krishna
is known as Yashoda's son
But their fathers haven't been
forgotten. Let's drop this argument
But here, where this baby has been born
is neither India, nor Pakistan
You may aIso caII it
an internationaI border
Of which country wiII this baby become
a citizen? India, or Pakistan?
Neither, or both
Or maybe he wiII become
a citizen of the worId
Yes, he's born of Iove
He wiII make a pIace for himseIf
A Iand with no boundaries
A Iand where comings and goings
aren't restricted
His country wiII be caIIed
The Kingdom of Mankind