Yes, Doctor Ye.
A walk? I'd love that.
I really wanted to go for a walk too.
The weather's nice too.
I want to hold hands with you.
I really want to see you too.
Okay, I'll see you later then.
Bo Young and Doctor Ye
are dating? For real?
She told me to keep it a secret
but she got caught again.
Why doesn't she just post a notice
about her new relationship?
Wait, did you know all along?
What? You acted like a pain because
you were annoyed about them dating?
You even threw away the
bracelet Doctor Ye got her?
Yeah.
Geez, I see why Bo Young has been
acting cold towards you lately.
Does that mean you're not
even friends anymore?
I should apologize
so that we can at least remain friends.
I can't just remain a jerk.
[Episode 15 - I Thought It Was
Okay for Mothers to Do That.]
Doctor Park took a  holiday today
so I need Doctor Kim and Doctor
Park to work harder than usual.
- Yes, Sir.
By the way, you know that Doctor Ye
is going to be on a TV show, right?
Yes, I heard it'll go on
for three months.
Doctor Ye insisted that he wouldn't do it
but the director begged him to do it
for the promotion of this hospital
so he had no choice but to do it.
I didn't want to do it because
I'd have to readjust my schedule--
May I give you some advice?
Since you've agreed to do it,
do it willingly, Doctor Ye.
Other people would fight each other
and go crazy for this TV opportunity.
Wow. If you do this program,
you'll become more famous.
I know, right? Doctor Ye's
girlfriend must be happy
that his boyfriend is so capable.
But, I've never seen you talk on the
phone with your girlfriend before.
Are you really dating?
I'm sure they're lovey dovey
and doing just fine.
May I give you some advice?
Please don't make me
repeat the same advice.
I already told you to
mind your own business.
That's right. Stop it already.
But I thought the production crew was
coming today. When are they coming?
- There they are.
- What?
Get out there.
Hello.
This is Doctor Ye. You know him, right?
- Yes.
- Camera.
Cue.
Then, I'll explain the most
basic concepts first.
In sling therapy, cognitive
memory is very important.
And this is how it works.
Okay, there are many types of patients
and these slings can help all of them.
He's so cool.
Do you think he'll become famous for
being a handsome physical therapist?
I know, right? He's no joke.
But shouldn't we get them some drinks?
- Yes, I'll do that.
- Okay.
- That's pretty much it.
- That's all we needed.
- Thank you for your efforts.
But, when you come to the studio
and talk about osteoarthritis exercise
it'd be nice to have another physical
therapist. Do you have anyone?
- Please have these drinks.
- Thank you.
It wouldn't be bad for another physical
therapist to do a demonstration.
This person. I think Doctor
Woo would be perfect.
Pardon?
Wait, what was that?
What is this? Am I really
going to be on TV?
What do I do? Should I do a face mask?
Then, am I going to be
the demonstration model?
Yes, I feel like a physical therapist
would show more accurate movements
than an average person.
Also, can you prepare
a one-minute exercise?
It'd be nice if you can do a segment
for the end of the show.
We're thinking of uploading
that clip on our homepage too.
Wow. Really?
But, I don't know if I'll do a good job.
You will.
With visuals like yours
our program will become quite popular.
No way. That's not true.
What do I do?
Thank you, Doctor Ye.
I'm benefiting a lot from my boyfriend.
May I give you some advice?
Don't think that this is thanks to me.
This is completely your doing.
Pardon?
Do you really think I recommended
you because you're my girlfriend?
I recommended you because I think
you're the most hardworking
and skilled physical therapist
in this treatment room.
I see.
Anyway, thank you.
I'll work really hard.
That's right, Mom. I'm going to be on TV.
No, I won't become famous.
But this is a good opportunity.
Yeah. Thanks, Mom. I'll call you later.
It'd be really nice
to be on TV, to be on TV.
I can't believe I'm going to be
on TV with Doctor Ye.
- What are you doing?
- What?
Nothing.
She's dying of happiness
about being on TV.
Don't worry about whether or not
she's happy. Get over her.
Shin Min Ho, Senior Kim wants to
pay you back for the meal last time
by treating you to lunch today.
See you on the roof in 30 minutes.
Nam Woo, you can come too,
since you know Senior Kim.
Hello.
- It looks good.
- I know, right?
Let's take a look at the menu.
- Oh, Nam Woo's coming too.
- Really?
Wow, what should we get?
They all look delicious.
Is lemon cream chicken better?
That one over there.
Or are spicy rice cakes better?
Lemon cream chicken is good though.
Spicy rice cakes are good too.
There's a combo with
both dishes included.
You're Solomon after all.
I'll take two of these to go.
- Sure, no problem.
- Thank you.
Hey, you were so excited about confessing
to her. Did she get a boyfriend already?
No way. Is that why you were
so irritable for the last few days?
Why did you have to bring this up?
They'll end up finding out anyway.
And talking to people about it
helps with the healing process.
- I know from experience.
- That's right, Min Ho, Min Ho.
I've also been in one-sided
love until not long ago.
I did a lot of studying
to get over the pain.
Do you want to know how
you can get over her quickly?
- How I can get over her?
- Yeah.
According to a study
from Harvard University
love roots from loneliness.
Especially when your body is lonely.
In other words, when you
lack physical intimacy.
- Pardon?
Basically, if you have physical
intimacy, you won't feel lonely
and if you don't feel lonely,
you can get over her quickly.
No way. How can he have
physical intimacy without a girl?
Who says it has to be a girl?
You can hug and kiss Min Ho.
- That's right.
- What?
Okay. I'll let you hug and kiss me.
Do it.
Okay, fine. I can do that for a friend.
I'm kidding.
That's nonsense.
Let's eat.
Okay. Let's eat. Eat up.
Wow, this looks good.
This is good.
Really? Are you going to be on TV?
Yes. I'm on to be on Health Plus on TVM.
- Please remember to watch it.
- Oh, of course.
I'll watch it for sure. Do a good job.
I will.
Doctor Woo, when you're finished
meet me in my office with Doctor Kim.
Okay.
Pardon? You want me to go on the show?
But Doctor Ye asked Doctor Woo for help.
I know. But when I told the director
he told me to send you,
since you're a full-time employee.
That show will go on for three months.
But Doctor Woo's contract
will end before then.
A full-time position could
free up before then.
He said that won't happen this year.
That means Doctor Woo has to
transfer to another hospital
and a doctor from another hospital
can't promote our hospital on TV.
He doesn't want to switch
her out midway either.
- Oh, I see.
- I'm sorry, Doctor Woo.
That's okay. There's nothing we can do.
I don't know. I can't do it.
I feel bad for Doctor Woo.
That's okay, Doctor.
I'm okay. Please do it.
But what do I tell Doctor Ye?
He'll definitely say,
"May I give you some advice?"
"Don't interfere in my decisions.",
as he glares at me...
like this. I'm too scared to tell him.
- I'll tell him then.
- Really?
Then can make it sound like
you don't want to do it anymore?
I'm afraid Doctor Ye will go to
the director and cause a scene.
Aren't you being too mean to Doctor Woo?
That's okay, Doctor.
Sure, I'll tell him that.
I'll be going now.
Wait, Bo Young...
I can't believe this situation.
Geez, what are you saying
all of a sudden?
I can't do the show in Bo Young's
place. I feel so bad for her.
If you need a full-time employee
to do it, how about Doctor Park?
Doctor Park likes to lead
so he'll like being on TV.
Doctor Park doesn't have
the time for that right now.
- He even took a paid holiday.
- Why?
You know his wife got fired, right?
It looks like she'll stay at home now
so he went to take his mother
back home to the countryside
because she doesn't have to
take care of the twins anymore.
Didn't she move here for good?
Why don't they just live together?
He feels bad because they can't
give her spending money anymore
and his wife doesn't want her to stay.
They've never gotten along.
Doctor Park must be very upset.
What will he do?
Mom, you're sad, aren't you?
I'm sorry. I even asked you to take care
of the twins until elementary school.
- But things turned out this way.
- That's okay.
I only took care of them because they're
my grandchildren. It's very difficult.
Especially if they're twins.
I'm happy to be free.
But what will you do now? You already
sold your farm before moving here.
And I can't give you spending money...
that I used to give you
for taking care of the twins.
Hey, don't worry.
I can go to your aunt's and help her out.
I won't have to spend as much money
down there, so I can support myself.
Plus, I didn't sell the house,
so I have a place to sleep.
Don't worry about me.
- I'll see you at the same time tomorrow.
- Be careful.
Please get back safely.
Chief, who's that?
Why does he have a secretary?
Don't you know him?
That's Congressman Han Sung Chul.
The one that's always on the news?
That's right. First, it was an athlete,
and now it's a congressman.
Doctor Ye is really impressive.
My boyfriend is that capable
while his girlfriend lost an opportunity
for being a terminal contractor.
In any case, I can't
get a full-time job here.
What do I do now?
Okay.
Hello.
Oh no, you didn't eat your lunch.
You can't keep skipping meals.
What if you collapse?
I don't have an appetite.
But you need to eat
to recover your energy.
In any case, don't skip your meal
tomorrow. Promise me.
Since you promised me,
let's begin the examination.
Okay, please relax, just like that.
Okay. Please lie down comfortably.
Please hold your breath.
I'll take it now.
Okay, all done.
Mother, remember to eat, okay?
I'm worried about that patient.
She keeps skipping meals.
She lost so much weight.
Can't you see that your junior
lost a lot of weight too?
I've lost a lot of weight these days.
You're right. Our Joo Yong,
Joo Yong's a lot thinner too.
Do you have a worry, Joo Yong, Joo Yong?
No, it's not that.
I'm studying really hard
to get into graduate school.
I don't have time to eat
properly because of that.
Hey, you need to eat while you study.
Okay. I'll buy you
pork belly. It's on me.
Is chicken soup with ginseng better for
your recovery? I'll buy you that instead.
Is pork belly better? Is chicken
soup with ginseng better?
That's okay. I'm tired of eating out.
I just want to eat my mom's cooking.
Oh, come to think of it, my mom hasn't
given me side dishes in a while.
She usually sends me some every week.
Hi, Mom. I want your glass
noodles, cooked beans
and grilled short rib patties.
Can you send it to me today?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm enjoying the flowers with
my friends today, so I can't.
Really? Then send it to me tomorrow.
I have a gathering tomorrow, so I can't.
Then what about the day after?
You have plans? What the heck?
I'm studying my ass off
to get into graduate school
while you can't make me food
because you're having too much fun?
Forget it. I'm hanging up.
This is good. I didn't
want to do the show
but if we do it together,
it'll become a good memory.
Um, Doctor Ye.
I don't think I can do the show.
I feel more burdened
the more I think about it.
But I'll be right there with you,
so you don't have to feel burdened.
I thought you were excited
to be on TV, so why...
I was...
but my heart keeps pounding really hard.
You even recommended me.
I'm sorry for being like this,
but please understand.
Sure. If you feel that burdened,
there's nothing we can do.
Thank you.
- Please eat.
- Okay.
Go inside already.
Go first. I want to see you off.
Ugh, you're still so stubborn.
- I should go so you can rest.
- Go on. Go on.
I'll go.
Geez.
I wish she'd go inside.
What's this?
Oh no...
Mom...
Goodness, what do I do?
I can't forget about my babies.
To the magpie that came every morning...
and sang before you left.
Once I leave, come back...
and comfort my parents.
Who will take care of my old parents...
after I leave?
Why is my trip back to Seoul so long?
[From Kim Min Ki's
"The Road to Seoul..."]
Hello?
Hello, Doctor Ye. This is the general
affairs office at Shinsun Hospital.
Oh, hello. What is this about?
I just called you to remind you that
once your contract ends in two months
you'll have to move out of your
dorm in two months as well.
Sure, I'll remember that.
Anyway, thank you.
I'll work really hard.
But my heart keeps pounding really hard.
You even recommended me.
I'm sorry for being like this,
but please understand.
Is something the matter?
Pardon? No.
This coffee's really good.
I must have mistaken you
for a friend for a little while
because we were never meant to get along.
I shouldn't have acknowledged you
when you showed up again.
Do you know that, you jerk?
- You're here.
- Yes.
I'm really sorry, Bo Young.
You missed a good opportunity
because of me.
That's not true. Don't say
that. I'm really okay.
I felt really bad so I did some research.
Do you know Woojoo Hospital?
It's just as big as our hospital.
I saw a post saying that a full-time
position freed up at their hospital.
- Do you want to apply for it?
- Of course, I do.
I'll check it out right now.
Look at how happy she is
about a full-time job opportunity.
I hope she gets the job this time.
That's right. They say there's always
a way out of the worst situations.
I'll get this full-time job
no matter what.
[Shinsun Hospital]
- You're here.
- If you feel any pain or discomfort
please let me know.
If you hold it in, you'll avoid the pain,
which will yield an abnormal result.
I see. By the way, I heard
you're going to be on TV today.
- Pardon?
- I heard from the other doctors.
- I'll make sure to watch it.
- Oh, thank you.
One moment, please.
Doctor Kim, pass me the charts.
We're here to give you an X-ray.
Doctor, you're here.
Mother, did you skip your meal again?
- Why do you look so out of energy?
- I'm okay...
What do we do? Will you be okay?
Please relax...
Mother! Mother! Mother!
- Mother!
- I think she's unconscious.
A patient just collapsed and is
unconscious! Please hurry!
Mother! Wake up!
I wonder what's for lunch today.
Whatever it is, don't eat too much.
- We're having a company dinner tonight.
- A company dinner?
That's right. Today's Doctor Ye
and Doctor Kim's first show
- so we should watch it together.
- I have to go home though.
My wife is having a hard time
looking after the twins by herself.
I can't go either. I have other plans.
What is it, Doctor Woo?
You can come right afterward.
But the thing is, it's really far.
- Where are you going?
- Pardon?
I'm going to Anseong to visit home.
- I can't go either.
- The star can't skip out.
You can't skip anymore.
Follow me.
Chief.
Hey.
You should have told him you have
an interview. Why did you lie?
Because I'll be embarrassed
if I don't get the job.
Anyway, keep it a secret, Big Sis.
What if someone sees us?
What do you mean? Can't two
colleagues have coffee together?
No one will suspect us. Don't worry.
But, why are you going to Anseong?
Pardon?
Oh, my mom said she wanted to see me.
Then I'll skip the dinner
and drive you there.
Don't do that. This dinner is for you.
In any case, I'm sad that I can't
watch the show with you.
I'll watch it afterward.
Oh, Nurse Choi, did Patient
Kim Jung Sook wake up?
Yes, she's okay now. She was
exhausted due to malnutrition.
- Pardon? Malnutrition?
- Yes.
I noticed that she wasn't
eating for a few days.
I think you should stress
this to her guardian.
Tell her to make her eat more
so that she doesn't get sick.
But the truth is, she's not eating
because of her guardian.
- What do you mean by that?
- Patient Kim Jung Sook is a paraplegic.
So her daughter helps her go
everywhere as her guardian
but she worries that her daughter
will struggle if she's too heavy.
- Pardon?
- And if she eats, it'll come back out
which her daughter will have to clean up.
That's why she hasn't been eating.
Hey, Young Chul. It's been
a long time. What is it?
I was reminded of you
when I saw your mother today.
But why is your mother hospitalized?
What? Hospitalized?
Isn't it true? I thought
I saw her at our hospital.
- Isn't she hospitalized here?
- What?
I'll call you back.
Why isn't she picking up?
Hi, Mom. Are you hospitalized
at Jinsung Hospital?
Wa... wait, how did you know?
Why? Why are you hospitalized?
It's not a big deal.
It was a simple procedure
of removing a small
abnormality in my uterus.
Why didn't you tell me?
You should have told me.
What for? You're busy trying to
get into graduate school.
Why would I worry a kid
who's really busy studying?
You still should have told me.
I didn't know that and complained
about you not sending me food.
Then, are you okay now?
- Did the surgery go well?
- I'm just fine.
Okay, Mom. Get some rest.
Joo Yong, Joo Yong, I feel bad
for Patient Kim Jung Sook
so I want to buy her something. Should I
buy her a healthy juice or a snack?
They both sound good to me.
Do what you think is best.
I don't think there's anything
greater than a mother's love.
She didn't eat for days
in fear of troubling her child.
I guess mothers would rather
strain their own bodies
than make their children
go through a hard time.
Right?
Yes, I realized that too.
[Woojoo Hospital]
There are a lot of people here.
I'm so nervous.
Hi.
I'm at an interview for
a physical therapist position.
My uncle told me to take it.
He's the vice president here.
Hey, so many people are
here for the interview.
Hey, of course, I'll get it.
My uncle was the one who
posted the full-time job notice
just in time after my graduation.
They're only holding
the interviews as a formality.
Yeah.
No way.
Uncle.
- Let's begin.
- Sure.
- First, Kim Song Ae.
- Yes?
What are you determined to do
if you get the job here?
- I'll work hard.
- Oh, how impressive.
Yes, I can feel your passion.
- Ask her a question too.
- Sure.
Woo Bo Young, you worked at
Shinsun Hospital as a contractor.
Why didn't you continue working
there as a full-time employee?
There were no available--
Hey, I'm sure you would have gotten
a position if you did a good job.
- I did a pretty good job--
- Forget that.
What are you prepared to do
if you get a job here?
I'll use my past hospital experience
to understand the patients--
Hey, did you reserve it?
What? Korean Beef Village?
Okay.
I told him to reserve a place for dinner,
and he chose a Korean beef place.
- Korean Beef Village?
- Beef?
You're happy because you're not
paying for it, aren't you?
I'm sorry. Please continue.
No, thank you. I have
no interest in working here.
But then again, I'm sure you never
intended on hiring anyone anyway
when you've already decided on someone.
May I give you some advice?
Don't try to make any excuses
when everyone will find out anyway.
If you're going to waste our time,
at least treat us with respect.
What kind of bullcrap is this?
Hi, Mom. What is it?
I heard there's a doctor at your hospital
who's really good at disk surgery.
There is. Why?
A client of mine wants to
have him do her surgery
but he has so many patients
that she has to wait months.
She asked me if you can use
your connections to help her out.
Can you do that?
Mom. I told you I'm not in
the position to do those things.
Why not? When I said you're a physical
therapist at a huge hospital in Seoul
and that you're going to be on TV,
they all said you succeeded.
Make me proud, will you?
Succeeded? Does it look like I succeeded?
I can't do the show
because I'm a contractor.
And my contract is almost over,
so I have to quit soon
and once I move out of my dorm,
I'll be no different from a beggar.
What kind of power do I have
to get her an earlier surgery date?
How can I help anyone else
when I'm struggling myself?
Forget it. I'm hanging up.
Did you arrive in Anseong?
Eat lots of good food and have
a fun time with your mother.
I wanted to get a full-time job
so I could act dignified.
It looks like I lost my chance again.
Wait, why isn't he at the dinner?
Hey, hurry up already.
Never mind. Go and buy
some cold medicine.
You skipped the dinner
by saying you're sick.
You're tiring me out.
I can't even turn on
the lights if I go home.
I'll stay here and de-stress.
Those bastards shouldn't
fool around with interviews.
Die. Die, die, die!
Eating is the best way to de-stress.
Die! Die! Die!
Look at you.
Die.
Die! Die!
Since scoliosis is a type of back pain
isn't that a problem with the back disk?
No. That's why we'll learn
about scoliosis today.
We invited a professional
who'll teach us in more detail.
Eating is the best way to de-stress.
- Wow, that man is so handsome.
- He's really handsome.
I'm a physical therapist, Ye Jae Wook.
That's right.
It's time for Doctor Ye's show.
[He graduated from NYU!
He wrote SCI-level papers!]
[He's the youngest national
lecturer of sling therapy.]
That man must be very impressive.
I know, right? If he's on TV,
he must make good money.
I want him as my son-in-law.
He probably has a girlfriend, right?
Goodness, I'm sure he does.
They say birds of
a feather flock together.
I'm sure he's dating a successful
woman with a great salary.
Probably.
Bo Young, I'm sorry
I was unreasonable.
It seems like I'm burdening you
when I should be helping you instead.
But, don't worry too much.
I'll do whatever I can to get you
money for a small apartment.
Cheer up, my daughter.
You look good on TV, Doctor Ye.
Yes, he doesn't seem nervous either.
Can you show us a simple
stretch we can all do?
Wow, Doctor Kim must be coming up.
What's that?
We will show you an exercise
for scoliosis prevention.
You like you came from the underworld.
Let's begin. First...
I mean, I'm scared
it'll pop up in my dreams.
Doctor Ye, didn't you
give her some advice?
I did, many times.
I heard that you have to put on a lot
of makeup to look average on TV
so I put on a little more.
If you put on anymore, you would have
given the viewers a heart attack.
- Is it that bad?
- There goes the hospital's reputation.
Hi, Ji Eun. Oh, did you see it?
My makeup?
Hey, you wench. I was startled too.
Yeah.
What? Woo Bo Young?
Why?
Bo Young caused a scene
at her interview?
Why?
Oh, really?
Okay. Sure, let's talk later.
Doctor Kim.
- What did you just say?
- What do you mean?
- Did Doctor Woo have an interview?
- Pardon?
- What did you just say?
- What do you mean?
- Did Doctor Woo have an interview?
- Pardon?
Bo Young wanted to keep it a secret
in fear or not getting the job.
Oh well. I don't see why
you shouldn't know.
Bo Young's contract at our
hospital is almost over
so she went to an interview,
but they had someone in mind.
This happened after she lost her TV
opportunity for being a contractor.
- What will she do?
- Are you saying...
Doctor Woo didn't voluntarily
turn the opportunity down?
Pardon?
- Yes, Director.
- I saw the show.
The broadcast station wants you
to stay on the show for good.
- You can do that, right?
- No, I only agreed to three months.
Hey, just think about how it'll promote--
May I give you some advice?
Please don't try to change my mind.
I will no longer allow you to pressure
me in such a dogmatic manner.
Yes, it's finally time to rest.
Oh no.
I can't believe Mom did this by herself
when it's so difficult with both of us.
By the way, give Mom a call.
I have a feeling she wants to hear your
voice because she asks about you.
I'll call her later. I'm too tired
from watching the kids all day.
Okay.
By the way, did you cancel the
automatic transfer to your mother?
No, not yet.
I told you to cancel it
before the next transfer.
Speaking of which, can't we send her
a little bit of money every month?
Are you kidding? We have to live off
of your paychecks from now on.
We can barely afford to pay for the kids'
expenses. Cancel it right away.
Fine.
[Transfers]
[Cancel automatic transfer]
[The automatic transfer
has been cancelled.]
Hey, Jae Hoon.
Professor Seo Dong Gyun's
number? I have it.
I'll text it to you when I find it.
I had his business card somewhere.
Shi Won, I saved up the spending
money you gave me every month.
You said they raised your security
deposit too. It's not much, but use it.
The PIN number is your birthday, okay?
Cheer up, my son.
"I Thought It Was Okay for Mothers
to Do That" by Shim Soon Deok.
"I thought it was okay
for mothers to do that."
"Even if she works herself
to death on the farm fields."
"I thought it was okay
for mothers to do that."
"Even if she sits on the furnace
and eats a cold bowl of rice for lunch."
Mom.
Why didn't you tell me?
"I thought it was okay
for mothers to do that."
"Even if she does laundry with her bare
hands and cold water on a winter day."
"I thought it was okay
for mothers to do that."
"'I'm full. I'm not hungry.' Even if she
starves while feeing her family."
"I thought it was okay
for mothers to do that."
"Even if her heels are so worn out
that they make noises in her blanket."
["I Thought It Was Okay for Mothers
to Do That." by Shim Soon Deok.]
"I thought it was okay
for mothers to do that."
"Even if her fingernails are so worn out
that they can't even be clipped."
[Mom, I'm sorry I got mad at you.]
"I thought it was okay
for mom's to do that."
"Even if Father's anger and our
rebellion don't phase her."
"I thought it was okay
for mothers to do that."
"'I miss your grandmother.
I miss your grandmother.'"
"I thought those were just complaints."
"She woke up in the middle of
the night and cried in silence."
Goodness.
"When I saw that..."
"'Ah.' It was not okay
for mothers to do that."
Bo Young's contract at our
hospital is almost over
so she went to an interview,
but they had someone in mind.
But, why are you going to Anseong?
Pardon?
Oh, my mom said she wanted to see me.
This happened after she lost her TV
opportunity for being a contractor.
I don't think I can do the show.
I feel more burdened
the more I think about it.
I'd be back from Anseong
at around this time.
My key. I must have
left it in the restaurant.
What the heck? There's only 12,000 won.
Her clothes are decent though.
- This?
- Throw those away.
What are you doing?
Damn it! Run!
Hey, stop right there!
Stop right there!
Hey! I'll kill you!
I was really robbed.
I'm sorry. Can't I go home and transfer
it to you? I'll pay for the eggs too.
Do you know how many people
say that and run away?
Forget it. You can't leave until you pay.
I understand.
Why isn't Yoon Joo picking up?
I'm running out of battery.
[Shin Min Ho]
- What?
- Hey, Cry Baby Bo Young.
Um...
About how petty I was to you...
during the weekend trip,
I want to sincerely apologize.
- Forgive me.
- Forget it.
Do you think I'll forgive you...
I will. Hey, I'll forgive you if you
come here with some money.
What? Where are you?
Hey.
What happened to you?
I thought you went down to Anseong.
Doctor Woo, I know
I'm lacking in many ways
but I want to be a comfortable
person whom you can lean on
and tell everything to.
- It's all wrapped up.
- Great, thank you.
The phone is currently turned off.
Please leave a message--
Thanks. I'll wash this
and return it to you later.
Hey, why didn't you call Doctor Ye
in such an urgent situation?
How could I do that?
Doctor Ye doesn't know about the
interview. He thinks I'm in Anseong.
And how could I let him see me in the
state that I was in? It's embarrassing.
Aren't you embarrassed in front of me?
I thought you were in Anseong too.
Why are you telling me the truth?
That's because...
it's you.
Seeing how I asked for your help
as soon as you called me
after we fought as if we'd
never see each other again
I must feel comfortable with you.
Let's go inside.
Hey.
Can you really be happy with Doctor Ye?
What?
Can it last long if you feel
uncomfortable with him?
If you truly love him and like him
shouldn't you be comfortable enough
to show him everything about you?
Just like how you are with me.
What?
I was going to try to remain friends
but I can't do that anymore.
Hey, what are you saying?
I like you.
I've felt this way for a while
and I wanted to tell you...
but when I saw you liking Doctor Ye...
I felt hesitant.
But, if you can't call him
in such urgent situations
and you feel this
uncomfortable with him...
I can't let you go.
Please stop.
I clearly asked you to get over her.
And I clearly told you
that I can't accept that
Bo Young is dating you.
I'm more sure about it now.
Hey, Shin Min Ho.
Let's go, Doctor Woo.
Hey, Woo Bo Young.
I sincerely like you.
I like you a lot.
[A Poem A Day]
What do I have to do to make
Doctor Woo comfortable with me?
Bo Young, since we're dating,
let's drop the formalities.
- What do you think, Bo Young?
- "Bo Young?" What's this?
Shi Won. Yoon Joo.
- Myung Chul.
- What's wrong with you?
If you're so uncomfortable with Doctor Ye
that you can show him your true self
then I won't let you go.
What's the matter?
Since I've decided to be
comfortable with you
I'll tell you.
I appreciate your gesture, but I can't.
We won't have to date secretly within
the workplace for that much longer.
Cry Baby Bo Young,
see you when you get home.
I'm going to resolve this today.
Follow me.
What's with that face? I wanted to
make a good memory with you.
Thanks, Min Ho.