Police! Open up!
Police, ma'am! Hello?
Open up! Come on! Come on. Open up.
Hello?
Miss Olsen, are you there?
We will have to make a forced entry...
if you refuse or are unable to open up!
Nancy Olsen!
Open up! Come on!
The door down the hall.
My God!
How awful!
Look!
He went out there! Get him!
On June 3, 1985...
at approximately 5:58 a.m.,
Richard Beacon, a
seven-year-old Long Island boy,
shot and killed his father
in a heated family argument.
Felicia Beacon, the boy's
mother, astonishingly claims...
she then saw her son take off in
flight from the patio balcony.
What really happened the night of June 3?
Who was Richie Beacon, and where is he now?
In '44,
I was sent to Fontenal Prison
on several counts of theft.
Name?
Broom.
First? John.
Age?
Thirty-one.
Date of birth?
October 29, 1913.
Orphan? Yes.
Where?
First...
Prison was not new to me. I'd
lived in them all my life.
Various foster homes.
In submitting to prison life, embracing it,
I could reject the world
that had rejected me.
The sexual behavior, which includes...
Hold him! Males...
Is that correct? What?
I will bash your fucking skull in!
The state obliges us to,
inquire as to whether or
not you engaged in the...
practice of...
that you practiced...
Yeah.
Whatever.
That word there, is it
written as two words?
We're gathered here today...
in the shadow cast by the
penal preserve of Baton...
by the trusty and loyal inmates,
Harold van Roven and John Broom,
who hereby pledge to one another...
in the eyes of their comrades and
fellows in misery...
their loyalty and faith to
one northerly’s and soul.
The ring upon each man's finger...
will prove to them and
those in their company...
that each is betrothed to the
other for life and to love...
till death do come.
Place the rings on each finger.
Pledge to truth and faith...
above and beyond God, the oppressor.
Ever since he was a child,
Thomas Graves had been
hungry for knowledge.
Hungry to discover all the
secrets of the universe.
Science...
man's sacred quest for truth...
was his first and only love.
Years of hard work and research...
led him to the mysteries
of the sex drive...
and its potential for the
betterment of mankind.
At the age of 32,
Dr. Thomas Graves was called upon...
to present his theories
to experts in his field.
And thus, as I have demonstrated,
I have determined that once extracted...
the application of the
hormonal equivalent...
of the sexual instinct to
practical neurology...
will not only provoke a dramatic
reassessment of geriatric research...
but will end paralysis as we know it today.
Thank you.
Why, this is ridiculous!
I ask you, are we to
take this charade seriously?
I demand that this man be reexamined...
by the panel on grounds of
medical incompetence!
I agree.
That's it.
It's putrefacted condensation sustained,
allowing molecular
coagulation by producing...
bio magnetic gas.
I did it. I did it.
Dr. Graves? Yes. I'm Dr. Graves.
And I've just captured the sex drive.
That's marvelous.
It means the molecular coagulation
theory holds true.
Molecular coag...
How do you know that? Who are you?
I'm Dr. Olsen.- Who?
Dr. Olsen. Nancy Olsen?
From Boston?
Dr. Strick recommended
me to you regarding...
You're...
I... I didn't expect a woman.
I didn't expect you to.
I've been following your
work for years, Doctor.
Ever since Evaluations of Molecular
Sustention of Hormonal Conductivity...
appeared in the science journal at MIT.
Your discovery of the white cellular
clotting predominance in neurasthenia...
completely altered my understanding of...
conditional bioflavonoid neuropathology.
I wrote my doctoral thesis on your
molecular coagulation theory,
and I'm now a hormonal specialist.
I've come here with the
hopes of assisting you.
Well, how do you do?
Very well, Doctor. Thank you.
And now I really should leave
you to record your success.
But, please, feel free to call
on me anytime that you need.
And congratulations, Doctor.
You're making medical history.
Molecular coagulation...
conditional bioflavonoid neuropathology.
Evaluations of Molecular
Sustention of Hormonal Conductivity...
appeared in the science journal at MIT.
Putrefacted condensation sustained...
You're making medical history.
The quiet residential
community of Glenville...
was stunned to learn of the
strange death of Fred Beacon.
It gave everybody the creeps.
All the neighbors were afraid
to come out their door.
It was absolutely...
the most dreadful thing I have experienced...
in my entire lifetime. It was awful.
It was terrible.
You know, I heard every shot.
You never know who your friends
are. I heard every single shot.
You think you know people, but
you really don’t know them...
and you live next door to them.
You don't, till something like this happens.
Richie Beacon's disappearance provoked...
one of the toughest missing person
investigations in Long Island history.
Whole thing lasted at least a year.
His face is still on milk cartons.
What was found?
Nothing.
Felicia Beacon became the center
of Glenville controversy...
following her extraordinary account
of her son's disappearance.
I guess I just didn't...
I definitely didn’t know what he was.
I mean, I punished him.
His father hit him, just like any kid.
But I definitely didn’t realize...
Realize what?
That he was a gift from God.
By the time I was 16 years old,
I was notorious as a kid with
a terrific knack for theft.
Foster homes would no longer take me,
and I was sent to the Boys'
Reformatory of Baton.
There, in the counterfeit
world of men among men...
Down! Three!
I found my true family. Four!
Halt!
Step to the left! At Baton, I was
astounded by the discovery...
Step to the right! That each
male had a male of his own.
Step to the right! And that the
world of force and manly beauty...
loved in that way within itself...
from link to link.
Down! Five!
It was from then on, when
they merged in shadow,
that each group offered me a puzzle.
The stiff, silent males
possessed the violence of love.
And my life's study...
would be to find it.
Sixteen years had passed...
when the maximum security
prison of Fontenal...
brought me face-to-face
with my deliverance.
Jack Bolton. Age 28.
175 pounds.
Seventy-five inches.
Formerly a captive of Baton.
Poor kid!
Somebody up there knows. Come on, pussy!
You know what? You make me want to puke!
You want to suck it, bitch? When
was the last time you saw rock?
You want to suck it! You
want to crawl for it!
Yes, you do!
Is it Jack Bolton?
You hear that? Pussy!
Canon!
Here?
Since today.
Coyle, Jack Bolton.
Hey, John. A friend of mine, man.
You make me want to puke!-
Jack Bolton, Johnny Broom.
Baton? Yeah. Yeah.
I knew it.
You swallow it by the
mouthful, don't you, Birdy?
Jism by the jug, right?
You want it real bad, don't you, punk?
Don't you, slug? Don't you, pretty boy?
Hey, you! Shine!
Annoying Mr. Rass?
Not me, chief.
That's a good boy.
That's a smart little fag.
Think fast, faggot!
You want it real bad, don't you? Don't you?
You want me to shoot it up your hole.
Is that it?
Go on. Marry him. You know you love him.
What? Me marry him?
How's the wife shaking?
Keeping you out of trouble?
You gotta be kidding.
Looking like a dream. A bad dream.
What do you say, angel-puss?
Richie was a complicated boy.
On the one hand, very intelligent,
but at the same time,
withdrawn.
What's really strange, though, was,
the amount of animosity he would induce...
in the other children... out of nowhere.
Like this one kid, Brad. Yeah.
He started hitting him... Yeah.
'Cause he didn't believe that he was
really a prince and his dad was a king.
The weird thing was that
Richie didn’t fight back.
He just sat there until... He just
sat there until the teacher came.
And he was all bloody.
He was a perfect child.
A perfect baby.
Very independent.
Very smart.
Never fussed.
He always kept himself
busy with stories and coloring.
He was always doing these private things.
Private games.
All right, keep it moving.
There's no rec for today.
All inmates proceed directly to shop.
No rec today.
Move it along.
A trip to the brig, Gecko? Is that
what you want? Move it along!
Would you fuckin' pigs shut up?
Thanks a lot, man. Forget it.
Guy from Baton.
It's loyalty.
Man, to a shithole. Maybe.
Better than this one.
No way, man.
The guys are... They're
straight with you here, you know?
You know what's what.
Don't be too sure.
Hey, you got any rolls?
Thanks a lot, man.
Look, forget it, okay?
Baton.
Okay.
I'll see you later.
Bolton's reemergence in my life...
contradicted any memory I
had of him as a child.
At Baton, he was sullen and small.
Even I picked on him.
Stay out of my way, Bolton.
You hear me?
**
Something about my memory
of Bolton disturbed me.
But I couldn't put my
finger on what it was.
All night long I built an imaginary life...
of which he was the center.
And I always gave that life...
which was begun over and over
and transformed a dozen times...
a violent end.
Hello.
Hello. Dr. Graves?
This is Dr. Olsen. Nancy Olsen?
I've been trying to reach
you for quite some time now.
Are you...
Is everything all right?
Yes, I'm fine.
Good. I'm relieved to hear that.
I didn't know what happened.
I thought maybe you had
decided against the internship,
that perhaps I had interrupted you at
such a critical moment that...
It's just that after your terrific success,
I wanted to be the first to
congratulate you.
Hello?
Hello. Dr. Graves?
Hello!
Hello?
Dr. Graves?
Dr. Graves, this is Dr. Olsen.
Dr. Graves, I know you're in there.
Dr. Graves.
What happened to your face?
Do I... look lascivious?
Like the pitiful, decrepit result...
of some hideous indulgence?
Well,
take a good look, Miss Dr. Olsen.
Because that's exactly...
what I am.
Dr. Graves... Please, call me Tom.
Tom.
What happened?
I... accidentally ingested...
The serum? Yes.
God! All of it?
What are you going to do?
There's nothing l can do.
You know as well as I the hormonal
system is self-perpetuating.
The bio magnetic field is irreversible.
I'm a monster.
No, you're not.
Then look at me.
Now...
kiss me.
Sorry. That was uncalled for.
No.
I have the greatest respect for you, Doctor.
And of all the people this
could happen to...
why it had to be you, I just don't know.
The fact is...
it doesn't disgust me in the slightest.
On the contrary.
It breaks my heart.
Don't.
He was a meek soul.
People pick on meek souls.
It's something in human nature...
something very sad about human nature.
We have to pick on those that
are weaker than us.
And that's exactly what
started happening at Park Street.
During the two and half years...
that Richie attended Park
Street Elementary School,
he allegedly made 47 visits
to the nurse's office.
His mother was called as many as 25 times,
and Richie met with the
principal at least 10.
Twelve classmates were
suspended, and three expelled.
He was a little kid,
and I remember having to pull him out
of a few fights in the cafeteria...
and even in the playground.
For a little kid, he was noticeable.
Well, some people felt sorry for him,
but most of them wanted
to hit him and stuff.
It was weird,
'cause he's just a person that
you want to see get creamed.
Once I was right in the middle of
giving him an injection...
and he called me "fatso."
You know, I mean, I could
have hurt him or something. I...
I just... I... I think he was evil.
If it wasn't a bloody nose,
it was a sprained ankle.
If it wasn't... I don't know...
skinned knees, it was somebody put
something in his milk.
Once, unfortunately, I discovered
him and a slightly older boy,
Gregory Lazar, in the equipment room.
And,
Gregory had the poor kid over his knee...
and was apparently,
really giving it to him.
Everything the principal said about
it was completely a lie.
I didn't attack Richie Beacon at all.
He just...
kept bugging me, kept
bothering me every second.
He... He... He made me.
I got this when I was a kid.
This guard was always just calling
me "pretty boy," right?
"Pretty boy."
Until I caught him.
This is a tough one though. Look at this.
I mean, that looks tough, right?
Yeah.
You're a kid, you get something like that,
you think you’re gonna die, you know?
This one...
I was crashing in church.
You know, you should never
crash in churches.
It's just bad luck.
I told Nick.
This one over here...
You can't really see it.
But it's...
it's right there.
It's the pink, see?
I got it in... in LaSalle.
Nah, in Leden, I think.
Anyway...
There's nothing wrong with
being out in the world, Tom.
I don't know why you’re so nervous about it.
People come down with all
sorts of conditions.
This is just one of them.
Hello.
Just ignore them.
* Reach up to me
**
Don't!
Why?
I can't.
Well, I can't do this.
Not now.
But, Tom...
I'm in love with you.
Look at me, Nancy.
Think about what you're
saying and look at me!
Tom!
Tom! Tom!
Well, Richie was extremely gifted.
Imaginative.
Always telling these elaborate stories.
He was a chronic liar...
and, would often engage the
other classmates...
in these stories of his.
And they'd get very angry.
He liked controlling people...
and watching them boil over.
I was back one day in the garden...
I think it was a Sunday.
And all of a sudden I
saw something coming running...
from the Beacons' house over here.
And I thought it was a deer
at first... a little deer.
But then, as it came towards me,
I saw it was a little
boy, about five or six.
And he was naked.
And he came running closer,
and he was exhibiting
himself right in front of me.
As he got closer to me, he squatted down...
and...
and he made a B.M.right in front of me.
He turned Ar... He got up.
He turned around...
and he ran away just like a wild animal.
I didn't know what he'd do, so I just...
came into the house and closed my door.
I just was so shocked.
Pus-sy.
Like a lookee!
Like a, like a lookee!
Like a, like a lookee.
Pus-sy.
Every time I do a job...
I get stiff.
Every single time.
'Cause you were doing them
with... What's his name?
Nick.
That goof of yours.
What?
I do my jobs solo, man. You can't
do them with somebody else.
That's not what I heard.
Well, what you hear? Hey! Hey, Diego!
Nothing. What?
Bitch! Got a present for you.
Nothing.
What?
Just that you and Nick were
partners or something.
Who said that? Don't remember.
Who?
Look, I don't remember.
What do you think you’re looking at?
You fucking queer.
Fucking scum.
You think Nick gives a
shit what people think?
You know what Nick would do?
Man, he's busted into a joint.
He'd fucking piss all over it.
But first he'd do it up, you know. He'd...
He'd drink or eat...
and take a bath.
Screw.
I'm telling you, that guy...
One time, we were in this bankers'
joint, right? In Orleans.
We? What?
Listen, don't you
fucking start with me, man.
I mean that. Hey.
I mean that. Don't you start with me.
Bolton.
So what? So we did shit together.
We got busted.
Big fucking deal!
And who the fuck are you anyway?
You know, you walk around... You
try to act like a big shot.
Who are you kidding?
You are the biggest fucking
fruit in this joint.
Hey!
It was only a matter of time...
before Bolton would be
accepted by the big shots.
Go ahead.
And nothing threatened our friendship more.
I could tell Rass, the group's kingpin,
had an eye for him from day one.
I still could not take lightly...
the idea that people made love without me.
All over his forehead and
coming down like a...
all pussy on his cheek like a...
Hey. Hey, lady.
My goodness. And in such a hurry.
La-di-dah.
Yeah.
Sugar.
Tom.
Vodka, tonic.
How'd you find me?
Never mind.
Tom, come home.
We belong together.-
How can you say that?
I know what I'm saying.
I don't belong with anyone!
You're wrong.
The search is still on for the leper
murderer of Priscilla Monroe...
and possibly four other
unidentified leper victims.
Already, the venomous cancer
has spread to hundreds...
of innocent men, women and children,
and counts of sexual violence
are also on the rise.
Be on the lookout for a dark-haired man...
with intense eyes and a
badly infected mouth.
You don't know anything about
that, do you, Tom?
Tom?
Do you?
It's you, isn't it?
Remain calm...
You're the leper they've all
been talking about.-
Why didn't you tell me you were contagious?
When were you going to tell me this?
I was...
I was scared that I would frighten you away.
You're all l have left, Nancy.
What makes you so certain that
I'm safe with you?
Nancy.
I love you.
Tom.
I have to think.
Tom, I need some time alone to think.
Nancy... I'm sorry.
I'll call you.
Please.
Nancy.
In mid-November of 1984,
Richie Beacon was treated at
Cloyfield Medical Center...
for injuries to the thighs and lower back.
His parents claimed he’d been
hurt by the other kids at school,
but, well, frankly, I doubted it.
Why?
I felt they were
being purposefully vague with me.
There were other strange
circumstances surrounding the case.
I found an infectious discharge.
It was genitally secreted.
Sharp yellow color.
What did you guys used to do?
Just stupid junk.
Like what?
He'd go, like,"You're the
dad, and you're really mad,
and I'm, you know, the son.
"I just did this thing or something."
It was just some stupid game.
What kind of game? He just
totally forced me to do it.
I mean, it's like he got into
trouble or something.
Well... Well...
If I didn't do it, he'd just,
like, sit there and laugh,
and I'd get so mad I'd just
finally do what he said...
totally spank him... just
to make him shut up.
It's very odd,
but...
Mrs. Beacon's account of
Richie's disappearance...
you know, him killing his
father and flying away...
came directly from one of his stories.
Nancy?
Stop it! Piece of trash! Hear me, you slut?
Let go of me!
Slut! Slut!
You're hurting me! You are a pig!
What did you just call me?
Nancy? What did you just
call me, you little tramp?
Just go, you rotten filth.
Good for nothing!
What did you just call me?
Nancy.
Nancy!
God. No.
Tom.
Atmospheric toxins...
changed the magnetic field.
That's what caused it to spread.
Don't blame yourself.
Nancy.
I love you, Nancy.
Now it begins.
Hello, ma'am.
Miss Olsen?
Better open it up in here.
Open up! Come on! Come on. Open up.
So...
Hey.
Shit. I gotta go.
Go ahead.
You want a drag, pal?
You're a slut, you know that?
Anyone ever tell you that?
And your little man, he can
ride my fucking prick.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Hey, smile. Take your cap off.
Look, John, get lost, would you?
Got my hands in my pockets.
If they see us together, they're
gonna start bullshitting about me.
Why? I don't know. Just get lost.
Why?
They think you’re a...
Look, I tried to tell 'em that you're okay.
Come on. Let go, man!
You're my man.
Bolton's friendship with
Rass and the others...
filled me with jealousy but
instigated a transformation.
I felt myself growing mean, icy, stiff,
gleaming like a sword blade.
Hey, you! Stop there! Come on.
Let's go around.
Halt! I said halt!
We'll get you!- Get outta here!
Get outta here!
Well, I don't know what
kind of shouting they heard,
but, yes, we were fighting.
Fred was under a lot of
stress, and I was busy.
Richie kept getting hurt.
It was a bad period of time in general.
Did your arguments have
mostly to do with Richie?
No. Not at all.
Fred was angry at me.
He thought that I wasn't
spending enough time with Richie,
and he had to know where I was every second.
A neighbor claimed she saw him ripping
up your flower beds one night.
He was just angry.
He'd fired our gardener,
this Spanish kid, Jose,
and... he was just very angry at me,
so he tore up my flowers.
I know that I was wrong.
But my child was watching over me.
My child was an angel of judgment,
and I sinned against the Lord.
We are at 69 Gold Street,
the residence of Dr. Thomas Graves,
the notorious leper murderer...
who has been the cause of countless
deaths in the Centerville area alone.
Local authorities have the
premises surrounded...
and police are presently escorting all
other tenants out of the building...
which is considered highly contaminated.
To think I've been living next
door to him for three years,
not so much as suspecting what he did.
I knew something was odd about him.
I'll never forget the first
time I laid eyes on him.
Get your Dr. Graves mask right here.
Authentic mask of the leper murderer.
I have no doubt that we’ll be able to
seize this menace to the community...
and stop the spread of
this despicable contagion.
About a week before the 3rd,
Richie had sprained his wrist at school.
He twisted it, and this teacher
that lives near here drove him home.
It was about 1:15 or something.
I had no idea that he would
be coming home when he did.
So he walked in on me with this kid...
Jose, the gardener.
Hey, Broom, what's up?
What's wrong with you?
All right, Dr. Thomas Graves,
this is Deputy Hansen of Centerville County.
I'm required by law to tell you...
that you are under arrest. Get your Dr.
Graves masks here!
This time we have you
completely surrounded,
and there is no chance of escape.
The apartment is surrounded,
and you are ordered to
make yourself visible.
Dr. Thomas Graves, you are under arrest.
Come to the window.
The apartment is surrounded.
Why? Make yourself visible.
Why?
Dr. Thomas Graves, come to
the window and show yourself.
All I could remember thinking was, "God.
It's Richie."
But when I saw his face, it reminded
me of this time years before...
when Fred was spanking Richie...
and I was watching.
And I swear...
he looked at me with the
exact same expression.
It was like some... oath...
in some other language.
His face was so weird.
It made me feel ashamed.
My God.
Still, I did you.
You just don’t think.
It's the same. I shot.
And I'll do it whenever I want.
God!
Don't worry.
Come on.- Let's get that open.
Open your mug.
Open your mug!
Shorty, play Jacobs. Yeah.
You're dead. We're gonna fuck you up.
Open it up, cocksucker.
I said open your fuckin'
mug. Open your fuckin' mug.
Yeah.
Cocksucker.- All the way.
Open it up.
Lookee, lookee.
Chanchi. Chanchi.
You keep that mouth open, bitch.
All right, Shorty.
Yeah!
Go get him. Go on.
Open. Wider.
Keep your fuckin' mug open.
Yeah!
Science tells us there is
always a reason why...
a star forms or a body is ill.
And religion does the same.
This is the story of one
man's quest into darkness.
True or false?
Both.
There he is.
I'll tell you something.
My God!
Don't jump!
We'll talk. Wait.
Let's talk.
You think I'm scum.
You think I'm dirt, don't you?
Don't you?
Well...
I'll tell you something.
Every one of you down
there is exactly the same.
Only you’ll never know it.
You'll... You'll never know it...
'cause you'll never know what pride is!
'Cause pride is the only thing...
that lets you stand up to misery.
And not this kind of misery...
but the kind of misery the whole
stinking world is made of!
Nothing, Doctor.
He's gone. He's gone.
Doctor?
I can hear the angels...
farting on the ceiling.
We'll head him off at the north wall!
Load up and go stand at the north wall!
It's the North Tower.
Bolton! He just told us to shoot!
Fire on escapee. Fire!
Bolton!
Three days later,
Rass took Bolton with him on an
attempted escape from Fontenal.
Rass made it as far as Orleans.
Bolton was shot by a prison guard.
After Fred heard about everything...
Leave me alone! Will you stop?
He bought this gun. I told you!
I told you!
And he came home one day and he just
started going totally crazy with it.
You tell me who else knows.
Richie. Richie, go away.
Just go in your room. No! Leave it.
Go on. Get outta here. Just go...
Don't hit him. You shut the fuck up!
You know, he's swinging it all over the
place and he's showing it to Richie.
So when he fell asleep on the couch later,
I put the gun away in the drawer.
But sometime in the middle of the night,
he got up and he just started in again.
He was smacking me around
and screaming his head off,
and, of course, it woke up Richie.
I wanna know! But Fred
was like some crazy man.
He just kept coming at me and coming at me,
and he just throws the lamp at me,
which knocked me down.
How many times did you fuck him in my bed?
Fuck him in my bed?
Listen! Listen!
Bring some fucking spic in my bed?
Tell me! Tell me.
How many people know?
What do you want from me?
I just wanna know the goddamn truth!
I just remember him coming
at me around the throat...
and me trying to hold his arms
down, but he was like steel,
and I just thought, "This is it."
And then, all of a sudden,
I hear this explosion.
It was like a bomb.
And then another.
And then Fred just collapses on top of me.
I look up, and Richie's
standing there with the gun.
I think he looked at me...
and then sort of took
off toward the window.
I was pulling Fred off of me...
when I saw him standing on the ledge.
And I screamed. I thought
he was gonna jump.
And then, all of a sudden, he did.
He just jumped off the ledge and went up...
like a wind or something had come and
taken him 'cause he was so light,
but it wasn't the wind.
He just took off.
It was so weird.
When I ran and watched him go up,
he just flew up.
And I called to him,
and he sort of tilted my way...
before he kind of rolled out of sight.
My little boy.