Subtitles - English by  srjanapala
(as spoken in English Audio)
Your power to tell the future
is the question..
Answer you already know.
Why, I called you here
So, tell me Prophet!
In this... we have any
any reason to fear
The skills my Lord Conquer
on the battle field
are exceeding those of any other
opponents in the world, now.
Your mastery of Martial Arts
promises a clear victory
and no Name in the south nor...
Sword Saint in the north
Your studies are just like
my Jester, over there
Oh Master! I didn't tell him
what to say
If he is correct,
if we fight with Sword Saint
and we defeat it
it is possible to match with...
and rule the world.
I have to tell you,
there may be complications here.
I think, you may have to wait
almost for ten years...
to fight with Sword Saint.
Why do you say that?
I sense the time is all wrong
My Lord, I have a gift for you
What is it?
A prophesy!
"When the Wind and Cloud combine,
the Fish with Golden Scales
becomes a Dragon"
I give you
these two birth charts
they are for the two disciples
your attention is required
One is named Wind
and the other one is named Cloud
Why, Wind and Cloud?
The wind is a beam without
form, light and frame
The cloud is forming motion
constantly changing
Cloud...unpredictable.
These three is for me the essence of 108...
the circumstances, how you will find them?
that depends entirely on your fate
What is the Curse,
when I locate them?
It is written that
You will be invincible
for the first half of your life
The second half!
What about that?
You must deal with
Wind and Cloud first half.
Jester!
Yes, my Lord!
What do you desire?
Use Heaven and Earth,
You must...
I must find Wind and Cloud
Right!
Be hold! My Lord!
This is a great treasure from Persia.
it is very old order packed
called, the Ying Yang Magic Box
and on the box, there are 108 Celestial Stems
and Terrestrial Branches
My Lord is so intelligent,
He will master...
if you can identify
the correct combination of elements
and arrange them in proper order
the box will open
and it will reveal its secrets to us.
That My Lord!
then I can interpret
the direction of
the second half of your life;
Once this is done
I will be able to give you
more complete explanation
of your destiny.
A warning before you begin
... You must not attempt to use
force to open this box
If you do...
results, disappear.
The box could explode
on your face
Your hands will be lost
Good!
I should have no difficulty
in opening this box
Get Back!
Out of my way!
"By order of Lord Conquer...
... any children who match with the
birth charts we have just posted
must come this side
of the Clan immediately"
Father!
Wind!
... of any help to you
No! Hurry!
Father!
Over the last three years
we have been growing
and gaining prominence
We become a
powerful Clad in the world.
Further to strengthen us
today I am naming my heirs.
Therefore, I accept
my closest disciple
Frost! Cloud!
and Wind
With the Wind blows, the Cloud forms
and the Frost serving our force.
We will be an invincible force.
"Unable to meet in battle
Duel to death in ten years. Sword Saint"
Exactly, as predicted.
Mud Buddha!
You are a true prophet.
Why you are not attacking
with the full force?
Young Master's body is
invaluable or not?
You fool!
If I cannot handle your attacks,
then I deserve to die
Master Cloud!
His Lordship wants to see you.
you and Master Wind.
Collect the cultured stones
and bring them to Charity.
Yes, Master!
This is the place
Charity, we are not allowed
to every where
Its forbidden.
Frost!..to outsiders, Yes
but to the daughter of Conqueror
one should not create...
It is the Sword Grave,
we will keep our weapons
It may not be forbidden,
but, it is pretty dangerous
That's why my reason
having you alone
I'll go in myself, cowards
You go with Wind!
I will keep watch for you.
You, sweet heart Frost!
Let's go
Any trouble
Look! Magic fire!
These are just fire flies
and nothing more.
I want to catch up here
Guards! Someone's coming.
Come on! Let's go
What you see here
is the prophesy given by Mud Buddha.
As soon as I am able to retrieve
the final words from the Magic Box
I would be able to determine
what fate holds for the second half of my life.
But, unfortunately, for me
the retrieval process
is taking longer than I thought it would
For the past ten years
I have been unable to discover
the right combination and
for that sake Theorian Mud Buddha
has completely disappeared
Frost! Wind!
I have been patient for these many tears
but, I can wait no longer
I want to go out
find Mud Buddha for me
and bring him back here
His choice is simple
Now, if you want to find Mud Buddha,
one must first seek the Fire Monkey"
It should help in your search
Aren't you coming with us to help
No, I am only a..action
Once I step outside these gates
I'll be doomed.
I am Very fragile, you know!
I am quite delicate,
I can't take any kind of hardships
Jester!
My Lord!
Wind, your martial arts
techniques are good.
But you lack
battle experience.
So, I am putting
Frost in charge of this trip
I want you to obey him.
As you wish..
and Cloud!
I have an important
mission for you
At your service.
Lord Fong in Unchallenged City says
his wish to become our ally
I agreed on condition
that is, his Unchallenged Sword
is to be handed over to prove he is sincere
I want you to meet Lord Fong
on his birthday
I would come back
with the Sword, Master!
I want more than that...
I want you bring
Lord Fong's head back with you
You do this for me.
I will.
Hawk and Bat go along
to support you
Your skill is already at 7o%
You will succeed
with their help
Wait, Father, I would like
to go as well
What’s come over you, Charity?
You want to be Viol?
me. No, It has nothing on me, Father.
Alright!
Well, whom do you go
with Wind or Cloud?
You are going to kill,
I can't help
Wind, I'll go with you
We're not going
to the place of game
I know that,
We can help out the weak
I know that
we...
.. you are mistaken...
Jester, let them be out.
It’s all settled, then.
You will leave tomorrow.
We obey.
Charity, stay with me
for a moment
Yes sir!
Cloud!
Have you been to the forbidden
cave with Charity?
Yes, please don't tell the Master.
... Better to leave, these soldiers
have spoiled our fight.
Surround him!
I don't want to harm you
I respect your position
as a monk
Give me the Fire Monkey!
That’s not possible
The Fire Monkey belongs to Shaolin Temple
It was stolen
I am returning it.
You refused
Penalty is be taken
I am Whispering Wind
Sorry to intrude you
Aah, They are going to have a fight
We, then leave
Wait old man!
Hope, you are in such a hurry to go
Who knows?
We have to find out there
It will be dangerous to stay here
Who dares in
my business?
I am introducing
I thought you surely would recognize
the Master Wind and Master Frost
the Masters of Conquer's Clan...
He refused to give The Fiery
The Monk is right!
We are still one family
Why fight each other?
Help us in our mission, cousins!
Don't be presumptuous?
You seem to be lacking an honour
Look at this, You sent your battalion
to fight one man
You mean,
we don't have to fight...
He is right,
we should not have a fight.
I use to have my powers...
... Buddha!
Your Holiness, this is my first quest
Lend me the Fire Monkey
I swear I will return it
I will be back to you within one month
I said it belongs to
the Shaolin Temple...
If you steal it,
you will be the same as these people
Without Fire Monkey,
we won't find Mud Buddha
I would fail My Lord.
Sorry, I can't help you.
You have no respect for me at all!
You are right!
Shut up!
Oh Monk! Get us ahead
We need that Fire Monkey
It’s not my integere.
Sorry Holiness!...
Insult me as you want
Now that I have Fire Monkey. Hah!
Wind!
Forget him
Why?
We only needed it
to find Mud Buddha
Since..., he already is here
we don't need that
Fire Monkey.
We can drop disguise now.
How did you recognise me, Frost!
You have got a reputation as one,
you can change your appearance
I saw her telling
why you were in the midst of heavy fighting
Now, that was my clue...
and when the innocent girl
cried out, so that
she was worried about the monkey,
Convince me.
Grand Father, where are
the soldiers are taking Fiery?
Don't worry, they are not to hurt him
I promise!
I revealed too many secrets
about the future
and I was punished for it.
I have the boils all over my body now.
Only this animal, Fire Monkey
can suck out the poison
and can ease my pain
I beg you, Masters
Please bring it back to me
I will promise you
We both do our best
That's a great comfort.
I am ready to go
Your Master must be anxious to see me
Up to you!
Who is that?
Forgive my intrusion.
Oh! You must have been sent
by Lord Conquer, Correct?
He asked me to bring
the proof of your...
Please don't kill me!
How did this happen?
Father!
What good is Mud Buddha?
What good are you?
Fire Monkey is innocent. Don't punish it
Please
Your Holiness, please
I beg for your guidance..
Help me to bring the murderer
and justice
All this happened in a single night
It’s obvious
Only Conquer can do this
Ah,...Buddha!
Wind!
What is in your mind?
Here is the cave.
My father died there
Master rescued me
According to myth...
The Cave is
with Blood Bodhi fruits
They heal the people
and increase the powers
No one has ever been
able to go in there...
and come out alive.
They say a Fire Beast guards the fruit
Master Wind!
do you know much about
your father?
Are you knowing that too?
Ofcourse!
Southern Unicorn as well
Authorities killed them.
I request
a favour from you
This little girl
according to Pigtails
she lost her parents
I'm the only family
she has now
and we must find someone
to take her in.
Do you expecting
something bad?
What happened to you?
When Mud Buddha travels
across the river,
he is in great peril.
Grandpa! come back,
Grandpa!
"The Dragon is powerful
but will be stranded
when Wind and Cloud become a storm"
Buddha, you have disappeared
you left me with this piece of junk
Now that the puzzle is revealed
... promise you made
at that time
Tell me, What the prophesy means?
"Wind and Cloud will make you,
and break you as well"
That means, terrible.
You can't escape your fate.
My Lord's ten years of good fortune
has passed
you reached the turning
point of your life
your destiny,
future will tell us.
"Wind and Cloud will make me,
and break me"
Obviously, it means that my life is now
controlled by wind and cloud
But does any wind and cloud...
or is it Striding Cloud
and Whispering Wind?
My Lord! It is written
The Master will be crushed by slaves.
This is destiny. Mortals cannot fight it
Destiny?
Don't talk to me about destiny
I don't believe in destiny or fate
When destiny favored him
My Lord accepted it
Suddenly, he doesn't believe in...My Lord
Someone has to say
if... wants to escape,..God now
even you,
Lord Conquer!
We set our own fate!
I will force my destiny
straight at my will
and when I want
I will change my fate!
Four famous weapons
of the martial arts world...
One blade. Three swords
All priceless
But one blade
the most precious of all
is buried in Cirrus Cave.
The Ultimate Sword, which
has never been found
Fire Unicorn Sword
and the Unchallenged Sword
these are both mine.
And I am pleased
These stand as testimonials
to my power.
Cloud, you didn't disappoint me
You taught me well
That's Good!
Father!
Charity!
You behave yourself modest
Sorry!
Someone said Cloud is here.
I wanted to come
and welcome back.
I appreciate!
It wasn't just for you?
I want to see whether
you are going to honour your word
Well,
Did you bring them?
Charity!
What is it Cloud owes you?
Father,
your passion is to collect famous swords
well, I am collecting
on my passionate colorful stones
Master Cloud owes me 19
for my collection
..stupid!
My Lord! My Lord!
Masters Frost and Wind have returned
from mission
Where are they? Jester!
Outside, but they are
too afraid to come in
Get up!
Don't be ashamed.
You lost Mud Buddha due to inexperience
You did your best
Thank you,
Thank you, My Lord!
But your brother
Cloud succeeded in his mission
He was able to
bring back the Unchallenged Sword
I'm going back to my chambers
Cloud's mood is
like a wild horse...unpredictable
It's been ten years,
with Fong's death...
I'll soon hear from Sword Saint
He wanted our intervention
over killing his brother
I must finish for..
long away this duel
I have to increase
my Trinity Strength
But, first
Come
Before I go into seclusion,
I fear
I must settle something
You Wind among my three disciples,
are purest
and so, it is my wish
you marry Charity.
I will arrange for a suitable date
Charity, I take it you do like Wind?
Don't you?
I couldn't say
See to her
Can we talk about
this marriage later?
No,
Your father and I promised
to each other one
both just.. have more children
I didn't tell you earlier
because it wasn't the right time
I want You and Charity
grow up together
I have never seen
who perfectly suit each other
I think you make a wonderful couple
and should you do not consent
I will be disappointed
Congratulations, Wind
Skinny, Girlie, I have a problem...
I am really thorned
That..
I do like Wind...
and I also like Cloud
Charity, it's Wind
Are you busy?
Hi!
I think we should talk
Come in
This is not Sword Grave
You won't be punished
It won't take long
Talk
I felt very scared
when your father brought me here,
you gave me a cup of tea
You helped me feel
I had a home here
Father told me he hadn't rescued you,
you would've snatched by wolves
He was right!
Anyway, when he mentioned
marriage today,
I was very happy
But I must realize love must
come from both sides
I don't know whether
merely it is your father's idea
I hope, it was you want?
But if this is not,
I won't force you
she approved the marriage?
That’s in-consequential question?
As a father, I make the decision
She has to accept it
You are angry?
The expression in your eyes is the same as
when I took you in ten years ago
If you're unhappy about this
you may be excused from attending
the wedding banquet
I am Doctor Yu from Lake region
I want to present
sixteen towns
I want to give it to master.
Your invitation?...
Oh! you mean
some kind of celebration
How is this? wonderful, What a function exiting!
I have never been to a banquet!
Can you tell me
it’s a baby or a marriage celebration
Yah,Look at the crowd!
I think here one more
or one less wouldn't even matter
... please, let us go inside.
... over there..
Master Jester, I am Doctor Yu
Oh! Mr. White Face, How much time
wait outside somebody to get inside?
What a Smell!.
It stinks!
It’s a women's scent.
Ah! woman, actually we gathered
some herbs. That’s is the smell
Why?... You mean, you are
Doctor Yu with the Fire Beast Arm?
Give us
He also mean you...
Thank you for your visit
We will hand it over to Lord Conquer
Come with me
we'll talk after the banquet
Father!
Conquer, you bastard!
We have come to avenge your people.
Hold! Ming!
You think, you can't wait and fight against us
You must be...
something
Your people murdered my Clan
and stole Unchallenged Sword
we are not going
without any punishment
We want Unchallenged Sword
be given back
Hold!
What brings you here.
Monks should be charitable and kind
So I promised this Young Master...
and helps out to find
the murder of his family
I hope you will resist us,
in the name of Buddha
For those, who doubt now
... Today is my daughter's wedding
It will be a happy occasion
I don't want any conflict interrupted
The Shaolin Priests are
the best known
but, there are many other Clans
we are the largest of them
Simply put by virtue of size and strength
choose...is obvious
Align with us and prosper
Or oppose us and die!
Buddha have pity
You clearly outlined your position
Ming must now decide
what to do?
How do you wish
to proceed in this matter?
My Martial Arts skills
are too weak,
Wirlspring Wind can beat me
So, I have no way to defend my honour
I give up, my uncle
Sword Saint send you this..
Ten years has already passed
There is no reason
but to fight
"We will battle
on the autumn solstice"
Well, I have waited for
this time to happen
Everything's fine now!
Thing is the celebration
Hold the wine,
we have A Toast and Bride, Yes!
Now Wind, You have to promise,
to treat Charity well
Do I have you a word?
Absolutely My Lord!
Let's bow to the ancestors.
Hold it!
What are you doing?
Cloud!
Come!
How dare you
to do such a thing?
You would never go
This is my...!
I thought you are never coming!
Why did you agree to marry him?
You never asked why
I cannot bear another man touch you!
I can marry him
and see you
Charity!
Over here!
I obeyed you for 10 years now
I'm leaving here
with Charity
If you're a man,
you fight for your wife
You cannot afford to have
the world laugh at you, Coward!
Defend for your reputation!
Wind!
Master! Shut up!
Father!
Look out!
Charity!
She is already my woman. Go away!
Is it fine? Tell me.
I'm sorry, Wind
Why you married me then?
Did you love me ever?
Yes
Don’t worry, you are mine.
It makes no difference!
We will be together, forever.
Nothing will come
in between us.
Charity, I love you!
I am always...
Master!
I killed my own daughter...
Striding Cloud, return Charity's body
No one can take her away
You are not that strong
I never completed your lessons
the craft of Cloud Palms
Prepare!
You will get a demonstration
you can die in peace.
Your Cloud Palms will not work
here in the desert
Yours...to be effected
However Clock, I am also
the Master of other techniques.
Now, let us see
how much blood you have
I will be back...
Father, Come on
Someone wounded badly
yeh!
It's Striding Cloud who stole the bride!
What!
Striding Cloud...
Striding Cloud!
Cloud!
Its lunch time.
You missed her a lot, Right?
I have to tell you
when I saw your lover
that wearing beautiful Bridal Gown
she was...
watching and watching
and I am in pride of that
I am envious of the woman
Have you got news?
I am amused easily
Don't be silly!
I was just blessed by a Muse
on the day I was born
so,...me that if you..
Thank you,
for rescuing me that day.
Come and sit on it.
You are planning
to go back to the Clan?
I have to go back
for revenge
.. secrets...so on
In this world some men
have no friends and no lover and aligns
I am such a person!
Master Wind!
Have some water.
Thanks!
... all over the place
This must be
Blood Bodhi fruit!
His Lordship says...
just one increases powers
Go away!
Go Away!
Come on here!
Fire Beast!
Master Wind!
Come out!
House him.
He is dangerous.
Sir, Please don’t blame us.
It’s the same who killed, all 296 people
at Unchallenged City completely
and tact works out very quickly
your flesh and bones
both bright
Why did you do it?
We must obey
Our Master ordered it.
It doesn't make sense.
Lord Conquer said
bring back your head
and the fruits
we'll be rewarded
I'll give you back the fruit
Then it may be even. Right?
"With a heart as clear as ice,
the sky may fall and I will not fear"
But Horns clear as ice!
Who is it?
It's me, Jester
Congratulations my Lord,
You have increased straight 100% powers!
You now can dominate the World
What you are saying?
I am saying Sword Saint,
such fool challenged you my Lord
You have gained Powers
Oh yes! He is there
Oh! You are bound to be...
What you are telling me?
You're fulfilling destiny
Destiny, you say
You are a complete idiot, you don't know
what you are talking about
you are right, Master.
I am a complete idiot
But every word comes
from my heart
Get out!
Yes Sir!
You are the only one
I trust
Wind and Cloud have disappeared
without a word
and tomorrow
I must go into battle
So, Frost!
you must take out...
and help me
to rule the world
I hope that, I am
not capable sir!
I have full confidence in you
You, are ready.
My life's goal to
beat Sword Saint
You will become leader
of the Clan when I do
Congratulations!
Thank you, Master
Knowing that battle is imminent
We can't afford mistakes...
to preserve our interests...
Any one disloyal to me
has to die
Jester has betrayed the Clan
kill him at once.
Jester, been around here?
No, no
I haven't see him, Sorry.
Wait a minute!
Don't kill me, please
Master Frost!
Don't believe
what Lord is saying
He is using tricks on us all
You are a liar.
You betrayed Master.
Now you must die!
No, He murdered
the parents of Wind and Cloud
Look, believe me
I can prove it.
I will take you to Mud Buddha,
Lord Conquer has...
Take me to him.
..uniform?
Use your..down
I have to hurry
Can you wait here?
Master Frost...
So the man who kidnapped
was Lord Conquer
I must fight. I must command
I must command!
I won't die here
I want...
You need to know the truth
Master Wind!
Lord Conquer killed your parents
I purposely gave him
birth charts of you and Cloud
so he would let you live
Destiny...Young Master
All things go in cycles
Cause, in fact...
Everyone faces judgment.
What can I do?
"The Dragon is powerful,
but it will be stranded
when wind and cloud become a storm"
Sword Saint has come for the duel
Well, I waited many years for this
Although I now dominate the world
Thanks to my extra ordinary
Martial Arts Skills
now having defeated you
I comfort my throat
I want
comfort...mood
I am aware your danger strength
that keeps fair and fine
If I can't defeat you at the
waiting today's battle
I know that I can
die as a peaceful man
Peace will come from
my Challenge Sword
Once I use...You Saint Sword
and your family are defeated in the battle
Only I will...
Wait here.
Is he human? Why is he not moving?
No!
You wait here, I am going in.
Uncle! Uncle!
Don't go, I don't care!
I must fight
He has come to know...
Help me,.. revenge
Wind and Cloud must be together
Or it won't be a storm
Cloud!
Blood Bodhi can increase
your powers
It’s over Frost,
You may announce to the world,
I have defeated my ultimate opponent
and I am now truly invincible
You killed the disciple's parents
You ordered you men
Hawk and Bat to kill Wind,
right?
Admit it
So apparently
you didn't kill Jester, I ordered?
You bastard
you are murderer!
I was right
about you
Of the three, you are most naive
You never made me your heir
You're...that’s all
It’s the way in the world
The King manipulates the power
Frost!
You must be my den
To be in yours is quite foolish
Align now once more.
Where do you think
you are going?
I'm leaving your Clan
You think that easy
No one leaves my Clan
unless I give permission to go
Frost
So two of you
are still alive
Some of you
disobeyed my order
Now the real question is
why you have come back here
Sword Saint is dead
I will... you, bastard
I will avenge my Family
Well, I took you in
I knew this day has to come and
I have planned for it.
Master Wind
Take hint.
You have great power
You must not use it at all
It ends soon
to Conquer to be killed.
I taught you all the martial arts
as one of you ever knew
Don't think I did leave few moves out
Cloud is unpredictable, Wind is formless
You two definitely aware it
you can't assault me
...fight here
Since this will now be... inside
Prepare to die!
I taught you Fists, Palms and Kicks,
but I never told that
my greatest skill is in the sword!
Which I neglected to teach you
"The Dragon is powerful,
but will be stranded
when wind and cloud become a storm"
Well Mud Buddha,
I don't believe in your prophesy
the truth is
I only believe in myself
you.. cannot use the sword
It might be true.
But you also require my boy's blood..
Wait
Dead razors
I will...I am.
.. end to soul
... to challenge the...
Conquer to be killed
..I am the Conquer of the world!
... I am the Conquer of the world!
Subtitles by
srjanapala