Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
This drama is set during the Joseon Era
under the rule of a fictitious king.
All characters and events are fictitious
and have no historic basis.
Episode 9
Who are you?
Who are you to dare to be here?
Tell me!
Who the hell are you?
Bring in the candles!
What are you doing? Bring in the candles
and light up this room immediately!
You...
Why are you here?
No way...
Nothing happened, right?
Hey, Jan Sil.
Don't you feel anything?
Darkness is approaching.
What darkness is approaching?
What do you mean by that?
- What are you saying?
- Gosh.
You're blocking the light so it's dark.
Aish, seriously!
Whose orders are you following?
That night,
our meeting at Oh Nyang,
was it something you planned
because of someone's orders?
What did that person order you to do?
Did he tell you to seduce me?
If not, then did he tell you
to strangle me with these hands?
If that's also not it, did he tell you to
stab me with a knife so no one will know?
Tell me!
Whose orders are you taking as a spy?!
A spy you say?
I am not one.
I am just a human talisman.
Human talisman?
Your Majesty.
Please repress your anger.
This girl
is a Seongsucheong shaman
and brought here to protect your health.
She is not a spy.
Only a shaman. Not a spy?
That's right.
Just regard her as a talisman
and not human.
Then,
you're not even a human,
but you dare place a hand on my body?
Tell me!
The fact that these hands
will not strangle me,
who can guarantee that?!
Yo, Your... Your Majesty!
For placing my hands on your body,
I deserve a thousand deaths.
However, please give me a chance
to explain myself.
Explain?
Try then.
Generally, even though
the seasons are changing,
one must rest a bit in order for the ground
to be covered and flowers to bloom.
And so, a king who has to carry
the burden of the nation on his shoulders,
what more do I need to say?
You read the Classics,
so your excuses are great.
Your Majesty's body is the base
of this country's reign of peace.
With a weak body, how will you deal
with the citizens' problems?
So all I wanted to do was,
during the time
that Your Majesty was asleep,
to help you put down the
weariness of government affairs
and the pain in your heart,
and rest peacefully...
Did you just say the pain in my heart?
- What?
- You said you're a shaman,
so in your eyes, you're able to see
everything about a person, right?
Is that why you dare place
your hand on my body?
In order to read my heart?
I'm sorry,
but while you were asleep,
you called out a girl's name.
It carried the weight of all your pain.
And because I wanted to console you,
I dared to violate the law of
not touching the royal body.
No.
This girl is not Yeon Woo.
If she was, she wouldn't pretend to know me
even after hearing her own name.
It's a misunderstanding.
It's an illusion.
Your Majesty.
I have to struggle free.
Take that girl...
out of the palace immediately.
- Your Majesty.
- What are you doing?
Did you not hear my order?!
Your Majesty...
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty!
How dare you!
You dare place your hand on the royal body.
Are you out of your mind?
Once you were discovered,
you should have waited quietly
for your punishment.
Who do you think you are
to talk back to him?!
Lock this girl up
in the secret cell immediately.
- Yes.
- Yes!
- Miss!
- Stop this.
This girl
is a shaman of Seongsucheong,
so I'm going to punish her
according to shaman laws.
For a girl who touched the royal body, how
can she be tried according to shaman laws?
What are you doing?
Lock her up!
Sir!
On her forehead, I am going to inscribe
"criminal" and send her away,
so without my permission, you cannot
give her even a drop of water.
Yes.
Open the door!
Mistress.
Mistress!
Open the door!
Open the door
Please, open the door!
Seol!
Your Majesty...
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty!
That's right.
Just regard her as a talisman
and not human.
Then you're not even a human,
but you dare put a hand on my body?
It seems like the professor
has caught the shaman, so let's go.
This matter cannot be known by others.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Let's go.
Wow!
It's been a long time.
Professor of Prophecy.
Don't be so nervous.
You don't think I'll eat you, right?
It is dangerous for the royal
to imitate the ministers,
don't you know that?
Of course, I know.
Why wouldn't I know that?
Was there ever a time when the
Office of Gwansanggam, Seongsucheong,
and Sogyeokseo tried to get credit
for someone else's work?
Ah!
That is what you're talking about, right?
I'm sorry but if you are aware of that,
what is the reason you have come here?
First of all,
take a look at this.
How is it?
It looks really painful, right?
Oh...
It does look painful but...
Aren't you going to ask how this happened?
How...
did you become like that?
Not too long ago, I was helping a shaman
who was being chased and got this wound.
In front of her,
I pretended to be cool,
but a few awful men came along
and messed everything up.
According to those unidentified assailants,
the Professor
had taken the shaman.
So,
I used my broken head a bit.
Professor, you say?
It can't be the professor of
medicine and nursing, doctor, or translator.
Then,
the Princess's etiquette professor,
is it?
I thought so but it's not.
The professor of fermentation from Hyung Joo
doesn't personally go out
and work on their own...
Then,
there is just one left.
The Office of Gwansanggam.
Among them,
it's the professor of prophecy.
That shaman,
where is she now?
How would I know about
the whereabouts of the shaman?
I received an order to tackle
the heresy and send out guards,
and brought in all the shamans and monks
inside the capital for investigation.
At that time, I was disguised as a monk.
Then,
why didn't you arrest me?
That is...
that girl committed a crime of
adultery and foulness,
so we were keen on arresting her.
After arresting her,
where did you imprison her?
Is it Yongsankang?
No, it's not.
She was filled with such evil that
we sent her far away to the south.
Then tell me her registered name!
She did not even register her name
and committed a promiscuous offense,
that is why we were arresting her.
Prince Yang Myung.
It seems like both of you are quite in a
hurry to get to the King's quarters.
By any chance, did something happen
to His Majesty The King?
Why do you ask that?
Are you hoping that
something does happen to the King?
- Queen Dowager...
- The Royal Concubine
is no longer in the palace.
The warning about entering the palace
from the previous King,
have you forgotten it already?
Why are you acting this way,
Queen Dowager?
He came because he was worried
about His Majesty.
Isn't that right?
Recently, I heard that
villainous people are gathering.
That...
has nothing to do with me.
Haven't you heard that
when there's smoke there's fire?
They're gathering because
they smell a foul odor from someone.
But, you need to keep something in mind.
As long as I am alive,
you will never be king.
Do you understand?
It will never happen.
Let's go, Queen.
Grandmother...
Your vigor isn't what it used to be,
so it makes me quite upset.
Just now,
what did you say?
The flies gathering in front of my house
are not because of a foul smell,
but isn't it because the King
doesn't have an heir to his throne?
For the King to be safe,
you will have to live until
you're 100 years old.
I am very worried,
because it seems like
I will live longer than you will.
While you're alive,
you must be filled with worries.
For your health and prosperity,
I will come visit you often
and act cute for you.
Then,
please remain healthy.
Are you feeling well?
As you can see, I am fine.
I am well.
That is a relief.
In the middle of the night,
your attendants were frantic,
so I thought your health had worsened again.
Nothing has happened.
Do not worry.
You must become stronger.
So that
the villainous supporters of
Prince Yang Myung becoming king
will not be able to rise and incite trouble.
Why are you acting like this, Queen Dowager?
They're just acting on their own,
so how could Prince Yang Myung have known?
Prince Yang Myung...
his presence alone
is plenty a threat to you.
You have to become stronger, Your Majesty.
You must produce an heir soon.
More importantly, you must distance
yourself from Prince Yang Myung.
That is the only way that you can
remain on the King's throne.
Do you understand?
Prince Yang Myung.
Mother.
What were you so sincerely praying for?
I always pray
for the safety of His Majesty The King.
I ask that Buddha brings you
a beautiful wife,
I pray for that, as well.
What is it?
Even without any adornment,
your hair is still as beautiful.
Even though I converted to Buddhism,
I am unable to forget about the past,
and I haven't been able
to shave my head, yet.
One day, when I can forget
about the past, I will...
Just...
keep your hair.
Who knows?
If His Majesty The King were to have
an unfortunate accident,
Mother will become Queen.
Prince Yang Myung.
How can you say such treacherous words?
Don't you know that His Majesty's safety
is also your safety?
How could I not know?
From the day I was born until today,
isn't that what you've been telling me?
Prince Yang Myung.
A tree tries to remain standing
but the wind never cease.
In the end,
the tree will bend and shake.
Please, don't bend
no matter what wind may come.
Don't waver.
That is the only way
for the King to be comfortable
and Prince Yang Myung will be safe.
Prince Yang Myung...
Mother,
do you believe in reincarnation?
I have emptied my heart.
I have no desire for power
or to reside in the palace.
I have no greed for any of those things.
I just...
want one person.
If another life does exist,
I wish to meet this person again.
I'm afraid that
she will not recognize me.
That again,
she will not choose me
but someone else.
We may have met already,
but I might lose her again.
That is my only concern.
Where do I have to go
to find you?
Woon...
Do you also believe
that Yang Myung hyung
is someone who would do that?
You know Brother very well,
so tell me.
Are you questioning his motives?
Is there any reason
why I should doubt him?
Since there are people
continually shaking him,
before he bends, I'm afraid that
he will break. I'm worried.
Isn't it funny?
The King's throne...
Even my brother who I share
the same blood with,
I must view him as an enemy.
Especially today,
this position is overwhelming.
During the time that
Your Majesty was asleep,
to help you put down the
weariness of government affairs
and the pain in your heart,
and rest peacefully...
- Woon
- Please give your order.
Seongsucheong's records,
check them.
What is it that you want to confirm?
Also check on the movements
on Minister Yoon's side.
Do you want me to confirm
that she's a spy?
Or is it that you want confirmation
that she isn't a spy?
Yeon Woo...
Yeon Woo.
Yeon Woo!
You mustn't, Yeon Woo!
Yeon Woo.
Yeon Woo...
Aigoo, my baby.
My precious baby!
You're alive?
You're alive.
It is cold, but why are you wearing
such thin clothes?
What are you going to do
if you catch a cold?
Didn't it hurt?
Wasn't it difficult?
Weren't you cold?
Weren't you scared?
Please say something.
Mother.
Yes.
Please...
take care of yourself.
Mother...
Are you going to leave Miss like that?
You're the High Shaman, aren't you?
They said
they're going to brand her face!
I'm going to charge in and break the...
Be quiet.
I'm gathering my thoughts.
Can you solve anything
just by thinking?
My Miss,
thanks to someone,
cannot breathe well in a small,
confined dark space.
It would be better to go to the King
and tell him the truth.
The Shaman Wol that His Majesty is
trying to kill is actually Heo Yeon Woo.
Shut that mouth of yours!
Just one more time,
if you dare to say such nonsense again,
I will tear open your mouth.
I'm trying to find a solution, so stop
disturbing my concentration and get out now!
Brother,
it's Yeon Woo.
I see it's time for us
to read already.
Let's see. What book did we say
we were going to read today?
Your face has worry written all over it.
Mother.
You were fine for a while,
so why are you acting like this again?
Yeon Woo...
Our Yeon Woo,
came to see me.
Mother...
It seemed like...
she had something to say.
She wanted...
She wanted to say something to me.
That sweet child...
because she didn't want
to hurt her mother's heart,
she just cried
and left.
That poor child.
Aigoo, my baby.
Ow!
What is wrong?
Did you prick your finger
with the needle again?
Something feels ominous.
It's not the first time
you pricked your finger,
so what feels ominous?
If I said it's ominous,
then it is!
Look at this.
The embroidery that I'm stitching onto
his official clothes is stained with blood.
So, didn't I tell you
to go to sleep tonight,
and continue tomorrow
when you're awake?
Wha... what's wrong?
I'm going to ask Mother to teach me.
Princess, it's already past 10pm!
Princess!
Princess.
Prince Consort.
Husband!
Mother!
What happened to Mother, Husband?
I'm bringing her back
from our old home.
You haven't been there for a long time...
why did you suddenly go back
to the old house?
I'm sorry, but
please take care of Mother.
Housekeeper Park!
Bring the key to the old house.
Yes, sir.
That child... why?
The dead child...
why is she in my dreams?
I'm sorry,
but while you were asleep,
you called out a girl's name.
It carried the weight of all your pain.
And because I wanted to console you,
I dared to violate the law of not touching
the royal body.
- You're from the palace kitchen?
- That is correct.
This morning, you served me
the same stew again.
That is correct.
Then, do you want me to keep eating
the same stew until I die?
If you serve me stew again,
I will chase you out of the palace.
Why is His Majesty cold again?
We can't ever
serve him stew again, right?
When he smiled, he was so much
more handsome than now.
- Yes.
"The stew was very delicious.
I ate it well".
He said that and smiled.
If I can see his smile just one more time...
Your Highness The Queen!
Your Highness, please kill us.
You girls!
Where do you belong?
Immediately, punish...
That's enough, Court Lady Jo.
His Majesty's complexion
has become brighter,
so what other news
is better than this?
I'm not going to keep it in my heart,
so you do not need to worry.
What did you just say, Queen?
It is shameful for me to say this,
but there are rumors
about His Majesty and me
circulating in the palace.
What rumors?
They say that His Majesty is ill
because of me...
and that his recent improvement
is because he is privately hiding a woman.
What do you mean that the King
is keeping a woman by his side?
You know better than anyone about that.
Aside from the rumors themselves,
if they were to spread
outside of the palace,
what will the citizens think of their king?
So please, grant me permission to go to
the King's quarters whenever I want to.
It is because I am unable
to stay by His Majesty's side
that rumors like these keep spreading.
But,
the Ministry of Astrology and Seongsucheong
say that it is best to keep you two apart
until you share the same room.
Then, as his rightful wife,
I have to continue to bear the disgrace?
Just wait a little longer, Queen.
Once you share a room,
the rumors
will disappear on their own.
But, there is no way of knowing when
His Majesty's body will become ill again.
That...
you do not have to worry about.
To tell you the truth, Queen Dowager has
placed High Shaman Jang's spiritual daughter
as a talisman in the King's palace.
Did you say a human talisman?
That's correct.
The reason His Majesty has improved
is also thanks to her skills,
so just have a little more faith and wait.
They say that the workers in the north
are freezing to death. Is that true?
The north has always been a cold place.
Then,
I suppose the thing I spoke about
last time, the winter...
Pi Han Dol
...plan was not even set up, right?
Since it's always cold in the north, are you saying
that the citizens should just freeze to death?
Send relief so the citizens
can counter the cold immediately.
Yes, Your Majesty!
Oh, I left something out.
Pi...
I was right.
It is Pi Han Dol
Pi...
Please write up a report
about the damages and submit it.
In addition, at the last meeting,
the issue that was brought up
about the Ministers and bribery,
I heard that you did not execute
the order to return the bribes.
There wasn't a lot of items,
so is there a need to go through
the trouble of returning them?
However, those bribes were squeezed
from the citizens.
They did not give them freely.
What do you think, Minister Yoon?
Your Majesty is correct,
but it wasn't that much.
The citizens cannot even eat
porridge made from blood,
but you squeezed their sweat
and blood from them,
so you must return in full.
The fancy clothes
that you received as bribes,
send them back immediately!
We will end the meeting like this.
Oh, right. Royal Court,
there is something I want to ask you.
Please ask the court.
Is the construction
of Boryeong Palace going well?
If you are that worried about it,
what about going to the site yourself
and look around?
Oh, that's a really good idea.
But you know,
I may be a little late.
That's what I end up thinking.
That was just like him playing with us.
Pi, Pi, Pi! Throwing out that syllable
as though he was going to say his name.
He messed around with us.
It definitely seems like
he knows something.
But I don't know why we aren't getting
a response out of him.
Well, it seems like he is planning
on slowly killing us with words.
About the Boryeong Palace construction,
even if he were to investigate,
he knows he is too late.
Hence, are you saying he has given up?
Rather than giving up,
he is probably waiting for an opportunity.
Opportunity?
What opportunity?
Instead of acting like you know something
and posing all the time,
can't you just tell us
all at once?!
Opportunity?
What opportunity are you referring to?
It is probably the opportunity
to remove the problem from its roots.
The Queen requests your presence.
What did you just say?
Did you say that High Shaman Jang
has returned to Seongsucheong?
Yes.
She is using her spiritual daughter
as a talisman to ward off evil spirits.
It definitely must be
the Queen Dowager's order.
So Father, on my behalf, go to
the Queen Dowager and make a request.
A request?
Even though she is a lowly shaman,
ultimately, she is a woman.
I cannot let her stay by His Majesty's side
and watch over him.
Then,
the shaman that was sent
to His Majesty's side has to be removed.
Is that the request I am to make?
However,
there are the disturbing dreams
I've been having for the past few days.
There is also the improvement
in His Majesty's health.
It is making me uneasy.
As the Queen of the country,
are you jealous of a lowly shaman?
Even though His Majesty
keeps you far away,
do you think he'll turn
to a lowly shaman?
High Shaman Jang has returned.
That Jang Nok Young...
What brings you all the way here?
When I was in power,
you used to come see me every day,
but it's getting harder to see you
as the days go by.
I apologize, Your Highness.
The Minister position is not that easy.
I know that well.
Think about how
you came to that position.
Who helped you get
into that high position?
You dare show off in front of me?
A toothless tiger still thinks
she is the owner of the forest.
For you to come here,
Minister Yoon,
what did you want to discuss
with an old woman?
I heard that you put back High Shaman Jang
to her position in Seongsucheong.
- And so?
- Seongsuchong already
has Shaman Kwon.
She was a temporary one.
Her abilities cannot compare
to those of Shaman Jang.
However, Shaman Jang,
wasn't she deeply involved
in the incident 8 years ago?
If she were to say something...
Shaman Kwon is also
deeply involved in
Prince Ui Seong's Mother's accident.
If we want to talk about dangerous,
the two are the same.
However...
that happened a long time ago.
Is 8 years a short time?
We need Shaman Jang's talent.
In all of Joseon, there is no other
who has her talent,
so how can I get rid of her?
Shaman Kwon...
has a lot of greed for power and authority,
so she is easier to control.
But Shaman Jang
is someone we do not know.
Those who are difficult to control
are dangerous.
The more dangerous she is,
the more I need to keep her by my side.
Your Highness...
What are you afraid of, Minister Yoon?
It is all in the past anyway.
More importantly,
the dead do not talk.
You will receive your punishment,
so drag her out!
- Yes!
Shaman Wol,
received an order to become a human talisman
and entered the King's chambers,
but she ignored her duties.
Instead, she committed a crime
of unfaithfulness to her duty.
Committing this crime is punishable
by His Majesty's law of the land.
Everyone present,
keep your eyes wide open
and witness this scene.
Start.
- Yes.
Are you positive that her name is
in the Seongsucheong's registry?
- I am.
- What about Minister Yoon?
It seems as if they do not know about
the shaman's existence.
Please revoke your royal order.
That girl is not a spy.
I, too, have sinned because I did nothing
when I saw the girl committing the crime...
You're taking the girl's side.
That's not like you.
I know.
The dangerous person is not her
but me.
What am I to do, Ari?
If I reveal the truth, she will live,
but she will die soon.
If I let this continue, even if she lives,
it won't be worth living.
What am I to do?
Please answer me, Ari!
Stop!
Stop.
This is a royal command.
Shaman Wol,
from this point forward, will return to
the King's chambers and finish her duties.
This is the royal command.
- Unni!
- Miss!
Miss, are you alright?
Did you say I've been bewitched?
You say that's why
I need to push her away.
I am bewitched.
However,
I cannot push her away.
Mistress...
For a little while,
I would like to go out.
In your state,
where do you plan on going?
Just for a while...
Just a little while will be enough.
There is something I must do.
Are you out of your mind?
After going through that,
you will again...
I know.
A shaman who serves His Majesty
cannot go out in public as she wishes,
and that I am just a lowly shaman.
A lowly shaman
cannot overstep her boundaries.
I know for sure
through this experience.
Even though I cannot do anything about
the hardships of being a shaman,
the misunderstandings I got
because I am a shaman,
I want to be sure to clear them up.
Please give me permission.
It is my first...
and my last request.
I was able to bring you out after all that,
but you do not want any ornaments
and refuse clothing material.
Mother,
you really do not want anything?
Yes. I don't.
So don't worry about me.
If there is anything that you need,
please tell me.
If you don't want anything,
then I don't, as well.
Oh!
I do have one.
The rice paper that Husband uses
is running low.
Since we are out, what do you think about
getting him the best quality one?
Since Princess is always considerate
and thinking of her husband,
I am thankful as a mother.
Mother.
You smiled just now, right?
You will stop being sad now, right?
Yes.
Because of me, you're trying so hard,
so I have to cheer up for you.
They say that if you smile,
luck comes to you.
So you must smile often, okay?
Yes, I will.
First, let's take a trip to the trinket store,
then go to the stationery store.
Yes, Mother.
Seeing that you're taking such care
in choosing the paper,
you must be writing a love letter.
It's not a love letter,
but a letter of apology.
It's not a letter,
Will you wait for me?
Wait for me?
Oh? Where are you going
in the middle of choosing?
I will be back in just a little while.
Many days have passed since then,
so there's no way he'd still be here.
Now that I think about it,
I wasn't able to thank him.
I'm sorry to have kept you waiting.
I came out for an errand and I dropped by
the clothing factory, just in case.
I really didn't expect you to be there.
I'm glad that I am able to thank you
after so long.
That day...
Thank you so much.
For not keeping my promise,
I am sorry.
There's no need to be thankful.
I wasn't able to save you anyway.
Did you get badly hurt?
Because I was raised tough,
this small injury is nothing.
But, how come you're not wearing
your monk clothing today?
What?
Oh! It seems like you have misunderstood.
I am not a monk. At that time,
I was in a desperate situation
that is why I changed my appearance.
You're really not a monk?
That's right.
I am still single,
and I can rival the heavens
and earth in freedom.
Of course,
I can register for marriage too.
The wound on your face,
how did you get it?
It seems like you have suffered a lot.
If you want to escape again,
tell me.
I will help you.
Although I am thankful for your words,
I am in a safe place now.
So, you don't have to worry...
If you want to run away from
these troubling circumstances,
if that's the case,
I can throw away my prince hood,
the title of Prince Yang Myung, all of it,
wrap you up in a parcel
and run away with you.
Are you, by any chance,
the King's brother?
That...
How did you know that?
It is my spiritual power.
Spiritual power?
Yes.
Just now,
I saw some of your past.
So it is just your power?
Although it may not be enough
to repay you,
as a shaman,
may I give you an advice?
Go ahead and give it.
Now,
let go of the woman
you have in your heart.
For a new relationship,
empty that place in your heart.
Please do not...
try to smile
to cover up your real feelings.
Deceiving yourself and living like that
is an awful way of living,
isn't it?
Your name...
can I ask for your name?
I'm sorry, but I have no...
I will call you Wol.
Wol...
I am Wol.
Wol?
Oh,
I must return now.
I am very grateful
for your help that day.
Assuredly, I will pray for you
to meet your soul mate.
Then, goodbye.
Wai... wait!
- Mother, are you okay?
- I am sorry.
- I was in a hurry, so I wasn't careful.
- I'm okay, so you may go.
Thank you.
How can a woman be so clumsy?
Don't you agree, Mother?
- Yang Myung Brother!
- Prince Yang Myung!
What brings the two of you here?
How are you feeling?
You disappeared suddenly,
so everyone was very worried.
But Mother, I'm a bit busy.
I will go and visit later.
Do you have a lover now,
Brother?
Yes, she is.
Are you satisfied now?
Looks like she went that way,
so hurry after her.
It must be true, Mother!
I should have looked more closely
to see what kind of maiden she was.
Is she around the age of my Yeon Woo?
That, you do not have to worry about.
To tell you the truth,
Queen Dowager has placed
High Shaman Jang's spiritual daughter
as a talisman in the King's palace.
Your Highness,
why are you acting this again?
Get out of my way.
If you block me again,
I will bite my tongue and die.
Were you surprised?
I did not drink the tea
that the physician made.
I will continue to do so
from now on.
So you will have to be responsible
for what you have said.
Didn't you tell me to forget the weariness
of government affairs while I'm asleep?
That is correct.
Didn't you tell me to forget about
the pain in my heart?
That is correct.
I am extremely exhausted right now.
Moreover, the pain in my heart
that I can't bear
is completely occupying it.
Therefore, you
need to help me forget about all of it.
This pain in my heart,
you have to put it to rest.
Do you think you can do it?
Answer me.
Please allow me to do so.
If Your Majesty permits,
the misfortune and death that threaten you,
I will prevent them from harming you.
The problems and worries
that distress your sincerity,
I will help you solve them.
Although I am lacking,
I am the human talisman who has the duty
to protect Your Majesty's royal body.
From the beginning,
one month's time was decided on.
So during that time,
I will fulfill my duty.
Your Highness The Queen,
I will inform His Majesty
that you are here,
so please wait a moment.
- Open the door.
- Th... that...
cannot be done.
Your head,
lift it up.
Lift it.
That is an order.
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Main Translator: ahsieee
Spot Translator: meju
Timer: asianhottie
Editor/QC: PTTaT
Coordinators: ay_link, mily2
It wasn't enough to be afraid
of a dead girl,
now I am uneasy
because of a lowly shaman!
There is no way I am not the owner
of those memories, right?
I can't be that person, right?
The person that you are looking for,
I will help you meet her.
I keep seeing weird memories.
Those memories are confusing me.
Who exactly am I?
Watch dramas legally at
dramafever.com | crunchyroll.com