Spain, 1944
The civil war has ended.
Hidden in the mountains,
armed groups continue fighting
the new fascist regime,
which struggles to put them down.
They say that a long, long time ago,
in the Underground Realm –
where neither deceit nor sorrow exists –
lived a Princess who
dreamt of the human world.
She dreamt of the blue sky,
soft breeze, and shining sun.
One day...
eluding all oversight,
the Princess ran away.
Once on the surface,
the light of the sun blinded her
and erased from her memory
any trace of the past.
The Princess forgot who she was...
where she came from...
her body suffered cold,
sickness, and pain,
and with the passing
of the years... she died.
Nevertheless, her father, the King,
knew that the soul
of the Princess would return...
perhaps in another body,
at another time and in another place.
And he would wait for her
until his dying breath...
until the world ceased to turn.
I don’t understand why you’ve
brought so many books, Ofelia,
if we’re going to the
countryside, outdoors.
Fairy tales.
You’re too old to be filling
your head with such trifles.
Tell him to stop the car, please.
Ofelia... Ofelia, give me a moment.
Your brother’s not feeling very well.
Madam, are you alright?
Madam, do you need anything?
It’s nothing. Just give me some water.
Water! Water for the Captain’s wife!
Let’s go, let’s go!
Ofelia.
Ofelia?
Come.
– I’ve seen a fairy.
– But look what you’ve done to your shoes!
Let’s go.
When we arrive at the mill,
I want you to greet the Captain,
and I want you to call him “father”.
You don’t know how good
he’s been to us, my daughter.
It’s a word, Ofelia.
It’s nothing more than a word.
Captain, they’re coming!
Fifteen minutes late.
Carmen.
Welcome.
I have no need of that.
I’m perfectly able to walk.
Doctor Ferreiro would rather
you not exert yourself.
No.
Come, now.
Do it for me.
Thank you.
Ofelia, come out.
Greet the Captain.
Ofelia.
It’s the other hand, Ofelia.
Mercedes!
Let them bring the luggage.
Yes, sir.
It’s a labyrinth.
Nothing. A heap of really old rocks
that have always been there.
Even before the mill.
Best that you don’t come near it.
You can get lost.
Thank you.
Have you read them all?
Mercedes!
The Captain is calling you.
Your father needs me.
He’s not my father.
The Captain is not my father!
My father was a tailor.
We lost him at the start of the war.
The Captain is not my father.
I’m clear on that.
Shall we go?
Have you seen my mother?
– Isn’t she lovely?
– Yes.
She’s pregnant – have you noticed?
The guerrillas have taken to the hills,
and it’s much harder to track them there.
Those fuckers know the
terrain better than anyone.
We’re going to block
access to the mountain.
Food and medicine –
everything will be rationed
from our storehouse.
We need to force them down from there,
make them come to us.
I want three new checkpoints:
here, here, and here.
Mercedes.
Tell Doctor Ferreiro
to come down and see me.
Yes, sir.
With this, you’ll sleep
through the night.
No more than two drops
before you go to bed.
Two drops.
Very good.
All of it, all of it.
Don’t hesitate to call
if you need me. Day or night.
You, or your nurse.
Good night.
Go close the door and
turn down the light, dear.
You have to go up and see him.
His wound is not mending.
His leg is getting much worse.
I’ve been unable
to obtain more than this.
I’m sorry.
Vidal is waiting for you in his office.
Yes.
Ofelia, come here.
Blessed Virgin, your feet
are frozen, my love.
Are you scared?
A little.
What’s that noise?
It’s nothing, my daughter.
It’s the wind.
Nights here are very different
from those in the city.
There, you can hear
motorcars, trolleys.
Here, the houses are old.
They grumble.
What does it seem
that they’re saying?
Tomorrow I’m going to give you
a surprise. You’ll see.
A surprise?
– A book?
– No, something much better.
Why did you have to get married?
We were alone for too long.
I’m with you.
You weren’t alone.
You’ve never been alone.
Someday you’ll understand that
it hasn’t been easy for me, either.
Your brother’s a little restless.
Come, tell him one of your stories.
I’m sure it’ll calm him
to hear your voice.
My brother.
Many, many years ago,
in a distant and dismal land,
stood a vast mountain
of black, rough stone.
At the fall of evening,
on the crest of that mountain,
a rose that granted immortality
bloomed each night.
However, no one dared approach it
since its numerous thorns were poisoned.
Amongst themselves,
people spoke only about
the fear of death and pain,
but never about the
promise of eternal life.
And every evening,
the rose withered,
unable to confer its gift to anyone...
forgotten and lost atop
that mountain of cold stone...
alone... until the end of time.
Proceed.
– How is she?
– Very weak.
She’ll get rest, whatever it takes.
I’ll sleep down here.
– And my son?
– Pardon?
By your leave, Captain...
My son.
How is he?
For the moment,
there’s no cause for alarm.
Very well.
Captain?
Your wife should not have traveled
at such an advanced stage of pregnancy.
That is your opinion?
My professional opinion – yes, sir.
A son should be born
wherever his father may be.
That is all.
Another thing, Captain.
Who has told you
that the child is male?
Don’t fuck with me.
At eight o’clock, activity was
detected in the northwest sector.
Gunshots.
Sergeant Bayona combed the area
and apprehended a suspect.
The other one is his son,
who has come from town.
Captain, my father
is an honorable man.
I’ll be the judge of that.
Uncover yourself
when you’re before me.
The detainee was found with
this weapon. It’s been discharged.
– My father was hunting rabbits, Captain.
– Shut up, cunt.
“Neither God, nor country, nor master.”
That takes some fucking balls.
Red propaganda, Captain.
It’s not propaganda, Captain.
It’s an old almanac, Captain.
We’re farmers.
Continue.
I went up into the hills,
Captain, to hunt rabbits...
for my daughters, who’ve fallen ill.
Rabbits, huh?
Captain, if my father says so,
he was hunting rabbits.
No! Leave him in peace!
You’ve killed him!
Murderer!
Son of a bitch!
See that you learn
to search this rabble
before coming to bother me.
Yes, Captain.
Mother... Mother, wake up...
Mother... there’s something in the room.
Hello.
Have you followed me here?
Are you a fairy?
Look.
This is a fairy.
You want me to go with you?
Outside?
Where to?
Hello?
Echo!
Is it you?
It is you! You have returned!
No, do not be afraid, I beseech you.
Look! Look!
My name is Ofelia. Who are you?
I?
I.
I have had so many names...
old names that can only
be pronounced by the wind...
and the trees.
I am the mountain,
and the forest, and the earth...
I am...
I am... a faun.
Most humble of your subjects,
Your Highness.
– No... I’m...
– You are Princess Moanna,
– daughter of the King of Bethmoora,
– No...
the Underground Realm.
My father was a tailor.
You are no daughter of man.
The moon begat you!
On your left shoulder,
you will find a mark that proves it.
Throughout the world,
your true father
did open portals that
would enable your return.
This... is the last of them.
But... we must make certain
that your essence has not been lost...
that you have not turned into a mortal.
You shall have to pass
three tests before the full moon.
This...
This is “The Book of Crossroads”.
When you are alone, open it.
It will show you your future.
It will show you... what to do.
But there’s nothing here.
Mercedes.
Prepare these rabbits
for tonight’s dinner.
They’re a bit too young, sir.
– Well, see if they might do for a broth.
– Yes, sir.
This coffee is badly burnt. Try it.
You should watch it more carefully
when it’s on the flame.
As you command, sir.
To the table.
He’s been displeased with the coffee.
That one’s a prissy dandy.
A prissy dandy!
We’re going to need some
lamb and one more hen.
Well, let’s see where we’re
getting it from, my girl.
Since the Doctor’s and
Mayor’s wives are coming.
Those women?
They eat more than a suckling pig!
And they don’t shut their mouths.
Not even underwater.
Mercedes, I’ll carry
these downstairs now.
Ofelia.
Your father’s giving
a dinner party tonight.
And look what I’ve made for you.
Do you like it?
What I would’ve given as a little girl
to have a dress like this!
And look at the shoes!
Patent leather!
Do you like them?
Yes, they’re very pretty.
Go on, now. Take your bath.
Ofelia?
Ofelia, don’t take long.
I’d like to see the dress on you.
I want you to be beautiful
when the Captain sees you.
Truly...
You will look like a princess.
A princess.
You’re cleaning those hens well, eh?
And the beans in the black pot –
don’t forget them.
You are precious, my girl!
– Precious!
– What a cute little dress!
Go on, now. Back to work.
You’re all wasting time.
Do you want a bit of milk with honey?
Stand back, my girl.
I wouldn’t want to splash you,
with you being so gorgeous.
Mercedes...
Do you believe in fairies?
Not anymore...
but when I was a little girl, yes.
Back then I believed in
many things that I don’t now.
Well, last night, a fairy visited me.
You don’t say?
Okay, it wasn’t just one.
There were others – and a faun.
A faun?
That’s what he said.
He’s very tall, very old,
and smells of earth.
As my grandmother used to say:
with fauns, one must tread carefully.
Mercedes.
Come with me.
Captain, everything is here.
Flour, salt, oil, medicine, Caldo de Gallina...
Olives, bacon...
What tobacco! What tobacco!
And the ration cards.
– I need you to look over the inventory, Captain.
– Very well.
Mercedes.
– The key.
– Yes, sir.
– Is this the only copy?
– The only one, sir.
As of today, I’m carrying it.
Captain!
It may not be anything, Captain.
It’s them.
“At the dawn of time,
when the forest was young,”
“there lived in harmony animals,
men, and magical creatures.”
“They protected one another”
“and slept together under
the shade of a lush tree”
“that grows on the
hillside near the mill.”
“Now, the tree is dying –”
“its branches are barren,
its trunk old and crooked.”
“Beneath its roots
has nested a monstrous toad”
“that does not allow it to heal.”
“You will have to put the three
magic amber stones in its mouth”
“and retrieve a golden key
hidden in its belly.”
“Only in this way shall
the tree flourish again.”
Probably less than twenty minutes ago.
They took off like a shot.
A dozen, at most.
Antibiotics.
For fuck’s sake!
On top of that, they forgot
their lottery ticket!
They’re here.
Those sons of whores are here.
They’re watching us.
Hey!
You’ve left this behind!
And your lottery ticket!
Why don’t you come down for it?
If you had any balls,
you could play with yourselves!
H-hello...
I’m Princess Moanna...
and I’m not afraid of you.
Aren’t you ashamed
of staying down here,
eating all these bugs,
and growing fat
while the tree dies?
Hey!
Have you looked in the bedroom
and the storehouse?
Yes, madam.
Have you checked the garden?
– And the granary?
– Yes, madam.
But where will that girl
have gotten to?
Through here, please.
Allow me to introduce you
to my wife, Carmen.
– Charmed.
– My pleasure.
Starting today,
one ration card per family.
Have a look at them.
– Only one?
– Only one.
– Captain, I don’t know if it’ll be enough.
– If the people are prudent, yes.
What we can’t allow is for anyone to keep
sending food to those in the mountains.
They’re losing ground,
and they’ve been towing
at least one wounded.
Pardon me, Captain.
How are you so sure?
Today we almost caught them,
and they were carrying this:
antibiotics.
These people, God has
already saved their souls.
What befalls their bodies
matters very little to Him.
We’ll assist you in all that
you may require, Captain.
We know you’re not here by choice.
In that, you are mistaken.
I’m here because I want my son
to be born in a cleansed, renewed Spain.
Because these people
share a misconception:
that we are all equal.
But there’s a big difference:
the war is over, and we won.
And if, in order for everyone to understand this,
we have to kill those bastards,
then we kill them, and that’s it.
All of us are here by choice.
By choice!
Paz, put the coffee on, please.
I’m going for more wood.
What has you so ill at ease?
Ofelia?
So, how did you
and the Captain meet?
Ofelia’s father used
to make his uniforms.
Ah. Well, then.
And when he died, I started
working in a general store,
and a little more than a year ago...
the Captain and I...
we met again.
How curious, isn’t it?
I mean, running into each other
again – after so long.
Curious. Most curious.
Pardon my wife.
She hasn’t seen much
of the world, you know?
She believes we’re all
interested in that bullshit.
As you say, Captain.
Madam, the girl has turned up.
If you would excuse me?
Have I told you before that I was
acquainted with your father, Captain?
No. I had no idea.
In Morocco.
I knew him briefly,
but he left a vivid impression.
A great soldier.
The men in his troop used to say
that when General Vidal
died on the field of battle,
he dashed his watch to the ground
so that it might show
the exact hour of his death –
so that his son might know
how a valiant man dies.
Rumors.
He didn’t have a watch.
What you’ve done... it hurts me.
When you get out of the bath,
you’ll go to bed without supper.
Did you hear me?
Sometimes I think that
you’ll never learn to behave.
You’ve disappointed me, Ofelia.
And your father, as well.
The Captain?
Him even more than me.
I already have the key.
Take me to the labyrinth.
Hello.
I’ve brought the key.
That is me...
and the girl... is you.
And the baby?
You have acquired the key.
I am delighted.
She has believed in Your Grace
from the beginning.
She is quite pleased by your success.
Preserve the key.
You shall have need of it –
very soon.
And also this: a bit of chalk.
Only two more tests remain,
and the moon will presently be full.
Have patience.
Soon enough, we shall promenade through the
seven concentric courtyards of your palace.
How do I know that
what you say is true?
Why would I lie,
a poor faun like me?
Let’s go.
Card in hand, in view!
Let’s go, let’s go!
Your name?
Sofía Nadal, and my children.
First name and last names?
Narciso Peña Soriano,
at your service.
Name?
This is our daily bread in Franco’s Spain,
which we keep safe in our granaries.
The Reds lie.
Because in Nationalist Spain –
One, Great, and Free –
there is neither a hearth without fire
nor a family without bread.
Come on.
Tell me what’s going to happen now.
Tell me.
Ofelia...
Ofelia, help me...
This is our daily bread in Franco’s Spain,
which we keep safe in our granaries.
– Captain! Captain!
– The Reds lie.
They lie when they say
there is hunger in Spain.
– Come, quickly!
– Do not believe them.
Because in Nationalist Spain –
One, Great, and Free –
there is neither a hearth without fire
nor a family without bread.
This is our daily bread in Franco’s Spain.
Your wife requires absolute repose.
She must remain under sedation
most of the time.
The girl ought to sleep
in another room.
I will stay here until the delivery.
Make her well.
I don’t care what it takes
or what it costs.
Make her well.
Don’t you worry.
Your mother will get better
very soon. You’ll see.
Having a baby is complicated.
Well, then I’m not going to have any.
You’re helping those
in the mountains, right?
Have you mentioned
this to anybody?
I won’t tell anyone. Ever.
I don’t want anything bad
to happen to you.
Nor I to you.
Do you know a lullaby?
Only one...
but I don’t remember the words.
It doesn’t matter. I want to hear it.
No, no, no! Don’t be alarmed! It’s me.
Ready?
Yes.
Let’s go, then.
This is sheer madness.
When that man finds us out,
he’s going to kill us. All of us!
Do you realize that?
Are you so afraid, Doctor?
No. It’s not... it’s not fear.
At least not for myself.
Pedro!
My brother!
You have avoided the test.
No... my mother is sick.
That is no excuse for negligence!
See here. This... is a mandrake...
a plant that dreamt of being human.
Place it underneath your mother’s bed
in a bowl of fresh milk.
Each morning, give it
two drops of blood to drink.
Now – carry through with the test.
The full moon is already upon us.
Let them be your guides.
You will be going to
a very dangerous place.
Take heed:
that which slumbers there...
is not human.
You will see a lavish banquet.
Do not eat or drink anything.
Absolutely nothing!
Your life depends on it.
I’ve brought you some
brandy and tobacco...
Cheese...
A couple of letters
for Trigo and Piloto...
Powder for lice...
How’s that leg, Francés?
Well, how’s it going to be, Doctor?
It’s fucked.
Let’s see.
“T-t-troops from N-N-North America,”
“B-B-Britain, and C-C-Canada”
“have landed on a small beach
in the north of F-F-F...”
– “Of France,” stutterer.
– “France.”
– “Of France.”
“More than one hundred
fifty thousand soldiers”
“under the command of
General Dwight D. Eisenhower...”
Is it serious, Doctor?
Look, Francés...
There’s no way to save it.
I’ll try to do it in
as few cuts as possible.
One moment, Doctor.
One moment.
“With the chalk, you shall trace the
outline of a door anywhere in your room.”
“Once the door is opened,
start the hourglass.”
“Let yourself be guided
by the fairies,”
“do not eat or drink
anything during your stay,”
“and ensure that you return before
the last grain of sand falls.”
No.
It’s this one.
No! No!
Before long, we’ll have
people in from Jaca.
About fifty men.
Then we’ll go head-to-head with Vidal.
And? What’s going to happen?
You kill him and another like him will come.
And another. And another still.
You all have it really screwed up.
Vidal has guns, shelter.
You need food, medicine.
You should be looking after Mercedes.
If she really does matter to you, cross
the border with her. This is a lost cause!
I’m staying here, Doctor.
There’s nothing else.
You have to leave.
The key.
But you can’t go down there now.
That’s what he’s waiting for.
Leave it to me.
I’m a coward.
No. You aren’t.
Yes. Yes, I am.
A coward, a piece of shit.
Stuck there all day beside
that son of a bitch.
Washing his clothes,
making his bed, feeding him.
And what if the Doctor’s right,
and we can’t win?
At least we’ll make it difficult
for that asshole.
Left... turn! Left... turn!
Captain Vidal.
Her fever’s going down.
I don’t know how, but it is.
But she still has one?
Yes, but it’s a good sign.
Her body’s responding.
Listen well.
If you have to choose...
save the child.
That boy will bear my name,
and my father’s name.
Save him.
My brother...
my brother...
If you can hear me...
things around here aren’t that good...
but soon you’ll have to come out.
You’ve made Mama very ill.
When you do come out,
I want to ask you for one thing.
Just one.
Don’t hurt Mama.
You’ll get to know her.
She’s very pretty,
although sometimes she may
feel sad for many days,
but you’ll see it when she smiles.
You’re going to like her a lot.
Listen...
if you do what I say,
I promise you this:
I’ll take you to my kingdom,
and you’ll be a prince.
I promise you. A prince.
I blew the whistle,
but they didn’t move aside.
I attempted to stop the engine,
but it was much too late.
The stoker and I
jumped out in time, but...
just look at the mess they’ve made!
What was contained
in the cars that they raided?
They haven’t opened
a single car, Captain.
What the fuck are you talking about?
They’ve blown it to hell,
and they haven’t opened one car.
They haven’t taken anything.
Nothing?
Are you sure?
God alone knows
what they were going after –
besides making us waste time.
Captain! Captain!
They came out of nowhere, Captain.
All of a sudden.
They’ve looted the storehouse. They have grenades.
And they’ve pulled back up the mountain.
Captain, we’ve corralled a group
that has lagged behind.
They’ve taken shelter on an outcrop.
Come, Serrano – be fearless!
This is the only decent way to die!
Serrano!
Let me see.
Let me see!
Can you talk?
Fuck.
These are good for nothing.
One alive is worth more than ten dead.
Do you understand, imbecile?
There’s no way to get anything out of them.
Anything! Do you hear me?
Captain!
Here’s a live one!
He only has a hit to his leg.
– What’s going on?
– They’ve caught one!
– What?
They’ve caught one of them – alive –
and they’re taking him to the storehouse!
Mercedes!
Pedro...?
Mercedes?
Captain, I need to get
into the storehouse...
Not now.
Fall back.
My girl, enough.
Shall I carry it?
Take this. It’s just half the dose.
I don’t think I need it, Doctor.
I’m feeling better. Much better.
I can’t account for it, but I’m glad.
Mother.
Fuck, is this good!
Shag tobacco.
Hard to come by, eh?
F-f-fuck off.
Fucking hell, Garcés. We finally catch one
and he turns out to be a stutterer.
We’re going to spend
the entire night here.
As long as he talks, Captain.
Garcés is right.
You’re going to tell us
everything, aren’t you?
Because to do just that,
we’ve brought along a few little things –
things one picks up here and there.
At first, I’m not going
to be able to trust you.
But when I finish using this...
you’re going to tell me one thing or another.
When we move on to these...
we’re going to have
a relationship that’s...
how should I say...?
Much closer.
Like brothers, eh?
You’ll see.
And when we get around to this...
I’m going to believe
everything you say to me.
I’m going to propose
something to you.
If you count up to three –
without st-t-tuttering –
you’ll be able to leave.
Don’t look at him.
Look at me.
Above me, there is no one.
– Garcés!
– Yes, Captain?
If I say this lucky fellow is going to leave,
is anybody going to contradict me?
No one, Captain. He can go.
Come on.
Up to three.
One.
Very good.
Two.
Come on.
One more and you’ll be free.
Pity.
Your mother has improved,
Your Highness.
Surely, now, you must
be greatly relieved.
Y-y-yes. Yes, thank you...
but...
things haven’t come out
all that well.
Ah? No?
– There was an accident.
– An accident?
Yes.
You have broken the rules!
It was only two grapes,
and I thought that no one would notice!
We have been mistaken!
Mistaken?
You have failed!
You cannot return!
– It was all an accident.
– You cannot return!
The moon will be full in three days!
Your spirit shall remain
forever among men!
You will grow old like them,
you will die like them!
Your memory shall vanish in time,
and we will disappear along with it.
You will never see us again!
Good morning, Doctor.
Sorry to bother you so early,
but I think we need your help.
My God, what have
you done to him?
Not much.
But things are on the mend.
I like having you around, Doctor.
It has its advantages.
Serrano, stay with them.
I talked...
V-very... little...
B-b-but... I talked...
I’m sorry.
I’m so very sorry.
K-k-k...
Ki-ki-kill me...
Ki-kill me now... p-please...
Son of a bitch.
You won’t feel any more pain.
It’s almost over.
Keep an eye on Doctor Ferreiro.
I’ll be right there.
Yes, Captain.
You’re not moving anymore.
Are you sick?
What the fuck are you doing
down there? Huh?
– Call him!
– Who?
Who else, imbecile?
Ferreiro!
What the fuck is this?
No, no, no, no!
– Leave her alone!
– No, no!
Leave her alone already!
Please.
Look! Look at what
she had under your bed!
Huh? What does it
look like to you?
Ofelia, what was this thing
doing under the bed?
It’s... a magic root.
The faun gave it to me.
This is because of that
shit you let her read.
Look at what you’ve
accomplished!
Please, leave us alone.
I’ll talk to her, darling.
Very well.
As you wish.
He told me it would
make you well. And it did!
Ofelia, you have to
listen to your father.
You have to change.
No! I want to leave here!
Take me far away
from here, please!
Please, let’s go!
Things aren’t that simple.
You’ll be getting older...
and soon you’ll understand that
life isn’t like your fairy tales.
The world is a cruel place.
And you’re going to learn that...
even if it hurts you.
No! No!
Ofelia!
Magic does not exist!
It doesn’t exist – not for you,
not for me, not for anybody!
Mother! Help!
Help!
Why did you do it?
It was the only thing I could do.
No. You could have obeyed me.
I could have, but I didn’t.
Then it would have been better for you.
Do you know that?
I don’t understand it.
Why didn’t you obey me?
The thing is...
to obey for the sake of obeying...
just like that,
without thinking about it...
that’s only something
people like you do, Captain.
Captain!
Garcés!
Summon the chief paramedic!
Let him come up immediately!
Yes, Captain.
Captain, your wife has died.
Because the ways
of the Lord are inscrutable.
Because in His word
and in His mystery
lies the essence of His mercy.
Because even though God
sends us the message,
it is on us to decipher it.
Because upon opening
its arms to us,
the earth takes in only
a hollow and senseless shell.
Far away now is the soul
in Eternal Glory.
Because it is in suffering
where we find the sense of life
and the state of grace
that we lose at birth.
Because God, in His infinite wisdom,
puts the solution in our hands.
And because only
in His physical absence
does He reaffirm the place
that He occupies in our souls.
You knew Doctor Ferreiro pretty well,
isn’t that so, Mercedes?
We all knew him, sir.
Everyone around here.
The stutterer spoke to us
of an informant – inside the mill.
Can you imagine?
Right under my nose.
Mercedes.
Please.
What must you think of me?
You probably think that I’m a monster.
To you, sir, it doesn’t matter
what someone like me thinks.
I want you to go to the storehouse tonight
and bring me more brandy, please.
Yes, sir.
Good night, sir.
Mercedes.
Aren’t you forgetting something?
Sir?
The key.
I have the only copy,
isn’t that true?
Yes, sir.
Do you know... there’s
something that’s bothering me.
A small detail.
It’s not very important, but...
The day that they
got into the storehouse –
with all those grenades
and explosives –
the lock wasn’t forced.
In any case...
Surely it’s not important.
Be very careful.
Until tomorrow, sir.
Ofelia!
Ofelia, I’m leaving tonight.
– Where to?
– I can’t tell you.
– I can’t tell you, but I promise...
– Take me with you.
– No, no. I can’t. I can’t. No.
– I promise to come back for you, my girl.
– Take me with you.
– I can’t. I promise...
I’ve heard something...
No...
It seems that it’s nothing. It’s quiet.
Mercedes.
Ofelia.
Since when have you
known about her?
How long have you
been laughing at me?
Whore!
Watch her!
And if anyone tries to get in...
kill her first.
Sausage.
Tobacco.
If you’d asked me for it,
I’d have given it to you, Mercedes.
I want the names of those
who have written these letters.
And I want them
in front of me tomorrow.
Yes, Captain.
Remove yourself, Garcés.
Are you sure, Captain?
For the love of God,
she’s nothing more than a woman.
That’s what you’ve always thought.
That’s how I could get close.
Because I was invisible to you.
Fuck.
You’ve discovered my weak point:
Pride.
But we’re here in order to
search for your weak points.
The matter is quite simple:
you’re going to talk...
and I have to know...
that you’re telling me the truth.
To do just that...
we’ve brought along a few little things.
Nothing complicated.
Things one picks up here and there.
At first, I’m not going
to be able to trust...
I’m not an old or injured man,
motherfucker!
Motherfucker!
Don’t you even think
about touching the girl.
You won’t be the
first pig I slaughter!
– Hey.
– Shhh!
He let her go.
What the fuck are you saying?
Hey!
Catch her!
– Go! Bring her to me!
– Captain...?
Bring her to me, you cunts!
To the mounts!
It’s best that you
come along willingly.
The Captain has told me
that if you behave...
Don’t do anything foolish,
pretty one.
If anyone’s going to kill you...
I’d rather it be me.
I have decided to give you...
another opportunity.
Do you promise to obey me?
Will you do all that I tell you?
Without question?
This is your last chance.
Then...
listen to me well.
Collect your brother
and bring him to me
in the labyrinth
as soon as possible...
Your Highness.
My brother?
We have need of him.
But...
No more questions.
The door is locked.
In that case...
make your own door.
By your leave, Captain.
Come quickly.
So now what’s happening?
Serrano has returned.
He’s wounded.
Wounded?
Where is Garcés?
How many were there?
I don’t know exactly, Captain, but...
no fewer than fifty men.
None of the others have returned, and the
checkpoints are not responding to our calls.
How many men are left
in the encampment?
Twenty... perhaps fewer, sir.
We’re going to get out of here.
You and me, together.
Don’t be scared.
Nothing’s going to happen to you.
Set a watch at the
perimeter of the woods.
As soon as one of the patrols
gets back, I want to see them.
Communicate by radio with
the Lieutenant Colonel.
We need support, urgently!
Yes, Captain.
Leave him.
Ofelia!
Quickly, Your Highness!
Deliver him to me!
The full moon shines in the sky,
and we can open the portal.
What do you carry in your hand?
The portal will only open if
we shed innocent blood upon it.
Just a little blood.
Merely a prick.
It is the final test.
Come on.
You promised to obey me
without defiance!
– Surrender the child!
– No!
My brother stays with me.
You will sacrifice your sacred title
for this brat you scarcely know?
Yes. I sacrifice it.
You will renounce your
birthright for him?
He, for whom you have been
humilated, ignored?
Yes. I renounce it.
Then let your will be done...
Your Highness.
No!
My son.
Tell my son...
Tell him what time his father died.
– Tell him that I...
– No.
He won’t even know your name.
Rise to your feet, daughter of mine.
Draw near.
Father.
You have shed your own blood
rather than that of an innocent.
That was the final test,
and the most important.
And you have chosen well,
Your Highness.
Come to my side,
and be seated alongside your father,
so long a time has he waited for you.
And it is said that the Princess
descended to her father’s realm...
and that there she reigned with
justice and kindness for many centuries...
that she was loved by her subjects...
and that she left behind small traces
of her passage through the world...
visible only to those...
who know where to look.
“The Faun’s Labyrinth”