English dub subtitles by:
MightyMike77020
Studio Ghibli, Nippon Television Network, Dentsu, Hakuhοdο
DΥMP, Walt Disney Japan, Mitsubishi and Τοhο present
planning & screenplay by Hayao
Miyazaki produced by Toshio Suzuki
based on the original graphic novel by Chizuru
Takahashi & Tetsuro Sayama screenplay by Keiko Niwa
music by Satoshi Τakebe
in some places
you can tell what time of year it is
music by Satoshi Τakebe
by which flowers are in bloom.
In Yokohama it's which boats you see
passing through the harbor.
Poppy Hill
only there are more and more them now
since Tokyo was awarded
Poppy Hill
the 64 Sumner Olympics.
"Summer of farewells" performed by Αoi Τeshima
"Ue o muite arukou by Kyu Sakamoto
we have a great view of the boats
from my house on Poppy Hill.
Character design Katsuya Kondō, imagining
Αtsushi Okui, sound design Koji Kasamatsu
voices of Masami Nagasawa, Junichi Okada
actually it's...
Voices of Masami Nagasawa, Junichi Okada
my grandmother's house.
Keiko Takeshita, Rumi Hiiragi, Yuriko Ishida, Jun Fubuki
but with my father gone
and my mother studying in America,
Takashi Naitô, Shunsuke Kazama, Nao Ômori, Teruyuki Kagawa
it's my job to cook
and do laundry for our borders.
Takashi Naitô, Shunsuke Kazama, Nao Ômori, Teruyuki Kagawa
and look after my
little brother and sister.
Ever since the wars,
it seems the whole country
is eager to get rid of the old
and make way for the new.
Directed by Gorō Miyazaki
directed by Gorō Miyazaki
but some of us aren't so ready
.
to let go of the past.
And sometimes the past is not
ready to let go of us either.
♪ The pot is bubbling,
the rice is steaming. ♪
♪ The cutting board
is standing by ♪
♪ The tofu is jiggly, the
eggs are slippery. ♪
♪ The natto* is sticky
as can be. ♪
♪ Drop the eggs in a frying pan. ♪
♪ Stir the miso* in a pot. ♪
♪ Pile the rice in a server ♪
♪ everything is ready to go. ♪
♪ Time to wake up the house. ♪
♪ Get everyone to the table. ♪
♪ Now dig in, eat hearty. ♪
♪ It's another sunny day. ♪
♪ Another beautiful
breakfast together. ♪
♪ And I made it all for you. ♪
♪ Hurry up, dig in now. ♪
♪ But be sure to taste
every bite. ♪
♪ Another beautiful
breakfast together. ♪
♪ And I made it all for you. ♪
♪ Hurry up, dig in now. ♪
♪ But be sure to taste
every bite. ♪
♫ Good morning Umi. ♫
Good morning Miss. Saori.
Is Sora up yet?
Wouldn't that be a miracle.
Good morning.
- Good morning Miki.
- ♫ Morning. ♫
So, late night at the hospital again Miki?
Yep, and I'm going tonight.
If you like, I can save dinner for you?
Oh, your a saint.
What would we do without Umi?
- What would I do without...
- Hay sis, I got another hole in my sock!
Just leave it beside the sewing machine.
That boy has holes in his head?
Hay, I heard that!
Two eggs please.
One is enough for you.
Well I've got sports today:
So, pack a big lunch.
Is there a hole in your stomach too?
Ha-ha.
- Here Riku, have my egg.
- Yes! Thank you.
You should take it Miki.
You need it more than him.
Now, which one of you is the doctor?
At least someone cares
about my hunger pains.
Hay! Easy on the soy sauce.
But I like it this way.
Ooh, pass me the soy!
Breakfast is ready, Sachiko.
Yeah, I'll be right there.
- Good morning, Grand Hana.
- Good morning, Hana.
Good morning.
Riku, why don't you and Umi
share your mother's plate.
Thank you.
Grandmother, would you like me
to make you some tea?
Yes Umi, that would be lovely.
Good morning Sachiko.
I bid you all good morning.
Good morning.
Thank you dear.
Please begin, everyone.
I gratefully receive.
You're late.
I couldn't get my hair to look right.
It looks like hair is supposed to look.
I'm starving.
- Evening rounds again, Miki?
- Yes.
- I don't know how you keep up...
- Can I have your dinner?
Got it.
Watch your head.
Is every thing ok.
See you tomorrow Umi.
Bye Miki.
- Good morning.
- Good morning Umi.
Do you want a ride Umi?
- No thank you, I'll walk.
- Ah, to be young.
Τomoko could you finish
the laundry for me?
Of course. I'd be happy to.
Thank you.
Hay, wait up!
[KONΑN ACADEMY]
Umi, over here. Come see this.
What is it?
Oh, just an article about you.
It must be about you. Who else
raises flags every morning?
"Fair girl, why do you send
your thoughts to the sky?"
"the wind carries them aloft
to mingle with the crows."
"trimmed with blue, your
flags fly again today."
Oh! Looks like someone's
getting your messages.
Uh-huh.
I doubt it. Someone at this school.
Getting those messages
just doesn't calculate.
Math club freak!
He's one of those snobby guys that
live in that dirty old clubhouse.
All rise!
There you are.
Morning.
Save me a seat.
Who ordered the curry noodles?
Nobuko, over here!
- Thanks for waiting.
- Curry udon again?
Oh and you're one to talk.
Let me guess. Tuna sandwiches again.
Who cares, I like them.
Umi, your lunches always look so good.
It's not difficult.
You should try making your own sometime.
It'll never happen.
I don't have the time.
- Hay! - Hay!
- Hay!
Great. Now what?
And up!
One two, one two, one two,
one two, one two.
Men, its time.
Save our building!
[LATIN QUARTER ANTI-DEMOLITION LEAGUE]
Let's go!
Ok, batter up.
Ahh!
Ugh!
Ooh!
Woa!
Go for it!
He just _?_ Latin club.
Smile for the camera love birds.
Smile.
Oh!
That was so cool.
Umi, are you okay?
So stupid...
- I'm home.
- Welcome back.
Oh, thank you Τomoko.
My pleasure.
There, all finished.
The mackerel was on sale today.
Mackerel that's good.
Maybe I'll fry it.
I almost forgot, I have
a meeting with Grandmother.
Grandmother?
It's me, Umi.
Come in.
Very impressive. You're managing
the house beautifully.
Only because your paying Τomoko's wages,
which is a tremendous help.
Nonsense.
I would have hired her anyway
even if we hadn't taken in boarders.
Tell me my child, is this
too much work for you?
I worry about you.
But why? I promise I'm not letting
it get in the way of my studies.
Umi,
believe me I know how much
you miss your father.
But it makes me sad watching you
every morning raising those flags.
I hope you find someone,
then maybe you won't need
to raise those flags anymore.
- I'm sorry to interrupt.
- Come in.
I'm finished for the day ma'am.
Thank you, Τomoko.
Excuse me Grandmother.
I should get dinner going.
Mmm...
Very exciting.
In fact it created such a stir
some of the girls are talking
about starting a fan club.
A what?
Okay so what's his name?
Shun Kazama. He is a real live wire.
So he's the electricians son.
What?
What???
"Fair girl, why do you send
your thoughts to the sky?"
thus the principality
of Wallachia was hemmed in
by the Ottoman, Turks and Russia,
and its territory was coveted by both.
Now why was it coveted?
[SAVE OUR CLUBHOUSE FROM DEMOLITION]
Hay Umi.
Sora? What's going on?
I bought this for 30 yen.
Wow, that's a waist of money.
I don't care what you say.
I think he's cute and I want
to get his autograph.
Please come with me
to the Latin Quarter Clubhouse.
So that way when I meet him
he doesn't think I'm weird.
Are you crazy? I don't want
to go to that old place.
- But I'm desperate.
- Well I'm not.
I know your not
but you'll do it for me, won't you?
Come on, say yes.
Yes. Yes?
Wow, they really like signs.
[DON'T DEMOLISH OUR CLUBHOUSE]
"Save the Latin Quarter."
"Don't extinguish the flame of culture."
Ready?
Uh-huh.
Did you see those spots?
Um, excuse me, gentlemen?
I've never seen
them so distinct!
This might be more awesome
than the solar flares of 1960.
Don't even joke about that.
I said, "excuse me!"
- What?
- What'd you say?
I'm sorry to interrupt but we're looking
for the school newspaper office.
Third floor, same room
as the archeology club.
Thank you.
What are girls doing here?
I have no idea.
You think they liked us?
Well, I love what they've
done with the place.
Wait!
Woa???
Ahoy.
Excuse me where's the archeology club?
Upstairs. Listen for the sound
of smug portentousness.
Ok, thank you.
Ready?
Uh-huh.
Ahh!
Ah, at last!
Inquiring minds seeking answers
to life's great mysteries.
- Huh?
I will personally offer you my stewardship
and share with you my passion
for the philosophical arts.
That's a very kind offer but we're
actually headed for the archeology club.
Fine as you wish but when you find
yourself seeking the meaning of life.
I'll be right here to enlighten you.
- Ahh!-Ahh!
- Ahh!
Chemistry club you ruined
our contemplation.
Oh well, you're welcome ladies.
That guy will talk to you ear off.
Hey that's enough. Show some respect
you second grade alchemist.
Here's a thought try experimenting
with something that actually exist.
To obtain new transparent energy
from the clouds, from the
light, from the storms
and suggest to man in the universe
the shapes they are to take.
Copernicus of the new age, set this
galaxy free from the oppressive.
CQ! This is OM4 FMKK.
Next Fm.
We're high school
student from Japan.
A new splendid beautiful system.
Darwin, not the new age!
Or the challenges of the new...
Watch your step.
Uh-huh.
[LITERATURE CLUB LATIN QUARTER WEEKLY]
That's it.
Uh-huh.
Oh! Hi Umi.
Υamazaki...
Hey, couple of potential
groupies here to see you.
Chow.
Welcome to lit club.
Or archeology club.
Or maybe you're the two who actually
read that failed weekly rag we publish.
Knock it off Mizunuma. Bring
them in and close the
door.
The crux of the matter is.
How can we make archeology cool again.
We can't.
Uh... uh...
Oh...
- Can you please give me your autograph?
- Huh?
Go ahead Elvis.
Mmm.
Here.
Thank you, thank you so much.
How's your hand?
This? This isn't from the fall.
I cut myself shaving.
He shaves!
Shaving.
Hey, how would you like to help
Mr. Whiskers here cut some stencils.
- Huh?
Cuz' we're pretty busy
with the campaign
keeping Latin Quarters
from getting demolished.
You're the little sister right?
Yes, I'm Sora Matsuzaki.
But, if you need help with stencils
Umi has better handwriting.
Right Umi?
What are you talking about Sora?
Look, if you're a second year student,
[PHYSICS MIDTERM FORECAST!]
You take physics
And your teacher is old man Suzuki.
Mr. Suzuki.
Right, well,
Mizunuma's uses these old tests to make
up a mock test for the upcoming physics exam.
That's right. But its not really
cheating if you're only half accurate.
Shun, see you at 6:00?
Right.
Miss. Sora please come with me.
Ok.
With your permission.
I will escort you to the door
lest you be ambushed
by our resident philosopher.
Permission granted.
Mmm.
- From here to the end.
- Uh-huh.
And I say we are cool!
We have to get people interested
in the paleolithic period.
To the library!
Meeting's starting, Shun.
Oh you might want
to join us Umi,
if you like a room full of guys
screaming at each other.
Is it that late?!?
I'm sorry I have to go!
It's ok, you were a big help.
Meeting time!
All club members to the first floor!
Check it out. Next chromosome.
I'm home.
Wow, starting kind of late.
Yes, I know.
And I still need to cut some vegetables.
Can you help me out?
I hope so.
Oh.
[Sukiyaki (Ue o muite arukou) - Kyu Sakamoto ]
[Billboard hot 100 - June 1963]
Grandmother, I'm home.
Your running a bit late Umi.
Riku, were all out of pork,
and I need you to run
down to the butcher shop and get some.
♪ Ue wo muite arukou ♪
Ahh...
No...
♪ Ue wo muite arukou ♪
.
Sora?
♪ Ue wo muite arukou ♪
But the program just started
♪ Namida ga kobore nai you ni ♪
And this is my favorite part.
But didn't Τomoko buy you some?
♪ Namida ga kobore nai you ni ♪
I used it all for the lunches.
♪ Omoidasu ♪
♪ harunohi ♪
.
♪ hitoribotchi no yoru ♪
Sachiko,
Start the rice in 10 minutes, okay?
♪ hitoribotchi no yoru ♪
Rice and chopping and rice.
♪ Ue o muite arukou ♪
♪ Nijinda hosi o kazoete ♪
.
♪ Omoidasu natsunohi ♪
Going shopping?
.
♪ Omoidasu natsunohi ♪
Sort of.
.
♪ Omoidasu natsunohi ♪
Hop on. I'll give you a ride
to the bottom of the hill.
Don't worry about this. I can brake
just fine with three fingers.
Wadaya' say?
♪ Shiawase wa kumo no ue ni ♪
Uh-huh.
♪ Shiawase wa sora no ue ni ♪
.
♪ Ue o muite arukou ♪
I thought you were at your meeting?
.
♪ Ue o muite arukou ♪
Yeah I was, but I left.
I gotta get back home before my curfew.
♪ Namida ga kobore nai you ni ♪
.
Did you finish printing
♪ Namida ga kobore nai you ni ♪
The mid term mock test?
.
♪ Nakinagara aruku ♪
Not even close.
I'll get in early tomorrow
♪ Nakinagara aruku ♪
And do it before school starts.
.
♪ Hitoribotchi no yoru ♪
Shun, do you mind if I ask you a question?
Huh?
About the poem in the paper...
♪
Hang on!
You were saying?
Uh-uh.
Nothing.
♪ Omoidasu aki no hi ♪
♪ Hitoribotchi no yoru ♪
Thank you Shun.
♪ Kanashimi wa hosh ino kage ni ♪
.
Hi Mr. Ishide,
♪ Kanashimi wa hosh ino kage ni ♪
I need some sliced pork please.
Hi Umi.
♪ Kanashimi wa tsuki no kage ni ♪
Two to go please.
Because its for you,
♪ Kanashimi wa tsuki no kage ni ♪
Theirs a little extra.
Your very kind.
♪ Kanashimi wa tsuki no kage ni ♪
.
♪ Ue o muite arukou ♪
Have a good evening.
.
♪ Ue o muite arukou ♪
Thanks for waiting.
.
♪ Namida ga kobore naiyouni ♪
Have one.
.
♪ Namida ga kobore naiyouni ♪
You won't make it on an empty stomach.
Where do you live?
♪ Nakinagara aruku ♪
.
Downtown.
♪ Nakinagara aruku ♪
Oh, that's pretty far.
.
♪ Hitoribotchi no yoru ♪
Gotta go.
.
♪ Hitoribotchi no yoru ♪
Thanks for the ride!
Your welcome.
♪ Hitoribotchi no yoru ♪
.
♪ Hitoribochi no yoru ♪
This is nice.
♪
Sachiko, can I come in?
Are you not feeling well?
Uugg.
You'd better go ahead without me.
Wake up Sachiko.
Whoa...
I know...
Bah! The colors are wrong
when I paint at night.
It's beautiful.
What's this?
That's a boat I often see passing by.
This might sound crazy but I think
it's answering your flags.
Oh yeah, you can't see it from the garden.
Answering my flags?
What day is it?
Good morning.
Morning Shun, did you finish?
All printed up. Would you
like to see your handy work?
Look at that.
Shun I ah...
There was something printed in the
paper I wanted to ask you about?
O-Kay.
Um, now might not be the best
time, maybe just after school?
Yeah, I was going to ask you
to do some more stencils so
maybe we can meet at the club house?
That works.
It'll have to be tomorrow though
because theirs a big debate today.
- Do you wanna' come?
- I'd love to.
But I have too much I have to get done.
- But I'll try.
- Sure ok.
Umi, wait up!
You wanna' get ice cream.
I thought you had practice?
It was canceled because
of that stupid debate.
I can't go, Τomoko's off today
and I really should get home early.
This way for the historic debate. Future
of the Latin Quarter to be decided.
[RESOLVED THE LATIN QUARTER SHOULD BE PRESERVED!]
Alright. Good. Stop there.
This is gonna get rough.
Umi.  You heading home? At least I got
you a really nice flounder.
Um, sure, I'll take some.
Coming right up.
Hay is your mom
back from America?
Not yet.
I'll come back for the fish later!
How much later?
Stuck a new state of the arts
student center in it's place!
Transformation in transition.
We've suffered the scars of war
and have emerged a stronger people.
A peaceful people.
A modern people.
A Tokyo where we can
showcase our new democracy.
We can not stand in the way of progress.
The Tokyo exhibition
will showcase our democracy
as a prime leader in democracy...
Oh, Umi!
What's he yelling about?
I have no idea.
We still cling to the past.
It is time we throw these old buildings out
as relics of a bygone era.
Our poles say 80% of you
want the Latin Quarter torn down.
Ah ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-ha-haa.
You're ideas of democracy make me laugh.
We've come here to debate, you
already made up our minds for us.
Sit back down or I'll have you thrown out!
Your just like the old
men who run this country.
Domining ever with the new.
Listen!
If you're so hell-bent on demolition,
demolish your shortsighted thinking!...
That's enough! Sit down!
You cannot move into the future
without first knowing the past!
Destroy everything old and you dishonor
those who lived and died before us.
The Olympics has the whole country
thinking all that glitters is gold.
Well I say its not!
And just because the majority disagrees
doesn't mean were going
down without a fight!
Anarchists! Charge!
Here they come.
Stand fast!
Stand fast, men!
You love history.
You're history!
Very graceful.
♪ I still remember
that day long ago. ♪
♫ You looked away, but I saw
you crying for me. ♫
♫ “Sayonara” you
said, my love. ♫
♫ When morning came you
left an ivory flower. ♫
♫ My own memory of you. ♫
♫ I walk alone still
hoping to find you. ♫
♫ The flower that blooms
inside of my heart. ♫
♪ I walk alone still
hoping to find you. ♪
♪ The flower that blooms
inside of my heart. ♪
Umi,
so what did you think?
I think it was amazing.
You're all so passionate.
Yeah, debates are always like that.
I hate that everyone thinks the
clubhouse is just an eyesore.
They don't care what's going on inside.
You really think so?
[When I was first in love]
[Teshima Aoi]
Hey, I know. Why don't you
all just clean the place up?
It's a great old building but no
one can see through the dust.
So clean it up.  Make it look like new again.
Make it cool.  Maybe invite a few girls.
Then the boys will like it too.
You're probably right.
I would just have
to convince everyone
that dust isn't an important
part of its history.
The physics midterm mock
test was a huge success.
I think it won you guys
more then a few admirers.
Me included.
Hey, well um...
Here are the stencils. Thanks again.
- Bye Shun.
- Bye Umi.
And thanks for the advise.
Forgot about the fish!
There was such a big fight
and we were going to be
in so much trouble but
Mizunuma got them all to start singing
and the teachers were totally fooled.
Sounds like nothing's changed.
When I was there that stuff
happened all the time.
Your president Mizunuma is the
little brother of a classmate of mine.
Really?
Was his brother also a genius?
His sister. She's an astrophysicist.
Wow...
Here ya' go doctor, from my secret stash.
Is that whiskey?
As a matter of fact, it is.
Oh, glasses.
- Can I have some?
- Sora, your too young.
Hay, how about we invite some of the guys
from school to my going away party?
Ooh, what guys?
The really cute ones.
Really cute what?
Hey Umi.
H - O - K - U - T...
Hokuto.
Hay, I didn't know you
could read signal flags?
Thank you both for coming.
Umi we're ready.
Ok.
Forgive my sense of tradition
but why not get married
and start a practice right here.
Would that mean we'd all have to move out?
You'll probably be married by then.
Oh, if only that were true.
I'm going to marry a man
who's brilliant but sensitive.
Ooh, is he here?
The trustees are the problem.
We can't let them tear the place down.
Agreed. What can we do?
We need to go over their heads.
To who, the principal just
does what the board tells him.
I don't know...
We all just need to be
really smart about this.
We need a strategy.
We need one fast before its too late.
We keep running out of glasses.
Well, I'll wash some.
- You take that out.
- Ok.
Ok every one, Sushi's ready.
Yes!
This building was built
at the turn of the century.
It actually used to be a hospital.
See that carving up there?
It's over a hundred years old.
My Great Grandfather loved cats.
Compared to the clubhouse, this
all looks practically brand new.
It's incredible.
And I'm guessing your part
of the reason why.
Uh-huh.
So your Grandfather was a doctor.
Was your dad a doctor too?
Uh-uh.  He was the captain of a ship.
♫ From this valley
they say you are going. ♫
♫ We will miss your bright
eyes and your smile. ♫
♫ Far from us you are
taking the sunshine. ♫
So your mom married a sailor.
My Grandpa and Grand, they didn't
approve of the marriage
and so they tried to stop
it from happening.
But my mom wouldn't let anything
stand in the way of true love.
That took guts.
See defied her parents
and marred him anyway?
Uh-huh.
And your dad, he taught you
how to use the signal flags?
Yeah he did. When I was just a girl.
He said they helped him
find his way back to us.
So I raised them every day.
That was at our old house.
I raise them from the balcony
until his ship docked again.
Everyday.
Every single day.
Then, we got news
about his ship.
That it sank during the Korean war.
They never found him and that was that.
But I kept raising the flags
hoping they might help him find me.
And when we moved here, I was so
upset I couldn't stop crying.
There was nowhere
to raise the flags.
I felt so lost.
So Grandpa built
me that flagpole.
We could use a little light.
Grandmother said, this used
to be my Grandfather's office.
But now it's sorta' becomes
my mom's private study.
She sure likes to read.
This is your family?
Yes.
Your father?
Uh-uh.
That's my Grandfather.
My dad's right there.
Handsome isn't he?
That's from around the
time they got married.
Now this is the photo
I really love.
Υuichiro Sawamura?
That's my dad name. My mom
kept the name Matsuzaki.
Umi, come on, your gonna
miss Miki's speech.
Ok, coming. We better get back.
Thanks for coming.
Goodbye.
Hay, I'm home.
You're late.
When your late your mother worries.
Mmm.
Shun, would you like some dinner?
I ate already.
≡⚡ and here's the pitch. ⚡≡
≡⚡ Nagashima swings! And he misses.
Nagashima strikes out. ⚡≡
Now this is the photo I really love.
Onodera Sawamura Τachibana
They never found him.
Υuichiro Sawamura...
Welcome.
Thanks for coming.
Ohh!
We members of the Latin Quarter
welcome, all volunteers.
And for offering
to help us to restore
and preserve this treasured
and magnificent cultural landmark,
we humbly salute you.
Ohh!
Fellow club members, are you ready
to fight for what you cherish?
Yeah!
Let's get to work!
No! My hut!
- No exceptions.
- That's the rule.
Ok men. Lift.
Hay watch out.
No, no, no! The rail!...
Watch out below!
- Aah!-Ahh!
- Ahh!
Hey, your welcome.
1st year math... 2nd year math...
Wow, these are really old exams.
We use all these for the
mock test we print.
Woa! This is Miki's math final.
She got a perfect score.
Oh.
I gotta go.
Yamazaki, take over for me will you?
Sure thing.
Here Umi.
Huh? Oh!
Mizunuma said to toss
anything we don't need.
No reason to get sentimental.
Ugh, what a mess.
Didn't you guys ever clean this place?
Nope, and neither did the guys before us.
Eugh.
I think tomorrow we better
bring the badminton team.
We love badminton.
Wow its really hot.
Fire often is.
Sora, its time to go home now.
Okay.
I'm just gonna stay
a little while longer.
Bye.
So what's going on between you and Umi?
Uh, nothing's going on.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah.
Father, there something
I would like to ask you.
I have to concentrate so make it short.
Υuichiro Sawamura, is the man in this
photo and he's my real father right?
We've already discussed all of this.
You're my son and that's that.
Hum.
We didn't know what to think
the night he brought you.
We had recently lost a child of our own and
were struggling through a difficult time.
Sawamura came to our
door with you in his arms
and a copy of his family
register in his pocket.
The war had taken its toll.
He was going off to sea and his wife
was unable to care for you.
Before I knew it,
your mother had you
in her arms, nursing you.
She wouldn't let you go.
Sawamura was a good sailor.
In the Korean war he was on the supply
ship that sank and all of the men died.
He sent money and asked about you often.
You remind me of him
more and more everyday.
But you will always be our son.
Thank you father.
Sachiko do you see it? Is there any answer?
Not yet.
I guess its not coming by today.
[THE LATIN QUARTER REBORN!]
Hello Miki.
Umi, come on in.
You're really leaving aren't you?
We all have to move on don't we.
I wish I could see you off.
It's ok, I know you have to get to school.
I'm going to miss you.
I'll drop by now and then.
Now, go, before I start crying.
Uh-huh.
I hope everything works
out with you and Shun.
Take care Miki.
Extra extra extra. Latin
Quarter gets a face lift.
Thanks very much. Here you go.
Extra edition of the
Latin Quarter Weekly.
Thank you
Latin Quarter gets a face lift.
We'll need your help today. Thanks.
- Extra, extra!
- Extra edition Latin Quarter Weekly.
There ya' go. Thank you.
- I'll be there again today.
- Great, still lots to do.
Hi Shun, how's it all going?
Fine.
I'll see you there later, all right?
Spread the word.
Extra, extra extra! Get
your Latin Quarter Weekly. Extra.
Extra, extra. Read all about it.
Latin Quarter Weekly right here.
The next label is complete.
Ok.
Don't hurt yourself Shun.
He's so brave.
Don't fall.
- Man, he's cool.
- Totally cool.
Oh.
Ok, I'm confused. Why are you mad at me?
Υuichiro Sawamura,
is my real father.
Huh?
It's like a cheap melodrama.
I don't understand.
I didn't want to believe it either. But
I checked with city hall and it's true.
No.
Umi, we're brother and sister.
So what do we do now?
I guess, we stopped feeling how we feel.
We'll just have to go
back to being friends.
Hey, Sora, did something
happen to Umi at school today?
I don't think so. At least
not that I'm aware of.
Are you certain?
That dinner was surprisingly odd.
And she was soaking wet.
Something must've happened.
Umi's never made a bad
meal that I can remember.
- Mmm.
It's me Umi, the bath's ready.
Not tonight.
You ok?
Umi?
Umi.
Umi!
Good morning, Umi.
Did you sleep well?
Mom? Your home. When did you get back?
Don't be silly. You know
I've been here all along.
Umi, I'm hoisting the flags.
Come give me a hand.
Dad is that you?
Your flags led me home Umi.
You're such a big girl now.
As Latin Quarter alumni,
we are more than happy to help.
And if you need more supplies,
Jiro here is in construction.
So just give him a call.
Not for free!
No? Why not? You told me
business was booming didn't you?
Goodbye and good luck to ya'.
- Thank you very much.
That was cool.
Good thing we went to Miki's party.
That Umi comes through for us again.
She must be our goddess of good luck.
- Hi guys.
- Hi guys. - Morning.
- Morning.
Wow, this looks like a real
construction site.
- You call that plastering?
- Well ah…
Give me that trowel and let
me show you how it's done.
First you have to swirl it into a smooth
paste to get all the lumps out.
Then up,
over, left,
right, left,
right, spin and up.
Awesome!
Yeah, they don't call my dad
the plaster king for nothing.
You are beautiful.
What did you say?
The wall, I was talking to the wall.
No you weren't.
Hey.
It's already looking better.
Sorry you had to stay late.
I hope you won't be in trouble.
Sora actually agreed to cover for me.
Anything you need help with Shun.
Mmm, ah, well.
These papers need transcribing.
Ok.
So, is that all you need from me?
Yup', that's all I can think of.
At least for now.
- Ok then.
- Ok.
So, everything cool between you two?
All cool.
New Latin Quarter Weekly!
Details about the renovation.
Read about the new building,
then see for yourself.
Hot off the press. Majority
of girls oppose demolition!
Read about it in the
Latin Quarter Weekly.
Midterm results announced,
another victory for
Latin Quarter Mock Test.
More mock test in this
week's Latin Quarter Weekly.
New poll results give new
life to old building.
Read about it here.
Majority of all students
opposed demolition.
Everybody ready?
Hooray!
Umi, don't go anywhere!
Shun, we're holding an emergency meeting.
The board just voted to tear down the
Latin Quarter over the summer break!
I did, I tried reasoning with them.
Believe me.
But the principle says,
it's out of his hands.
What about all our hard work!
They decided without even looking at it?
The massive ego's wouldn't
fit through the doors.
Right!
Let's start a revolt!
Why don't we just take it
straight to the chairman.
The chairman's running
a huge company in Tokyo.
We'll never get to see him.
In the words of Plato:
Tyranny must not prevail.
Go! Flight the good fight!
Let's go to Tokyo and make our case.
That's right Shun.
Please!
You have to.
Only, if our goddess of good luck joins us.
Umi! Of course she'll go.
Hey Umi, good luck tomorrow.
Mmm.
Good morning thanks for waiting.
You're welcome.
We're very happy you're coming with us.
Me too. It'll help take my
mind off... other... things.
Yes, ok, let's go.
[A SUCCESSFUL OLYMPIC,
MAKE TOKYO BEAUTIFUL]
Well, into the breech?
Uh-huh.
Students from the Konαn Academy.
That's right.
You don't have an appointment?
No sir. We're appealing directly
to Mr. Tokumaru.
Something about a direct appeal.
Nope. No, they don't seem like radicals.
There's three of them.
All right, I'll tell them.
Take the elevator at the end
of the hall to the fourth floor
and his office will be on the right.
Thank you very much for your help.
Don't forget to sign in.
And next time make an appointment.
Are you those students from Konan?
Ma'am.
Mr. Tokumaru is a very busy man.
He doesn't normally see people
who haven't made an appointment.
Yes ma'am, we understand.
But speaking frankly ma'am,
we didn't actually believe we would get
an appointment if we called to make one.
Ma'am.
Your probably
wasting your time...
But since you seemed determined.
You can wait on the bench as long
as you don't disturb anyone.
We thank you for your time ma'am.
I wanna hear Nagashima's heavy.
He could win another MVP.
He scored a lotta' goals.
"Goals???" Have you even seen baseball?
Thank you ma'am.
Ooh!
- Let's go get a drink.
- Quick before he makes us stay.
Your still here? Well, come on in.
Thank you.
- Ah yes. Right.
- Thank you for seeing us.
Uh-huh.
Yes.
Uh... hang on.
Have a seat.
I'll be with you gentlemen in a minute.
Alright I've made my decision.
I can't agree to that right now.
Yes.
Bye.
Sit down.
Why are you kids here
today and not in school?
Because sir, we escaped.
Escaped huh. I did
that a lot myself.
Well I guess you're here to talk
to me about that old clubhouse.
Yes, we've come to you directly to ask
you to see the building for yourself.
We've put a lot of work into it.
Come see what we've done
that all were asking.
What year are you young lady?
Second year. My name is Umi Matsuzaki.
Sir, that building is more
than just a building.
And tell me, how is it "more
than just a building?"
Because, we all love it.
And it makes us feel
connected to our past.
Like we belong to something.
"Connected to our past."
Hum...
May I ask what your father did?
He was a captain...
on a supply ship..
But his ship sank during the Korean war.
It made a delivery and were coming home.
But his ship hit a mine.
Hum.
A supply ship?
Yes sir.
I'm sorry.
I know it must've been very hard
for your mother, raising you on her own.
She obviously did a fine job.
Thank you.
All right, I'll go.
Thank you Mr. Chairman!
So tomorrow.
How's it look?
Right, that's in the evening.
Move the rest to Friday.
Now, I'll be there
tomorrow afternoon.
I'll handel everything with your principal,
the rest will be your job.
I actually didn't think that would work.
Yeah, I'm not sure it has.
Well, I'm glad we came.
I promised my mom I'd go visit my uncle.
See you tomorrow.
♪ Hitoribotchi no yoru ♪
♪
What do you think you'll do,
you know after graduation?
Mmm, well, we don't have much money
so probably National University.
What will happen to The Weekly?
I'll have to find somebody
dedicated enough to take over.
What about you?
I haven't decided but...
I'm sort of thinking I might
like to be a doctor.
Mmm.
Shun, are you...
Are you the one who wrote
that poem in the paper?
Uh-huh.
I saw those flags every morning
from my dad's tugboat,
and I found out it was you.
Well, I can't really see any of
the boats from the garden.
So that's why, I never noticed there
was somebody out there answering me.
Can I tell you something?
Huh.
Those flags that I raise...
There a message to my father that's
says, "I pray for your safe return."
But he knows he can
never come back to me.
So what I think he did
was send you instead.
And I don't really know
what to do because we're...
Umi...
Look I know we can't do anything
about it but just know
I love you.
And I love you too.
Ok, I'm home.
Mom, your home!
Umi, it's good to be back.
Tell me about America and your study's?
Oh, I learned something new every day.
But mostly how much I missed home.
And we missed you.
- This is the best thing I ever ate!
- Uh-huh.
It's beef jerky.
So is it pork?
Sachiko, beef means cow.
Mom?
What's wrong? Why are you awake?
There's something I need
to talk to you about.
Of course Umi.
It must be the time change.
I can't sleep, so I thought I'd organize
these books I got in America.
There's this boy at school
his name is Shun Kazama.
I'm so confused because he
came here for Miki's party
and I showed him
the photograph of dad
and he had the exact same photo.
And he said his father and my father
were one in the same.
This photo?
Uh-huh.
Well, I knew the day would come when
I would have to explain this to you.
I told you the story about how your
father and I eloped. Didn't I?
Uh-huh.
And you remember where we used to live?
Downtown in that second-floor apartment
with the balcony off the living room.
We were newly married
and I was pregnant with you.
And your dad was
away at sea a lot,
and I was working on my
degree studying very hard.
I was determined to do well in school,
in case something happened.
Our lives were already complicated.
When your father returned
home that night with a baby.
Hey?
Welcome...
Υuichiro, whose baby is that?
He's Τachibana's.
We need to take him.
What?
Τachibana was killed in an accident
aboard a repatriation ship.
His poor wife died from
complications during childbirth.
The rest of his family
was killed at Nagasaki.
I won't have this child
sent to an orphanage.
Your father had legally adopted a
newborn baby without even asking me.
The war had just ended. And things
like this was were happening everywhere.
Still, there was just no way I could give
the child the love and care it deserved.
One of Υuichiro's friend recently lost
a child, so we gave the baby to him.
How is he? Tell me, is he doing well?
Uh-huh.
I'm glad.
Your father was impulsive but he always
did what he thought was right.
It was a relief to see the baby
end up with a loving family.
Are you absolutely sure that Shun
couldn't possibly be dads real son?
I don't think I ever considered it.
Why do you ask?
Don't tell me he actually
looks like your father.
Uh-huh.
Oh Umi.
Sweetheart.
- See you tonight.
- Yeah mom, see you tonight.
Have a great day girls.
Mmm.
Hello again Mr. Chairman and welcome.
Egh.
[LATIN QUARTER WELCOMES
CHAIRMAN ΤOKUMΑRU]
Never knew this existed
underneath all that dust.
Oh yes sir, they've done a good job.
And what is your club studying young man?
Sir! The astronomy club has been studying
sunspots for the last 10 years. Sir!
The last 10 years huh?
Tell me, what discoveries have you made?
That the sun is very very old
and our life span is very very short.
No discoveries so far! Sir!
Honest answer.
Philosophy club?
Seems to me you could really benefit
from a brand new clubhouse.
Something nice for your junior members?
We as human beings have complicated
every simple gift of the gods.
Quoting Diogenes!
I must say principle these students
of yours are very very impressive.
I'm gonna take a little look inside.
- Shun Kazama?
- Yes.
Well where's Plato?
And what's that dog doing in there?
Hello, dad? What's wrong?
The third man in that photo
is here at the harbor.
I know he can tell you about your father.
But his ship is leaving at… four o'clock.
And he'll be away for several months.
Get here!
Get here fast!
♪ If the world should
sink beneath the sea. ♪
♪ Reach out your hand
and find a friend in need. ♪
♫ Brave the storm
with head held high ♫
♫ stand together side by side. ♫
♫ Just like the mighty
mountains ♫
♫ rising high above the fields. ♫
♫ If we all stand together ♫
♫ then there is nothing
that will make us a yield. ♫
♫ If the world should
sink beneath the sea ♫
♫ reach out your hand and find
a friend in need. ♫
♫ Brave the storm
with head held high ♫
♫ stand together side by side. ♫
Students, while I am very
impressed with your dedication,
it doesn't change the fact,
that a new building is needed.
So I guess that makes it my job
to find a different place to put it.
All right!
Umi, you did it.
We all did it.
Thank you, thank you sir.
Hooray!
On to the next experiment.
None of this would have happened without our goddess Umi.
Thanks but I... really didn't do anything.
Come on, quit being so modest
and say you're welcome.
She's right.
You are heaven sent!
Thank you, Umi.
Thank you.
She's our little angel, Umi.
Umi!
You have to come!
The perfect couple.
Good luck!
Sorry sir,
I am certain Umi and Shun wish they could
be here to thank you personally.
But urgent matters have taken them away.
Urgent matters eh.
Ah, to be young.
Hay Shun!
Gen! Can you give us a ride?
Umi!
Ahh!
Umi, don't you worry and hang on.
I'll get you there with time to spare.
If we're going to make it we'd better run!
Ok.
Thanks Gen!
Sorry I could get you there, Umi!
Shun. Hurry!
Thanks.
That's my dad's tug.
C'mon.
The kids are here to see you captain.
- Push our departure back 15.
- Ay.
So when, you're my good
friend Τachibana's boy.
Yes sir.
And you must be
Sawamura's daughter.
Pleasure to meet you both.
Your name is Shun, right?
Yes sir.
Your father was Hiroshi Τachibana.
And that's him sitting in the front
row, fourth from the right.
And sitting next to him is Sawamura.
We were just like brothers,
the three of us.
Τachibana, you should
take the seat of honor.
But why me?
Because you're our fearless leader.
You belong there.
If I'm your leader, we're in trouble.
Don't be the hero and die before me, ok.
Same goes for you.
Gentlemen, hold still.
They were the best friend's a man ever had.
I think about them every day.
They were brave and honest and I am
honored to have known them.
When I look at you, what I see is
the legacy of those two great man.
And I know they would be very proud.
♪ Hikaru umi ni kasumu fune wa ♪
The ship veiled in the shining sea
♪ sayonara no kiteki nokoshimasu ♪
leaves a whistle of the good-bye.
♪ Yurui saka wo orite yukeba ♪
If I go down the gentle slope
♪ Natsu iro no kaze ni aeru kashira ♪
will I meet the wind of summer color?
♪ Watashi no ai sore wa melody ♪
My love, it's a melody.
♪ Takaku hikuku utau no ♪
i sing highly and low.
♪ Watashi no ai sore wa kamome ♪
My love, it's a gull.
♪ Takaku hikuku tobu no ♪
I fly highly and low.
♪ Yuuhi no naka yonde mitara ♪
If I call for you in the setting sun
♪ Yasashii anata ni aeru kashira ♪
will I meet tender you?
♪ Sanpo michi ni yureru kigi wa ♪
Trees shaking in a promenade
♪ Sayonara no kage wo otoshimasu ♪
cast a good-bye shadow.
♪ Furui chapel kazami no tori ♪
Can the weathercock of an old chapel
♪ Natsu iro no machi wa mieru kashira ♪
see the town of summer color?
♪ Kinou no ai sore wa namida ♪
The yesterday love, it's tears.
♪ Yagate kawaki kieru no ♪
It dries before long and disappears.
♪ Ashita no ai sore wa refrain ♪
The tomorrow love, it's a refrain.
♪ Owari no nai kotoba ♪
Words without the end.
♪ Yuuhi no naka meguri aeba ♪
If I meet you in the setting sun
♪ Anata wa watashi wo daku kashira ♪
will you hug me?
The natto* is sticky as can be.
* a traditional Japanese food made from
soybeans fermented with bacillus subtilis.
Stir the miso* in a pot.
* a traditional Japanese seasoning.
Original translation by Jim Hubbert
and Rieko Izutsu-vajirasarn.
Original subtitles by Oura.
English dub subtitles by:
MightyMike77020
and C. Guzman.
A studio Ghibli film.
Events and characters depicted
in this film are fictional.