Oh, shit.
Duffy split.
Yeah, fuckin Duffy, Cavanagh, Tyrell
Duffy rolls outta here
in a brand new Cadillac.
Has the nerve to ask me to clean out
his fucking locker and save it for him.
Probably has dirty
pictures of his wife.
I don't know what
the fuck is in here.
Uh-huh.
He does have dirty
pictures of his wife.
Yes. He does.
Fuck he met her at hooters.
You like that, huh?
All right. Here is
what I'm gonna do.
I'm gonna keep them.
Well, now, I gotta
answer to Duffy for that.
I'll answer to him.
I mean he is a duffus but
he's not a bad guy.
Fuck Duffy. Just fuck
him. Fuck all of them.
Five copies of
an arrest report.
If the prisoner was transported, there
wouldn't still be five copies here.
Duffy might've left him downstairs.
What's his name? Chavez.
Let's go find him.
Who's there?
It's strange, 'cause the manifest
says the prisoners all evacuated.
Anything's possible
in this storm.
I feel a bet coming on.
Shall we open the casino?
Please.
All right. Up to his nose by 4:00.
What the fuck took you
so long, man? Please.
Please what, shitbird?
Get me the fuck outta here,
man. The water's rising.
It's been rising for like three
hours. It's already up to my neck.
I'm not gonna be able to stand here long,
man. I'll drown. The water doesn't stop.
Get me the fuck outta here. There's
fucking snakes and shit in this water.
Twenty bucks and the Polaroid
he says nothing before five.
Twenty bucks. What the fuck is that? Let's
make it worth our while, at least. A dime.
I'm not betting
you $1,000.
Five hundred.
Get me the fuck outta here,
man! The water keeps rising.
Two hundred
and the polaroids.
Please, motherfuckers.
Please what, shit turd?
Got a broke leg. Please,
get me out of here.
Wait a minute. You want me
to get wet on account of you?
Think the world
owes you a living, huh?
I'll drown.
Hey, man, I got on
Swiss cotton underpants.
Yeah, that's right.
Cost me $55 a pair.
You think I wanna get all this
brown water and shit over them?
That don't come out.
You got underwear on
that cost $55?
My girl gave them to me.
Come on, we get the time
of death from autopsy.
What are you doing?
Hold this.
Oh, come on, man.
Let the Fire Department get
him out. What are you, crazy?
He ain't worth it!
Come on, man.
You are crazy.
You okay, man?
You okay?
The good news, Terence, is I'll
okay you to return to full duty.
The bad news is
that in all likelyhood
you'll be experiencing
moderate to severe back pain.
How severe?
You'll wanna be taking
something for it.
Gonna write you a
prescription for Vicodin.
For how long?
From now on.
No. For how long
am I gonna have pain?
We're gonna try to manage
this as along as we can.
For the rest
of my life?
Probably. But they're making
advancements every day, so,
just work with me
on this, all right?
Now, when this runs
out, call the office.
Thank you for helping me
honor our fallen heroes today.
We will now move on to
the awards and promotions.
Among those being promoted
to lieutenant today,
it gives me
great pleasure
to additionally award the
Distinguish Service Cross
to Sergeant now Lieutenant
Terence McDonagh,
in recognition of extreme
valor in the line of duty.
Congratulations, Lieutenant.
There's three more.
You don't wanna look.
It's execution style.
What did you
come up with?
Scale in the closet, bundle
of glass in envelopes.
Dob been around?
I thought he went away.
He's out. I saw him the other day.
Let's get him in.
His baby mama is over by
General Taylor and Annunciation.
Uniforms doing the canvass?
The duty captain
sent them out.
Whoever they talk to, I want
followed up by a member of the squad.
You'll see to that
personally, Armand.
Are they pulling
security cameras?
Yeah.
Every license plate
in the area.
Got it.
My Friend
by Babacar Ndele.
"My friend is a fish.
"He live in my room.
"His fin is a cloud.
He see me
when I sleep. "
Couple's name: Dauta
and Yasin Ndele.
Dauta's mother's name:
Ramatullai Ndele.
Children's names:
Animata and Babacar.
Family's from Senegal.
Immigration status: illegal.
From what we know,
Dauta had been dealing heroin to
supplement his income as a peddler.
Now, I want
every drug dealer,
every junkie within
a five-mile radius
hassled into giving up
who his supplier was.
Due to the nature
of this crime,
you've got full authorization
for overtime if you need it.
Lieutenant McDonagh's gonna be
heading up the investigation,
so coordinate with him.
That's it. Let's see some results.
McDonagh, see you in
my office for a minute.
You up to this?
Why wouldn't I be?
I know you're still having
problems with your back.
Dealing with being in
pain a lot of the time.
I'm managing.
You still taking
medication for it?
Only what
the doctor prescribes.
Ordinarily there'd be somebody
with more time on the job
handling this kind
of investigation.
But I'm gonna go out on a limb with
you 'cause you got good instincts
and don't do nothing'
but work.
But if I find that you needed
help and didn't ask for it,
I will be mad.
Yes, Sir.
How is your
old man doing?
He's drinking himself
into an early grave.
Give him my best,
would you?
I will.
Lieutenant, no more
unnecessary jumps, huh?
Yes, Sir.
Good morning,
Mr. McDonagh.
Hi, honey.
You bring me something?
You're out already?
Yes.
Mm.
Frankie, hi. This is Andy.
Hey, hey, hey! Hoping to see
if you have any time tonight.
I'm at the Monteleone.
You need to call him back?
No.
You know I'd rather go
to the Monteleone with you.
I can't afford it.
I can.
I can afford it.
Yeah?
Who brought him in?
That's who's
questioning him?
I'll be there in ten minutes.
Tell him I'm on my way.
Tell him if he puts his hands on
this guy, he's gonna have a problem.
I don't give a shit, Armand. You
tell him to take a fucking break!
Excuse me. Could you tell me
how much longer that's gonna be?
Hello, Miss? I'm a Lieutenant
in the Police Department.
I'm in the middle of
a homicide investigation.
Can I get my
prescription, please?
Do you see
I'm on the phone?
Hey, you can't
come back here.
You got me waiting 40 minutes so you
can make a fucking personal phone call!
Security. Security to Pharmacy.
Security to Pharmacy, please.
This is it. This is
it. Police emergency.
You're no cop.
What's that look like?
Why are you acting
all crazy for?
This is, uh, $23
with my copay, right?
There's 40. Give
everybody a drink.
Get the fuck
out of my way.
Dob, look at me.
Okay?
Two hours.
That's enough.
Tell me something
I don't know.
Man, you gotta
get me outta here.
Get you outta here?
Are you crazy?
I got you on possession.
You're on parole.
Maybe but one
skinny ass joint.
That joint's gonna
get you back.
I've got five
dead people, man.
You understand?
I don't know
nothin' about it.
Tell me something.
What do you
want me to tell you?
I want you to tell me something I haven't
heard. I don't want you to tell me,
look at me, I don't want you to
tell me that you don't know nothing.
But I don't know nothing.
Did you tell him
what I said?
You understand
what that means?
I'm entitled to whatever
I want in this room.
That means Guantanamo Bay.
You believe this motherfucker?
I've busted my ass for yambos
and this yambo won't tell me shit.
Detective, can I see you
outside for a second?
Uh, yeah, sure.
Two minutes.
Think about it.
Uh, not a great time
to take a break.
What are you doing?
He's about to go.
Bullshit. He's scared out of his mind.
You and your partner made a
spectacle out of picking him up.
Everyone in Central City knows
he's in here. No, just shush.
You think he's gonna go out if
you keep insulting him like that?
You trying to tell me
how to do my interrogation?
Yes. I'm gonna tell you when
you're doing something wrong.
Go fuck yourself.
I'm gonna treat
you respectfully.
You treat me respectfully.
I'm looking at some bullshit pot
busting. Because you're on parole
you wind up back in Angola.
Why would you do that?
I ain't the one
doing it.
Who did this African
guy piss off?
I never said two words
to him. I don't know.
But you knew he was
selling dope. Come on.
Shall I call your parole officer?
He'll violate you, stop wasting my time.
I knew he was selling.
Okay. Tell me where he was
selling, whose neighborhood was it.
Man, look. I got me a good
job at a cleaning service.
I check in when
I'm supposed to.
I smoke a little
weed, but that's it.
Tell me whose
neighborhood it was, Dob.
Man.
You know Fate?
Big Fate? Yeah.
Ain't nothin' moved that part of
town. He ain't got a piece of it.
Where can I find him?
Shit. I'm saying
all I am gonna say.
If you want me to lead you to
him, you well just lock me up.
Check Stevie's arrest
report on Dob.
If it mentions marijuana,
make sure it gets lost.
What do I tell Stevie?
You can tell him
to go fuck himself.
I'm gonna go upstairs and
crash an hour in the crib.
What do you want, Mundt?
Internal Affairs is checking
the property room vouchers.
So?
That means they're gonna
find out the shit missing.
Not if you don't
tell them, they won't.
I can't do it
anymore, Terence.
Oh, fuck.
I'm-I'm really sorry.
I just can't.
Mundt,
whatever drugs might've been
taken out of the property room,
you will have a
voucher, you understand?
They won't turn up as missing, 'cause
there's no record of them being there
in the first
place, okay?
They're installing cameras.
So then you
don't do anything
where the cameras
can see you.
I can't.
When it was me re-doing paperwork
to cover the cash you misplaced,
that was all right. That was
entirely fucking reasonable.
I'm sorry.
Hey, Mundt.
Hey, Mundt?
You bad boy.
Oh, yeah.
Stand against the wall.
Come on! Stand
against the wall.
You're too busy making
out with your girlfriend
you don't know when you've
done something illegal?
What are we
high on tonight?
Nothing.
You passed drugs
in that club?
No.
The two of you match a description. Empty
your pockets and dump out the handbag.
Why?
I said you match
a description.
Somebody seen
passing drugs.
I wasn't passing drugs.
What does that even mean?
Empty your pockets. Dump out the
handbag. I'm not gonna tell you again.
This is bullshit!
Just do what
he says, okay?
What you got in there?
Nothing.
I'm not gonna
get stuck, am I?
No.
I get stuck, I'm gonna
be very fucking angry.
You're not
gonna get stuck.
Where's your badge
if you're a cop?
Here's what
I'm looking for.
Here's where it
says I'm a cop.
Sir, it-it's obviously
just for personal use.
I mean,
I'm not a dealer.
That's for
the DA to decide.
You're gonna dump that
bag or I gotta do it?
Sir, is-is there any way my parents
don't have to find out about this?
I mean, can we, can we just handle this?
I'll go to jail on weekends or
something like that if I have to do that.
My father has a
heart condition, okay?
This would kill him. Please.
Just let me keep this from him.
You think he want
might to know?
Yeah. I'd wanna know
if you were my child.
Here.
This fur is nothing, but
this was my grandmother's.
It's worth $60,000.
You can give it
to your girlfriend.
If you don't have
a girlfriend,
you can give it
to your mother.
It's attempted bribery.
Excuse me!
This is worth $60,000.
Doesn't that get
us pass attempted?
Where's the rock at?
Come on, come on,
who's got the kibble?
You wanna hit?
Yes.
Jesus Christ.
Again.
Yeah?
Are you fucking
kidding me?
This what's gonna take? Yeah?
You're worried about
your father finding out?
No.
What about your mother?
I don't give a shit
about either one of them.
Did they beat you?
No.
Molest you?
Didn't buy you new clothes
at back to school, huh?
Didn't see you in the
high school play, huh?
I wonder what'd they
say if they saw you now.
Smokin' crack.
Going out with
no panties on?
No panties?
I bet they think about you
when you were a little girl.
Wonder what the hell
happened to ya?
Don't fucking move!
You stand there and watch!
You watch her! Watch
your fucking girlfriend.
Fuck!
I need the coke back.
What happened?
I snorted what I thought was
coke. It turned out to be heroin.
I gotta be at
work in a hour.
Oh, baby, okay.
I'm not alone.
Just get the coke.
I'll get out of here.
You didn't break it
out for your client?
Nah. He brings his own.
Uh-huh.
Who are you?
I'm the last person in the
world you want me to be.
He's just
an old friend.
Come on, missy, we've had you
under surveillance for weeks.
Do you have any illegal
substances on you?
Like what?
Asshole.
Cooperate with me, I'll
let you walk outta here.
You play games,
come with her.
I got some coke.
Get it.
Get out.
That was fun.
Hey.
Come. Come!
Are you a policeman?
Yes.
Do you know
who do this?
I don't know, yet.
Look here.
This dead.
Babacar.
This little girl,
no more.
He's dead, dead.
Older man.
Oh, my angel, she's
dead. All my whole family.
How are you related?
Yasin. She were
my sister.
When was the last
time you saw her?
I see her dat morning. I go
by in case she need anything.
But dat morning she says she
needs something from the grocery,
and she called there and had it
delivered by a boy to her home.
Help me, please.
Please, help me find
the killer of my family.
Please, sir.
Help me. Help.
Are you the manager?
No, sir.
The manager's
over there.
New Orleans Homicide. You got
people making deliveries here?
We get different guys making deliveries.
Different days, different guys.
What about Tuesday?
Different times a day.
Different guys.
Late afternoon.
We don't keep track of
who takes what to who.
Is there a delivery boy who
hasn't shown up in a while?
Excuse us. Hello!
Police Department.
We're looking
for Binnie Rogers.
I'm Binnie Rogers.
We need to talk to you for a second.
Do you mind stepping in the hall?
No, I can't step
into the hall.
Can't you see this
lady needs me here?
We're looking for your
grandson, Miss Rogers.
What are you
looking for him for?
Just to talk. We just wanna talk to him.
He do somethin' wrong?
He might've been
a witness to a crime.
I don't know
anything about that.
Where can we find him?
Young man, what do you think gives
you the right to come into my room
and have a conversation without
even acknowledging my presence?
We're terribly sorry.
It's very important we talk
to this woman's grandson.
And she told you she
doesn't know where he is.
Actually, she hasn't
told us that.
I don't know.
I'm sorry, Grandma.
What do you
wanna know?
Did you make a delivery Tuesday
on Josephine and Danneel, son?
Uh-huh.
What did you see there?
This is a 15-year
old boy, sir.
We need you to tell us
what you saw, Daryl.
He don't get involved
in drugs, in gangs.
He go to school.
He hold down a job
and he come home.
A family was
murdered, ma'am.
And I feel very
bad about that.
But I don't want my
grandson involved in it.
Maybe your grandson has
some feelings of his own.
Well,
the lady told me to set the
grocery bags in the kitchen.
Uh, as I was setting the grocery
bags down, I heard screaming.
And I heard gunshots.
So I hid in the closet.
When I came out,
everybody was dead.
Did you see
who shot them?
That a yes or a no?
This is who we're looking
for. Name is Donald Godshaw.
Street name "Big Fate. " You should
familiarize yourself with his record.
It goes back to '91. Did
time for rape, sodomy,
aggravated assault, narcotics, and
possession of automatic weapons.
We believe he's also behind at least
three homicides including the Ndele family.
Lieutenant, wanna show
some of those victims?
All three were
possible witnesses.
Godshaw has two flunkies
that he runs with.
Deshaun Hackett,
street name "Midget. "
Has a girlfriend on Burgundy and Mazant.
We'll set up surveillance on the block.
Maybe we'll get
lucky he'll turn up.
Gary Jenkins,
street name "G."
His grandmother lives
in the Iberville Projects.
If his laying low chances are,
that's where we'll find him.
Let's bring him in.
Give me a minute.
I need access to the apartment
next door. Do you mind?
Oh! It's okay, baby.
Why you need
access for?
We had complaints about
disturbance, not answering the door.
Don't fucking breathe.
I love it.
I just love it.
I've told you
everything I know.
This is your
lucky day, son.
You're the first person we've picked up.
You're in a position to help yourself.
Help myself do what?
You know something about
this family that got murdered.
I don't know nothing.
You were in the apartment when the Africans
got shot. Who was with you? Midget Donald?
Donald Godshaw, "Big Fate. "
Where is he? Where can we find him?
I don't know
no "Big Fate. "
We find them on our own
we don't need you no more.
There's gonna be five
homicides to answer for
and Donald's gonna
hang them on you.
He gets eight to ten.
You get natural life.
I don't know nobody
named "Midget".
named "Big Fate. "
Renaldo Hayes!
Oh. Man!
That's bad luck.
I keep hoping once in a while this
kid throws to somebody on his own team.
I love the guy. By the end of the
fucking game, I'm starting to hate him.
What do you want
for the weekend?
What's the spread on
Louisiana-Arkansas?
Four.
Louisiana.
Minus to four
for a dime.
You got it. I got
a favor to ask.
My kid got
a speeding ticket.
I'll get it taken care of
if you give me half a point.
You're gonna grind me
for helping out my kid?
Grind you? You're funny
guy, you know that?
There's guys getting half a point
on the street for nothing. Grind you.
All right. But you take care of it.
Hello. Hello!
I'm Lieutenant McDonagh,
New Orleans Homicide.
What can I do for you?
A friend of mine's daughter
got written up for speeding.
She was doing 75 on the way to the
hospital to visit her grandmother.
Has a couple of minor,
minor violations in the past.
She's in danger
of losing her license.
What do you
want me to do?
I'd like you to take
care of it for me.
You come out to the scene of
an accident to ask me that?
There shouldn't
be a problem.
Are you asking me to break the
law? Is that what you're doing here?
I'm asking you one cop to
another to do me a favor.
The answer's no.
Just like that?
Just like that.
Is this the same Police
Department my father was in?
You'll excuse me.
Great.
Guardian of the Flame,
right? Fucking ass.
Get back in you
car, Lieutenant.
Or else what?
Hey there.
Hey, what are
you doing here?
You know the Lieutenant?
Yeah. We used
to work together.
Why don't you walk him
back to his car?
I could've told you not to
bother with that asshole.
You needed a ticket fixed,
why didn't you come to me?
I didn't know
you worked here.
They only let me out on patrol
when they're short handed.
Mostly they got me
in the property room.
Property room?
What are you
doing tonight?
You asking me out?
Yes, I am.
Hey.
You like these
boots, don't you?
You got some body on
you, you know that.
Yeah?
You horny?
Oh, yeah.
No, you're not.
You're high on dope.
Not true.
Whatever I take
is prescription.
Except for the heroin.
Hey! Wake up, McDonagh.
Yeah, there's times I can't get
what I need with the prescription.
Really?
Yeah. When my back
hurts sometimes.
Well, maybe there's something I
can do to make that pain go away.
You definitely can.
What's that, baby? What do
you want me to do for you?
Check out your
property room
and see if there's
any Oxycontin
or morphine
you can sneak
outta there.
Just make sure you get
rid of the voucher copy.
You're nuts.
Hey.
The ticket's gonna be a little
more complicated than I thought.
You're kidding me.
The best thing to do is to
have her plead not guilty.
By the time a court day comes around,
I'll talk to the cop who wrote her up.
I thought that's what
you were gonna do.
I went straight
to the Lieutenant.
He wound up being
a hard on.
It'll work out. It's just gonna
take a little longer. Come on.
Kinda calls into question the
half-a-point-for-nothing
concept, don't you think?
You're some cheap
prick, you know that?
You say you're gonna do
something and you don't do it.
Good! Charge me
for the half point.
And after last weekend,
you're down $3,000.
You might,
I mean, might
have thought to bring me
a little something.
Two dimes!
On Louisiana
against Georgia.
Okay, you got it.
How long has he
been in there?
About 20 minutes.
Who else?
His girlfriend. At least
one. That's as far as we know.
What are these fucking iguanas
doing on my coffee table?
There ain't no iguana.
Yeah, there are.
What the fuck is that?
Fucking iguana.
Are we set up?
SWAT's around
the corner.
No! No, just, just no
SWAT. Let them stay there.
The duty captain said he wanted
to coordinate with us when we-
Is that what you're fucking doing now?
Reporting back to the duty captain?
I'm telling you
what he said.
If we need SWAT,
we'll call 'em.
Let's go.
Who else is in here?
Nobody.
We're gonna come back
every day, you understand?
More times we come back, more
chances that child getting shot.
Ain't nobody here.
He's hiding back
there in the armoire.
You all stay
with her. Armand.
Get up.
I said get up!
Damn, man.
It's always nice to see
an intact family.
A father who honors
his obligations
as far as his
children are a concern.
You're here.
That's important thing.
You may be hiding in an armoire,
but your child knows you're here.
Are you tripping, man?
Armand, give us
a minute.
You're tripping.
You on that shit.
Shut the door. Shut up. Shut the door.
Sit down.
Sit down, sit down.
Now we can talk.
You don't mind if I
light one up, do you?
Fuck, man.
I find it relaxes me.
What the fuck, man?
You know we got your boy, "G." Right?
Man, I don't know no "G."
He knows you.
It's amazing how much
you can get done
when you've got a simple
purpose guiding through life.
My purpose is
to find out
who shot up this
apartment on Josephine.
I know the guy who was
living there was from Senegal.
I know he was
selling heroin.
I know whose territory
he was stepping on.
And I know who went over to the
apartment to straighten him out.
I found out all that
in the past few days.
Where is
"Big Fate," son?
I don't know
no "Big Fate. "
You see, I know
that's not true.
'Cause everybody who comes from where
you come, knows who "Big Fate" is.
The fact that you're lying to me,
tells me you're hiding something.
You know my only reason for being here
is to find out who shot up the apartment.
I know that's what you're
hiding. See? It all,
all comes back to that
same simple purpose.
Man, I ain't
telling you shit.
Hey.
What's wrong?
Your father's mad at me 'cause I
can't take care of his fucking dog.
Why does he need you
to take care of it?
'Cause he's going
back into AA.
He says he can't do with
any more responsibilities.
Besides that he,
he's gotta stop drinking.
I mean, ain't like I don't
wanna take care of it,
but I leave at 7:00 in
the morning to go to work!
Oh, let me
talk to him.
I try to be a good wife to him,
Terence. I do. But you know,
I got a limit, too.
You know, he's got a drinking problem.
He says he's got a drinking problem.
He wants to so something
about it. That's good.
You know, he's been down this
road before and it didn't take.
He wants to try it again. Good!
But I, I say to him, why don't you
just stick to beer the way that I do,
but he says
he can't do that.
Hey, Pop.
How are you doing?
I thought you said
the meeting was at seven.
I gotta get there early.
Set up the chairs.
I'll take you.
She can do it.
I came over to see you. Let me
take you for a ride, at least.
You feed the dog?
I can take
care of him.
What are you
talking about?
Genevieve told me a little
about what's going on.
I'll take the dog off
your hands for a while.
How are you gonna
take care of a dog?
I got a friend. She just loves
animals. All of them. Dogs, too.
Let's go.
Have a good time!
No. No!
Fuck you.
Did we not discuss
this on the phone?
How come you only call me
when you need something?
You're fucked up,
aren't you?
What? Yeah.
Yeah, I'm fucked up.
What are you doing?
I'm going to work. I have
to go to Biloxy tonight.
Go to the hotel casino.
How are you gonna take care
of the dog if you're fucked up
and you're going
to Biloxy?
All right. The doorman's
gonna walk him in the morning
and I get back
in the afternoon.
Oh, he's sweet.
What's his name?
I don't know.
You don't know
his name?
I'll ask my father.
You are unbelievable.
I gotta get going.
Unbelievable, you don't
know the dog's name.
Baby, be nice to me.
He smells.
You need a bath.
Try to understand. It doesn't matter
that you were just along for the ride.
It doesn't matter that you
didn't actually shoot anybody.
You're playing the prices now. The
price of "Big Fate" getting off,
it's gonna help the DA
convict you and your boy "G. "
I guarantee you that's
just what he's gonna do.
Why don't you
smoke, man?
What are you
talking about?
I gotta listen
all this bullshit.
Break out
to smoke, man.
Flipping out on
us, Midget?
No, man. Your partner lit
up a motherfucker blunt
before he put
the cuffs on me.
I love this guy.
You say I smoked marijuana
in your presence? Huh?
Cannabis? Is that
what you're saying?
Right. Your word
against mine,
so they fuck won't
believe me, right?
Lieutenant.
Lieutenant, can you
step out for a moment?
My name is
Eugene Gratz, Lieutenant.
I'm an attorney. This is
my client Donald Godshaw.
I understand you've
been looking for him.
How can I help you?
I just wanna talk to
these guys for a second.
Why don't you
wait there?
Gentlemen.
Can I get you
a glass of water?
Um, no, thanks.
I gotta turn over the names of
my witnesses to Godshaw's lawyer.
As soon as I do that, Godshaw
will look to scare the kid.
He can't scare him,
he'll kill him.
He'll never get to him.
Since Godshaw
turned himself in,
I've authorized 24-hour
protection to start immediately.
Just remember,
we have no prints,
no DNA, no weapon.
We lose the kid,
we lose the case.
Understood?
He's a nice dogs.
I just can't keep him.
She said she'd be back
at 1:00 this afternoon.
I'm off at 4:00, and I got
another job I gotta be at.
She didn't call?
No. And the night guy ain't
gonna go walk him.
I can't leave the animal in her
apartment. It might do damage.
How did you
get my number?
Miss Frankie gave it to
me in case of emergencies.
Emergencies?
This is what I'm talking about.
Doesn't pick up the phone.
She isn't where she's
supposed to be. Not showing up.
Terence, think they're gonna put
me on the witness stand by May 15?
Don't know, why?
That's when my mom goes
in front of the parole board.
I'm sure we can get people
to put in a good word for her.
Hello?
Where are you?
I'm about an
hour from there.
I'm on my way.
Frankie, I'm on my way.
You ever been
to Biloxy?
Now, you stand there.
Don't move.
I'll be back
in five minutes.
Baby.
Hi, baby.
What are you doing?
You all right?
Yeah.
You okay?
Who did it?
Do you have
anything for me?
Some coke.
That's it?
And Vicodin.
I'll take both.
What the fuck is
going on in here?
Who's this?
Hey, hey, hey!
Take it easy.
Just get my money.
What are you,
jealous boyfriend?
Just get me
my money.
I usually pay
when I'm done.
Done smacking her around?
It was erotic shit, man.
I didn't hurt her.
Didn't that hurt?
Did I hurt you?
Terence, let's just go.
We don't hit
women down south.
You just made
a big mistake.
My father is Andy Winnick,
you ever hear of him?
One of the biggest
developers in the gulf coast.
Congratulations.
Tommy Leonardi is one
of his best friends.
Listen, scumbag. Don't try to impress me
with you-father knows-some-guinea hood.
What you gotta take
away from this experience
is that if you ever see that girl again,
you turn around and you walk in the
opposite direction. You got that?
Yeah, man.
I ever hear you so much
as look at that girl,
you're gonna wish you
were born without a dick.
Oh! Whoa, whoa,
whoa. Oh, whoa.
Whoa. Big mistake.
Oh, yeah.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Big mistake.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa.
Whoa.
Oh, yeah.
Daryl, this is Frankie.
Frankie, Daryl.
Hi, Daryl.
Hi.
I gotta go talk
to someone.
You go ahead and take
Frankie to the coffee shop.
And you stay with her.
You can do that, right?
Yeah.
Do you have
to do that now?
I'll be with you
in a minute.
Let's go?
Take care of me.
What did Louisiana
go off at?
Three-point underdogs.
What are they losing by?
Eight.
Eight? What
the fuck is that?
There's still two
minutes left to play.
Louisiana ain't got
its passing game, friend.
Good point.
You wanna hear my picks
for the Pac-10?
Do I look like
I wanna hear 'em?
Where is the kid?
He went to the bathroom.
Hi. Are there any other
bathrooms beside that one?
Yeah, on the other side.
Hey, man, insert
more coins.
Insert more coins.
Play again.
What's going on?
What did he say
when he left?
He asked me if I'd be okay
waiting here by myself.
I said yeah. He said he had to go
to the bathroom. What is going on?
He's a witness
to a homicide.
To what?
To five homicides.
Let's go.
Where are we going?
To find him.
Where is he?
Binnie, call security.
Nobody's calling anybody.
Where's your
grandson, Binnie?
I don't have
to tell you anything.
Yeah, you do.
I haven't done anything. My
grandson hasn't done anything.
If he doesn't wanna be a witness,
he doesn't have to be a witness.
This is bigger
than one, two.
This was a massacre.
Children
were executed.
Maybe you should've
thought of that before.
I need to know
where he is.
Young man, I would like to
know the name of your superior.
Right now I'm working on
about an hour and a half sleep
over the past
three days.
And I'm still trying
to remain courteous.
And I'm beginning to think that that's
getting in the way of my being effective.
What are you doing?
What-what
are you doing?
I wanna know
where Daryl is.
My God.
Nobody saw me come in.
Nobody knows I'm here.
This old woman's
gonna run out of air,
and you're gonna have a tough time
convincing people that it wasn't you
who did it to her. And even if,
and even if you do convince them
that you didn't
kill her on purpose,
you're still gonna have a
tough time selling them that you
took care of her
with a fuck!
Now, listen to me.
Where the fuck is he?
I said where
the fuck is he?
He's on an airplane.
Miss Antoinette
bought him a ticket
and send him to live
with her family in England.
All right, it's okay. That's okay.
That's a good girl. Suck it up.
There you go. That's it. Take it
in. That's a good girl. Take it in.
Good! Good.
Good.
That's it. Breathe.
Maybe you should drop
dead, you selfish cunt.
You ever think about your
kids or your grandkids? Huh?
Sucking up their inheritance
through that fucked oxygen tube?
And Binnie's fucked
intensive care?
You fucks, I hate you.
I hate you both.
I should, I should
fucking both, right now,
I should fucking
kill you fucking both.
You're the fucking reason this
country's going down the drain.
Watch out. He's not
in a good mood.
Come in.
Have a seat.
Scotland Yard called.
The kid's in England.
Make him a material witness.
Maybe Scotland Yard will hold him.
Can't do that. He had no
involvement with the crime.
He don't want testify,
we can't compel him.
Well, we could still try
flipping one of the three.
You can try
all what you want.
Nobody flipping on Godshaw.
They're scared to death of him.
As of now, all are
persons of interest.
You gotta let him go.
Oh, come on! Five homicides
and you're letting him go?
You weren't supposed to let
the kid out of your sight.
Be glad he didn't
turn up dead.
This is bullshit.
Get the hell outta here.
You're not the one
on the street-
Get out of my office.
Risking our lives
on the street!
You know what's
involved, right?
Maybe if we had a prosecutor
that worried about something
besides his won lost record
we would stand a chance.
What happened when you
went to see the grandmother?
I told you.
She said the woman she takes care of, bought
a plane ticket. He was on his way to England
to stay with
her relatives.
Any incidents took
place over there?
What kind of incidents?
Any kind.
No.
Whatever it is, you're gonna
wanna have your story down.
Public Integrity is waiting
for you back at the house.
Oh, come on. There gonna pull
Public Integrity into this?
What for?
That old woman, her son is
a United States congressman.
I asked where
Daryl was.
His grandmother told me.
You didn't, at any time,
threaten his grandmother?
No, I did not.
You didn't, at any time,
threaten Antoinette Fahringer?
No, I did not.
You should know a formal complaint's
been filed alleging you cut off
Mrs. Fahringer's
oxygen supply.
Who's saying that?
Mrs. Fahringer?
Is it true?
I think she might be suffering
from a little dementia.
Lieutenant, we're
asking if it's true.
Absolutely not.
Lieutenant.
You know, I saw five of those
driving into work this morning.
I want you to clean it up. Clean it up.
Ned, excellent. You got
my message. Good. Come on.
What message?
You get the flowers
I sent? How's Jenny?
What the fuck are
you talking about?
Okay, that's good.
Stop it!
Cut it out.
What are you
doing here?
What do you think?
I don't have
anything for you.
Then this is
a problem.
Yeah, who
needs a problem?
You owe me
five large, Terence.
I haven't got it.
Then, you gotta
give me something.
Give me goods if you don't
have cash. Give me a gold Rolex.
Ned, I look like
I got a gold Rolex?
Don't pine me for
a fucking stooge.
Keep your voice down.
Just keep it down.
Don't play me
for a fucking stooge.
Are you done?
Do you think these guys care
you're a cop? They will fuck you up
just like
everybody else.
Let me get something
down with the Texas game.
'Cause that's where
the season turns a lot.
No.
Nothing. You pay
what the fuck you owe.
I'm a little late on
my rent, that's all.
Lieutenant.
Uh, somebody named
Frankie called.
What's going on?
All kinds of things.
Come closer. I'm Dave.
Who are you?
Andy.
Jeff.
What do you want?
What I want right now is to
get this behind position right.
He wants money.
Who are you?
Sit down. I told you, I'm Dave.
And the guy you robbed,
I know told you he was.
You make a date with a
pretty girl. You gotta pay.
Dear. Like this.
You want the schwantz, not
the prosty. See? That's it.
When you engage with another human being,
we remind ourselves we're not alone.
Plus, who knows, maybe we
even learn a little something.
How much?
You took 10 off. To make it
right, you gotta come up with 50.
No, that's bullshit.
No, it's punitive damages.
What can I tell you?
I don't get it. She kept
up her end of the bargain.
He says no.
He's a fucking liar. I did
everything he asked me to do.
Which was what?
You want details?
You sick people.
Oh, listen to her stand up
for herself. The indignation.
I love it.
Where's the money?
In my bag.
It's all here?
Okay. Here are
five thousand.
There's ten
in change here.
Why don't I give you
this, call a day.
We could do that. Alternatively, I
could tell Jeffy to shoot the dog.
Do you want me
to shoot the fucking dog?
Or put my calling card on
this gorgeous punum here.
I don't give a shit
about the dog.
But you mark her up, I'm gonna have
a tough time getting you your money.
By my money you
mean $50,000.
I'll need a
couple of days.
By a couple
you mean two.
Yeah.
Good.
Hey.
I know. Relax.
The boys wanna saddle her up just
in the spirit of friendliness.
You mind?
Well, let her get cleaned
up, put on something hot.
She looks like
shit right now.
Beautiful.
What are you
waiting for?
I don't wanna put
any pressure on you,
but she has a client
coming over in 15 minutes.
You boys can be
done by then, right?
The both of us?
They'd had been done in 15
seconds you hadn't mentioned it.
My mistake.
You'll hit her
when we come back.
Two days, same time,
same station, yes?
Okay. You got it, baby.
Don't make me look
for you, Terence.
They're gone.
I'm gonna take you
to my father's house.
Buy some time at least.
Frankie.
They're gone.
I can't take her.
I just need a place where she
can stay for a couple of days.
Why can't you put her
up in your place?
I can't take a chance these
guys find out where I live, Dad.
Christ!
They gave me the job of
bringing cookies to a meeting.
It takes me half
a day to get it done.
You want me to
baby-sit a pros?
You don't have
to baby-sit her.
She's very
self-suficient.
Well, I'm not in any kind of shape
to take on something like this.
Look, I get home
from one meeting.
I lie on the couch and I wait till
it's time for the next meeting.
That's all I
can do right now.
Let your wife
deal with her.
They'll get along
like sisters.
Get away from me, you rag.
My husband is trying to quit drinking
and you bring this shit into our house?
Give it back or I'll swear to
God I will stab you in the heart.
I will stab you
in the heart.
What kind of trash
you're bringing in here?
She's going through my
bag! My personal shit!
Everybody calm down.
It's hard enough
for your father.
He's gotta put up with
narcotics under his nose.
Oh, God. It can't be any worse than you
being shit face on beer all the time.
Enough!
You tell her I'm
shit face all the time?
Oh, it's pretty
fucking obvious, lady!
Oh, yeah?
You fucking whore.
Watch this. Come get
it. Come fucking get it.
Get her outta here. I
can't deal with this shit.
You cunt.
Hey, the neighbors!
You're a cunt,
you whore.
I'll fuck you up.
We come in
or you come out?
Alright, come on,
let's go.
So, uh, Francesca
Donnenfeld. Do you know her?
Just cut the bullshit, Yasco,
and tell me what you're here for.
I'm Yasco.
Here's the thing, tough guy. You
keep fucking with the wrong people.
First the old lady, now your
prostitute friend's customer.
The old lady, you might've written
out. She, uh, doesn't remember so good.
The colored nurse, she's covering
for the grandson, whatever.
But why I get a call
from the chief D's office
that you've shaken down
your pros friend's customer
whose father's hung all the way
from here to fucking City Hall.
You're done, Lieutenant.
What do you want?
Your gun, for starters.
Come on.
Until the outcome
of the hearing,
you're on modified duty.
Better call your delegate.
You got an ass kicking coming.
You have a good
day, Lieutenant.
A man without a
gun is not a man.
Oh, well, I know. Look, you
cut the best deal you can
and you get the hell out of the Police
Department. 'Cause if you stay in,
it's gonna get worse.
Can I talk to you
for a second?
I can't stay here. I didn't
take this shit from my own mother
and I'm not gonna
take it from her.
Can I get a minute alone
with my girlfriend?
Just give her a day or two.
She's gonna calm down, I promise.
I'm so, I'm so happy
you're here.
And I got something
else I want to show you.
She's really mean.
I wanna show you
this place.
I spent a lot
of time here
when I was a boy.
That doesn't
work anymore.
I was here
alone a lot.
This was my
special place
as a child.
My, my castle.
And I would imagine things
here. Pirates, a buried treasure.
And my dad didn't like that so
much, but my mom, she, she got it.
And, uh, and
before she died,
she bought me a metal detector.
Come on, let me show you something.
Look at that.
Right out there,
I thought that pirates
came up the Mississippi
and that they buried a treasure right
there by that tree next to the house.
So I, I took the metal
detector my mom gave me
and I went out there with
it and it start beeping.
It was like beep-beep,
beep, beep, beep.
And I started digging, and
I-I-I dug and I dug and I dug,
and I found a, a Sterling
silver spoon, and I was so happy.
I started screaming
and jumping and laughing.
And I went, "Hey, man,
this is treasure.
This is pirate treasure. " And
I came back in here with it.
And I hid it somewhere,
this Sterling silver spoon.
I still can't find it.
It could be anywhere.
I-I know it's here.
I don't know what
to tell you, Terence.
Not a lot I can do
under the circumstances.
I know.
I tell you guys all the time, you cannot
get away with that cowboy shit anymore.
You don't listen, now
this is where were at.
My best fucking detective, I
gotta put him in the property room.
Terence, come on.
Man, I-I don't wanna you get
jammed off for all of this.
You're doing all this wrong shit and I'm
here. They're gonna think I'm doing it, too.
So, go to the store warehouse in
Metairie that way you're not here.
And while you're there, get me my.
45 Magnum and bring it to me. Okay?
Hey.
You're working here?
Looks like.
What you got there?
Nine, ten grams of
heroin and a Glock nine.
Yeah. You see that
scale over there?
It's broken.
See? useless.
I sent for a new one.
As soon as it gets here,
I'll weigh the drugs
and I'll get you
your voucher, okay?
All right, bye-bye.
Can I help you, sir?
Can I talk
to you a minute?
Excuse me?
Mind stepping outside?
I'd like to talk to you.
You interrupted my meal.
I'm gonna pretend to be polite, so you
look a big man in front of your friends.
You give me a hard time,
I'll put the cuffs on you
just like any
other shitbird.
I'll be back.
You a'ight?
Motherfucker wanna
talk to me.
You ain't gonna shoot me,
are you, motherfucker?
Why would I do that?
I got something for you
I think you're gonna like.
Let's take a walk.
You crazy for
coming down here.
I'm gonna give you a chance to
make some money the old fashion way
with a cop protecting you.
What I need
protection from?
Other cops.
A cop will protect
me from cops?
You'll know when a supplier
is under surveillance.
You'll know when it's safe to
make a pick up, when it's not.
What I gotta give you?
Fifteen thousand
a shipment.
Oh, I'm sorry,
am I being unfair?
How I know you ain't
looking to set me up?
Tomorrow I'll bring you
some information. Small shit.
You decide if you wanna
go to the next step.
What about the murders? You don't
give the fuck about them no more?
Look at me.
Now look at you.
I never did.
Hey, I got the weight
on that dope finally.
Thanks.
That's all there was?
I'll double check it
if you want.
Don't matter. Still
got enough for felony.
What are you guys
got going on today?
Buying bust on Fourth and
Ferret on Andre's outfit.
Happy hunting.
Undercover just busted one
on Andre's. Fourth and Ferret.
What do you know?
Man of your word.
Are you running me
back to my car?
Yeah. I need to make a stop
first. Is that all right?
Yes.
This, this is prime
real estate.
Doesn't look prime.
See, that's the point.
Now is the time to get in.
Two, three years from now, all
this we'll be river front condos.
Marble floors,
health spas.
By that time, another
motherfucker made all the money.
Don't be going legit
on me now, "Big".
Money's money.
Tell you what. You'll be the front man,
I'll be the power
behind the throne.
It's like we're working
for a greater good.
Yeah, you're right.
This is a good spot
to build condominiums.
See? I know I likes you, man. Come on.
May I ask you to step
out of the vehicle?
What'd I do?
You bought dope. I watched you buy dope.
Now stand the fuck up.
Put your hands
on the car.
I didn't-I didn't
buy nothing, man.
No? What's this?
Officer, please, let-
Please what?
I don't know how
that shit got in there.
Did I put it there?
No, sir.
Just some
freaking currants?
Yes, sir.
That's what you
tell the judge, then.
Maybe you'll get lucky and
he will be a football fan.
You know who I am?
Oh, I know who you are.
Then why you wanna
fuck my life up for?
That's gonna knock me
out the draft.
I'm sure you'll get a contract
of some kind eventually.
You run the 40 and what?
What's that, four-three?
Why do you do
this to me?
For some motherfucking
marijuana, man.
I was gonna by
my mama house.
So, you're going off for six
points favorites against Texas.
You win by five or less or you lose
altogether, none of this ever happened.
Sir, I can't do that.
A fumble, a missed blocking
assignment. You can absolutely do it.
Sir, please. Please,
don't make me do that.
Listen to me, Renaldo.
I dumped a lot of
money this year on you.
I got the chance to get some of that
back, I wanna take advantage of it.
You're gonna tell me the integrity
of the game is too much to you, fine.
I wouldn't dream of trying to convince
you to go against your conscience.
Turn around. I'm
placing you under arrest.
You-you won't
tell nobody.
You ain't gonna
tell nobody?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. This that
Taliban shit. That's what's this is.
That shit Osama give a motherfucker
before they blow themselves up.
That's money.
Money.
Shut up!
Where's the 15,000?
You'll get it, man. Relax.
Did I not do what I
said I was going to do?
Yeah, man.
Relax.
Tell me again to relax.
I'm not looking
to beat you, man.
Where's my money?
I'll get your money.
When?
Tomorrow.
Where?
My place.
Give me a cut of
the uncut dope.
Look, I'm gonna
pay you in money.
This is interest.
That's bullshit, man.
What's that, little man?
Midge, chill out.
Here.
Now, put that gun away
before you kill somebody.
I'll kill all of you.
To the break of dawn.
To the break
of dawn, baby.
Wassup, wassup, wassup
wassup, motherfucker?
No fucking
bets, Terence.
What's the matter?
You don't like me?
You don't pay your debts. I don't
wanna know you. I can't afford it.
Ten grand!
Five I owe.
Yeah? Five for Louisiana.
Right there. Wassup?
Where did you get this?
What, are you my priest?
Right there, here.
You got it.
It's a six-point spread.
No shit.
Frankie?
Frankie!
Hey.
I got something for you.
I need to get
my clothes.
Don't worry about your clothes
right now. This is uncut dope.
Just a bunch of stuff from my closet
and then from my dresser by the bed.
I'm not gonna give you much until we know
how strong it is 'cause it's pure, you know?
Baby, I've been talking
to your father a lot
and I think I'm gonna go
to a meeting with him.
What does that mean?
You don't want any?
I mean, of course I want some
but I, maybe when I get back.
Frankie. Frankie,
we gotta go.
Okay? Right.
Thank you.
This the way
to do business.
This, this way I ain't gotta
worry about what I'm walking into.
I got you.
Yeah, let me hit
that shit.
Yeah.
You hitting this shit?
Hey, Midget, light
the Caucasian's rock.
You're my kind of
motherfucking cop, man.
You're a crazy,
motherfucker.
What did that Ki run you.
What do you care?
I'm guessing 60,000.
Very good guess.
Will you shut
the fuck up?
You owe me 15 thousand. I'll
take 25% of the dope uncut.
That means you're
getting my price.
It's one way
of looking at it.
The other is, you get to keep 75% and not
go to prison for the rest of your life.
Yeah.
Go ahead.
Make sure you cut that
shit before you sell it,
unless you wanna kill the
motherfucker who buys it.
Did I ever tell you the
story about nigger Elk?
I was watching TV,
the game, right?
Reynaldo Hayes, He got tossed
the ball. He was running with it.
He jumped over three
linebackers in midair.
He sprouted antlers
like a gazelle.
Like an elk.
He landed again.
He ran, ran, ran.
He scored a touchdown!
Crack talking.
Listen, I'm not worried about you,
so don't be concerned about me.
'Cause I'm not concerned if you're not
concerned. I'm not really concerned.
I'm worried 'cause
if you drop dead,
I'm the motherfucker
they come looking for.
And then I gotta end up
having a nigger from Africa
trying to move in
on my shit.
And I don't wanna shoot no more
purple ass niggers from Africa.
Easy, easy, easy, easy.
'Cause I'm not Eazy-E.
Fucking god.
Hey. Hey. I need
to go to the store.
So?
So I need you
to watch him.
Fuck, no,
I can't watch him.
Don't be yelling. There
ain't nothin' to eat.
Get the fuck
outta here!
Get the fuck outta here!
Hit me again with
another one on them rocks.
What the fuck's that?
It's my lucky
crack pipe.
You crazy motherfucker.
You don't have
a lucky crack pipe?
No, I don't have a lucky
motherfucking crack pipe.
Then, Donald, you're
gonna take a hit of mine.
Why I gotta do that?
'Cause it's lucky.
Shit.
Lucky crack pipe.
Sorry we're late, fellas. I
hope you didn't wait dinner.
Who the fuck are you?
Third party beneficiary.
Your friend here can fill
you in on the details.
I'm working on getting your money,
Dave. That's what I'm doing here.
I don't know about you, but the
hardest part of collecting debts
is having to listen
to the stories.
Terence owes you
some money?
$50,000. Plus my two
young friends here
were supposed to have a sexual
experience of their choosing
with an attractive woman. Nothing.
He came across with none of it.
That's wrong. That's wrong you don't do
what you say you're gonna do, Terence.
The dope's worth
more than 50,000.
Take it.
Why don't I take
all the dope?
Why are you gonna take
what belongs to me?
Well, there was a time
when I wouldn't have.
I would've taken what was mine
and left the rest on the table.
But, you see, I never
got rich enough to retire.
I'm stuck
doing this shit.
And I'm not
young anymore.
So now I don't leave
nothing on the table.
Pick it up.
Shoot him again.
What for?
His soul's still dancing.
Shoot him again.
Good night, Lieutenant.
What are you
doing tonight?
I'm getting outta
here and go to bed.
Just for fun, why don't you stop
by the apartment on Josephine?
For fun?
You might find something
interesting there.
Like what?
These bushwhackers might've hit a
crack pipe while they were there.
You know? The off chance that he dropped
it under the bed where the kids were.
And we missed it.
The DNA'd place
them at the scene.
You had a vision, right?
Deoxyribonucleic acid.
Frankie? Frankie.
Where's Frankie?
She's not in the house?
Frankie's on her
way to rehab.
Rehab?
What about her clothes?
Someone will
bring her her clothes.
Anything else
you wanna know?
You don't have
to hide it from me.
We're birds
of a feather.
We both like
our poison.
You just drink
beer, I thought.
Do you mind if
I watch the game?
Mh-mh. Be my guest.
I cannot believe
what I'm witnessing.
Louisiana up by 18 points
in the second quarter.
For another score.
You wanna share?
Back to pass.
He scrambles.
Hobbs builds his
way to another-
I don't know.
And all this without
Renaldo Hayes.
We still don't know
the nature of his injury.
Just that he's taken
himself out of the line.
I'll kill him.
Renaldo Hayes being out, the
freshman Johnson has really stepped up
for this football team. You're
in the land of miracles, my boy.
I'm looking right there at
Hayes, and I'll tell you what.
The guy just does not look like
a happy guy. He's on the sideline.
He's obviously suffering
from some sort of injury.
Hey, guys.
Good to see you.
Listen.
First off, this
thing between us,
it's gotten way out of
hand. Got way outta hand.
Okay?
Those gumbos, couple
of fucking assholes.
They disappeared because of
something you did to them.
Whoa, man, I got no
beef with you whatsoever.
Everything between you and
me, right as rain.
And I want
you to know
that my father got in touch with his guy
and he told him
whoever it is,
that complaint has been
withdrawn. Finished.
Oh, yeah.
Okay?
Okay.
Oh, yeah?
Uh, phew.
Okay.
That's the way out.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, no. Look, Ned,
if you'd called first, I
would've saved you the trip.
I'm guessing that you
didn't see the game.
How did this happen?
Louisiana by three.
Hayes ended up playing?
Nope.
Worked out anyway.
What are you
talking about?
Nothing.
Oh,
and my daughter's
tickets, speeding tickets,
thank you, thank you, thank you.
This female highway
patrol officer calls up,
says they're
taken care of.
It's $10,000. Sure you
don't wanna count it?
I trust you.
All right, man. You
take care or yourself.
All right.
Great news.
Our man came up with this at
the crime scene on Josephine.
I just got lucky.
The lab found
Godshaw's DNA on it.
That is fantastic!
Yes!
Oh, look at that.
I found the spoon.
It's not silver.
It went rusty.
I wanna give it to you.
It's yours.
It's for me?
That's so sweet.
It's beautiful.
Yeah, I need
eight of them.
Yes, eight.
Uh-huh. It's
going down, baby.
Yeah, I got some help.
I'm telling you.
Police Department. Stand up. Keep
your hands where we can see them.
What the fuck is this?
We got it.
Check the outside,
check the backyard, check
upstairs, check his car.
We got this. It's okay.
Good. We're good. Upstairs.
Cuff him.
No.
What do you
mean no?
This is what happens. Before we can
cuff him, he goes for this weapon,
we shoot this prick
and steal his shit.
Fuck. Terence, what-
What are we doing?
I thought we had
our thing going.
You're wrong, baby. He acts like he
likes you 'cause he likes to get high.
Huh? That don't mean
he stop bein' the police.
Cuff him, Stevie.
No. Can you draw
a line of murder?
It's interesting
where to wreck its fun.
I said cuff him, Stevie.
This is about money.
You want my fucking money?
You want my fucking money? Take my
money! You won't kill me for this shit.
Go for it, son.
Go for it.
Got for it.
Go for it!
Yeah, yeah.
Next time.
Now fucking cuff him.
I said cuff the
motherfucker, Stevie!
Ladies and gentlemen, it is an honor to
conclude this year on a positive note.
In recognition of his
leadership and tenacity
in the investigation
of the Ndele family murders
resulting in the successful
apprehension and prosecution
of the three
individuals responsible,
I'm proud to include Lieutenant Terence
McDonagh among those being promoted
to the rank of captain.
Captain McDonagh.
Woo!
Excuse me. Would you care for some wine?
No, thank you. We're all gonna
stick with our sparkling water.
I would like
to make a toast.
To the new Captain.
To new life.
I'm probably gonna
start to cry right now.
Oh, that's okay.
To my new family.
God bless.
Here, here.
You still gonna be working on night
shift when I get closer to the due date?
I'll make sure I'm
not. How is that?
I could get to the hospital and all,
but I like having you home at night.
I like it better
that way, too.
Thank you, darling.
All right.
There we go.
Where are your keys?
Did I give them to you?
No, I don't
think you did.
Stand against the wall.
What'd we do?
Hey, stand
against the wall.
What are you doing?
The two of you match a description.
Passing drugs in the club.
Don't say anything. Do
exactly what I tell you to do.
So, what are we
high on tonight?
Nothing.
Empty your pockets.
Dump out the handbag.
Room service.
I didn't order
any room service.
Oh. It must've been
a mistake again.
Holy shit.
I'm Evaristo Chavez, man.
You saved my life.
I was in the prison
that was flooding.
Oh, yeah.
Do you remember me?
Are you still with
the Police Department?
Port of call
still New Orleans.
Okay.
What happened with you?
The judge remanded to a
drug treatment program.
November 14th
I have a year clean.
Congratulations.
Are you all right?
Sometimes I
have bad days.
Listen,
you saved my life.
I'm almost done working. I'm
gonna get you out of here, okay?
Okay?
Do fish have dreams?
You know, Chavez,
I still hate that I ruined
my underwear for you.