Let me go! Let me go!
- What is it?
- A drowned woman.
- A drowned woman?
- She had cramps.
The water is still too cold.
Let me go!
But it's Gösta!
Yes, hello.
Really! Hello.
I got off the boat today.
Hi!
We sailed together.
- From The U.S.?
- From the East Indies.
Really?
Tea, peppers, rice,
zinc and wool from Australia.
Yes, but now, it is finished.
Eight years at sea is enough.
You can settle down here, at home.
This bed is free
and the rent is modest.
You could work at the port.
No, not at the port...
So you want to become director
straight away?
You could at least begin there
while looking for something else?
It's a good job.
Everything will be alright, you'll see.
955.
Yes.
346.
- 376.
- Yes.
650.
Yes.
You will start at 7h30
at no. 34, the "Saga".
You're not going out this evening?
Not, I don't think so.
Although it's a Saturday,
I don't feel like it.
You're in love with someone?
or maybe you're sick?
It's been a while since that
happened to me.
Well, cheer up then.
Besides, you have money.
With money, you can get women.
And whisky.
I don't care about that!
Everyone has their ups and downs.
Let's say that it's
because of spring.
What are you reading?
- A book...
- Yes, I can see that.
But by whom?
A sailor. He's called Martinsson.
And you read that?
Don't books interest you?
Not any more.
My father was a teacher.
He had loads of books.
At that time, we felt lonely.
We wanted to sail away,
See lots of things.
We thought we were missing
essential things.
Ah yes.
Then I stopped,
and I began to drink.
Books make everything worse.
Well read, then.
Goodbye!
See you.
There's a crowd.
Yes, really.
It's hot.
Yes.
They're not playing badly.
I've heard better.
It's funny when they go for it.
I find that rather silly.
You need strangers for that.
There's a lot of people.
It could be worse.
It's hot with all these people.
There's only one thing left to say.
What's that?
That they play well.
Yes, indeed.
Everyone says that.
Really?
But they can say it
in a thousand ways.
It's boring here. Shall we go?
With pleasure.
Good. Let's get out of here.
Hi, Berit.
Hi.
Come here.
I don't want to.
Bitch.
She's pretending to be a virgin.
Shut up!
Don't pay attention to
those bastards!
But you could have said hello to me.
You shouldn't be so afraid.
Laugh in their faces
and give them back the change.
I don't want to belong
to the group any more.
I won't go back any more.
You think you're escaping?
Sure, if you don't want to.
We could become just friends again.
I have to go.
I understand just
how you feel.
Is it better like that?
Why?
Why? Don't get upset.
You think I want to?
Say,
you live alone here?
Not, it's my parents' place.
Where are they?
Dad is at sea. He is second mate.
And mum is at an aunt's.
cigarette?
No thanks, I don't smoke.
Smart not to.
You're well set up here.
It's OK.
If only there was
a little more freedom.
Why did you kiss me?
What a question!
Because I like you, of course.
Really?
I find you beautiful
and I would like to kiss you more.
Yes, I see that.
You are strange.
Don't worry about it.
So, would you like some coffee?
Not, I don't want a coffee.
Goodbye, then.
Bye.
Are you tired?
So-so.
I have to go to work.
On Sunday?
Yes, I work in a team.
Goodbye.
Will we see each other again?
Yes, we will.
We are agreed.
Wednesday? 8 o'clock, without fail.
Hello.
Alone.
Are you there?
That is my business, isn't it?
You don't care about coming late.
You, you had to go back on Monday.
I changed my mind.
So you could spy on me.
I was worried.
I have to believe that?
Who did you make out with, yesterday
evening?
I was at the cinema.
And afterwards?
Afterwards I went home.
Alone?
What do you think?
You're lying.
Ah right!
There was a boy.
False.
False?
It was I who smoked.
I know well that you don't smoke.
So?
What are you going to do?
You know well that I must
submit a report to Villander Assistance.
Go ahead. Denounce me, without shame.
Let them come and get me!
You come here with boys.
It was better
when you were elsewhere.
I should have known
not to trust you.
- What are you saying?
- Stop this theatre.
Go ahead. Hit your mother.
That's just like you.
I was only waiting for that.
Berit, you don't have anything to say to me?
Leave me.
If you apologise, I won't say anything.
will not ask for your pardon.
Never.
Be careful.
- Let me pass.
- Don't touch me.
Engineer Villander
wants to speak to you.
His sister is there.
You know, the assistant.
Villander has asked how you
were behaving.
I said “well”, but the assistant
wasn’t too pleased.
Oh right.
You didn't do anything stupid ?
How would I know?
I did all I could.
That’s worth a small reward, isn’t it?
And you believe that?
That could cheer you up too.
- I doubt it!
- You’re sure?
The girls say
that you are not a real guy!
- Hello.
- Hello, Miss Holm.
I don't have anything to say,
but Miss Villander does.
I understand.
Berit understands what it’s about.
I will leave you.
No, stay.
I’m used to it.
Your mother called me yesterday.
Yes, she often grasses on me.
It is a privilege
to live at your mother’s.
It is worse than being
in a reformatory.
You should be ashamed.
And don’t interrupt me, Berit.
If I must keep silent,
I will go back to work.
Don’t take that kind of tone. You really want
to come back to the family home?
Who worries about the
tone in which they question me?
And they will send me back home despite my protests.
They won’t ask me how I feel.
You should understand your mother.
She only wants what is good for you.
Yes, by hassling me all the time.
Berit! It is what, this language?
I learned it in the reformatory,
and here and everywhere else
where you have put me.
My hope of any possible
improvement disappeared.
You want to send me back to the family home.
I don’t want to go there or here.
I want to be free! Free!
People don’t understand
that I want to make it by myself.
I’m not the only one who decides.
Berit, you can leave.
Wait.
Listen to me a moment.
You like it here?
If I can change something,
I will do it with pleasure.
You can speak frankly.
I don’t like to ruin my hands.
I am a milliner - it is my job.
I like to make hats.
Perhaps you would like
some cleaner work. In the checking department?
Yes, Sir, I would.
Agneta, give him another chance
before you submit your report.
I have not decided alone.
Go to your machine, Miss Holm.
You were really kind
and considerate with her.
And why not?
I do what I can,
it is not easy.
And if you give her
a real chance?
It’s not so simple, Bengt.
Does she really
have to live at her mother’s?
You are dealing with a bastard.
When she arrives
with all her band
or when she is infected
or has stolen something?
Your lack of optimism
is attractive.
What good is that?
You don't want to use a
strong hand against the rabble?
Are you afraid of her?
Afraid?
One would think so.
It is very difficult to
deal with her.
Everyone says so.
If it’s true, it doesn’t matter,
if the experiment fails.
No. I must speak about it
with my colleagues.
Of course.
Don’t be so ironic, dear Bengt.
I do not have the right
to take decisions alone.
Who, then?
You will know.
I have to work my supplementary hours.
Are you staying?
Like the little girl in the street, I’ll say:
of course, of course.
OK, good.
Didn’t you have to meet that chick
at 8 o’clock this evening?
It’s her evening to go out.
You must look after her.
It is not so important.
The youth of today!
She is nothing to you, then?
How beautiful you have become!
Not me.
I see well enough. Who are you going to see?
Who should I see?
I’m going to the cinema.
Which cinema?
I don’t know.
Go then, so you get there on time.
Stop! Leave me in peace.
Are you waiting for someone?
No.
You look nervous.
So?
He’s not coming?
Go away.
If he is a nice boy,
you could introduce him to me.
But I don’t believe it.
Believe what?
That he’s a nice boy.
Not, there isn’t anybody.
Father has telegraphed to say that he’s coming back.
That’s good, isn’t it?
Are you going to divorce?
No, not at all.
We will start again.
Who decided that?
It was I who decided.
Then the hell will begin again.
What are you speaking of?
Poor dad.
Dad writes that he misses me.
He always was a little insane.
I would like you to be happy,
you too, little Berit.
Leave me.
I love you very much.
I only think of you
and worry about you.
That’s nice.
But leave me in peace.
You speak like that to your mother?
Oh, shit!
You are hard, Berit.
But you pay for that.
I would like to see you dead.
I would like to be dead myself.
That’s what one says at your age,
my daughter.
I see you are already waiting for dad.
I know how it will finish up
when he returns.
It will start with salt
in the gruel,
and then all those slanging matches.
At first the small ones,
then whole evenings
All that is finished, now, Berit.
We got older.
You know that I have talked
with Pasteur Broman.
It will be different.
For you too.
You lie so much that you are
not the only one to believe it.
But all others do, and dad too.
But not me.
Because I know that you always
lie, always.
You will regret
what you have just said.
I ought to beat you to death.
You do not frighten me.
I should kill you.
and Berit and myself.
You are mad. You belong in the asylum.
What are you saying? Me, insane?
And you.
Who shout and then speak calmly here?
You do not understand yourself.
I can always go.
Yes, go. Go away again.
There is no worse hell
than when you are here.
Berit!
Come here. Come and see dad.
Don’t be afraid.
Is it hell when dad is here?
You hurt him.
And what are you doing here?
It is you who hurt him,
nobody else.
Is it true, Berit?
Come and see dad.
Don’t touch her.
If you do, I’ll slap you.
But she is my child.
Poor little Berit who has
such a father. Poor little Berit.
My little Berit
who has such a father.
You came, all the same.
You didn’t think I would?
I thought you didn’t want to.
Shall we go to the cinema?
There’s a good film on at the Viktoria.
Gösta!
What is it?
You didn’t want to come.
I don’t know. Maybe not.
Why did you come?
We have to go down here.
Hello, Berit.
Who’s that there?
It’s LeCoq.
He’s the foreman at the factory.
Two seats at 2,50.
Hi, Berit.
Are you freezing?
Look at those tits she’s got.
- What’s the matter?
- Don’t worry about it.
Are you in a hurry or what?
Come with us.
Drop that guy.
No, Gösta.
I saved you several times at the
Factory, didn’t I?
Her bottom rolls well!
Berit, a chick like you would
be enough for three men.
Get lost!
Let’s go, Gösta.
Don’t bother with them.
What did you say, kid?
You want a taste of the tilt hammer?
Where will you find the arms?
And if the police arrive?
The police! You heard that?
What a hero!
Listen, pull in your chin
and save your breath.
Who dares to come?
Who dares to do what?
Gösta! Look out!
Behind you, Gösta!
Bunch of bastards!
Bitchy girl from the reformatory!
Wake up, Gösta!
How do you feel?
Leave me!
You didn’t go back?
Go back?
Yes.
Look at your tights.
It doesn’t matter.
I will refund them to you.
Don’t be silly.
It would be better if you could pay for a taxi.
Help me to get these rags off.
We don’t have any rings.
Put your left hand in your pocket.
I haven’t got any pockets.
Keep your gloves. It looks very chic.
Because this weekend, we will
be a count and countess.
Would a walk before dinner
suit you, Madam Countess?
Why thank you, Mister Count.
What a charming idea!
You rang?
No. Did you?
No.
Excuse me.
No, but was it you, Berit?
Gertrud!
You are here, now?
Ah, you know each other?
School friends?
You could say that.
Your man?
Yes, I am his man.
Congratulations, Berit.
Thank you.
Not everyone
finishes up as well.
Telephone me.
I would really like to speak with you.
Of course.
Excuse me. If you want
something, you only have to ring.
Promise to me one thing, Gertrud.
Do not speak about the family home.
Not to please to me,
but for Gösta.
He doesn’t know anything?
Not, he doesn’t know anything.
Count on me.
Really?
Do you think that the old gang
is abandoning you?
Thank you very much, Gertrud.
Is he OK?
I’m sorry?
He knows how to keep silent.
He’s only a simple sailor.
What are you doing here?
He’s celebrating my birthday.
That’s nice.
Looks after him well.
And you, how are you?
Thank you for asking.
I am just fine.
You know Mrs. Krana?
What do you mean?
You’re going to…
To see her, yes. I intend
to visit her very soon.
Poor Gertrud.
But she is sweet.
Can you lend me some money?
How much?
I need 50 crowns.
I can give you 25.
But be careful, Gertrud.
To be careful.
Could you send the money
to the hotel?
Gertrud, can’t I
help you differently?
You are kind.
Go back and see your man, now.
He will be wondering
what we are talking about.
What were you talking about
for such a long time?
Nothing spcial.
We just gossiped a little.
Were you surprised to see her?
I don’t like her so much.
She is beautiful.
Yes, not bad.
What’s the matter?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
- I said a stupid thing.
- No.
Never leave me.
Yes,
but do it quickly,
if not, it will do too much harm.
Why would I leave you?
Because you don’t know.
I don’t know?
I don’t know what I’m saying?
Yes, I do know.
I love you,
and I have said it more than once.
You have said it.
Yes.
You don’t believe me?
You, you never tell me
that you love me.
- Do it. If not…
- Yes.
Well, say it then.
I don’t want to.
I hate those words.
Nobody takes them seriously.
They want to…
Don’t say anything.
That hurts.
Do you think I only said it
for that?
No…
Yes…
because each time you…
But I depend so much on you.
I have only have that to give
in order to keep you…
And perhaps it is that
which will tire you out…
When one really loves…
What makes you afraid
makes you love each other more.
You must believe me.
Why do some people have everything
and others nothing?
It is terrible to be alone.
You have been so kind to me.
My little one.
Life is not as difficult
as people think. You will see.
One day, luck will be on our side.
And I will teach you to say
that you love me.
Excuse me, Gösta.
How about a walk?
Gösta.
My dear Gösta,
I thought you were asleep.
I’m not awake at all.
I’m dreaming.
What did you say?
I am so stupid.
I spoke to you the whole time.
Repeat what you have just said.
That I love you…
that I adore you…
You see -
you finally learned it.
You taught it to me.
Are you happy now?
It would have been better
If we had never met.
Because now,
I know what happiness is,
and everything will
become more difficult.
Are you starting again?
I have thought so much.
I have decided to tell you
everything that has happened to me.
It would be better if you learnt it from me
than from others.
It is difficult.
Drop it.
You don’t leave school
on Sunday. Me neither.
It’s the past.
I have to tell you.
So that you don’t accuse me later.
Go ahead.
Anyway, that is not important.
We all have the right to live.
Are you afraid?
Me?
No.
Why do you think I am?
I have that impression.
I could easily accuse
my parents and say it is their fault.
They didn’t want to divorce
because of me.
When dad was away at sea
it was still OK.
But he was injured
in a torpedo attack
and had to stay at home.
And everything got worse.
The house was a hell.
In the evenings, I went out
with the other girls from school.
I came back home
as late as possible,
when my parents were asleep.
But one evening, mum was
waiting up for me…
Where were you all evening?
That has never been a problem.
And it is not your business.
Right, that is not my business.
You will remain outside to reflect,
and you will learn
to come back on time.
Mom!
Mom, open the door!
Hello.
Why are you sitting there?
None of your business.
Are you sad?
No. Don’t worry about me.
Your mother put you outside?
Or perhaps your father?
No.
And you are waiting nicely
until they come and open the door.
I don’t know where to go.
Can you imagine what they would think
if you disappeared?
What?
Come and live at my house.
You’re crazy.
Come on.
Where do you live?
You don’t know?
No.
I have no idea.
Follow me. I have my own pad.
With all the traditional comforts.Come with me.
No.
I don’t know if I dare to.
Don’t worry, little one -
I have honest intentions.
Clean sheets
and one meal per day.
I’m called Thomas.
I’ll say that once and for all.
Yes, I’ll come with you.
- And the name of the lady?
- Berit.
Berit! How charming! Hello, Berit.
We lived together.
He was very kind to me,
but they searched for me
and somebody betrayed me to
the police.
At first it was the
Childhood Council.
Then mum said that
she couldn’t do anything with me.
She asked them to help.
They took charge
and promised to arrange everything.
It was the Re-education Centre.
With regard to
the case of Berit lrne Holm,
the circumstances are clear.
referring to paragraph 220
of the Law on Protection of Children,
we have decided
according to the paragraph of the same law,
taking into consideration
that there is no other solution,
and according to paragraph 24,
to take the girl into our charge
by placing her in a reformatory
for girls.
With immediate effect.
Passengers travelling to
Göteborg, please board now.
Close the doors.
As you have arranged everything properly,
I wondered where we should go
during our stop at Stockholm.
I’d like to give to the girls
a memory before they leave,
from which they can
draw strength.
That’s really nice of you.
I’m sure the girls will really
appreciate it.
That time hurt me more
than I thought.
I wanted to scream
out of fear and loneliness.
It was OK in the winter
and in spring,
but the summer was horrible.
For Gertrud, it was worse.
Every night, she went and
slept with the gardener.
She wanted to break the rules,
like cigarettes, perfume,
and lipstick,
and real underwear.
I was there for fourteen months.
Afterwards, they placed me with a lady
who had a social hobby. [?]
At work, we were
closely watched all the time.
The lady had a nice son.
He had a bit of a crush on me.
Mum surprised us one day,
and of course she reported it.
Later, I ran away
to Stockholm.
They caught me again -
the second time.
They put me in another place
for more than two years.
When I got out, I had to work
at the factory, where I met Gunnar.
He was so nice. He didn’t care
that I’d been in prison.
I could go to see his parents.
They were kind, too.
I thought it was all over.
Then one day, there was a catastrophe,
and everything fell apart.
We thought you were Gunnar’s girlfriend
but you didn’t say anything.
We cannot forgive that.
- It’s not true?
- She was afraid.
We must always tell the truth.
What shall we do?
There is one thing to do.
I will leave with Berit.
Be quiet.
But it is true.
It is for your own good.
It’s pointless to drive me out.
I can leave by myself.
Don’t follow me.
It was my fault.
I thought you’d said everything.
You told me.
I know, I know.
Goodbye.
Will we see each other again?
No.
You want to say
that you don’t want to see me again?
It is finished.
You’re not going to hurt yourself?
I threw myself in the water,
just before I met you.
Now, you know.
Aren’t you leaving?
Well, go then!
Don’t worry about me.
Do as you wish.
How many guys have you had?
No, Gösta…
Why didn’t you kill yourself?
You look soft, sailor.
It’s a chick?
Before, they had to stab me
to get out the marrow.
Perhaps she dumped you?
You should have seen
the chick I went out with!
What a number!
Your mouth!
What is it?
Calm down, calm down, my friends.
Make an effort, Gösta.
You’ll find another.
Those who speak about love
are mistaken.
Everything is difficult. Why
can’t we be ourselves?
We can forgive our own
faults, but not those of others.
Yes, it’s the same everywhere.
We want to be just.
It’s a pity for Berit.
If you want to play
at saving the world, be careful.
It is so absurd.
Absurd?
Everything is.
You are so ironic.
You have to believe…
In what?
Women? Justice?
Brotherhood?
Not, everywhere, it is the same misery,
the same shit.
There is nothing?
Don’t speak to me about it.
- What else?
- Idiot. The girl!
If you need to
hold someone’s hand,
take hers. Only she loves you.
You want to say: forget everything?
You can always try.
Yes One can always try.
What is it?
And you?
Why don’t you eat anything?
I don’t have any appetite.
Who’s that guy?
It’s Gunnar.
Oh, him.
The one before me, that you talked about.
He looks fine.
You think so?
He looks sharp. Very sharp.
Wonderful. Was he as wonderful as he looks?
We could become buddies
with this guy. If we bump into him.
He’s exactly the type I like.
I know very well
that you loved him.
Get lost!
You’re so odd.
What have I done?
Why torture yourself?
Don’t mess around.
I can’t bear it any more.
Get lost, I said.
I know - I should have told you
when we first met.
It’s all my fault.
Go then.
Nothing is worse than that.
Don’t cry! That drives me crazy!
Telephone.
Hello.
Oh it’s you, Gösta.
Berit has told me so much about you.
Oh right.
Take care of her.
I will tell you one thing:
she doesn’t listen to me.
I dont know why.
It’s as if she hates me.
It’s not easy to say,
but I am her mother.
I’ve thought about it a lot:
To grow up there, where
we were fighting, is not easy.
It wasn’t always nice at home.
I’ll tell you another thing.
Her father has very sensitive nerves.
We always have tried
to be just and honest, but…
You understand…
You know that Berit
has been in a family home.
I think that helped a lot.
She’s not a slut,
but she’s had lots of boyfriends.
It’s true.
But if you’re fond of Berit,
as I hope you are,
you should know everything.
Thank you. I already know “everything”.
I would be so happy if you could
stay together. For Berit’s sake.
She has a bad character.
She gets it from her father.
- Let me go.
- Where are you going?
- Why does it matter?
- Tell me where you are going.
To see Gertrud.
Why?
She called me. She needs me.
Stay there and listen to mum.
You will learn my true nature.
It’s good to know.
Go away with this girl.
I can’t keep her here.
You understand, don’t you?
She says it hurts.
It’s normal after anesthesia.
I made the usual intervention.
She’s not dangerous.
The foetus will come out
in a few days.
Yes, it hurts, but not so much.
That’s her nerves.
How do you feel?
Thank you for coming.
We must leave from here.
But it hurts so much
You must leave.
I have made hundreds of
interventions. None has failed.
I’m very careful.
I don’t take risks.
You must leave.
But where?
I don’t know.
I have no idea.
I can’t go back.
You, you know?
I’ll call a taxi.
What has she done?
She gave me an injection.
At first, it was really bad,
but I had a sedative.
It began just before I left.
I’m so scared.
Where will we go?
Yes, where will we go?
The taxi is here.
Wait, I know where we can go.
You really have to whistle that? [?]
Am I crazy?
It’s just that that
drives me completely nuts.
Gustav wants to speak.
Not, we won’t open.
He’ll break everything.
Ask him what he wants.
What is it?
Gertrud is sick.
I’m getting out of here.
She needs a doctor.
No doctor.
She may be sent away.
Why?
Oh, no!
No, no doctor, no doctor!
I don’t want to go back there,
I don’t want to, I don’t want to.
But what can we do?
Call an ambulance.
I feel so strange, Berit.
Do you think it’s dangerous?
I’m so scared, Berit.
I think it’s bleeding a lot.
You have to help me somehow.
There’s… a lot?
I don’t understand
what she did.
Gösta.
Please follow me.
Look how Joe
is nice to you,
and he doesn’t even know you.
It is for you, he would say,
and you certainly need it.
I told him you were drunk.
He heard the lapping inside you.
Was it your friend who
was taken away in an ambulance?
What was wrong with her?
She died.
Oh, shit!
You don’t need to cry.
Be happy that you
are being looked after.
I was rather sad.
I had hardly drunk anything.
Joe said you have nice eyes.
He’s right.
But do not cry.
It is the drop of water
that makes the vase overflow.
When the boat sinks,
one throws oneself into the sea.
One tries to swim
to firm ground.
To swim.
To swim in the South
Sea, anywhere,
where one isn’t sucked up
by whirlwinds.
sucked up, you see.
That’s how it is, Mr Andersson.
You said conscience - no.
You are a new baby [?]
who cries at the back,
and wipes its tears.
because it misses its mother.
What a conscience!
You know how old I am?
Twenty-nine.
You didn’t believe it, did you?
Me neither.
Have you ever seen dead toes?
Ever seen a dead man?
Did you ever see a pig with two legs
That weighs 70 kilos
Somebody asked you to
remain,
and you left!
I saw all that.
But I do not draw any
Conclusions from it,
in spite of my twenty-nine years.
Because I have no
conscience, you see.
And you then
Reply!
Stupid conscience.
Open, open!
My God, look at that.
What is it?
What a spectacle!
Get out of there, old man. [?]
That’s it - love, for you.
You drank… It’s not worth the trouble,
really not.
Get it out. [?]
Berit!
You can go back. We don’t
need you any more.
Thank you.
She could have told me.
It wouldn’t have affected me
If she had had a child.
Now she is dead.
The Lord has given and He has taken away.
I always knew that my daughter
was destined for misfortune.
She never gave me happiness.
It is better this way.
I’m going.
Thank you all
for your kindness.
Miss Holm, could you give me
the address of this abortionist?
Berit, do you understand
that your silence harms you?
Murderers must be stopped,
mustn’t they?
This abortionist has killed your friend
and you want to protect her?
I knew a girl from a good family
who got pregnant by a useless guy.
She aborted herself.
With the help
of the Health Council
and a well-known surgeon.
How does that concern us?
Those who do not have the means
must get by somehow.
With such consequences?
It is the risk that they take.
We should be grateful that
we can get help.
You hear! [?]
Stop.
Calm down. Wouldn’t it have been better
if your friend had had this child?
I don’t know.
Would you have
acted in the same way?
Yes.
Whore!
If you do not calm down,
I shall ask you to leave.
I think that assistant Villander
has something to propose.
That depends, yes.
What then?
If you give me the
address of this abortionist,
we will arrange things so that
you do not come before the law.
I promise I will do all I can
so that you avoid trouble.
You don’t believe me
No. Why should I believe you?
You have my word of honor.
Help us now, Berit.
Why?
Does somebody have a cigarette?
Morally, I am by no means
offended by your attitude,
but I am angry
because you are stupid.
You understand that this will get you
at least three years.
And perhaps it will be prison,
I don’t know exactly.
But you don’t care, of course.
Very well.
This affair must follow its course.
Come in.
Follow me.
I will say it.
I will tell everything.
Excuses me, I am a…
What, Gösta?
I said, excuse me
because I am an idiot.
I’m happy that you’re here.
You missed me?
Yes, I missed you.
Let’s get out of here. [?]
We can’t.
What if we get picked up?
No worry. I’ll talk to
my buddy. He knows what to do.
Let me speak.
Hello, little Dutch boy. [?]
The captain.
I can speak a little German.
Hey, me too.
We want to speak.
with your
Oberkommandogeneralführer.
Do you speak English?
You have a beautiful boat.
I have two friends -
a boy and a girl.
They would like to leave from here,
you see.
For Antwerp.
I understand.
A Swede who wants to leave Sweden.
We will arrange that. Come.
So?
Everything is arranged. It went like it was
on casters. We leave tomorrow.
- It is expensive?
- No more than it’s worth.
- You’re regretting it?
- Regret? Me?
What do you mean?
You’re not saying anything.
One cannot speak all the time.
It is strange to run away like this.
You did it before.
Yes, I did.
- I thought of something.
- What?
A year ago,
our situation was worse.
Now, many things have changed
to make us think carefully about it. [?]
You mean it’s ridiculous to leave.
I didn’t say that.
So many things
haven’t yet been settled.
The supervision, your mother, my work.
All kinds of worries,
it’s true.
It’s too much for us.
But we are together.
It wasn’t like that before.
I am worthless.
Yes, for me.
It is certainly our destiny.
Something tells me
it’s stupid to leave.
They probably won’t arrest us,
but it will be stupid for us.
- You believe that too.
- You too.
And it isn’t any more difficult
for me than it is for you.
I’m more used to it.
I really want to speak
with all these people.
The assistante?
Yes. And with your mother too.
and the devil’s grandmother
if I have to.
What’s the matter?
We stay. Everything is clear
for me, now. We stay.
It’ll be difficult. But it’ll be alright.
People like us do not leave,
and are not discouraged.
No. And the summer will soon be here.