MY LIFE:
Life, for most people,
is going from point A to point B.
But not for me.
I've got a point B problem.
Mia, I have your dress.
Give that to her.
Hurry up!
Yet I'd love to have
a throughline to my life -
a point B.
Tom!
For most people,
those small, daily trips
add up and, little by little,
lead to one goal -
a unique, ultimate goal.
Like the light
at the end of the tunnel.
It's all wonderfully linear.
Over there!
But not for me.
I always keep changing direction.
Why is my life like this?
Why is it such a fucking mess?
CHINESE PUZZLE
Ni Hao!
My life may not go
from point A to point B,
but a novel has to go
from point A to point B.
Hold on, let me tell this in order.
I'm writing a novel...
I'm trying.
This guy's my editor.
He's helping me focus.
- You in Paris?
- No, New York.
He's helping me get to point B.
- That's New York?
- Yeah.
- Really?
- I've been here 2 months.
D'you get my title proposal?
Yeah. Why "Chinese Puzzle"?
Well, I'm taking stock.
I used to think
my life wasn't simple.
But here in New York,
I see that my old life
was really simple.
So, there! "Chinese Puzzle."
Look at me!
So that is...
Well, that was my life a year ago.
Okay, everybody look at me.
That's great! Smile!
Tomato!
Get closer.
Smile! No, a real smile.
Tomato!
You're seeing
our last idyllic moments.
I can't stand writing stuff I hate
anymore.
Well, you can handle it.
I can't anymore!
Did I say that?
Did I say that?!
Stop screaming!
I never said that.
It's weird to think that
for 10 years
we had been so happy.
It's really horrible.
To think that that. That there
that can disappear.
You gotta watch out with happiness.
Happiness is disaster for fiction.
Drama's what sucks us in.
Life is drama.
But you wanna be happy in life,
don't you?
Sure, in life.
But I'm talking about stories.
What?
You see? That's a bore.
Problem over!
Wendy and I broke up 6 months ago.
I don't believe it!
It's true.
Oh, no, Xavier!
Don't make the same mistake
Dad and I did.
This is horrible!
But why?
You made such a great couple.
Everyone reacted like my mother.
I know it's horrible.
I know it's dumb.
But no.
And yet, I tried everything.
What about the kids?
Nothing could be done.
I don't know yet.
You'll still see them, I hope.
- Yeah.
- Don't be like your father.
Isn't there... I don't know,
some effort that will lead you
back onto the path of love?
It's not a question of effort.
That's how it is.
That's life.
You love each other...
then you don't
love each other anymore.
You change!
Was it Wendy's idea?
Yes, but I didn't do much
to hold her back.
She went on about
how I never wanted to marry her.
Then, this was my fault...
I screwed up.
I really screwed up big time.
How so?
- Remember Isabelle?
- The lesbian?
The Belgian girl
I met in Barcelona.
How can I sum this up?
Isabelle's like a buddy to me.
Isabelle's my buddy.
She's crazy about my kids
and wanted some herself.
She and a girlfriend almost did it
but then they split.
Then she fell in love with
an American - a Chinese-American.
The love of her life.
Since they hooked up,
all they wanted was
to have a baby and move to NYC.
But my buddy was up shit creek.
She cried about it every day.
And when your best buddy's
dying to be a mommy...
It's hard to handle.
Tell me honestly,
would...
Would it piss you off
if I help Isabelle have a baby?
I wish I had a picture of Wendy
at that moment.
Just so you could see
the look she gave me.
Put yourself in her shoes.
It is kind of hard to swallow.
Even if we don't fuck and
I don't cheat on her technically,
she can't accept it.
Did you tell her
we're moving to New York,
that I got a job on Wall Street?
You'll never even hear
about the kid.
I know.
I'll be with my chick.
You won't be a father in
the traditional sense of the term!
I remember her words exactly,
"You won't be a father in
the traditional sense of the term."
The rest happened in a clinic.
The least sexy place on earth.
I hadn't bought a porn magazine
since I was 19.
Getting back into that
seemed absurd.
And then...
I don't think it ever took me
so long to ejaculate in my life.
Are you crazy?
What are you doing?
Get back here!
It's dangerous to leave the dorm.
Shit!
- All done?
- Yeah.
See you in 20 minutes.
D'you shoot your wad?
Now it's your turn.
Xavier,
I don't know if this will work
but...
What you just did,
I'll never forget.
Never.
I was happy to help you.
I don't think I could have said no.
You're like my chick.
That's great! Hold onto that.
The baby?
No, "You're like my chick."
I don't know.
I'm kind of ashamed.
Who gives a shit about shame?
Pounce!
Shame's great! Shame's insane!
It's a thousand times better
than happiness!
So then what?
Wendy went to New York for
a few weeks to work on a script.
And then, when she got back...
What?
Then we schlepped back and forth
between apartments.
- Let me open it!
- I'm opening the door!
- No, let me!
- Let go!
Come on, kids!
Don't start fighting!
Not every time we go to Mom's.
The worst
wasn't Wendy's evasive look.
It was my son's insistent look.
Bye, Daddy.
He could see that
Wendy and I were unhappy.
And...
I could see
that made him unhappy.
Bye, Mommy.
Be right there, Mia.
How do we deal with summer vacation?
Want me to take July or August?
What?
Are you crazy?
Are you out of your mind?
New York?
You can't take off with my kids!
Are you shitting me?
If you're honest,
you just have to face the fact
that you've ruined your life.
That's it!
I'm turning 40 and
in fact...
I've ruined my life.
Your only salvation
at times like this
when you've lost hope
and never believed in God -
are... German philosophers.
For example, Schopenhauer said...
Life is like embroidery.
You spend the first half of life
on the front side,
the pretty side of the embroidery.
But you spend the second half
on the other side.
It's not as pretty but...
you can see
how the threads are woven together.
You can see how it's made.
Fuck, that's true.
Thanks, Schopenhauer.
That helps.
- How many of you are traveling?
- Three.
Bon voyage!
I'll see you soon.
Bye-bye.
Will you come see me
on your vacation?
When is that?
In just a few months.
Last call for Air France Flight 612
to New York.
I think that's you.
Shall we go?
Can I talk to you?
What is it?
I don't wanna go live there.
New York's a great town.
It's gonna be great!
I don't wanna go.
I wanna stay here.
You don't know New York.
New York's a really beautiful city.
They've got skyscrapers.
You're really lucky to be going!
So are you glad we're leaving?
No. Of course I'm not glad.
Then why do you keep saying
it's so great?
Xavier!
- It's gonna be great.
- Okay.
- Bye-bye, Daddy.
- Bye-bye, sweetheart.
Don't be sad.
If Xavier were here,
I know what he'd say.
"My first two novels
are being released."
"They're about me"
"but mostly about you."
What happened?
You really gave us a scare!
The place is packed.
Jean-Claude just started.
You must be thrilled!
Hi, remember me?
- Your neighbor from the olden days.
- Incredible.
I wanted to say hi.
I just happened to be here.
You must be over the moon!
We'll talk later.
Let me introduce Antoine Garceau.
Watch out!
He's the next Proust!
Congrats! Looks like you're a hit.
Here's my card, on the off chance
you wanna get in touch.
Here he is now!
Xavier Rousseau,
the man of the hour!
We were afraid you wouldn't show!
I'll turn the floor over to him.
I'm sure he has lots to say.
Despite all that was happening
for me in Paris, I decided to leave.
Life! The unforeseen!
All that stuff
you can't even imagine.
That's what I got hit with.
Yet again.
And frankly, I wasn't up to it.
Yet again,
I was taking off on another journey.
Sorry.
It was hard not to wake you.
That's okay.
So... Classy, huh?
Waking up in New York!
Yeah.
I'm so happy you're here!
Isn't it great?
Just like old times!
We'll live together.
It'll be great!
Isabelle, you know,
times have changed.
We're turning 40...
Stop acting like an old geezer!
It's not about being old.
It's just that
our lives have changed.
I'm gonna have my kids over.
And I'm not sure Ju's into living
with her chick's old pal.
We know where that goes.
Ju doesn't give a shit.
No, it's fine.
See.
No, Ju does give a shit.
And she's right.
You're really sweet to take me in.
But I'll try to find
an apartment soon.
Think about my kids being here.
Plus yours.
It'll never work.
I need my own place.
I dunno...
It would make me happy.
Anyway, feel free to stay
as long as you like.
And Ju and I will help you
find a place.
Is that far?
Let me make a quick digression.
As a foreigner in the US,
you inevitably confront
one excruciating thing.
That!
If your English isn't impeccable,
you quickly begin to feel
like some sort of retard.
Everyone politely
lowers themselves to your level.
Maybe I'm being paranoid,
but I got the sense
he wasn't really seeing at me.
To this New World man,
as a Frenchman,
I seemed to represent
the Old World.
I have journeyed one hundred leagues.
And with nary a blush,
Nor on bended knee,
I proudly sit upright before you.
Daddy!
How are you, my darlings?
I'm so happy.
- When did you get here?
- Yesterday.
I really missed you.
Did you enlist in the army or what?
Why do you say that?
Look at you!
A uniform?
Who says it's good?
Stop right now!
Over my dead body!
No uniforms for my kids!
Sorry but this is making me crazy.
Calm down. It's not my fault.
But I understand.
I'd flip out, too.
They probably couldn't
get into a public school.
Wendy did that at the last minute.
And their neighborhood
must be murder.
It's another culture.
Another culture!
Then she says...
Like I'm gonna go see her lawyer!
Know how much
Wendy's guy charges?
$200 an hour! Just to chitchat!
He's even got a gadget
that clocks your phone calls.
I swear!
You know what that asshole said?
What the hell does that mean?
Going to her lawyer was
a huge mistake.
I'm looking for a cheaper one.
Hi, there!
- Martine, I just got your message.
- So?
I'm in New York.
- Are you shittin' me?
- No.
Oh, shit!
I wanted us to celebrate my 40th,
like we did 10 years ago.
What's with you women?
You all wanna relive the past!
Excuse me, Monsieur!
Surrounded by sentimental women!
I didn't mean
to disturb you and your harem...
Martine, calm down!
I'm as single as they come!
Isabelle's putting me up.
She just wants to relive old times.
Still, we're making progress.
Yeah.
It used to take us days
to get over stuff.
Both of us sulking
and never saying why.
That would've taken us a week.
We have made progress!
Look who's here!
Hey, Lucas! Whaddup, my man?
Nobody says "whaddup" anymore.
You're such a noob!
What's a "noob"?
You're a dinosaur, Xavier!
For sure!
Say hello to Xavier.
He's in New York.
You shittin' me?
You're in New York?
You got all the luck!
Xavier! Chow time!
Coming!
You guys are lucky!
It's so beautiful here.
Now I get it. Rents are insane.
And all I've seen is shit.
Xavier...
Ju had an idea.
Ni Hao!
Where'd you disappear to?
Brooklyn.
Let me introduce your new neighbor.
Okay, no problem. Bye!
Bye!
Nothingness...
- Hegel?
- Yes.
Come in.
Thank you.
You write, too?
Yeah.
What are you writing?
A book called "Chinese Puzzle."
It's a novel about
how complicated life is.
Well, sort of.
I wrote a book called
"The Phenomenology of Spirit" -
"Phänomenologie des Geistes."
My book presents
a simple vision of life.
Really?
Boy, am I jealous.
Thank you.
Can you quote me something?
"All nothingness
is the nothing of something."
is the nothing of..."
Hegel?
When you begin a new story,
your job is to envision.
To try to glimpse stuff
that doesn't as yet exist.
That's what writing is.
Going out to meet
the ghosts of the future.
Not out of the past, not the ones
that are dead and buried.
Ghosts of the future.
Those who don't exist yet.
Great!
Here.
It doesn't have to be perfect.
How's it going, Tom?
- Almost done.
- Very, very soon.
- Just that little bit there.
- We're fast workers!
Mommy doesn't let us eat McDonald's.
Really?
Why?
She says it's no good.
Really?
Oh, shit!
So you don't want anymore?
Saturday is "daddy day"
at the playground.
Mia, take it easy!
Easy, Mia!
Let's go home.
Say goodbye.
Coming, Tom?
Ray laid out a whole theory about
divorced fathers being warriors.
Guys who won't let go of their kids.
Tom.
"The new 21st century adventurers,"
he said.
Want your banana?
I'll see you in a week, okay?
One beddy-bye, 2 beddy-byes,
3, 4, 5, 6...
Bye.
Daddy's kiss!
Why the fuck
would you take this asshole?
would you call me an asshole?
You speak Spanish!
I studied in Spain, man.
Thanks to Ray,
I started guzzling asphalt.
Pinned to the ground, you see that
New York's obsession is the sky.
The image NYC sells
is the skyline, skyscrapers,
penthouses, rooftops.
All anybody cares about
is reaching for the sky.
In reality, the city's split in two.
When you first get here,
you can't be part of the "up" world.
You belong in the "down" world.
You live downtown.
You have no right to the sky.
You gotta work your way up
from the bottom.
The New York asphalt
is like a boxer's skin after a bout.
The skin of a zombie -
a tattoo, body-piercing,
crack, scarification junkie.
So that's my life in New York
at the moment.
Things any better with Wendy,
now that you're settled?
No.
I should've just told her the truth.
We're driving along,
we get stuck in traffic...
Nothing unusual.
The guy tried to get out.
But he'd turned
onto West 11th Street.
And West 11th Street
is a rarity in New York.
It's not completely straight.
It elbows down, branches off.
So we're in that
little West Village maze
and stop at the corner of West 4th.
No, not here.
Streets are supposed
to run parallel, not cross!
So the guy loses it.
So the truck driver says...
Then the shit hit the fan.
Holy shit.
The guy blows a gasket,
hops out of the car
and he gets bashed
with the baseball bat.
So now I'm driving a yellow cab
in some tawdry
Manhattan detective story.
I pull up at E.R.
with my unconscious Chinaman.
I should have just
told Wendy that but...
What's wild is the Chinese guy
had just moved to New York.
And that corner contradicted
his entire image of America.
He'd heard it was simple
and organized.
That New York was laid out
in a mathematical grid
to simplify things.
But the fact is
things are never simple.
See what I mean?
Could you knock out
something a tad more linear
by next week?
Next week? Sure.
I'll give it all I've got.
I don't believe this!
- Hi, there!
- Hi, Martine.
Listen, Xavier,
can you do me a favor?
Sounds scary but go ahead.
I'm coming to New York.
Can you pick me up at the airport?
That's kind of complicated
because...
If I come to New York,
I'd hate to miss you.
No, of course.
I'll figure it out.
Don't worry, I'll be there.
Ni Hao.
Is that him?
What did he say?
He says he's looking
for a wife.
It's so weird to see you here.
I feel like I'm in Barcelona.
You really are a nut job.
So what are you doing here?
I have to meet a guy named Zhang Yu
who's based in New York.
He's sort of the "Mr. Tea"
for all of China.
I'm trying to get his support
in setting up a reliable brand
of Chinese-produced organic tea.
Because food safety
in the global environment
is "the" hot issue these days.
And don't laugh at me.
Boy, you've really changed.
You used to wanna save the world.
Business is a great way
of saving the world.
Think of the impact
this could have.
It would be like bringing
an organic mindset to China.
And not just for tea!
Then there's soy or...
It could be a real revolution!
Hello.
Oh, shit!
How high a fever?
Of course you're a good mother!
You're away on business
and she got sick.
It's not your fault.
She's dumb, too.
Why get sick on the day I leave?
I've obsessed about this meeting
for months.
I don't know why but
things never jibe for me.
They're never in sync.
I don't know why.
Relax, I know exactly what you mean.
Do I look okay?
Not too pathetic?
You don't look pathetic
and you're not a lousy mother.
I'll call the pediatrician.
Don't call him back.
Sonia's there, don't worry.
It's under control.
Go to your meeting
and knock 'em dead!
I should get going...
Would you stay for the meeting?
You want me to?
We'll say you're my assistant.
You're fine.
She seems to be a little better.
I can't find a single ticket.
Forget about leaving tonight.
You sure I can stay at your place?
Scared I'll rape you?
Good night.
Good night!
Yeah, I said good night.
Martine!
What? Am I embarrassing you?
No, but...
Let's not make things
more complicated than they are.
Sleeping in the same bed
doesn't mean...
We're sleeping in the same bed,
I'm cuddling.
What's complicated about that?
Martine!
What?
Martine, that's my dick!
I know.
It's been a really long time...
since I fucked.
How about you?
"Go deeper..."
What?
- What?
- Nothing.
Boy, you really have changed!
You'd never have said that before.
I wanted to.
Gimme a break! I'm getting old.
I'm not gonna spend my life...
I'm gonna be 40.
I know what I like
and I say so.
If that sounds slutty, too bad!
No way!
On the contrary, I love it.
"Go deeper..."
Stop!
Wait! Xavier!
See? We made it!
- Maybe we shouldn't have done it.
- I know...
I'm not so sure it was a good idea.
Okay, bye.
I'm just happy
we came to an agreement.
I didn't have the nerve to tell her
I was getting married, too.
And that I clearly wasn't crazy
about her coming to my wedding.
Mia, you could smile.
- I did smile.
- Okay.
Oh, right! This is Nancy,
my American wife, who I've been
madly in love with for a month.
And the 3 days we spent
fabricating a relationship.
Immigration Services would buy.
I don't understand.
I lucked out.
She was a great sport.
On the other hand,
the Immigration guy
wasn't such a great sport.
"We're not there yet."
Dad?
My father called to say
he was coming to New York.
Is everything okay?
I was surprised.
We hadn't seen each other in ages.
I thought about how my father
never did any of the stuff
I did for my kids.
Not just the happy, eventful times,
but even the uneventful moments,
like this.
When you think nothing's happening.
They seem meaningless but,
in fact, they're important.
Because those empty moments
are also part of life.
That's what childhood is.
And I'd missed that.
I'd missed him.
This has all really changed.
It's unrecognizable.
We walked for hours.
He talked about
the New York he knew.
He didn't ask one question about me
or the New York of today
I might know.
We didn't have much
to say to each other.
As if being apart when I was little
made for too little complicity,
too few topics of conversation.
What?
Hold on...
Your mom and I once
wrote our initials in the cement.
My J and her S
with a heart around them.
One of those goofy things you do
when you're 20.
We looked a little longer.
We saw something
that looked like a heart
but time must have worn it away.
Great! Everything okay?
I don't know.
Let me think it over.
I'll call you back.
Anything serious?
Isabelle had just given birth
and asked if I wanted
to recognize the baby.
- Remember my friend Isabelle?
- Yeah.
I hesitated to tell him
the whole story.
But in the end,
I told my father everything.
And now she's asking
if I wanna recognize the baby and...
I remember, all he said was...
Don't get involved in that shit.
Well, if I were you...
Bye!
After he left,
I realized
I had tons of questions for him.
Why had he and Mom split up?
Did they really love each other?
But...
Then without really knowing why,
I walked home on Avenue A.
And at the corner
of Saint Mark's Place...
My father got the street right
but the avenue wrong.
It wasn't First Avenue,
it was Avenue A.
There, on the streets of this city,
it was carved.
A trace of something
I'd never really known.
Here, in New York, at the corner
of 8th Street and Avenue A,
my parents were in love.
Those tiny initials in the sidewalk
held a kind of fundamental proof
that my birth wasn't
a total accident.
Two people were in love.
Really in love.
Even if they weren't together long.
No matter why
they eventually broke up.
All that mattered now
were those tiny initials.
- Dumb question.
- Spit it out.
Do either you or Ju
take on the daddy role?
I adore you!
Guess what?
I found a Belgian babysitter
who did Erasmus in Barcelona!
Isabelle?
Isabelle!
Yeah?
I mean my name's Isabelle, too.
Okay, sorry.
No need to be sorry.
Hi. Come on in.
Sorry... I mean, hi.
Let me explain
'cause we have to run.
You've taken care of infants before?
No.
I mean, yeah. Yeah.
Well, I mean...
Sort of.
I have tons of brothers and sisters.
I've never done it professionally
but it's like I have.
See what I mean?
Yeah, I see.
Hi!
Pretty girl, huh?
Not my type.
Really?
We never had the same taste!
That's for sure!
Wanna go to a dyke bar later?
Can't! With all my legal fees,
I took a gig here tonight
for big bucks!
Cool! We'll stay here!
- You wanna stay?
- Yeah.
- You sure?
- Yeah!
- I'll be over there.
- I'm watching!
I was really good!
I didn't even pick up a girl!
Even though I was dying to hump
that nymphette like this.
Ever see me piss standing up?
- No.
- You're not the only one,
I can do it, too. Watch!
- You can't piss here.
- I'm just demonstrating!
It's after 4 o'clock.
Oh, shit.
Oh, shit...
Shit, I said 2 o'clock.
Fuck!
Hello.
You okay?
I'm sorry.
I said 2 at the latest.
I think it's 4. I'm really sorry.
Everything go okay?
Oh, yeah, great.
It went really well.
She's incredibly cute.
She went right to sleep
and never woke up.
Could your husband
take me home or call me a cab?
It's kind of late.
Sorry.
There's something you should know.
This guy's not my husband.
I thought he was the father.
Yeah, yeah!
He's the father but not my husband.
I live with a woman.
With a woman?
Yeah. A woman.
Oh, yeah. Okay!
You have seen lesbians before?
Yeah, yeah.
No, yeah. Sure.
Can you watch Kitty and my trains
and build her house?
Okay. I'm building her house.
But it's not her lunchtime.
No.
If she groans,
ask her what's wrong.
Okay.
If she's hungry, give her
some crackers.
- Hi, Xavier.
- Hi.
- You progressing?
- Yeah.
How's it going?
I'm working my ass off.
I'm almost done.
I have a secret.
Why can't I see you?
I can't seem to get the camera
to work.
Neither can I.
I have sound but no image.
I'll call you in a few days,
when I'm done.
Without fail!
The publishers' congress
is in 2 weeks. I need it.
I know.
They're all waiting.
I can't show up empty-handed.
It's really important, understand?
I understand, don't worry.
I'll call you in a few days, okay?
Okay, take care.
Okay, bye.
Mia, how many times do I have to
tell you? When Daddy's on the phone,
he's doing very important stuff.
I'm done.
Let's see.
Did you do them all?
Oh, no. There's one more.
Tom, you have to work
systematically.
Otherwise, we're lost.
You have to do them all.
See, it says to do them all.
You've gotta be a little more...
Understand?
Mia, shall I feed her or wait?
So, you getting laid?
No, it's zilch
in the chick department.
You gotta get laid.
I'm not saying fall in love.
But I know you. You gotta...
And you?
No way!
Hey, mum's the word! No kidding.
Of course. Go on, spill it.
I don't believe it!
She really annoyed me.
You sleep with everyone
who annoys you?
No, but...
I couldn't find another babysitter,
so I asked her back.
It all went smoothly?
Yeah.
Can I give you a lift?
It really is beautiful here.
The bridge...
all that.
I love it!
I often work till 9
and bike home.
That's even more beautiful.
I can't drive you tonight,
Ju's away.
I'll just take the subway.
No, I'll pay for a taxi.
That's nice.
I'm sorry.
Then what?
Then we saw each other again and...
She's crazy about me.
I'm in deep shit.
Shit.
And Ju?
What about Ju? Ju's great!
- Yeah, Ju's great.
- Yeah, Ju's great!
Yeah, Ju's great.
I really like her.
Fuck, Isabelle!
You're so lucky
to have a stable relationship...
Take it easy!
Why do you need a kid like that?
Are you gonna lecture me now?
I'm not lecturing you.
I've tried to stop, believe me.
I said,
"I don't wanna see you anymore."
And?
Isabelle!
I can't resist that, Xavier.
It's just so yummy.
She's beautiful, she's...
she's young! I don't know...
She's alive!
And Ju's not alive?
Sure, but...
I need to know
that spark's still there,
that I still can, that I'm still...
That you're still what?
Take it easy, Xavier!
Know what I think?
I think you're jealous.
And you need to get laid, too!
I know you like a book!
You just need to get laid.
Fuck some chick!
Anyone. A slut, anybody!
Because you're turning
into an asshole!
I'd love to get laid!
But with work, the kids...
My head's not into it.
I don't wanna talk about it.
Martine and her kids came to NYC
for Easter vacation.
I'm really sorry.
Did you forget us?
No, I was just over there.
Hi, kids!
Hi!
How's it going?
Hey, Xavier, I've got a question.
You got a new girlfriend?
Can't you say hello
before asking questions like that?
The kid's got no manners.
Sorry.
Now Xavier can answer your question.
So, Xavier?
No, I live alone.
Ni Hao.
Let me help you.
Watch the door!
Ever since we broke up,
he's been very lonely and sad.
After your mom dumped me,
I fell madly in love
with a fabulous woman.
She was so fabulous
she dumped him, just like Mommy.
But otherwise, she was fabulous.
Where's Tom and Mia?
Where are they?
They spend every other week with me.
They'll be here soon.
Come on!
What's that over there?
What's that?
See that?
What bridge is that?
The Manhattan Bridge!
That's the Brooklyn Bridge.
Too bad it's cloudy. On a clear day,
you can see Barcelona!
Really?
Go to sleep.
Tom, get in bed.
Got a kiss for Daddy?
Good night. Turn off the light.
Mom, what time is it?
Nine o'clock.
That's 3 AM for you.
Three o'clock!
Time for some shut-eye.
And don't make a ruckus.
It's late. That's enough now.
Good night, Tom.
Good night, Daddy.
Calm down.
Fat chance! They're so excited.
Where do I sleep?
You can have my room.
Xavier...
I'd love for us
to be in love again.
Does that happen?
I don't know if it happens.
But why not?
We can try.
Even if it doesn't exist,
we can invent things
that don't exist, can't we?
I dunno.
I know you. I knew it would
freak you out if I said that.
We can try, at least.
We're so lucky.
You've got two kids. I've got two.
They get along really well.
We know each other inside out.
You know my defects.
I know yours.
We've both been knocked
around by life.
I don't know...
I feel like...
we could make a fresh start.
I'll be honest with you.
I'm scared it'll feel
sort of warmed over.
I'm not sure it's possible.
On paper, maybe. But I'm not
sure things work like that.
I feel like love's
about confronting the unknown.
There's gotta be a spark.
Know what Cyrulnik says about love?
Know what I say about Cyrulnik?
Look!
Martine, wait!
A tankful of Prince Charmings!
No way! Those aren't princes!
I want that one.
Jade, you pick one, too!
Pick out a prince, girls!
Wanna pick out your Prince Charming?
Can frogs be princesses too?
Sure they can!
Go ahead.
Grab the one you like.
- That one.
- You want a prince, Mommy?
I already found my frog!
That one's ugly.
Who wants to kiss him?
Who wants a Prince Charming?
Mia!
- You?
- Not me! Mia.
Now you have to kiss him!
Who wants it?
A little kiss on his head!
One little kiss.
He's so sweet.
Sure you don't want to?
I put a video on for them.
What are you writing these days?
It's done?
No, it's not done.
- Can I read it?
- Yeah.
It's so much better
than what you used to write!
- Really?
- It's really good.
I'm really impressed!
It's funny that you find life
so complicated.
Look at your life or mine...
It's complicated. So what?
I came to New York
to be near my kids,
who I had with a Brit,
who I lived with for 10 years,
who moved here
to be with an American.
I had a baby with 2 lesbians.
I married a Chinese woman
to become an American.
And life's not complicated?
I can tell
you've never lived in China!
What does that mean?
- Mom!
- Coming!
Isn't she beautiful?
She's my neighbor.
Big hit!
Sometimes it works.
What?
Nothing.
Come here!
Be right back.
- What's up?
- I have to see her.
Can you babysit?
And slip me your keys?
I warn you, we'll be home
in an hour and a half, max.
Oh!
Okay, thanks.
Give her a bottle in half an hour.
You're a real pain!
Isn't she sort of your daughter,
too?
Yeah, right!
What?
So now I am a father
in the traditional sense?
Hi, Tom!
I'll take off.
Yeah.
Why'd you say
you were her father?
So, that's it.
It's complicated but that's why
she's sort of your little sister.
So she's got two mommies
and one daddy?
Yeah, that's it.
Daddy, can we go on the slide now?
Yeah.
You can go.
I'll watch the baby.
- Thanks.
- No problem.
Mia!
No slipping allowed.
Isabelle's got a problem.
I have to go home.
- Everything okay?
- Yeah.
- Can you handle them all?
- Sure, no problem.
- We'll meet up later.
- Thanks.
I don't want any interruptions.
Fuck, Isabelle!
We're almost 40!
What a fucking pain!
Fuck!
Isabelle!
Isabelle...
Yes, Isabelle...
Ni Hao.
Isabelle!
Isabelle, open the window!
Open up!
I don't believe this!
Over here!
Yeah, that's right.
Hi! How's it going?
Hello!
Hi, Maria, how'd it go?
Thanks a lot for taking the kids.
Get lost!
No problem, sir.
Say goodbye to Maria and her kids.
Let's go!
See you tomorrow?
Yeah, same time tomorrow!
I'll call you.
Xavier, I came to pick up the...
Oh, Ju!
You doing okay, Mia?
No shells in the yolks!
Maria,
when you're done with the kids,
make dinner.
Hey, do it yourself, buddy!
Just kidding.
Can you help me, Mommy?
Be right there!
- I'm so happy to see you!
- Me, too!
I couldn't believe my eyes.
They could never stand one another.
But now that they'd both dumped me,
they were two peas in a pod.
They insisted
we all go out to eat together.
Ju offered to watch the kids.
And I ended up
with Martine, Wendy and Isabelle.
Whenever I take the NYC subway,
I'm always humming the Ellington
tune, "Take the A Train."
He likes feisty chicks.
Xavier plays his cards
close to his chest.
I think he needs a tough broad.
If she's too delicate...
Yeah, but sweet.
What he really needs
is a sensitive girl
who's attentive.
Yeah, but not too clingy.
If she's wimpy,
he'll suffocate.
I can relate to that.
I agree with you both!
Sure you don't want a taxi?
No, the bus is fine.
Let me help you then!
No, you have to put Mia to bed.
We're fine.
- Bye-bye.
Bye.
Okay, we're off!
Mia, I'll read you a story.
Okay?
- Then you can take your nap.
- Yeah.
It's getting late.
Why is Martine leaving?
Martine has a life in Paris, a job.
She just came for vacation.
It's too complicated to stay.
Don't you want her to stay?
Of course I'd like her to stay.
But it's complicated.
Who knows if she'd like living here?
New York's great!
It's a great town!
It's complicated, you know.
You don't realize.
Daddy,
Jade was sad to be leaving.
Lucas was sad to be leaving, too.
Martine!
Don't go!
- What?
- Don't go!
- What does that mean?
My plane takes off in two hours.
The bus is about to leave.
Who cares? Stay!
The kids have school in two days.
We'll figure it out. Stay!
There is a spark. Stay.
Yeah, Mommy, stay!
But if I stay,
I'll have to find a job,
get a visa...
We will.
I'll find you an American.
We're staying here now.
It's our town!
We're not gonna budge.
We're gonna settle down.
That's disgusting.
So, did you read it?
Yeah.
- And?
- So happy days are here again?
Yeah. Is that a drag?
I have a problem
with the ending.
Why?
It's sort of the hideous
happy ending.
What does that mean? What do you
care if they end up happy?
Calm down!
I will not!
Who is this guy, to say such a...?
Calm down.
I know your spiel about tragedy.
It's true, most stories
do feed on misery.
But when you find happiness,
there's nothing more to say.
So it's time to stop.
Are you talking about in life
or in the novel?
What are you thinking about?
Life.
Subtitle by bozxphd
Enjoy the Movie