A film by Manoel de Oliveira
OPORTO OF MY CHILDHOOD
"To my children"
Producer
Director and voice off
To recall moments from a distant past
is to travel out of time
Only each person's memory can do
this. It is what I shall try to do.
This is nothing more than the ghost
of the house where I was born.
A fatal ruin, a final vision,
with nothing surprising for anyone...
But to one for whom it was
the cradle in which he grew up,
where he became aware of himself
and of the world,
a painful longing
remains in his soul.
Oh, how many years ago
Did I depart in tears
From my cosy
Caring home
Twenty, Thirty?
Do I not even know when
My old nanny
You who are watching me
Sing me songs
So I may remember
I have been around the world
I have been around life
I only found cheating
Deception, sorrow
Oh! How disillusioned
Is the innocent soul
My old nanny
With your doleful voice
Sing me songs
To set me to sleep
In front of the proud house
there rose three leafy lindens,
the protectors of a beautiful
garden, the Eden of my boyhood.
My heart is broken
With bitterness
See what deep pain lies
In my misty gaze
Oh, had I never left
My narrow nest
My old nanny
Sing me songs
To lull me to sleep
From high up at the windows
one enjoyed a vast view of the city.
God once gave me in
The down of the nest
Precious stones from stars
Gems of moonlight
See, I have been robbed of
Everything along the way
My old nanny
I am a wretched poor man
Sing me songs
To make me cry
Like once before
In the beloved lap
I am dying, dying
Let me rest!
Oh, how your little boy
Has changed
My old nanny
How he has changed
Sing him songs to sleep
To dream
Sing me songs, softly
So, so softly
Sad, so sad
Like the sea at night
Sing me songs to see
If I can manage
To make my soul sleep
Be at peace, at rest
When soon Death
Comes to take it from me
Once, a long time ago, there was
only one birth there, mine,
there was only one death there,
that of my father.
The years have passed
and the times have changed.
Everything has been taken,
everything has been forgotten.
It only remains alive
in my sad memory.
''Eu sou toureiro, toureador
Bandarilheiro, farpeador... ''
My parents had a season ticket
to the opera,
and had another box
at the Sá da Bandeira Theatre.
I remember this scene
from the operetta Miss Diabo,
by the distinguished Oporto authors
Arnaldo Leite and Carvalho Barbosa,
just as I saw it
from box number 16.
Hands up!
- Hands up!
- And the step backwards...
I fell in like a duck!
Hands up!
Okay Madame!
You'd better point that away,
it might be loaded
and I don't want to march off
to the angels...
Would you like one, Madame?
Don't worry, Madame, this
won't kill anyone from a distance.
This is a real good smoke!
Put that thing away and
let me suck this beauty in peace.
That tool wasn't made
for lady's fingers...
Put that down!
Will you put it down or not?
Who lives here?
My father, the servants and me.
And the dog that almost
ruined my trousers...
What now?
Are you going to call the police?
No, I'm not.
In fact I thank you for coming.
I have finally seen a...
A thief? You can say it.
I don't stand on ceremony...
But, what's this?
Bravo, we have music!
- Do you play?
- I scratch a little. It's obligatory.
I was born in the Moorish Quarter.
Criminal hands
Sad rejected hands
Capricious
Desolate
Hands of hunger
And bitterness
Criminal hands
Sad rejected hands
Capricious
Desolate
Hands of hunger
And bitterness
Hands of Fado singers
Who never sought
A sweet kiss from you
Hands to whom I give
All my impure life
Chilly hands
Poor, frightened hands
Foreboding, aching hands
Now weary of suffering
Hands of wretchedness
That sob out a Fado song
On the guitar...
Hands that freeze
And that Death will forget
I remember the Hanging Tree,
which at the time existed
in the Cordoaria Gardens.
And I used to ask whether thieves
were also hanged there.
I never got an answer.
I was afraid. And in the
dark night, seized by fear,
I found security in hearing
the horse guard go by.
I don't know whether it was
to chase away my fear of thieves
or through a desire to travel
through the deserted streets at night,
I asked if we could take
the long way home.
My mother indulged me
in my whim,
and told the chauffeur to do so.
The chauffeur's name was...
Lamas.
The chauffeur was called Lamas.
Lamas, that's it!
His name was Lamas!
This is the street were
my long-gone house used to exist.
It is named the 9th of July,
because, on the 9th of July 1832,
King Dom Pedro IV's troops
came along this street,
having disembarked on Mindelo
Beach on the previous day.
This is King Dom Pedro IV,
the Liberator,
who left his heart to Oporto,
the City that was the birthplace
of the Liberty of the Nation.
Almeida Garrett,
a poet and a liberal from Oporto,
disembarked with King Don Pedro's
troops. And he sang like this.
''When I dreamt, it was like this
That I saw it in my dream
''It was like this that the fleeting
''Image that I could never reach
Would flee from me
''Now that I am awake,
Now that I see it stare...
''What for? When it was vague,
An idea, a thought,
''An uncertain shine of star
In an immense firmament,
''A chimera, a vain dream
I dreamt, but I lived
''I knew not what pleasure was
But pain, I felt it not... ''
With my head pressed against the
glass of one of those windows,
looking at the city, I sometimes
thought of the beggars
who asked for alms
outside Sunday Mass,
and I saw myself with my hand
outstretched like them,
next to my mother.
And I saw myself as naturally as I
had seen the actors in the theatre.
I also heard of someone
who had fallen into disgrace
and wretchedness. And I thought...
What if a similar misfortune
befalls us?
I added a thousand
other possible misfortunes,
which clouded my mind
like breath on the glass.
And then I thought
that I could perhaps
work as an apprentice stonemason.
It was a tradition
passed down from father to son.
I liked to watch them work.
But could I do it? I still remember
the song they hummed,
when they were dragging
a large stone
and they moved it
with long iron poles,
two men on each side,
as if rowing rhythmically.
Stone... oh!
Stone... hey!
The profession
of these honest stonemasons,
as humble as it is noble.
In those days all the houses
were built of stone.
A beautiful tradition
that is now lost,
as can be seen
in the old houses and palaces,
and in what remains of
the old wall around the city.
As sweet-toothed as I was,
when they used to take me
to the confectioner's shops
in the afternoon,
I used to hide,
hoping to be left behind,
and to be able to enjoy
all those pastries.
The Confeitaria Oliveira
a cake-shop was my favourite
and was considered
to be the most chic.
But I wasn't attracted
by the luxury...
- It was the pastries!
- It was the pastries.
There were the ''babás''and others.
But the puff pastries
with egg-paste filling,
the ones they called ''cocós''
those were really good.
Those pastries are delicious!
But the cake-shop disappeared,
and the cakes went with it.
This is it today.
I'm just remembering
a curious episode I witnessed.
At that time the tradition was
to have two exhibitions
at the Crystal Palace,
the Motor Show
and the Flower Show.
Because of their similarity
and being stopped at rest,
this is certainly the poets Fernando
Pessoa, on the left, and José Régio.
Another tradition
was the after-dinner stroll,
a back and forth
along the Avenida das Tilias,
where it was chic
for the society ladies
to show off their dresses
in the latest fashions.
There were some houses opposite
the Crystal Palace gardens.
In one of them, which belonged
to my uncle Casimiro,
I stayed along with brother,
his godson,
living with my cousins
while my parents travelled abroad.
- My cousins were...
- António and his sisters...
Virginia,
Alice,
Amélia,
Maria,
Guilhermina,
and Helena.
Of the three youngest ones,
the ones closest to my age,
the most romantic was Guilhermina,
and we were sweethearts.
At night I used to go upstairs
to meet her,
careful not to wake anyone.
These were
our very green years and,
with the innocence of children,
we would exchange a pure kiss...
Careful!
And immediately run off in fright
to our respective bedrooms,
carrying with us the delight of
that sweet and innocent adventure.
Time passed.
Guilhermina disappeared forever,
with tuberculosis, like her brother.
The houses are now different,
only the memory of the brief
encounter has remained.
And in this old Crystal Palace
they continued to have
a Motor Show every autumn.
We were in 1922,
the date of the
Lisbon-Rio Atlantic crossing
for the first time
in the history of aviation,
with the sextant of Gago Coutinho and
Sacadura Cabral flying this plane.
Somewhat later on
a branch of the Confeitaria Oliveira
opened here
in the Rua 31 de Janeiro,
the date commemorating
the Oporto Movement,
the first attempt to set up
a republic in Portugal.
The shop window was protected
by a thick yellow metal rail,
against which certain bohemians
used to lean in the afternoon...
bohemians who were... raffinés.
- Raffinés... and a little pedantic!
Raffiné... was Joel,
with his monocle.
And Diogo, who always
came along in uniform
and acting like a lady-killer.
The youngest one, Chico,
had a certain blasé air.
- Blasé... Very blasé...
- We nicknamed him ''Fantasias''.
Fantasias thought
it was of no interest
to carry on living
after the age of forty.
I think it is really inelegant
for a man to let himself grow old.
Longevity was shorter
in those days,
and forty was a ripe old age.
That's what you say,
but you don't know why you say it.
- Oh, yeah? I say what I feel.
- But you don't know what you feel.
And you do?
- I think there is a reason.
- You think so? Well explain it.
It's simple.
Men like women, don't they?
And women like men, don't they?
I think we've understood that!
Before there used
to be the androgen,
which included the masculine
and the feminine.
They were happy!
So? What do you mean by that?
That when they were together they
didn't have to look for each other.
How dull...
You think it's dull?
That's the way it was.
And from this union the masculine
came out on one side
and the feminine on the other.
That's where the expression
'soul mate' comes from.
Yes, I like the soul mate bit.
Well, what Fantasias wants
is to bring the two parts together...
That's what we all want!
Exactly.
And so, what Fantasias is afraid
of is that when he reaches forty
he will lose strength.
Lose his power
of attraction over women.
But has anyone ever heard you say
you would kill yourself at forty?
I don't have to...
I'll never get there...
Prettier and prettier!
It was extravagances like this that
attracted the younger boys like me.
They would tell tales of scandals...
Shocking things
that aroused our imagination.
Today's youth is rather different
and the metal rail on which
those bohemians used to lean
no longer exists.
Today, it is this.
I fell
into the bohemian lifestyle early.
I started frequenting nightclubs
here, at the Palace,
the largest and most popular one.
From the Palace we went on
to the Clube do Porto,
which was smaller and more refined.
Here there was the Primavera,
which was more popular,
and which always acted as a last
resort to find an available lady.
Have a seat.
Girl, come here. Have a seat.
- Get your paws off... rascal!
- Don't be coy, sit down here...
Will you let go
or do you want trouble?
Hello, sharp guy!
The lady whore has an owner!
- To each its own, my friend!
- Now you're talking!
- There goes the merchandise.
- It's a little difficult today.
Be careful.
This is full of pimps today.
So I see, so I see...
It's a little difficult today.
Tell her to sit down here.
Sit down here with us...
I'm promised to another guy.
I've got to go...
Shame... A great shame!
Some other night... When I come.
And you come too. Cutie...
Don't pay any attention
to these lads.
They just want free rides.
They're nice.
Nice?
But they won't give you anything!
It doesn't matter. They're nice.
What about me?
You? My darling!
You give me great comfort.
- Cod.
- Squid.
Women pay no attention to us.
We have to become philosophers.
Women, always women.
An American woman
scandalizes feminist society
because she preaches
a return to the home
and to the minute details
of correct upbringing.
How to behave at table
and to say thank you.
Jesus never washed his hands
before eating,
which surely did not go unnoticed
by the highborn disciples.
It wouldn't be Peter, the fisherman,
who would notice
his Master's lack of etiquette.
The fact is that nowadays
women move in a difficult terrain,
having to opt for children
or a career.
They eat badly, do their hair
to appear on television,
and hardly look in the mirror
in order to look at their watches.
It is extraordinary how a watch
outdoes a pearl necklace.
In a few years women
will have to choose
between the kindergarten teacher,
the technician in a company,
workshop or laboratory,
and the geisha.
A geisha also needs
a university degree.
She knows about music and books,
she reads Espinosa,
consults the dictionary,
personally knows Valentino
and has an apartment
in Ille de France
with a view over the Bois de Bologne.
She does not go on cruises
to the Caribbean or to Tahiti,
she bets on the horses and,
above all,
she stopped playing golf
since it became a way
for the bourgeois to keep
their names and feet clean.
The geisha may be sixty years old
and be magnificent.
She has many admirers
and very few lovers.
Men are proud of her,
confide their secrets in her,
and do not expect her to undress or
to cut up the meat on their plates.
The geisha
is a misdemeanour of democracy,
but without misdemeanours there is
no culture, so there you have it.
Other times I used to come here
with Adolfo Casais Monteiro,
who I met before he had published
his poems, 'Confusao', in 1929,
and his companion
Rodrigues de Freitas,
the author of the short story
'Meninos Milionários',
which would later inspire me
for my film 'Aniki-Bobó'.
This is where the Café Central
used to exist,
where I used to meet with Casais
and Freitas, university students,
and with others, some of whom
were students of fine arts,
like Boaventura Porfirio,
Camarinha, Augusto Gomes,
Alvarez, and the architect
Januário Godinho.
The group was more visionary
than political,
and was not welcomed
by the regime.
It also included philosophers
and poets,
with a natural propensity
towards ascending to the sublime.
From the Central we moved on
to the Café Majestic,
a magnificent work of the
ornamentation of the twenties
by the architect Joao Queiróz.
The Café Majestic was fashionable
then, and is so again today,
now conserved just as is was
when it opened.
We used to get together
in this corner and,
on other occasions
and at other times of day,
I would come here on my own.
And here I withdrew
to write almost the whole plan
for a film, 'Gigantes Do Douro',
that I was stupidly
not allowed to make
because it showed the effort
carried out by workers
to transform the steep slopes
into terraces,
and afterwards planting
and cultivating the vines,
up to the extracting of the precious
nectar that is our Port Wine.
Times that have now gone,
but which have left forgotten
a work that was unique,
difficult and cruel,
and today is done by machines.
This was in 1934.
We ended up in the Café Palladium,
located on the ground floor
of this remarkable building,
the Grandes Armazéns Nascimento,
the work of the great architect
Marques da Silva.
Very late on certain nights,
we liked to wander through
the dark alleys of the old city.
Besides me there were Casais,
Rodrigues de Freitas
and António Silva.
We would stroll through the alleys,
giving free rein to our imagination.
Casais Monteiro, a humanist poet,
was arrested
and persecuted by the regime.
He ended up taking refuge
in Brazil.
The years went by
and his exile reminded me
of the figure of the Desterrado.
Soares dos Reis, the sculptor,
committed suicide,
when he felt insulted
by the accusation
that he had plagiarized Rodin's
The Thinker. An unjust accusation.
What the 'Desterrado' expresses
is longing.
And it seems to hold, in its hands
crossed and resting on its knees,
the deep sadness
coming down from its face.
Adolfo Casais Monteiro
died in exile.
His bitterness towards
his homeland
and the despondency
he received from Europe
were overshadowed
by hopefulness,
as is shown
in his long poem 'Europe',
broadcast by the BBC in London
in 1945.
''Europe, without future
Europe, morning to come
Frontiers with no guard dogs
Gates left open
Europe without the suffering
Dragging their rags
Will you come one day?
Will there come the day
On which you are reborn purified?
Will you one day be
The common home
Of those who were born
On your devastated soil?
Will you rise, phoenix,
Out of the ashes
In which, false grandeur,
Burns
The glory that your peoples
Dreamt themselves
Each in wanting all of you?
Europe, future dream
If one day it ever comes!
Europe who did not know
How to hear in the depth of time
The voice in darkness crying
That your grandeur was not
In only being prodigious of spirit
If avaricious of bread!
Your grandeur was made
By those who never asked
What race they served
Your glory was won
By hands that in freedom molded
Your unshackled body
In an ever to be achieved dream
Europe, oh world to create!
Europe, oh dream to come
Before descend to earth
The voices that have molded
Your ideal figure
Europe, unraised dream,
Until the day on which falls
Your spirit over the waters
Europe without the suffering
Dragging their rags
Will you come one day?
Will there come the day
On which you are reborn purified?
Will you one day
Be the common home
Of those who were born
On your devastated soil?
Will you rise, phoenix,
Out of the ashes
Of your divided body?
Europe, you will only come
When among nations
Hate does not have
The last word
Hate is not guided
By the avaricious hand
The hand is not made bold
By the empty sound
Of the burying of the coffers
Digesting the blood of the flock
Of the flock killed in daylight
The man you dreamt, Europe
Be life!
Oh dead civilization!
No more your rotten blood!
Stiff, parched corpse,
To the grave, to the grave!
Yes to your new song!
Purified
Your name
Europe
The evil you were
Redeemed
The good you gave
Shared!
There goes the corpse adorned
In speeches
Blooming with wounds
With pus, with repulsion...
A corpse adorned by frontier wars
Fiction to serve
The dream of violence
Masks of ideal
Covering old rage
Go, corpse covered in crimes
For the restless gravediggers
Find the whole earth little
No blood is enough for them!
On the corpse your gravediggers
Dance their dance
Black foreboding crows
Suck your wretched blood
The more the blood
The more they dance
And you are carried
You perform
The steps of your
Funeral dance
But from the blood
You will be born
Or never again
Europe of the future!
And the hand to stop you
On the brink of the abyss
Will be born of the blood!
And the arms to defend
Your tomorrow
Will be born of the blood!
The blood will teach
Or a new, greater slavery
Will bring mourning
To your fields sown
With gallows and tyrants
You will cleanse of blood
Your tormented body
And, phoenix, you shall live''.
Exiled like Casais,
under different circumstances
was Agostinho da Silva, another
illustrious figure from Oporto.
We would go down to the river
and hold discussions
like the crossed iron beams
held up the bridge.
Or we would remember
the 'Douro Faina Fluvial'.
This is where I wrote that film,
the first that I directed.
A passion that stole me from sport,
just as the latter stole me
from the bohemian life.
From passion to passion
I became the filmmaker I am today
and that I will be to the end.
In this house I wrote and imagined
many films that I could not direct.
In this garage,
which was the garage of my house,
turned with António Mendes
into an impromptu laboratory,
we developed most of the negative.
In order to save money
I did the editing by hand,
directly over the negative,
with these rolls around
the billiard table in the house
that saw the birth of both myself
and my first film.
Thanks to the cinema,
we can see these bits
over and over again.
But only each person's memory
can recall things
that only we did live through.
And is doing so not the best way
of showing who we are?
But many of my memories,
in going back into the past,
have been lost and today
are entombed,
just as this ruin has been
entombed...
Oh, how many years ago
Did I depart in tears
From my cosy, caring home
Twenty? Thirty?
Do I not even know when
My old nanny,
You who are watching me...
On other occasions
we would recall Paz dos Reis,
and would think about the
Camisaria Confiança shirt-makers,
in the Rua de Santa Catarina.
Saint Catherine,
patron saint of the seamstresses,
who were the unknowing performers
in the first Portuguese picture.
In those days the showing of films
was improvised in sheds.
Only much later was there
the building of the first cinema,
the 'Cinema High-Life'.
A bell used to ring
to warn the audience,
''Ring-ring, ring-ring''.
When it stopped,
it meant that the film had started.
During the film, when the bad guy
would hide behind the door,
there was always someone in the
stalls that would warn the hero,
shouting. ''Don't go in,
the guy's behind the door... ''
Today it is this modern building,
the 'Cinema Batalha',
built on the site
of the former 'High-Life'.
So the 'Batalha',
conserved by the City Council,
remains as the historical bastion
of the cinema here in Oporto.
And as we have turned to the
first page of Portuguese cinema,
let us work some magic
and have Paz dos Reis filming the
workers leaving their workplace,
at 'Oporto 2001,
European Capital of Culture.
The city is being renewed,
but no matter how much
it is changed
it will always be
my childhood Oporto
with a gold stream
running at its feet.
''Do you want to play with me?''
Like once before
In the beloved lap
I am dying, dying
Let me rest
Oh, how your little boy
Has changed
My old nanny
How he has changed
Sing him songs to sleep
To dream
Sing me songs, softly
So, so softly
Sad, so sad
Like the sea at night
Sing me songs to see
If I can manage
To make my soul sleep
Be at peace, at rest
When soon Death
Comes to take it from me