Previously, on "Preacher."
_
I don't hate you.
Odin Quincannon, this is Gary Cutler,
President of the bank.
Oh!
Ahh!
Ahh!!
Are we going steady now?
Even better!
Where is he?
You are in possession...
of an enormous power.
We need it back!
Where, exactly, are you guys from?
We're from Heaven.
No, no, no, no,
no, you don't understand.
What's inside of you, it isn't God.
It isn't God?
No.
What is it, then?
It's a mistake.
What's that mean?
None of your business.
Just give it back.
Back into the coffee can?
That's right. The domicile.
Take care, preacher. See you Sunday.
Oi, oi. You listenin'?
I'm trying to figure out
what's going on here.
We told you what's going on.
No, you have not.
Not much, anyway.
What is it?
If it isn't God, tell me what it is.
Like we said, it's none of your business.
I could make you tell me.
Well, don't.
You mustn't use it. Do you understand?
Never, under any circumstances.
Tell me what it is.
It's called Genesis.
Genesis.
What is that?
Deblanc.
It began with Heaven and Hell.
Two armies fighting, two sides hating
for as long as we can remember.
Heaven and Hell?
That's right. The Endless War.
One day... thought to be impossible...
but somehow, a soldier from one side
and one from the other became
drawn to each other.
Here you go. Can I get you some coffee?
An angel and a demon... fell in love?
Traitors.
Strictly forbidden. They didn't care.
Snuck off.
Met in secret and conjoined.
Disgusting.
Traitors.
And then after a time, Genesis,
a thing never meant to be...
ya know.
Came to be.
So, you're saying this Genesis
is some sort of...
angel/demon baby?
If by "baby," you mean
the most powerful entity ever known,
the singular force that
could shift the balance of power,
threaten all of creation,
then, yeah, it's a baby.
Now do you understand
why we need it back?
Okay, so...
Seraphim.
Going for her phone.
We'll be right back.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Sorry.
Hello.
Don't fool us.
We just need one more day.
You got a phone in there?!
Yeah, we're not messing about.
Hey! Hey!
You all right, ma'am?
No. Let go.
See her?
Not yet.
Okay, body in the car.
Wait! Wha-What's goin' on here?
Get her phone.
Guys! Guys!
What the hell just happened?
Time to go. Come on.
Go where? We... You just killed her.
- No, we didn't.
- I left my car keys inside.
What?
Yes, you did. There's a
dead woman right there!
Do you have your car keys?
What the hell was that?
It was one of the Seraphim,
Angels of the First Order.
Angels?
Seriously? What's it want?
What all Seraphim want, order
and control. "Peace."
How'd it come back like that?
It's called reinvigoration.
Lubbock's the nearest phone for us.
We've got two, maybe three hours.
Lubbock? There's phones a
lot closer than Lubbock.
Not like this. This one's a direct line.
Direct line to what?
Wait... you're saying
if I picked up that phone
in my hand right
now, I could call Heaven?
No. You couldn't.
Why not?
You need angel hands.
God damn.
Angels.
Someone left their keys.
Eh, just leave 'em there.
_
But if you're an
angel, and she is an angel...
There are rules for
coming down here to Earth.
We don't have permission.
We don't have much time
before she calls in reinforcements.
Right now, they're just looking for us,
but if they find Genesis, too...
I'll just use it.
- What?
- I have the power.
Worked on you, right? It'll work on...
Genesis isn't a power.
It's a scandal, embarrassment
to both sides.
An agreement was made...
What is that?
That's just Annville.
An agreement was made
at the highest levels.
Genesis must remain a secret.
The other angels and
demons find out about it,
they'll want it for themselves.
It's not for you...
or anyone else to have or use.
Do you understand?
It was our first time.
We didn't know what we'd need.
How's it work?
How do you get Genesis to come out?
I sing to it.
Or...
I'll sing to it. It will come.
Probably just the towels.
It's not.
Here's a phone.
See?
Told him don't got to go to Lubbock.
Go ahead.
Make your call.
Now, dialing only takes a second,
but you're gonna have to look away.
Ugh!
Don't!
You dying?
No.
What the hell?!
If we don't die, we can't come back.
Watch out. She'll be back.
How do you do that?
Just happens.
What's it feel like?
Don't feel like anything.
We just come back.
Sometimes immediately in
the exact same place.
Other times...
Shh. Shh.
I think she's...
Oh!
Ugh!
My dentist.
Remember... don't kill.
Restrain it.
Restrain it?
- How do we...
- Shh!
Ugh!
Restrain it!
Is she alive?
Damn.
Shite!
Restrain it!
What do you think I'm trying to do?!
Fiore, hold tight!
We gotta work together,
otherwise we don't stand a...
Pull her off!
Stab her gently.
I said stab her gently
you... Fiore, don't.
Duck!
Oh! She's got an ax!
Preacher, kill me.
- Synced and corrected by VitoSilans -
- Re-sync by GoldenBeard -
-- www.Addic7ed.com --
Use the bed!
Aah! Tie her legs!
Yes! Grab the sheets! Grab the sheets!
She's clawing my face off!
I've got her legs! That's good!
Fight it!
You boys threw a
party and didn't invite me?
Oh, you're welcome, you know.
Clones. Bloody clones.
Watch out for the cord! She's
gonna electrocute you!
Do you know what this reminds me of?
- Shut up, Cassidy.
- Oh, fair enough.
Oh, Jaysis, what'd you do?
I disarticulated her.
Ugh.
We need Genesis back now.
Genesis? What? Like the bloody band?
That's a terrible name.
- Back into hiding?
- Correct.
You're what... Genesis' jailers?
No, no. We're its custodians.
We take care of it.
You let it get away.
It escaped.
How?
We dunno.
Why me?
Why did it choose me?
We don't know that, either.
We're just custodians.
I'm sorry.
I'm keeping it.
What?
You can't keep it.
I think I have to.
Listen, please, we need it back.
We'll give you anything you want.
I have what I want...
What God wants.
God does not want this.
How do you know? Like you
said, you're just custodians.
And you're just a
person... a sinful human being.
True.
So if I'm wrong and
God wants Genesis back...
he can come and take it.
Till then, I've still got a job to do.
Sorry about the mess.
Cass, let's go.
Oi! Oi!
We can't let you do this!
You're not letting me do anything.
Consequences, preacher.
Unwelcome, unforeseen consequences.
This? This is just the beginning.
I agree.
We can't let you do this.
Stay away from me!
'Course, there's the other option.
No!
Hey, Eugene.
Great.
Okay.
I-I'm sorry. What are you doing in my...
Stay away from my boyfriend!
I-I didn't... I-I'm not.
Mommy?
It's okay. That was just...
What are you doing?
I'm sittin' in my car.
You just broke my kid's art thing!
So, yeah, nice job.
What?
I'll fix it.
What?!
The art thing... I'll fix it.
Hello, Miles. It's Cynthia
again from Green Acre Group.
Sorry to keep bothering, but
I haven't heard back from you.
We're wondering if Jerry
Cutler and the other partners
made the meeting with Mr. Quincannon?
We haven't heard from
them since they left,
and could you let us
know soon as you get this?
♪ Blue, blue party ♪
♪ I'm so excited ♪
Can I get you something to
drink... water, lemonade?
I have beer.
It's 10:00 in the morning.
Water?
Sure.
How long you in town for?
How long have I been here,
or how long am I gonna be here?
Both. I don't know.
Either.
Never mind.
♪ I'm so excited ♪
♪ Blue, blue party ♪
That's a nice car.
Mm.
'72 Chevelle SS.
Crate 350 with a cowl induction hood,
4-11 gears.
Flowmaster.
TA tires.
Nice.
Mm.
I like this ashtray.
Oh. Thanks. It's a sugar caddy.
Well, it's nice.
♪ Don't hold her so close ♪
It's a bit like "Pulp Fiction."
And I'm Vinnie Vega.
That's cool.
I'll be Samuel L. Jackson.
That's a proper hard man, you know.
Oh, that's really boggy. I'm
gonna hit the shower, man.
Cold only with the washer running.
Beer while we wait?
At 10:00 a.m. in the morning?
♪ But while she's mine,
better hear what I say ♪
Clone people.
See, I tried to tell you about that.
You did.
Thanks.
So, what else has been goin' on?
What you been doin'?
Or don't I wanna know?
Ah, the odd mischief here and there.
I got pushed off a building.
Fell in love, went to hospital.
Nothing to worry your head over.
Some serious ink there, Padre.
Where'd you get that back one?
Mean old lady gave it to me.
What about you? You look
like a men's room wall.
I went through a
period of low impulse control.
Thank God that's over with.
Yeah.
What's that one there?
- This?
- Yeah.
That's my tulip.
Oh. It's lovely.
What are you gonna do, man?
- About what?
- About Genesis.
Honestly, I mean, what a terrible name.
It's just awful.
I'm keeping it, like I said.
I dunno, Padre.
Now, those fellers might not seem
the sharpest shivs in Heaven's shed,
but still, I mean, you
said they were bloody angels.
Yeah, and?
And I don't know how it works,
but don't... I don't know...
don't they outrank you?
Don't you kind of
have to listen to them?
I don't have to
listen to anyone but God.
Oh. Forgot about his
plan for you and all that.
You still doubt that?
After everything that's happened?
I doubt everything all
the time, all right?
It's the only way to live.
Well, that's where you
and I part company.
Now look, I'm just
sayin', if it was up to me,
I wouldn't be messin' about with it.
Well, it's not up to
you, Cassidy. It's up to me.
All right.
All right, so what are you gonna do?
Come on.
Same as before.
Nothing's changed.
There's a still a lot more
goin' on 'round here needs doin'.
Like what? More what?
More.
Hey, Eugene. Can we sit here?
_
Come on. He's okay.
I got the chicken fingers here.
You can't just crap on people.
I don't care who you are.
Wow.
Elizabeth Taylor... you
really slashed her tires?
Mm, I punctured one with a wine opener.
Pretty nice lady, actually.
Just a super-shitty tipper.
Los Angeles and Hollywood... that's cool.
Well... they're pretty
much the same place.
Oh, I-I... I know.
Right? Of course.
L.A.'s stupid.
We weren't there long.
Ran around the southwest, mostly...
New Mexico, Arizona... Texas, of course.
In the end, Dallas.
We were all over the place.
- Mommy!
- Excuse me.
- You thirsty?
- Yes.
Okay.
Here you go, now. Drink some water.
Your hands broken?
Have some more.
Okay.
Go back to sleep.
You'll be okay.
Made 200. I hope it's enough.
200 people? Really?
Imagine so... maybe more.
Can't believe Jesse's,
like, any good at it.
Yep. No, he's all of a
sudden really popular.
Can I ask you something about him?
Sure.
Mommy!
- What?!
God. Driving me crazy.
Sorry.
It's just, I have, like,
10,000 things to do
before Sunday, and sick days just...
Well, I can watch her...
if you got stuff to do.
Thanks. I'll be okay.
I mean, I seriously don't mind.
I-I can read to her, bring
her juice... whatever.
Let her sleep.
Yeah.
I just worry.
Go do your thing. We'll be fine.
Have you ever watched kids before?
I mean, do you have any experience?
I had a kid once.
That count?
Oh. That's, uh...
I'm sorry.
It's fine.
Of if you want, I can
take the church stuff,
and... you can stay here.
Whatever, if it'll help.
Thanks.
That'd be great.
Mm-hmm.
Mommy!
Now, look, I ain't one to back down
from losing a fight or
making a bad decision,
but there's asking for trouble,
and there's bloody beggin' for it.
Now, listen, even...
even to myself, right,
even I'm saying
this looks like a mistake.
This is why Genesis
was given me, Cassidy.
This is what it's for.
God doesn't make mistakes.
Grab the ladder.
God may not make mistakes,
but people are bloody famous for it!
Ugh.
Gowns are paid for.
You just need to pick
'em up from the cleaners,
and I told Javier
to expect you before 3:00.
Mm-hmm.
Macro Mart has
paper towels, toilet paper,
plastic cups, paper plates.
Don't get the flimsy ones, but don't get
the too-firm ones, either,
'cause they're expensive.
Candles and cleaning supplies,
you'll put in the storage closet
with the bulletins and the wine.
Right.
My number's there
in case you need anything
or anything comes up, so... questions?
Nope.
Um... what's that word?
"Ammonia."
Hmm.
Are you sure about
this? It's just, it's a lot,
and I can always call Miles.
- No, I got it.
- No?
I mean, it's just errands.
Yeah. You're right. Thanks.
T-Testing.
One, two, three. Testing.
Hey, Eugene? Want to
see something awesome?
Come on!
Spooky, huh?
_
Wanna see crazy, Eugene?
Check this out.
See? Awesome, right?
Wow.
_
♪ Tonight I'm alone without your touch ♪
♪ What could I do, baby ♪
Shit.
♪ Without your love? ♪
♪ Baby, baby, baby... ♪
Chairs, huh?
Uh-huh.
Wanna lend me a hand?
Sure.
♪ Even for all my foolish pride ♪
♪ Would you still be mine? ♪
♪ Would you come back, baby? ♪
♪ And be mine, oh? ♪
Mr. Mayor?
Everything all right?
I'm thinking about doing
something really wrong.
I can't tell you what it is, but...
I just wanted to know whether
or not I should do it.
Well...
based on what I'm hearing,
I'd probably say "No."
Well, what if doing
what's right is worse?
In a sense that it hurts more people.
You wanna give me
a little more to go on here?
How do you know what's
the right thing to do?
You pray.
For what?
Direction, what's the next best action.
How do you know it's
God... giving you the direction?
You know, not just the
voice in your own head
telling you what you
already want to hear?
Miles, unless you tell
me what's wrong, I can't...
In my head... it all
sounds the same, you know?
God, he-he's telling me to do one thing,
and I-I'm saying something else.
How do you know o-one
voice from the other?
It's not the same.
You know which is which.
I don't know.
They're really similar.
Either you and God are
saying the exact same thing...
Either that or you're
not hearing God at all.
What is that?
Emily asked me to drop some stuff off.
What stuff?
Programs, plates, wine.
Church stuff.
So...
You tried to forget about me, huh?
You tried to put me out of your head.
But the craving came on so strong,
you couldn't help yourself.
You had to hunt me down like a wild...
Wait. What are you doing here?
I work here.
What are you doing here?
Tulip?
You're his Tulip?
Of course. I should have known that.
So what do we do now?
What you doing?
Putting stuff away.
Emily asked me to help
out, so, uh... I'm helping out.
Emily did?
Mm-hmm. Been helping her all day.
Pretty much folded
all these program things,
did a bunch of errands.
You kept this.
No, I just... forgot to throw it out.
No, you kept it.
Put it back.
What's going on?
Everyone's waiting.
I was just about to open up.
Eugene's outside, wants to talk
to you. Says it's important.
I'll talk to him later.
Okay.
- Hey.
- Hmm?
This is good, right?
It's a lot of people.
Lot of people coming to get saved.
Nothing wrong with that.
Didn't even need to
bet your daddy's land
or bribe 'em with a TV, neither.
You disapprove.
I understand.
This is all working now, right?
This is all good.
Good. Yeah. It's good.
I think so, too.
Thanks for all this, Em...
for everything.
You're welcome.
You and Tulip done a
great job setting this up.
Tulip? Yeah.
I'll send in Eugene.
Everyone's waitin'.
What's goin' on?
_
Take what back?
I see.
_
Don't want to be forgiven?
- _
- Cheating?
You know, Eugene...
you're a hard kid to please.
Sometimes I wonder,
"What's it gonna
take to make him happy?"
_
Do you even want to be happy?
'Cause I'm starting to
think you got a big investment
in feeling bad all the time.
This is God's will... what I've done.
What I've done for
you, what I'm about to do.
Understand?
It is not "cheating."
_
I'm gonna save the damn town!
Jesus.
Eugene.
I don't understand
why you keep coming to me.
_
That's right.
I am.
I made a promise.
That's what this is for.
I'm gonna open those doors.
I'm gonna make them see the light
and fulfill my promise.
Then I will be free.
That's what I'm gonna do.
_
Oh, yes, I can.
Well, I'll choose for them, and
unlike you, they won't complain.
_
I don't need to hear someone
like you lecture me on sin.
It's a blessing.
_
- Eugene.
- _
- This is not a sin!
- Go to hell, Eugene!
Hi, Cynthia. It's Miles
Person calling you back.
I apologize, but something's been
going on with my voicemail.
You know, well, o-one minute,
it's totally empty, and then the next...
Right, exactly. I have 30 messages.
Yep.
No, I-I-I know... annoying.
I'm sorry to call on a Sunday, uh,
but I just got a call
myself from Highway Patrol
about 20 minutes ago to
come down here, and...
Well, officers, they off-offered
to reach out to you,
uh, which is the usual
way of doing things,
but, um, well, I said no.
I wanted you and your company
to hear it from me first.
Yeah.
Well, you see, Cynthia,
I'm afraid there's been...
a terrible accident.