Timing and subtitles brought to
you by The Ugly Ducklings@Viki
[Final Episode]
My dream is to become
a writer of children's stories.
Through fun stories, where anyone
can become the cool main character,
my dream is to become a writer of
children's stories who makes people happy.
When you're young, many people ask
What is your dream?
However, as I mature, the number of people
asking what my dream is gradually disappearing.
Holding onto my dream until I become
an adult isn't easy in this world.
When faced with reality, somewhere along the line,
the fact that the dream seems way out of reach,
and seems to have disappeared,
causes me not to even remember what my dream
was to begin with at any given moment.
However, before completely
forgetting my dream,
Instead of just being envious, how
about you giving it a try too?
Thankfully, someone asked the
adult version of me again.
What are we going to do
now when Hye Jin leaves?
-I'm sad.-Isn't that so?
Hye Jin, farewell. We'll miss you.
Farewell, Hye Jin.
Farewell.
Thank you for everything
during all this time.
-Goodbye!-Take care.
Fighting!
-Let's get something to eat.- I'm hungry.
I heard the stone pot
bulgogi stew was delicious.
-Let's get married, Sung Joon.-Huh?! What?
I also prepared the rings. This
one is mine. Give me your hand.
This one is yours.
I'm proposing to you right now,
but I'm not saying let's
do it right away...
You're asking me to give
you about a year, right?
-I'll come often.-I'll also visit often.
You have to go and be sure
to do a good job. Okay?
I'll REALLY work diligently.
So, I remained here and once more
decided to pursue my dream.
- What? - Oh.
- Is that it? - No.
Hello! I've come.
-Hye Jin!-Hye Jin! Welcome!
Totally welcome! Welcome!
So am I no longer the youngest?
How can we make Chadol's
Adventure more fun?
Instead of having him just holding that box of wishes,
what if we made it so he could fly around on it?
- Or rather have him just fly
around on it?-That sounds fun.
- I think the scope of his
trip will also widen.
It's such a good idea. If I had that
kind of box, I'd immediately fly.
So how about we come up
with an incantation?
Sounds great!
What incantation should we come up with?
Ppyo-ro-rok?
- Are you in the
workroom?-It's so nice here.
All the writers are good to me and
it's so fun talking about stories.
How are you doing? Is your
organizing going well?
I'm in the middle of meetings with new
places while doing my organizing.
Because of the overwhelming amount of love calls
from here and there, it's hard to handle.
Woah!
November, 2015. Happiness depends on ourselves.
December, 2015. Success is never final.
Kim Hye Jin, I'm hungry. Come quickly!
Sorry, sorry! I couldn't
find the sesame oil.
-Shall we eat? - I'll eat well.
Wow! It's bibimbap?
Looks delicious.
Give me a bite too.
Ah, it's delicious!
-Seong Joon.-What?
I think you've become a bit crazy.
Isn't that right?
I'm going crazy because I miss you.
There's still 11 months left
before we can see each other?
No way!
January, 2016. Life is a
long lesson in humility.
You've been in a meeting until now?
Yeah.
And you? Getting ready for work?
Yeah, but because it snowed a lot, I
think there'll be a lot of traffic.
Is it not snowing over there?
Hello?!
Hye Jin?
Sleep well.
I really miss you.
February, 2016. The language of truth is
simple. March, 2016. Love will find a way.
Everyone must be working
really hard writing articles.
Oh! It's such a welcome sight!
-Customer number 140.-Yes.
-Hello, customer.-Hello.
10,000 (Won); 100,000; 1,000,000;
10,000,000; 80,000,000 (Won)!
With this amount, it'll be enough to give.
- Hye Jin.-Did you sleep?
Your voice sounds stuffy.
-No-
Why are you coughing? It's a cold again,
isn't it? Did you take your medicine?
It's not bad enough for me to take medicine.
It'll probably go away on its own.
It may not get better. You're still taking the subway
leaving the refrigerator empty and not eating again, right?
If you don't feel like cooking, then at least
buy something to eat. Make sure to eat fruit.
I should be by your side
taking care of you!
Really, I said it isn't anything serious.
Even if it doesn't seem like anything serious, make
sure to take your medicine and go to bed early today.
Mmm. Talk to you soon.
Hello?
Really?!
You arrived? Okay, I'll be there.
Hye Jin, where are you going?
Someone came.
I'll be back!
Ha Ri!
You surprised me!
Ah, seriously!
But, don't you think
you're working too hard?
Don't try to stop me. I'm going to
receive a scholarship this time.
When did I ever try to stop you? Make
sure you receive it. Definitely!
But how did you get here?
Class ends late today.
I skipped class to see you.
You did?
One moment.
Hey! I told you not to call.
I love you Noona.-Ah, seriously.
What's with this?
If you really call me one more
time you're seriously dead!
Seriously, kids these days are really strange.
No matter what you say, they don't listen.
Who is it?
There's someone. A university student who likes
me and follows me wherever I go. A 22 year old.
22 years old?!
Wow!
So there's that kind of fun when you attend
grad school. It makes school worth attending.
Hey! Shut up. Let's go and
have something to eat.
♪ Noona, because you're my woman,
Noona, because you're my woman! ♪
Stop it.♪ I'll call you "you"♪
Stop it. Stop it!♪ No
matter what anyone says♪
-I told you to stop it!-Let's go!
Aren't you getting your hair done again?
It has totally come back.
Ah, my hair. After being here, it
just naturally became that way.
I think I'll just leave it the way it is.
Here, it seems to suit you better.
Don't you think so?
But, you really seem to
like having come here.
-Why?-Because you appear at peace.
Seeing how it turned out, you should have
done what you wanted to since the beginning.
If I hadn't gone over to work for The Most
team, I wouldn't have been able to come here.
What are you talking about?
Meeting Writer Lee was because of The Most,
so it gave me an opportunity
to dream again.
Where, how, and for how long I should
stay somewhere as someone who belongs,
it taught me that too.
What?
It's just amazing and
remarkable, that's all.
It's true.
What is?
How could you leave so
suddenly without a word?
How could you do that?
Why only to me... Why only to
me did you not say good bye?
That's why I came here to say good bye now.
Do you know how worried everyone is?
Where have you been living?
Are you eating well?
Are you really okay? So why did
you do something like this—
Since Deputy Chief could get
angry, everyday won't be possible,
but whenever you see a
pickled-radish, please think of me.
It really does make me think of him.
So what does?
It's nothing.
I suddenly had a thought
about that idiot reporter.
Ah. That Room ♪2024?
I wonder if he's well.
Seeing how his personality is, don't you think
he'd be good at living on a desert island?
That's kind of true!
Get back home well and drive safe.
Okay, I'll call you when I get back.
Seong Joon
The customer's phone has
been turned off— Huh?
After the beep, you will be
charged for the call. It's off.
He has never turned it off once.
Maybe the battery died.
Seong JoonConnecting... There is no answer.
Would you like to leave a video message?
The customer's phone has been turned off and your call will be
forwarded to voicemail. After the beep, you will be charged—
What's going on?
He said he was coming down with a cold. Maybe
he fell asleep after taking some medicine.
How come I can't get a hold of you?
Are you sleeping? Your cold
hasn't gotten worse, has it?
Thanks to Our Channel Managers:
yukimarie &amp; abracadabrax3
Thanks English moderators: mirna023_316,
lupita311, wafaahs, cgwm808
What's going on?
He isn't even writing me back.
The customer's phone has been turned off and your call will be forwarded
to voicemail. After the beep, you will be charged for the call.
- The rain is really coming down. - Huh?
It really is. Is it going to rain all day?
Hye Jin.
Hye Jin?
Yes?
I've spilled everything.
Why are you so deep in thought?
Are you worried about something?
No...
The customer's phone has been turned off and
your call will be forwarded to voicemail.
Why is it still turned off?
I've always been able to get a hold of him.
By any chance, did something happen?
No! What reason could there be for something to
have happened? He's probably just busy, that's all.
Hye Jin. Hye Jin?
Hye Jin!
Yes? Oh...
Why have you been so distracted since this morning?
Really, is there something you're worried about?
Not at all...
Could you go over to the
art department for me?
They told me the illustrations have come
out for the story-line we worked on.
Okay, I will.
Okay.
- I will be back. - Okay.
- Where are you going? - Pardon?
- The door is over there.
Oh. I'll be back.
I guess she can't get in touch with her boyfriend.
She's been staring at her phone all day.
Right? They talk to each
other every single day.
You know a long distance relationship isn't easy,
and it's about that time when things become tiring.
- Take care Writer Kim. - Work hard.
Thanks to Editors: cgwm808 (Chief), mirna023_316,
leogregory, ajumma2, elisem1902, waafahs
Seriously, what's going on?
Something couldn't have
really happened, right?
No! What reason could there
be for something to happen?
Has his cold become that much worse?
What if he has a temperature—
What if he fell in that state but no one knew
for days since the phone battery died...!
Oh! Stop writing stories, Kim Hye Jin!
I'm sure he's just busy, that's all.
Or what if he was driving
alone but it was pouring down
and it made him think
about his past accident?
Stop coming up with delusional
assumptions, Kim Hye Jin!
Seong Joon has long been over his trauma!
Ringing! It's ringing! The phone's ringing!
Yes, Hye Jin.
What happened to you? Are you okay?
Why didn't you pick up? Nothing
happened to you, right?
Nothing is wrong, right?
You're not sick, right?
Probably... not?
So why didn't you answer my calls?
Do you know how worried I've been?
Your pink sweater is pretty.
It looks good on you.
Oh. I bought one the othe...
What? But how did you know I
was wearing a pink... sweater?
Because I was on my way to see you.
That's probably why.
Seong Joon!
Rain, the rain! Rain!
♪ The time that is left for you and I ♪
Seong Joon!
Have you been well?
Do you know how worried I was?
Why didn't you tell me you were coming
today? You didn't even answer my calls,
so I was thinking all kinds of things.
I just wanted to surprise you.
I've missed you!
That's all? I thought I was going
to die from wanting to see you.
Let's see.
Now I can live.
♪ I'll only love you. ♪
So how were you able to
come all of a sudden?
With the way I was feeling, I thought
I might die from being lovesick.
You must have been working a lot.
Seriously! Did you get a vacation?
No. I came for good.
I took care of the house,
the car, and the company.
What?
I thought I could do it, but I
just couldn't wait a whole year.
I can't be away from you.
Hey!
Like I was cool, I told you
that I'd wait for you,
but I wasn't as mature as I thought.
I can't do it. Until you're finished with
your project, I'd rather wait beside you.
But then, what about your company?
You'll have to support me.
- Me? - Yes.
Wait a minute.
First, reducing the amount taken out
for living expenses from my salary...
What are you doing?
Wait a second. Let me calculate what I
have to do in order to support you.
What else do I have to reduce?
Wow, seriously. I can't even joke with you!
You know I'm capable. I've already found a place to
stay and work while I look for a permanent home.
Already? Where?
My lovelies, let me introduce to you.
Someone who has come to be my successor,
the new Editor-in-Chief of The Most Korea.
Nice to meet you. I'm the new Editor-in-Chief, Ji
Seong Joon, who will be working with you as of today.
It's great!
You came back from the U.S.?
Yes. I came back.
Oh, welcome back!
He's the new Editor-in-Chief.
Welcome!
Wait, wait, wait. Then what about
our Editor-in-Chief Ra Ra?
Me?
Our aunt... is getting married.
- Really? - What?
Oh.. I don't know... It
just happened that way.
With whom and when?
- Ra Ra - My Most Dario!
You know Dario, right?
- That Italian model who did a
photo shoot with us? - Yes.
- She's getting married to him. He's
15 years her junior. - Wow! No Way!
He said that she's the most beautiful person he's ever met
in all his life and fell head over heels for my aunt.
I'm dizzy. Let me down.
Ra Ra! Mia cara!
O sole mio! Amore mio!
Wait a second! I think I've hurt my back!
Aigoo! Noona!
Berry Delight Chocolate Oh? That's
a new drink Give me two of those.
Yes.
I bought these and they gave me a diary.
You can use it.
Really? Oh, it's pretty! Thank you.
But really, it was a shock seeing
our editor-in-chief, wasn't it?
I know.
I'm so envious.
Envious?
Of course I'm envious.
- What about us? You and I... later...
- Later what?
What I'm saying is...
you and I later... b...
Both?
Are we getting married is what I'm asking!
Of course we will.
Really? When?
- Within the year? - Within the year?
Joon Woo, I'm so happy right now.
I'm happier than you are.
Joon Woo, then where should we get married?
- Where do you want to get married?
- Somewhere cheap.
- No— - And let's not do the photo
shoot either. That's all wasteful.
You'll soon love me too, Noona. - Oh.
Noona! I love you!
I love you!
Oh, you're going to your
parents' house tonight, right?
Yes. I'll come back early in the morning.
It's an important day today.
What kind of day?
It's...
the day I get to keep my
promise I made to myself.
I'm home!
- Why are you here? - What brings you by?
Just because. I missed Mom and Dad.
And I can see our pretty dongseng too!
Take those hands off me while
I'm telling you nicely.
Ogoo, you're so cute.
Oh, really.
What about dad? The print
shop was already closed.
He wanted a good soak, so
he went to the bathhouse.
He should be back soon.
Oh, that was refreshing.
He's home. Dad! I'm home!
It's my first time at a public bathhouse.
Let's go together often, Father-in-law.
You... What are you doing here?
Oh! You're here?
"Oh! You're here"?
So the place you are staying at until
you find your own place was...
our house?
What are you doing to Son-in-law Ji?
We told him not to tell you!
Why not? How come? Huh? Exactly why?
Because you keep nagging at my
brother-in-law. That's why!
When did I?
- You always did!
- You always did! - You always did!
What do you mean? You're among family!
Of course, were family!
What do you mean, family? Why did
you drag in someone who's busy?
I'm glad you're here. Eat before you go. I'm
sure you have to eat, even if you're busy.
No! He's really busy!
Have some bulgogi too.
Chew well.
Just let him eat however he wants!
Son-in-law Ji should be in
the picture too. Come here.
Of course. Son-in-law Ji
has to be in the picture!
Stop calling him Son-in-law Ji!
But still, you should have told me.
I tend to listen very well to the elders.
- Thank you. - Oh, it's sweet.
Dad, here.
What's this?
I really wanted to get you
a new printing machine,
but since I left the
company, it took me longer.
Please accept it.
Oh no! No! When it breaks down, I
just have to fix it and use it again.
That's right. How can we accept this?
We haven't done anything for you.
Keep it and use it when you need.
That's right. Use it for
when you get married.
No, it's okay, Father and Mother. When Hye
Jin marries me, she can just bring herself.
You don't even need a spoon. You
really can just bring yourself.
Take it. This was my goal.
I will only feel at ease if you accept it.
Please accept it, Dad. Please.
Why? Do you need something?
No.
You're pretty, Kim Hye Jin.
-Let's do it together.-I'm fine!
Let's do it together!
Oh? What is this?
This newlywed couple feeling?
Hey!
Come on!
Seong Joon!♪ Beside me you,
not some other person, ♪
♪ are always looking ♪
♪ The way you talk and
look are not unfamiliar.♪
♪ You are the person
I've been waiting for ♪
♪ Perhaps I, because I don't know love ♪
♪ I am afraid I can't even say anything ♪
♪ Your voice calling me
(my voice calling you)♪
♪ Your eyes looking at me
(My eyes looking at you) ♪
♪ It seems you love me too ♪
♪It seems you don't know anyone except me.♪
You don't have to drop me off.
Just go to work.
I can drop you off and go to work.
What's this?
We didn't even properly
pay for your tuition,
when you get married, Dad said we should
provide you with a set of nice blankets
so he's saved up for 10 years.
Now seems like the time to give this
to you. We're thankful and sorry.
We love you, our daughter.
You're crying?
Why are you crying?
Why are you giving this to me?
You should've gotten a new
printing machine a long time ago.
I really like becoming
a part of your family.
Aigoo.
You cried?
Good morning.
Good morning!
Editor in Chief! Editor in Chief!
Editor in Chief!
You came into the wrong room again.
Ah, that's right. I did it again.
It's become a habit. I'm sorry.
Deputy Editor in Chief Cha.
Your clothes...
This is why they keep
saying, Moron Ji, Moron Ji.
Omo!
What's with this chair?
It keeps falling out,
it'll have to be fixed.
-Do we have a hammer?-Hammer?
There's no hammer.
Sunbaenim, just one moment.
Oh, are you going to clean it for me?
Ah, that's it, that's it.
What are you...
Here I go.
Hey, be careful with that! No matter what,
I'm... still the Chairman's son.
Hit it harder.
You really are hitting it harder.
I used it well. -Thanks.
But Editor, was Ten really
a part of this team?
Of course, he was.
What kind of person was he?
He seemed really chic from his photos.
That idiot is cool or whatnot.
Isn't this the time to laugh out loud?
But I'm really curious. What
does Shin Hyeok look like?
I know right? I'm curious.
He totally went into hiding. He
hasn't updated his SNS afterwards.
That idiot is probably living somehow.
I do kind of miss him though.
He always had this expression...
There's a meeting in 10 minutes.
Yes.
Aish.
This isn't it.
-Are you traveling alone?-Yes.
- Where else have you been?
- I'm just coming in from Switzerland.
- Nice. - Just here and there
and having no fixed plans.
Right on.
Oh, nice beanie by the way.
Thank you. I got it from my friend.
What do you think? Is it pretty?
Yes well, it's pretty.
It looks like a thimble.
How much is it?
-10,000 Won.-He said it costs 10,000 Won.
- Pardon?-Jackson, you're buying
this for me. Didn't you know?
Thank you. I'll use it
for a long, long time.
Goodbye.
What...
Wait, aren't you Ten?
Yes, I am.
Really? Can I have your
autograph or photograph?
I'm kidding. I'm not.
I wish I was.
Dude, that's not funny man.
Hey.
It works 100% of the time.
Where should I travel to next?
Writer Kim?
Writer Kim!
Write Kim Hye Jin!
Oh! Hello.
- I called your name.
Didn't you hear?-Pardon?
I didn't know you called my name.
I saw the illustrations and
thought we should have a meeting.
Would you like to come to my workroom
with the writers and writing team?
Yes. I'll go and ask.
Okay. See you later, Writer Kim.
Yes, goodbye.
Writer Kim?
-Number 180, Miss Min Ha Ri?-Yes.
You're older but don't have any
particular work experience.
Yes.
By any chance, didn't you
work at the Ara Hotel?
Pardon?
I was at the Ara Hotel until last year.
I'm certain that I saw you at the hotel.
Aren't I correct?
Yes, you're right.
But, why didn't you write
down your work experience?
Because it wasn't a position that
I earned with my own abilities.
It finally came out!
Wow!
Wow! We really worked hard.
Everyone really worked hard for a year.
You've worked hard.
Hye Jin!
You worked hard.
Look at the color. Isn't it fantastic?
I think it came out really
well.The Peeper Story
Oh, now for several days,
I'm just going to...
Oh! There was a person in this corner.
You found it.
That's the peeking girl
Peeking girl?
Ah! She's really peeking!
But the peeking girl is just
like a hidden picture game."
Hidden picture game?
Look. If you look carefully, you
don't even know she's there.
Just like a hidden picture game.
That's right. It's just
like a hidden picture game.
Story about a Peeping Girl
Story: Story Compilation Group
Writers: Lee Mi Eun, Kim Hye Rang, Kim
Ee Jin, Yoo Rim Seon, Kim Hye Jin
Did you decide as a group to concentrate solely on
the color white when you made up this proposal?
Pretend these plans never existed, start
from scratch, and plan another meeting.
Everyone, let's do things properly.
I knew it ever since he wanted
us to do a big clean up.
Excuse me, Editor-in-Chief.
That's not your office.
Do you want me to switch
the rooms around for you?
No, it's okay.
He can't even find his own room.
Ah, please take one of these.
- Why?- What is it?
Put it right on top of here.
Here you go.
I...
- I'm getting married.- What?!
- Omo? - You're getting married overnight?
Getting married?
If you have time I hope you
can come to at least eat.
- This...- Hye-Hye-Hye-Hye...
Ja-Jackson? Isn't it Jackson?
- Oh! - That..that's... our Hye Jin?
So..our... no..it's Hye Jin right?
When did those two get together?
- How? - Oh my God!
Our Hye Jin was... our Sin Hyeok...
Omo, omo.
They should have made the invitation
a bit better. More Most-like.
Wifey! Come out. There's
somewhere we need to go.
Where are we going all of a sudden?
For the last time, let's go somewhere
with a great view and have fun.
The last time?
You're getting married tomorrow. I
want to congratulate you properly.
Congrats on your marriage, Wifey!
Ah, if I call you 'Wife' now,
won't a certain someone get mad?
I put lots of effort into it with
hope that you will live well.
Thank you Ha Ri. You're the best.
I still have one more thing
to congratulate you.
What?
Employment Notice Miss Min Ha Ri. Congratulations
on your employment with Q Hotel.
Then, you...
Congrats, Ha Ri! It turned out well!
Cheers! Yay!
To a happy married life for Kim Hye Jin,
and to the bright future
of hotelier Min Ha Ri!
- Cheers! - Cheers! One shot!
Oh, how pretty.
But, why isn't she coming
out of the bathroom?
- Ta-da!- What is this?
Not yet, not yet. Ta-da!
I wanted to give you a bouquet of flower
that I made myself when you get married.
You know that even took classes to make
these and worked very hard to prepare them.
There's a little uneven,
but I wanted to make it
myself and give it to you.
Ha Ri. How did you...?
Thank you.
For today, tears are not allowed.
Today, I'm definitely not going to cry!
Okay. I'm not gonna cry.
You have to go and live a good life.
You really have to live
really really happily, okay?
Okay. I'll live really well.
Even when you're married, you have to
come running to me when I'm crying.
You know, right?
My Hye Jin is so pretty.
Now, now, now. I'm taking it.
One, two, three.
One more, one more!
Ha Ri, hurry, come here.
Let's take one together.
Hold on.
- Ah, hurry!- I'm coming!
- One, two, three.- One, two, three.
I'm so nervous.
Shall we go?
Hye Jin, where are the nail clippers?
Look in the second drawer.
Oh yes. This is Writer Kim Hye Jin
from the story compilation group.
Yes. We haven't been able to look it over because
Writer Choi hasn't sent me the illustrations.
Ah, yes. I understand.
It's not there.
- Did you look carefully?- Yeah.
It should be there.
I said it's not there. When I find
it, cut my nails for me, Sweetie.
Okay.
Kiss.
What do you think you're doing right now?
Ah Hye Jin changed. Weren't
you a kissing maniac?
Today is the deadline. I will
give you tons of kisses later.
We got married but I'm lonely.
I'm soooo lonely!
So, very, extremely lonely!
I closed my laptop.
Hey, where are we going? Hey!
The wheel on the trunk has broken and needs
to get fixed. Where can I get it done?
You're in Room ♪701, right?
Yes I am.
I thought so. I saw your suitcase
was broken so I already fixed it.
Oh, really?
Aiyoo, thank you. Thank you so much.
No, don't worry about it.
Then, have a good trip.
Yes. Thank you.
To my best friend, Jackson...
I think I'll cancel that.
What?
About how I said I wouldn't be friends
with you. I think I have to cancel it.
No matter how much I think about
it, I think we really are friends.
Not just any friends, but
totally great friends.
♪ You look different to me.
You, who were just my friend. ♪
♪ I think this is what love is♪
♪This feeling that feels
like the first time for me♪
Where is your house? Tell me!
Ah, let go! I'm going by myself!
Don't push me! -I didn't push you.
I told you to not push me!
- I didn't push you!
Hey, drunkard. It's a green light.
Then, you're saying that the younger
sister you were talking about was a dog?
The dog that goes woof woof? -Yeah. Why?
You said it's your younger sister! -She is my
younger sister. I took care of her like a family.
Did you actually think that it was a human?
Why are you being
delusional all by yourself?
De-lu-sio-nal. You were delusional!
This guy! Are you trying to play me?
Come here! Come here!
I never said she was a person!
- How can you name me after a dog!
- You shouldn't bite people! You can't!
Jackson!
Editor Kim!
Do you want a bite?
- Editor, are you coming back?- Maybe.
Let's go, Jackson!
Wait wait. I didn't sprinkle sesame seeds.
What do we need that for when seeds are pouring
out of us?(living very happily together)
- There we go.- Here.
Let's go quickly there might be traffic.
There, all ready!
Slowly slowly. Let's clean this up later.
Let's go let's go!
One day, I started
thinking about something.
I started thinking that main characters
are not only in dramas or movies.
In reality too, there are people
who live like the main characters,
and some who live as
supporting characters...
kind of thought.
♪ Let's hurry up and go! ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
Oh! You're totally tone-deaf!
It's shocking!
No, if you keep listening you get addicted.
♪ let's hurry up and go!♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
Hurry!
Rock and roll!
Peace!
It's fun, isn't it?
But now, I have this thought.
Maybe it was me who decided that I was
one of the supporting characters...
kind of thought.
Why don't you try writing something about children's stories? Whether
it's a feature, fashion, or beauty piece. Whatever you can write.
Oh how could I? I couldn't even
dare and I don't have that ability.
Just try it once. Short. About two pages?
Oh! No no, it's okay. How
could someone like me?
Giving up so easily by letting
life dictate your path,
wasn't it me who turned off the spotlight
that was shining down on me...
kind of thought.
People often say that
life is not a fairy-tale.
But sometimes like a child,
and sometimes like a fool,
how about dreaming of a life that's like a fairy-tale?
- Thank you for the food! - I will eat well!
Why? What happened? Why?
My tooth! I think my tooth came out!
What the heck?
This is so good! You should eat too.
Eat it. How is it?
It's yummy.
-Is it good? -It's good.
If you don't turn off the spotlight,
and if you don't give up on your dream,
maybe then, something that's even more
fairy tale-like than a fairy-tale
might happen.
Such as...
Ddol Ddol's family gathered together to
celebrate the safe return of Ddol Ddol.
In front of Sook Hee's
house, a red mailbox stood.
- so Sook Hee... - Yes. I see.
- when she was young— Hey! - Uh huh.
The first love that was thought
to never come true comes true,
or a childhood dream which had been pushed
aside into your distant memory comes true.
Miracle-like things could really happen.
Hand!
Ah, it's a go!
Let's go!
Yeon Woo. Let's go quickly
mom will be waiting.