Captain Yurine will be released from
the position of Captain of the ST.
The transfer will take place in a week.
I wished for the status quo
to last forever, but...
I thought about the same thing
just before.
Don't shoot!
Ikeda has been shot.
As for the mysteries of the 'Momotaro'
cases, I did solve them all.
This group of criminals pose as
heroes of justice
and punish the people that are
publicly considered bad.
This is 'onitaiji', exterminating ogres,
by 'Momotaro.'
The person they're going to
kill next is...
either Yurine-kun or Akagi-kun.
Now, which do you think they're
going to kill?
Subtitles by DramaFever
[ST: Scientific Task Force]
[Special joint investigation HQ of the MPD,
Saitama and Chiba Police Forces]
[Administrative Chief of HQ,
Superintendent Shiori Matsudo]
This has never happened before.
For them to act well-behaved like this.
For some reason,
Akagi-san is really motivated.
There are several culprits in these cases.
They act together in a group and repeat the
crimes in accordance with their own rules.
The rule, number one.
Leave an unicursal marking of 'Gobosei'
(Pentagram) where the victim is abducted.
Rule two. The person who carries out
the murder is different each time.
They're killing one victim per person
by strangulation.
It ensures that every member of
the group carries out a murder.
From the ligature marks on the victims' necks
we deducted the physical features of
three members of this group.
The culprit who killed Kurachi Hisanori is,
175 cm in height and 72 kg in weight.
Izumida Machiko's murderer is rather small.
170 cm in height and 65 kg in weight.
Hatakeyama Rokutaro's murderer has a large
build. 185 cm in height and 90 kg in weight.
Rule three. After the murder, they carve out
the word 'Momotaro' on the back of the victim
and dump the corpse.
These factors show that this group of criminals
is united by one ideology, which is...
social reform.
Kurachi Hisanori, the first victim, was a gym
teacher, and caused the death of his student
by physical punishment, but the high school
never admitted it and he wasn't blamed.
Victim two, Izumida Machiko, forced people
to buy beauty products by fraudulent means
and was sued by the customers,
but won the lawsuit.
Finally, Hatakeyama Rokutaro,
published a book confessing that he
was the culprit of a murder case
which the statute of limitations had
run out on, and made a fortune.
All of these people are publicly
considered bad.
This group of criminals punishes the villains,
just like 'onitaiji' of 'Momotaro.'
These are the executions while neglecting
the police and the law.
And rule number four.
At the place where the corpse is discarded
they leave evidence which suggests
the location of the next corpse, on purpose.
What do you think this is implying?
This is provocation against the police,
who are stupid and idiotic!
I've been repeatedly pointing this out, but
none of you ever reconsider your conduct
and that's why we're in this situation!
Shame on you!
You should be ashamed of yourself!
He's been behaving well in order
to say this to everyone.
Making a speech in front of you people
wears me out. I'm leaving!
Our work is finished!
Good job, everyone!
Ugh, so filthy!
Okay, everyone! May I have
your attention, please!
There's another person who
was abducted.
This is Koganei Makoto-san, and the owner of
a restaurant chain called Koganei Holdings.
But, this company has been criticized
as a 'sweat-shop'
and the other day a class action
lawsuit was filed
by the surviving family members of the
employees, who died from overwork.
The court was in favor of Koganei, and it
fueled more criticism for the company.
- [Koganei Makoto, The fourth victim]
- Bribe the surviving family members if they'll appeal.
Then, they'll keep their mouths shut.
By going through this trial, they must
have realized that they can't beat me.
Who are you people?
There was a Gobosei marking at the
location where Koganei-san was abducted.
He's also publicly considered a villain.
We've already requested for the
media not to cover this.
If people get alarmed,
it works in the culprits' favor.
We're going to solve the case before
Mr. Koganei is found dead.
I apologize for my delay.
I'm Sekimoto of the First Investigation
Division of the Saitama police.
We've discovered evidence which
indicates the location of the next corpse.
This is a souvenir from the amusement
park in Nerima Ward.
- Confirm with the local precinct!
- Yes, ma'am!
No, it's too late!
The pictures are on the
internet already...
[Is it really true that Koganei was killed?]
[Fake crying Kotanei, dead.]
- [Momotaro is justice!]
- [Momotaro, don't get caught by the stupid police!]
[Tokyo, Nerima Ward, 1:48 p.m.]
[Momotaro]
This is the fourth victim.
[Fare]
He couldn't have been helped.
Couldn't have been helped?
He was abducted by the
criminal group four days ago.
He was already as good as dead. The
question is who will become the fifth victim.
Akagi-san, what you just said
is inexcusable!
How could you say it couldn't have been
helped when someone was killed?
Quiet! Shut up! Quiet!
Shut up! Quiet!
This was left at the crime scene
this time.
'The next location is the whole country.'
That's the message, I assume.
It can't be!
That won't be good for a hint!
The culprits have stopped giving us the notice.
I'm going to ask Aoyama's opinion.
Back to the lab.
No matter how he was publicly considered
a villain, I'm sure he had a family as well.
He must have had things
he wanted to do.
I said the same thing once before.
But, Akagi-san just discarded me
by saying 'Of course.'
That's very important, isn't it?
Feelings like that for a detective.
Now, could you please let me hear
your opinions or thoughts?
I'll bring word to the investigation
headquarters, as it is.
Go ahead!
Please go ahead!
What's the matter? You always
speak up without reservation!
Mister, how long are you going
to stay at the ST?
Mister?
They are none of Mr. Yurine's business.
- Mister?
- Oh, I see.
He's not our Captain anymore.
I'd say, it depends on the physical
condition of Inspector Ikeda.
What? Aren't you going to leave?
Please stop creating such an atmosphere
by saying 'it's okay to leave.'
I really don't like the state of limbo
we're in, you know?
Because I can't decide whether I should
call you Mister or Captain.
Why don't you ask the person in question
what he'd like to be called?
Captain! I'd like to be called Captain,
the same as always!
In that case, Mister it is!
Let's leave it at that.
Yes, I think so, too.
[Change from Captain to Mister]
Well then, can I speak up
without reservation?
You have permission from... Mister.
Even though the person who carries out
the murder is different each time
these series of crimes are perfectly
'organized' in a fascinating way
and this group is united wholly
as an organization.
So there may be several people involved
but we'll consider that it's
just a single personality right here.
There are three points to think about.
One, the victims. Two, the evidence.
And three, a contradiction.
A contradiction? What do you mean
by a contradiction?
Mister, you're going too fast! Let's start
with number one, the victims.
The culprits has a clear intention
in selecting the victims.
All victims were the people who
never got punished
even though they were
publicly considered bad.
A case similar to this happened in
New York in the 1980's.
A criminal named Bernhard Goetz
attempted to kill four gangs
who had become an object of public
concern, as a punishment.
Goetz was arrested, but the people's
reaction was so simple.
'He did a good job.' 'We don't want you
to give him a heavy sentence.'
Whether reflecting those citizens'
demands or not
he wasn't even accused of the
attempted murder
but only convicted of illegal possession
of the handgun.
The culprits this time, want the very
demands of citizens.
Once they learned that the police
restrained the media coverage
they made sure to leave the corpse in a way
that would spread throughout the news.
It's pointless if the incident doesn't
come into the light.
In that case, wouldn't it be better if they
left the corpses openly from the beginning?
Bzzz! Stupid! That's a matter of how
much impact it can have, you know?
What if, after the incident comes to light,
they find out that there had been
actually three similar incidents before and
the police didn't make them public?
The police will be openly condemned.
Ding-dong!
Next, number two, the evidence.
The culprits nonchalantly leave things
which represent themselves
such as Gobosei and the carved
seal of 'Momotaro'
and also take the trouble of leaving
a hint for the next crime scene.
It's a so-called theatrical crime.
As Akagi-san said before, this must be
a challenge to the police.
They want to appeal themselves,
who carry out justice, to the public
and spread the awareness of how tepid justice
according to the police and the court is.
But for this reason, number three.
A contradiction occurs.
And, that's all so far.
That's all so far?
I think that they have an intense
contradiction, but...
I'm sorry.
I can't quite explain it yet.
After you stirred up like that?
You're so annoying!
Then, I'll tell you this much.
The principal offender of this criminal
group has a suicide wish.
What?
He wants to accomplish his magnificent
goal, but is also willing to die.
I sense that kind of contradiction.
But, I don't even know why
I sense that.
A suicide wish.
[Koganei Holdings]
- Could you say a few words?
- Please tell us something.
[Office general reception]
Yamabuki?
Do you know much about the Theory of
Yin-Yang and the Five Elements?
The Theory of Yin-Yang and the
Five Elements?
Well, I only know a rough outline.
How much do you know?
The Theory of Yin-Yang and the Five
Elements is based on, namely...
Wood.
Fire.
Earth.
Metal.
And Water.
And these five elements can be
applied to all things in the world
such as the direction, the colors, and
the internal organs of a human being.
Even from the senses of smell and taste,
to the animals, flowers, nuts and fishes.
And that marking of Gobosei is related
to the Five Elements theory, isn't it?
Yes, it represents the the functions
of the five elements.
On one hand the culprits put up a magnificent
purpose of murder in the name of justice
but on the other hand they want us
to solve the mysteries.
You're right.
And that's also a contradiction.
And the principal offender has a suicide wish,
and the reason is...
Aoyama, continue agonizing over this.
Okay, I'll agonize.
And now, the culprits are telling us
to solve this mystery as well.
- What kind of mystery is it?
- So I did a favor and already solved it.
The first victim, Kurachi Hisanori.
- [Earth]
- [Kurachi]
The second victim, Izumida Machiko.
- [Water]
- [Izumida]
The third victim, Hatakeyama Rokutaro.
- [Fire]
- [Hatakeyama]
And the fourth victim,
Kotanei Makoto.
- [Metal]
- [Koganei]
And they left each corpse at the locations
where these Kanji characters were relevant.
For Kurachi as earth, the playground.
For Izumida as water, the swimming pool.
For Hatakeyama as fire, the incinerator site.
For Koganei as metal, the fare sign
of the amusement park.
In the name of the next target...
there should be a Kanji character
which contains 'wood.'
That applies to many people, doesn't it?
I'm in there too.
The person they're going to kill next is...
either Yurine-kun...
or Akagi-kun.
Mister, I'm ordering you.
Don't ever leave this room.
Sorry? Do you perhaps think
I'm the next target?
Your apartment isn't safe either.
You should retreat into the lab.
I haven't been publicly certified
as a bad person.
Shut up! Don't join the investigation either.
I will investigate! I'm the Captain
here for five more days!
You're going to slow me down, bastard!
At last, you called me a bastard.
If this man tries to go outside, hit him.
I'll allow you to go as far as to
half-kill him, okay?
[Akagi: I solved the mystery.]
[Akagi: The next target is Captain.
The reason is Gobosei. The culprits are...]
[going in order of 'Earth', 'Water',
'Fire', 'Metal' and 'Wood'.]
[Saegusa: Incorrect. Please hurry up
and solve the mystery.]
Akagi-san!
Lieutenant Sekimoto of the Saitama
police has been abducted.
That marking was left at the crime scene.
- [Wood]
- [Sekimoto]
What about the video recording of
this security camera?
The recording disk has been taken out
from the security office.
There's someone who belongs to the
criminal group inside the company.
- Check the list of the security guards.
- Right away!
'Earth' comes after 'Wood.'
- [Earth]
- [Akagi]
The person they're going
to kill next is...
either Yurine-kun, or Akagi-kun.
Among the security guards of Koganei Group
there's just one person who
fits the physique of the culprits.
Samejima Kenichi. He's a former police
officer at the Saitama police
and joined the company as a bodyguard
for President Koganei.
Understood.
But, this person is not publicly
considered a bad person.
On the contrary, there are many people
who conclude that the police are bad.
And after these incidents, the police
are now totally portrayed as the villain.
[Sekimoto]
What did my husband do?
He's not a bad person!
We know.
There are two types of people
who investigate murders.
One type, like this man, gets the burning
desire to arrest the criminal
from sympathizing with the
surviving family members.
The other type...
proceeds with the investigation by
imagining how the murderer feels.
I heard that he's been a detective
for over 20 years.
That means, murder has become an
everyday affair for him.
What are you saying?
Your husband has been troubled with
his job as a detective, hasn't he?
His mind was exhausted, and
he wanted to quit.
Earlier, you were talking about yourself.
The 'type of person who imagines how
the murderer feels', wasn't it?
What do you think about these culprits?
Of course, I can't...
forgive them.
And Sekimoto-san told me this.
No matter how he was publicly considered
a villain, he must have had a family.
His family must be grieving.
But, there are people who were
tormented by those villains.
Don't you think these culprits relieved
them from their suffering?
Akagi-san, I don't like that part of you.
Murder is murder.
'He who fights with monsters might take
care lest he thereby become a monster.'
That's the important part.
There's no need to solve a mystery by
imagining how the murderer feels.
This is such a rare situation,
that I'm actually nervous.
Did you notice anything about the suicide
wish of the principal offender?
I don't think I can explain it
well yet.
Is that by any chance...
something you felt as a result of imagining
how the murderer would feel?
Um... that's not quite right.
People often misunderstand that the profilers
investigate by imagining how the murderer feels
but it's simply the study of statistics.
So, it feels like, the massive
statistical data inside
is pointing to the suicide wish of
the principal offender.
Do you get it?
Akagi-san, you're acting strange.
Profile me.
What?
Why am I so obsessive about
solving mysteries?
Is it because I want to find out the feelings
of the monsters who commit murders?
Sorry, but I don't know.
You should talk to Captain about
things like that.
What'll happen to me when he's gone?
It's not like you to say things like that.
But, I'm also worried.
It's time for me to be independent
from Captain.
Independent...
Even after the new Captain comes,
we'll have to be the same as before.
Our mental rehabilitation is finally over.
I'm sorry for asking you to
come all of a sudden.
Not really.
You came alone as I requested,
didn't you?
Yes.
Oh, where's Captain...
I mean, Mister?
The Director would like to
have a talk with him.
- He should have been back.
- What do you want to talk to him about?
It's about Captain Yurine.
His withdrawal from the ST has
been officially decided.
Even though we're right in the
middle of the investigation.
The higher-ups don't have a clue.
Tell Captain Yurine to contact me.
Someone who's closely related to the crime
should be more careful not to commit
a crime or to become a monster.
It's the same with police officers.
I may become...
Akagi-san won't become a monster.
- How can you be sure?
- I'll make sure to stop you.
So, this really is our farewell, isn't it?
I want to say my thanks to Captain.
Say, thank you for taking care
of people like us.
I'm sure that you all feel
the same as me.
As I said before, it's against the rules
to profile your colleagues.
Right. You feel the same too,
Akagi-san, don't you?
- Is everyone assembled here?
- Cap...ster isn't here, though.
- Caster?
- Cas... I mean, Mister. Mister Yurine.
Oh. It seems like this series of incidents
didn't just happen recently.
Apparently three months ago
a corpse with the carved seal of 'Momotaro'
was also discovered in Kasukabe, Saitama.
The culprit in this case hasn't
been arrested yet.
Since we're temporarily closed, I can't
guarantee the condition of the coffee beans.
Please.
Temporarily closed means, you're
going to open it up again someday?
Did you hear something from Akagi-kun?
Something?
About me.
No, nothing at all.
I see.
Actually, once it had been decided
that I'm to leave the ST
Akagi-san doesn't talk much
to me anymore.
He also loses his temper and tells
me to get off the investigation.
These cases will be my last, so I want to
be helpful for Akagi-san in the end.
I'm going to tell you a little bit
about 'Momotaro.'
You're going to cooperate with
our investigation?
Please go ahead.
Momotaro was modeled on someone
named Kibitsuhiko-no-mikoto.
The official history is that, he came to Okayama,
which was called Kibi-no-kuni back then
and fought the people who were committing
crimes, according to the Chronicles of Japan.
But, there are some people who
interpret the story differently.
In what way?
Kibitsuhiko-no-mikoto was an aggressor
sent by the Yamato Imperial Court
and no one was committing
crimes in the area.
Momotaro was an aggressor?
History is always written by the winners.
There's always a conflict between
good and evil in any age.
Actually, that's not true.
There's always a conflict between
good and good in any age.
Our justice and their justice.
It's an old, stale remark, but this is
the very truth I believe in.
[Saegusa Toshiro]
We need to tell this to Captain,
I mean, Mister now!
The person who told me about the story
of Momotaro being an aggressor was
my best friend.
Best friend?
We joined the force in the same year
and often had a long talk about
the justice of the police.
When justice became our topic, he
always talked about Momotaro.
Where is he now?
While I continued working as a detective,
his mind had become exhausted.
In a manner of speaking,
he had become a monster.
The reason I created the ST was to
create a place for Akagi-kun and everyone
and also for more people to
believe in the police.
Please take care of Akagi-kun
until the end, Captain.
Yes.
This.
Akagi-san gave me this before, but
I was too embarrassed to use it.
Not too bad.
Oh. Excuse me, it's from the lab.
There's an Episode Zero in this
series of murders.
Three months ago, a corpse with the seal of
'Momotaro was also found in Kasukabe, Saitama.
In Kasukabe?
The victim was Amaki Shinpei,
37 years old.
He was also publicly considered a villain.
Amaki was arrested for suspicion
of rape and murder
but the evidence was denied in trial
and he was acquitted.
But right after his release, Amaki committed
another rape and murder.
This time, a female police officer was killed.
It was his revenge against the police.
The police persistently investigated,
but Amaki ran away and disappeared.
And three months ago,
he was murdered.
- What about the culprit?
- Hasn't been arrested yet, but
there are many suspicious people.
Most of the detectives who joined the investigation
must have felt the intention to kill Amaki.
And there's one more notable
person among them.
- Who is it?
- It's Saegusa-san.
Saegusa-san and the female
police officer, who Amaki killed
joined the force in the same year
and were friends.
And three months ago,
when Amaki was murdered
was the time Saegusa-san left
the police department.
I'm leaving the police department.
There is something I want to do.
Japan has become an unhealthy country,
even before we knew it.
Where do you think the feelings of someone
who lost their loved one should go?
Hey Mister, are you listening?
I'm not done yet. Mister?
Saegusa-san! Saegusa-san!
Mister is with Saegusa-san
right now.
Mister! Where are you now?
Mister!
Answer me, Mister!
Captain!
Captain, pull yourself together!
Ugh!
Captain, what happened?
Midori, start tracking the GPS
on Captain's cell phone!
Captain! Captain!
He's at Saegusa-san's cafe!
Captain!
It's Captain's blood.
Captain is going to be killed, too.
I was supposed to be their
next target.
What do you mean by that?
Leave me alone, please.
You're Akagi.
You can solve the mysteries for sure.
It's certain that Saegusa has been contacting
this criminal group and knows their plan.
And he said clearly that the next target
would be either Captain or me.
But, what was the reason?
What's their purpose?
What are they thinking?
Murder in the name of justice.
Provocation against the police.
A suicide wish.
Here we go!
Don't worry. This man used to
be a medical examiner.
There's no problem with your wound.
I was impressed. You attempted to
shoot me at gunpoint.
But, I had no intention of
shooting you.
That's him over there?
Yeah.
Sekimoto-san.
It's Yurine from the ST.
Are you alright?
Captain Yurine? Yes!
Saegusa-san, it's too bad.
The mysteries are all solved.
I'm going there right now to
tell you everything.
So, will you please tell me
where you are?
And I'm coming alone.
I guess it'll be about 20 minutes
before Akagi gets here.
Then, let's finish what we
need to do before that.
It's 'Onitaiji' by 'Momotaro.'
What I'm about to tell you is, the mind of the
principal offender of this criminal group.
If the victim of the first murder by the
principal offender was Amaki Shinpei
the motive was perhaps revenge.
He found the monster named Amaki, who was
released into the wild, 15 years later
and brought down the hammer of justice.
But, it was still murder.
So, he wanted to justify his own actions.
And, he assembled his friends
with the same ambitions
and started executing other villains in the name
of justice, but couldn't hold back anymore.
That's what happened in this series
of crimes in the past week.
And, I don't want to you to be surprised
but one of the candidates for the principal
offender of Amaki's murder, is Counselor Saegusa.
He's a villain. Kill him.
A villain?
What you told me was that, there's no
difference between good and evil in this world.
Didn't you make up your
mind to join us?
Then, you can do it.
Saegusa-san, don't!
I have no idea what's going on,
but don't do it anyway!
Sekimoto Yuzo, the First Investigation
Division of the Saitama police.
15 years ago, when he was still a rookie
detective, he made a huge mistake.
In order to arrest a murder suspect,
he fabricated evidence.
As a result, the court ruled that all evidence
lacked credibility and acquitted the suspect.
And a few days later, that suspect
killed a female police officer.
That's about the rape and
murder case...
It's all this man's fault that
Amaki Shinpei was left at large.
Now, the time has come!
I will carry out justice.
He is the one...
who killed Seiko.
Saegusa-san!
Indeed, it has been said that Saegusa-san
and Yoshimura Seiko, the female police
officer who Amaki killed
joined the force in the same year and
were very close to each other.
But, we're doubting the theory that
Saegusa-san is the culprit of this murder.
After killing Yoshimura Seiko,
Amaki was nowhere to be found
even though the police put their
prestige in the investigation.
Who can find that kind of person?
Do you think an ordinary person has
the ability to investigate like that?
No!
No matter what someone says, you guys are
detectives even in your own stupid way, aren't you?
Different from the general public.
Then, what kind of person was
able to find Amaki?
A former detective.
Someone who used to be an
excellent detective
quit his job right
after Yoshimura Seiko was killed
and got obsessed with finding Amaki,
then eventually found and killed him
and got his revenge.
Wait a minute.
It was only three months ago when
Counselor Saegusa left the police department.
Until then, he was at a busy post and it would've
been difficult to track Amaki's whereabouts.
You're correct.
So, when we searched for the people who
were close to Yoshimura Seiko-san in the list...
Hey, Presto!
There was one detective who resigned
right after Amaki had disappeared.
Yuhara Keita.
He joined the force in the same year
as Counselor Saegusa.
The principal offender of this series
of crimes is... Yuhara.
Yuhara?
What's the matter, Saegusa?
Make up your mind.
Stop this nonsense.
What you said about him fabricating
evidence is a lie.
You're not serious about
killing him, either.
This gun is too light.
There's no bullet inside.
As expected of you.
Instead, he's a member of your
group, isn't he?
You tested me, didn't you?
No. I just bet on the slightest possibility.
I couldn't believe you no
matter how hard I tried.
I wish you would have pulled the
trigger without arguing.
Sekimoto-san, why?
You'll eventually understand, if you
continue investigating the murderers.
Since when did you notice
our activities?
You must have gotten an inkling
after Amaki was killed.
That's why you left the
police department.
And you waited for me to contact you.
Why did you leave the police department?
The same as you, Yuhara.
I can't forgive him.
There is a limit to what the police can do.
But, the true evil lies beyond
that limit.
I want to create... another justice.
Do you remember what I told you
about 'Momotaro'?
Yeah.
Yuhara's ambition is to punish the
evil in place of the police.
And the comrades who gathered
around him
must have all grown tired of the
existence of the police itself.
For example, some like Samejima, who
used to be with the Saitama police.
I'm sure you all can understand
very well.
When you make the murder investigation your
daily work, anyone can get a weakened heart.
But, the devil plays on your
weakness right then.
The devil I'm talking about is the
concept of justice.
The detective with a weakened heart
lowers the stake of murder
and he would do anything for the
sake of justice he believes in.
Even though he is a police officer,
he also becomes a murderer.
For the nobler purpose of 'onitaiji'
he becomes Momotaro
who assembles his friends and goes out
of his way to invade the enemy's territory.
Look at this.
When you connect the locations where
they left the corpses on the map...
Don't you think they look alike?
Establishing another police organization
is what Yuhara intends to do.
Wait... Wait for a minute!
I almost ignored it, but didn't you say
Momotaro was an invader just before?
Yes, I did.
What are you talking about?
It's just one of various theories
and an anecdote, which has been
handed down to the local people in Okayama.
Did everyone know?
Why don't you all know this?
Are you stupid? It's a matter of
common knowledge! Shame on you!
Get out of here now!
I just pretended to be Akagi-san.
I wanted to do this once.
That's what the culprit intends to do!
Thinking from a different angle! Turning
the sense of values upside down!
Momotaro, who has been regarded as a
good person, actually was not a good person!
Give me a detailed explanation.
I've been wondering the whole time.
I felt that this culprit wasn't
consistent with himself.
You're talking about the suicide wish.
The culprits have been challenging the
police by leaving many hints.
They have no intention of losing, and
want to finish with the perfect victory.
And I thought it contradicted
with the suicide wish
but, it really doesn't contract at all!
There's just one way not to get caught
by the police, his enemy, forever.
And that's suicide.
By doing so, the culprits will become
eternal beings.
They'll be the gods of citizens, who denounce
the police and sing the praises of the culprits!
And everyone realizes that
evil always gets destroyed.
For this world where the police and the law
can't beat the evil people anymore...
For this world where evil prevails...
And for the exhausted general public
they're going to make a paradigm shift and
turn the sense of values upside down.
Evil always gets destroyed.
They'll learn that it's okay to destroy evil
themselves, without relying on the police.
- [Let's follow Momotaro!]
- [We're going to continue the chain of justice!]
- [We can't leave justice to the police!]
- [Where should we start?]
Weren't you going to stop us after becoming
a member of our group?
It's too bad. I knew you were lying
from the very beginning.
That's why we've done all the crimes
without you.
And I also made good use of you.
Thanks to you,
I was able to provoke Akagi Samon.
The person they're going to
kill next is...
either Yurine-kun or Akagi-kun.
Now, which do you think
they're going to kill?
[Akagi: The next target is Captain.
The reason is Gobosei.]
That's what happened.
Now you know that...
my brain is better than anyone else's.
Of course, better than him, too.
Let's hear the answer.
Which of you are we going to
kill next, you or him?
It'll be Captain.
If Captain gets killed,
I'll never forgive you.
I'll get my revenge no matter what.
I'll make you pay the same price.
I'll kill you.
I will definitely kill you.
You're reading my moves that far.
And you don't care about dying
if I'm killing you.
It's your suicide wish,
in a manner of speaking.
When you die,
you'll become a god.
A god who won the police.
An eternal being.
On the other hand,
I'll be arrested for murder
and I won't be able to solve any mysteries,
to reason or to investigate ever again.
There'll be no one to stop
your organization.
That's the best scenario you've written.
This is the answer to the mystery.
You lose, Akagi Samon.
Your reasoning is all wrong.
I just wrote here the answer
to the mystery.
Now.
Kill me!
Kill me, then cut up my stomach
and take the answer out!
- It must be so easy for a doctor!
- Stop doing such a foolish thing, Yuhara!
The police have changed.
They're different from how you
were back then!
They can carry out justice now.
They have become stronger!
No, they haven't!
That's why I created the ST.
There are no mysteries they can't solve!
Yes.
That's my point, Saegusa.
I've been always watching ever
since the ST was formed.
Akagi Samon.
You get weirdly obsessive about
solving a mystery.
It's too bad!
The mysteries are all solved now!
That's because you want to find out the
feelings of the monster who commits murders.
But, you couldn't solve the mystery
this time. Why?
That's because you can't understand the
feelings of a murderer if you haven't killed anyone.
Once you kill someone, you'll be able
to solve the mystery.
Don't!
Akagi-san, don't shoot!
As I told you before,
murder is murder!
We just took care of the villains!
And you'll still deny us?
Of course!
What you've been doing are the serial
murders committed as an organization!
You must be arrested and
judged by law.
That's an old-fashioned sense of justice.
And let me tell you this.
The reason Akagi-san obsesses over solving a
mystery is because he wants to be helpful to others.
Akagi-san knows that everyone becomes happy
if he solves a mystery and settles the case.
And so, you shouldn't nonsensically conclude
he wants to find out the feelings of the murderer!
It's you who's all wrong!
Akagi-san is not a monster!
He's only a human.
He's my important friend!
My very best friend in the history of me!
If you don't hurry up,
your friend is going to die.
Stop, Yuhara!
I'm sure that these two will be able to
get to the person who let Amaki run loose!
They can settle old scores for Seiko!
Let's entrust these two with
what we couldn't do!
Akagi-kun will never forgive someone
who would solve a mystery
by taking it so far as to
forge evidence.
That's why I bet on you.
What a shame!
The mysteries are... all...
solved now!
I did solve all the mysteries,
you mean-spirited bugger!
The person you want to kill is neither
me nor Captain!
It's yourself!
And it'll have to be me who kills you!
You want me to get a taste for killing
someone, don't you?
You couldn't hold back anymore after
killing Amaki Shinpei.
You sought out comrades and made them
understand the feelings of a murderer one by one.
And finally it's my turn.
You thought, I wouldn't be able to hold
back anymore once I killed you.
And you hoped for me to continue killing for
justice by leading these men from now on
while succeeding the last wish of yours.
But, you're misunderstanding me.
It's too bad.
I have no interest in the feelings
of a murderer.
I just...
It was just as Captain said.
Solving a mystery is the only way for me
to get recognized by everyone.
Solving a mystery is the only way for
me to relate to society.
I have anthropophobia, a dirty mouth,
and a rotten personality.
So, I have to solve a mystery in order
to become helpful to others.
Thank you, Captain.
I was able to finally figure it out,
because you were there.
The carved seal of 'Momotaro' is
to send a message that there is only good
in this world, not the good and the bad.
It's so ridiculous that it
makes me vomit!
You're wrong!
Times may change,
and society may change
or even the law may get distorted and the
interpretation of the Constitution may change
but killing someone is absolutely bad.
A human killing another human
should never be forgiven!
There's no existence value in such a thing!
The last remaining mystery.
Why do you want to die?
I finally understood the meaning of what
you said at that time.
Akagi-kun will never forgive someone
who would solve a mystery
by taking it so far as to
forge evidence.
You were telling me to find the detective who
fabricated evidence in order to arrest Amaki.
You entrusted me with the person
Yuhara hated the most
since you wouldn't be able to
search by yourself.
You won your bet, Saegusa-san.
The detective who fabricated
evidence was...
you.
Your upper eyelid lifted and
lower eyelid got stiff.
Your lips are twitching sideways.
That's the expression of fear.
Are you scared of me hitting
every mark that much?
Because you fabricated evidence, Amaki
was acquitted and Yoshimura Seiko was killed.
And that's why you can't forgive yourself.
Even after killing Amaki Shinpei, your
feelings of guilt didn't go away.
And that's why you couldn't
hold back anymore.
Because you wanted someone to stop
you from going out of control
you left the marking of Gobosei,
carved out 'Momotaro'
suggested the next crime scene, and
provoked me using Saegusa-san.
That's the answer!
Perfect solution!
I'm not going to hear
your objection.
Don't shoot! Don't kill anyone!
Capture them!
Captain!
Captain! Captain!
Hang in there! Captain!
- Yuhara! Yuhara!
- Let me go!
You're wrong!
Akagi-san.
Until the very end...
I'm useless...
And I couldn't even return a favor.
I'm sorry.
But...
Aoyama-san.
Midori-san.
Kurosaki-san.
Yamabuki-san.
And Akagi-san.
I'm glad I met all of you.
Thank you very much.
It's been fun.
Captain!
This is just a skin-deep wound.
Huh?
Are you kidding?
You're not going to die!
Ouch! It hurts!
- Of course! Pull yourself together!
- Akagi-san, you're hurting me!
- Get on your feet! Now!
- Ow, ow, ow, ow, ow!
- It hurts! It hurts!
- Of course!
- I thought I was going to die.
- I'm so sorry. He's alright.
I'm sorry for having troubled you.
Ouch! Ouch!
Akagi-kun, what about this?
- Now walk!
- Ouch! Ouch!
Akagi-san, for a skin-deep wound...
The case was over.
Even Director Matsudo wasn't aware of what
Saegusa-san was doing for the last three months.
The higher-ups told me.
You pretended to have left the
police department.
I didn't mean to pretend, but...
So, I guess it was an
undercover investigation?
I still can't believe it.
This was an extraordinary situation.
We were fretting that bad.
Both the higher-ups and I.
I'm sorry for having troubled you.
I'm sure you had many troubles
taking care of the ST.
Not at all.
Since I was in succession to
someone I respect.
Me, too.
If my successor wasn't you, I would have
stayed the guardian of the ST.
I couldn't have gone after Yuhara.
Justice may not be something
you carry out selfishly
but something you share with
and support each other with.
Yes.
I wish I could have made him
realized that sooner.
What's that?
Are you trying to be funny?
[Ikeda Sosuke]
You guys are such good friends,
aren't you?
I can't wait for Akagi-san to see this.
Akagi-san will go mad in jealousy,
he says.
Since they're in matching outfits.
Your wound was just a scratch.
That's exaggerating!
I'm sorry.
It's all thanks to you, Captain.
I'm extremely grateful.
I don't know why, but it doesn't bother me
anymore even when Captain put restraint on me.
This is amazing!
I've been transformed.
What am I supposed to say
at a time like this?
It would be 'Thank you'.
Was it?
The more you express words
of appreciation
the higher your happiness index
will become.
I did some research.
It made me feel happy, indeed.
I heard that they produce pleasure chemicals.
So, I'm going to say it.
Captain, thanks.
If Captain wasn't here, it would've been
pointless for us to form the ST.
And because Captain was here, we
thought we were fine like this.
'Not at all.'
'I'm the one who's been receiving favors
from Aoyama-san and everyone
and I'm grateful for that.
Thank you very much.'
Speech like that won't be necessary.
We all know that.
You're welcome.
All of you, just can't be honest
about it, can you?
Thank you.
Honest! Kurosaki-san is the most
honest person here!
Huh? Are you crying?
I'm not.
- I'm not crying.
- Aren't those so-called tears in your eyes?
Yes, I guess they're probably tears. Yes.
- That's so gross.
- Why do you say that?
Your eyes are all red.
My eyes are all red?
Of course, from my tears.
- Oh, Kikukawa-san?
- Are those for Yurine-kun?
Aren't you going to say good-bye?
Don't be rustic and clumsy to hinder his
farewell with friends, you know?
Now, that's it for your farewell party!
What? Was this my farewell party?
Good job, you can leave now.
Was it, the Countermeasures Office against
Special Crimes? Do your best, I guess.
To the point you don't die on duty.
- Everyone, listen to me!
- Ah, how long are you staying?
We got to say our good-bye nicely,
so why don't you just leave?
Be a man,
or we'll be disappointed in you.
Like I said before, I belong to the ST
for four more days.
Until then, I'm the Captain here!
You're all going too fast!
And also, I haven't said good-bye
to Akagi-san yet.
Is this Akagi-san?
Everyone's giving me a hard time!
Please hurry!
Huh? Who am I?
It's me! Captain!
It was the next day.
Go in.
Akagi-san was arrested.
As a suspect for the murder case.
Subtitles by DramaFever