Been on -
Garaa
Baja Peninsula
Mexico
Can not be true
Yes
No
Professor
"Doctor," Lehman
These figures can not be
To be true
I hope this
Do not see
Calculations assume
We have to make sure it is correct
I will say a small sell
And direction
This means it is heading
Us
And is fatal to the planets
This is impossible
Have been achieved from the database
And is not something one finds a large
But hit something
Something big out of orbit
I'm sure it
"Cassandra"
Impossible
This hide
It is 61 miles
"Three times the size of the" Everest
Talking about the extinction
Such as the dinosaurs --
Yes --
What is ridiculous in this --
He said a large "Apollo" by Belan "Cassandra" to become a killer --
So what do we do?
Follow up and study and find
Rate approaching
"We send the coordinates to the" de. Me. The
And claim that there is enough force to detonate in the sky
Taft / California
Hi, I second that
I'm back to school
I am ....
Vecdi say hello to you
I love
Contact me when you can
Well --
Jenny I know that there are problems between you and your father and he loves you too --
Well, if he found time
Can present itself Roundup
Los Angeles / California
Vecdi say hello
I love
The timing of my child a great
"Generation"
Hai
You provide the electricity
Yes. With the policeman's salary
This must be done
Therefore,
You contacted me
I think we have agreed to go in the morning
Do you want to go now?
Why not
Is told, "Mary"?
Yes, had told
What did?
Wow
Handed the gun
"Do not look away," Jack
See the manual for the practical
I see you
I fired at the same
What is this? --
What do you think will happen Knti "Jack"? --
I should hand myself over and you become a great hero
Who left the dirty Bacharty
Former partner
I can ....
I can help you
"Beautiful," Jack
But I can act from here
Pasadena / California
Halo
"Dr." Chuck Wayne
"You" Aimjn O'Neill
"Aimjn"
Dear
To our emergency
"And Dr." Lehman
Emergency
Atnin one another
"Dr." Chuck Wayne
Not. Qublty if the job with us
"Kantian Ttardy for ghosts with the" Daniel
To not only flush out the ghosts
Will put you on speaker now
The space object 114 is our part
Should tell everyone this
Cassandra, "a giant celestial body"
Daniel "It's a small planet"
Closest to us, the passage of
Arbaimh thousand miles away from our
We have changed the track after colliding with another object
If we were not ready in the morning This will be a late sell
Tell "Lalji. Me. The" Now we do not have --
We do not have time --
"Gosh," Daniel
Daniel "Go to bed"
I shall give it to the office when Aaty
Will come to you now, our figures
Nreha for you. Every minute, we now calculate
Signs have arrived
Meaning of the imminent arrival of the main body have a 24 hour
I know what is the promise
"Doctor," Lehman
They belong to you. Does not it?
They stay on the cause of life now
I took my family, Mona
"Jack"
Now you will be known as Ward
I will visit a small
To College "Jenny" luxury
Oh
Your father in the same way
Is not it?
Appropriate
Lamy. Abe
Wake
Why? --
Why Dear? --
Must see this
Well
Oh, F.
This is beautiful
"Ross"
Almighty accelerating
Gave an
Come on
Fantastic
It's what --
Yes --
It is somewhat
Away from the window
Go Go
To lower
When the prayer I want you there
The Taatsaly P.
Will be too late --
... Important that it does not matter --
Ross Habestr "There has fire in his field"
Says that the meteor fell there
What?
Informed the fire brigade and I will be behind you --
Present Sir --
Come on, darling --
Did he meteoroid? --
Ross "had great imagination,"
I want you to Tcody in the permitted speed limits --
Well --
With serious safety
Thank you for Kdomk
I know you are not a big fan of
"Bcanuto" Chuck Wayne
Do you think he will be able to resolve the issues
"When you reach" Ji. PLN
And read the reports of the radar
So why go?
Because we are the only ones who are being monitored from the outset
Will need for our objection and destroyed
And most computers will not be accurate
See. Dr. "Lehman" Please
Do not understand this the wrong way
But ..
Come Qouliha
Why go?
He did not believe you
B will be the firmest bonds Isedkna when
Get it
Why?
That time many of the meteorites will fall
And many people will die
Task Force to respond to the Meteoroid
Undisclosed location
Ladies and gentlemen,
Has been Ahoudarkm of your
Here in the middle of the night to that on the last what
You Ttuatm or Rahtkm and to Kalatkm
Become part of the Task Force to respond to the Meteoroid
"For those who do not knows me I am your general," Pracejr
WFP chief in the army and was appointed by the president to lead this force
To solve this crisis, which we address today
There is simply a large asteroid
Moving us
Hai
Nick Chadoin - from Lalji. Me. The --
Hague --
Welcome to the world of missile
We in the last 6 hours
A hail of meteorites on the west coast
We continue to draw data from satellites
But we can say that there are 12 strikes
Came in the Pacific
"Doctor," Chan
I think our team is following up that
This media has been since the early
Following information is still
Yes, we have information we received from one of Mlahzina
Network tracking meteoroid
Analyze the information, but still there is a possibility that the reason for this may be guilty
If this is true
Vsnchahd significant meteor activity
How could the volume of the rock?
Any size to the size of small trucks
The bad news --
The collision of the meteor may cause the body to change the course of Heaven --
May be on its way to us
Size and shape and weight
We believe that as we speak --
What is the worst that could happen? --
"Maybe we look for 114," Cassandra
Belt of giant space
He
Large enough to account
Small planet
60-mile
And a collision with us may end life as we know it
This is the worst that could happen
The time remaining before the collision --
Which we are still, but I think the day or two --
"Unfortunately, if" Cassandra
Must cite the earlier
For if we Dharbnaha and is close to our air
Output of the blast
Would be catastrophic
Well, to begin to act
"Chuck"
I want a full report on the space object that we are dealing with
And a point of objection, which can in less than 30 minutes
Do not want you to tell me how too early
I want you now and I want your Dr. "Lehman" Now
Los Angeles / California
Firmest bonds B
Stark, "moving away will not do my best" --
.... Is not the captain --
This is not enough
That "Calvin" You know
This "Jenny" from talking about
I know
But does not see what is happening
Abroad?
Tom, "but I put it on Rkpetk"
Please
Will not move away. Well
Of this?
Lahu for "Jenny"?
That the mayor --
Contact me if I heard anything --
Will do
Take some comfort
Come on, darling --
But all he tried to contact the lines were jammed at a later time --
Follow this story, the report confirms the existence of
Meteorites fall in California
With a meteor the other on the west coast
With the Pacific
Will, "NASA," a press conference half an hour from now
We expect answers, and what it believed to
Meteorites fall to the largest recorded on the planet
Throughout history
It is beautiful
Arahenk he is the best on the mountain
Let us
Hai
I forgot this --
Thank you --
You are wonderful
The best companion of housing at all
Let's go to
See you later
This terrible
Yes
Hai
Has brought us for assistance. Does not it?
Atrdiny to stay in the house?
You are not to go
One must pay bills
Should not have to deal with all of this on your own --
Hai Hai --
Amused at least one of us in this
Still here?
I missed the bus and all the excitement
The school will be at least
I will not
I will be a good mother for some time
Ye boy
Let's go
School time
Limousine deceased
But we must stay to help?
Good attempt
Come ride the car
Will try to return early
"Hai" Misle
Firefighters told me it was safe now
Want to come to look?
How bad the situation?
See for yourself
You are you the opportunity to watch the news
This morning?
No electricity is still cut off
It seems
Some of these things had fallen
Sometime in the evening
Strange display of the fall of meteorites
Most of them landed in the Pacific Ocean
Except this one
Frazier Park / California
Oh Hai
Alradetyr Can I have hot water
Thank you. Getting a good day --
Amnesty --
Captain, "Stark" is considered armed and dangerous
Very careful
All units pay attention
Hai --
"Aimjn" --
With you, "Nick Chatwein" Is "Daniel" with you?
I'm here
"Unfortunately I was wrong about the" Cassandra
You are you the opportunity to calculate the track?
Contact us interrupt the transmission again
We are preparing for the launch --
Lala launches you do not have the right track --
Haluw
Coordinates does not have the correct path
Will use the coordinates of their years
Contact will make mistakes again
No signal
He said, unfortunately,
Why? --
He said, unfortunately, has already apologized --
Wait
Center Naizk / Region unknown --
Ms do not do not tell you how you are to your business --
But we must Takbry president
Tell people this is now
Or will happen to the spread of trance
Thank you, Madam
Sir
"We have reached more of the" NASA
Satellite, saying it was
114 "Cassandra"
Colonel, "Baker," How much time until we
Missiles?
The minutes twenty-one Sir --
To prepare for a good five --
.... And I still need to --
"Dr." Chuck Wayne --
What about the coordinates? --
With me, sir, only re-confirmed --
We need them now
Oak
They have
Excellent
They want to speak with Dr. "Lehman" leave a message? --
Dr. "Lehman" We are on the verge of the launch of the figures I want to make sure the wrong thing --
Only Contact Contact
Taft / California
I'm sorry
Do you help me please?
Thank you
Have the additional funds are
How large is this?
I can not find anything --
"Russell Hascon" --
A meteoroid --
Simon, "long time" --
What's going on here, I think
The home is the only one who was injured?
Some people are told to store the goods
So .... P
F on the right
These waters belong to me
Is your name on it? --
I'm here to bring before the milk is also being carried out --
I'm sorry, sir
I said that my water
It's my family
"Hai" Blakt --
Why not leave the cities and back where I came from? --
Repeating what I said
It does not deserve to leave --
Yes, leave it --
There are a lot of water there
Getting a good day, sir
Have you heard what he said to me?
Yes, I heard
I was born here --
It's just talk --
Word of the problems it will bring
I did the right thing
Baja Peninsula / Mexico
Damn
I think it was broken down
Regret
Do not feel scared
Must be optimistic
Nationalist stop any vehicle passing
They always stop to a girl
Hai Hai
Stop
Great
See
Ward will be on the phone
"Doctor," Lehman
Darn
Do not speak
Do not try to speak
Darn Dr. "Lehman" No --
..... That --
"Doctor," Lehman
What do I do?
Los Angeles / California
Ajebe Oh dear
Ajebe
Hai I am, "Jenny," Leave your message
Jenny "Asamay to your father and I"
Asamay carefully
You are in great danger
Former partners, "Calvin Stark," Are
Taatzkrene?
By something horrible. You are in danger
When the call letters Tsamay Pal ... Do not go to the police
Adjalehm contact me
Or captain, "Vinajin" in the Los Angeles Police fast
Well
This real dear
I love you. Go now
Result of a meteor strike closed all the roads --
Told you he was a shortcut --
Yes, certainly
Must return
Why?
Things fall from the sky
Tell people to move away from the road
They are exaggerating
Only Fekry
A hot bath. A hot bath
I'm serious --
I also --
There is also a full bar
Dear
If the world ends
I would prefer to be with you
Well
You are full of Bahera
Let's be real
Sakbarak something
If you're a good boy for the rest of the way
Adjalk may come out of this
Stopped fighting the water
Yes, our house is a hit
But everyone here terrified
Are you okay? --
Yes, only the fittest before the window is "Michael" to the White --
Children who will come out Mbkraa
Dr. We Nanajk
subtitle by garaa
Well, dear, I heard this
I love you. Must go
What are you doing?
The crowd going
In all radio and TV stations
What they say
Away from the road
As the organizers of the traffic
Not true
Dharaibk working there
I was in the city, people store water and supplies
The next thing will be hiding in their homes
And then life will be cheap
Taanon on slow Garage
Halo Chief of Police
What?
Are your plans for a fishing trip?
You know the duck season soon
Today is a day to stay within the appropriate doors
What if the problems occurred?
Some men will need the table beside your keyboard --
I need people to remain calm and carry weapons --
I have not heard that martial law
Announced
I have my rights
"Dwight"
I started bothering me
This would not be in your favor
Do you threaten me?
I do not Ahiddk
I tell you how things
Suggested that the family is
More than Aslank
Outside Tijuana / Mexico
Where you want to go
In Los Angeles?
"Lalji. Me. The"
After the border
Thank you for Astahptny
You Tzkriny Babinty
I do not let him alone
We received an official statement on what is happening
Increasing the rate of fall of meteorites
Jamil, who appeared Kbbah
It turns out to be a blueprint for disaster warning Qomiq
Taft / California
May not go to school
Tomorrow
Michael had "friendly"
Kantian if you want a real man --
And would leave --
If not, why?
Will not help you
Because he can not protect Amrath
Stop
Is she will cry?
Coordinates have been identified?
Yes
Confidence is not complete
Was
We started
Launch code --
Ready and willing, sir --
Valentaleg
Start Kollenel
With references
Tlkmwa me
What happened?
We have lost, sir
There is no data
I'm also
We are out of service
Satellite
Spoke
Is satellite in the launch control? --
Yes, this is true --
I think she was beaten
Promise
The reason for the small comets
Yes Yes
Was to confirm this, please prepare
Missile sound
Only lost satellite
Recommendations? --
Launch at the track --
No
subtitle by garaa
Without satellite
I do not recommend this
Tracks are not accurate
I need more time
Damn --
I'm sorry I do not think we call nuclear weapons, we are blind --
Me
What were you doing during this period?
As far as I can
Did not expect a space object of this size
And not so close
And equations used by the I can not contact those who invented
Find it
Where is he?
In the way of Mexico
! Mexico
What is he doing there if he so important?
The expelled
It has become crazy
The two Dr. "Chuck" to find the leg
Use the White House - that the Marines must find him now
But regret is not my fault that it Schent
The car made from scrap
Well
This spectrum
Stupid
Unfortunately, Ms Los Angeles Police
I'll take your car to an emergency
Has caused me a heart attack
The crowd about the car, please --
Do not see what is happening must go to the house --
Ms
Must be insisted
Attended Zabott please
I live in a "Bumvista" My kids Intzeronny
I can not access on foot
Bumvista "living near the college"
Yes
It is a day that has won
Tzmhy Tokveny Is that you?
Aakzk would, of course, to the place you want. Ride --
Ms Hkuraa --
Outside the "Tijuana," Mexico
Amasal there is no response?
Nothing
The small school started today
I'm sorry
You do not
Everything is fine
Aenasbk Aqlk the border?
No
I'm really ..
I'm sorry Ms
Must go to my family
Of course
Is this police station? --
Yes --
Perhaps they can contact the Embassy or address, "Ji. Me. The" from here --
Ms good idea --
Earning a good
Thank you very
Are you sure you Cetkony fine?
Of course
Go to your family
Thanks
Good luck
Good luck to you also
Taft / California
Darn
It is a big rock
Let's go
What about the rest of the children?
Amtlana We must take this group for Hayb Lyon
And to the center of this group
You have one ambulance
We have accidents everywhere
It is crazy
I want you to go to the place, "Dillon" for cars
As soon as possible
Brought every man available
Each vehicle is available here as soon as possible
"Michael"
Take things simply built
Will be fine
Will Aakzk to hospital
And Make sure that your parents are Ikablanc
Sir. Satellite, covering all subject
- The Pentagon - Space Agency
How the size of this thing?
I do not think it alone Leveraging
All satellites around the world this happened to her
Let's not give up
We won the Second World War would not give up now
Never all contacts
What if it could not solve?
At some point will be
However, his opinion is important to take
This is another reason why we should maintain the
Our missile for which the large
May underestimate the rocket, which will
We need here
Kollenel "Page" identified more than 500
Important in the life of fire
I do not speak for the attacks
Baghdad
You are trying to injury is four times the size of
Manhattan "to small pieces, even if hit,"
Does not kill us anyway
It is one opportunity
We must use all
This will take the mind
I want to quickly Arqamk
Halo
Why? Where?
Where?
I'm coming
How Akhbarak? --
I am fine, Thank you for your question --
Thank you and the vehicle
I owe you
My boys will go to the University
After Itrdony
Will not Ttrdy
Will Asandk
Well, I'm sure you, you handsome
You are the phone of my dreams
"Trish"
Must go
Outside the "Tijuana," Mexico
Haluw
Regret not see
Not see
U.S.?
Yes
Must go to
"Lalji. Me. The"
In Los Angeles, there is information on this computer
Badly needed
I am a scientist and work on
Meteorites, which fall
It is very important
This important
URGENT
Yes --
Why do not Tkelmehm on the telephone? --
Come in the office --
Telephones what we say?
Long-distance
Hkuraa you --
Bureau --
Locomotive
Amsktha roam in the neighborhood
It alone
Please I am trying to access
"To" Los Angeles
It was beautiful
Is not it?
Locomotive
The subject of this meteor. Of course, concerned
Do not worry? But I feel excited
I'm not crazy
But I like adventures, from time to time
Are you married?
Yes --
Happy? --
I think I can tell you this
Well
But the time will be forced
To kill you
This was a good
We have tricked me in this
Losses so far? --
The only forty-one It's a miracle --
Hundreds casualties
Stadium was the last case
Shopping for Children
It's getting worse
General
Prefer
We want to put people under the ground
How do we do this?
Turn anything into a shelter
Mlajo bomb shops and markets, and anything
Ouselny from the Pentagon and they allowed for civilians
To stay in underground storage space and missile
We have a general picture on the radar
On the screen please
Iaalahy
They are growing in size
Any of them, "Cassandra?"
We can not see a "Cassandra" after the
Things will get worse
Should put people under the ground, and the National Guard to do this
More importantly Kollenel "Page"? --
Complete missiles --
We have covered every manned exclusive
Missiles and anti -
Well, good work
To move
"Sir, I have found Dr. Mexicans" Lehman --
Good --
We have found dead
Complain that the incident
Collision and escape
What about the help, "Aimjn"? --
Did not find one another --
Regret
San Francisco / California
Phoenix / Arizona
Seattle / Washington
What's this?
What is the problem, the presence of Zabott?
Must be due and graduated from Alavth
Which ignored
Will lead you to the point of capture
Eachdhunk will be there to shelter from
Unfortunately, this is not acceptable --
Hist do what it says --
We have multiple injuries
General hospital
How many are they? --
Seven children --
School bus
Kilometers away from here?
Here
Here??
Is that Ncioa Taatsaloa?
Idle telephone
And radio as well as
"Tilsy" --
Why? Why? --
Bus
"It's for school," Michael
Darn
Rapid pulse and low pressure
There are internal injuries
And two units of plasma
And preparing for the process
Darn
Low pressure and breathing regularly
Might be suffering from concussion
Dr.
Chelsea, "What do we do?"
Oh my --
"Doctor" Habscon
Ten units of intravenous solution
Mqaip-ray
Next patient
Lala
Gasoline
I'm stupid
Not Tmlye reservoir --
Not everything was so fast and I wanted to return home --
We have had three petrol stations
I know
It is somewhat funny
Shut up --
But I'm Here is nice --
Stay away from me --
Do you assist me in these things
In the bag, please?
Well
This is ridiculous
I'm working as fast as I can --
You are not working fast enough to come back to my family --
Can we return to the house? --
Asamty --
Let me leave
You sir did not pay the price of this
Place Sidi
Please
Put these things and leave
To the children --
Let him go --
Please stop --
Why do Stguetlny for Jalonen of water --
No but I will do
We will not accept any of these
Theft
We will not accept complacency in the law
You are on the right
Therefore, we have to go home
I was trying to help
Here, the Chief of Police
We have helped enough
Now is the time to go home
And if Wright decried with its arms
Asadrp and will Aziba
Go to the hospital and ask if the
Wants to charge
I'm trying to be
Effective part here
Does not mean lack of respect for you grew up in the age
And the place was a steal and I came late
Please Leave --
No one speaks to you --
Wants to rest
Give him some ice
Nice
There is no need for this
Has the point of view
Lose a lot of time in a row
While it is necessary to help
Each other
Go to your home and your children brought
And medicines and blankets, coverlets and go to school shelter
There will be safely
Do everything we can to comfort Ncarkm
And remember, we are all in this together
Other and took care of some of you told
Jerankm and friends and helped each other
As you have heard
You can pay me later
This is your child
Go to all home
Experts say the same as one in a million
Meteor strike aircraft corridor
212 passengers killed
And the whole crew
Tragedy is that while landing the plane hit
After the aircraft were banned in North America
Due to the transformation of this meteoroid
To the worst days in the history of the aircraft
"Asteroid is coming to the" Los Angeles
And is the chief
About the data to the base land
Los Angeles / California
We have him
To see at least half
Swollen from the bottle
You do not have enough missile
Dropped for all
U.S. armed forces
Has many resources
Should offer the most
"" The Cassandra
And whatever you did not die
How is the course?
I work for
All highways closed
Until further notice
Except emergency medical and military
Dr. Dr.
From here
Mode in this room
Will quickly lose
Is inspected "Michael"?
Normal rates
There is no concussion
Do you want to?? --
No, no, this must be ended --
Michael "stable that he was very lucky for this child"
Now T-shirt
Please
If not for the "Lalji. Me. The" We all die
Tdeiny not repeat this
T-shirt
Oak Oak Oak
Please
Should not do this
Please do not
Must go to a shelter
Now the rest
Do you want to die? --
If it were today --
Will die and smile on my face
Woe to you
Will do this myself
The Rkptik
Now
San Diego / California
Go Go
Go to there --
Present Sir --
Ready
Come fired
They do not believe me
My car
How is Bsartk
At a time like this?
Unfortunately, I have news
Of shelter that is the number of allowable
This is not true
We left here can not
We have a congestion there and in the "Carpl" shelter empty
I can not walk the distance
With two children
Please, you Zabott
Please
Come Atrkiha of the same
Sir
Must Taudy truck
We made
I think we can assume
The shelter was full of gravity
Please --
Rahltm as quickly as the fastest and Theltm --
Come on
Arkpy truck
I Aattiyky the place
I can not, darling --
We can not go 15 miles Ante No --
Let's go --
Why? --
Intervention to move the truck
I'm leaving and my friend --
They are three --
That child --
You are silly --
Go with him not to worry
I would be fine
Come on surely we are not
We came in early
Please anyone
This lady has her own children
"Jenny"
Let's intrusive
Will go
God bless you
Move
Do you think we get to "Kaervoll" before the night?
And the highway is not closed
We have to find a place where the rest
I know somewhere
Well --
And pounces on a hot bath --
Abe hello --
Thank God --
Are you okay?
I'm fine
subtitle by garaa
Is well
... Is the only
Have a simple concussion
If these thick brain good
For something
You are funny Abe
"Sorry, Mr." Hapson
Why there?
There is no response from the company
And supplies did not reach
Damn
Why there?
Today of all days
We had to take our share of medicine
But the truck did not show
Indeed, lacking fundamentals Kalpnsleyn
Should not do half of my operations
What about the pharmacy? --
What does? --
Rangir "his daughter with me in the chapter"
To be with them what they need --
Yes --
Yes
I do not know, why did not I think of that?
The Kantian busy dear --
Do you think they are still working? --
I know, "Dan" will certainly help
Give me a list of only
Cuba genius
Love love
Find a room
Snay list
I will go to contact them in the pharmaceutical
Went to rest
Well
Care Bwaldtk
Come on
Take Action
Damn
Stop your car Ms
Stay where you can see them
Why the rush?
I am a U.S. citizen
... And I am
Are you police? --
... But I do not --
Out of the car, please --
You do not understand --
Now Ms --
Asma "Aimjn O'Neill," and working with the meteoroid Mlahzy
There is a gun in the car --
Why? --
No, no, this is not the gun --
Is Tstdery and Tusbandy Mon cart please? --
Astdery and Usbandy cart
Kane surged cart
Situations by your hand and your legs Aferdy --
Please be out of the phone --
"In Dr. coordinates" Tak
Government wants to hit comet
It clean
Can I see your passport? --
Of course --
Sterty left in the police department --
I see this --
Why Tcoden a Mexican police car?
... And because I am
Was the attack on the
Of these men
Who killed two policemen in the police department
Should come with me --
No --
You do not hear me
We do not have the time
Therefore, we must end this quickly
Los Angeles / California
We have a problem
Meteoroid size and quantity increase
We will start firing rockets
Losses
More than a thousand
We have Nizquin coming to New York and there is no batteries to them --
Population --
Seventeen thousand Anthpt to keep records of --
Sentlgahm from the coast to Nbkm --
We can not afford to lose large missile
Must provide all Cyel "Cassandra," the same
Do I have to let the 17 thousand people die?
I do not know
Saved if a few thousand now will lose the planet in the morning
Is not most of the people in the shelters now? --
It takes some time --
With two others in the land
Menusoda "the same subject there is no rocket"
General You can not --
This is enough --
What I hear from you
This is where the comet strike?
I'm sorry
But I will not become all of these people
Take everything you need to drop anything --
Come on man you have heard this --
Santa Fe / New Mexico
North Atlantic
Las Vegas / Nevada
Continued to walk
Lose the right to peace
There is food and water there will be safely
I brought this from the hotel --
Well-developed below --
Dear President
Had a gun
Do you think you Stdharbny
Bfltk and escape?
Mona does not reduce
Built
May seem to you that you you the advantage
But I assure you I do not see how
I do not forget this
As
Therefore, I guarantee you this
First and then the streets of Ajrdek
Then Saguetlk
You do not want this
Is not it?
Do you want to?
Do you want to Ihtermk everyone?
Must gain
Here is your chance
Do you hear this voice
It is our challenge
That God is testing us
To know and what we will do?
Want to know what to do in the face of
Disaster?
May we will be together
Or fight?
Can die in seconds
However, before we die
Must each and every one of us
That reflects the test
What would be your response, "Heat"?
How can I help?
You have the right choice
Many people need below
To help
I have contacted myself Boualdk
There can be no
I'm sorry
Try to get some rest
Both of you
Lamy skilled doctor
Will be addressed by well -
You will see
Darn
Lamy. Lamy. Lamy
Faced with technical problems
Hai
"Mister," Kroll
Ward did not Akhavtk
Where is "Jenny"?
I went to Kaby weekend
"With" Chen
We have been given the title to your partner
Calvin was "here"
Since when?
Since the half-hour --
Is Akbertih Where is she? --
Yes, regret. We have told me you are busy
And asked him to attend with Jodalaniazk
But working with you? --
Yes, yes, your parents address? --
Here
Well, thank you
Should not you at the shelter? --
I'm heading --
Come on locomotive
Now, officially we do not have places
Well
All of the outside
Abroad
Thank you, man
I mean this really
A good brother to help you
You are a good man
US-Mexican border
Allen come to talk with me?
You Dyke volatile mood
We all will die
But when she speaks to me
I work 35 years ago
The first I've heard people say this
I am aware I am --
Moment Ms --
It is said that a meteor strike
"Computer" in Nevada
We do not have Internet
So I can not verify your identity so that works
Do you know what happens when you hit the guilty class
The first guilty last
Not Ms --
It is of course --
Orbit becomes undefined
Only if it knew how to consider
And when it hits the ground
We all come back to our creator
You are a man of faith
See in the eyes of
I lie and tell
You are now Taatlaobein P.
Miss
Wait Wait
Ahpsony Abakiny here forever
I do not care
Contact the "Ji. Me. The" tell them that you have
Daniel Lehman, "a computer and have the necessary equations,"
Will write to you
Please do not have the time
Sakbarak something
I'll be coming to you Tel
Thank you --
You Hakakhaivh? --
I Mraobp
Come on
Take it this way
Where would you go to the second floor is not stable --
My son should be brought --
Accounts
Orbit, "Cassandra" at the most
That we have with a blind
But hitting is better than never
We have 11 minutes
Maximum 30-minute
Will enter our atmosphere
Must cite before becoming close
Enter the data
Will hit in 5 minutes
Sir we will --
Dr. "Chuck" There is contact with you --
Wait --
Permission from Mr. President --
They help, "Lehman" may have the data
Aimjn "I had over the equations Cassandra" --
I know I'm trying, but there is always a mistake --
The figures do not fit
This is what Dr. tried "Lehman" Akhbarak by
Equations has the right to intervene in your network
"Aimjn" --
We must rely on a mini-computer was used objects --
We are preparing for the launch --
Give me 5 minutes --
I want now coordinates
Hours have passed since the
Dr. See "Lehman" These figures
Are we will defer the launch?
Aimjn "now now"
Will call in about two minutes --
Well, here it is --
Here is the
We have found it - was never
General --
I found the coordinates
Will put you on the loudspeaker
Give me the coordinates are now
Coordinates, "Cassandra" from
5-17-46/0-2-20-0-6
Are we ever programming? --
Are you sure of these figures? --
I'm sure more than anything with us
It was a "Lehman" genius "--
You are expelled, and he is crazy --
Sir --
We will program the new figures --
Adharbha strongly
To be fatal to the planets
Thank you, Miss
I think we knew this
Sir we will
Was --
The exact coordinates Azbtoa Saatkm --
5 --
When we reach it, there will be aftershocks --
Was
They are on their way
If we do not have a radar
How will we know if Esbnaha?
Will follow us, a window
Bring ???? "O'Neill" to the air base
Want her at the place of secure communication
It does not fly
There will be many Meteorites
Suspended all flights
Even the military
To do so
Canceled all flights
Mrs. bring "O'Neill" at any price --
Present Sir --
Thank you
What's wrong?
I'm not sure
I revise the equations
Dr. "Lehman" something wrong
Time --
One minute of the collision --
"Murphy" --
Yes, sir
It is here
Of course, sir
Thank you, sir
This was the Vice-President
Vice-Why?
Vice-President of the United States
Iridonk at the base of "Edward," Air
Urgently
Well, be patient --
Are you can do this in the car? --
Yes Yes --
Well, to go --
Will Aakzk myself
Not every day I get a call like this
We have contact
Situation?
Prepared
Target was
Kept ready missiles
We have succeeded --
Kept ready missiles --
Why?
"Jenny"
Dear
This was very easy, my friend
You are not police officers --
Leave --
You are funny man. Msdsk Leave --
Leave and not killed
Leave
Thus,
Ihdu and kindness
Adfh departments now
Now the Rkpetk
Inflicted on Rkpetk
Born Matiur
Take me and leave
This impressive
But you forgot the goal of this
I want you to feel what I feel
Illiterate --
I feel it --
You Achar Plame
But you feel it --
No --
What a fireworks
Darn --
Nice, does not it? --
These things will fall
Must be something Nanmy
Now
Held
Inside
"Michael"
I'm your mother
Do you hear me?
Rear stairs
Darn
"Michael"
"Qhozi"
Do you hear?
Look at the bright side
I did
The Angztina
No, I do
Should have been to see this early
What is wrong
Space object had to be up early
And somewhere in Europe
Everything opposed to the equations
Unfortunately, not Affhmk
Here
From the beginning of a misjudgment
Dr. "Lehman" a mistake in the calculation of
Mass of the comet
Orb Astdemb "Cassandra" already
But not sent to the surface only
Well
The dividing them into two halves
Therefore,
Therefore did not end up
The second half of the "Cassandra" is coming
And I think it was the largest
We only know that
Must engage with them now
Follow in Part II
Translation was by
Garaa