Previously on Prison Break
I'm giving you an opportunity
to avoid 15 years in jail.
In exchange for...?
Scylla.
Theses are gps ankle monitors.
I am your boss.
And if I ask you to put on a monitor
you put on a monitor.
This data card-- th-this
'scylla' to a Company executive.
And his job was to-to protect it.
When this is all Done.
you and me, we're gonna settle up.
I'm looking for Alex.
Mum.
We're Done talking...
hey! you Don't want to go in there.
You Don't want to go in there.
where are Michael Scofield
and Lincoln Burrows
I swear to you, i-i have
no idea where they are.
What's wrong?
Whatever it is, it ain't it.
If-if Scylla was like a pizza,
all we got's a slice.
So Scylla isn't one card,
it's six.
Hey!
What'd you pull us into? Excuse me?
You figured you'd get us on the hook,
So we could find out for ourselves
How screwed this whole thing was!
What the hell exactly
are you talking about?
The card, agent Self! I'm
talking about the card!
It's useless! Wait, wait, hold on.
You already got the card?
Yes, but without the other
five cards, it means nothing!
And I can only assume you knew that!
What other five?
Don't.
Roland downloaded the card.
There's no Company data on the card.
Without the other five
cards, it's unreadable.
It's like one-sixth of the puzzle,
But that's not my problem,
Because we had a
deal, and we gave you
Exactly what you asked for.
No, you didn't! No, you didn't!
We had a deal for
you to get me Scylla,
And you haven't gotten
me that, have you?
You gave me your word.
And I'm giving you my
word again-- you will go
Back to prison if you can't
get me those other five cards.
But if you're telling me
you can't get this Done,
Just let me know right now,
and we'll get your cell ready.
I'll get it Done.
There's one more thing.
So what'd he say?
We got to find the other
cards. Screw that, man.
We got the card. Let's
do the second step,
The break-in thing,
and end all this.
It doesn't work that way now.
It's not fair. We did what
he said. Then call agent Self,
Tell him you want to
go back to Fox River.
Hell, we're all going to prison
If we can't find the other cards.
When the government gets scared,
They tend to cut the cord.
Did Self talk about shutting us down?
Let's just concentrate on
finding Scylla, all right?
Alex.
Where's he going?
Who cares?
How are we gonna find
Scylla? We Don't even know
Where to start.
Where's the rest of
the stuff you found?
Still printing it up.
When my device was
In Tuxhorn's house it must've
been left next to his pda.
Sucked up all the data from
it and got e-mails and photos.
You see anything we can use?
No, and let me be crystal clear
I point and click.
That's it, other than
that, I'm off the clock.
Shut up. Wait a minute.
Where's his calendar?
Dr. Feelgood's got it.
Here, um, take a look at this.
This is today's date.
There's absolutely
nothing on it but a star.
Every other date, Tuxhorn has
details for his appointments
And meetings-- who he's
with, when and where.
This is the only thing
with nothing on it.
Must be a reason he's
keeping that secret.
Why are we letting this
Self guy call all the shots?
Maybe we should play some hardball.
No. Either help out or get out.
If you open your mouth,
I expect you to offer up a solution.
Hello?
Do you know who this is?
Yeah.
Where are you being held?
I'm not in prison.
Where are you?
I can't say.
I need you to get something to me,
In l.A. Alex...
It's nothing dangerous.
Please, i-i...
I Don't know how much
more Time I have here.
Look... Don't ask
me to do something...
You just need
To reach out to the
residential agency in durango.
Alex, no.
Do you know what they did?
They killed my son.
They killed my boy.
I Don't know what to say.
Just say that you'll help me.
Please?
I just need your help.
I need to find out who did it.
Please.
So listen, I know in Fox River
You had to keep secrets from me.
You Don't now.
What's going on?
Self said we have
until the end of the day
To find the next cardholder.
Or we all go back to prison.
I know that you bailed
out Scofield and Burrows.
And I know they aren't
In a supermax in texas.
But you know where they are.
Don't you, Bruce?
You Don't want any more
trouble than you're already in.
I'm not the one in trouble.
Let me help you relax.
It's a beautiful day.
The sun is shining.
Do you feel that gentle breeze?
It's a great day
For a family picnic.
Don't you think so, Bruce?
Six cards?
That's not what you sold me, Don.
I realize it's more
than we anticipated...
More than you anticipated!
I already have people questioning me
About the supermax
line we're Selling.
This whole thing was a mistake. No!
No, this wasn't a mistake.
Scofield got us a
card within 24 hours
Of being dropped in los angeles.
He knows what he's doing.
Look, I'm willing to take
The risk and do my job.
I Don't understand why you aren't.
I've been in homeland security
since before it even had a name!
Since before you even had
a single short and curly...
Then you should know what's
at stake here, director.
We could stop it, but not--
not if you end this now.
I'm calling senator Dallo now.
I will see if he wants
this thing killed or not.
But he follows my
recommendations, Don.
"sir, changed your
late london arrival,
Now 7/16 at 4:00 p.M."
Today's the 16th,
But there nothing about london
in his calendar, is there?
Not that we've seen, no.
Nothing about travel to
or from the uk at all?
No, nothing.
Now, why would he get an e-mail
About an arrival in
london when he has
No business scheduled there?
Probably because the e-mail
Is a code.
Alex, I'm so glad you joined us.
S-c-y-l-l-a.
Scylla, the meeting today
at 4:00 is about Scylla.
I think we can assume that
Tuxhorn did not schedule
A meeting with himself, so that
Is where we're going to
find our next cardholder.
Okay, so 4:00 p.M. Is
our when, we need a where.
If you were having a secret meeting,
You wouldn't send all
the information together.
You'd send the where and the when
Separately as a precaution.
Were any other
e-mails sent to Tuxhorn
At the same Time as
the london e-mail?
Within a few seconds of the
london mail, two more e-mails
Followed from the same ip
path, but that's when my device
Ran out of hard drive space.
It picked up the ip address,
But not the content.
Trace the ip address
And find out who sent these e-mails.
Oh, look, e-mails get bounced
To routers all over the world
Before they end in your inbox.
Wherever the mail's been,
It leaves a shadow file.
Based on the geography,
I'm guessing these e-mails
Probably squatted at the Anaheim
Server cluster a nanosecond
before reaching Tuxhorn.
So that's where you're going
to find your shadow file.
So get it.
Not every geek with a commodore 64
Can ha into nasa. I
mean, these servers
Have more firewalls
than the devil's bedroom.
You want those e-mails, I'm sorry.
It's on a main server in Anaheim.
It is possible to find
those e-mails at that server?
Technologically possible, yeah.
Then we're going to Anaheim.
I want you two to go
to Tuxhorn's workplace.
Stake it out-- if you see
him, tail him, call us.
You think you're
just going to walk up
To a main server?
You know there's going
To be security, right?
We Don't have a choice.
We have to find that e-mail message.
We can find out where the meeting is.
Find out where the meeting is,
we find our next cardholder.
Got it? We stay out of jail.
Yeah, well, good luck, man.
Actually, you're coming with us.
Guess again. Self told me to sit here
And make with the
clickety-clack on the keyboard.
I'm not going nowhere.
Oh yeah, you are.
Hello?
"instahomes welcomes you home
To your furnished apartment."
Why must you go after this man?
Where I come from, there's
something called a blood feud.
You're coming back, right?
Michael Scofield left me
for dead one too many Times.
Good news, Bruce.
Your favorite aunt
made it to the picnic.
She brought lemonade.
The little cousins are
Swimming in the pond.
Brothers and sisters are
Playing catch in a lush,
Green field.
Everyone is here.
Well, almost everyone.
Two very important people...
...Are missing.
Where are Michael Scofield
and Lincoln Burrows?
I Don't know.
That's okay, Bruce.
I'm sure you'll remember soon.
Just enjoy the picnic.
Hi, uh, my name is Stephanie Reed.
I'm here for a job interview
with human resources.
Okay, then.
Sorry, your name's not in the system.
Um, would you look
again under r-e-e-d?
Sure.
You know, she should drop
a few buttons on that shirt.
The guard will give her the e-mails.
Great.
Yes.
You're in Anaheim, Michael?
This is a strange Time to
be taking a trip to disney.
Listen to me, I promise you,
if you're trying to run...
I'm trying to get you
Another card.
From where? Tomorrowland?
From an e-mail on a main router.
We think there's a Scylla
meeting this afternoon at 4:00.
Where? Hopefully that information
Will be on the e-mail.
Michael, we're running out of Time.
Then stop wasting mine.
I got to go, I got to go.
Did you talk to senator Dallo?
Yes, I did, and now
I need to talk to you.
I'm shutting it down.
Sorry, ma'am, I Don't have
you down for any meeting today.
Okay, um... The, uh,
the temp agency said
That they were going
to set the interview.
Again, I'm sorry.
Okay.
It was really hard
to get a sitter today.
Would you be willing just to
call human resources and see
If they'll see me since I'm here?
Sure.
Hey, it's Tim at the front desk.
Yeah, I've got a Stephanie Reed.
She said she had a job interview.
Stephanie
reed, r-e-e-d.
She just passed it off to Michael.
Server room could
be anywhere in here.
Network and wiring
specifications require
A server that's on the first floor,
Centrally located, like right there.
What are you-- an
engineer or something?
Are you sure you know
how to drive this thing?
Yeah, but it's going to take a while
And I Don't want to get busted.
Just relax and find those e-mails.
Listen, man, when I steal, I do
it from my home, in my boxers,
Eating a bowl of
krispity krunch, okay?
No chance of being seen,
no chance of getting caught.
Just get it Done.
Okay.
All right.
Come on, Michael, come on.
Hey, lady.
Did you get what I need?
Yeah, I got it.
Thank you.
I know what you're planning, Alex,
But listen to me.
If you do track him down, call me.
Don't do something
that could get you hurt.
I won't.
So the material will be
where you asked by 5:00 p.M.
And Alex... I'm so sorry.
Good-bye, Lang.
I'm sorry, they can't see you today,
And there's nothing more I can do.
Okay.
Thank you for your
help, I appreciate it.
Uh, what was the name
Of the temp agency that sent you?
Uh, maybe we can...
Call them together and...
Figure this all out.
I have it written down in my car.
Where the hell's my
security badge, sweetheart?
It ain't at my station.
It was there when you showed up.
Take your hands off me.
I Don't have your badge.
I Don't have your badge. Yeah,
well, we'll see about that.
Sara's in trouble.
What's going on?
She's been made.
Michael, Sara's been made.
Is she all right?
The guard has her; you got
To get out of there now.
Roland, I'll be back.
Where are you going?
Just keep working.
Like I said, sir, I
Don't have your badge.
Excuse me, I need to leave.
You can tell your story
to the cops, sister.
Don't move.
What the hell?
Roland, talk to me.
We're almost there, almost there.
We got to go.
We got to go now.
Got it!
Why won't the door open?
What the hell is that?
It's a fail-safe device, activated
When the alarm gets pulled,
To protect the server
from fire damage.
Then why the hell did you pull it?
This is an old building.
It shouldn't have such an
advanced system. Oh, yeah?
Well, clearly it does.
Wha-wha-what's it do?
To kill the fire
It sucks all the
oxygen out of this room.
Michael, where the hell are you?
It's getting crowded out here.
Linc, Linc, we're trapped.
What? We're in the server room.
What? It's sealed.
They're sucking all the oxygen out.
We've got... Two, maybe
three minutes of air left.
Linc?
I can't breathe.
Calm down.
You panic, it gets worse.
Come on.
Let's go.
You think we're spinning our wheels?
No, we ain't got no choice.
We got to wait and
see if he shows up.
I'm not talking
about finding Tuxhorn.
I'm talking about finding the cards.
I'm talking about finding six cards,
And I'm talking about whether we have
A snowball's chance in haiti
of actually doing this deed.
Better than no chance.
Just saying we're a
couple hours from mexico...
...And I wouldn't mind
having someone with me
Who could actually
speak the native tongue.
Just do your job, Brad.
You feeling good, Bruce?
You look great.
Your father, Josh,
Is so happy you made it to
the family reunion picnic.
He's missed you very much.
My father is dead.
That's right.
He is.
You see that, Bruce?
You just told me the truth in
response to something I said
Because lying is so hard right now...
...But telling the truth is so easy.
So tell me the truth.
Tell me what everyone at
the picnic wants to know.
Where are Michael Scofield
and Lincoln Burrows?
I, I Don--
I Don't know.
Bruce.
A bad storm's coming.
A real bad storm.
Don Self.
Good.
So, so the senator
did get my message?
No, no, I'm sorry,
tomorrow's too late.
Okay, i-i-i need
to speak to him now.
Thank you... Thank you.
Agent Self, it's Time to go.
Pappa paul's pizza palace.
Yeah, I'd like a large
With extra pepperoni
and extra cheese.
The knobbit.
Add momma to the train.
Amateur screen tests #9.
And we have a winner.
Thank you for calling Gate.
How may I help you?
The first e-mail is
an ad for discretia.
An e-mail for pecker pills?
You want the number?
That's great.
Definitely worth almost
losing my life for.
Second e-mail's an invitation
To join some kind
of stargazers' club.
You know, constellations can be
used to track points on earth.
There is a website that
can let you know coordinates
Of star patterns, and
depending on the date,
It'll pick a corresponding
location on earth.
And you know this because...?
Because my son and...
My ex and... And I used to go
On this site, so they could look
Up at the sky and know where I was.
That's not it-- that
constellation's over antarctica.
He's not going to get
there today by 4:00 p.M.,
Not from l.A.
So, I almost died for nothing.
That's good to know. A
lot of people have died.
Well, that's their problem, okay,
Because anyone who gives
up their life for this crap
Is a sucker,
'cause you guys can't win!
Say it about the people who died.
Say it.
Alex.
Get up.
Get back on your nerd
box and do your job.
We can get a little
place by the water,
And you'd be better off
Not being on the run
by yourself, either.
I vouched for you, Bellick.
I told Michael, "brad
helped me get to chicago.
He's a good guy, trust him."
Are you crazy?
And now you just want to run
When we have a chance
to clear our names?
Odds of that Don't look so good.
Tank's full, gas
pedal's on the right,
I say we get the hell out of dodge
Right now-- we can worry
about the ankle bracelets
Once we get over the border.
You listen to me.
There's only one thing
I'm thinking about.
She weighs seven pounds,
has her mother's eyes
And my heart in the
palm of her tiny hands,
So if I have to find one card
Or six cards
Or six million cards,
I'm going to do whatever it takes
'cause I only got to hold
my baby girl for ten seconds,
And that wasn't nearly long enough.
What are you doing?
This guy ain't showing up.
Hey, get your hands
where we can see them!
Get your hands up!
Oh, my god, this ain't good.
I got them up, I got them up!
Put your hands up,
Sucre, come on, man.
Who you calling? Hold on.
Come on, put your hands up!
Okay, okay, Don't shoot, Don't shoot.
Don't shoot, man, we're all right.
Computer's frozen.
What do you mean, it's
frozen? I-i Don't know.
It's just not responding.
I've rebooted twice now.
It's still not letting me on.
Try again.
Look, I've tried a stop
route, a jock program,
Even a back-door entry--
I mean, you were in prison,
I'm sure you're
familiar with that one.
You want to stop breathing?
What happened?
They locked me out.
I'm telling you,
They're shutting us down.
We gotta go.
They're coming after us. Whoa.
We gotta go, let's go,
come on. Whoa, whoa.
Wait a minute, we run, they shoot us!
Stay.
Sara? Yeah.
Let's go, we gotta go.
You said we'd have
until the end of today.
No, this goes way over my head.
Look, this project's been terminated.
Now pull over and end this.
We can finish the job.
There is no more job, okay?
If you make this takedown
public, going back to prison
Is going to be the
least of your worries.
Lose him.
Stay on him, stay on him.
Let's go, let's go!
It's this
way-- go!
Go, go, go!
Thank you for calling Gate.
How may I help you?
Yes, hi, my name is Cole Pfeiffer.
Uh, I'm calling about my,
uh, commencement bonus.
I haven't received it yet, and, uh...
Oh, of course, mr. Pfeiffer.
Um, mr. White is out right now,
But he's going to be so
upset he missed your call.
Here, let me try to track him down.
Oh, no, no, Don't bother.
Uh, maybe you just could, uh,
uh, forward the check to me.
No, mr. White has to
sign off on any checks,
And I know that he really
wants to talk to you,
So can I have him reach you
At the number that
came up on my i.D.?
Looking forward to it.
Why the hell did you tell Self
That we could get a
cardholder by today?
He set the terms, Alex!
I didn't have a choice!
And now none of us have a choice.
And I am not going back to prison.
And I still have
things that I need...
Not going back. Go ahead and run!
Guys, stop.
We ain't running anywhere
With these things on
our ankles, all right?
It's over here.
It's this way.
Wait a minute.
Wait a second.
The signal... The signal's gone.
The signal is gone.
Where are they?
Okay, we gotta go looking for them.
We cannot stay here forever.
They will eventually figure this out.
I Don't care if this place
blocks the signal or not.
Mike, what the hell
are you doing, man?
We Don't have Time for this.
The answers are in
here, they have to be.
If I can just find them,
we might have a chance.
It's an ad-- the
words Don't make sense.
It's gibberish.
Exactly, and that's what
Makes them ideal for hiding data.
Forget about the damn cardholder.
Self pulled the plug on us.
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah.
We're going to figure this out.
We're getting good at
pulling off the impossible.
Hell, I came back
from the dead, right?
What is it?
What do you see?
They go over each other.
Power plant.
New beach.
There's a power plant
in Newport beach.
That's your meeting.
We ain't got long until 4:00.
How the hell are we
going to get out of here?
How fast can you run?
Is that signal?
Yeah, they're heading west.
Four blocks.
Go!
Move, damn it.
What? Get out of the cab.
What the hell do you
think you're doing?
Hello?
Cole Pfeiffer, Gregory White here.
Oh, sorry
To disturb you, sir,
I was just calling
About the, uh... The bonus stipend.
Bother me? What are
you talking about, son?
I'm just thrilled to finally be able
To put a voice to the
e-mail, and better yet,
I'm going to be able to
put a face to the voice.
Right... Because we haven't met yet.
Yes, and that is a crime, my friend.
I gotta tell you, there are
a lot of people over here
At Gate who are very
excited about meeting you,
But I'm going off to oahu
tomorrow with my wife.
I'd love to see you
Before I go, so why
Don't you come to Gate
First thing in the morning?
I think we can all learn something
From the number one salesman
in the entire northeast region.
Well, it... It's what Gate teaches.
"you can unshackle others
With the keys of knowledge."
It... It... I... It's
what I'm here to share,
It's what I know, it's
what I want to give back.
See, that's why I
started this Company,
So that people can avoid
"the captivity of negativity."
Amen to that, mr. White.
Now I gotta go, I've got a lunch,
But I'll see you at Gate
first thing tomorrow,
And I'll set your office up,
Get you in the payroll system,
and I will personally hand you
Your bonus check.
Well, I'll see you at
Gate tomorrow, then.
Grab a bat, Cole Pfeiffer.
Coach just put you in the game.
Strange place for a meeting.
A little cloak-and-dagger,
Don't you think?
Belts and suspenders,
Stuart, belts and suspenders.
Why Laos?
A doctor doesn't perform
his first dissection
On a human cadaver.
First, he learns on
a frog, then a pig,
Then one day, a human.
Laos is our frog.
Perhaps Denmark or
Chad will be our pig.
After that, anything we
want can be our cadaver.
All right, let's
check on the other side
Of the complex; they
could be meeting there.
Run!
Don't move, Burrows.
Don't you move an inch.
I'm taking you down.
Don't move.
Do not move an inch.
Hold! Stop!
Go.
Are you sure about this. Yeah, go.
Freeze. Don't move.
Hands up. Keep your
hands where I can see 'em.
Aah! Come on.
Stop! Hold it!
Hands up.
Hold it.
Let's see your hands.
Get him up.
Scofield ran.
Won't take long to find him.
You're just delaying the inevitable.
What's inevitable is a
meeting with Scylla. Shut up!
Put him in the car.
Listen. We went
through Tuxhorn's pda.
They got a meeting on the
other side of that building.
It's over. It's not over.
It's over, Lincoln, okay?
I know you wanted this to work out,
But it's beyond me now.
Okay, it's Done.
I have orders. It's over.
It's-it's not.
It's finished!
So, when exactly does the
op-order commence, general?
It already has.
No. I mean, when do
we see ramifications?
I'll tell you what, Stuart.
You worry about the gigahertz
and the offshore drilling.
Let me worry about the op-orders.
Oh.
There they come.
What about her?
Let her go.
Hey, hey, real group of winners
You hooked me up with
Here, Donnie. Thanks
a lot. I appreciate it.
Look, man, we both have
worn the badge in our day.
I-i can't survive any
more Time in lock-up.
Can-can we please
work something out?
No. You can work your
ass into this van. Get in.
Congratulations. Company wins.
Come on, get in.
What? Get in.
You got to be kidding me.
It's Michael.
Easy.
Gave you a good enough head start.
Should have took advantage of it.
Yeah, but then I wouldn't have
been able to give you this.
Press the video function.
It wasn't a meeting
Between two Scylla
cardholders, agent Self.
It was a meeting
Between all six cardholders.
So now we know who has
the other five cards,
And that should mean something,
Even to someone whose
word means nothing.
I'm gonna call senator Dallo now.
But he follows my
recommendations, Don.
The next Time you run from me,
I'm not gonna be chasing
you down in a car.
It's gonna be with a
bullet in your back.
Let 'em go.
All of 'em.
Come on.
Let 'em go.
Put 'em in the warehouse.
All of 'em.
Come on
Yeah, it's Don Self.
I need to talk to him right now.
Right now.
Some day soon, we're gonna
drop that lifeboat of yours
In the water and disappear forever.
I promise.
Hey, where's mr. Personality going?
They check his wrists?
'cause he must...
Let him be.
Insubordination's tiring, huh?
Where the hell do you get off
calling senator Dallo directly?
You Don't move into my city,
Into my regional office
and go over my head!
What do you want from me?
You know how it works, Herb.
You think when the Company's
breathing down your neck,
Senator Dallo's gonna
bring in the cavalry?
He'll pretend he's
never even heard of you.
You're on your own from now on, Self.
You're an island.
If I'm an island, what
are you doing here?
Get out of my office and
let me finish what I started.
When you do get buried,
I'll be the first one
there with a shovel.
Great. See you then.
Sara Tancredi's
Somewhere safe, isn't she, Bruce?
You would have made sure
of that, wouldn't you?
So tell me, where is Sara?
Help me get your family to Sara,
Where it's safe.
Safe.
Los angeles?
Where in los angeles?
I Don't know.
I believe you.
Good job.
Picnic's over,
Bruce.
What's up with Mahone?
They murdered his son.
The Company killed his son like...
Like they tried to kill lj.
Alex, i, uh...
Uh, i-i know what happened.
I'm sorry.
They did this...
...To get to me,
To flush me out.
And then they let my ex-wife
Stay alive...
...Just so she could
tell me that she was next
If... If I didn't turn myself in.
Now she's in protective custody,
And I'm living in a
warehouse trying to find
The son of a bitch who killed my kid.
We're all here for something.
All of us are here for something.
You need to stay focused
until this is Done.
I can do my job.
I promise.
Good.
And I promise I'll
do whatever it takes
To help you find the
person that killed your son
And the people behind the hit.
We're gonna get these guys, Alex.
I'm gonna help you.