1
00:00:29,100 --> 00:00:32,100
Marry, that 'marry' is the very theme
I came to talk of.

2
00:00:32,101 --> 00:00:36,120
Tell me, daughter Juliet,
How stands your disposition to be married?

3
00:00:36,121 --> 00:00:39,540
- It is an honour that I dream not of.
- An honour!

4
00:00:39,821 --> 00:00:44,021
Were not I thine only nurse,
I would say thou hadst suck'd wisdom from thy teat.

5
00:00:44,511 --> 00:00:46,420
Well, think of marriage now;

6
00:00:46,421 --> 00:00:50,580
Younger than you, here in Verona, ladies of esteem,
are made already mothers.

7
00:00:56,181 --> 00:00:58,591
- Thus then in brief...
- Madam,

8
00:00:58,901 --> 00:01:01,301
the guests are come, supper served up

9
00:01:01,621 --> 00:01:04,021
you called, my young lady asked for,

10
00:01:04,061 --> 00:01:09,980
the nurse cursed in the pantry,
and every thing in extremity.

11
00:01:09,981 --> 00:01:11,980
I must hence to wait.

12
00:01:11,981 --> 00:01:14,741
- I beseech you, follow straight.
- We follow thee.

13
00:01:37,981 --> 00:01:39,741
Five, six, seven, eight

14
00:01:40,981 --> 00:01:42,741
nine. ten, eleven, twelve...

15
00:01:50,981 --> 00:01:52,741
Good-morrow, Romeo.

16
00:01:55,341 --> 00:01:58,421
- Is the day so young?
- But new struck nine.

17
00:02:00,341 --> 00:02:03,421
Ay me! Benvolio, sad hours seem long.

18
00:02:03,422 --> 00:02:06,423
What sadness lengthens Romeo's hours?

19
00:02:08,261 --> 00:02:11,700
Not having that, which, having, makes them short.

20
00:02:11,701 --> 00:02:13,700
In love?

21
00:02:15,701 --> 00:02:19,140
- Out.
- Of love?

22
00:02:19,141 --> 00:02:21,781
Out of her favour, where I am in love.

23
00:02:21,981 --> 00:02:25,301
Tell me in sadness, who is that you love.

24
00:02:26,582 --> 00:02:29,311
What, shall I groan and tell thee?

25
00:02:29,581 --> 00:02:32,331
Groan! Why, no.
But sadly tell me who.

26
00:02:34,581 --> 00:02:37,331
In sadness, Benvolio, I do love

27
00:02:38,332 --> 00:02:40,332
a woman.

28
00:02:42,181 --> 00:02:44,420
I aim'd so near, when I supposed you loved.

29
00:02:44,421 --> 00:02:48,221
A right good mark-man!
And she's fair I love.

30
00:02:48,421 --> 00:02:51,021
A right fair mark, fair coz, is soonest hit.

31
00:02:51,022 --> 00:02:53,022
Well, in that hit you miss:

32
00:02:53,821 --> 00:02:57,060
She'll not be hit with Cupid's arrow;
She hath forsworn to love

33
00:02:57,061 --> 00:03:00,860
and in that vow
do I live dead that live to tell it now.

34
00:03:00,861 --> 00:03:03,341
Farewell: thou canst not teach me to forget.

35
00:03:03,861 --> 00:03:06,341
I'll teach you, or else die in debt.

36
00:03:11,901 --> 00:03:14,900
Mark time, march!

37
00:03:14,901 --> 00:03:18,101
Left. right, left, right!

38
00:03:18,102 --> 00:03:19,900
Then,

39
00:03:19,901 --> 00:03:22,101
halt!

40
00:03:23,901 --> 00:03:27,101
Dress right, dress!

41
00:03:32,102 --> 00:03:33,900
Ready,

42
00:03:33,901 --> 00:03:36,101
front!

43
00:03:38,901 --> 00:03:41,101
Listen up!

44
00:03:41,901 --> 00:03:45,140
Those of you who did not qualified
for the land navigation excersises

45
00:03:45,141 --> 00:03:47,140
and are remaining here on campus,

46
00:03:47,141 --> 00:03:51,341
you'll be under the command
of cadet Moreno and myself.

47
00:03:52,421 --> 00:03:57,341
There will be no officers or faculty
on campus for the next four days.

48
00:03:58,221 --> 00:04:01,461
We'll follow a regular schedule without variation.

49
00:04:01,561 --> 00:04:04,260
Classwork, homework, physical fitness.

50
00:04:06,261 --> 00:04:10,420
We are all McKinley Military Academy cadets.

51
00:04:10,541 --> 00:04:14,581
Which means we will maintain the highest standards
of neatness, promptness, orderliness,

52
00:04:14,621 --> 00:04:18,060
and military bearing at all times!

53
00:04:18,061 --> 00:04:21,060
And no trouble!
Understood?

54
00:04:21,061 --> 00:04:22,661
Yes. sir!

55
00:04:24,061 --> 00:04:25,661
Dismissed!

56
00:04:27,461 --> 00:04:28,621
Cadet Neff!

57
00:04:30,221 --> 00:04:35,421
Take our good meaning, for our judgment sits
Five times in that ere once in our five wits.

58
00:04:35,861 --> 00:04:36,981
Had I say to stop?

59
00:04:39,421 --> 00:04:43,660
And we mean well in going to this mask,
but 'tis no wit to go.

60
00:04:43,661 --> 00:04:45,861
Why, may one ask?

61
00:04:45,961 --> 00:04:47,861
I dream'd a dream to-night.

62
00:04:47,661 --> 00:04:49,861
And so did I.

63
00:04:49,961 --> 00:04:54,861
- Well, what was yours?
- That dreamers often lie.

64
00:04:55,821 --> 00:04:59,060
In bed asleep, while they do dream things true.

65
00:04:59,061 --> 00:05:03,261
O, then, I see Queen Mab hath been with you.

66
00:05:03,321 --> 00:05:06,341
- She is the fairies' midwife...
- Dismissed!

67
00:05:08,941 --> 00:05:13,100
What lady is that, which doth
enrich the hand of yonder knight?

68
00:05:13,101 --> 00:05:15,461
I know not, sir.

69
00:05:15,501 --> 00:05:18,901
O, she doth teach the torches to burn bright!

70
00:05:25,941 --> 00:05:28,381
Read!

71
00:05:28,861 --> 00:05:32,100
It seems she hangs upon the cheek of night
Like a rich jewel in an Ethiope's ear;

72
00:05:32,101 --> 00:05:34,100
Beauty too rich for use, for earth too dear!

73
00:05:34,101 --> 00:05:37,301
So shows a snowy dove trooping with crows,

74
00:05:37,341 --> 00:05:40,421
As yonder lady o'er her fellows shows.

75
00:05:40,741 --> 00:05:42,941
Josh!

76
00:05:42,981 --> 00:05:45,261
Cadets! No running in the hall!

77
00:05:45,262 --> 00:05:47,262
Yes, sir!

78
00:06:25,161 --> 00:06:27,661
- Hi.
- Hi.

79
00:06:38,662 --> 00:06:40,662
Where are you going?

80
00:06:40,663 --> 00:06:42,663
Glenn!

81
00:08:07,741 --> 00:08:09,741
Gus!

82
00:08:21,741 --> 00:08:23,741
Gus!

83
00:08:38,941 --> 00:08:41,461
Do you think I'm gonna get into West Point?

84
00:08:50,941 --> 00:08:53,461
You really think so?

85
00:08:55,941 --> 00:08:58,461
You ask me everyday.

86
00:09:02,941 --> 00:09:05,461
Feel this.

87
00:09:09,941 --> 00:09:12,461
I've load 130.

88
00:09:15,941 --> 00:09:18,461
Can I go back to sleep now?

89
00:09:58,101 --> 00:10:00,141
- Cadet Singleton!
- Yes, sir!

90
00:10:01,141 --> 00:10:04,621
- You've to be showering and be not late for inspection.
- Yes. sir!

91
00:10:05,141 --> 00:10:06,621
Dismissed!

92
00:10:44,141 --> 00:10:45,621
Right dress!

93
00:10:48,141 --> 00:10:49,621
Left dress!

94
00:10:52,622 --> 00:10:54,622
About face!

95
00:11:00,141 --> 00:11:03,140
- Omar.
- Shit!

96
00:11:03,141 --> 00:11:04,621
- Cadet Madsen/
- Ya!

97
00:11:10,581 --> 00:11:13,781
Now, by my maidenhead, at twelve year old,
I bade her come..

98
00:11:15,821 --> 00:11:18,021
What, lamb! what, ladybird!

99
00:11:18,061 --> 00:11:21,261
Where's this girl? What, Juliet!

100
00:11:21,661 --> 00:11:24,101
What, lamb! what, ladybird!
Where's this girl? What, Juliet!

101
00:11:24,102 --> 00:11:26,102
What, Juliet.

102
00:11:28,661 --> 00:11:31,101
How now! Who calls?

103
00:11:46,661 --> 00:11:49,101
What, lamb!

104
00:11:49,661 --> 00:11:52,101
What, ladybird!

105
00:11:56,661 --> 00:11:59,101
Hi. Julia!

106
00:13:00,461 --> 00:13:04,541
And we mean well in going to this mask;
But 'tis no wit to go.

107
00:13:06,461 --> 00:13:07,541
Why, may one ask?

108
00:13:11,621 --> 00:13:14,421
I dream'd...
I dream'd a dream to-night.

109
00:13:15,101 --> 00:13:17,301
And so did I.

110
00:13:17,341 --> 00:13:18,981
Well, what was yours?

111
00:13:21,341 --> 00:13:22,981
That dreamers often lie.

112
00:13:25,341 --> 00:13:28,461
In bed asleep, while they do dream things true.

113
00:13:34,341 --> 00:13:37,661
O, then, I see Queen Mab hath been with you.

114
00:13:38,781 --> 00:13:40,981
She is the fairies' midwife,

115
00:13:40,982 --> 00:13:43,982
and she comes
In shape no bigger than an agate-stone.

116
00:13:44,301 --> 00:13:49,581
On the fore-finger of an alderman

117
00:13:50,821 --> 00:13:55,021
Drawn with a team of little atomies
Athwart men's noses as they lie asleep;

118
00:13:56,421 --> 00:13:59,461
Her chariot is an empty hazel-nut

119
00:13:59,462 --> 00:14:03,462
Her wagon-spokes made of long spiders' legs

120
00:14:03,861 --> 00:14:07,181
The cover of the wings of grasshoppers,

121
00:14:07,561 --> 00:14:11,181
The traces of the smallest spider's web.

122
00:14:11,941 --> 00:14:16,141
Her whip of cricket's bone, the lash of film,

123
00:14:19,381 --> 00:14:24,581
Her driver a small grey-coated gnat

124
00:14:25,621 --> 00:14:31,701
Not so big as a round little worm
Prick'd from the lazy finger of a maid.

125
00:14:59,981 --> 00:15:02,620
And in this state she gallops night by night

126
00:15:02,621 --> 00:15:05,101
Through lovers' brains, and then they dream of love;

127
00:15:05,301 --> 00:15:07,261
O'er ladies ' lips, who straight on kisses dream,

128
00:15:07,301 --> 00:15:11,261
Which oft the angry Mab with blisters plagues,

129
00:15:11,301 --> 00:15:13,261
Because their breaths with sweetmeats tainted are:

130
00:15:16,981 --> 00:15:22,181
Sometime she driveth o'er a soldier's neck,
And then dreams he of cutting foreign throats,

131
00:15:22,981 --> 00:15:26,781
Of breaches, ambuscadoes, Spanish blades,
Of healths five-fathom deep;

132
00:15:26,981 --> 00:15:31,901
and then anon
Drums in his ear, at which he starts and wakes,

133
00:15:31,902 --> 00:15:33,902
And being thus frighted

134
00:15:34,981 --> 00:15:38,901
swears a prayer or two

135
00:15:40,421 --> 00:15:41,741
And sleeps again.

136
00:15:42,421 --> 00:15:43,741
Peace, peace,
Thou talk'st of nothing.

137
00:15:44,421 --> 00:15:45,741
I talk of dreams,

138
00:15:47,421 --> 00:15:52,420
Which are the children of an idle brain,
Begot of nothing but vain fantasy,

139
00:15:52,421 --> 00:15:55,420
Which is as thin of substance as the air
And more inconstant than the wind...

140
00:15:55,421 --> 00:15:59,420
This wind, you talk of, blows us from ourselves;

141
00:15:59,421 --> 00:16:01,420
Come! Knock and enter!

142
00:16:01,421 --> 00:16:04,741
Supper is done, and we shall come too late.

143
00:16:45,113 --> 00:16:46,495
Welcome, gentlemen!

144
00:16:49,444 --> 00:16:54,370
Ladies that have their toes
Unplagued with corns will have about with you.

145
00:16:55,370 --> 00:16:59,284
A hall, a hall! give room! and foot it, girls.

146
00:16:59,968 --> 00:17:04,103
She that makes dainty,
She, I'll swear, hath corns.

147
00:17:05,103 --> 00:17:07,951
Nay, gentle Romeo, we must have you dance.

148
00:17:07,952 --> 00:17:13,985
Not I, believe me: you have dancing shoes
With nimble soles: I have a soul of lead

149
00:17:13,986 --> 00:17:16,708
So stakes me to the ground I cannot move.

150
00:17:16,709 --> 00:17:18,709
You are a lover;

151
00:17:18,710 --> 00:17:22,710
borrow Cupid's wings,
And soar with them above a common bound.

152
00:17:23,711 --> 00:17:27,711
I am too sore enpierced with his shaft
To soar...

153
00:17:28,712 --> 00:17:31,712
Under love's heavy burden do I sink.

154
00:17:31,713 --> 00:17:33,713
And, to sink in it, should you burden love;

155
00:17:33,714 --> 00:17:36,994
Too great oppression for a tender thing.

156
00:17:37,995 --> 00:17:39,640
Is love a tender thing?

157
00:17:40,829 --> 00:17:45,905
It is too rough,
Too rude, too boisterous, and it pricks like thorn.

158
00:17:45,906 --> 00:17:49,448
If love be rough with you, be rough with love;

159
00:17:50,449 --> 00:17:53,449
Prick love for pricking,

160
00:17:53,587 --> 00:17:55,361
and you beat love down.

161
00:18:07,939 --> 00:18:09,822
What lady is that,

162
00:18:09,823 --> 00:18:12,704
which doth enrich the hand
of yonder knight?

163
00:18:12,705 --> 00:18:14,543
I know not.

164
00:18:16,296 --> 00:18:19,315
O, she doth teach the torches to burn bright!

165
00:18:20,845 --> 00:18:25,590
It seems she hangs upon the cheek of night
as a rich jewel in an Ethiope's ear;

166
00:18:25,591 --> 00:18:31,125
Beauty too rich for use, for earth too dear!

167
00:18:32,125 --> 00:18:37,606
So shows a snowy dove trooping with crows,
As yonder lady o'er her fellows shows.

168
00:18:40,607 --> 00:18:44,805
The measure done, I'll watch her place of stand,

169
00:18:44,806 --> 00:18:48,806
And, touching hers, make blessed my rude hand.

170
00:19:03,583 --> 00:19:05,669
Did my heart love till now?

171
00:19:07,069 --> 00:19:11,524
For swear it, sight!
For I ne'er saw true beauty till this night.

172
00:19:19,524 --> 00:19:21,580
What?

173
00:19:21,524 --> 00:19:24,580
What dares the slave
Come hither, cover'd with an antic face,

174
00:19:24,581 --> 00:19:27,025
to fleer and scorn at our solemnity?

175
00:19:27,026 --> 00:19:31,026
Why, how now. Wherefore storm you so?

176
00:19:33,027 --> 00:19:35,027
This is our foe,

177
00:19:36,028 --> 00:19:38,028
that villain Romeo.

178
00:19:39,029 --> 00:19:41,029
Ttake no note of him.

179
00:19:42,029 --> 00:19:44,029
Show a fair presence and put off these frowns,

180
00:19:44,030 --> 00:19:48,030
And ill-beseeming semblance for a feast.

181
00:19:53,148 --> 00:19:56,462
- I'll not endure him!
- He shall be endured.

182
00:19:56,463 --> 00:19:59,332
Am I the master here, or you?

183
00:20:02,333 --> 00:20:05,333
Go to.
Go to!

184
00:20:12,600 --> 00:20:14,600
Why,

185
00:20:15,601 --> 00:20:18,841
'tis a shame.

186
00:20:19,842 --> 00:20:23,842
Be quiet, or... for shame!

187
00:20:23,843 --> 00:20:26,843
I'll make you quiet.

188
00:20:28,728 --> 00:20:31,060
Sure.

189
00:20:31,160 --> 00:20:33,162
I like your kicks in it, nice.

190
00:20:33,162 --> 00:20:36,080
- Thanks.
- Is it like a...

191
00:20:36,081 --> 00:20:38,552
- That's the loose string.
- It's cool.

192
00:20:38,552 --> 00:20:43,369
I like it.
And what is... Oh!

193
00:20:44,731 --> 00:20:52,663
If I profane with my unworthiest hand
This holy shrine, the gentle thin is this:

194
00:20:52,664 --> 00:20:56,907
My lips, two blushing pilgrims, ready stand

195
00:20:56,908 --> 00:21:00,030
To smooth that rough touch with a tender kiss.

196
00:21:12,612 --> 00:21:17,200
Good pilgrim, you do wrong your hand too much,

197
00:21:17,201 --> 00:21:20,201
Which mannerly devotion shows in this;

198
00:21:21,202 --> 00:21:24,954
For saints have hands that pilgrims' hands do touch,

199
00:21:24,955 --> 00:21:29,996
And palm to palm is holy palmers' kiss.

200
00:21:32,996 --> 00:21:35,966
Have not saints lips, and holy palmers too?

201
00:21:35,967 --> 00:21:39,848
Ay, pilgrim, lips that they must use in prayer.

202
00:21:40,849 --> 00:21:45,587
O, then, dear saint, let lips do what hands do;

203
00:21:47,588 --> 00:21:52,588
They pray, grant thou, lest faith turn to despair.

204
00:21:54,834 --> 00:21:58,848
Saints do not move, though grant for prayers' sake.

205
00:21:59,848 --> 00:22:04,292
Then move not, while my prayer's effect I take.

206
00:22:16,385 --> 00:22:17,844
I will withdraw:

207
00:22:20,086 --> 00:22:28,209
but this intrusion shall
Now seeming sweet convert to bitter gall.

208
00:22:36,669 --> 00:22:38,960
Thus from my lips, by yours, my sin is purged.

209
00:22:39,389 --> 00:22:42,953
Then have my lips the sin that they have took.

210
00:22:42,954 --> 00:22:44,954
Sin from thy lips?

211
00:22:44,955 --> 00:22:47,955
O trespass sweetly urged!

212
00:22:49,944 --> 00:22:53,068
Give me my sin again.

213
00:23:00,336 --> 00:23:04,585
It makes my flesh tremble in their different greeting.

214
00:23:17,609 --> 00:23:19,321
Madam, your mother craves a word with you.

215
00:23:24,610 --> 00:23:27,233
Come!

216
00:23:28,234 --> 00:23:30,113
Let's away.

217
00:23:37,671 --> 00:23:39,671
Romeo,

218
00:23:39,672 --> 00:23:43,156
Away, begone; the sport is at the best.

219
00:23:43,754 --> 00:23:47,022
Ay, so I fear; the more is my unrest.

220
00:24:06,254 --> 00:24:07,677
Romeo!

221
00:24:14,486 --> 00:24:15,778
My cousin Romeo?

222
00:24:17,779 --> 00:24:19,777
He is wise, Benvolio.

223
00:24:19,778 --> 00:24:22,854
And, on my life, hath stol'n him home to bed.

224
00:24:24,855 --> 00:24:28,597
He ran this way.

225
00:24:28,598 --> 00:24:31,598
- Call, good Mercutio.
- Nay,

226
00:24:32,599 --> 00:24:34,599
I'll conjure too.

227
00:24:40,600 --> 00:24:42,600
Romeo!

228
00:24:46,597 --> 00:24:49,306
Humours!

229
00:24:50,306 --> 00:24:51,987
Madman!

230
00:24:55,988 --> 00:24:57,988
Lover!

231
00:25:01,170 --> 00:25:02,687
Passion!

232
00:25:04,687 --> 00:25:06,736
Romeo!

233
00:25:10,736 --> 00:25:13,024
Romeo!

234
00:25:23,982 --> 00:25:26,629
Appear thou in the likeness of a sigh:

235
00:25:28,629 --> 00:25:31,206
Speak but one rhyme, and I am satisfied;

236
00:25:31,206 --> 00:25:33,605
And if he hear thee, thou wilt anger him.

237
00:25:33,606 --> 00:25:35,606
This cannot anger him:

238
00:25:35,607 --> 00:25:38,604
my invocation Is fair

239
00:25:38,605 --> 00:25:41,351
and honest.

240
00:25:44,351 --> 00:25:45,572
Come.

241
00:25:45,573 --> 00:25:49,573
He hath hid himself among these trees,
To be consorted with the humorous night:

242
00:25:51,574 --> 00:25:53,574
Blind is his love

243
00:25:54,575 --> 00:25:56,575
and best befits the dark.

244
00:25:58,576 --> 00:26:00,576
If love be blind,

245
00:26:02,577 --> 00:26:05,577
it cannot hit the mark.

246
00:26:10,299 --> 00:26:12,489
Romeo...

247
00:26:14,198 --> 00:26:15,918
Good night.

248
00:26:18,918 --> 00:26:20,791
I'll to my bed:

249
00:26:24,359 --> 00:26:26,581
This field-bed is too cold for me to sleep.

250
00:26:28,582 --> 00:26:30,582
Go, then.

251
00:26:31,583 --> 00:26:35,583
For 'tis in vain
To seek him here that means not to be found.

252
00:26:58,581 --> 00:27:03,301
He jests at scars that never felt a wound.

253
00:27:07,302 --> 00:27:09,302
But, soft!

254
00:27:09,303 --> 00:27:12,303
What light through yonder window breaks?

255
00:27:21,304 --> 00:27:23,304
It is the east,

256
00:27:24,305 --> 00:27:26,305
and Juliet is the sun.

257
00:27:34,301 --> 00:27:38,983
Arise, fair sun, and kill the envious moon,

258
00:27:39,984 --> 00:27:43,110
Who is already sick and pale with grief,

259
00:27:43,111 --> 00:27:46,908
That thou her maid art far more fair than she.

260
00:27:53,385 --> 00:27:55,220
O Romeo.

261
00:27:56,220 --> 00:27:59,778
Romeo! wherefore art thou Romeo?

262
00:28:01,261 --> 00:28:04,737
Deny thy father and refuse thy name.

263
00:28:05,737 --> 00:28:07,869
What's in a name?

264
00:28:08,141 --> 00:28:10,242
That which we call a rose

265
00:28:10,243 --> 00:28:13,242
By any other name would smell as sweet.

266
00:28:13,243 --> 00:28:17,243
So Romeo would, were he not Romeo call'd,

267
00:28:17,244 --> 00:28:20,244
retain that dear perfection which he owes

268
00:28:20,245 --> 00:28:22,245
without that title.

269
00:28:23,246 --> 00:28:25,246
Romeo, doff thy name,

270
00:28:25,247 --> 00:28:29,066
and for that name which is no part of thee

271
00:28:29,067 --> 00:28:31,131
take all myself.

272
00:28:32,326 --> 00:28:33,995
I take thee at thy word:

273
00:28:33,996 --> 00:28:35,994
call me but love, and I'll be new baptized

274
00:28:35,995 --> 00:28:37,709
Henceforth I never will be Romeo.

275
00:28:37,710 --> 00:28:40,708
What man art thou that thus bescreen'd in night
so stumblest on my counsel?

276
00:28:45,108 --> 00:28:48,439
By a name
I know not how to tell thee who I am,

277
00:28:48,440 --> 00:28:54,515
My name, dear saint, is hateful to myself,
because it is an enemy to thee.

278
00:28:55,644 --> 00:29:02,449
My ears have not yet drunk a hundred words
of that tongue's utterance, yet I know the sound.

279
00:29:02,450 --> 00:29:06,199
Art thou not Romeo?

280
00:29:06,807 --> 00:29:08,863
- and a Montague?
- Neither,

281
00:29:09,863 --> 00:29:11,838
if either thee dislike.

282
00:29:13,067 --> 00:29:14,687
How camest thou hither,

283
00:29:15,687 --> 00:29:18,205
tell me, and wherefore?

284
00:29:18,205 --> 00:29:19,604
The orchard walls are high and hard to climb.

285
00:29:19,604 --> 00:29:25,259
And the place death, considering who thou art,
if any of my kinsmen find thee here.

286
00:29:26,684 --> 00:29:33,114
With love's light wings did I o'er-perch these walls.
For stony limits cannot hold love out.

287
00:29:33,901 --> 00:29:38,400
And what love can do that dares love attempt;
Therefore thy kinsmen are no stop to me.

288
00:29:39,401 --> 00:29:42,058
If they do see thee, they will murder thee.

289
00:29:42,059 --> 00:29:47,059
Alack, there lies more peril in thine eye
Than twenty of their swords.

290
00:29:47,060 --> 00:29:51,780
Look thou but sweet,
And I am proof against their enmity.

291
00:29:53,651 --> 00:29:56,576
Thou know'st the mask of night is on my face,

292
00:29:57,576 --> 00:30:03,752
Else would a maiden blush bepaint my cheek
For that which thou hast heard me speak to-night.

293
00:30:06,674 --> 00:30:09,027
O gentle Romeo,

294
00:30:11,028 --> 00:30:13,356
If thou dost love, pronounce it faithfully.

295
00:30:14,357 --> 00:30:18,350
Or if thou think'st I am too quickly won,

296
00:30:18,351 --> 00:30:23,346
I'll frown and be perverse an say thee nay.

297
00:30:23,347 --> 00:30:26,145
So thou wilt woo.

298
00:30:26,145 --> 00:30:29,195
- If my heart's dear love...
- Well, do not swear.

299
00:30:31,195 --> 00:30:36,669
Although I joy in thee,
I have no joy of this contract to-night:

300
00:30:36,670 --> 00:30:41,969
It is too rash, too unadvised, too sudden.

301
00:30:41,970 --> 00:30:46,805
O, wilt thou leave me so unsatisfied?

302
00:30:46,806 --> 00:30:48,806
What satisfaction canst thou have to-night?

303
00:30:48,807 --> 00:30:52,807
The exchange of thy love's faithful vow for mine.

304
00:30:54,242 --> 00:31:01,061
I gave thee mine before thou didst request it:
And yet I would it were to give again.

305
00:31:01,061 --> 00:31:06,049
Wouldst thou withdraw it?
For what purpose, love?

306
00:31:06,049 --> 00:31:09,478
But to be frank, and give it thee again.

307
00:31:11,478 --> 00:31:13,866
And yet I wish but for the thing I have:

308
00:31:14,866 --> 00:31:18,136
My bounty is as boundless as the sea,

309
00:31:19,136 --> 00:31:22,139
my love as deep.

310
00:31:22,139 --> 00:31:25,397
The more I give to thee,
the more I have,

311
00:31:25,397 --> 00:31:28,482
for both are infinite.

312
00:31:31,510 --> 00:31:33,649
Juliet!

313
00:31:35,412 --> 00:31:36,974
Anon, good nurse!

314
00:31:41,740 --> 00:31:45,438
Three words, dear Romeo, and good night indeed.

315
00:31:47,439 --> 00:31:49,864
If that thy bent of love be honourable,

316
00:31:50,962 --> 00:31:53,060
thy purpose marriage,

317
00:31:53,937 --> 00:31:55,386
send me word to-morrow
by one that I'll procure to come to thee,

318
00:31:55,387 --> 00:31:59,387
Where and what time thou wilt perform the rite,

319
00:32:00,394 --> 00:32:06,469
And all my fortunes at thy foot I'll lay
and follow thee my lord throughout the world.

320
00:32:06,698 --> 00:32:09,011
- Madam!
- I come, anon.

321
00:32:15,712 --> 00:32:18,395
But if thou mean'st not well,
I do beseech thee...

322
00:32:19,395 --> 00:32:22,993
- Madam!
- By and by, I come.

323
00:32:23,661 --> 00:32:27,116
To cease thy suit, and leave me to my grief.

324
00:32:42,116 --> 00:32:44,874
- To-morrow will I send.
- So thrive my soul...

325
00:32:44,874 --> 00:32:47,135
A thousand times good night!

326
00:32:47,135 --> 00:32:50,178
A thousand times the worse, to want thy light.

327
00:32:50,117 --> 00:32:52,618
Love goes toward love, like schoolboys

328
00:32:52,619 --> 00:32:57,953
from their books.
But love from love, toward school with heavy looks

329
00:32:58,505 --> 00:33:02,020
At what o'clock to-morrow
shall I send to thee?

330
00:33:02,021 --> 00:33:04,327
By the hour of nine.

331
00:33:04,859 --> 00:33:05,640
I will not fail.

332
00:33:06,640 --> 00:33:09,596
'tis twenty years till then.

333
00:33:27,596 --> 00:33:30,334
Parting is such sweet sorrow,
that I shall say good night ,

334
00:33:30,335 --> 00:33:32,335
till it be morrow.

335
00:33:32,736 --> 00:33:34,557
Sleep dwell upon thine eyes,

336
00:33:35,558 --> 00:33:37,558
peace in thy breast!

337
00:33:56,559 --> 00:33:59,559
Would I were sleep and peace, so sweet to rest!

338
00:34:16,449 --> 00:34:18,288
<i>Follow me</i>

339
00:34:18,144 --> 00:34:20,917
<i>To the shipwreck shores of a dark and strange country.</i>

340
00:34:20,918 --> 00:34:23,426
<i>I was born</i>

341
00:34:24,081 --> 00:34:26,901
<i>A stranger thinking out loud in a foreign tongue.</i>

342
00:34:26,901 --> 00:34:29,161
<i>I was out of place.</i>

343
00:34:29,161 --> 00:34:31,237
<i>I was looking all around
just a'trying to find a friendly face.</i>

344
00:34:32,237 --> 00:34:34,660
<i>But they're all gone.</i>

345
00:34:37,126 --> 00:34:43,257
<i>Did you ever think? Did you ever think?
Did you ever think? Did you ever think, think?</i>

346
00:34:56,785 --> 00:34:58,785
<i>Who left me all alone in this town.</i>

347
00:35:00,786 --> 00:35:04,786
<i>And a busted heart
Is a welcome friend</i>

348
00:35:05,784 --> 00:35:10,068
<i>And when that heart leaves
What will you do then?</i>

349
00:35:11,069 --> 00:35:15,069
<i>And if I cry,
Is that a sin?</i>

350
00:35:22,068 --> 00:35:24,922
<i>And the wisdom is a whisper.</i>

351
00:35:27,519 --> 00:35:30,907
<i>And I'm trying to understand,</i>

352
00:35:32,482 --> 00:35:37,924
<i>What I say, what I think,
Where I sleep, when I breathe.</i>

353
00:35:37,925 --> 00:35:40,925
<i>What I do with my hands.</i>

354
00:35:43,926 --> 00:35:47,926
<i>Did you ever think? Did you ever think?
Did you ever think? Did you ever think, think?</i>

355
00:35:48,927 --> 00:35:52,927
<i>A lotta people everyday who will surely drown.</i>

356
00:35:54,923 --> 00:35:58,758
<i>Did you ever think? Did you ever think?
Did you ever think? Did you ever think, think?</i>

357
00:36:00,758 --> 00:36:03,932
<i>Who left me all alone in this town? </i>

358
00:37:08,932 --> 00:37:10,658
Here is the McKinley Military Academy!

359
00:37:10,659 --> 00:37:13,657
Which strives to develop young men
with good character.

360
00:37:14,658 --> 00:37:18,919
To cultivate the traits of honor, duty, respect, and pride.

361
00:37:19,920 --> 00:37:22,628
Now to accomplish that the Academy
follows a military system,

362
00:37:23,298 --> 00:37:26,499
in which discipline is cornerstone.

363
00:37:26,676 --> 00:37:30,629
Any cadet who violates regulations or commits
offences against good order and discipline

364
00:37:30,629 --> 00:37:35,036
must be punished appropriately and justly.

365
00:37:35,037 --> 00:37:38,037
You are all recievied one demerit.

366
00:37:39,232 --> 00:37:41,675
Put yourself to the mess for breakfast!

367
00:37:42,675 --> 00:37:44,728
Company, dismissed!

368
00:37:45,174 --> 00:37:46,783
Carlos!

369
00:37:52,597 --> 00:37:54,970
You take care of Neff.

370
00:37:59,970 --> 00:38:02,012
Pick up the pace, cadet Neff!

371
00:38:11,787 --> 00:38:13,892
Good morrow, father Laurence!

372
00:38:15,892 --> 00:38:18,254
Good morrow, father Laurence.

373
00:38:18,254 --> 00:38:20,584
What early tongue so sweet saluteth me?

374
00:38:21,584 --> 00:38:26,468
Young son, it argues a distemper'd head
So soon to bid good morrow to thy bed.

375
00:38:27,468 --> 00:38:32,544
Or if not so, then here I hit it right,

376
00:38:34,348 --> 00:38:37,058
Our Romeo hath not been in bed to-night.

377
00:38:43,945 --> 00:38:45,892
That last is true.

378
00:38:46,495 --> 00:38:48,126
The sweeter rest was mine.

379
00:38:48,158 --> 00:38:51,306
That's my good son: but where hast thou been, then?

380
00:38:51,307 --> 00:38:54,189
I'll tell thee, ere thou ask it me again.

381
00:38:54,190 --> 00:38:58,190
I have been feasting with mine enemy,

382
00:38:58,191 --> 00:39:03,188
Where on a sudden one hath wounded me,
that's by me wounded.

383
00:39:03,189 --> 00:39:07,264
Both our remedies
within thy help and holy physic lies.

384
00:39:07,265 --> 00:39:10,675
Be plain, good son, and homely in thy drift.

385
00:39:10,676 --> 00:39:14,100
Riddling confession finds but riddling shrift.

386
00:39:14,919 --> 00:39:19,465
Then plainly know my heart's dear love is set

387
00:39:19,466 --> 00:39:21,744
on the fair daughter of rich Capulet.

388
00:39:25,072 --> 00:39:27,623
As mine on hers, so hers is set on mine.

389
00:39:28,069 --> 00:39:29,748
And all combined.

390
00:39:31,631 --> 00:39:34,120
By holy marriage.

391
00:39:36,120 --> 00:39:37,802
Holy Saint Francis,

392
00:39:39,426 --> 00:39:41,603
What a change is here!

393
00:39:41,604 --> 00:39:43,932
- I pray thee, chide not...
- But come,

394
00:39:43,933 --> 00:39:46,074
young waverer, come,

395
00:39:46,075 --> 00:39:48,075
go with me,

396
00:39:48,076 --> 00:39:50,409
in one respect I'll thy assistant be.

397
00:39:50,410 --> 00:39:54,914
For this alliance may so happy prove,
to turn your households' rancour to pure love.

398
00:39:54,915 --> 00:39:56,915
O, let us hence.

399
00:39:56,916 --> 00:39:59,913
- I stand on sudden haste.
- Wisely and slowly.

400
00:40:00,914 --> 00:40:03,245
They stumble that run fast.

401
00:40:24,077 --> 00:40:25,926
Where the devil should this Romeo be?

402
00:40:27,138 --> 00:40:29,600
Came he not home tonight?

403
00:40:33,741 --> 00:40:35,532
Came he not home tonight?

404
00:40:36,532 --> 00:40:40,168
No, he didn't come home.

405
00:40:41,169 --> 00:40:44,189
Where the devil should this Romeo be?

406
00:40:45,370 --> 00:40:47,950
- Hie Romeo!
- Signior Romeo!

407
00:40:48,950 --> 00:40:50,970
Bonjour!

408
00:40:50,970 --> 00:40:52,871
French salutation for your French slop.

409
00:40:54,656 --> 00:40:57,192
You gave us the counterfeit fairly last night.

410
00:40:57,192 --> 00:40:59,142
Good morrow to you Mercutio, Benvolio.

411
00:41:00,142 --> 00:41:02,333
What counterfeit did I give you?

412
00:41:02,333 --> 00:41:04,436
The slip, sir.

413
00:41:04,437 --> 00:41:07,437
- The slip; can you not conceive?
- Pardon, good Mercutio.

414
00:41:07,438 --> 00:41:09,438
My business was great.

415
00:41:10,318 --> 00:41:12,232
And in such a case as mine a man may strain courtesy.

416
00:41:12,588 --> 00:41:17,200
That's as much as to say, such a case as yours
constrains a man to bow in the hams.

417
00:41:17,201 --> 00:41:19,301
Meaning, to court'sy?

418
00:41:19,302 --> 00:41:21,302
- Thou hast most kindly hit it!
- A most courteous exposition.

419
00:41:22,303 --> 00:41:24,303
Nay,

420
00:41:24,304 --> 00:41:26,304
I am the very pink of courtesy.

421
00:41:26,305 --> 00:41:28,305
Pink for flower?

422
00:41:29,386 --> 00:41:32,878
- Right.
- Why, then is my pump well flowered.

423
00:41:32,879 --> 00:41:36,638
Why, is not this better now than groaning for love?

424
00:41:38,730 --> 00:41:41,820
Now art thou sociable.

425
00:41:41,821 --> 00:41:44,030
Now art thou Romeo.

426
00:41:44,031 --> 00:41:46,031
Now art thou what thou art,

427
00:41:47,295 --> 00:41:49,010
by art as well as by nature.

428
00:41:49,011 --> 00:41:51,009
God ye good morning, gentlemen.

429
00:41:51,010 --> 00:41:54,275
God ye good evening, fair gentlewoman.

430
00:41:54,276 --> 00:41:56,276
- Is it greasy?
- Just no less.

431
00:41:56,318 --> 00:42:00,103
For the bawdy hand of the dial
is now upon the prick of noon.

432
00:42:00,185 --> 00:42:03,042
Out upon you! What a man are you!

433
00:42:03,043 --> 00:42:06,153
One, good nurse, that
God has made for himself to mar.

434
00:42:06,037 --> 00:42:09,017
By my troth, it is well said:

435
00:42:09,018 --> 00:42:11,018
'for himself to mar,' quoth a?

436
00:42:15,981 --> 00:42:19,006
Sir, I desire some confidence with you.

437
00:42:21,714 --> 00:42:23,745
She will invite him to some supper.

438
00:42:24,615 --> 00:42:26,796
Romeo, will you come?
We'll to dinner, thither.

439
00:42:26,797 --> 00:42:29,070
I will follow you.

440
00:42:30,071 --> 00:42:32,246
Farewell, ancient lady.

441
00:42:33,716 --> 00:42:36,110
Lady.

442
00:42:36,110 --> 00:42:38,444
Lady, lady!

443
00:42:39,459 --> 00:42:42,953
I pray you, sir, what saucy merchant was this,
that was so full of his ropery?

444
00:42:42,954 --> 00:42:46,356
A gentleman, nurse, that loves to hear himself talk,

445
00:42:46,357 --> 00:42:48,357
and will speak more in a minute
than he will stand to in a month.

446
00:42:48,358 --> 00:42:51,358
An a' speak any thing against me,
I'll take him down!

447
00:42:51,717 --> 00:42:54,365
An a' were lustier than he is, and twenty such Jacks!

448
00:42:54,366 --> 00:42:58,366
And if I cannot, I'll find those that shall.
Scurvy knave!

449
00:43:03,833 --> 00:43:05,543
Pray you, sir, a word.

450
00:43:10,715 --> 00:43:12,927
My...

451
00:43:12,928 --> 00:43:16,429
young lady bade me inquire you out.

452
00:43:16,430 --> 00:43:19,995
And what she bade me say,
I will keep to myself, but...

453
00:43:20,996 --> 00:43:22,656
first let me say, if you...

454
00:43:22,800 --> 00:43:25,842
should lead her into
a fool's paradise, as they say,

455
00:43:28,842 --> 00:43:32,260
it were a very gross kind of behavior,

456
00:43:32,261 --> 00:43:34,261
as they say.

457
00:43:35,261 --> 00:43:38,261
For the gentlewoman is young; and, therefore,
if you should deal double with her,

458
00:43:38,262 --> 00:43:42,262
truly it were an ill thing to be offered
to any gentlewoman, and very weak dealing.

459
00:43:42,263 --> 00:43:46,263
Bid her devise some means
to come to shrift this afternoon.

460
00:43:46,264 --> 00:43:49,264
And there she shall at Friar Laurence' cell

461
00:43:50,265 --> 00:43:52,265
be shrived and married.

462
00:43:55,266 --> 00:43:57,266
This afternoon?

463
00:43:58,267 --> 00:44:00,267
Well,

464
00:44:01,268 --> 00:44:03,268
she shall be there.

465
00:44:04,269 --> 00:44:08,259
Farewell.
Be trusty, and I'll award thy pains.

466
00:44:08,260 --> 00:44:09,907
God in heaven bless thee!

467
00:44:10,907 --> 00:44:13,037
Farewell.
Commend me to thy mistress.

468
00:44:13,822 --> 00:44:14,795
Ay, a thousand times.

469
00:44:15,827 --> 00:44:18,324
Cadets Singleton, Madsen!

470
00:44:18,423 --> 00:44:20,431
Hi, Ken, Carlos.

471
00:44:21,431 --> 00:44:24,000
Too busy to workout today, cadets?

472
00:44:24,000 --> 00:44:26,070
Come on!

473
00:44:26,070 --> 00:44:28,835
Since you didn't get your exercise
in this period why don't you both drop and give me 40.

474
00:44:28,836 --> 00:44:30,882
- Yes, sir!
- Forty?

475
00:44:30,882 --> 00:44:33,928
- I can't, I have to...
- Fifty for you, Omar!

476
00:44:34,928 --> 00:44:36,637
Shit!

477
00:44:37,637 --> 00:44:40,088
And when you're done, cadet Madsen,

478
00:44:40,088 --> 00:44:42,941
give me 5 tours around the track.

479
00:44:42,941 --> 00:44:47,858
Physical fitness is an important component
of cadet's education and training.

480
00:44:47,859 --> 00:44:50,385
Yes, sir!

481
00:44:59,834 --> 00:45:02,906
The clock struck nine when I did send the nurse.

482
00:45:02,906 --> 00:45:06,248
In half an hour she promised to return.

483
00:45:07,249 --> 00:45:10,311
Now is the sun upon the highmost hill

484
00:45:10,312 --> 00:45:13,312
of this day's journey, and from nine till twelve

485
00:45:13,313 --> 00:45:17,153
Is three long hours, yet she is not come.

486
00:45:19,806 --> 00:45:23,087
O honey nurse, what news?

487
00:45:24,186 --> 00:45:26,138
Hast thou met with him?

488
00:45:27,735 --> 00:45:29,884
O Lord, why look'st thou sad?

489
00:45:30,502 --> 00:45:34,956
I am a-weary, give me leave awhile.
Fie, how my bones ache!

490
00:45:35,368 --> 00:45:36,944
I would...
I would thou hadst my bones,

491
00:45:36,945 --> 00:45:39,387
and I thy news.

492
00:45:39,388 --> 00:45:41,546
Speak! Speak!

493
00:45:41,547 --> 00:45:44,547
What haste? Can you not stay awhile?
Do you not see that I am out of breath?

494
00:45:45,346 --> 00:45:50,124
How art thou out of breath, when thou hast breath
to say to me that thou art out of breath?

495
00:45:50,965 --> 00:45:53,696
- Is thy news good, or bad? Answer to that.
- Lord, how my head aches!

496
00:45:54,266 --> 00:45:56,143
What a head have I !

497
00:45:57,221 --> 00:45:59,156
It beats as it would fall in twenty pieces.

498
00:45:59,156 --> 00:46:01,037
O, my back!

499
00:46:02,022 --> 00:46:03,987
Now other side...

500
00:46:03,988 --> 00:46:05,988
O, my back, my back!

501
00:46:06,778 --> 00:46:10,879
Beshrew your heart for sending me about,
to catch my death with jaunting up and down!

502
00:46:11,874 --> 00:46:13,761
I am sorry that thou art not well.

503
00:46:14,762 --> 00:46:18,422
Sweet, sweet, sweet nurse,

504
00:46:18,423 --> 00:46:20,458
tell me,

505
00:46:21,748 --> 00:46:24,179
what says my love?

506
00:46:24,545 --> 00:46:26,783
What says he of our marriage?

507
00:46:27,784 --> 00:46:31,784
Your love says, like an honest gentleman,

508
00:46:31,785 --> 00:46:35,785
and a courteous, and a kind, and a handsome,,

509
00:46:36,786 --> 00:46:38,786
and, I warrant, a virtuous.

510
00:46:40,714 --> 00:46:42,897
Where is your mother?

511
00:46:43,267 --> 00:46:44,724
Where is my mother!

512
00:46:45,724 --> 00:46:47,989
Where should she be? How oddly thou repliest:

513
00:46:47,990 --> 00:46:49,990
'Your love says, like an honest gentleman,
Where is your mother?'

514
00:46:49,999 --> 00:46:51,681
O God's lady dear!
Are you so hot?

515
00:46:52,891 --> 00:46:55,865
Is this the poultice for my aching bones!

516
00:46:56,904 --> 00:46:59,034
Henceforward do your messages yourself!

517
00:46:59,035 --> 00:47:02,033
Here's such a fourth come, what says Romeo?

518
00:47:05,034 --> 00:47:06,982
Have you got leave to go to shrift today?

519
00:47:09,388 --> 00:47:11,488
I have.

520
00:47:13,471 --> 00:47:15,117
Then hie you hence to Friar Laurence' cell.

521
00:47:16,117 --> 00:47:18,850
There stays a husband to make you a wife.

522
00:47:18,851 --> 00:47:22,260
Go! I'll to dinner.

523
00:47:22,261 --> 00:47:24,760
Hie you to the cell!

524
00:47:26,054 --> 00:47:28,862
Hie to high fortune! Honest nurse.

525
00:47:28,863 --> 00:47:31,349
Farewell.

526
00:47:35,821 --> 00:47:38,551
Hey you up for some hoops then?

527
00:47:56,622 --> 00:47:58,926
How long is it now
to Lammas-tide?

528
00:47:59,497 --> 00:48:00,771
A fortnight and odd days.

529
00:48:00,780 --> 00:48:03,049
Come Lammas-eve at night shall she be fourteen.

530
00:48:03,050 --> 00:48:05,690
As I said, I remember it well

531
00:48:05,691 --> 00:48:07,645
'Tis since the earthquake now

532
00:48:07,646 --> 00:48:10,211
eleven years and she was wean'd.
I never shall forget it,

533
00:48:10,212 --> 00:48:12,284
of all the days  upon that year.

534
00:48:12,285 --> 00:48:15,285
Thou wast the prettiest babe that e'er I nursed.

535
00:48:15,286 --> 00:48:17,286
An I shall live to see thee married once,

536
00:48:17,287 --> 00:48:19,287
I have my wish.

537
00:48:19,288 --> 00:48:21,288
I'm sorry.

538
00:48:24,415 --> 00:48:25,610
So smile the heavens upon this holy act,

539
00:48:25,610 --> 00:48:28,940
that after hours with sorrow chide us not!

540
00:48:32,780 --> 00:48:36,144
But come what sorrow can
it cannot countervail the exchange of joy

541
00:48:36,145 --> 00:48:39,145
that one short minute gives me in her sight.

542
00:48:40,146 --> 00:48:42,146
Then love-devouring death do what he dare,

543
00:48:42,147 --> 00:48:44,147
it is enough I may but call her mine.

544
00:48:48,148 --> 00:48:50,148
Here comes the lady.

545
00:49:08,569 --> 00:49:10,618
Juliet,

546
00:49:10,612 --> 00:49:13,520
if the measure of thy joy
be heap'd like mine...

547
00:49:13,521 --> 00:49:16,521
But my true love is grown to such excess,

548
00:49:17,993 --> 00:49:20,477
I cannot sum up sum of...

549
00:49:20,478 --> 00:49:22,476
half my wealth.

550
00:49:22,477 --> 00:49:24,302
Come.

551
00:49:31,547 --> 00:49:34,402
Go.

552
00:49:34,403 --> 00:49:36,401
Incorporate two in one.

553
00:49:48,449 --> 00:49:51,183
Thou art like one of those fellows that
when he enters the confines of a tavern

554
00:49:51,184 --> 00:49:53,183
claps me his sword upon the table and says:

555
00:49:53,184 --> 00:49:55,482
'God send me no need of thee!'

556
00:49:55,482 --> 00:49:58,855
and by the end of the second cup draws
it on the drawer, when indeed there is no need.

557
00:50:01,393 --> 00:50:03,665
Am I like such a fellow?

558
00:50:03,666 --> 00:50:06,666
Thou! Why, thou wilt quarrel with a man

559
00:50:06,667 --> 00:50:09,169
that hath a hair more or a hair less,
in his beard, than thou hast.

560
00:50:09,170 --> 00:50:12,677
Thou wilt quarrel with a man for cracking nuts,
having no other reason

561
00:50:12,678 --> 00:50:15,170
but because thou hast hazel eyes.

562
00:50:14,920 --> 00:50:18,298
Didst thou not fall out with a tailor for wearing
his new doublet before Easter?

563
00:50:18,299 --> 00:50:22,297
With another, for tying his new shoes with old riband?

564
00:50:27,159 --> 00:50:28,823
I pray thee, let's retire.

565
00:50:28,823 --> 00:50:32,455
- The day is hot, we shall not escape abroad.
- By my heel, I care not.

566
00:50:40,840 --> 00:50:42,521
Gentlemen, a word with one of you.

567
00:50:42,522 --> 00:50:44,522
And but one word with one of us?

568
00:50:44,523 --> 00:50:47,523
Couple it with something;
make it a word and a blow.

569
00:50:49,363 --> 00:50:52,486
You shall find me apt enough to that, sir,
an you will give me occasion.

570
00:50:52,870 --> 00:50:55,533
Could you not take some occasion without giving?

571
00:50:57,751 --> 00:50:59,366
Thou consort'st with Romeo!

572
00:51:00,487 --> 00:51:01,547
Consort!

573
00:51:04,548 --> 00:51:06,548
What, dost thou make us minstrels?

574
00:51:06,549 --> 00:51:09,206
Thou make minstrels of us,
look to hear nothing but discords.

575
00:51:09,207 --> 00:51:10,954
We talk here in the public haunt of men.

576
00:51:12,114 --> 00:51:13,667
Here all eyes gaze on us.

577
00:51:13,668 --> 00:51:15,668
Men's eyes were made to look, and let them gaze.

578
00:51:15,669 --> 00:51:17,669
I will not budge for no man's pleasure, I.

579
00:51:17,670 --> 00:51:20,959
Well, peace be with you, sir:
here comes my man.

580
00:51:20,960 --> 00:51:22,587
But I'll be hanged, sir, if he wear your livery.

581
00:51:23,215 --> 00:51:26,424
Romeo, the hate I bear thee can afford
No better term than this:

582
00:51:26,425 --> 00:51:28,275
Thou art a villain!

583
00:51:29,043 --> 00:51:32,710
Tybalt, the reason that I have to love thee
Doth much excuse the appertaining rage

584
00:51:32,711 --> 00:51:34,863
to such a greeting: villain am I none.

585
00:51:34,864 --> 00:51:38,424
Therefore farewell; I see thou know'st me not.

586
00:51:39,971 --> 00:51:43,511
Boy, this shall not excuse the injuries
that thou hast done me.

587
00:51:44,512 --> 00:51:46,512
Therefore

588
00:51:46,513 --> 00:51:48,513
turn and draw.

589
00:51:50,514 --> 00:51:52,754
I do protest, I never injured thee.

590
00:51:52,755 --> 00:51:54,754
O calm,

591
00:51:54,755 --> 00:51:57,979
dishonourable, vile submission!

592
00:51:58,980 --> 00:52:00,980
Tybalt!

593
00:52:00,981 --> 00:52:02,981
You rat-catcher/

594
00:52:05,356 --> 00:52:07,394
Will you walk?

595
00:52:07,395 --> 00:52:09,395
What wouldst thou have with me?

596
00:52:10,590 --> 00:52:12,561
Good king of cats,

597
00:52:12,562 --> 00:52:14,562
nothing but one of your nine lives.

598
00:52:15,563 --> 00:52:17,563
that I mean to make bold withal,

599
00:52:17,564 --> 00:52:21,564
and as you shall use me hereafter,
drybeat the rest of the eight.

600
00:52:25,790 --> 00:52:28,909
Will you pluck your sword out
of his pitcher by the ears?

601
00:52:28,910 --> 00:52:31,910
Make haste, lest mine be about your ears ere it be out.

602
00:52:31,917 --> 00:52:33,668
I am for you.

603
00:52:33,669 --> 00:52:35,637
Gentle Mercutio, put thy rapier up.

604
00:52:35,638 --> 00:52:37,876
Draw, Benvolio; beat down their weapons.

605
00:52:37,536 --> 00:52:42,256
Gentlemen, the prince expressly hath
Forbidden bandying in Verona streets.

606
00:52:42,534 --> 00:52:44,700
Hold, Tybalt!

607
00:52:44,524 --> 00:52:47,211
Good Mercutio!

608
00:52:53,384 --> 00:52:54,735
- Away!
- Tybalt!

609
00:53:01,823 --> 00:53:04,522
- Is he gone, and hath nothing?
- What, art thou hurt?

610
00:53:04,523 --> 00:53:06,523
Ay, ay, a scratch, a scratch.

611
00:53:07,436 --> 00:53:09,067
Marry, 'tis enough.

612
00:53:09,068 --> 00:53:10,885
Courage, man; the hurt cannot be much.

613
00:53:10,886 --> 00:53:16,183
No, 'tis not so deep as a well,
nor so wide as a church-door,

614
00:53:16,184 --> 00:53:18,184
but  marry 'tis enough.

615
00:53:19,647 --> 00:53:23,066
Ask for me to-morrow,
and you shall find me a grave man.

616
00:53:24,066 --> 00:53:26,997
I am peppered, I warrant, for this world.

617
00:53:33,198 --> 00:53:35,694
A plague on both your houses!

618
00:53:38,694 --> 00:53:40,907
Why the devil came you between us?

619
00:53:41,908 --> 00:53:43,908
I was hurt under your arm.

620
00:53:43,909 --> 00:53:45,909
I thought all for the best.

621
00:53:50,910 --> 00:53:53,910
Help me, Benvolio, or I shall faint.

622
00:54:02,176 --> 00:54:03,810
A plague on both your houses!

623
00:54:15,810 --> 00:54:18,745
They have made worms' meat of me.

624
00:54:27,259 --> 00:54:28,982
O sweet Juliet,

625
00:54:29,982 --> 00:54:34,263
Thy beauty hath made me effeminate

626
00:54:34,263 --> 00:54:37,483
and in my temper soften'd valour's steel!

627
00:54:38,483 --> 00:54:40,068
Romeo!

628
00:54:42,361 --> 00:54:47,425
This day's black fate on more days doth depend;
This but begins the woe, others must end.

629
00:54:48,426 --> 00:54:50,271
Here comes the furious Tybalt back again.

630
00:54:50,271 --> 00:54:52,729
And fire-eyed fury be my conduct now!

631
00:54:52,729 --> 00:54:57,096
Tybalt, take the villain back again,
that late thou gavest me.

632
00:54:57,097 --> 00:55:02,182
For Mercutio's soul Is but a little way above our heads,
staying for thine to keep him company.

633
00:55:02,183 --> 00:55:04,512
Either thou, or I, or both, must go with him.

634
00:55:05,083 --> 00:55:08,630
Thou, wretched boy, that didst consort him here,
shalt with him hence!

635
00:55:08,631 --> 00:55:10,748
This shall determine that.

636
00:55:28,748 --> 00:55:31,515
Romeo, away, be gone!

637
00:55:32,515 --> 00:55:36,911
Stand not amazed: the prince will doom thee death,
if thou art taken!

638
00:55:36,912 --> 00:55:39,396
Be gone, away!

639
00:55:53,606 --> 00:55:55,798
O, I am fortune's fool!

640
00:55:57,798 --> 00:56:00,432
Where are the vile beginners of this fray?

641
00:56:01,432 --> 00:56:03,089
Benvolio?

642
00:56:03,089 --> 00:56:06,721
O noble prince, I can discover all
the unlucky manage of this fatal brawl.

643
00:56:08,598 --> 00:56:12,827
There lies Tybalt, slain by young Romeo,

644
00:56:14,229 --> 00:56:16,191
That slew thy kinsman, brave Mercutio.

645
00:56:16,208 --> 00:56:17,659
Prince, as thou art true.

646
00:56:17,660 --> 00:56:21,231
For blood of ours, shed blood of Montague!
I beg for justice,

647
00:56:21,232 --> 00:56:22,993
which thou, prince, must give.

648
00:56:23,044 --> 00:56:25,552
Romeo slew Tybalt, Romeo must not live.

649
00:56:26,492 --> 00:56:28,470
Romeo slew him, he slew Mercutio.

650
00:56:28,471 --> 00:56:31,128
Who now the price of his dear blood doth owe?

651
00:56:31,129 --> 00:56:33,139
Not Romeo, prince!

652
00:56:34,139 --> 00:56:35,654
He was Mercutio's friend.

653
00:56:36,259 --> 00:56:39,137
His fault concludes but what the law should end,
the life of Tybalt.

654
00:56:39,138 --> 00:56:42,402
And for that offence
immediately we do exile him hence.

655
00:56:43,806 --> 00:56:45,926
I will be deaf to pleading or excuses;

656
00:56:45,927 --> 00:56:50,532
nor tears nor prayers shall purchase out abuses:
therefore use none.

657
00:56:51,532 --> 00:56:58,230
Let Romeo hence in haste,
else, when he's found, that hour is his last.

658
00:57:04,978 --> 00:57:09,140
Spread thy close curtain, love-performing night,

659
00:57:11,088 --> 00:57:13,680
that runaway's eyes may wink ,

660
00:57:13,680 --> 00:57:16,298
and Romeo leap to these arms,

661
00:57:16,299 --> 00:57:18,299
untalk'd of and unseen.

662
00:57:24,988 --> 00:57:27,543
Come, night; come, Romeo,

663
00:57:28,544 --> 00:57:31,132
come, thou day in night,

664
00:57:32,304 --> 00:57:35,902
for thou wilt lie upon the wings of night

665
00:57:35,903 --> 00:57:37,851
whiter than new snow on a raven's back!

666
00:57:48,290 --> 00:57:50,217
Why dost thou wring thy hands?

667
00:57:51,045 --> 00:57:52,987
He's dead, he's dead!

668
00:57:54,488 --> 00:57:57,178
Alack the day! He's gone, he's dead!

669
00:58:00,360 --> 00:58:02,202
He's dead!

670
00:58:02,484 --> 00:58:04,424
Hath Romeo slain himself?

671
00:58:04,425 --> 00:58:08,345
I saw the wound, here on his manly breast,
all bedaub'd in blood.

672
00:58:08,346 --> 00:58:09,838
I swounded at the sight.

673
00:58:09,839 --> 00:58:12,839
O, break, my heart!
Poor bankrupt, break at once...

674
00:58:12,840 --> 00:58:14,840
O Tybalt, Tybalt.

675
00:58:15,931 --> 00:58:19,106
What storm is this that blows so contrary?
Is Romeo slaughter'd, and is Tybalt dead?

676
00:58:19,107 --> 00:58:22,438
Tybalt is gone,

677
00:58:22,439 --> 00:58:24,439
and Romeo banished.

678
00:58:25,624 --> 00:58:28,492
O God!

679
00:58:28,658 --> 00:58:30,170
Did Romeo's hand shed Tybalt's blood?

680
00:58:30,171 --> 00:58:32,171
It did.

681
00:58:32,368 --> 00:58:34,204
Alas the day, it did!

682
00:58:34,959 --> 00:58:38,757
There's no trust, no faith, no honesty.
Shame come to Romeo!

683
00:58:38,758 --> 00:58:41,756
Blister'd be thy tongue for such a wish!

684
00:58:41,757 --> 00:58:44,225
He was not born to shame.

685
00:58:44,226 --> 00:58:47,058
'Tybalt is dead, and Romeo - banished'.

686
00:58:48,059 --> 00:58:51,971
That 'banished,' that one word 'banished,'
hath slain ten thousand Tybalts.

687
00:58:53,972 --> 00:58:59,521
There is no end, no limit, measure, bound,
in that word's death.

688
00:59:00,780 --> 00:59:03,382
No words can that woe sound.

689
00:59:05,648 --> 00:59:08,590
Go! Find Romeo.

690
00:59:08,590 --> 00:59:12,545
Give this ring to my true knight,
and bid him come to take his last farewell.

691
00:59:42,545 --> 00:59:45,094
What news?

692
00:59:45,094 --> 00:59:47,339
I bring thee tidings of the prince's doom.

693
00:59:47,340 --> 00:59:49,340
What less than dooms-day is the prince's doom?

694
00:59:49,341 --> 00:59:52,341
A gentler judgment vanish'd from his lips,
not body's death,

695
00:59:53,342 --> 00:59:55,342
but body's banishment.

696
00:59:57,343 --> 00:59:59,343
Ha, banishment!

697
00:59:59,344 --> 01:00:01,344
Be merciful, say 'death'!

698
01:00:01,587 --> 01:00:04,587
This is dear mercy, and thou seest it not.

699
01:00:04,588 --> 01:00:08,357
'Tis torture, and not mercy: heaven is here,
where Juliet lives.

700
01:00:08,358 --> 01:00:09,790
Thou fond mad man, hear me but speak.

701
01:00:09,791 --> 01:00:11,789
O, thou wilt speak again of banishment.

702
01:00:11,790 --> 01:00:14,718
I'll give thee armour to keep off that word.

703
01:00:14,718 --> 01:00:19,179
Adversity's sweet milk, philosophy,
to comfort thee, though thou art banished.

704
01:00:19,180 --> 01:00:21,386
Hang up philosophy!

705
01:00:21,387 --> 01:00:23,386
Unless philosophy can make a Juliet,
it helps not.

706
01:00:23,387 --> 01:00:25,079
O, then I see that madmen have no ears.

707
01:00:25,080 --> 01:00:28,080
How should they, when that wise men have no eyes?

708
01:00:28,081 --> 01:00:31,081
Thou canst not speak of that thou dost not feel.

709
01:00:32,082 --> 01:00:34,082
Romeo, hide thyself.

710
01:00:34,083 --> 01:00:36,083
Who knocks? Whence come you?

711
01:00:36,084 --> 01:00:38,084
What's your will?

712
01:00:41,576 --> 01:00:46,065
O, tell me, where's Romeo?

713
01:00:46,066 --> 01:00:47,911
There on the ground.

714
01:00:50,912 --> 01:00:52,912
Stand up.

715
01:00:52,913 --> 01:00:54,702
Stand up!

716
01:00:56,703 --> 01:00:58,915
For Juliet's sake,

717
01:00:59,090 --> 01:01:01,351
for her sake, rise and stand.

718
01:01:06,067 --> 01:01:10,196
Spakest thou of Juliet? How is it with her?

719
01:01:10,867 --> 01:01:14,436
What says my conceal'd lady to our cancell'd love?

720
01:01:14,437 --> 01:01:16,437
O, she says nothing.

721
01:01:16,448 --> 01:01:20,611
And now falls on her bed; and then starts up,
and then on Romeo cries, and then down falls again.

722
01:01:20,612 --> 01:01:22,828
As if that name did murder her!

723
01:01:22,829 --> 01:01:25,371
What, rouse thee, man!

724
01:01:27,973 --> 01:01:29,973
Man!

725
01:01:29,974 --> 01:01:32,968
A pack of blessings lights up upon thy back.

726
01:01:32,969 --> 01:01:34,969
Happiness courts thee in her best array.

727
01:01:34,970 --> 01:01:39,970
But, like a misbehaved and sullen wench,
thou pout'st upon thy fortune and thy love.

728
01:01:40,968 --> 01:01:43,334
Take heed, take heed,

729
01:01:45,335 --> 01:01:47,335
for such die miserable.

730
01:01:49,336 --> 01:01:52,336
Go, get thee to thy love.

731
01:02:07,439 --> 01:02:10,126
I'll tell my lady you will come.

732
01:02:17,127 --> 01:02:19,127
Here, sir,

733
01:02:21,202 --> 01:02:23,333
a ring she bid me give you.

734
01:02:24,334 --> 01:02:27,334
Hie you, make haste, for it grows very late.

735
01:02:29,335 --> 01:02:32,335
How well my comfort is revived by this!

736
01:02:35,336 --> 01:02:38,336
Go hence.
Farewell; good night.

737
01:02:44,710 --> 01:02:47,506
But that a joy past joy calls out on me,

738
01:02:48,132 --> 01:02:51,188
it were a grief, so brief to part with thee.

739
01:04:30,188 --> 01:04:32,384
Wilt thou be gone?

740
01:04:32,455 --> 01:04:33,778
It is not yet near day.

741
01:04:35,779 --> 01:04:39,777
It was the nightingale, and not the lark,
that pierced the fearful hollow of thine ear.

742
01:04:39,778 --> 01:04:42,150
It was the lark, the herald of the morn,
no nightingale.

743
01:04:42,151 --> 01:04:46,151
Look, love, what envious streaks
do lace the severing clouds in yonder east.

744
01:04:46,152 --> 01:04:49,152
I must be gone and live, or stay and die.

745
01:04:49,153 --> 01:04:51,153
Yon light is not day-light, I know it, I.

746
01:04:51,154 --> 01:04:57,154
It is some meteor that the sun exhales,
to be to thee this night a torch-bearer.

747
01:04:58,155 --> 01:05:00,155
Therefore stay yet.

748
01:05:06,156 --> 01:05:08,156
Thou need'st not to be gone.

749
01:05:14,454 --> 01:05:16,019
Let me be taken,

750
01:05:16,020 --> 01:05:18,084
let me be put to death.

751
01:05:18,085 --> 01:05:20,580
I am content, so thou wilt have it so.

752
01:05:24,552 --> 01:05:28,287
I have more care to stay than will to go:
Come, death, and welcome!

753
01:05:28,288 --> 01:05:30,288
Juliet wills it so.

754
01:05:34,289 --> 01:05:36,289
Madam!

755
01:05:39,800 --> 01:05:42,028
Then, window, let day in,

756
01:05:42,029 --> 01:05:44,029
and let life out.

757
01:05:46,305 --> 01:05:50,053
Farewell! One kiss, and I'll descend.

758
01:05:52,806 --> 01:05:55,165
Art thou gone so? Love,

759
01:05:55,332 --> 01:05:58,880
lord, ay, husband, friend!

760
01:06:01,480 --> 01:06:04,458
O think'st thou we shall ever meet again?

761
01:06:04,459 --> 01:06:06,459
I doubt it not.

762
01:06:06,617 --> 01:06:11,858
And all these woes shall serve
for sweet discourses in our time to come.

763
01:06:32,916 --> 01:06:37,147
O fortune, fortune! All men call thee fickle.

764
01:06:41,139 --> 01:06:42,937
Be fickle, fortune,

765
01:06:43,959 --> 01:06:47,677
for then, I hope, thou wilt not keep him long,

766
01:06:47,678 --> 01:06:49,678
but send him back.

767
01:06:56,540 --> 01:06:59,473
But now, my lord Capulet, what say you to my suit?

768
01:06:59,474 --> 01:07:03,474
But saying o'er what I have said before:
my child is yet a stranger in this world.

769
01:07:03,475 --> 01:07:06,169
She hath not seen the change of fourteen years.

770
01:07:06,170 --> 01:07:09,793
Let two more summers wither in their pride,
ere we may think her ripe to be a bride.

771
01:07:09,794 --> 01:07:11,609
Younger than she are happy mothers made.

772
01:07:11,610 --> 01:07:14,610
And too soon marr'd are those so early made.

773
01:07:14,609 --> 01:07:18,359
The earth hath swallow'd all my hopes but she,

774
01:07:20,360 --> 01:07:22,360
She is the hopeful lady of my earth.

775
01:07:23,361 --> 01:07:26,361
But woo her, get her heart.

776
01:07:26,362 --> 01:07:30,362
My will to her consent is but a part;
and she agree.

777
01:07:34,363 --> 01:07:36,358
Lady Capulet.

778
01:07:38,359 --> 01:07:41,206
Nurse, where's my daughter? Call her forth to me.

779
01:07:44,525 --> 01:07:47,173
Are you up?

780
01:07:48,828 --> 01:07:50,960
Who is't that calls?

781
01:07:52,960 --> 01:07:54,928
Why, how now?

782
01:07:57,470 --> 01:07:58,960
I am not well.

783
01:08:01,960 --> 01:08:04,643
Evermore weeping for Tybalt's death?

784
01:08:06,799 --> 01:08:10,402
What, wilt thou wash him from his grave with tears?

785
01:08:11,249 --> 01:08:13,826
And if thou couldst, thou couldst not make him live.

786
01:08:13,827 --> 01:08:16,221
Therefore, have done.

787
01:08:16,222 --> 01:08:20,861
Some grief shows much of love;
but much of grief shows still some want of wit.

788
01:08:21,862 --> 01:08:23,862
Yet let me weep for such a feeling loss.

789
01:08:23,863 --> 01:08:27,863
So shall you feel the loss, but not the friend
which you weep for.

790
01:08:27,864 --> 01:08:30,864
Feeling so the loss, cannot choose
but ever weep the friend/

791
01:08:30,865 --> 01:08:32,860
But now

792
01:08:32,861 --> 01:08:35,193
I'll tell thee joyful tidings.

793
01:08:36,193 --> 01:08:39,261
And joy comes well in such a needy time.

794
01:08:40,261 --> 01:08:42,228
What are they?

795
01:08:42,228 --> 01:08:44,710
Well, well, thou hast a careful father, child.

796
01:08:44,711 --> 01:08:50,308
One who, to put thee from thy heaviness,
hath sorted out a sudden day of joy,

797
01:08:50,309 --> 01:08:53,651
that thou expect'st not nor I look'd not for.

798
01:08:54,302 --> 01:08:57,473
In happy time, what day is that?

799
01:08:58,473 --> 01:08:59,603
Early next Thursday morning,

800
01:08:59,603 --> 01:09:02,662
the gallant, young and noble gentleman,
the County Paris, at Saint Peter's Church,

801
01:09:02,663 --> 01:09:05,041
shall happily make thee there a joyful bride.

802
01:09:05,041 --> 01:09:10,593
Now, by Saint Peter's Church and Peter too,
he shall not make me there a joyful bride.

803
01:09:11,594 --> 01:09:14,554
I pray you, tell my lord and father, madam,
I will not marry yet.

804
01:09:14,555 --> 01:09:17,555
And, when I do, it shall be Romeo!

805
01:09:18,652 --> 01:09:22,745
Here comes your father; tell him so yourself,
and see how he will take it at your hands.

806
01:09:23,746 --> 01:09:25,746
How now, wife?

807
01:09:32,747 --> 01:09:36,747
- Have you deliver'd to her our decree?
- Ay, sir; but she will none.

808
01:09:36,748 --> 01:09:38,748
I would the fool were married to her grave!

809
01:09:39,749 --> 01:09:41,749
Is she not proud?

810
01:09:42,750 --> 01:09:48,502
Unworthy as she is, that we have wrought
so worthy a gentleman to be her bride?

811
01:09:48,503 --> 01:09:51,569
Not proud, you have; but thankful, that you have.

812
01:09:51,570 --> 01:09:54,570
Proud can I never be of what I hate.

813
01:09:54,571 --> 01:09:58,571
But thankful even for hate, that is meant love.

814
01:09:59,572 --> 01:10:01,572
How?

815
01:10:02,573 --> 01:10:04,573
How now, how now, how?

816
01:10:07,574 --> 01:10:10,574
Chop-logic! What is this?

817
01:10:10,575 --> 01:10:15,575
'Proud,' and 'I thank you,' and 'I thank you not;'
and yet 'not proud'.

818
01:10:17,577 --> 01:10:20,373
Mistress minion, you,

819
01:10:21,374 --> 01:10:23,823
thank me no thankings, nor, proud me no prouds,

820
01:10:23,824 --> 01:10:27,041
but fettle your fine joints 'gainst Thursday next,
to Saint Peter's Church,

821
01:10:27,042 --> 01:10:31,315
or I will drag thee on a hurdle thither.

822
01:10:33,316 --> 01:10:38,882
Good father, I beseech you on my knees,
hear me with patience but to speak a word.

823
01:10:38,883 --> 01:10:40,860
Hang thee,

824
01:10:40,861 --> 01:10:42,683
young baggage!

825
01:10:42,683 --> 01:10:45,351
Disobedient wretch!

826
01:10:46,352 --> 01:10:48,968
Speak not, reply not,

827
01:10:50,969 --> 01:10:52,514
do not answer me.

828
01:10:59,230 --> 01:11:00,781
My fingers itch.

829
01:11:13,782 --> 01:11:15,782
O, sweet my mother, cast me not away!

830
01:11:15,783 --> 01:11:17,783
Talk not to me, for I'll not speak a word.

831
01:11:17,784 --> 01:11:20,784
Do as thou wilt, for I have done with thee!

832
01:11:30,781 --> 01:11:32,748
What say'st thou?

833
01:11:33,748 --> 01:11:37,153
Hast thou not a word of joy?
Some comfort, nurse.

834
01:11:41,531 --> 01:11:43,819
Here it is.

835
01:11:44,820 --> 01:11:46,820
Romeo is banish'd.

836
01:11:47,794 --> 01:11:50,919
And all the world is nothing,

837
01:11:52,920 --> 01:11:54,918
that he dares ne'er come back to you.

838
01:11:55,380 --> 01:11:58,090
Or, if he do, it needs must be by stealth.

839
01:12:01,091 --> 01:12:06,522
I think it best you married with Paris.

840
01:12:07,523 --> 01:12:09,551
Speakest thou from thy heart?

841
01:12:10,552 --> 01:12:12,976
And from my soul too!

842
01:12:13,977 --> 01:12:15,977
- Amen!
- What?

843
01:12:18,978 --> 01:12:20,978
Well,

844
01:12:23,979 --> 01:12:26,979
thou hast comforted me marvellous much.

845
01:12:28,980 --> 01:12:31,980
Go in: and tell my lady I am gone,

846
01:12:32,981 --> 01:12:38,484
having displeased my father
to make confession and to be absolved.

847
01:12:39,485 --> 01:12:40,839
I will.

848
01:12:49,839 --> 01:12:51,585
This is wisely done.

849
01:13:04,639 --> 01:13:08,066
Ancient damnation! O most wicked fiend!

850
01:13:29,066 --> 01:13:30,505
Sir, he is fine.

851
01:13:30,505 --> 01:13:33,197
He was treated in the emergency room.

852
01:13:34,198 --> 01:13:35,962
Yes. sir!

853
01:13:36,962 --> 01:13:38,510
Yeah, but the doctor said...

854
01:13:40,406 --> 01:13:41,615
Yes, I realized that, sir.

855
01:13:45,212 --> 01:13:47,507
I take full responsibility, sir.

856
01:13:51,507 --> 01:13:53,841
Of course.

857
01:13:53,841 --> 01:13:56,099
Yes, sir!

858
01:14:37,099 --> 01:14:39,098
Come weep with me.

859
01:14:40,098 --> 01:14:42,674
Past hope, past cure, past help!

860
01:14:44,085 --> 01:14:45,810
I already know thy grief.

861
01:14:47,810 --> 01:14:51,765
I hear thou must, and nothing may prorogue it,
on Thursday next be married.

862
01:14:51,766 --> 01:14:57,003
Tell me not, friar, that thou hear'st of this,
unless thou tell me how I may prevent it.

863
01:14:58,568 --> 01:15:02,584
If, in thy wisdom, thou canst give no help,
do thou but call my resolution wise,

864
01:15:02,585 --> 01:15:05,425
and with this knife I'll help it presently.

865
01:15:05,330 --> 01:15:06,978
Hold!

866
01:15:12,978 --> 01:15:14,847
I do spy a kind of hope.

867
01:15:15,913 --> 01:15:18,392
And, if thou darest, I'll give thee remedy.

868
01:15:20,586 --> 01:15:23,313
O, bid me leap from off the battlements of yonder tower,

869
01:15:23,314 --> 01:15:26,314
and I will do it without fear or doubt.

870
01:15:27,313 --> 01:15:28,641
Hold, then:

871
01:15:29,641 --> 01:15:31,563
go home.

872
01:15:36,563 --> 01:15:38,806
Take thou this vial,

873
01:15:39,806 --> 01:15:43,418
and this distilled liquor drink thou off.

874
01:15:43,419 --> 01:15:49,689
When presently through all thy veins shall run
a cold and drowsy humour.

875
01:15:52,344 --> 01:15:55,162
The roses in thy lips and cheeks
shall fade to play ashes,

876
01:15:55,162 --> 01:16:00,223
thy eyes' windows fall,
like death, when he shuts up the day of life.

877
01:16:02,224 --> 01:16:05,505
And in this borrow'd likeness of shrunk death

878
01:16:06,506 --> 01:16:08,607
thou shalt continue.

879
01:16:11,607 --> 01:16:15,618
And then awake as from a pleasant sleep.

880
01:16:17,498 --> 01:16:22,125
In the mean time, shall Romeo come:
and he and I

881
01:16:23,126 --> 01:16:24,833
will watch thy waking.

882
01:16:25,833 --> 01:16:29,399
And this shall free thee from this present shame.

883
01:16:31,399 --> 01:16:32,928
Give me!

884
01:16:33,928 --> 01:16:36,040
Go, hence.

885
01:16:36,041 --> 01:16:39,428
Be strong and prosperous In this resolve.

886
01:16:41,429 --> 01:16:43,429
Love give me strength!

887
01:16:49,430 --> 01:16:51,430
Farewell.

888
01:17:39,428 --> 01:17:41,517
What if this drink do not work at all?

889
01:17:43,843 --> 01:17:50,388
What if it be a poison, which the friar
Subtly hath minister'd to have me dead?

890
01:17:52,495 --> 01:17:54,098
I fear it is:

891
01:17:56,098 --> 01:17:57,860
and yet, methinks, it should not,

892
01:17:59,258 --> 01:18:02,036
for he hath still been tried a holy man

893
01:18:31,501 --> 01:18:34,315
How if,

894
01:18:34,316 --> 01:18:35,545
when I am laid into the tomb,

895
01:18:36,546 --> 01:18:40,546
I wake before the time that Romeo comes?

896
01:18:41,861 --> 01:18:44,106
There's a fearful point!

897
01:18:46,107 --> 01:18:49,022
Shall I not, then, be stifled in the vault

898
01:18:51,023 --> 01:18:54,023
and there die strangled?

899
01:19:23,589 --> 01:19:25,589
O, if I wake,

900
01:19:28,590 --> 01:19:31,590
shall I not be distraught?

901
01:19:32,591 --> 01:19:36,591
And madly play with my forefather's joints?

902
01:19:37,592 --> 01:19:41,592
And pluck the mangled Tybalt from his shroud?

903
01:19:43,593 --> 01:19:45,593
And, in this rage

904
01:19:46,594 --> 01:19:49,594
with some great kinsman's bone,

905
01:19:50,595 --> 01:19:53,595
as with a club, dash out my desperate brains?

906
01:20:39,106 --> 01:20:41,959
O! Methinks I see my cousin's ghost.

907
01:20:44,960 --> 01:20:46,960
Stay, Tybalt!

908
01:20:48,795 --> 01:20:50,936
Stay!

909
01:20:54,107 --> 01:20:55,917
Romeo!

910
01:20:57,457 --> 01:20:58,852
Romeo...

911
01:21:04,853 --> 01:21:06,901
I drink to thee.

912
01:21:46,615 --> 01:21:49,679
<i>High school ring,
High school ring.</i>

913
01:21:51,132 --> 01:21:55,334
<i>Who would have guessed it was a homicidal thing?</i>

914
01:21:55,357 --> 01:21:58,553
<i>Crying, crying, crying,
on your front porch swing.</i>

915
01:21:58,554 --> 01:22:02,554
<i>Eyes swollen up like a yellowjacket sting.</i>

916
01:22:02,555 --> 01:22:06,555
<i>Call him a thief, call him a crook,</i>

917
01:22:07,556 --> 01:22:11,556
<i>You never get back what the magpie took.</i>

918
01:22:11,557 --> 01:22:15,557
<i>Call him a raven, call him a rook,</i>

919
01:22:16,558 --> 01:22:18,557
Sam!

920
01:22:18,558 --> 01:22:20,558
<i>You never get back what the magpie took.</i>

921
01:22:20,559 --> 01:22:22,559
Sam!

922
01:22:25,560 --> 01:22:27,560
Sam!

923
01:22:29,561 --> 01:22:32,561
<i>Your boyfriends mean,
Your boyfriends mean,</i>

924
01:22:33,687 --> 01:22:37,050
<i>I swear, I swear, I swear I didn't say anything.</i>

925
01:22:37,654 --> 01:22:41,471
<i>Your grandmother's silver
You kept it so clean,</i>

926
01:22:41,472 --> 01:22:46,280
<i>And those dark glasses, can you see what I mean.</i>

927
01:22:46,281 --> 01:22:50,378
<i>Call him a thief, call him a crook,</i>

928
01:22:50,379 --> 01:22:54,196
<i>You never get back what the magpie took.</i>

929
01:22:54,433 --> 01:22:58,002
<i>Call him a raven, call him a rook,</i>

930
01:22:59,003 --> 01:23:03,025
<i>You never get back what the magpie took.</i>

931
01:23:44,386 --> 01:23:45,945
Help!

932
01:23:46,946 --> 01:23:48,946
Help!

933
01:24:30,236 --> 01:24:32,942
Juliet's dead!
Juliet's dead!

934
01:24:42,943 --> 01:24:45,188
How now?

935
01:24:45,188 --> 01:24:47,295
How doth my lady?

936
01:24:47,338 --> 01:24:49,959
How fares my Juliet?
For nothing can be ill, if she be well!

937
01:24:50,342 --> 01:24:53,743
She is well, and nothing can be ill.

938
01:24:54,102 --> 01:24:56,286
Her body sleeps in Capel's monument,

939
01:24:57,287 --> 01:24:59,287
and her immortal part with angels lives.

940
01:25:24,286 --> 01:25:26,824
O well you art not conquered.

941
01:25:26,846 --> 01:25:30,246
O my love!

942
01:25:38,261 --> 01:25:40,419
Beauty's ensign

943
01:25:40,419 --> 01:25:44,032
still Is crimson in thy cheeks and thy lips,

944
01:25:47,182 --> 01:25:49,913
and death's pale flag is not advanced there.

945
01:25:57,048 --> 01:25:59,569
Shall I believe
that unsubstantial death is amorous,

946
01:25:59,569 --> 01:26:02,645
and keeps thee here in dark to be his paramour?

947
01:26:03,453 --> 01:26:06,554
For fear of that, I still will stay with thee.

948
01:26:07,555 --> 01:26:11,555
And never from this palace of dim night
depart again.

949
01:26:32,560 --> 01:26:35,519
Here's to my love!

950
01:26:57,521 --> 01:27:01,304
Here will I remain.

951
01:27:36,506 --> 01:27:38,595
How long hath he been there?

952
01:27:39,596 --> 01:27:41,596
Full half an hour.

953
01:27:43,597 --> 01:27:45,597
Go with me.

954
01:27:56,018 --> 01:27:58,151
Fear comes upon me.

955
01:28:00,582 --> 01:28:03,287
O, much I fear some ill unlucky thing.

956
01:28:22,443 --> 01:28:24,229
Where is my lord?

957
01:28:25,989 --> 01:28:30,178
I do remember well where I should be,
and there I am.

958
01:28:30,624 --> 01:28:32,579
Where is my Romeo?

959
01:28:33,579 --> 01:28:35,762
Come from this nest

960
01:28:36,763 --> 01:28:38,563
of unnatural sleep.

961
01:28:38,564 --> 01:28:41,938
A power greater than we can contradict
hath thwarted our intents.

962
01:28:41,991 --> 01:28:43,931
Come!

963
01:28:44,949 --> 01:28:46,777
Stay not to question,

964
01:28:46,778 --> 01:28:51,487
for the watch is coming.
Come, go, I dare no longer stay.

965
01:28:51,488 --> 01:28:53,707
Go, get thee hence, for I will not away.

966
01:29:06,708 --> 01:29:08,694
I will kiss thy lips.

967
01:29:10,993 --> 01:29:13,392
Haply some poison yet doth hang on them,

968
01:29:14,401 --> 01:29:16,285
to make die with a restorative.

969
01:30:12,625 --> 01:30:15,951
<i>You made me love you</i>

970
01:30:15,952 --> 01:30:20,620
<i>I didn't want to do it,
I didn't want to do it.</i>

971
01:30:21,621 --> 01:30:25,129
<i>You made me want you,</i>

972
01:30:26,081 --> 01:30:28,143
<i>And all the time you knew it.</i>

973
01:30:28,626 --> 01:30:31,504
<i>I guess you always knew it.</i>

974
01:30:31,505 --> 01:30:35,505
<i>You made me happy sometimes</i>

975
01:30:36,837 --> 01:30:39,775
<i>You made me glad.</i>

976
01:30:42,004 --> 01:30:45,493
<i>But there were times, baby,</i>

977
01:30:46,374 --> 01:30:50,391
<i>You made me feel so bad.</i>

978
01:30:51,829 --> 01:30:56,112
<i>You made me cry for</i>

979
01:30:56,113 --> 01:31:00,227
<i>I didn't want to tell you,
I didn't want to tell you.</i>

980
01:31:01,041 --> 01:31:05,576
<i>I want some love that's true.</i>

981
01:31:06,577 --> 01:31:08,577
<i>Yes I do, indeed I do, </i>

982
01:31:08,576 --> 01:31:10,985
<i>You know I do.</i>

983
01:31:10,985 --> 01:31:15,064
<i>Give me, give me, give me what I cry for.</i>

984
01:31:15,065 --> 01:31:20,850
<i>You know you got the kind o' kisses that I'd die for,</i>

985
01:31:20,851 --> 01:31:27,342
<i>You know you made me love you.</i>

986
01:31:40,201 --> 01:31:44,587
<i>You made me cry for</i>

987
01:31:45,205 --> 01:31:47,764
<i>I didn't want to tell you,
I didn't want to tell you.</i>

988
01:31:49,208 --> 01:31:52,889
<i>I want some love that's true.</i>

989
01:31:54,399 --> 01:31:56,782
<i>Yes I do, indeed I do, </i>

990
01:31:56,854 --> 01:31:59,181
<i>You know I do.</i>

991
01:31:59,182 --> 01:32:02,472
<i>Give me, give me, give me what I cry for.</i>

992
01:32:03,199 --> 01:32:08,324
<i>You know you got the kind o' kisses that I'd die for,</i>

993
01:32:09,165 --> 01:32:15,572
<i>You know you made me love you.</i>

994
01:32:17,573 --> 01:32:23,060
<i>You know you made me love you.</i>

