Subtitles by DramaFever
Episode 35
Was there anyone
that you liked?
Well...
What about you?
How was my sister?
Yeon Ah.
You know I really hate
being asked to hire
somebody that I don't
even know, right?
I'm sorry to say this
but I was going
to fail her for sure.
Unexpectedly, she can
touch people's heart.
Strangely, she's very attractive.
Can I look forward to
hearing good news then?
Well... I don't know yet.
Anyway, thank you for coming here
even though you have
a very busy schedule.
Oh, there will be a meeting
only with lead roles soon.
I want you to come.
Sure.
Why not? Just tell me when.
Bye.
It's Go.
You will be
so surprised, man.
Hey, Soon Shin.
You're late.
You didn't sleep yet?
Yeah.
Mi Ryung is in her room.
Do you want me to tell
her to come down?
No. I'm tired.
I'm going to take a rest.
- Good night.
- Okay.
She's stubborn as Mi Ryung.
No wonder she's
Mi Ryung's daughter.
Can I come in?
Are you sleeping already?
Did the audition go well?
Have you heard
from Soon Shin?
She's doing just fine.
I met her a few days ago.
- You met her?
- Yeah.
I think she feels awkward
about coming home.
And she's busy
preparing for an audition.
No, she's not!
If her dad had been alive,
would she have done this?
I bet she looks
down on us.
Grandma, you need to let go
of your anger.
I wouldn't be able to
keep in contact.
How could I keep in contact
when you're acting
like you're going to kill me.
Do you even
deserve to say
that to me, Yoo Shin?
Don't you know
why the atmosphere
in our house is
so depressing now?
It's not because of Soon Shin.
It's because of you.
Don't you know? Don't you see
the wrinkles
on your mom's face have doubled?
Grandma, don't worry.
Mrs. Park is going to approve
our marriage soon.
I can see that, you know.
Are you kidding me now?
I thought you had pride
in yourself, at least.
Is Chan Woo so great that
you had to do that?
Aren't you mad at him?
Don't you feel sorry
for your mom?
Let's go.
Bro, you need to invite me
to your new house.
Bro, aren't you going to
have a housewarming?
You should have that since
you moved to a new place.
It has been long time
since you moved
to a new place, you know.
I'm not having
a housewarming.
I'm going to move.
Why? Is it because of
that married woman?
That married woman?
Watch your mouth.
I'm going to go find a
different place to live.
- You overslept, didn't you?
- Yeah.
Do you want to go
exercise with me?
You need to start taking
care of your body.
I have to go practice.
Then have breakfast
before you leave.
The maid prepared
rice and soup for you.
It's okay.
I'll be back.
- Doctor Shin.
- Wow.
- Do you come here to exercise?
- You too?
Yeah. I have been a member
of this club
a long time ago.
Did Soo Jeong recommend
this place to you?
No.
I searched it.
Because I knew
you come here.
You're so funny.
I thought you would play
a static sport like golf.
You exercise at the gym as well.
I like to run actually.
When I was young,
I heard I was good at sports.
How young was that?
When I lived in
the country side.
Because I didn't
have a soccer ball
I had to use a pig urinal
tub to play soccer.
Have you heard of this kind of story?
Of course. I grew up
in the country side too.
Around this time of season
whenever I got hungry,
I would eat mulberries from the street
and pick apples from trees
and eat them.
But after getting a stomache
from eating them
there were a lot of times
I couldn't go to school for a few days.
Who would say
that's how you lived?
That goes the same
for you, too.
People would think
you grew up in a rich family.
Let's go have lunch.
What do you want to eat?
How about soy bean
paste soup?
I was thinking about
the same thing!
Let's go!
- Mr. Shin.
- How did it go?
The director hasn't
decided yet.
Really?
You know he's well-known for deciding things
very carefully.
I think it's going
to take some time.
Call him again.
Mr. Shin, why do you
care so much
about Soon Shin's audition?
No, I don't.
Go call him again.
- Hi, Mr. Shin.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- Hi, Mr. Shin.
- Hi.
You came early.
Did the result for the
audition come out?
You think you can
pass the audition?
You're so greedy.
This is just the start.
- Did I fail the audition?
- He hasn't decided yet.
Just think that you didn't pass
the audition
and forget about it.
Don't be so disappointed.
You can prepare for another one.
Okay.
You need to go
somewhere with me.
What?
You want to know too, right?
Let's go find out.
To where?
So you want to know
whether you passed
the audition or not?
How is it?
Is she going to pass?
Is she going to fail?
Courage and determination.
It seems very mild and
meek but it can be a lion.
This card symbolizes an
iron will and strength.
- It also means that you...
- So is she going to pass or not?
Miss, are you dating somebody?
Pardon? No.
I don't have a boyfriend.
This card symbolizes very
noble and pure love.
The guy is very close to you.
Dude, I asked you
if she will pass or not
and you're talking nonsense.
So is she going to pass?
Who's this guy?
Is he your uncle?
Your brother?
He's a CEO of my agency.
CEO?
You're very impetuous.
Whether she passes the audition
or not isn't important.
I told you before.
It's an iron will.
If you're trying to live,
you will die.
If you're trying to die,
you will live.
Do you think being nervous,
would make things work?
Can you get out, Mister?
My spiritual energy is declining.
- Pick one more card.
- One more?
He's such a swindler.
He can't even guess
what we asked right.
He shouldn't be a
fortuneteller.
Who is it?
Are you talking
to yourself?
He said there's someone
who likes me.
He said the guy is close to me.
Close to me?
I don't have any guys close to me.
A man that's close to me?
I don't have anyone.
Is it...
Boss?
What am I saying now?
Don't tell him I said that.
Since there's a guy
close to me.
He's the only one
that I can think of.
I must be crazy.
That guy isn't a fortuneteller.
Can't you tell?
He had the word
'swindler' written on his face.
A real fortuneteller
wouldn't act like that.
You said this was a famous place.
Didn't you search it
before you came?
Yes, I did.
Maybe it changed.
Or maybe his spiritual energy declined.
What a waste.
Who's the guy anyway.
What's up?
What?
Okay.
Thanks.
Are we not going?
What are you doing?
You passed the audition.
What?
Soon Shin,
you passed the audition.
Really?
Oh my God.
Oh my God!
- Are you that happy.
- Yeah.
Me too.
You did a good job.
Cheers.
Finally, we have a star
in our restaurant.
Come on, Boss.
- I was just lucky.
- No, it wasn't that.
It's the result of
practicing so hard.
You helped me a lot.
Thank you for saying that.
Congratulations.
It's my treat today.
- Why?
- Why not?
She might be a model
for my restaurant's promotion,
you know.
You said you're playing
a would-be singer role, right?
Yeah. She's a cooking assistant
who keeps going to singing auditions.
Can you teach me how to cook?
You're a would-be singer.
Why cook?
There are some scenes
where I have to cook.
I want to look real.
It's an honor to me.
Yeah. If you decide
to do something
you should do it right.
That's so Soon Shin.
Many people want me
to teach
how to cook these days.
Why do you want
to learn that?
Just focus on acting.
Who's the main lead role?
Choi Yeon Ah.
Yeon Ah?
Hi, Yeon Ah.
- How did it go?
- She got the role.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
I got the call from
the assistant director.
Lee Soon Shin got the role.
Congratulations.
You get to be in a drama with your sister.
Thanks.
Are you on the way
to my house?
Mother Park.
Guess what this is?
I heard you like wheat buns.
This bun is really famous.
It tastes like the original.
Come on.
I'll steam it for you.
You're so brazen.
How can you act like this
without even
blinking your eyes?
Mother Park?
Don't give it to me.
Just go to your house
and give it to your grandmother.
Mother Park, come on.
What's wrong with you?
I didn't tell you to buy that.
This happened because
you're doing something
you usually don't do.
You think I don't know you?
You should've been
nice to me before.
Get up.
Go home.
I'll call you.
I said go home.
Are you going at me now?
Are you mad at me
because I shoved her?
Mom, I'm just going to marry
her without your permission.
What?
If you keep opposing to our marriage
we'll register our marriage
and move out together.
What did you say?
Do you even have the money
for a place?
I can rent an apartment.
If I can't, I will just
live in Yoo Shin's house.
I'm sorry. No matter how hard
I think about it
this seems to be
the only way.
I don't think you will
ever like Yoo Shin.
And I'm never going
to give up on her.
There's no other way.
You...
How could you say
that to me?
Honey, is that
really our son?
I knew this would happen.
You're going to lose him forever,
like this.
Hey, honey.
Give me a glass of water.
Hello, sir.
- Mom.
- Soon Shin.
- What's up?
- Mom...
I...
- Did something happen?
- Mom, I...
I passed the audition!
What?
Really?
That's so great, Soon Shin!
Mom, I can't believe if
this is a dream or not.
I couldn't even sleep last night.
I am in the broadcasting
station now.
I came here
to meet the director.
- I kind of believe it after I got a call...
- You can go ahead.
Mom, isn't this so great?
Huh?
I'm so glad to hear that.
Soon Shin
I'm kind of busy right now.
I'll call you later.
What?
Oh, you're busy?
Okay.
I'll call you later...
Soon Shin.
I guess you just talked
to Mom on the phone.
Can I talk to you
using the familiar form?
Yeah.
I heard the good news.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
I'm so happy for you.
Now we're going to be
in the same drama.
Do you best so you don't
disgrace me and Mom.
Okay?
You're on the way
to see the director, right?
Good thing.
Let's go together.
Since you two beautiful
siblings are sitting together
the room got really bright.
Director, thank you so much.
I was so happy when I heard
she passed the audition.
Your sister cares
about you a lot.
Looks good.
Don't worry about
her acting.
I'll take care of her.
I liked your emotional feeling
when you sang the song.
You said somebody you like
used to sing that song, right?
Who is that person?
Your first love?
My late father.
Ah, I see.
That's why it touched
my heart.
Anyway, let's do our best.
Don't hold your head high
just because of your connection
to Actress Song Mi Ryung.
Your skill is the most important
in this field of work.
Okay.
Director, please take
good care of my sister.
Don't worry about it.
Then I'll see you at rehearsal.
Okay.
Let me help you.
- I'll carry it.
- No, it's okay.
Did you hear what I said
the other day?
That was...
That was a joke.
I must've been out of my mind
because of the hot weather.
Okay.
I'll take that as a joke.
Um...
I think I'm going to have to
quit getting lessons from you.
I've gotten busy lately.
I think I'm going to stop
studying for a while.
Oh, I'm also looking
for a new home.
I think I'm giving
you pressure.
I'm very sorry.
I think I'm making you
feel uncomfortable so...
I'm sorry.
Let's go.
Hey, Hye Shin.
Why didn't you
answer my call?
Mrs. Han...
You're the owner of the bakery
who kicked me out, aren't you?
What kind of relationship is it
between the both of you?
Now that I look at it
you made me look like a fool!
No, Mrs. Han.
Then what is it?
Now that I look at it,
you're such a scary woman.
It hasn't been that long
since you got a divorce.
You're seeing another man already?
You told me not to send
you the child expenses
because of this man?
- Excuse me.
- You be quiet.
You don't have a right to get
involved in this conversation.
It's not that.
You come here.
We need to talk.
Mrs. Han, I don't have anything
to talk about with you.
Why? Because you got caught
right in front of my face?
This is ridiculous.
The say the quiet ones
are the most conniving.
And you are the one.
- How could you say that?
- Don't say anything.
Just follow me.
Grandma, don't do this
to my mom!
Woo Joo.
Go!
Leave now!
Long time no see, Woo Joo.
We rent out one of the
rooms in our house to him.
You're misunderstanding her.
Oh, really?
Grandma, why are you doing
this to my mom?
What did she do wrong?
Why are you doing this to her?
It's not that, Woo Joo.
I have something to discuss
with your mom.
No, you don't.
Just leave.
Mom, let's go.
Come on.
Hey, call me later.
Okay?
Oh my God. How did she become so fierce
after all this time?
This isn't good.
How did her mom educate her?
My son...
A relationship contract?
Rule number one: If our families find out
about the relationship
we're going to break up.
Rule number two:
Respect each other's jobs.
Don't come to the work place
without telling first.
Rule number three: Don't
control each other's privacy.
Don't ask why one doesn't
call the other
what time one came home,
who one met with.
What's this?
It's ridiculous.
Lee Yoo Shin!
How could she treat my son like this?
I heard you're sick.
I bought some rice porridge, Mrs. Park.
You come sit here.
Here.
This is...
Where did you find this?
This is why I don't like you.
How could you make my
son sign this contract?
There was a reason to do this
at that time.
I didn't know I would
marry him back then.
You're going to control my son
like a slave if you marry him.
Am I right?
Don't say that.
That's so mean.
So I'm going to make you
sign this contract too.
Pardon?
If you sign this contract
then I'll approve your marriage.
Read it.
What do you think?
You think you can take it?
- Mrs. Park...
- Why?
Letters are too small to read or something?
Then I'll read it out
loud for you.
Contract.
Rule number one: I, Lee Yoo Shin,
will respect
and obey Park Chan Woo forever.
Respect?
Obey...
Rule number two: I, Lee Yoo Shin,
will respect
and obey in-law's family and live with them.
And support my in-law parents forever.
Mrs. Park, are you telling me to live here?
Yeah. I can't let Chan Woo
get controlled by you.
I'm going to teach you
how to respect people
and how to do housekeeping.
Here. Take this home
and think about it.
You can either choose
to break up with him
or sign the contract.
It's one or the other.
Understand?
Hey...
I'm sorry about
what happened earlier.
Don't be.
Hye Shin, would you
come here
and punch
this sandbag?
Like this.
Try it.
I hung this here
so you can punch it
when this kind of stuff happens.
Even an idiot like me says
what he wants to in life.
But... how come a smart person like you,
endures everything?
You know...
Everybody needs a single blow
in their lives sometimes.
Endure over and over...
It's not a great thing
in the long run.
Why do you have
to live like that?
For what?
If you want to scream,
then do it.
If you feel heavy
with worries...
Like this.
Don't put up
with them.
I must be crazy.
Why did I move in here?
What?
Me?
Are you telling me to be
Soon Shin's manager?
Yeah. You're the most
competent person here.
That's true.
That's why I'm telling you to do it.
So be her manager.
Mr. Shin, do you hate me?
I've always hated you.
I'm going to see how you do.
Then I'm going to decide
if you can be my assistant again.
Look for her stylist
and make-up artist.
Make a team
and report it to me.
Okay.
[Lee Soon Shin]
Wow, who is this?
Actress Lee.
Are you not practicing?
I'm going to.
I have something to tell you.
What is it?
Thank you, Mr. Shin.
What?
You're acting like you became
a famous actress already.
This was just the first step.
I know.
But this is a big deal to me.
I never dreamed this would
happen in my life.
I like how you appreciate everything.
So what is it
you want to tell me?
This.
You...
How did you get it?
It was so hard to find this.
I had to search every website to buy it.
It's so embarrassing.
No, it's not.
Mr. Shin,
you were a singer.
You had good skills.
Don't make fun of me.
I'm not making fun of you.
I really liked it.
So I want your autograph.
I really became your fan.
Thank you for encouraging
me all the time.
I'm really going
to try my best.
And trust yourself.
I trust you.
You think I would be
impressed by this?
What is your name, Miss?
It's Lee Soon Shin.
I'm not making fun of you.
I really liked it.
So I want your autograph.
I really became your fan.
What are you doing, Joon Ho?
When did you come in?
What's this?
It's your old album.
The one that didn't
even sell at all.
Get out.
- You're acting weird.
- What is?
You're snickering a lot, lately.
Did something good happen to you?
Just get out.
You were so quiet
for a few days.
Did you overcome
the break up already?
Why did you enter without knocking?
You purchased a new
membership at a health club.
It was the magazine about
the club so I opened it.
Why do you open my mail
without my permission?
Isn't this where Mi Ryung
also goes to exercise?
Does that matter?
Why doesn't it?
I really don't understand.
Why didn't you tell me about the
model thing and this earlier?
Stop talking nonsense.
Why are you being so sensitive?
This is something to be sensitive about.
Don't you have
other things to do?
You got tired of cooking so
you're doubting your husband now?
What?
Please get out.
I have to work. I'm busy.
How can you be
so busy everyday?
Is there nothing else to say
besides telling me that you're busy?
There has to be some of kind connection
in order to talk with you.
You either cook or gossip
about celebrities everyday.
Or you shop with Yi Jeong.
Or gossip about your friends.
How can that be fun to me?
Is that why?
But there are things you can
talk about with Mi Ryung?
What's wrong with you nowadays?
Do you have a delusional jealousy
towards your husband?
A delusional jealousy
towards my husband?
That's enough.
Let's just stop talking.
What's the use in talking about it?
My mouth would only hurt.
What are you doing, Mom?
Nothing.
Did you fight with dad?
No.
Mom, don't you think
Joon Ho is acting weird?
I don't think he's dating Yeon Ah.
Is he seeing
a different woman?
A different woman?
Who?
I don't know.
He snickers a lot.
Seems like he's dating somebody.
But I don't think that's Yeon Ah.
Hey, don't worry him.
Worry about yourself.
Are you going to live like this?
Go on a blind date.
You should get a job or something.
Until when are you going
to follow me around?
Mom, what's wrong?
Are you okay?
Why are you yelling at me
all of a sudden?
Hey.
What's this?
I'm sorry it's late.
It's your birthday present.
Are you still mad at me?
I don't know why but I
forget things these days.
Please lighten up.
Yeon Ah, I'm kind of disappointed
in you too, honestly.
How come you haven't visited
my house for weeks?
I told you I've been busy.
Even if you're busy, don't
you have time to stop by?
You can help Soon Shin practice
for auditions and get along with her.
She already passed the audition.
What else is there to prepare?
What are you talking about?
She passed?
She passed the audition?
Didn't she tell you
she passed?
I asked the director a favor.
It's the drama I'll be shooting too.
Really?
Thanks, Yeon Ah.
She hasn't told you that she
passed the audition yet?
She had a meeting with me
and the director yesterday.
'Mom, I passed it.' I think
she called her mom.
I guess she meant
the other mom.
- Is Soon Shin home?
- Yeah.
She just came home.
We need to talk.
What is it?
I heard you passed the audition.
Why didn't you tell me?
Why didn't you
tell me you passed?
Because you're going
to find out anyway.
You think that makes sense?
I have to practice my guitar.
Please get out.
If you were going
to keep acting like this
why did you decide
to come into this house?
Did you come here
so you can make me suffer?
I came here
because you told me to.
If you want me to leave,
I'll leave.
What?
How can you do this to me?
How can you be so spiteful?
Where are you going?
I'm going for a walk.
Mother. We have good
news about Soon Shin.
How about inviting her over
and having dinner together?
Let's buy some pork belly and
throw a BBQ party for her.
I'm planning to invite her tomorrow.
You're okay with this, right?
Do you make decisions
with my permission?
If you want to do it, do it.
If you want to invite her, then invite her.
Please let go
of your anger now.
I think she feels so sorry
that it's awkward for her
to come here.
Please be nice to her, Mother.
Why would I be nice to her?
She hasn't done anything that I liked.
She betrayed her family.
She decided to go live
with her real mother
and wants to become an actress just like her mother.
Is it something I should
congratulate her for?
Do we have to throw
a party for that?
We should congratulate her.
It's hard to become an actress.
She has wanted
to become an actress.
It doesn't matter if
she's with her mother or not.
I'm just so happy
for her now.
Her voice was so excited.
I bet she wants us
to congratulate her the most.
I'm going to invite
her tomorrow, okay?
Please don't be so mean to her, Mother.
Okay?
I told you to do
whatever you want.
Oh my God.
She's just too nice.
She's ridiculous.
[Mom]
She must be really busy.
Soon Shin, I'm sending you a
text since you're so busy.
Congratulations on passing the audition.
Do you want to come over
for dinner tomorrow?
I'm throwing a party for you.
[Delete]
You weren't sleeping yet?
You said you quit drinking
but you're drinking again.
Mind your own business.
Where's Soon Shin?
Did she go out?
I don't care.
I heard she passed the audition.
Where did you hear that?
I got a call from
Gabi Agency.
I heard they're making
a team for Soon Shin.
I think Mr. Shin
is working so hard for her.
I guess she is very talented.
She got that from you.
I'm so proud of her.
How did she pass the audition at once?
Il Do.
Let's throw a party
at our house tomorrow.
A party?
Yeah.
A party.
My daughter passed
the difficult audition.
Shouldn't I throw a
party for her as her mother?
Let's invite the staff that's going
to work with Soon Shin
along with her friends
and have a party tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
Don't you think that's too soon?
Why is that soon?
We can do it.
Call people right now.
Hire a buffet caterer and check
the director's schedule.
But isn't tomorrow
too soon?
Does it have to
be tomorrow?
Yeah. It has to be tomorrow.
We're doing it tomorrow.
Oh, who else is
in that drama?
I'm going to tell other actresses
to take a good care
of my daughter too.
Welcome.
It's really spicy.
This is a very fresh one.
It's kind of expensive.
No. I need one more pound.
Did something good happen
to your family?
Yeah.
My daughter became an actress.
She passed an audition,
so I'm throwing a party for her.
Really?
Congratulations.
- I'll give you some more.
- Thank you.
I got a call from Mr. Hwang.
He's inviting people for dinner
at Mi Ryung's house.
Teacher Song is throwing
a party to congratulate
Soon Shin
for passing the audition.
- A party?
- Yeah.
She invited all the staff, the
director, and main leading roles.
Why is she making such a
big deal out of this?
Why is she doing that?
What's wrong with that?
It's good.
We get to have some
nice food there.
You're going, right?
Wow. That's a lot of food.
Why did you make
so much food?
She cooked all day
for Soon Shin.
Didn't you go
work today, Mom?
I told Gil Ja that I won't work
for a few days.
Why?
Are you kidding me now?
I'm not going work
until you figure things out with Chan Woo.
Nice. I didn't want you
to work there anyway.
You should just quit there, Mom.
How are things going anyway?
I don't know. She's so much
more spiteful than I thought.
- What are you going to do?
- I don't know. It should go well.
Anyway, Soon Shin is so lucky.
Even if she left us like this
Mom is having a party for her.
Don't be so mean to her
when she comes.
Just congratulate her.
Okay?
Okay, Mom.
Okay.
Why isn't she calling?
That's such a nice wine.
Switch the position
with this one.
Hey, Soon Shin.
Is today
a special day?
It's a celebration party.
A celebration party?
Yeah. I invited some people
to congratulate you
on passing the audition.
Soon Shin.
Chan Mi.
I'm Park Chan Mi, also Soon Shin's stylist.
And her friend.
I see.
What's going on?
Aren't you surprised?
I didn't tell you to surprise you.
Your agency offered me the
position so I said I would do it.
Why didn't you call me?
Soon Shin, go change your clothes.
- I prepared a dress for you.
- What?
Go get changed.
- Go have a seat.
- Thank you.
What time is it?
She's very late.
She must be busy now.
Let's just start
eating first.
She should've called
and let us know
if she's going to be late.
Let's roast the pork.
Woo Joo must be hungry.
Okay, Grandma.
[Song Mi Ryung]
- Hello.
- Hi, Mrs. Lee.
Did you hear the good news from Soon Shin?
Ah...Yeah.
Her director came to my house
and is having a meeting with Soon Shin now.
Soon Shin said she's having a sore throat.
Do you still have some
balloon flower tea?
Balloon flower tea?
Yeah. The one you
made for Soon Shin.
I think my maid
accidentally threw it away.
Can you bring
that for her now?
- Now?
- Yes, now.
She's practicing
her acting now.
I want her to do well
in front of the director.
Please bring it now.
I'd really appreciate that.
What are you doing here?
Everyone is here.
Really?
Thank you for spending
your time here with us.
As her mother, I'm really happy
that she got a great
role in this drama.
I'm having this party for my
daughter and for people here.
Here.
Shall we all have a toast?
Cheers.
Congratulations, Soon Shin.
Thank you, Director.
Mom, isn't Soon Shin coming?
Yeah. She said she can't come.
I think she's really busy.
- Oh my gosh.
- Go eat. I have to go somewhere.
Go where?
Our writer, too.
Here.
Enjoy the food.
- Excuse me.
- Yes?
When is Mr. Shin coming?
He'll come soon.
Soon Shin, the food here
is so delicious.
I think these are
from a hotel.
- Can I take some home?
- Yeah.
Are you also good at singing,
Teacher Song?
Singing?
I wasn't sure at first but the way
Soon Shin sings has emotion.
I heard that from Director too.
Can I hear her singing?
Why not?
I also want to hear it.
- In Sung.
- Yes?
Can you go to Soon Shin's room
and bring the guitar?
Okay.
Give it up for Soon Shin.
Come on.
- Who's there?
- I came to see Soon Shin.
Subtitles by DramaFever