To our limits
Well done, champ.
Super.
Okay. In front of you.
Compact, yeah, come on!
Strong pulse, strong.
Your place.
Super, forward. Come on.
Come and get it.
Very good.
Compact, robust, very good.
Okay, stop.
- Go! Go ahead!
Come on! Final set.
Beware, concentrate!
Okay, come back! It does not matter.
- Damn!
Yes, come on!
Winning point. Each ball.
Come on, final ball, winning point! Okay.
Very good.
Your wrist.
- Yes.
Top.
Super. That's enough for today.
Thank you.
Top, how much?
- 42.
Good training, Jonas, very good.
Bye, Jonas, see you Wednesday.
Hi!
- Ready?
Yes.
- Hi, Jonas.
Hey, you all right?
- Yes.
Are you ready for today, Jonas?
Want a ride?
- No, it's okay.
He runs back.
I take the train.
Want something to drink?
- Yes.
Let's go.
Will you join us?
- Yes.
Bye, Bernard.
- Ciao, Bernard.
But Jonas, those are excuses.
You're an idiot and you do not have the guts.
- Whatever!
No, but love and sexuality,
that is not the same.
The first time is important, no?
I want to do it with someone I love.
Who is it?
Come on, who is it?
- No one.
She doesn't want to anyway.
And why?
She is super intelligent,
she goes to the 6th year.
And then?
- She will not want to.
But Jonas
you're not inferior.
Jonas, you have to take your chances.
You should not underestimate yourself.
If I were your age,
I would definitely be in love with you.
Yeah, but you're an idiot.
What's the girl's name?
- Delphine.
To Delphine!
I love you.
I would like to take the time
to talk with you, but ...
well ...
I take it you already suspected this ...
We don't think it's a good idea
to hold you back another year.
Then your classmates will be
3 or 4 years younger than you.
We believe it's better if you
go to a technical or vocational school.
How much did I have for French?
9.
But Ms. Libotte says that
without your big problems in spelling
and grammar, you would have had good points
Go to Ms. Lambert in the PMS center.
She will help you find a new school.
Agree?
Will you ask your mom to call me?
You will not forget?
All the best.
Goodbye, Jonas.
Jonas!
What?
- How did it go?
No, they do not want me restart.
Really?
- Yes.
What a bunch of assholes.
Mom called. You have to call back.
Hey, Mom, it's Jonas.
Well, I just wanted to say that I failed.
I got my report card and ...
Anyway ...
They will not let me pass.
I'll call you later.
She has played well.
40-0.
And?
- It's okay.
What, it's okay?
- I have two transition exams.
Which subjects?
- Chemistry and Geography.
Come on!
- Forget it.
Get in the water!
No, no, it's okay.
- How brave, Pierre!
No, no.
- Yes, come now!
He will not go in the water.
Come on.
- No, I don't want. Damn!
Okay, we do nothing. We're leaving.
- No!
On your lovers, Jonas!
- On your dick!
We drink on Jonas his dick.
Well, how was it?
- It was good.
Yes?
- Yes.
It was good, that's it?
How good was it?
- Really good.
It was really good!
- Leave him alone!
So you're happy?
- Yes.
How many times have you done it?
- 1 time.
And how long did it take?
- I do not know ...
An hour?
But no, not even.
- How long than approximately?
I do not know ... 5-6 minutes ...
- Oh yes!
5-6 min plaisure,
that's still 5-6 min of happiness.
And how was she?
Wait! How was she?
Was she good, at ease?
What has she done to you?
Nothing fancy.
Has she sucked you,
shown you things,
caressed you down there?
- No.
He takes it easy.
- And how did you do it?
On the sofa.
- Yes.
Yes?
- Was she down? On all fours?
We lay down.
- She on top?
Yes ... uh no ... vice versa.
Okay, the missionary position. Yes ...
One brave little missionary.
Was it her 1st time too?
- Yes.
That's normal. My 1st time was with someone
my age, just as inexperienced.
He was ready in 5 minutes,
I was not even damp.
It was horrible.
It was only when I met someone with
more experience who showed me things,
otherwise I would still not have cum.
Well yes, sorry, with you I would have ...
I started to get worried already.
And the guy with more experience, am I?
No, an old man.
I thought so, if her 1st orgasms
were with me ...
That was late!
- Well, yes ...
Everything okay?
Where have you been?
- At the sea.
When you pass you can clear the table, no?
- Okay, I'll do it.
You also want to move your ass please?
What are you going to do for school?
What are you waiting for?
It's vacation, relax!
When are you going to spring into action?
- What is that to you? Help me!
40/30.
Damn.
- Game ...
5/4.
Time.
0/15.
The training is okay.
In a game, you're too nervous.
You lose it.
Listen, Jonas,
take it easy on the tennis.
Concentrate on your studies.
Okay?
Okay, Jonas?
I screw up everything.
At school, tennis,
I'm a failure.
Calm down.
You'll pass year exams.
I don't even have exams!
They don't want me anymore.
I have to go to the losers.
And where is that?
- The vocational school. Where failures go.
Bastards!
Come on, Jonas.
No, no, I don't want to.
- Yes, come.
Do you have a bucket?
- In the bathroom.
About the school,
don't sweat it.
You're not dumber than another.
And what does she think?
Mom says it's okay.
She has faith in me.
And what do you want to do?
I want to go to the federation, but ...
But Jonas
You really thought you were going to be a pro?
Or there is the exam committee.
But that's super heavy.
And how would you prepare for that?
Well, a private school ...
Wait, your mother can not afford that.
My father, he can at least do this.
If you need help,
Give me a call.
Pierre has even managed to drag Didier
through college.
It was hard.
I have two transition exams.
If I succeed, I still have three years to go
and I've had it.
That's why I thought of the exam committee.
Because at the exam committee, you can
do three years in one.
I do not understand.
You only have two exams, that's not too bad.
For once that you can succeed ...
- Yeah, but ...
I'm tired of sitting with little brats of 14
Yes, Jonas, but then you had
to start working earlier.
How much does it cost?
1000 euros per month?
No way!
Can't you give a part of it?
No, you go to school like everyone else,
it's not that bad. 1000, what else!
I failed.
- What!
I failed,
They won't even hold me back.
I have to go to the vocational school.
I told you that if you had failed,
I would stop paying alimony.
What does she do? She leaves you alone.
She goes to the south
and thinks that everything will go well here.
She wants to take care of you by herself
but she does not.
Then it's her fault if things go wrong.
Why do I always have
to fix everything?
Has she told you to come here?
- No.
1000 euros per month! She has never
had scruples, but now she exaggerates!
She has always gotten everything,
and she wants more! I gave her the house.
Do you know what that means?
That she fixes it herself now!
What should I do?
- Ask your mother.
She has to find a solution.
You go to Brussels? Great, thanks.
You can make the exam for the
exam committee as a free student.
You should therefore not go to school.
That's impossible. That is much too heavy.
But no, we can help you.
- Yes.
I will make inquiries.
We'll do it together, okay?
The bastard!
He makes another child with a slut
and he can not even take care of his own.
Don't call your father a bastard.
He probably does what he can.
You can also see this as a real opportunity.
It is a challenge.
If you succeed,
you will always be safe.
Do you know what you have to learn
for the exam committee?
Yes.
And it's not because Pierre is going to help,
that you will succeed.
Have you been to dad?
- Yes.
What did you tell him?
I told him.
And what did he say?
Nothing.
Nothing at all?
He said nothing.
Are you sure I need all that?
- Yes.
I'll pay you back.
Don't worry. I can pay it.
Do you have a historical atlas?
- No, I'll use yours.
I prefer that you have your own stuff.
For example: A is your pencil,
B is your eraser.
What is C then?
That.
- Yes. And what is "it"?
Pencil and eraser.
- I restart the exercise.
I have a pencil and an eraser,
equal to a pencil plus an eraser.
Then a pencil plus an eraser
minus an eraser equals ... ?
A pencil. So A.
- Exactly.
Mathematics is not more than that.
It is sometimes complicated,
but it remains very concrete.
You have to promise me that if you don't
understand it, you ask me immediately.
Otherwise it will not work.
You have to learn how to learn.
And I will be glad
if you do not longer need me.
Well?
Do not touch me!
I wanted to know if you're okay. Why?
Everything okay?
Come on!
Hey, you're jealous!
Fuck you!
Everything okay?
Why didn't you come?
- I had a game.
How did it go?
- Super.
I've had enough of it.
I'm going to study for the exam committee.
That's all right.
Are we going out?
- Yes.
What is it?
Nothing.
Is it okay?
I do not know ...
What?
I don't go too fast?
No.
Did you cum?
Yes.
He is ready
to throw the bomb at the Duke
when he realizes that the Duke is accompanied
by his 2 children. He would rather wait.
The whole piece is about commitment,
and how far you are willing to go
for that commitment.
For example, would you blow
yourself up in a bus
in the name of freedom?
- No.
I don't want to kill innocents.
You think like Camus. He says:
What are the limits of
striving for justice?
Even though our intentions are good,
is there a limit that we are not
allowed to cross to reach them?
Then Camus replies:
"Between my mother and my country
I choose my mother."
He thinks that his mother
could be in the bus.
Is everything alright with Delphine?
- Yes, it is.
That does not sound very convincing
If you want to talk, go ahead.
What is it?
I'm afraid that ...
Afraid of what? Don't be afraid!
We have no secrets from each other.
I think I'm going too fast.
I think she does not have orgasms
and I can not ...
You can not last longer.
- Yes.
This is normal in the beginning.
You lack experience, that's all.
Sexuality is like all the rest,
you still have to learn.
How can you please a woman with good sex
if you've never touched one?
That's impossible.
This takes time.
You should try experimenting.
Nathalie can explain a few things.
If I had someone with more experience
when I was your age,
it would have saved me a lot of problems.
What is super important is foreplay.
Do you think you can make a woman
cum even without penetrating her?
I can do that anyway. You, I do not know.
And Delphine,
has she rather vaginal
or clitoral orgasms?
I don't know.
When you are inside her,
do you feel contractions?
I don't know.
If she twitches,
she is vaginal.
Nathalie has no contractions,
she's looking for years already.
Do you know what a clitoris is?
- Of course.
I hate to ask,
but do you still have your foreskin?
My what?
- Your foreskin.
I ask you that because they cut
Didier his foreskin
making it less sensitive
so he lasts longer.
If you still have your foreskin,
it is normal that you're so quickly to cum,
you're more sensitive.
But what is super important when having sex
is that you are relaxed, otherwise
it is normal that you cum too quick.
It's hard to relax,
as she is always below you.
If you are in her,
you must ask the right questions.
Come on, come to me?
- It's okay.
But no, come here.
- Let me do it.
Come.
- But why?
Didn't you like it?
- Yeah, that's not it.
It was good, right?
Yes, but I want you to cum inside me.
Let me continue, it will do you good.
No, Jonas.
- But let me do it.
I don't want to.
Do you feel anything?
Yes, but I just want you to cum inside me.
Here! Do you take that?
- Yes.
Put it straight into the freezer?
- Okay.
Good?
What's for dinner tonight?
- Chicken croquettes, okay?
Yes, great.
We have found a working method.
It's really cool.
I don't know how to thank you.
I owe you a favor.
Hold on, Pascale.
- No.
You have food prepared for us,
that is very good.
And have you seen your Italian again?
- Shut up about that.
What?
- Thanks for that formidable plan!
Want some wine?
- Who is that Italian?
It was your idea, no?
It is really fun going back
to studying this curriculum,
teaching Jonas. Really enjoyable.
Make him work hard.
If he doesn't work, then call me, okay?
I am confident.
And you accepted Tommaso's gift?
No, and you know it.
Why?
- Because you don't accept something like that.
Yes you do.
- No, not if it happens like this.
What does that mean?
- Who is this Tommaso?
Nothing, a ...
moronic ...
Italian ...
- Not a moron, very generous.
Didier introduced me to him.
Yes, that's correct.
Pierre,
would you like a drink?
- Yes, please.
Thank you.
Big kiss.
Work hard, huh?
- Yes.
If there's anything, you'll call me, okay?
We'll leave it at that.
The written examination was bad,
why should it go better now?
No, wait! I know this.
You must know your material better.
- 2 minutes, please.
Sorry, there are still candidates waiting.
Goodbye.
- Work well.
And it's still the 1st test.
It's like tennis.
You put yourself under too much pressure.
It's not a race, Jonas.
You'll get there at your own rhythm.
You will become tired.
But no, I know very well
that it will take time.
And it's not because you're not capable.
Think you can just absorb
3 years of material at once?
You're not Superman.
Nobody expects you to be.
You did not get the necessary help for years.
You don't fix that at once.
Did you call your mom?
What did she tell you?
I should not lower my courage.
Do not worry.
I know very well
what I started.
I especially don't want
that you doubt yourself.
Agree?
Come on!
You're lucky that someone with a lot of patience
deals with you.
Do not wear blinders,
don't believe in a religion
that makes you empty promises,
don't blindly follow a moral
that imposes you a way of life
that you have not chosen.
That's revolt!
Remain conscious,
Always look at things more closely.
Example, if I tell you:
You must love your parents?
Yes.
Why?
Because they have put us on the world.
And because they did,
they deserve a life of respect
that you shouldn't doubt?
Yeah, maybe.
No, wait, if you consciously think that,
that's okay.
But if you're just applying an imposed
morality, I do not agree.
Someone can have very good reasons
to hate his parents.
If he doesn't do it for external reasons,
he is not aware,
and certainly not a rebellious man.
Later we have a chapter
on Don Juan.
In your eyes, is he a decent man?
Yes.
What did you think honestly?
No.
Why?
- Because he runs after all the girls.
Is that bad?
Wait, I ask the question differently:
Is that necessarily bad?
No.
What does Camus say? That we,
faced with an absurd world,
have to live as intensely as possible
use all that is given to us,
challenge the world,
experience as many experiences.
No imposed limits or prohibitions,
because borders are totally artificial.
He says: "Every healthy creature
attempts to reproduce."
And so does Don Juan. He experiences
various love affairs very intensely
rather then reduce himself to a single passion.
I want to read you a passage.
Listen: "The only generous love
is the one who realizes that she's both
volatile and particular at once.
These are all the endings and rebirths
that constitute Don Juan's life.
That is his way
to give and let live.
Everyone can judge whether or not
this is selfishness.
Well, it's late. We go to sleep.
Think about it?
- Yes.
You should not feel obligated.
Really, I'd prefer that you work.
That's for you.
Are you crazy?
- It's my pleasure.
Would you like lasagna?
Lasagne?
- Yes.
You're crazy!
It's his last novel.
But he died
before he could finish it.
It is about his childhood in Algiers.
He lived with his mother and grandmother
because his father died when he was one.
His mother could neither read nor write
and they had no books at home.
His mother did not even want him to study.
But when his teacher saw
he was super intelligent,
He has paid his studies.
Thanks to him, he was awarded the Nobel Prize.
When he received it,
He wrote a letter to thank him.
The letter is at the back of the book.
It's beautiful.
You can borrow others too
if you like to read it.
I have them all.
Thank you.
I don't know,
I have not actually felt much.
Maybe she doesn't know how.
A good fellatio is not that easy.
Yes,
or maybe I have a problem.
That you can only know if you do it
with someone who has more experience.
Otherwise, it's impossible.
But I can't find someone
else to do it.
I understand that.
Anyway ...
It would be stupid if your relation would
end because of sexual problems, no?
4 NH35 O2. Yes.
4 NO. Okay. Super.
There, that is 18 +2.
Yes. All right.
Will you continue?
- Yes.
You like that actress?
Yes, she's okay.
And her?
Yeah, you like her.
Pierre has explained it a little.
If you want, I want to try to see
if everything is okay.
It is only to check
if there is a problem with you or ...
Perhaps with Delphine, I don't know.
And Didier?
- He doesn't care.
He doesn't care?
- No.
It's not because you occasionally cheat,
that you don't love each other.
Well, it's like you want.
I just want to help.
You should not be embarrassed.
It does not matter.
I leave them on my rack for you to watch.
Find the limit of that function.
How can you find it?
By determining the derivative.
Jonas, what do you think of Nathalie?
Handsome.
- Yes.
I believed you thought she's ugly.
- No, why?
I don't know ...
It doesn't matter,
I have no problem with that.
What is cheating someone for you?
I do not know,
go to bed with someone else.
Are you sure?
- Yes.
I think it's not.
For me, someone is cheating,
if he stays with that person
without wanting that.
What do you mean?
Well, the guy who always dreams
to be with another woman,
but who never does it because he's afraid.
To me he is unfaithful,
while the guy who's in a good relationship
with his wife,
but occasionally does it with someone else
is not necessary unfaithful I think.
Besides, in your case
it's sex education,
it's not even about greed.
But it's when my father
began to cheat,
that it went wrong with my mother.
That might be because he does not distinguish
between love and sexuality.
I would not cheat on Delphine.
Okay. If you don't want to do anything with
Nathalie, no one will force you.
I'm not going to rape you.
We might be able to show you things.
Just looking, that's okay.
When you watched a porn movie,
you didn't cheat on Delphine.
- No.
This is the same.
But without a screen.
See?
Moreover, Didier and Nathalie like that.
It is important that
you say what you like.
Whether you want her to jack you off
or suck you right away.
You see, while ... you're in her mouth,
she needs to continue to jack you.
Softly, in the same rhythm.
If you want her to slow down,
you tell her.
Or that she firmly grips you,
or with a continuous motion.
That is especially good in the beginning.
She can caress your balls.
If you don't want to say it,
you just lay her hand on your balls.
So. Gently.
And when she enters?
- But no, she will not come.
You will like it.
What are you doing?
Let me.
Hold on, hold on.
Why?
I'm sorry.
You don't have much experience.
- No.
Does it bother you that we talk about it?
Then you have to say.
No, it's okay.
At your age I also was ...
- Nervous?
No, but I was not at ease.
The pleasure does not come easily.
You should be well supervised.
You have to dare to let go,
you have to trust each other.
It's not that simple.
It's all normal.
That will gradually be okay.
You know,
if you need advice, ask me.
I'm here for you.
Fine by me.
What is it?
- What did you tell them?
Nothing!
- Yeah, right.
Delphine, come on. Wait.
- No, I must go.
It's okay.
What are you doing? Stay!
- No, I don't want to.
The coordinates of the four points?
Concentrate, will you?
Excuse me.
What's up?
Nothing.
She'll call you. She panicked.
You have to understand her.
But you should not run after her.
Let her come back.
And concentrate now.
Reread the problem.
Specify on the graph points A 'B' C 'D',
the respective image of A, B, C, D
by the orthogonal symmetry
the axis of which is the straight line of the quotients,
Y is equal to X.
And give their coordinates.
I don't understand.
I have to concentrate on my work.
I don't prevent you from working.
Is it because of that night?
What have I done?
You've done nothing.
- Why are you so changed?
I'm no different.
- Yes you are.
I have to work, that's all.
Work well.
After a week you won't think about it anymore.
You will see, you will still
have enough adventures.
It is simply because you are evolving faster
than your peers.
It's normal that they're less interesting.
Now you have to ...
You have to concentrate,
otherwise it will not work.
But it doesn't matter.
It's normal, it's the 1st time.
It's normal that you want to believe
you're in love.
But you will see later, you will laugh.
You can't spoil everything
for the sake of a little adventure.
That's it.
Is it correct?
- Yes.
Really?
- Yes, it's perfect.
Bravo.
- Goodbye.
And good luck with the rest.
- Thank you.
Your hand down on the handle.
Turn it a little more to the right.
Okay.
- Like this?
Come on, you. Concentrate
- Okay.
Move, move.
Calm down.
- What?
Why do you hit so hard? Easy.
- Okay.
Wait, wait, a service,
here, Pierre.
Forward. Calm down.
What are you doing? More serious.
- Okay.
Come on, yeah. Forward.
That's better.
- Yeah, last one, quickly.
What? Come on. Okay.
- Come on.
Hi, Bernard.
Okay, just stop.
Hi, Jonas.
- Hello.
Hi.
Hello.
And?
- Success.
Super.
Bernard, Jonas has passed math.
- Bravo, Jonas.
On your success, Jonas.
- Same for chemistry.
Here, this is for you.
You're crazy.
- Thank you.
We are spoiled.
- I'm fond of gifts.
Yours is great.
- It's bigger, yes.
Thanks, it's fantastic.
Thanks, Jonas.
Thank you.
What is it?
No, you are thanked.
- For what?
What you have done for me.
It's not done yet, Jonas.
Come on.
Well, to your discoveries and ...
to freedom.
- And to freedom, right.
It was strong, huh?
Yeah, it was good.
And what if I would say that
Didier was the one sucking you?
How would you respond?
- I don't know ...
Well, Didier blew you.
You get the best blowjobs from other men.
And Didier?
Is he ... homosexual?
What do you think?
Nathalie is a boy?
It's not because you act homosexual
that you're gay.
I think we really
are all bisexual.
Then it's a matter of choice.
There are curious and courageous people
and there are others.
The weak, who tell make believe stories
and lie to themselves.
We are afraid of our natural
curiosity to approach one another.
But disapproval, inhibition,
that makes no difference.
Whatever you do,
where there is fear, there is desire.
Yeah, but I'm not attracted
to boys.
How can you say that
if you haven't tried it?
People who claim to be straight, without ever
trying to do something, make me laugh.
How can you say in a restaurant
whether a dish is good or bad,
if you have not tasted it?
When Didier blew you, it was the same
as with Nathalie. You noticed no difference.
But I'm not attracted to them.
If I see a boy, I feel nothing.
No, wait. I understand that.
I was like you.
Then, I started to doubt.
I needed to experience things first to
understand. I have evolved, and then ...
It's true, I've started
experiencing too late and ...
that's why I feel like I messed up my
childhood a little, but ...
But you ask yourself these question already,
so you're not far from the answer.
But at your age
I didn't have your maturity.
And you, do you sometimes have relationships
or are you gay?
No, I'm not gay.
What annoys me are men who act
like they are women.
When I was your age,
I was madly in love with a girl.
She was the woman of my dreams.
And then she was gone.
After that I never felt the same.
But good. There is something that I ...
There is something of great importance.
And that is that sex and feelings
are very different things.
I think that sex
is not that important.
You have to keep it in the right place.
Okay, Jonas?
I've had enough of it.
You should occasionally relax.
Otherwise, you can not hold on.
Calm down.
It's like with Didier.
Let yourself go.
Can you check that, please?
- Yes.
"Moment" is neuter, so ...
It is "it".
Where are you?
Yeah, shit.
No, but that's okay, Pascale.
That's okay.
Listen, here everything is fine.
I am super happy.
He works very well.
Yes, yes, but don't worry.
Really.
Okay, I'll ask him.
I will tell him that you called.
If anything, you call me.
Okay?
See you later. Yes.
What does she want now?
You should call her back.
She quarreled with her boss.
She went home.
Okay, sweetie?
Am I interrupting?
What is it?
Nothing. I'm just visiting.
May I come in?
Are you alone?
Yes.
Why don't you come see me?
I don't understand.
I have exams.
It's a little complicated.
I would like to have you at home.
Do you have it good here?
- Yes, it's good.
What is it?
Nothing.
Do you eat well?
- Yes.
You can give me your laundry if you want.
- Mom, stop it.
What do you mean, "stop"!
Don't you miss the garden?
No.
What is it, I do have the right to see you?
Yes, but not here.
Okay, you come to me.
If I have time.
You're gonna get some fresh air
from time to time?
I've got a lot of work, Mom.
I have the impression that you ...
That you don't realize it.
Do you know what it takes,
to succeed for the exam committee?
I have to continue working.
Here, give it to Pierre.
What will you do?
- I'm fine.
Take care of yourself, okay?
How was your day?
- Fine.
My mother came by.
What did she have to say?
- Baloney.
Here, she has given this for you.
Thank you.
What's that money for?
I don't know, it's for you.
She gives you nothing, and I get money
while I don't need it?
What does she think?
I don't do it for the money. Here, take it.
What does she imagine?
I like her, but ...
It's especially for you, that it hurts me.
Are you coming to eat?
Yes, I'm coming.
Turn around, turn around.
What?
- Turn around.
We don't even talk to each other.
I don't know how to approach it.
Will you talk to him?
If you want it, yes.
To you, he will say what's up.
And ...
If he has had enough of me,
You tell me, huh?
We don't see you anymore, Pierre,
that's too bad.
It's a lot of work, though.
Yes. You are not obliged
to spend your whole life with him.
You're not his father.
I have to finish it, that's all.
The people begin to believe
that you're a couple.
They think what they want.
I know very well what I'm doing.
The introduction, I think that's super.
Therefore, it's a pity ...
Because your statement is a bit ...
- Okay, it's good.
The Government will only next year
consider the issue of a social VAT.
Today we notice some
hesitations, some steps backwards,
an endless prevarication about
the second stage of reform?
The relationship between the government and the public
opinion and the media is sometimes ambiguous.
They accused the President
of going too fast, doing too much.
Now they're blaming him
for blocking new ideas.
There seems to be a need
for a clear economic policy ...
You know that the mass is equal to 32.
What do you need then?
Jonas, I'm asking you a question.
The mass is equal to 32.
I have no idea.
Damn.
You have to be a moron
to study sciences.
How could you be doing
five years of such bullshit?
Okay, calm down, and we resume the exercise.
All for a job that you dislike.
You can only teach brats.
I have already explained this 15 times.
Who is the moron then?
Well,
you calmed down?
We resume the exercise.
Jonas?
Leave me alone.
Leave me alone, damn.
You are disappointed, but that doesn't
mean you should talk to me like that.
You know I've done everything
to make sure you would succeed.
You don't care.
That's not what interests you.
What?
You don't care if I succeed.
That's not what interests you.
Stand up.
Damn! Stand up,
Let me go.
- And what interests me?
You don't have the right to
speak to me like that.
I did not deserve it.
Okay, I'm listening.
- Deze namiddag ik zal naar de sportclub gaan.
No, I told you that's not correct.
What a fucking shitty language.
- If you get agitated, I quit.
I'm not Pierre.
Without him, you would be nowhere.
Therefore, calm down;
He's not your dog.
He is not obliged
to do all that for you.
What is the first word of the sentence?
- No idea.
Is it the subject?
No.
Well then, we often talked about this.
What is the rule?
Conversion.
- So?
And where does the infinitive go?
Hi Jonas.
Everything okay?
What's happening?
- What are you going to tell?
What do you mean, what am I going to tell?
What did you say to Nathalie?
Nothing, I told her what happened.
Nothing more.
I also have my story to tell.
Did you tell it to Nathalie?
What then?
You have abused me.
Take it back immediately.
Leave, I don't want to see you anymore.
Do you know what abuse is?
Ask the cops what abuse is.
Poor victim.
Why didn't you tell me
you're a faggot?
Why didn't you tell me that?
It's not bad, huh?
I'm tired of everyone messing with me.
I'll take you home.
Let's go to your house.
You will see how it is there.
Come on.
I'll stay here,
I want to succeed for the exam committee.
I didn't think you were so opportunistic.
You're just a whore, Jonas.
You can continue your exam committee alone.
That's not what interests you.
Damn. What have I started!
I have listened to you, helped you.
You're crazy, dude.
Damn. Get out of here, Get out.
Listen.
From now on, we separate
the work from the rest.
I never forced you into anything.
Samantha Servais, adjourned.
Sion Christophe adjourned.
Patricia Steelman, succeeded.
Terlasen Bruno, succeeded.
Tellin Jrme, adjourned.
Thomas Bocamoussa, succeeded.
Oussalef Jennifer succeeded.
Vanbrussel Michelle, succeeded.
Vanguysegem Lift, adjourned.
Vanleer Jonas succeeded.
Vanvercorn Louise, adjourned.
Walravens Luc succeeded.