Previously on Defiance...
First we need to secure
his marriage.
If they're against us,
we'll never be able
to take control
of the McCawley mines.
I'm thinking about
our son's future.
Wanna come back
to my place later?
- What's at your place?
- Me.
No.
Come back and work with me.
I can't do this alone.
- No thanks. Not interested.
- You sure about that?
I finally got my hands
on one of the artifacts.
Yeah!
You'll never please your bride
with that shriveled worm of yours.
Your mother
didn't seem to mind.
- Who's next?
- Well, look at you.
You ain't worthy
of Christie McCawley.
Yes, he is!
Defend my honor, Alak.
Kick his ass.
On the eve of your wedding,
you've defeated
your savage brothers.
Now it's time to taste the
fruits of your victory.
I'm ready for you,
husband.
Rembu! Rembu! Rembu!
Boys.
____________
- Claim your wife.
- Another round, Jared.
- Koni shots for everyone!
- Casti punk.
Not until we get to see you
pony-mount your bride.
Ritual coitus
is so old-school.
It's 2046.
Wait, are you saying
no to your bride?
Are you?
Look, the thing is, Tirra,
my real bride would probably
have a problem with this.
Come on, man.
Nobody's gonna know.
Let it go, kupack.
I guess that's what happens
when you hook up with a Human.
Pink meat makes your
jondura go soft.
Hey!
Is that a hand?
_________
Holy shtako.
S01 Ep10
= The Bride Wore Black =
Sync and corrected by dr.jackson
for www.addic7ed.com
Christie.
You are a vision.
It's all because
of Kenya.
She made this dress.
She does have
an amazing touch.
Well, it's only
been worn once,
and it looks
much better on you
than it ever did on me.
Kenya, I'm sure
you were a stunning bride.
In another lifetime.
I'll see you both
tomorrow.
Christie,
in Human tradition
I understand
the mother of the bride
gives her daughter
something borrowed
to wear during
the ceremony.
As your mother's
not with us,
I thought I would give you
something I wore at my wedding.
When we boarded the ark, we were
only allowed to bring three items.
I took my family gem,
my diary, and this.
It's called a telo.
- How do I wear it?
- I'll show you.
My mother wore it,
and her mother before that.
You know, the Human phrase
daughter-in-law
is so cold, so distant.
Our word, hanya tavo,
means "heart daughter."
You are my hanya tavo,
Christie.
I can't see anything.
You're not supposed to.
In Castithan tradition,
the bride is blind
until her betrothed
opens her eyes
at the end
of the ceremony.
I'll never forget
the moment my handmaidens
lifted my telo.
At first,
the light was so bright.
But then, after a moment,
he came into focus.
My new husband.
It was magical.
It's beautiful.
I'm looking forward
to this wedding tonight.
- This town needs a party.
- Weddings are stupid.
Okay.
See, most people, Irisa,
they don't do everything alone.
They think life's
more meaningful
with someone
at their side.
Some even like to celebrate this
idea with friends and family.
You're going, right?
You're going. You're
gonna be my date.
- I don't date.
- Why not?
I'm from the badlands.
You see, when I first
came to Defiance,
I was nothing
but a card hustler.
Couldn't read or write,
never thought
I'd amount to anything.
Now I'm wearing
a badge.
- People change.
- You're an idiot.
So are you.
Wound's triangular.
Paperweight?
Possibly.
Whatever it was, our John Doe took
one pretty hard to the coconut.
That's one hell
of a big damn rock.
Obviously robbery
wasn't a motive.
I've seen that ring before.
This is no John Doe.
His name is Hunter Bell.
Who's that?
He owned the needwant back when
it was just a hotel and bar.
Slow down, hot shot.
Nobody cheats in
my establishment but me.
I'm not cheating.
__________
Back off, Datak.
I got this.
Kenya, bring these gentlemen
a free round.
Let's go.
What are you thinking trying
to hustle my poker table?
I'm thinking, damn, I'm gonna
get rich off these Casti punks.
They're crap players.
You got that right.
You gonna cut me?
First lesson's free.
So is this one.
You're not as slick
with the cards as you think.
Come with me.
- Hey, lawkeeper.
- Clancy.
Hey, Hunter.
Who's the kid?
My friend here just got off
the truck from Yosemite.
Needs a bed and a job.
Does he mind
scrubbing toilets?
He can't
get enough of it.
So you and this guy
were close?
Not exactly, but he helped me.
I owed him.
When did he go missing?
About seven years ago,
give or take.
I'd only been on the job
three days
when I caught
my first case.
My husband's missing.
Hunter had a lot
of enemies...
And most people figured
he'd blown town.
Except me.
I found one drop of blood,
and that's it.
If it was murder, why
isn't there more blood?
Somebody cleaned the floor.
They missed a drop.
Yeah.
Look, Hunter was a...
He owed money.
He got into a fight,
he lost a little blood,
and he hightailed it
out of Defiance.
No, look.
Okay, I've never
owned a home.
Never owned a business.
But in this day and age,
a man doesn't simply walk away
from their accomplishments.
Yeah, right.
Yeah, not a man like Hunter.
I think someone killed him.
Turns out, I was right.
We've been in town, what,
four months?
Never heard Kenya mention
a missing husband.
How do you know
it's Hunter?
I'm sorry.
Hunter owned the needwant.
When he was gone,
you took over, right?
It was in his will,
which is the same answer that
I gave you seven years ago.
Tommy, you wanna give us
a minute?
People thought
that he ran off,
but I knew that
he wouldn't do that.
You guys had a good thing?
Stop!
I miss him a lot.
I feel weird
officiating this wedding.
Well, Rafe asked you
personally.
Yeah, but that was before
Datak was my opponent.
The whole town will see
you standing up there
looking authoritative
and elegant.
It's good politics.
You know, Datak's putting all his
resources into this campaign.
- Should I be worried?
- Now listen.
You have a very strong track
record and my endorsement.
If Datak's going to beat you,
he's going to need
a lot more ammunition
than he's got right now.
Madam mayor?
Nolan.
Tommy.
You boys excited
about the wedding?
I hope you're both going
to save a dance for me.
Yes, ma'am.
We found
Hunter Bell's corpse.
- My God.
- Where was it?
He'd been murdered.
Body stashed in a hollow wall
in the needwant.
What is this?
I thought
you said he stopped.
This is just something
I got caught in a drawer.
Here's to my big sister,
the new assistant mayor.
Hunter's never gonna stop.
Someday you're gonna
be running this town.
He's never gonna change.
Hunter sees something in
me that no one else does.
Stop being so stupid!
He's gonna kill you!
Look at the choices that
you make with your life.
Look what you did to Connor.
Look what you did
to your own baby.
You don't even want to let
anybody into your life.
I have someone in my life. You.
And I'm not gonna let
anyone hurt you.
I think I'm old enough
to look after myself.
No, you can't, Kenya.
And if it comes to it, I
will do whatever it takes
to make sure he never
lays a hand on you again.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Mayor Nicky,
I'm gonna have to ask mayor
Rosewater some questions.
Yes, of course.
I'm really sorry
about Mr. Bell.
Hunter Bell was
your brother-in-law, right?
Yes.
You woulda known him
pretty well.
What was he like?
Charming, rich, handsome.
Maybe
a little bit dangerous.
He was a bully.
Did he...
Did he bully your sister?
No.
He loved her,
she loved him.
She was devastated
when he disappeared.
They're lying,
both of them.
Maybe.
You know, I think that Hunter
was beating on Kenya,
and Amanda could've killed him
to protect her sister.
Or Kenya killed him, and
Amanda's lying to protect her.
So what are you gonna
do about it?
I'm gonna go home,
put on some fresh clothes,
and go to a wedding.
Nolan.
A man was killed.
A bad man,
long time ago.
You're gonna try to bury this,
aren't you?
It's my job
to keep the peace,
not run around like Sherlock
Holmes chasing old ghosts.
What about justice?
Make sure you wear
a tie tonight.
My daughter is not wearing this
hockey mask at her wedding.
This is an heirloom.
Show some respect.
She'll be able to see when
she's walking down the aisle,
and folks will be able
to see her.
A Castithan wedding
isn't a wedding
if the bride doesn't wear
her telo.
I'm the one footing
the bill for this thing.
Christie wears
what I say she wears.
You Humans believe
you're so superior.
The truth is
you're primitives.
Your minds are dull,
your hands are clumsy.
The scent of your pink skin
sickens me.
Does this skin
look pink to you?
You all look the same.
Let me ask you something.
You hate Humans so much,
why are you letting
your boy marry one?
- Well, Alak wishes it.
- No.
You've been good
with this the whole time.
So I gotta ask myself,
what's your angle?
What do you get out
of this wedding?
I believe in love.
You know, I was thinking
about how the McCawley mines
are built on land stolen
from Irathient settlers.
Now that's a tainted legacy
that I do not want
to leave to our kids.
So when I die, my
mines go to a trust
benefiting the Irathient
population of Defiance.
You do think I'm doing
the right thing,
don't you, Datak?
Well, they're your mines,
Rafe.
I don't care
what you do with them.
Good.
Breakfast is on me.
The wedding is off!
Datak, I understand
you're upset,
but if Christie does not want
to wear the telo...
It's not about
the gwoking telo.
Rafe McCawley has written
Christie out of his will.
The mines are going
to the I-raths.
Rafe may say that now,
but be patient.
Once his first
grandchild arrives,
he'll reconsider.
I will not wait.
Instead I will win
this election.
Then when I'm mayor,
I will find a way
to take the mines away
from Rafe McCawley.
How does Alak
feel about this?
Alak's a child.
He'll get over it.
My parents would not have
wanted me to marry you.
And yet, here we are.
Alak is more pliable
than either of us at his age.
We were immigrants.
We were strong
because we had to be.
Alak will never
have to endure
the same hardships we did,
and I thank Rayetso for that.
Don't you want him
to be happy?
Our son loves
this Human girl.
She makes him smile.
She lifts his spirits in a way
that nobody else can.
A Castithan woman can
lift his spirits... just fine.
Alak is of this New World.
He doesn't see the Humans
the way we do.
He sees beauty in them.
Kindness.
Then he's lost
the sense of smell.
Maybe you have too.
I'm calling the priest.
Perhaps Alak should be the first
to hear of your decision.
You know, Nolan should
really be here right now.
It's a waste of time.
Yeah, looking for evidence
is a big waste of time.
You want evidence?
You know,
if I ran things
I'd have five deputies
combing over every inch
of this place.
You don't need
five deputies.
What is that, a hair?
Whisker.
Liberata.
Jered.
Jered the bartender was working
here when Hunter owned it.
Jered, it's Tommy.
You around?
Jered?
- It's locked.
- So?
So we've got
to go back to Nolan
and get a warrant
or something.
- We can't just...
- Can't just what?
Poor Jered.
His throat's been slit
earlobe to earlobe.
Just like Elah Bandik.
Someone didn't
want him to talk.
- Why are his fingers like that?
- I don't know.
Maybe nitrogen depravation.
This has all the markings
of a Casti hit.
When I was about your age,
the arks were going through
their final preparations.
I had just won passage
playing ivali.
But my father
refused to leave home.
I don't understand.
Why would he stay
on a dying planet?
He said if the suns were
to swallow up our world,
he needed to be inside
the walls of the holy temple.
He could not leave the Castithan
scrolls unattended.
Not even in the face
of death.
- Do you know why?
- No.
Because he'd made that promise
to his own father.
Fine.
I'll talk to Christie
about the telo.
When I gave you permission
to marry outside of our race,
I knew it was a dishonor
to my father's memory.
But I let you
and your mother sway me.
I was wrong.
Dad. No.
I regret allowing it
to have come this far.
But you are my only son, Alak.
And our Castithan blood
will not be diluted.
Do you understand?
No, no, no,
I don't understand.
Okay, I love her.
This is bullshtak.
Watch yourself.
Without the name Tarr,
you're nothing.
Nothing but a street haint
with dyed hair
and a record collection.
Street haint?
Isn't that
how you see yourself?
You're always talking
about how you pulled yourself
out of the mud and made
the Humans respect you.
I said to watch
your tongue.
I don't give
a kanga rat's ass
about the sacred scrolls.
All right, maybe
your father chose to die
guarding a bunch
of stupid papers,
but I wasn't born on Casti
I was born on Earth,
just like Christie.
And we're getting married.
I didn't expect you
to be happy about this,
but you will obey my wishes.
Or what,
you're gonna slit my throat?
That's the Casti way.
I'll give you time
to cool off.
Datak.
Not now, lawkeeper.
- Can't wait.
- Will wait.
Datak Tarr,
you're under arrest.
On what charges?
For the murder of
Jered Kikema and Hunter Bell.
- Hey.
I'm so excited.
I even decided
to wear the telo.
I know I said
I didn't want to,
but then I was thinking,
my wedding...
My dream of what
I wanted it to be like
when I was a little kid...
That's never gonna happen
because my mom
won't be there,
my brothers
won't be there.
All that matters
is that you're there.
And if it makes
your parents happy
for me to wear
a metal mask over my face,
- then so be it.
- Christie...
There's something
that I need to tell you.
Christie?
What did you do? What
did you say to her?
It's my father.
He... he's trying
to stop the wedding.
I don't know what to do.
I can't live without her.
- You really love her, don't you?
- Yes, sir.
Then that's all
that matters.
Why in the three hells
would I kill
a knee-high
Liberata bartender?
Maybe because he knew
you killed Hunter Bell.
Or maybe because
he helped you hide the corpse.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
- You don't recognize this?
- No!
Really?
'Cause we found that
in your closet.
And that handle,
that matches the caved-in part
of Bell's skull
like a key fits a lock.
Well, I've never seen it
before in my life.
Tommy tells me
that you and Bell
were in business
together.
Yeah. You might say that.
- You're asking for a raise?
- I'm asking for a stake.
I built this tent.
Quadrupled profits
every month.
- I deserve it.
- Look who's all grown up.
When I first came to town,
you were running brawls
in dark alleys,
jacking rollers
on Urdu street.
My money made you, Tarr.
Don't ever forget that.
With all due respect, I
suggest you reconsider.
You know,
in some cultures
when a man
challenges the chief,
there's a fight
until only one of them
is left standing.
You want power?
Power isn't seen. It's felt!
How does that feel?
What's wrong,
can't win a fair fight?
I win.
That's all that matters.
Drop the blade
or I drop you.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I believe
your life expectancy
has taken a turn
for the worse.
Why did you do it?
Yeah, well,
call me old-fashioned,
but I believe
in a fair fight.
Yes, you are old-fashioned,
right down to your choice
of antique weapons.
Well, I like to hit
what I'm aiming at,
and my aim isn't
always too good.
I'll try to remember that.
That clown's making
a move on my mines.
I imagine you have
no intention
of allowing that to happen.
See, normally I wouldn't
think you and I
have much in common,
but when it comes
to our friend Hunter Bell,
I think we do.
Let me buy you a drink.
I wish I had the pleasure of
hearing Hunter Bell's last breath,
but I'm afraid
someone else beat me to it.
Whoever it is,
they're trying to frame me.
They planted that walking
stick in my closet.
Any idea who?
I pay my taxes
so people like you
can figure things
like that out.
Get out of here! Go on.
- What was that?
- Theater.
Datak Tarr
is an egomaniac.
If he had killed
Hunter Bell,
that body wouldn't be
holed up in a wall.
It'd be on display
in the town square.
So then why did
we bring him in here?
Now he's good
and riled up,
maybe he'll lead us
to the person who framed him,
the real killer.
You knew this
this whole time?
Why didn't you tell me?
Thought you'd be
more convincing this way.
Where I come from, framing a
man is the act of a coward.
Tarr, I don't know
what you're talking about.
Hunter Bell.
You had as much reason
to kill him as I did.
Why not just have the jondura to
admit it instead of implicating me?
You really think I killed
that sack of shtako?
Well, if you didn't do it,
who did?
Don't know, don't care. I
have a wedding to attend.
- The wedding is off.
- That's what Alak said at first.
Then we started talking.
Your son loves my daughter,
and my daughter loves him,
and that's good enough
for me.
He may never get
my mines,
but I will
look out for him.
And I will make sure
that those kids
have a wedding that they
will always remember.
Please.
We should get over there.
The ceremony's
about to begin.
Dr. Yewll? I got your message.
I'm just on my way
to the wedding.
I won't keep you long.
Would you mind
locking the door?
Have you come
to a decision?
Are we partners again?
We'll get so much farther
working together.
This isn't about
the artifact.
Our favorite Liberata
bartender was killed today.
No, how sad.
A Casti charge blade
slit his throat.
Datak Tarr.
Why am I not surprised?
Nicolette.
It's me you're talking to.
I had no choice.
He was the only person who knew
that we killed Hunter Bell.
There was no reason
to hurt him.
Jered has known the truth
for seven years,
and he never said a word.
It was preemptive.
I was exposed once, doctor.
I couldn't risk that
happening again.
Well, vision seems to be
functioning okay.
I told you, I'm fine.
It's just this damn ache
in my arm and leg.
Okay.
Let's take a look at it.
Okay, wiggle your fingers.
How did you get in here?
Kenya slipped.
I needed some salve.
Well, get out.
This is a sterile
environment.
Thought you might come by.
Excuse the renovations.
Drink, ladies?
Or should I call you
something else?
I'm afraid there's been
a misunderstanding.
Yes, there certainly has.
The citizens of this town believe
their mayor is a Human being.
- What do you want?
- Well, let's start with the truth.
'Cause I am bubbling over
with curiosity.
- I am an Indogene, Mr. Bell.
- Nicky...
Camouflaged biologically
to appear Human.
What are you,
some sort of spy?
There is something very important
in this town, Mr. Bell.
In the wrong hands,
it could be very dangerous.
We're here to prevent
that happening.
We're here to protect Earth.
- Yeah? For my kind or your kind?
- For all kinds.
Well, I don't want to get in
the way of your important job,
so why don't you give me
a cool hundred "G"
to keep that secret of yours
nice and safe.
I've heard what an enterprising
young man you are.
- Quite the negotiator to boot.
- This isn't a negotiation.
You're right about that.
You psycho piece of shtako.
You chuping killed him.
I was afraid I hadn't
hit him hard enough.
Jered, dear.
Would you mind helping us
clean up this mess?
Relax, doctor. It's
all cleaned up.
- It's over.
- Yes, I suppose it is.
You know, when I first
came to this town,
I wanted to start over.
I wanted to right my wrongs,
and you...
Well, you told me everything
that I wanted to hear.
You were my inspiration.
But you changed.
You unleashed the Volge,
Nicky.
You murdered
a harmless bartender.
It has become
painfully clear to me
that there is no end
to the lives
that you're willing
to sacrifice
for what you call
the greater good.
If I can't trust you
with a simple walking stick,
how am I supposed to trust you
with a genocidal weapon?
The first needle
was a paralytic.
It'll stop you from struggling
and also from experiencing pain.
You know, I've changed too.
I've become a healer
instead of a destroyer.
And that's why I'm so sorry
for what I have to do.
But it's for
the greater good.
Good-bye, old friend.
There. You look beautiful.
Didn't think
I'd be this nervous.
You have nothing
to be nervous about,
as long as you remember
that your husband
is your partner
and your equal,
and you are never gonna let him
treat you as anything less.
No.
Christie, can I have
a word with you, please?
Good luck. Bye, Stahma.
I understand you're not
comfortable wearing the telo.
- It's all right, really.
- So I made this for you instead.
An old world bridal veil?
I copied it from a book.
- Stahma, you didn't have to.
- I wanted to.
As my grandmother
said to my mother
on the day
of her wedding...
__________
Datak accused Rafe
of framing him.
- I don't buy it.
- Nor do I.
Dad.
It's okay, Alak.
Here, give me your hand.
You okay?
- Weddings are just weird for me.
- Yeah, I get that.
No knives?
Why is she not wearing
the telo?
I don't know.
Nicky isn't here.
That's strange.
Red's fingers.
I knew I'd seen that
somewhere before.
The Liberatas
during the war
when the EMC used
oxygen bombs...
That's what
they looked like.
Liberata breathe nitrogen,
not oxygen.
Oxygen poisoning.
Today is a special day,
an important day
for Defiance.
That's why I didn't
want to spoil it
with my presence.
I killed Hunter Bell
for what I thought was
the betterment of this town.
When his body
was recently discovered,
I killed Jered Kikema,
whose only crime
was witnessing my own.
I realize it's only
a matter of time
before the lawkeeper
discovers the truth.
With my health, I'll never
survive Vegas prison.
So I've decided
to end my life.
I told myself I was acting
for the greater good.
But that kind of thinking
leads you down a dark road.
I can only hope
I've left the town I love
in better hands
than my own.
I'm sorry.
She used to be
good people.
Sometimes good people
do bad things.
Congratulations, kid. You
solved your first case.
Yeah, I just
can't believe it.
- Mayor Nicky.
- I know.
People are
a mystery, kid.
Sometimes even
to themselves.
And they all have secrets.
Only rule I know
is that every time you think
you have them figured out,
they change.
We all do.
Sync and corrected by dr.jackson
for www.addic7ed.com
Previously on warehouse 13...
He killed my friend.
An alchemist used a stone
to keep my body from aging.
If I blow your heart
out of your chest,
do you think that'll stop you?
I'm gonna guess
that's Charlotte.
No!
Myka!
A poisoned dart.
A 15year-old boy?
Yeah, Nick Powell.
Why don't you come back
to South Dakota with us?
Nick, hey.
How's it going, man?
We could be looking
at ovarian cancer.
- Hey, mykes.
- Hey.
What are you doing up?