Timing &amp; subtitles brought to you by Gone with the Shirt Team @ Viki
Episode 17
Please everyone, I have one thing to say.
Let's gather in the big hall.
Don't act alone. As long as we're all together,
Fu Hongxue will have no opportunity to hurt anyone.
Well said. No matter how dangerous Fu Hongxue is,
he can't handle all of us.
You've been guarding the Hall for several nights, you must be tired.
What are you up to now?
I see you working hard earning a living,
let's make a deal.
Deal. What type of deal?
Something that'll earn you some money.
What do you want us to do?
Release me and let me see the big boss.
You think you can just walk in to see him?
I have important information for him.
What kind of trick are you playing?
Release me. Not only will you earn some money,
you will also get some recognition.
This win win situation, why not take advantage?
Search carefully.
When I see the big boss,
I will definite praise all of you.
How dare you,
to betray Ten Thousand Hall!  We won't dare.
I'll deal with you later.
You've already been driven out of Ten Thousand Hall.
Why are you still here?
I wan to see the boss and tell him about Fu Hongxue's past.
I haven't forgotten 5 year ago, you tried to trick big boss.
If it wasn't for the Miss, I would have killed you with my sword.
GonSun Duan, Ten Thousand Hall is under serious threat.
If you're really concerned then stay out of my way.
Be quiet!
How can someone like you help?
Fine. If you won't leave,
then don't blame me. Guards.
Here. Take her away.
Yes sir!
Enjoy your stay.
Put her in there.
Why are you here?
How are you?
Let me ask. Where were you on the day Murong Mingzhu died?
You really want to ask me,
if I killed Murong Mingzhu.  Did you kill him?
No.
On wedding day, everyone was there except you.
If you're not the killer then who?  You don't believe me.
Why won't I believe you?
Actually, I rather the killer is you.
At least it proves that you returned because of me.
You belong to the demon sect, right?
Right, I belong to the demon sect.
I really don't care.
What really mattered was why did you tell me
you were an assassin?  Why did you lie?
I wanted to tell you the truth.
Knowing I must kill you
I just can't do it.
But you still lied.
Yes, I lied.
I was deceitful back then,
trying to get close to Ten Thousand Hall and you.
But you changed my mind.
Leave quickly.
I know there is a secret tunnel.
Only known to me and my father.
I'll take you.  No, I can't leave yet.
Why?  Because I need to capture Heaven Dog,
to prove my innocence.
But everyone thinks you're the killer. They're after you.
You must face not only Heaven Dog but also everyone else.
I'll tell them you're innocent.
No. That's unnecessary.
If you do that, then they'll think you're covering up for me.
Then how can I help?
Just stay safe.
Say no more. Do nothing. Wait for my news.
You're alone. What if something should happen?
Miss.  I should leave.
Promise me you'll be fine.
Wait for me.
Miss. Are you there?  Coming.
Gonsun da ge, what can I do for you?
Have you seen anything strange inside?
Nothing. What's happening?
Fu Hongxue may be nearby.
I'll stand guard outside. Just call if you need me.
Fine. I'll take a rest.
Timing &amp; subtitles brought to you by Gone with the Shirt Team @ Viki
I just took a headcount,
other than the 38 horse slaves in the cell
and Flying spider who has left, the dead Murong young master, and Left sect leader,
everyone else should be here. Total is 181 people.
No trace of Fu Hongxue.
You're an intelligent woman.  Keep quiet.
I thought you're smart but you still foolish things.
No matter what, you shouldn't consider suicide.
What...even you're scalding me.
I won't dare. I swear
that I nothing will happen to you.
Ye Kai, let me ask you something. You're always joking around,
are you really happy?
Of course. Why won't I be happy?
I'm the leaf on a tree, heart of joy.
Kai (opening) of the word "happy"
You're right.
I used to think I was happy.
What I want, I get.
After I met him, I discovered I was only fooling myself.
He must have drugged you.
Do you know anything about real love?
What a joke. I"m a casanova.
Thousands of beauties cannot capture me.
Not wilingl or won't dare?
Yes, you're willing to help anyone in need.
But have you ever thought
there is someone different in this world.
When I'm with him, the way I see him is different.
Even talking to him feels different.
If I can't be with him,
then life becomes meaningless.
See him with different eyes,
how different?
Just like how Ding Linglin watches you.
I'm really fine.
If you have time, then go spend it with Ding Linglin.
You two haven't spoken a word these past few days.
She must be upset.
Miss Ding. There is nothing between us. You're assuming too much.
I'm not over assuming. You're just too thoughtless.
What are you doing?
Stop drinking. You already drank too much.
Stop bothering me. What's with your World's fastest sward.
acting like a bothersome dog I can't shake off.
If I''m a bothersome dog, then
you're a bone dangling in front of me.
You!
So annoying.
Quick. Come closer.
Miss Ding, I have something to say to you.
Ye Kai,
can't you see that the two of us are happily drinking here?
You two? No way.
Why not?
Brother Lu is brave and handsome. And is extremely considerate.
I should really thank you.
If not for you, then I won't have met him.
For real?
How long since you met?
It was love at first sight.
When a boat gets to a bridge, it will automatically straighten.
Oh right, Brother Lu, In a few days, aren't we going to the hot springs?
Hot springs?
That's right.
Hot springs,
sounds great. Great for circulation and extend your longivity.
When you go soaking in hot springs, are you dressed or naked?
Idiot! Who wears clothes soaking in hot springs?
Right.  Naked! You...
Right. No clothes.
You...
You...you...what about us?
Fine. That's your business.
Then why are you standing there like a pole?
Here's some wine.
You're acting like a crazy drunkard.
Fine. Miss Ding.
Based on our past relationship,
can I ask a favor?
What relationship?
What do you want?
Something strange about Heaven Dog's killing in the Ten Thousand Hall.
I probably can't capture him by myself.
If you're willing to help, then we can definitely get him.
Wulin experts are everywhere,
why ask me?
These people may be skilled, but you're the only medical expert here.
I thought the only lead to capture the killer, must be hidden in the dead body.
Only now do you think of me.
I must ask if Lu gē is okay with this.
Brother Lu, is it okay?
No way.
You brat how could you have no code of brotherhood?
Whenever Sister Ding is with you she always gets hurt.
This time, there is no way I'm letting you have her!
Well said.
If Brother Lu doesn't agree, then I can't help it.
Hero Lu, I promise you I won't disrespect your precious Miss Ding.
I won't insult her, won't let her come to her. Is that okay?
Really?
Then if it's like this, if I say something you cannot disagree.
If I say go East, you can't tell me to go West.
Fine.
Run from here to there and from there to here. 100 times.
Aren't you being ridiculous now?
Exactly.
Do you not want my help now?
Fine, I'll run.
Run! Run!
Faster!
Run faster!
Stupid fool.
I already said it before! You need me with you, there's no way you don't need me!
Miss Ding, then when are we going to go to the hot springs without our clothes?
In your dreams.
I say, why are you women always so weird?
I've missed you so much!
Today you've ended up in our hands, this feels great!
In awhile I will satisfy you!
Should you strip first? Or should we strip first?
Hurry hurry!
The grand masters are here!
This blade is quick, be careful you don't hurt yourself.
I know how to use a knife. Don't worry.
You obviously know who I am.
You know I want to kill you.
Why are you here to save me?
No reason.
Was Murong Mingzhu killed by you?
No.
How much money did the Ten Thousand Horse Hall give you that you are here selling your life?
Seems like Fang Ling never told you about me.
Ma Fang Ling?
Have you not heard about how she has an older sister who grew up with her?
You are her sister?
Do you want the truth?
Of course.
We are not blood related.
My mother is just a servant working in their house.
She was raped.
Then she gave birth to me.
In order to protect me and let me stay with the Ma family,
she didn't let me interact with anyone else,
until I met Fang Ling.
She took care of me.
She even made her father take me as their god daughter.
But my mother... in order to let me leave the manor earlier,
she killed Fang Ling's mother.
I owe her.
So I have to protect the Ten Thousand Horse Hall,
protect Ma Fang Ling.
Anyone who hurts them is my enemy.
So you only live because you have a debt to repay.
But me, I live to claim a debt.
That's why heaven let us meet. That's quite funny.
You were together for so long,
so the two of you are similar in many ways.
Alike? I don't think so.
There is at least one point in common.
When you both talk to me, you like to keep a knife at my throat.
You're wrong.
We are not the same.
She uses a knife at your neck because
she is angry at you.
But me, I really want to kill you.
If you had to choose between one of us,
who would you choose?
Leave.
Leave the Ten Thousand Horse Hall.
Now it is not safe here.
You think I will leave so easily?
Someone come! There's an intruder!
Timing &amp; subtitles brought to you by Gone with the Shirt Team @ Viki
It's been two hours but nothing has changed.
It seems you are wise. As long as we are together,
that Heaven Dog will definitely not come!
No matter how great he is, there is no way he will dare go against so many people.
But us just sitting here, is not a method.
Big Boss! Something went wrong!
Flying Spider has died!
What happened?
Big Boss. At the main entrance
we discovered Flying Spider's body.
Damn that Heaven Dog. If you have any guts, come out and
let's fight to death.
Again, died of thirteen knife wounds.
He also cut off his right arm. He's so cruel.
Is that Heaven Dog even human?
Heaven and earth are disturbed.
Ma Kongqun.
you allow two people die for you.
You're the leader of Wulin's largest sect but you're such coward.
Are you still human?
Heaven Dog. Come out!
Come out. Show yourself.
Come out! Come out.
Come out now.
Quiet. Quiet.
Heaven Dog is intentionally messing with your concentration.
If you act this way, you're walking right into his trap.
Ma Kongqun.
You're wasting your time. You can't kill me.
Ma Kongqun. You can't kill me. Ha ha.
Open the door.
Don't kill him. He's a fake.
He's not Heaven Dog. He's the leader of Zulongshan, Bao Erlei.
How is that possible?
I just saw him in the main hall.
He's not Heaven dog but a scapegoat.
Ma Kongqun. That's the third person.
This time you helped me killed with your own hand.
I should thank you.
You killed without batting an eye. You animal!
Animal. You're the animal.
You killed them. They died for you.
No one will hate me. They hate only you. Ma Kongqun.
Come out. You come out!
Come out. Heaven Dog!
Don't think I'm afraid of you. Come out!
Look at yourself. Your strength is useless.
You can't hurt me.
If you don't die, I will keep playing with you.
Come out, Heaven Dog!
Heaven and earth are disturbed. Bloody eyes and dark moons.
One Ten Thousand Horse Hall. Knifes weakens, people loses their innards.
Ma Kongqun. If you add Murong young master, that's
4 people.
As the leader of Ten Thousand Horse Hall, shouldn't you do something?
What do you mean by that?
Fu Hongxue just said, after every set time
he will kill one person until everyone's dead.
Only way to stop him
is for you to commit suicide.
You mean for me to die?
I don't want you dead. It's Heaven Dog that wants you dead.
We only received the invitation to attend the wedding.
You're dispute with Heaven Dog is none of our business.
Only thing for us to do is to leave here safely.
If you want to leave safely,
then we should kill the murderer together.
Ma sect leader, don't blame me if I say anything rash.
From my perspective, you're not his equal.
If we continue like this, we'll all
die needlessly.
You're rude.
GongSun Duan, have you forgotten what Fu Hongxue said?
As long as Ma Kongqun is alive, after each set time
he'll kill one of us.
Maybe the next time is you.
You!
Ma Kongqun. You're Wulin's big brother.
Now act like a big brother.
Normally, Ten Thousand Horse Hall assigns us tasks.
Now it's time for you to do something for us.
Are you afraid to die?
Yuan Village leader, no matter what you're still an elder.
Do you realize what you've said is helping the Demon sect?
You became his accomplice.
Are we his accomplice or
you, Ma Kongqun, is his accomplice?
Wu Sec leader, are you inciting a mutiny?
You're life is a life but what about us?
Our lives are not lives?
We want to continue to live.
Do you think if I die, you'll be able to live?
If I die, it'll be easier for him to kill you.
My only hope is to save everyone.
If you don't trust me, the door is open.
You're free to leave. I won't stop you.
Those that stay can help me find the killer.
If anyone can find the murderer
I will reward him.
He can take any one thing he wants from the Ten Thousand Horse Hall.
That includes your precious daughter?
As I said already,
he can take anything he wants from Ten Thousand Horse Hall.
Father.
Is the Ma Big Boss going crazy?
How can he use his daughter as a reward?
He's not crazy. Every Central Plain Sect is here.
This incident is not so simple as Heaven Dog killing someone.
The entire Wulin world will see a major shuffle.
Now Murong Mingzhu is dead. The contract between the families is automatically nullified.
Ma Kongqun can choose another son-in-law.
If Ten Thousand Horse Hall can survive
then isn't this a wonder way to remake the world scene.
Big boss...something bad has happened.
Big boss. Fu Hongxue kidnapped the Miss. He's coming this way alone.
Fu Hongxue. What have you done with Miss Cui Nong?
Where is she?
Rest assured. She's safe.
You shouldn't have locked her in the cell where it's very dangerous.
Pull your sword.
Why?
Let me see if there is blood on it.
You suspect I killed the people and the horses.
Just now, everyone was at the Ten Thousand Horses Hall.
Only you were missing. Of course I suspect you.
Too bad I didn't kill them.
I said again. Pull your sword.
Stop! You said you're not the murderer.
What evidence do you have?
I don't have any.
Then how can we believe you?
I will personally capture the killer and bring him to you.
Boss Ma, if I kill the Heaven Dog,
whatever I want at Ten Thousand Hall, I will get.
I give you my word.
I would never thought, Fu Hongxue is such a power grabber.
Nothing wrong to want power.
Especially if Ten Thousand Hall has something he wants.
Come with me.
Go in.  What for?
Leave here. Now they all believe you're Heaven Dog.
Given an opportunity, they'll try to kill you.  They won't be able to.
Fu Hongxue. Can't you listen to me for once?
I'm not worried about gossips or being blamed,
I just want you to live.
Hongxue, I'm really afraid.
What do you fear?  I fear losing you.
Even if I can ever marry you,
even if we can't live together until we die,
I only want you alive.
Go quickly.  I won't leave.
I will definitely capture Heaven Dog. Keep yourself safe.
Father.
Young Fu Master. My daughter was frightened.
If she was impolite, please excuse her.
Boss Ma, you're being too polite.
Looks like the incident 14 years ago when fire burned the Demon Sect hasn't concluded.
No only the fire incident 14 year ago hasn't been solved
I suspect the murder at Plum Blossom Monastery wasn't solved either.
Fu young master, what thoughts do you have about this?
Same as your thoughts.
Since we have Fu young master stepping forward to help
I'm so much more confident.
If I capture the Heaven Dog,
don't forget your promise.
I keep my promises.
Ling'er. Fu young master is right.
This most important thing now is self protection.
Don't worry about anything else.
Ten Thousand Horses Hall has many capable fighter plus the help of Fu young master.
I'm confident the villain will not succeed.
Since there is nothing else. Ling'er you should go rest in your room.
Feng Mantian.  Here.
Accompany the Miss to her room.
Miss. This way.
Fu Hongxue.
I always thought you have no interest in other's business.
Never thought you can be so considerate.
Why do you want to capture Heaven Dog?
My guess is...this has something to do with you.
You're overthinking. I only want to help.
Lately I keep thinking about one thing that relates to you.
I know your mother is Demon Sect's oldest princess, Hua Beifeng.
Who is your father? Bai Tianyu.
Not a bad guess, hum?
Why do you look for trouble?
Because I like trouble. Fu Hongxue.
To be friends, you shouldn't try to hide or keep everything in.
If there is a need, I can help you.
I don't need it.  You need it.
You only have 2 ways when facing this type of situation.
One is anger. The other is endure.
With only these two methods you won't be able to manage.
Ye Kai. What do you plan to do?
As rumor has it, Heaven Dog killed your father 12 years ago.
You must find Heaven Dog. Let's work together.
This is my own business.
Fu Hongxue. Ten Thousand Horses Hall is the center of public criticism.
Don't be the boat for arrow practice  (scapegoat).
Life is our own.
That's where you are. I finally found you.
Fu Hongxue. Everyone wants to kill you.
I must keep a good eye on you
otherwise the tasty morsel will get stolen.
Look, Fu Honxue. I also have a boat.
It's large and steady. On board there are friends.
Why not come aboard?
I hope next time we meet,
you haven't drowned.
This Fu Hongxue is strange.
What is he thinking?
Don't worry needlessly. What about the task I gave you?
I asked around. Murong Mingzu's body
is placed in Zewei Court. Only one watchman. No one will block us.
Fine. You go look for Murong family's idiot swordsman.
I'm going to reminisce the past with Murong young master.
What? What do you have to say to a dead person?
Sometimes, the dead can talk.
Don't scare me. No way.
What Brother Ye meant is no matter how clever a murderer is
he'll leave some traces when killing a person.
If we find the traces, then we'll discover some clues.
Then it's like dead talking to us.
I think you're more enthusiastic talking to the dead than to me.
Why is there a fire?
Who's so unfortunate? Where is that?
Oh.Isn't that where Murong Mingzue is placed, Zewei Court?
Help with the fire. Get water quick!
How did it catch fire?
We don't know. Help with the fire.
Quick.
Oh no. The information must have leaked out.
The killer wants to destroy the evidence.
Now what? He's a step ahead of us.
At least our suspicion is validated. They came to burn Murong Mingzu's body
means there is something we want on those bodies.
Now the killer knows we're investigating.
I suspect he'll want to kill us too.
Come get us.
I must see this to the end.
That's right. Let's go.
Quick. This way. Quick.
What are you doing?
Where are you going?
Do I need to tell you where I'm going?
Did you set the fire over there?
No.
What do you want?
Perfect. I also want to look over there. Let's go together.
Then you go. I'm not interested.
Fu Hongxue. You wait.
I will definitely find the evidence. You're not to leave here alive.
Mother.
Who is this woman?
She doesn't appear to be a commoner.
Fu Hongxue actually called her mother. She must belong to the Demon Sect.
She appears to be very competent.
Looks like things are progressing well.
I did as you instructed.
However on the wedding day, someone disguised as Heaven Dog suddenly appeared.
Heaven Dog?
Yes. He's killed many people.
Now the Ten Thousand Horses Hall is in chaos.
Everyone is afraid the next victim will be them.
What about Ma Kongqun?
Ma Kongqun is also struggling.
Just punishment. Ten Thousand Horses Hall's just punishment.
Timing &amp; subtitles brought to you by Gone with the Shirt Team @ Viki