In previous episodes.
What did you put in the stamps Chaz?
Codeine and morphine to soften the brain.
Take in as soon as it will not.
You are married.
but it is in cahoots with Sykes.
Flying to be careful that your mother is not a crime.
I ask you a favor.
My new assistant.
In business, the easiest to forget,
these are the feelings of others.
2 weeks ago
because of its
with senior managers ".
and if it looks back
and served coffee.
but we all do.
How are you?
Very good.
I'm very good.
It does not work yet.
I am too well the small tasks to be entrusted me big.
I trust you and believe in you.
It does not displease me to be your assistant. Simply ...
- I could do more. - It will come.
I promise you.
You'll be late for an appointment with Mr. Gracen.
The FBI will land next week
and accuse me of selling missiles to China.
What are their sources?
They come from the government and are infallible.
It's not you, but one of our subsidiaries, Wong Industries.
The board does not care.
I wanted this deal. If they open the investigation, I'm fired.
It is a new redemption, we can break before the survey.
By aligning 100 million dollar fine?
The board châtrerait me.
Wong selling missile components to the Chinese.
We must get rid of them quickly
without paying a fine.
For that, I need your help.
I know you will reach there in one way or another.
Wong is equally disturbed Industries
by the FBI investigation that you, Mr. Profit.
We shall break our relationship before the start of the investigation.
I do not think it will be possible.
Why did you agree to see me?
Come into my office.
The device is called
Ultrachip, you know?
It is a descrambler.
Its user can penetrate all systems. It has been developed.
It was Dr. Jeremy Batewell who developed
and embarked upon leaving your company.
It is coveted by your Ministry of Defence.
I understand. You also want.
And how!
You will break our agreements if you get it back? No fine?
Absolutely.
If I were the suspicious type,
I would think that you have this handset to retrieve it.
I wish you success.
The good doctor Jeremy Batewell.
in G & G for 5 years.
Ultrachip the descrambler.
for unknown reasons.
of intense speculation
Washington and elsewhere.
Sadly
at G & G was shortened
who accused him of sexual harassment.
was returned.
s'appelait Gail Koner.
You remember her.
The temptress of hell. You know her?
I can enter?
G & G wants to talk about what happened?
to keep you returning.
it misinterpreted
emotional and fleeting.
What is your interest in all this?
This is my assistant. I like it.
She would like to buy but do not dare take the first step.
You are telling me
she wants me?
I almost go to court to get rid of this man.
He has to come back into your life.
Batewell something we want.
You only can we provide.
Listen ...
I do not know what you know, but ...
I read the report. I know he called you, you followed ...
He held obscene about yourself in public.
He touched you, caressed ...
I do things for you that I should not do.
You also do for me, but I will not do that.
Call the police, send me to prison ...
You send ...?
I will never force you to do anything.
Go see your mother.
It's late, visits will stop.
Good evening mother.
How do you feel?
Doctors say you take strength.
They say you're going to get you out.
They also say that you can hear me.
It's true?
I need you, Mom.
You see, I made
ugly things to make you care.
I could give you all that, but now,
I feel depress me even more.
Fax intercept my brother, this is sometimes pleasing.
On Friday, the office will be infested by the FBI.
Chaz will be returned faster than we think.
Okay, but I have bad news.
Profit sent us a draft separation.
You abstracts me?
He hopes to cut us off from Wong before the survey.
For that, it will bring 100 million.
He must have a reason. I followed.
You really have a sneaky side.
Profit went to Jeremy Batewell.
The mad scientist?
He had been fired.
He continues to develop defense systems.
Wong would love to get their hands on.
It could be extremely serious.
Profit and Chaz could end up in jail.
Jim is a friend. It is very useful to our society.
As for Chaz imagine in prison, I really like the idea.
Profit could use as his assistant Batewell covets.
He was fired for trying to skip it.
Very good.
Chaz does not let escape.
It left for detoxification.
- I will inform you about our deal. - And I, on Profit.
Sorry it did not call. She's a bit disoriented.
Her mother goes wrong.
I feel that mocks me.
She is very concerned. Be understanding.
I will. I censure me for what ...
200 days. No letters,
or call ...
on a government contract,
but his mind has been busy.
All that to agree to wait.
I know you are very busy. She will call tonight.
How are you?
You'll see my brother?
I would like to leave a message for Bobby Stokowski. It's urgent.
Tell him I still called ...
Pete, I'm on the phone.
I wanted to say goodbye.
I go.
In rehab. As you have asked me.
She knows my number. Thank you.
Jim, enter and close the door.
You did well in need.
From now on,
everything will change.
I hope.
You'll be surprised
to see how quickly things will change.
- It advances with Wong? - All was launched.
We will be released by Friday?
Yes, if all goes as planned.
Your wife is on line one.
I have for a second.
Good morning my darling.
- How are you? - I have a lot of work.
Finally, I will stay here until the end of the month.
I walk well on this story and I thought ...
Perfect. I miss you, have fun though.
I'm not here to write for fun.
We talk soon.
My wife thinks he's a writer.
This is more economical than when she played the architect.
I always have this migraine.
Since...
and gives him more morphine.
I try to reach your friend, Bobby. She does not remember ...
I got it yesterday.
And?
You are Marie.
Tell him this.
My divorce Constance would have legal consequences
for my family and this company.
This is what she wants?
I'll tell him you want to talk to him.
When you invited me to lunch,
I imagined something more class.
I could flirt with you and do the usual cinema
but I just wanted to be alone with you
to know what you think of Jim Profit.
It is complicated.
We are alone. There is no spy, it is far from G & G.
By the.
It's a dangerous guy that follows rules that I not know.
There are no rules.
If you stuck, you will be fired.
That's why I need a friend.
It's not for my mind and my smile?
Read that and then destroy it.
You tell me what you think of Profit during dinner.
A dinner in your office?
- In my car. - Your car!
Why Mr. Gracen office?
I want to show you something.
It should be here so late?
Of course. That's your problem.
You do not imagine in an office like this.
Do not you think you might be at the top.
Sit down.
Why this? You are as hardworking, intelligent,
as gifted as Gracen.
I believe in you.
You have a bright future in this business.
The key to this success depends on the choices you make.
All choices made with me were the right choices.
If I tell you that we will look after you,
and your mother,
you believe me?
And if I tell you that I have plans for you?
- Although I want you to believe. - Very good.
If I tell you to call Batewell,
you know that you risk nothing, is not it?
I do not know what you want me to do.
I want you call and tell him ...
Dr. Batewell.
I would like to explain my true feelings.
Go for it.
I love when you call me, you touch me,
at the office.
other women, I was jealous.
Your jealousy made me suffer a lot.
What I said about the harassment, it was wrong.
That is why I would like to redeem myself.
It's more like penance than of love.
I wonder if your boss does not push you.
- Do not forget who you work for.
G & G hopes to take me?
You are part of the lot of my eventual rehiring?
If you do not want to listen to me, let's drop.
I wanted to talk to us.
From what we could live, but I was wrong.
Tomorrow.
I do not have a car, come get me at 20 pm.
I have an appointment.
You really are at the leadership level.
Constance Grace.
whichever request
all rights,
and alimony.
It does not have the means.
Leaving Bobby in plan.
Chaz leaves.
with her husband.
away from it
and seminars.
someone who attracts.
Someone like...
Excuse me. My name is Eleanor Meecham.
Where do I register?
I will show you. Constance Gracen.
Enchanted.
Me too.
They can live a lie.
for whiling happiness.
are autobiographical,
since college
with her teacher.
my terrible mother?
some like their mother.
What are you doing here?
I go from time to time to see how it goes.
Doctors say his prognosis is excellent.
- Why bed ... - I placed near the window.
This is more pleasant for her.
This is important, your visits and what you tell him.
She hears everything.
It seems.
When you were a kid,
she boasted to other mothers?
I put myself at the window and I heard
on the porch, telling that I would succeed in life,
I would win money
and that I would take care of her.
Your parents were like my mother?
My father...
He never expected much from me.
Perhaps it was easier for me.
It has been?
It's late, let's talk.
You'll need that.
- And that. - What's this?
A medicament for the voltage. Harmless if one knows how to use it.
Pour into his glass, he will sleep for 12 hours.
After that?
What was said. Call me at home.
You look lovely.
Speak!
Hello, it's me.
and extreme paranoia
with the Ministry of Defence,
Impressive security
and from which one can not escape.
You look fit.
- Where do you go to dinner? - Nowhere.
Reference may be delivered later.
What a beautiful home!
A small question, where are you going like that?
I wanted to serve us a drink.
You're welcome,
serve yourself.
I get you something?
I do not drink.
Pardon?
I spoke Turkish? I said that I did not drink.
I hate to drink alone.
Share this glass.
I am not thirsty.
I do not like that word.
No! Harder! Pull me stronger hair!
That's it. Do you have another dose?
Let yourself go.
Burg Agent, FBI.
This is Sykes. You've heard of Jeremy Batewell?
I am busy.
He invented the "Ultrachip".
A super descrambler that the Pentagon expects.
Someone will steal it. Are you listening now?
vas-y.
A secretary at G & G is in Batewell.
She works for which Jim Profit works for Chaz Gracen.
G & G would be involved in this flight?
Completely. They want to pass on to the Chinese.
This is liable to how many years in prison?
I would say 140 years.
That must happen when?
- I jumped on a plane.
I booked you a flight. Tomorrow, Tony.
We drank earlier than expected.
- In the living room.
Return to the entrance and go up.
Je monte.
Proceed down the hallway.
Right, the Office Batewell.
Ça va, Gail?
I'm a little nervous.
No reason to worry.
Unless he lives with someone.
You could?
A cat. It was a cat.
to the server. You see?
Turn on the computer.
And if there is an alarm?
Do not worry.
This is a violation ...
- Insert the disk.
Type "lock" and "load" then "Enter."
He designed our IT security
and carried her off with everything he could.
Type "Ultra" and figures
3-6-3, asterisk then "Enter."
What is there on the screen?
Un logo. "Ultrachip".
All right, turn off the computer.
Excuse me.
Ms Gracen wants to see you.
Take it up, thank you.
You know what?
Make it work, make sure it is the right and get him out.
in fact detox.
Nora is the only one to know.
You want some? It's good for stress.
What happened?
Uncle Art.
He was with Pete?
I must not tell anyone. They want to seize G & G.
more Society uncle.
to get rid of Chaz.
I am his wife, I have to support it.
Your uncle abused you.
What should I do?
When they plan redemption?
After Chaz has sold a chip that will drop capital.
What's happening?
I hate to see you like this, caught between his hatred and greed.
It's ugly.
Excuse me.
There is a problem.
The diagnosis does not work on the chip.
- This is Ultrachip.
It does not work. I thought it had to be ready.
Since a month. You are right.
What should I do?
As agreed, but meet me at the office.
When Batewell discover what I have done, it will come at G & G.
Trust me.
le secret
is how to improvise.
Thank you for seeing me so quickly.
What do you say?
If I give you the Ultrachip I conned you.
- What do you mean? - It's fantastic today
but it could be obsolete within 2 years.
Then you have to buy the version # 2.
It can be anything. The chips are time-sensitive.
Fleas are.
Not those who make them.
- You are married? - Somehow.
You belong to him, and drag whatever passes under his nose?
He had a difficult childhood.
His father beat him.
Not enough, apparently.
My God, I'm horrible!
Who had a happy childhood? That's no excuse.
What hurts is that men treat us
like we did not matter.
It's unbelievable.
You understand me so well and we hardly knows.
Qu'y a-t-il?
I feel so alone.
It sometimes happens to you?
I wrote a book about it.
My husband died a long time ago.
I do not really have any friends.
No one to talk.
I am uninteresting.
Not at all. You're great.
You're so nice.
You remind me of my best friend in high school.
We often spent the night at one another.
All is well.
Hello.
It's late. I've got to go.
- What do you ... - We did everything, it was great.
Why am I lying there
with this horrible pain?
You threw your head back and you're hit you in ...
Really enjoyed it, but I gotta run.
Secretary of Profit is now hand over the Ultrachip.
My secretary did not even make me a coffee.
It goes back to the Chinese people, is not it?
Of course.
- About Coffee ... - I'm on it.
Profit must not know that the FBI is here.
I read the report on Profit. All that is written is true?
All.
Patience! Just now, you will have excellent news.
Put that.
Why did you decide to be here?
You will see.
- There is a small problem. - Which one?
Batewell did not drink the medicine.
And so?
I knocked him out.
I made him believe it was an accident.
Put that locked.
Call Mr. Wong on her direct line. He must be anxious.
But the chip is not working.
You thought you were smart?
Here's my fierce and expensive lawyer with a legal writ
that is only the beginning of a civil and criminal process
to rid the company of a large weight.
Here is the thief and the one who pushed her. Find the chip.
What are they talking about?
You will soon find yourself in prison, Gail.
How do I know what they're talking?
It is locked.
Give her the key.
Gail has nothing to hide.
The key!
reacts under pressure.
Will she panic or obey?
Why pick this chip is not working?
Pardon?
You have defrauded the US government.
This will be discovered when we stopped, but ...
It'll be good to out of here.
Stop!
Drop the writ, I retract. Go!
That was exciting.
Come into my office.
You said at the Defence Ministry
your research on the descrambler would be delayed by a month.
We all know that it's a scam.
You can not make it in time.
I dealt with the government and they do not forgive so quickly.
You will believe a robbery,
that a foreign power you stole the chip.
The chip is gone, you stash your money
and wait a contract with the government that will bring.
I am delighted to be an honest American citizen.
Want a piece of the pie?
I found you a real buyer, if you're implying.
Wong Industries.
I should sell the Ultrachip the Chinese?
For $ 10 million plus 20% commission for me.
Not bad, since the chip does not.
You do not think they'll be unhappy?
I'll take care of that. You enter the game?
Okay.
But I will never forget that.
- Good. - Do not be rude not.
Chinese buyers await.
Oh yes?
Doctor Batewell,
you must understand that you work
for me now.
I pay much more than the government.
$ 8 million for a working day, it will not refuse.
Your appointment is at 2:00.
I can not drive.
Gail will take you there.
Excuse us.
And it is surprising that I was never married me!
Wong Batewell must be at 10 am sharp.
I should believe you when you said you épauleriez me.
People fight,
mature,
who they actually are.
- You dry this morning? - Well seen.
- You slept well? - Very good.
Thank you for helping me last night.
I told myself that I had perhaps not need a man.
But someone guessing my feelings.
We all need someone like that.
Come here.
Constance, you feel like ...
I've never felt that before.
That's wonderful.
I can not.
You are married.
He is calm.
Very.
He let others sweat.
It reminds me of someone.
Here it is.
Wait until he passes it.
Go for it!
FBI. We stop you!
Lower your weapons. I know him.
Larry Sun, Ministry of Commerce. Remain calm.
We're all in the same camp.
What do you mean?
Mr. Profit intercepted the cryptographic program.
Intercepted?
And prevented its illegal export. He will be rewarded.
Mr. Profit, if all citizens were as lucid as you!
Not so lucid. Dr. Batewell disappeared.
You should send ... how do you say again?
A message to patrols.
Un message.
Go for it!
Larry, forget all that.
You also deserve a reward. I will make the request.
I love you well, I'll talk to you nicely.
Lose my phone number.
We return to the mine?
I wait in the car.
Benefit he will get me to do other things?
That would be logical. It takes you a hard time?
I do not mind it. I'll see for myself.
And now?
Nice bunch!
Slowly, I was joking.
What are you doing?
We end the agreement for the inventor of the chip.
Go ahead, Miss Koner.
Do not look at that.
Let me go!
Help me!
Call for help.
Do something.
Help me, Gail!
to judge his moral character.
it would succeed brilliantly.
Here I am kidnapper.
Not really.
Batewell is a wanted fugitive. They help to escape.
This is a fugitive because of us.
No, because of what he did.
The government would have quickly realized that the chip was unusable
and had been swindled them.
Batewell has just fled
instead of going to jail.
Moving is the best solution.
I thought that I would relish my revenge.
He deserved what will happen to him, but it did not seem right.
Of course.
Revenge is useless. It is a weapon for the weak.
You are not weak.
Not anymore.
I was looking for you.
Jim told me that you had taken risks with Wong.
I wanted to show my gratitude.
Thank you sir.
We will follow this young woman closely.
Of course.
The secret of real success
all fears,
and lock them up.
Of course,
enclose all evils.
That is the challenge.
Dealing with our own darkness
where they can not hurt us.
to make the world
a better world.