(The following content may not be suitable for viewers under 15.)
(Viewer discretion is advised.)
(Episode 63)
What are you doing?
I know I'm out of line,
but this is how I feel.
I don't know anything.
I can't remember anything.
Aren't you refusing?
Aren't you just refusing me and your memories?
I don't know how much the old Baek Do Hee loved you,
but this Baek Do Hee knows nothing.
So...
don't force your feelings...
upon me.
I can't wait long.
I've gone too far.
I can't stop my feelings, no matter how hard I try!
I won't wait any longer.
I'll go to you.
How did you know?
I could tell...
it was your car.
Do you plan...
to marry Park Hui Kyung?
Why do you ask?
Tell me.
Do you or don't you?
I have no reason to tell you.
No.
To be more precise,
I don't know what my answer is...
yet.
Then I will...
answer for you.
Don't...
marry him.
Why must I do that?
Please.
If you marry Uncle,
you and I will become family.
We may live together in the same house.
I can't handle that.
Is it because I look like your past girlfriend who died?
It's not just your face.
Of course, Na Yeon...
is completely different...
from you.
She was warm...
and sweet.
But every so often,
I see Na Yeon...
in you.
Do you not like that?
I keep making mistakes.
I don't want to be associated with you any further.
So what do you want?
Once the franchise project is completed, I'll return to Baekdo.
You should return to BSS.
Then everything ends.
That way, everyone will be happy.
I'll suffer...
until then.
Since that is...
the burden I must bear.
I understand.
But who decides...
your burden?
Isn't it difficult to judge on your own?
I suddenly want...
to marry Hui Kyung.
Ms Baek.
Don't be so shocked.
I'm not saying I will marry him.
But seeing you make mistakes...
is fun.
And I'm curious as to why you feel...
you deserve to suffer.
I feel like it'll be more fun...
if we live in the same house.
I'm sorry,
but I don't plan to leave AP.
I'm sure you don't, either.
Goodbye, then.
Dong Jin!
Come here, Dong Jin!
Did Hui Kyung come by?
Yes. We spoke briefly outside.
Go visit his mother often.
She seems very lonely and weak.
Please do it for me.
Yes, I will.
Good night.
Must you make it so obvious?
What do you mean?
I've taken all I could.
Do you know how you look when you talk about Hui Kyung's mum?
Do you know how loving and desperate you look?
I've lived with your shell all my life,
seeing only your back.
Go!
If you long for her so much,
go right now!
What's wrong?
Pardon?
Did you want to say something?
No, I don't.
Good night.
What is it?
Is something wrong?
If you don't mind,
may I sleep here with you tonight?
Do Hee...
hated sleeping...
with someone else.
She hated...
someone touching her.
I'm sorry for inconveniencing you.
You are not.
Once in a while,
it hurt my feelings.
I wondered if she would've been like that if I were her real mum.
May I ask...
how Do Hee and I...
were separated?
You must want to know.
Your real mum...
was a single mum.
One of the twins...
was deathly ill...
and needed heart surgery...
as soon as she was born.
In exchange for the surgery,
I adopted Do Hee.
Dad...
doesn't know. I didn't want to tell him.
I wanted...
to keep a secret from him as well.
I guess I am...
your third mum.
But...
for me,
you are one.
Because...
there must be only one Do Hee.
So...
don't...
try so hard.
Don't try to be nice to me,
and don't work so hard.
Just...
make mistakes,
hurt me,
make me worry...
and...
act like my daughter...
once in a while.
Please.
You're home late.
Did you go somewhere?
I had some stuff at work that I didn't want to push off.
I stayed late to work on them.
You're fast.
What do you mean?
They say men...
start lying about 2 to 3 years after marriage.
Isn't a few months too soon?
Baek Do Hee's house and a café!
Is this the office?
Was the work you didn't want to put off, meeting her?
What is this?
That's what I'd like to ask.
I'm sorry I couldn't tell you the truth.
I didn't want to complicate things.
But you.
What do you think you're doing?
What matters is that you started to lie to me!
Why do you make me so pathetic?
Why must I become the type of woman...
whom I thought was the most pathetic?
You're the one torturing yourself...
with those wild ideas!
No. Something is definitely there between the two of you.
You're definitely suspicious!
That's enough.
Okay?
Please.
Please stop! You're exhausting me!
Se Jin.
I know you find me comfortable,
but you should still knock.
I'm sorry,
but I'm in no state to think about manners.
Tell me. What is it that made you lose...
all manners?
Do you plan to marry Baek Do Hee?
Why do you ask that out of the blue?
If you plan to marry her,
keep an eye on her.
You're making no sense.
You understand exactly what I mean.
Baek Do Hee is confusing people all over the place.
With work, you...
and even Tae Joon.
Please be the only person who is confused by her.
Just marry her already.
This is what I needed to say.
Please.
(Baekdo Construction)
(AP Foods Apgujeong)
Wow. This is great.
(Wow. The famous Onion Chicken. It's really delicious.)
Look at the comments. They love it!
This is all thanks to the experts' tasting,
as Mr Kang suggested.
I only did my job.
He's right. I guess the more pressed you are, you must take proper steps.
Next is the advertisements.
Let's hear some ideas.
Many comment that the chicken is very unique.
How about a unique approach to the advertisement as well?
That's right.
Rather than the big celebrities that are plastered everywhere,
how about something different?
Something comfortable and new.
What about a middle-aged mum as the model?
That's a good start, but is there a suitable model?
Of course, there is. We already have one.
Ms Yang Mal Sook, the owner.
She can be in the advertisement herself.
She has that "mum" look, that is pure and not fake.
Wow. That is a great idea.
She has my vote.
The model of an advertisement is the face of the company.
We can't decide so flippantly.
We must hear what the chairman and the business strategy team think.
We must work on it together.
Is that right?
Then call a meeting right away...
so that we can work on it together.
Do you think that makes any sense?
Marketing is just as important as product development,
but you want to use the owner of the chicken place as the model?
I agree.
Ms Yang Mal Sook as the face of the new brand?
I believe that is a reckless idea.
What do you think?
A brave idea always faces opposition from logic and reason.
We want to create a sense of trust and dependability...
by using the creator of the product.
They say many times,
people remember the celebrity in an advertisement...
and not the product they endorsed.
We want to go beyond star-marketing.
We believe the owner, Yang Mal Sook,
can be novel and help distinguish us.
We will move forward.
You're avoiding my gaze.
Did I?
I know it's difficult, but look me in the eye.
I need to give you a warning.
Go ahead.
I'm sure it'll be very amusing.
Why did you intentionally approach Tae Joon?
Is that what he said?
That I'm approaching him?
What?
If you keep it up, you'll end up being an adulteress.
Who do you think will be hurt if a scandal breaks out?
Unless you want to be humiliated and disgrace your father,
watch it.
Don't worry about me.
Shall we weigh the odds?
For whom will it be more detrimental?
Me or you?
I don't care...
since it isn't true anyway.
What is this?
Why did the experts give it such high scores?
And what are these complimentary reviews?
I'm more baffled than you are.
We can't underestimate them just because they're a local shop.
We need to take proper measures...
to get rid of Baek Do Hee and Yang Mal Sook.
How?
I'll think about it.
The more baffled you are, you must use a more baffling method.
Stay out of it.
What?
Careless schemes like last time won't work.
I learned a lot from that.
I'm different now.
Yang Mal Sook killed my baby.
I won't let her succeed.
Isn't there anywhere we can get money from?
You startled me.
The investment funds are too low.
"Ms Turtle" is taking turtle-steps.
We can't risk losing this.
Why would we lose it when we put in our money?
There's a tough lady in Gangnam...
who raised the ante.
My goodness.
Can't you get 20 or 30 thousand dollars somewhere?
Where would I get money?
I can't even afford to buy pills to kill myself with!
This isn't time for this!
I sweet-talked the director and got this far.
We can't give up now!
What do you want me to do?
Then... Yes, your daughter-in-law.
Can't you go see her?
Yes. I'm sure she has a lot of money.
Mother.
That's a scam. Don't believe him.
It is not. You say that because you haven't met the director.
He's good-looking.
He'd never stab people in the back.
Invest a little bit...
for my sake.
You can spend that much money without making it show.
He has no past works that I can find.
Why are you letting those people scam you? It's pathetic.
What? Pathetic?
People will laugh.
Don't waste your time on senseless things...
and focus on running the store that we gave you.
What?
Focus on running the store that you gave me?
People's lives change overnight.
How dare you talk down to me just because you have money?
I won't ask you for money because you're so cheap.
Fine.
(Don't Ask Loans)
Hello? Is this Don't Ask Loans?
Can I really borrow money without collateral?
It isn't much.
I just need 50,000 dollars.
- Enjoy. - Thank you.
I'll call you back after discussing it with her.
Okay. Goodbye.
You were on the phone for a while. Was that Mr Park?
Yes. They want to ask something about choosing a model...
for their advertisements.
They should handle it themselves.
Why does our opinion matter?
It matters a lot.
They want Mum to be the model.
Mum? Who's mum?
- Our mum. - Oh my gosh.
They want our Madam Yang Mal Sook to be the model.
What?
How could I do that?
My gosh.
- Enjoy. - Do you need anything?
May we get some more radish?
- Would you like more of this? - It's so good.
Would you like more chicken?
- Yes, please. - Just a minute.
Get back to work.
Hello.
Did the real estate broker call you?
I really like the building.
Yes.
If you agree,
I'll buy it for a handsome price, higher than what you want.
Ms Park!
I'll wait for your call.
What are you doing here?
I was passing by. I heard this place is good,
so I stopped by.
Yes, it tastes great.
The problem is the owner has zero manners.
But...
do you still see Na Yeon's family?
No way!
I came against my will today...
to give them a piece of my mind.
Fine.
Fine, so please be cautious.
Like mum, like daughter.
They need to learn to fear their in-laws.
You should clear a table for your customer.
You're no customer.
Can't you see we're packed?
How did you know?
What? What do you mean?
Our boss is going to be the model for the chicken.
You'll see her on TV and in magazines, from now on.
Modelling isn't for anyone.
You know I was cast in a movie.
I was bumped up to the lead, too.
The classy and elegant Ms Turtle.
Ms Turtle...
Why are you laughing? It's true.
Don't even think about asking for autographs...
or photos later.
We are too humble...
to ask such a big star for an autograph.
A big star such as yourself should go and film your movie.
Please leave, Ms Turtle. Goodbye, Ms Turtle.
My gosh.
(Baekdo Construction)
I felt bad that I didn't come in yesterday,
so I packed lunch for everyone.
You're making us welcome your absence.
- I'll give Mr Park his. - That isn't his.
Why? Are they all different?
- Yes. - What?
You wrote us a letter.
That's why the lunch boxes are all different.
I wrote a little something to brighten your day.
It's brighter already. Thank you.
Take your time.
Thank you.
Enjoy.
You skip breakfast often, don't you?
You pass on lunch...
and forget to eat dinner.
Make sure to eat lunch today.
Enjoy, and have a wonderful afternoon.
Did you ask for me?
I wanted to thank you for the delicious lunch.
Thank you.
Did I confuse you?
What?
You are...
a good person.
You are also a good business partner.
That's enough.
Tell me the rest another time.
I made some for your mother, while I was at it.
Please have an assistant bring it to her.
Please bring it to her yourself.
Don't feel awkward. Keep it separate from me.
To be honest, my mum has grown very weak.
If not for your visiting every so often,
she may crumble.
Yes. Not Lee Yoon Ae, but her daughter.
Please find her daughter.
Of course.
What I sent its everything I know about Yoon Ae.
Yes. Yes.
Please.
What do you think you're doing?
What are you doing?
What's wrong with you?
Why do you care about me looking for Yoon Ae's daughter?
Why are you looking for her now?
You're acting strange.
Is there any reason why I can't find Yoon Ae's daughter?
Do you...
know where Yoon Ae's daughter is?
Where is she? Tell me, if you know.
I need to tell Yoon Ae's daughter something!
What? What will you tell her?
That's none of your business.
What are you doing?
You're being rude to your elder.
Are you all right, Madam?
How long have you lived with me?
It's almost 10 years.
It's been that long already.
We must've grown on each other quite a bit.
It must be easier since we have two housekeepers now.
It's better being alone.
That housekeeper constantly nags...
as if she's my manager.
It's quite stressful, actually.
Is that right?
Aren't we going to have lunch?
Madam, you already ate.
You said you were hungry and ate early.
That's right.
I did.
What are you looking for? I'll find it. What is it?
Forget it.
Forget it!
(I hope today will be so precious that you'll be sad to let it go.)
(Have the best day today, so good that you'll be sad to let it go.)
You changed your room.
Yes, it just happened.
The frame broke, so I just put it up like that.
Why? Do you recognise someone?
No.
I packed you lunch. I hope you like it.
Wow. A lunch box.
This reminds me of the times we hung out in high school.
Actually,
I'm looking for the daughter of a close friend from high school.
A friend's daughter?
Who?
Here.
Do you see this pretty girl?
Her name is Lee Yoon Ae.
Actually, she passed a long time ago.
So I'm looking for Yoon Ae's daughter.
I have something to tell her.
Something to tell her?
Yes. I need to tell her something. I have to.
(The Promise)
I don't want you coming so frequently.
You signed with AP Foods, correct?
Sign with us instead.
Take care of your mother. She's grown mentally weak.
Are you treating me like a patient? I'm fine!
Cry when you want and get angry when you want.
To think the heir of Baekdo tails her husband...
because she can't trust him. It looks bad for your image.
Shut it. Shut it!