(heavy breathing)
(mumbling)
- It's all my fault.
It's not fair.
Okay.
Shh.
It's good, you're okay.
Shh, now.
Shh.
(airplane zooming)
(brooding instrumental music)
- What is this place?
- It was, he had a
terrible former associate.
Now it's just a place we use.
- How long is this gonna take?
The whole process.
- Well, the first part is done.
You're dead.
- That was quick.
- The second part, the new
creds, the paper trail,
credit history, that's gonna
take...
However long it takes.
I don't know how the
hell you managed to get
that past security.
- You'd be amazed at what
all you can fit in your ass.
- Well I'm gonna need it.
There's no hardware allowed in
here.
It's house rules.
- [Voiceover] Yeah let's have
it.
- What's to stop me from
going out and buying one
- [Voiceover] Look I
just work here alright.
- I'd like that back when we're
done.
- [Voiceover] Yeah we should
be able to get it back to you.
- [Voiceover] Yeah we
need to talk about that.
- Talk about what?
- Payment.
what this is going to cost.
- [Voiceover] Something's come
up.
- What's that mean?
and they want to leverage your
services in lewd of payment.
I don't know much about it,
but someone came to town,
lost something very expensive.
- [Voiceover] Sounds
like a real gang fuck.
- Oh it is, it is bad.
they'll need something
done, that's all I know.
Your creds will be delivered
promptly there after.
- Well I'm sorry, but this is
how it is.
to be the clean up man for
you half ass consortium.
out in the world, but as I
said earlier, you're dead.
So good luck getting a mortgage.
- [Voiceover] Just give me what
you got,
point me in the right
direction, I'll take care of it.
- Right, we don't work that
way here in civilization.
You're an American now.
Not in some eastern European
wild west shit hole.
- So just sit in the ice
box for God knows how long.
- Yep.
- Keep this charged on your
person.
Computer is over there if you
get bored.
Just try not to get yourself
in any terrorist watch list.
And since you're sitting
on all that cash now,
randevu.xo is a local favorite.
If you're into girls that is.
(soft knocks)
- Bonjour.
- Ah yes sir.
Crowley, from the internet.
- It's kind of cold out here.
- Now if I remember correctly,
you said something about ropes.
- Yep.
(loud snap)
- You are quite trusting of
strangers.
- Not usually.
(loud whip)
You must have the magic touch.
- Yes, my magic touch.
(loud whip)
Do you like my magic touch?
(laughs)
I think you do.
Crowley from internet.
Is this what you like?
Yes?
Just like that.
There.
Yes.
Shh, it's okay.
It's okay.
Just let go.
Yes, just.
Let.
Go.
(heavy breathing)
- Mr. Crowley.
(speaking in foreign language)
- Where's my phone?
- How long have I been asleep?
- Why you worried that
your wife has called?
- No.
- Don't burn me with that
please.
- Why you so worried?
You some
big Hollywood producer or
something.
- No.
- Damn.
- I should get out of here.
- Yes, probably you are right
and on fact there's always a
long,
hard line of men waiting
for me outside the block,
but you know what we can make
them wait.
(speaks in foreign language)
- Let me ask you something,
How the fuck do you make any
money
running your business like this?
- Like what?
- You always just let guys
fall asleep in here for hours.
- Normally they do not fall
asleep.
If you want you can be Dublin.
But you know what,
you are very cute when you
sleep.
Just like a child.
- Alright.
- Woohoo.
I'm about to fall.
Uh you know you can be nice.
- I'm not nice.
- Well fuck you too.
- [Voiceover] The current
situation is not good Greer,
we need to talk.
- About what?
- [Voiceover] About next steps.
- It's not next steps time yet.
Not when I still got this thing
going on.
- [Voiceover] You keep
talking about this thing,
but nothing's happening.
We haven't seen anything
from you for a long time.
- I'm telling you, I'm this
close.
And then we're gonna be square.
- [Voiceover] I think
we got different ideas
about what square is.
- I mean square, trust me.
You'll be one happy mother
fucker when this little project
comes to finish my friend.
- [Voiceover] Today Greer,
meet me at the spot.
- Yeah we'll be in touch.
- [Voiceover] You ready
to do some work now.
- Yeah why not.
- It's pretty cut and dry.
Territory dispute.
They came in through the fire
escape.
Took out the resident over
there.
on domestic when it happened
and they locked it down.
- You should hire professionals.
- Yeah I agree.
- Except for the dead
occupant, the loft is clean.
- Where's Captain?
- The Captain is 20 minutes
away.
The wagon will be here in 10.
- We don't have much time.
- Okay we need the room!
Clear the room people, let's go!
Come on people pick up the pace!
- Okay.
Obviously you guys are in
a serious jackpot here,
but that dead guy in the other
room.
I'd say ya'll are pretty much
fucked.
But one of you has the chance
to walk away today free and
clear.
Like it never happened.
We knew who you guys are
alright.
We know who you are and what you
do
and somewhere out there
is a cash of goods in your
possession.
- What the fuck is a cash of
goods?
- We know you guys got a stash
somewhere.
Maybe here, maybe somewhere
nearby.
One of you road scholars is
gonna tells us
exactly where it's hiding.
And for that, you go free.
- Fuck you!
You don't gotta tell anything
man.
- That attitude is not
advisable.
(loud slap)
- [Voiceover] So what do you
plan to do with the new you?
- I don't know, move out west.
Join the human race, do what
people do.
- And what is it you think that
people do?
- I don't know, not what I've
been doing.
- Ah Mr. Crowley.
May I help you.
- You gonna make me show my
dick every time I come here?
- Depends, are you
gonna be nice this time?
- You want this money or not?
- Oh Mr. Crowley you...
Goodbye.
- Okay.
- Okay what?
- I'll be nice.
(heavy breathing)
- Already?
Okay.
So Mr. Crowley,
- Business overseas mostly.
- Business overseas?
That's sounds very boring.
- Well you know at least you
learned a cool language, no?
- Yeah your french was pretty
good once,
it's rough now.
- Some people like it rough.
- [Crowley] How long have
you been in the States?
- About thirteen years.
- You don't work for someone?
- No I am my own boss.
- Cool me too.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Mysterious Mr. Crowley.
You know I actually used to work
for
an American when I first
arrived.
I thought it was a good thing,
but we had a difference in
opinion
and I got rid of him
and now nobody tells me what to
do.
Nobody.
- I'll drink to that.
- Sit.
We are going to be friends.
Sit.
What do you do Crowley from the
internet?
- Well right now I watch
that phone over there.
That's about it.
- Ah yes.
Your precious phone.
Let me guess,
are you a drug dealer?
- I wish I was a drug dealer.
Let's just say my job is very
demanding.
- Oh I know.
I know you must be a
phone sex operator.
- Yes I am a phone sex operator.
- I knew it, I don't
know how you guys do it
all the moaning and cumming
and fucking.
(loud moaning)
- That's good.
That's very funny.
Give me the phone.
- No.
(speaks in foreign language)
(laughs)
- No I don't want.
I'm having too much fun.
(loud moaning)
- Give me the phone.
Give me the phone.
Thank you.
(distant sirens)
- You're no fun.
- I'm sure I am.
(loud slap)
- I think something moved.
- Jorge Chavez.
- What about him?
- I got confirmation on my
little theory.
- The one about the
whorehouse in South Brooklyn?
- [Greer] Oh it's more of a
garage band
than any legit criminal
enterprise.
- [Voiceover] Misha, Misha?
- Misha Golluv.
Yeah that's his house.
My source confirmed that Jorge
the Bagman
was in fact there
at the time of death,
- I'll be damned.
Your little tonk junkie CI came
through.
- She did indeed.
Your parents home little girl?
- Nope.
- Been over there a lot lately.
You gonna fill me on what's been
going on?
- I learned about the man who
died.
- Little Amanda Surben.
I put her in there two
weeks, she knows everything.
♪ Ah yeah
♪ I lost my V card when I was
seventeen
♪ Ever since then got
hoes attached to my pen
♪ I'm pretty sure it's that
potent ring
♪ Now I see why I got
you under my phone screen
♪ If it grows when I'm walking
around and then I'm charged
♪ But them panties go down
when you get them hard
♪ No need to ask why, no need to
ask why
♪ That's just a perk for
fucking with a stand-up guy
♪ My old girl cut me off,
she caught me slippin'
♪ That's why I'm drinking,
I'm drinking, I'm drinking
♪ Attitude change when you red
cup sippin'
♪ You sing a double that is mine
♪ Ben does it in the
parking lot, taking new kids
- Judge me, you can't
♪ When you wake up you do
that fucking strange thing
♪ Bitchin' out a wild life
♪ It won't be my last one
♪ Friday night, her fat ass is
on my tats
♪ Swerving through my hill
so the niggas gotta ask
♪ Where the, where the hoes at
♪ Where the hoes at
♪ Right here dog
(loud thud)
- How much money are
we talking about here?
I need to know where they put
that money.
- I wish I knew.
- They knew it was bad money.
That's why they dumped the bag
down.
- Smart move, setting him up
like that.
Not so smart leaving his
passport on him,
but what'd you gonna do they
were high.
- You gotta get that money
before someone else does,
or they blow it all.
- Correct.
- You wouldn't be holding out on
me,
would ya honey?
- Of course not.
- You remember how we met right?
- Yes.
- Remember what I did to your
dad?
- Yes.
- Remember what I told you
right?
About all the terrible
things I can do to you.
- Yes.
- Remember what I did to your
father,
just remember.
Just remember.
- Listen you don't have
to talk like this to me.
- Sure I do hun.
Sure I do.
- You have hands like
construction worker.
Am I close?
A fighter?
- Maybe some other guy was
a fighter once, not me.
What's your availability on
Saturday?
- If you keep coming over so
much,
I could give you a
package deal, like a gym.
- That won't be necessary,
I'm leaving town soon.
- What?
Where you going?
- I'm going out West
to join the human race.
- That's where the human race
lives.
- I hope so.
- You're so dramatic Crowley.
You know I,
I have a place out west.
It's in farm country.
One day I,
I am just going to go out there
and I'l disappear.
Poof.
- What you gonna do out
there, fuck farmers?
- Yes why not, I like farmers.
I think they're honest and
they're strong.
Well some of them are honest.
- You'd be surprised what
farmers could afford.
(speaks in foreign language)
- Time to go?
- What?
Oh no, it's not a job it's...
Actually it's this...
It's this (speaks in foreign
language)
that I know in south Brooklyn.
His name is Misha, he's...
He's a pimp.
Wants me to work for him,
and thinks he owns me
and he won't leave me alone.
- Tell him to fuck off.
- Be real.
- [Crowley] He's a Russian guy.
- Yes.
Well he likes to think he is
actually,
I think he's just a piece of
shit American white trash,
you know but no offense.
Hey.
Maybe you could help me.
You know get rid of him?
I could pay you.
- No.
- Let's talk.
You don't have to repeat his
stuff okay.
It was just, I didn't mean get
rid of him, get rid of him.
I just meant, you know?
He's bad for business and...
- Don't ask me again please.
- Crowley.
- It was the night, I
go out after sunlight.
Can I get two dollars for the
subway?
- Amanda!
Baby he don't want none
of your busted ass.
Do you brotha?
Do you?
Baby you can't go wonder off
like that.
You could've got hit
by a car or something.
- I just wanted some money for
the subway.
- I'll get you a ride home baby.
You gotta cost the gentlemen
in public for that shit.
What's up player?
You need something?
- No.
- Alright now.
- Let me ask you something?
Do I look like a joker to you?
Your credit situation is dire my
friend.
Do you understand what I'm
saying to you?
- Look, that hole is probably
worth at least a few grand.
- So what?
- So that's my good deal, that's
what.
- Greer,
this isn't going to work for us.
- It's just a one shot
deal to tie you over.
you can't rob the evidence
locker to pay the man.
It creates risk.
For you, for him, it
brings heat, you know this.
- This isn't evidence.
It's something we found
in an abandoned building.
It belongs to nobody.
- Are you from this planet?
Of course it belongs to
somebody.
- You know what an exclamatory
clause is?
- Nope.
- Sure you do.
It's a clause in a trust
agreement.
It relieves the trustee from
liability
resulting from any act
performed in good faith
under the trust.
It's like a provision in a
lease.
Where they say they're not
responsible for any damages.
Eddie, baby.
Anything that could possibly,
cosmically come from this
rolls back on me.
Just take the shit.
It'll buy some time.
- You know what happens after
next week?
Do you know what happens?
- There isn't going to
be a next week, Eddie.
- What happens is your
issue gets escalated.
To someone else, someone with
significantly less affection
for you than I have, do you get
me?
- Well it doesn't make much
sense dropping me down a hole.
Can't make money for the man
down there.
- And you can't go on
robbin' front down there.
- Look, I'm here in good faith.
Trying to medicate damages to...
- With stolen evidence.
- [Greer] Not evidence.
- Greer listen,
get the money, all of it.
- Look you tell the man,
it's not a good idea
to threaten the police.
- You stopped being the
police a long time ago.
- Enjoy the tar, check's in the
mail.
- Fucking better be.
- What is this?
- What?
- This.
This thing.
- You remember
that guy I told you about
before?
- Yeah you work for him.
- I come from the pimps they are
not...
They are more like secretaries
than they are like bosses.
- He was a smoker.
- You got rid of him.
Right?
- It's okay.
about the Moroccans we
shook down last week.
You hear what I said?
- Yeah I'll take care of the
Captain.
- You wanna tell me what's
going on with the man?
- It's nothing.
- It's nothing?
- Official police business.
- Well I know that's bullshit.
(laughs)
- Idea, why don't we just
focus on Jorge the bag man.
Okay, can we do that?
- We can do that.
Just don't get your legs
broken and fuck everything up.
Jorge Chavez,
we know he's plugged into a
major cartel.
What are the odds his major
cartel friends
are looking for him too?
- Doesn't matter.
- I'm just thinking about what
happens
if and when they come looking.
- You having second
thoughts about all this?
- I'm just trying to anticipate
any potential problems.
You should try it some time.
- What's the fun in that?
- Listen mother fucker,
I'll do whatever needs to
be done to see this through.
The only way this doesn't
happen,
is one of us gets clipped.
And that sure as fuck isn't
gonna be me.
So put the death wish on
hold and let's finish this.
(laughs)
- Look at this fucking jerk off.
How can I help you?
- Yeah hold up man.
- No man he's alright.
- Look, you see.
- What's up tough guy?
Glad to see you changed your
mind.
- He's gonna wanna see a girl,
we got anybody free?
- Let's find out.
- Say buddy,
you wanna top it off with
something sweet.
- No I'll stick with the coke.
It's a less hooch.
- That ain't no hooch Kemosabe.
That there is not
available in this country.
Top shelf shit.
Russians don't drink hooch.
Even when we smoke rock.
- My apologies.
I didn't realize this
was a Russian household.
I didn't see the fat
lady cooking and cleaning
for all you mother fuckers.
(laughs)
My compliments to the bartender.
- Yeah.
This shit is worth your whole
paycheck.
So it looks like you're gonna
have to wait a few my man.
Girls are all busy.
- It's alright I'll wait.
- Yo Sherman is here man.
You wanna see him?
- Yeah.
Hey,
thanks for waiting.
Busy day.
- It's no problem.
- What's your story man?
You in the army or something?
- No.
- Sure as shit look like it.
- Yeah,
you really Russian?
(laughs)
- Full blood.
- You sure as shit don't act
like it.
I'm just sayin' you're friendly.
I don't know a lot of Russians
with your customer service
ethic.
- What can I say?
The customers always right,
right?
Hey man, hey.
Why you looking at my girl?
- No.
- Hey it's all good brother.
You can look, we don't judge.
This here is a safe...
Nurturing environment.
What'd you say Amanda?
You feel like going to work
today?
No.
Don't be like that girl.
We all gotta work.
Right?
Supply and demand and shit like
that.
What'd you say?
- Listen that watery fuck
is still hanging out there,
he says he's gotta go.
If you don't see him now, he's
out.
- Alright, alright.
Why don't you take GI Joe here
to my room.
You want that thing, I touch
you.
You in business bud.
Hey.
Nothing freaky now alright?
That's my girl
and I'm the only freak up in
here.
- Why'd you take the knife?
Why did you take it?
- It's mine.
- No it's not.
- You should leave this place.
You deserve better.
- Did you think I should leave
here before you fucked me?
- You shouldn't hang
around guys like Misha.
And guys like me.
(water streaming)
- Yes.
- You alone?
- Yeah.
- This is Mr. Jorge Chavez,
cartel bag man that came to town
last week
to do some business.
He's the guy that
disappeared along with his
very expensive luggage.
And apparently he's a bit of a
fuck up,
nepotism, inbred retard, who
gives a shit?
Anyway,
and everyone wants to know
who's got the bagman's bag.
- So who is the target?
- No leads yet, but evidently
there's reason to believe
the material he was handling...
- The money.
- The luggage is still here
somewhere.
The thinking is the personal
persons who did him in
are still sitting on it.
- So that gang shank thing is
fully on.
- Yeah internal resources said
he OD.
They think he croaked
getting high with someone.
They dressed him up with
rough bowls in the cartel,
make it look like a very nasty
mugging.
- So what's the timeline?
but I just wanted to give you
some context around the job.
they're going to want you
to go to work yesterday.
- Well in the meanwhile,
would you mind breaking me off
some per diem, I'm burning
through my own money here.
'Cause takeout is getting
expensive.
- Takeout?
Is that what they're calling it
now?
- Yeah.
- I'll look into it.
- What's wrong?
- Wah-lah.
- Did Misha do this to you?
- What do you think?
- You know what...
(speaking in foreign language)
Okay.
(speaks in foreign language)
- He's dead.
- What are you going to do?
Are you going to ride in and
save me?
Like I asked before.
No you're full of shit.
You're so full of words
and you never do anything.
Big words for a big man.
You're so full of shit.
You always talk and you never do
anything.
You know why, because
you never fear anything.
What are you gonna do tough guy?
- I'm very sorry this happened
to you.
He's gonna be very sorry too.
(mumbles)
- Do you care about me at all?
At all?
You know maybe we could...
We should go away together.
You and me, we...
We could, you have money, I
have money, we could just...
Go away together and we could
disappear.
A different life.
We could be different.
- You are different.
(loud knocks)
- Man, service doesn't start
until 11.
Girls aren't even here yet.
- I need a fifth of bang.
- Alright, alright.
(loud grunting)
- Mother fucker, you.
(struggled grunts)
- Drop it.
Drop it.
Turn around.
(loud grunts)
(brooding instrumental music)
- You should burn this place.
Or I'll have to come back
and kill them all anyway.
- [Voiceover] I'm texting
you dead drop coordinates.
Instructions are as follows,
army with hard known diplomats
in the system in the
acquisition of the goods
and the new target.
- [Crowley] Who's the target?
outside the whorehouse
Chavez supposedly died in.
The target murdered the
occupants
and likely has a missing
item in his possession.
- Did you see the cados were
murdered?
- [Voiceover] Affirmative.
- Same MO as the bag man.
- [Voiceover] Alright diplomats
will contact you by phone
with an RV in the next 12 hours.
They have a lead on a target
already.
- No shit.
- [Voiceover] Some people want
to meet with you today Greer.
- Yeah where should we meet?
- [Voiceover] You won't
be meeting with me Greer.
These are new people.
(gasp)
(loud grunts)
(phone ringing)
- [Voiceover] Amanda?
- It's done.
I have it, come get me.
- [Voiceover] Where the fuck are
you?
- [Voiceover] Take the
money, I need to see him.
Hide the money where we said.
- [Voiceover] (speaking
in foreign language)
- No matter what, don't let him
get it.
I need to see him suffer.
I need to see him in pain.
- What the hell do you think
you're doing in here Greer?
- I'm saying hi to my friend
Eddie.
We're friends right?
- You're up on something aren't
you?
Of course you are.
Why the fuck else would
you be in here right now?
- That's not necessary.
- Your issue has escalated
Greer.
- Escalated, what's escalated?
What's that mean?
- Are all those drugs
making you fucking retarded?
'Cause that's about the
only God damn explanation
I can think of when it comes to
you.
This is over Greer.
No more extensions,
no more special treatment,
and no more me.
More than likely,
no more you.
You fucked up with the man.
Now get the fuck out of my diner
and enjoy what's left of
your short little life.
- That hurts my feelings.
- Get your fucking hands off me,
you God damn monkey.
(loud grunting)
- I'm gonna miss you.
- [Voiceover] You fucked
up with the man didn't you?
I fucking told you not to do
that.
- [Greer] You want out go.
This is my problem, it's my
solution.
- That's my money too princess.
Do not crash on me.
- I'm not crashing.
- If you got another
play then let's do it.
- I don't crash.
- Fine you don't crash.
So?
What's the play?
- We may need to take
some extreme measures.
- Fine.
- Hello, honey you here?
Very bad people are doing
very bad things to each other.
You're all caught up in it
aren't you?
You must have seen some
scary stuff in that house.
It scared me, so it must have
scared you.
Tell me again what happened
honey.
- I told you everything I know.
This GI Joe looking guy came
into the house and killed them.
- And where were you?
- I was hiding outside.
- Hiding outside.
You hid out front?
- So GI Joe must have
seen you when he left.
- I don't know.
- Seems reasonable that he would
have.
- Okay.
- Did you see him?
- Did GI Joe say anything
to you as he went home?
- I don't think so.
- But he saw you and you saw
him.
- Yeah.
- That scary looking guy,
looking right at you.
I bet you thought he'd be the
last thing you'd ever see.
Listen honey.
I gotta ask you something
and I want you to think before
you answer.
There's no rush.
What happened to all that money?
- I told you I don't know.
- I need it honey, counting on
it.
- I know you are,
so what are you gonna do about
it.
Who is that?
- That's my partner.
Dale.
(soft whimpering)
(loud slap)
(struggled grunts)
- I didn't kill those
guys you fucking bitch,
but I should kill you.
- No.
(mumbles)
(loud scream)
- Nobody.
He's perfect.
- He gambles, he has bad debts.
Without his money, he's dead.
I want this, his money's already
rich.
- Sophie.
- I want him to suffer.
- And what would you want?
(loud gasping)
- You know this doesn't
have to be this way.
You can talk to us.
- Such a player.
Please no more, please no!
(gasping)
- We know you're the guy
that robbed the house.
Okay.
Your friend over there, she's a
dead duck.
You can still save yourself
for a little while.
Just tell us where you put it.
- [Sophie] Fuck you, fuck you!
(loud punch)
(gasping)
- You guys are going to
kill us no matter what.
So why don't you just get
it the fuck over with.
(loud punch)
(struggled grunting)
- I'll tell you everything.
- No man.
Never been up here, it's pretty
though.
I should take Lana up some time.
but you know with the kids and
all,
we just never get around to it.
- I hope there's some booze at
this place.
I could sure use a fucking
drink.
- That's 'cause you're fucking
alcoholic.
- I can quit anytime.
You'll need a drink too man.
That bump on your skull,
you're gonna have one hell of
a hangover tomorrow morning.
They told me you work in the
CIA.
Is that true?
Man I hope not.
'Cause your clandestine
tree craft leaves something
to be desired.
And I'm not fucking with
you when I tell you this,
it's fucking ridiculous.
- Fuck you.
- Okay, where to?
Listen honey,
it's time for you to tell us
where that money is buried.
(whispers)
- I'm sorry honey, I
didn't quite get that.
- I swear to God, I'm going
to cut this bitch's hands
and feet off.
- Hey, no.
- I am not fucking playing here.
- Let me handle this, okay.
I'm sorry honey.
I'm sorry I hurt you.
You had a tough life.
I know you were just trying
to look out for yourself.
You saw a chance at a future
and you decided to grab it.
I can't blame you for that.
I can't blame you for doing
something,
I've been doing my whole life.
I can't blame you.
Truth is, you're probably
the closest thing
I had to love in my life.
You're the only person I've
been able to open up to.
Ever.
That's powerful.
Those feelings.
Don't you feel the same?
I hope you do because...
I care about you.
I guess I love you.
- They're gonna kill you.
- What's that honey?
- Who the fuck is that?
- You guys can't be here,
you need to clear out.
Official police business.
You can't be here.
Did you not hear me?
You need to clear out.
(speaking in foreign language)
Get the fuck out!
(loud gun shots)
(gun shots)
(rapid gun shots)
(struggled grunting)
(gun shots)
- Amanda!
(rapid gun fire)
Amanda!
(loud punches)
(screaming)
(struggled groans)
(loud gun shots)
- Amanda stop!
(gun shot fires)
Amanda!
- Amanda?
(speaking in foreign language)
It's all my fault.
It's not fair.
Okay.
Okay, shh.
It's good, you're okay.
Wish me luck.
Shh.
(rapid gun fire)
(gun clicks)
(loud gasp)
- [Voiceover] You're
in the shit, it's bad.
- [Voiceover] Yeah someone
got away with your money.
- [Voiceover] Huh huh.
There's no papers without that
money.
- [Voiceover] Yeah I
think I'll take my chances
out in the world.
- You know I think you
have beautiful scars.
They're like, how do you say,
they're like a map
to another country.
You know maybe in another life,
we could've been different.
We could've gone away together.
You and me, we could've...
Poof, disappeared.
(brassy rap music)