A Czech is a cyclist
who hunches over
as he pedals
Producers
With assistance from the
State Fund of the Czech Republic
for the Support and Development
of Czech Cinematography
Starring
Screenplay By
Casting
Dramaturgy
Costume Designer
Production Designer
Music
Sound Design
Editor
Cinematographer
Director
Emil?
Emil!
Today, May 27, at 10:30
an attempt to assassinate
Deputy Protector, Police General,
SS Obergruppenführer
Reinhard Heydrich was made.
One of the suspects
escaped on a bicycle
towards Stara Liben quarter
wearing nondescript dark
clothes and a dark hat.
- You were crying?
- Leave me alone, please.
I shan't. You could
do something silly.
Silly? You think love is silly?
Don't worry.
You are safe here with me.
Safety with you
is farfrom safe...
With my eyes closed
I disappear...
A concrete fortress
with a barbed wire fence reveals
that we are reporting
from a secure location.
For security reasons I can't
give away our exact position.
After meeting conditions
of the Munich agreement
we have lost over 30% of our
original territory to Germany,
Poland and Hungary.
Tens of thousands of Czechs
left the occupied territories
and are looking for
a new home inland.
They are refugees
in their own country.
Staff captain, how does
our army view this situation?
Although we weren't allowed to
fight, the border has calmed down
and by being prudent, careful
and orderly we've kept peace
for our European allies.
Hopefully our powerful allies
won't forget this sacrifice.
Just like Alice in Wonderland
I close my eyes
and feel so grand...
- You are safe here with me.
- With you... Sorry...
Cut!
Bravo!
Franta, I'm totally with you
but the censors won't allow it.
Any problems are mine.
You don't have to worry.
We can't give up now, can we?
- You're just drawing attention.
- Thas what you like about me.
Les go. I want to fetch
Hanka at the film studio.
Come on, join us for dinner.
She can get home on her own.
She's been a bit restless lately...
so I have to go calm her down.
You're jealous. Afraid someone
might hit on her there.
- No, I'm not.
- To hell with it.
If she wanted she could cheat on you
any time during the shooting.
Why are you saying that?
Look how pissed off he is.
That was a great tip of yours. This
girl's got a career in front of her.
But beware of her.
She was much better than you!
You're right. I've never been
good in female roles.
Here she is.
Your eyes are magic, Hana. In a film
is everything. Do you believe me?
That you're too shy to ask
for an autograph?
No way! Producers are never
shy. You're not shy, are you?
You'll see how far we'll go.
This will be a blockbuster.
Soon ill be in shops. Everyone'll
buy it. People want nice things.
Les hope enough people
share your taste.
- Aren't you too tough on him?
- Not really. He likes that.
He thinks is artistic.
To our new star.
Is totally dead here.
Whas going on? Is there going
to be some entertainment?
Just like Alice in Wonderland
I close my eyes
and I feel grand
Oh how the world
would suddenly seem
if I could close my eyes
and dream.
Strings of wind
will gently play
All the clouds will cast away
Thas just the way
my world should be
With my eyes closed
I clearly see.
- Is there anything wrong?
- No.
I just want you
to stop bothering Hanka.
I don't think
I've been bothering her.
- And you are who?
- I'm her husband.
Anyone could say that.
Excuse me.
Wait a minute!
Get off each other!
Don't go nuts. I'm sore all over.
Serves you right.
You acted like an idiot.
I just wanted to talk to him.
He was touching you.
That means nothing in film.
You think is all orgies.
Fantl is my friend, full stop.
A friend? Why is he
all over you all the time?
He's not all over me.
We work together.
I just can't get used to
these new friends of yours.
Alright.
We kissed.
Once.
On screen.
You're such a dummy, Emil.
There's nothing going on between me
and anybody else. Honestly, darling.
My watch is broken.
Is nothing.
I'll buy you a new one.
Close your eyes.
- I love you, Hanka.
- I love you too. Very much.
Make sure you're careful.
I have anotherfilm coming up.
Cut!
You can't just leave
in the middle of shooting.
This was my last scene.
You've got one more week left.
What about the premiere?
Won't you be here?
Arnost, this is
ourfirst film together...
When the Germans come,
thas going to be a real premiere.
- People like us will be done.
- What kind of people are we?
You can't imagine
whas about to happen. I can.
I'm ready and don't intend to wait.
Come away with me while we can.
You're panicking.
The situation's calming down.
- We'll make anotherfilm.
- Are you listening at all?
The two of us are done, for good.
You get it?
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm not leaving Emil.
You'd better go.
He already suspects there's
something going on between us.
- Excuse me. They need you.
- Yeah, I'm coming.
Hang on.
Here, Visa, contacts,
everything. Take it.
- Where did you get my photo?
- Just don't put it off.
Are you mad? I don't want this.
Yes, there is a huge chance
for introducing new industries.
Our businessmen must establish
healthy industries capable...
Hi. This was left for you
at reception.
...of thriving and providing
good livelihoods for all.
If it comes to favors
and protecting those
who never cared about our state
then all attempts to develop
our businesses are in vain.
At the behest of the President
of the Republic we report
that today, 15 March at 6:00 A.M.
German forces
occupied Czech and Moravia.
It is impossible to oppose this
action and no incidents must occur.
I was so scared.
What will happen to us?
Don't worry,
I'll take care of us.
I was promised that the independence
and advancement of our country
will be protected.
I received this promise
today in writing,
a declaration of the Protectorate
of Bohemia and Moravia.
A script may be broadcast
only if the text is censored.
Each section will submit
everything to the Czech censors.
The Czech censors will then
submit it to the German censors.
And, after this is executed,
we receive the text back.
Does that mean
that a censor censors the censor?
Mr. Vrana, all censored texts
will be given to the inspector.
He will hand it to the commentator
who will give out
relevant instructions.
He is in charge
of the whole broadcast, ok?
And he'll confirm the text.
You don't mind we're to
censor each other now, do you?
After censorship comes ratting out
and eventually collaboration.
If you think I'll bootlick
such a scumbag
who'd be a janitor under
normal circumstances...
Only an idiot acts like this.
So he's flipped out a bit.
We're all a little nervous.
...and to start working again.
- Explain how you can act like this.
Why? They can't bust you
for a constructive remark.
It was an unconstructive
provocation.
I just expressed my opinion.
Is my right. This is my home!
He just doesn't get it...
...I was expressing my view. - We
all have views but keep them quiet.
I won't grovel
before these usurpers!
Tell him something.
You know whas going on here.
They should know
they came uninvited...
Franta, I know we should
protest. But tactically.
Could you repeat that, please?
We've got a chance
to express our views pretending
we mean the opposite.
People will understand.
You know what? To hell with you!
You did that well.
Don't get me wrong. Maybe you're
overreacting, maybe Franta's right.
Franta is an idiot. With them
we have to do something else.
Hello?
Speaking.
First there was this hassle
with Fantl. And now your wife.
Sorry for being frank but she was
selfish to hold back her descent.
My new film is being
withdrawn from cinemas. Get it?
No, I don't get it.
Just tell me where my wife is.
Calm her down. Take her home.
I can't afford another scandal.
Don't come here!
Or I'll jump!
Don't be silly and get down here.
Mainly don't drink!
Everything will be alright.
- Like shit it will!
- At least we'll be together more.
You can relax at home, read...
What are you babbling about?
You're actually happy about it!
- No need to be jealous anymore!
- Stay there! We're going home!
Blackouts in Prague
We Have What We Need
The German Army
Charmed By Beautiful Prague
And In Prague Now Driving
Is Only On The Right
Jews Prohibited At Swimming Pools
Jewish Music Forbidden
Jews Prohibited To Be Among Aryans
Jews Prohibited From Cinemas
Jews Prohibited From Leaving Prague
Jews' Use of Prague
Trams Restricted
Jews Stroll Through The Cemeteries
- Won't you stoke it?
- I shouldn't deliver coal at all.
This is the last time, because
you're injured and I'm a gentleman.
Hi, Otto.
Hi. Franta's inside.
- What happened?
- Another of his provocations.
Forgot to mind his tongue
but this time live on-air.
- What are we going to do?
- Nothing. I'm through with him.
How come?
I broke up with him.
I won't sleep with someone
who never listens.
Mr. Vrbata, come in.
- How's your German?
- We studied it at school.
So we'll understand each other.
Your colleague tells me
you're a sportsman.
I rowed.
I boxed.
I have a problem.
I can't rely
on the Czech reporters,
that there won't be
more cases like Mr. Vrana's.
Your wife is Jewish.
My wife isn't really Jewish.
She's Czech. Always has been.
So you know, I, as a National
Socialist, must care about this.
But this time
that isn't my priority.
I need to replace Mr. Vrana.
And I think
the best solution is you.
If I can rely on you, you can
rely on me. Fair enough, yeah?
- Could I think it over?
- Don't think too long.
I have no interest
in dismissing efficient reporters.
Every Czech citizen
can find their perfect place here.
We might not have our own state
but we are part
of a powerful Reich
which gives us
the chance to develop.
Prague. Hitlerjugend roll call
took place in the German House...
Thank you so much for
such a wonderful explanation!
Yes, yes.
You've no idea how happy I am
to be born in this lovely century.
Yes.
A military parade
on Wenceslas Square
was watched by Commander-ln-Chief,
General Blaskovic.
This military spectacle showed the
greatness and power of the nation
which now protects
Bohemia and Moravia.
Two men left, two right.
The whole street.
Every house.
I.D., please.
This is your cellar.
This passage leads
to a staircase.
- What was that?
- A round up I guess.
How about coming straight to me
next time? For a private screening?
I don't think so.
But thank you. For everything.
What are you doing?
I did a horrible thing.
- I went to the cinema.
- Hanka, you can't do that!
You know what time it is?
You're under curfew.
- We should get divorced, Emil.
- What are you talking about?
I'm dangerous for you now.
Come here...
You're not dangerous,
just really silly.
Drink up. There's rum in it.
How about Franta?
Whas going to happen to him?
Hard to say. He got arrested.
I don't know...
I hope it won't look
as if you exploited this.
If I don't say yes,
they'll fire me. If I do...
This can't last forever.
We have to hold on.
All right. But make sure
that you stand by me.
That you don't do anything
you shouldn't. Promise?
Don't worry.
I'll look after us.
I'll protect you.
Hallo, hallo. After a short break
yourfavorite reporter Emil Vrbata,
signs on from the German
art exhibit Greatness And Beauty.
I am standing in the middle
of this historical hall
and right behind me
there is a statue of a rider
who is waving his right hand
at an imaginary audience.
Now, let me welcome
our special guest,
the exhibition's curator,
associate professor Kouba.
Could you tell us how this
event came into existence?
The art of the new Germany
is an example for all of us.
Such an exhibit works best
when seen with one's own eyes.
How did you manage
this exhibition?
It was hard to imagine these
big pieces being moved in here.
Fortunately, everything went
smooth thanks to our ability.
We are all happy to hear that.
Our Czech workers
have received much praise.
- They worked like ants, they...
- Thank you very much, Mr. Kouba.
And now les move
into another hall.
For Voices of Our Home,
at the microphone Emil Vrbata.
Thank you, Mr. Kouba.
Good day.
...of course, very pleasant,
especially for longer journeys.
- I like going to the woods.
- I wouldn't say no to that.
Longer pace and more space.
One - two - three...
One -two - three...
Stop! You have to arrive sooner!
I've been working on this for
three days and is still wrong!
Les go!
One, two, ready!
- Hello.
Are you Emil Vrbata?
For Voices of Our Home,
at the microphone Emil Vrbata.
Could you give us an autograph?
I want an autograph too. Would you
give me one, for old times?
Don't mind me,
I'm not here on business.
We just decided to go out
for the evening.
Gentlemen, this is the rising star
in our radio firmament,
reporter Emil Vrbata.
- Good day.
Pleased to meet you.
Voices of Our Home,
Emil Vabata.
Vrbata...
Your hat... Don't forget your hat...
Good night.
- What is it you're wearing?
- I thought you'd like it.
Yeah. Is marvelous, splendid.
What is it? Anything wrong?
Nothing.
All night drinking great schnapps,
smoking expensive cigars,
and in the end
I even sang beautifully.
You think I had a better time?
Sitting here all day alone,
waiting for you to come home?
Emil, take me out.
I wouldn't be such a nuisance.
Where to? Is night.
Not now, of course.
Not very lively here, is it?
If you don't like it, we can leave.
Why? I like it here. Is like
a Jewish Wenceslas Square.
Is hard when you can't go out.
A park's not possible so this is it.
Sure, is logical.
A cemetery is a promenade,
an occupation is protection...
Why don't we go to that café
of ours? We could go there.
Or the gentleman thinks
Jewish cafés stink?
The gentleman doesn't think so,
but he'd rather be here.
Is quite pretty here.
You're ashamed of me.
No, I'm not. Is just that
I don't think is very smart.
That café is really crowded.
Is much better here.
Right now we are in a cozy room,
sensibly furnished.
Opposite me is the cute face
of our young listener
trembling with anticipation
because she can't wait to hear
some national news.
This is what our youngsters are
like now. Eagerfor new knowledge
which our radio station
can bring them.
For Voices of Our Home,
at the microphone, Emil Vrbata.
See? I'm no star but my voice,
thas a different story.
- It will go far.
- Don't joke. You're popular.
Half and half. Nothing
compared to actors or sportsmen.
Still, it must affect you.
How about your personal life?
You're married, aren't you?
It doesn't matter...
How did you get
to where you are now?
- What did you do 10 years ago?
- I wanted to be a champion rower.
- Why aren't you, then?
- Because I realized
an average rower
cannot become a champion.
But don't quote that either.
You know, is hard work with you.
Can you at least
pick a photo for the cover?
How about this one?
Sorry! I didn't know
you had a visitor.
- She's a journalist.
- I'm just on my way.
Is starting any minute now.
4 legs and 4 feet, and winch
and grinch and ring-o-ding
run to the barn
and sleep there til spring.
Did you do anything bad this year?
- I didn't, Your Saintliness.
- Good, good.
Here you are.
What about you in the back?
Did you do anything bad?
- Even something little?
- No, I didn't.
Here you are.
We'll drink to that.
And now you!
Have you been good?
All year? You weren't bad? Really?
Franta! Is it you?
I heard they released you.
- So they have.
- Thas great.
What are you doing here?
I work in the archive.
Thas good.
Was it bad?
Pleasant it wasn't.
You must be angry with me, huh?
But there was
nothing else I could do.
Franta, the whole situation,
it was unbearable...
I'm not angry with you.
I hope you're a decent man.
- We have to make use of it.
- Of what?
Of your position.
No one will suspect you.
Franta, you're on your own. I'm
in a totally different situation.
Wait!
Sorry, but provocateurs
are everywhere.
Don't worry. Nothing will happen
to anybody. Les spice things up!
Vrbata!
You're still a sportsman.
Les show them...
show them that we're men.
If you don't give, you get.
Bravo! Bravo!
- Sorry. I didn't mean to.
- Is alright. He's used to it.
Won't he take it personally?
You mean when he discovers
you hit him for real?
Don't worry, he's asleep.
But I don't want to sleep.
Hi.
Does it have to be so loud?
Look what I've brought you.
A Christmas tree.
You're so sweet.
Us Jews are so into Christmas.
- What is it? Are you upset?
- No... I'm not upset.
You'd better go wash yourself.
Someone must have rubbed
herself against my face.
Somehow it all lasted
till morning. We were boxing...
At least don't lie, Emil.
- Where are you off to?
- I don't know. I have to go out.
I can't listen to this anymore.
But I'm not lying. Really.
I couldn't leave an official party.
I'm not doing it for myself.
Who are you doing it for?
This is not about me anymore.
It was naïve to think
we'd get through this easily.
So far nothing's happened to us.
Emil, hush.
For Goïs sake shut up!
You know what?
Do whatever you want.
Is not my fault you're Jewish.
- Were you crying?
- Leave me alone, please.
I shan't. You could
do something silly.
Silly? You think love is silly?
- So you're a photographer?
- No. I work with corpses.
Don't worry.
You are safe here with me.
You want to scare me?
I neverfinished my medical
studies so I work at pathology.
Where did you get this? I thought
it never made it to the cinemas.
- It did. It just wasn't screened.
- Do you realize how dangerous I am?
- You're not dangerous.
- How so?
I'm in a cinema
even though I can't be.
But no one can see you here.
Quite a safe danger.
Would you like to try
something really dangerous?
Oh how the world
would suddenly seem
if I could close my eyes
and dream.
Strings of wind
will gently play
All the clouds will cast away
Thas just the way
my world should be
With my eyes closed
I clearly see
- Will you have something?
- Cognac.
What are you doing here, Hana?
Here goes my wish
when the world goes sore
To close my eyes forever more.
Tell me what would you do
if you were in my place?
You don't lead a bad life.
Your husband takes care of you.
So how did it go?
Good.
- What did you tell him?
- Nothing. It wasn't about him.
Do you still have some film?
Jews Not Admitted
Box Office
Jews Forbidden To Enter
Pure Aryan Business
- Hi there, sailors.
- Hello.
Admit it. You're old. You can never
keep up with these young stallions.
I could care less.
I'm worried about other things.
I see. You know what?
I've been thinking and I say
screw your conscience.
Your wife should be grateful
you make such sacrifices. There's
nothing she can reproach you with.
She doesn't reproach me.
She simply doesn't talk to me.
Can't you make a deal with her?
How can I make a deal with her
when we don't talk?
Or do you consult
these things with Tomek?
No. Thas what I've got you for.
- Why don't we consult more often?
- Because we can't.
- You know I'm getting married.
- I know but I don't get it.
You know is good with us.
Emil, I thought a sportsman can
tell when is only about sport.
What if we take them
with us tonight?
23...
24...
25...
26...
- 27!
- Bravo!
You can't do this!
Ladies and gentlemen, this here
is our caretaker, in person.
And this is his guest book
so les all sign it now.
This party was
duly announced and permitted.
Don't worry. You're safe with me.
Wait. I haven't signed yet.
The one with the gate
doesn't count. I didn't get in.
It counts. What would he have done
if he'd known you're Jewish?
What are you staring at?
Haven't you seen The Springman?
You haven't because
no one's ever seen him.
He's a mysterious phantom
who always escapes the Nazis.
He jumps like a kangaroo,
with these springs on his feet,
and he can jump over everything,
houses, walls... stuff.
Nice bit of nonsense.
Guys, who are you provoking?
Why such barking?
Humor.
- Don't provoke anyone!
- We're not provoking anyone.
Oh yeah?
You're not?
Wearing shirts with emblems of a
non-existent state isn't provoking?
That helps a lot, boys.
Where does he get
all the grocery tickets from?
All this butter.
We've got nothing
but margarine and he's got butter.
You want some butter?
Do you now?
Here, have some butter then.
Will you sleep with me?
No.
Good evening.
I'm so stupid.
What am I to do when I love him?
I can't help you with that.
You have to do it yourself, miss.
- Where were you?
- At the cinema.
When will you finally
throw out that Christmas tree?
You have all the time
in the world, sitting at home.
You're his wife?
Hey!
DEATH TO THE OCCU...
Despite an excited atmosphere
over the last few days
marked by a state of emergency
in the Protectorate
of Bohemia and Moravia,
our defenders and representatives
of the great German Reich
have come to listen
to a concert of classical music
which is to honor Deputy
Protector, SS Obergruppenführer
and Police General
Reinhard Heydrich.
All eyes are set
upon the Deputy Protector
whose tall figure attracts
attention like a magnet.
Now it looks as
if the event is about to start.
The lights are going down.
The ceremony will open
with the German anthem.
Please.
Papaver somniferum is a poppy.
It produces opium
which isolates into morphine.
It can calm you down,
ease your pain, bring euphoria,
colorful dreams...
Many reasons to give it a taste.
Alright then.
- You know where to inject it?
- Don't worry,
I was a semesterfrom graduation
when the Germans closed the school.
What now?
We wait.
Will you sleep with me?
No.
Attention! Attention!
General Heydrich Has Taken Office
The Marking of Jews Introduced!
Beware of Jews Without Stars
Marriage With a Jewess Is Hell
Jews Out Of Europe!
You may go.
I'd like to assure you I had
nothing to do with any of this.
Mr. Vrana made a mistake.
We let him go
and he interpreted
our generosity as weakness.
Don't make mistakes.
Thas the main thing.
There are many people here
discussing a recent event,
a repeal of martial law,
and the kind attitude of Deputy
Protector, General Heydrich
toward Czech workers.
Mr. Deputy Protector helped us
through great hardship.
He arranged for better wages.
We've gotten much more peace
to meet our obligations
and thanks to him, we've got
the best work conditions ever.
Fellow workers, Mr. Deputy Protector
understands us, the Czech laborer.
May the Reich lead its
victorious fight to the end!
A Jew.
Gas poisoning.
- He's young and handsome.
- He was to be transported.
- What are you doing?
- I thought I could smell the gas.
Name, surname,
official title orfunction,
address and religion.
You need to fill in the same
about your wife.
Add birth
or marriage certificates,
or official abstracts
from state and parish registers
for your wife, parents -
hers and yours - and grandparents.
This is how we reference
all our employees.
But my marriage has
no influence on my work.
The new guidance
is non-negotiable.
Once we agreed
we're both in the same boat.
Now we need to agree
we're both rowing with the flow.
You get rid of your wife
or I'll throw you overboard.
Get a divorce.
Is enough as a formality.
- Yes?
- Yourfiancée has arrived.
Hi there!
I won't disturb you.
What happened?
Is he making problems?
The problem is his wife.
Will you sleep with me?
No.
But you can take pictures of me.
Hanka!
Is me!
Will you let me in for a while?
Just like Alice in Wonderland
I close my eyes
and I feel grand
Oh how the world
would suddenly seem
if I could close my eyes
and dream.
Strings of wind
will gently play
All the clouds will cast away...
- Couldn't you turn it off, please?
- Why?
I like it.
Sorry, it reminds me of times when
I had my booze and cigars, a bath
and things were normal.
Why didn't you show up earlier?
We could have figured something out.
Like what? Your husband
is the Reich's mouthpiece.
We'll have to talk
with him anyway.
Mind you, I'm also in hell.
- Do you have a phone at home?
- Yes.
And a radio? Grocery tickets?
Stuff it and stop whining.
Your life is a paradise!
Take a whiff of me.
This is the smell of despair!
May I take a bath?
What if he reports us?
Maybe he'll drown.
What happened to you?
- Nothing.
- Wait!
- What does this mean?
- Nothing. He needed to wash up.
How did he get here at all?
I thought he'd run away.
He had bad papers
so they sent him back.
Get him out. Is my bathroom.
- I'm not taking it. I only used it.
- Shut up. You're not here at all.
Is it clear? He emigrated.
We haven't seen him since.
We've got to help him!
He's a friend.
Les just hide him
until the transpors gone.
He escaped from a transport?
For Goïs sake, Hanka, think!
What will happen if someone
sees him? What if someone has?
We can't throw him out.
He'll be caught!
He'll be caught anyway and put
on another train, and you with him.
If he goes, I go.
He's on your conscience now!
Ladies and Gentlemen,
it is my privilege
to be your host
at this special radio wedding.
My main task is to be the funny
guy so I'll start with a joke.
On a gloomy afternoon one of
Prague's female broadcasters said:
And now, dear listeners,
I Want A Baby with Jara Benes.
Of course, she meant
a record by Jara Benes
with a song called
"Mum, I Want A Baby".
A colleague of hers, though,
swiftly sent her this message:
Dear Madam, do you really
insist on Jara Benes?
Long live our newlyweds!
My husband locked me in.
Emil!
Why are you lolling about?
The bride wants to dance with you.
How about asking me
whether I'm happy?
- Are you happy?
- The two of us are realists.
May I?
Let me go! No!
No, not there!
I won't let you destroy
everything I've done for you!
- Emil!
- Be quiet! Is for your own good!
Emil!
What was that?
Are you insane?
How could you let your Jew
show up at my wedding?
- I'm so sorry...
- Spare me your apologies.
You have to make a clear
statement. Come tomorrow at 11.
And be on time. I want to deal
with this before my honeymoon.
You're an idiot, Emil. Don't
count on me. I'm not suicidal.
- Good to see you here!
- Yes?
I'm here for work.
I write for the gossip column.
Yes.
Very good.
Please.
- Hi.
- Hey.
- Whas up, honey?
- I overslept.
I shoulïve been there by now.
- I can't explain this.
- Tell them you're getting divorced.
Right...
Emil!
- Is he in there? - Yes.
...towards Stara Liben quarter...
I'm really sorry. I missed
everything and overslept.
- It all just went wrong...
- Speak German.
He was wearing nondescript
dark clothes and a dark hat.
You don't know what happened?
A ladies bicycle with a dirty
net was found at the crime scene.
The other bicycle used
by the culprits, probably a man's,
dark in color,
is being searched for.
If anyone is familiar with
the whereabouts of these items,
please, report
to the nearest police station.
Emil?
Emil!
Today, May 27, at 10:30,
an attempt to assassinate
Deputy Protector, Police General,
SS Obergruppenführer
Reinhard Heydrich was made.
The Deputy Protector was driving
in his carfrom Panensky Brezan
towards Stara Liben quarter
and was just about to turn...
Wait. Wait.
I have to explain something to you.
...28 May at 6:00 AM
announced house
searches commence.
This is not a guest book.
Is a salad!
Take this drunken pig home
where he can sleep it off.
House search.
Documents, please.
- You are here alone?
- My wife is here with me.
You wife is a Jew?
- Yes.
- And where do you have her?
For Voices of Our Home
at the microphone, Emil Vrbata.
Okay.
Attention! Attention!
We appeal to citizens
to help with the investigation
of the assassination attempt
against Deputy Protector
and SS Obergruppenführer
Reinhard Heydrich
which was perpetrated
on May 27, 1942 in Prague.
- Any information including...
- Come help me!
...seemingly irrelevant details
can be of great importance.
Attention! Attention!
Whoever knows the owners of
the items presented in detail here:
Lady's bicycle, black frame.
Here, it is nickel-coated.
Here, it is painted red.
The net on the back wheel
is quite dirty and tattered.
This beige cap
is dirty and shabby.
The dark brown cowhide briefcase
has a glossy front side.
...the criminals
who attempted to assassinate
the highest-ranking official
of the Reich in our territory.
We appeal to those
who today hide the British agents,
whether out of compassion orfear,
to make the appropriate
denouncement.
Is me.
...if he confesses,
would save his family.
Hana!
- What?
- I need to talk to you. Let me in.
Not now.
Hana.
- What are you doing? - I'm here
because you don't come to me.
- Petr...
- You were in the cinema.
I saw you. Why didn't you come?
I can't. Go away, please.
He's at home, isn't he?
He locks you up in here.
Are you content now?
Go away before he comes back.
You said you didn't love him.
Is not so easy, Petr.
I can't keep running away.
I have to go back to reality.
For me, the reality is I love you.
I know.
- So why aren't you with me?
- I can't.
I have to be with Emil now.
I don't understand you.
Try...
Things have changed.
I can't tell you more.
You'll come back.
- Hey.
- Hi. Why is it so dark here?
Is safer.
Whave you got?
You really think this will help?
Is a cover.
Thas the way they do it.
Emil, you don't believe in me.
You think I don't get it.
- What don't you understand?
- I'm not totally blind.
If you'd just give me a hint, I'd
understand you're up to something.
And I'll keep quiet, promise.
But how about the bicycle?
People keep talking about it.
But they've already got it.
Is on display in the Bata store.
I mean the other one.
This is the bicycle
they're looking for.
Emil, you don't have
to patronize me. I'll help you.
No way! You'll be better off
if you don't know anything.
I'll sort it out.
I'll take care of it.
This morning Reich Protector
Reinhard Heydrich,
succumbed to injuries
suffered during the deadly attack.
On the occasion of the transport
of the Deputy Protector's remains,
before the coverage
of the funeral itself,
we will broadcast a radio workers'
oath of loyalty to the German Reich.
If anyone misses this
without a serious reason,
there will be consequences.
Thas all. You can go.
Vrbata.
Though I withdrew you
from the microphone,
our management wants you
to read the oath.
They think it should be read
aloud by a popular person.
This time, be punctual.
Any lapse can be regarded
as a nod to the assassination.
Emil? There's someone
waiting for you at the gate.
- What do they want?
- Nothing.
Listen, I hear
if they don't catch anyone,
they'll execute every
tenth Czech. Can it be true?
Why are you asking me?
I know nothing about it
and don't want to talk about it!
You know about Franta?
He was executed.
Why didn't you call?
I thought you were ill.
- Were you ill?
- What are you doing here?
I've brought you your bow tie.
And I also came to tell you
I probably love you.
Krista, thas great
but this is not the right time.
- You're not happy?
- Don't you understand the situation?
- What situation?
- I can't talk about it now.
Is dangerous...
We've been looking for you upstairs
the whole time, and here you are.
You have a pretty daughter.
I don't have any daughter.
We know you don't.
Les go.
...Miks Frantisek, Police Sergeant,
born 12 March 1915, living in Tabor.
Convicted of conspiring
and abetting the perpetrators
in the assassination
of SS Obergruppenführer Heydrich.
I still see him, how he looked
at me, how they led him out.
Definitely he wanted to go to you
and tell you the truth about us.
- Only he didn't make it.
- When exactly was it? - What?
- What time did they grab him?
- I don't know.
Around noon.
You've got to help me.
Can you keep a secret?
Why are you keeping
a bicycle in an airshaft?
You have to get it out of here.
Good day, Mr. Vrbata.
Good day.
Do you know
why we've called you here?
If they don't find anything
they can't charge him.
Shall I call home...
that I'm not coming?
Why wouldn't you go home?
Have you done something?
Wait a minute. We're needlessly
afraid. This is our bicycle.
What do you mean, your bicycle?
What are you babbling about? This
is the bicycle they're looking for!
Do you know this photograph?
This bicycle is from our house. Emil
took it as he was rushing to work.
What do you mean?
Emil has never taken anything.
He did. He overslept at my place.
So then he just borrowed the bike
and as he was in such a rush
he forgot to bring it back.
He probably
didn't want to tell you.
- What?
- You have to get divorced.
You see, we love each other...
You can't take them seriously.
Maybe they look like adults
but really they're still boys.
They don't do anything. Only
exercise. Nothing more than that.
No one's banned exercising yet.
Is just games.
Turn around.
And? Do they strike you
as if they're playing games?
Okay, gentlemen, les go.
Move it.
Don't you want to tell me something?
I don't know.
I don't know. I haven't
seen them for ages.
And you won't ever see them again.
The paradox is that they think
you informed against them.
But I haven't informed
against anyone.
Thas not essential.
Ultimately, it really
doesn't matter who did it.
You simply have to decide
on which side you stand.
You have the night
to think about it.
Petr. Turn it off!
Is a national day of mourning.
Someone might report you!
Safety with you
is farfrom safe...
I close my eyes
and feel so grand...
Come on. We have to go!
Police here! Open up!
Showing a film is forbidden!
Stop the film immediately!
Run.
I'll take care of this. Run!
Force the door!
- Is a national day of mourning!
- You support the assassination!
You're under arrest!
- Hello?
Hanka?
- Is me. Where are you?
- Is it you, Krista?
I thought I'd never see you
again. I'll come for you.
We radio workers swear to
stay unfalteringly loyal
to president Hacha
and our lawful government
and assure them
we want to be fully duteous
and that we shall
fulfill our duties to the Reich
with the highest faithfulness
and honesty,
being aware that theirfight for a
better order in Europe is also ours.
We fully agree with Mr. Benes
being called a public enemy
of the Czech nation.
If it were not for instigations
by Mr. Benes, his people abroad,
our country would be
the most blessed and quiet place
- in an otherwise disorderly Europe.
- The sun is setting.
Lights of fire, a scent of flowers.
It was a hard,
mournful and sad day.
At 7pm, when long shadows
are cast over the Castle courtyard,
Deputy Protector,
SS Obergruppenführer
Reinhard Heydrich shall leave
the Prague Castle forever.
Where is Vrbata?
Third floor.