Mum! David took my hairbrush.
David, give your
sister her brush back.
One minute.
♪ The sun came up
With no conclusions ♪
♪ Flowers seeping
In their beds ♪
♪ The city Cemetery's humming ♪
♪ I'm wide awake It's morning ♪
♪ I have my drugs
I have my woman ♪
♪ They keep away
My loneliness ♪
♪ My parents they
Have their religion ♪
♪ But sleep in
Separate houses ♪
♪ I read the body count
Out of the paper ♪
♪ And now it's written
All over my face ♪
♪ No one ever plans To
sleep out in The gutter ♪
♪ Sometimes that's just
The most comfortable place ♪
♪ So I'm drinking Breathing
writing Singing ♪
♪ Every day I'm On the clock ♪
♪ My mind races
With all my longings ♪
♪ But can't keep up
With what I got ♪
Quit it.
You know, the keyboard of the
typewriter was actually designed
to slow people down.
Oh, yeah?
♪ A telephone
To talk to strangers ♪
♪ Machine guns ♪
Here we go.
♪ So when you're
Asked to fight a war ♪
♪That's over nothing ♪
♪ It's best to join The
side that's Gonna win ♪
Overdose. PCP.
[Indistinct)
♪ How all of this Got started ♪
♪ But we're gonna make
'Em goddamn certain ♪
♪ How it's gonna end ♪
♪ Oh yeah we will
Oh yeah we will ♪
Dammit. Keep him still.
My bad. I'm trying to
give him a.
Shit! Shit!
What?
It got stuck.
Go. I got this.
What happened?
She got stuck.
All right, let's
get this thing moving.
I took April's
regular into the VIP room
and he gave me $7,000.
I don't give a fuck.
Fuck that bitch.
She freak out?
Yeah. Is there anything
more unflattering
than patterns on hotel rooms?
- I know.
- Why can't they just use solid colors?
It's easier to hide the stains.
That's so right.
We gotta get that
fucker on the stand.
Oh. What are you waiting for?
Hi, Mike.
Don't you know what time it is?
The Fire chief is responsible for all decisions
made from the Fire department, right?
Uh, for the most part, yeah.
If the chief of the fire department
was deleting work orders
which directly resulted in sending non-working
trucks to a fire, that's his fault?
Yeah, I guess
you could say that.
Then it's all bullshit
they fired a guy for falsifying his resume.
It's 'cause he exposed
the work orders.
It's a little late to change
our tactic, isn't it?
He was wrapped up in the price
of repairs but it didn't matter
because they were never
gonna do the repairs.
Hey, shut the fuck up.
Mike, where are you?
Just hanging out
with some friends.
You know what? You get some sleep.
I got this, okay?
Bye!
Hi.
Are you still sleeping?
Yes.
Ah.
You're joining the jury.
The reason my client is fired
was because he
falsified his resume,
not because he went
above your head
and reported that trucks were not getting
fixed and people were dying as a result.
Say yes.
Yes.
You also said you only went
to review my client's resume
after he went to the media.
Correct?
On May 9th, a truck went to the house of
Alex Foreman with a broken wafer pump.
That resulted in Mr.
Foreman burning to death.
On June 17th, another truck went
to the house of Crystal Dougan
also with a non-working pump,
also resulting in Ms.
Dougan burning to death.
Is that true?
It is.
No shit? Damn.
He knew he sent non-working
fire trucks to houses on fire?
He says he didn't.
You said the trucks were broken
because the work orders were deleted.
The work order could be anything.
It could be a tire alignment,
it could be a tear in the
fucking seat fabric.
But it wasn't a tear
in the fucking seat fabric.
The damn pumps
wouldn't work, right?
So, if the work orders
had been deleted
and you didn't know the
trucks needed to be fixed,
they were never gonna be
repaired to begin with.
After you realized the paperwork system
for the work orders were so screwed up
that you accidentally
approved two fire trucks
that didn't actually have
working water pumps,
realizing this,
because my client
exposed the fire department's
bureaucratic mess to the public,
after you realized this, you
felt the best usage of your time
would not be to go back
and fix the system
in an effort to prevent the
death of more innocent people.
You thought the first
thing you should do
was looking to my client's
job application and resume
even though he'd already been working
for the department for four years.
That may be what it looks like.
I'm sorry, sir, it's a simple question.
Which did you look into first?
The work order system that
had just caused the death
of two innocent people,
or a four-year-old job
application of an employee
that had just publicly
humiliated you?
And I remind your, sir,
that you're under oath.
I guess that the
application was first.
No further questions,
Your Honor.
Have you or someone you love
been injured in an accident
due to the negligence
of another person?
Call Danzinger and Weiss.
The phone call is free
and so is the consultation.
You need professional,
experienced trial lawyers
that care about their clients
to get the cash settlements that
you and your family deserve.
Don't wait. Call today.
Are you serious?
The fact is that auto accidents
and negligence result in
higher personal injury awards
and higher jury awards.
90% of them never even see the court room.
You should really
take me serious.
You should have a drink, counselor.
We're celebrating.
I remind you that we
would've made more money
if we had settled today's
case before the trial.
Should I remind you
that we won?
Oh, damn.
We won't stay long.
Like five minutes, okay?
Oh, no, thanks.
Have you seen my husband?
Oh, no.
Beer, tequila, Jack, rum?
Fine.
Mike 's my legal aide.
Please, tell me you're joking.
Uh, no.
He really hasn't changed
since eighth grade, has he?
No, he hasn't.
Have you seen
my fucking husband?
I think he might be out back.
I haven't ever heard of a goddamn
coaster, you fucking animal!
Can we go now?
How did you get to teach your
class tonight, by the way?
I didn't.
You can't keep canceling your class.
The students have been complaining.
Why? They're all here.
Oh. And the lady, she's still waiting on
those articles on the transportation.
Jesus Christ, you're worse than all legal acts.
No more talk about work.
Everybody, no more talk about work.
This is a party.
It's an interesting
party, too, Mike.
Hey, what's going on?
Hey. What the fuck is that?
It's an alligator.
It's just left outside,
walk around.
Hey, listen, guys.
I can't keep having
my firm give you work
is gonna take
you twice as long...
Twice as long to find the 1994 case
of Kings County vs. Stevenson
which protects the rights of people
with disabilities to keep their pets,
including animals used for emotional
support in cases like depression.
Regardless of the
landlord's policy
making the eviction of
your client illegal,
and upping the value of what will
now be a really nice settlement.
You're welcome.
I'll have it for you by Monday.
Thank you.
You guys are gonna go see
that nurse tomorrow, right?
Yeah.
All right. I gotta go.
What do you mean you gotta go?
I can't stay.
Rita's in the car right now.
Your lizard tried
to bite her foot.
Was she wearing white shoes?
He hates those.
Don't go. You just got here.
I got a white supremacist I
want you to straighten out.
Are you serious?
It'd be a great conversation.
Jamie, what the fuck? Are you nuts?
There are people upstairs.
In our bed, in our fucking
bed, you asshole!
Jamie, we should talk about
this, but this is not the way.
Apologize.
Apologize!
♪ We are the same ♪
I'm sorry.
I want a divorce.
♪ We are the same ♪
I'll see ya.
All right, everyone,
drama's over.
Fuck.
Why do you still have
this piece of crap?
I love this car.
You can drive it.
That drink smells
like wide open ass.
Good for the body,
good for the soul.
Mr. Health Nut.
You treat your digestive
tract like a sewer.
All that soda is gonna
destroy your esophagus.
So, did you get your gun back?
Not yet.
You all right?
She'll be back soon.
So, after I got
over myself a bit, I decided to fight.
Oh, thank you, sweetie.
I mean, AIDS isn't a
death sentence any more.
And the medicine gets better
and better every year.
Oh, sure, yes, of course.
This is all we had.
David, a glass?
That's fine. We're okay.
Thank you, David.
Can I play with Mr. Deedles?
Of course, hon. Of course.
Anyway, Daryl said if anybody
could help, it'd be you fellas.
My friend Jeffrey invented
this after my accident.
It's a safety needle.
Can't prick yourself,
can't be reused.
A safety needle like this could prevent
incidents like mine from ever happening.
And the hospital refuses
to even look at if.
Excuse me, so you were
injured on the job,
but are you receiving
worker's compensation?
Yes, they've kept up
with that end of it.
Uh, unfortunately
I don't think there's anything
else that can be done.
That's all of the law
provides for and, uh...
It's really all we can get you.
But I-I don't want
anything else.
Not personally anyway.
You see, my case is not an isolated incident.
This thing is happening to front line
health care professionals all the time.
We 're very sorry.
We have to make them use this.
The bottom line is,
the hospitals are knowing they're
putting their employees at risk
letting them get hurt.
People are dying.
And then
again I feel this tap.
More like a late dump.
it's a babe.
What I'm saying is we've
been netting on average
for each injury settlement
about 50 to 20 K, right?
Keep stringing a few
of these together a month
and we can actually be in
the black by February.
How often do you think that
needle stick thing happens?
You think it's
like a daily thing?
I don't know.
There's no case here anyway.
If we could prove the
hospitals were negligent,
our clients could be every
hospital worker in the country.
Mike, we can't afford to go on a
fishing expedition right now.
I think we should
go meet that guy.
The guy that invented
the safety needle.
If you come with me to
meet Jeffrey the inventor,
I'll give you three
focused days.
Three extremely focused,
eight-hour days,
interviewing as many accident victims
trying to squeeze the insurance company
for an extra $12
as you want. Deal?
Deal.
Give me that clamp.
Jeffrey Dancort.
That's me.
Paul Danzinger.
We're lawyers from Danzinger and Weiss.
He a lawyer, too?
This is Mike Weiss, my partner.
I was working as a mechanical and
structural engineer when Vicky got stuck.
So, you guys met her?
Uh, yeah, we did.
It's a terrible shame.
She's my best friend 's kid.
That really hit me.
I spent about a year working
on developing the concept.
Sooner or later the National Institute
of Health gave me a $50,000-grant
to develop a prototype
for reproduction.
Anyone ever use it?
San Antonio Memorial Hospital
used it for two years.
How's that working out?
Not a single needle stick
incident in two years.
So, there's no way you can
get stuck with this thing.
Can't get stuck with it,
can't reuse it.
Doctor's love it and
nurses are begging for it.
Only San Antonio
Memorial will buy it.
Why?
I thought you guys
could tell me that.
To start you should call at least 200
hospitals over the next couple of weeks.
Two hundred hospitals.
I know it sounds a lot, but we 're
gonna need to do is get a data base...
I've already approached
2,000 hospitals.
What'd say when you
showed them the needle?
They asked me to leave.
Is there any way we can sue a
hospital for not buying something
that saves people's lives?
So called miracle drug allegedly
causes client to suffer a stroke.
He's currently waging his battle against
another pharmaceutical company.
Top personal injury,
attorney Mark Lenier.
This is absolutely outrageous.
This is big pharma deciding
that they can take my client
and make him a Guinea pig,
test their medicines on him,
make their money off of him,
and then just disregard him and
throw him away when he breaks.
And that's outrageous
and we're gonna stop it.
We're gonna stop it right
here in this court house.
He's good.
He's very good.
Thank you for agreeing
to talk with me.
Sure, no problem. Talk.
On the phone you said you
were aware of the high number
of accidental needle sticks.
How about 800,000 a year?
Is that an accurate number?
You don't believe me?
No, it's not that
I don't believe you.
I just wanna know if
it's an accurate number.
I, Karen Brown, head of the Texas
Nurses' Association District Five
do officially swear that that
number is accurate. Better?
I'm just trying to get a
better understanding here.
Good. Then here's what you
need to understand. Okay?
The major cause
of these diseases,
hepatitis B, hepatitis C, HIV,
affecting all front line
health care workers
is because of accidental
needle sticks.
Okay?
Okay. The reason I'm
here is 'cause my client
has invented a safety needle that can
prevent this from ever happening again.
Then don't talk to me.
Who should I talk to?
The purchasing department.
Purchasing. Thank you.
Mr. Weismann.
Weiss. Mike, please.
Mr. Weiss, I cannot and will
not look at your needle.
Because of the purchasing
contract that the hospital has.
Will you at least
look at this data?
No.
Would you mind telling me why?
I don't want you
to show me your data,
and I don't want you to show
this product to my nurses
because they'll want it,
and they can't have it.
What kind of a shirt was it?
Was it a nice shirt?
- Yes, Mr.
- Paul, it was nice.
Was it a special shirt?
Special?
Maybe it was, a, uh, gift.
It was just a shirt.
How much did you say it cost?
Uh.
I don't remember.
Let's say $70.
Sylvia, could you, uh,
try Mike again, please?
Not if you wanna leave with all ten of
those tiny little fingers, young man.
I just left him
a fifth message.
Mike.
Paul, you're awake.
You're not gonna believe this.
I worked my way into a meeting with the
director of Infection at the hospital.
What?
That was today? Oh, shit, man.
Hello?
He said that Safety Point is fucking
essential to the safety of hospital...
I mean, we're looking at a shitload
of violations under State Law.
Several violations on a shitload
of counts under false claims.
I'm looking for it.
Take it, take it.
And I'll call him after lunch.
All right.
I'll call him after lunch.
The Nursing Association I
represent requested I call
in hopes that you'd help them with their
campaign in regards to this matter.
If you'd give me a call back,
that'd be great, if not...
Senator O'Hara's from Nebraska.
Nebraska?
Yeah, there's only 100 centers.
We could call...
You mean we're like a team?
That we agreed upon things
then we do them together?
I said I was sorry.
Twenty-two straight hours...
I'm sorry.
Did you get the file I sent over?
I got it. GPO's have been bribed to buy
certain products for the hospitals.
I sent it over
to Dancort already.
In the '80s, these GPO's got so big,
they managed to pass a bill in Congress
allowing them a 3% commission
from the manufacturers
they're supposedly
negotiating with.
We have a great case here.
Yeah, we do.
I'm sorry, what was your name?
Susie.
Would you give us
a second, please?
Sure. I'll be right outside.
Look. Mike, I think that
we have a great case here,
potentially really great, but I need you
to be practical with me for a minute.
Like hospitals
letting people die
because Safety Point
costs five cents more?
Mike, I'm in, all right? I'm in.
It's just that if this thing gets too big,
you need to let me bring in
another firm to help out.
This thing is gonna
settle by Christmas.
It could drag for years. It's a monopoly
case and we're not an antitrust firm.
What kinda firm we wanna be, Paul?
This is gonna make us.
It could break us.
It's gonna be extremely expensive.
Dancort can't afford to pay us and I
can't do enough injury cases on my own.
What do you want me to say?
I'm sorry, all right?
I'm sorry I messed
the fucking line.
Mike, listen to me. I'm telling you
that we don't have the resources
to take this thing
all the way, so please.
I need your word that when I tell
you that the well is running dry,
we bring in another firm
to help out, okay?
Yeah. Yes.
Can we get to work now, please?
Sorry.
Am I interrupting something?
No, not at all. Come in.
Thanks for coming down.
Have a seat.
Well, right here
I got an invitation
to a supplier's to
attend a conference
from the United Medical
Health Supplies people.
Largest group purchasing
organization in the country.
And guess how much it costs
to attend the conference?
How much?
$25, 000.
Twenty-five grand?
What does that get you?
I went to one of these dog and
pony shows about three years back
for the low price of 75 grand,
and I didn't get jack shit.
Hey. Mike Weiss.
How are you?
I am excited.
These GPO guys represent over 4,000
health care providers in the US
and they supply 'em
with $80 billion
in medical products every year.
Walkers and canes
and wheelchairs,
commodes, bedpans.
The only way to get your
product into hospitals
is to go through these fuckers,
so you have to pay
thousands of dollars
for the opportunity to grovel in front
of a couple
of United Medical Health
Supply muckety-mucks.
Mike Weiss.
Thanks for coming.
But it's all just horse shit.
You need real money
to get anything done...
Gonna help prevent accidents from
happening to your patients and employees.
And over time, it's gonna save you
money and it's gonna save lives.
Does that sound like something
that might interest you?
Are you aware there are over 800,000
accidental needle sticks a year?
For 25,000, you can't
even stay for lunch.
How much does it cost
to stay for lunch?
Millions.
♪ Take me to see
The voodoo queen ♪
♪ Let her put A spell on me ♪
♪ A little Bit of change
7'0 ease my pain ♪
♪ Gonna set a Young man free ♪
Whatever you do, don't
let me fall asleep.
I think you'll be okay.
For four hours only.
Want a hand job?
Sure.
They're gonna videotape me?
We're gonna be okay.
Hi. Paul Danzinger.
Over here?
Yeah. Let's have a seat.
Oh, fuck! Fuck!
Gentlemen.
Thank you for coming.
It's much appreciated.
Paul Danzinger.
You must be Mr. Dancort.
This grip. You golf?
No, I don't golf.
Why so grumpy?
You get the chance to eat?
Breakfast's the most important meal of the day.
Would somebody please bring Mr.
Dancort a cup of coffee and a Danish?
So, let's get down to it.
Are we waiting for one more?
Let's just begin.
Okay. Mr. Dancort,
we are here today
so we can ask you some questions regarding
your allegations against my client.
Before we begin, I would like
to establish for the record
that you're aware that the deposition
is sworn testimony under oath.
Yeah, yeah.
The court reporter will
be recording the session
in the event that we would choose
to show the jury your testimony
in a court of law.
If at any time during these proceedings
you feel the need for a break,
please feel free to do so.
Is everything clear so far?
Is that a yes or a no, sir?
Yes.
Thank you. I'd like to
start by asking questions
about your background.
Would you please tell me your full name?
Jeffrey Matthew Dancort.
Could you spell that, please?
Jeffrey, J-E-F-F-R-E-Y.
Matthew, M-A-T-T-H-E-W.
Dancort, D-A -N-C-O-R- T.
Thank you.
Current address, please.
1429 Merryweather drive,
Houston, Texas, 74561.
Thank you.
Is that an apartment or a house?
It's a house.
For how long have
you lived there?
I don't know, about ten years.
About ten years
or exactly ten years?
We moved in there in 1986.
That would be 12 years.
Yeah, that sounds about right.
Sounds right or is right?
If you moved there in 1986, that would be 12 years.
Be polite.
Yes, that's right, sir.
One moment, please.
Right.
Oh, Shit.
Oh, fuck.
Fuck.
Fucking.
Fuck!
Besides football, did you
play any other sport?
What the hell are we
talking about football?
We case here to discuss the case.
Let's discuss the case.
We wanted to get some simple
background information.
I'd like to request that my
client take a break now.
Let the record reflect that the plaintiff's
attorney has asked for a break
without answering the question.
That's okay. Keep going.
Just keep going.
Continuing, besides football,
did you play any other...
Excuse me. Nathaniel Price.
I am.
Mike Weiss.
Guess I'll be seeing you in court.
I'm looking forward to it.
Good.
Excuse me.
Where the fuck were you?
Not here. Outside.
And what was the name of your first
dog, Mr. Dancort?
Oh, well, Rufus.
And how do you spell that, Mr. Dancort?
R-U-F-U-S. And were you fond
of this dog, Mr. Dancort?
Not particularly. Does that mean
you dislike dogs, Mr. Dancort?
They showed themselves today.
They wouldn't have brought up the big
guns if they weren't scared of you.
Yeah, they're terrified.
Scared fucking shitless all twelve of them.
The reason I wasn't there today is 'cause
I was talking to a good buddy of mine.
Henry Matthews, editor-in-chief
of the Houston Chronicle.
They're going to run
a story on you.
I'll see you guys
back at the office.
Houston Chronicle.
This is attorney Mike Weiss
calling for Henry Matthews.
We don't have a Henry Matthews.
We have a Henry Mathers.
That's what I meant.
Henry Mathers. Thank you.
He's not in.
Would you like his voice mail?
Sure.
One moment, please.
As soon as the sun goes down,
I'll be over there.
Hey.
Law and order. What's up?
What you need?
Two hundred.
This is Mike.
What the hell kinda friends
have you got, Mike?
Maybe you got some other
friends who can help us out.
It's how these people operate.
They must've threatened the paper.
I don't know what they
did or how they did it.
I've just spent hours on the
phone dealing with my investors,
my wife, my mother. This article claims
I'm having an affair with my assistant.
Are you having an affair
with your assistant?
No.
Then what are you worried about?
They're just trying to smear you.
This is to be expected.
They're gonna try and make as many
people hate your guts as possible
before we go to trial.
Paul is making a lot of traction
with a lot of investors for you.
When I get these motherfuckers
in front of the judge,
we're gonna get your needle in every
single hospital in the country.
Stay strong.
I'll see you in court.
Is that Armani?
Believe it.
Is that a tux?
It's Armani.
All rise.
The United States Federal
District Court is now in session.
The Honorable Judge
William Black presiding.
Be seated.
Right.
We are here
on plaintiff's motion
to compel the
production of documents
that the plaintiff
claims are necessary.
Since the defendants
are not allowing him...
Your Honor, the
defendant's client has...
No, no, Mr. Weiss.
Sorry, Your Honor.
It's an extraordinary large
request for production.
Which documents must
you have and why?
Request for production one.
All exclusive long term
and multi-product contracts
between United Medical Health
Supplies and all hospitals
over the last ten years.
We feel this information will prove the GPO
is engaged in anticompetitive
behavior, price fixing,
and a contract that requires
the company to buy products
even though they may not
be the safest available.
Under Dakota
vs. PMI Industries,
the Supreme Court
found this information.
Mr. Price, your response.
Judge, this is a fishing
expedition with no merit.
To expect thousands
of pages of documents
is unduly burdensome to my
client's time and money.
And the Dakota case
is not on point.
Next request.
Request of production 75.
All donations made by the defendant
to health care organizations
or political entities.
Political contributions are not
discoverable under Benet vs. Lappin.
Contributions to health care
organizations are not political.
Next request, please.
All purchase history of syringe
manufacturers made by the GPO
in the past ten years.
We feel that this information proves
that United Medical Health
Supplies has created a monopoly
by buying syringe manufacturers,
then jacking up the price.
Your Honor, the purchase and sale of
businesses are all of public records.
My client shouldn't have
to go through the expense.
Your Honor, we've submitted
cases supporting our position.
The law clearly states we're
entitled to these documents.
All right. My decision
is as follows.
The court denies document
production one, two, three.
Your Honor, we have the right...
Request of production 1 through 12 denied.
13, 14, 15 are firm,
but I'm limiting production
to one year, not ten years.
Sixteen through twenty-nine, denied.
Court adjourned.
You must
be so relieved.
We are ecstatic.
It's been three years in the making
and we finally
got some justice.
How do you suppose the jury
arrived at a $53 million verdict?
I think the jury took that figure
from the profits the company made
off not putting
the safety feature on.
They are not gonna let corporate
greed trump the value of human life.
Let's talk about the family.
We're dealing with an eight-year-old boy.
How are they doing right now?
They're doing okay, but the
eight-year-old boy, he goes home with...
Safety Point's a
bigger case than that.
You know that every American will get into
at least one car accident in their lifetime?
You know what the biggest reason is
that people get into car accidents?
Eating while driving?
Mm. No, that's only 49%.
Talking to the other
passenger, 81%.
Fascinating.
Where are you going?
I'm gonna go talk to him.
Hi, fellas.
Are you boys hungry?
Yeah, sure.
Well.
The process is one where
you fight in the courtroom
for three weeks, and then
you've got an appeal going.
And then we'll have that fight
and we'll win that fight.
Could you bring us a couple of
orders of shrimp cocktail, please?
I'm allergic to shellfish.
Good to see you.
Listen, I-I don't wanna be
here today as a law firm.
I'd like to talk.
One person to another.
What do you want?
I'll tell you
what I don't want.
I don't wanna see you two going
down, and you're going down.
Do I care who wins or loses?
Hardly. I have a job,
I do my job
and I get paid at the end
of the day either way.
How much you get paid?
You're funny, Mike.
I like that you
have a sense of humor.
What can we do for you?
You know who my client is.
You're looking
at 300 attorneys,
two dozen of the top anti-trust
experts in the country,
millions of dollars in resources,
connections in every corner
of the health care system, not
to mention the justice system.
Don't forget the newspapers.
The banks.
Mm-hm. That's correct.
Your client,
he's something else.
He's an idealistic bumpkin
who's been knocking on
every door in the city
trying to get a loan.
And you know why
he's not getting one?
'Cause my client
didn't want him to.
So, are you saying that
there's a possibility
of us actually
settling this fairly?
Absolutely not. 7'hat's the only
thing that my client can't afford.
If they gave you a settlement, they'll be
looking at lawsuits the rest of their lives.
They aren't gonna do that.
So, just do yourselves a favor.
Cut your losses now.
You guys got no case.
No way out.
Well, we appreciate
your concern.
Son, you can't make chicken
salad out of chicken shit.
Good day.
Bob.
She left a note.
Come on, buddy.
Providing the
best health care products
from Asia to Africa
to here at home.
United Medical Health Supplies.
Together in caring.
What's up?
My new equity partners just
backed out on Dancort.
That was the last investor.
Sorry.
Me foo.
Is there anything I can do?
Can you convince another firm to come
on board and take over the case?
Sorry. You need something?
Bills. The most pressing being
the electric and the phone.
I got an extension till Monday.
It's okay.
I'll just figure something out.
Hey, hon. Sorry.
I should be about ten more minutes...
No. No, no, no, no.
Can you drive? Okay.
Get in the car and go
straight to the hospital.
I will meet you there.
No, get straight to the hospital.
Take the express route
that we mapped out.
♪ When I die Lord ♪
♪ Won't you put my
Soul up on a train ♪
♪Won't you send It southbound ♪
♪ Give it a cool
Bluesman name ♪
♪ I've been lost out
On those beck reeds ♪
♪ So many times
I've gone blind ♪
♪ Losing faith In my family ♪
♪ Had drove me right
Out my damn mind ♪
♪ But on the south
Side of heaven ♪
♪ Won't you Take me home ♪
Nicole Morris, sex therapist.
Who am I speaking with?
Hey, I'm Mike.
Are you okay, Mike?
Do you need someone to talk to?
I've been better.
My wife left me.
She, uh, she took
all my furniture.
Oh, I'm sorry, baby.
Yeah.
At least she left me
my alligator.
You know my alligator
is 49 years old?
Wow. So cool for a pet.
Actually not
for an alligator.
You don't sound that old, Mike.
Me? No. No, I'm, uh,
I'm in my prime.
Is that your baby crying?
No. That's the, uh,
that's the office next door.
It's a pediatrics therapist.
A little late for a baby to
be at the doctor, isn't it?
Tell me what's
on your mind, Mike.
I don't like to be alone.
It feels better now that you're
talking to someone, doesn't it?
Yeah.
Hey, you think
we could meet up?
Possibly.
Mike, do you have
a credit card?
Yeah, hang on.
Immediate
medical attention.
I 'd like to encourage you to
fake yourselves to our clinic.
It's just two blocks away
on Main Street. Please.
If you have a stomach
ache, a sprained ankle,
anything that does not need
immediate medical attention...
- Pete, don't.
- You're gonna get fired.
They're not gonna
kick me out today.
What's going on?
Who's getting kicked out?
Welcome to the hospital.
I 'm sorry.
They canceled
my insurance today.
Pre-existing conditions.
What kind? Propensity to be
stabbed by sharp objects?
Some goddamn thing.
Let me go talk to somebody.
No, no, no. Please, it's okay.
I'll take care of it.
Pete, why don't you
get the boxes for him?
David, Kia, you go
help him out, okay?
Come on, guys.
Hey, guys.
Why don't you let me
talk to somebody, Vicky?
You okay?
Thank you.
Sure. You all right?
What about you?
Oh, that's... Yeah.
I, uh, I'm good.
Jill, this is Mike.
Hello.
So strange being on the
other side of things.
Having all the floor
nurses stand over me.
I trained some of them.
They got these crazy patterns
on their shirts these days,
like supposed to calm
the patients but...
it ends up making you
feel dizzy.
Mm.
So, you said you
had something for me.
You know, it's true what they say
about the stages you go through.
Denial, anger, acceptance,
blah, blah, blah.
But it doesn't happen quite as
cleanly as the pamphlets tell you.
In reality,
it's a stew.
Everything happens
all at the same time.
Just because
you can't really get
over the dark parts,
it doesn't mean you can't
get to the good ones.
Sometimes the brightest light
comes from the darkest places.
There you go.
Thank you.
Where did you get this?
Don't worry where
we got them from.
Hey.
Thompson Needles is coming out with
their own line of safety needle.
You think they're threatened
by Safety Point or what?
These are internal documents from United
Medical Health Supplies proving...
Mike, stop it. Kim had to go
to the hospital last night.
What?
She's fine. False alarm.
Is everything okay?
No, everything's not okay.
Our insurance lapsed.
What do you mean
our insurance lapsed?
You told Sylvia to pay for you to attend
the United Medical Health Supplies dinner
from the firm's account, and that you
would pay the insurance bill later.
I'm sorry. It's not how I
meant for it to happen.
That's not how you meant for it to happen.
Kim is pregnant, Mike.
Look,
I don't see how we can
possibly continue the case.
Mike, we agreed that
we would drop this.
I agreed to take in another firm.
I never agreed to drop anything.
I've called 50 firms
and no one will touch it.
I'm not dropping the case.
That's not your
decision to make.
Do you wanna call
Dancort or should I?
It's too big, Mike.
I have Senator O'Reilly calling from
Washington, D.C. for you, Mike.
Hello?
Then the GPO, in our case
United Medical Health Supplies
will draw up an exclusive
contract with Thompson Needles,
who in turn give them a
kickback for every needle sold.
Boxing out any competition
regardless of how superior
or how much safer
their product is.
If Thompson Needles is gonna come out
with a safe needle they'd have to retool,
recast the molding. They'd have to
replace their entire assembly line.
Something they're not interested in doing
because of the high upfront costs.
Hm. Ingenious.
This is a
tremendous innovation.
As you know, I've been addressing safety
issues for hospital workers for years.
I'm intrigued by your product, Mr.
Dancort, to say the least...
Thank you.
This is a bill proposal mandating
the use of sound needles.
We're in the process of
circulating a petition
in every single hospital
across the United States,
so we can mobilize nurses' unions
an associations to help you lobby.
Right. We have some interest
from some financial institutions
regarding investment packages,
and we're gonna try and get them in
every hospital across the country.
Senator, you're giving us the
impetus to safe thousands of lives.
Incredible.
That was incredible.
Great job.
I'm gonna go to the bathroom.
Are you happy?
Excuse me, Mr. Weiss.
Could I speak with you for just a second?
Yeah.
Senator.
Mr. Weiss.
I wanted to let you know how much I
appreciate you and your colleagues
bringing this to my attention.
As I said, the safety and
well-being of health care workers
has been high on my
agenda from day one,
and we also agree that urgent
action is what is called for.
That's great. It's...
it's just-it's good to meet someone who
is on board to fight the good fight.
It would be an honor
to offer my support,
but only if you drop this case
and let Mr. Dancort
team up with another firm.
The cocaine under your nose.
That's, um...
I 'm not judging you, Mike.
You're not the first person to lobby
a Senator hopped up on narcotics
and I'm sure you're not even the
first person to do so today,
but there's absolutely no way we can
put you before the House Committee
let alone the Senate.
Wait, just...
My client has approached every law firm in Texas.
They've all said no.
He's broke.
This is...
This is a major antitrust case.
You know the type of money and
muscle that goes into it.
Mr. Dancort does
not have the money
to sit across from the receptionist
at some of these firms.
My partner and I are the only ones
who are willing to take this risk.
We believe in this case.
We believe in it.
Give me a chance.
I'll go back to Houston.
I'll get myself cleaned up.
Okay.
But know this.
You only get one chance.
Don't fuck it up.
Understood.
They're talking to
fucking Senators now.
They're knocking on doors,
chickens with their heads cut off.
We need to fix
this now, Nathaniel.
I'll take care of it.
They're losing patience.
I just need a bit more time.
I'll try.
But you need to hurry.
Or it's not gonna
be good for any of us.
This is
a waste of time.
Mike.
Show some respect, huh?
I'll show some respect by winning the
case that put her in the ground.
Fuck this.
Fuck.
Come on.
The reason you...
The reason why you should invest in
Safety Point is because it's safe
and it's affective.
It's a life saving...
it's a life saving device.
It's a life saving device.
Your involvement...
Are you all right, Mike?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You want something?
I was always more of a
tinkerer than a businessman.
It's how I thought
about myself anyway.
My first office was in the
corner of a bicycle shop.
My first customer was an amputee
with an artificial leg.
Hi. Good evening.
I'm Paul Danzinger, and, uh,
I'd like to welcome you
on behalf of my partner,
Michael Weiss,
and of course the man who really
brought us all together tonight,
Mr. Jeffrey Dancort.
I've been doing this
a long time, you know.
Long, long, long time.
And what I've come to realize is
that there's just people out there
that all they wanna
do is fuck you up.
Right. You know what
I'm talking about.
So, on this one I just
decided to say fuck it.
'Cause you know what?
A good idea is a good idea.
We're talking about
people 's lives here.
Saving people's lives.
This girl is dead because of
what we're talking about here.
So, who gives a shit
about the bottom line?
Well, I'll tell you
who gives a shit.
The goddamn miserable
sorry ass motherfuckers
who won't let the
hospitals use my needle.
None of us in here might
even make ever a dime.
The point is,
that it's... The point
is Safety Point.
And I want you all to
think about helping us out.
It's just a good thing
to be part of and...
Thanks for being here.
Good night.
Thank you very much
for coming and...
How are you doing, Mike?
I'm sorry.
Oh, Shit, Mike.
People don't bring
checkbooks to these things.
I can't do this any more.
Paul, let's go home.
Hey, Sylvia.
Call ahead and tell them I
need an anesthesiologist.
Put naltrexone on.
And I want the full treatment.
I want the implant
under the abdomen.
Not the posterior...
Not the posterior rear.
I don't want anything in my
ass that doesn't have to be.
Collapsed veins, infection of the heart
lining and valves,
few abscesses.
The beginning of liver disease.
Minor pulmonary complications and
what could be the start of pneumonia.
Christ.
Typical.
He's going through withdrawal.
I had no idea. I mean, I...
I know he's taking some
painpills for his leg,
but I didn't...
He's a pretty heavy user.
I guess the good thing
I reactivated the insurance.
By the way, the treatment he
requested is gonna run about 25,000,
and it's not covered by insurance.
Just a heads up.
Great.
What the...
Hey.
Hey. You got my clothes?
Yeah.
Whoa. Hey, don't you want me to get someone
to checkout? I'm gonna find a nurse.
That's a great idea.
We're always underestimating nurses.
I'll be right
with you, Mr. Weiss.
You wouldn't happen to be a member of
the nursing association, would you?
I'm standing in front the the
Houston Community National Hospital
with a few hundred nurses and assorted
health care workers in protest.
Joining me now is Karen Brown,
President of the Texas Nurse...
Every needle stick accident costs the hospital
thousands of dollars in follow up testing.
If it's with an infected needle, it's
between 500,000 and $1 million per case.
In this country there are roughly one
million needle stick accidents a year.
Think about that.
You do the math.
We're fighting for the right of
every citizen to live in a country
that values human
life over profits.
Mr. Weiss, the hospital...
Senator O'Reilly's office.
This is attorney Mike
Weiss for the Senator.
Hi, Mr. Weiss. She just ended a meeting.
Can I take a message?
Sure.
Why are these here?
They were supposed to go out yesterday.
They sent it back.
What the hell is that?
I thought we had a contract.
Tell the Senator to return
my call as soon as possible.
It's regarding the San
Antonio Memorial Hospital
canceling their contract
with Safety Point Syringes.
The CEO of San Antonio
Memorial hospital
has been invited to sit on the board
of United Medical Health Supplies.
Yeah, you think she'd like to hear
that in the news or return my call?
Please, have her call me back.
This is attorney Mike Weiss.
I'm about to book a flight to DC.
This is bullshit.
The Senator's chief aid called this morning.
She's tabling the issue.
Tabling the issue?
What the fuck does that mean?
I'm going down there.
United Medical Health Supplies just
made a very generous contribution
to the Senator's
reelection campaign.
What's this?
Kim gave birth last
night to a baby girl.
Six pounds, eight ounces.
Sam. She's beautiful.
Congratulations.
I'll be home with
them if you need me.
What are we gonna do
about the Senator?
Nicole Morris, sex therapist.
I like sex therapy.
Nice to meet you.
She creeps me the fuck out.
I should say something, right?
Probably.
You wanna be the one?
No.
Me neither.
Oh, hey, thanks for being
flexible attending the case.
I 'm a little behind.
It's okay.
You don't have to worry about it.
I know. I'm just gonna check a few
facts and then I'll get it to you.
No, I mean, we don't need
it from you any more.
Look, I didn't... I didn't wanna
bring this up here but...
I'm really sorry.
My firm won't let me subcontract
any more work to you guys.
Not while you're working
on the Safety Point case.
Are you serious?
I'm sorry.
I mean, you can
keep the retainer.
I wish there was something
else I could do, but...
I understand.
Excuse me.
I'm not sure that's
gonna work for us.
Well, yeah, I don't...
Okay.
Let me talk it over with
my partner and my client.
I'll get back
to you in an hour.
All right.
That was Price. He wants us to
come out to his house tomorrow.
His house? Why?
You said that we'd settle by Christmas.
Maybe you're right.
I gotta call Dancort.
Mike!
Hand me that bag.
Mike, come on.
Just give me the fucking bag!
Gentlemen.
Thanks for coming out.
Give me a few minutes to wash up.
I'll be right with you.
Stephanie will show you
the way to the library.
If you need anything, she'll be
happy to get it for you, okay?
Right this way, gentlemen.
Dial nine if you need
to get an outside line.
And I'll be just down the
hall there to the left
if there's anything else I
can do for you gentlemen.
We're fine, thank you.
Great.
You got any fresh
squeezed juice?
Uh, I can check.
Orange is fine.
Grapefruit is preferable.
I'll see what I can do.
Where 's your bathroom?
It's right here.
How long do we have
to fucking wait?
Gentlemen. It's nice, isn't it?
Fresh air.
Mm. Okay.
Let's get down to business.
First of all,
thank you for coming all the way out here.
It's much appreciated.
Now, putting aside
the fact that Safety Point Syringes
is having financial difficulties,
one of our manufacturing clients
is ready to put an offer
for it which I think you're
gonna find satisfactory.
Where 's that girl?
The girl that showed us in?
I'm not sure, Mr. Weiss.
Waiting on some juice.
I'm sure she'll bring it
when she can.
Like I said, one of our manufacturing
clients is interested in your company
and the needle and has
been for quite some time.
This generous manufacturer wouldn't
happen to be Thompson Needles, would it?
They would like to remain anonymous
until there's an accepted offer.
And this anonymous client would then
own the patent to Safety Point?
That's right. My client is
interested in purchasing the equity
that comes from Safety
Point Syringes.
Would there be a contractual provision
guaranteeing a certain production
and distribution of the
Safety Point Syringe?
Once my client purchases
Safety Point Syringes,
they'll have the right to
do with it as they see fit.
And what do they see fit?
Mr. Dancort,
my client is prepared to make
a more than generous offer.
This is great. You know your
client is in direct violation
and federal and state
antitrust laws.
You damn well know you won't win
this case if you go to trial.
You are a brilliant
engineer, Mr. Dancort.
Try applying some of that
towards your business sense.
I didn't sacrifice everything because
I was looking for a big payday.
I just want my needles
in those hospitals.
I'm sorry, Mr.
Dancort. I truly am.
I won't take any pleasure
in seeing you ruined.
That proposal is only
valid for three days.
No amendments, no negotiation.
Now, gentlemen, I have taken
up enough of your Saturday.
Stephanie will see you out.
I look forward to your response.
We have to take it.
Excuse me?
The offer. We have
to take the money.
What do you mean?
That offer at Dancort
Is not fair.
They made the offer 'cause they know
they can't win. They're scared.
They're not scared, Mike.
They're scared we'll
take it to trial.
Do you even really care
if Safety Point needles
end up in hospitals?
No, seriously, I-I'm
asking you a question.
Do I care? Yes.
People are dying.
7'haz"s what you care about?
People dying?
Really?
We're taking the settlement.
No, we're not.
You want Dancort to walk away from
millions of dollars, and then what?
What happens to him when we
go to court years from now
and he's lost his
business and his house?
And then, then after all
that we lose the case?
We won't lose the case.
Okay, fine, we don't lose.
How do you want us
to survive until then, Mike?
We are broke. Broke, broke.
We have three weeks of overhead left
In the bank.
United Medical Health Supplies
has pretty much paid off
or pressured everyone in the United States
of America from giving us any new work!
How are you gonna go and rally
people behind Jeffrey in court
when you don't have a phone to call
them and to tell them where to show up?
I'm ending this...
I'm not ending shit.
I'll take a loan on my house.
You are so fucking delusional.
You're a big fucking pussy
who'd rather chase ambulances
then use the law
to save peoples lives.
So you care about
people 's lives?
Yeah, I do.
Whose? The troop of hookers you
pay to hang out with? Your wife?
Fuck you, Paul. Like you really give a
shit about those pathetic scam artists.
We do neck braces
and fucking crutches.
Not just the settlements
they bring in, right?
You just wanna win.
That is all you've ever cared about.
At least I have the courage
to lose for what's right!
I'll call Dancort and tell him you're
no longer involved with the case.
I'll walk from here.
Hey, man.
How are you doing?
Thanks.
Excuse me.
I'm all set, man.
Mr. Weiss, I used to work for
Thompson Needle Manufacturers.
Then go fuck yourself.
I was a friend of Vicky's.
She asked me
to come talk to you.
Thought it might be helpful.
You got a car?
Yeah. Follow me.
It's right over here.
You see, up until the 1960s.
Needle syringes
were made of glass
which hospitals
sterilized with heat.
Thompson Needle Manufacturers refused
to switch to plastic needles
despite the money they'd make
because plastic needles
can't be sterilized.
The founder of the
company, James Thompson,
he was quoted to saying, "We'll switch
to plastic needles over my dead body."
Sure enough. In 1966,
the year he died,
Thompson Manufacturers
switched to plastic needles.
Within ten years,
hepatitis C and AIDS
were on the map.
They knew that they'd be responsible for
spreading epidemics around the world.
This tape
has footage taken by a Peace
Corps worker in Nigeria.
Look.
You see those kids?
Children.
They get paid pennies to bring
used needles and syringes
to local pharmacies.
The clinics save on health
care by reusing needles
up to 200 times.
This is what's
going on everywhere.
Thompson Needle Manufacturers,
they're not only
not acting on this,
they're actually suppressing
knowledge of it.
The plastic syringe is the root
of the AIDS epidemic all across
Africa and Russia and India.
I'm sorry, they made an
offer to buy Safety Point.
We're advising
our client to take it.
Oh, come on, Mike!
You know if they buy it,
they're not gonna use it!
That needle
can save more than nurses here.
It can save millions of
lives around the world.
Yeah, well I'm just
a personal injury lawyer.
Not exactly in the best
place to go around
saving people's lives.
You know something, Mike?
Sometimes the brightest light
comes from the darkest places.
Get it before
it wakes the baby.
Hello?
Jesus Christ, Mike, you're
gonna wake the baby.
I'm hanging up now, all right?
We can talk about it tomorrow.
Okay. Sorry.
Is she up?
I like people that are nuts.
Keeps things interesting.
Do you know anything about the
original glass needle manufacturers?
Or anything about
plastic syringes?
You know, Michael?
Everyone goes to law school
to become a good guy.
To fight the good fight for justice.
Is that what you did?
Yes, I did.
How is that working out?
Do you remember the big
tobacco law suits?
Of course.
Seven CEOs under oath lying in
front of Congress and on camera.
And every state in the
Union suing them, right?
That's right.
You remember what
happened after that?
Yeah. We shelled out a $165 billion settlement.
That's what happened.
No, nothing happened.
Cigarettes are everywhere.
You know, new teenagers
start smoking every day.
Billions of people
smoking worldwide.
Millions of people
dying every year.
Nothing happened.
Big tobacco got a spanking.
Slap on the wrist.
And the y were right back
to business as usual.
Hm. I assume you came here tonight to
try convince me to do the right thing.
You know, I'd look in your eye
and I'd go, "Oh, my
God, you're right!"
Then what?
Guys like me are
like cafeteria trays.
Take one off the top and there's
another one right underneath it.
Now I bet you
spent your whole life
waiting that you, you were
born to do something great.
Make a difference,
do something special.
Important.
But Michael.
It's the most ordinary
thought anybody's ever had.
I'll see you in court.
That might be difficult since
your client and partner
have already
accepted the offer.
You're right.
You might've settled with them,
but you haven't settled with me.
I'm gonna travel the country
making every hospital worker
who's ever been infected by
a needle stick my client.
Every mother
that's lost a child,
every child that's
lost a parent.
I'm gonna put them
on the stand,
and I'm gonna tell them that
your client has a needle
the could've prevented
it from ever happening,
but he keeps it locked up 'cause
it costs too much to make.
Trust me.
You're about to see just
how ordinary I can be.
Good morning.
Good morning to you.
What is this?
That is a bonus
for all the hard
work you've been doing.
Are you serious?
I am.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Um, listen, there's
along rambling message
on the machine from Mike.
Figures.
There he is now.
You're up early.
Yes?
You're his partner?
Yeah.
Died in his sleep.
So, here 's your partner,
Michael Weiss.
He die...
He die alone?
The detectives will be able to
answer some of those questions.
They'll wanna talk to you also.
Have you seen
these needles before?
That's, uh, it's
a safety needle.
They were used.
That'll explain why
there're so many of them.
Are you okay, Mr. Dancort?
Can we offer you something to drink?
Some tea perhaps?
No, that's all right.
Mr. Danzinger.
Sorry to hear about Mr. Weiss.
We offer our most
sincere condolences.
So, since we're all here
we should probably...
Hello, Nat.
It's been a long time.
You and me?
We're going
to court on this one.
Looking forward to it.
♪ So you ♪
♪ Can't hold ♪
♪A star♪
♪ In your ♪
♪ Hand though ♪
♪ At least you can ♪
♪ Hold on ♪
♪ To another plan ♪
♪ Rusted wheel ♪
♪ Planted still♪
♪ I can ♪
♪ Tell it's ♪
♪ Summer ♪
♪ From the ♪
♪ Size of♪
♪ the bugs that fly
Through my window ♪
♪ Flying through My window ♪
♪ Rusted wheel ♪
♪ Planted still ♪
♪ Can't' move on ♪
♪ I can ♪
♪ Tell it's ♪
♪ Winter ♪
♪ From the ♪
♪ Size of♪
♪ The lump in ♪
♪ My throat ♪
♪ Got a lump in my throat ♪
♪ Rusted wheel ♪
♪ Planted still ♪
♪Can't move on ♪
♪ And it feels ♪
♪ Just like ♪
♪ The ground ♪
♪ Trapped in Another way ♪
♪ Just still in the ground ♪
♪ And it feels ♪
♪ Just like ♪
♪ The ground ♪
♪ Trapped in Another way ♪
♪ Just still In the ground ♪
♪ The ground ♪
♪ So you ♪
♪ Can't hold ♪
♪A star♪
♪ In your ♪
♪ Hand though ♪
♪ At least you can ♪
♪ Move on ♪
♪ To that better plan ♪
♪ Rusted wheel ♪
♪ Planted still ♪
♪ Can't move on ♪
♪ Rusted wheel ♪
♪ Planted still ♪
♪ Can't' move on ♪