1
00:00:13,260 --> 00:00:16,821


2
00:00:16,897 --> 00:00:21,027


3
00:00:23,203 --> 00:00:24,761

4

00:00:24,838 --> 00:00:27,329


5
00:00:39,319 --> 00:00:41,844

 

6
00:01:34,107 --> 00:01:36,803
This is the city of
Silicon dreams.

7
00:01:36,877 --> 00:01:39,368
And this is the story of
one of those dreams.

8
00:01:39,446 --> 00:01:43,280
Its breath is life, and it's death.

9
00:01:47,554 --> 00:01:49,886
The destruction of the fund
business to business.

10
00:01:49,956 --> 00:01:52,925
And don't take less than $18
a share on that German

11
00:01:52,993 --> 00:01:55,826
startup that we bought last month.

12
00:01:55,896 --> 00:01:59,161
See if you can pick up more
bargains of dot-com land.

13
00:02:01,635 --> 00:02:05,230
Digital Dreams is a better
company. That's right.

14
00:02:18,752 --> 00:02:22,415
Pleasure to see you.
Pleasure.

15
00:02:33,934 --> 00:02:37,802
John Elias's Office.
It's in his office.

16
00:02:37,871 --> 00:02:40,738
It's strange. I think
he's going crazy.

17
00:02:41,608 --> 00:02:44,372
Mondo chere for me, Reg.

18
00:02:44,444 --> 00:02:46,935
You know how high the rents 
are in San Francisco.

19
00:02:49,950 --> 00:02:52,544
Mr. Elias...

20
00:02:52,619 --> 00:02:56,055
The board members are here.
Anna Simmons has just arrived.

21
00:02:56,122 --> 00:02:58,784
They'll be ready soon.

22
00:02:58,859 --> 00:03:02,886
So today is the big day, huh?
We're going to get rich.

23
00:03:02,963 --> 00:03:06,194
- I mean - you -
- Yes. Today is the big day.

24
00:03:07,200 --> 00:03:09,691
In most of American Industrial history,

25
00:03:09,769 --> 00:03:12,203
people worked for simple salaries.

26
00:03:12,272 --> 00:03:15,070
But today, everyone wants
the big enchilada...

27
00:03:15,141 --> 00:03:17,405
the stock options of IPO.

28
00:03:17,477 --> 00:03:21,914
Now, no one dreams of doing
his or her first million before 40...

29
00:03:21,982 --> 00:03:24,473
but his first billion
before 30.

30
00:03:45,672 --> 00:03:46,661
Fuck!

31
00:03:52,679 --> 00:03:54,943
- Hello?
- Mr. Elias.

32
00:03:55,015 --> 00:03:58,212
- Claire, you're fired!
- You're fired! You're fired!

33
00:04:02,689 --> 00:04:08,059
Fuck this shit!
Fuck, fuck, fuck!

34
00:04:46,900 --> 00:04:49,494


35
00:04:58,278 --> 00:05:00,769
- Business or pleasure?
- Pleasure.

36
00:06:31,504 --> 00:06:35,440
Yes. I never knew how it all ended.

37
00:06:35,508 --> 00:06:40,275
All I had at the beginning,
in truth, was an idea

38
00:06:40,346 --> 00:06:42,507
for a great piece of software.

39
00:06:55,028 --> 00:06:57,394
Coffee.

40
00:06:57,464 --> 00:06:59,455
I was wondering where you went.

41
00:06:59,532 --> 00:07:02,899
- Did I wake you up before?
- No, it's okay.

42
00:07:02,969 --> 00:07:04,960
I like watching you when you work.

43
00:07:05,038 --> 00:07:07,563
But now it's making me kinda 
horny now.

44
00:07:07,640 --> 00:07:10,131
And you resisted the impulse to
drag me back into bed?

45
00:07:10,210 --> 00:07:13,202
Well, you were so engulfed
with what you were doing.

46
00:07:13,279 --> 00:07:15,270
I was writing down a dream I had

47
00:07:15,348 --> 00:07:17,839
about a new kind of server structure.

48
00:07:20,053 --> 00:07:25,252
- Sexy.
- Don't move. Don't. Move.

49
00:07:27,961 --> 00:07:30,657
Sorry. Are we intruding on John
and Lisa having sex, again?

50
00:07:30,730 --> 00:07:33,790
- What?
- We just wanted to see if you 
wanted to get breakfast.

51
00:07:33,867 --> 00:07:36,097
Do we remember us?
We're your friends.

52
00:07:36,169 --> 00:07:38,160
- Don't wanna,

53
00:07:38,238 --> 00:07:41,674
No, thanks.
We're gonna have breakfast here.

54
00:07:41,741 --> 00:07:44,232
Mhm. Kay. Well. Just remember
who loves you for your mind.

55
00:07:44,310 --> 00:07:48,747
- And not just for your body. Okay?
- I'll remember that. Thanks.

56
00:07:48,815 --> 00:07:53,252
I had a great idea that would have 
a huge value for every person on this planet.

57
00:07:53,319 --> 00:07:55,844
I will - I don't know.

58
00:07:55,922 --> 00:07:58,413
More kids in the middle of 
Australia and the outbacks

59
00:07:58,491 --> 00:08:00,982
more access to the best teachers
in the nation and Ivy League colleges.

60
00:08:01,060 --> 00:08:03,051
Yes, it's gonna -

61
00:08:03,129 --> 00:08:05,620
Well, no. I don't have a business.
No, sir, I -

62
00:08:05,698 --> 00:08:08,189
Of course I do not know what
will be my profit.

63
00:08:08,268 --> 00:08:11,362
Yes, John Elias
for Mr. Barber.

64
00:08:11,437 --> 00:08:14,099
Will you let him know
that I called? Again?

65
00:08:17,443 --> 00:08:20,879
It's about a startup.

66
00:08:20,947 --> 00:08:21,936
Thanks.

67
00:09:15,835 --> 00:09:21,171
BACK OF THE MOON CAFE

68
00:09:21,241 --> 00:09:23,903
It uses motion-vector compression to 
make the video truly on the max

69
00:09:23,977 --> 00:09:27,936
with a stable transmission.
No waiting, no downloading, no nothing.

70
00:09:28,014 --> 00:09:30,278
I love it when you talk dirty.

71
00:09:30,350 --> 00:09:32,614
This is something radical, folks.

72
00:09:32,685 --> 00:09:35,176
You're like the man of
compression algorithms.

73
00:09:35,255 --> 00:09:37,246
Can you, um.
Hello?

74
00:09:37,323 --> 00:09:40,451
Can you explain this
step by step for me, please?

75
00:09:40,526 --> 00:09:42,960
Later. It'll work.
Trust me.

76
00:09:43,029 --> 00:09:46,123
We take this, we write the code,
we start a company.

77
00:09:46,199 --> 00:09:48,565
Pay attention to me.

78
00:09:49,369 --> 00:09:51,963
You're amazing.
Better than ever.

79
00:09:52,038 --> 00:09:54,529
You're beautiful, you will become
a big star...

80
00:09:54,607 --> 00:09:57,303
- And forget all about me.
- Yes?

81
00:09:57,377 --> 00:09:59,868
Well, tonight I just want you
to take me home.

82
00:10:01,314 --> 00:10:03,305
Kay guys, I have to go.

83
00:10:05,885 --> 00:10:10,151
Another weekend of binge
drinking and casual sex now?

84
00:10:10,223 --> 00:10:13,420
But here you are, back for
another fun time of

85
00:10:13,493 --> 00:10:15,484
of punishment and humiliation.

86
00:10:15,561 --> 00:10:17,028
Excellent!

87
00:10:18,064 --> 00:10:21,500
You will notice scattered throughout
the hall today are glasses

88
00:10:21,567 --> 00:10:23,933
filled with standard forty-mil nails...

89
00:10:24,003 --> 00:10:28,497
along with, you will find,
a chunk of old wood

90
00:10:28,574 --> 00:10:31,168
with a big nail buried,
right in the middle of it.

91
00:10:31,244 --> 00:10:34,680
We're doing an experiment today.
The Great Nail Experiment.

92
00:10:34,747 --> 00:10:37,773
The rules are as following:
You must find a way...

93
00:10:37,850 --> 00:10:39,841
to balance all of these nails...

94
00:10:39,919 --> 00:10:42,683
onto the big central mother.

95
00:10:45,158 --> 00:10:48,093
Balance. That's it.
Those are the rules.

96
00:10:48,161 --> 00:10:51,358
No more, no less, kay?

97
00:10:51,431 --> 00:10:55,868
This is not a competition.
However, if I win...

98
00:10:55,935 --> 00:10:59,166
and if you can't perform this
simple balancing act,

99
00:10:59,238 --> 00:11:01,229
then you must treat my words...

100
00:11:01,307 --> 00:11:05,676
as if they are the words of
God Almighty.

101
00:11:05,745 --> 00:11:09,442
However, if you win,

102
00:11:09,515 --> 00:11:12,973
I will be very impressed
with you.

103
00:11:13,052 --> 00:11:17,045
Start, begin.
Use all the nails.

104
00:11:20,626 --> 00:11:23,220
Good. Thank you for using the glass.

105
00:11:23,296 --> 00:11:26,891
I put it there to see
if you have imagination.

106
00:11:26,966 --> 00:11:31,733
Now imagine a solution
without the glass.

107
00:11:31,804 --> 00:11:34,466
Now, you may have already discovered that

108
00:11:34,540 --> 00:11:38,067
balance in business -
but much more importantly, in life -

109
00:11:38,144 --> 00:11:40,908
can be very difficult to achieve.

110
00:11:40,980 --> 00:11:44,177
Each nail is equally important
and each nail has a function.

111
00:11:44,250 --> 00:11:47,549
So privileging one element over another

112
00:11:47,620 --> 00:11:51,454
or forgetting that everything
needs to be integrated as a whole…

113
00:11:53,826 --> 00:11:57,523
can result in a collapse
as you have just seen here.

114
00:11:57,597 --> 00:12:00,259
Thank you for showing it.

115
00:12:00,333 --> 00:12:03,825
Come on. Somebody. It can be done.

116
00:12:03,903 --> 00:12:06,770
I assure you.
Thanks.

117
00:12:06,839 --> 00:12:10,775
No more calls here, we have a winner.
Excellent. Excellent work.

118
00:12:10,843 --> 00:12:16,873
Look at that. As promised,
I am very impressed.

119
00:12:16,949 --> 00:12:19,611
Now, what do you think that the solution to the
Great Nail Experiment tells us about

120
00:12:19,685 --> 00:12:21,676
 businesses, Mr. Elias?

121
00:12:21,754 --> 00:12:24,917
That a professor's words don't come
from God Almighty?

122
00:12:26,993 --> 00:12:30,451
Whoo. Whoo. I won't be throwing any
lightning bolts at you anytime soon, my friend.

123
00:12:30,530 --> 00:12:33,124
Come on, what else?
Anybody?

124
00:12:33,199 --> 00:12:36,032
Hey, I know. I'll spell it out for you.

125
00:12:36,102 --> 00:12:39,230
A company is strong -
and our life is strong -

126
00:12:39,305 --> 00:12:44,470
If it is balanced together
on a central core.

127
00:12:44,544 --> 00:12:47,707
An unchanging core of values and beliefs.

128
00:12:49,382 --> 00:12:51,816
A central p urpose.

129
00:12:51,884 --> 00:12:55,615
Because if you have that,
nothing can knock you down.

130
00:12:58,057 --> 00:13:00,048
Hey, Einstein, wait up!

131
00:13:00,126 --> 00:13:02,651
What you did there was like
being with Mahatma Gandhi.

132
00:13:02,728 --> 00:13:03,717
Thanks.

133
00:13:03,796 --> 00:13:07,823
Hey, guys. Hey, can I talk with 
you for a second?

134
00:13:07,900 --> 00:13:10,562
- I'll catch up with you guys later.
- See ya, buddy.

135
00:13:12,071 --> 00:13:14,562
- New friends?
- Yes

136
00:13:14,640 --> 00:13:16,631
And drop the Einstein, okay?

137
00:13:19,045 --> 00:13:21,513
Come on, I come in peace.

138
00:13:21,581 --> 00:13:25,381
You're with Lisa now, that's cool.
I'm over it.

139
00:13:26,752 --> 00:13:29,949
And we can still be friends, can't we?

140
00:13:30,022 --> 00:13:32,013
I don't know.

141
00:13:32,091 --> 00:13:35,527
Listen. There's going to be a party
in the city tonight.

142
00:13:35,595 --> 00:13:38,689
Run by guy I just met.
Went public, and just earned 200 million.

143
00:13:38,764 --> 00:13:40,755
You interested?

144
00:13:55,515 --> 00:13:57,506
Hey, take the wheel for a second.

145
00:14:11,297 --> 00:14:14,630
Remember when we went to Tijuana
that night? All night?

146
00:15:08,521 --> 00:15:11,684
This is Jimbo. It's his party.
This is John.

147
00:15:13,359 --> 00:15:17,022
Congratulations, man.
You're like Bill Gates with breasts.

148
00:15:17,096 --> 00:15:19,587
- Robert says you're smart.
- Yeah, I try.

149
00:15:19,665 --> 00:15:22,156
That does not mean you're going to 
be anything major.

150
00:15:22,235 --> 00:15:24,726
Glad you made it.
See you later, pal.

151
00:15:27,373 --> 00:15:29,933
- Don't hate the player.
- Hate the game.

152
00:15:31,477 --> 00:15:34,913
Are you working on anything now?

153
00:15:34,981 --> 00:15:36,972
- Yeah, right? I knew it.

154
00:15:37,049 --> 00:15:39,540
What people talk about on the Internet
brings the world together.

155
00:15:39,619 --> 00:15:42,110
Total breakthrough. It's really going to
happen.

156
00:15:42,188 --> 00:15:46,818
That's great, John.
No, really, that's inspiring.

157
00:15:46,892 --> 00:15:48,883
Do you have the money to do it?

158
00:15:48,961 --> 00:15:52,988
- No. Do you?
- No. But it's out there.

159
00:15:53,065 --> 00:15:55,556
I can't even get him to return
my calls.

160
00:15:58,571 --> 00:16:00,835
Sounds like a personal problem.

161
00:16:00,906 --> 00:16:02,897
Maybe Professor Fisher might.

162
00:16:02,975 --> 00:16:07,173
No, maybe we should talk
about going into business together.

163
00:16:07,246 --> 00:16:10,443
You've got the engineering skills while
I've got the juice.

164
00:16:10,516 --> 00:16:13,974
I can get some calls in. I have connections.

165
00:16:14,053 --> 00:16:16,783
My dad is president of the
Confederate Consortium.

166
00:16:16,856 --> 00:16:22,192
You're smart, John,
you always have been.

167
00:16:22,261 --> 00:16:24,252
But I'm a closer.

168
00:16:24,330 --> 00:16:29,267
This fraternity is
already beginning to eat my fill.

169
00:16:29,335 --> 00:16:32,202
What are you planning on doing
after graduation?

170
00:16:32,271 --> 00:16:34,262
I don't know.

171
00:16:34,340 --> 00:16:37,969
I don't know where I even should be

172
00:16:38,044 --> 00:16:40,035
in my life.

173
00:16:40,112 --> 00:16:41,943
I know where I should be going
with it.

174
00:16:44,116 --> 00:16:45,310
Heaven.

175
00:18:23,516 --> 00:18:27,976
Yeah, Vic? No, I can't 
see you in Back of the Moon.

176
00:18:28,053 --> 00:18:30,715
My folks are in town and I have to eat
dinner with them.

177
00:18:30,790 --> 00:18:32,781
$45 for a steak.

178
00:18:32,858 --> 00:18:35,349
- You can't have everything you see.
- Sure I can.

179
00:18:35,428 --> 00:18:37,419
Why can't I have steak?

180
00:18:38,798 --> 00:18:41,198
- His doctor said his heart -
- My doctor says my heart...

181
00:18:41,333 --> 00:18:45,133
can not stand paying $45 for a steak. 
What, are there gold plates in there?

182
00:18:47,573 --> 00:18:50,508
Mom, what are you not telling me?

183
00:18:52,745 --> 00:18:56,181
He had a mild heart incident last
month when he was out of the country.

184
00:18:56,248 --> 00:19:00,844
I was an American in a
Iraqi prison. What do you expect?

185
00:19:00,920 --> 00:19:03,946
Did you have a heart attack
an Iraqi prison? You're pushing 60.

186
00:19:04,023 --> 00:19:07,925
I had a cardiac event. I was there
interviewing a client.

187
00:19:07,993 --> 00:19:10,154
I'm a lawyer.
That is what I do.

188
00:19:10,229 --> 00:19:12,220
John, I saw my doctor.

189
00:19:12,298 --> 00:19:15,756
He said take it easy for a couple
weeks and not to worry.

190
00:19:15,835 --> 00:19:18,531
- And he said to stop eating steak.
- Enough!

191
00:19:18,604 --> 00:19:22,040
I don't want to talk about it.
Pushing 60?

192
00:19:22,107 --> 00:19:26,339
Anytime you want to step outside, kid,
and hang out with the old man

193
00:19:26,412 --> 00:19:28,471
I'll slap you down like a dog.

194
00:19:31,784 --> 00:19:35,117
Tell me about your new classes.

195
00:19:35,187 --> 00:19:38,179
The truth is that I was
thinking about leaving.

196
00:19:38,257 --> 00:19:43,160
Three years at Stanford.
Two years at Oxford.

197
00:19:43,229 --> 00:19:45,891
- You're not going to leave school.
- If it's a question of money -

198
00:19:45,965 --> 00:19:49,901
John, we know you're brilliant.
But I think your father...

199
00:19:49,969 --> 00:19:52,460
just wants you to have
a diploma as a backup.

200
00:19:52,538 --> 00:19:55,234
I do not need a backup.
I got a great idea, and with that

201
00:19:55,307 --> 00:19:58,708
- I want to start a company.
- I run a company, right?

202
00:19:58,777 --> 00:20:03,680
It's a lot of work.
You are not ready for it yet.

203
00:20:11,390 --> 00:20:13,824
Mr. Elias, nice to see ya.

204
00:20:16,161 --> 00:20:18,925
Thank you for being
my victim yesterday.

205
00:20:18,998 --> 00:20:22,900
- Is this a bad time?
- I've got a minute. What do you got?

206
00:20:22,968 --> 00:20:25,459
I want to talk to you
about my idea for a business.

207
00:20:27,339 --> 00:20:31,435
So why me? I'm just a
lowly college professor.

208
00:20:31,510 --> 00:20:34,604
I thought you might be able to help me.
I've called all the major D.C. firms

209
00:20:34,747 --> 00:20:37,409
but they don't return my calls.
I don't know anyone.

210
00:20:39,518 --> 00:20:43,215
Let me ask you this.
Do you like to get high?

211
00:20:49,695 --> 00:20:52,220
Can we fly level for a while?

212
00:20:52,298 --> 00:20:54,061
Sure.

213
00:20:56,035 --> 00:20:58,026
Do you get scared a lot?

214
00:20:58,103 --> 00:21:00,094
Well, who said this?

215
00:21:00,172 --> 00:21:03,630
"We think too small,
like the frog at the bottom of the well.

216
00:21:03,709 --> 00:21:06,405
The surface is something different entirely.

217
00:21:06,478 --> 00:21:08,139
Mao Ze Dong.

218
00:21:09,448 --> 00:21:12,815
Very impressive, Mr. Elias.
Very impressive.

219
00:21:12,885 --> 00:21:15,376
And so, you get to drive for 
a little while.

220
00:21:15,454 --> 00:21:16,785
No. No.

221
00:21:18,457 --> 00:21:21,824
- Jesus!
- You drive for a while...

222
00:21:21,894 --> 00:21:25,057
while telling me all about the
business plan.

223
00:21:27,232 --> 00:21:29,894
Let's hear it.
Go ahead, rock my world.

224
00:21:32,104 --> 00:21:34,095
My idea can change the internet.

225
00:21:34,173 --> 00:21:37,165
With a click, we can see
real-time video happening.

226
00:21:37,242 --> 00:21:39,972
Not the old, bandwidth with the internet?

227
00:21:40,045 --> 00:21:42,275
It's kind of an urban legend, 
don't you think?

228
00:21:42,348 --> 00:21:45,579
- No.
- I think you're out of your mind.

229
00:21:45,651 --> 00:21:48,142
- What?
- You heard me.

230
00:21:48,220 --> 00:21:50,211
You're out of your mind!

231
00:21:50,289 --> 00:21:52,814
You and every other gold brick
on the internet.

232
00:21:58,764 --> 00:22:02,131
- Sorry.
- Those who want to start businesses...

233
00:22:02,267 --> 00:22:04,758
understand the rewards
and the glory, but...

234
00:22:04,837 --> 00:22:07,328
What if something goes wrong?
It will happen. Are you ready...

235
00:22:07,406 --> 00:22:09,397
to take the wheel...

236
00:22:09,475 --> 00:22:13,104
of a company and have the future
of the entire people on your hands?

237
00:22:13,178 --> 00:22:16,773
You sound just like my father.
He just wants to get me a job.

238
00:22:19,451 --> 00:22:22,045
Well, I think he's wise man.

239
00:22:22,121 --> 00:22:24,988
- What do you do?
- He's a human rights lawyer.

240
00:22:25,057 --> 00:22:27,719
Bernard Elias.
I've heard of him.

241
00:22:27,793 --> 00:22:31,229
You may not know technology,
but you know people.

242
00:22:31,296 --> 00:22:36,063
He fears for you. He's seen the worst
things of human nature.

243
00:22:36,135 --> 00:22:39,127
- He just wants you to be safe.
- I don't want to be safe.

244
00:22:43,809 --> 00:22:46,175
- Very well.
- What?

245
00:22:46,245 --> 00:22:48,736
So let's have a little fun, shall we?

246
00:23:05,931 --> 00:23:07,922
This is John.

247
00:23:08,000 --> 00:23:10,662
We're going to see a man
named Tom Walker.

248
00:23:10,736 --> 00:23:13,227
- We are waiting.
- "Dr. Fisher? 

249
00:23:13,338 --> 00:23:16,933
Yes, it is Tom Walker.
Have you heard of him?

250
00:23:17,009 --> 00:23:20,775
Sure. He did police time.
Sorry. I read that he was crazy.

251
00:23:20,846 --> 00:23:24,612
Yes? Well, he's a friend of mine.
He's an angel investor.

252
00:23:24,683 --> 00:23:28,949
- Experience in the field.
- I understand.

253
00:23:29,021 --> 00:23:33,617
Listen, sorry I puked
in your plane, and thank you very much -

254
00:23:33,692 --> 00:23:38,026
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
And don't ever bother me again.

255
00:24:02,554 --> 00:24:05,045
I don't know how we're going to even find him.

256
00:24:05,124 --> 00:24:07,957
- There are no numbers anywhere.
- We should start looking.

257
00:24:20,072 --> 00:24:22,404
If they kill me, keep the car.

258
00:24:28,080 --> 00:24:30,071
Hey, how you doing?

259
00:24:33,085 --> 00:24:36,680
Do you know where Tom Walker's house is?

260
00:24:36,755 --> 00:24:40,122
What do you want with him?

261
00:24:40,192 --> 00:24:42,683
- A friend sent me.
- Who?

262
00:24:44,096 --> 00:24:46,326
Ben Fisher.
He's a professor at Stanford.

263
00:24:47,966 --> 00:24:52,164
I haven't heard from that guy in a while.
You've got five minutes.

264
00:24:55,440 --> 00:24:58,102
The graphs show how we
we can begn speed things up.

265
00:24:58,177 --> 00:25:00,771
This is the internet application
that will make all of us...

266
00:25:00,846 --> 00:25:04,373
on one planet, one people, without borders.

267
00:25:05,617 --> 00:25:08,814
These are just small pictures.
You want to invest in that?

268
00:25:10,389 --> 00:25:12,880
I can show you some code
I've written so far.

269
00:25:12,958 --> 00:25:15,791
No, thanks.

270
00:25:15,861 --> 00:25:18,728
- Do you like horses?
- I suppose so.

271
00:25:18,797 --> 00:25:21,459
It seems that that is why
I like your girl.

272
00:25:21,533 --> 00:25:25,128
Do something. If you can stay
on that horse for 30 seconds...

273
00:25:25,204 --> 00:25:28,731
I'll give you money.
Deal?

274
00:25:28,807 --> 00:25:31,401
You got to be kidding me.

275
00:25:31,476 --> 00:25:33,740
Do I look like I'm kidding?

276
00:25:37,316 --> 00:25:40,581
- This guy is not serious. Let's go.
- Say what?

277
00:25:40,652 --> 00:25:43,815
He said he would give me the money
if I could stay on the horse for 30 seconds.

278
00:25:43,889 --> 00:25:46,824
- Come on.
- Then stay on for 30 seconds.

279
00:25:48,760 --> 00:25:50,819
Hold on. It's pretty fiery.

280
00:25:54,266 --> 00:25:56,257
Let's see what you have, son.

281
00:25:56,335 --> 00:25:59,202
Don't look at me.
It's between you and the horse.

282
00:26:04,343 --> 00:26:07,506
Take it slowly.
See what you can do.

283
00:26:12,684 --> 00:26:14,675
This is very easy.

284
00:26:23,395 --> 00:26:25,386
This is a piece of cake.

285
00:26:25,464 --> 00:26:29,059
- Relax! 10 seconds.
- How do I get out of this thing?

286
00:26:35,207 --> 00:26:39,166
Keep going, baby!
15 seconds!

287
00:26:43,882 --> 00:26:47,545
Be a Cowboy, John!
10 seconds to go!

288
00:26:58,563 --> 00:27:00,929
30 seconds!
You did it!

289
00:27:05,871 --> 00:27:08,840
- Easy, boy. You're fine.
- Good rodeo, kid.

290
00:27:10,475 --> 00:27:14,172
You did it, crazy shit!
You did it!

291
00:27:14,246 --> 00:27:16,237
He earned it.

292
00:27:20,852 --> 00:27:24,845
You're either a complete idiot, very brave
or just damn lucky.

293
00:27:24,923 --> 00:27:27,414
So, I'll give you five million
to get something going.

294
00:27:30,595 --> 00:27:33,428
And don't try to negotiate with me.
It pisses me off.

295
00:27:34,666 --> 00:27:39,262
But if your company isn't successful,
I will hunt you down and kill you.

296
00:27:40,772 --> 00:27:44,936
These is the big time.
Do not fuck with me.

297
00:27:56,621 --> 00:27:59,715
We got it.

298
00:27:59,791 --> 00:28:01,884
Oh my God!
You did it!

299
00:28:01,960 --> 00:28:04,451
I will! You guys
are my best friends...

300
00:28:04,529 --> 00:28:07,555
and I want you guys to be my partners. Only
I need to know if you will.

301
00:28:07,632 --> 00:28:10,692
- Are you kidding?
- Of course I will!

302
00:29:09,428 --> 00:29:11,419
You're the man, Tiger.

303
00:29:11,496 --> 00:29:13,487
Courtesy of my father's membership.

304
00:29:14,866 --> 00:29:17,357
Well I have an angel.
I got out of Stanford.

305
00:29:17,436 --> 00:29:20,405
Vic, Kiko and I are in a business. 
We're in the process of...

306
00:29:20,472 --> 00:29:22,963
getting an office.
You won't believe it.

307
00:29:23,041 --> 00:29:25,032
Great, man.

308
00:29:26,378 --> 00:29:29,643
- What about you, how are you?
- I don't know.

309
00:29:29,714 --> 00:29:32,205
I mean, I got some pretty big offers already.

310
00:29:32,284 --> 00:29:34,809
I thought it'd be good
for this business.

311
00:29:34,886 --> 00:29:37,377
I'm definitely interested.
I just want to know...

312
00:29:37,456 --> 00:29:39,947
if you have a good deal.

313
00:29:40,025 --> 00:29:42,823
Sure. The next step is to gather
a team of boardmen

314
00:29:45,497 --> 00:29:47,988
15% of the company stock profits
and an executive title. That's what I want.

315
00:29:48,066 --> 00:29:50,557
Do you want someone to make
dealings? That's what it'll cost you.

316
00:29:50,635 --> 00:29:53,729
- 10% and 2k a week.
- I need 3k.

317
00:29:53,805 --> 00:29:57,036
- You can't have it.
- Just testing.

318
00:30:01,079 --> 00:30:03,172
You got yourself a deal.

319
00:30:03,248 --> 00:30:06,411
Executive VP of Business Development.

320
00:30:06,485 --> 00:30:08,976
Yeah, yeah. That's what I want 
to be called.

321
00:30:09,054 --> 00:30:11,852
DIGITAL DREAMS

322
00:30:11,923 --> 00:30:14,858
Failure means certain death.
Hang him high, boys.

323
00:30:14,926 --> 00:30:17,520
- What is that?
- I sent him e-mail this morning.

324
00:30:19,764 --> 00:30:24,360
I heard he was crazy, but
this is fucking weird.

325
00:30:24,436 --> 00:30:27,132
- The failure means death.
- It is good animation.

326
00:30:27,205 --> 00:30:30,800
Hang him high, guys.
Hang him high.

327
00:30:30,876 --> 00:30:33,868
- How did you find us?
- I hired him.

328
00:30:33,945 --> 00:30:35,936
He's got great contacts.

329
00:30:36,014 --> 00:30:39,882
His dad knows all the
investors of the city.

330
00:30:39,951 --> 00:30:43,546
- How many stocks is he gonna get?
- 10%

331
00:30:43,622 --> 00:30:46,318
- It's almost as much as -
- Guys!

332
00:30:46,391 --> 00:30:48,382
We were just talking about you.

333
00:30:48,460 --> 00:30:51,725
I love this piece, man.
This is awesome.

334
00:30:51,796 --> 00:30:54,287
These are Victor and Kiko,
our co-CEOs.

335
00:30:54,366 --> 00:30:57,164
No, no. I know.
What's going on, Vic? Kinky?

336
00:30:57,235 --> 00:30:59,726
You guys run the lab thing in school, right?

337
00:30:59,804 --> 00:31:02,967
Actually, John used to, but now
Kiko and I run this lab thing.

338
00:31:03,041 --> 00:31:05,373
- Cool, cool!
- How are you, man?

339
00:31:05,443 --> 00:31:09,004
You need to check out my new digs.
Brought some of my dad's art collection

340
00:31:09,080 --> 00:31:11,344
to hang up on the wall in this place.

341
00:31:11,416 --> 00:31:15,853
- Are you going to show me my office or what?
- Right this way.

342
00:31:15,921 --> 00:31:19,254
Hey, keep up the good work.
See you around.

343
00:31:19,324 --> 00:31:21,986
- This is my office.
- Yeah? Mine is bigger than that, right?

344
00:31:23,495 --> 00:31:26,396
- Did he just call me "Kinky"?
- Yes.

345
00:31:27,566 --> 00:31:29,557
Okay. College Sucks!

346
00:31:31,503 --> 00:31:33,494
Boys, this generation...

347
00:31:33,572 --> 00:31:36,268
has an inability to listen.

348
00:31:36,341 --> 00:31:39,606
There's too much, too much going
on around you guys. Too much TV,

349
00:31:39,678 --> 00:31:42,511
too much technology,
too much sodium.

350
00:31:42,581 --> 00:31:46,073
It is the paradox of progress,
my friends.

351
00:31:46,151 --> 00:31:48,551
The more technology you use,
the less time we have.

352
00:31:48,620 --> 00:31:51,783
How is Mr. Elias going to run a 
whole company, when he

353
00:31:51,856 --> 00:31:54,825
can't even listen to his sweet
middle-aged college professor?

354
00:32:01,933 --> 00:32:02,922
Yeah?

355
00:32:03,001 --> 00:32:06,459
- Hey, it's me.
- Hello.

356
00:32:06,538 --> 00:32:08,870
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.

357
00:32:08,940 --> 00:32:11,408
Just that I haven't heard from you
in four days, that's all.

358
00:32:11,476 --> 00:32:16,470
Listen, it really has been a big four days.

359
00:32:16,548 --> 00:32:18,778
That's fair.
I forgive you.

360
00:32:18,850 --> 00:32:20,841
But here are the rules:

361
00:32:20,919 --> 00:32:23,410
when you're in a relationship
especially if it involves sex...

362
00:32:23,488 --> 00:32:27,015
should call at least every 24 hours.
That's how it works, ask any girl.

363
00:32:28,560 --> 00:32:30,551
I'm very sorry. I really am.

364
00:32:30,629 --> 00:32:33,029
In the future, I'll have sex, and I'll
call within the next 24 hours.

365
00:32:35,100 --> 00:32:37,091
Haha, okay. Tell me everything.

366
00:32:37,168 --> 00:32:39,898
Right, well. I hired Robert
as my business guy, uh.

367
00:32:39,971 --> 00:32:43,737
Really?
Interesting choice.

368
00:32:43,808 --> 00:32:45,799
Well, don't worry.

369
00:32:45,877 --> 00:32:48,573
I'm just hiring his Rolodex, basically.

370
00:32:48,647 --> 00:32:51,013
Two things have to happen here.
One...

371
00:32:51,082 --> 00:32:53,573
John and I have to go and assemble
a board of directors

372
00:32:53,652 --> 00:32:56,177
that can guide us through the rack
of taking a product on the market

373
00:32:56,254 --> 00:32:58,688
and connect us on all the right
levels.

374
00:32:58,757 --> 00:33:01,248
We're gonna put quality over
quantity, and going to make the work 

375
00:33:01,326 --> 00:33:03,988
funner and more exciting
for ourselves and for customers.

376
00:33:04,062 --> 00:33:06,860
All of you have three months...

377
00:33:06,931 --> 00:33:10,196
to create a kickass beta version of our
software that we can take

378
00:33:10,268 --> 00:33:13,260
to the internet press vultures and
blow their fucking minds

379
00:33:13,338 --> 00:33:16,205
Yeah, we're making a product, but this
is a product that will bring everybody

380
00:33:16,274 --> 00:33:19,141
on this planet a little closer together.

381
00:33:19,210 --> 00:33:22,873
Three months, people. That's all the 
time that we have at our present burn rate.

382
00:33:22,947 --> 00:33:25,211
It will go by quickly, rest assured,

383
00:33:25,283 --> 00:33:29,720
but hey, no one said
that getting rich would be easy.

384
00:33:29,788 --> 00:33:33,554
This is business, up and down,
round the clock, balls to the wall

385
00:33:33,625 --> 00:33:35,718
all out seeding and doesn't stop.

386
00:33:35,794 --> 00:33:39,560
So we mix this up, cash in our shit

387
00:33:39,631 --> 00:33:41,963
and go home a millionaire!

388
00:33:42,033 --> 00:33:45,935
Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?
I know I want to be.

389
00:33:54,312 --> 00:33:57,406
Hey. What's wrong?

390
00:33:57,482 --> 00:34:01,350
I don't think we should talk to people about 
listing when we don't have a product yet.

391
00:34:01,419 --> 00:34:03,910
Oh, no, come on, John, that's just
to get their blood flowing.

392
00:34:03,988 --> 00:34:06,479
Be thinking about their shares

393
00:34:06,558 --> 00:34:09,049
is what will keep
working all night.

394
00:34:09,127 --> 00:34:11,618
I just don't want people to be
thinking in the short-term.

395
00:34:11,696 --> 00:34:14,187
- Our product will take time to develop.
- Oh I know, I know. It's just talk.

396
00:34:14,265 --> 00:34:17,860
I promise you.
Your stylist outfit you?

397
00:34:23,007 --> 00:34:28,035
- That suit is so you, Mr. Elias.
- It's expensive.

398
00:34:28,113 --> 00:34:30,104
Excuse me for a moment?

399
00:34:31,349 --> 00:34:35,752
John, this suit is another
business tool.

400
00:34:35,820 --> 00:34:39,551
- I actually have a suit.
- No, you don't. I've seen it.

401
00:34:39,624 --> 00:34:42,115
This is a real suit
and you'll need 5.

402
00:34:42,193 --> 00:34:46,960
- Five? That's 10 grand.
- Good math, man.

403
00:34:47,031 --> 00:34:49,522
You want to be big time?
You're gonna to have to act big time.

404
00:34:49,601 --> 00:34:52,092
You gotta dress big time.

405
00:34:52,170 --> 00:34:54,661
This is part of capitalism and what
it's all about.


406
00:34:54,739 --> 00:34:57,936
Let's get Natalie to find
a nice shirt and then -

407
00:34:58,009 --> 00:35:00,671
- Then what?
- Then a little surprise.

408
00:35:13,391 --> 00:35:15,882
- What is this place?
- You'll see.

409
00:35:15,960 --> 00:35:17,951
Mr. Jennings, welcome.

410
00:35:29,474 --> 00:35:31,806
- My God!
- Yes, members only.

411
00:35:31,876 --> 00:35:33,867
This is where a lot deals get done.

412
00:35:33,945 --> 00:35:37,711
The only reason we're here is because
my father is a member.

413
00:35:41,920 --> 00:35:43,410
Oh my.

414
00:35:45,089 --> 00:35:48,786
We're meeting some friends. 
Here they are.

415
00:35:58,102 --> 00:36:01,538
This is John. CEO of our new internet
company.

416
00:36:01,606 --> 00:36:04,507
I'm Amanda.
She's Halle.

417
00:36:04,576 --> 00:36:07,067
Give us four glasses
of champagne, please.

418
00:36:11,616 --> 00:36:13,607
Someone miss me?

419
00:36:16,087 --> 00:36:21,389
So. Must be exciting being CEO of
a new internet company?

420
00:36:21,459 --> 00:36:23,450
It's exciting. It's -

421
00:36:24,863 --> 00:36:27,832
The truth is that we've barely
been in business long.

422
00:36:27,899 --> 00:36:30,891
Well, you'll be great. I can tell.

423
00:36:30,969 --> 00:36:32,163
Thanks.

424
00:36:32,237 --> 00:36:36,230
I used to work for one of the biggest
investment houses on the east coast.

425
00:36:36,307 --> 00:36:38,298
And I can pick the big ones out.

426
00:36:39,811 --> 00:36:43,440
Drink to your company and your success.

427
00:36:46,317 --> 00:36:49,753
Did you work in bank
investment?

428
00:36:49,821 --> 00:36:52,756
Yes, I did.

429
00:36:52,824 --> 00:36:57,591
I got a little tired of the hurly burly. I got a
big role in a TV pilot

430
00:36:57,662 --> 00:37:02,224
and I came down and it films in
three weeks but until then -

431
00:37:04,502 --> 00:37:07,335
You don't believe me?
I went to Columbia, you know?

432
00:37:07,405 --> 00:37:09,396
I believe you.

433
00:37:10,842 --> 00:37:15,040
We'll only be hanging out in San Francisco
until it's over.

434
00:37:15,113 --> 00:37:20,073
These days only the cool people
open up internet companies.

435
00:37:20,151 --> 00:37:22,642
- Not in Hollywood.
- No?

436
00:37:22,720 --> 00:37:27,214
Yes, so we decided to spend
time here over the summer.

437
00:37:29,527 --> 00:37:31,859
That's a lovely suit, by the way.

438
00:37:35,099 --> 00:37:37,090
It's new.

439
00:37:45,209 --> 00:37:48,042
There you are!
What happened to you last night?

440
00:37:49,714 --> 00:37:52,478
I had some meetings with Robert.

441
00:37:52,550 --> 00:37:55,314
Well, Lisa came by.
Nobody knew where you were.

442
00:37:55,386 --> 00:37:58,150
We tried the cell.

443
00:37:58,222 --> 00:38:01,316
What's on your face?

444
00:38:01,392 --> 00:38:03,986
It's nothing.

445
00:38:04,062 --> 00:38:06,826
We have some new stuff for you and
we can go over there for a look.

446
00:38:06,898 --> 00:38:09,560
Until you see it.
It still has flaws.

447
00:38:11,469 --> 00:38:14,233
- Hey, it's 11 o'clock.
- Okay.

448
00:38:14,305 --> 00:38:17,331
I'll take a shower
and I'll be there.

449
00:38:20,411 --> 00:38:22,902
Good morning, sunshine.
We're on the move.

450
00:38:22,981 --> 00:38:25,472
You're going to love me when
I tell you who we're meeting with today.

451
00:38:25,550 --> 00:38:27,882
- Who?
- Anna Simmons.

452
00:38:27,952 --> 00:38:30,443
We get her on board and all the
other investors

453
00:38:30,521 --> 00:38:32,512
will line up to massage
our genitals.

454
00:38:32,590 --> 00:38:36,686
- How'd you do that? I thought she was in investment banking.
- Yeah she is. That's because I have a bigger set.

455
00:38:36,761 --> 00:38:39,594
If I have to pimp myself out to be
her love slave, I will.

456
00:38:39,664 --> 00:38:42,155
I'll give her months of oral sex
for the rest of the year

457
00:38:42,233 --> 00:38:44,224
until she comes on board, huh?

458
00:39:10,795 --> 00:39:12,820
Five more minutes and we'll enter.

459
00:39:13,665 --> 00:39:19,069
Move 200,000 shares of TAC from Darcastle
into Mirrorview.

460
00:39:19,137 --> 00:39:22,231
Check on all the prices of our holdings
in Southeast Asia.

461
00:39:22,306 --> 00:39:25,742
Anything under 20%, sell.

462
00:39:25,810 --> 00:39:29,576
Yes, by the way
I've got this report on

463
00:39:29,647 --> 00:39:32,480
Digital Dreams. I see
it's rated impeccable.

464
00:39:34,986 --> 00:39:37,921
"The advertising campaign
of the decade?

465
00:39:37,989 --> 00:39:41,152
I've got the two young men
founders right outside my door.

466
00:39:43,261 --> 00:39:47,254
I want them to sweat a little.

467
00:39:47,331 --> 00:39:49,322
Thanks, Marcie.

468
00:39:57,742 --> 00:40:01,109
I'm terribly sorry, but Ms. Simmons
can't see you today.

469
00:40:01,179 --> 00:40:02,840
No, no, no -

470
00:40:02,914 --> 00:40:06,111
Today we made the appointment with
her and we'll see her now.

471
00:40:06,184 --> 00:40:09,278
I'm sorry, she's very busy.
Please leave.

472
00:40:09,353 --> 00:40:11,150
Wait.

473
00:40:11,222 --> 00:40:13,213
Come on.

474
00:40:13,291 --> 00:40:18,285
We had an agreement, Marcie? Didn't we.

475
00:40:18,362 --> 00:40:22,628
We had an appointment with her
and we're going in to see her.

476
00:40:22,700 --> 00:40:25,191
- Robert let's go.
- No, we have a meeting. Come on.

477
00:40:25,269 --> 00:40:28,136
- Hey, you can't -
- Thanks.

478
00:40:28,206 --> 00:40:30,697
I'm Robert Jennings,
son of Doug Jennings...

479
00:40:30,775 --> 00:40:34,802
- Marcie, call security.
- My father is Doug Jennings.

480
00:40:34,879 --> 00:40:38,042
I do not care who your father is.
Get the hell out of this office.

481
00:40:38,116 --> 00:40:40,243
- Hey, I'm sorry, but we -
- Now!

482
00:40:40,318 --> 00:40:44,345
John. Excuse me. I apologize.
We'll go now.

483
00:40:44,422 --> 00:40:46,913
But if you have a chance if you
could just look at our business plan

484
00:40:46,991 --> 00:40:49,482
Take a look at it.
That's all I ask.

485
00:40:49,560 --> 00:40:52,222
Is this the internet company, 
per chance?

486
00:40:54,565 --> 00:40:57,056
It's not just any company.
Digital Dreams...

487
00:40:57,135 --> 00:40:59,626
has the most amazing product
you've ever seen...

488
00:40:59,704 --> 00:41:02,195
and we thought you might like to 
be on board.

489
00:41:02,273 --> 00:41:04,764
I don't do startups.
But if your idea is as good as you say,

490
00:41:04,842 --> 00:41:06,833
Then someone else will back you

491
00:41:06,911 --> 00:41:10,779
and maybe I'll broke with you 
through your acquisitions.

492
00:41:10,848 --> 00:41:12,839
I don't want anybody else.

493
00:41:14,318 --> 00:41:18,311
I know you were behind the IPO
Herradura Technology Societies.

494
00:41:18,389 --> 00:41:22,189
You were pulling strings all this time.

495
00:41:22,260 --> 00:41:24,251
Is that right?

496
00:41:24,328 --> 00:41:26,819
Only you, Anna, can guide us through
listing on the stock market...

497
00:41:26,898 --> 00:41:30,834
and make us the millions we
richly deserve.

498
00:41:32,603 --> 00:41:35,401
Oh. You richly deserve millions, do you?

499
00:41:38,109 --> 00:41:40,873
Awesome! This is unbelievable!

500
00:41:40,945 --> 00:41:43,209
I'm glad it's over.

501
00:41:43,281 --> 00:41:45,374
She was eating out of your hand.

502
00:41:45,449 --> 00:41:48,213
I can't believe I just signed away
a huge chunk of the company.

503
00:41:48,286 --> 00:41:51,778
What are you talking about?
You still own 25% of the company.

504
00:41:51,856 --> 00:41:55,656
Compared to my lousy 10%. And the surrender to
Anna Simmons,

505
00:41:55,726 --> 00:41:58,217
She makes kings.
So relax, we got it all worked out.

506
00:41:58,296 --> 00:42:00,730
I just cut to Vic and Kiko
4.5% each.

507
00:42:00,798 --> 00:42:03,232
She receives 5 for looking at our plan.
And a board of

508
00:42:03,301 --> 00:42:06,634
people I don't even know have
have 26%.

509
00:42:06,704 --> 00:42:09,195
Right now Vic and Kiko are
writing the source code and you

510
00:42:09,273 --> 00:42:11,741
virtually promised to leave the
public tomorrow when it still has flaws.

511
00:42:11,809 --> 00:42:17,406
You talk about our code changing
the world, making it a better place

512
00:42:17,481 --> 00:42:19,972
promoting world peace.
For that to happen...

513
00:42:20,051 --> 00:42:24,920
we take care of business.
Once we achieve our goal,

514
00:42:24,989 --> 00:42:29,585
there will be plenty of time
for us to become heroes, all right?

515
00:42:29,660 --> 00:42:33,255
Now if you want my personal opinion,
we need to throw  big party.

516
00:42:33,331 --> 00:42:37,961
- Party, party, party, party!
- Well, we'll have a party.

517
00:42:40,504 --> 00:42:42,495
Is everybody having fun?

518
00:42:43,941 --> 00:42:47,342
As you know, we just closed
a deal with the board of directors.

519
00:42:47,411 --> 00:42:49,902
And it's important to people
in the world of technology.

520
00:42:49,981 --> 00:42:53,246
None of this - and I mean none of this
this would have happened without you.

521
00:42:53,317 --> 00:42:56,286
So from the bottom of my heart
I thank and applaud you.

522
00:42:56,354 --> 00:42:59,289
And I long to tell
about the incredible...

523
00:42:59,357 --> 00:43:03,293
second round of funding
that this meeting will provide.

524
00:43:03,361 --> 00:43:07,559
We are going to get rich, people!

525
00:43:07,632 --> 00:43:10,624
Who's with me?
Who's with me?

526
00:43:10,701 --> 00:43:14,262
Now, go have fun!
That's an order!

527
00:43:35,226 --> 00:43:37,888
Did you feed the dogs?

528
00:43:37,962 --> 00:43:40,453
You said you would feed the dogs.

529
00:43:46,203 --> 00:43:48,671
They have good music.

530
00:43:48,739 --> 00:43:52,675
Remember those who put
disco music all night?

531
00:43:52,743 --> 00:43:53,732
Yes

532
00:43:55,913 --> 00:43:58,245
Mine is being awful
conscious tonight.

533
00:44:00,484 --> 00:44:04,147
I think that's his girlfriend.

534
00:44:20,504 --> 00:44:23,268
There you are.
I couldn't find you.

535
00:44:23,341 --> 00:44:26,435
- Are you leaving?
- Yeah. I have to go.

536
00:44:26,510 --> 00:44:29,775
- What's wrong?
- I don't know. I just want to leave.

537
00:44:29,847 --> 00:44:33,305
Thanks a lot. I go see your band
every time you play

538
00:44:33,384 --> 00:44:36,046
and now that I have the light on me, 
you leave in the middle of the party.

539
00:44:37,955 --> 00:44:42,051
John, be careful.
You're so smart and so good.

540
00:44:42,126 --> 00:44:46,222
- I don't want to see you lose that.
- What are you talking about?

541
00:44:47,231 --> 00:44:49,665
This is not what I thought it would be.

542
00:44:49,734 --> 00:44:51,725
Sorry.

543
00:45:00,311 --> 00:45:01,300
Hey.

544
00:45:04,315 --> 00:45:06,579
- Hi.
- Hey.

545
00:45:06,650 --> 00:45:08,641
It's a cool party, huh?

546
00:45:14,992 --> 00:45:15,981
Another one.

547
00:45:19,663 --> 00:45:20,652
What?

548
00:45:23,667 --> 00:45:25,726
Time for a little
e-commerce.

549
00:45:29,173 --> 00:45:32,108
Come on, John, we've been working
hard to build this company.

550
00:45:32,176 --> 00:45:35,612
Sometimes you just have to let it go.
Let it all out.

551
00:45:35,679 --> 00:45:39,513
We had a big success today, man.
Celebrate with me.

552
00:45:41,685 --> 00:45:42,674
All right.

553
00:45:44,355 --> 00:45:47,119
With another swig of tequila.

554
00:45:47,191 --> 00:45:49,182
Give me that.

555
00:45:55,866 --> 00:45:57,857
Follow me.

556
00:46:06,777 --> 00:46:11,476
I think our lady friends would
like to leave and have some fun.

557
00:46:11,549 --> 00:46:13,540
Shall we, ladies?

558
00:46:15,653 --> 00:46:17,644
I can't.

559
00:46:17,721 --> 00:46:20,554
John, let's leave the kids.

560
00:46:22,660 --> 00:46:24,651
Let's go.

561
00:46:33,304 --> 00:46:35,772
- Please?
- That means "yes."

562
00:46:37,074 --> 00:46:40,407
The name is Bond -
James Bond.

563
00:46:43,747 --> 00:46:45,305
Oh my God.

564
00:46:58,762 --> 00:47:00,821
To Elijah likes that.

565
00:47:17,681 --> 00:47:20,172
- You deserve this.
- Enough.

566
00:47:20,251 --> 00:47:22,981
I have someone and I don't know you.

567
00:47:59,490 --> 00:48:01,720
Let's see what we've got here.

568
00:48:01,792 --> 00:48:03,783
Are you ready?
We'll see.

569
00:48:06,730 --> 00:48:09,062
Houston, we have taken off.

570
00:48:34,525 --> 00:48:35,514
Hello?

571
00:49:10,227 --> 00:49:11,717
 

572
00:49:11,795 --> 00:49:14,320


573
00:49:14,398 --> 00:49:17,128


574
00:49:40,758 --> 00:49:44,717


575
00:49:58,609 --> 00:50:01,373
Houston, we have a problem.

576
00:50:01,445 --> 00:50:05,882
- I think it's the protocol.
- You think?

577
00:50:05,949 --> 00:50:08,440
Listen, I know that
I haven't been here much

578
00:50:08,519 --> 00:50:11,044
but all of this business stuff
takes top priority.

579
00:50:11,121 --> 00:50:13,612
Well, it is a tough life being
an internet playboy!

580
00:50:13,691 --> 00:50:16,182
Sure it is.
You have to buy new clothes...

581
00:50:16,260 --> 00:50:18,922
out with new friends
sleep with new hoes -

582
00:50:18,996 --> 00:50:22,261
Come on, guys. Let's get out of here 
and go get something to eat.

583
00:50:22,333 --> 00:50:24,324
Let's go.

584
00:50:36,980 --> 00:50:39,380
- Hello?
- Hey you!

585
00:50:39,450 --> 00:50:41,941
- We did it!
- Sit down. We need to talk.

586
00:50:42,019 --> 00:50:44,010
No, listen to me.
We did it.

587
00:50:44,088 --> 00:50:46,579
I just got a phone call from Anna Simmons.

588
00:50:46,657 --> 00:50:49,649
We just secured our second round of funding.

589
00:50:49,727 --> 00:50:54,221
- How much?
- $30 million.

590
00:50:55,999 --> 00:51:00,333
$30 million dollars!
$30 million dollars, people!

591
00:51:00,404 --> 00:51:02,531
i $ 30 million dollars!

592
00:51:02,606 --> 00:51:05,097
Do you think a lot of money?

593
00:51:05,175 --> 00:51:09,908
Digital Dreams will sell software
to the world!

594
00:51:18,455 --> 00:51:20,446
This is...

595
00:51:20,524 --> 00:51:23,220
a pussy-mobile.

596
00:51:23,293 --> 00:51:25,784
- It's a nice car.
- Are you going to go?

597
00:51:25,863 --> 00:51:28,696
I do not know.
No, of course not.

598
00:51:30,367 --> 00:51:33,495
Robert, this is getting out of hand.

599
00:51:35,305 --> 00:51:37,796
- What?
- Sorry. It is not -

600
00:51:37,875 --> 00:51:39,866
It's not your problem.
It's Lisa.

601
00:51:39,943 --> 00:51:42,434
Every time I call her,
she keeps hanging up on me.

602
00:51:44,515 --> 00:51:46,506
Are you guys in a fight?

603
00:51:52,890 --> 00:51:56,656
Hey, let's go show Lisa the car.
That'll impress her.

604
00:52:10,240 --> 00:52:11,229
Honey!

605
00:52:12,910 --> 00:52:15,310
I just close my second round
$30 million.

606
00:52:15,379 --> 00:52:17,370
Go to hell, John.

607
00:52:21,285 --> 00:52:23,776
Whoa... I don't know, you'd think
she'd be a little more excited than that.

608
00:52:42,105 --> 00:52:44,096
We're gonna blow their minds.

609
00:52:44,174 --> 00:52:46,369
And this is just the beta.

610
00:52:48,779 --> 00:52:51,270
- Do you know Adam from PC Week?
- Yes

611
00:52:51,348 --> 00:52:54,715
When Yahoo launched, they
bought 5,000 shares.

612
00:52:54,785 --> 00:52:57,515
So today he's not here.
He's in the Bahamas.

613
00:52:57,588 --> 00:53:02,719
Ladies and gentlemen,
the CEO of Digital Dreams...

614
00:53:02,793 --> 00:53:07,230
a man with vision,
a man with a purpose...

615
00:53:07,297 --> 00:53:09,731
Mr. John Elias.

616
00:53:15,138 --> 00:53:17,629
We are here today
to launch a product...

617
00:53:17,708 --> 00:53:20,199
that will change the face
of computing history with the convergence

618
00:53:20,277 --> 00:53:22,768
of television and the cyber network.

619
00:53:24,248 --> 00:53:26,910
Who here has all the speed they want?

620
00:53:26,984 --> 00:53:29,919
Who is happy with the way things are?

621
00:53:29,987 --> 00:53:32,979
Well, today all that will change.
We have developed a software...

622
00:53:33,056 --> 00:53:36,082
that dramatically intensify
the internet experience.

623
00:53:36,159 --> 00:53:38,650
No installation charges.
No monthly charges

624
00:53:38,795 --> 00:53:41,286
for an expensive
high-speed connection.

625
00:53:41,365 --> 00:53:43,856
A single purchase, that on demand,

626
00:53:43,934 --> 00:53:46,630
High Quality Video in
real time for life.

627
00:53:46,703 --> 00:53:48,694
Lights, please.

628
00:53:51,174 --> 00:53:53,768
We have installed our software
on this PC, which is

629
00:53:53,844 --> 00:53:58,645
connected to a remote server
using a regular modem.

630
00:53:58,715 --> 00:54:00,706
To start the demonstration.

631
00:54:05,689 --> 00:54:10,353
This is a transmission
real-time, no hard disk.

632
00:54:32,215 --> 00:54:36,743
It's okay. Just an operating system
mistake, everybody.

633
00:54:38,622 --> 00:54:40,613
I will restart.

634
00:54:43,560 --> 00:54:45,755
All right. Just -
Please, please.

635
00:54:57,174 --> 00:54:59,165
I need some help here.

636
00:54:59,242 --> 00:55:01,972
In San Francisco, newcomer
Digital Dreams, was ready...

637
00:55:02,045 --> 00:55:05,845
to demonstrate their access
the high-speed lnternet access software...

638
00:55:05,916 --> 00:55:08,407
when their plans went up in smoke -
literally.

639
00:55:08,485 --> 00:55:09,975
Can you help?

640
00:55:10,053 --> 00:55:12,248
Experts say that the
odds of this happening...

641
00:55:12,322 --> 00:55:14,313
is 1 in 76,000,000.

642
00:55:17,661 --> 00:55:18,650
Please?

643
00:55:18,729 --> 00:55:21,220
Digital Dreams
says there is no connection...

644
00:55:21,298 --> 00:55:24,631
between their software launch
and their hardware burning.

645
00:55:24,701 --> 00:55:27,192
However, young CEO John Elias...

646
00:55:27,270 --> 00:55:30,171
is likely to be the butt of many
jokes for a while.

647
00:55:32,275 --> 00:55:35,073
My God.

648
00:55:35,145 --> 00:55:37,136
Are there sprinklers?

649
00:55:54,464 --> 00:55:57,729
This is Tom Walker. Call me
you little ass-wiper.

650
00:55:57,801 --> 00:56:00,793
I'm watching TV, I'm seeing
my money go up in smoke.

651
00:56:02,472 --> 00:56:04,963
John, this is your father.
Please call me...

652
00:56:05,042 --> 00:56:08,443
as soon as you receive this message.
I saw you on TV.

653
00:56:12,115 --> 00:56:14,811
Where have you been?

654
00:56:14,885 --> 00:56:18,082
Hiding. But it's a new day
and things are looking up.

655
00:56:18,155 --> 00:56:21,682
I had lunch with Anna.
She says that when you meet her again...

656
00:56:21,758 --> 00:56:26,252
any publicity is good.
Everyone knows Digital Dream now.

657
00:56:26,329 --> 00:56:29,765
This helps us return a comeback
of monumental proportions.

658
00:56:31,668 --> 00:56:34,193
Vic and Kiko needed more guidance from you.

659
00:56:34,271 --> 00:56:36,262
Obviously, you're the genius.

660
00:56:36,339 --> 00:56:38,830
Our whole company is based
on your designs.

661
00:56:38,909 --> 00:56:41,776
If you'd been there
working with them...

662
00:56:41,845 --> 00:56:44,939
maybe things would have been different,
I don't know.

663
00:56:45,015 --> 00:56:47,006
COMDEX is in a month.

664
00:56:47,084 --> 00:56:49,575
We need to relaunch our product
at that convention.

665
00:56:49,653 --> 00:56:53,054
It is our best and last chance at this thing.

666
00:56:53,123 --> 00:56:55,284
Look -

667
00:56:55,358 --> 00:57:00,352
I would like to take control
of our strategy so far.

668
00:57:00,430 --> 00:57:03,695
You need to go back and focus
on what you know best.

669
00:57:06,536 --> 00:57:08,527
That's what I think.

670
00:57:12,342 --> 00:57:13,900
Entrepreneurs.

671
00:57:13,977 --> 00:57:16,969
People of action are decisive.
Even if they take...

672
00:57:17,047 --> 00:57:21,006
three steps forward and two steps back,
they always progress.

673
00:57:21,084 --> 00:57:23,075
Don't waste time.

674
00:57:23,153 --> 00:57:26,145
Entrepreneurs are people who
jump out of a plane without a parachute...

675
00:57:26,223 --> 00:57:28,885
and instead, carry a backpack
full of silkworms...

676
00:57:28,959 --> 00:57:31,450
and pray that the silkworms
are overachieving.

677
00:57:35,565 --> 00:57:37,726
There you are.
Call on one.

678
00:57:43,907 --> 00:57:44,896
Hello?

679
00:57:47,244 --> 00:57:48,905
Hey, Mom.

680
00:57:52,749 --> 00:57:55,149
Is it bad?

681
00:58:22,112 --> 00:58:24,603
- Did you get my faxes?
- They're right here.

682
00:58:26,616 --> 00:58:29,949
Put them over there, please.
I'll see you in the morning.

683
00:58:37,627 --> 00:58:40,118
- I guess you saw me on TV.
- Yeah.

684
00:58:42,465 --> 00:58:44,456
You kinda made a fool of yourself.

685
00:58:46,303 --> 00:58:47,292
Yes.

686
00:58:49,539 --> 00:58:52,030
I just want you to know
I'm trying to do something good...

687
00:58:52,108 --> 00:58:54,099
and not just only to make a pile of money.

688
00:58:54,177 --> 00:58:57,476
Money can be good.
You saw my office.

689
00:59:02,819 --> 00:59:04,810
Had to let everyone go.

690
00:59:06,489 --> 00:59:10,721
After 30 years,
I thought I'd have more.

691
00:59:12,162 --> 00:59:16,121
There won't be a lot to pass on, I'm sorry.

692
00:59:16,199 --> 00:59:20,465
I don't care.
Just you getting better.

693
00:59:21,671 --> 00:59:24,606
I'll be fine.

694
00:59:24,674 --> 00:59:27,336
But you have to get your life on track, John.

695
00:59:29,512 --> 00:59:32,879
Maybe it would be nice to try to
get back to Stanford.

696
00:59:32,949 --> 00:59:36,282
It would be nice to give me
a little encouragement, you know?

697
00:59:36,353 --> 00:59:38,685
Since when have I ever let you down?

698
00:59:47,430 --> 00:59:50,627
I really appreciate you coming.

699
00:59:50,700 --> 00:59:55,137
But you need to go home
and take care of your life.

700
00:59:55,205 --> 00:59:58,697
That would be the best thing for my health.

701
01:00:11,554 --> 01:00:15,149
This is going to look...

702
01:00:15,225 --> 01:00:17,887
absolutely fabulous.

703
01:00:19,562 --> 01:00:23,555
Cool shades of gray
and turquoise...

704
01:00:23,633 --> 01:00:28,570
encased with silver, and surrounded in aluminum.

705
01:00:30,407 --> 01:00:33,501
Cool, calm and confident,
evocative of technology.

706
01:00:33,576 --> 01:00:36,739
We'll speak to the new millennium in visual prose.

707
01:00:36,813 --> 01:00:38,804
Sounds good.

708
01:01:00,103 --> 01:01:02,298
I was here a week ago.

709
01:01:02,372 --> 01:01:04,363
Members only, sir.

710
01:01:04,441 --> 01:01:07,706
But you let me in the last time.

711
01:01:07,777 --> 01:01:09,768
You were with a member.

712
01:01:11,614 --> 01:01:13,878
Fine. Whatever.

713
01:01:13,950 --> 01:01:17,442
Could you tell Halle to come out here?

714
01:01:17,520 --> 01:01:20,114
I can't do that, sir.

715
01:01:20,190 --> 01:01:23,023
- Why not?
- Members only.

716
01:01:25,795 --> 01:01:28,286
Here. This what you need?

717
01:01:29,799 --> 01:01:32,290
Do you think this is good enough
to come in here?

718
01:01:35,071 --> 01:01:37,062
Don't need your money, sir.

719
01:01:39,642 --> 01:01:42,577
Just tell Halle come out here, okay?

720
01:01:42,645 --> 01:01:45,637
- She and I are -
- Do you and Halle are what, sir?

721
01:01:50,820 --> 01:01:53,311
Now listen to me, you fucking gorilla!

722
01:01:54,824 --> 01:01:57,315
Take-Take your hands off me!

723
01:02:22,952 --> 01:02:24,943
Just remember, folks:

724
01:02:25,021 --> 01:02:29,515
If you don't stand for something,
you'll fall with everything.

725
01:02:32,228 --> 01:02:35,356
A little more.
A little more.

726
01:02:39,002 --> 01:02:41,630
A little more.

727
01:02:41,704 --> 01:02:44,195
- What happens here?
- Hold on a sec

728
01:02:44,708 --> 01:02:47,699
How is your father?

729
01:02:52,051 --> 01:02:57,986
Okay. Uh, there's a little change of plans.

730
01:02:58,054 --> 01:02:59,545
We're not going to COMDEX. Instead we're 

731
01:02:59,546 --> 01:03:03,114
doing personalized demos for top journalists right here in our office.

732
01:03:03,193 --> 01:03:05,184
So we're doing a little remodeling.

733
01:03:05,261 --> 01:03:08,492
How much does this cost?
How much does this cost?

734
01:03:08,565 --> 01:03:11,432
Uh... it-it doesn't matter.
Now we look like the world

735
01:03:11,501 --> 01:03:13,992
headquarters of an international
internet company.

736
01:03:14,070 --> 01:03:18,006
Trey, our designer, he arranged
Anna's offices, too.

737
01:03:18,074 --> 01:03:20,668
- Wait until you see our boardroom.
- So she's behind it?

738
01:03:20,343 --> 01:03:22,904
Guys, could you excuse us for a few seconds?

739
01:03:25,081 --> 01:03:27,572
- Trust me.
- I will.

740
01:03:30,587 --> 01:03:34,683
We need to do remodeling, because
need good press, okay?

741
01:03:34,757 --> 01:03:37,248
Because we need to go ahead and
list this company on the NASDAQ.

742
01:03:37,327 --> 01:03:39,955
It is the only way.
Now, go supervise Vic and Kik.

743
01:03:40,029 --> 01:03:42,520
- They need you.
- Stop.

744
01:03:42,599 --> 01:03:45,830
We're not listing anytime soon. There's a baseline 
fault in the code

745
01:03:45,902 --> 01:03:48,700
and that code is going to crash every
computer on this planet if we don't fix it.

746
01:03:48,771 --> 01:03:51,296
How can you sell shares of something
if it doesn't work properly?

747
01:03:51,374 --> 01:03:55,868
The code will be fine, John.
I trust you. Trust me.

748
01:03:55,945 --> 01:03:59,039
Let's go out and create this hype,

749
01:03:59,115 --> 01:04:02,710
enroll the company in NASDAQ
and watch our stocks go sky-high

750
01:04:02,785 --> 01:04:05,310
and it'll be Boo-Yah, hello
big money!

751
01:04:05,388 --> 01:04:07,879
And we need you to act fast while
you still can.

752
01:04:07,957 --> 01:04:10,448
That's not my vision for this company.

753
01:04:10,527 --> 01:04:13,519
What the fucking vision -
I didn't mean that. I didn't mean that.

754
01:04:16,966 --> 01:04:20,231
Your vision is my vision, John.
To accomplish that vision,

755
01:04:20,303 --> 01:04:23,739
we need to go public
as fast as we can.

756
01:04:23,806 --> 01:04:25,797
Right or wrong, this is the way.

757
01:04:25,875 --> 01:04:28,366
So we need to do it now while we
still can.

758
01:04:28,444 --> 01:04:31,709
Listing is a perfectly viable strategy.

759
01:04:31,781 --> 01:04:34,841
I want to build an inspiring company, 
that's why I started this.

760
01:04:34,918 --> 01:04:38,012
That's why I hired you, now what part
that don't you understand?

761
01:04:38,087 --> 01:04:40,248
We need cash, John.

762
01:04:40,323 --> 01:04:43,588
To sell your vision to the world,
we need cash, John!

763
01:04:43,660 --> 01:04:45,651
Listing is a way to get cash.

764
01:04:45,728 --> 01:04:48,697
What part of that fucking equation
do you not understand, Einstein?

765
01:04:48,765 --> 01:04:51,029
Now, we're friends.

766
01:04:51,100 --> 01:04:53,591
Do you want to keep it that way?

767
01:04:53,670 --> 01:04:57,197
Yeah, John, we're friends.
You don't think I know tha-

768
01:04:57,273 --> 01:04:59,264
We're the best of friends.

769
01:05:06,349 --> 01:05:10,115
Hey, remember now, -

770
01:05:10,186 --> 01:05:12,177
Remember that night?

771
01:05:12,255 --> 01:05:15,884
These two fucking hot women.
Remember this?

772
01:05:15,959 --> 01:05:18,826
I mean -

773
01:05:18,895 --> 01:05:22,126
your friend got all on video
in a limousine.

774
01:05:22,198 --> 01:05:25,964
There is nothing better than that, does it?
I don't think so.

775
01:05:26,035 --> 01:05:28,697
The next time you watch this,
remember who your friend is.

776
01:05:31,274 --> 01:05:33,299
This is the first time I've seen that.

777
01:05:35,545 --> 01:05:38,981
What? What are you talking about?

778
01:05:39,048 --> 01:05:41,107
I emailed this to you a month ago.

779
01:05:41,184 --> 01:05:43,846
Where the hell have you been?

780
01:05:45,221 --> 01:05:47,212
Hello, are you Mr. Elias?

781
01:05:49,225 --> 01:05:51,887
- Who are you?
- I'm your new assistant, Claire.

782
01:05:53,896 --> 01:05:56,387
I have fresh fruit and coffee for you.

783
01:05:56,466 --> 01:05:58,457
Can I get you anything else?

784
01:06:08,911 --> 01:06:10,902
Oh my God.

785
01:06:25,228 --> 01:06:27,958


786
01:06:28,031 --> 01:06:29,396


787
01:06:29,465 --> 01:06:32,593


788
01:06:49,786 --> 01:06:50,775
Fuck!

789
01:07:02,799 --> 01:07:06,667
- You okay?
- I'm fine.

790
01:07:06,736 --> 01:07:08,966
Do you need anything?

791
01:07:11,441 --> 01:07:13,432
I need to call a board meeting.

792
01:07:13,509 --> 01:07:15,841
- Where is my list?
- I have it.

793
01:07:15,912 --> 01:07:18,574
Why don't you let me make the calls now?

794
01:07:18,648 --> 01:07:21,412
All right.
Begin -

795
01:07:21,484 --> 01:07:23,816
Yeah, let's start with Anna Simmons.

796
01:07:26,489 --> 01:07:29,424
You look very nice in that suit, 
by the way.

797
01:07:29,492 --> 01:07:30,823
Thanks.

798
01:07:37,367 --> 01:07:39,927
- Yeah?
- He's calling the board...

799
01:07:40,002 --> 01:07:42,493
- Starting with Anna.
- Fucking man.

800
01:08:06,529 --> 01:08:08,520
You again?

801
01:08:08,598 --> 01:08:11,260
- She's out of town.
- Where did she go?

802
01:08:13,536 --> 01:08:16,471
She got a signed.
Went to New York.

803
01:08:16,539 --> 01:08:19,030
And you know what?
She was really happy.

804
01:08:19,108 --> 01:08:21,099
Is not it just great?

805
01:08:26,215 --> 01:08:29,309
- It's late.
- It's late. Thanks.

806
01:08:29,385 --> 01:08:31,376
You're welcome.

807
01:08:36,225 --> 01:08:38,955
What did John say?

808
01:08:39,061 --> 01:08:41,552
Obviously, he wants to keep
the company private...

809
01:08:41,631 --> 01:08:45,328
so he's calling on the entire board
for their support.

810
01:08:45,401 --> 01:08:47,392
Will he get it?
 
811
01:08:47,470 --> 01:08:50,928
Highly unlikely. They're saying
not to butter the bread.

812
01:08:51,007 --> 01:08:53,498
But we got a lot that we need to fix

813
01:08:53,576 --> 01:08:55,567
in away that he can't jerk us around.

814
01:08:57,180 --> 01:08:59,171
That's going to be hard.

815
01:09:01,250 --> 01:09:03,241
How can I get him to join us?

816
01:09:05,354 --> 01:09:06,685
But -

817
01:09:06,756 --> 01:09:09,589
The board, the second-round VCs, you and me...

818
01:09:09,659 --> 01:09:12,150
control as much stock
John and Tom Walker.

819
01:09:12,228 --> 01:09:14,719
Walker is a wild card,
but let's assume he's

820
01:09:14,797 --> 01:09:18,597
will vote with John.
That leaves 6% out standing.

821
01:09:18,668 --> 01:09:21,694
6%, that's the swing vote.
We gotta control that.

822
01:09:21,771 --> 01:09:22,760
6%.

823
01:09:27,410 --> 01:09:30,743
You're fired. Both of you.
Now, please leave, go away.

824
01:09:30,813 --> 01:09:33,304
- What is happening here?
- He thinks he can fire us.

825
01:09:33,382 --> 01:09:36,215
Together John and I can fire you.
Didn't you get the memo

826
01:09:36,285 --> 01:09:39,379
I became co-CEO.
I'll show it to you if you want.

827
01:09:39,455 --> 01:09:44,051
The first showing is in ten days.

828
01:09:44,126 --> 01:09:46,390
I keep coming in here and seeing
people fooling around 

829
01:09:46,462 --> 01:09:50,865
playing games and drinking coffee, 
not working.

830
01:09:50,933 --> 01:09:52,924
We need real talent in here

831
01:09:53,002 --> 01:09:55,562
that take the job seriously.

832
01:09:55,638 --> 01:09:58,869
- I quit.
- I'm so outta here.

833
01:09:58,975 --> 01:10:01,637
- You coming, Kik?
- Wait. Don't go.

834
01:10:04,647 --> 01:10:07,138
- Get outta here.
- No, I can't do that.

835
01:10:06,216 --> 01:10:09,707
We keep not getting the work
out of these people that

836
01:10:09,785 --> 01:10:12,015
Anna and I expect. You're
letting everyone down, John.

837
01:10:12,088 --> 01:10:16,252
Let these two people go. Give the 6% to 
someone a little more deserving.

838
01:10:16,325 --> 01:10:18,316
Wait a minute.

839
01:10:19,662 --> 01:10:22,324
We have 12.5% each.
What's he talking about?

840
01:10:24,333 --> 01:10:26,824
We had to back to 4.5% each when 


841
01:10:26,903 --> 01:10:28,894
we brought in the new board.

842
01:10:28,971 --> 01:10:32,771
with the second round of VC in
I had to cut them down to 3%

843
01:10:32,842 --> 01:10:36,073
- So guys were -
- You asshole.

844
01:10:36,178 --> 01:10:38,942
When were you going to tell us?

845
01:10:39,015 --> 01:10:41,006
Yeah. Yeah.

846
01:10:41,083 --> 01:10:44,951
Now, you own 6% of the company

847
01:10:45,021 --> 01:10:48,354
that's worth way more than the 25%
you guys had when you began.

848
01:10:48,424 --> 01:10:49,755
Fuck off!

849
01:11:15,384 --> 01:11:18,820
What you want, boy?
I'm busy.

850
01:11:17,888 --> 01:11:21,379
I need to talk to you
about the company.

851
01:11:21,457 --> 01:11:24,119
There's an important vote coming up
and I need your support.

852
01:11:26,062 --> 01:11:29,998
- Did you lose my money?
- No, not that. Believe me...

853
01:11:30,066 --> 01:11:32,864
it's gone way beyond than just
making money on your investment.

854
01:11:36,238 --> 01:11:39,435
There are elements within
the company. They want

855
01:11:39,575 --> 01:11:43,602
to take things public right away.
The software is nowhere near ready for that.

856
01:11:43,679 --> 01:11:45,340
We - we -

857
01:11:50,586 --> 01:11:53,555
So, the problem
as you see it...

858
01:11:53,623 --> 01:11:56,114
is that they want to make us
a pile of money and you want me

859
01:11:56,192 --> 01:11:58,683
to help you stop it.
Is that what you're telling me

860
01:11:58,761 --> 01:12:00,752
you little sick?

861
01:12:19,649 --> 01:12:21,207
Think so.

862
01:12:21,283 --> 01:12:24,275
Tom Walker, a big investor.
What you don't you see in this house?

863
01:12:29,959 --> 01:12:33,395
- A computer.
- Bingo.

864
01:12:33,462 --> 01:12:37,159
Not one in the whole damn place.
You want to know why?

865
01:12:37,233 --> 01:12:40,225
I know nothing about them.
Never used one in my life.

866
01:12:40,302 --> 01:12:42,998
Hate the damn things.
Just a decade ago...

867
01:12:43,072 --> 01:12:45,734
farming was all about
producing the best crop

868
01:12:45,808 --> 01:12:48,333
Now, it's all about the number.
The biggest crop.

869
01:12:48,411 --> 01:12:51,847
That's what computers
represent to me.

870
01:12:51,914 --> 01:12:52,903
Numbers.

871
01:12:56,152 --> 01:12:58,916
Stick with the fundamentals, kid.
That's what I say.


872
01:12:58,988 --> 01:13:01,479
Money isn't the only way
to measure success.

873
01:13:02,992 --> 01:13:06,860
Do you invest in these companies,
but not know anything about them?

874
01:13:06,929 --> 01:13:10,387
Why would a man invest in
companies he knows nothing about?

875
01:13:13,836 --> 01:13:15,827
Because it's not your money.

876
01:13:17,907 --> 01:13:21,070
Your angel is outside
with the horses.

877
01:13:22,578 --> 01:13:25,843
Sir? Tom Walker
said I should come out here -

878
01:13:28,250 --> 01:13:30,411
Howdy, partner!

879
01:13:30,486 --> 01:13:32,477
So Tom Walker is your backman?

880
01:13:32,555 --> 01:13:35,456
It's my cousin, believe it or not.

881
01:13:35,524 --> 01:13:38,721
I actually come out here on 
weekends pretty often.

882
01:13:38,794 --> 01:13:40,785
And he is a front
for your investments.

883
01:13:40,863 --> 01:13:42,854
A front?

884
01:13:42,932 --> 01:13:45,992
You make it sound so very sinister.
He's -

885
01:13:46,068 --> 01:13:48,127
We have a corporation...

886
01:13:48,204 --> 01:13:50,798
and he is the face, and I'm
the mind and - That's it.

887
01:13:50,873 --> 01:13:53,398
- It's that simple.
- Why didn't you tell me?

888
01:13:53,476 --> 01:13:56,877
I suppose not telling you was a
risk I was willing to take.

889
01:13:59,548 --> 01:14:04,315
But also, I don't think you were really 
ready to hear anything I had to say.

890
01:14:04,386 --> 01:14:06,377
You were too proud.

891
01:14:06,455 --> 01:14:09,015
You got intellect to burn, but
it's a handicap for you.

892
01:14:09,091 --> 01:14:12,322
So I stayed out of the way 
and let you learn

893
01:14:12,394 --> 01:14:16,455
a thing or two by yourself. 
I've noticed that entrepreneurs...

894
01:14:16,532 --> 01:14:19,023
desire to ask forgiveness
than for permission.

895
01:14:19,101 --> 01:14:21,331
And also, worst case scenario,

896
01:14:21,403 --> 01:14:25,499
even if you fuck up everything
and you've lost all my money...

897
01:14:25,574 --> 01:14:27,667
I would live.

898
01:14:27,743 --> 01:14:31,008
I've been rich for long time...

899
01:14:31,080 --> 01:14:33,708
so I tend not to worry so much.

900
01:14:34,583 --> 01:14:36,574
So it was an experiment
for you?

901
01:14:36,652 --> 01:14:39,120
If you choose to see it
that way, sure.

902
01:14:39,188 --> 01:14:42,180
Don't get me wrong, I think
you have a great idea.

903
01:14:42,258 --> 01:14:47,525
But I didn't invest in the idea.
I invested in you.

904
01:14:47,596 --> 01:14:50,429
So, drink to ya.

905
01:14:52,768 --> 01:14:56,670
- Do you have a girl?
- I did. But I think I lost her.

906
01:14:57,940 --> 01:14:59,931
What happened?

907
01:15:00,009 --> 01:15:02,773
I did some bad things.
On videotape.

908
01:15:06,448 --> 01:15:10,544
Wow. Well, I'll tell you something.
A little secret.

909
01:15:10,619 --> 01:15:12,746
It's a lot more fun to have
money

910
01:15:12,822 --> 01:15:15,313
when you have someone you love
to spend it with.

911
01:15:15,391 --> 01:15:18,383
Go get your company, John,
because it's going to be a great thing.

912
01:15:32,341 --> 01:15:35,970
I move that we take this 
company public.

913
01:15:36,045 --> 01:15:38,536
I'm calling for a vote of
the whole board.

914
01:15:38,614 --> 01:15:40,605
Here, now, today.

915
01:15:42,818 --> 01:15:45,651
When I started this thing, it
wasn't money that motivated me.

916
01:15:47,156 --> 01:15:49,647
I got really excited about some
computer code that could

917
01:15:49,725 --> 01:15:53,923
change the world. Profit makes 
this company grow,

918
01:15:53,996 --> 01:15:57,727
but they aren't what make it
work. People make it work.

919
01:15:57,800 --> 01:16:00,769
Ideas make it work. The company 
is not just

920
01:16:00,836 --> 01:16:03,361
where you make money.
It's where you make your friends.

921
01:16:03,439 --> 01:16:08,672
The company has a purpose
beyond just making money.

922
01:16:10,946 --> 01:16:13,915
We have no business going 
public right now.

923
01:16:13,983 --> 01:16:16,474
We have a few lines of code,
some good ideas...

924
01:16:16,552 --> 01:16:20,318
and some damn good people.
Now that, over time...

925
01:16:20,389 --> 01:16:22,380
will make something great.

926
01:16:22,458 --> 01:16:26,758
So, let's build a quality 
company, not a casino.

927
01:16:26,829 --> 01:16:30,697
I voted against this listing.
I need you to join me.

928
01:16:38,040 --> 01:16:41,305
- Ben, good to see you.
- Likewise.

929
01:16:42,544 --> 01:16:44,876
Ben Fisher and I go way
back.

930
01:16:44,947 --> 01:16:48,007
Many companies.
Many board meetings.

931
01:16:48,083 --> 01:16:50,745
So he knows I don't mind
being the bad guy.

932
01:16:50,819 --> 01:16:55,483
But it's fun to get our
virtues all screwed up.

933
01:16:55,557 --> 01:16:58,151
But the truth is that 
at the end of the day,

934
01:16:58,227 --> 01:17:03,392
Companies exist solely to
maximize shareholding value.

935
01:17:03,465 --> 01:17:05,456
And it's not even fun to say.

936
01:17:05,534 --> 01:17:08,867
Now, you talk about quality.

937
01:17:08,938 --> 01:17:13,500
Quality is what we're about here.
The quality of our earnings.

938
01:17:13,575 --> 01:17:18,808
You spoke of purpose. Making 
money is our purpose here.

939
01:17:18,881 --> 01:17:21,372
And if we have a way
to make more money

940
01:17:21,450 --> 01:17:23,441
such as listing this company

941
01:17:23,519 --> 01:17:28,183
then we not only have the right,
we have the responsibility to do so.

942
01:17:28,257 --> 01:17:31,693
Now, if-if you want to run this
company as a charity...

943
01:17:31,760 --> 01:17:35,423
then you shouldn't have accepted
any outside investment, but you did.

944
01:17:37,599 --> 01:17:40,261
So, now, it's showtime.

945
01:17:43,105 --> 01:17:45,596
Those opposed to the listing
company...

946
01:17:45,674 --> 01:17:47,665
raise your hand.

947
01:17:58,954 --> 01:18:01,787
All in favor.

948
01:18:06,795 --> 01:18:10,231
Well, to the board members
present,

949
01:18:10,299 --> 01:18:14,167
it appears we have a tie.
However,

950
01:18:14,236 --> 01:18:19,333
we nearly forgot your
two buddies, Victor and Kiko

951
01:18:19,408 --> 01:18:23,174
who went AWOL and lost their stock

952
01:18:23,245 --> 01:18:25,907
As for company bylaws
They share their vote -

953
01:18:25,981 --> 01:18:28,779
their 6% vote goes to favor
the board.

954
01:18:28,851 --> 01:18:35,154
So that means we have 47% against 
the listing, and 53% in favor.

955
01:18:40,496 --> 01:18:44,489
Anna has requested time for
one further item of business

956
01:18:44,566 --> 01:18:46,557
than you would like to take
care of.

957
01:18:46,635 --> 01:18:50,071
Obviously there's a real disagreement 
as to where this company's headed.

958
01:18:50,139 --> 01:18:52,869
I stress there are irreconcilable 
differences

959
01:18:52,941 --> 01:18:54,932
between John Elias
and the board.

960
01:18:55,010 --> 01:18:57,774
I therefore propose
that the board vote to remove

961
01:18:57,846 --> 01:19:00,781
any executive power that
John Elias has

962
01:19:00,849 --> 01:19:03,613
and transfer said power to
Robert Jennings, 

963
01:19:03,685 --> 01:19:06,449
who's been acting CEO anyway
for the last three weeks.

964
01:19:06,522 --> 01:19:08,513
We might as well make it
official.

965
01:19:09,958 --> 01:19:12,893
Let me see if I understand
this.

966
01:19:12,961 --> 01:19:16,863
This is a proposal to remove
me as CEO

967
01:19:19,101 --> 01:19:22,070
and replace me with Robert 
Jennnigs.

968
01:19:22,137 --> 01:19:24,128
All in favor?

969
01:19:33,715 --> 01:19:36,206
It had to be this way, John.
You had to have known.

970
01:19:36,285 --> 01:19:37,775
Fuck you.

971
01:19:37,853 --> 01:19:41,186
John, in a year's time, 
you're gonna thank me.

972
01:19:43,892 --> 01:19:45,883
We're still friends, John.

973
01:19:45,961 --> 01:19:48,452
Don't hate the player,
hate the game.

974
01:20:17,426 --> 01:20:21,920
Well, Anna, business as
usual, eh?

975
01:20:21,997 --> 01:20:24,864
- Don't start with me, Ben.
- What?

976
01:20:24,933 --> 01:20:27,993
When they get rich, they'll
come knocking on my door to thank me.

977
01:20:28,070 --> 01:20:31,096
- They always do.
- Yeah, maybe.

978
01:20:31,173 --> 01:20:33,573
But, maybe not.

979
01:21:45,347 --> 01:21:47,338
Are you John Elias?

980
01:21:47,416 --> 01:21:50,783
Yeah. Is this hell?

981
01:21:54,523 --> 01:21:59,290
- You're a very lucky man.
- I don't remember a thing.

982
01:21:59,361 --> 01:22:03,422
Let's see. We were
pursuing you...

983
01:22:03,498 --> 01:22:06,160
when you passed out and
hit your head on the sidewalk.

984
01:22:06,235 --> 01:22:09,966
- You're in a lot of trouble.
- I'm sorry.

985
01:22:10,038 --> 01:22:12,268
I've had a really bad day.

986
01:22:13,875 --> 01:22:16,969
It could get worse.

987
01:22:21,049 --> 01:22:25,145
Actually, that's a very nice 
car you have.

988
01:22:25,220 --> 01:22:27,882
What is it? An Audi TT?

989
01:22:31,827 --> 01:22:33,818
How do you drive?

990
01:22:36,064 --> 01:22:38,055
Like a dream, my friend.

991
01:23:37,626 --> 01:23:40,959
After losing just about everything
I dreamed that I was back with Lisa.

992
01:23:43,131 --> 01:23:45,964
It might have been a coincidence but
when I woke up,

993
01:23:48,303 --> 01:23:50,294
I solved the malfunction.

994
01:24:19,334 --> 01:24:21,325
Morning.

995
01:24:22,904 --> 01:24:25,395
- Want one?
- No thank you.

996
01:24:25,474 --> 01:24:28,341
- Try it. All right.
- Thanks a lot.

997
01:24:36,251 --> 01:24:38,242
Is this what you do all
day long?

998
01:24:40,255 --> 01:24:44,191
Not every day.
But most of the days.

999
01:24:44,259 --> 01:24:47,820
I have a wife in the city.
When I go there, I work.

1000
01:24:51,933 --> 01:24:55,164
- You should get a net.
- Why?

1001
01:24:56,571 --> 01:25:02,134
- You use it to catch more fish.
- I don't need more fish.

1002
01:25:02,210 --> 01:25:04,804
No, but you can sell the extra
ones and buy a boat.

1003
01:25:04,880 --> 01:25:07,815
And then what?
Catch more fish?

1004
01:25:06,883 --> 01:25:09,111
Sure.

1005
01:25:09,184 --> 01:25:12,449
Maybe I could buy a whole fleet of
fishing boats.

1006
01:25:12,521 --> 01:25:15,012
and sail all over the world.

1007
01:25:15,090 --> 01:25:17,650
and have employees that
catch fish for me, right?

1008
01:25:17,726 --> 01:25:21,321
- Sure, I guess you could.
- And then what would I do?

1009
01:25:24,065 --> 01:25:26,727
Could stay on the beach
all day fishing.

1010
01:25:28,904 --> 01:25:31,395
This is for you.
Come on, bring it.

1011
01:25:31,473 --> 01:25:33,498
Go ahead.
Row it in slowly.

1012
01:25:33,575 --> 01:25:35,566
- Put it here.
- Well.

1013
01:25:35,644 --> 01:25:39,671
Yes, bring it up.
Good. There.

1014
01:25:42,250 --> 01:25:46,346
- Vic, this is John.
- I don't know anyone named John.

1015
01:25:46,421 --> 01:25:49,515
- Cut it out, I'm in Mexico.
- Fine, whatever.

1016
01:25:49,591 --> 01:25:52,526
Okay, I was an asshole and
I'm sorry. But listen,

1017
01:25:52,594 --> 01:25:55,563
I think I've got a way to get
the company back and on our terms.

1018
01:25:55,630 --> 01:25:59,862
It's too late.
Shit. Look, we're

1019
01:25:59,935 --> 01:26:02,597
trying to get back to school
and get on with our lives.

1020
01:26:02,671 --> 01:26:05,162
We've wasted way too much 
time no this bullshit.

1021
01:26:05,240 --> 01:26:07,504
We're not your friends, we're 
not.

1022
01:26:08,443 --> 01:26:10,604
Vic, I know what the budge is.

1023
01:26:13,448 --> 01:26:15,780
- You do?
- Yeah.

1024
01:26:15,851 --> 01:26:18,376
And I have a plan. We'll talk
about it when you get here.

1025
01:26:18,453 --> 01:26:21,388
- Where, Mexico?
- Yeah I lost my car

1026
01:26:21,456 --> 01:26:24,289
and I have don't have a way to drive back.
Can you come to the border?

1027
01:26:25,126 --> 01:26:27,720
You want to go to Mexico
and pick up John?

1028
01:26:27,796 --> 01:26:29,787
He lost his loser-mobile.

1029
01:26:31,666 --> 01:26:33,293
Poor Johnny.

1030
01:26:35,403 --> 01:26:40,636
Do you have any idea how much
you owe us when this all ends?

1031
01:26:41,476 --> 01:26:43,740
We own you. We. Own you.

1032
01:26:43,812 --> 01:26:45,973
In fact, I want you to say.

1033
01:26:46,047 --> 01:26:51,007
- I want you to say: "You own me". 
- You own me.

1034
01:26:51,086 --> 01:26:53,577
Oh that was nice, but I didn't 
believe it.

1035
01:26:53,655 --> 01:26:57,591
- Say it once more, with feeling.
- You own me!

1036
01:26:57,659 --> 01:27:02,255
And now, what about this?
"I am a complete ass!"

1037
01:27:02,330 --> 01:27:04,924
I am a complete ass!

1038
01:27:33,128 --> 01:27:35,119
The code is loading.

1039
01:27:36,865 --> 01:27:38,196
Ready?

1040
01:27:43,238 --> 01:27:44,933
SERVER ONLINE

1041
01:27:49,010 --> 01:27:51,001
Greetings, people of the world.

1042
01:27:51,079 --> 01:27:53,775
That video you see right now, is being
transmitted with our software.

1043
01:27:53,848 --> 01:27:56,316
And notice, it is clear
as a whistle.

1044
01:27:56,384 --> 01:27:59,683
NUMBER DOWNLOADED: 3528

1045
01:27:59,754 --> 01:28:02,245
Unfortunately, people within
our company

1046
01:28:02,324 --> 01:28:04,815
want to list on the stock 
and make a lot of money.

1047
01:28:04,893 --> 01:28:07,384
We feel that if they take our business
before it matures then you'll 

1048
01:28:07,462 --> 01:28:09,953
end up paying much more than
you should by our software

1049
01:28:10,031 --> 01:28:12,693
to be achieved
unrealistic gains

1050
01:28:12,767 --> 01:28:14,758
for our company.

1051
01:28:18,840 --> 01:28:21,308
A bunch of shareholders
and analysts...

1052
01:28:21,376 --> 01:28:23,867
will control the future development
of our software company

1053
01:28:23,945 --> 01:28:26,345
and leave us with
something mediocre.

1054
01:28:26,414 --> 01:28:28,939
You can stop this from happening,
by sending an e-mail

1055
01:28:29,017 --> 01:28:31,542
to the board members
after you see this message.

1056
01:28:32,754 --> 01:28:35,518
Please help.
And enjoy our software.

1057
01:28:50,939 --> 01:28:54,500
DON'T list Digital Dreams!

1058
01:28:57,078 --> 01:29:00,878
- There's my man!
- Hey, guys.

1059
01:29:00,949 --> 01:29:03,440
Hey! the Three Stooges.
How you guys doing?

1060
01:29:03,518 --> 01:29:06,009
That was good.
I think you have mail.

1061
01:29:06,087 --> 01:29:09,215
Yeah, I saw that. A stupid play,
John. Stupid play.

1062
01:29:09,290 --> 01:29:11,884
Which of you is Curly?
He was my favorite.

1063
01:29:11,960 --> 01:29:14,451
- Hey, hey, hey!
- Take it easy, Kaka.

1064
01:29:16,297 --> 01:29:19,664
- The listing is being stopped.
- Yeah, right.

1065
01:29:19,734 --> 01:29:22,225
Two board members called me.

1066
01:29:22,303 --> 01:29:25,739
They're going to vote with
me to stop IPO.

1067
01:29:25,807 --> 01:29:29,038
- You're living in such a dream world, John.
- Call them yourself.

1068
01:29:29,110 --> 01:29:32,910
No, I don't have to.
It doesn't matter anymore.

1069
01:29:32,981 --> 01:29:36,041
- It's too late.
- What are you talking about?

1070
01:29:37,152 --> 01:29:40,713
You don't know, right?
Haven't you been watching the news?

1071
01:29:40,789 --> 01:29:43,553
We're being acquired. Anna is 
negotiating now 

1072
01:29:43,625 --> 01:29:46,287
and will close the deal
by the end of the day.

1073
01:29:46,361 --> 01:29:48,352
Those two board members?

1074
01:29:48,430 --> 01:29:51,092
They changed their mind fast
when they heard the price.

1075
01:29:51,166 --> 01:29:54,602
All thanks to you, man.
You proved your idea works.

1076
01:29:54,669 --> 01:29:58,730
And now major software and major 
hardware company wants us.

1077
01:29:58,807 --> 01:30:02,106
It's better than the listing.
We could cash out now.

1078
01:30:02,177 --> 01:30:04,839
You're gonna be rich, John!
All of us are!

1079
01:30:06,681 --> 01:30:10,617
All thanks to your buddies here
who quit just before payday.

1080
01:30:10,685 --> 01:30:13,620
Sorry, guys.
I hope there's no hard feelings.

1081
01:30:26,067 --> 01:30:28,058
What's up, Vic? "Kock?"

1082
01:30:28,136 --> 01:30:30,627
Maybe he is weak,
but someday he'll be strong.

1083
01:30:30,705 --> 01:30:32,969
But you, you'll always be
a prick.

1084
01:30:33,041 --> 01:30:36,477
You'll never be good and 
you'll never be happy.

1085
01:30:36,544 --> 01:30:39,707
You are about to get rich
off of his ideas.

1086
01:30:42,884 --> 01:30:45,546
Just show a little fucking
gratitude, huh?

1087
01:30:49,557 --> 01:30:52,651
Digital Dreams was acquired today
after board members met and agreed on

1088
01:30:52,727 --> 01:30:55,491
John Elias, founding CEO
was unavailable for comment -

1089
01:30:55,563 --> 01:30:58,327
Robert Jennings, current
CEO of Digital Dreams...

1090
01:30:58,399 --> 01:31:02,335
said he felt extremely 
optimistic and trusted that --

1091
01:31:02,403 --> 01:31:04,963
Our chief goal remains providing 
high quality software

1092
01:31:05,039 --> 01:31:07,872
the American public
and to the world.

1093
01:31:07,942 --> 01:31:10,274
What about John Elias after
his efforts

1094
01:31:10,345 --> 01:31:12,677
to rail the Digital Dreams
public offering?

1095
01:31:12,747 --> 01:31:16,649
John Elias became a 
multi-millionaire today.

1096
01:31:16,718 --> 01:31:18,709
He should take comfort in that.

1097
01:31:57,792 --> 01:31:59,783
Can I come in for a while?

1098
01:32:01,629 --> 01:32:05,065
I don't think that's such a
good idea.

1099
01:32:05,133 --> 01:32:07,192
Well, I understand.

1100
01:32:07,268 --> 01:32:11,398
I'm not trying to be hard on you.
I know you've tried to make it right.

1101
01:32:11,472 --> 01:32:15,636
But what you did… it was a big
deal.

1102
01:32:16,644 --> 01:32:20,603
And I'm not saying I'll never
forgive you, but

1103
01:32:20,682 --> 01:32:22,741
it won't be anytime soon.

1104
01:32:25,553 --> 01:32:27,544
When I'm ready, I'll call you.

1105
01:32:33,228 --> 01:32:35,219
I love you, Lisa.

1106
01:32:38,499 --> 01:32:40,490
I really love you.

1107
01:33:03,925 --> 01:33:06,450
The idea is being marketed
under a different name.

1108
01:33:06,527 --> 01:33:09,018
Our best employees are
working in other startups...

1109
01:33:09,097 --> 01:33:11,088
or not working at all.

1110
01:33:20,141 --> 01:33:22,132
When the market crashed...

1111
01:33:22,210 --> 01:33:24,701
valuable dot-com stocks
became worthless

1112
01:33:24,779 --> 01:33:27,907
and many hot flyers came 
crashing down floor.

1113
01:33:28,016 --> 01:33:30,007
Easy come, easy go.

1114
01:33:54,242 --> 01:33:57,837
Lisa put me on probation as an 
assistant to prove how much I loved her.

1115
01:33:57,912 --> 01:34:01,507
It was so strange how that 
felt like more than enough.

1116
01:34:01,582 --> 01:34:05,074
And although it would take
some time to get moving,

1117
01:34:05,153 --> 01:34:07,519
I had a big idea 

1118
01:34:07,588 --> 01:34:10,580
for a cool piece of software.

1119
01:34:13,594 --> 01:34:15,585
John? Hello? Earth to John!