FEMALE REPORTER: ...the campaign trail
continues for both President Nixon
and Democratic challenger George McGovern.
However, Nixon again
refused McGovern's request
to debate as the two men
prepare for next week's election.
MALE REPORTER: Authorities have
determined that the remains found
in the aftermath of
a school bus yard explosion
are those of Eugene Linwood,
who was recently implicated
in the attack on a Memphis school bus
- that resulted in the assault of black student...
- (VOLUME INCREASES)
JONI: Apparently,
our staff meeting got moved up.
Well, I can give you a ride if you need.
What about Marcus?
Ruth's got him this morning.
Andrea's already on her way.
I put the classifieds on the kitchen table.
- And will you get some Halloween candy...
- (KNOCKING ON DOOR)
No, I got it, I got it, I got it, I got it.
- Morning.
Mattress. Where you want it?
Around there,
in the bedroom on the right, please.
All right. Are we taking the old one?
- Yes, sir.
- Mmm-hmm.
Morning.
Surprise!
We talked about this.
I thought we were gonna wait
until we're back at sea level.
Oh, it's just a mattress, Joni.
Please tell me you didn't do store credit.
I didn't do store credit, okay?
- I got some cash.
- From where?
I've been tracking every red cent.
Well, I got some from my dad.
Asked him.
- When did you talk to him?
- After you asked me to, you know?
I asked him for $4,000
and he, uh... He gave me
a hundred dollar bill, so...
Hey, hey, I didn't
think it'd put a dent in our situation,
so I thought I'd do something nice, you know,
for, uh... For us, for our home, huh?
Hey, that's, uh...
That's cranberry juice.
Right. Anything else?
No. No, that's it.
- All right, thank you.
I didn't think you'd take it this hard, Joni.
Don't be angry with me, okay?
What, Joni?
I talked to Lloyd, too.
Please tell me you didn't ask him for money.
About selling the house.
Okay.
Well, we're not doing that, so...
He said we could get
eight and a half grand for it.
That's good to know, Joni.
We're not selling the house.
Mac, he already listed it, okay?
Excuse me?
Mac...
I'm sorry. I...
I should have talked to you about it.
(SCOFFS)
- Mac.
- Yeah.
Mac.
What are you doing?
Well, you know, I'm packing, Joni,
'cause that's what you do
when you move, you know?
There's not even a... A sign out front,
- so how's that supposed to work?
- Will you stop, please?
- Can you calm down?
- No, no, this is what you wanted, Joni.
You want me to get rid of our home, okay?
What I want is just to be able to breathe again.
Okay? I want my husband back
and I want our life back to what it was.
Yeah, but that's the big
fucking difference, okay?
'Cause I'm willing to fight
for us and for our home.
What the hell
do you think I'm trying to do, Mac?
You lied to me.
You bought a mattress, okay?
- So there's a lot going on...
- You're selling our home, Joni.
You're selling our goddamn home, okay?
It ain't the same thing.
(CHUCKLES) And, oh, l...
I went to him.
Hat in fucking hand,
- I went to my dad 'cause...
- I know, I shouldn't...
No, no! I went to him 'cause you asked me to.
I know I should've told you.
Mac, you wouldn't listen,
okay, and I had to do something,
- so I went to him for help because he's...
- Yeah, before talking to me!
- Because you wouldn't let me...
- Exactly, Joni!
Which you fucking knew!
What do you expect me to do, Mac?
I sit here or at work
and all I think about
is that you're out there doing something.
Some plan is going down where you're gonna
have to end somebody's life, okay?
You're gonna have to
take a human being and end his life.
Or that you'll die.
Eugene Linwood or some other asshole
will get the best of you and you'll be dead.
And so every minute
that I'm not at least trying
to do something to get us out of this,
I'm complicit.
I'm putting other people in harm's way.
I'm putting my husband in harm's way.
Yeah, but you're not, Joni. You're not.
You're just not, Joni, 'cause I did this.
No, I did this. This was my decision.
And to think
that you are even taking a part of this on,
that you...
That you feel responsible, I...
(HORN HONKS)
Mac.
Mac, hey.
I'm sorry, okay?
Please don't think
that I'm not willing to fight for us.
(HORN HONKS)
Jesus, Andrea.
Hey, you sell the house
if it makes you feel better.
Yeah, I want you to do
whatever you need to do
to make yourself feel better.
So...
(DOOR CLOSES)
(LOUD MUSIC PLAYING)
(PINBALL CLANGING)
(SHUTTER CLICKS)
That don't look like too much.
- Where's the rest?
- Wasn't no rest.
Well, I sure as shit paid for a rest.
That's all they give us, Credence.
What, you didn't ask them where the rest is?
Of course I asked him where.
That's all they give us.
They said that's the New Orleans...
(YELLS)
Christ.
We just got that in.
What in the name of all the fuck
does that got to do with me and mine?
How am I supposed to know?
CREDENCE: We barely got enough stock
to last us through the week.
We're gonna have a word
with the Marcellos about my resupply.
You're gonna take
that little fishing boat of yours
downriver and pick it up.
Now, how about
we get them boys on the phone?
Corn Fed.
(MELLOW SONG PLAYING)
(SCOFFS)
We don't have any candy.
Oh, Well.
A moment on the lips, a lifetime on the hips.
Could've knocked.
You would've invited me in?
- Well, my wife could've been here.
- But she's not.
Did you hear about the explosion
down at the bus yard?
Some racist peckerwood
tried to put a bomb on a school bus.
The racist peckerwood went boom instead.
I must've missed it.
THE BROKER: How'd it feel?
It felt like I was a little closer to
you being out of my life, okay?
And don't act like there's some
higher purpose to this shit, 'cause there ain't.
Ah, and here I thought
we were starting to get somewhere.
How much is left anyway, 16?
No, 12.
THE BROKER: Had to try, right?
How's the housing market?
Did you bug my house or something?
No, but I got a subscription to the newspaper.
Why does your wife wanna sell
a lovely home like this
all of a sudden, anyway?
She thinks that we're having money trouble,
which we are,
and I'm having trouble
finding a job, which I am.
8,500 seems like a good price point.
She doesn't know anything, all right?
You keep saying that.
All she needs to know is that
it's in everyone's best interest
to keep her mouth shut.
But I'm not here about all that.
Something big's going down
and I need my best and my brightest.
I need you.
That supposed to make me feel special?
THE BROKER: It should.
Wait, this is that...
That big and tall asshole
from, uh, the plantation.
They were fucking.
(SINGING) Joni's smile
Lights the way
No night is so dark
When she stays
- This is just fucking terrible.
- TOMMY: It was Cliff's.
Cliff wrote it
and I've concluded they were, in fact, fucking.
This is puppy dog crush bullshit.
(SCOFFING)
This ain't some smoking sex gun.
God damn it, Verne,
tell me the story doesn't track.
Okay, but this isn't evidence.
- Where'd you even get this?
- Get what?
- His diary.
- No, that's a song book, my friend.
His sister found it, gave it to me.
I'm gonna take another run at Mac Conway.
We got a dozen open bodies right now
and you wanna waste our time
turning accidents into murder cases?
- What if they're not accidents?
- Look, I get it.
You feel an obligation to your friend
and you wanna do right by him.
But this is grasping at straws, son.
Our job is to close cases, not reopen them.
What about Arthur Solomon?
Shot through the throat just a month
after coming home with this asshole.
Or what the buzzards left of our boy
Rickey Suggs down in South Texas?
I mean, tell me that Conway wasn't mixed
up in that bullshit, Verne.
I mean, come on! You know I'm right.
- Son of a bitch.
- What?
- You fucked the sister.
- I did not.
- VERNE: You did. Son of a bitch, Tommy!
- (CHUCKLING)
Is she putting you up to this?
She's not putting me up to anything, Verne.
I could smell the pussy on you from here.
Whether or not I fucked her
is not the goddamn issue.
Something is off with this fucker.
VERNE: "Off" ain't no charge.
So I'm not supposed to give a damn
that Conway probably murdered my friend?
I mean, do you actually know what they were
accused of doing in Quan Thang?
Pretty sure our jurisdiction
don't extend that far west of the Mississippi.
- I'll check a map, though.
- It's heinous, Verne.
It's the very worst in this war.
Now he's brought this shit
back here to Memphis.
So you want justice
for Quan Thang, Senator McGovern,
or is it your dead friend? Which is it?
You didn't serve, Tommy.
Now what the hell does that
have to do with anything?
I did.
Let me tell you something.
Unless you've been in a war,
you can't judge a man who has.
This son of a bitch Conway
may have done some bad shit over there.
He may not.
He fought for his goddamn country
so you could be free
to stick your dick in a dead man's sister.
Have some respect.
(BOAT MOTOR WHIRRING)
(GUNSHOT)
(MAN GROANING)
You bag anything?
A couple of heroin hillbillies.
Not sure how good they'll look
in the trophy room, though.
Mmm-hmm.
Chinaman's Nightcap, all right.
There goes their resupply.
Ought to slow down their little operation.
KARL: Depends how well they're stockpiled.
Well, if you could figure out
where they have their stockpile,
we'd know the answer.
It's a heroin stash.
Even these imbeciles realize
you have to hide it well.
Milky Way.
The Jumble.
KARL: Maybe taking out
the biggest heroin dealer in Memphis
isn't as easy as you might've thought.
THE BROKER: We cut off their supply route,
Quarry and Buddy
will take out what you couldn't.
RUTH: It's gonna be okay, baby.
LOU: Will I still be able to go trick or treating?
Well, of course you will.
You have to be careful with her out here.
I didn't do anything.
She tried to get the ball and then she fell.
All right, there's peroxide and bandages
under the bathroom sink.
Go on.
Who's my big, tough girl?
(KISSES) Hmm?
Marcus?
- Marcus!
- Huh?
RUTH: Come on!
It's okay.
You're not in trouble.
Marcus, you okay?
- Honey-lamb?
- (MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
BUDDY: Yeah?
I want you to remember something.
You're as good as the best
and better than the rest.
Which?
Oh, the red.
- You sure?
- Well, yes, I'm sure.
Red's a power color.
They're gonna take you serious.
You're saying,
"Listen to me. I have got a vision."
BUDDY: I look like a goddamn tomato!
Well, try the blue, then.
I think blue's gonna work a treat, too.
If he don't see the vision that you have,
oh, man,
I want you to look him straight in the eye
and you tell him, "You can kiss my twat."
Mama, I don't have a twat.
You have a twat!
- A twat is a butt!
- A twat is not a butt.
(SONG PLAYING ON RADIO)
(SINGING ALONG TO RADIO)
(EXHALES)
"Good as the best, better than the rest."
Boss man! How you been?
Where'd you get that tan?
Okay. You want something.
(SIGHS)
To what do I owe
this distinct pleasure, old friend?
I'm here today to talk to you about
guns.
- I see that, yes.
- The very lifeblood of our industry.
I know what guns are, Buddy.
Okay, so here's the system we have now.
This is you up at the top there.
- You make that yourself?
- I did.
And here's me just below you,
an ombudsman of sorts
for all your weaponry needs.
A role in which you positively excel.
And I deal
with the gun dealers so you don't have to.
Now, just below that
we have these four suppliers.
- There's Joe Don.
- Resting in the arms of the savior.
BUDDY: Nate Jessup.
And Nate's serving 20 over in Tiptonville
for weapons.
And these two
can barely get a cap gun from a Toys"R"Us.
What I'm saying is
the system we've been using,
it's not a system that exists anymore.
You've presented the problem well.
Now, what's the solution?
Why deal with a bunch
of low rent gun runners
when you can deal
directly with someone you know and trust?
Yours truly.
I'm confused.
Isn't that what I do already?
I'm saying, I stop working for you taking jobs.
Okay? That's over.
And I move over
to providing you and the network
with all its firearm needs.
You cut out any middle man.
- Because you're my middle man.
- Exactly!
Where?
What?
Where are you getting the guns?
BUDDY: Where am I getting guns?
You think I don't know where to get guns?
Come on.
So, what do you think?
I'm impressed, Buddy.
I'm impressed.
Very well thought out.
Compellingly presented.
The stock we got from Joe Don is dwindling.
I got a lead that could see us
flush through the new year.
Now is not the time.
Of course it's the time.
- We... We...
- THE BROKER: Buddy, I'm counting on you
to do what you do so well,
and that ain't running guns.
But things aren't the same as...
Now, when the dust settles,
we can come back around to this.
Now, you hold onto this wonderful artwork
and we'll talk.
Buddy, you're an absolute treasure to me,
you know that?
And I take care of you, do I not?
Hmm?
You're sure?
I wouldn't want you to feel ill-used.
- No, I don't. I...
- I'm glad to hear it. I'm glad to hear it.
'Cause some individuals
might mistake your enthusiasm
for self-interest.
- No, no, no. I wasn't... I wasn't doing that.
- No, of course not.
Of course not. Of course not.
Now, let's talk.
You and Quarry got some work to do first.
(SIGHING)
- Can he be direct?
- You both are.
Like I said, there's a lot going on presently.
Hey.
Hey, hey, wait a minute.
Wait a minute. Hi.
Hey. Remember me?
No? Remember the Sunnyside Motel?
Great seeing you again.
Hey, what happened after we left?
It's okay, you know? I work for him, so...
Oh, wonderful.
I'll be sure to look for you
at the Christmas party.
What did you do with Harlow?
Can you kindly
get the fuck out of my way now?
Listen to what I'm fucking
asking you right now.
What did you do with Harlow?
You got him killed if my memory serves me.
No, you know what I mean.
(CHUCKLES)
Hope that wife of yours
is getting the help she needs.
- Yeah, with what?
- You.
Now, not so kindly,
get the fuck out of my way.
(ENGINE STARTS)
Hey, what's her story?
Who gives a shit? Let's go.
(MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
How much we got coming in that shipment?
Uh, about five kilos.
$80,000, give or take, street value.
Hand me that pipe wrench.
MAC: So what's so special about this bastard
that we both need to be on direct?
BUDDY: Old Credence is a Highway 61 boy.
Been in and out of the penal farm
since he was just a little redneck drug dealer.
These things that you're saying
are supposed to mean something to me?
Dixie-fried wildasses
that are meaner than a sack of weasels.
They're all related or fucking or both.
And Credence Mason is their goddamn king.
MAC: And now we have to kill that man.
Yeah, not just him.
MAC: See, I... I thought the system
wasn't supposed to work this way, you know?
Multiple targets, two on direct. (SCOFFS)
How's anything supposed to work, anyway?
No, we're on the job.
Well, I'm thirsty.
Hey, what the hell is wrong with you?
- (SCOFFS)
- Hmm?
You did two tours in 'Nam, right?
How many people did you kill over there?
When I first started working for The Broker,
I'd keep track.
Not, "Write Shit Down", keep track.
Nothing stupid like that, but just
remember their names.
Like they were lovers or something,
I don't even know what.
Wasn't even something
I was consciously trying to do.
I just did.
Until one day, I...
I didn't.
How come?
I don't know.
I don't even remember stopping.
Just realizing that I had.
I never knew none of their names.
And yet, you're one of the two
most important people in their lives.
Their mama
who brought them into this circus
and us,
the ones who took down the tent.
(POUNDING ON CAR)
Can I help you boys with something?
Oh, no. We're just playing hooky from work.
We're looking to, uh... To kill some time.
I think we're gonna hit a movie instead.
Are y'all cops?
Oh, God, no. No.
Well, y'all come play.
I'm about to get the Sizzler back up.
I'll go two-for-one.
- Halloween special.
- Oh, that's mighty generous of you, sir.
- I think we're gonna hit that movie.
- CREDENCE: No, no, no, come on, now.
Movies are bullshit.
We got pinball inside and rides galore.
We got a mechanical bull that...
(WHISPERING)
CREDENCE: Uh...
My man Burkhalter here
says y'all is a couple of faggots.
- Is that true?
- No. No, sir.
- We're just gonna be on our way.
- No, no, no.
You know what?
What makes your man Burkhalter
such an expert on the matter?
- MAC: Buddy, Buddy...
- What if we were, Burkhalter?
You know what? I'm fucking sick of it.
MAC: Hey! Hey, hey, hey.
Hey.
Hey, we... We didn't mean any harm, okay?
We're just trying to have
some time to ourselves today, all right?
We're gonna be on our way.
Look here, boys.
Don't know y'all.
Don't know your business.
But I am into fun.
And even faggots gotta have fun, right?
Ride the carousel if you want.
Hell, we got this thing in here called Scat.
It'll whip your ass inside a little metal cage.
I say you're welcome here at Dixieville,
you understand?
Thank you, sir.
Now scat.
(ENGINE STARTS)
Something ain't right there.
(SCOFFS) Yeah.
Fucking log-jammers.
I ain't talking about
what they do with their dicks.
(MAN SINGING UPBEAT SONG)
How are we not fucked, huh?
(BUDDY SCOFFS)
- Maybe we need to tell him.
- The hell we do.
We nearly came to blows with the target.
I wouldn't exactly call it careful and cautious.
BUDDY: Fuck him.
Who, Credence or The Broker?
BUDDY: Well, how about both?
Look, all I'm trying to do right now
is to finish these last few jobs
and not get myself arrested
or fucking killed in the process, all right?
Now, he said... He said it was something big.
I don't know much,
but a man like that says it's big,
I'm gonna take it seriously.
BUDDY: So how do you think he'd react
if we waltz in there
and tell him our cover's blown
a few hours after we started?
So...
All right, what's our timetable?
Two, three days for direct.
But what's to say
we don't just go back there right now
and we kill all three of them shitheads?
- We could do that. We could do that.
- Yeah.
But we still have to recover
Mr. Mason's stash.
Wait, what?
BUDDY: Boss wants it brought in.
- All of it. He didn't tell you?
- What's "It"?
No, he didn't tell me. What...
So, wait, we're dealing drugs now?
BUDDY: "Dealing drugs."
Drugs are about as useless to boss man
as tits on a boar hog.
Okay, so why does he want them?
BUDDY: Only thing he cares about?
Whoever's willing to pay
to kill whoever they want dead.
This time it's drugs.
Next time it's gambling debt
or someone's spouse or
the person they're sleeping with.
MAC:
Okay, so we gotta recover Credence's stash,
but the fuck who ran the scout on this
didn't even tell us how?
It's a perfect fucking system.
Scratch a cynic, you find an idealist.
You want perfection,
listen to some Bobbie Gentry.
Beyond that, you're gonna be hard pressed.
All right, what are we gonna do?
Well... (SIGHS)
I could run down to Kmart
and get us some Halloween costumes.
Fuck it.
It's called direct, right?
I'm just grabbing my jacket.
My friend's waiting outside.
Or you could've just called
and asked me how it was going.
JONI: I know. (CHUCKLES)
What if people had questions?
That's what you got me for.
JONI: Right.
Right, sorry.
I'm just nervous.
- Mmm.
- I mess you up?
No, no. It's okay.
None of them know you own the place.
Right.
Is this a good turnout?
LLOYD: Yeah, pretty good.
I wouldn't go getting too excited, though.
Open houses are mostly for kooks.
They get bored
and wanna come see how other people live
and go through their stuff.
Showings will catch
a lot more flies than these things.
JONI: Okay.
- All right, I'll be back when it's over.
- LLOYD: All righty.
JONI: Hi there.
Sorry to interrupt.
I'm the homeowner if you have any questions.
I live a street over.
Always loved this house, thought I'd pop in.
- Hope you don't mind.
- No, not at all.
THE BROKER: I remember
seeing you two moving in.
Wife and I were so happy
to see a young couple
moving in the neighborhood.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, we're very sad to be leaving.
You moving to a bigger place?
No. Uh, maybe.
My husband got a new job,
so we have to relocate.
What line of work he in?
He's a loan officer.
New bank opened up over in Jackson.
Hey, that's my line. Maybe I know him.
Probably not.
- He... He's pretty new to the business.
- Oh.
- Well...
- My niece and her fiancé
are actually in the market.
And they love this area.
- That's great.
- Young and in love.
Oh, that's wonderful.
Oh, you... You gotta see them.
They want the whole deal...
The babies, the house.
Probably just like you and your husband.
(CHUCKLES) Well, you know, uh,
there's a spare room down the hall.
Make a pretty great nursery.
- And you got the pool.
- Yeah.
That beautiful pool.
That has to be loads of fun.
My husband installed that himself, actually.
- Is that right? Impressive.
- Yeah.
My wife, Viv, and I,
we've been in our place now 25 years.
Thought about moving a couple times,
but could never quite pull the trigger.
You know, you can live in a lot of houses,
but not all houses are homes.
Still, a lovely couple like you,
I'm sure y'all will find ways
to fill your house full of love.
Yeah.
I should be going.
My wife, she likes to give candy apples
to trick-or-treaters, which, of course,
means I give candy apples
to the trick-or-treaters.
- Right.
- Nice talking to you.
You, too.
LLOYD: It's solidly built.
I don't know if you've
rapped your knuckles on it,
but those two bedrooms,
that full bath in there...
(MUSIC PLAYING)
Well, this ain't good.
CORN FED: Careful, Credence.
Morris!
Where you boys at?
They're right there
getting a tan.
CORN FED: The hell you think
happened to them?
Got me.
What you think?
Well, if I had to wager on it,
I'd say that somebody knew
them boys was coming.
Surprised them, shot them dead,
loaded them up in the truck right there,
set fire to it,
sunk the boat,
made off with a bunch of your heroin.
Well, shit.
Beats my guess.
I was gonna say it was Apaches.
How are we doing on stock?
CORN FED: Low.
Business is fine,
but that means dwindling stock.
We needed this here drop.
You, uh, think someone's making a move?
Yeah.
I think somebody already made it.
- (MUSIC PLAYING)
- I'm just so sorry for your wait.
Ladies first, enjoy.
They are working you too damn hard.
Oh, I have done a sight on Earth of work.
How y'all doing?
Been here since 5:30 this morning
'cause our new girl never showed.
And the busboy quit
'cause the boss accused him of stealing.
- Well, was he?
- Well, I sure wasn't the one
- jimmying open the cigarette machine.
- (LAUGHING)
Two? Right this way.
Hi.
What time do you get off?
I got another hour.
I am gonna go home
and spend the rest of the night
soaking in a warm bathtub.
- That sounds heavenly.
- It does, doesn't it?
- Mmm-hmm.
- It's also a lie. (CHUCKLING)
- I got two kids and it's Halloween.
- (LAUGHS)
- No rest for the weary.
- Mmm-mmm.
A burger and fries, Ruth.
No rush.
What about you?
Any big plans for Halloween?
Well, I was thinking
I could take you to dinner.
Oh, thank you, Felix.
That's real sweet of you.
Another time, huh?
What about sometime next week?
You could come to my house. I'll cook.
Whoa, I'm not letting you do
anything fancy for me,
not after how hard you work in here.
It's not gonna be fancy.
If I remember what's in my cupboard,
it's gonna be macaroni and cheese
- and canned lima beans.
- (LAUGHING)
All right, then. I'll bring some meatloaf.
- I know just the place.
- (LAUGHS)
- SANDY: Close your eyes.
- They're closed.
- Can I open them?
- Not yet.
I wanna open them.
(SIGHS)
Okay.
(LAUGHING)
- Hi.
Holy fuck. Happy Halloween to me.
SANDY: You know where this is from?
Uh, every fantasy I ever had?
Cabaret.
The movie?
Ugh, you haven't seen Cabaret.
I have not, but evidently,
it's the sexiest goddamn movie ever made.
- Well, now it doesn't mean anything.
- Yeah, it does.
Come here. Come here, sweetie.
I'll show you what it means.
Come here.
- Hey, guess what.
- What?
I'm gonna take another run at Cliff's case.
- That song book you gave me.
It made it all make sense.
Okay, Okay.
Okay, what?
I thought I could do this, but it's too weird.
What... What's weird?
You used Cliff's death to have sex with me.
Well, hang on a second. I did not.
Yeah, you did, and that's fine
because I went along with it, too,
'cause you're hot and you're funny,
and I needed hot and funny.
But you keep bringing it up.
Well, I'm sorry I cared about your brother.
- SANDY: (SCOFFS) You don't care.
- I do care!
- Not really.
- No, I do care!
You cared about him so much,
you didn't call him for 15 years?
Or bother to come to his funeral?
If you did care, you would realize
that constantly reminding me
that he's gone forever
isn't something I wanna think about
any more than I already do,
which is pretty much all the goddamn time!
TOMMY: You are living in his fucking house.
Yeah, and maybe I shouldn't be,
but if I don't, then there's nothing left of him.
- There's nothing.
- Sandy, that doesn't even make sense.
(SIGHS) Yeah, it probably doesn't.
Listen, I...
I shouldn't have brought it up, all right?
It was bad timing. I'm sorry.
Okay, can we just...
Can we just move past this, please?
I don't think I can.
I'm sorry.
Thirty seconds ago, you were about to
fuck me in this stripper costume, and...
And now, what, you're fucking dumping me?
Looks that way.
Oh.
You know what? Maybe...
(CLEARS THROAT)
Maybe Cliff wasn't murdered.
- Maybe he was just fucking stupid.
- (SCOFFS)
Yeah, maybe he was.
Yeah, maybe it runs
in the fucking family, huh?
- (DOOR OPENS)
- (SIGHS)
(DOOR SLAMS)
LOU: Marcus!
Will you help me put on my costume?
(SIGHS) Do it yourself.
Please?
(SIGHS)
- Hold still.
- Where's your costume?
I told you, I'm too old to wear a costume.
You don't like candy?
I'm just gonna eat all yours
when you're sleeping.
- (DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
- (RUTH SIGHS)
- Mommy!
- (LAUGHS) Look at you!
Oh, my goodness!
- MARCUS: Hey, Mama.
- Hey!
Okay, I'm gonna change
out of my uniform and then...
What is this?
Marcus, where'd you get these?
A man was selling them down the way.
RUTH: But where'd you get the money?
I had some allowance saved up.
It didn't cost much.
(STAMMERS)
(LAUGHING) What on Earth?
My Sweet boy!
Don't you spend your money on me.
That's for you, okay?
(LAUGHS) Oh!
Uh, now, who's ready to go
trick-or-treating, huh?
Give me one minute.
(KIDS CHATTERING)
(DOORBELL CHIMES)
KIDS: Trick or treat!
Whoa! Lookie here!
What we got? We got ourselves Superman,
and we got ourselves, oh, a tooth fairy.
I'm a princess.
Oh, of course you are, darlin'.
We can't forget you and you
and you and you.
Now, Happy Halloween, y'all.
KIDS: Bye!
(DOORBELL CHIMES)
I like Tootsie Pops if you got 'em.
What the...
Fuck! Oh, shit! Ow!
- BUDDY: You remember us?
- Ow.
(DOOR CLOSES)
Oh, come on, 'course you do.
It's not every day you see
the two most handsome men in Memphis.
Now, you're gonna tell us where your boss
keeps his stash, you understand?
Well, I can't tell you what I don't know.
- (GUNSHOT)
- (GROANING)
Oh, my...
I don't... I don't know.
Well, you might wanna think hard on it,
'cause by my count,
you still got one more foot,
uh, two hands, some teeth.
You fucking homos.
(SIGHING) Oh, dear.
No! No, no!
- Stop! What the fuck?
- What about now, huh?
What about now?
Oh, shit!
Did you kill him?
No, he passed out. Fuck.
- I got a little carried away.
- Yeah.
Yeah, well, that tends
to happen a lot with you.
Oh, excuse me for being results oriented.
(DOORBELL CHIMES)
- Trick or treat!
- (MIMICKING DRACULA) Well, hello, children.
Look at you! So adorable!
Here, take all the candy!
Fucking monsters.
- Mac.
- (BURKHALTER WHIMPERING)
BUDDY: Oh, it's so nice of you to rejoin us.
BURKHALTER: Pinball... Pinball machines.
Pinball machines.
BUDDY: What?
The heroin is in the pinball machines?
BURKHALTER: Yeah. Pinball machines.
(GUNSHOT)
You ready?
(LINE RINGING)
- JONI: Hello?
- Hey.
- You okay?
- I...
Yeah.
Baby, what's wrong?
The hell are you going?
Just stay here. I'll call you.
(ENGINE STARTS)
You'll call me?
- Baby.
- JONI: Mac.
- Hey.
- What'd you see?
I saw... I don't know what I saw, okay?
It's probably nothing.
What's the job this time?
Who is it?
- Joni.
- Yeah, sorry.
Sorry I worried you, okay?
It was stupid. I just freaked out.
It's okay, baby, okay? You freaked out.
No big deal.
Now I'm here, we'll go freak out together.
(CHUCKLES) You should go do
whatever you have to do.
No, this is what I have to do.
Mac, I'll be fine. Go.
- It was a trick-or-treater, wasn't it?
- (CHUCKLES)
JONI: Probably, yeah.
Okay, I won't be long.
JONI: You won't?
Honestly, I...
I don't have any idea.
Just be safe, okay?
Okay.
(ENGINE STARTS)
That all we got left?
Yeah, that's all she wrote.
How much them Biloxi boys
say they was bringing us?
CREDENCE:
Enough to make up for what we lost.
Burkhalter say
he was gonna see that fat farmer girl tonight?
All right.
All right, we're gonna
cut through the park, okay?
And then you need to keep a line of sight
on that back door, all right?
What?
For a reluctant motherfucker,
you sure are gung-ho sometimes.
What are you taking?
Well, why? Are you a fucking narc?
All right, listen,
we're gonna
need a signal word or something, okay?
Okay.
How about... (WHISTLES)
You listen to me.
You sharpen the fuck up right now,
you understand me?
You know what he'd do if he knew
you were fucked up on the job, huh?
You wanna get twisted?
You wanna get fucked up?
You do it on your own time,
not when my life is at stake,
you understand me?
Let's go.
You see something, you know what to do.
Come on.
(CAR APPROACHING)
Oh, fuck.
What the hell we got here?
(CAR DOORS CLOSE)
(KNOCKING)
- That them?
- (KNOCKING CONTINUES)
CREDENCE: Could be.
Them Biloxi boys drive fast.
Let's get this done so we can get down there
and see them clabber-butted girls
shake their titties
to Kool and the Gang songs.
TOMMY: Conway.
The fuck?