I saw the car coming.
If you was Miss Jennifer,
you'd be expected.
Go right in.
I'll tell them in back you arrived.
It's Mama! I heard the car.
It's too soon for Mama.
Hey there, be careful.
He's learning.
He has to learn sometime.
Oh, my, but I'd be afraid.
We're Phillips people.
Phillips people aren't afraid.
I don't like you.
Well, I like you.
Don't make no never mind.
I don't like you.
I like you.
I'm Jennifer.
How do you do?
Children, here's your mama's cousin,
Jennifer from Chicago.
She's come to stay with us.
Say, "How do."
Are we kissing kin?
I hope so.
I'm Trissa, and that's Ted.
He won't kiss you.
He hates kissing.
You'll get over that, boy.
Show Miss Jennifer to her room.
In the left wing, across from you.
Thank you.
Don't you pull away from me, boy.
I got a good look at you.
And I never saw such ears
on a human in my whole life.
You fixing to grow potatoes in there?
My, what a lovely room!
The bathroom's across the hall.
We all use it.
You have to jiggle the handle
three times, or it runs forever.
That's my room, next is Ted,
then Aunt Carol.
You'll admire her.
She's old like you.
Don't go worrying about the bathroom.
About us all using it, I mean.
We always knock.
Almost always.
Carol, we've talked enough.
Jud, wait, will you please?
We've gone over it 100 times.
What more is there to say?
I don't want her to know
we're engaged, that's all.
Does it make any difference?
It makes me a heel with your brother.
After all, he is my friend and my job.
Your job!
Everything you do starts
with the mill.
I'm getting sick of the mill!
Why? It pays for all of this.
We have an audience.
Welcome to Phillips House.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to--
Pay no attention to what Jud says.
He isn't usually so bad-tempered.
I'm Carol Lee Phillips.
You must be Jennifer.
You're just in time for tea.
That's what we call it when we drink
too much in the afternoon.
The mills have
to get together on this.
Jud runs the mill.
Or it'd have to run itself.
Talk to Jud.
This is Sue McKinnon,
one of our dearest friends.
This is Jennifer, Eva's cousin.
She's come to visit us.
Jennifer Stewart.
The Beauregard Stewarts, of course.
My dear, I knew your mother very well.
You knew my mother?
When we were girls, Sally Stewart
and I were best friends.
You look like her.
You're favored that way.
But I'm not the girl--
My mother never lived here.
My, we did have frolics,
your mother and I.
You men!
Here's Sally Stewart's girl,
Jennifer.
It's nothing. Pay no attention.
Well, you must be Eva's cousin
I've been hearing so much about.
And this is Sue's brother, Ty.
He's a terrible flirt
and wicked as can be.
That's nice. I've always wanted
to meet somebody wicked.
I'm just a poor, scared little boy
that nobody understands, honey.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
And this is Eva's husband,
Avery Phillips, my brother.
They call me Beauty.
Well, well, you didn't faint
or even shudder.
Stop it, Beauty.
You can understand why I have
such a sickening nickname.
It's a joke.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
That's the way to handle him.
He uses that scar to terrify people.
You just ignore him.
Jennifer Stewart.
You come talk to me.
I'll regale you, child.
I'll tell you all the delicious scandal
I can think of around here.
Not all, I hope.
That scar is deeper
than it used to be, isn't it?
I'll try and act more like
a true Southern gentleman.
That would be a pleasant change.
It's like seeing Sally again.
So young and shining.
I like you already.
I hope Cousin Eva likes me.
My mother spoke of her so often.
Is she so very beautiful?
Eva?
Beautiful? You might say that.
You might very well say that.
It's in the eye of the beholder.
She is beautiful.
This is Jennifer's first trip
to the South.
Did you know that, Sue?
That's strange.
That's really very strange.
Your mother's family
were quality folk.
If you're really a Beauregard Stewart,
then you'd know--
Well, I've been waiting for this.
Now you're going to hear about
our notable Southern ancestors.
We all have them.
Why, child, let me tell you...
...your grandpappy fought
with Lee at Shiloh.
It was Chickamauga, I think.
I'll have you know, child,
that your grandpappy had 1000 slaves.
Your grandmammy never spoke to anyone
from further north...
...than Atlanta, G.A.
Georgia, that is. Sir!
Sam!
Where are you, Sam?
Come and help me with my packages.
A delightful afternoon,
suddenly complete.
Is it--?
Your cousin, my dear wife.
Eva.
Mommy's home!
Did you bring me something?
How about a kiss?
This is for you.
And you know something?
I forgot all about you.
Put those things in my room, please.
My, how cozy you all look!
Darling, is that for me?
How sweet!
Just give me a minute
to get my breath back.
There.
Now I'm ready for people.
Sue McKinnon, it's just ages.
We don't see enough of you
or your handsome brother.
Hello to both of you.
Carol, you look sweet...
...even in those tacky
old riding clothes.
Who are you, you pretty thing?
You look mighty like....
You must be Jennifer.
Of course, you are.
I'd recognize you anywhere.
I'm sorry I didn't meet you, but we
didn't know what train you were on.
That's all right. I'm used
to taking care of myself.
I have to entertain our company now.
But later we'll talk about you.
Are you going?
I was looking forward
to a long visit with you.
Some other time, I hope.
We're late now.
Goodbye, all.
It's been most enjoyable.
I do thank you.
Oh, here.
You are a good girl.
- Walk out with me.
- The car's in back.
I hope you get a chance
to go over those papers.
You do favor your mother.
It pleasures me to see you.
She'll always think of you
as Sally Stewart's daughter.
I'll always think of you
as a very sweet girl.
You know, I'm kissing kin
with the Stewarts of Beauregard.
He's nice, isn't he?
Looks like Sue took a fancy to you.
You didn't mind her being
a little strange?
No, I liked her right away.
Did you hear?
Jennifer likes Sue enormously.
It's very nice of Jennifer.
Poor Sue.
She's our local legend.
Every town in the South has one.
Beautiful girl jilted
on her wedding day...
...still waiting for
her unfaithful lover to return.
Her unfaithful, uncaring
scoundrel of a lover.
I can't imagine anything
like that happening to her.
But it did.
The bridegroom-to-be
ran away with somebody else...
...and left poor Sue at
the door of the church...
...and she's been as she is
ever since:
A walking reproach
and a constant reminder of tragedy.
Eva, never come between
me and my liquor.
You'll get knocked down.
You might give Jennifer
the wrong impression.
My dear Jennifer,
don't get the wrong impression.
If I seem drunk, it's because I am.
My normal condition.
- I'm sure you don't mean to be rude--
- What makes you think that?
- Don't talk to me in that tone.
- I won't talk at all.
There's time to show you
the house before dinner.
I'd like that.
It's a beautiful house.
A beautiful house...
...beautiful people...
...in the eye of the beholder.
How dare you embarrass me like that?
Carol.
Please tell me,
was it because of me?
No, Jennifer.
Really, it wasn't.
But I feel responsible somehow.
It was my brother who left
Sue McKinnon at the church.
And the woman
he ran away with was...?
Eva.
I can't bear to see her.
What was she doing here?
Do you think I enjoyed it?
She feels guilty.
She's punishing herself.
Don't worry about it.
She'll be gentle.
I can endure the rest of it,
and I don't mind anything else.
Doesn't he understand?
Can't he realize how she must feel?
Carol, it must be terrible for Eva,
knowing what's happened to Sue.
Just seeing her that way.
He sees her too.
I'm to blame for everything.
If only you'd try
and understand what I feel.
Good morning.
- We have servants to carry things.
- It's breakfast for Eva.
They'll fix it.
Coffee for me, Sam.
Coffee for Mr. Phillips.
I like your new shoes.
How'd she know I got new shoes?
Morning, Avery.
I see you're out of hiding.
We haven't seen very much
of each other.
Is your name Jennifer?
- You've been away.
- No, I've been drunk in my rooms.
Jennifer's not interested
in your drinking.
Everybody's interested in my drinking.
It's rather remarkable sometimes.
Makes me a bad host.
I hope you've enjoyed your stay,
despite my absence.
Very much.
Thanks to Eva and Carol.
They've been wonderful to me.
Jen's very fond of Eva.
So many people are.
You don't care for me, though.
You don't tell polite,
social lies, I gather.
I don't blame Jennifer.
You've been rude to her.
Have I been very rude?
No, not very.
Good.
Then I don't have to apologize.
The children in town?
With Miss George.
I asked her not to come
back until after lunch.
Are you going hunting?
Not exactly.
I'm going to kill this dog.
- He isn't--
- The dog is old, sick and in pain.
Just moving is torture
for poor old Tiddly.
But how can your brother take
that little dog?
He'll start drinking again.
But he can't bear
to see an animal suffer.
He loves them so.
Sometimes I think
more than people even.
Does she know?
We'll tell her the dog died
in its sleep. And I said "we."
I don't like lying.
Eva would rather be lied to
than know the truth.
You do hate her, don't you?
Of course.
Eva.
You've brought me my coffee.
How nice you are!
No, not yet.
Don't stand there staring at me
and looking so ridiculously young.
Go away for a minute.
Put it down over there. Anywhere.
I'll open the shutters.
And let in all that nasty light?
No, darling.
Not until I get ready for the day.
I hope it is a day.
I'll get my robe.
Well, do I look fairly human?
Lovely.
Then you can bring my coffee
and open the shutters.
Thank you.
I feel guilty about neglecting you
these last few days.
That's okay.
I know how busy you've been.
And Carol's been taking me everywhere.
You like Carol?
Very much.
She doesn't have many friends.
Her personality, I suppose.
She doesn't even like me.
It's probably Beauty.
I've asked him not
to hunt near the house...
...but he won't listen to me.
You and he must have...
...loved each other a great deal,
running off together that way.
He was mad about me. Simply mad.
And I was worse, much worse.
I knew I couldn't live without him.
I knew that right away.
And it's never changed...
...not with me.
I admire you so much.
You're so nice...
...in spite of the way things are.
I believe you're being sympathetic.
Don't feel sorry for me.
I like people around me
to laugh and be gay.
Oh, dear, it's getting very late.
Be an angel
and run my tub for me.
I like it very hot.
I'll get it.
Oh, it's you.
You never call me. Simply never.
Don't tell me you're finally going
to succumb to my fatal charm?
What?
Well, I'm simply bursting
with jealousy.
You'll have to bribe me, Ty.
That's all there is to it.
No, something large
and terribly expensive.
And I have to know
everything that happens.
Promise now?
I'll see what I can do. Bye.
- I can't take this.
- Of course you can.
You know who that was?
It was Ty McKinnon calling about you.
Why?
He wants my permission to beau you.
He wants to be your beau.
Your fella!
Shouldn't he have asked me?
He will now.
I gave him permission.
Oh, I just love it!
He's the most eligible man around.
Isn't it exciting?
Aren't you excited?
Aren't we rushing him?
Make up your mind.
Decide you want the best things
out of life and go get them.
You can, you know.
Any woman can.
You can get anything you want.
Even Ty McKinnon.
But Eva, I don't think
I want anything.
Every woman wants something.
Not me, Eva.
I guess I'm different.
I don't want anything.
For you, Miss Jennifer.
From Mr. McKinnon, the boy said.
I hear Ty's being rounded up for
branding. Apparently, he's willing.
It's mostly Eva's idea.
Eva has the instincts
of a headhunter.
It's very sweet of her to go
to so much trouble just for me.
You have such nice eyes.
A little small, perhaps,
and certainly not wide open.
I wonder how they'll look
when they're wide open.
Eva does it better.
She does everything better.
I'll do that.
You're very kind.
Not always.
You may not believe it,
but I can be nasty.
Like the other day.
We didn't meet the other day.
Do you know who I am?
Judson Prentiss.
You take care of the mills
for Mr. Phillips.
You don't come here often,
but you and Carol are secretly engaged.
You forgot to mention my middle name.
I don't know what it is.
At least I have one secret from you.
I couldn't help listening to you
the other day.
You didn't seem to care who heard you.
That's right.
It doesn't matter to me
whether anyone else knows or not.
It's Carol who's dead set
on keeping it quiet.
Mostly from Eva.
I won't tell her...
...if that's what you're asking me.
That's what I'm asking you, all right.
Jud, darling.
You've come back.
You've actually come back.
I've just been getting acquainted
with your cousin.
I didn't see you.
You're so quiet.
We'll have to put a bell on you.
Do sit down.
I've never thought of you
as a gentleman.
I hope you're able to
stay with us awhile.
I'm spending the night.
Avery wants me to go over
some business tomorrow.
Nobody told me.
I'm supposed to go out to dinner
tonight. Isn't that terrible?
It would have been nice
spending the evening with you.
Like old times.
The wonderful old times.
Jen.
You must learn to join in conversations.
Otherwise, you give
such a mousy impression.
But you look nice
in the dress I bought you.
It is nice.
Thank you.
But it's really not like me.
Then you be like the dress.
Nobody wears these things anymore.
That's Ty.
He always drives in the back way.
Hold still.
Your gentleman caller, Miss Jen.
There.
You go out that way now.
And have a lovely, lovely evening.
And don't forget! Smile a lot.
Make character with people.
How young and lovely she is.
And how you hate her for it.
Mrs. Goff, please.
Mrs. Phillips calling.
She gives the worst dinners.
Serves health foods.
She's such a hypochondriac.
Natalie, darling.
A terrible thing happened.
My dog, Tiddly, remember?
She died in her sleep,
and I've been so upset.
I'm an absolute prey to disease.
Virus, the doctor says.
What, darling?
I can hardly hear you.
But I'm determined to
drag myself to your party.
Do you really think I should?
Of course, if you don't want me.
All right.
Then I'll go back to bed.
All right. Bye, now.
Now I can stay home
and enjoy your company.
Aren't I wicked?
Yes, as a matter of fact, you are.
Have a nice time?
It was a frolic.
- Is that the right word?
- It certainly is.
"Frolic" means...
...anything real nice.
Like this.
I'll call you tomorrow.
We'll start all over.
It's incredible.
Absolutely incredible!
You're just in time to hear the news.
Such exciting news.
Carol and Jud, they're engaged.
Getting married.
Jud's just told us this minute.
Isn't it revolting that
he's only just told us?
I asked you not to do it this way, Jud.
I didn't want anyone to know yet.
I had to.
I'm fed up.
I've had enough.
Enough of what?
The deal Carol's getting.
I don't like the deal she's getting.
You know what I'm talking about.
Go to bed, Carol.
You too, Jud.
We'll talk more about it tomorrow.
By all means.
We will have a talk, won't we, Jud?
Like old times.
- There's nothing to discuss.
- I think we should talk.
I don't like to insist.
But I insist.
All right.
I expect you to do something about this.
It's natural for Carol to want to
marry and have a place of her own.
I'm not so sure.
Of what?
That she will get married.
This can't be very amusing for you.
Come and tell me all about your evening.
Is there anything I can do?
I never get used to it...
...even though it happens so often.
He dreams the same dream
over and over again.
He's in the car, and
it starts down the driveway.
It's dark in his dream, he says.
And the car starts going
faster and faster.
He sees the mountains
coming nearer, nearer.
He sees the mountain?
That's all there is.
Before the car reaches the mountain...
...he screams and wakes up.
He says when they reach the mountain...
...they'll die.
I wonder what it means.
Do you know who's with him
in the car in his dream?
Eva.
You seem to blame everything on her--
Stay here long enough.
You'll find out.
She's sweet with him.
It wouldn't have to do with her.
She's sweet, all right.
She's sweet with everybody.
Just like she was tonight with me.
Has it occurred to you
Eva might be worried...
...about Jud being good enough for you?
She's worried about anyone
getting away from her.
She's so unhappy,
she can't bear the idea...
...of someone living a normal life.
- I don't want to hear any more.
- I used to wonder about Eva...
...until I read a book about bees.
Now this is ridiculous.
We used to keep bees for the orchard.
There's a whole chapter
devoted to the queen...
...the ruler of a hive.
The queen bee...
...who stings all her rivals to death.
I won't listen--
Your turn'll come.
She'll sting you one day.
Ever so gently...
...so you hardly even feel it.
Till you fall dead.
You want me to hate her,
like you do.
After all she's done for me.
She's never done anything for you.
It was my brother. He paid your
bills, put you through school.
Eva asked me to come down here.
She probably thought it'd be
cheaper than hiring a secretary.
I didn't mean that.
She is fond of you.
And while it lasts,
she can be very charming.
I just don't want her laughing at you.
I'm sorry, Jennifer.
Don't be sorry for me.
Be sorry for yourself,
feeling the way you do...
...about a wonderful person like Eva.
That book on bees...
...it's in the library.
You might read it one day.
Jud?
Darling, are you here?
I'm here.
You knew I'd be here.
Of course, I did.
But I remember too, you never liked
being taken for granted.
It's been so long.
It'll be longer.
Stop teasing and come here to me...
...before another minute goes by.
It's no good, Eva.
I'm going to marry Carol.
Are you, darling?
Are you really?
You might as well save the charm.
You're out of my blood.
I've forgotten you.
I can look Avery in the face again.
And I'm going to marry Carol.
I'm not out of your blood.
And you haven't forgotten me.
Not completely.
Never completely.
I'll make you remember me.
It's like old times.
I don't like the lights.
I remember what you like
and what you don't like.
Turn them out again.
You're something.
You're really something.
You never give up, do you?
Well, give up with me, Eva.
Don't tell me you've developed
a set of finer instincts since Chicago.
That was ten years ago.
Long ago...
...and far away.
I'm grown-up now.
I grew up when you married Avery.
Don't forget, you introduced us.
I mention that to myself occasionally.
It was rough getting you out
of my little round head.
But I worked at it, and you're gone.
I'm in love with Carol,
and we'll be married.
- Then why did you meet me here?
- To tell you that.
And to talk over old times.
The wonderful...
...dead old times.
Jud?
Isn't there anything left of us?
You're like some fancy kind of disease.
I had it once. Now I'm immune.
I'll make you sorry for this.
Will you?
You know I will.
Naturally, I've been anxious...
...but you've relieved my mind
tremendously, Doctor.
It's a difficult situation...
...but not entirely strange
to a psychiatrist.
I admire you professional men.
Such strength of mind.
Well, we're not entirely...
...unimpressionable, Mrs. Phillips.
Is someone sick?
Not exactly.
This is Doctor....
Pearson.
The famous Dr. Pearson.
How do you do?
He's here about Ted
and those dreadful nightmares.
It's most unfortunate.
I hope you'll follow my advice.
I will.
Believe me, I will.
And right away, too.
Jen?
Would you call Miss George
from the library, please?
You're so kind and helpful.
It's been my pleasure.
Entirely.
Miss George.
Would you please come to the library?
Mrs. Phillips, yes.
Really, that Dr. Pearson.
He's so absurd.
He actually trembles when I talk to him.
You'd think he'd never seen
a beautiful woman before.
What were you reading?
A book about bees.
A sad little book, all about bees.
Aren't you quaint!
Imagine anyone caring about bees.
You must think me terribly vain,
always staring at myself in mirrors.
I was just thinking
how beautiful you are.
How very beautiful.
Aren't you nice!
You're as flattering as Dr. Pearson.
What did he say?
The most extravagant things.
About Ted.
Just what I've always said.
It's Carol who's responsible
for his nightmares.
He said that?
- Why should he say that?
- You know how neurotic she is.
Since this engagement,
she's even worse.
She's so possessive and clinging.
But she loves Ted.
- That's what he needs.
- Did you ring for Miss George?
Then where is she?
Carol is very sweet with Ted.
- Why does the doctor blame her?
- It's just not normal.
She's smothering the child with
affection, making him dependent on her.
He says it's...
...unnatural.
There you are!
- You wanted me?
- I've been wanting you for some time.
Have Sam and one of the stable men
come up to Carol's room.
Tell them to bring boxes.
We're moving her things.
But Miss Carol's been in that room
since she was a child.
From now on she'll be in the other wing,
next to Mr. Phillips.
Won't Carol wonder
why you're moving her?
Of course.
And naturally she'll think
I'm doing it just to hurt her.
She gets such weird ideas.
She'll be leaving soon.
Wouldn't it be better to wait
until she and Jud are married?
That may be a long wait.
Wasn't he the handsomest thing
before that scar?
Was it some kind of accident?
Automobile.
I was with him.
He was drinking heavily.
I'd rather not talk about it.
If you only knew how I've ached
to clear out this room.
How did you meet each other?
I arranged it.
Isn't that naughty to admit
something like that?
I was perfectly bold about it.
I guess you have to be bold
to get what you want.
That's the only way, darling.
When you see something you want,
grab it.
That's how I got
Mr. Avery Phillips Ill.
It happened in Chicago.
He came north with Jud Prentiss.
You know Jud.
He had some silly ideas about us.
Jud did.
Maybe I did too.
But it was over when I met Avery.
Over and done with.
I followed him down here...
...and after a while, we were married.
Then is when the trouble started...
...with Carol...
...and Sue...
...and all the others.
I'm an outsider.
And they hate outsiders.
They're polite enough.
That's how they are.
You don't know the things they've
made me do trying to protect myself.
And how ashamed I've been sometimes
because of them.
You don't know how they are.
But you'll find out.
As I have.
How they whisper...
...talk about you...
...laugh!
As if you have to be from the South
to be any good.
They're so smug...
...and namby-pamby.
I wish I could get rid of them
as easy as this trash.
I did get carried away, didn't I?
Whatever will you think of me?
Not that I blame you.
I don't know when I've been
in such a temper.
They say it's good to get things
out of your system.
There's no point...
...in overdoing it now, is there?
You're not thinking
bad thoughts about me, are you?
I'm feeling sorry for you.
That's not nice.
I don't like that.
It's a bad thought.
I don't want you ever
to think bad thoughts about me.
Not you.
Don't hate Carol so much.
Let her leave without making her
unhappy, and yourself as well.
Don't oppose me, Jennifer.
Everyone else does.
It makes me terribly cross
when people oppose me.
I've been thinking.
Perhaps I ought to leave.
You'd leave me?
Go away...
...when I need you so badly?
You've seen how things are here...
...and what I have to put up with.
And you'd leave me all alone here...
...just when I've gotten used to you.
Please, try to understand.
I am trying.
I'm trying very hard.
If there's one thing I detest,
it's selfishness.
I won't remind you what I've done
for you, and I don't expect gratitude.
You know I'm grateful.
Then stay with me.
Don't frighten me like this.
If you left, I wouldn't have
anyone to call my own.
Promise me you'll stay.
I can't hurt you, Eva.
I'd never be able to hurt you.
You gave me such a terrible moment.
Aren't you ashamed to frighten me?
I didn't mean to.
We'll never talk
about you leaving again.
Not ever again.
You came to quarrel with me
about my drinking?
You aren't even going to ask me
to give it up?
In that case...
...come in.
What's the occasion?
Curious to see the household freak
in his native lair?
You said you wondered how my eyes
would look when they were wide open.
So that's the occasion.
The bloom is off the rose,
the butterfly has lost its wings.
And there are holes
in the image of Eva.
Large holes? Small ones?
Large.
That's the way it goes.
You are disenchanted with Eva.
I'm married to her.
- She told me how you were married.
- I doubt it.
The real version is rather ugly.
I met her in Chicago
on a business trip.
We loved each other. It was
slightly insane then it was over.
But Eva doesn't believe in goodbyes.
She told me a convincing,
old-fashioned lie.
It was frantic, appealing and wistful.
I fancied myself a decent man.
Within a week, I knew I'd been gulled
like a hayseed at a carnival.
You could have broken away.
Very sensible suggestion.
We even discussed the possibility
on one occasion...
...in an automobile.
It was a short discussion.
I found out I was to be a family man.
Since I'm old-fashioned...
...we've been happily married ever
since, like in the storybooks.
I found the perfect escape
from literature.
All I have to cope with now
is a hangover.
I've come to you for help.
Me?
That's amusing.
Eva's trying to stop Carol's marriage.
Predictable, for various reasons.
You can't just hide away in here
and let it happen.
I wish you'd never come to this house.
I'm sorry you don't like me.
I'll do what I can about Eva.
I've never been able to do much,
but I'll do what I can.
I'll come out of hiding
and be down for dinner.
I'll talk to Carol, Jud and Eva,
if necessary.
Is that what you want?
That's not everything.
I wish I could help you.
I wish you'd try and like me,
just a little.
I'm not much good, and that's a fact.
Sorry.
- But you mustn't--
- Get away from me!
I thought you were aware by now...
...I'm not someone to be sent for,
like a kitchen maid.
Are you drunker than usual, or
have you lost all sense of courtesy?
I'm making a rare appearance
as head of the house.
Quite an occasion!
- And what am I supposed to be?
- We won't go into that.
Sit down.
Sit down, my dear.
I've been discussing things with
Carol and Jud. I've made a decision.
Really?
A whole decision, all by yourself?
I won't argue with you.
I don't believe in long engagements.
I can't very well argue
against that.
We didn't have a long engagement,
and look how idyllic we are.
Exactly.
They're willing to get married
immediately, and I've asked them to.
I'm very happy for both of them.
Thrilled, in fact.
We knew we could count
on your blessing.
There's just one little thing.
I know it sounds terrible...
...but with everything happening
so quickly, won't people wonder?
And talk?
People will talk, you know.
Without reason, of course.
There isn't any reason, is there?
No, Eva.
Not the way you mean.
This may come as
a surprise to you...
...but the only reason we're marrying
is because we love each other.
Just thought I'd ask.
You know how people are.
- Whatever you are, Eva, you're--
- The matter is settled.
The wedding will take place on Sunday.
Of course, darling.
Whatever you say.
Now you can go back to your drinking.
It'll make you feel more at home.
You should've been here.
Beauty's been making decisions
all by himself.
About Carol and Jud.
They're getting married right away.
That's wonderful!
I was hoping they wouldn't wait.
I'm so happy for them.
I don't know--
The wedding supper. How sweet!
And how I detest not being with you,
tonight of all nights.
Where's Jen?
In her room.
She's not feeling well.
It's all this excitement.
It's too much for her.
It's almost too much for me.
The Aherns' party will seem dull
compared to this.
I wish they hadn't insisted
on my coming.
It was very inconsiderate of them.
But what can I do?
You could stay home.
And miss a party?
Darling, a party is to women
what a battlefield is to men.
I forgot. You weren't in the army,
were you?
Something about drinking, wasn't it?
You'll miss the party.
They're terribly disappointed
that you aren't coming.
I told them you had the virus.
Just a touch,
but enough to keep you at home.
Wasn't that clever of me?
Whatever lie you told them,
I'm sure it was expert.
You're priceless. Really, you are.
I like you much better this way...
...than the usual way.
My, isn't she strange?
Nervous, I suppose.
I was nervous before our wedding too.
How well I remember!
Here I am, chattering away,
and it's getting late.
I hate to ask,
but I've lost my car keys.
I'm afraid you'll have
to drive me to the Aherns'.
How can I?
I'm locked in my room with the virus.
- Drive me in.
- Take my car.
That heavy thing?
It drags my arms.
I'd be a wreck before I got there.
You'll drive me.
Jud, darling.
I hate to beg.
But you can see how it is.
I won't keep you long, and
you can be back in less than an hour.
Please?
You will drive me in.
After I've had a drink.
You are a sweet thing.
I knew you would.
You never could refuse me,
could you?
Don't be long.
I'll get my purse.
I know about you, Jud.
About you and Eva.
I've known for a long time.
Then you know it was over
when you married her.
I was making sure...
...because of Carol.
That's fair enough.
I've had the impression you find it
hard to look me in the eyes.
I'm looking now.
What do you think?
She's been after you, hasn't she?
And not only you.
- You stay locked in your room.
- I'm out of my room.
I guess you are.
Have you told Carol
about knowing Eva?
Are you going to?
You be noble and tell her.
You break her heart.
I want her to be happy.
Someone in this house
deserves to be happy.
If all it takes is me not saying
anything, that's all right with me.
How is it with you?
I want her to be happy.
- Then we forget about Chicago.
- I can't forget anything about Eva.
- If she were mine, I'd beat her.
- She's not yours.
Jud, darling!
You mustn't keep the lady waiting.
- Good night.
- I'd like to come in for a drink.
Thank you so much
for driving me all this way.
I'm so grateful.
- Will I see you tomorrow?
- No, good night.
And it's got
the cutest kitchen, Jen...
...with an open fireplace.
Right here. See?
The floors are old and
have cracks so wide...
...that you can practically
see right through them.
It used to be the garonnire,
what they call the bachelor's house.
Every plantation had one
for overnight gentlemen callers.
Jud says that he feels wicked,
taking a girl to a bachelor's house.
I told him that if he--
Go on.
It's such a pretty thought.
I forgot what I was saying.
You do forget things,
don't you, Carol?
I'm sorry about this afternoon.
But I was upset about something.
I'm not upset anymore.
Please forgive me?
I'm interested in you.
I am fond of you
and want you to be happy.
And even though
it hurts me terribly...
...I think we should talk...
...about you and Jud.
What about us?
Carol, you're so good.
It's hard for you to imagine
that others aren't...
...as nice as you are.
I'd like to prepare you, that's all.
For anything you might hear about Jud.
Eva?
Don't.
Why, Jennifer!
I think you've found out.
How clever of you!
And so quickly too.
You'll have to tell me how you knew.
Some other time, of course.
What are you talking about?
I'm talking about men.
I know men, and I know Jud.
You know your men.
Any man's my man,
if I want it that way.
Not Jud.
Jud's like other men,
no better, no worse.
Are you telling me
Jud's carrying on some affair...
...I don't know about?
Is that it?
Ask him.
Do you think I'll run to him
with something as stupid as this?
Do you think I'll let you spoil things
for us at the last minute?
- Ask him.
- No, I won't ask him.
I won't go to him with your lies.
I wouldn't lie to you about
something as important as this.
Well, then...
...if it's true,
tell me who it is.
Who do you think?
Ask him.
Phillips people are not afraid.
Isn't that what
your grandfather used to say?
I've heard the children say it.
Phillips people are not afraid.
You're afraid.
Don't let her do this to you.
I'm not afraid.
You've done a terrible thing.
If you're not happy here, darling,
you really should leave.
I'll help you pack tomorrow,
if I have time.
I'm not leaving.
Not now.
Then you'd better be polite to me.
And, darling, turn out the lights
when you come upstairs.
Where's Carol? I've been phoning
ever since she left my place.
I waited up for her,
and she didn't come home.
She isn't in her room. I looked.
She may be at the stables.
She usually goes riding
when she's upset about something.
She's upset.
We could see if her horse is gone.
She made me spell it out for her.
I told her it meant nothing, but she
just looked at me that way she has.
Maybe I should have lied to her.
But I thought it would be better
if I told her the truth.
She never said a word,
not a solitary, mumbling--
You didn't bring me breakfast.
- It's Carol.
- I forgive you.
- Listen.
- It's a beautiful day!
It's about Carol.
She's dead, Eva.
She's killed herself.
Hey, now, I'd better button you up.
Come on.
It's fun being with you.
Not like that Miss Breen.
She's too busy to enjoy herself.
Your mommy's been ill for two weeks.
Miss Breen's taking care of her.
She said I was a brat.
And she said Aunt Carol Lee was dead.
Is she dead, Jen?
She shouldn't have told you that.
She was talking to Miss George.
We heard her.
She said Aunt Carol was nutty
as a fruitcake.
What does that mean?
"Nutty as a fruitcake"?
I'd better have a talk
with Miss Breen.
Do what I do.
Last night, I spit on her.
That wasn't nice.
It wasn't very much spit.
Come on, you two.
- Last one in is a rotten egg!
- I won't be!
Looks like I am, doesn't it?
Jennifer's a rotten egg!
Children, let's remember
our manners.
Upstairs to your room
with Miss George.
And get all your things picked up.
Or Breensy will slap lazy hands.
Miss Breen, just to clarify
things for you...
...I'm taking care of the children.
Mrs. Phillips hired me.
I understand she's
feeling much better.
You must be taking good care of her.
It's no trouble at all with her.
She's such a sweet lady.
Some of my patients....
You wouldn't believe
what I go through in some cases.
You look like you can handle
almost anything.
I don't know about that.
But I do know that you have
to keep people in line.
All kinds of people.
And how are you?
I'm fine.
We don't get along very well, do we?
I'm not very good at hiding
my feelings, I'm afraid.
I don't like you.
That's all right. Neither do I.
These look all right.
We'll do the inventory tomorrow.
First thing in the morning.
I have to be in New Orleans
to settle the contracts...
...before I leave the company.
I wish you'd change your mind.
You'll be a hard man to replace.
You'll find someone.
Make an effort.
You ought to take time,
think things out.
I don't like to think.
Jud leaving the mill?
In a few weeks.
He's very tired.
You look tired yourself,
like the rest of us.
You were so young and happy
when you came here.
That was when I had pride.
Why do you say that?
You know why.
Apparently, everybody does.
I guess it's the way I look at you.
There's no future in me.
Fall in love with Ty McKinnon.
I don't want him.
Perhaps someday you will.
I like to think you will.
It pleasures me to think of you
and Ty laughing and having fun.
At least there'll be one mistake
I didn't make.
Really?
It's simply amazing what
you stumble over in dark corners.
But then, nothing surprises me
in this house.
It's that kind of house.
If you'd think more about my children
and less about my husband....
After all, he is old enough
to be your father.
I gather you've been amusing
yourself while I was ill.
There's no reason to worry.
I'm not worried.
Really, I'm not.
Why don't you come in
and see if you can amuse me?
That's enough of that, young man!
You're just a great big baby.
- Please hurry.
- Is something wrong?
The children. It's that woman.
Hold still!
Do you want me to slap you again?
Why, Mr. Phillips!
Teddy, you go to my room.
Trissa, you sleep with Cousin Jen.
I was only doing what I think best.
You have to handle
these things very firmly.
If you're not out tomorrow,
I'll throw you out.
Do you understand?
Yes, I do understand.
I understand everything perfectly.
Of course, you know
I shall have to report this...
...episode to your wife.
Make sure you leave right afterward.
These look all right.
We'd better start stockpiling cotton.
I've set the bins aside for it.
Anything else, sir?
There is something.
We used to be friends.
Did we...
...friend?
Since Carol's death,
you've been acting like this.
Will you live with it
the rest of your life?
No, you are.
Are you blaming me?
We're nearly through.
I don't mind Jud hearing
what I have to say.
We haven't seen you for some time.
I don't think I've seen you since--
Since the funeral.
- If you want to talk--
- It's about Miss Breen.
I fired her.
No, darling.
Don't go.
We have no secrets from you.
I might need protection from my husband.
If he still feels brutal this morning.
Miss Breen said you were brutal.
She leaves today.
You'll change your mind.
If only to please me.
I am your wife.
That can be corrected.
Perhaps you were thinking
of divorce again.
I haven't said so.
I hope not.
Because that would be
very difficult for you...
...and Jen.
She has nothing to do with it.
Yes, she does.
- Imagine what the newspapers would say.
- About what?
My testimony, sweet, in court.
How you and my dear cousin
have been acting.
Right under my very nose too.
Scampering along the corridors at night.
From one room to another.
I imagine Miss Breen would even
exaggerate a little.
Don't leave. This is just
a friendly discussion.
I have a weak stomach.
If you're looking for Eva,
she's with him...
...ripping him to shreds
and smiling all the while.
A lovely smile.
The same way she was
with Carol that night.
What night?
When she told Carol about you and her.
Eva!
Of course.
I thought it was him.
I thought he'd changed his mind.
It was Eva who told Carol.
Didn't you know?
No, I didn't know.
Now I do.
It makes sense now.
We're through, Eva.
All through.
I've had enough of you, if I have
to break your neck with my hands.
That would hardly solve matters,
would it?
For you, or Jen either.
Don't be stupid enough to think
I won't fight you if you try anything.
I'll use any weapon I can find.
And there are weapons.
You're a known alcoholic...
...Miss Breen has her
filthy imagination.
And your own sister, Carol,
when she found out about you....
You can imagine how it would sound.
You wouldn't enjoy it.
Whatever I am, and I know what I am...
...you can't get away from me.
One more thing.
I'm afraid I'll have to insist
that you stay away from Jennifer.
I can't have you carrying on openly
in front of Miss Breen and the children.
It's very naughty.
This is our home.
I want to play football.
You promised.
In goes in the doctor.
In goes the nurse.
In goes the lady
with the alligator purse.
For Jennifer.
Come on.
Please. All right?
I'm so bored I could scream.
Imagine the two of us
having dinner alone together.
Alone in a world of men.
It's incredible.
You sit there. You can see
yourself in the mirror.
I must say you're not the most
sparkling company I've ever enjoyed.
Why bother to set a place
for Mr. Phillips?
He never comes down to dinner.
One would think he didn't
find us attractive.
On the contrary.
The charming Mrs. Phillips, I believe.
What brings this on?
I decided there's very little
comfort sulking in my room.
Especially when there are
more attractive alternatives.
Alternatives?
You.
And Jen, of course.
But mostly...
...you.
Aren't you overdoing it a trifle?
After all, you haven't been exactly
a devoted husband lately.
My error.
You can't do it one way, do it another.
That's my motto.
Here's to other ways.
And to the past.
May it rest in peace.
This is all so unexpected.
I'm simply overwhelmed.
And, I might add, not at all convinced.
I suddenly realized what
a fool I've been all these years.
That's true.
I was wrong.
Refusing to go out with you...
...refusing to like your friends.
Refusing to be my husband, in fact.
That's the past.
The future will be different.
I'll go anywhere you want to go.
I want to be with you.
I believe you actually mean it.
Suddenly, you're very important to me.
I want everyone to know
how devoted we are.
How completely in love.
If you really feel this way...
...I couldn't be happier.
To our second honeymoon?
You're not drinking
to our second honeymoon.
She will, of course.
Won't you, Jen?
To our second honeymoon.
To your second honeymoon.
May it last forever.
Forever.
Miss George?
Is that you, Miss George?
Oh, it's you.
I thought....
I don't know what I thought.
You frightened me.
I didn't think it was possible.
You could do anything to me.
You always could.
Don't you want me to kiss you?
I'm getting something out of my pocket.
What is it?
Please tell me what it is.
The stars!
Look at them.
They're so beautiful.
You got it for me,
as you said you would.
You wanted it, didn't you?
I was mad for it.
It's so beautiful.
Put it on for me.
Well, it's yours.
Now you can die happy.
What an odd thing to say.
Remember, you said
if you could only have it....
I remember.
I said I'd die happy.
Now you can, darling.
Now you can.
You're doing the right thing.
Go back and make a place for yourself.
No use in pining away
because of some fool man.
I was in love once myself.
But it didn't work into anything.
He was just no good.
Still...
...he did make me laugh.
Now, now, honey.
What's the matter?
Come on, come on.
Jennifer isn't leaving
till the morning.
You'll see her again.
It's past your bedtime.
Both of you.
You will come back, won't you?
You have to come back.
Someday I'll come back.
You wait and see.
Now you'd better be getting to bed.
You know how you hate to see people cry.
I'm going to in a minute.
Remember when you came here?
I said I hated you.
I remember.
I never did.
I was only fooling.
There, you see.
Now I'm crying.
So am I.
Mr. Phillips says
he'll be down in a minute.
Thank you.
Miss Jennifer's in the library.
My train leaves at 11.
I'll pick you up at 10.
I thought you were still in New Orleans.
I got back today.
You're in time to help me with this.
There's the catch, right there.
Put it on the couch, please.
Isn't it lovely?
Looks real.
Everything I have is real.
I'd be the last to deny it.
Thoughtful gift from one of your many...
...admirers?
From the most exciting man
I've ever known.
You'd never guess.
Avery Phillips.
I'm impressed.
I hear everything's sweetness
and light since I've been gone.
We're on our second honeymoon.
It's wonderful.
I've never been happier.
And he....
He's a different man.
Different man.
That's what I hear.
Now I'm ready for any kind of frolic.
Really?
With my husband.
I'll be expecting you.
Goodbye.
Who was that?
Ty McKinnon.
He'll take me to the train tomorrow.
That's right, you are leaving tomorrow.
I almost forgot.
What do you think about that?
Jennifer's leaving us.
She probably has her reasons.
I can't think of any.
But we mustn't stand
in her way, must we?
A noble attitude.
What upsets me is our not being at home
on your last evening here.
But Avery insisted on going out.
We're going to a party.
In fact, we're late now.
I wonder what's keeping him.
Why don't I tell him you're ready?
Is that what you had in mind?
You're a love, an absolute love.
Not at all.
I'm just curious to see
the different man.
Don't be bitter, Jennifer.
And you mustn't hate me.
It isn't good for you.
You're young. There are things
you don't understand.
I am not that young.
I'm not a very nice person.
But I wasn't always like that.
Once, I was a great deal like you:
Young and innocent.
Always trying to do the right thing.
That must have been long ago.
That hurt.
Sounds like something I might say.
You see, there's a little of me
in every woman.
I guess there has to be.
I don't understand you.
I don't want to.
You think I've been cruel.
And I have.
It didn't start with you.
It really had nothing to do with you...
...until you started peeking into
closets where you didn't belong.
You asked me to come here
and then begged me to stay.
Did you ever ask yourself why?
I tried to tell you once.
Because I was lonely.
Saying goodbye?
- I thought you were in New Orleans.
- I got back today.
Just in time, apparently.
What are you doing?
Looking for the farewell letter.
There's always a farewell letter.
Or were you smart enough to leave it
in your safe-deposit box?
I suppose, eventually, you'll tell me
what you're talking about.
Sure.
You're going to kill Eva.
I'm wondering how and when.
Watching you with the boy...
...I'd say it's due for tonight.
That leaves how.
Guess some more.
Automobile.
It's happened before with you and Eva.
Another accident, only this time
you don't walk away.
"Too bad," the neighbors will say.
"They were so happy."
Good guess?
Don't say it out loud again.
You'll spoil the effect.
My hands would be shaking.
You can't do it.
Stay by the phone.
You'll get the news quicker.
Do you think it solves anything?
Will it make your children happy?
Jennifer or anybody at all?
Me.
You don't deserve to be happy.
You're to blame for all of this.
All of it!
You created your own private hell,
then went into your room...
...and drank yourself into
not caring about anything.
- What does that make you?
- I know what it makes me.
Why do you think simply breathing
is more than I can bear?
Leave me alone, Jud.
I know what I'm doing,
and Eva goes with me.
That's the end of it.
I'll tell her you're nearly ready.
I spoke to Avery.
He asked me to drive you to the party.
He'll be delayed.
- Business call from New York.
- I don't mind waiting.
He knows that, but he
insisted that I take you.
All right.
Good evening.
Eva was disappointed--
This is one party
I don't want her to miss.
I'll get the car.
Tell her I'm ready.
But she just left.
Why should she leave without me?
Jud said you wanted her to go.
He said he spoke to you, and
you told them to go on without you.
Stay with the children.
It's raining.
It's pouring.
The old man is snoring.
Isn't that how it goes?
I haven't thought about that in years.
I like the rain.
I like it myself.
You have to be careful
driving in the rain.
Funny how a car skids on a wet road.
A lot of people get killed
on a night like this.
I'm not worried.
You're a good driver.
You know what I've been doing all day?
Checking up on you two.
You and Avery.
What about us?
Everyone's talking about you...
...how happy you are.
Why not?
That's what Avery wants
people to think.
You're going too fast.
Not as fast as he would.
He wouldn't care about explaining.
Explaining what?
Why he's convincing people
you're the ideal couple...
...just before it was set to happen.
It would've happened tonight, all right.
This rain's too good to miss.
Take me back to the house.
Beginning to get the idea?
You're right.
He was going to kill you.
And himself too.
Go back!
Glad I came back from New Orleans?
I am.
I wouldn't want anything
to happen to Avery. Not to him.
But he loves me.
I know he does.
You're the one.
You want to kill me.
Don't do it.
Let me off.
Let go of me!
Will you stop it!
Please, let me--
Take me back!
It happened! It happened!
I know how it ends.
Go to sleep.
Yes, I'll be there.
All right.
They want me down there.
Questions.
I'll go with you.
The sun's shining.
Funny, I didn't expect
the sun to be shining.