The market is higher
with the Dow-Jones industrials
up one and a half points.
On the commodities market,
grain closed higher
with November fixings at .03.
Three dollars
and seventy-five cents.
That's down 25 cents
from yesterday's close.
London silver is up one cent
to 6.08 cents, and the dollar...
Hey, hey!
See that guy up there?
Here's $50 if you can beat him
past the station.
All right, let's go, let's go!
%% I've been watching
as days go by %%
- Look at this guy go!
-  %% I'm counting the time %%
%% now I'm takin'
another Chance %%
%% putting me on the line %%
- %% but there's nothing at all %%
- all right, that's it.
%% nothing at all in my way %%
%% hey %%
%% nothing at all
nothing at all %%
%% like I say %% hey, look out!
%% yeah, nothing at all
nothing at all %%
Yo, look at this guy!
- Damn!
-  %% nothing at all %%
%% nothing at all in my way %%
%% nothing at all
nothing at all %%
- %% like I say %%
- we got him, we got him!
-  %% nothing at all %%
%% nothing at all %%
Thanks a lot.
I'm gonna walk.
Listen, I've got an hour,
m-maybe... maybe two.
I'm gonna sell every option
I can get, steal or invent.
I don't know, Jack.
I'm scared.
Yeah, I got it covered.
Be sure, okay?
Okay. Relax, man.
All right.
I'll see you over there.
Okay.
Hey, Jack, what are you doing?
I've got these 30s
at three dollars!
I'll accept these 30s
at two and three quarters.
Buy 250,
two and three quarters.
Sold! Sold! Sold!
Sold at two and a half!
Sold! Sold!
Three hundred fifty...
three hundred seventy dollars.
We had it split for 300!
Sold!
Don't worry!
Hey, Jack,
what are you doin'?
I know what I'm doin'.
- Sold at a quarter.
- Cancel my bid!
Sold at a quarter!
Sold at a quarter.
Hey, where is everybody?
Where are my buyers?
This is it. This is it.
Sold at a quarter.
- What's goin' on?
- quarter bid. Buy 20!
You got it. You got it.
What are you doin'?
Too low. Too low.
Cancel my stock.
Did you see
the way they were buyin'?
Relax, Gabe. The market
doesn't close for another hour.
Excuse me, guys.
Say, Jack, if Semco
moves one goddamn point up,
It's four million in margin
we're liable for.
It'll slide down.
What about Bressler? Didn't
they position with us?
No.
No? Sullivan?
It's like we got the goddamn
clap all of a sudden.
Whiskey, rocks
and club soda.
Jack.
Hi. How ya doin'?
How are you?
Well, Marcus will stand by us
if we lose a point or two.
He said he's thinking about it.
Semco's still trading.
He said he didn't know.
He said he didn't know?
Shhh.
Geez, that
son of a bitch!
We started him.
He owes us.
Come on. Table.
So the guy says to me,
"the horse was gelded late."
what do I know?
He said the horse
was gelded light.
I'm thinking to myself...
yes?
Mr. Casey,
telephone call.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Sam.
Thank you.
Hello?
Yeah.
What about Marcus?
Okay. Thank you.
Jack.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
The buyout took place.
Semco just closed at 30.
Mom?
Dad?
What is it, son?
Uh, dad, we've, um...
We've had some trouble.
See, we... we had this deal
that was goin', and, uh,
We were sellin' very heavily
on, on, on margin.
We didn't expect
this buyout to happen,
Which, unfortunately,
it did, and...
How bad is it, son?
Bad.
I lost it all.
Everything.
And you and mom...
your savings.
Oh, Jesus.
Hey! We're Caseys.
We can take a punch, right?
There'll be other days, son.
I was just
gonna make a sandwich.
Nice, nice roast beef.
Salt and pepper, mayonnaise.
Join me?
No. No, I can't, thanks.
Come on.
Your mother'll be right back
from the beauty parlor.
She'll be mad if you leave
without seeing her.
No, no, I got a taxi waitin',
and I got some other people
I gotta...
I got some things...
I can't.
Don't you worry about us, son.
You're gonna take a minute,
catch your breath,
get right back.
Right?
Yeah. Yeah, sure. Sure.
Won't change your mind?
No, I gotta go.
Here you go.
Thanks a lot.
falcons leading six to nothing,
And it's the wildcats' ball now
on their own 20-yard line...
As Norm Shutter, the quarterback,
spinning and handing off
to carnie foster.
He's loose at the 25, 30, 35...
he may go all the way.
40, 45, midfield stripe,
45, 40, 35, 30...
Carnie foster.
25, 20, 15, 10, 5...
Touchdown, wildcats.
An 80-yard run by carnie foster,
and this game is all tied up,
Six and six,
wildcats and falcons.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Hey, watch it!
what are you doin'? Hey, easy!
Son of a bitch!
quicksilver.
See over there?
That's Apache.
Before he got here, he
used to work for the mayor.
That's right, the mayor.
Shortstop! Get over here.
I got one for you.
Seventh avenue,
two together. Go, shortstop.
Yes, that's right, sir.
Over there, that's France...
tour de France.
You know what he does?
he's a ballet dancer.
Really.
That's Teddy bear
and airborne.
Airborne over there was gonna be
the middleweight champion.
Teddy bear's just saving up
to go back to college.
Educated and dedicated. They
used to be college professors.
The rest of 'em around here
are just come and go's.
They come, try to ride
a couple of days,
They can't hack it, so they go.
Come and go's.
Don't worry, I'll hack it.
%%
They harpooned you
again, peewee.
Hey, Hector, a little
present for you... new pen.
So where are you from?
Different places.
Oh, yeah?
Like where?
Uh, Chicago, Detroit,
Denver. My family,
we moved around a lot.
Hmm.
Yeah, my father's
in the air force.
He's a jet pilot.
Yeah? No kiddin'?
Yeah.
He won a medal once.
Yeah, for savin' his
buddies in a plane crash.
They went down in the war.
His arms were all burned,
and his hair too.
That's why he
doesn't have eyebrows.
They never grew back.
Hey, look, I'm...
I'm sorry.
So, if you're gonna work here,
you're gonna need some wheels.
Tell you what.
Have this beauty right here.
It's in perfect shape,
brand-new tires.
And for 50 bucks,
I'll throw in the bag.
I don't have 50 bucks.
What do you have?
I got ten.
Ten?
Five down, five a week...
Till you pay me 55.
You just said 50!
Yeah, but on time payments,
you pay interest.
I know that much.
Okay.
Ooh, man,
it's a mean machine.
Yo, look, don't touch.
Okay, man.
I won't touch your bike.
What you doin'
with these chicken bones
around your neck?
Hey, man, be more respectful
of your African heritage.
Youngblood, I want coffee.
I want it light.
I want it sweet. Now!
What you still doin' here?
Okay, okay.
Money, money, money.
He makes all that money
bein' a messenger?
Yeah, well,
he's not too particular
what he carries...
And for who.
it's gonna be a good day today.
Spider, do me a favor.
See what Murray’s got for me.
Yo. I'll check.
Thank you, man.
Hey, Jack,
how you doin', man?
How you doin', Hector?
What's new? How's Maria?
Ah, very big.
She's out to here.
Doctor says no twins,
but I don't know.
Six on midtown.
Okay, thank you.
that's Terri.
- She's new today.
- How you doin'?
All right, look,
I gotta make the number.
Okay. I'll see you
later, Jack.
See ya.
%%
Hi there.
Hi. I'm busy right now.
Busy right now?
Oh, really?
%%
%% out of control %%
%% 'cause you need so much
from anyone who's there %%
%% lay on your pillow
with dreams %%
%% thinkin' it's that
someone really cares %%
%% every night
a table is turned %%
%% every time another heart
starts to burn %%
%% walk the line
just tryin' to find %%
%% somethin' that's real
you can feel %%
%% baby, do what you want %%
%% but you can't
walk away forever %%
%% just take enough
it's a casual thing %%
%% you can get what you need %%
%% 'cause we got something
here together %%
%% can't get too much %%
- Aw, poor baby.
-  %% it's a casual thing %%
You think you're so tough.
%% don't say you love me
until you know it's really
what you mean %%
%% it's such a big waste of time
makin' promises %%
%% that I don't really need %%
%% if you'd known
a second thought %%
%% lettin' go
a victim is never caught %%
%% take it slow
maybe we won't go out %%
%% with sparks in our hearts %%
%% you can do what you want %%
%% but you can't
walk away forever %%
%% just take enough
it's a casual thing %%
%% got to get what you need %%
%% 'cause we got somethin'
here together %%
%% can't get too much
it's a casual thing %%
%% ahhhh %%
Can I get anything else
for you, dearie?
I had five bucks,
and I don't know
what I did with it.
- Hey, Joey.
- Yeah, what is it?
Another bum.
No money.
No, I did have it.
I swear to God.
Yeah, I've heard that before.
Where the hell did I put it?
I gave him a five,
I put five in my pocket...
Hey, Pete.
What's your name?
What's it to you, huh?
I just want to know who
I'm loaning five bucks to.
Terri.
Where you from, Terri?
D.C.
Thanks.
Thank you.
- Three.
- Five.
That's too much.
Five... Or get out.
Okay, we'll take 'em.
Five thousand.
Come on, come on,
come on. Take it.
No, I haven't seen him
for a while.
Yeah, I know. It's business
before pleasure, baby.
I've gotta go now.
Bye.
I'll catch you later.
Hey, gypsy, what's happenin'?
What is this?
Huh?
You deliver short, hustle
my customers for yourself?
Wait a minute.
What you talkin' about?
You don't work for me no more.
Go back to bumpin' envelopes.
Disappear.
The street is free
enterprise, gypsy.
You work your side.
I work mine.
Come on, come on...
come on, man!
Hey.
Emilio, let me have a hot dog
with everything on it...
And a vegetarian
for my friend here.
It's chevere, man.
Beautiful!
Look at the wheels.
They're new.
Yeah, well, almost new.
And dig, man,
it's got two sections.
Got your hot dogs,
got your ices.
The umbrella...
I'd get rid of that.
I'd put my own, you know.
Thank you.
"Hector's hot dogs."
uh-huh. Uh-huh.
So what do you think, man?
You know what I think?
I think you're gonna get
flat feet standin' in one place.
Ah, there's
no future on a bike.
You fall, you get hurt,
can't work, no money.
Look, I want something
to look forward to.
Can't stay on a bike
forever, man.
Seventh avenue,
two of 'em, shortstop.
Go ahead.
I'm telling you, they would
never kick a door down,
not my guys.
- Apache, midway. Go.
- I'm goin'.
Whoa. Excuse me.
You dropped something.
- Thanks.
- Okay.
hey, all right!
All right!
%% I got the thunder %%
%% it's a wonder %%
%% but I don't mind the Storm %%
%% and even lightnin' %%
%% ain't so frightenin' %%
- All right!
- %% 'cause you keep me so warm %%
%% you are one sunny day %%
%% you're like a breath
of fresh air %%
%% you just blow clouds away %%
%% like you blow my mind %%
%% I pray you're gonna stay %%
%% and shine on me %%
%% my sunny day %%
%% hey, hey %%
All right!
%% how could you find it %%
%% that silver lining %%
%% even when the skies are grey %%
%% yeah, yeah %%
%% you're the reason %%
%% that this season %%
%% is like the first of may %%
%% you are one sunny day %%
%% you're like a breath
of fresh air %%
%% you just blow clouds away %%
%% like you blow my mind %%
%% I pray you're gonna stay %%
%% and shine on me %%
%% my sunny day %%
%% you are one sunny day %%
%% you're like a breath
of fresh air %%
%% you just blow clouds away %%
%% like the way
you blow my mind %%
%% I pray you're gonna stay %%
%% and shine on me %%
%% my sunny day %%
Come on, fellas.
Back to work.
Anyway, I see interest rates
going down.
The fed is expanding
the money supply,
So I would move
to decrease our cash position,
increase stock equity.
Yeah, but not yet.
Interest rates will bump
a few more points first.
I'd buy high tech...
IBM, Teledyne. What?
That's what
old man Anderson said.
I wasn't sure.
Now I am.
Listen, Jack.
I want to be straight with you.
Anderson wants to back us.
But it's you they really want.
I'm just part of the package.
I mean, not that I'm not good.
I make that jerk Anderson
look like a hero.
But I don't have
half of what you have.
You had the touch, Jack.
Anyway, he'll back us
a hundred percent.
I spoke to the lawyers,
Burke and Blum.
They're the best.
Two years, three years tops,
we buy out Anderson's interest.
And, Jack, we'd be back
in business our way.
Gabe, I'm happy for you.
I am. But... I can't.
- What do you mean, can't?
- Look, you're my friend.
The best. And I know you
want it to be like it was,
but it's not for me.
Not now.
You're telling me that driving
a bike, delivering junk,
that's for you?
I don't believe it, Jack.
I don't.
If not now, Jack, when?
Gabe, don't you understand?
I don't have it anymore.
I don't have the nerve.
Okay, you see, that was my...
That's what drove me.
And it went that day.
I don't know where it went,
you know, but it's gone.
And, you see, now all
I'm responsible for is me.
Okay? I pick up here,
I deliver there.
It's simple.
Nobody worries.
Nobody gets hurt.
I pay my rent.
I got a couple extra bucks.
If I need more, I work
a few more runs.
And when I'm on the street,
I feel good, man.
I feel... Good.
I feel... Exhilarated.
I go as fast as I like,
faster than anyone.
A street sign says
"one way, east," I go west.
They can't touch me.
When I'm on a bike,
I forget about...
Well, I don't know. I...
Hey, no, no, no, no.
No, I got it, I got it,
I got it, I got it.
Thanks for the coffee.
Hey, what's that mean
right there, Jack?
Collateral.
Right. What's
"collateral" mean?
What's this?
"loan application."
what are you doin'?
I'm borrowing some money.
Well, you know, for the cart.
Ahhh.
So?
So what?
So what does "collateral"
mean exactly?
It means you ain't
gettin' no loan.
What it means is,
you've gotta have capital goods.
- Capital goods?
- Yeah.
Something that is worth
the same amount or more
than the principle.
The principle is the amount
of money you want to borrow.
Seven grand.
Yeah, right. You got
something worth $7,000?
Oh, yeah.
His pretty ass on the street.
let me get this straight.
You mean I gotta have
something worth seven Gs if
I want to borrow seven Gs?
- Right.
- Shit, if I had something
worth seven grand,
What the hell would I need
to ask the bank for?
Well, it's a little
more complicated than that.
Don't you understand, brother,
that you's a spick, a beaner?
I mean, ain't gonna be
no white shirt and tie for you.
It takes it to get it.
The man says,
"if you don't have it,
then you ain't gonna get it."
It ain't the man
that steals your future.
It's your bitterness.
Oh! Oh, I guess I'm just
a dumb ol' uptown nigger.
I don't know nothin' about
what Jack here knows, right?
Right.
Well, if that's the case,
and Jack is so smart,
Then what's he doin' here?
Hey... hey, voodoo, you got
somethin' to say to me?
- I say you full of shit, Jack.
I say he'll beat
your ass on any street,
any day of the week.
Oh, yeah? Well, where
did you hear this? I want
to know how you knew that.
Because your big mouth
would catch too much wind,
that's why.
All right, flyboy.
money talks...
And bullshit walks.
Hey, hey, hey. Check it out.
It's on the table, man.
- Hey, I'll take some of that.
- Yeah!
hey, voodoo, we down.
Hey, where are you
going, Jack?
Look, Hector.
This is a job, okay?
It's not a game. I got
deliveries to make.
Hey, but the fellas,
they got the money down on you.
I got a cheese sandwich
and a coffee.
You can give the change
to Bernadette, all right?
Okay.
Hey, watch it!
Yo! One side!
Hey!
what's the matter with you?
What are you doing riding
on the sidewalk? Are you crazy?
Wait a second! I gotta
get this stuff picked up!
%% lately I feel like
I keep losing ground %%
%% every day, running in place %%
%% tearing around
on this merry-go-round %%
%% same rat race %%
%% oh, but I get so hungry
to break from the pack %%
%% I'm goin' far %%
%% oh, so far %%
%% lightnin' I am lightnin' %%
%% changin' %%
%% I am trading
these chains for wings %%
%% for wings %%
%% lightnin' I am lightnin' %%
%% changin' %%
%% I am trading
these chains for wings %%
%% for wings %%
%% lightnin' I am lightnin' %%
%% changin' %%
%% I am trading these chains %%
%% for wings, for wings %%
- Voodoo!
I'm tellin' you, Jack,
forget about it.
You're messin' in something
you don't know nothin' about.
All I'm sayin' is...
He could've avoided him.
He could've.
I was there, man.
He ran him down for nothin'.
Not just for nothin'.
Voodoo was known to carry
product for some people.
- Yeah, to gypsy.
- I don't know who.
He doesn't know who.
The brothers know who.
I don't wanna know who.
Voodoo stepped
into that meat grinder because
he wanted the fast money.
He volunteered.
Just be happy
it wasn't a closer race...
Or there would've been
two funerals.
Dig?
yeah. Quicksilver.
Oh, yeah. Sure.
She's still with us.
Right. Uh-huh.
You got it.
Terri?
What?
Terri, you got
a command performance.
2829 grand.
- What's a command performance?
- That means you did a good job.
They asked for you by name.
Terri.
- Come here.
- I can't. I'm working.
Yeah, 2829 grand.
That's me. Come here.
You know where this is?
Yeah.
Yeah? You didn't look
at the address.
- 21 west 88th street.
- Know where that is?
Yeah, it's off the park.
What do you need me for?
You got a car.
You wanna conduct an interview,
or do you wanna work?
I was just...
look, Terri.
I'll find someone else.
Give it back.
No, that's all right.
I'll do it. I-I'm sorry.
Terri.
I'll call you
from time to time.
I call... You come.
%%
Thank you, Maria.
So?
So it's all there.
All right.
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute. You don't
have the money yet.
All you got there
is a neatly typed
loan application.
What I got here is a Chance...
a Chance at somethin' better.
Yeah, we'll see.
Friday, huh?
Yeah.
Hey, Jack, I'm telling you,
this is just the beginning.
This cart is just number one.
I'm gonna work hard.
I'm gonna watch the money.
Pretty soon two,
then three, then four.
Who knows? Five, six.
You're gonna see "Hector."
That's my dream.
Well, you know, Hector,
sometimes things don't
work out the way you plan.
I mean, they can
backfire on you...
Knock you lower
than where you started.
Jack, when you come
from around here, ain't
no place to go but up.
Jesus, man, you are
one optimistic Mexican.
Listen, Hec,
uh... When you go to see
the loan officer on Friday,
Wear something nice,
like a suit.
Dress like a winner...
Be a winner.
Right.
Hi, Jack.
Hello, pat.
I got a pickup for Macy.
Thank you.
Uh-huh.
Five, four, three, two, one.
Hey, Terri!
Hey, what the hell
are you doin'?
Hey, you moron!
Whoa! Ohh!
You okay?
Let me see that.
Yeah.
No sweat. I'm okay.
Let me see it. Come on,
come on, come on.
Whoa.
All right, uh...
here, look.
Put this around...
yeah.
Ju-just hold it
there, okay?
So, you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
Who's gonna fix
your bike?
I'll take care of it.
You know how
to reset a wheel?
Yeah.
No.
You don't have a bike,
you don't work.
You know? You don't work,
you don't get paid.
There's no workman's comp...
yeah, I don't need
a lecture, okay?
I told you I'll take care of it,
I'll take care of it.
Thank you very much.
I appreciate what you've done.
Okay?
What are you doin'?
I told you I'd take care of it.
Come on, tough guy.
How come it's so empty in here?
Less to miss.
Ah! Ah, this is you, isn't it?
Hector said you were some kind
of big head honcho once.
No one knew
what you were, but...
is that what Hector said?
Well, you know Hector.
He likes... he likes myths.
What he doesn't find,
he invents.
Were you?
Was I what?
Were you rich?
You look like you were.
Oh, yeah?
What does rich look like?
suntan at Christmastime.
Yeah, always smiling
'cause there's nothin'
ever to worry about.
You know, like on TV
on those commercials.
They're always smiling.
What happened
to all of it?
To all of what?
To all that money.
Nothing happened to it.
The money's still there. It just
belongs to somebody else now.
If I had it,
I'd never lose it. No way.
You can lose anything in life.
Well... There you go.
Thanks.
So, you makin' any money?
I'm doing all right.
Yeah, well,
the reason I ask is...
Being a messenger isn't
for everybody, you know.
I'm doin' fine.
Okay.
It's just that, uh...
There are other jobs that'd be
a little easier on the bones...
Say, waitressing.
I don't like waiting
on people. I don't like
touching their food.
Look, Terri, let me try
to explain this, okay?
There are people out there
who use messengers...
To do their dirty work.
You know?
So it's our ass
instead of theirs.
- You know what
I'm talkin' about?
- Yeah, I do. It's cool.
Okay.
What are you doin'?
I'm oiling my chain.
Why?
Make it go faster.
It does?
Yeah.
Hmm.
- You livin' with your folks?
- No, I live with a friend...
A girlfriend of mine.
Your family here in the city?
Yeah.
No, actually, my parents
like to travel a lot.
- So they're in Vegas right now.
- Oh, yeah? Vacation?
Uh... No.
They work there.
- They're singers.
- Huh.
I don't know if you've heard
of 'em. They're pretty famous.
They open
for Frank Sinatra’s act.
They're very close with Frank.
No kidding.
Yeah. A lot of people
don't know this, but Frank
is a profoundly religious man.
I should know.
He's my godfather.
Of course, I don't remember
a lot of him, because, you know,
I was a baby and everything.
But he sends me birthday cards
and Christmas cards.
He's a good man.
I know a lot of famous people.
Let's see. Who do I know?
Wayne Newton, Bobby Hackett...
they're all friends of my dad.
Yeah. I-I think you mean
buddy Hackett.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, buddy Hackett.
I get so confused sometimes.
Bobby, buddy, you know.
Yeah, yeah.
Don't they worry about you?
No, they trust me.
They know I'm okay.
How'd you do that?
Oh, yeah, it's
magic, you know?
Unbelievable.
Ladies and gentlemen,
For the first time ever,
a full 360...
Hi, rand. Terri,
this is my friend rand.
- Rand, this is Terri.
- Hi.
Thanks.
Okay.
See you later.
How's it goin'?
So now I'm
your friend.
What?
That's what you said.
"this is my friend rand."
Gonna screw her?
Tough day in dance city?
Hey!
I don't know, man.
I don't know.
I use my lock on my
rear wheel, you know? So...
Listen, Jack, you're always
working on that bike.
Have a look at it.
Quick release, huh?
Right. Make things a lot
easier on yourself.
yeah... well, it's nice.
Oh, shit.
oh, Jesus.
I thought I'd come by for
you guys to wish me luck.
- Hey, Hector, you gonna
audition for the four tops?
- Hey, funny.
Hec, what is this?
What are you doing?
What? What's the matter?
The tux. Why are you
wearing a tux?
You told me to.
No. I told you to wear a tux?
- You said, "wear somethin'
nice. A suit," you said.
- Yeah. A suit.
- So I ain't got no suit.
- So buy one. Borrow one.
From who? What money?
Hey, Jack look... I blow
a hundred bucks on a suit,
and what do I got?
A crummy suit
pee-wee Herman wouldn't
wear to his own funeral.
- But for 40 bucks, I got
the best tux Hernando had.
- Hernando?
Hernando. Go ahead.
Feel it.
Come on. Touch it. Feel
the fabric. This is linen.
This is a 250
set of threads.
So many ruffles.
Yeah.
- Did I screw up? Jack,
did I do somethin' wrong?
- No.
No. Uh, look...
Say you came from
a wedding, okay?
Say you came straight from
a wedding right to the bank.
Yeah, but I...
Hector, just do it, okay?
Okay.
Hey, Hec...
- Good luck.
- yeah, knock 'em dead, Hector.
- Thanks, Jack.
- mazel tov, Hector.
Hector! All right. Go get 'em.
Come on, you son
of a bitch. Move!
Bastard.
Okay...
Hi, dad.
Jackie.
Here you are.
I thought maybe
you got held up.
No, no.
You came all the way
on that thing?
Yeah, yeah. So,
what's the damage here?
All the way from the city?
Yeah.
Why didn't you call me?
I would have picked you up.
It's okay.
I like to ride.
Is the alternator shot?
Plymouths are a pain.
Everything is ass-backwards.
Let me give you a hand.
You got grease
on your hands right now.
It's okay. It's all right.
- Dinner's ready.
- Hi, mom.
- Hi, Jackie.
- We'll be in
in a minute, all right?
Well, just don't
make it too long.
Mar, where's the paper?
It's right there
on the chair.
Oh.
So, how do you like Notre Dame?
I like Notre Dame.
That's the wall street journal.
Yeah, I know what it is.
So aren't you gonna look?
I gotta go.
Where are you going?
I don't want
to start anything.
What am I supposed to do
to make you realize...
there's nothin' to talk about.
The hell there isn't
anything to talk about.
There's something.
I'm your father.
I say there is, damn it.
You wanna talk? Let's talk, huh?
Talk about you working
a double shift at the garage.
Let's talk about you fixing
these junk cars in the yards
on weekends, huh?
Let's talk about you
and mom not being able
to take a vacation.
That's not the issue. We are
talking about your future.
You are smart.
You have brains.
You're throwin' it away
on that goddamned bicycle.
What about your future, dad?
You and ma.
What... mar, what am I supposed
to do to get through to that
thick skull of his?
What? Just
tell me, please!
Remember that day, dad?
What day?
- I said to you,
"dad, I lost it all"?
- Why are we bringing this up?
You know what he says
to me? "we Caseys,
we can take a punch."
- Right. We can take a punch.
- And then you wanted
to make me a sandwich!
I tell you I've lost
everything you and mom have...
And you're worried
if I'm hungry or not.
You know, I went out
to the cab and, uh,
I thought about what you said.
And I guess I really...
I really wanted to believe it.
You didn't hear me
come back in, did you?
You were sitting right there
all slumped over...
You know, in my whole life,
I never saw you cry...
Not once... until that day.
I gotta go finish
Sweeney’s car.
I don't understand you, son.
You make me so damn mad.
You ever try eating
one of these things?
They're Terrible.
You wanna try another bank?
Ah, wouldn't do no good.
Would it?
- No.
You know, I've been
on both sides.
Being a messenger is not so bad.
I ain't going back
to riding no bike, Jack.
Hey, and besides,
We have our own
lending institutions
here in the neighborhood.
Se habla Español.
No. No, th-they'll bleed you.
That's crazy, man. They...
they break people's legs.
Jack, you been watching
too many movies.
Hey, they don't do that no more.
Not all the time.
Look, I gotta get out of here.
I gotta return this monkey suit
or else they're gonna stick me
for another day.
%%
Thank you.
Um, excuse me.
Hi. You're
dressed up.
Hi.
- Yeah. I'm glad you came.
- Yeah. Listen, can we go now?
rand?
Hello.
- beautiful.
- mmm. Thank you. Hi, sweetie.
- Ax and Rolf,
this is Jack Casey.
- Hi.
- Jack is a stockbroker.
- Really?
I was...
a very successful
stockbroker.
I peeked at your clippings.
clippings! My God,
a celebrity.
In three years on the floor,
Jack grossed $30 million.
- My, my.
- - it was some kind of record, wasn't it, Jack?
Yeah, yeah, I set
another record.
I lost it all in 24 hours,
right down the toilet.
Excuse me.
was it something I said?
you guys go
ahead. Go on.
I want you to come with us.
Come on. I want you
to be their friends too.
Come on.
Come with us.
I can't leave it.
Leave it.
It'll get ripped off.
I need my bike, you know?
I'm a bicycle messenger?
It's just a job.
A job for kids.
It's my life.
It's a waste of life.
Leave it.
I don't want to.
All right!
Oh, shit.
Hey.
Hey, what's
goin', Jack?
I'll, uh...
I forgot my...
I for...
I'll be back.
Okay.
That'll do it for you?
%%
Look. Even here,
they check references.
Look... Hector?
Um, you know, I-I've been
thinkin', and, you know...
What'd you say?
You don't need him.
Jack, come on. What
are you talkin' about?
Listen, I-I've been noticing
a trend in the market...
the stock market...
And I...
I see some leverage.
See, I was a trader.
Yeah, and?
I was one of the best, and...
I could take
your money in for you.
And we could lose, huh?
We could, huh?
Yeah.
Yeah, you're right.
It's...
Hey...
But we could win, too, huh?
Right?
Yeah. We could.
All right.
Guyamo!
¿que?
Siempre no.
Otro día.
Gracias.
'tá bueno.
We could win.
Jesus Christ.
dropped my stuff.
What are you doin' here?
Uh, could you
help me out?
I, uh... I would've
called you, but...
I don't have a phone.
You're right.
No, I...
I don't need that.
Um...
Look, I need a place
to crash tonight.
It's just for tonight.
I don't wanna make any waves
between you and your girlfriend.
I noticed you had a big place.
I was just gonna take
a space in the corner. I'll
be out before you wake up.
I got kicked out of my
girlfriend's apartment,
so I thought that...
Uh,
I guess you can sleep
on the couch.
You know, there's some
blankets in the chest...
Oh, no, that's okay.
I brought my sleeping bag.
Where's your girlfriend?
%%
Look, there's a pay phone
on the corner, okay?
Why don't you go downstairs and
call your mother and father?
What?
In Vegas... isn't that
where you said they were?
I don't wanna bother them.
No, wait. Uh, I'm sure
if you called them,
Told them you were in a jam,
they'd help you out.
Parents are like that.
- So?
- So what?
So are you going to call them?
I told you, they're busy.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah, they're...
they're busy in Vegas
singing with Frank, right?
They're not in Vegas,
are they, Terri?
Who are you, dick Tracy?
If you don't want me
to stay here, just say so.
I got other friends.
Aw, cut the bullshit,
would you, Terri?
I-I mean, you tell Hector
that you're from Chicago,
That your father is some kind
of a jet pilot/war hero,
Then you tell me
they're singin' in Vegas
with Frank Sinatra?
So what is it with you?
Why did you lie to me?
What about you? What are you,
some big man/stockbroker...
With millions on wall street...
And pictures
of expensive vacation
and fancy girlfriends, huh?
Or is it Jack
the bicycle messenger...
Living in some... Warehouse
like a stray cat?
What about that one, huh?
You don't know what
you're talking about.
So do me a favor...
Call up mommy and daddy
and go back to wherever
you ran away from.
I wish that I could, but, uh...
There isn't gonna be anyone
there to take the call.
You're supposed to have
all these brains, right?
You're supposed to be
really smart, huh?
You're dumb.
You see, you have all these
choices that you can make.
I don't have any choices.
I'm sorry that I bothered you.
Hey, hey, hey, where are
you goin', hothead, huh?
Look, um,
I-I thought you needed
a place to stay?
So stay, all right?
I want you to stay.
Okay?
Okay.
Come on.
Here. Watch my bike.
Good luck.
listen, I got this Guy
on the phone...
Hey, Dave.
Look, uh, could you
get chip for me?
- Mr. Casey.
Wonderful to see you again.
- Yeah, good to see you too.
It's been
a long time, huh?
Yeah.
What can I do for you?
Yeah, look, I need to get on
the floor. Can you help me out?
Sure.
buy! Buy!
So, what do you like today?
I'm gonna spread out, I guess.
Try to build up some momentum.
I'm looking for lightning
to strike.
You can make that happen,
Mr. Casey. I remember.
Look, if it's okay, I'd like
to handle the phones for ya.
Thank you, chip, but...
No, really. I'd like to.
Like old times, huh?
Okay. Okay, thanks.
sold! Sold! Sold!
forty-five.
go higher. Go!
- Forty-five's a nine.
D's 30, 35.
- I've got the market...
40s at three quarters.
- Buy! Buy! Buy!
Twenty-five, thirty.
No, no...
%%
okay. Okay, mama.
Si. Si... si, ya...
iya comprendo!
I love you, good-bye.
Hey, Jack, it's Maria.
They got her at the hospital.
My mother, she's babblin',
I don't know what.
- Look, I'm sorry, I gotta leave you to do this alone.
-  %%
Look, I'm having kind of
a rough time...
hey... hey, hey...
What do you think,
boy or a girl?
I need you to float me.
The market closes
in three hours.
For chrisake, let's not
jump before we look.
The market's a mess. Even
Marcus is holding tight.
You said to me,
"if not now, when?"
I know what I said!
but not now.
Besides, it'll take time
to put this together.
Listen to me, listen to me.
I-I'm in it already, okay?
I used up what I had.
I'm down but I'm not out!
Why didn't you come talk to me?
I'm talkin' to you now.
I need 15 grand.
What the hell are you
gonna do with 15 grand?
That's not money.
That's nothing.
You wanna get back in?
Let's do it right,
go for it.
Back in business, you and me.
We'll make a plan. Not this way.
Gabe...
I don't know how
I got here, okay?
But I'm here and this is it.
Right now. This is the time.
This isn't about
business, is it?
No.
Okay.
I guess I got 15 grand.
I think you should know,
I have nothing, okay?
Just a feeling.
What are you trying to do,
talk me out of it?
Ceil, I want you to
put me on the floor. Open
an account for Jack Casey.
Yeah, that's right...
smilin' Jack Casey.
Chip?
Yes?
Raydon.
Six and a quarter, up
three eighths. 29,000 traded.
How about Belltech?
four and a half, up a half.
That's 40,000 traded.
What do you smell?
I like zenon.
Two and three quarters, holding.
Only 15,000...
Jack, Jack...
It's been weak all month,
and it opened down this morning.
Yeah.
It's a dog.
Let's see. Let's see.
zenon... I'm the seller
at five and three quarters.
At three quarters.
- I'll buy five.
- Sold! Sold!
- Five, Jack.
- I'm out. I'm out.
I'll... I'll sell the 30s
in zenon at two and a half.
- I'll buy 15.
- sold! Sold!
Why is he buying that junk?
Five eighths!
- I'm gonna sell 'em
down to two.
- I'll buy 20.
Sold! Sold! Sold!
Jack, I'm sorry, man.
This was not the day.
Get out. Take the loss while
you still got something.
I'm stayin' with it.
Down to one and a quarter,
Mr. Kaplan.
Get out.
It's a mistake.
I'm stayin' with it!
- Get me out.
- Out! Out! Out! Out! Out!
Jack, it's up two.
Two and a quarter.
All right.
Here we go.
- Two and a half.
- That's right. That's
right, baby. That's right.
Now we got ten and
a quarter. Come on, come on.
Buyers everywhere.
Bid for a thousand!
- Two and three quarters, Jack.
- My! Oh, my!
- Three.
- All right.
Three and
a quarter.
All right.
- Jack, it's up to four.
- Okay, sell it.
What? It's on a roll.
Lightning is striking twice.
Nah, it already has.
Sell it out
at four.
You got it.
Geez, I was having such a good
time, I forgot to buy in.
That leaves 38 grand
for you, pal.
Listen, take a vacation.
Go down to the islands,
do some marlin fishing.
And then you and me,
we gotta talk.
So who should I make
this one out to?
Him.
My father.
I thought only Jews did guilt.
You do.
We do shame.
Hey.
Huh? Hey.
How's mama?
Mama ain't
mama yet, man.
She's been in there
for, like, eight hours.
Like, what time you got?
There's a clock right there.
It's 9:00. Come here.
Oh.
Hey, hey, it's okay.
Look, I know you did
your best in there.
Look, why don't you
just stick around
and wait for the baby?
Open it.
team blue.
Team blue to radiology.
Look, there's a $170
broker's fee. I deducted it.
But I saw your face
this morning and you...
I had a better second half.
Mr. Rodriguez?
- Yes?
- It's a boy.
Eight pounds, six ounces.
It's a boy. It's a boy!
- wonderful.
- God, it's a beautiful boy.
%%
Terri!
Come here.
%%
do you think I could
bum a cigarette from you?
Hey, Terri.
Not for nothin'.
But what's it gonna cost you?
Get in.
I ain't workin' for you no more.
Get someone else.
Whoa.
I don't... Talk business
in the street. Get in.
Wanna go to a little party?
What do you mean, "a party"?
What kind of party?
What do you care? You'll
get paid for your time.
Let me out. I said,
let me outta the goddamn car.
Stop this goddamn car!
What the hell
are you doing to me?
Stop it!
Let me out of here!
What... Is this?
I carried your shit for you,
and I don't say anything,
But I'm no whore.
Don't mess with me.
Please... Don't
mess with me.
Don't...
%%
Okay!
okay. Okay. Okay.
okay. I'll go.
Hold it. Cool it!
Hold it.
It's okay. You're okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
Okay.
you okay?
You stay with us. We won't
let him get to you.
I think Apache
should tail him.
Keep an eye on him.
What do you think, huh?
Yeah.
He's comin', man.
Good work,
Apache.
Gypsy!
You don't mess
with her no more!
Terri, no! Come back.
Get back here.
Terri!
Jack?
Jack!
- Oh, Jack.
- What happened? What happened?
What happened to you?
He had a gun, and
he shot airborne.
Who shot airborne?
The gypsy. He shot him.
He just...
- All right. Okay.
Terri!
Let's just get outta here,
okay? I just wanna
go away, please? Okay?
This is what I want
you to do. Take the keys.
Go inside, lock the door
and don't let anybody in.
You hear me?
Don't let anybody in.
What are you
gonna do, huh? What?
I don't know.
I don't know. Maybe he'll
follow me. Maybe I can
get him away from here.
Just stay here, all right?
Just stay here.
hey, I'm okay. I'm okay.
I can walk.
Hi. Boy,
you look great.
Hi.
Thanks. Uh,
how did it go?
Great.
Yeah, I got a couple
of real good offers.
Great. That's good.
You wanna get
something to eat?
Oh, yeah.
Okay. How'd
it go for you?
Well, uh...
I'm gonna be a paramedic.
Yeah, it's this
trainee program.
It's for six months.
I get to learn how to save
people and I drive an ambulance.
Oh, yeah?
That sounds great. A paramedic.
Well, you've had experience
with accidents...
I'm very serious
about this.
No, I think it sounds great.
So, what do you say?
Pizza, Chinese, what?
Pizza. Definitely pizza.
Yeah? 'cause I was thinkin'
that Chinese might be good.
Yeah, well, I really
wanted pizza.
Okay, that sounds good.
Pizza.
No, really.
We'll go
for Chinese.
No, pizza sounds good.
I just have
a little allergy...
let's not fight.
wait, wait,
I know the perfect place.
%% you follow me
through the night %%
%% from dark until it's light %%
%% you follow me
through the night, oh %%
%% I need a place to hide, baby %%
%% you follow me
through the night %%
%% it ain't easy
when you tell me %%
%% you're gonna be lonely %%
%% can't you see
the lead you own %%
%% would be wastin' your time %%
%% gotta break it to you gently %%
%% lovin' me's a waste of time %%
%% you follow me
through the night %%
%% from dark until it's light %%
%% you follow me
through the night, oh %%
%% I need a place to hide, baby %%
%% you follow me
through the night %%
%% from dark until it's light %%
%% you follow me, baby %%
%% you follow me
through the night %%
%% from dark until it's light %%
%%
%% lately I feel like
I keep losing ground %%
%% every day, running in place %%
%% tearing around
on this merry-go-round %%
%% same rat race %%
%% oh, but I get so hungry
to break from the pack %%
%% I'm goin' far %%
%% oh, so far %%
%% lightnin' %%
%% I am lightnin' %%
%% changin' %%
%% I am trading
these chains for wings %%
%% for wings %%
%% lightnin' %%
%% I am lightnin' %%
%% changin' %%
%% I am trading
these chains for wings %%
%% for wings %%
%%
%% I've been watching
as days go by %%
%% I'm counting the time %%
%% now I'm takin'
another Chance %%
%% putting me on the line %%
%% but there's nothing at all %%
%% nothing at all in my way %%
%% hey %%
%% ooh, nothing at all %%
%% nothing at all like I say %%
%% nothing at all
nothing at all %%
the end...