Excuse me!
Hello.
Hi.
Sorry to bother you.
I just, um...
Do you live around here?
Yeah.
Um, I'm supposed to meet
my friend at this diner
on, um, 4th and 7th?
Right.
Do you know where that is?
Am I going the right way?
Um...what diner?
Um...hang on.
I wrote it down somewhere.
Uh, Daisy's?
Oh, yeah.
You know where it is?
Yeah.
OK, so what should I do?
Uh...OK.
Um, basically, um, OK,
go out this exit,
go to your right,
and then take the left staircase
out to the floor level.
Um, and then, OK,
you're going to get out
and go left on the street right there.
So l--
This street right here.
So I take a left when I go
out to the street?
Yeah, go left,
go left out of the station,
left on the street,
and then go, like,
two blocks up,
and then, um...
what do you see over there?
I'm trying to think.
Um...
Thanks for walking with me.
It's really nice of you.
Yeah, no problem.
Kind of a bad situation right now.
My friend--
I should have known.
It's typical of my friend, Samantha.
She, um...
last I heard from her
was on this message
where she said she had lost
her phone charger.
And the only way
I knew where to go
was that she
left me that message
saying to meet at the diner,
so otherwise I would be...
I don't know what I would do.
Really?
Yeah.
That sucks.
It does.
But anyway,
she's really irresponsible,
and, like, she's that kind of person
where if you want to hang out
at, like, 8:00 at night
or something,
you should probably tell her
to get ready around 7:00
because just give her
an hour extra
because she's going to be
late anyway.
Then she'd still be late
even if you did that, you know?
Yeah.
Yeah, my friend Rick
is actually like that.
Really?
Yeah, like the other day
we went to eat
at this Mexican place,
and, like, the bill came
and it was like...
like I had cash and, like,
he only had his card,
so he was like, "Oh, I'll just
pay for it on my card
and you can give me cash
or whatever."
And I was like, "OK, cool",
like, not that big of a deal,
and then, you know,
like, two hours later
we were at home
and we realized
that, like, he forgot his card
at the restaurant.
But then it was even worse
because then for, like,
the next three days,
anytime we went and, like,
ate somewhere together
or, like, did anything
that cost money,
he was like,
"Oh, I don't have my card",
and then, like, I was the only
one who, like, had cash on me
so I'd end up paying
for everything, you know.
Oh, that's not cool.
That's not good.
Just, like, flaking
and, you know,
being really, like, forgetful.
Yeah, although I have to admit,
I just did that about a week ago.
What? Like forgot
your card somewhere?
Yeah.
Although it's usually
my keys that I forget
because when I come home,
I just, like, throw my stuff down,
I just throw my keys,
but not ever in the same place.
Like it's always just, like,
somewhere where I can't find them.
And, like, I probably waste
ten minutes a day
looking for my keys.
- Hey.
What's up?
Uh, she's not in there,
so, um, I guess I'm just going
to wait inside for her,
see if she calls me
or shows up, you know.
OK.
Cool.
Well, I don't know.
Nice meeting you, I guess.
Yeah, nice meeting you, too.
No luck.
No.
So do you come here a lot?
Um, well, I used to,
but I don't so much anymore.
My ex-girlfriend actually
used to like to come here.
Are we going to run into her?
No. She actually
doesn't live here.
She lives in Alaska.
Why Alaska?
She's from there.
She's from Alaska?
Yeah.
Interesting.
What is she doing there now?
She just went back home, or...
Yeah.
She, like, teaches history.
What's her name?
Amy.
Do you guys still talk a lot?
Uh, not really.
We're not on bad terms,
but we just don't happen
to speak as much anymore.
We shared a room.
I had, you know, two roommates
at the time,
and she moved in with us.
So it was us two in one room
and then my two other roommates,
which was kind of weird
because the whole, like,
eight months that I was living here,
and she was still in Florida,
I was kind of hanging out
with them all the time
because they're my friends
or whatever.
And then kind of when she
got here, it was more about...
I guess I sort of...
we just only kind of wanted
to hang out together,
so it was, like, we kind of,
you know, fenced ourselves
off from them
even though we were all living
in the same place.
It was, like, this thing
that you want to just
keep it to yourself, I guess,
if that makes sense.
What do you think
you're going to do?
That's a good question.
Uh...
is this place open 24 hours or...
Yeah.
What, are you just going
to hang out here all night
and wait for her?
Um, yeah.
You think that's a bad idea?
Uh...I don't know
if it's a bad idea.
Maybe it's not necessarily
a great idea.
I mean,
I don't know what--
I guess I could just
keep calling her,
like, try to find--
I don't have her address
or anything.
You can...
if you want to hang out
with me, I don't mind,
and I mean, just while you keep
trying to find her, you know.
I mean, we could just
hang out at my place
so you don't have to just sit
in the diner alone, you know.
Really?
Yeah, I mean, my couch is open.
It's available.
Well, hopefully
I won't have to spend--
No, no, no, no.
That's really nice.
It's not weird.
I just hopefully won't have to
spend the night or anything
because I'm hoping
that she'll call me back
before that happens.
What are you doing now?
Just making sure
she hasn't called me.
I'm sorry.
I'm really, I'm really
nervous right now.
I hope I'm not
freaking you out or, like...
I'm just really nervous.
Sorry.
Can I put my stuff down, like...
Yeah, yeah, wherever.
OK.
Do you want a drink
or something?
Sure.
Let me see.
I'm not sure what we have.
Looks pretty barren.
Do you want, like, a drink
or do you want a drinky drink?
Like alcohol?
Yeah.
I mean, do you want a drink?
Yeah, we can drink.
Get a little loosey goosey.
Um...
All I have is this bottle of wine
that I was actually
kind of trying to save
because my dad sent it to me.
My dad's, like,
kind of a wine nut
so he'll send me these
random, like, wines.
I never really understand them
when I get them.
Like he'll talk about
how great they are,
and then I'll taste them,
and they all taste
the fuckin' same to me.
But we can try it.
I don't know.
Do you know what pinot noir is?
Is that good?
I think it's supposed to be better
than, like, merlot or cabernet.
I like most of those
that I've tried,
if you want to try it.
All right.
We'll give it a whirl.
Thank you.
Yeah, no problem.
So this is really nice of you
to let me stay
at your apartment.
I know I already said this,
but I really appreciate it a lot
just because
I don't really know
what I would be doing
right now if...
No, that's fine.
You know?
Sorry, but I don't have
any wine glasses.
Would it be weird if...
I'm not really picky.
It's fine.
You want to "cheers"?
Yeah, we probably should.
OK. To what?
I have no idea.
My old man?
Nah.
Why not?
Why don't we just cheers
to drinking this wine
that I've been saving?
OK.
Sounds good.
It smells weird.
It's pretty bitter.
And kind of sweet
at the same time.
Is that good?
It depends on what you like.
I don't really know.
Do you like bitter things
or do you like sweet drinks?
I guess I like sweet, maybe.
Do you know how to play
this keyboard?
Not really.
It looks like you were trying
to teach yourself right here.
Yeah.
I just hold the easy, like,
chord button.
How would I make a G
over here?
Right here.
This is G.
That's C Major.
What's that?
Is it D?
No.
D Minor.
Yeah.
So you hear
the difference in this?
This sounds like it's Halloween.
1, 2, 3, 4...
So D...
- A.
C.
OK.
Ooh, that was good.
That's good!
Sounds like a real song.
Ooh, you got sad there.
That was the Halloween,
wasn't it?
Yes.
You're getting good at this.
That song was genius.
I noticed you have
a little recorder over here.
What's on here?
Nothing.
Just words.
Words?
Yeah.
Can I play it?
Um...
I'm curious to see
what's on it.
What's that?
Did I do that?
I don't even remember.
Sounds like a bunch
of stuff going on.
Yeah, it sounds like music
that maybe
I would have recorded,
but I don't remember
doing it, so...
But you?
Like this is you,
or, like, you recorded
some music?
No, recorded me.
Oh, really?
Yeah, sometimes if l, like,
don't feel like actually
recording properly with a mike,
I'll just do that so I can remember
the notes of the song
or the idea, you know.
Mm-hmm.
So what do you play?
I can barely play guitar
and barely play drums.
And now you can play this.
Yeah, barely.
This much.
Who cuts your hair?
Why? Does it look stupid?
No.
Hey.
Sorry.
That's OK.
It took forever.
I couldn't find these matches.
It's so cold.
I know.
I'm freezing.
It's really bad.
It's so cold!
It's super windy.
I don't even know if I'm going
to be able to light this.
I'll help you.
Do you want to build
a little fortress?
Try it again.
Got it.
Do you always
roll your own cigarettes?
No, no.
I just didn't have enough money
to buy any nam-brained--
I mean, name-brand.
You just switched the letters.
I do that all the time.
Me, too.
How do you feel about the hair?
Um...I like it.
Can you tell any difference?
Not really.
Yeah, me either.
I was scared.
It was 'cause I was nervous.
I didn't want you
to not like it.
No, it was a valiant effort.
Thanks.
You're welcome.
I did cut hair, though.
I wasn't pretending
to cut your hair.
I mean, I did cut some,
so there is a difference.
No, I can feel the little, like,
hairs on my neck and stuff.
Oh, can you?
It's kind of making me itch.
Sorry.
No, it's OK.
It's natural, it happens.
Yeah.
Man, it's cold.
Are you almost
done with that?
What's that?
Are you almost done?
Yeah, actually, I only need
about half to get the fix.
I think I'm going to go
and take a shower anyway
just to get the, you know,
get the little hairs off.
OK.
Yeah.
Hello?
What are you doing?
It's not good.
No, I can't find my friend.
I can't find Samantha.
No, I'm not, I'm not...
I don't know
what's going on.
I was staying with her.
I'm staying with some--
this guy.
I met this guy, and I'm staying
with this guy.
Yeah, this guy named Charlie.
I don't really know.
It's not like that.
What else am I supposed to do?
Do you know what I'm saying?
Hello?
Do you want me to explain
what happened?
Why don't I just tell you
Don't be like that.
Hello?
Why did you hang up?
Well...
I'm not doing anything wrong.
I would not do that.
I wouldn't do that.
Fine.
Hi.
Hi. What are you doing?
Just practicing.
Yeah? How's that going?
It's going good.
Whose is this?
Is this yours?
No, it's my roommate's.
I don't even know what it does.
This is basically
the most useless thing
I've ever seen in my life.
It woke you up.
Yeah, that's true.
I think it's fun.
Sorry.
How'd you like my bed?
It's very comfortable.
Yeah.
Are you mad?
I didn't mean to fall asleep.
No, I didn't mean
to say it like that.
So...what's up?
Did you find your friend?
She hasn't called.
Are you sick of me yet?
No.
Are you sure, because
I understand if you are.
Nope, it's OK.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I really have
nothing else to do,
so it's actually
a nice, pleasant distraction.
Guess what.
What?
I think I found her address,
my friend's address.
How'd you do that?
The Internet.
I tried to look her up.
I found it.
Really? You can do that?
Yeah, you can do that.
You didn't know that?
I don't know if I like that.
Well, let me see it just so l
see if I know where it is.
Yeah, I wrote it down.
See anything?
Nn-nnn.
You want to ring
the second floor people,
and maybe they'll just
let us in?
How's it going?
Aah!
Shhh, someone might hear.
Don't do that.
Someone might hear.
Are these hula hoops?
They look kind of big
to be hula hoops.
I was going to say
the same thing.
They look really big.
Oh, they're really heavy.
Try to pick one up.
You look so beautiful.
Thanks.
You kind of look like a pilgrim.
I kind of look like a pilgrim.
But if you put this on,
it's kind of like you can
hear yourself really, really well.
I know.
I'm hearing really weird, too.
With that hat on?
Uh...yeah, it sounds
really different.
Put this hat on.
OK.
It's really weird.
"Feast For Crows."
That's kind of a cool cover.
Here.
What is that, a leaf?
Mm-hmm.
That's weird.
Maybe she's trying to flatten it
for, like, a scrapbook.
Is it flat?
Do you think it's done?
I don't know.
I don't want to mess it up.
I should put it back.
You're next.
Kind of, um...
kind of cowardly
so I don't really
face the problem head on
and just say,
"This isn't working."
I kind of do this really
half-assed gradual...
kind of just maybe try to avoid
the person or ignore them
until they figure it out
because I'm too afraid
to just do it.
I just want to be--
I want what I do and what I feel
to affect only me.
I don't want to be responsible
for other people
and what they feel, you know?
Does that make any sense?
Well, I guess I've been dating
people like you
for the past couple of
relationships until now,
and now I'm you.
But I don't really like that,
but I do know for sure
that I don't want to be
with that person.
Yeah.
I don't know.
Do you think it's like that
we're just kind of, like,
naive and impatient,
and then when you get older,
you sort of mature
into, like, a person
that can actually sustain
a real relationship?
Or is it that you just...
you know, you're stubborn
when you're young,
and then as you get older,
you kind of lower your standards
and settle?
I hope that's not true.
I don't like the latter at all.
What was the first one again?
You just, you hope that
we're going to grow up?
That we'll grow up
and be able to not freak out
when it starts to get,
you know, intense
and not feel trapped, yeah.
Right.
And just kind of actually go with it.
Well, this is my first time
feeling like that.
My bouncy ball
doesn't work in the grass.
Really?
Yeah, you try it.
It sort of does.
Let me try one more time.
That's not very fun.
No, it's better on the pavement.
You want to have a race?
You want to race?
Yeah, I want to race.
Are you fast?
Maybe.
Probably.
Probably?
All right, where are
we going to race to?
That brown patch of grass
and back.
To your jacket?
No.
To this.
OK.
Ready?
Hold on. Get behind it.
OK, ready?
All right, wait.
Does it go, "1, 2, 3, go",
or, "1, 2, 3" and 3 means go?
1, 2, 3...go!
OK.
Ready?
1, 2, 3...go.
I beat you.
I think I swallowed something
on the way back.
Like a bug?
Yeah.
I ran track in high school.
Really?
Yeah.
But I'm out of shape now.
Me, too.
But I still beat you!
I know. I'm terrible.
So I'm not holding you back
from doing anything today, am l?
Nope.
You sure?
Yep.
Well, do you want to go
to my friend Robin's
art gallery tonight?
Is it going to be
totally awesome?
Yeah, it's going to be
totally awesome.
Robin's totally awesome.
All right, then I'll go.
It's at 6:00.
It's at 6:00?
Mm-hmm.
You know what
I could do, actually?
What?
While we're in the neighborhood,
I could go get my hat.
My friend has had
this hat that I own.
OK.
And he's had it forever.
I could get it back from him.
Let's get it.
Is that OK?
Yeah.
Whatever you want to do.
Yeah, let's do that.
You want to go now?
Yeah.
I'm still out of breath.
Are you?
A little bit.
Which one is it?
4-D.
Those are sort of backwards.
Maybe he's not here.
Hello?
Hey, man, it's Charlie.
I was taking a nap.
Oh, sorry.
Um, I don't know,
can we come up?
What? Did you say,
"Can we come up?"
Yeah.
Who are you with?
Um, my friend.
Who's your friend?
Open the door, please.
What?
I can't understand you.
I don't know.
Come on,
can we please come in?
Did I hear a girl's voice?
Yeah.
Who are you, stranger?
I think he said,
"Who are you, stranger?"
I'm Jamie.
Hey, Charlie, my friend.
Hold on.
Step back from the peep hole.
Are you serious?
I can't focus you.
Hey, buddy, how's it going?
How you doin', man?
Good. Good to see you.
It's been a long time.
Hey, you guys
got to take your shoes off.
It's a house rule.
Are you serious?
Yeah.
No shoes on the rug
or beyond this point, basically.
OK.
Come on in.
My name is Adam.
I'm Jamie.
Nice to meet you.
Wow, that's a strong handshake.
Boy.
Uh...
Charlie, today, man.
Sorry.
What do you got there?
Got where?
Never mind.
They're stool coasters,
chair coasters.
I don't know what they're called.
Jess likes them,
but, you know,
'cause they keep the rug smooth,
but you can see them, you know.
You don't like
that you can see them?
Well, I don't care.
I'm just saying
you can see them.
I like your curtains here.
Did you pick all this stuff out?
I did not.
I picked out very little
of this stuff.
Who picked it out?
Your girlfriend?
My future wife.
Wow. Since when?
Since when?
Um, since...
June is when I proposed,
is when I got down
on one knee and...
what do you say?
Made it...made, uh...
Made her an honest woman.
I don't know.
Guys don't wear rings, though.
There's no way...
To know.
Yeah.
How long have you been dating?
Seven years.
Impressive, right?
It's a long time.
It's almost, like,
embarrassingly long
to now finally be engaged.
You wanted to be engaged...
Well, it's like, you know,
once you've reached
the seven-year point
and then you're like,
"Oh, now we're engaged?"
It's like we might as well have
gotten engaged four years ago.
He really just found out
she had all this nice shit.
Yeah, I found that out.
She finally invited me
into her place,
and I was like, "Whoa,
you've got a cool apartment.
Can I live here?"
Out came the ring.
Yeah.
Uh, Charlie?
Adam.
What are you doing here?
Um, I just thought
I'd pay you a visit.
No, I actually...I wanted to get
my hat that you've had for ages
that I am going to need
to reclaim.
That figures that
the first time I see you--
How does that figure?
You're all locked up
in paradise here.
I've got your hat.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Are you invited
to the wedding?
Yeah, of course.
Are you going to be
the best man?
Um, I don't think so.
I think somebody else
snatched it.
I appreciate the use
of that fine hat.
How did it
work out for you?
It worked out great.
That's a great hat.
Hey, are you guys hungry?
Do you guys like cole slaw?
Yeah.
You want some?
I've got this great cole slaw
that I'm actually
really hungry for.
And so I figure if I'm going to
go get myself some...
I feel like cole slaw
is not something
that our generation
really appreciates
as its own thing.
I get it for sides
at restaurants all the time.
Yeah, but it's a side.
It's been relegated to the sides
of other meals.
But I'm saying I just sometimes
eat cole slaw.
Like a salad of cole slaw?
Not like anything.
Just a big old bowl of cole slaw.
It's good, right?
Yep.
There's more
where that came from.
Eat up.
Where's your hat?
Oh!
What's that?
My electric bill,
but it's, like, always incorrect.
I need a...
something to spread the mayo.
Use this.
Yeah, but we just used that.
Is yours delicious?
It's pretty awesome.
Is it?
Yeah.
Are you afraid to try this?
To what?
To try this?
Sort of.
That is a slathering
of the mayonnaise and mustard.
Eat your own sandwich!
I am.
OK, I'm going to
cut it in half first.
This is the worst game
I've ever played.
That's funny.
Isn't that good?
That's kind of enjoyable.
I know.
Can I take a shower?
Do you mind?
No.
Hey, Charlie?
Charlie?
Oh, my God! Jamie!
I can't believe you came!
You look great!
It's so good to see you...
It's great to see you, too!
...in New York!
I'm so excited to be here!
I have this friend, Paul,
who kind of treads
the androgyny line,
and I was sort of
inspired by him.
Um, I think I'm going to get
another one...
Which one?
The blue and green one.
It's, like, the only one
that I really can, like,
definitely say I'm proud of.
Charlie Miller.
Ha ha!
What the fuck is up, buddy?
How's it going?
What the fuck
are you doing here?
Nothing, you know.
Checking out some art.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Are you writing a paper?
What?
On...
The art?
No.
I don't think I've seen you
come out of Park Slope
in what, like a month?
Uh, I leave.
I come out.
Yeah?
Get the paper
or something like that?
I'm out right now.
Yeah, you are right now.
Well, why don't you
call me back sometime?
What do you mean?
Like I don't know,
I called you like two weeks ago.
Still haven't heard from you.
No, seriously,
like, what are you doing?
I mean, I haven't seen you
in, like, a month.
I don't know.
I mean, I've been kind of...
well, I haven't really
been that busy.
Just forget it.
Who the fuck is this?
I'm Jamie. Hi.
Hi.
So what are you...
how'd you end up here?
You just were like, "Hey, I want
to come out of Park Slope
for the first time in a year,
so I'm going to go to an art show"?
Well, no, her friend
is actually...
Yeah, Robin did...
Oh, Robin's your friend?
Yeah, from high school.
Yeah, I know Robin.
That's why I'm here.
Oh, great.
I met Robin, like, a year ago.
It was one of those, like,
here's some rock bands
and here's some art
and here's some, you know,
face painting,
and get some cotton candy--
this little carnival thing.
That's awesome.
It was, like, over on the piers.
OK.
Are you from here?
No, no,
I'm from Atlanta actually.
I was here visiting not Robin,
but another friend,
who I can't find, so...
Isn't Robin from Atlanta?
Yeah, she is.
So you've known her
for, like, a long time, right?
Yeah, we pretty much
grew up together.
Was she always like that?
Like too cool for school
and all that?
Too cool for school?
Kind of.
That's kind of Robin.
But maybe now more so--
her hair.
I haven't seen her hair like that.
What do you do?
Well, right now I work
at, um, a restaurant.
Oh, yeah?
What kind of restaurant?
A chain restaurant.
What do you mean
"a chain restaurant"?
Like Long John Silver's?
Not quite.
Like at the drive-thru,
you're like, "No fish sticks."
Applebee's, actually.
Applebee's!
You're not gearing up to what,
go back to Florida, are you?
What?
Last time I talked to you,
you said you were like,
"Oh, I'm moving back to Florida,
I'm done with this", and all that,
"it's too cold up here,
I hate it."
I didn't know that.
No, he's, like, hung up
on some girl back in Florida.
No, I'm not.
Whatever. You talk about her,
like, all the time.
No, I don't!
I'm just saying, I mean,
if you move back to Florida,
I'm just letting you know
right now
that that means officially
you and I are no longer friends.
That's all. That's all.
Well, thanks a lot for that.
It's just a rule I have to make.
This is my good friend,
so you better be nice to her.
Jamie. Yeah, I met Jamie.
He's been OK.
Not too bad.
I had my shots today.
I'm totally right.
Your shots, or your shots?
No, both.
OK.
That's good work.
Thanks.
Is that sincere?
Do you...
so do you know Robin?
No, we just met.
Oh, OK.
Me and him, way back.
Yeah, sure.
Ar, ar.
Really?
Yeah.
Like this.
High school, middle school...
Isn't that kind of weird
that they go back
and we go back?
You guys know--
for real?
Yeah, Charlie Miller.
Tell me something
about Charlie.
Charlie used to--
Wait, wait, wait.
OK, uh, tell me...
tell me something
that you know about Charlie
from hanging out with him
for a day,
and then we'll ask,
we'll ask Kyle,
because I don't believe him.
Should I whisper it to you?
Yeah, whisper it to me.
All right, all right.
What have you been doing
for the past day?
Nothing.
We've just been hanging out.
OK, What is Charlie's
least favorite aspect
of getting his hair cut?
Um, any part of it--
paying for it.
So you're saying he's stingy.
The back, the back--
making the back look right.
No, it's wrong.
It's the itchy hair.
He doesn't like having
itchy hair down his shirt.
I never cut his hair
when we were in high school
or middle school
because that's not something
you do.
Like who does that,
like, "Hey, guy, let's put
this Nintendo 64 down
and cut each other's hair"?
Who does that?
Friends.
We've gotten
our hair cut together.
OK, you're girls.
I've cut her hair, actually.
What guy, except for the military,
gets their hair cut together?
I mean, seriously.
So you guys really--
I'll give you $20.
Go find me a guy
who got his hair cut with
his friend on a regular basis,
enough to know he doesn't like
what, itchy hair?
How does she know that?
Is that even true?
I don't like it.
She gave me a haircut, man.
I thought you met her yesterday!
It was yesterday.
What is wrong with you?
You just meet some girl
and you're like,
"Hey, what's up?
Cut my hair, girl."
You can't even tell.
That's like a $200 haircut
in this city.
You gave her $200
for that haircut?
That will be $250.
I barely did anything.
I was a little nervous.
Can you cut my hair?
I thought you worked
at Applebee's.
You cut hair, too?
Yeah, I do, on the side.
Kyle, be nice.
She brought it up.
I didn't tell you
to be rude to my friend.
Do you guys, like,
want to leave soon?
Sure.
I'm just kind of...
OK.
Yeah?
Are you guys coming?
Where?
Ah, I think, actually,
a bunch of people
are coming to my house later,
but it'll be a little while.
Do you just want to sort of
chill out and listen to music?
We got a girl.
Ask the girl.
If you meet some strange guy
and you go home--
I'm not a strange guy.
He's not that strange.
He's a stranger.
And you go home with him,
and you sleep over
at his house,
doesn't that mean
you kind of dig him?
Yeah.
OK, ready?
Let me see.
Do you know Robin?
Uh, not really.
I went with a friend of hers,
and I mean,
I subsequently met her,
but I don't know her very well.
Do you live in the city?
Yeah, I live in Park Slope.
Nice.
I live in Park Slope, too.
That's a lovely place to be.
Yeah, it's great.
And what do you do?
As of right now, not much.
I actually, I just quit my job
a few weeks ago,
and I've just kind of been
slinking around, you know.
I've heard of that.
I think I've done that.
Actually I'm doing that, too,
to be honest--
slinking around.
How's it going for you?
It's not paying the rent, really,
but I'm hoping someday it will.
I'm waiting
for the glory to come.
Yeah, we need to devise a plot
to where we can basically do
absolutely nothing
and get our bills paid.
I don't know.
What happened?
Nothing.
Nothing happened?
No, I mean,
some stuff happened.
What happened?
I don't know.
Just some stuff.
What? You don't have to tell me.
I didn't sleep with him, though.
But the thing is
that, like, you know,
I've just sort of had,
like, a hard time, um...
crossing that line a little bit,
and I don't really know why.
Like a lot of, like, my,
like, recent boyfriends,
like, I've just had, like,
such an intense connection
to them kind of emotionally
and we just talk about
so much stuff that l, um...
it's sort of hard for me
to, like, imagine,
like, being sort of, like,
sexy with them
when, like, it's sort of like
it's all, like, cute
and, like, sweet
and, like, intense
but like in a cerebral way,
kind of.
You, like, see these,
like, movies
and, like, these sex scenes
are, like, so animalistic,
and l, like, don't...
I don't know.
I just, like, don't--
I can't, like, I can't reconcile,
like, something like that
with, like, something like
what I've had with these people
that I've sort of had, like,
a little bit longer term
relationships with, you know.
Mm-hmm.
Um, so I guess
I decided recently
that, like, what I really needed
was, like, someone,
like, totally hot,
like, unquestionably hot
that was kind of a jerk maybe
and so I could just get over it.
So you could cross the line--
Well, maybe just get over
some of it, you know,
because, like--and someone maybe
who I didn't have to...
like, I would never do anything
with anyone
who, like, I didn't feel,
like, a connection to,
but I kind of just wanted, like,
to not have to worry about...
like, I didn't want this,
like, long history,
like, I didn't want
all these memories of us,
like, sort of having, like,
this, you know,
psychological stuff going on.
I just wanted it to be, like,
sort of more visceral.
I think that's what I need.
I've had some drinks,
I will confess.
What's your drink of choice?
Well, the gallery
had beer, so I drank that.
And, um, there was a few nips
of something along the way.
I don't know,
I haven't really been--
Like illicit nips,
or liquid nips?
Liquid.
What would be illicit?
Well, there's, you know,
there's pills, there's powders,
there's pipes...
No, none of that.
Strictly something
you put in a glass.
And is legal.
Yeah.
But, uh...
like, I remember
this one time,
um, I was sitting in that chair
over there,
and he was, like, lying on
his stomach, like, on the bed,
and we were just
listening to music and stuff,
and l, like...
I never would have, like,
asked anyone this before,
but he was lying on his stomach,
like, reading a book,
and I was just like, "Hey,
Scott, can I ask you something?"
and he's, like, "What?"
And I was like, "Can I just,
like, lay on top of you?"
What did he say?
He was, like, "Uh...OK."
So l, like, came over here
and, like, just laid,
like, directly, like, stacked,
like, right on top of him
and just laid on top of him,
and, like, we talked for a while.
And I just remember thinking,
like, you know,
like one of my roommates,
like, here,
like, has never even
had a boyfriend,
and, like, I just remember,
like, saying to him,
"Like, this, like, feels really good.
Like, I don't even
know you that well.
It just feels really good
to, like, be, like,
close to someone and stuff."
And it wasn't, like,
really, like, a sexual thing.
It was kind of like
I was fully clothed,
just, like, laying on top of him,
and I was just like,
I just sort of felt,
like, sort of sad in that moment
for, like, people who, like,
don't have,
like, that, like, contact ever.
You know what I mean?
Because, like, in a sense,
like, it was like,
in a sense
it was, like, all I needed.
Like I didn't even need,
like, I didn't even need,
like, to get over,
like, all this stuff really.
Like, I think that's really
just what I needed
was just, like, closeness
and, like, being, like,
comfortable with someone,
and I think that's
why it was so hard
to, like, say the things
that I said to him that night,
like, when I sort of told him
that I couldn't do it anymore.
I talked to this girl,
and her dad, like,
runs some old carpet place,
and she can get, like, remnants,
like, old carpet pieces
and then just, like,
sew the edges.
It's, like, 50 bucks
to sew the edges.
So I got, like, a bunch
of, like, little weird rugs.
I feel really bad.
No, you should not feel bad.
I just have this class tomorrow.
Oh, my God.
You should have told me
you had class tomorrow.
Hey.
How's it going?
Good.
I'm just...
Enjoying the taps?
Oh, yeah, messin' around.
What have you been doing?
Nothing, just walking around.
Talk to anybody interesting?
Talked to the same folks.
Folks.
But no, you can't really get
into anything that important
in this environment,
can you?
Depending.
Depending if, you know, what
both people want to talk about.
What's that for?
Your concert.
My playing?
I was kind of trying to be quiet.
Watch.
This is a good technique
for high-five.
If you look at my elbow
and I look at yours,
supposedly
we'll connect better.
Instead of hands.
Yeah, like, don't look
at my hand when you move.
Look at my elbow,
and I'll look at yours.
OK, ready?
Ready, go.
Wait, hold on.
OK.
Do it again.
You know, I mean, I don't want
to, like, stop your fun.
You should have
told me earlier
when I said
about the sort of party.
Maybe if we could, like,
lower the music or something,
and you can blame it on me.
You can tell everybody that
I'm a horrendous awful...
No, you're not
a horrendous awful.
I would never say that!
I would never
say that.
You have to find it.
It's, like, way back here.
This thing?
Yeah.
Make it as tight as possible.
I'm giving the doubled up...
It's like, here's the single one--
Not this one.
Yeah, I know.
This one.
You just have to...
I don't know how
to describe it.
You just...
I'm doing it.
Yeah...
You said, "I'm doin' it."
I'm doin' it.
OK.
Looks good.
Thanks.
When is your birthday officially?
My birthday is October 28.
I just have a dollar,
but I can sign it if you want.
OK. Can you sign it?
The good thing about that
is I can cash--
well, it is cash.
I can't cash this.
This is a totally
erroneous present,
as far as I'm concerned.
That's why you should just
smash it over your head.
But it's not erroneous.
I like it, though.
That was nice of him
to give it to me.
Do you want the dollar or not?
Yeah, I want the dollar.
Bye.
It was good meeting you.
I don't know
if I'll see you again.
We'll do hugs.
We're doing hugs.
It was nice meeting you.
Bye.
All right, guys.
Have a good night.
Hey, so you're...
Oh, no, I'm going to...
Is it...I was going to hang here
for just a couple more minutes.
That's cool, right?
Carroll Street.
Transfer for the F train.
Smith and 9th Streets
next and last stop...