- I should get a Rune Pedersen.
- Exactly.
It is you who is Rune, what? Come with me. This way.
So.
That you will not have to enter. Not there either. And is not it.
Take off your clothes. Alt.
Pants, underpants, undershirt ... Alt.
Stand over there and go down on their haunches!
Farther down. Up again.
Lift left foot. Thank you. Right. Thank you.
Spit out the gum! Thank you.
Gap and stretch out your tongue!
Hands. Palms upward.
Run them through your hair this way.
Thank you.
Out of curiosity ... What have you done to end up on the 4-West?
The other is the much greater than you. You should know that awaits you.
They know you're going. You must have done something very stupid.
Bear!
What will the new cell have?
He should have 465
Come here.
465 is your cell. Welcome.
Is everything okay?
- What do you want?
- Can I get the cleaning?
- I want to wash the cell.
- It will do later.
You are out in the yard first.
Claus! What will you do with it?
It's ok. He said it was too soft.
- It's not yours.
- He will not have it.
It belongs to the cell.
Be so good. Add it to your cell!
- He will not have it!
- Shut up. Otherwise, go to bed.
The whole gang. If someone says a knyst to, then it's goodnight.
Helmuth, you varførst. Go into the cell! Good night!
You can also enter the cell.
Are there any more that would be smart?
Now what the heck me be quiet!
Thank you.
It's unbelievable.
Welcome to Horsens!
Come here. Lie still!
I've been waiting for you. It was my buddy to put down.
Such things can not get away with.
Either tap the other, or you'll get credit.
You should take the guy in the red jacket. He goes next to the Negro.
Look at him! Remember how he looks!
Look at me! Do you remember him?
Give him credit, or you'll get credit.
Put now before I change my opinion!
Do you have cigarette, Sune?
- Can I get one?
- Sure.
What the hell laughing at? What's so funny?
Walls, give a damn about it! Go out and calm down!
Be seated!
I heard that you should do one thing for us.
Think you can do it?
There are Albanians. Drive out the teeth on him.
Do it in the second floor when we are in the yard, when the guards are not there.
Make it real! He will not be able to come back for a while.
- What happens to me afterwards?
- Nothing.
You fit just yourself.
Out in the yard, you are last!
Otherwise there will be nothing.
Set up the pace if you want to go out!
- Though with some fresh air.
- I can penetrate.
Now I close fourth.
Next.
Be quiet. Shut up and calm you down!
Not more shit now.
I'm sick of this. Next time it will be the hole!
Shut up and do what you will!
Thank you.
Your turn. Come here.
Turn around.
Next.
- We close a vdelingen.
- Into c ellene.
468 closed.
465 closed.
461 closed.
When we go, buddy. Extinguish it there!
Faster.
Come on!
What did you do the stairs?
What did you do the stairs? Reply!
Who beat him? You know for sure. Answer me!
You owed the other a service. If you are not new there?
- Are not you? Answer properly!
- I do not know, damn it!
Do not you know? Are you stupid? What?
Tell us now. You did, huh? What?
Go to hell, you fucking pig!
- No mertull. Answer now!
- I do not know, damn it!
Well, you know it. You are full of crap. Who did it? Answer now!
"I don't know!"
Then a few days of solitary confinement.
Hello, my friend. Have you come back?
Have you missed me?
I've missed you.
What are you hiding?
Nothing.
Turn around, then and show me nothing.
- To Hell. Is it your sister?
- It's my boyfriend.
Is that your girlfriend? She is leaking.
How the heck could you get her?
Are you in control of her?
Do you know what she's doing now? She fucks a nigger for sure.
Shit so clean and tidy you have it.
The clothes are fine. Has your mom been here?
Do you like to clean?
- What?
- It's ok.
You are so damn good to clean ...
A fucking idiot piss off the leader. You can wash it.
Could you do it?
- What?
Yes
- Keep them for me! Want to taste?
No
Do not you want one? Take a fucking grape now!
Are not they good?
Gap!
One more time.
One more time. Gap now.
One more time. Gap. Higher!
Sune!
- What are you doing here?
- See here. That's his girlfriend.
It is not his girlfriend. Do you have nude pictures of her?
Want to buy some?
Check the type walls. He looks Rune.
Taste in hairstyles.
- Is it really clean now?
- What?
Can you put a baby there? Add you there!
Add yourself now like a little baby! In the fetal position.
On the side and pull up my legs.
Suck on your thumb now.
So fucking pathetic you are! Get up.
You know what? You are doing a good job.
You can get this-
- And dick sucking pictures and with hairy legs.
But it lets you hang.
- Nice, huh? Say that I'm good!
- You are kind.
I thought you almost.
Rune ...
You will help me as much as you help masons.
I'm beginning to dislike you. Do you understand?
When I say "jump", so you just ask "how high".
I take no more shit now.
What happens?
We went not to the same transport?
My name is Rashid.
Rune.
- How long will you sit?
- Two years.
You?
- One year.
With good behavior, it is probably less.
- Is there anyone who bothers you?
- No, it is not.
Take it easy. No one bothers me either.
- Want a cigarette?
- No, I do not smoke.
- Thinking of your health. Do you like your job?
- It's quiet and nice.
- It's better than cleaning up.
- What the heck are you doing?
Get some friends! I'll talk to him.
After work, go to the cell and stay there for half an hour.
Do not go, masons. I will talk to you.
Do not stand and hang. Give me a towel!
A clean towel, damn.
- What happened on the ward yesterday?
- What do you mean?
Yes, he said.
This ertåpelig. It was the third time.
- You have to recruit better people.
- It is not easy.
Fuck him.
You can take a proper chat with him.
- I will not see him again.
- No problems.
Sharpen up now.
- Are you ready?
- I'll just ...
You are ready. I will talk to you.
It should be something that the guards can not see.
Go and soap into the windows to guard the room, so they can not see out.
Jesper, what does he do? Have you spoken out about it?
- What are you doing?
- I polish the windows.
- What was that?
- Go out of office!
- What are you doing?
- Wiper windows. Kim said yesterday.
- Have you heard anything about it?
- He said it yesterday.
I'd take the floor and windows. It's dirty here.
So go ahead, then.
Nicely. Do the rest too!
Alarm! An attack down here. Come, quick!
Hurry!
Go!
Stay away!
To hell!
What the hell ... Do not like my drawings?
Have you rolled a joint for us?
Keep watch at the door!
Shall I light it?
So you got the order of things?
Right on the nose. He howled.
We threw him into the sink. And into the radiator.
Into the shower. Then he was silent.
I had to drag him away in the end. "Now hold up," I screamed.
I do not know if he heard it, but he has enough understood
I had said that smoke and money should not be arrived at once.
- Then we have the second problem.
- I know.
We must think of what to do.
The monkeys down there has not gained anything in three weeks.
After that the Albanians breasts themselves.
Think out something, otherwise we lose livelihood. Close the door.
Move up.
You can damn well do not open the door when I stand here with a joint?
Think about it!
Hi, Grandma. It's Rune.
It goes well. How are you?
That's good. I wonder if you want to visit me.
In Horsens.
Take with you some of Kinder eggs that I like.
Kinderegg. Sjokoladeegg.
That's good. I can not talk more now. Bye.
- What happens?
- Not much.
I never finished the dishes.
You are on 2-West, what? Can you do me a favor?
Go to the first toilet to the left.
Check whether you can open the door that sits at the bottom of toilet seat.
I'm coming!
Do it.
Say stop!
Do you get smoke here?
- How are you?
- Good.
You've lost weight, huh?
- I think it?
- Yes, it does.
- Do you get good food? What did you today?
- Potatoes.
- You must surely have been something more?
- It was hash.
It feels strange to sit here. I do not know what to say.
Can not we just sit here?
I have something for you.
These.
- It was such you would have?
Yes
- Thank you.
- Do not take everything!
- You must show what was inside.
- Should I open it?
A small lion.
Remember when we were in the zoo? It liked you.
We were often there. You never got enough.
We went to the circus and all sorts of places.
You were a very happy boy.
You were always so happy.
Dear boy ... Soon it is over and then you're going to get it good.
It will work out forever.
- You must give me a hug.
- Grandmother ...
It must.
Pass the coffee!
Ok.
Get your head.
Bye, Rune.
We erferdig.
- Could you open it?
Yes
- Can you stick your hand?
- Do it.
Go into the bathroom at seven.
The time now seven sticking your hand when I flush.
Then, tap three times when you have caught it.
You'll see what it is when you take it. Do not forget to put the hatch in place.
No one will know what we do.
Rune ....
- Open!
- I'll bore shit done.
Close up now, otherwise I'm going to give a shit c ella di.
- Now, damn it!
- I come.
Did you get it? That I sent down.
There was nothing.
If you do not believe this, then.
- Don 't you see what we can do now?
- Yes, I'm not completely stupid.
- Which banks?
- Is there Mince woodpecker?
- Can I talk to you?
- Sure. Come in.
During the four eyes.
Under four eyes? It sounds dirty. Are you dirty?
"What is it?"
- I can help you.
- With what?
- With it there.
Close the door and sit down!
I can get things down to the 2-West.
First on Krita. So money in advance.
If something disappears, I pay. Otherwise I will have a share.
And then you leave me in peace.
Let you alone? Only if it works out.
It does.
Think about it.
Why? I have nothing to lose. Say that the masons to come back.
What is it? Your little gay.
Swallowed him?
I will talk to you.
You should go help us.
Close the door. I have something for you.
Do not look.
- Hello.
- What happens?
Wait there.
- It lacks a bundle.
- Yes, I know.
Be so good.
- How you tell them?
- It's not my money.
- I need to know how much it is.
- Do you think I trick you?
- It lacks a 50-patch.
- No, it does not.
Yes, it does.
Bullshit. I almost got heart attack.
- This goes well.
- Where is bloody good!
It could not have gone better. Yes, it could ...
- How are you?
- Good.
I will talk to you. Come!
The road.
What do you say about air change? Mini to move. You can get the cell.
This view is slightly better than on the other side.
And then we have poker night tonight. It's just to get there.
- Johnny agrees. The old, then?
- I give myself.
- Now we will see a great hand.
- Yes, it comes.
- Holy shit so bad you give.
- I know.
I give myself.
Do you like to rub up against me?
- I am so fucking sick of you!
- I'm just joking.
Do you think it was funny?
- Do you like your new apartment?
- It's fine.
You are now on the sunny side.
The lady up there, I know. Visit her up too?
I found this inside of walls.
Thank you.
- Now, Ladby. Is the game soon?
- It begins to approach.
- We have marked the path.
- We had to help him.
- Should we have heating first?
- No, they have warmed up enough.
- Who plays?
- QPR against FCK.
Queers Park plays in yellow. They can not escape.
- They often try to escape.
- Yes, they do.
Now it is immediately kick off.
The game is started.
It is an own goal! The first goal ...
We lead with a 1-0!
Queers Park ...
1-1. Is he alone on the track?
Now it is clear. Come on, Queers Park.
Own goals again. The goalkeeper is ready and staring!
What is this? I put in more food.
- The lining makes them focused.
- He is angry ...
Close the door!
Quiet and calm.
Do not be afraid of it!
It does not take much to ...
For hell, come now.
You little bastard! Open the cage. Is it a predator you have?
- Do you know who have small dick?
- Who?
- Walls.
No
- Why check your cocks?
- Do not you?
If you have never checked anyone else's dick?
- I stand up and do not stare.
- It allows for the heck not me either!
I'll just happen to see ...
If you are finished, we have food to be made and dishes are included.
Go ahead! Is that understood?
- 3-2 to the Danes!
- You play fucking good.
What is it, man?
I know what you're doing.
As of now do business directly with me.
I do not know what you're talking about.
"Do not know" ... Are you a stupid Danish?
Are you stupid or what?
Or is it Rashid who is lying?
Should I talk to him?
So can I talk to walls. He will certainly know.
- Ahmed, set up the goal!
the word "why?"
Because I said so.
- Okay. Then I will have the same price,
- We can not talk about it now.
Are you still here? Put!
Sune!
You should not have told how we are doing.
I had no choice.
Now I have to do business with Bazhir, and I do not trust him.
- It's me who carries it.
- The same who have it in the ass.
We are worthless now that everyone knows how we are doing.
You'd understand if you were in my situation.
I want a decent chunk. More than usual.
How much?
How much will the small Arab space? Three times the usual.
- I can not fix.
- Yes, do it.
What are you afraid of? Are you afraid of the tattooed gay?
See why I get it tonight!
Have you heard that Albanians are here again?
Can I talk to you?
I will send three times more than usual tonight.
You obviously trust the monkeys there.
Can you do it? It is you who have problems if something goes wrong.
You'll take the chance.
Where's my queue?
Fire.
You made good today.
What happens?
- Do you have my ...?
- I have no money.
I swear that I do not have them.
He said you had made it that way.
What are you staring at?
Fix your money! I do not care how you do it, but do it.
I know nothing. I thought that you and Bazhir had a deal.
Reply parliaments are trying to fool us.
- Is it you he talks to?
Don't know?
- The monkeys messing with us.
- Which "us"?
- Reply parliaments fooled us.
- What the hell do you mean by "us"?
Have you money? Listen up, damn it!
- Do you have money?
- Yes. No problems.
- What moves you about, then?
- The monkeys are trying to fool us.
- Who they are wondering?
- Us!
Which "us"? There is no "us"!
What's so fun?
Grandmother, it's Rune.
Thanks for visiting. Yes, that was nice.
Yes, Grandma, you have some spare money?
Save Money. Money.
No
It does not matter.
Take it easy, Grandma. There is no problem. I was just wondering.
Bye.
Our Lord and Savior.
You who are with us with all your love wealth.
Let us receive your flesh and blood
- In memory of you and as confirmation of our faith.
I have talked with the old.
You have an outstanding.
I have it under control.
- You control nothing.
- I find it out.
The down there have something that is ours, and that you have gone for good.
- I'm going for a solution.
- Say it again, so I turn up.
Do you realize how serious this is?
The only reason that Ali is not hartatt you, -
- Is that the old has protected you. But it's over with now.
You must think of something.
Will not you at something, do it another.
Sleep well.
You owe me money.
What the hell is wrong with you?
You owe him money?
I'll cut you, you bastard!
You are dead, fucking gay.
Keep him on!
Shut up, damn it!
- Are you ready?
- Turn him!
Now he is strapped.
If you have both the showers? Do you have any problems, or?
I spoke with Bazhir. He would like to buy some more.
The guards took his money. It was not his fault.
Come! We can not talk here.
Come on, man.
Rune ...
Guard!
Who went into the cold room? You must have seen something.
Answer now.
Was not he your friend?
Rashid ... Walls will talk to you.
How are you, Rashid?
- How are you?
- Good.
- They interrogated you, what? What happened?
- Nothing. What would happen?
Some speak when they are interrogated.
We sit in the shed. It's freaking cold.
- Do you know what the morning coffee is?
No
- Have you never heard of it?
- Is that coffee?
He does not know what tomorrow's coffee.
It is called at least morning coffee.
You take the kettle and fill it with oil. Olive oil.
So pour a pound of sugar into it.
And then the boil.
When sugar is completely melted, -
- You go into the cell to the informer who, -
- Pulling away the covers, nor the oil over him.
There once was a little song bird that sat in my cell say.
We made the morning coffee for him.
I have never heard anyone scream so much.
Sometimes you have to set an example when someone is talking too much.
That's why stuff happens.
I just wanted you to know that. Now we drive on as usual.
- What is he doing?
- He will eat. Give me a plate!
_jeg do not want him here.
- It's ok for me. Understood?
Can you give him a fork?
Eat now.
"What is it?"
- It's ok.
It's tough.
Real tough. I know.
Fortunately it's not your fault.
- He should not die.
- It's the way it is here.
Continue to be focused now.
- You will not be here forever.
No
Concentrate on your tasks! Then everything to work out.
Rashid? How erdu?
- Rashid, you've visited.
- I'll just change clothes.
- Come on.
- It takes two seconds.
- You visit. Now!
Will not you take them? Come now!
It was not so difficult?
Are you okay, honey? How has the little kiddo that?
How are you?
You have no idea how much I miss you. I can not sleep at night.
I think about you all the time.
I do not understand how you think. What is going on with you?
God will guide you. You ask your prayers well?
Do not lie to me. Do you pray regularly?
- Why do you say no?
- What do you want me to say?
Kim ... I will go to the mosque.
Not now. It's the middle of the night.
I will go there now. Only this time around. I need it.
Kim ...
I would like to chat with you.
What is it Rashid?
I know how these are smuggled in prison.
That I never saw.
Go and live it to the proper owner.
Son your last three months, and be not involved in this.
It's too good for you.
There is another thing ...
I know who killed Rune.
There were masons and Albanians.
Good morning, Rashid.
You have something that is mine. Where is the damn egg?