10
00:00:16,920 --> 00:00:18,050
Truth?

11
00:00:19,580 --> 00:00:20,910
What is truth?

12
00:00:35,460 --> 00:00:39,730
Many here have seen you employ demons to heal

13
00:00:39,860 --> 00:00:42,680
and call it the work of God!

14
00:00:47,480 --> 00:00:51,600
Many heard you say you would destroy the temple

15
00:00:52,510 --> 00:00:56,570
and in three days build another.

16
00:00:57,390 --> 00:01:00,330
Some testified here before the sanhedrin

17
00:01:00,330 --> 00:01:01,770
that you said this.

18
00:01:02,430 --> 00:01:04,110
How do you respond?

19
00:01:07,620 --> 00:01:09,590
Are you going to refuse to answer?

20
00:01:17,000 --> 00:01:21,200
Are you or are you not the Messiah?

21
00:01:22,880 --> 00:01:24,210
I am.

22
00:01:24,600 --> 00:01:27,050
And soon you will see the son of man

23
00:01:27,060 --> 00:01:30,210
sitting at the right hand of God.

24
00:01:34,380 --> 00:01:37,480
How dare you speak his name?!

25
00:01:39,500 --> 00:01:41,500
The charge is blasphemy.

26
00:01:42,100 --> 00:01:44,070
He deserves to die!

27
00:01:51,270 --> 00:01:52,850
Judas!

28
00:01:58,870 --> 00:01:59,690
You.

29
00:01:59,690 --> 00:02:00,690
You're one of his men!

30
00:02:00,690 --> 00:02:02,340
No. I-I'm not.

31
00:02:02,340 --> 00:02:04,610
This man is one of the Nazarene's men!

32
00:02:04,610 --> 00:02:06,510
I-I don't know him. You're mistaken!

33
00:02:06,510 --> 00:02:08,820
This man walks with this "Son of God"!

34
00:02:08,830 --> 00:02:12,160
I do not! I don't know him!

35
00:02:12,160 --> 00:02:14,880
I've never seen him before!

36
00:02:15,990 --> 00:02:17,210
Take him away.

37
00:02:29,130 --> 00:02:30,250
Governor.

38
00:02:30,800 --> 00:02:32,590
The Nazarene's popularity has strengthened

39
00:02:32,590 --> 00:02:35,120
The Zealots' resolve to rise against us.

41
00:02:35,310 --> 00:02:37,440
His trial could trigger rebellion.

42
00:02:37,440 --> 00:02:40,710
The word of one Jew against the might of Rome?

43
00:02:41,000 --> 00:02:43,030
I don't think so, Marius.

45
00:03:02,070 --> 00:03:03,080
Don't!

46
00:03:03,480 --> 00:03:04,860
Release him!

47
00:03:05,340 --> 00:03:06,630
Let him go!

48
00:03:09,220 --> 00:03:12,850
Are you the king of the Jews?

49
00:03:13,210 --> 00:03:15,960
My kingdom is not of this world.

50
00:03:16,000 --> 00:03:18,000
So you are a king, then?

51
00:03:18,030 --> 00:03:19,630
You say that I am.

52
00:03:20,950 --> 00:03:23,650
I was born and came into this world

53
00:03:23,650 --> 00:03:25,920
To testify to the truth.

54
00:03:26,690 --> 00:03:30,020
Everyone on the side of the truth listens to me.

55
00:03:31,260 --> 00:03:32,430
Truth?

56
00:03:37,210 --> 00:03:38,460
What is truth?

57
00:03:55,050 --> 00:03:58,210
I find no basis for a charge against him.

58
00:04:02,080 --> 00:04:03,750
Crucify him!

59
00:04:31,090 --> 00:04:32,160
Take him...

60
00:04:33,140 --> 00:04:34,740
and crucify him.

61
00:04:39,480 --> 00:04:41,220
Crucify him!

62
00:05:02,130 --> 00:05:03,310
Out of the way!

63
00:05:41,070 --> 00:05:42,190
Nail them in.

65
00:07:32,510 --> 00:07:35,440
See how they come in their hundreds of thousands

66
00:07:35,580 --> 00:07:37,520
to keep themselves in God's favor.

67
00:07:37,520 --> 00:07:40,610
It is undeniable that the temple is a great focal point

68
00:07:40,610 --> 00:07:42,810
for their celebrations, Father.

69
00:07:43,040 --> 00:07:45,490
However, they thrive in their daily lives

70
00:07:45,490 --> 00:07:48,070
due to the leadership of the high priest.

71
00:07:48,070 --> 00:07:50,610
You have protected our sacrificial rites admirably

72
00:07:50,620 --> 00:07:54,560
against the Nazarene's desire to sweep them away.

73
00:07:54,800 --> 00:07:57,060
My one regret is that you involved the Governor.

74
00:07:57,060 --> 00:08:00,720
It was necessary to call upon the full force of Roman law.

75
00:08:01,040 --> 00:08:03,100
The Nazarene's crucifixion sends a message

76
00:08:03,100 --> 00:08:06,650
to all who might challenge what we labor so hard to uphold.

77
00:08:06,650 --> 00:08:08,210
You did the right thing.

78
00:08:08,300 --> 00:08:09,650
That is open to question.

79
00:08:09,650 --> 00:08:12,990
Day by day, more and more people were being seduced

80
00:08:12,990 --> 00:08:16,500
by the Nazarene's simplistic homilies.

81
00:08:16,860 --> 00:08:18,010
He had to be exposed.

82
00:08:18,010 --> 00:08:19,920
And so brutally executed?

83
00:08:19,920 --> 00:08:21,130
My husband took a decision

84
00:08:21,130 --> 00:08:23,340
any high priest would have taken.

85
00:08:23,340 --> 00:08:24,900
Though my methods may have differed

86
00:08:24,900 --> 00:08:26,040
during my time in office,

87
00:08:26,040 --> 00:08:28,540
I would have pursued the same objective.

88
00:08:28,540 --> 00:08:30,290
It was the needless death of a harmless soul.

89
00:08:30,290 --> 00:08:31,780
"Harmless"?

90
00:08:32,490 --> 00:08:34,760
He threatened everything we represent

91
00:08:34,760 --> 00:08:36,100
and these people believe in.

92
00:08:36,100 --> 00:08:39,180
The life of one man is as nothing, Joseph,

93
00:08:39,180 --> 00:08:40,760
for the sake of God's nation.

94
00:08:40,760 --> 00:08:41,490
Caiaphas --

95
00:08:41,500 --> 00:08:42,880
Ah, enough.

96
00:08:43,010 --> 00:08:44,700
We shall see you at supper.

97
00:08:51,290 --> 00:08:53,430
Joseph and his lofty morals.

98
00:08:53,430 --> 00:08:56,270
Floating above the daily grime of public affairs.

99
00:08:56,270 --> 00:08:58,440
Well, words come cheap.

100
00:08:59,030 --> 00:09:01,520
Without actions to test them,

101
00:09:01,530 --> 00:09:03,640
his opinions are fruitless.

102
00:09:17,290 --> 00:09:19,500
Share this feast. We're hungry.

103
00:09:20,360 --> 00:09:21,890
Is it correct the Nazarene alleged

104
00:09:21,890 --> 00:09:23,670
he would rise from death?

105
00:09:23,670 --> 00:09:25,380
One of his many outrageous claims

106
00:09:25,380 --> 00:09:28,190
and crude manipulations of prophecy.

107
00:09:28,640 --> 00:09:31,570
Then ensure he dies swiftly

108
00:09:31,710 --> 00:09:34,790
before he has the chance to perform a final deception.

109
00:09:34,910 --> 00:09:37,310
Before the first star, Caiaphas.

110
00:09:37,460 --> 00:09:38,740
Before the very sight of the rogue

111
00:09:38,740 --> 00:09:41,040
is allowed to pollute our celebrations.

112
00:09:48,320 --> 00:09:49,620
To you Lord, I call.

113
00:09:49,620 --> 00:09:51,090
You are my rock.

114
00:09:51,380 --> 00:09:54,580
Do not turn a deaf ear to me, for if you remain silent,

115
00:09:54,610 --> 00:09:57,310
I shall be like those who go down to the pit.

116
00:09:58,000 --> 00:09:59,860
Hear my cry for mercy.

117
00:10:00,130 --> 00:10:01,660
I call for your help

118
00:10:01,660 --> 00:10:05,460
as I lift my hands to your most holy place.

119
00:10:15,300 --> 00:10:16,610
My God?

120
00:10:20,000 --> 00:10:21,330
My God?

121
00:10:23,840 --> 00:10:26,340
Why have you forsaken me?

122
00:10:43,710 --> 00:10:45,290
Two items, Governor.

123
00:10:45,750 --> 00:10:48,910
A request to expedite the death of the Nazarene

124
00:10:48,910 --> 00:10:50,920
from high priest Caiaphas

125
00:10:51,670 --> 00:10:55,910
And a petition to repossess the Nazarene's body upon death.

126
00:10:57,870 --> 00:10:59,410
Who requests the body?

127
00:10:59,410 --> 00:11:00,680
A Jewish elder

128
00:11:00,680 --> 00:11:03,420
troubled by the Sanhedrin's persecution of the Nazarene.

129
00:11:03,420 --> 00:11:04,310
His name?

130
00:11:04,310 --> 00:11:06,640
Joseph of Arimathea.

131
00:11:10,560 --> 00:11:12,470
Grant each request.

132
00:11:12,850 --> 00:11:14,180
Keeping them at each other's throats

133
00:11:14,180 --> 00:11:17,480
prevents them from wrapping their fingers around ours.

134
00:11:18,760 --> 00:11:21,030
And have Cornelius

135
00:11:22,260 --> 00:11:24,580
put the Nazarene out of his misery.

136
00:11:53,770 --> 00:11:56,090
Are you enjoying the spectacle?

137
00:11:56,090 --> 00:11:57,420
Spectacle?

138
00:11:57,660 --> 00:12:00,540
Is that how you regard the crucifixion of the Nazarene?

139
00:12:01,060 --> 00:12:04,780
Any man who claims to be king in a Roman province

140
00:12:05,020 --> 00:12:06,750
is committing treason

141
00:12:07,110 --> 00:12:08,850
and must suffer the consequences.

142
00:12:08,850 --> 00:12:11,790
He does not behave as a king in my dreams.

143
00:12:12,030 --> 00:12:15,370
The running of the province can hardly be determined

144
00:12:15,370 --> 00:12:17,730
by the dreams of the governor's wife.

145
00:12:18,120 --> 00:12:20,430
The gods find us in our sleep.

146
00:12:20,820 --> 00:12:22,670
Their message was clear.

147
00:12:22,780 --> 00:12:24,680
The Nazarene is a good man.

148
00:12:25,440 --> 00:12:27,720
Humble. Pure of heart.

149
00:12:27,870 --> 00:12:32,070
The man was a danger to the status quo.

150
00:12:34,400 --> 00:12:37,920
Our garrison in judea is not large, Claudia.

151
00:12:38,100 --> 00:12:40,760
You'll live to regret your hand in his death.

152
00:12:40,820 --> 00:12:42,190
I took advice.

153
00:12:42,580 --> 00:12:43,510
I weighed it up.

154
00:12:43,510 --> 00:12:45,140
I acted accordingly.

155
00:12:45,140 --> 00:12:46,050
Advice from men

156
00:12:46,050 --> 00:12:48,490
who feared his popularity would eclipse their own.

157
00:12:48,490 --> 00:12:50,940
He claimed to be their messiah.

158
00:12:50,940 --> 00:12:51,950
It was intolerable.

159
00:12:51,950 --> 00:12:53,310
At worst, he's mad!

160
00:12:53,310 --> 00:12:55,010
Is that reason enough --

161
00:12:56,810 --> 00:12:57,910
Claudia.

162
00:12:59,200 --> 00:13:01,950
It's tiresome enough

163
00:13:01,950 --> 00:13:05,350
having every jewish priest on my back.

164
00:13:05,350 --> 00:13:07,440
I don't expect my own wife to join them,

165
00:13:07,440 --> 00:13:09,630
and, yes, even if he were mad,

166
00:13:09,630 --> 00:13:12,610
we should nail him up to destroy the messenger

167
00:13:12,610 --> 00:13:15,020
and to warn the people against his message!

168
00:13:18,770 --> 00:13:21,160
Killing him won't be the end of him.

169
00:13:23,110 --> 00:13:25,780
It usually is, my darling.

170
00:13:59,620 --> 00:14:03,310
I-it is...finished.

171
00:15:20,360 --> 00:15:22,040
Save yourselves!

172
00:15:22,040 --> 00:15:23,220
Come with me!

173
00:15:24,380 --> 00:15:25,810
Out of my way!

174
00:15:30,060 --> 00:15:31,180
This way!

175
00:16:19,570 --> 00:16:21,000
This is his mother.

176
00:16:21,070 --> 00:16:22,090
So?

177
00:16:22,090 --> 00:16:24,840
Spare her this. You can see he's dead.

178
00:16:24,840 --> 00:16:26,480
I'll be the judge of that.

179
00:16:27,190 --> 00:16:29,750
There's no need for this.

180
00:16:32,040 --> 00:16:33,460
Please.

181
00:16:34,120 --> 00:16:35,710
The order is to make sure.

182
00:16:46,880 --> 00:16:48,500
Identify yourself.

183
00:16:49,320 --> 00:16:50,580
I have permission to take possession

184
00:16:50,580 --> 00:16:51,780
of the nazarene's body.

185
00:16:51,780 --> 00:16:52,780
On whose authority?

186
00:16:52,790 --> 00:16:54,010
The governor's.

187
00:16:56,470 --> 00:16:57,770
If you will allow,

188
00:16:58,040 --> 00:16:59,500
I would like to offer my own tomb

189
00:16:59,500 --> 00:17:01,670
as your son's final place of rest.

190
00:17:03,340 --> 00:17:04,800
He'll be at peace there.

191
00:17:18,680 --> 00:17:20,920
I've done the most terrible thing...

192
00:17:21,680 --> 00:17:24,350
for which there can be no forgiveness.

193
00:17:27,660 --> 00:17:30,550
I've betrayed innocent blood!

194
00:18:56,790 --> 00:18:58,120
She's exhausted.

195
00:18:58,700 --> 00:18:59,980
She's waiting.

196
00:19:04,590 --> 00:19:05,650
Does she really believe it,

197
00:19:05,650 --> 00:19:07,920
or is it what her grief wills her to believe?

198
00:19:09,390 --> 00:19:12,040
I think she truly believes he will rise from death.

199
00:19:12,250 --> 00:19:13,380
Do you?

200
00:19:20,600 --> 00:19:24,900
And I'll tell you the rest of the story tomorrow night.

201
00:19:28,950 --> 00:19:30,800
Good night. Come, off to bed.

202
00:19:31,020 --> 00:19:32,210
Good night.

203
00:19:34,170 --> 00:19:35,320
Good night.

204
00:19:40,820 --> 00:19:42,240
Drink something.

205
00:19:44,280 --> 00:19:46,930
In my lifetime, I could never have imagined

206
00:19:46,930 --> 00:19:49,460
such an assault on the house of God.

207
00:19:52,280 --> 00:19:53,870
My heart breaks.

208
00:19:54,560 --> 00:19:56,060
We can restore it.

209
00:19:56,470 --> 00:19:58,230
It was not of your making.

210
00:19:59,160 --> 00:20:01,740
Miraculous that no one was killed.

211
00:20:06,830 --> 00:20:08,250
We thought you weren't coming.

212
00:20:08,250 --> 00:20:09,230
Apologies.

213
00:20:09,230 --> 00:20:10,670
Come in. Come in.

214
00:20:10,670 --> 00:20:12,550
We were waylaid.

215
00:20:12,550 --> 00:20:13,620
Why?

216
00:20:14,360 --> 00:20:16,640
I was laying a poor soul to rest.

217
00:20:17,480 --> 00:20:18,760
A relative?

218
00:20:19,460 --> 00:20:21,180
The crucified Nazarene.

219
00:20:21,250 --> 00:20:22,530
I beg your pardon?

220
00:20:22,530 --> 00:20:24,670
He deserved greater respect in death

221
00:20:24,670 --> 00:20:26,730
than he'd ever been afforded in life.

222
00:20:26,840 --> 00:20:30,500
Because his followers named him Rabbi, Joseph,

223
00:20:30,510 --> 00:20:31,740
doesn't mean he was one.

224
00:20:31,740 --> 00:20:32,960
The Nazarene gave succor

225
00:20:32,960 --> 00:20:36,040
to those would take up arms against Rome.

226
00:20:36,640 --> 00:20:38,040
Which would have been a disaster,

227
00:20:38,050 --> 00:20:40,600
prompting Rome to unleash reinforcements

228
00:20:40,600 --> 00:20:43,560
that would turn the Mediterranean red with Jewish blood.

229
00:20:43,560 --> 00:20:45,870
I don't agree he posed the threat you believe.

230
00:20:45,870 --> 00:20:48,390
Which is why you will never become the High Priest.

231
00:20:48,780 --> 00:20:52,840
The Jewish people have survived the tyranny of many empires

232
00:20:52,840 --> 00:20:55,660
with pragmatism and compromise.

233
00:20:56,730 --> 00:20:58,680
With careful helmsmanship,

234
00:20:58,680 --> 00:21:00,630
it will outlast the Roman occupation.

235
00:21:00,630 --> 00:21:03,410
Not by asking Rome to crucify Jews, it won't.

236
00:21:06,750 --> 00:21:08,110
In my tomb.

237
00:21:09,500 --> 00:21:11,000
"And he made his grave with the wicked

238
00:21:11,000 --> 00:21:12,480
and his tomb with the rich."

239
00:21:12,480 --> 00:21:14,770
You are familiar with Isaiah's prophecy?

240
00:21:14,800 --> 00:21:17,180
I wasn't compelled by prophecy, but decency.

241
00:21:17,180 --> 00:21:18,670
I find this hard to believe.

242
00:21:19,010 --> 00:21:20,340
At the very hour we sought

243
00:21:20,340 --> 00:21:22,830
to extinguish this dangerous flame,

244
00:21:22,830 --> 00:21:26,490
you take it upon yourself to re-ignite it!

245
00:21:26,490 --> 00:21:27,700
I had no intention other than

246
00:21:27,700 --> 00:21:30,730
to bring this sordid episode to a dignified conclusion.

247
00:21:30,730 --> 00:21:32,010
But to the weak of mind,

248
00:21:32,010 --> 00:21:35,690
you create the appearance of fulfilling Isaiah!

249
00:21:36,100 --> 00:21:38,120
Do you not understand the issue here?

250
00:21:38,320 --> 00:21:40,740
What precisely was his crime?

251
00:21:41,260 --> 00:21:43,650
To preach that we should treat each other

252
00:21:43,830 --> 00:21:45,850
as we ourselves would wish to be treated?

253
00:21:45,850 --> 00:21:47,870
He was killed for the repeated blasphemy

254
00:21:47,870 --> 00:21:49,780
of claiming to be the messiah.

255
00:21:49,780 --> 00:21:52,310
- And if he was? - Then he is no more.

256
00:21:52,330 --> 00:21:54,830
Rome holds Judea loose in its hand

257
00:21:54,830 --> 00:21:58,140
only as long as the Sanhedrin is able to manage its people.

258
00:21:58,390 --> 00:22:01,330
In addition to peace and love,

259
00:22:01,350 --> 00:22:03,520
the Nazarene preached insurrection

260
00:22:03,520 --> 00:22:05,500
against all authority.

261
00:22:05,510 --> 00:22:06,560
I disagree.

262
00:22:07,600 --> 00:22:09,220
Such arrogance!

263
00:22:16,850 --> 00:22:19,640
But you will see, Joseph.

264
00:22:21,440 --> 00:22:24,630
You have my word, in or out of your tomb,

265
00:22:24,640 --> 00:22:26,410
the Nazarene's doctrine

266
00:22:26,410 --> 00:22:30,160
will decompose with his corpse.

267
00:22:40,940 --> 00:22:41,870
Peter!

268
00:22:48,710 --> 00:22:49,900
What happened to you?

269
00:22:53,320 --> 00:22:54,780
I was recognized.

270
00:22:56,580 --> 00:22:58,210
I managed to get away.

271
00:23:03,460 --> 00:23:04,520
The others are here?

272
00:23:04,520 --> 00:23:07,940
No. Mary is convinced the authorities will be hunting us down.

273
00:23:07,940 --> 00:23:09,460
You should leave immediately.

274
00:23:09,460 --> 00:23:10,580
Without them? No.

275
00:23:12,250 --> 00:23:13,820
Where were you, Peter?

276
00:23:21,300 --> 00:23:22,620
Is he dead?

277
00:23:24,000 --> 00:23:26,000
I laid him to rest myself.

278
00:23:40,530 --> 00:23:41,830
Then it's over.

279
00:23:50,230 --> 00:23:54,280
Jesus foretold that Judas would betray him to the Sanhedrin.

280
00:23:56,060 --> 00:23:57,170
And he did.

281
00:23:59,550 --> 00:24:03,430
He also foretold that you would deny him.

282
00:24:05,470 --> 00:24:06,870
Tell us you didn't.

283
00:24:09,640 --> 00:24:11,290
I can't lie.

284
00:24:12,420 --> 00:24:13,950
There was a trial.

285
00:24:16,140 --> 00:24:19,380
The mob was baying for his blood, and...

286
00:24:21,410 --> 00:24:22,910
I was recognized.

287
00:24:29,550 --> 00:24:33,740
What difference does any of this now make if he's dead?

288
00:24:35,070 --> 00:24:39,940
The last three years of our lives for nothing.

289
00:24:40,300 --> 00:24:43,710
His mother believes he will rise.

290
00:24:43,800 --> 00:24:48,040
I would give this arm to believe the same!

291
00:24:49,380 --> 00:24:51,480
I never had you for a coward.

292
00:24:53,680 --> 00:24:54,710
Never.

293
00:25:12,480 --> 00:25:13,950
Back! Back up!

294
00:25:26,310 --> 00:25:27,440
Send him away.

295
00:25:40,690 --> 00:25:42,120
Drusus.

296
00:25:54,900 --> 00:25:55,910
Governor.

297
00:25:56,050 --> 00:25:57,700
The High Priest of the temple.

298
00:25:57,700 --> 00:25:59,220
Can't it wait until after I've eaten?

299
00:25:59,220 --> 00:25:59,970
No, I'm afraid it can't.

300
00:25:59,970 --> 00:26:01,690
This is a matter of some urgency.

301
00:26:01,690 --> 00:26:02,920
"Urgent" appears to be

302
00:26:02,920 --> 00:26:05,050
your default state of mind, Caiaphas.

303
00:26:05,050 --> 00:26:06,740
We live in turbulent times, Governor.

304
00:26:06,740 --> 00:26:07,950
I have a request.

305
00:26:07,950 --> 00:26:08,890
Another one?

306
00:26:08,890 --> 00:26:11,850
Please tell me it doesn't concern the Nazarene.

307
00:26:11,850 --> 00:26:13,800
I'm certainly grateful for the decisive manner

308
00:26:13,800 --> 00:26:15,840
in which you've acted on our behalf so far.

309
00:26:15,840 --> 00:26:16,860
"So far"?

310
00:26:17,790 --> 00:26:19,470
You seek more from me on this.

311
00:26:19,470 --> 00:26:20,560
I'm afraid so.

312
00:26:20,840 --> 00:26:24,470
You wanted him crucified, I had him crucified.

313
00:26:25,550 --> 00:26:27,060
What more is necessary?

314
00:26:27,990 --> 00:26:30,000
What is it about this nobody

315
00:26:30,000 --> 00:26:32,130
that so disturbs you?

316
00:26:32,240 --> 00:26:34,490
As you know, his corpse has been placed

317
00:26:34,490 --> 00:26:35,960
in the tomb of an elder.

318
00:26:35,960 --> 00:26:37,600
What do you mean, "as you know"?

319
00:26:37,770 --> 00:26:38,960
Is this true?

320
00:26:39,010 --> 00:26:40,540
A petition was made.

321
00:26:41,280 --> 00:26:43,550
You must have known the friction it would cause.

322
00:26:43,750 --> 00:26:45,460
It never crossed my mind.

323
00:26:46,270 --> 00:26:48,010
In keeping with his practice,

324
00:26:48,010 --> 00:26:50,390
the Nazarene distorted ancient prophecies

325
00:26:50,390 --> 00:26:52,110
relating to the rise of our Messiah

326
00:26:52,120 --> 00:26:55,840
and spread rumor that he would rise from his own death

327
00:26:55,840 --> 00:26:57,210
after three days.

328
00:26:57,210 --> 00:26:59,970
Roman crucifixion really doesn't allow for that, Caiaphas.

329
00:26:59,970 --> 00:27:02,690
Nevertheless, by allowing his body to be entombed

330
00:27:02,690 --> 00:27:04,390
and not consumed by wild beasts,

331
00:27:04,390 --> 00:27:06,700
you've granted an opportunity to his followers

332
00:27:06,700 --> 00:27:09,120
to enact the appearance of resurrection.

333
00:27:10,410 --> 00:27:12,490
And as we know, in Jerusalem, the appearance of a thing

334
00:27:12,490 --> 00:27:14,910
is often as potent as the thing itself.

335
00:27:16,930 --> 00:27:20,430
You believe they will raid the tomb after three days?

336
00:27:20,430 --> 00:27:23,220
It'd be the simplest way to manipulate events.

337
00:27:23,220 --> 00:27:24,880
Then ensure it isn't removed.

338
00:27:24,890 --> 00:27:26,660
Post temple guards outside.

339
00:27:26,660 --> 00:27:28,950
I fear my men would pose no deterrent

340
00:27:28,950 --> 00:27:30,440
to a band of fanatics.

341
00:27:30,450 --> 00:27:34,530
You want me to waste Roman soldiers

342
00:27:34,840 --> 00:27:36,780
guarding a Jewish hole?

343
00:27:36,780 --> 00:27:38,970
And place a Roman seal across the tomb.

344
00:27:38,970 --> 00:27:41,550
Its unlawful breaking carries the death penalty.

345
00:27:41,550 --> 00:27:43,140
You ask too much.

346
00:27:43,190 --> 00:27:45,210
Had you not granted permission to entomb him,

347
00:27:45,210 --> 00:27:47,290
this situation would not have arisen.

348
00:27:47,390 --> 00:27:49,910
Where he lies, he currently remains a threat

349
00:27:49,910 --> 00:27:52,580
both to the Sanhedrin and to Rome.

350
00:27:52,630 --> 00:27:53,960
One man?

351
00:27:57,480 --> 00:28:01,540
You underestimate the might of your Roman overlords.

352
00:28:04,890 --> 00:28:08,680
But if it will finally bring an end to this,

353
00:28:08,920 --> 00:28:13,030
I will post a small guard outside the tomb.

354
00:28:13,030 --> 00:28:14,700
I cannot thank you enough.

355
00:28:14,990 --> 00:28:17,270
At last, something we can agree upon.

356
00:28:25,730 --> 00:28:27,150
Why didn't you tell me?

357
00:28:27,480 --> 00:28:29,140
I don't have to account for my decisions

358
00:28:29,140 --> 00:28:30,710
to you or anyone else.

359
00:28:45,770 --> 00:28:46,750
Don't look now, Matthew,

360
00:28:46,760 --> 00:28:48,710
but I think we may have been spotted.

361
00:28:48,770 --> 00:28:50,100
Do you want to go back?

362
00:28:50,550 --> 00:28:52,080
If we do, we confirm their suspicions.

363
00:28:52,080 --> 00:28:53,210
Just keep moving forward.

364
00:28:53,210 --> 00:28:54,260
Hey! You!

365
00:28:54,870 --> 00:28:55,710
Run!

366
00:29:08,050 --> 00:29:09,870
Shout out and you're dead, understood?

367
00:29:10,720 --> 00:29:13,080
This way! Keep looking!

368
00:29:17,200 --> 00:29:18,980
Why were you running from the Romans?

369
00:29:20,670 --> 00:29:22,610
You have one chance to speak the truth

370
00:29:22,610 --> 00:29:24,280
before we leave your corpses here.

371
00:29:24,940 --> 00:29:27,560
We're disciples of Jesus of Nazareth.

372
00:29:28,750 --> 00:29:29,590
Go on.

373
00:29:29,590 --> 00:29:31,550
We fled the city after he was captured.

374
00:29:31,550 --> 00:29:33,440
Then why come back to where there are more roman soldiers

375
00:29:33,450 --> 00:29:35,030
than anywhere else in Judea?

376
00:29:35,570 --> 00:29:37,220
To find our brothers.

377
00:29:44,510 --> 00:29:46,210
Well, he bled like a man.

378
00:29:57,150 --> 00:29:58,340
Remove it.

379
00:29:58,950 --> 00:30:00,410
But break it up.

380
00:30:05,180 --> 00:30:07,010
I recognize this man.

381
00:30:07,920 --> 00:30:09,130
Boaz.

382
00:30:09,130 --> 00:30:10,820
You know this Zealot?

383
00:30:12,490 --> 00:30:15,440
We played together in Galilee as children.

384
00:30:16,290 --> 00:30:18,040
An age away, Peter.

385
00:30:19,230 --> 00:30:21,030
The times reshape us all.

386
00:30:22,190 --> 00:30:23,210
They do.

387
00:30:23,580 --> 00:30:25,700
You are disciples of the Nazarene?

388
00:30:28,610 --> 00:30:29,720
We are.

389
00:30:30,030 --> 00:30:32,720
Your leader had a great following on the streets.

390
00:30:33,500 --> 00:30:36,320
The authorities colluded and murdered him.

391
00:30:37,300 --> 00:30:39,700
Join us and become a real force

392
00:30:39,700 --> 00:30:41,080
to be reckoned with.

393
00:30:41,520 --> 00:30:43,470
Fighting the Romans?

394
00:30:43,790 --> 00:30:46,440
Whatever it takes to drive them off our land.

395
00:30:46,510 --> 00:30:49,000
Live by the sword, and you die by the sword.

396
00:30:49,230 --> 00:30:51,900
Better that than like a dog on a leash.

397
00:30:53,460 --> 00:30:55,260
Your master preached love.

398
00:30:55,730 --> 00:30:57,880
I shall die preaching freedom.

399
00:30:58,390 --> 00:30:59,600
Join us!

400
00:31:11,390 --> 00:31:15,740
We are fishermen, not fighters.

401
00:31:17,480 --> 00:31:19,260
They won't stop with him.

402
00:31:19,710 --> 00:31:20,910
You do know that?

403
00:31:22,040 --> 00:31:23,210
Once the Romans realize

404
00:31:23,210 --> 00:31:25,280
your message remains a threat,

405
00:31:25,280 --> 00:31:27,110
they will root you out.

406
00:31:27,550 --> 00:31:29,460
And when they've killed each of you,

407
00:31:29,880 --> 00:31:32,460
they will snuff out his ideas one by one

408
00:31:32,750 --> 00:31:35,800
until it will be as if you never existed.

409
00:31:36,740 --> 00:31:38,020
Join us.

410
00:31:38,190 --> 00:31:39,440
I cannot.

411
00:31:47,600 --> 00:31:49,280
What are we waiting for?

412
00:31:50,660 --> 00:31:52,830
The means by which I intend to put an end

413
00:31:52,830 --> 00:31:56,150
to your incessant mewling about this Jesus.

414
00:31:56,150 --> 00:31:58,240
Am I not entitled to an opinion?

415
00:31:58,380 --> 00:31:59,370
You are.

416
00:31:59,370 --> 00:32:01,850
But obsession is not opinion, Claudia,

417
00:32:01,850 --> 00:32:04,980
and unhealthy obsession requires radical treatment,

418
00:32:04,980 --> 00:32:07,470
which I believe is arriving now.

419
00:32:12,420 --> 00:32:15,750
Cornelius, I have a certain matter

420
00:32:15,750 --> 00:32:17,890
only you can clear up.

421
00:32:17,900 --> 00:32:19,250
If I can, of course.

422
00:32:20,150 --> 00:32:22,440
I need to know one thing from you.

423
00:32:22,500 --> 00:32:26,030
When he was placed inside his tomb,

424
00:32:27,080 --> 00:32:28,710
are you certain

425
00:32:28,920 --> 00:32:32,000
the Nazarene was dead?

426
00:32:32,270 --> 00:32:35,370
Sir, when I'm instructed to do a job, I do it.

427
00:32:35,890 --> 00:32:37,030
I was instructed to ensure

428
00:32:37,030 --> 00:32:38,450
the death of the Nazarene on the cross,

429
00:32:38,450 --> 00:32:39,430
And that's what I did.

430
00:32:39,440 --> 00:32:41,260
He expired before you?

431
00:32:41,440 --> 00:32:42,650
Better than that.

432
00:32:43,700 --> 00:32:45,500
He expired because of me.

433
00:32:45,660 --> 00:32:47,570
And you performed the proofs of death?

434
00:32:47,880 --> 00:32:50,000
I instructed Longinus to insert his spear

435
00:32:50,000 --> 00:32:51,760
hard between the Nazarene's ribs.

436
00:32:51,760 --> 00:32:52,700
And he was dead?

437
00:32:52,700 --> 00:32:54,350
Before and after the spear.

438
00:32:55,110 --> 00:32:57,170
So, to anyone who might entertain

439
00:32:57,170 --> 00:33:00,160
the notion that he might not be dead,

440
00:33:00,160 --> 00:33:04,030
that the Nazarene might actually somehow have remained alive

441
00:33:04,040 --> 00:33:06,590
after all of what you've just described,

442
00:33:06,620 --> 00:33:08,380
you would say what?

443
00:33:08,380 --> 00:33:10,880
I would say they were either mad or a fool.

444
00:33:12,920 --> 00:33:13,970
Thank you, Cornelius.

445
00:33:13,970 --> 00:33:15,060
You may go.

446
00:33:23,880 --> 00:33:27,120
Enough of your dreams and nonsense, Claudia.

447
00:33:27,450 --> 00:33:30,780
The Nazarene was only ever flesh and blood.

448
00:33:31,320 --> 00:33:33,160
And we have butchered the former

449
00:33:33,800 --> 00:33:37,870
and spilled the latter all over the city.

450
00:33:38,410 --> 00:33:41,300
But if you should dream of him again,

451
00:33:41,650 --> 00:33:43,720
be sure he proves his true identity

452
00:33:43,720 --> 00:33:45,990
by his real incarnation.

453
00:33:47,500 --> 00:33:50,250
Not as a handsome prophet with charisma,

454
00:33:51,760 --> 00:33:56,110
but as a rotting pile of meat on the floor.

455
00:34:06,600 --> 00:34:07,490
I'm just questioning

456
00:34:07,490 --> 00:34:10,000
whether leaving Jerusalem at this moment in time

457
00:34:10,000 --> 00:34:11,160
is the right course of action.

458
00:34:11,160 --> 00:34:13,060
How can saving our lives

459
00:34:13,060 --> 00:34:15,420
not be the right course of action?!

460
00:34:15,430 --> 00:34:17,560
There's no guarantee we'll make it to the city wall.

461
00:34:17,560 --> 00:34:19,740
But there's no guarantee they're actually coming after us.

462
00:34:19,740 --> 00:34:22,920
The High Priest walks hand-in-hand with Pilate!

463
00:34:22,920 --> 00:34:24,160
They killed our leader.

464
00:34:24,160 --> 00:34:26,630
How do we continue to pose a threat to their authority?!

465
00:34:26,630 --> 00:34:31,140
5,000 people on a remote hillside

466
00:34:31,140 --> 00:34:33,030
just to hear him preach...

467
00:34:33,030 --> 00:34:35,040
That was him, not us.

468
00:34:35,200 --> 00:34:38,080
Have you forgotten his prophecy already?

469
00:34:40,030 --> 00:34:42,250
Have you forgotten, Peter?

470
00:34:45,620 --> 00:34:47,310
On the third day,

471
00:34:47,460 --> 00:34:50,530
he promises to rise from death.

472
00:34:55,150 --> 00:34:56,780
You need to rest.

473
00:34:59,670 --> 00:35:02,000
Have they forgotten so quickly?

474
00:35:04,480 --> 00:35:06,080
Can they not wait?

475
00:35:07,470 --> 00:35:09,530
Can you not wait?!

476
00:35:15,230 --> 00:35:17,900
She watched him being tortured and killed,

477
00:35:18,030 --> 00:35:19,780
moment by moment.

478
00:35:19,800 --> 00:35:21,250
He's dead.

479
00:35:21,640 --> 00:35:23,410
But we are not.

480
00:35:23,640 --> 00:35:25,280
Our flesh and blood waits up north

481
00:35:25,280 --> 00:35:27,490
in Galilee for our return.

482
00:35:27,880 --> 00:35:30,130
Our duty now is to our families.

483
00:35:31,610 --> 00:35:32,790
Three days.

484
00:35:36,230 --> 00:35:37,750
I owe him that much.

485
00:35:39,550 --> 00:35:41,250
Our faith in him

486
00:35:42,480 --> 00:35:44,470
has to be worth three days.

487
00:35:44,660 --> 00:35:47,090
And if he fails to rise on the third?

488
00:35:47,090 --> 00:35:48,790
Then we leave like men.

489
00:35:50,750 --> 00:35:52,160
Not cowards.

490
00:36:03,340 --> 00:36:05,090
You think he's coming back.

491
00:36:06,900 --> 00:36:08,320
I know he is.

492
00:36:09,670 --> 00:36:11,360
How are you so sure?

493
00:36:12,690 --> 00:36:14,570
He raised others from death.

494
00:36:16,670 --> 00:36:18,700
This is what was prophesized.

495
00:36:18,710 --> 00:36:20,170
And he promised.

496
00:36:22,350 --> 00:36:24,310
Then why not himself?

497
00:36:30,800 --> 00:36:32,620
High Priest.

498
00:36:32,750 --> 00:36:35,890
I want you to post temple guards at Arimathea's tomb.

499
00:36:35,890 --> 00:36:38,100
It must remain sealed.

500
00:36:38,100 --> 00:36:39,100
They speak to no one,

501
00:36:39,100 --> 00:36:40,200
they let no one pass,

502
00:36:40,200 --> 00:36:41,590
and they report only to me.

503
00:36:41,590 --> 00:36:43,190
Iscariot's been found.

504
00:36:43,190 --> 00:36:44,420
The betrayer?

505
00:36:45,790 --> 00:36:47,510
Well, will he lead us to the others?

506
00:36:47,510 --> 00:36:49,570
He lies dead in the potter's field.

507
00:36:49,570 --> 00:36:51,050
He hanged himself.

508
00:36:53,190 --> 00:36:55,020
What is it about this Jesus

509
00:36:55,980 --> 00:36:58,140
that drives them to such madness?

510
00:36:58,140 --> 00:36:59,470
What does it matter?

511
00:36:59,470 --> 00:37:00,280
Without his body,

512
00:37:00,280 --> 00:37:02,380
they can't pretend he's risen from death.

513
00:37:29,100 --> 00:37:30,650
You were with him at the end?

514
00:37:31,680 --> 00:37:33,020
Only John.

515
00:37:37,400 --> 00:37:39,690
The romans turned his death

516
00:37:39,700 --> 00:37:41,410
into an atrocious spectacle.

517
00:37:44,090 --> 00:37:48,550
They flayed him until his back split open.

518
00:37:49,930 --> 00:37:51,010
It was as if they wanted to

519
00:37:51,010 --> 00:37:53,490
cut him down one piece at a time

520
00:37:54,130 --> 00:37:55,810
Until he could barely move.

521
00:37:58,060 --> 00:37:59,700
They forced him to his feet

522
00:38:00,180 --> 00:38:02,010
and drove thorns into his head.

523
00:38:03,130 --> 00:38:04,280
They made him...

524
00:38:06,180 --> 00:38:09,230
drag his cross to Golgotha,

525
00:38:10,770 --> 00:38:12,540
where they nailed him to it...

526
00:38:14,050 --> 00:38:15,990
and raised him up for all to see.

527
00:38:21,770 --> 00:38:23,690
It doesn't matter that you weren't there.

528
00:38:24,560 --> 00:38:26,520
He understood our weakness.

529
00:38:27,120 --> 00:38:28,720
He loved us for it.

530
00:38:29,070 --> 00:38:30,330
Died for it.

531
00:38:31,570 --> 00:38:33,900
None of this matters now.

532
00:38:34,580 --> 00:38:36,040
You heard the Zealot.

533
00:38:36,040 --> 00:38:38,940
We need to leave before they find us.

534
00:38:41,250 --> 00:38:44,160
Before it's our turn to look down from golgotha.

535
00:38:51,360 --> 00:38:52,860
You need to rest.

536
00:38:54,470 --> 00:38:56,590
It's been a stressful period.

537
00:38:57,450 --> 00:38:58,880
You've done exceptionally well

538
00:38:58,880 --> 00:39:01,240
to steer the community to calmer waters.

539
00:39:02,160 --> 00:39:04,940
With your support, as ever.

540
00:39:05,630 --> 00:39:08,730
You've used Pilate to great effect to protect us.

541
00:39:11,950 --> 00:39:13,280
Come to bed.

542
00:39:15,120 --> 00:39:16,320
I won't be long.

543
00:39:25,240 --> 00:39:27,460
The charge is blasphemy.

544
00:39:28,490 --> 00:39:31,180
He deserves to die!

545
00:39:41,670 --> 00:39:42,680
Truth?

546
00:39:44,430 --> 00:39:45,660
What is truth?

547
00:39:49,110 --> 00:39:50,860
I don't know him!

548
00:39:51,250 --> 00:39:52,940
You're mistaken!

549
00:39:53,270 --> 00:39:56,230
I've never seen him before!

550
00:41:40,540 --> 00:41:42,580
Roman's seal has been broken.

551
00:41:42,580 --> 00:41:43,860
The tomb is now open,

552
00:41:43,860 --> 00:41:47,020
and that should mean, he's gone.

553
00:41:48,120 --> 00:41:49,920
What do you mean, "gone"?

