Come on, Harry. Come on, honey.
For over three years now,
I have run...
this office.
I make...
fifty-five...
dollars...
a month...
Which is not enough to keep a boy alive.
Good morning, Miss Waller. Just a moment.
I am hoping...
you had a chance...
to look into...
a transfer...
for...
As we've discussed all these
months since I took this job.
I swear, Henry. Why is it
you're always up in that tree?
I'm looking for Tojo. Have you seen him?
No, I certainly ain't seen Tojo.
Hey, wait a minute.
Damn, boy. Watch that
fool thing, will ya?
Here's what they look like.
Why don't you plant a
garden or somethin'?
No, sir. I'm not getting
an answer on that line.
Would you like me
to place the call again later?
You oughta keep them two boys
of yours in the backyard.
We can't have them bothering
everybody that walks up here.
Good morning, Mr. Rigby.
Bad for business.
Henry settin' up in that tree all day!
He looks like a damn idiot!
Well, if looks were gold, you wouldn't
exactly be a rich man yourself,
would you, Mr. Rigby?
These the receipts? Yes, sir.
Mama. Would you like a cup of coffee?
Mama. No, thank you.
Mama. Honey, I'm at work now.
Mr. Rigby, you know my situation.
I'm a divorced woman... A
war is going on, Nita.
Nobody's on easy street.
Yes, sir. I know that.
But I've got two fine young
boys to think about.
Harold Allen and... William Henry!
Henry's gonna be
in the first grade this year.
Harry's gonna be... Yes, sir. I know that!
Well, what I was wondering is...
have you had any luck
on that transfer for me?
I'm workin' on it.
Yes, sir.
Well, how you doin' on it?
Something'll turn up.
I don't see where Clarence
Miller paid this month.
He paid. It's there.
Yeah. Here it is.
If it was a snake, it woulda
jumped up and bit ya.
The transfer, Mr. Rigby, remember?
We talked about something
secretarial with regular hours?
This is me typin', Mr. Rigby.
Look, Herman Calloway's late again.
You tell him if he can't pay on time,
we'll just have to disconnect him.
Mr. Rigby, I'm sure I could get another
job somewhere else if you'd ju...
I'm sorry, Nita, but you're frozen here.
Yes, sir.
But they might just change my
status if you'd recommend it.
Mr. Rigby.
I'd really like to situate
myself in a better situation.
The way things are now, I hardly get a
chance to kiss my boys good night without...
Number, please.
One moment. I'll connect you.
Mr. Rigby?
Pool shooters and domino players.
And beer drinkers!
Hey, Arnold, look. There's
her two little boys again.
Hey! You boys, what are you lookin' at?
Hey, hang on there. Where're
y'all goin' so fast?
Home. Home? Home to Mama?
That ain't no bad deal.
Why ain't y'all off fighting the war?
You're a real little smart
aleck, you know that?
I don't like him, Calvin.
Come on, Henry. We've gotta go.
Hey. Y'all don't want an
Orange Crush or somethin'?
I'll take me an Orange Crush.
You're gonna have to win it.
We ain't gonna just give it to you.
Come on, Henry. They're just teasing you.
What do I have to do?
Set down there with your
legs around this puddle.
We'll show you.
It's an old Indian game, ain't it, Cal?
Yep. I learned it from an Indian chief.
Now, here's the bet.
I bet Arnold there can wipe up that
puddle before you can stab his hand.
Henry, let's go. You
just hold your horses.
Okay, you ready? We got a
Orange Crush on the line here.
- I don't wanna hurt him.
- You're not gonna hurt him.
No, he likes it.
Yeah, I like it. Makes my hand feel good.
Looky here! This boy wet his britches!
I hope old Tojo gets you!
You better git, you little monkey,
before I take a mind
to paddle your behind.
You and your brother both!
Loony old raggedy man son of a bitch.
Where you been? Out back, takin' a leak.
I'm about ready to ask her out.
Ain't you?
Tonight? Yeah, tonight. What the hell?
We can't put it off forever.
I don't know.
Well, what are you afraid of?
Every time, you back off.
She won't go. Ain't no need to ask her.
How you know that? Hell,
you don't even know her!
I don't care.
She ain't goin' out with us.
Nobody else, neither.
She keepin' herself special.
Arnold.
You remember how we
used to get to itchin'...
when they had us in them tight
little cells in Huntsville?
Same thing happens to a woman. Especially
one that's already been married.
Know what I'm sayin'?
She ain't that way.
Arnold, she's just like us.
She ain't got nobody.
You'd like to do her
a favor, wouldn't you?
Arnold, how's it gonna look, both of
us goin' up there to ask her out?
Well, it's both of us gonna
be takin' her out, ain't it?
Yeah, but you better
let me do the askin'!
Hell, I can do the askin' as
good as anybody can, by God!
Fine, then, Arnold. Go on
up there and do the askin'.
Yes? Mrs. Longley?
Yes. Could I help you? My
name's Calvin Triplett.
General haulin'. Maybe you seen
my truck goin' by sometime.
Do you need to use the phone, Mr.
Triplett?
No. I was just hopin'
to talk to you for a minute.
Yes?
I mean, how ya doin'?
Everything goin' okay?
Just fine.
I was wonderin' if maybe you wouldn't
like to go out with me sometime?
Well, I...
I work most of the time.
I don't get to go out much.
That must get old, all that workin'.
It's all right. There's a war.
Yeah, I know. Everybody gotta
take a break once in a while.
You oughta let me take you out and show
you a good time one of these nights.
I know how it gets, bein'
all cooped up like you are.
I'm sorry. It's nice of
you to offer, though.
Good night. How 'bout if I
brought you a Coke sometime?
We could sit in there and visit.
What would you think about that?
That'd be fine, but this
is a company here.
They don't permit people
comin' in to visit,
you know, unless it's
strictly... strictly business.
- All business in there?
- Yeah.
I mean, we live here,
but it is a business.
I guess I'll just have to think up
some business with you, won't I?
I have to go now,
Mr. Triplett. Good night.
I told you she wasn't that way.
She's gotta work. Ain't
got time to go out.
I'm gonna go up there
and talk to her sometime.
Nothin' else. Just talk a little.
Yes?
I'm sorry to wake you. The man at the gas
station said you had a pay phone here.
Okay.
Phone's over there.
I appreciate it.
I'm sorry. That's okay.
Just give me a minute.
Thank you, ma'am.
Number, please.
Is that you, ma'am?
Sorry, habit.
That's n... That's number 1-8-2.
It's in Ardmore, Oklahoma.
Operator, this is number zero in Gregory.
The number is 1-8-2.
Ardmore, Oklahoma. My party's holding.
It'll be just a minute.
That's gonna be 65 cents for the first
three minutes after they answer.
Yes, ma'am.
It's ringing.
Maybe nobody's home.
They're probably asleep.
Hello, Mr. Quinn?
This is Teddy.
I'm callin' from Texas.
Yes, sir, I sure am fine. How are you?
That's good. I'm glad.
That's real good.
Mr. Quinn, may I speak to Jalene?
I'm hitchhikin' in from Texas.
I got a four-day liberty, and I want
to let her know I'm on the way.
Sir?
Well, why not, Mr. Quinn?
When was that, Mr. Quinn?
Mr. Quinn, you're teasin' me.
No, sir...
No, sir, I guess you wouldn't.
Who to, Mr. Quinn?
Him? Really?
Yeah.
No, no...
No, I'm all right. Just kinda
caught me off guard, I guess.
W-Well, I know Mrs. Quinn
always liked him a lot.
Yes, sir. I know that.
Well, you must be proud.
That guy's got a big
reputation around town.
Yeah.
People say he's the sorriest son
of a bitch in Ardmore, Oklahoma.
All through?
Yeah.
You better hang up.
You're still on long distance.
Thanks.
Sixty-five cents?
Let's see here.
There's twenty-five,
fifty... and sixty-five.
Thank you. Thank you.
I appreciate it.
Would you like a cup of coffee?
Maybe the rain'll
slow down out there in a bit.
Well...
What's a little water
to a sailor, anyway?
Thanks, though.
Sugar? No, I wouldn't want
to take any of your sugar.
That's okay. I don't get the
chance to bake much anyway.
Besides, I have to hide it or
Henry'll eat it by the handfuls.
Henry's your husband. No, one of my boys.
I have two of them. Henry and Harry.
Henry's the little one.
Your, husband's off in the war?
No, I'm divorced.
- Look at me.
- Let me get you another cup.
No, this is just the way I like it.
You just out of boot camp?
I'm gonna be a gunner's mate.
For heaven's sakes.
It'll come back on in a minute.
You there?
Yeah, yeah, I'm right here.
What's a gunner's mate?
That's the guy that passes him the ammo.
Yeah.
Passes who the ammo?
The gunner. Yeah.
When are you shipping out?
I got three more days.
You know where you're going?
No.
I guess I'll find out
when I get there, though.
They don't tell us much.
- Do you want a Lucky?
- No, thank you.
I'm Teddy Roebuck, Ardmore, Oklahoma.
Nita Longley, Gregory, Texas.
The lights. Yeah.
Well, I'll put your sugar up. Okay.
I appreciate the coffee.
That's all right.
Good luck. Thanks.
Look. What's that? I don't know.
Who are you? Put those hands up!
Yeah, look. I don't want any trouble.
I'm just passin' through town.
Hey, you're a sailor. You bet.
You better keep those hands up!
Henry, you can put the gun down now.
He's one of ours.
Thank you. Boys, run get Mrs.
Lester right quick.
It's Washington. Look,
I hope you don't mind.
I laid down... No, that's okay.
Hurry, Jean.
Is it Jim? Jim?
Jean, hurry, they're holding.
Here. Wha...
Operator, your call is ready.
I'll connect you.
I don't know.
Hello?
Yes, it is.
What did you do to her?
Thank you. Thank you!
Her husband's been wounded,
but he's comin' home.
Well, that's just fine.
Why don't you boys walk Jean home, okay?
You ain't leavin', are ya?
Well... You wait right here.
We'll be right back.
All right.
Boy.
You get a little bit of everything
through here, don't you?
Yeah. Seems like it sometimes.
You get a lot of phone calls like that?
Yeah.
He's kinda messed up.
Faster, Mommy, faster.
Shoot. I'm hurryin' as
fast as I can, honey.
Okay.
Okay!
Faster, Teddy, faster!
Hey, Mama. Come on!
Yeah, come on, Mama. No, honey, I can't.
Please? Yeah, please?
Come on.
Please?
Okay.
Here, Nita. Take it. No.
No, take it, take it.
All right, run with it!
Run with it! Come on!
I'm gonna answer that.
Mama!
Mama.
I'm sorry.
What are we gonna do tomorrow, Teddy?
I'm afraid I go back tonight, Harry.
Teddy, don't go. You don't have to go.
Does he, Mama? No, really, now.
I don't wanna wear out my welcome.
You're not gonna wear out your welcome.
Is he, Mama?
Honey, Teddy's got
more important things...
See? She said you could stay.
Didn't you, Mama?
Really, you're welcome
to stay if you want to.
See? Will ya?
Yeah, will ya? Shoot. Come on!
Well, I got a couple
of days of liberty left.
You sure it's all right, Nita? Really?
No, really, it's fine. We'll just make
a pallet for him in the front room.
Hot dog!
Mrs. Longley? Mr. Calloway. How are ya?
I'd be doing better if the end of the
month didn't come around so fast.
Sorry I'm late with this.
Fifteen-twenty, isn't it? Yes, sir.
He owes money.
Fourteen,
50, 75, 15, 10 and 20.
Fifteen-twenty. I'll get your receipt.
Thank you.
Hi.
How ya doin'?
- Just fine. How are you?
- Okay.
This is Teddy. He's stayin' with us.
Well, isn't that nice?
Well... How's the war goin'?
Pretty good.
Sure wished I could be
over there with you boys.
Yes, sir. I wish you could too.
I got a store to run.
Shirts, shoes, whatnot. You
know how confinin' that is.
But someone's gotta keep
that home front goin'.
Yes, sir. We don't necessarily
like it, but we gotta do it.
Yes, sir. We understand that.
Yep. Truth is, don't like it at all.
I'd rather be over there with you boys.
Yes, sir. Well, we know that.
Mr. Calloway, got your receipt. Fine.
Well, you give 'em a good
lickin' for me, okay?
You bet. Nice boy.
Brother? Cousin? No.
Mama, is Teddy gonna be our daddy? Henry.
- Just asking.
- Kids.
Yeah, kids.
That don't look good, that...
That young man in there.
Mr. Calloway, if it's givin' you any
ideas, why don't you call Mrs. Thompson?
She's always glad to hear from
you about this time every day.
Ma'am.
I don't see any spiderwebs.
Better make sure.
It's okay. You go first.
Mama. What, honey?
Is Teddy gonna stay with us?
For a few days he is.
We like him.
I know, honey. I like him too.
Do you, Mama?
Old Tojo ain't gonna
get him, is he, Mama?
No, I don't think so, honey.
Okay, you kids go to sleep.
Hello?
Number, please. That thing
was about to eat me up!
Number, please.
I'm sorry.
Well? What'd I tell ya?
I thought she weren't supposed
to have no visitors over there.
That's the line she give me.
She lied to us. Didn't she, Calvin?
She's a divorced woman, Arnold.
You know about 'em, don't you?
Where the hell you been not to know?
Where you goin'?
Coffee's ready. Can I get you a cup?
I'd love one.
You bet.
You know, today sure has been fun for me.
For the boys too. They're in hog heaven.
Yeah, I know it.
They don't get a chance to play
with much of anybody around here.
Yeah.
I don't mean to pry,
but does their daddy ever come visit?
No, he never has.
That's a shame.
Well, our marriage ended kinda messy.
I guess that's why.
I heard he joined the army
when the war broke out,
but we never heard from him.
I have trouble understandin' that.
Number, please.
Hello, Mr. Calloway.
You don't have to worry about that, Mr.
Calloway.
Well, I don't listen in
to conversations, anyway.
You could have been talkin' about
shoes and socks, for all I know.
And other dirty laundry.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, I do know
it's just your business.
Yes, sir, well...
Well, I'll remember that.
Yes, sir, I will.
And thank you too.
Thank you. You bet.
Listen. What would you think
about me takin' the boys...
over to Corpus Christi
to see a picture show?
Teddy. It's so far.
It's just a few miles.
We can go on the bus.
Well, they'd love it.
Neither one of them's ever
seen a picture show before.
All right.
Any chance of you comin' along with us?
Goodness, no! Come on and go!
Teddy, I just... I couldn't!
Who'd run this? You can get
somebody to run that thing.
Mr. Rigby'd have a fit.
Hey.
John Wayne.
Teddy. I wish I could, though.
*lf you ever go down Trinidad
*They make you feel so very glad *
*Calypso sing and make up rhyme *
*Guarantee you one real good fine time *
*Drinkin' rum and Coca-Cola *
*Go down Point Cumana
*Both mother and daughter *
*Workin' for the Yankee dollar *
*Beat it, mon, beat it *
*Since the Yankee come to Trinidad *
*They got the young girls all goin' mad *
*Young girls say they treat 'em nice *
*Make Trinidad like paradise
*Drinkin' rum and Coca-Cola
*Go down Point Cumana
*Both mother and daughter
*Workin' for the Yankee dollar *
*You vex me, you vex me *
Comin' in low. Hey, hey! Get up! Get up!
Is that what happens?
What the hell...
Start working Selby and Maclntosh as a team.
They're about ready.
Okay, Jim. Don't worry about a thing.
I'll try and take care
of things while you're away.
Okay. And no gin rummy with Brooke!
She's my pigeon.
'Bye, pigeon.
There's no one out there, Mrs. Longley.
Well, there was somebody.
And there was that man kinda
watching the house this afternoon.
What man is that?
He pushes a lawn mower around town.
You mean Bailey? Face all buggered up?
Well, I never saw that.
I think he's all right.
Been around here a couple of
years, mowin' lawns and stuff.
You just had a window peeker.
I wouldn't worry about it.
Wait a minute, Sheriff!
I do worry about it.
I'm in here by myself
with just two little boys.
Well.
It was my understanding that,
you had a young friend over
here... a sailor, I believe.
People do talk, Mrs. Longley.
And what do they say?
Well, they say...
- An experienced woman like yourself is...
- You mean a divorced woman.
A divorced woman like yourself has got no
business with some young boy over here.
It's nobody's business what I do.
This town doesn't own me.
Well, people wondering what kind
of deal you run over here, anyway.
This is a telephone office. They want
to feel like they can depend on you.
There's a war going on, you know.
Well, thank you for coming by,
Sheriff Watson.
Good night. Good night.
Up. Give me your gum.
Those are the cutest little sailor suits.
You shouldn't have done that.
Listen, I was glad to do it.
I brought you something too.
It's for me? Yeah.
What is it? I'm not gonna tell ya.
You gotta open it and see.
Nylons.
Well, they're rayons.
But the lady at the store said they
was just as sheer as nylons, though.
They are! Look how sheer they are.
*lf there's a gleam in her eye *
*Each time she straightens your tie *
*You'll know the lady's in love *
*With you
*...the lady's in love with you *
*And when your friends ask you over *
*To join their table
*But she picks a faraway booth for two *
*Well, sir, here's just how it stands *
*You've got romance on your hands *
*Because the lady's in love *
*With you.
One, two, three, heil Hitler!
Morning, Miss Pud, Miss Beulah!
Boys, stop that. One,
two, three, heil, Hitle!
Did you hear me? Henry! One, two, three,
heil Hitler!
I want y'all to march in the
house right this instant...
and wash those silly
moustaches off your faces.
Heil Hitler! We're just playin', Mama.
They saw it in a newsreel, Nita.
Lord, Teddy. Couldn't
you've just stayed inside?
Why?
Hi. How y'all doin'?
Well, I never!
I'm sorry.
Cripes! Use some sense, walkin'
out in front of them half naked.
I just put my shirt on.
I've gotta live here, Teddy.
And there's already enough talk.
Excuse me. Good morning.
Was a good morning.
Are ya in?
I'll tell you what.
You guys get on home with the
groceries, and I'll go get the mail.
Pick a hand.
Open your mouth.
Okay, see you at home. Okay.
*You're in the navy now
You're not behind the plow *
*Digging a ditch You'll never get
rich You're in the navy now *
Well, now, would you look here, Arnold?
Them damn boys went and joined the navy.
Got 'em tiny little
sailor suits, don't they?
Y'all better get out of the way.
Now, we just tryin' to be friendly.
We figure maybe we owe you
them Orange Crushes...
for that joke we played
on you the other day.
It wasn't funny!
Wasn't funny at all, was it?
Well, come on in here and
let us make it up to you, then.
No, Henry. Let's go. Come on.
Let's have an Orange Crush.
Y'all come on. Ain't often we treat.
Henry, I said no!
You're not the boss of me!
Give us an Orange Crush
for this sailor boy.
He's about to ship out.
How's that drink? All right? Just fine.
How's that mama of yours been doin'?
Just fine. She got her boyfriend
stayin' over there with her?
You mean Teddy?
Come on, Henry.
They been takin' their clothes
off together over there?
Don't fool with these boys. Come on, Henry.
We gotta go.
You ain't goin' nowhere.
You let me go! Let me go! Let me go!
- You want your butt whipped?
- No, he don't.
Teddy!
Goddamn, if it ain't the rest
of the U.S. Navy, Arnold!
Harry, go stand by the door.
Henry, you get down off the bar.
We're talkin' here. Ain't we?
- I'm gonna kick you if you don't move.
- Henry?
You ain't gonna do no
such damn thing. Yeah?
Back off, you boys!
Teddy!
Let go of me! Goddamn it!
Let me go! Teddy! Teddy!
Siguiente van a ser tu sesos.
Agarre tu hermano y vete pronto.
Thank you.
Come on.
Don't, Nita!
Good night nurse, Harry! What were you kids
thinkin' of goin' into a place like that?
I just can't get over it. What
were you thinkin' of, Harry?
Nothin'. Nothin'?
You weren't thinkin' of nothin',
were you? Henry?
I wasn't thinkin'
of nothin', either, Mama.
Well, from now on, I want you kids here!
I do not want you gallivantin'
all over this town!
That's over and done with. I want you
here, or in the yard and nowhere else!
- But, Mama...
- No, sir.
Not one word, Harry. I won't have it!
As old as you are, not showin'
any more sense than a rock.
Nit... Good G... Sorry.
Number, please.
Just scared her. She'll get over it.
Hello, Miss Ola.
No, I'm fine. Can I help you?
Look at these shoes.
How 'bout if you boys were to take these
out on the porch and clean 'em up for me?
Yeah? It's 2:18, Miss Ola.
No, ma'am, I don't believe everything
that comes over the radio, either,
but they're usually
pretty close on the time.
Yes, ma'am. You're welcome.
You kids, do not leave this yard!
Don't be too hard on 'em, Nita.
I can't keep an eye on this
switchboard and them too...
if they're runnin' here,
there and yon all over town.
Yeah, well, you can't lock 'em up, either.
They're just kids.
I know they're kids, Teddy.
They happen to be my kids!
I meant what I said.
And don't you go tellin'
'em anything different.
God, I feel so... so... caught!
Nita.
Hey, you oughta quit this job.
You can get somethin' better.
I can't quit this job. I'm frozen here.
They can't do that. Can they?
They can do whatever
they want in wartime.
Look what they're doin' to you. They're stickin'
you on a ship, you don't even know where to.
Yeah, but I wanna go.
I mean, I'm not afraid
to go. Not anymore.
There's a whole world out there
you don't know anything about.
That's okay with me. I'm not
gonna run and hide from it.
No, I know you're not.
I want you to leave, Teddy.
I still got one more day.
No, I want you to go on and go.
This doesn't work for us.
I can't make it work.
I'm sorry.
Here you go, Teddy.
Whooee! Don't these look snappy!
Thanks.
You know, maybe some rainy night...
and you'll hear a knock at the door,
it'll be me again.
Maybe. Yeah.
I love you, Nita.
Number, please.
Hi, Doc Wood.
Just a minute. Let me
get a piece of paper.
At the Phelps 'til 9:00.
Then to the Higgins.
Where ya goin'? I got a call from a ship.
They want me to come on in.
Do ya have to go? Yeah, I have to.
You don't have to go.
Harry.
Yeah.
You know what I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna name this shoe Henry,
and I'm gonna name this shoe Harry.
Henry and Harry? You bet.
And that way, wherever I go, it'll be
Henry and Harry right there with me.
Okay?
You take care of your mama.
We will.
Good-bye, pigeon.
Henry and Harry. Henry and Harry.
Henry and Harry.
Did you make Teddy leave?
Eat your supper, Harry. And, Henry, eat!
You made him leave, didn't you?
Honey, he was gonna have
to leave tomorrow anyway.
Now let's just eat our supper, okay?
We're not gonna stay around
the house like you said.
You're gonna do what I tell you to
do, young man. I'm your mother!
You're not a mother,
you're a telephone operator.
I know you're upset, Harry, but things...
You made Daddy leave too!
Don't talk to me in that tone of voice!
Now eat your supper! Both of you!
We don't wanna live here anymore.
I don't wanna live here, either, Mama.
We wanna go live with our daddy.
Well, whatever gave you
the idea he wants y'all?
Did he write you a letter or somethin'?
I don't hear him knockin' at the door.
He wants me and Henry.
He just don't want you.
We'll just give it to the chickens.
Now go to bed, both of you!
Right this instant!
Come on, Henry.
Mr. Rigby?
Yes, sir, I do know it's late.
Hey, watch out there, kids!
What do you think you're doin'?
Come in, Mr. Rigby.
Now, what is it that's so important...
I had to come all the way over here?
We've been through all this.
Yes, sir, but you haven't
been listenin' to me.
You know there's a war.
Yes, I know there's a war, and I know
things are bad all over because of the war.
And everybody's gotta work. And you know,
I'm not afraid to work, Mr. Rigby.
Well, this is not a bad place.
I've seen worse.
The boys in the Philippines
don't have it this good, I bet.
No, sir, I'm sure they don't, but
I... Everybody's makin' sacrifices.
I make 'em too. I make 'em all the time.
Yes, sir, but when I took this job,
you said it was gonna lead to
somethin' with regular hours.
This was supposed to be
a stepping-stone, remember?
Don't you get uppity with me now, Nita.
I'm askin' for help, Mr. Rigby.
Now, if the company
can't give me a transfer,
I'd at least like to be free
to look for a job on my own.
Well, you're frozen here, Nita.
It's not my doin'.
They've got laws in wartime.
Now, let's stop this nonsense!
No, sir.
What are you doing? MX, this
is number zero in Gregory.
Yes, thank you. I'll hold.
My God, Nita, there is a war going on!
Will you please stop tellin' me
there's a war! I know there's a war!
It all comes through here!
Tommy Patterson got his arm blown off!
And Billy Patrick's comin' home in a box!
And Charlie Jones isn't comin' home at all,
because they couldn't find enough pieces!
So don't tell me nothin', Mr. Rigby!
I hear the wives and the mamas and the
daddies cryin' and sayin', "No, no, no!"
I hear it! Day in and day out I hear it!
So don't you stand there
and tell me there's a war!
I can tell you plenty
about there bein' a war!
San Antonio. The number's 2872.
Are you callin' the company?
I've got my own boys
to think about, Mr. Rigby.
Yes, personnel office, please.
Nita Longley, you won't get a job anywhere
else. I'll put the word out on you.
Do what you have to do.
Disconnect.
Personnel office?
I'll tell you what, Mr. Rigby.
No law is gonna keep me
from doin' right by my boys.
War or no war, frozen or unfrozen!
You cannot stop me from making this call.
You're not frozen. MX, this
is number zero in Gregory.
You don't make enough money to be frozen.
Yes, thank you. I'll hold.
You're not frozen!
You'd do that to us?
This is a company, Nita!
I've got responsibilities!
A company?
A company!
Excuse me!
You oughta thank your lucky
stars I even gave you a job.
A woman in your situation,
divorced with two kids!
The fact is, Mr. Rigby, that's a
fine situation for me to be in!
Nita, you come back here!
Mama, where we goin'?
Yeah, Mama, where we goin'?
Good morning, Mr. Bueford.
Good morning, Mrs. Longley.
I'd like three tickets. One adult and
two child. Where to, Mrs. Longley?
San Antonio. One way.
Will this be today? No,
sir, that'll be tomorrow.
All right. And your bus will leave 7:10,
and that will be six dollars, please.
Okay.
Five, six.
Thank you.
Thank you. See you in the morning.
Mornin', Miss Pud, Miss Beulah.
We're moving!
You kids play outside
for a little bit, okay?
Okay.
Nita Longley, don't you ever, ever
leave me settin' there again!
Just who the hell do you think you are?
I'm the lady who just quit this job!
That's who I am!
Y'all come on. We got our packin' to do.
Mama, did our daddy love us?
Maybe we'll find ourselves
a new daddy someday.
You really think so? We just might.
We'll be there watchin'
in case a good one walks by.
Mama, are we gonna live
in a telephone office?
No, sirree! I'm gonna get a job
at one of the military bases.
There's a lot of paperwork during a war.
They need people who can type.
And I can sure type.
William Henry Longley, I'm gonna
paddle your little back porch!
Give me that sugar bowl!
Hey, don't tickle me! No, please, don't!
Could I help you?
Excuse me, ma'am.
I'm sorry to be botherin' you this
time of night. I need a telephone.
Well, it's awfully late. We're closed.
I know, ma'am. I'm broke
down out on the highway.
I need to call somebody
to come and git me.
Well, all right.
Just give me a minute, though,
and the phone is, in here on the wall.
Thank you, ma'am.
Thank you.
Number, please.
Number, please!
Hello?
I don't have a number.
Well, then... what's the name, please?
I'll have to look it up.
Nita Longley.
I told you I'd think up some
business with you one of these days.
Didn't I?
I'm gonna have to call the sheriff.
No!
Please. I've got two little boys.
I'll tell you what, ma'am.
You don't give us no trouble,
and we won't give them boys none.
Please don't do this.
Please!
Make 'em bounce.
- Make 'em bounce!
- No!
Mama? Mama!
Calvin?
Who was it? Sailor?
Go see.
Go on!
Mama?
Arnold!
Arnold, where are you?
Hey! Who is that?
Mama?
God!
Arnold! Arnold!
Harry! Honey, where's Harry?
Where's Harry?
I don't know.
God! He must be outside.
Honey, listen to me.
I want you to crawl under the bed and
don't move for nothin', ya hear me?
Not nothin'!
Okay, honey, hurry!
Mama? Mama!
Mama?
Mama, is that you?
Mama!
Mama! Mama!
Harry! Harry! Harry! Run!
Harry, run!
Come on!
Come on, Harry.
Mama.
Come here.
Don't move.
Harry!
Mrs. Longley and the boys all right?
Yeah. Yeah, they're okay.
Still a little scared.
And I don't see any reason to keep
'em around here for this sorry mess.
Our daddy saved us, didn't he, Mama?
Yes, he did, honey.
Must've loved us a I... a lot.
More than anybody else in the world.
More than anybody.
Mama, I hope we see Teddy
again someday, don't you?
I hope so too, honey.
Mommy, when are we gonna get there?
Henry!