Tom, wait up.
I heard about Megan. You doing okay?
Train's running in 10 minutes.
That's the thing
about this messed-up disease.
My mother-in-law, God rest her soul,
she was only 66.
Megan's 42.
It's about time, Hog Head.
Car trouble. Sorry, Tom.
What do I care?
I got your train today.
It's all set with the boys upstairs.
Take some time off.
We got you covered.
I wanna work.
Wait up, Tom.
All right, I wanna tell you this
as a friend and not your boss, Tom.
You're not dealing with this.
I'm dealing with it, my way.
All right.
I'll give you all the streaks you want...
...but if you don't
spend time with her now...
...you're gonna regret it
the rest of your life.
Give him his orders.
See you, Tom.
How long do I have?
I can't answer that.
Well, give me your best bet.
I won't hold you to it.
- Are you all right, Megan?
- Oh, yeah. I'm fine.
Hey, what's the date today?
Tuesday, February 2nd.
Tom, do you really think
you should be driving?
Don't you start with me too.
This is Stargazer Express.
We are setting up and running.
Wanda, your favorite train is leaving.
About time. Stargazer Express.
Come on, baby. Don't give us
a hard time over five little minutes.
Because you know you want me.
Like I want hemorrhoids.
Over and out. Romeo.
Over and out.
- Romeo, huh?
- Yes, sir.
Love on a train.
Man, there ain't nothing like it.
So. what do think about trains now?
I love trains.
I love you.
Tom? You done?
Yeah, I'm done.
Welcome to the Stargazer Express.
We'll be taking you all the way to
Oakland. and from there. on to Seattle.
So sit back, relax, and enjoy the ride.
Why, hello, Davey.
How's your poor mother, bless her,
on this lovely Tuesday morning?
- She's okay.
- Up and around, is she?
Not yet. But soon.
You sure?
Better tell her to watch her step then...
- ... all that drinking.
- Okay, later, Mrs. Brown.
Breakfast is ready, Mom.
Did you say your morning prayers?
Eat your eggs before they get cold.
No, sweetie, I don't want it.
Mom, you have to eat something.
Kneel, Davey.
I said my prayers.
Well, say them again, sweetie.
O God, come to my aid.
I can't hear you, sweetie.
O Lord, make haste to help me.
Glory be to the Father, and to the Son,
and to the Holy Spirit.
Hallelujah.
You know, it's after 10.
You slept so hard,
I didn't wanna wake you.
I feel stronger.
I knew it. I told you you'd feel better.
How long before the train gets here,
sweetie?
Thirty minutes.
We're gonna see the train?
Yeah, Davey.
You mean it?
We don't have to,
if you're not feeling well.
I'm fine, baby.
Here, that's two for you...
...and three for me.
- What for?
- To make us happy, baby.
To make us happy.
Honey, can you get the phone,
please?
I got it, Mom.
Hello?
Hi. this is the principal
at Eastside Elementary School.
I'm calling because Davey
hasn't been in school.
Well, you see, his mother died.
Oh. I'm very sorry.
We weren't aware of that.
Please let us know
when he'll be back. all right?
Okay. Thank you.
Are you still taking classes?
- Yeah. Of course.
- Accounting 101?
Intermediate Accounting 3.
I'm telling you, Tom, if you were smart,
you'd be going too.
Trains, I mean, I love it, man,
but it's a dying business.
Mom.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
We'll wait, Davey.
- We'll wait until it comes, and then-
- Did you know the Stargazer Express...
...goes all the way to Seattle?
I love you, baby.
- Cold today.
- I know.
Good morning, passengers.
We are approaching
beautiful Simi Valley...
...right on time.
O God, you are my God.
I wait for you from the dawn.
There's two engineers
on each passenger train.
My body longs for you.
Pray with me, baby.
- But I already prayed.
- Pray with me, Davey.
My lips will praise you...
...for your mercy is better
than life itself.
It's here.
Wait, Mom, don't go, it's coming.
Mom, what are you doing?
Mom!
It's time to rest now, baby.
- Mom. Mom, wake up.
- Be brave, honey.
It's gonna be over soon, baby.
Mom! The train's gonna come!
- Mom, wake up! What are you doing?
- It's okay.
- Object on the tracks.
- What?
Objects on tracks. Call it in.
- Jesus Christ. Jesus Christ.
- Call it in!
All right, I'm slowing down.
This is Stargazer Express,
approaching Highway 6.
We have an object on tracks.
repeat, object on tracks.
Sixty-eight miles an hour.
Mom!
Wake up!
Oh, my God.
- What's the speed?
- Fifty-five miles an hour.
Still too fast, man. We're still too fast.
- We gotta stop this train, man.
- No!
No, no, no!
You're not stopping the goddamn train!
What are you talking about?
We gotta try!
We can't.
We got too many cars on the turn.
- We have to take the chance!
- Hands off! We're following procedure!
- Screw procedure, Tom!
- There's nothing we can do about it now!
There is nothing we can do!
Help! Someone help me!
What are you doing?
Mom! Mom! Get out!
Fifty miles per hour.
- Oh, my God.
- Forty-eight.
- All right, brace for impact.
- Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Mom!
Perfect.
Thanks.
May I?
The railroad.
Are you a trainman?
You ever been on one?
I don't know
if I should kiss you or slap you.
Repeat after me: I.
- I.
- Would like.
Would like.
To take you out sometime.
You'd go out with me?
Well, now that you've asked me
so nicely, why not?
Hey, Megan.
Whoa, whoa, what are you doing?
- What's going on?
- Okay.
- Jesus.
- I'm...
I'm planting flowers.
Well, not in your condition.
You can't do this kind of work.
Where's Tom? Oh, jeez. Hold on.
Okay, thanks.
I thought he was keeping
an eye on you.
Sometimes I think he can't stand
to be around me.
Here.
Just in case you change your mind.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
The piano?
- I ordered it.
- You're kidding me.
Oh, Megan.
I'm gonna learn how to play.
I've always wanted to learn.
Megan, you have to rest.
Do not go gentle into that good night.
Rage. rage. rage
Against the dying of the light.
Is that what you're doing? Raging?
It's a poem.
It's a Dylan Thomas poem.
- Do you want me to get that?
- Yeah. Thanks.
Stark residence.
No, no. It's not.
Who should I say is calling?
Oh, is he all right?
Yes.
Yes. Thank you.
Tom had an accident.
Give your specimen samples
to this officer.
Cheers. Let me know if I'm pregnant.
Visual clearance coming
off the corner was 300 feet.
If you do the math, the posted was 60,
figure it was between 50 and 45, but...
It was a suicide.
No doubt about it.
We did everything by the book.
- The box will tell you that.
- We know you did, Tom.
It's just a complicated situation.
It's a suicide. It's not complicated.
Not when there's a woman
and a young child involved.
We're bringing you on the carpet.
Some whack-job
drives a car in front of my train...
- ... and it's my fault?
- We don't have a choice on this one.
No one remembers Victor Lopez,
but everybody knows Susan Smith.
- What the hell's that supposed to mean?
- Victor Lopez.
It's the homeless man
who dove under my train in Oxnard.
Tom, nobody cares if some wacko
throws himself under a train...
...but everybody feels
for a mother and her child.
Wait, Tom, look.
Look, I'll talk to him. Hold up, Tom.
Hey, it's a week, 10 days max,
you know?
Take time off. Give us a chance...
- ... to prove you did everything right.
- You know we did.
You know this is a formality, Tom.
We gotta do this.
I'm sorry, excuse me.
This way, this way. Excuse me.
You didn't stop.
Hi. Are you okay?
- Yeah, I'm all right.
- What happened?
Taking some time off.
- They're making you?
- You saw the doctor?
- Susan brought some soup over.
- Not hungry.
You have to do chemo again?
You know, this room, the kitchen?
It's my favorite room
in the whole house.
The only room we fully unpacked.
Yeah. What did the doctor say, Meg?
What are the options?
We don't have any options.
I have days, weeks, maybe months.
The cancer has metastasized
to my bones.
So we'll treat it again.
It's gonna be hard, but-
It's over.
What are you talking about?
No, no, no. We gotta fight this. We-
I'm done fighting, Tom.
The chemo made me sick,
and the cancer's too advanced.
I don't wanna spend the rest of my life
in a hospital room...
...full of tubes and syringes
and oncologists.
- Come on, there's gotta be something.
- There's nothing.
We have to. We gotta try.
I mean, we gotta try to...
Gotta try to find a way to deal,
you know, with-
Death.
Say it.
You know what, this is only for tonight.
Tomorrow, we'll find you a good home.
Okay? You don't feel tired?
You need to get a little bit of sleep
if you can.
Good night, David.
Okay.
Well, maybe now that you have
some time off...
...maybe we can go to San Francisco.
There's gonna be a hearing.
I have to be around to find out when.
Great.
An official excuse.
No, it's not an excuse.
If I'm absent at the hearing,
I'll lose my job.
You're like sand, Tom.
Harder I try to hold onto you,
the faster you slip through my fingers.
Okay.
It's okay.
No.
Out.
Meggie?
Tom thinks that we can help you.
He was very convincing
over the phone.
Well, we're a center
for alternative approaches...
...to treat or ameliorate disease.
We offer applied kinesiology,
cupping, even electromagnetic therapy.
Can you cure me?
As a professional in the medical field,
you know that there are no guarantees.
However, we can try
to rejuvenate your system...
...teach you a number
of relaxation techniques...
...such as meditation,
deep breathing, self-hypnosis.
All of these will help you relax.
I don't wanna relax.
- I wanna live.
- Honey...
Why don't we just
hear what she has to say.
It's all right, Tom.
Of course you wanna live, Megan.
And I would like to spend
what little is left of my life...
...doing exactly what I want to do...
...which does not include
electromagnetic therapy.
Okay. Thank you.
- You're not even listening to me.
- What do you want?
- What would you like me to do?
- What happened to us?
- What are you talking about?
- You heard me.
- Meggie, come on.
- Don't "Meggie" me.
- I'm not some fragile thing.
- What do you want?
I wanna know why
we never had children. How about that?
I don't know, because we never found
the time. We never found the time.
How could we have time?
We moved in 10 different houses
in 15 years of marriage.
I'm a trainman.
That's what trainmen do.
That is not what trainmen do,
that's what you did.
That's not what trainmen do.
It's not the rules for trainmen.
How could anybody, anybody,
have a child like that?
You got sick.
You're blaming me?
No, I'm not blaming anyone.
It was just the way things worked out.
I thought I had all this time...
...to be a woman.
To be a wife...
...and a nurse, and a mother.
Then I found out I didn't. I just didn't.
I don't have any time.
I probably would have made
a lousy father, anyway.
I'm not afraid to die.
But to think that I haven't lived?
That terrifies me.
Thank you so much
for agreeing to do this so quickly.
You will be gentle with him,
though, Judy?
I think he suffers from PTSD.
These kids don't need pity.
They require structure and discipline.
That's my gift to them.
- Right, it's just that his mother was-
- Now, stop. You already told me.
Separate yourself from your job, Renee.
They're not your children.
Of course. You're right.
Thanks.
It's a nice room, huh?
Well, it's a little pink, but at least
you have it all to yourself, right?
It's definitely better
than temporary boarding.
I don't wanna stay here.
This is gonna be a great place for you,
David.
Please don't make me stay.
- You're gonna be safe.
- Please.
Honey, you'll be safe,
and I think you'll really like Judy.
You let her know if you need anything,
and she'll get in touch with me, all right?
Bye.
Used to be my girl's room.
We asked for a girl...
...but you were an emergency.
You want some clean clothes?
This'll have to do for now.
We'll talk later.
And it cleans for months.
Never scrub your toilet again.
Authorities have just revealed
the identity of the woman...
...that was killed in the Simi Valley
train crash as 27-year-old Laura Danner.
The police say that her 11-year-old son.
David Danner...
...had been with her in the car...
...but he somehow managed
to escape the accident unharmed.
I'm told that the senior engineer
who was driving that train. Tom Stark...
...and his partner. Otis Higgs.
have been suspended pending-
Kitchen is off-limits
between mealtimes.
TV privileges are permission only.
Understood?
- Yes.
- "Yes, ma'am. "
As long as you live here,
you'll play by my rules.
Listen to your own rules.
Go to your room.
You're the one
who should stay out of the kitchen.
You're bad.
I knew it the moment I saw you.
Get to your room. Now.
Go.
Get dressed and go to sleep.
Hello?
Hello? Anybody here?
I fancy they're long gone.
The officers.
They collected their evidence and left.
You knew them?
Laura and Davey? I suppose so.
You look a bit pale, dearie.
- I do feel a little...
- Come on. Let me get you a cup of tea.
Tom? Where are you?
I'm out in the garage.
Hey, man, I'm sorry to disturb you
at the house, but...
I had no idea you were
into model trains. This is nice.
Hey, man, you mind
if we go get a beer or something?
Yeah, sure.
Let me get my coat.
We'll let it brew a while.
- You're very kind.
- Now...
...I've lived in this building five years.
Now, Laura and I,
we were never bosom buddies...
...but you don't live
that long next door to someone...
...without getting to know
them on an intimate level.
So did she ever mention suicide
to you?
Oh, you are a nosy one.
Poking and snooping.
Now, how did you find us?
Who sent you?
- It's listed in...
- Well, dear, dear, dear.
- Call information if you don't believe me.
- Trying times indeed, huh?
Oh, cookies!
No, thank you.
Really.
So you were saying, about Laura.
Oh, yeah. Bless her.
I looked after the boy
here and there, you know.
Couldn't help but notice the men
coming and going from her apartment.
I mean,
haven't been anybody for ages.
But they used to flock
around her like hungry birds.
But they stopped coming?
Well, she had a breakdown.
Nerves disease.
Monstrous, really,
the tricks our mind plays on us.
Well, I used to drop by, do chores.
Cook for the boy.
But frankly,
she needed professional help.
Tea?
So she gave up.
Is that why you think she did it?
I really don't know.
- Have you thought about it?
- About what?
The accident.
I'm just...
I'm having a little bit
of a hard time with it.
Yeah, I- I don't wanna talk about it.
Look, I'm- I'm gonna talk to N.B.
I'm gonna give him my notice.
No, you- You can't do that. That makes
it look like we did something wrong.
- That's because we did.
- We didn't have a choice.
- We didn't?
- No.
If we'd used that emergency brake...
...wheels could've flattened,
train could've derailed.
- We'll never know-
- We're not gonna know...
...but- But it was a judgment call,
and I- I made it.
We killed a human being.
A person, Tom. I don't know...
...how I can...
It was a suicide.
Suicide.
You know, the homeless man
was my first one? Victor Lopez?
Come on, come on.
Can we talk about something else?
It was right before
the end of the run and...
I mean, we had a smooth ride
going for like 10 hours.
And then I see him. I mean, he's
standing on the tracks, clear as day.
And I'm blowing the horn. I'm-
I'm ringing the bell.
I mean, I'm doing everything.
He just ignored us.
They turn us into executioners.
You know what he did
right before we hit him?
He smiled at us.
He had a death wish, you know?
Some people do.
Other people don't wanna die,
they die anyway.
I'm gonna wait
till the hearing's done...
...but I'm giving my notice.
Yeah, fine. Go ahead, do that.
- Come on, man. Don't be an asshole.
- Because I got no time for a quitter.
You know what your problem is?
Everything is dying around you and you
just can't deal with it, can you?
Hey! Hey, get out!
Get out! Now! Let's go!
Get out!
Talk about my wife again, I'll kill you.
You know what? Fuck you, Tom!
At least I'm alive.
You're dead inside
and everybody knows it!
What are you doing?
I'm leaving for San Francisco,
tomorrow, alone.
No, just wait...
...wait until after the hearing
and I'll come with you.
No, you won't.
You'll- You'll sign up
for more train trips.
Come on, Meg,
let me make it up to you.
What for?
A final goodbye?
Good night.
- Are you the conductor?
- Yes.
I'm looking for my Uncle Tom.
Yeah, I've seen him in this cab.
This is his train.
You mean Tom Stark?
I didn't know he had relatives.
Yeah. He has a sister.
Sorry, kid, but Tom's not on duty today.
He's off because of the accident.
Well, actually, I don't think
I have the right address.
You want me to check his address?
Could you hurry?
My mom's waiting in the car.
You're bossy.
You're just like your uncle.
I'll just wait right here.
Are you ready to say you're sorry?
What happened?
Don't go.
I have to.
What's gonna happen if you get worse?
I mean...
...who's-?
Who's gonna take care of you there?
I'll figure it out.
Please don't go.
Please. I'm sorry.
Please.
Okay, I'll notify the police, Judy.
Thanks.
Crap.
I can't do this.
It's too late, Tom. Come on.
- You didn't stop!
- Hey!
- What?
- What are you doing? Hey!
- Stop! All right, stop.
Get off me, kid.
He killed my mom!
Tom! Don't hurt him!
- What are you, nuts?
- Stop!
I didn't kill your mother,
she killed herself!
- Will you stop it!
- No, she didn't!
How fast were you going?
Sixty? Seventy?
- I was going 48.
- You didn't even try to stop!
I don't owe you an explanation!
- Hey, Tom, stop it. Sweetie.
- Yes, you do!
- Stop it!
- You could've stopped! You didn't try!
- You didn't even try!
- Listen, come on.
Okay, come on.
- He killed my mother.
- Your mother killed herself.
Come sit down. Let's have some water.
Come on.
- It doesn't say.
- Yes, it does.
Show him where.
Page 55, code 343.
See, the- All the rules
are sort of listed in...
Imagine a train
and it's g- It's going very fast.
- It's on the track and there's passen-
- Over 45 miles per hour.
The engineer's gonna use the
emergency brake on the turn...
- hundreds of passengers onboard-
- A chance that the train could derail.
- That's what it says.
- Right. That's right.
- Well, it's not for sure.
- It's a chance I couldn't take.
Okay, let me clean this hand up.
Here, all right,
it's just gonna hurt for a second.
There we go. Okay, push down.
What's your name, David or Davey?
What do you...?
Davey.
How'd you find me?
- I went on the train.
- What train?
And who's watching you now?
No one.
No family?
They put me in a foster home.
We gotta call the police.
If they're not here already.
Okay, here, just hold that like that.
It's gonna be okay. Don't worry.
No, just push it down.
Okay.
Don't go anywhere.
Is this the Stark residence?
Yeah.
Megan Stark?
- Yes.
- We have your piano.
My piano?
My piano.
Where do you want it?
- Inside.
- Okay.
- What piano?
- I...
My piano. I ordered it last week.
Hey.
What are we gonna do?
- We gotta get him out of here.
- No.
- Let him stay.
- Why? What are you talking about?
Just for one day.
No. I can't have contact
with the victim's family.
- I could lose my job.
- Please, Tom.
Did you see his face?
Did you see his-? His clothes?
He just lost his mother.
Somebody could be looking for him.
If he leaves, I'm leaving with him.
Do you want some more?
No, thanks.
What are you doing?
- I'm washing my dishes.
- No, no, I'll do it.
No, really, I don't mind.
It's okay.
You- You go on
and make yourself at home.
Do you play?
No.
Oh, come on.
Let's get you cleaned up.
Right back this way is the restroom.
How you doing?
Good, ma'am.
You can call me Megan.
I'm just gonna leave some clean
clothes here by the door, okay?
Okay.
Where is he?
Taking a bath.
He's so polite.
He's a strange kid.
He's too grown-up.
You should have seen
how he was raised.
What do you mean?
Don't get mad.
- I went to his house.
- Whose house?
David. Dav- David and
Laura's house in Simi Valley.
Why, why, why would you do that?
I went because I saw them
talking about her on the news.
- I had to know.
- You had to know? Had to know what?
There's nothing to know.
She put her car on the tracks.
She was young, Tom.
She has a child.
I mean, why would anybody...?
It was important to me.
It was horrible,
the way they lived in their house.
It was just...
It was horrible.
Judy Neasy has been a
foster parent for many years.
She has an excellent reputation
with us.
She is a disciplinarian, but I got him
on such short notice, I thought that...
...after living with a mentally
ill mother, I thought maybe...
- ... discipline might be good for him.
- I'm sure you meant well.
- Do you have a picture?
- Yes, I do. Here you go.
We'll circulate it to our patrol units.
You will find him, won't you?
Gonna try this thing out?
No, he's sleeping.
I don't wanna wake him.
He won't wake up.
I'm glad that you didn't...
I know.
I wish we could keep him.
You promised one day.
He needs us.
We could get in a lot of trouble.
It's against the law, and besides,
that's like kidnapping.
- So?
- So...
...if they find out
that he was even here for one day...
...they're not gonna reinstate me.
I'm asking you to do this for me.
If I don't work the rails, I'm nothing.
You're my husband.
I slept for almost a whole day.
I was so tired
and I didn't even know it.
Where's Tom?
He's out working on his model railroad.
He has a railroad?
It's out in the garage.
You can see it when you're all done.
I'm done!
This is really cool.
Why is it broken?
Well, I'll fix it in no time.
Gosh. All these stations and people.
It's so real.
Well, I've been at it for a while.
You ready?
Come on, kid.
Hey, Davey, here's our number.
And if you need anything,
anything at all, you just call me, okay?
I don't wanna go back there.
I know. But you can't stay here.
They won't let you.
Because of the accident?
Yes.
Meg.
Hey, tuck your head down.
What are you afraid of?
Nothing.
I just- I don't want
anyone to see you, is all.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
Okay.
When did you start driving trains?
Running trains.
How old were you?
I don't know, I was about 30.
Passenger trains?
Freight first.
Well, I'll be 12 in August.
- Hope you like chicken.
- Yeah, I love it.
My mom used to make it a lot.
Aren't you gonna say grace?
We don't do that here.
Tom.
Dear Jesus,
I wanna thank you for the meal...
...that we're going to receive and-
Excuse me.
Davey...
...don't worry.
Thanks.
He didn't mean to.
- I'm going out for a little bit.
- Where you going?
I'm gonna go get him some clothes.
- He can't keep wearing your T-shirts.
- Well, let me go.
I mean, you've been going nonstop.
No, let me go. Yeah.
Are you sure?
Yeah, wh-? Wh-?
What should I get?
I made a list.
- Boy's jeans.
- Yeah.
Don't know what size.
Socks, a toothbrush, definitely.
- I'm not sure if you think-
- Okay, get whatever's on here, right?
Yeah.
What the hell are we doing?
I don't know. I don't know,
but it feels good.
I feel better than I have in a long time.
Wanna help?
Yeah.
Okay.
Figure out where your passengers might
want some shade, put these trees there.
- Okay.
- All right?
So, what do you call your railroad?
I call it the Stark Special.
That's a nice name for a railroad.
Yeah, I like to think so.
I like that engine you got there.
My mom gave it to me.
She was a lot like Megan.
She cooked a lot and cleaned.
And she'd help me with my homework.
Yeah, I'm sure she was
Mother of the Year.
Shit.
You know what?
All that won't be necessary.
I just want you to teach me
one really beautiful song.
That's perfect. What's it called?
"A Maiden's Prayer. "
"A Maiden's Prayer"?
It's pretty. Okay. Now...
Okay, just place this finger here.
- Like so.
- Okay.
You've really never seen one?
They don't have them in Simi Valley.
Well, they're big and blue and wet.
You're such a poet.
How you doing? You all right?
Thank you.
Maybe I should dance with Davey.
Come on, man.
Don't keep a lady waiting.
Thank you.
Davey?
Davey? Are you okay?
What's going on?
Can I get you something?
Do you wanna talk about it?
Was it a bad dream?
I was pretending.
Pretending what?
That you were my mother,
and that we were a family.
I told Tom that my mom cooked,
and helped me with homework.
She didn't.
Not for a long time.
She did the best for you
that she could.
She tried really hard.
I know she did.
Here.
You go to sleep, okay?
Let's get you back in bed.
Davey?
Do you want me to sit with you
for a few minutes?
Okay.
Morning.
Oh, my God. I fell asleep.
Want tea?
Thank you.
So how long have you had
that engine?
My mom said my dad left it for me.
He wanted me to have it
when I turned 6.
I guess he liked trains.
Did your dad like trains?
Never knew him.
I didn't know mine either.
It's a bird.
Cool.
Good.
- Sexy stuff, huh?
- That is irresistible.
- That's for you.
- Do that again.
You only get it once.
Thank you.
Oh, my gosh.
My gosh.
Tom.
We can't afford that. That's beautiful.
Repeat after me.
Happy.
- Happy.
- Valentine's day.
Valentine's Day.
Oh, my, so much time has passed.
Do you know something?
I remember certain moments
with such clarity...
...like it was just yesterday.
Let me do that.
That's perfect.
Remember the first time
you spoke to me?
I remember.
- Our first train ride.
- And our second.
Good night. Sweet dreams.
"He fought by instinct,
but he could also fight with his mind. "
What's instinct?
It's a feeling that you get
in your stomach...
...that tells you
if something is right or wrong.
"He rushed as if trying a shoulder trick
that had failed before.
I I
But at the last moment...
What is it?
The hearing's in five days.
In five days what?
It's the official hearing.
It's when they'll decide
whether Tom did the right thing...
...in the accident.
What if they decide
he didn't do the right thing?
He won't be an engineer anymore.
It's okay. Tom is capable.
He can do a lot of different things.
But there's nothing like running a train.
Go on.
What do you call this one?
That's the Atlas 3086.
- It's really nice.
- Yeah, thanks.
I could tell them she wanted to die.
What?
You could say it at your trial.
No, it's a hearing. It's not a trial.
It's all right. Thanks.
You don't want me to tell them?
It doesn't really matter
if your mom wanted to die or not.
The only thing that matters
is if I handled the situation correctly.
I forgive you.
You forgive me for what?
She took away my options
when she put her car on the tracks.
Yeah, she did.
It just so happens she chose my train.
I know.
I got zero.
- No sick days?
- None.
Excuse me. Hi, I was wondering
if you could help.
Well, what is a pretty girl like you
doing in a train station all alone?
Well, I'm looking for a missing boy.
Maybe you've seen him.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We saw this guy, right?
- When did we see him?
- Yeah. He just left.
He was riding a horse,
and he said Darth Vader was his father.
- Yeah-
- Yeah, thanks a lot.
Wait, wait, wait. Let me see that.
This is Tom's nephew.
- No.
- Yeah.
Who's Tom?
He said he forgave me
for killing his mom.
It used to be so simple, you know?
Black and white.
There was a right thing to do...
...and a wrong thing to do.
Life is more like a gray area, Tom.
Not everything.
Some things you know for certain.
Meggie.
Hey, what's wrong?
She's fine.
Here.
- The lady from Child Services.
- What?
- She's at the door.
- It's all right. Stay here.
Who?
The woman who put me
in the foster home.
- Oh, hi. Tom Stark?
- Yeah.
Hi, I'm Renee Hargrove.
Ventura Children and Family Services.
We didn't actually meet, but I remember
seeing you at the scene of the accident.
Would you mind if I came in?
Sure.
Thank you.
This is a lovely home.
I am looking for a missing boy.
David Danner?
I know who he is.
- Have you seen him since the accident?
- No.
Really?
Oh, I forgot the book.
Oh, this is a great book.
- Do you have children, Mr. Stark?
- That's my wife's.
Would you mind terribly if I just took
a little look around? Do you mind?
- Well-
- Thank you.
David ran away from his foster home.
So, what's that to me?
Oh, Mr. Howie Pugh,
the train conductor.
He told me that David
was on the train looking for you.
He claimed to be your nephew.
My nephew?
Do you mind?
Yeah, actually I do.
I mean, this is my home.
I'm sorry. I know this is an imposition.
Okay, you should go in here.
Go in here. Just be quiet.
Excuse me,
I don't think you heard what I said.
Tom? What's going on?
My wife, Megan.
Oh, I'm sorry to barge in like this,
but I'm looking for a missing boy.
Yes, and I couldn't help but notice...
...that the walls
in this room smell freshly painted...
...and there's a little toy train.
- You okay?
- She's sick.
I have cancer, stage four.
It's in my bones.
This is the spare room.
I have trouble sleeping.
At night I come in here...
...because I don't wanna disturb
my husband.
He's just painted it for me...
...because blue is my favorite color.
- I'm sorry.
- You said that already.
Do you want to look around?
No, no, that's okay.
I hope you feel better.
I could just show myself out.
Thank you.
She's gone, kid.
Still high.
We should tell him I'm sick.
No, it's too soon.
I don't think he's ready.
I can call Susan
and tell her to bring some dinner.
Don't worry about dinner, all right?
Tom?
It's gonna be okay.
Almost ready.
And he wants to stay.
He needs us.
So that's that.
Yeah.
- That's the craziest thing I've ever heard.
- I know.
- I mean, really.
- Yeah, it's pretty bad.
Good. Let it out.
Get it up.
That's all you gotta do. Ready?
Simi Valley Police Station.
Detective Crane, please.
Detective Crane speaking.
Hello?
Is anyone there?
- You have to go. I'll be fine.
- Let's not kid ourselves.
Once they find out about the kid,
I'm out of a job. How many of these?
Two. They're not gonna find out
about him. You have to testify.
So you know for sure.
I know I did the right thing.
Then tell them.
I don't want you to have any regrets,
Tom. Not because of me.
No, honey, I won't.
I'm gonna go with you.
No, Meg. You're not well enough.
Well, I'll feel worse if we don't go.
What about the kid?
We'll take him with us.
We'll wait in the car.
Oh, boy.
All right.
- Thanks a lot, N.B. I appreciate it.
- You bet.
Ready for you, Tom.
Hey, Otis.
You're gonna be the sexiest accountant
in town.
So this is an unofficial hearing, Tom,
and the goal of the proceedings...
...is to determine if
an official investigation is necessary.
- I understand.
- Okay.
For the record,
were you the senior engineer...
...on February 2nd,
the date of the fatal incident?
I was.
And could you describe for us
what happened that day...
...to the best of your recollection?
- I wish I could go in.
- Me too.
Why do we have to hide?
Why can't I just tell the social worker
I wanna stay with you?
It doesn't work like that.
But why?
People like to follow rules...
...and you staying with us
definitely goes against that.
And what was your first reaction
when you saw the car?
I slowed the train down.
But you didn't use
the emergency brake.
I decided not to. The emergency brake
wouldn't have stopped that train in time.
But your partner thinks
the impact might have been prevented.
I disagree. At that speed,
with that many cars on the turn...
...we probably would've derailed.
If you could do it all over again,
would you do anything differently?
Mr. Stark.
- I can't do it all over again.
- But if you could.
No.
I wouldn't have done
anything differently.
It's over, Tom.
There's no official investigation.
Everything was by the book.
Where you going?
Hey, we got a streak schedule
for you tomorrow, Tom.
Megan. Megan...
- I didn't do anything.
- It's okay. Get in the car. Get in the car.
Honey. Meggie.
- Honey.
- Megan.
Megan.
So...
...Megan's sick.
She's got cancer.
Can't they cure her?
They did.
Twice.
It came back.
Can't they cure her again?
Is Megan gonna die?
Can I see her?
Tom, she wants to go home.
- Hey, listen. Thanks a lot.
- Of course.
- Let me know if anything changes, okay?
- Yep.
See you.
- Drive safely.
- Yeah.
Hey, hey, hey. Stop it. Stop it.
What are you doing?
Hey, hey. Come here. Look at me.
Look at me. Look at me.
- What's going on? What's going on?
- Let go! Let go!
- No!
- Hey, hey, hey.
- Take it easy.
- I can't be here.
- What? What are you talking about?
- I can't. I'm bad.
You're ba- What did you do?
What did you do?
I told the principal
that my mom was dead.
- You lied? Is that what you did?
- Yes. I shouldn't have.
- God's punishing me. I killed her.
- What are you talking about?
- She shouldn't have gone that day.
- No, no, no.
- God's not punishing anybody.
- Megan is gonna die too now.
Hey, look at me. Look at me.
Look at me.
Megan was sick long before
you ever got here.
- I shouldn't have let her out.
- No. Take it easy. Just take it easy.
I was on the tracks, and I tried.
Mom.
- Davey.
- Mom, I'm so sorry.
- I shouldn't have let you die.
It's okay. It's all right. It's all right.
- God is punishing me.
- No, you did the right thing.
You did the right thing.
Look. Listen to me.
It's okay. It's not your fault.
- You di-
- Megan's dying now.
- Because she's sick.
- No. God's punishing me.
Easy, kid.
It's not your fault, okay?
Here you go.
Why don't you go see Megan now?
Come sit by me.
I wish we had more time.
I would like to take care of you
a little bit longer.
You know, if you think really hard,
maybe you could stay longer.
I love you, Davey.
And I will stay with you.
I will. Forever.
Right here.
I love you too, Megan.
- Promise.
- Anything.
To fight for him.
He is so much like you.
Whatever you want.
Promise.
I promise.
Oh, Meg.
She's gone.
Hey.
You remember that lady, Renee?
The social worker?
Yeah.
I think we need to go see her.
Why?
Well, you can't hide forever,
you know?
And you need to go to school...
...and be a kid again.
Hey, listen.
I want you to know
that whatever happens...
...we're in this together.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Okay.
So you ready to see
how that engine of yours does?
All right. Hit it.
Okay, pick up a little speed.
There you go.
Okay, back it off just a little.
Yeah. Not bad.
Not bad at all.