Birju.
Uncle.
Greetings, Brother Birju.
Birju, you've become such a wealthy man. . .
. . . but you still haven't changed a bit.
Aunt, whatever this kite-seller, Birju is today. . .
. . . it's because of your blessings.
But brother, where is our birthday boy? - Yes.
He was here right now.
Look. There he is.
Brother.
God bless you, my brother. May you live a long life.
I wish our parents were alive today.
They'd be so happy.
Brother, I've never seen our parents.
But every time you bless me. . .
. . .I feel their presence around myself.
See, Uncle. Till sometime ago, I used to carry him in my arms. . .
. . .and today, he speaks such wise words.
Come on. Let's go and cut the cake.
Brother, Madhu.
Of course. You won't cut the cake without Madhu.
Raja.
Hi.
Happy birthday, Raja. - Thank you.
Heartiest greetings on your brother's birthday, Brijnath.
Wow, king and queen? - Yes.
This is you and this is me.
You're the Raja ( king ), and I'm the Rani ( queen ).
I'm Raja all right, but you're Madhu.
Yes, that's right.
Come with me.
Brother, when his name is Raja then why isn't my name, Rani?
Yes, it should have been so.
Fine, now we'll call you Rani.
Thank you, sister-in-law. Come on, Raja.
What are you thinking, Brijnath?
No, I was thinking. . . - I get it.
Why don't we convert our friendship into an alliance?
To tell you the truth, that's just what I was thinking !
Please accept this ring as an auspicious token.
That means, we're now relatives.
Sir, there's a call for you. - Yes, just a minute.
Yes, this is Brijnath here.
Sir, our factory is on fire. - What?
No.
Help! Fire!
Don't cry, Raja. Everything will be fine.
Look, Rana.
It's all over.
There's no way I can compensate for this loss.
I knew it, Rana there's only one man. . .
. . .who'd come to my aid at such a time.
If my aid could change your destiny. . .
. . .I'd have surely done that.
But that doesn't happen.
I've come to return this ring.
This alliance is not possible now.
What are you doing? - Be quiet.
I know what I'm doing.
He no longer matches us in stature now. He's ruined.
Mr. Rana, were we friends. . .
. . .only because of our stature? - Yes.
And now that you've lost that stature. .
. .we can no longer be friends. . .
. . .and when we are no longer friends. . .
. . .this alliance can't happen either.
Here's your ring.
Let's go, Madhu. - No brother, I want to be with Raja.
Forget Raja. Come with me.
Raja. - Come on.
No. - Come on.
No, I won't leave Raja. - Come on.
Raja. - Where are you going?
Come on. - Raja.
Raja.
Madhu.
Raja. Raja, stop.
Madhu. - Raja.
Madhu. - What are you doing?
Madhu. - Raja, stop.
Madhu. - Raja.
I want to be with Raja.
Raja. - Madhu.
Raja. - Aunt, is brother Birju okay?
Why are you quiet? Tell me, is he okay?
For God's sake, tell me how is my brother.
No. No.
Brother Birju.
Brother. - I can't join it back.
I can't join it back.
My toy is broken.
I can't join it back. . . - Brother.
I can't join it back.
I can't join it back. I can't join it back.
Brother.
Brother Birju. Brother Birju, what's wrong with you?
Brother Birju, what's wrong with you?
Brother Birju. Brother Birju.
Brother Birju.
What's wrong with Birju?
Birju.
Put him on the bed, quickly. Quickly. - Yes sir.
Careful.
Sister, call the mental asylum quickly.
Aunt, tell the doctor not to send my brother to the asylum.
He can't live without me, Aunt.
He can't live without me.
Raja, they must to take him to the mental asylum.
It's for his own benefit.
And son, if he sees you crying. . .
. . . it'll be difficult to take him along.
Wipe your tears, son.
Son, I can understand your agony. . .
. . . but you must get a grip of yourself, son.
I want to go see Raja.
Look son, they are bringing him.
Please, be quiet.
Brother.
Raja. Where are they taking me?
Brother, they are taking you to a better hospital.
There'll be better doctors there.
They'll treat you better.
Once you're cured, I'll take you back home. That's it.
I'll come back home soon, won't I?
No, I won't go anywhere without you.
I'm coming along with you. - No.
Go sit in the car, I'll get your luggage and your medicine. Okay?
Do come. I'll wait for you in the car. - Okay.
Let's go. Take me to the better hospital.
I want to be cured. I have to go home soon.
My brother is all alone.
Why did you close the door?
Doctor, my brother is coming. - He'll come, Birju.
Driver.
I won't go without my brother. - What are you doing?
I won't go without my brother.
My brother is a kid.
Raja ! - Brother.
I won't go without my brother. . .
My brother. . . - What are you doing, Birju?
Leave me.
My brother. - Birju.
My brother. . .
Brother Birju.
Raja. Raja. - Brother Birju.
Raja. - Brother Birju.
Raja.
Brother.
I. . . can't live without you.
They wanted to separate me from you.
I can't live without you.
Brother, no one can separate you from me.
I promise, I'll never leave you alone, Brother.
Never.
There's a lot of pain.
I can't tolerate it.
''If you're hurt, I feel the pain. ''
''If you cry, my heart feels the grief. ''
''That's the bond between brothers. ''
''If you're hurt, I feel the pain. ''
''If you cry, my heart feels the grief. ''
''That's the bond between brothers. ''
Brother Birju !
''Come to me, let me shower my love on you. ''
''Let me ward off any evil eye that might befall you. ''
''Brother, I can lay down my life for you. ''
''You're the reason I'm alive. ''
''I can sleep only when you lie in peaceful slumber. ''
''If you cry, my heart feels the grief. ''
''That's the bond between brothers. ''
Raja. Raja, we won.
I hit a goal. We won.
Yes, Brother. We won.
We won, Brother.
Here, Birju. A kilo of carrot.
Birju.
Doctor.
How are you? Hello. - Hello.
How are you? - Fit as a fiddle.
Doctor, please come home for a cup of tea.
No Birju, I must rush to the hospital.
Just one cup, please. - Okay.
Come. Look, what a clean neighbourhood.
Oh God.
What sort of misbehaviour is this?
Aren't you ashamed of throwing rubbish on the road?
Who is it? Show up.
No one will admit to it this way.
Whose silver spoon is this?
Silver spoon?
That's mine. - Yours?
Take it.
Next time, put your garbage in the garbage dump.
And take the money for your egg from him. - Fine.
Let's go, Doctor.
Raja, your brother is truly amazing.
He is so witty.
Now that man will never dump garbage on the road.
And he'll never eat eggs either.
You'll sit and have a chat while I make you some carrot pudding.
Listen. . . Birju.
Unbelievable.
Raja, I can't believe that he's the same man. . .
. . .you begged to bring home from the hospital 15 years ago!
The change I see in him today. . .
. . . is a result of your love and efforts.
Really son, you've worked wonders.
A wonder is what I've worked, Raja.
I've found such a beautiful girl for you. . .
. . .that you'll be shocked to see how pretty she is.
Here's her photograph.
Isn't she beautiful?
Is this the match you've found for me? This one.
She's no ordinary girl.
She belongs to a very rich family.
Her father owns eight country bars. . .
. . .and 15 breweries.
He's the uncrowned king. The uncrowned king.
Get lost, idiot.
My Raja won't marry any ordinary girl. He'll marry a queen.
You're right, Aunt.
God has definitely created my partner.
But I wonder where she is right now.
Sorry. Sorry.
Drunkard, rascal, moron.
You're eating my hand instead of the toast.
Have you gone crazy?
Hi. - Hi.
You're looking gorgeous today. - Thank you.
Madhu, where were you last night?
What do I tell you? Last night, I was in such a big mess that. . .
Sorry, sorry. - Sorry, sir. Sorry.
I ruined your clothes. - It's okay. . .
Can't you watch where you're going? You ruined his clothes.
Don't be angry, don't be angry.
He's a poor man. Must have done it by mistake.
Go, son. Do your work. - Thank you, sir.
Go, go. - Sorry, sir.
Don't be angry.
Strange man.
All his clothes were ruined, but he didn't say a word.
Who's this man?
He's a Godly man.
He doesn't know what anger is.
He's Gandhi reincarnated.
People call him Shantipati.
I can get him enraged in a snap.
Forget it, Madhu. You can't annoy him for anything in the world.
Is that a bet?
Without saying a single word, I'll push him to the edge. . .
.Just watch. . . he'll start yelling like a madman in rage.
And this manager will send him to the mental asylum.
It's impossible. - It's possible.
If I do it, will you hit yourself with your shoe?
Done. - Done.
Okay.
Shantipati.
It's a gift from God.
I keep anger miles away from me.
Greetings. - Greetings.
Sir, I want to talk to you urgently. May I sit here?
Yes, please have a seat. - Thank you, thank you.
Now tell me, what is it?
Actually, it's like this. . .
First promise me, you won't get angry.
Why would I get angry? Just tell me what it is.
I would tell you but I'm afraid it'll annoy you.
No, no. You're getting scared unnecessarily.
Never get angry.
Tell me without hesitation. - Fine.
Actually, it's like this. . .
Forget it, you might get upset.
Look, Sister. I've already told you I don't get angry.
Tell me what you want to say.
Look, you're already a little annoyed.
Sister, I don't get annoyed.
Please tell me what you want to say.
You're lying. I can see you're getting angry. Look.
In swear on God, I'm not.
Please, tell me what you want to say.
Forget it, you're getting angry.
Just a minute, madam. Hold on.
Ram Prasad, look at my face and tell me.
Do I look angry? - Yes sir, a bit.
This is not anger. - Of course it is.
There's sweat on your forehead.
What are you saying?
Your eyes are red. - Red?
Your nostrils have puffed up.
You're breathing fire.
And you still say you're not angry?
No, I am not. I don't get angry.
I don't, I don't. I don't.
Manager. Manager. - Yes, sir.
Do you see anger on my face? - Yes, I can.
You call this anger.
I don't get angry, I don't get angry.
Brother.
Baldy. My friend, my companion.
Do you see anger on my face? - There's anger.
This isn't anger. It isn't, it isn't.
Say, that I don't get angry.
Say it, say it, say it.
Leave him. He'll kill him. - Say it.
I don't get angry. I'll kill you.
Say that I don't get angry. I don't get angry.
Come on, madam. Go on, pick up your shoe and do the honours. . .
And don't bet against me again.
Stop basking in the glory of your victory.
Give me a chance to show my talent too.
Really? Fine, given.
You see this matchbox.
I'll keep this on the table, and fling it. . .
. . .such that it lands straight into that man's cup.
That one? Impossible.
Is that a bet?
If I win, will you do as I say? - Done.
Done.
Yes.
Now you'll have to do as I say. - Fine, what do I have to do?
You'll have to kiss the first man to enter this restaurant.
What? - Yes.
Oh, come on. It's okay to have fun.
This is not fair.
She has placed a bet, and she'll have to fulfill it.
Or else, she can admit that she's a coward.
I will surely fulfil my bet.
Come on.
Hey, fatso. - Are you blind?
Madman.
I'm so hungry.
I'll have a good meal.
Oh, my God.
Listen. - What is it, dear?
I don't want to eat here. - You get good food here.
No, let's go home I'll cook good food for you.
No, no. - You'll get good food here.
''There's romance in the air. ''
Where to darling?
Fine.
''There's romance in the air. ''
I'm done for.
Go ahead, Miss Madhu. Your beloved is here.
What sort of misbehaviour is this?
I lost a bet.
I had to kiss him, but you came in between. I'm sorry.
Look, madam. A girl's first kiss is for her lover.
The one she loves. . .
. . .and has given her heart to.
Not for any stranger passing by. Do you get that?
Madhu.
Madhu, what's wrong?
Looks like she's bowled over.
Deepa, I've found the man of my dreams.
'Look madam, a girl's first kiss is for her lover. '
'The one she loves. . . '
'. . .and has given her heart to. '
'Not for any stranger passing by. Do you get that?'
We've been sitting here all morning. . .
. . . but your lover boy is nowhere to be seen.
My heart says that he will surely come.
Even if he does, you can't woo him.
I'm in love with him, Nisha. . .
. . .and I won't rest in peace until I've wooed him.
Impossible, he won't even turn to look at you.
Want to bet Rs. 1,000?
One shouldn't bet on matters of the heart.
Just say that you don't have the guts.
That's an insult to you, Madhu.
Bet on it. - Yes, Madhu go ahead.
Fine, it's a bet. - Done.
He's here.
Please tell me, what you wanted to tell me.
I won't get angry. I won't. Please.
Please let me go now. - No.
Or else I'll be furious.
I broke out from the mental asylum just for you.
Please. What did you want to tell me?
Please, please.
Please tell me, what was it?
I think she's calling me. - Not you.
She's calling that handsome boy.
Hey, handsome. She's calling you. Look, look there.
Hi.
Say hi. - Hi.
Did you recognise me?
I'm the same one, yesterday. . .we kissed. - Kissed?
Can I come there? Okay, I'll come there.
I was deeply moved by whatever you said yesterday.
Kisses here, kisses there.
Kisses everywhere, in everything I do!
Kisses everywhere. - So many kisses.
Yes. - Look. Everyone's listening.
So what if they are?
Why does it bother anyone if we are romancing?
Hey, does it bother you? - No, it doesn't.
It doesn't bother him. We can continue with the romance.
You were right yesterday.
A girl's first kiss is for her lover. . .
. . .and I've chosen you as my lover, my beloved.
Behram, she's such a daring girl. - Correct.
Look madam, neither am I your lover, nor are you my darling.
So, please leave me alone.
The fool says, ''Leave me alone''. - Idiot.
Look, don't mistake me for an ordinary girl.
I belong to a very wealthy family.
I'm the sister of the wealthiest man of the city. . .
. . . Rana Mahendra Pratap.
My name is Madhu.
'Wow, king and queen. - Yes. '
'This is you, and this is me. You are the king, and I am the queen. '
For your information, I have finished my BCom.
I know six languages. I am five feet six inches tall. . .
. . .and I weigh only 55 kilos.
Now, what do you think about me?
Hey stupid, say that you like her.
I like you.
So, quickly kiss the miss.
Very good. Hey fool, you're done for now.
''Someday, I'll be the queen to my king. ''
''Say it again. ''
''It's an enchanting tale. ''
''We've just met. Don't leave me so soon. ''
''My heart's crazy for you. ''
''Say it again. ''
''Someday, I'll be the queen to my king. ''
''Your demure glance enchanted me. ''
''Your eyes were flooded with numerous questions. ''
''My heart always craved for you. ''
''I felt it was you I was searching for. ''
''I'll engrave your face on my heart. ''
''I'll play with your curly tresses. ''
''Say it again. ''
''Someday, you'll be the queen to this king. ''
''Someday, I'll be the queen to my king. ''
''Say it again. ''
''You're a blossoming flower. I'm the blooming spring. ''
''Engrave the tale of your love on my lips. ''
''You're love and beauty personified. ''
''You're enchanting, my love. You're my life. ''
''Don't praise me so much, that I lose my senses. ''
''I might just forsake the world in your love. ''
''Say it again. ''
Bhanwar Lal, I saw Abhishek five years ago. . .
. . . but his trip abroad has changed him completely.
I would to beg to differ, sir.
He did stay abroad for a while. . .
. . . but has emerged as untouched as wax from water.
He hasn't learnt their ways or culture.
He come back the same person he was.
That's the reason why we selected him for our sister.
There comes Madhu.
Come, Madhu. Meet him.
He's the Prince of Nigampur, Abhiskek Sanyal.
That's his uncle, and she's my sister, Madhu.
Greetings. - Greetings.
Beautiful. Very beautiful.
Fool. A complete fool.
Did you say something? - Yes.
No. Yes, she was praising you.
He's beyond praise.
He owns hundreds of mills and factories. . .
. . .and dozens of magnificent bungalows.
Yes. And the bungalow where I live. . .
. . .also has a personal zoo in it.
I'm sure they all live there.
Did you say something?
No. Yes, she was saying. . .
. . .that you all have a chat while we get something to eat. - Yes.
Come, sit. Please sit.
Your sister is very pretty and polite. Just like my nephew.
Sister-in-law, who is this moron?
You shouldn't speak like that. They're royalty.
They own property worth millions.
Your brother is arranging your alliance with him.
Fixing my alliance with him? - Yes.
I wouldn't appoint him a servant in my house.
Sister-in-law. - Yes.
I've chosen my man. - What?
And I've. . . promised to meet him today as well.
Mr. Ranglani, don't worry.
I will have this container sent to Kolhapur. . .
. . .and I'll take these two containers to the docks.
I need to leave early today.
I've to take my wife out for shopping.
So take care of the work here.
Mr. Ranglani, today I'd like to leave early as well.
You aren't even married. Why do you want to go home early?
I see. You're having an affair.
Go on, have fun. - Thank you, sir.
Hello. You are on your way to meet Madhu.
And you are?
Nisha. Madhu's friend.
I want to tell you. . .
. . .that Madhu is playing a charade of love with you.
What? - Yes.
It's her hobby to fool people. . .
. . .and this time, you happen to be that wealthy, pampered girl's victim.
For a mere bet of Rs. 1000.
You are lying. - And what if it turns out to be true?
I'll never forgive that wealthy girl.
Here Madhu, your bet money.
All of Rs. 1000? - Yes. All of them.
There's one thing, Madhu. No one can win a bet with you.
Really, you made Raja fall for you so easily.
Dear, I always do what I say.
And I never keep the money that I win.
Eat, drink and be merry. I'll pay the bill.
Raja. You. . .
Shut up. Don't you dare take my name.
I know the truth now.
Look, Raja. I admit I did bet. . . but. . .
. . .the truth is that I really love you.
You'll never know what love really means.
It's just a bet for you.
A mere bet made for Rs. 1000.
Thankfully Nisha made me see the truth.
Else, I'd have continued believing your pretence of love.
Never show me your filthy face again. Get that?
Raja. Raja.
You cheat.
Raja, please listen to me. You're mistaken.
She. . . it was she who instigated me.
That's why I betted.
I really love you. Really.
I don't want to hear anything.
Stop following me. Okay?
Listen to me.
Please forgive me.
And say that you love me. - I hate you.
Tell me, you love me. - I hate you.
Please, tell me you love me. - I hate you.
You won't say it. - Never.
Then, take this.
What are you doing? - I'll show you.
Thief. Thief. - Look. . .
Thief. Thief. - Leave me.
That thief is stealing that girl's purse.
Constable, constable. That thief is snatching that girl's purse.
There, there. Not me. Over there.
Save me. - Yes, quickly.
Help. - He's the one. He's the thief. Catch him.
You rogue, you dare snatch the girl's purse.
You thief. - Constable, I'm no thief.
My purse. Sir, this is my purse.
Thank God, you caught him.
Madhu, what is all this? Tell them who I am.
Madam, do you know him? - No, sir.
How would a decent girl like me know a thief like him?
So he's a liar.
Come on, I'll take you to the police station and teach you a lesson.
Just a minute, sir. I want to have a word with this thief in private.
Look Raja, there's still time.
Say that you love me.
Even if I were sentenced to death. . .
. . .I wouldn't say that I love you.
Take him away. He says he won't mend his ways.
Come on, come. - Take him away.
What have you done, Madhu? You got Raja arrested.
What else could I have done? He wouldn't agree to say 'I love you'.
You've invited trouble.
Now he'll hate you all his life.
What should I do now?
Now, try his family.
You mean get his family arrested as well? Fantastic.
Idiot, I mean try to win them over.
I'll do that.
? '
Birju. - Yes.
Abdul was saying that Raja didn't come home all night.
Yes, that's what has been troubling me.
Oh, God.
When young boys start staying out all night. . .
. . .assume that youth has overflown.
Shut up, you fool. Must you talk rubbish all the time?
Did you inquire at Raja's factory? - Yes, Aunt.
He didn't even go to work. - Oh, God.
He didn't go to work, nor did he return at night.
Then where did he go? - I'll tell you.
He was with me all night.
But who are you?
The queen to my king.
Now you'd will ask, how all this happened.
Aunt, this is a two-year old story.
Oh God, you've known Raja for two years? - Yes.
We've been in love for the last two years.
But last night. . .
. . .there was an accident.
Accident? - Yes.
Not the one with the cars, but our eyes and hearts.
How was that?
In the dark of a rainy stormy night. . .
. . .amidst old ruins. . .
Both of us were shivering with cold.
Raja somehow lit a fire.
That fire burned outside. . .
. . .while we burned within.
And somewhere far away, there was a song playing. . .
''Your beauty is enchanting. ''
''My love is passionate. ''
''I might make a mistake. ''
Shut up, puny guy.
Then what, Sister? - Then.
He looked at me like Dilip Kumar ( Indian actor).
I smiled like Vyanjanti Mala ( Indian actor).
Then he winked at me like Rajesh Khanna ( Indian actor).
I shied away like Sharmila ( Indian actor).
Then he held my hands like Amitabh ( Indian actor).
And I fidgeted like Rekha ( Indian actor).
And suddenly, he turned into Shatru ( Indian actor).
And I got scared like Reena ( Indian actor).
He took me in his arms like Dharamendra ( Indian actor). . .
And I wriggled and squirmed like Hema ( Indian actor), but. . .
But what happened?
''Oh Lord Ram, your Holy Ganges has been rendered impure. . . ''
''. . . in cleansing sinners of their sins. ''
Oh, God. That means, you did it. - Yes.
And at the crack of dawn, he left me like a villain.
I can't face anyone now.
If Raja doesn't accept me, I'll commit suicide.
I'll kill myself.
I'll sacrifice myself to the pyre of a husband that never was.
I'm killing myself, isn't anyone watching?
Look, I'm killing myself. - Wait.
What are you doing, my dear?
Why should I stay alive now, Aunt?
No dear, you must live.
Brother Raja is here.
Let him come, I'll set him straight today.
Aunt, it's your personal issue. . .
. . .you deal with it, I'll go inside.
Fine, go in.
Greetings, brother Raja.
What's the matter? You look very fresh.
Do I look fresh to you? Do I look fresh to you?
I'm tired after last night. - I know, I know.
What was it that tired you?
Get lost. Just get lost.
Yes, go inside. You're going to get it there.
So you've got yourself disgraced?
'Oh, God. How did they come to know that I spent the night in jail?'
You mean, you all know where I've been all night?
We don't just know about it. We have the complete report as well.
Look Aunt, it wasn't my fault.
That girl got me into this mess.
Yes, I'm sure the girl got him into it.
Stop it. He's not a baby. . .
. . .that any girl would trick him that easily.
Didn't it shame you to besmirch her honour?
Let it be, Aunt. How was she dishonoured?
I'm the one who was disgraced.
Great. You eat the forbidden fruit. . .
. . .and blame someone else for it?
What are you saying?
I didn't even get a piece of bread.
I slept on an empty stomach in the lock up.
In the lock up? - Yes, Aunt. In the lock up.
And do you know why?
Because I didn't tell that girl that I love you.
That's why she got me .
I swear, Aunt. If I ever run into that girl again. . .
. . .I'll teach her a lesson she'll never forget.
I won't spare her.
Please calm down and have water. - Thank you.
You? What are you doing here?
Aunt, this is the girl who got me arrested.
Tell them, tell them what's the truth. - No.
Tell them, tell them or else I'll. . . - I'll tell them.
Everything I said was a lie.
The truth is, I really love Raja. . .
. . . but he doesn't love me.
When if I didn't succeed by hook, I had to resort to crook.
What would you have done, had you been in my place?
We'd have done the same thing.
Mind your tongue, and get out of here.
Come on. Come on. And you too.
Get out, come on get out.
Don't push her. She's our sister. Get that.
You moron, take your sister with you.
And where are you going? - Inside.
Come on, get out. Come on.
Go on.
''Oh, my heartless, infidel tormentor. . . ''
''. . .you refuse my love?''
''You show me attitude just because I love you?''
''Oh heartless one, why do you torment your lover?''
''Raja, come to your senses. ''
''Or else, I'll teach you a lesson. ''
''If you don't cast a loving glance at me. ''
''I'll renounce this world. ''
''Don't be stubborn, dear, heed my request. ''
''Or else I'll never come back. ''
''If you don't cast a loving glance at me. ''
''I'll renounce this world. ''
''It's the moon that illuminates the dark, and not the stars. ''
''You fall in love with just one, not many. ''
''I love you, and I always will. ''
''I cannot live without you. ''
''If you don't stop being rude. . . ''
''. . .I'll renounce this world. ''
''Don't be stubborn, dear, heed my request. ''
''Or else, I will never come back. ''
''In course of trying our love for each other. . . ''
''. . . let's not waste this life in appeasing. ''
''You'll miss me every moment. ''
''The yearning will torment your moments of peace. ''
''Oh beloved, if you break my heart. . . ''
''. . .I'll renounce this world. ''
''Don't be stubborn, dear, heed to my request. ''
''Or else, I will never come back. ''
''If you don't look at me lovingly. . . ''
''. . .I'll renounce this world. ''
Strange girl.
A minute ago, you were prancing and dancing around. . .
. . .and now you are crying.
Tell me one thing. You love Raja a lot, don't you?
Don't you worry. I'll fix your problem.
I'll need to put up a false act for that. . .
. . . but I'll do it.
''I've stepped into youth. ''
''My beauty is now in full bloom. ''
Yahoo!
You scared me, scoundrel.
I'm in love with you.
When did the fledgeling spread wings?
Let me show you how it pecks.
Look Birju, those days of youth were different. . .
. . .when I was in love with you.
But these days. . . my heart yearns for someone else.
What? You dare love someone else while I'm alive.
Before you disgrace yourself. . .
. . .I'll marry you right away. Come.
Let's go, you wretched soul. Let's go.
Brother Birju, what are you doing?
I'm going to marry him. - What?
Raja, save me. - Let's go darling, to the temple.
You are not going to any temple. Come home with me.
Raja, I'm his husband. - You're not.
Don't separate us. - Come on. Come with me.
She'll be widowed. She'll be widowed.
Where are you running off too? Come here.
Come on. - She'll be widowed.
She'll be fine.
Aunt, what's wrong with brother Birju?
I don't know, Raja. This morning he came home and said. . .
. . .that he has a severe stomach ache.
So, that aunt of yours who's come from the village. . .
. . .gave him a potion. - Potion?
Yes. - Yes, this is the bottle of potion.
Brother Birju downed the entire bottle.
It's a result of a that.
Charred gold potion?. But where is this aunt?
Aunt. Aunt.
Dear, can't you watch where you're going?
Who are you?
She's Madhu. - Madhu?
Aunt. Aunt. Aunt Madhu.
Hey, Aunt. - What?
My brother is acting weird.
What potion did you make him drink?
What potion did I give him?
That man drank all of it? - Yes.
It's a terrible mistake. I gave him the wrong potion.
Catch. This has charred gold. . .
. . .and the effect won't wear off for eight-ten days.
What, the effect won't wear off for eight-ten days? - No.
Aunt, there must be an antidote for it.
There is an antidote all right. . .
. . . but we'll have to go to the jungle to get the herbs.
Aunt, let's go quickly.
You are not my husband that I'd wander off to the jungle with you.
Get lost. I won't go with you. - Why won't you go?
If you don't, I'll take you forcefully.
Come on.
You'll take me forcefully? - Yes.
Me? - Yes, you.
Take me along. Take me along.
What are you doing? - Take me with you.
Take me with you. - Leave me.
Look Aunt, I am warning you. . . - To hell with your aunt.
Don't lock horns with me.
Don't try to threaten us.
Quietly go to the jungle.
Or else, I'll punch you, fatty.
Why you. . .
You call me fatty?
Does your dad pay for my food? You, fool.
Does your dad pay for my food?
You call me fatty. Back off. - I'll die.
You son of a drunkard. Does your dad pay for my food?
Let go. - Leave me.
I'll die, let go of me.
Aunt, I beg of you. I plead to you.
Let him go, or else he'll die.
Aunt.
Now that you're requesting politely, I'll let go.
Go.
Bloody fool.
For one who talks nicely to me. . .
. . .I can go to any lengths.
Let's go, my boy. Let's go to the jungle.
Now, they'll make merry in the jungle. - Yes.
''Today the weather is capricious. ''
Aunt, I'm tired of going around these mountains.
Where would we find that herb?
No pain. . . no gain, Raja.
What are you doing?
Should I say something? I find you very adorable.
Look, Aunt. Enough is enough. If I lose it once, I'll. . .
Why you. . .
''Tequila. ''
Aunt, what are you doing? - Where are you hurt?
Forget that.
Shut up.
What nonsense is this? What nonsense is this?
Aren't you ashamed to do all this?
She's not going to mend her ways. Never.
Now it's punctured. The city is 200 km from here.
We'll have to spend the night in the jungle.
Not at all. I'll arrange to get us out of here.
Yes, come on. Come on, Raja.
Come on. Fantastic.
Do it. Come on, Raja. Come on.
Fantastic. You can do it.
Come on, Raja. That's it. That's it.
Come on, Raja. Come on. Yes.
Fantastic. You're great. Superb.
Raja, you're great. Great.
Come on, Raja. Do it.
Come on. Twist more. Come on.
Come on, Raja. You can do it.
Come on. You can do it.
Come on, Raja.
You did it.
No matter what you say, all this is happening because of you.
Had you listened to me. . .
. . .I wouldn't have had to don the guise of an old woman.
Neither would our Jeep have a flat tyre. . .
. . . nor would we be stuck in the jungle
Look, there is still time.
Admit that you love me.
What are you harping about love?
You love me a lot?
Yes, Raja.
Will you do whatever I say?
Try me.
Then strip. - No.
I want to love you.
Right now.
Come on. - No, Raja.
Is that a way to show love?
This is my way.
You wanted me, right?
Then you'll have to fulfil my wish too.
You'll have to surrender yourself to me.
No, Raja. You can ask for my life. But. . .
I don't want your life. I want your body.
No.
I knew that your love is nothing but pretence.
It's a sham. - No.
Raja, listen to me.
Believe me.
I love you. I really love you.
No.
You don't love me.
You're a liar and your love, a lie.
Stop, Raja.
If this is the only way to win your love. . .
. . . if this is what love means to you. . .
. . . if lust is a paradigm of love in your eyes. . .
. . .then come, and take my body.
Come. Satiate your desire.
Obliterate your limits and my chastity.
Come, Raja. Come. I said, come on.
Madhu, your chastity is dearer to me than my life.
Lust is not a paradigm for love in my eyes. . .
. . .and I haven't forgotten my limits.
I made a grave mistake by disbelieving your love.
Forgive me, Madhu.
Forgive me.
Madhu, my name is Raja ( King ).
Why didn't your family name you Rani ( Queen )?
'Brother, when his name is Raja then why isn't my name Rani? '
Raja. - Yes, your childhood friend Raja.
Raja. Raja.
''Neither do I ask for flowers nor spring. ''
''Beloved, I just ask for your love. ''
''Neither do I ask for peace nor solace. ''
''Neither do I ask for flowers nor spring. ''
''I expressed whatever was hidden in my heart. ''
''I never kept the secret of love from you. ''
''Tell me what love is. ''
''It brings along fervour and intoxication. ''
''Neither do I want to be in my senses, nor in a trance. ''
''Beloved, I just ask for your love. ''
''Neither do I ask for flowers nor spring. ''
''No lover could have ever loved me as much. ''
''I can forsake the world for you, my love. ''
''How would I spend my life alone?''
''Now every joy of mine is yours. ''
''I want neither beauty nor adornment. ''
''Beloved, I just ask for your love. ''
''Neither do I ask for flowers nor spring. ''
''I ask for neither peace nor solace. ''
''Beloved, I just want your love. ''
Today, I'm really happy.
Thanks God you both have united.
This had to happen, brother.
The bond which you had formed in our childhood. . .
. . . had to come true someday.
Yes, brother. She's Madhu.
My childhood Rani.
God bless you, dear.
You don't know your brothers.
Raja has told me everything, brother.
I know why this alliance was broken.
So we have to decided to register our marriage in the court, brother.
No, Raja. No.
This won't be right.
I will go to my friend to mend this broken alliance.
I will.
I'd never imagined that the auspicious day would arrive so soon.
I'll take your leave now.
I need to make arrangements for the engagement. - Bye.
I have to invite the relatives too.
There are countless things to do. Bye. - Bye.
Bye. - Come.
Hurry up, driver. Hurry up.
I see. So that's your brother.
Yes, Mr. Rana. He's Raja.
Won't you ask your friend to come in?
Your stature doesn't permit you to enter this house.
Mr. Rana.
Mr. Rana, you don't know.
Raja and Madhu love each other.
I know. I know very well.
My sister loves a man. . .
. . .who can't even match Rana Mahendra Pratap's boots in stature.
Mr. Rana. - No.
Mr. Rana, it's true that we're poor.
But love never considers social differences.
The truth is that marriages are made in heaven.
No. Marriages are made on earth.
You deliberately trapped my sister in the web of your brother's love. . .
. . .so that you can settle your scores with me.
No, brother. That's not true.
Of course it is.
It's a filthy conspiracy of a devious mind.
Mr. Rana, I had heard of lowly people existing in this world. . .
. . . but you've proved to be worse than them.
I could have replied aptly to your insolence. . .
. . . but you're not worth even that.
And you better get one thing straight.
You're getting engaged to Abhishek tomorrow.
If anybody tries to hinder this auspicious ritual. . .
. . .then be it a palanquin or a bier. . .
. . . it'll leave this house in all grandeur.
Ladies and gentlemen, I need a couple of your minutes.
I announce my only sister Madhu's engagement. . .
. . .with the Prince of Nigampur, Abhishek.
Congratulations. - Thank you.
Congratulations.
Sumitra, get Madhu. - I'll call her right away.
Why do you all look so shocked?
Brother made the right announcement.
I'll surely get engaged. . .
. . . but the groom won't be the prince of some kingdom.
He'll be the ruler of my heart, Raja.
Madhu, what nonsense is this?
This is not a nonsense. It's my decision, brother.
Who are you to take the decisions for yourself?
Rana Mahendra Pratap is the only one who takes decisions in this house.
I'm leaving the house where I'm not free to live my life.
It's because of this rogue that you're humiliating the family. . .
. . . in the presence of all these people and leaving.
I'll see how he leaves this house alive.
You may shoot, but only over your sister's dead body.
Shoot.
Yes, shoot if you have the guts to.
No. Have you lost it?
Yes, I have. I'll kill her.
Who has stopped you? Shoot me.
Yes, I will. - Stop it.
And you. . .you're ready to die for this boy.
But ask him once. Ask him what he can do for you.
Ask him.
You sling mud on the age old repute. . .
. . .earned by your ancestors for his sake.
Ask him what he can do for you. Ask him.
You reject 20 years of our love. . .
. . .for the few days of togetherness with him?
Ask him what he can do for you.
Ask him.
Ask him if he can walk these 20 steps barefoot.
No, Raja. Don't do that.
Raja.
No.
See that. It took all but four steps for your love to give up.
How will he stand by you all your life?
Love is no child's play.
It puts the bravest of the brave to trial.
Well said ! Well said !
No!
Raja.
Don't ever put true love to trial.
It puts the best of the best to shame.
Well said, Raja. What a couplet. Wow!
Please give my Madhu's hand in mine.
Take her and lock her up in her room. - No.
Don't beat Raja.
Throw him back into the filth he came from.
Scoundrel.
That's Raja ! That's Raja !
What? No.
Raja.
Raja. Raja.
Open your eyes, Raja. Open your eyes.
What happened?
Oh, God. Who did this to Raja?
I know who thrashed my brother, Aunt.
I won't spare them.
Hey, you can't go inside?
Come down. Come out.
Rana Pratap, come down.
Come out. Come here.
If you're man enough, come down. Come down.
You scoundrel, how dare you challenge us right in our home?
Stay there. Stay there. I'm coming.
Come down. I won't spare you. Come down.
You're acting too smart. I will. . .
Are you crazy?
What are you doing?
Move.
You thrashed my brother.
Brother. Brother.
Brother, call the police. Help me, brother.
Birju, leave me.
Hello, police station. This is Rana Mahendra Pratap.
Inspector, look what he has done to my brother.
Take this beast, and put him in the lock-up.
You're a beast, a bloody beast.
Come to your senses. Come to your senses.
You don't know. He thrashed my brother.
He left him bleeding.
I won't spare him. I won't.
Get lost. What harm will you bring to me, you madman?
Then hear this madman loud and clear, Rana.
If I don't get your sister married to my brother. . .
. . .then shame befall Birju's name.
Before your brother marries my sister. . .
. . .I'll shred your brother to pieces.
Forget shredding to pieces. . .
. . .If as much as touch my brother. . .
. . .I'll won't leave you worthy enough of being called a man.
I still don't understand who thrashed Raja so badly.
Once I find out who it is. . .
. . .I swear I'll knock the shining daylights out of him.
Well done. - Abdul. Abdul.
Uncle. - What happened to him?
There's terrible news. - What happened?
What happened?
The police arrested Birju. He is in the lock up.
What are you saying? - Yes.
What are you saying? That's bad news.
So, Raja shouldn't find out.
Otherwise his health could deteriorate. - Yes.
But how to release Birju from the lock-up?
The inspector asks for a bail amount of Rs. 15000.
I won't let him get a bail, Mr. Rana.
For nothing in the world.
Shame on me if I don't break as many bones of his body. . .
. . .as the broken glasses in your mansion.
You talk of six months, sir?
I can easily leave him to rot in there for a few years.
Yes, sir. I've received your bundle.
Now my job begins. Good day, sir.
Hello, sir.
Divide this among yourselves. The rest is mine.
That is fine, sir. But we shouldn't keep it here.
I've received confirmed news. . .
. . .that anti-corruption officers are going to raid this place.
If we are caught with the bribe money. . .
. . .then our jobs would be at risk, sir.
Sir, do something.
I suggest you deliver this money to my home.
Hang on. - What happened?
Come here.
Tell me quickly. What is it? Tell me.
Sir, give me your hand. - Why? Are you an astrologer?
Sir, give me your hand. Please.
Here. See this. See this properly.
It's the same hand I'm going to thrash you with.
Nice hand. You have five fingers.
Leave me. Leave me.
Leave my hand. Help. Help.
Divide the money later. - Come.
Help.
Leave.
Liked it? Thrash me, will you?
My stick. Pandey, get my stick.
Open the door. - Beware.
Nobody moves.
We've come from the anti-corruption bureau.
Come. Come, sir.
You won't find any corrupt officer in this police station.
Everybody here is honest.
Don't listen to him. This man must have been born on a bribe.
Don't spare him.
Shut up. We know what we have to do.
Got it?
Frisk him.
Found it. Found it. Found it.
Tell me. Tell me, how we should punish you?
Sir, tie him up and pour molasses all over his body.
So that ants eat him bit by bit.
Sir, forgive me. I'll never make this mistake again.
I'll do as you say.
Release that innocent man. - Okay. Okay.
Harpal. - Yes. - Open the door quickly.
And bring Mr. Birju out. - Right away.
Beware. Nobody moves.
Everybody stands still.
But who are you?
We're from the anti-corruption bureau.
Anti-corruption bureau?
What's going on here?
Leave him, sir. He's innocent. - Quiet.
Who are you all? Why are you all wailing?
Sir, he locked that man up without a reason.
He asked for a bribe of Rs. 50000 to release him.
We have paid him Rs. 50000. - Yes.
Now he wants Rs. 7 5000.
Sir, they are lying. I. . .
Tell me. From where did you get this money?
I am telling you the truth. This is not bribe money. I will. . .
Shut up. Gaitonde. - Sir.
Tape his mouth. - Yes, sir.
Constable. - Yes, sir.
Release that innocent man.
Thanks a ton, sir. Thanks a ton. . .
. . .for having released this poor man.
Thank you, sir. - It's okay.
Sir, may I take my money? - Take it.
Give it to me.
Thank you, sir. Come on.
Thank you, sir.
I'll handle this bribe taker.
Raja. Raja.
Raja, are you okay?
I'm fine, brother. But you shouldn't have gone there.
What if something had happened to you?
Nothing will happen to me, Raja.
Those rogues will have to pay a price.
No, brother. This is my battle.
No, this is our battle.
Don't be stupid, both of you.
They have money, power and men.
You can't defeat them.
We will win, Aunt. We surely will.
By hook or by crook.
With all due respect, sir.
I proudly say that you did the right thing with Raja.
And that madman was making tall claims.
Just watch. Now he'll never come here.
May I come in please?
Think of the devil and the devil is here.
Good morning.
Rogue, how dare you come inside? Get out.
Looks like you were born on Diwali ( festival of lights ).
You explode like a firecracker before you speak.
You. . . - Don't beat me. I have not come here to fight.
I've come with the invitation card for Raja's wedding.
Hello.
You look like a lunatic, but you're quite sensible.
Come.
Good that you arranged your brother's alliance elsewhere.
Sukhiram, bring almond sherbet for him.
With some saffron.
Yes, add saffron too.
Tell me. Where's the girl?
She is from this city. - Okay.
With your blessings, I have fixed the alliance with a rich family.
I see. - Read it for yourself.
Wow!
Birju, the kiteseller invites you to his younger brother, Raja's wedding. .
. . .with Madhu, sister of Mr. Mahendra Pratap Garhwal.
You rogue, how dare you do this?
It is customary to give the in-laws the first invite.
You dare form an alliance with us? With us?
You can't leave from here alive.
I won't spare you.
Good. Good. Shoot me.
You'll only make things easier for me. Shoot me.
You fool, how will dying make things easier for you?
You fool, you don't understand.
If he shoots me, I'll die.
If I die, they'll be hanged.
Then there's no stopping Madhu and Raja.
Shoot me. Shoot me. Shoot.
He's right, sir. Don't shoot. - Shoot.
No. No. - Don't shoot.
Don't shoot. - Move.
Come here. Don't shoot.
Rana, don't shoot. Rana, don't shoot.
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
Don't shoot. Rana, don't shoot.
Rana, don't shoot.
Try to understand, sir. He's right.
He has done half the task by printing the wedding card. . .
. . .and the rest will be done after you're hanged.
Good you didn't shoot him.
You're the only intelligent one among them.
The rest of them are all morons.
You stupid fellow.
Yes, Brother Birju. - Come here.
Look, I don't know about them.
But at least you look like a human being.
I will give you some free advice. Follow it.
Forget Madhu.
Otherwise I will make your plight such that. . .
. . .you won't be able to call yourself a man.
Mr. Vishwa, I'm leaving.
Mr. Rana, see you on 25th of October. . .
. . .at Hanuman street, Pasta lane. Bye.
Brother, he comes to our house and threatens us.
I beg your pardon, sir.
You should never underestimate your enemy.
This madman can do anything.
Mr. Rana, uncle is right.
There are still 25 days left for 25th October.
And in these 25 days this madman can do anything.
So we'll hide Madhu somewhere for 25 days.
I have a bungalow 25 miles from Alibaug.
We'll take Madhu there.
And before 25th of October we'll get her married to him. - Yes.
Then we'll see what this madman can do.
Fine, Bhanwarlal.
Madhu will be in Alibaug by morning tomorrow.
Let's go.
Don't worry, sister-in-law.
Nobody can separate Madhu from Raja.
Leave me. - Shut up, Madhu. Sit quietly, Madhu.
Sit quietly. - No.
Sit quietly. - Nobody can separate me from Raja.
Shut up. - Leave my hand.
Madhu, sit down. - No.
Sit down, Madhu. - Leave me. Leave me.
Madhu, I'll hit you. Sit down.
Raja.
Driver, buck up. Drive faster.
Left. Push left.
Right. Push right.
Faster. Faster.
Oh, God. The bus is stuck in mid-air.
It's hanging over a cliff. - Shut up.
Madhu, relax. Relax.
Sit. Sit. I'm coming.
Raja. Raja. Raja.
No, Raja.
No. No. Come back. Come back.
Come back.
We're safe. We're safe.
The cliff is going to fall over the bus.
I mean, the bus is going to fall over the cliff. - No.
Let's leave quietly. Come on.
Where are both of you going? - We've reached Alibaug.
We've reached Alibaug. - Sit.
What are you doing? What are you doing?
Why are you tying us up? - Quiet.
What's the matter? - Quiet.
Leave us. - Raja. Raja.
Raja. Raja.
Raja. - I don't know why he has tied us up.
Don't go ahead.
No. - The bus will fall over.
Don't go ahead. Don't go ahead.
Saved. We're saved again.
He is tying the drape too. - Yes.
Today he is tying everything. - Yes.
But why has he doing it? - I don't know.
What is he doing? What is he doing?
Uncle, he is hanging upside down.
I think he is doing a circus trick.
But why is he doing it here?
What are you doing? What are you doing?
It's falling, nephew. The bus is going to fall again.
We're done for!
We're going to die.
Saved. We're saved again. We're alive.
He's swinging again.
Raja, this bus. . . - What are you doing?
Saved. We're saved again.
We're saved again.
What are you doing? What are you doing?
Let's go, Madhu.
He's released the girl. Now he will release us too.
Where are you going?
Raja, release me. God will bless you.
Release me. - Me too. - Release you? - Yes.
But I'll release only one person.
Release me. - No. Me.
Release me. I'm elder to you.
I'm elder to you. - Shut up. Shut up.
Shut up. - Shut up.
We'll take a stroll while you decide.
Let's go, Madhu darling. - Come.
Carefully.
He went away. All because of you.
Because of you. - Because of you. - Fool. - You're a fool.
Shut up. You.
Listen. - What happened?
Where's this bus headed to? - To hell.
Fine. I'll get down one stop before.
Don't get in. Don't get into the bus.
Hey, blind man. Don't.
Why not? Do you own this bus that you're stopping me?
I'll surely travel in it. I surely will.
Fool. - I'll surely travel in it.
Do you own this bus? - Don't go there. Don't go there.
Fool.
Is this a bus or a boat?
Come to this side. Come to this side.
I think even God doesn't want us to separate.
Okay. I'll sleep beside you.
Madhu.
''Our eyes met, and my heart started beating fast. ''
''My heartbeats say. . . ''
''. . . love you, Raja. ''
''Our eyes met and my heart started beating fast. ''
''My heartbeats say. ''
''., love you, Raja. ''
''A magic spell was cast. ''
''I'm enjoying the inebriation. ''
''My desires are not in control. Embrace me. ''
''Kiss me. Come. ''
''Our eyes met and my heart started beating fast. ''
''My heartbeats say. . . ''
''. . . love you, Raja. ''
''Beloved, I took your name in my dreams. ''
''When you came in front of me, I braced my heart. ''
''Beloved, do you know how fervent I am for you?''
''My love, now it's difficult to live without you. ''
''Love you, Raja. ''
''Our eyes met and my heart started beating fast. ''
''My heartbeats say. . . ''
''. . . love you, Raja. ''
''A magic spell was cast. ''
''I'm enjoying the inebriation. ''
''My desires are not in control. Embrace me. ''
''Kiss me. Come. ''
''Our eyes met and my heart started beating fast. ''
''My heartbeats say. . . ''
''. . . love you, Raja. ''
''Now my love will be with me day and night. ''
''My fate will be the best, different from the rest. ''
''We have together decided that we will never part. ''
''We met and the love bloomed. ''
''Kiss me. Come. ''
''Our eyes met and my heart started beating fast. ''
''My heartbeats say. ''
''Love you, Raja. ''
''A magic spell was cast. ''
''I'm enjoying the inebriation. ''
''My desires are not in control. Embrace me. ''
''Kiss me. Come. ''
''Our eyes met and my heart started beating fast. ''
''My heartbeats say. . . ''
''. . . love you, Raja. ''
''Kiss me. Come. ''
''Love you, Raja. ''
Do you willingly accept each other as man and wife?
Yes. - Yes.
Okay. Both of you sign here.
Wait.
Brijnath, don't think that I've come to stop this marriage.
I've no objections to this marriage.
I always wished for my sister's happiness, Raja.
If her happiness lies in you then. . .
. . .I'll never come in the way of her joys.
My blessings are with you both.
I have just one request, Brijnath.
I raised my sister like a daughter.
I've always dreamt of the day she gets married.
If you allow that sister to leave for her in-law's house. . .
. . .from her brother's house instead of the court. . .
. . .then it will be a huge favour on me.
A huge favour.
Mr. Rana, look. We didn't intent to hurt your feelings.
Forget whatever happened. I'll surely honour your wish.
Madhu's wedding procession will leave from your house.
I will forever remain indebted to you, Brijnath.
I'll remain indebted to you forever. - Mr. Rana.
Brother.
What have you done, brother?
You fell at their feet who are worth nothing.
What has happened to you?
Mr. Rana, don't forget that you have taken a loan worth millions. . .
. . .from me to save your business from going bankrupt.
You've promised me Madhu's hand in marriage.
If that didn't happen then the unimaginable would happen.
Are you people done?
Now listen to me.
What do you people think? I have bowed down to them?
No, Vishwa.
I've bowed down so that I can get rid of them forever.
I have disarmed the enemy by winning his trust.
Now watch how I attack him.
''At times I lock eyes. At times I steal a glance. ''
''What spell have you cast?''
''I embrace you with a fear in my heart. ''
''I'm not in my control. ''
''Without an anklet, there is a tinkling sound. ''
''At times you lock eyes. At times you steal a glance. ''
''What spell have I cast?''
''You embrace me with fear in your heart. ''
''You are not in your control. ''
''Without an anklet, there is a tinkling sound. ''
''Crazy lover, don't love me so much. ''
''I feel shy. Don't look at me. ''
''Don't argue after stealing my solace. ''
''Swear you would never refuse me. ''
''Your desires have invigorated me. ''
''I blossomed when you saw me. ''
''My heart skipped a beat when I saw you. ''
''I am smitten by your style. ''
''At times I lock eyes. At times I steal a glance. ''
''What spell have you cast?''
''I embrace you with fear in my heart. ''
''I am not in my control. ''
''Without an anklet, there is a tinkling sound. ''
''My love, you're marvellous. ''
''You're dearer to me than my life. ''
''Don't praise me so much. ''
''I know what you want. ''
''I am entranced in love. ''
''My love, it's fun. ''
''Gradually I alienated from the world. ''
''I fell heads over heel in love with you. ''
''At times you lock eyes. At times you steal a glance. ''
''What spell have I cast?''
''You embrace me with fear in your heart. ''
''You are not in your control. ''
''Without an anklet there is a tinkling sound. ''
''Without an anklet there is a tinkling sound''
Mr. Rana, all this. . . What is this?
This is a humble auspicious gift from our side.
Please accept it.
No, Mr. Rana.
Rana sir, you've given us your honour. . .
. . .the treasure of your family.
There's nothing else that we want.
I'm proud of my sister's choice.
She has chosen a family. . .
. . .that has contentment and values.
You are talking about money. . .
. . . but I'm sure to go bankrupt.
Greetings, Mr. Rana. - Greetings.
What's wrong, Ranglani. You look worried?
The problem is, the cheque of one million. . .
. . .the Sitanagar party gave us, has bounced.
I've tried calling them so many times since morning.
But they refuse to talk to me.
I think something is wrong.
Raja. You'll have to go to Sitanagar by this evening's train.
But Mr. Ranglani, I can't leave my brother alone.
It's just a matter of two days.
You don't have to separate forever.
But try to understand.
There's no one to look after brother, except for me.
What are you saying, Raja?
We are there for him.
If our relative stays with us for two days. . .
. . .then we'll get a chance to show our hospitality.
Isn't it, Madhu? - Yes, brother is right.
Madhu, you don't know. . . - No ifs and buts, Raja.
Go, and get ready to go.
Go Madhu, take him. - Let's go, Raja.
I've cleared your path, sir.
He's all yours, pounce on the prey.
Greetings, Mr. Rana. - Come Natwar, we've been waiting for you.
Brother, can he do what we want him to?
You don't believe me, sir.
I give you a small demonstration.
Look Raja, don't irritate me.
If I get angry, I'll slap you.
Amazing, brother. Simply amazing.
You've found a wonderful artist.
Listen, Natwar. - Yes.
If you do our job properly, I'll reward your handsomely.
But remember one thing, don't cross your limits. . .
. . . because that girl is my sister.
Have faith in me, Mr. Rana. Your job will be done.
And that madman, will be sent to the mental asylum.
Bravo.
You. What are you doing here?
I've heard everything. . .
. . .and now I understand everything as well.
The compromise that you made with Birju. . .
. . .was just a fraud.
But I won't let you stoop so low.
I'll tell Madhu everything right away.
Beware, if you dare open your mouth. . .
. . .then you'll lose your husband. - No.
Then keep your trap shut, okay?
Now go to sleep.
And call me if you need anything.
Madhu. Madhu.
I'm very scared of thunder.
There's no need to be scared.
Go to sleep. You'll be absolutely fine.
Relax. Go to sleep.
Don't leave me alone. - Fine, I'll sit here.
Look, I am sitting right here.
You sleep. Okay, sleep.
Who. . . who are you?
I. . . it's me, Birju. Birju.
Oh, my God.
You scared me.
What are you doing here? Go and sleep in your room.
I'm scared.
I said, go and sleep in your room.
I said I feel scared.
Madhu, I really like you.
Birju. What are you doing?
Come close to me. Come closer. - No.
What are you doing? Birju.
I. . . want to. . . touch you. . .
Madhu. . .
I want to kiss you. - Leave me.
No!
Brother.
Leave me.
Help!
Brother.
No.
Leave me.
Madhu.
Madhu. . . - Brother. . .
Madhu. . .
Brother. . . - Madhu was. . .
Brother, he. . . he. . . Brother.
He. . . he. . . brother.
Under the guise of insanity. . .
. . .you tried to tarnish the honour of your sister-in-law!
Madhu, I didn't. He escaped from the window.
I saved her. - Dare you lie.
I won't spare you. - Madhu.
You scoundrel.
Come on. - No.
Acting smart.
Do you want to kill him?
Birju. - Sister-in-law, help me.
You scoundrel, you fake your insanity, and beg for mercy.
I beg of you, leave him.
Sister-in-law, back off.
You rascal. Call the mental asylum. - No.
Ask them to take him away. Rascal.
Dr. Sinha, this is Mahendra Pratap speaking.
There's a madman in our house, creating a havoc.
Please come quickly and take him away.
Get up, get up. Take him away.
Take him away. - Madhu. Madhu.
I'm not the culprit. Don't send me to the asylum.
Don't send me to the asylum.
No!
Madhu.
Hi, Madhu. There you are.
And I've been looking for you all over the house.
Look Madhu, what I got for you.
Actually, you don't get anything in Sitanagar.
But still, I bought a shawl for Mr. Rana. . .
. . .and sweater for brother Birju.
It'll look good on him, won't it?
But where is brother Birju?
Madhu, tell me where's brother Birju?
Why. . . why don't you'll tell me?
Where's brother Birju?
Tell me, where's brother Birju?
Madhu, why are you quiet?
Why don't you tell me where is brother Birju?
For God sake Madhu, tell me where's brother Birju?
I'll tell you.
Your brother is in the mental asylum.
My brother is in the mental asylum, Madhu?
What? Who sent him?
Why did you send him to the mental asylum? Why did you send him?
He did something so cheap.
He tried to dishonour Madhu.
That's a lie. You dare accuse my brother.
That's a lie. - Have you gone crazy?
Tell me it's a lie.
Tell me it's a lie. Say it. - He has lost it.
Tell me it's a lie. - What are you doing?
Rascal.
You dare accuse my brother.
Tell me it's a lie. Tell me it's a lie.
Leave him.
Every word of what my brother said is true.
The younger brother's wife is like a daughter.
But your brother tried to violate me.
That's. . . you. . . you are saying this, Madhu.
Yes, I am saying it.
Because I was the one who was victimised.
You are committing a sin.
By accusing a helpless man of such a crime, you are committing a sin.
The clouds can shower fire.
The earth can spew blood.
The moon and the stars can shatter into a million pieces.
But my brother. . . He can never do such a cheap thing, Madhu.
He can never do it.
I'm sure someone has conspired against him.
Don't you dare try accuse my brothers.
If the other day they hadn't come on time. . .
. . .then I could have never have faced you.
Now you must choose, Raja.
You'll have to choose me or your insane brother.
Don't you dare call my brother insane.
And if you want a decision, then listen.
I can forsake many girls like you for my brother. Get that.
Go, get lost.
I don't want to anything to do with you as well.
I hate you.
See Vishwa, the brilliance of my wit.
This love story has ended forever. . .
. . .and our sister has returned to us as well.
Brother Birju.
Raja.
They'll kill me.
Take me home, Raja.
Take me home.
You'll be absolutely fine, brother.
As long as I am there, you'll be absolutely fine.
Raja, I. . . didn't do anything to Madhu.
I know, brother. You could never stoop so low.
Those rascals have trapped you.
But now that I'm back, everything will be fine.
Everything will be fine.
Congratulations, sir.
I've heard that you've sent Birju to the mental asylum.
When will I get my reward?
You'll surely be rewarded for this.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
Scoundrel ! - Raja, you.
You accused my brother.
Tell me. Tell me, what the truth is.
Tell me. - I'll tell you. I'll tell you.
Raja, I'll tell you the truth. Leave me.
Come on. Come, you rascal.
You'll have to admit your crime to Madhu.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
Give me the keys. Give me the key. - I'm doing it.
Driver, push off.
Raja.
Raja, my brother.
Madhu.
Madhu. Madhu.
No. No. No.
Do you own this your house that you're barging in? Get lost.
I want to meet Madhu. My brother, Raja. . .
Madhu. Madhu.
Save Raja. Save Raja. He has met with an accident.
Save him, Madhu. Save him.
Save him, Madhu.
Now I get why you have come here.
This is what has brought you here, right? Take this.
You can buy your brother's life with this money. Take it.
I didn't come here for money.
I have come to take you.
Raja wants to see you.
He is calling for you, Madhu.
He loves you. You're his life.
Come. Come, we don't have much time, Madhu. Come.
Come. - Leave me.
I have nothing to do with that man's life.
He has ruined my life.
Our relationship is over. Go away.
Madhu. - Go away.
Listen to me. - You madman, didn't you hear what my sister said?
Get lost. - Listen to me.
Get lost. Otherwise I'll break your bones. - Madhu. . .
You were his last hope.
You turned your face away.
Now where will I go?
What will I do?
Raja is going to die.
My brother is going to die.
Well done, Madhu. Very good. You did the right thing.
You did the right thing by throwing him out.
This is what you should have done.
You have proved that you're their sister.
You all belong to the same bloodline.
Because the filthy blood that runs in their veins. . .
. . . is coursing through yours too.
Are you mad, Sumitra?
What nonsense are you talking?
I'm not talking nonsense.
I'm speaking the truth, so that she sees your true face. . .
. . .which is hidden behind the mask of decency.
Stop yourself.
Otherwise your marriage might be at stake.
Since the origin of the world. . .
. . . men have been threatening women with the same thing.
And poor women have been enduring it quietly.
You threaten me with this bond of marriage.
So today I free myself from this bond.
Now you can't stop me from telling the truth.
Madhu, you don't know.
Your brothers have plotted a conspiracy against you. - Sumitra.
You considered them your brothers. . .
. . .and they snatched your happiness.
Sumitra, if you utter another word. . .
. . .then I will chop you into pieces.
Do as you wish, Mahendra Pratap. Go ahead.
Today I am stronger than your sword.
If you have the guts bring it down on me. Come on.
Madhu, you don't know. . .
. . .to convert their defeat into victory. . .
. . .they arranged for you to marry Raja.
But it was all a farce. It was pretence.
That night not Birju but a goon. . .
. . . hired by your brothers tried to rape you.
Not just that.
They even tried to kill Raja to save themselves.
So that his death breaks the last link of your love.
Once, seeing how much you love me, I prayed to God. . .
. . .that in every life is be blessed with brothers like you.
But today after seeing your true form I pray to God. . .
. . .that no sister has brothers like you.
And for brothers like you I rejected my love.
No. I will go.
I will go to my Raja.
You won't leave this house.
Didn't you hear? You won't leave this house.
I will go. I will surely go.
Then your dead body would leave from this house.
Leave me. Leave me.
Brother. - Let her go, Vishwa.
What? Are you in your senses?
Yes. Today I've come to my senses.
Sumitra has opened my eyes.
She has made me realise all my mistakes.
Let her go. Let her go.
You might give up.
But I won't give up in the face of her obstinacy.
I won't let her go. - No, Vishwa.
Dare you stop her. Leave her.
Go, Madhu. Go far away from selfish brothers like us. . .
. . .and don't ever come back.
Go and settle down.
My blessings are with you.
Go, dear. Go.
No. - Brother.
No. - You were leaving, weren't you? Now leave.
Now let me see how you leave.
I will. I will surely go to my Raja.
You can shoot me if you want.
No. No. I won't kill you.
But I will make you forget that loafer.
Try. You will fail.
You challenge me?
Now take his name. - Raja.
Raja. - What?
Vishwa, leave her. Let her go. - Move.
Not just once, I will say it countless times.
Raja. Raja. Raja. Raja.
Move.
I won't spare you.
I will make your plight such that. . .
. . .you won't be able to take your lover's name.
God hasn't made men strong enough. . .
. . .to break a woman's resolution.
Today you too will witness this truth.
What? You dare argue with me?
Raja.
Madhu.
Tell me. Tell me. Will you take his name?
No.
Today I will burn the body in which his love. . .
. . . is coursing like blood.
I will set you ablaze.
No. - I will burn you.
Scoundrel.
You dare hit Madhu?
No.
No, Raja. No. What are you doing?
Raja, no.
No. Raja.
No. No.
Raja.
No.
What are you looking at?
The girl is there. The fire is lit.
And today is 25th of October.
Take the nuptial rounds of the sacred fire.
The elder brother has the right to tie the knot.
No, Brother. No. No.
Help.
This is your punishment. Nobody will save you.
No, Mr. Rana. Our aim is not to kill him.
His atonement is our victory.
Look at this.
In spite of being so unjust to him, he forgave you.
Come on. Apologise to him.
Forgive me, Birju.
Brijnath, I'm your offender as well.
Forgive me too.
Today I know that marriages are made in heaven.
No power in the world can break them.
No power can break them.
I won't let you go.
I won't let you go on your honeymoon.
This is the second time that I've escaped from the mental asylum.
Now tell me. What was that thing? Tell me.
Come here.
Tell me quickly.
Look, I request you. I beg of you.
Please tell me. What was that thing?
Fine, actually. . .
Let it be. You'll get angry.
I don't get angry. I told you.
Fine. I'll tell you.
I will ask my husband, and tell you.
Ask anybody you want to. But tell me.
Raja, he is mad. Push off as soon as you get the chance.
Actually. . .
No. Tell me.
Oh, madam. . .
Cheater woman, you fooled me again.
Where are you all going?
At least you tell me. What was that thing?
I won't get angry. I won't get angry.
''Our eyes met and my heart started beating fast. ''
''My heartbeats say. . . ''
''. . . love you, Raja. ''
''A magic spell was cast. ''
''I'm enjoying the inebriation. ''
''My desires are not in control. Embrace me. ''
''Kiss me. Come. ''
''Our eyes locked and my heart started beating fast. ''
''My heartbeat said. . . ''
''. . . love you, Raja. ''
''Beloved, I took your name in my dreams. ''
''When you came in front of me, I braced my heart. ''
''Beloved, do you know how fervent I am for you?''
''Beloved, now its difficult to live without you. ''
''Love you, Raja. ''
''Our eyes met and my heart started beating fast. ''
''My heartbeats say. . . ''
''. . . love you, Raja. ''
''A magic spell was cast. ''
''I'm enjoying the inebriation. ''