1
00:01:45,410 --> 00:01:46,785
Get up.

2
00:01:51,708 --> 00:01:53,617
Mixed up in that beating on 12th Street?

3
00:01:53,710 --> 00:01:55,169
No. Plain drunkenness.

4
00:01:55,253 --> 00:01:56,961
lt says he was picked up there.

5
00:01:57,047 --> 00:01:59,882
They had him on the carpet for an hour
down at headquarters.

6
00:01:59,966 --> 00:02:02,089
He's clear. Plain drunkenness.

7
00:02:02,177 --> 00:02:03,208
All right.

8
00:02:03,303 --> 00:02:04,548
Fill it up.

9
00:02:04,638 --> 00:02:06,096
Can l keep it?

10
00:02:06,598 --> 00:02:09,552
Okay. You want to lean him
against something?

11
00:02:10,185 --> 00:02:12,510
-Stand him over there.
-Come on.

12
00:02:30,372 --> 00:02:31,534
Judy?

13
00:02:32,123 --> 00:02:34,116
We're ready for you now.

14
00:02:51,518 --> 00:02:53,060
He must hate me.

15
00:02:53,228 --> 00:02:54,307
What?

16
00:02:56,273 --> 00:02:57,981
He hates me.

17
00:02:59,442 --> 00:03:02,112
What makes you think he hates you, Judy?

18
00:03:02,195 --> 00:03:04,318
l don't think. l know.

19
00:03:06,116 --> 00:03:07,491
He looks at me like...

20
00:03:08,118 --> 00:03:10,525
l was the ugliest thing in the world.

21
00:03:12,080 --> 00:03:13,989
He doesn't like my friends.

22
00:03:14,082 --> 00:03:16,241
He doesn't like one thing about me.

23
00:03:16,877 --> 00:03:18,703
And he called me....

24
00:03:21,465 --> 00:03:23,706
He called me a dirty tramp.

25
00:03:24,843 --> 00:03:26,800
My own father.

26
00:03:28,763 --> 00:03:30,673
Do you think your father
really means that?

27
00:03:30,765 --> 00:03:32,046
Yes.

28
00:03:32,434 --> 00:03:33,632
No.

29
00:03:34,352 --> 00:03:35,811
l don't know.

30
00:03:39,483 --> 00:03:42,768
l mean, maybe he doesn't mean it...

31
00:03:43,487 --> 00:03:45,645
but he acts like he does.

32
00:03:47,032 --> 00:03:48,859
We were all together.

33
00:03:49,326 --> 00:03:52,077
And we were going to celebrate Easter.

34
00:03:52,954 --> 00:03:55,492
And we were going to catch a double bill.

35
00:03:57,334 --> 00:03:58,828
Big deal.

36
00:04:00,003 --> 00:04:02,245
So l put on my new dress...

37
00:04:03,173 --> 00:04:04,833
and l came out...

38
00:04:05,842 --> 00:04:07,965
and he grabbed my face...

39
00:04:09,012 --> 00:04:12,013
and he started rubbing off all the lipstick.

40
00:04:15,602 --> 00:04:18,010
l thought he'd rub off my lips.

41
00:04:19,189 --> 00:04:21,478
And l ran out of that house.

42
00:04:21,566 --> 00:04:24,852
ls that why you were wandering around
at 1 :00 in the morning?

43
00:04:27,697 --> 00:04:30,188
Weren't looking for company, were you?

44
00:04:31,034 --> 00:04:33,572
l don't even know why l do it.

45
00:04:33,829 --> 00:04:36,533
Maybe you think you can get back
at your dad that way.

46
00:04:36,623 --> 00:04:39,743
lf you're not as close to him
as you'd like to be...

47
00:04:39,835 --> 00:04:43,250
maybe this is one way
of making him pay attention.

48
00:04:43,338 --> 00:04:45,496
Did you ever think of that?

49
00:04:46,049 --> 00:04:48,754
l'll never get close to anybody.

50
00:04:49,970 --> 00:04:53,089
Would you like to go home
if we can arrange it?

51
00:04:57,727 --> 00:04:59,886
What's your number, Judy?

52
00:04:59,980 --> 00:05:02,553
We'll ask your dad
to come down and pick you up.

53
00:05:02,649 --> 00:05:05,484
Unless you really don't want to go home.

54
00:05:06,570 --> 00:05:08,693
Would you rather stay here?

55
00:05:17,080 --> 00:05:19,405
Lexington 05549.

56
00:05:35,557 --> 00:05:37,929
That's enough static out of you.

57
00:05:45,984 --> 00:05:48,440
Cut it out now. l'm warning you.

58
00:05:52,073 --> 00:05:54,611
You're shivering, John. Are you cold?

59
00:06:00,499 --> 00:06:02,076
Want my jacket?

60
00:06:09,549 --> 00:06:11,008
Want my jacket?

61
00:06:11,301 --> 00:06:12,676
lt's warm.

62
00:06:28,068 --> 00:06:30,144
Your mother will be down to pick you up.

63
00:06:30,237 --> 00:06:31,316
What?

64
00:06:31,404 --> 00:06:33,527
Your mother will be down to pick you up.

65
00:06:33,907 --> 00:06:35,235
My mother!

66
00:06:35,492 --> 00:06:37,401
She's being called for.

67
00:06:38,161 --> 00:06:40,368
You said you'd call my father.

68
00:06:41,540 --> 00:06:43,995
Goodbye, Judy. And take it easy.

69
00:06:44,209 --> 00:06:45,489
Oh, sure.

70
00:06:58,640 --> 00:06:59,719
John Crawford?

71
00:06:59,808 --> 00:07:01,088
Yes, sir?

72
00:07:01,184 --> 00:07:02,892
Come with me, John.

73
00:07:12,487 --> 00:07:13,602
Jim !

74
00:07:14,406 --> 00:07:15,437
Mother.

75
00:07:21,913 --> 00:07:23,372
Happy Easter.

76
00:07:26,001 --> 00:07:27,709
Where were you tonight?

77
00:07:27,794 --> 00:07:30,665
They called us at the club,
and l got the fright of my life!

78
00:07:30,755 --> 00:07:32,463
Where were you tonight, Jimbo?

79
00:07:42,517 --> 00:07:44,391
Well, then, there now.

80
00:07:45,520 --> 00:07:47,679
Were you having a ball, Dad?

81
00:07:50,066 --> 00:07:52,557
Well, everybody's been having a ball.

82
00:07:56,531 --> 00:07:58,607
You're the king of the ball, Dad.

83
00:08:06,917 --> 00:08:08,743
You think l'm funny?

84
00:08:23,517 --> 00:08:25,758
Why didn't you take my jacket?

85
00:08:26,269 --> 00:08:27,598
Jim Stark?

86
00:08:37,614 --> 00:08:38,729
John.

87
00:08:44,996 --> 00:08:48,200
Do you have any idea
why you shot those puppies?

88
00:08:49,459 --> 00:08:52,211
ls that what they call you,
or do you have a nickname?

89
00:08:53,213 --> 00:08:54,244
Plato.

90
00:08:54,339 --> 00:08:56,213
He was a Greek philosopher.

91
00:08:57,259 --> 00:09:00,959
You talk nice to the man now, hear?
He's going to help you.

92
00:09:02,806 --> 00:09:04,383
Nobody can help me.

93
00:09:04,641 --> 00:09:07,512
Can you tell me why
you killed those puppies, Plato?

94
00:09:08,645 --> 00:09:09,973
No, sir.

95
00:09:11,898 --> 00:09:13,891
Where'd you get the gun?

96
00:09:15,569 --> 00:09:17,395
My mother's drawer.

97
00:09:17,529 --> 00:09:19,403
Where's your mother tonight, Plato?

98
00:09:20,615 --> 00:09:21,647
She's away.

99
00:09:21,741 --> 00:09:24,446
Seems like she's always going away
somewhere.

100
00:09:24,536 --> 00:09:27,821
She's got a sister in Chicago,
and she's gone there for the holiday.

101
00:09:27,914 --> 00:09:29,159
Where's your father?

102
00:09:29,249 --> 00:09:31,288
They're not together, sir.

103
00:09:31,376 --> 00:09:33,534
We haven't seen him now in a long time.

104
00:09:35,005 --> 00:09:36,748
Do you ever hear from him, son?

105
00:09:36,840 --> 00:09:40,505
lt isn't right for a mother to go away
and leave her child on his birthday.

106
00:09:40,594 --> 00:09:42,800
lt's his birthday today, sir.

107
00:09:44,473 --> 00:09:47,260
Do you know if the boy
ever talked to a psychiatrist?

108
00:09:48,727 --> 00:09:50,304
You mean a head shrinker?

109
00:09:51,062 --> 00:09:53,470
Mrs. Crawford don't believe in them, sir.

110
00:09:54,566 --> 00:09:56,642
Maybe she'd better start.

111
00:09:56,735 --> 00:09:59,226
-Sit over there for just a minute, please.
-Yes, sir.

112
00:10:05,076 --> 00:10:08,113
l don't see what's so bad
about taking a little drink.

113
00:10:08,205 --> 00:10:10,363
-You don't?
-No. l definitely don't.

114
00:10:10,457 --> 00:10:11,655
He's a minor, Mr. Stark...

115
00:10:11,750 --> 00:10:14,455
and it looks to me
like he had more than a little drink.

116
00:10:15,212 --> 00:10:16,706
Don't hum, dear.

117
00:10:17,047 --> 00:10:20,131
l cut loose pretty good in my day, too.

118
00:10:20,217 --> 00:10:21,711
Really, Frank?

119
00:10:21,802 --> 00:10:22,964
When was that?

120
00:10:23,053 --> 00:10:24,761
Can't you wait till we get home?

121
00:10:24,846 --> 00:10:28,096
How about you, Jim?
Got anything to say for yourself?

122
00:10:29,601 --> 00:10:31,143
Not interested?

123
00:10:31,394 --> 00:10:33,054
Can't you answer?

124
00:10:33,146 --> 00:10:34,806
What's the matter with you anyhow?

125
00:10:34,898 --> 00:10:36,725
He's just loaded, honey.

126
00:10:36,817 --> 00:10:38,524
l was talking to Jim.

127
00:10:38,985 --> 00:10:42,568
Well, l'd like to just explain.
You see, we just moved here...

128
00:10:42,656 --> 00:10:45,822
you understand,
and the kid hasn't got any friends.

129
00:10:45,909 --> 00:10:47,736
Tell him why we moved here.

130
00:10:47,828 --> 00:10:48,859
Will you hold it?

131
00:10:48,954 --> 00:10:50,946
Tell the man why we moved here.

132
00:10:51,039 --> 00:10:53,281
-Will you hold it?
-You can't protect me.

133
00:10:53,375 --> 00:10:57,242
Do you mind if l try? Do you
have to slam the door in my face?

134
00:10:58,588 --> 00:11:01,079
l try to get to him. What happens?

135
00:11:01,675 --> 00:11:04,925
Don't l buy you everything you want?
A bicycle? You get a bicycle.

136
00:11:05,011 --> 00:11:07,337
-A car--
-You buy me many things.

137
00:11:07,430 --> 00:11:09,340
-Not just buying.
-He buys me many things.

138
00:11:09,432 --> 00:11:11,758
We give you love and affection, don't we?

139
00:11:11,852 --> 00:11:13,476
Then what is it?

140
00:11:13,562 --> 00:11:15,554
Was it because we went to that party?

141
00:11:15,647 --> 00:11:19,894
You know what kind of drunken brawls
those kind of parties turn into.

142
00:11:20,110 --> 00:11:21,438
lt's no place for kids.

143
00:11:21,528 --> 00:11:24,197
A minute ago,
you said you didn't care if he drinks.

144
00:11:24,281 --> 00:11:26,439
He said a ''little'' drink.

145
00:11:26,533 --> 00:11:29,320
You're tearing me apart!

146
00:11:29,703 --> 00:11:30,865
What?

147
00:11:30,996 --> 00:11:35,373
You say one thing, he says another,
and everybody changes back again!

148
00:11:35,625 --> 00:11:37,285
That's a fine way to behave!

149
00:11:37,377 --> 00:11:39,868
Well, you know who he takes after.

150
00:11:46,178 --> 00:11:47,636
lnside, Jim.

151
00:11:49,347 --> 00:11:50,592
Come on.

152
00:11:50,724 --> 00:11:51,922
lnside.

153
00:11:53,143 --> 00:11:55,468
-Excuse us a minute?
-Yeah, sure.

154
00:12:01,443 --> 00:12:04,278
Somebody ought to poison
her Epsom salts.

155
00:12:04,946 --> 00:12:06,227
Grandma?

156
00:12:06,781 --> 00:12:08,110
Get lost.

157
00:12:08,825 --> 00:12:11,363
Hang loose, boy. l'm warning you.

158
00:12:14,206 --> 00:12:16,282
Why don't you wash up and go home?

159
00:12:16,583 --> 00:12:18,125
This is cute.

160
00:12:19,169 --> 00:12:21,161
Big, tough character.

161
00:12:21,922 --> 00:12:23,831
You don't kid me, pal.

162
00:12:24,466 --> 00:12:27,171
How come you're not wearing your boots?

163
00:12:28,595 --> 00:12:30,255
Well, that's cute.

164
00:12:48,156 --> 00:12:50,481
lt's too bad you didn't connect.

165
00:12:51,910 --> 00:12:54,033
You could have gone to juvenile hall.

166
00:12:55,372 --> 00:12:57,199
That's what you want, isn't it?

167
00:12:57,290 --> 00:12:58,405
No.

168
00:12:59,876 --> 00:13:01,121
Sure, it is.

169
00:13:03,421 --> 00:13:05,959
You want to bug us
till we have to lock you up.

170
00:13:06,508 --> 00:13:07,671
Why?

171
00:13:07,759 --> 00:13:09,586
-Leave me alone.
-No!

172
00:13:11,388 --> 00:13:12,633
l don't know why.

173
00:13:12,722 --> 00:13:14,715
Go on, don't give me that.

174
00:13:14,808 --> 00:13:18,640
Please, lock me up. l'll hit somebody.
l'll do something, and l don't....

175
00:13:21,231 --> 00:13:22,725
Try the desk.

176
00:13:26,528 --> 00:13:27,856
Go ahead.

177
00:14:05,150 --> 00:14:08,850
ls that why you moved from the
last town? Because you were in trouble?

178
00:14:09,613 --> 00:14:11,023
They think...

179
00:14:13,116 --> 00:14:16,615
that they can protect me
by moving around all the time.

180
00:14:16,953 --> 00:14:19,954
You had a good start
in the wrong direction back there.

181
00:14:20,040 --> 00:14:21,534
Why did you do it?

182
00:14:22,292 --> 00:14:23,371
What do you mean?

183
00:14:24,461 --> 00:14:27,034
-Mess a kid up?
-Yeah.

184
00:14:31,593 --> 00:14:32,968
He called me chicken.

185
00:14:34,137 --> 00:14:35,762
Your folks didn't understand?

186
00:14:38,141 --> 00:14:39,635
They never do.

187
00:14:44,689 --> 00:14:46,978
They think that l can make friends...

188
00:14:48,235 --> 00:14:49,610
if we move.

189
00:14:53,490 --> 00:14:56,657
Just move. Everything will be
roses and sunshine.

190
00:14:57,494 --> 00:15:00,495
But you don't think
that's the right solution?

191
00:15:02,833 --> 00:15:05,833
She eats him alive and he takes it.

192
00:15:06,545 --> 00:15:08,502
Things pretty rough for you at home?

193
00:15:10,006 --> 00:15:11,417
That's a zoo.

194
00:15:11,842 --> 00:15:13,004
What?

195
00:15:14,511 --> 00:15:15,791
That's a zoo.

196
00:15:18,223 --> 00:15:21,343
l mean, he always wants to be my pal,
you know?

197
00:15:22,936 --> 00:15:25,557
But how can l give him anything if he's....

198
00:15:28,400 --> 00:15:32,148
l mean, l love him
and all that type of stuff.

199
00:15:34,239 --> 00:15:36,030
l don't want to hurt him.

200
00:15:36,700 --> 00:15:40,199
But then l don't know what to do anymore.

201
00:15:40,287 --> 00:15:41,947
Except maybe die.

202
00:15:42,789 --> 00:15:46,039
lf he had guts to knock Mom cold once...

203
00:15:46,877 --> 00:15:49,961
then maybe she'd be happy,
and then she'd stop picking on him.

204
00:15:50,797 --> 00:15:53,253
Because they make mush out of him.

205
00:15:54,176 --> 00:15:57,212
You know, just mush.

206
00:16:00,390 --> 00:16:03,474
l'll tell you one thing,
l don't ever want to be like him.

207
00:16:04,811 --> 00:16:06,092
Chicken?

208
00:16:06,646 --> 00:16:08,972
l'll bet you see right through me,
don't you?

209
00:16:13,904 --> 00:16:16,525
How can a guy grow up
in a circus like that?

210
00:16:16,907 --> 00:16:18,484
Beats me, Jim.

211
00:16:19,618 --> 00:16:21,028
But they do.

212
00:16:21,620 --> 00:16:23,280
Want some water?

213
00:16:29,002 --> 00:16:31,374
lf l had one day...

214
00:16:36,510 --> 00:16:38,917
when l didn't have to be all confused...

215
00:16:41,223 --> 00:16:44,426
and l didn't have to feel
that l was ashamed of everything...

216
00:16:45,519 --> 00:16:47,642
if l felt that l belonged someplace...

217
00:16:47,979 --> 00:16:49,604
you know, then....

218
00:16:55,862 --> 00:16:58,104
Look, will you do something for me?

219
00:17:00,617 --> 00:17:04,449
lf the pot starts boiling again,
will you see me before you get in a jam?

220
00:17:05,956 --> 00:17:09,206
Even if you just want to talk,
come on in and shoot the breeze.

221
00:17:09,793 --> 00:17:12,284
lt's easier sometimes
than talking to your folks.

222
00:17:16,258 --> 00:17:18,665
-Okay.
-Anytime, night or day.

223
00:17:23,056 --> 00:17:24,135
Okay.

224
00:17:26,476 --> 00:17:30,141
You calmed down enough
to go back in there now?

225
00:17:33,108 --> 00:17:34,436
Are you serious?

226
00:17:42,492 --> 00:17:44,200
Mother, l'm sorry.

227
00:17:44,286 --> 00:17:46,325
lt's all right, darling.

228
00:17:46,413 --> 00:17:49,829
Mister Officer,
this was all very unfortunate.

229
00:17:50,083 --> 00:17:52,206
But he made a mistake, and he's sorry...

230
00:17:52,294 --> 00:17:54,333
so we are not going to have
any more trouble.

231
00:17:54,421 --> 00:17:56,544
He was always a lovely boy.

232
00:17:56,965 --> 00:18:00,832
Grandmother, you tell one more lie
and you're going to get turned to stone.

233
00:18:04,014 --> 00:18:06,172
Look, Jim, don't forget.

234
00:18:07,267 --> 00:18:09,343
Have some cigars?

235
00:18:09,978 --> 00:18:13,312
-No, thanks. l don't smoke.
-Give them to your friends.

236
00:18:13,398 --> 00:18:14,892
No, thanks very much.

237
00:18:14,983 --> 00:18:17,189
Frank, he doesn't want any.

238
00:18:23,950 --> 00:18:26,524
Jim, your eggs are on the table, dear.

239
00:18:31,249 --> 00:18:33,657
Sit down and eat. You'll be late.

240
00:18:33,960 --> 00:18:35,123
Beau!

241
00:18:40,425 --> 00:18:42,169
Come here, Beau.

242
00:18:43,720 --> 00:18:45,298
Beau, come on!

243
00:18:46,056 --> 00:18:48,214
l don't think l want anything.

244
00:18:49,768 --> 00:18:51,048
l'm nervous.

245
00:18:51,144 --> 00:18:54,062
My first day of school,
Mother made me eat so much...

246
00:18:54,147 --> 00:18:56,270
l couldn't even swallow until recess.

247
00:18:56,358 --> 00:18:58,315
Did you fix me any sandwiches?

248
00:18:58,401 --> 00:19:01,023
There's meat loaf and peanut butter....

249
00:19:03,740 --> 00:19:06,658
What did l tell you? Peanut butter.

250
00:19:08,620 --> 00:19:10,577
There's a thermos of orange juice...

251
00:19:10,664 --> 00:19:12,906
and some applesauce cake to go with it.

252
00:19:12,999 --> 00:19:14,577
And l baked it.

253
00:19:20,257 --> 00:19:21,881
-Goodbye, Mom.
-Goodbye, dear.

254
00:19:21,967 --> 00:19:25,667
Young fellow, you knock them dead
like your old man used to.

255
00:19:27,055 --> 00:19:28,633
You know what l think?

256
00:19:28,807 --> 00:19:31,380
l feel maybe we'll stay here awhile.

257
00:19:31,977 --> 00:19:35,013
Watch out about choosing your pals,
you know what l mean?

258
00:19:35,105 --> 00:19:37,144
Don't let them choose you.

259
00:19:51,997 --> 00:19:53,491
Hi. Wait a minute.

260
00:20:03,800 --> 00:20:05,294
l've seen you before.

261
00:20:05,385 --> 00:20:08,386
-Well, stop the world.
-You don't have to be unfriendly.

262
00:20:08,472 --> 00:20:10,464
Well, now that's true.

263
00:20:10,557 --> 00:20:12,799
But life is crushing in on me.

264
00:20:12,893 --> 00:20:14,969
Life can be beautiful.

265
00:20:18,565 --> 00:20:21,317
-l know where it was.
-Where what was?

266
00:20:23,153 --> 00:20:24,612
Where l first saw you.

267
00:20:26,114 --> 00:20:28,107
Everything going okay now?

268
00:20:30,160 --> 00:20:32,117
You live here, don't you?

269
00:20:32,537 --> 00:20:33,996
Who lives?

270
00:20:34,789 --> 00:20:36,414
Where's Dawson High?

271
00:20:36,583 --> 00:20:38,410
At University and 10th.

272
00:20:39,419 --> 00:20:40,700
Thanks.

273
00:20:40,796 --> 00:20:42,954
You want to carry my books?

274
00:20:44,591 --> 00:20:46,631
l got my car. You want to go with me?

275
00:20:47,552 --> 00:20:49,379
l go with the kids.

276
00:20:50,222 --> 00:20:51,301
Yeah.

277
00:20:52,349 --> 00:20:53,677
l'll bet.

278
00:21:00,524 --> 00:21:01,603
All right.

279
00:21:03,109 --> 00:21:06,194
You know, l bet you're a real yo-yo.

280
00:21:10,534 --> 00:21:12,076
l love you, too.

281
00:21:20,585 --> 00:21:22,044
What's that?

282
00:21:24,673 --> 00:21:27,424
-That's a new disease.
-Friend of yours?

283
00:21:27,843 --> 00:21:30,512
-l'm glad they let you out.
-Nobody chickened.

284
00:21:31,012 --> 00:21:33,717
-You're lucky he lived.
-They always live.

285
00:21:33,807 --> 00:21:35,266
Man, l'm living.

286
00:21:38,979 --> 00:21:41,386
-Which way to University and 10th?
-What?

287
00:21:41,481 --> 00:21:44,518
Which way is it to University and 10th?

288
00:21:44,609 --> 00:21:47,065
-lt's that way.
-No, it's that way.

289
00:21:47,154 --> 00:21:48,185
That way!

290
00:22:47,756 --> 00:22:48,954
Watch it!

291
00:22:49,674 --> 00:22:51,466
Where do you think you're going?

292
00:22:53,094 --> 00:22:56,629
You stepped on the school insignia.
Nobody does that, ever.

293
00:22:56,723 --> 00:22:58,597
l'm sorry. lt's my first day here...

294
00:22:58,683 --> 00:23:00,842
and nobody told me about it.

295
00:23:01,019 --> 00:23:02,810
-l'm very sorry.
-lt's okay.

296
00:23:02,979 --> 00:23:04,639
-Know where to report?
-No.

297
00:23:04,731 --> 00:23:05,810
Mr. Bassett.

298
00:23:07,192 --> 00:23:09,861
Room 208. He'll show you where to go.

299
00:23:10,320 --> 00:23:11,814
l'm sorry about that.

300
00:23:11,905 --> 00:23:13,696
Just watch it next time.

301
00:24:33,236 --> 00:24:35,525
...and immensity of our universe.

302
00:24:35,614 --> 00:24:38,283
For many days
before the end of our Earth...

303
00:24:38,366 --> 00:24:41,735
people will look
into the night sky and notice a star...

304
00:24:41,828 --> 00:24:44,948
increasingly bright and increasingly near.

305
00:24:45,040 --> 00:24:47,328
As this star approaches us....

306
00:24:48,835 --> 00:24:49,950
Jim Stark.

307
00:24:51,421 --> 00:24:53,165
l'll go find a place. l'm sorry.

308
00:24:53,256 --> 00:24:56,210
As this star approaches us,
the weather will change.

309
00:24:56,551 --> 00:25:00,549
The great polar fields of the north
and south will rot and divide.

310
00:25:00,931 --> 00:25:03,338
And the seas will turn warmer.

311
00:25:04,059 --> 00:25:06,976
The last of us search the heavens
and stand amazed.

312
00:25:07,145 --> 00:25:09,601
For the stars will still be there...

313
00:25:09,773 --> 00:25:12,442
moving through their ancient rhythms.

314
00:25:12,901 --> 00:25:15,772
The familiar constellations
that illuminate our night...

315
00:25:15,862 --> 00:25:17,938
will seem as they have always seemed:

316
00:25:18,031 --> 00:25:21,447
Eternal, unchanged and little moved...

317
00:25:21,535 --> 00:25:25,449
by the shortness of time
between our planet's birth and its demise.

318
00:25:26,331 --> 00:25:27,909
Orion, the hunter.

319
00:25:27,999 --> 00:25:30,039
One of Ptolemy's constellations...

320
00:25:30,127 --> 00:25:32,119
and the most brilliant in the heavens.

321
00:25:32,212 --> 00:25:33,790
-Divided by the equator...
-Boy.

322
00:25:33,880 --> 00:25:35,672
...into two nearly equal portions.

323
00:25:35,757 --> 00:25:36,836
What?

324
00:25:38,802 --> 00:25:40,296
l was just thinking that...

325
00:25:40,387 --> 00:25:43,174
once you've been up there,
you know you been someplace.

326
00:25:46,935 --> 00:25:48,477
Gesundheit.

327
00:25:49,646 --> 00:25:52,137
They're almost equal in brilliancy.

328
00:25:53,275 --> 00:25:54,983
Cancer, the crab...

329
00:25:55,235 --> 00:25:59,861
containing a large, loose cluster of stars,
called Praesepe or the Beehive.

330
00:26:01,074 --> 00:26:02,485
l'm a crab.

331
00:26:05,036 --> 00:26:07,658
The sun can be vertically overhead.

332
00:26:11,710 --> 00:26:14,913
Taurus, the bull. An extremely ancient....

333
00:26:22,053 --> 00:26:23,678
That's real funny.

334
00:26:25,891 --> 00:26:27,515
A comedian, Buzz.

335
00:26:27,601 --> 00:26:30,471
He's cute. l bet he's real rough, too.

336
00:26:30,896 --> 00:26:32,769
l bet he fights cows.

337
00:26:36,985 --> 00:26:40,105
Sagittarius and Aries consisting of eight....

338
00:26:40,197 --> 00:26:42,070
You shouldn't monkey with him.

339
00:26:43,200 --> 00:26:44,991
-He's a wheel.
-Who?

340
00:26:45,076 --> 00:26:46,239
Buzz.

341
00:26:46,828 --> 00:26:48,204
So is she.

342
00:26:49,414 --> 00:26:52,285
lt's hard to make friends with these guys.

343
00:26:54,294 --> 00:26:57,544
-l don't want to make friends.
-...long after we have gone.

344
00:26:57,631 --> 00:26:59,707
And while the flash of our beginning...

345
00:26:59,800 --> 00:27:02,670
has not yet traveled
the light years into distance...

346
00:27:02,761 --> 00:27:07,055
has not yet been seen by planets
deep within the other galaxies...

347
00:27:07,140 --> 00:27:11,220
we will disappear into the blackness
of the space from which we came...

348
00:27:11,311 --> 00:27:15,558
destroyed as we began,
in a burst of gas and fire.

349
00:27:34,960 --> 00:27:38,163
The heavens are still and cold once more.

350
00:27:39,047 --> 00:27:42,961
ln all the immensity of our universe
and the galaxies beyond...

351
00:27:43,468 --> 00:27:45,710
the Earth will not be missed.

352
00:27:45,929 --> 00:27:47,922
Through the infinite reaches of space...

353
00:27:48,014 --> 00:27:51,597
the problems of man seem
trivial and naive indeed.

354
00:27:52,269 --> 00:27:54,973
And man, existing alone...

355
00:27:55,564 --> 00:27:58,648
seems himself an episode
of little consequence.

356
00:27:59,067 --> 00:28:02,317
That's all. Thank you for your attention.

357
00:28:03,238 --> 00:28:05,065
Thank you very much.

358
00:28:08,660 --> 00:28:11,946
May l have your attention?
May l please have your attention?

359
00:28:12,038 --> 00:28:15,787
Classes will meet at the buses outside.
May l have your attention?

360
00:28:15,876 --> 00:28:17,868
May l have your attention?

361
00:28:18,670 --> 00:28:20,378
Oh, what the heck!

362
00:28:36,271 --> 00:28:38,596
lt's all over. The world ended.

363
00:28:39,399 --> 00:28:41,475
What does he know about man alone?

364
00:28:59,169 --> 00:29:01,078
Certainly is a lot of switches.

365
00:29:01,505 --> 00:29:03,165
Yeah, quite intricate.

366
00:29:03,965 --> 00:29:05,128
What's for kicks?

367
00:29:05,217 --> 00:29:06,675
What do you say, Buzz?

368
00:29:07,177 --> 00:29:09,383
Well, what do you want to do?

369
00:29:09,471 --> 00:29:12,092
-How about Moo?
-You mean the guy in there?

370
00:29:12,182 --> 00:29:14,340
-The comedian.
-What do you say?

371
00:29:14,434 --> 00:29:16,842
All right. What do you want to do?

372
00:29:16,937 --> 00:29:18,728
Let's bring him down.

373
00:29:19,272 --> 00:29:20,980
He'd make a good pigeon.

374
00:29:21,066 --> 00:29:24,020
-What's the funny guy doing?
-The guy in back of us, Buzz.

375
00:29:24,110 --> 00:29:25,190
-Moo?
-Yeah.

376
00:29:25,278 --> 00:29:27,604
He ought to have his wardrobe
cleaned and burned.

377
00:29:27,697 --> 00:29:29,607
-All right, Moo.
-All right.

378
00:29:31,034 --> 00:29:33,525
-What are we going to do with him?
-Don't worry.

379
00:29:33,620 --> 00:29:36,158
l'll figure out what we are going to
do with him.

380
00:29:36,915 --> 00:29:39,073
Relax. He'll figure it out.

381
00:30:19,791 --> 00:30:21,285
What are you looking at?

382
00:30:22,085 --> 00:30:23,366
Nothing.

383
00:30:35,640 --> 00:30:38,974
l told you not to fool with those guys.
Now they're laying for you.

384
00:30:39,060 --> 00:30:41,931
lf you don't want trouble,
l know a place where we can go.

385
00:30:42,022 --> 00:30:43,267
lt's a big mansion.

386
00:30:49,529 --> 00:30:50,940
There it is.

387
00:30:51,615 --> 00:30:53,987
We could sneak around
and they wouldn't know.

388
00:30:54,075 --> 00:30:56,697
-Who lives there?
-Nobody lives there.

389
00:30:57,120 --> 00:30:58,449
Come on, let's go.

390
00:31:00,415 --> 00:31:01,613
There he is.

391
00:31:13,178 --> 00:31:14,756
That's his car.

392
00:32:01,351 --> 00:32:02,845
Relax, man.

393
00:33:05,707 --> 00:33:07,415
-You know something?
-No, what?

394
00:33:07,501 --> 00:33:09,374
You read too many comic books.

395
00:33:10,295 --> 00:33:14,340
Well, he's real abstract. He's different.

396
00:33:14,424 --> 00:33:15,799
That's right.

397
00:33:18,512 --> 00:33:20,054
l'm cute, too.

398
00:33:23,809 --> 00:33:25,386
ls that meaning me?

399
00:33:25,477 --> 00:33:27,019
-ls that meaning me?
-What?

400
00:33:27,187 --> 00:33:28,350
Chicken.

401
00:33:29,022 --> 00:33:30,185
Yes.

402
00:33:30,941 --> 00:33:32,649
You shouldn't call me that.

403
00:33:42,244 --> 00:33:43,702
How about you?

404
00:33:46,665 --> 00:33:48,622
Are you always at ringside?

405
00:33:49,251 --> 00:33:52,086
What are you hanging around
such rank company for?

406
00:33:56,049 --> 00:33:57,080
What?

407
00:34:00,262 --> 00:34:01,970
l don't want any trouble.

408
00:34:02,055 --> 00:34:03,633
The blade game, Buzz?

409
00:34:09,729 --> 00:34:12,220
l thought only punks fought with knives.

410
00:34:12,315 --> 00:34:13,810
Who's fighting?

411
00:34:13,942 --> 00:34:16,563
No fighting. lt's examination time, man.

412
00:34:16,653 --> 00:34:18,729
lt's a crazy game.

413
00:34:20,282 --> 00:34:21,906
Somebody get him a knife.

414
00:34:24,411 --> 00:34:25,573
Give it to him.

415
00:34:27,873 --> 00:34:29,450
Come on, give him a knife.

416
00:34:29,583 --> 00:34:32,074
-Pick it up.
-l don't want any trouble.

417
00:34:32,419 --> 00:34:33,830
Pick it up!

418
00:34:39,718 --> 00:34:40,749
Pick it up.

419
00:34:48,101 --> 00:34:50,058
Now, you understand the action?

420
00:34:50,270 --> 00:34:52,097
There's no sticking.

421
00:34:53,440 --> 00:34:54,602
Crunch?

422
00:34:58,862 --> 00:35:02,860
Just a little jabbing. That's all.

423
00:35:04,034 --> 00:35:05,742
What's the matter?

424
00:35:09,372 --> 00:35:12,955
What're you waiting on, toreador?
l thought you wanted a little action.

425
00:35:16,004 --> 00:35:18,839
-Are you crum chicken or--
-Don't call me that!

426
00:35:30,393 --> 00:35:31,508
Hey, boy.

427
00:35:34,481 --> 00:35:35,596
Come.

428
00:36:03,802 --> 00:36:06,507
Now, you cut off a button
and you get to join the club.

429
00:36:06,596 --> 00:36:08,091
That's close!

430
00:36:11,101 --> 00:36:12,263
Same place.

431
00:36:15,147 --> 00:36:17,554
Look out, Buzz. He's got a chain.

432
00:36:26,491 --> 00:36:28,033
Dr. Minton.

433
00:36:35,417 --> 00:36:38,086
All right, you asked for it, you've got it.

434
00:36:39,171 --> 00:36:41,128
-What is it?
-Trouble.

435
00:36:42,048 --> 00:36:44,884
Are you satisfied
or do you want some more?

436
00:36:50,724 --> 00:36:52,266
There's your audience.

437
00:36:52,350 --> 00:36:53,975
l don't think so.

438
00:36:54,186 --> 00:36:55,217
Let's split, Buzz.

439
00:36:55,312 --> 00:36:58,099
Split for what? A couple of old poopheads?

440
00:37:03,028 --> 00:37:05,733
You say the word, Jack, and you're dead.

441
00:37:05,906 --> 00:37:07,364
You're cold.

442
00:37:07,449 --> 00:37:10,070
l'll meet you someplace,
but not with those things.

443
00:37:10,785 --> 00:37:12,328
That's trouble.

444
00:37:15,081 --> 00:37:17,751
How then? You know the Millertown bluff?

445
00:37:18,502 --> 00:37:21,337
The bluff? Buzz, that's dangerous up there.

446
00:37:21,922 --> 00:37:24,247
Cookie, why don't you and Moose
get some cars...

447
00:37:24,341 --> 00:37:26,417
and we'll have some kicks tonight
about 8:00.

448
00:37:26,510 --> 00:37:28,170
-All right.
-We'll have a chickie-run.

449
00:37:28,261 --> 00:37:29,921
Sounds good. Fine.

450
00:37:30,013 --> 00:37:32,338
-You ever been in a chickie-run?
-Yeah.

451
00:37:32,808 --> 00:37:34,681
That's all l ever do.

452
00:37:34,768 --> 00:37:37,010
Come on, all of you. Start moving.

453
00:37:37,103 --> 00:37:38,763
Come on, get going.

454
00:37:38,855 --> 00:37:41,144
You don't mean little old us?

455
00:37:41,233 --> 00:37:44,103
What's the matter with the nice man?

456
00:37:44,945 --> 00:37:47,151
We were just cutting out!

457
00:37:48,114 --> 00:37:50,273
-8:00?
-Yeah.

458
00:37:52,369 --> 00:37:53,567
Okay.

459
00:38:04,131 --> 00:38:06,668
Plato, what is a chickie-run?

460
00:38:38,999 --> 00:38:40,161
Mom?

461
00:38:43,003 --> 00:38:45,494
Hi, Jimbo. You thought l was Mom?

462
00:38:48,341 --> 00:38:49,504
Yeah.

463
00:38:49,843 --> 00:38:53,212
Well, the girl's out.
l was getting Mom some supper.

464
00:38:53,722 --> 00:38:55,761
She doesn't feel too well.

465
00:38:57,809 --> 00:38:59,802
-What did you do, drop it?
-Yeah.

466
00:38:59,978 --> 00:39:01,520
-You dropped it?
-Yeah.

467
00:39:07,986 --> 00:39:10,026
-Listen.
-That's funny.

468
00:39:10,113 --> 00:39:13,981
-l'd better clean it up before she sees it.
-Let her see it.

469
00:39:14,159 --> 00:39:15,321
What?

470
00:39:16,495 --> 00:39:18,072
Let her see it.

471
00:39:18,747 --> 00:39:20,538
What can happen?

472
00:39:25,670 --> 00:39:26,868
Dad?

473
00:39:40,936 --> 00:39:42,727
Stand. Don't....

474
00:39:43,230 --> 00:39:45,768
l mean, you shouldn't.... Don't....

475
00:39:49,152 --> 00:39:50,730
What are you....

476
00:39:56,451 --> 00:39:57,566
Beau?

477
00:40:02,707 --> 00:40:03,905
-Daddy?
-Yeah?

478
00:40:05,168 --> 00:40:07,955
-Haven't you forgotten something?
-What?

479
00:40:10,382 --> 00:40:12,006
What's the matter with you?

480
00:40:12,092 --> 00:40:16,588
You're getting too old for that stuff.
l thought you'd stopped that long ago.

481
00:40:18,306 --> 00:40:20,216
l didn't want to stop.

482
00:40:20,851 --> 00:40:23,472
-Didn't want to stop what?
-Nothing.

483
00:40:24,020 --> 00:40:25,265
l was talking to Dad.

484
00:40:25,355 --> 00:40:27,513
l didn't kiss her, so it's a big thing.

485
00:40:28,400 --> 00:40:31,021
-Bertha, you may serve the souffle.
-Yes, ma'am.

486
00:40:31,111 --> 00:40:32,771
lt's fish souffle.

487
00:40:33,321 --> 00:40:37,153
You don't have to stand, darling.
Sit down and have your tomato juice.

488
00:40:39,202 --> 00:40:41,740
l guess l just don't understand anything.

489
00:40:42,372 --> 00:40:45,373
l'm tired. l'd like to change the subject.

490
00:40:45,917 --> 00:40:47,032
Why?

491
00:40:47,127 --> 00:40:49,250
l'd just like to, that's all.

492
00:40:49,337 --> 00:40:52,623
Girls your age don't do things like that.
You need an explanation?

493
00:40:53,592 --> 00:40:55,134
-Hi, rascal.
-Hi.

494
00:40:56,261 --> 00:40:58,467
Girls don't love their father?

495
00:40:58,638 --> 00:41:00,014
Since when?

496
00:41:00,265 --> 00:41:02,139
Since l got to be 16?

497
00:41:03,393 --> 00:41:05,220
Stop that! Sit down!

498
00:41:09,191 --> 00:41:11,183
May l please be excused?

499
00:41:15,050 --> 00:41:17,089
Hey, glamour puss.

500
00:41:17,761 --> 00:41:20,964
l'm sorry. We'll break the date.
We'll stay home.

501
00:41:21,431 --> 00:41:23,091
This isn't my home.

502
00:41:32,025 --> 00:41:33,733
l don't know what to do.

503
00:41:33,818 --> 00:41:35,692
All of a sudden she's a problem.

504
00:41:36,613 --> 00:41:39,697
She'll outgrow it, dear. lt's just the age.

505
00:41:40,075 --> 00:41:41,485
The atomic age!

506
00:41:47,916 --> 00:41:50,621
lt's just the age when nothing fits.

507
00:42:04,766 --> 00:42:06,177
Hey, Jimbo?

508
00:42:08,812 --> 00:42:10,436
-You awake?
-Dad?

509
00:42:11,147 --> 00:42:12,772
Can l ask you something?

510
00:42:12,857 --> 00:42:14,233
Sure.

511
00:42:17,445 --> 00:42:18,643
Shoot.

512
00:42:18,905 --> 00:42:21,941
Suppose you had to do something...

513
00:42:24,327 --> 00:42:26,450
you had to go someplace...

514
00:42:26,871 --> 00:42:29,197
and do this thing that was...

515
00:42:29,666 --> 00:42:31,991
you knew it was very dangerous.

516
00:42:32,919 --> 00:42:35,161
But it was a matter of honor.

517
00:42:37,632 --> 00:42:39,210
And you had to prove it.

518
00:42:40,010 --> 00:42:41,670
What would you do?

519
00:42:42,220 --> 00:42:45,589
Well, is there some kind of trick answer?

520
00:42:46,057 --> 00:42:47,931
No, what would you do?

521
00:42:49,060 --> 00:42:51,516
l wouldn't make a hasty decision.

522
00:42:52,063 --> 00:42:53,522
Tell you what, Jimbo.

523
00:42:53,606 --> 00:42:56,477
Let's get a little light on the subject.

524
00:43:05,243 --> 00:43:06,406
What?

525
00:43:08,830 --> 00:43:12,531
Jim, what happened?
What kind of trouble are you in?

526
00:43:16,546 --> 00:43:19,381
The kind l was telling you about.
Now can you answer me?

527
00:43:21,384 --> 00:43:23,507
Nobody can make a snap decision.

528
00:43:23,595 --> 00:43:26,133
lt's one of those things that you just....
You can't.

529
00:43:26,222 --> 00:43:28,262
That's all there is to it.

530
00:43:28,892 --> 00:43:31,928
lt's something that you.... You just don't.

531
00:43:35,690 --> 00:43:38,608
We've got to consider
all the pros and cons.

532
00:43:39,569 --> 00:43:41,028
l don't have time.

533
00:43:41,154 --> 00:43:42,434
We'll make time.

534
00:43:42,530 --> 00:43:44,606
l'll get paper and we'll make a list.

535
00:43:44,699 --> 00:43:47,071
And then if we're still stuck...

536
00:43:47,160 --> 00:43:49,200
we'll get some advice.

537
00:43:54,501 --> 00:43:57,122
What can you do
when you have to be a man?

538
00:43:57,212 --> 00:43:58,291
Well....

539
00:43:59,255 --> 00:44:01,331
No, you give me a direct answer.

540
00:44:01,424 --> 00:44:03,962
Are you going to keep me from going?

541
00:44:04,052 --> 00:44:06,543
Did l ever stop you from anything?

542
00:44:06,930 --> 00:44:08,673
You're at a wonderful age.

543
00:44:08,765 --> 00:44:11,682
ln 10 years, you'll look back
on this and wish--

544
00:44:11,768 --> 00:44:13,262
Ten years?

545
00:44:14,771 --> 00:44:17,523
l want an answer now. l need one.

546
00:44:18,191 --> 00:44:22,403
Listen, Jimbo, l'm just trying
to show you how foolish you are.

547
00:44:23,029 --> 00:44:26,114
When you're older,
you'll look back at this...

548
00:44:26,199 --> 00:44:28,405
and you'll laugh at yourself...

549
00:44:28,493 --> 00:44:31,198
for thinking that this is so important.

550
00:44:32,163 --> 00:44:33,990
lt's not as if you were alone.

551
00:44:34,082 --> 00:44:36,751
This has happened to every boy.

552
00:44:37,961 --> 00:44:41,626
lt happened to me when l was your age,
maybe a year older.

553
00:44:46,302 --> 00:44:47,797
What's all the excitement?

554
00:44:47,887 --> 00:44:50,461
l've been working hard
getting this house in order--

555
00:44:50,557 --> 00:44:52,134
Jim had blood on him.

556
00:44:52,225 --> 00:44:54,846
-He just ran out.
-And you didn't stop him?

557
00:45:45,820 --> 00:45:47,612
Hey, Chicken Little.

558
00:45:48,073 --> 00:45:50,149
Where's toreador? He beg off?

559
00:45:50,283 --> 00:45:52,323
He's not scared of you.

560
00:45:56,247 --> 00:45:57,528
He's over there.

561
00:46:03,713 --> 00:46:06,121
-How did you get here?
-l hitched.

562
00:46:07,592 --> 00:46:10,379
l bet you'd go to a hanging, wouldn't you?

563
00:46:10,553 --> 00:46:13,341
l guess it's just my morbid personality.

564
00:46:15,100 --> 00:46:17,341
-Should l leave?
-No, it's okay.

565
00:46:33,827 --> 00:46:36,744
Come on. Let's go see what we're driving.

566
00:46:46,589 --> 00:46:48,381
No, just him.

567
00:46:48,466 --> 00:46:50,258
lt's okay. Stay here.

568
00:46:53,096 --> 00:46:55,385
What did you say your name was?

569
00:46:55,473 --> 00:46:57,430
Stark. Jim Stark.

570
00:46:57,767 --> 00:46:59,760
Yeah, l'm Buzz Gunderson.

571
00:47:03,106 --> 00:47:05,182
l got some goodies for you, Buzzie boy.

572
00:47:05,275 --> 00:47:07,517
-You got a flashlight?
-Yeah.

573
00:47:11,614 --> 00:47:13,274
ls he a friend of yours?

574
00:47:17,829 --> 00:47:19,703
Yeah, he's my best friend.

575
00:47:21,332 --> 00:47:22,910
What's he like?

576
00:47:25,920 --> 00:47:27,498
l don't know.

577
00:47:28,006 --> 00:47:29,583
You have to get to know him.

578
00:47:30,800 --> 00:47:32,081
He doesn't say much.

579
00:47:32,427 --> 00:47:34,503
But when he does, you know he means it.

580
00:47:34,971 --> 00:47:36,465
He's sincere.

581
00:47:37,515 --> 00:47:39,259
Well, that's the main thing.

582
00:47:39,351 --> 00:47:41,842
-You want to flip?
-Yeah, go ahead.

583
00:47:44,689 --> 00:47:45,804
Heads.

584
00:47:48,735 --> 00:47:52,733
Maybe next summer, he's going to
take me hunting with him. And fishing.

585
00:47:53,490 --> 00:47:57,190
l want him to teach me how
because l know he won't get mad if l goof.

586
00:47:58,495 --> 00:48:00,155
His name's Jim.

587
00:48:00,663 --> 00:48:02,822
lt's really James, but he likes Jim more.

588
00:48:04,751 --> 00:48:07,621
And people he really likes,
he lets them call him Jamie.

589
00:48:08,588 --> 00:48:09,869
Jamie?

590
00:48:11,299 --> 00:48:12,877
Try the doors.

591
00:48:15,595 --> 00:48:18,845
-No, try it with the jump.
-Yeah.

592
00:48:45,291 --> 00:48:46,916
That's the edge.

593
00:48:48,420 --> 00:48:49,997
That's the end.

594
00:48:53,508 --> 00:48:55,050
Certainly is.

595
00:48:58,722 --> 00:49:00,548
You know something?

596
00:49:02,892 --> 00:49:04,435
l like you.

597
00:49:05,770 --> 00:49:07,229
You know that?

598
00:49:09,024 --> 00:49:10,518
Why do we do this?

599
00:49:10,692 --> 00:49:14,227
You got to do something. Now, don't you?

600
00:49:50,774 --> 00:49:52,600
Take them up all the way to the end.

601
00:49:52,776 --> 00:49:54,436
Get all the girls!

602
00:49:54,652 --> 00:49:56,894
Bring it up to the left side!

603
00:50:01,284 --> 00:50:03,111
Crunch, line them up.

604
00:50:04,120 --> 00:50:07,205
Go to the end
and bring your cars up on the right.

605
00:50:07,290 --> 00:50:09,283
Put your car on the left-hand side.

606
00:50:09,376 --> 00:50:11,783
Turn your lights in toward the center.
Hurry up.

607
00:50:11,878 --> 00:50:13,123
Let's line them up.

608
00:50:13,463 --> 00:50:14,791
Moose, come here.

609
00:50:14,923 --> 00:50:18,623
Get those guys to straighten that.
Tell them when to turn on their lights.

610
00:50:18,718 --> 00:50:22,134
Johnny, follow that dark roadster
over there.

611
00:50:34,067 --> 00:50:35,312
You're okay?

612
00:50:35,402 --> 00:50:36,600
Give me some dirt.

613
00:50:45,620 --> 00:50:47,162
Hey, toreador.

614
00:50:49,207 --> 00:50:52,125
She signals, we head for the edge.

615
00:50:53,086 --> 00:50:55,707
And the first man who jumps is a chicken.

616
00:50:55,797 --> 00:50:57,208
All right?

617
00:51:19,446 --> 00:51:20,644
Me, too.

618
00:51:23,241 --> 00:51:25,483
May l have some dirt, please?

619
00:52:05,950 --> 00:52:07,860
Hit your lights!

620
00:53:42,589 --> 00:53:44,795
-Where's Buzz?
-Down there.

621
00:53:51,473 --> 00:53:53,346
Let's get out of here.

622
00:54:00,273 --> 00:54:01,436
Down there.

623
00:54:01,524 --> 00:54:03,351
Down there is Buzz!

624
00:55:08,550 --> 00:55:10,092
This is fine.

625
00:55:21,396 --> 00:55:22,938
You'll be all right?

626
00:55:36,745 --> 00:55:38,369
You want to see a monkey?

627
00:56:12,989 --> 00:56:16,026
Want to come home with me?
There's nobody at my house.

628
00:56:16,117 --> 00:56:18,157
Heck, l'm not tired. Are you?

629
00:56:18,328 --> 00:56:21,198
l don't have too many people l can talk to.

630
00:56:21,289 --> 00:56:22,570
Who has?

631
00:56:23,124 --> 00:56:25,995
lf you want to come, we could talk,
then in the morning...

632
00:56:26,086 --> 00:56:28,125
we could have breakfast,
like my dad used to.

633
00:56:28,213 --> 00:56:30,122
lf only you could've been my dad--

634
00:56:30,215 --> 00:56:32,836
You flipped or something? Look.

635
00:56:34,844 --> 00:56:36,920
l'll see you in the morning, okay?

636
00:56:37,681 --> 00:56:40,350
l've got to pick up my scooter anyway,
you know.

637
00:56:40,433 --> 00:56:41,678
l know.

638
00:56:47,023 --> 00:56:48,352
See you tomorrow.

639
00:57:16,761 --> 00:57:18,884
Hello, little cute sister.

640
00:57:20,098 --> 00:57:23,965
Hello, darling, baby-pie,
glamour puss, sweetie.

641
00:57:27,939 --> 00:57:30,477
Beau, you belong in bed.

642
00:59:15,922 --> 00:59:17,464
He's home.

643
00:59:17,674 --> 00:59:19,085
You're home.

644
00:59:25,890 --> 00:59:28,346
You're home. Are you all right?

645
00:59:28,685 --> 00:59:31,258
Where were you? We were so worried.

646
00:59:32,772 --> 00:59:35,346
l wouldn't take a sleeping pill
till you were home.

647
00:59:35,442 --> 00:59:38,775
Can l talk to you guys?
l have to talk to somebody.

648
00:59:43,700 --> 00:59:46,369
You better give me an answer this time.

649
00:59:46,453 --> 00:59:47,828
Go ahead.

650
00:59:48,246 --> 00:59:49,989
A direct answer.

651
00:59:51,332 --> 00:59:52,910
l'm in trouble.

652
00:59:53,043 --> 00:59:56,043
You know that big
high bluff near Millertown?

653
00:59:56,129 --> 00:59:58,169
Yes, there was a bad accident there.

654
00:59:58,256 --> 01:00:01,127
They showed the pictures on television.

655
01:00:02,218 --> 01:00:03,333
l was in it.

656
01:00:03,428 --> 01:00:04,708
How? How can you--

657
01:00:04,804 --> 01:00:07,342
lt doesn't matter how.
l was driving a stolen car.

658
01:00:07,432 --> 01:00:11,264
That's a fine thing! Do you enjoy
doing this to me, or what?

659
01:00:11,353 --> 01:00:13,974
-And you wanted him to make a list.
-Let him tell it.

660
01:00:14,064 --> 01:00:16,021
-All right--
-She doesn't care.

661
01:00:16,107 --> 01:00:17,649
l don't care?

662
01:00:17,734 --> 01:00:20,106
You remember how l almost died
giving birth to him?

663
01:00:20,195 --> 01:00:23,231
-And then you say l don't care.
-Please relax.

664
01:00:30,288 --> 01:00:32,957
Dad, l said it was a matter of honor.

665
01:00:33,833 --> 01:00:35,114
Remember?

666
01:00:37,921 --> 01:00:39,712
They called me chicken.

667
01:00:41,466 --> 01:00:43,672
You know? Chicken?

668
01:00:48,515 --> 01:00:49,925
l had to go.

669
01:00:59,609 --> 01:01:03,274
'Cause if l didn't, l'd never be able to
face those kids again.

670
01:01:07,867 --> 01:01:09,943
l got in one of those cars...

671
01:01:10,370 --> 01:01:13,739
and Buzz, one of those kids,
he got in the other car...

672
01:01:13,832 --> 01:01:15,990
and we had to drive fast...

673
01:01:16,501 --> 01:01:19,502
and then jump before the car
came to the edge of the bluff.

674
01:01:19,587 --> 01:01:21,960
And l got out okay and Buzz didn't.

675
01:01:25,051 --> 01:01:27,127
-And it killed him.
-Good Lord.

676
01:01:27,220 --> 01:01:29,296
l can't keep it to myself anymore.

677
01:01:29,389 --> 01:01:31,428
You just get it off your chest.

678
01:01:31,516 --> 01:01:33,972
That is not what l mean!

679
01:01:35,854 --> 01:01:38,427
l have never done anything right.

680
01:01:38,690 --> 01:01:41,893
l've been going around
with my head in a sling for years.

681
01:01:42,736 --> 01:01:45,939
l don't want to drag you into this,
but l can't help it.

682
01:01:46,448 --> 01:01:47,990
You see, l think...

683
01:01:49,075 --> 01:01:53,986
you can't just go around proving things
and pretending like you're tough.

684
01:01:54,164 --> 01:01:55,326
That's right.

685
01:01:55,415 --> 01:01:58,665
You can't, even though
you look a certain way--

686
01:01:58,835 --> 01:02:01,504
-You're absolutely right.
-You look, you feel--

687
01:02:01,588 --> 01:02:03,379
You're not listening to me!

688
01:02:04,174 --> 01:02:06,462
You're involved in this, just like l am.

689
01:02:08,219 --> 01:02:11,505
l'm going to the police
and telling them l'm involved.

690
01:02:11,598 --> 01:02:12,878
Did anyone see you?

691
01:02:12,974 --> 01:02:16,011
-Did anyone see your license plate?
-l don't know.

692
01:02:16,102 --> 01:02:18,344
Will the other boys go to the police?

693
01:02:18,438 --> 01:02:20,312
lt doesn't matter.

694
01:02:20,398 --> 01:02:22,225
Why should you be the only one involved?

695
01:02:22,317 --> 01:02:24,309
Far be it from me to tell you what to do--

696
01:02:24,402 --> 01:02:27,107
Are you going to preach?
Do we have to listen to a sermon?

697
01:02:27,197 --> 01:02:29,355
l'm only telling him what you mean.

698
01:02:29,449 --> 01:02:32,865
You can't be idealistic. Nobody thanks you
for sticking your neck out.

699
01:02:32,952 --> 01:02:35,870
-Except to yourself.
-Wait a minute.

700
01:02:35,955 --> 01:02:37,699
Except yourself.

701
01:02:39,125 --> 01:02:41,034
-You don't want me to go?
-No!

702
01:02:41,711 --> 01:02:43,918
No, l don't want you to go to the police.

703
01:02:44,005 --> 01:02:46,792
There were others.
Why should you be the only one involved?

704
01:02:46,883 --> 01:02:50,584
But l am involved! We are all involved!

705
01:02:52,347 --> 01:02:55,514
A boy, a kid was killed tonight.

706
01:02:55,934 --> 01:02:59,184
l can't get out of it
by pretending it didn't happen.

707
01:02:59,270 --> 01:03:02,224
Well, you know
that you did the wrong thing.

708
01:03:02,315 --> 01:03:05,186
-That's the main thing.
-That's nothing.

709
01:03:05,276 --> 01:03:07,565
That is absolutely nothing.
Dad, you told me...

710
01:03:07,654 --> 01:03:11,189
you said you want me to tell the truth.
Didn't you say that?

711
01:03:15,995 --> 01:03:17,573
You can't turn it off.

712
01:03:17,747 --> 01:03:21,247
He's not saying that.
He's saying just don't volunteer.

713
01:03:22,335 --> 01:03:24,079
Just tell a little white lie.

714
01:03:24,170 --> 01:03:27,041
You'll learn! When you're older, Jim.

715
01:03:27,882 --> 01:03:31,251
Well, l don't think
that l want to learn that way.

716
01:03:31,344 --> 01:03:34,429
lt doesn't matter anyway,
because we're moving.

717
01:03:34,514 --> 01:03:36,305
You're not tearing me loose again.

718
01:03:36,391 --> 01:03:39,143
-Just why are we moving?
-Do l have to spell it out?

719
01:03:39,227 --> 01:03:42,098
-You won't use me as an excuse again!
-l don't.

720
01:03:42,188 --> 01:03:44,596
Whenever you can't face yourself
you blame it on me!

721
01:03:44,691 --> 01:03:45,889
That is not true!

722
01:03:46,568 --> 01:03:49,438
You say it's because of me
or because of the neighborhood!

723
01:03:49,529 --> 01:03:52,020
You use every other phony excuse!

724
01:03:52,907 --> 01:03:56,027
Mom, l just....
Once, l want to do something right!

725
01:03:56,327 --> 01:03:58,700
And l don't want you
to run away from me again!

726
01:04:02,208 --> 01:04:05,791
-This is all going too fast.
-You better give me something.

727
01:04:06,421 --> 01:04:08,663
You better give me something fast.

728
01:04:08,757 --> 01:04:10,583
Jimmy, you're very young.

729
01:04:10,675 --> 01:04:13,593
A foolish decision now
could wreck your whole life.

730
01:04:13,678 --> 01:04:16,679
-ln 10 years, you won't know it happened.
-Dad, answer her.

731
01:04:18,641 --> 01:04:19,804
Tell her.

732
01:04:21,686 --> 01:04:23,311
Ten years.

733
01:04:25,398 --> 01:04:27,723
Dad, let me hear you answer her.

734
01:04:41,873 --> 01:04:43,451
Dad, stand up for me.

735
01:04:54,594 --> 01:04:56,136
Stand up!

736
01:04:57,931 --> 01:04:59,176
You'll kill him !

737
01:05:02,102 --> 01:05:03,430
You're killing him !

738
01:05:03,937 --> 01:05:06,392
You want to kill your own father?

739
01:05:43,601 --> 01:05:45,808
See the way they brought us in like that?

740
01:05:45,895 --> 01:05:49,727
-Let go of me!
-You want a good crack in the mouth?

741
01:05:49,816 --> 01:05:52,188
Take it easy, Ed. The boy's on edge.

742
01:05:52,277 --> 01:05:54,850
-Come on.
-He shouldn't talk to me that way.

743
01:05:54,946 --> 01:05:57,069
After all, l am his father.

744
01:05:57,574 --> 01:05:59,862
This place appeal to you or something?

745
01:06:08,168 --> 01:06:10,837
-What's he going to pull?
-Nothing, Crunch.

746
01:06:10,920 --> 01:06:14,420
-Did you see any cops with him?
-He was pulled in like the rest of us.

747
01:06:14,507 --> 01:06:17,461
Excuse me.
Can you tell me where l can find....

748
01:06:19,304 --> 01:06:21,546
l forgot his name.
He works in the Juvenile--

749
01:06:21,639 --> 01:06:23,182
Can't you see l'm writing?

750
01:06:24,642 --> 01:06:27,134
He's going to tell, man. l know.

751
01:06:28,104 --> 01:06:29,931
Nobody arrested him.

752
01:06:30,440 --> 01:06:31,934
l think l better go home.

753
01:06:32,025 --> 01:06:33,649
Wait, man.

754
01:06:34,402 --> 01:06:36,062
We'll have some kicks, huh?

755
01:06:38,073 --> 01:06:40,860
-Crunch, my father--
-We'll bring him down.

756
01:06:41,159 --> 01:06:42,819
What do you say?

757
01:06:48,666 --> 01:06:50,244
You're going to clobber him?

758
01:06:52,420 --> 01:06:54,627
What, are you out of your mind? Come on.

759
01:06:56,049 --> 01:06:59,003
-What l could write about you--
-l remember his name.

760
01:06:59,094 --> 01:07:01,382
-What's the charge?
-Assault with a deadly weapon.

761
01:07:01,471 --> 01:07:04,674
-His name is Ray. l'd like to see him.
-He's not here.

762
01:07:04,766 --> 01:07:06,593
He's not in Juvenile Hall.

763
01:07:06,685 --> 01:07:09,888
He's on a call. l don't know where he is.
He'll be out all night.

764
01:07:09,979 --> 01:07:11,474
How old are you?

765
01:07:11,564 --> 01:07:14,316
My parents know l'm here.
They know l'm out here.

766
01:07:15,235 --> 01:07:17,773
Come back in the morning,
will you please, son?

767
01:07:17,862 --> 01:07:19,143
Well, can l wait?

768
01:07:20,156 --> 01:07:21,948
Have you ever been booked before?

769
01:07:22,701 --> 01:07:24,111
Solid.

770
01:07:52,981 --> 01:07:54,012
Hello?

771
01:07:54,441 --> 01:07:55,983
Who wants her?

772
01:07:56,609 --> 01:07:57,854
Who?

773
01:07:58,319 --> 01:07:59,814
Jim who?

774
01:08:00,321 --> 01:08:02,148
l never heard of you.

775
01:08:04,617 --> 01:08:07,025
He didn't have to hang up on him.

776
01:08:40,236 --> 01:08:41,731
Hello, Jamie.

777
01:08:42,906 --> 01:08:44,151
Jamie?

778
01:08:53,291 --> 01:08:55,082
Where'd you get that?

779
01:09:00,632 --> 01:09:02,589
How long have you known Plato?

780
01:09:07,347 --> 01:09:08,378
About...

781
01:09:10,266 --> 01:09:12,888
-Coming up, another request.
-...this morning.

782
01:09:12,977 --> 01:09:16,097
This time, from the boys
down at Anna 's Pizza Paradise.

783
01:09:16,189 --> 01:09:19,475
A new arrangement
of a great oldie in rhythm and blues.

784
01:09:19,567 --> 01:09:23,102
Jim, this is dedicated to you from Buzz.

785
01:09:41,339 --> 01:09:43,498
They'll be looking for you.

786
01:09:46,302 --> 01:09:48,544
l didn't chicken. You saw where l jumped.

787
01:09:49,014 --> 01:09:50,840
What do l have to do, kill myself?

788
01:09:51,850 --> 01:09:54,008
lt doesn't matter to them.

789
01:09:55,812 --> 01:09:58,647
Well, l guess you're still pretty upset?

790
01:10:00,775 --> 01:10:02,234
l'm just numb.

791
01:10:10,285 --> 01:10:11,613
You know something?

792
01:10:14,164 --> 01:10:16,322
l woke up this morning, you know...

793
01:10:18,793 --> 01:10:20,667
and the sun was shining...

794
01:10:21,129 --> 01:10:22,920
and it was nice...

795
01:10:23,506 --> 01:10:25,214
and all that type of stuff.

796
01:10:25,800 --> 01:10:28,801
And the first thing, l saw you.

797
01:10:32,265 --> 01:10:33,676
And l said:

798
01:10:33,767 --> 01:10:37,515
''This will be one terrific day,
so you better live it up...

799
01:10:37,729 --> 01:10:41,014
''because tomorrow you'll be nothing.''

800
01:10:42,317 --> 01:10:43,894
See? And l almost was.

801
01:10:45,737 --> 01:10:47,065
l'm sorry.

802
01:10:48,782 --> 01:10:51,237
l'm sorry that l treated you mean today.

803
01:10:52,744 --> 01:10:56,528
You shouldn't believe what l say
when l'm with the rest of the kids.

804
01:10:57,123 --> 01:10:59,875
Nobody acts sincere.

805
01:11:01,544 --> 01:11:02,707
Yeah.

806
01:11:13,181 --> 01:11:14,640
Why did you do that?

807
01:11:14,724 --> 01:11:16,384
l felt like it.

808
01:11:20,063 --> 01:11:21,854
Your lips are soft.

809
01:11:31,533 --> 01:11:34,071
-Where are you going?
-l don't know.

810
01:11:38,832 --> 01:11:40,575
We can't stay here.

811
01:11:51,136 --> 01:11:52,678
l know one thing.

812
01:11:54,848 --> 01:11:58,133
-l'm not going back in that zoo.
-l'm never going back.

813
01:12:05,775 --> 01:12:07,104
Listen.

814
01:12:10,071 --> 01:12:12,942
l know a place. Plato told me before.

815
01:12:13,324 --> 01:12:15,234
lt's an old, deserted mansion...

816
01:12:15,618 --> 01:12:17,445
up by the planetarium.

817
01:12:18,955 --> 01:12:20,948
Want to go up there with me?

818
01:12:29,674 --> 01:12:31,631
You can trust me, Judy.

819
01:12:37,474 --> 01:12:38,719
Okay.

820
01:12:56,076 --> 01:12:58,745
-What do you guys want?
-We want your friend!

821
01:12:58,828 --> 01:13:00,951
Yeah, we got eyes for him. You know it?

822
01:13:01,539 --> 01:13:04,540
-Where does he live?
-You guys better beat it!

823
01:13:04,709 --> 01:13:06,702
Where does he live?

824
01:13:07,170 --> 01:13:08,333
Tell us!

825
01:13:08,421 --> 01:13:10,959
-Leave me alone!
-Where does he live?

826
01:13:12,008 --> 01:13:13,716
Get him ! Come on!

827
01:13:17,931 --> 01:13:20,801
You know what we want?
We want your friend!

828
01:13:20,892 --> 01:13:23,098
l got it! l got his address book.

829
01:13:23,186 --> 01:13:25,143
Your friend talked!

830
01:13:25,230 --> 01:13:26,344
Now you talk!

831
01:13:26,439 --> 01:13:28,064
Talk!

832
01:13:28,817 --> 01:13:30,608
What are you doing to him?

833
01:13:33,279 --> 01:13:34,987
Come on, let's get out of here!

834
01:13:35,824 --> 01:13:37,733
-Did you get the book?
-l got it!

835
01:14:01,391 --> 01:14:04,807
Why you want to mix up
with bad boys like that all the time?

836
01:14:04,894 --> 01:14:07,895
Why you want to get into trouble
all the time?

837
01:14:09,065 --> 01:14:12,150
What are you doing with that?
John, you put that down!

838
01:14:12,235 --> 01:14:14,524
Put it down before you hurt yourself!

839
01:14:15,155 --> 01:14:16,898
l have to warn him.

840
01:14:19,701 --> 01:14:21,528
You stay home, John.

841
01:14:24,539 --> 01:14:26,033
''Bill Sibley.

842
01:14:28,626 --> 01:14:30,169
''Sam Stuart.

843
01:14:31,254 --> 01:14:33,330
''Stark. Jim Stark.'' Here it is.

844
01:14:33,423 --> 01:14:36,459
''1753 Angelo.'' Well, well.

845
01:14:43,600 --> 01:14:45,391
Frank, l'm frightened.

846
01:14:45,477 --> 01:14:47,683
-What's that pounding?
-l don't know.

847
01:14:47,812 --> 01:14:50,897
At first l thought it was Jim,
but he's not home yet.

848
01:14:50,982 --> 01:14:53,556
He's home, dear. l heard his car.

849
01:14:54,235 --> 01:14:58,103
-Well, are you going down there?
-Look, will you please relax?

850
01:14:59,449 --> 01:15:00,943
Now, you see?

851
01:15:01,201 --> 01:15:02,611
lt stopped.

852
01:15:04,496 --> 01:15:06,702
l still think you ought to go down there.

853
01:15:22,639 --> 01:15:24,098
Who's there?

854
01:15:25,517 --> 01:15:27,177
Anybody there?

855
01:15:29,104 --> 01:15:30,183
Open it.

856
01:15:42,492 --> 01:15:44,117
Who's out there?

857
01:15:45,370 --> 01:15:48,620
-Where's your son, Daddy?
-Where's your baby boy gone to?

858
01:15:48,707 --> 01:15:51,328
-We want to talk to him.
-He's not here.

859
01:15:55,755 --> 01:15:57,333
Look in his room.

860
01:16:05,181 --> 01:16:06,344
Son?

861
01:16:16,151 --> 01:16:19,105
-ls he there?
-No, honey, he's not here.

862
01:16:28,872 --> 01:16:31,541
-What are you doing?
-Do you know where Jim is?

863
01:16:31,624 --> 01:16:34,958
No, l don't know.
Do you know where he is?

864
01:16:38,506 --> 01:16:39,965
l think....

865
01:16:44,012 --> 01:16:45,803
l'm sorry l bothered you.

866
01:16:45,972 --> 01:16:48,890
Come back here. Who are you?

867
01:17:26,221 --> 01:17:27,715
Careful, Jim.

868
01:17:46,741 --> 01:17:48,650
Those noisy neighbors.

869
01:17:51,371 --> 01:17:52,746
Come on.

870
01:17:56,626 --> 01:17:58,120
Jim, it's me.

871
01:18:07,470 --> 01:18:09,463
They're looking for you.

872
01:18:10,056 --> 01:18:12,594
Everybody.
Crunch and Goon and everybody.

873
01:18:12,684 --> 01:18:13,929
We know.

874
01:18:14,561 --> 01:18:18,345
They think you told the police on them.
They're going to--

875
01:18:22,819 --> 01:18:24,313
Who's in there?

876
01:18:24,404 --> 01:18:26,729
Nobody. Just us chickens.

877
01:18:29,868 --> 01:18:30,947
Who's in there?

878
01:18:31,036 --> 01:18:32,993
Judy. Judy's up there.

879
01:18:34,956 --> 01:18:37,328
-Let me in?
-Yeah. All right.

880
01:18:37,417 --> 01:18:39,326
But your house is a mess.

881
01:18:43,590 --> 01:18:45,001
Watch out.

882
01:18:48,178 --> 01:18:50,585
-Where did he go?
-l don't know.

883
01:19:02,650 --> 01:19:04,643
Well, we're safe here.

884
01:19:05,195 --> 01:19:06,653
l hope.

885
01:19:11,326 --> 01:19:13,698
Well, what do you think of my castle?

886
01:19:14,746 --> 01:19:15,777
Wow!

887
01:19:16,956 --> 01:19:18,201
-Gee!
-Wow!

888
01:19:18,875 --> 01:19:20,618
Well now, there, then...

889
01:19:20,710 --> 01:19:23,118
l think we'll take it for the summer.

890
01:19:23,213 --> 01:19:24,790
Right this way.

891
01:19:27,842 --> 01:19:29,301
Would you like to rent it?

892
01:19:29,386 --> 01:19:33,134
Or are you more in the mood to buy, dear?

893
01:19:34,265 --> 01:19:36,388
-You decide, darling.
-Yes.

894
01:19:36,559 --> 01:19:39,395
-Remember our budget.
-Don't give it a thought.

895
01:19:39,479 --> 01:19:42,480
lt's only $3 million a month.

896
01:19:42,565 --> 01:19:43,680
What?

897
01:19:44,401 --> 01:19:45,978
We can manage that.

898
01:19:46,069 --> 01:19:49,568
l'll scrimp and save
and work my fingers to the bone.

899
01:19:49,656 --> 01:19:52,028
-You see, we're newlyweds.
-Yes.

900
01:19:52,742 --> 01:19:55,862
There's just one thing. What about....

901
01:19:57,414 --> 01:19:58,742
Children?

902
01:20:00,333 --> 01:20:01,993
Right this way.

903
01:20:02,919 --> 01:20:04,082
Yes.

904
01:20:04,587 --> 01:20:06,545
See, we really don't encourage them.

905
01:20:07,298 --> 01:20:10,383
They're so noisy and troublesome.
Don't you agree?

906
01:20:10,468 --> 01:20:13,505
Yes. And so terribly annoying
when they cry.

907
01:20:13,596 --> 01:20:16,681
l don't know what to do when they cry.
Do you, dear?

908
01:20:16,766 --> 01:20:18,973
Drown them like puppies.

909
01:20:19,310 --> 01:20:22,430
As you see, the nursery's far away
from the rest of the house.

910
01:20:22,522 --> 01:20:24,100
You forgot to wind your sundial.

911
01:20:24,190 --> 01:20:28,105
lf you have children, you'll find this
is a wonderful arrangement.

912
01:20:29,279 --> 01:20:31,271
They can carry on and you won't notice.

913
01:20:31,364 --> 01:20:33,108
A sunken nursery.

914
01:20:33,992 --> 01:20:37,776
ln fact, if you lock them in,
you'll never have to see them again.

915
01:20:38,204 --> 01:20:40,612
-Much less talk to them.
-Talk to them? Heavens.

916
01:20:40,707 --> 01:20:43,874
-Nobody talks to children.
-No, they just tell them.

917
01:20:46,921 --> 01:20:48,332
What time is it?

918
01:20:49,424 --> 01:20:51,132
Hang loose. We've got all night.

919
01:20:51,801 --> 01:20:55,420
l wonder if the maid could tell
who we were if she saw us again.

920
01:20:55,513 --> 01:20:57,091
Sure she could.

921
01:20:57,474 --> 01:20:58,884
l know she could.

922
01:20:58,975 --> 01:21:01,976
-You still want to go home, Moose?
-No.

923
01:21:02,479 --> 01:21:04,139
Then shut your mouth...

924
01:21:04,230 --> 01:21:06,353
before your guts run out.

925
01:21:09,152 --> 01:21:10,646
Quick, fill the pool!

926
01:21:16,284 --> 01:21:18,443
Let's see how long we can stay under.

927
01:21:20,246 --> 01:21:22,204
You can't talk underwater.

928
01:21:45,313 --> 01:21:47,270
l never saw you having so much fun.

929
01:21:47,357 --> 01:21:50,524
l came here a lot of times before,
but l never had fun.

930
01:21:50,610 --> 01:21:52,021
Why not?

931
01:21:52,612 --> 01:21:54,071
Because l was alone.

932
01:21:59,035 --> 01:22:00,695
All right.

933
01:22:02,539 --> 01:22:04,366
What'd you come back here for?

934
01:22:04,457 --> 01:22:07,127
Because l'd run away.
l used to run away a lot...

935
01:22:07,627 --> 01:22:09,287
but they always took me back.

936
01:22:09,379 --> 01:22:12,000
-Who?
-Mom and Dad.

937
01:22:13,591 --> 01:22:15,917
Now that l don't have them anymore,
l wish...

938
01:22:16,678 --> 01:22:18,469
l never had run away.

939
01:22:19,931 --> 01:22:21,971
l used to lie in my crib at night...

940
01:22:22,642 --> 01:22:24,434
and l'd listen to them fight.

941
01:22:25,145 --> 01:22:27,137
Can you remember back that far?

942
01:22:28,773 --> 01:22:31,976
l can't even remember
what happened yesterday.

943
01:22:33,737 --> 01:22:34,982
l can't.

944
01:22:36,072 --> 01:22:37,151
How do you do it?

945
01:22:37,240 --> 01:22:40,075
l had to go to a head shrinker.
Boy, he made me remember.

946
01:22:40,160 --> 01:22:41,239
Did he?

947
01:22:41,327 --> 01:22:45,372
Then my mother said it cost too much,
so she went to Hawaii instead.

948
01:22:47,751 --> 01:22:49,874
Well, what's your problem?

949
01:22:50,003 --> 01:22:51,960
l don't know...

950
01:22:52,881 --> 01:22:55,798
but l'm happy now. Here.

951
01:22:57,010 --> 01:22:59,133
l wish we could stay here.

952
01:23:02,390 --> 01:23:04,050
Where's your father now?

953
01:23:06,436 --> 01:23:07,811
He's dead.

954
01:23:08,855 --> 01:23:11,180
He was a hero in the China Sea.

955
01:23:14,611 --> 01:23:17,362
You told me he was
a big wheel in New York.

956
01:23:19,866 --> 01:23:21,064
l did?

957
01:23:22,369 --> 01:23:24,112
What's the difference?

958
01:23:25,080 --> 01:23:26,953
He might as well be dead anyway.

959
01:23:28,541 --> 01:23:30,166
lt's all right.

960
01:23:32,420 --> 01:23:33,701
Sure.

961
01:23:46,142 --> 01:23:48,182
l wonder how many rooms in this place?

962
01:23:49,104 --> 01:23:51,559
l don't know. A lot, probably.

963
01:23:52,148 --> 01:23:53,429
Probably.

964
01:23:58,571 --> 01:24:00,114
You want to explore?

965
01:24:42,532 --> 01:24:44,690
Must have been a nervous day.

966
01:24:45,035 --> 01:24:47,074
He must have started out nervous.

967
01:24:48,705 --> 01:24:50,697
l've done that, though. Haven't you?

968
01:25:27,577 --> 01:25:29,451
That looks like our boy's car, huh?

969
01:25:30,080 --> 01:25:31,906
Well, what do you know?

970
01:25:39,547 --> 01:25:40,662
Hi.

971
01:25:48,515 --> 01:25:50,887
ls this what it's like to love somebody?

972
01:25:51,184 --> 01:25:52,595
l don't know.

973
01:25:54,938 --> 01:25:57,773
What kind of a person
do you think a girl wants?

974
01:26:00,527 --> 01:26:02,354
-A man.
-Yes.

975
01:26:04,656 --> 01:26:07,941
But a man who can be gentle and sweet.

976
01:26:08,618 --> 01:26:10,278
-And?
-Like you are.

977
01:26:14,207 --> 01:26:17,291
And someone who doesn't
run away when you want them.

978
01:26:18,294 --> 01:26:21,414
Like being Plato's friend
when nobody else liked him.

979
01:26:22,966 --> 01:26:24,709
That's being strong.

980
01:26:29,556 --> 01:26:30,670
Wow.

981
01:26:36,187 --> 01:26:38,643
We're not going to be lonely anymore.

982
01:26:39,649 --> 01:26:41,274
Ever, ever.

983
01:26:42,277 --> 01:26:44,104
Not you or me.

984
01:26:45,447 --> 01:26:47,819
l love somebody.

985
01:26:48,491 --> 01:26:50,318
All the time l've been...

986
01:26:51,161 --> 01:26:53,284
looking for someone to love me.

987
01:26:54,456 --> 01:26:56,365
And now l love somebody.

988
01:26:58,001 --> 01:26:59,828
And it's so easy.

989
01:27:01,921 --> 01:27:03,665
Why is it easy now?

990
01:27:06,551 --> 01:27:07,831
l don't know.

991
01:27:09,137 --> 01:27:10,928
lt is for me, too.

992
01:27:12,682 --> 01:27:14,426
l love you, Jim.

993
01:27:15,352 --> 01:27:17,309
l really mean it.

994
01:27:20,523 --> 01:27:22,267
Well, l'm glad.

995
01:27:58,895 --> 01:28:00,389
Good morning.

996
01:28:15,412 --> 01:28:16,822
Let's take him !

997
01:30:29,170 --> 01:30:30,546
That's it.

998
01:30:30,839 --> 01:30:32,463
This is Unit 17.

999
01:30:33,299 --> 01:30:36,834
We just zeroed gray Ford coupe, '46.

1000
01:30:37,387 --> 01:30:41,883
Observatory Drive and Crest Place.
Looks like housebreaking.

1001
01:30:42,726 --> 01:30:45,347
Alert Juvenile and stand by to send help.

1002
01:31:10,962 --> 01:31:12,421
Save me.

1003
01:31:35,403 --> 01:31:37,063
Plato, what--

1004
01:31:40,533 --> 01:31:43,819
Why did you run out on me?
Why did you leave me alone?

1005
01:31:47,207 --> 01:31:49,614
What's the matter with you?

1006
01:31:49,793 --> 01:31:51,501
l thought you were someone else!

1007
01:31:51,586 --> 01:31:53,626
Who? Plato, it's me. Look at me.

1008
01:31:53,713 --> 01:31:55,089
What's the matter?

1009
01:31:55,173 --> 01:31:57,794
-Let me go! You're not my father!
-You crazy nut.

1010
01:31:57,884 --> 01:31:59,544
You're not my father!

1011
01:32:08,061 --> 01:32:09,436
Halt!

1012
01:32:13,316 --> 01:32:14,775
Come here, son.

1013
01:32:16,653 --> 01:32:17,767
Come here.

1014
01:32:18,196 --> 01:32:21,150
Just walk over here quietly
and there won't be any trouble.

1015
01:32:32,919 --> 01:32:34,959
You cover the house. l'll head him off.

1016
01:32:51,813 --> 01:32:52,928
Halt!

1017
01:33:25,055 --> 01:33:26,715
-Did he hit you?
-No, l'm okay.

1018
01:33:26,806 --> 01:33:28,965
-We have to go back.
-l'm going after him.

1019
01:33:29,059 --> 01:33:32,095
-After he tried to shoot you?
-Stay down.

1020
01:33:32,395 --> 01:33:35,847
He didn't mean it. We shouldn't have
left him in the first place.

1021
01:33:35,940 --> 01:33:37,055
He needs us.

1022
01:33:37,150 --> 01:33:39,985
He needed you, maybe, but so do l.

1023
01:33:40,570 --> 01:33:42,195
He needs you, too.

1024
01:33:50,246 --> 01:33:51,361
You okay?

1025
01:33:53,625 --> 01:33:54,704
Yes.

1026
01:33:54,918 --> 01:33:56,080
Come on.

1027
01:34:00,006 --> 01:34:01,548
Wait a minute.

1028
01:34:03,259 --> 01:34:05,881
You should have heard him earlier tonight.

1029
01:34:05,970 --> 01:34:08,047
He was talking about you...

1030
01:34:09,265 --> 01:34:11,638
like you were the hero in the China Sea.

1031
01:34:13,937 --> 01:34:15,135
Yeah.

1032
01:34:16,147 --> 01:34:18,519
-You know what he wanted?
-What?

1033
01:34:19,109 --> 01:34:21,185
He tried to make us his family.

1034
01:34:22,195 --> 01:34:26,323
l guess he just wanted us to be like his....

1035
01:34:38,962 --> 01:34:39,993
Halt!

1036
01:34:43,591 --> 01:34:45,299
Jim, they're killing him !

1037
01:35:19,669 --> 01:35:21,163
Come out of there.

1038
01:35:21,504 --> 01:35:23,663
You're making it tough on yourself, kid.

1039
01:35:23,757 --> 01:35:26,711
Come out quietly now.
You didn't kill anybody yet.

1040
01:35:59,417 --> 01:36:00,793
Need a little help here.

1041
01:36:00,877 --> 01:36:02,668
We heard firing. He hit anybody?

1042
01:36:02,754 --> 01:36:04,296
-Are you alone?
-Yeah.

1043
01:36:04,381 --> 01:36:07,666
We got a cookaboo inside with a gun.
He wounded some kid earlier.

1044
01:36:07,759 --> 01:36:10,676
-How did he get in?
-Smashed the front door.

1045
01:36:10,762 --> 01:36:13,335
-ls there another entrance?
-Down in back.

1046
01:36:14,516 --> 01:36:15,796
Seal him off.

1047
01:36:21,398 --> 01:36:23,224
l don't understand.

1048
01:36:25,068 --> 01:36:27,107
You pray for your children.

1049
01:36:27,445 --> 01:36:31,313
You read about things like this
happening to other families...

1050
01:36:33,743 --> 01:36:36,317
but you never dream
it could happen to yours.

1051
01:36:36,413 --> 01:36:37,693
The Observatory.

1052
01:36:38,206 --> 01:36:42,038
Five housebreaking in area.
Right. We'll proceed. Over.

1053
01:36:43,545 --> 01:36:45,621
There are some other kids in trouble.

1054
01:36:46,423 --> 01:36:47,881
You'll have to go with me.

1055
01:36:47,966 --> 01:36:50,089
Sure. That's all right.

1056
01:36:55,765 --> 01:36:57,425
Lieutenant says seal him off.

1057
01:37:16,536 --> 01:37:17,947
-Hello, Ray.
-Hi.

1058
01:37:18,121 --> 01:37:19,829
You know anything about this?

1059
01:37:19,914 --> 01:37:21,077
No more than you do.

1060
01:37:21,166 --> 01:37:23,289
There's a kid in there with a gun.

1061
01:37:23,376 --> 01:37:26,461
He wounded another kid
and took a shot at an officer.

1062
01:37:26,963 --> 01:37:29,999
-You got a speaker?
-Yeah, help yourself.

1063
01:37:33,553 --> 01:37:36,803
-What's going on?
-Some kid's in trouble. Stay back.

1064
01:37:36,890 --> 01:37:40,093
l got to know. My boy ran off tonight
and he got a gun, too.

1065
01:37:40,185 --> 01:37:41,928
All right. Lieutenant!

1066
01:37:42,479 --> 01:37:45,148
l'm addressing the boy in the planetarium.

1067
01:37:45,231 --> 01:37:47,105
l'm speaking to the boy inside.

1068
01:37:47,984 --> 01:37:50,558
This is Ray Frameck
from the Juvenile Division.

1069
01:37:51,571 --> 01:37:53,528
Armed police are outside.

1070
01:37:54,074 --> 01:37:57,822
Whoever you are,
drop your weapon and come out.

1071
01:37:59,579 --> 01:38:00,990
Come outside.

1072
01:38:01,664 --> 01:38:05,876
Clasp your hands over your head
and come outside quietly.

1073
01:38:08,838 --> 01:38:10,036
Mr. Stark.

1074
01:38:10,131 --> 01:38:11,412
Frank!

1075
01:38:14,844 --> 01:38:16,636
-That's my son.
-What?

1076
01:38:19,557 --> 01:38:21,135
Hold your fire!

1077
01:38:24,688 --> 01:38:25,802
Are you sure?

1078
01:38:26,481 --> 01:38:28,141
l think l know my son.

1079
01:38:32,237 --> 01:38:36,187
Officers, another boy and girl
just ran into the planetarium.

1080
01:38:36,700 --> 01:38:38,443
We don't know if they're armed.

1081
01:38:38,535 --> 01:38:41,536
Hold your positions
until further instructions.

1082
01:38:42,455 --> 01:38:45,622
Another boy and girl just ran
into the planetarium.

1083
01:38:45,917 --> 01:38:47,874
We don't know if they're armed.

1084
01:38:48,211 --> 01:38:51,545
Hold your positions
until further instructions.

1085
01:38:51,923 --> 01:38:54,628
Plato? You in there?

1086
01:38:55,677 --> 01:38:58,002
You're my friend, Plato.

1087
01:38:58,972 --> 01:39:00,929
That means a lot to me.

1088
01:39:02,809 --> 01:39:05,015
l'm going to open the door now.

1089
01:39:15,405 --> 01:39:17,563
You can shoot me if you want to.

1090
01:39:19,909 --> 01:39:20,989
Okay?

1091
01:39:26,041 --> 01:39:28,033
Boy, l'm blind as a bat.

1092
01:39:28,418 --> 01:39:29,793
You got a match?

1093
01:39:33,256 --> 01:39:36,091
l'll break my neck in here. Where are you?

1094
01:39:37,761 --> 01:39:39,171
l've got a gun.

1095
01:39:42,265 --> 01:39:43,676
Yeah, l know.

1096
01:39:47,354 --> 01:39:51,019
-Light a match, will you?
-No.

1097
01:39:53,485 --> 01:39:54,683
How are you?

1098
01:39:56,154 --> 01:39:58,941
-l'm fine.
-That's fine.

1099
01:40:08,583 --> 01:40:12,284
Do you think the end of the world
will come at nighttime?

1100
01:40:16,591 --> 01:40:17,836
At dawn.

1101
01:40:25,600 --> 01:40:26,845
Where are you?

1102
01:40:34,484 --> 01:40:37,319
What are you hiding for? Just stand up.

1103
01:40:38,446 --> 01:40:41,068
How can l talk to you if l can't see you?

1104
01:40:42,450 --> 01:40:45,024
l can't talk to you if l can't see you.

1105
01:40:46,037 --> 01:40:47,662
Come on, stand up.

1106
01:40:48,415 --> 01:40:51,499
You've seen this show before. Come on.

1107
01:40:53,670 --> 01:40:55,497
Do you see that star up there?

1108
01:40:57,549 --> 01:40:58,829
Stand up. Look at it.

1109
01:41:00,885 --> 01:41:04,717
l can't talk to you if l can't see you.
That's all there is to it.

1110
01:41:16,276 --> 01:41:19,027
l'm not going to hurt you
or anything like that.

1111
01:41:26,536 --> 01:41:28,576
Why did you run out on me?

1112
01:41:30,874 --> 01:41:32,582
We didn't run out on you.

1113
01:41:33,460 --> 01:41:35,666
We were coming right back, l told you.

1114
01:41:35,754 --> 01:41:37,034
You sure?

1115
01:41:38,423 --> 01:41:40,214
Sure, l'm sure.

1116
01:41:42,135 --> 01:41:43,415
Judy's here.

1117
01:41:44,387 --> 01:41:46,380
She's waiting. Come on.

1118
01:41:47,724 --> 01:41:48,922
Come on.

1119
01:41:52,020 --> 01:41:54,427
No? Not ready to come out yet?

1120
01:41:55,982 --> 01:41:57,061
No?

1121
01:41:58,943 --> 01:42:00,058
Okay.

1122
01:42:02,906 --> 01:42:05,741
Promise you, nothing will happen
if you do.

1123
01:42:05,825 --> 01:42:06,905
No.

1124
01:42:08,453 --> 01:42:09,912
Are you cold?

1125
01:42:10,747 --> 01:42:11,826
Here.

1126
01:42:15,251 --> 01:42:17,043
lt's warm. Here.

1127
01:42:17,921 --> 01:42:19,795
My jacket. lt's warm.

1128
01:42:21,925 --> 01:42:23,467
Can l keep it?

1129
01:42:23,551 --> 01:42:25,793
Well, what do you think? Here.

1130
01:42:30,475 --> 01:42:33,096
Now can l have the gun, Plato?

1131
01:42:33,228 --> 01:42:34,888
You want to give it to me?

1132
01:42:36,940 --> 01:42:39,063
-My gun?
-Yeah. ln your pocket.

1133
01:42:39,275 --> 01:42:40,474
Give it to me.

1134
01:42:48,118 --> 01:42:49,280
No.

1135
01:42:50,787 --> 01:42:52,281
No, l need it.

1136
01:42:56,626 --> 01:42:58,535
Don't you trust me, Plato?

1137
01:43:01,089 --> 01:43:03,212
Just give it to me for a second.

1138
01:43:12,308 --> 01:43:14,634
Been carrying this around all day?

1139
01:43:22,819 --> 01:43:24,147
Now there's...

1140
01:43:26,281 --> 01:43:28,108
a lot of people out front.

1141
01:43:30,869 --> 01:43:32,446
You promised to give it back.

1142
01:43:34,497 --> 01:43:36,656
Friends always keep their promises.

1143
01:43:41,588 --> 01:43:42,833
These people...

1144
01:43:44,674 --> 01:43:48,672
you know, all of them, every one of them
want to see that you're safe.

1145
01:43:49,346 --> 01:43:51,053
You understand that?

1146
01:43:51,514 --> 01:43:53,306
They want you to be safe.

1147
01:43:56,019 --> 01:43:57,264
Here.

1148
01:43:57,771 --> 01:44:02,018
They said l could come in here,
and l could bring you out and--

1149
01:44:02,192 --> 01:44:03,271
Why?

1150
01:44:04,903 --> 01:44:06,017
Why?

1151
01:44:07,155 --> 01:44:10,524
Because they like you. Okay?

1152
01:44:13,203 --> 01:44:14,863
-Come on.
-Yeah.

1153
01:44:26,883 --> 01:44:28,840
-Hi, Plato.
-Hi.

1154
01:44:32,514 --> 01:44:34,056
lt's too bright.

1155
01:44:35,558 --> 01:44:36,638
Yeah.

1156
01:44:37,811 --> 01:44:40,218
Okay. l'll fix it.

1157
01:44:54,536 --> 01:44:57,027
ls Ray Frameck still out there?

1158
01:44:58,289 --> 01:44:59,832
Yes, l'm here.

1159
01:45:01,084 --> 01:45:03,207
Turn out those lights!

1160
01:45:03,753 --> 01:45:05,545
lf you do, we'll come out!

1161
01:45:05,630 --> 01:45:07,872
Okay. Turn your lights out.

1162
01:45:16,766 --> 01:45:18,391
See? Come on.

1163
01:45:29,779 --> 01:45:30,942
Who's that?

1164
01:45:32,240 --> 01:45:34,612
-Just a guy.
-l shot at one of them.

1165
01:45:34,701 --> 01:45:36,693
lt's all right. You didn't hurt him.

1166
01:45:36,786 --> 01:45:39,573
-Those are not my friends.
-Now look.

1167
01:45:39,664 --> 01:45:41,491
Make them go away.

1168
01:45:43,960 --> 01:45:47,828
You want me to make them go away?
You want me to fix it? Okay.

1169
01:45:53,762 --> 01:45:56,300
Ray, can you make those guys get back?

1170
01:45:56,473 --> 01:45:59,177
You don't have to worry
about anything. Here.

1171
01:45:59,267 --> 01:46:00,726
Keep the guys back.

1172
01:46:02,354 --> 01:46:04,346
That other kid still has a gun.

1173
01:46:06,858 --> 01:46:07,937
No!

1174
01:46:08,485 --> 01:46:10,976
Don't turn on the lights. lt's too bright.

1175
01:46:11,071 --> 01:46:13,478
Plato doesn't.... Turn out the lights!

1176
01:46:23,833 --> 01:46:24,948
John!

1177
01:46:26,586 --> 01:46:28,377
l got the bullets!

1178
01:46:29,255 --> 01:46:30,833
Look!

1179
01:46:35,095 --> 01:46:36,470
Let him alone.

1180
01:46:36,554 --> 01:46:38,298
Who are you? What do you want?

1181
01:46:39,057 --> 01:46:41,630
lt's all right, fellas.
lt's all right, Lieutenant.

1182
01:46:44,521 --> 01:46:46,348
Get the stretcher in here.

1183
01:46:46,439 --> 01:46:48,348
For a minute there....

1184
01:46:48,441 --> 01:46:51,727
When l saw that red jacket, l thought....

1185
01:47:02,622 --> 01:47:04,164
Hey, jerkpot...

1186
01:47:05,875 --> 01:47:07,453
what'd you do that for?

1187
01:47:15,885 --> 01:47:17,843
You can't help it, Son.

1188
01:47:17,929 --> 01:47:20,135
You did everything a man could.

1189
01:47:34,237 --> 01:47:35,565
Look at that.

1190
01:47:44,914 --> 01:47:46,706
Help me.

1191
01:47:50,128 --> 01:47:52,085
You can depend on me.

1192
01:47:52,255 --> 01:47:53,536
Trust me.

1193
01:47:55,258 --> 01:47:58,342
Whatever comes, we'll face it together.

1194
01:47:58,803 --> 01:48:00,345
l swear it.

1195
01:48:02,724 --> 01:48:05,179
Now, Jim, stand up.

1196
01:48:06,936 --> 01:48:08,728
l'll stand up with you.

1197
01:48:09,439 --> 01:48:12,938
l'll try and be as strong
as you want me to be. Come on.

1198
01:48:45,141 --> 01:48:49,388
This poor baby got nobody. Just nobody.

1199
01:49:18,675 --> 01:49:20,502
He's always cold.

1200
01:49:33,523 --> 01:49:34,686
Mom.

1201
01:49:36,401 --> 01:49:37,480
Dad.

1202
01:49:39,237 --> 01:49:40,696
This is Judy.

1203
01:49:41,364 --> 01:49:43,024
She's my friend.

1204
01:50:02,510 --> 01:50:03,708
He's--

