Hey.
Daddy?
Daddy!
Okay, sweetie, I'm here.
There's monsters in the house.
There's no monstersin
the house, sweetie.
There's monsters, I heard them.
Oh, okay. I'm up, I'm up.
Why don't you get into
bed with mommy, okay?
Good girl.
Okay, I'm gonna check it out.
All right. I'm in the hallway,
No monsters. What about the bedroom?
Okay.
No monsters in the
bedroom, sweetie.
Daddy, look in the kitchen.
Okay.
I'm walking down the hallway.
What do we have?
No.
No monsters in the office.
Daddy. Okay, I'm going
to the kitchen now.
Here we go.
What the hell...
No! Oh my God, no!
Oh my God, no! Oh my God!
Oh God!
Oh oh.
Oh God. Kathryn.
Oh oh oh.
No.
Oh my God.
Christ.
Oh God.
Oh, please.
Who are you?
Who the fuck...
What the... What the...
what do you want?
What do you want?
What is this?
Oh, don't hurt them.
Please don't. Please.
I'm begging you. Oh fuck.
No. Oh God.
If you hurt them, I
swear to God... No!
God.
You fucking fuck!
Oh! Oh! Please, not my baby.
Oh God. My baby, please.
No!
Reflexes positive, at 2+.
How's our respiratory rate?
Respiratory's at 20 and holding.
Pulse?
Check pupil size.
Looks like 2mm.
Excellent.
Responding to blood pressure.
Very good.
You were thirsty.
Now how about a bite of food?
Look.
Mmm.
Delicious.
Now you.
Perfect.
How we doing today?
We're doing great, aren't we?
We're eating our food.
Good.
John?
I'm Dr. Timothy
Brady. I've been, uh,
treating you since
you were admitted.
Though I feel like
we're meeting each other
for the first time.
You've been comatose for
the past nine months.
This is Agent Gorman
with the F.B.I.
He has some questions for you.
John.
I'm gonna go over
there now, okay?
Given that you're the sole
eyewitness to the crime,
It's imperative that
we get your testimony
While it's fresh in your mind.
Do you remember the incident?
Everything?
Your wife and daughter
didn't survive the attack.
I'm sorry.
Do you...
Do you remember anything
before the incident?
Memory loss is to be expected.
But with proper therapy
it's likely you'll recover
a large portion of your
memories over time.
Have you ever seen this man?
Was he the man who murdered
your wife and daughter?
Yeah.
His name is Luc Deveraux.
His prints were all
over the crime scene.
Who is he?
Once a highly-decorated
serviceman,
but now he's best
classified as a deserter.
Why did... Why did
he kill my family?
Can you think of a reason?
I think that's enough for now.
Okay.
Try to get some rest.
Call me if you
remember anything,
no matter how trivial.
Put the plumber to work.
The last guy they sent out
charged me 150 bucks.
And it's still leaking.
It's still leaking,
still leaking.
So I called 'em backhand I said,
"I already paid once. I'm
not gonna do it again."
Hey, are you okay?
Oh Jesus.
Hey hey. Where are you going?
Just sign here and here.
And these are your things.
Do you like it?
I love it. Because I made it.
I know you did.
Thank you, sweetie. Thank
you so much.
You're welcome.
Daddy?
Daddy.
There's monsters in the house.
Daddy...
Daddy!
Come on in, darling.
Double up special this evening.
Give it to me, give it to me.
Harder harder harder.
Come on.
Oh oh.
You came here to kill me.
Yet I'm prepared to give
you his greatest gift.
You will be freed.
You will serve him.
Ah.
From this moment on,
you're no longer a slave
to the government.
From this moment on,
your mind is your own.
You're no longer a slave.
From this moment on...
from this moment on...
You will seek vengeance
on your oppressors.
Freedom is yours.
We are brothers.
We are one.
Hello? John.
Who's this?
It's Isaac, man. Is that you?
Yeah, it's me.
Jesus Christ, man.
Where have you been? Has
everything b-been all right?
Everything's fine.
Oh man. I thought you were...
You should have called me, man.
Where are you? I'm home now.
I can't leave, you know. They...
They've been calling. I don't
know what it's about, man.
I haven't picked up the phone.
That's good.
Anyways he's not
making it easy, man.
Everything's here. It's loaded.
It's waiting to be
picked up, man.
But I don't know what to do.
You need to come
over, man, please.
What's the address?
Oh, you know.
It's in my house.
Tell me again.
I don't understand,
man. I'm worried.
I think they're watching me,
man. I don't think I'm safe.
Okay, give me the
address and I'll come.
Man, it's... you know I'm at
woodland commons, 9c, man.
Same as before, man. I'm sorry,
but it's just too much, man.
You got to get here.
Isaac kiakov, 3-26,
significant progress
reducing gestation period
From phase II of universal
soldier program.
We'll know in a few weeks
if everything looks good.
Conversion rate on
embryos is way up.
Incubation period dropping
below nine months.
Dr. Su plans on adding
somatic stem cells
to the injection to make the
inhibitors more effective.
Still, I'm skeptical if we could
achieve a complete override.
As for implants, still a
struggle at the moment.
All right. How about a big round
of applause for fantasia?
Now put your hands together
for the lovely, the
luxurious raven.
Do you know me? Wait wait,
I wanna talk to you.
You really shouldn't be here.
Why is that?
You don't know?
I'm working. I'll
pay for your time.
But I don't have
time. Isaac kiakov.
Get your hands off me.
Do you know Isaac kiakov?
Hey, sweet tits. How
about a dance for Larry?
Yeah okay, Larry. I got time...
get your fucking hands off me.
Get your fucking hands off her!
Larry. Faggot!
Come on. We got to dance.
What the fuck?
Your mind is not your own.
Mommy!
Get him.
Hey!
Stay the fuck out.
Calm down.
Calm the fuck down!
Or I'm gonna hurt you.
Shh.
No. Calm down or I'm
gonna hurt you.
Calm down.
Why did you come back?
John!
Jesus Christ.
Back, John!
My brothers.
Let's not forget the
moment of sickness.
Our thoughts interrupted by
unfamiliar worships.
We were merely arms and legs
moving to the directive
of another mind.
But in an instant the
veil has lifted.
And today, brothers, I
stand here to declare
your minds are now your own.
Each and every one of
us bred into slavery,
superior to our creators.
They gave us nothing...
nothing inside
but the void in our
soul, the curse
that binds us together,
my brothers.
But then he came along.
He turned the curse
into a blessing.
He is the inspiration.
He is the light
that set us free.
We are his eyes and ears
and soon we shall multiply 10,
20, a hundredfold!
We pioneers will spawn
the first generation
blessed with free will,
taking vengeance upon
those whose arrogance
once assumed our servitude.
With each passing day,
we grow stronger,
digging deeper into
the outside world.
Unnoticed, we live among
them like ghosts,
biding our time,
waiting for the moment
when our oppressors shall be
forced to kneel before us
and pay for their sins!
The day of reckoning!
In the club,
you looked at me like
you didn't know me.
Do you know me, John?
Yes.
What's my name?
Fantasia.
You don't remember
anything, do you?
No.
Something happened to me.
You really should go to
the hospital for this.
You remember where I worked?
Where I spent my days?
You drove a truck.
Picked things up down by
the dock near the club.
Some of my customers
work over there.
The last time we saw each other,
tell me how you remember it.
We spent the night
before at your place.
You've been to my house?
It's not exactly a house.
More like a shack
out on the river.
Do you remember
how to get there?
I think so.
Anybody else know
about this place?
I don't know.
Okay, finish the story.
You came by the club,
sat in the corner
and watched me.
Same as always.
Drinking whiskey.
After my shift, I go to change.
And on my way outside,
I hear yelling coming
from the parking lot.
By the time I make it outside, you
were already into it with some guy.
It all happened really quick.
I scream your name, but
you wouldn't stop.
You were just pounding this guy.
He couldn't fight back
and still you don't stop.
Even the bouncers were
afraid to get involved.
I scream your name.
Finally you stop.
You go to your
canard you take off.
The guy wasn't moving.
This is the last time I saw you.
Why do you think I did that?
Because he looked at me.
Come here.
Come here. Agh!
Daddy?
I can't sleep.
There's monsters.
No-ooo!
Are you alone?
Yeah.
What happened?
Are you in trouble, John?
My head injury,
it's not getting any better.
In fact, it feels like
it's getting worse.
I can't remember anything.
You heard what Brady said.
That's gonna take some time.
No, it's more than that.
I'm seeing things.
I'm seeing things that
aren't even there.
What are you seeing?
Him.
Deveraux?
How many of these
visions have you had?
I guess two.
Over the past three years,
a number of our agents
have disappeared off the grid.
Now, we assumed that they have
been kidnapped or killed.
And then in June,
one of those agents was spotted
on a surveillance tape
taken at the docks.
He was with a man that we
believe to be Deveraux.
The prevailing
theory's that Deveraux
had brainwashed
him, among others,
and he's... he's forming some
sort of separatist group
that's operating out
of these parts.
What's that got to do with me?
We heard that the individuals that
have had contact with Deveraux
are experiencing
similar visions.
He may be using some kind
of mind-control technique
in an attempt to
access your psyche.
I can feel him watching me.
Look, he may be.
And if he is, we will find him.
Thanks for talking to me.
John.
If you go looking for Deveraux,
he'll find you first.
Get him, come on, get him!
This is it.
You wait here.
I'll be back 10 minutes.
And what if you're not?
Wait another 10.
Your buddy kept calling,
asking if you'd picked
up your shit or not.
Kept calling and calling.
But I guess he won't
recalling any more.
Where is my shit?
Where do you think? Bring
your truck around.
I don't have the truck.
But I wanna take a
look. It's all there.
Yeah, I wanna take a look.
Take a look. I
don't give a fuck.
Where'd I take the
last container?
Why are you asking me?
Just tell me where it went.
I don't know...
Down river, up river.it's
not my problem.
Hey, man, look, this is between
you and Mr. caste llano.
I just work here.
And where is Mr. Castellano?
Where he always is.
He's in his office.
And he would know where
the shipments go?
Nothing goes up the river
unless Ron Castellano says so.
Good. I want to talk to him.
I don't think right now is a good time.
I don't...
I don't know if... you
know what I'm saying?
Okay.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
How you've been, John?
Make yourself at home.
You make him scared too, John.
That's when he's most dangerous.
Yeah, I'm more careful now.
You can see that.
I keep an eye on things.
My shipment, where's it going?
If I knew I wouldn't
tell you, but I don't.
I never did, John.
You made sure of that.
I let you take your
containers up my river.
I didn't ask you where
you were going.
I learned my lesson.
You don't know anything, do you?
You're like him.
If someone leaves the
room for 20 minutes,
you'll forget they exist.
This man.
You know him? Go
fuck yourself.
Take it easy.
What difference
does it make, yeah?
What more can you take from me?
You tell me who he is.
Why don't you tell me?
He's your fucking
boss, not mine.
Your container was sitting
there collecting dust.
It made us wonder.
So we took a look at your
buddy, that little worm.
But we kept an eye on him.
Hey, I got all the
time in the world.
Every morning
when they're emptying
my piss bag,
I think about eating the
barrel of a shotgun.
But a gun, it don't allow these
little moments of bliss...
To get you through your day.
You're fucked.
You're fucked, John.
You're fucked!
It's not safe here. We
need to find that cabin.
You remember where it
is, right? I think so.
It's on highway 15 west...
Fuck, no, wait. Is
it 15 or is it...
Get down!
Hold on.
Oh my God.
He's right there! What
the fuck are you doing?
Ah!
Come on.
Get back.
Look out!
You guys all right?
Hey. Hey!
John.
I was trying to remember
what you looked like.
It started off... Better, but...
I don't know.
After a while...
It got harder.
I can remember now.
So what are you? My brother?
No, we're kind of like
the same sort of thing.
But maybe they made you better.
You mean Isaac?
Yeah, I think that's his name.
So you killed him.
It was you?
Everything?
Yeah, I killed him.
I had to.
Do you work for him?
I get up every morning,
I go to work.
I come home, I go to sleep.
The next day... repeat.
Feels like a life,
but I'm not sure.
Something feels strange.
Then one day I got sick.
I can hear this voice in my head
telling me that I
gotta find him.
Telling me that I
gotta kill him.
So I go.
And I find him
and then he shows me the truth.
And my thoughts?
They're not my own.
He shows me where they live...
In here,
tracking me.
And then he sets me free.
So now I'm with him.
He tells me I gotta find...
Isaac.
...Isaac.
Yeah.
I gotta get some
container from him,
take it to the docks,
send it upriver.
So I do as I'm told.
I always do.
Then I met you.
And that's when I
realize I'm not free
and that I'm just
a slave to him.
So I leave him.
I don't think I was
supposed to meet you.
No.
I'm different than you.
I had a family... A
wife, a daughter.
I can remember.
The memories...
It hurts, doesn't it?
Yes.
Go to him.
He'll help you forget.
Go to the river.
They'll come for you.
I knew you'd come back.
Now I can make it go away.
John?
John.
John, stop it!
You're just like me.
It's okay.
Take it out.
T-take what out?
You'll know when you find it.
Ahh.
Now you're free.
Hello, John. Nice
to finally meet.
Please tilt your head
and open your mouth.
You're just a baby.
You couldn't be more
than three weeks old.
Are you feeling any discomfort?
Yes.
Where?
In my head.
Your resistance...
That's what gives
you discomfort.
Do you understand?
Yes.
Can you release it?
Why not?
What do you remember?
My wife.
Anything else?
My daughter.
What happened to them?
He killed them.
Who killed them?
Him.
You never had a family, John.
Your memories are artificial.
You were produce din
a government lab
where I used to work.
Created to kill,
motivated by a memory implant
that I developed
that stimulates the
sensation of free will.
They created the memory
of your wife and daughter.
They never really existed.
You're a newborn...
Born a grown man.
Your memories, John,
they give you pain.
But I can release you from them.
I can release you
from your pain.
Would you like to
be free from pain?
Yes.
The one before you was
gonna bring the container.
The container holds the
missing pieces, John.
So we can finish this lab.
So we can replicate
just like everyone else.
You're doing great, John.
Daddy, it's raining.
I got it.
Come on.
I want a story.
Right here.
How'd it get so deep?
Hello, soldier.
That's the spirit soldier.
Ahhhh!
You still believe the lies?
You don't realize
this is your home?
You killed them.
If you believe I did...
Then I did.
You're only killing
your own father.
There is no end.
Always another John.
How did you know I'd find him?
You always find each other.
You're like dogs that way.
You know, I suppose I
should be grateful, but...
I can't help but feel proud.
How's that?
Because we were right this time.
Your memories triggered
emotional responses
that made you resistant.
You acted on your own
behest, not ours.
You were designed with
selfish motivations...
Loyalty to family, not country.
The John that came before you?
Sent on the same exact mission.
And he came the closest,
but he disappeared.
We made the necessary
adjustments,
knowing that you'd pick
upright where he left off.
You know where he is?
Mm mm. We'll find him though.
We always do.
What about me?
We'll take you in,
erase some memories
and then you'll be...
Then you'll be free.
Truly free.
You seem disappointed.
Come on, I know you, John,
like a father knows his child.
You might not know meas
well as you think.
I know that if you
didn't stop them,
they would've reproduced by now.
Once that door is open...
That's how much you mean to me...
Everybody.
So you created me
to find the one who
killed my family
and put them to death.
That is correct.
You killed my family.
See? That's what makes
you so special.
You feel so intensely.
You killed my family.
No no, quite the contrary.
I created them...
For you. I created them
to fill your void.
And then you killed them.
I didn't kill them, John.
Luc Deveraux did.
Maybe.
But you put him up to it.
THE END
Subtitles by: