I thought so!
This flow isn't worth a dime!
I told you Guidon
tapped them too young.
It'll take three years with the best
of care to get them back in shape.
Guidon, that squealing liar!
Before he left, he told me he'd
cleaned out all the bamboo in 347.
- Yes, he did.
- We could use some rain.
The rains will just flood us rotten if
those drain ditches aren't finished.
And look at those slugs!
That's another one of
Guidon's finished jobs.
Whining for leave
when I'm shorthanded.
I knew he'd overstay it.
He would have come up
on today's boat, sure.
Yeah? He tells me any more of his
lies, and I'm gonna kick in his face.
Not that, Denny.
It's hard enough for a man
to breathe up here as it is.
Here she comes, for fare!
That roof'll go in a minute!
Here's Limey.
Hey, did you bring Guidon?
Yes, I dropped him.
He's home to stay all right.
The prodigal is returned.
He's got a lot of nimble
explaining to do.
Maybe he's already pawned in here. ?
These dust storms...
are something like the fogs
off the coast of Labrador
Only the result is different.
Hold up a whole day's distilling.
Tomorrow, you and Guidon
take a clearing squad
Mr. Guidon come back,
him very happy see me.
Me hit like hell to see him.
Grab his feet.
Smells like he could have
been drinking benzene.
At that, he'd sell pretty
well in the States,
if you put a label on his chest
and  sealed up both ends.
All right...Heave!
Hey! What's the idea?
You poor sap...
How many times do I have to
tell you, you haven't a chance of...
Well, for the love of mud! Where
am I sleeping, on a race track?
Come on, let's have it. Who are you?
Where'd you come from?
Don't rush me, brother.
I'm Pollyanna, the glad girl.
I see. Came on up the boat
with him, eh?
I came up on the boat,
sure, but not with that.
He was in the steerage,
as far as I was concerned.
I thought I had convinced
this drunken...
Get him out of here, will you?
Why did you get off the boat at all?
You know it doesn't stop here
again for four weeks, don't you?
Sure, I do.
Think I'm overjoyed about it?
But it's just got to be, that's all.
- Well then?
- I left the boat here
for the same reason I took it
at Saigon. - What reason?
I got mixed up in a little trouble
and I thought I'd stay away out of town
until the gendarmes forgot about it.
And what a cast-iron nerve you got!
You have to have in my line.
But don't worry, big boy,
I'll stay out from under foot.
I'll even pay for my board if
you insist on it nicely.
You're the head man
around here, aren't you?
- Come on, Mac. - You're not
gonna leave the corpse here?
It's his room. Didn't you know?
Honest, I didn't. I just took the first
room the houseboy showed me.
Oh please, you guys.
This place is full of lizards
and cockroaches as it is.
One more won't hurt.
You know, Denny,
she might be able to sew.
I haven't got a pair of pants to my name
with a full set of buttons on them.
It's bad enough having to play
around with them in Saigon,
much less have one in your house.
Not bad-looking.
That doesn't change her.
Aha! Beans!
What happened to
that quarter of beef?
You leave the refrigerator
door open again?
Yes, sir, Mr. Denny.
Ice all water.
You don't want the beef now.
All stinky! Stinky!
Better eat something, Denny.
Yeah, later maybe.
Mac...did you ever want to quit?
Oh, sure.
I quit your old man once.
When I sobered up in Singapore
I saw a Britisher loading rubber,
and I turned around and came back.
The company's made me a swell offer.
I could sell out pretty.
- But you won't.
You was born smelling rubber
and sweating to get it
and you'll die that way.
You think so?
Do you think I'll spend my
whole life in this dry rot
just so the rest of the world
can ride around on balloon tires?
- Sure you will.
- Who says so?
Why should I spend the rest of my
days worrying about guys like Guidon?
Kicking a herd of crawling
coolies around...
fighting fever...
swallowing dust one month,
wading in mud the next,
just so some old woman can take
her hot water bottle to bed with her?
Yeah and just as long as
there's one baby in the world
to suck on a rubber nipple.
Now, listen, Dennis, you've got
your yearly case of nerves.
Now why don't you go
down to Saigon and...
to blow the lid off?
Get a laugh out of your liquor?
With this outfit running away as it is,
how am I going to get to Saigon?
Well, as a matter of fact, what came up
from Saigon isn't so bad-looking.
I've been looking at her kind
ever since my voice changed.
Let's lay off tomorrow,
and knock that fellow over.
I never got time.
Don't mind me, boys.
I'm just restless.
Hello, Polly.
I thought you were
going back to sleep.
Not with that alley cat
yodelling out there.
Guess I'm not used to
sleeping nights anyway.
Listen.
Tomorrow you and Guidon see about
clearing a road down to that creek area.
I thought you were
going to let that wait
until that new
survey engineer fellow...
- You mean Willis?
- Yeah.
He's due on Limey's
next trip up, isn't he?
Yes, but I'm not counting on him.
Probably some textbook
ingenue like the last one.
What's Polly's name?
She never had one.
Well I'll have to tend to that.
You can't have a poor
bird without a name.
You just tend to minding
your own business.
This place certainly reeks of
hospitality and good cheer.
Or maybe it's this cheese.
Oh, gorgonzola!
My favorite tango!
Mr. Denny, you no want eat?
No, clear this stuff.
You won't grow up to be
a big strong boy like
grandpa here if you don't
eat your din-din, Fred.
Say listen, Lily, as long as you've got
to use it, the name's Dennis Carson.
Okay, Fred.
This name is Vantine,
as long as you've got to use it.
Don't worry, I won't
have much occasion to.
Nice light-hearted
little fellow, isn't he?
We've had a hard day's
work, Vantine.
What else do you do besides work?
Don't you know any games?
If it was the summer of 1894,
I'd play games with you, sister.
But life is much simpler now.
I bet you painted
your hometown red!
I'll say I did.
Good night, Denny.
- Good night, Mac.
- Good night.
Here... Cut that out
and eat something.
You'll just get stewed.
- I never get stewed.
What if I did?
Would it turn your hair gray?
No, but it'll put red spots
on your liver.
Especially if you don't
eat something.
Come on, big boy, I know
you've had a hard day in the office.
Get out of here!
Put the rest of that cheese in your
mouth, where it'll do the most good.
I'll go quietly, officer.
That's roquefort,
the other's gorgonzola.
- I happen to like roquefort.
- I like gorgonzola.
Is there any brand that would
stop you from talking?
I'll order a ton of it.
I'll keep quiet.
You know you wouldn't like roquefort
if you knew the way it was made.
They've got a whole town that does nothing
but make roquefort somewhere in France.
I was reading about it
the other day.
It comes from sheep's milk,
did you know that?
And they do the rottenest
things to the sheep...
Ewes, don't they call 'em?
Before they milk them, the sheep people
slap them all around underneath
to make the milk thicker and
then they put it in a cave and...
I don't care where it's made
or who slaps who.
All I want you to do...
- You don't have to snarl about it.
There are a lot of people who would be mighty
interested to know how they slap cheese...
I'm not interested in cheese.
You said you liked roquefort
and I was just telling you
how they slap it out...
You want me to slap you
out of this room?
You and what man's army?
If you don't keep quiet I'm gonna
lock you up in one of the outhouses.
What would you think of that?
I'd still like roquefort.
I mean gorgonzola!
There, I knew you had
a laugh in you, that's perfect.
Shake and go to the
head of your class.
Now wait a minute, Fred.
Come here.
Hey!
You talk too much, but
you're a cute little trick at that.
Why haven't you been around before?
You change your mind quick enough.
Your hair's always been that color?
Always been a towhead.
And you always shut
your face off that way?
Well, I like that!
Hello, Lily!
Well...
Goodbye, Denny.
Goodbye, kid.
It's been nice having you.
- Where's the rest of that beer lot?
- Coming up!
Gee, Denny, I don't want
any ceremony but...
but...
turn around and give me the works.
What?
Oh, I'm forgetting the expenses, huh?
Oh, Denny, no.
- What's the matter?
- Please, don't.
This wasn't like that.
Where's that fellow, Willis?
Did you bring him?
He's in the port cabin.
Here you are, kid.
It isn't half enough.
But when I get down to Saigon,
there'll be more.
Keep your chin up.
Willis?
- Mr. Carson?
- Right.
Gary Willis, I take it.
Got any more luggage?
Yes?
Babs, this is Mr. Carson.
My wife.
Your who?
Mrs. Willis.
- Oh. How do you do?
- Well, thank you.
A rather longer trip
than we expected.
What's the matter?
Dizzy?
Gary's been feeling the heat
a little more than usual today.
- Oh, I'm all right.
- Take it up to the house.
Mr. Carson will see that you
run a nice cold tub, darling.
He looks like he's
ready for one himself.
Thanks, dear.
This is Mac, Mr. and Mrs. Willis.
How do you do.
This way, lad.
We'll get the duffel up.
My, it's good to be here!
Where's the plantation?
That's it.
- I mean the main house.
- That's it.
Why? Is it a big shock to you?
Well, of course,
I haven't been inside yet.
Well, you're a big shock to me.
What do you mean?
I didn't expect you at all.
Gary darling, wait a moment.
- Kind of rustic and
pioneering, isn't it? - Yes.
- We can't live the rest of our lives in
the bridal suite, darling. - No.
But where do you take a bath?
Would the lady like to
take a bath? I show you.
See?
Pretty lady just take off clothes.
Hold the water top side of head.
Water goes all over.
But isn't there any curtain?
No, no curtain. Take a bath,
talk with people in here, same time.
That will be fixed, darling.
- Where's our room?
- Follow Hoy.
Nice room, very nice.
Nice room. Very nice.
- That's all.
- All right, me come again.
Babs, I didn't know it was
going to be like this.
I may as well face it,
this is no place for you.
Here now, any place
is my place, where you are.
And I'll put a curtain
on that bath place,
I'm gonna get a broom, and some
soap and water for this room...
And I'll...
Why darling, what's the matter?
Here now, you're all worried and
hot and excited, all at once,
and that's bad. Take your
coat off and lie down.
Heat never hit me like this before.
It's gone now.
Men think they can stand anything.
Gosh. You think we can
stand this bed?
Who else is going to?
Pardon me.
I feel like a fool,
landing here this way.
You've no idea how anxious I am
to get started working, Mr. Carson.
Say, there's a great new mulch for
replanting I wanted to talk to you about.
Yes, lie down, will you?
Let me see your tongue.
Say, what's the idea of all this?
That's quinine.
Give him four right away.
And here's a bromide.
It will give him a good night's
rest, and he needs that.
Here's the thermometer.
Take his temperature every
four hours and let me know.
- Is there anything really
wrong with me? - Yes.
You've got the start of
a good attack of fever.
- Fever?
- Listen Carson, are you...
Now stop getting excited,
both of you.
It's the surest way
to help it along.
Get him undressed and
under the covers.
You'll pull through
if you follow orders.
Mr. Carson.
- I'd like to speak to you
a moment. - Certainly.
- Now, Babs!
- I'll only be a moment, Gary.
Mr. Carson, I wonder
if you really...
Of course, we must
get a doctor at once.
The nearest doctor's in Saigon.
That's three days down
and three back.
Then we must go back with the boat.
Frankly, I'd just as soon you did.
But I've got a little conscience left.
He'd likely be dead by the time
you got there.
Now, all I want you to do
is to keep your head.
He'd be burning up
by tomorrow night.
But if he's here with me instead of
being bumped about in that cigar box,
he'll have a chance.
I've only missed out on a couple,
and I've had dozens.
I won't stand for this!
Do you think you can treat Gary
like one of your coolies?
Why not? He's just another
worker on the place.
Only he's coming down with the fever
and therefore isn't quite as valuable.
I won't have you talk like that!
I never...
- I know you won't.
The only excuse you have for being
here is to help take care of him.
Now get in there and give him that quinine
and take a little yourself while you're at it.
Give him all the water
he wants and more.
The china boy will give you
whatever else you need.
You're not going to leave him?
You're not going out?
Yes. I work here.
You don't expect me to sit
around and hold his hand, do you?
All right. If that makes
you feel any better.
What was that?
That was a tiger.
A tiger? He sounded so close.
He just sits out there in the bush
and swears at us every now and then.
He won't come within a hundred
yards of the compound.
Now don't give him another thought.
I see. If you're sure he won't.
I...
I 'm sorry about this morniing.
Let me apologize.
It's quite unnecessary, really.
You know, running a plantation
sometimes gets on the nerves.
With your husband arriving sick and
wondering just how you were going to
fit into the scheme of things here...
You don't have to explain anything.
All you've got to do
is to get Gary through this.
Of course. I need him almost
as badly as you do.
You...
gave him that bromide?
Yes, he's asleep.
Is there anything more I should do?
No, let him sleep as late as he can in
the morning, and I'll look at him then.
- I will.
- By the way...
my room is that front
one off the porch,
If you should want me
during the night.
- Thank you.
- Are we friends now?
Does that really matter so much
at the moment, Mr. Carson?
Good night.
Lady scared of the cat?
Why not?
She probably never thought
of one except in the zoo.
She's beautiful, isn't she?
Very.
Only don't start
telling her, will you?
Reserving that privilege
for yourself?
Explain the joke
and I'll die laughing.
Somebody would have had
a lot of explaining to do
if she and Vantine had ever met.
What would you have said, Denny?
Called it your sister?
No, we'd have panned her
off better as your governess.
Can you imagine the mixed feminine
population we would have had then?
That's one trouble we
haven't got, so let's forget it.
She's gone and...
- Hi there!
Hey, you guys still up?
Hey, where's the
reception committee?
It's been a nice little walk. Did you
hear that hungry pussycat back there?
I'd begun to feel like
a porterhouse steak.
What's the idea?
I bounced back, that's all.
One month up here and
I turn into a rubber check.
What happened?
You tell him, Admiral. I want
to get away from these eagles.
A disaster, gentlemen.
A blooming disaster.
Well come on, out with it!
Let's have it.
I ain't saying how it happened...
But we got past
the rapids all right.
And I'd just left the bridge
to go down to get a pot of tea
and before you knew it,
that orangatang at the wheel
runs the nose right
in the mud bank.
The current gets her in deeper,
and tried to pull her out,
a shaft snaps in two...
like a stick of macaroni.
That old shaft's been due to snap
for the last twenty odd years.
That boat's a sister ship
to the Ark!
And Noah here couldn't understand
why I wouldn't stay onboard
with a bunch of monkeys.
What was the matter
with using the tender?
Tender? I'll say it was.
We put it in the water
and the bottom dropped out.
How long is that boat
going to be laid up?
Well, I gotta get a couple of boys
trekking down to Saigon for help,
and by the time I get a new shaft and
propeller in it, it'll be, let me see now...
It'll be at least six weeks,
even if you're lucky.
I guess you're right, Mr. Carson.
I'm not lucky this season.
Well, you boys can stay here and
give the story to the papers,
I'm gonna drop the
body in the hay.
Just a minute.
You'll be much more
comfortable upstairs.
Willis brought his wife.
Oh, a lady!
Now no noise, you understand?
Willis is up to his gills
in the fever.
What a pleasant little house
party this is gonna be!
Never mind about that.
Get upstairs and keep quiet.
Me very glad, Miss Van
come back. Very glad.
Hoy old pal, that's nice
to hear from someone,
even though you are
slightly simple-minded.
Thank you. I make
new kind of biscuits.
Special for Miss Van.
Say, which tree did
this one ooze out of?
Miss Van tell funny joke!
Oh, funny!
Clear that brush out on 291.
- Hey, Mac!
- Yeah?
That old bullock's gone lame.
I'll look after it, Denny.
Gary, don't!
Babs, I'm not sick.
If I get up and move around,
and stop thinking about it...
You don't know how sick you are.
Now, please, dear.
Where's Carson?
He'll know I'm all right
by just looking at me.
I know, but you can't get up.
You've got to stay in bed.
I'll speak to Mr. Carson and see
what you can have for breakfast.
- All right.
- That's a boy.
- Oh! Good morning.
- Hello.
We haven't met but don't let
that stop you if you're hungry.
I was looking for Mr. Carson.
He's outside, being noisy
about something or other.
You better sit down and drink your
pinapple juice before it starts cooking.
As you say, we haven't met.
I'm Mrs. Willis.
Yeah I know, they told me
about your husband.
How is he today?
I hope we can get a doctor.
Oh, these fool doctors!
Even if you did get one, why, all
he'd do is sit by the side of the bed
and start crabbing the government
for not stamping out fever.
Then they prescribe brandy
and have
to sample themselves
to see if it's any good,
and by the time you're
deciding whether to live or die,
they're under the bed
singing "Sweet Adeline"
You seem to be very familiar
with the country.
Are you...
married to one of the men here?
Do you think I'd live in
a menagerie like this?
I've been visiting my brother. He
has the next plantation below here,
and it's a lovely place.
You know he copied it from
our old family plantation
in Bluefield, West Virginia.
Have you ever been to Bluefield?
No, I haven't.
We're the Jeffersons there.
I'm Vantine Jefferson.
You know, I was supposed to
be happy about staying home
and marrying the son
of another FFB.
But I'm just the restless,
adventurous type I guess.
I had to come out to stay with
my brother and see the world.
Then you're visiting here too.
Oh no! But how I got here!
Mr. Carson nearly died laughing.
I got on a boat to go down to Saigon,
you know, to do a little shopping?
And the boat turns back to pick up
some elastics or something
and gets stuck in the mud.
My dear, and I had to walk
back through the jungle!
Wait'll the folks back in
Richmond hear about this.
Aren't you gonna drink
your pineapple juice?
When Mr. Carson comes in,
will you tell him I want to see him?
Yes, madam.
You didn't believe
a word of it, did you?
Did you expect me to?
No.
But there was a guy
on the next plantation,
even though he wasn't my brother.
and that story about
the boat's all true, see?
I haven't any connection
here at all,
whether you believe it or not.
Why Denny, you're all shaved
and dressed up fancy!
You even smell good.
What have you been telling her?
You don't think I'd...
Say, I know when to keep
my mouth shut. - I hope so.
I merely said I came
from the next plantation
and the boat broke down.
She'll believe that
if you'll back me up.
I don't want to crawl in and
dirty up her goldfish bowl.
Now listen, this woman's decent.
You watch your language and stop
running around here half-naked.
- I'll stay as comfortable as I like.
- You'll go back to Saigon.
On what? That speedboat
stuck in the mud?
No. Slung in a hammock
through the bush.
Oh, I see.
Two weeks in the swamp playing tag
with your trusted coolies at night.
I guess that would be
good enough for me.
You can keep your mouth shut
and keep out of the way.
Pretty lady want see Mr. Denny.
All right.
Now remember what I said.
Say, Denny.
What?
Oh, nothing. You look
kind of cute, that's all.
Gary, I told you not to get up.
You shouldn't.
Come in!
He insisted on getting up.
- Not obeying orders, eh?
Hoy! Bring me some blankets,
snap into it!
Gosh! What hit me?
Fever chills. You've got to get
used to them for a couple of days.
Get me a coat, anything.
- Denny, can I help?
- Yes, tell Mac to go on out.
- Get me the medicine box, Hoy.
- Yes, sir.
You won't leave him now, will you?
You'll stay?
Naturally.
There are things to be done.
Come on, boy, dig in your heels.
Here.
Hi, Doc.
How am I doing?
Great. Eat your spinach.
The rest of your milk.
All of it now.
Well, it looks as though
you were gonna stay married.
He's really through it?
There's no more chance...
- He'll be outside working in a week.
I don't know what to say.
You'd better think
about getting some sleep.
I know I am.
I mean, when I think of what I
did the first day we came...
slapping you.
And here, ever since...
it's been almost three days,
you stayed with him
practically every minute,
pulling Gary through
this terrible...
Don't you see how ashamed I am?
Oh that. I...
Out here we all slap each
other sooner or later.
You're just getting it out of
your system a little early, that's all.
Well, apologies or even
thanks would be silly now.
I just want you to know that
I owe you a great deal.
I'll take your IOU.
Remember now.
Don't hesitate to call me
if you need me.
I won't, thanks.
- Good night.
What are you doing here?
- I was just roaming around.
- Yeah?
Go to bed. Nobody asked
you to lose any sleep.
- How is he, Denny?
- He's through it.
Oh, gee, that's swell.
He's such a nice kid.
Say, what's this? Some new
kind of an alarm clock?
It doesn't seem to ring
or tick at all. - Hey!
It was a barometer!
I wouldn't swear to it now.
Say listen,
if you're just roaming around,
keep it up, will you?
I'm dead on my feet.
I'm sorry, Dennie, can't I...
Here. Let me get those.
There.
Denny, have you got a headache?
Maybe. I don't know.
Would you like me
to rub your forehead?
No.
Could I get you a drink
or something?
No thanks.
Beat it to bed, will you?
Let's forget about the drink.
I'll just rub your forehead
with sandpaper!
No, we'll just let Willis go out
and look around today.
I thought I'd show him
that roadside and then
where we're going to lay
out the new stand on...
I don't care what you show him! Let him
get his bearings andl know where he's at.
We'll find out soon enough
if he knows his business.
Well, don't bite my arm off.
What's the matter with you?
Hey, aren't you going out with us?
No, I'm not.
You were mean not to awaken me.
I wanted to see you off
on your first day.
You need all the sleep
you can get for a while.
You lost plenty over me.
All the trouble I've been to
everybody around here.
Dennis is a prince, isn't he?
He was rather wonderful.
Believe me, I'm going to
try to make it up to him.
Wish me luck, darling.
You don't need it, you're good.
I've got to hurry, they're waiting.
Bye, honey. Now don't worry...
- Here.
I don't know what
time we'll be back.
What the...
Hey! Hey!
How many times have I told you
to let down those curtains?
Why? They've all gone
off to work.
You heard me. Let them down!
What's the matter?
Afraid I'll shock the Duchess?
Don't you suppose she's ever
seen a French postcard?
You'll let those curtains down or
this is the last bath you'll ever have.
Get out of there!
Hey, what's the idea?
- What?
- Getting in that barrel?
Oh, I don't know. Maybe I'm
going over Niagara Falls.
You're supposed to
rinse off with that gourd.
Hey, listen. You know
we drink that water?
Yeah, well you won't this. Unless
you're stubborn and insist on it.
Come on, get out!
Oh, don't, Denny.
I'm in it now, stop!
No, don't, Denny!
Gee! Can't a girl take a bath
in privacy without...
Oh, good morning!
You're just in time to see
the trained seal.
Hey, Denny, scrub my back.
Get back in that barrel.
Don't, Denny! You just said
you didn't want me in it.
One more occurence like this and you'll
live in that shack across the river.
I will not! And if
you think I give a...
Pardon the disturbance. One of
the guests was misusing the plumbing.
I thought you'd gone with Gary.
No, I'm...tied up here this morning.
What are your plans?
I thought I'd take a walk
before it gets too hot.
By the way,
you haven't had much of a chance
to see what goes on here.
Would you like to see
how we make the stuff?
Why...
Why, yes. I'd love to.
Okay.
Should I put on some boots?
No, you're all right.
Thank you.
- Good morning, Bob.
- Good morning, sir.
Here's where we find out
what a bad day we've had.
- Why, it's milk!
- Oh no, just rubber.
But you could drink it if
you care to stretch a point.
I once knew a man
who made a joke like that.
He was run over by a truck.
- Were you driving it?
- Yes!
- You're out of luck here.
We only have ox carts, and
every ox knows me personally.
Here's where the milk
turns to cheese.
You know, it usually takes
three hours or more,
but for your entertainment,
I'll perform a miracle.
You see, nothing up the sleeves...
no trap doors, no mirrors...
All visible to the naked eye.
Just pour in acetic acid.
The more acid, the quicker the
liquid rubber resents the insult,
and stiffens up into
an indignant mass.
There. Crude rubber.
Well, I can't believe it.
But how does it...
Master cook refuses to
roll it thin enough.
You're a strange lot of
civilized barbarians...
working and living
your whole lives out here.
Somebody's got to do it.
But don't you ever miss the people
and the comforts of the outside world?
Don't you ever get tired of this?
We go on fighting it and grumbling
about the life but we're born to it.
Perhaps it's hard for
a woman to understand.
A little.
I just realised that I've seen but
one woman since I've been here.
For instance, where are the
wives of all these natives?
Back country, in the villages.
They've got to sign on
without them.
You mean you don't allow
wives on your plantation?
Women don't belong here,
white or native.
If they're white,
they can't stand the gaffe.
If they're native,
one of them is bound to drift
from the coolies' quarters,
and end up waiting
on you at breakfast.
And that's curtains for
a man in this country.
Here's something
that might interest you.
This is...
what pencil erasers look like
before they're born.
There you are.
See all the little pencil erasers
trying to erase each other?
Yes.
What about that girl...
back at the house.
Vantine, isn't it?
Yes, what about her?
I mean...
Is she a part of the life here?
Very definitely.
If a man wants to be interested.
- Big rain's coming.
- Yeah!
Perhaps we'd better
get back to the house.
- Is there going to be a storm? - Usually
it only threatens this time of the year.
It's a little early for the monsoon.
Look out for the traffic!
I'd have walked right into it.
I was wool gathering.
No profit in wool these days!
What about?
Well, you said...
that a white woman out here couldn't
stand "the gaffe", as you called it.
Perhaps I was thinking
of my mother.
Her grave is on the hill at
the far edge of the compound.
You know, I faintly remember asking
my father if he was digging a well.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I didn't know.
However, I'm not forcasting
any such dark future for you.
But don't you really think
I could fit in out here?
Don't you think that
I could be happy?
Would you mind if I made it
my job to see that you are?
Well, I want everyone
to like me out here.
That's not difficult.
I have a special fondness for somebody
who stands up and fights back.
Particularly if she's a woman who looks
extraordinarily beautiful when she's doing it.
And even more beautiful
when she's calmed down.
That's a very polished little
speech for a...
barbarian.
You admitted the barbarian
was civilized, didn't you?
Why, I've forgotten what I said.
Are you going to
forget what I said?
- Goodness, what's happening?
- Come on, we've got to make it!
Hoy, hurry up, you idiot!
Peep, peep! Like you, water!
Better be nice!
Better be quite nice!
Thank you.
Please, let me down.
Aren't you comfortable?
Why...
We shouldn't have done that.
But we did.
- Hoy! Tell them to saddle up.
- All right.
Did the Duchess sprain her ankle?
It must be wonderful
to be big and strong.
Think how all the girls...
Be careful the rain doesn't wash
the rouge off your mouth!
Do you mind if I stay
in here with you?
Think you can stand the company?
Please, it's...
It's just that I...
Pity the poor sailors
on a night like this.
Dear little sailors!
How long is it going to keep up?
Does it ever stop,
even for a minute?
Not even for lunch.
Stop playing stoop tag.
You'll know it if you're hit.
Here. Put this inside you.
All of it.
It'll make you forget
a lot of things.
That was nice of you.
It's stupid of me
to be so frightened.
This storm isn't the only thing that
has you worried around here, is it?
I saw him kick the door shut. He came
out with rouge all over his mouth.
Why...
I suppose he asked
to use your lipstick!
I don't know how it happened.
I didn't do anything.
He didn't have any reason
to believe that I'd...
I didn't hear any cries for help.
I don't know what came over me.
I should have stopped him.
I tried but...
- But you couldn't.
Even when you tried...
Could you?
No.
That's why I'm scared.
Oh, it's too silly!
What do I mean I'm scared?
It was just one of those
excitement-of-the-moment things.
Well, watch out for the
next moment, honey.
It's longer than the first.
Gosh, these peaches are good.
I never ate so much in
my life, how about that?
You know, ever since
we were married
that one over there has been
after me for not eating enough.
Guess you're not worried about me wasting
away after this meal, are you, Mrs. Willis?
You have rather stuffed yourself.
That's what a full day's
work will do for you.
Full day's work? I'll say it was.
Those coolies are tough
to handle, aren't they?
Didn't I tell you they
were a lazy bunch?
I mean, I didn't know they
were so sneaky about it.
The minute you turn your back on them, they're
up to something or other they shouldn't be doing.
Are they always like that?
- I'm afraid so.
I was telling him about the time
that malay tried to knife you in the back.
It's a great country
for that sort of thing.
I guess Mac could have
used you out there today.
But I imagine you had
plenty to do around here.
You should have seen us, Babs.
We were up to our knees in water trying to
get a drain ditch through to the main channel.
And every time
we looked for a coolie...
Hey, darling! What game are
you playing? What's the score?
Babs!
- What?
- Set them up in the other alley!
- Oh Gary, please don't!
Babs!
This little taste of bad weather we've had today is
enough to upset anybody, if they're not used to it.
Why don't you turn in early?
I think I will if you'll
all excuse me.
Good night.
- Good night.
- I'll be in soon, darling.
- All right, dear.
I might have realized, all that
thunder and lightning today...
Gee, I'm dumb.
No, how were you to know?
Well Gary, now that
you're in shape again,
we can start out on the first
real job I have for you.
Great! You know me.
You and Mac and Guidon will leave
here tomorrow, take a full crew.
Camp down below the south creek
for the next 3 or 4 weeks.
Remember? I started to tell
you about it the other day.
There's that 500 acres
I want you to survey.
Lay out a course for best drainage,
then throw up a bridge over the creek
and cut through a road
leading back to the compound,
for shortest
and easiest hauling.
We can't do that job now, Denny.
The rains have started.
It's a nice time to pick for it.
What's the matter with you guys?
Getting soft?
This plantation's got
to increase production.
Okay, Denny,
if you're dead set on it.
Well believe me, I am.
I've got to begin to
earn my salt here.
Let me see:
Three or four weeks.
What about Babs?
Will it be all right for her?
If she wants to go, but I think
it would be foolish to take her.
Down in them swamps? Why,
that's no place for a woman, boy.
There won't be a dry
blanket in the outfit.
No, it's tough enough for a man.
But I'll be riding down every
now and then while you're there.
Maybe I could bring her
along for a visit. - Fine!
I'd better go in and see if
there's anything I can do for her.
I'll come back later
and talk it over.
The morning's time enough,
just a few details.
Right.
Come on, you fellows.
We've got to cover up those vats.
That's a sensible girl.
You must be dreadfully tired, Gary.
Silly!
You'd better be
pretty nice to me, lady.
I'm gonna leave you widowed
for three or four weeks.
Why...
what do you mean?
Dennis is sending me out
on my first field trip.
Mac, Guidon and I
are leaving in the morning.
I asked Dennis if you
could go along, darling.
He says it's an awfully
rotten area, even for a man.
Gary...
- Yes?
- Maybe I...
Well...maybe I'd better go.
But do you really think you
could stand it down there?
It's nothing but a swamp, you know.
Sleeping in tents, in
the wet and everything.
What do you think?
I don't know what to think.
It's all right, darling.
Hey.
Yeah?
A few days ago you said something
about sending me back to Saigon,
in a hammock through the bush.
You've been behaving yourself.
Maybe.
Bring on the hammock and
the coolies, will you?
What's the matter with you?
Crazy?
Just a little nauseated.
This rain seems to have uncovered
a pile of garbage around here.
Stop looking through keyholes.
It's bad for the eyes.
Can I have the coolies?
Nice, speedy ones?
No. I can't spare one.
I'll reduce your rent, however.
Increasing production, eh?
Listen, what goes on
here is my business.
Suppose I were to tell
that nice white kid.
He'd make it his business,
wouldn't he?
Suppose I tell him myself.
Okay, mark it station 30 plus 24.
Station 30 plus 24.
Can't you whistle another tune?
That's all I've heard for three weeks.
Maybe Dennis will bring
my saxophone when he comes.
You didn't know I had one, did you?
Yeah? When's he coming,
that's what I wanna know.
Look, Miss Van!
Goodness, you even
find them in the jungle.
Pretty lady pretty pants,
peep peep!
Yeah, a lady! That's why
he's so nuts about her.
Mr. Denny very very happy.
Mr. Denny got love.
He's in love all right.
The real thing too, I guess.
Of all the people in the world!
Miss Van never been in love?
Hoy thought one time
you and Mr. Denny...
- Never mind about that!
- Yes, Miss Van.
What you been eating? Cement?
- Mrs. Willis, clean clothes.
- Come in.
- Where Hoy put this?
- Any place over there, Hoy.
All right.
- Hoy!
- Here, Mr. Denny.
Did you put that new lamp
in Mrs. Willis's room?
Yes, Mr. Denny.
You'll find a couple more pheasants
hanging up in the back shed.
Fix them for dinner tonight.
You know, the way
Mrs. Willis likes them.
Yes, Mr. Denny.
Can I come in?
Wait a minute.
All right, come in.
I...
Did you get the lamp all right?
Yes, thanks so much.
Does it light up all right?
Lights up perfectly.
I heard you order the pheasants.
Well, I thought you might
like a little change.
Yes...a change.
I'm glad.
You're glad?
I never thought this could happen.
What?
I'm afraid I'm pretty
crazy about you.
Always? For keeps?
And after that too.
We'll get out of
this rotten country.
I've always known that some day...
We'll have a swell time, Babs.
Don't call me Babs, dear.
Do you mind?
Why not?
Oh.
Say, look...
I've got to go down river today.
They're having a little
trouble with the coolies.
- You'll see him?
- Yes.
Are you gonna tell him so soon?
Sure. Might as well
get it over with.
Now?
No, can't we just...
- Oh, Dennis maybe...
- Want to back out?
Oh, no.
But he's so...helpless.
Well, it's just a tough break.
Oh, Dennis, you'll come back to me?
Day after tomorrow.
- I'm frightened.
- What of?
Say, at that,
it might be better if...
Did Gary leave you a gun?
- It isn't that.
You do love me, don't you?
Want it in writing?
Goodbye, kid.
It's only for a couple
of days, and then...
Goodbye, dear.
Now listen.
I'm going down river and probably
won't be back till morning.
If you can't be pleasant to her while I'm
gone, just keep out of her way, understand?
Oh, that's too bad!
She and I could have had
such a lovely day.
Just two girls together
with so much in common.
You heard me.
I thought we might run up a few
curtains and make a batch of fudge,
while we were planning what to wear to
the country club dance Saturday night.
Just remember, Lily:
All those lame cracks
won't help you any
if I come back and find out you've
been annoying her in any way.
Oh, I wouldn't touch her with
your best pair of rubber gloves!
Hey!
Hey, Denny!
Here's the boss!
Hello, boys!
I hear you're having
a little cat trouble.
Yes, he's a big tom tiger! The first
bullock was chewed up last week.
Same old story. I can't convince
them he isn't a man-eater.
Can't haul any more
lumber for his bridge.
The brave fellows won't
go in and cut it out.
All like that.
If you can't get them back
to work, Denny, nobody can.
The quickest way to fix that is to
put a little lead in the friendly cat.
Did the runners spot it? - He was
over the rim of the hill last night.
Let's have a look.
We'll put up some blinds, and
stake out a few bullocks tonight.
Babs didn't feel like
coming down, huh?
- Why, no...
- You see, I was...
I was sort of expecting it.
It's a long hard trip, you know,
bad weather and all.
She...
She didn't send a note or anything?
No, as a matter of fact,
she didn't have time.
I came right away, just yelled in that I was
going as they brought the horse around.
She...sends her love of course.
She couldn't send very much...
I brought most of it along with me.
How's your work been coming?
I'll take you over everything I've done
tomorrow. I think you'll be pleased about it.
I've worked night and
day to rush the job, I...
I sure want to get
back to the house.
- Hey, Mac
- What?
We'll each take a blind tonight,
you take Gary in with you.
Okay Denny.
Couldn't I stick along with you?
Mac and I have been cooped
up so long together
we haven't got
a new joke between us.
- Sure, if you like.
- Then we can talk things over.
That cat'll be good
and hungry again.
He'll start stalking one of the
baits soon after sundown.
Yeah.
- That's a mighty nice lad, Denny.
- I guess he is.
But just as you thought,
he'll never make the grade.
Poor lad.
He wants to make good, too.
His fever came back on
him a little bit yesterday,
but he sat up all night
going over his charts.
And say, to hear him
talk about you,
he'd cut off both his legs
if you gave him the word.
- Better stake out that
other bullock. - Okay, Denny.
Say...Can I have first shot at him?
If you guarantee you won't miss.
Well, you'll be right there.
I'd give anything to be able to
take the hide back to Babs.
Let's get up.
It's something like spearing
sunfish with a lantern.
Only not so easy.
Nothing's easy down
in this country.
That's what makes the life
worth living, I say.
What are you going to do
after you leave here?
Oh, I don't know.
That's a little far ahead
to think of now, I guess.
I always thought I'd like to
go on doing this sort of thing,
go to South America,
you know, expeditions?
That was B.B.
- B.B.?
- Yeah!
Before Babs.
Oh.
You must think I'm an awful ass,
to keep talking about Barbara
this way all the time.
No.
Here's your gun.
I always feel a fellow can talk about
things that are close and intimate to him
when he's with a guy who...
well...who understands.
That's why I'm not at all
ashamed to tell you,
I'd fold up without Babs.
Just being away from her
this long has proven that.
This would be a bad country to
raise children in, wouldn't it?
- Oh, I don't know.
- See...
Babs and I were going
to have children right away,
and this job came up.
Kids.
First a couple of boys,
and then a girl perhaps.
Will I walk down the main street!
I guess we'll wait until
we get back home.
Before we left, we bought a piece
of property outside New York
up on the Hudson.
We're going to build
and settle down there.
It's only 35 miles from New York,
and it's real rural country.
A guy can commute...
Babs will be right there with all the
people she's known and grown up with.
All our closest friends
have settled there too.
And it'll be a swell place
for the children.
And when their Uncle Dennis
comes up from the tropics,
he can tell them about the
time their dad shot a tiger
as he charged ruthlessly through
the... - Keep quiet, will you?
What's the matter?
I thought you said we could
talk until it got dark?
Well, we won't talk anymore.
Better not.
Yay! You got him!
Gee, that was a swell shot.
He was too fast for me.
Gee! Look at it!
Gee, what a thrill that was.
I'm going home tonight,
Mac. Get my horse.
But it's a rotten ride
this late, Denny!
I have to go, I tell you.
All right!
Feel like you could
eat some supper?
Not particularly.
I guess you must be
pretty well done in at that.
You take my cot, and
turn in right after chow.
I got the most comfortable
cot in the outfit.
No, I'm going back right now.
- Going back?
- Yeah.
I've got a fresh batch of young trees
coming through for coagulation tomorrow,
and I gotta be on hand.
I thought we could spend the morning
going over everything I'd done.
No, I'll leave it to you guys.
Mac says you're doing great.
- Say, I think it's too much for you.
- Can't be helped.
Goodbye, kid.
So long, Denny.
Bye, Denny!
It doesn't seem at all worthwhile
for Denny to go back this way.
Six hours in the dark.
Through this weather.
You ought to know whether
it's worthwhile or not.
What do you mean?
Just what I say. You ought to
know your wife better than I do.
What the devil are you driving at?
Why do you suppose he sent
you up on this job for?
He got you up and out of the house
as soon as you could walk, didn't he?
Why, the night before we left,
it was an open book on both their
faces there was something up.
He's been making a play
for your wife ever since...
- Hey!
- Why, you...
- Cut it, you two!
- Get him and hold him!
- Did you hear what he said? Why...
- Now wait.
Don't pay any attention to
his drunken mouth, lad.
He's been drinking all day,
and whenever he gets that way,
he always gets ugly about Denny.
Now forget it.
All right, Mac.
Okay.
Hey, Limey!
Hello, Mr. Carson!
What are you doing so far
off the manor this time of the night?
Communing with nature?
When will you get fixed up?
All ship-shape again.
We'll be dropping her back
again in the morning,
and then I'll head back and pick up that
little girl with the golden locks, eh?
Yes.
Won't you come aboard
and take a nip?
I'm just about to wring the
neck off another bottle.
No, thanks.
See you tomorrow, Limey.
Aye aye, sir!
Well, if it ain't old Master Fred,
back after all these years!
Is the burial private?
Or didn't you bring
the body with you?
You don't look a day older
than when you went away.
We just loved your postcard.
My, you ought to see
how little Emily's grown.
And the twins...
Thanks, old man.
Don't care if I do.
Well now, tell me everything
you've been doing.
Guidon sends you his love.
How is dear, dear Guidon?
As divine as ever?
Say, what's ever become of...
What's his name, that young
fellow with the attractive wife?
You'd be surprised.
Dear me!
And he was so nice too.
Treacherous climate down here.
Where did you get that kimono?
Now Fred, don't change the subject!
What are you trying to do,
get drunk?
That's not a bad idea.
What is it?
Did your team win?
No, we lost.
107 to nothing.
What's the matter? Wet field?
Sloppy. Sticky.
You know what I've just been?
- What?
- I've been noble!
I give you Saint Dennis,
the big sacrifice boy.
Oh...there isn't gonna
be any funeral.
Sure, mine.
With a lily in my hand!
Little Denny is an angel
now with a harp
and a big, round, rosy halo.
Fred, I'm awful glad.
Are you?
Well, I'm not.
Of all the sap tricks.
He is a nice white kid, isn't he?
What are you gonna do about...
I don't know.
I'll fix it up tomorrow.
You were pretty close to
something there, Fred.
- Yeah.
- Maybe you aren't out yet.
She'll get over it.
I was thinking more about you.
Forget it!
Mind if I get a little
drunk with you, Fred?
So you went noble, eh?
Hallelujah, brother!
Come here.
- Why! Mr. Carson!
- Come here, you lug!
Well, it's about time!
Welcome home, stranger.
You're not a bad kid, Lily.
You know about us?
We belong here.
They don't, those two.
Ah, it's a dirty rotten country.
And we're dirty rotten people,
I suppose, eh?
- Sure.
- Who is?
- You are!
- Take that back!
Dennis!
Wouldn't you know it!
Sorry we woke you up.
Are you?
We were just kidding.
Dennis!
Well Fred, it's not too late.
I don't want you here!
Why, certainly.
Okay, Fred, you can check
the wings and halo at the desk.
- I'll be right up, Vantine.
- Dennis!
What?
- What did you mean?
- I meant what I said.
- What's happened to you?
- Figure it out for yourself.
- You're drunk.
- Sure I'm drunk.
That's why I'm telling you the truth.
You want to hear some more truth?
I didn't say anything to your husband
down there and I'm glad I didn't.
I've just been kidding you all the
time, and everybody knew about it.
- Stop it!
- If you want to come down here,
you come down under our rules.
And if you want to cheat on your
husband, that's okay with me.
And I'm the boy you're
looking for. - Stop it!
And let me tell you this:
I'm not a one-woman man, I never
have been and I never will be.
And if you wanna take your turn...
All right, if it makes
you feel any better.
- Denny!
- I'm hit.
Where?
I'm finding out.
- No bull's eye?
- Naw!
Babs!
What's the matter? What happened?
- I shot him.
- Why?
- Because he...because he...
- Because I made a pass at her.
Oh, Gary! Help me.
Help me!
Then you haven't...
Guidon said that you and...
Guidon's a liar! You ought
to be proud of her.
This bozo's been after
her every minute.
And tonight he comes in drunk
and tries to break into her room
and she shoots him.
The way any virtuous woman,
with a beast like that...
If I were you, Mr. Willis,
I'd take her away from here,
and the quicker the better.
And now, as long as
you aren't dead,
I suppose we'll have
to save your rotten life!
Hoy!
I thought you were a great guy.
Never mind about me.
The boat will get here
in the morning, see?
You two pack your tennis rackets
and go back where you belong.
I'll do that all right.
If she hadn't plugged you,
I'd have done it myself.
Come on, Babs.
Oh, Gary, I'm so sorry!
So sorry.
- Sorry, nothing.
I'm proud of you.
Oh, Denny!
Denny, does it hurt awful?
Oh, stop blubbering.
You've been using your head
pretty well up to now.
Get me the medicine kit.
- Okay.
Oh, Mr. Denny...Mr. Denny...
Oh, shut up! Go heat some water.
- Yes sir!
- Medicine kit coming up.
- That's more like it.
Give me the iodine.
Here now...
Press that thing through there
and pull it out the other end.
You mean, push the bullet
out or something?
No, that bullet's 50 yards
out in the compound.
Come on, clean out that hole!
- Oh, Denny!
- Come on.
One for the money...
Two for...
Two for the show.
- Three to get ready...
- Oh, Denny!
Come on, hurry up, you sap!
Four to...go.
Come on, all the way through.
It was something I overlooked.
"And the next day, when the big
round sun was high in the heaven,
little Bobby Chipmunk could
hardly believe his eyes,
because there across Farmer Brown's
meadows he saw little Molly Cottontail."
A chipmunk and a rabbit!
Say I wonder how this comes out.
"But the faster he ran
across the ground,
the faster she went,
hippity hop hippity hop..."
Fred! Stop it!
Sorry. Once more and you
get the works right there!
Can't you read anything
but bedtime stories?
I've read you everything
four times.
Except one certain item.
- What?
Well, I didn't want to upset you.
You're not well yet, you know.
- Let me see.
- I'll read it.
Where is it?
Here: "Sailing for San Francisco
on the Mohawa Maroo,
was Mr. Gary Willis and
his attractive wife of...
Look how they spelled
"Philadelphia"! "Ffil".
Well anyway, let's see now.
"Way across the meadow..."
Come on Fred, shake out of it.
"Way across the meadow, as old Daddy
Sun was setting behind the purple hills,
little Molly Cottontail went
hippity hop, hippity hop..."
Fred?
What, Lily?
You big cheese!
Roquefort or gorgonzola?
Me come again, peep peep!
subs by ironhills and cinephage
for KG