剩女保鏢
Sweet Sweet Bodyguard
Episode 82
Let's eat! Why aren't you eating?
Okay, all the dishes are ready.
Ai-Jia...
Are you okay?
I'm fine, don't worry about me.
Let's have our meal.
I admit that I'm upset.
Upset that Zhong-Qi left with one letter.
But I believe that...
Zhong-Qi's eyes will get well.
And mother will bring him back.
I will wait for him. I
will surely wait for him!
Father.
From now on,
I'm Zhong-Qi's wife,
daughter-in-law
of family Qin.
Of course you are.
You are pad of family Qin.
Mother...
But Zhong-Qi
now... -Father.
Zhong-Qi and I wore
the rings in front of God.
God witnessed our marriage,
you must accept me.
Yes, you are my
daughter-in-law,
but it's unfair for you.
No, it's not.
From today onwards,
I will use my profession,
to protect family Qin,
and also my family.
I will also be dedicated
to do what I should do,
and never abandon my duty.
I will be patient.
I will wait for Zhong-Qi.
Grandma...
I'm your bodyguard in the future.
You are not only my bodyguard,
you are our bodyguard,
you are family Qin's bodyguard.
Let's eat!
This is cook by my grandson's wife.
Quick!
Everyone, let's eat.
We have to move on.
This is delicious.
Yes, they are.
This is good.
Delicious,
sister-in-law.
You have improved a lot.
Teach me next time.
November 26th, 2012.
Cloudy.
Zhong-Qi, how are you?
I'm fine here, learning
to be a good wife.
But my husband is not with me.
I miss you.
I really miss you.
December 25th, 2012.
Rainy.
Zhong-Qi, I've
waited for one month.
Today is Christmas day.
Merry Christmas to you.
It is snowing at your side.
I hate you for not
bringing me to see it snows.
You must compensate me
when you come back.
Everyone is good.
Father is healthy as well.
We will take care of him.
Recently I learnt a few
new dishes from Aunt Qin-Mei.
I'll cook all for you
when you come back.
How is mother? Is she alright?
Zhong-Qi's first
surgery failed.
January 10th, 2013.
Ya-Lun, I have a strong feeling
during this time when I saw Ai-Jia
waiting for Zhong-Qi.
That is...
I need to apologize
to you during this time.
I insisted in keeping this baby
to make you worry and scared,
and you spent your
effort taking care of us.
You must be in pressure, am I right?
And you have to deal with my father,
I bet you must feel uncomfortable.
Why did you say so?
We need to spent the
rest of our life together.
We must share it together.
And this baby belongs
to both of us.
I believe we can
have a healthy
baby
The most important thing is
to have a healthy mother
to grow up with him.
When I see the big
changes on Ai-Jia,
I have this little...
Tiny little thinking.
Is this little?
Or this tiny little?
Or this tiny little bit?
This tiny little...
I'm touched by
Ai-Jia's wedding.
I've been crying loudly.
And the image was so
beautiful and sacred.
To be honest,
I don't want to regret.
So my dear boyfriend,
let's get married.
Impossible. I can't go
and attend your wedding.
Let me ask you.
What is your purpose
of marrying her?
Is it because of the baby
she's having now?
Or you want to give her an identity?
This is too ridiculous.
Listen carefully!
You want to protect your baby,
I want to protect my daughter.
Do you hear me?
And you...
I can grant your wishes.
Why can't you promise me
when it's the only
time that I asked you?
Why do you risk your
life to have this baby?
Father, Cai-Jie knows.
I don't want to talk to you.
Don't call me father.
You didn't persuade her
to take care of herself,
but you supported her.
You are such selfish person!
Immature!
You totally didn't care
about Cai-Jie's life.
You are such a jerk!
You are being irresponsible.
Father, I love Cai-Jie,
that's why...
Father...
Ya-Lun knows what I want
so he supported me.
No matter how dangerous
I am being pregnant, he
is pan of me now.
Father, I believe you understand.
I can't let go,
and I won't let go,
just like how I won't let
go our relationship.
To me, owning
the relationship means
owning the happiness,
do you understand?
Okay.
You can do whatever you
want. I can't control you.
But you, listen carefully!
If Cai-Jie is being hurt
I won't forgive you.
You can go out now.
Father, I want you to walk
me down the red carpet.
I want you to hold my hands.
Father, I'm talking to you.
Why didn't you reply me?
It's been such hard work
that I found both of you.
Do you want me to see
you disappear just like that?
I cannot bear the
risk of losing you.
But you wanted to
to be worried and afraid.
Now you are getting married,
but I can't congratulate you.
Do you know why?
Because I'm afraid...
I'm afraid of losing you again.
Do you understand now?
Go out! Go out now!
Father.
I'm afraid...
I'm afraid of losing Cai-Jie.
But I chose to stay by her side,
to give her courage,
because this is what she
insisted to do.
If you can accompany her,
she can face this unchanged
fact bravely, father...
I hand my daughter to you.
Father Zhen, thank you.
Please be happy.
I'm considered your father as well.
I know.
She's pregnant, please be careful.
Before the actual wedding ceremony,
the groom's relative would like
to send their blessings through a video.
Now let's watch this video together.
I'm sorry, I need to congratulate
Cai-Jie and Ya-Lun
through this video.
Your wedding...
Aunt has been watching
you since the beginning.
I believe that you
can have a happy
and perfect marriage.
At the same time,
I want to pray for your family,
especially to Cai-Jie and your
baby to be healthy
and stay safe.
Yes, there's one important
person wants to send his blessings.
Actually I should
sincerely congratulate
brother and Cai-Jie.
But I don't want everyone
to see my face now.
I'm sorry.
I'm fine here.
Mother is taking care of me,
and I'm receiving treatments.
During the process,
I have a deep experience.
I knew that...
Real love can't
be waited!
I thought of brother and
sister-in-law
during this time.
They have gone through
a lot of difficulties together.
No matter what happen,
you will face it together
without any hesitation.
Even you know that
Uncle Du will not accept you,
but you still insisted
and walk down the red carpet.
You don't want to wait,
because you believe in
each other's love.
You have persistence
in your family
and to your marriage.
I believe that you will
be fine in the future,
and live happily.
I will be happy as well.
Brother and Cai-Jie,
you do not need to wait.
Today is the happy ending for you.
I sincerely give my blessing.
Under the witness of God...
What is there to witness?
It's useless even if my daughter's
wedding is witnessed by God.
Du Li-De, what are you doing?
Don't try to mess things up.
This is my daughter's wedding.
What are you saying?
Let me through!
Father.
You, go down.
Everyone...
God wants to witness my daughter's
wedding with eyes but
not with any talking.
Others can hand to me.
Father, what are you trying to do?
What do you mean?
You can stop talking.
Zheng Ya-Lun,
please reply me properly.
Are you willing to
love Cai-Jie for the rest of
your life and listen to
what she says in the future?
Yes, I do.
Are you willing to let
her be happy until she
will never leave you,
and stay with you all the time?
Yes, I do.
Are you willing to let
her be prettier than
your female customers?
Cai-Jie is the prettiest
girl in my eyes.
So, yes I do.
Father, that's enough!
No, not enough.
One more important thing...
Little Curly, let me ask you.
Are you willing to
be a good brother
when the baby is born,
to love him and take care of him,
but not to fight with him,
or take his toys away?
Are you willing to?
Yes, I do.
Great!
So now,
under the witness
of God and me,
I announce that
Zheng Ya-Lun
and Du Cai-Jie
are officially husband and wife.
Cai-Jie, put on
the ring for your husband.
Cai-Jie...
Be careful.
Where is my baby?
Don't worry, you are fine now.
The baby is safe now
and very healthy.
Although it's premature birth,
but baby is fine,
and he's a boy.
He's sleeping comfortably
in the cooler now.
Most importantly he's healthy.
He's healthy like you.
Thank God!
We've been worried for so long,
now everything is fine.
Ya-Lun, do you know that
I'm so afraid when
I fainted at that time.
God knows you are a good
mother so He didn't let you suffer.
Cai-Jie, let me tell you.
My grandson is as
handsome as I am.
Who said that?
He has our family Qin's genetic.
It's the same.
Like father like son.
I have a handsome and
healthy great grandson now.
Ya-Lun, if your mom
and aunt Min-Hui knows,
they would be happy.
Ai-Jia.
I want to give
all my luck to you
and Zhong-Qi.
I believe, he
will be back soon.
So you must promise
me that you will be happy.
I will.
I know that I will.
Where is my ring?
Your ring? Here!
You brought along your ring.
It's here.
Did you help me wear the
ring during the ceremony?
No.
Then wear it now.
Wait, are you willing
to marry me?
Yes, I do.
My dear daughter,
I've never seen a
girl so nervous.
Why are you like that?
But I heard you can talk
properly, it means you are well now.
Okay, please repeat for me.
Yes, I do.
Here I come.
I want to eat you up.
Why? Why do you want to eat me?
You never came back to visit me,
and never concern about me.
I'm sorry.
Everything is fine here.
Please do not worry.
But Zhong-Qi's eyes
have no further improvement,
he needs more time for treatment.
April 15th, 2013.
Zhong-Qi's condition did not change,
so I've decided to
change a doctor to
treat Zhong-Qi.
Please do not worry,
I will not give up.
May 20th, 2013.
Although I don't want to say this,
and I don't want this result,
but there's no improvement
in Zhong-Qi's eyes. I
hope you are prepared.
July 10th, 2013.
Ai-Jia, why are you crying?
Min-Hui sent a letter
saying she brought Zhong-Qi
to see few doctors.
Doctors said that his
eyes will not get well.
Min-Hui have decided to
bring Zhong-Qi back.
At least Zhong-Qi is coming back.
Ai-Jia, grandma feels hurt
seeing you waiting
for him for so long...
But you are still young.
You still have such
long life.
I don't want to say this,
but for your own good...
I'm thinking if you want
to leave Zhong-Qi now...
Ai-Jia.
Come here.
You are a good girl.
She's right.
For the sake of you,
I hope you can go
search for your happiness.
Like father like daughter.
Father is just like you,
I've been waiting for your
mother for so many years,
we only meet in dreams.
Did mother say anything to you?
She scolded me.
She scolded that we
are too stubborn.
But it will be a tough path.
No, it's not tough at all.
I'm happy to love him.
The plane is here,
they will be here anytime.
Why are you so nervous?
He should be nervous.
We knew the result,
am I right?
Zhong-Qi.
Zhong-Qi...
Ai-Jia came to pick you.
Walk this way...
Zhong-Qi...
Min-Hui,
Qi-Hong
Zhong-Qi,
Ming-Yu.
Mommy, Zhong-Qi...
Let's talk over there.
We will meet in front.
Okay.
Zhong-Qi.
Are you okay?
Min-Hui.
Qi-Hong.
You are finally back.
Ming-Yu, mother.
Zhong-Qi,
do you miss me?
Yes.
Are you okay?
Brother.
Zhong-Qi, here.
Ai-Jia has been waiting for you.
Ai-Jia.
Zhong-Qi,
I miss you.
Ai-Jia,
but he can't see now.
Mommy.
Let's go.
Grandma is waiting at home.
Okay, let's go home.
From today onwards,
you don't need this.
I am your eyes.
Let's go.
Have a seat.
Son, are you tired?
Did you sleep?
Yes, grandma.
How's everyone?
It's been a long time.
Aunt, everyone is fine.
Mrs. Qin.
This year Ai-Jia took care of
Chairman and grandma.
Ai-Jia.
Since we are back,
you should be doing
what you should do.
Aunt,Ai-Jia she...
Mrs Qin, before I
went out today,
I've cleaned the house,
and I've prepared
the dishes for you.
Yes, Min-Hui.
Now everything includes
eat, drink, use and all
the housework is
done by Ai-Jia.
She did a good job,
what more do you want her to do?
Since I touched down
until now, she never called me.
Why did she call me Mrs. Qin?
Mrs. Qin...
Ai-Jia, who am I to you?
Yes.
Ai-Jia.
You this little girl.
You are one of our family now,
you should change the title.
The wedding last year went half
and the most important part didn't finish.
You must give tea to
your father-in-law
and mother-in-law.
Yes, tea.
Let me prepare.
Grandma.
Please drink tea.
Okay.
This year everyone sees
your effort and what you've
done to family Qin.
I'm so happy.
Thank you.
Father.
Please drink tea.
Okay.
I'm happy like
your grandma.
You are our
daughter-in-law
now.
I'm happy to drink this cup of tea.
I'm really very happy.
Thank you.
Mother.
Please drink tea.
Actually I brought Zhong-Qi
overseas for treatment
because Zhong-Qi doesn't
want you to suffer and
wait for him.
Zhong-Qi hopes that
you can forget him.
Previously I said
that I want to test you.
But I didn't expect the
test from God is even worse.
To test Zhong-Qi,
and to test you.
Although he's overseas,
but he misses you
everyday and every night.
No matter what I say
or what I told him,
he kept saying that he's wrong.
He should not let you stay.
Because he believe in your
love towards him.
So I told him...
If...
you are still here
when we come back,
waiting for him,
I will give my blessing.
Frankly speaking,
when I saw you,
I was touched.
That moment, I've decided
to give my blessings to you.
So...
Ai-Jia...
You passed the test!
Mom is happy that
the one beside
Zhong-Qi is still you.
You are truly qualified
to be Zhong-Qi's
wife now.
Thank you.
Here, Zhong-Qi.
Ai-Jia.
From today onwards,
please take care of Zhong-Qi.
Mom believe that you
can take care better than I do.
Ai-Jia.
Thank you.
I'm sorry.
Why did you apologize?
As long as you come back,
everything is worth it now.
Ai-Jia, bring your husband here.
Father, what do you want to do?
Why don't I have tea?
Okay, leave this.
He didn't come to my house,
and didn't accompany Ai-Jia.
Say goodbye.
This is what he should do.
Okay.
Here, you can kneel down.
Be careful.
Okay, forget about it.
The most important thing is
you ran after the
first night of wedding.
I will not repeat it.
Is there any next time?
My temper has gone up.
I'll hit you.
Shi-Hao.
I scared him. He can't see it!
You are...
Okay, please take good
care of my daughter. OK?
Be careful.
It's not convenient to
go out during rainy days.
No, I'm looking at the cloud,
it's going to be sunny day.
You've been at home for so long,
I want to bring you out.
The best part of automatic transmission
car is to be able to hold your hands.
Okay, let's go.
We're here.
Be careful.
Why did you want to come to seaside?
Because seaside meant
a lot to us.
Yes.
We built our relationship here.
Be careful. -I was being pushed
off when I first met you.
Be careful.
Is that He Zhong-Qi
with spectacles?
What are you doing?
Take him away!
Ai-Jia...
Ai-Jia, be careful.
Ai-Jia.
Ai-Jia,
are you okay?
Don't take my husband!
Ai-Jia...
Ai-Jia,
Fun!
Yes.
Min-Hui,
what is wrong? Why are you laughing?
Yes.
You've been acting strange
since you came back.
I'm fine. I'm really fine.
She's been smiling since
she came back.
You must be careful.
Nonsense!
What are you saying?
Come, I'll carry you.
Quick, Ai-Jia.
You can't carry me. -Let me carry you.
How will you see the road?
You will be my eyes.
Okay.
Straight. Quick!
Let's go.
I'm going.
Be careful.
Every time you carry me.
Let me carry you this time.
Okay, stop talking.
Let's go.
In front,
go straight.
This smells good.
Honey, you changed your shampoo.
You asked me not to joke,
but you are playing now.
Honestly, your hair color
now looks better.
They are coming, quick!
Okay!
Quick!
Shit!
Be careful!
I can see them.
Stop!
You can see them?
So you can see?
I...
You can see all the while?
No, it's not all the while.
I just managed to see just now.
I... Actually I...
Why did you lie to me?
I came back once my eyes get well.
I wanted to surprise you.
I was just joking, honey.
Please don't be angry.
Honey...
Don't move.
You are so brave. -Father...
You pretend to be blind
to lie to me and Ai-Jia.
Father, I didn't do it purposely.
No...
Do you know how her days were?
Worried, scared, disappointed...
Hope and disappointed again...
I need to teach him a lesson. -Enough!
Have you had enough?
Zhong-Qi apologized to me
and I pushed him into the sea?
What? Why did you do that?
Mother.
Relax.
I'm fine.
It's really my fault.
Okay.
Let me warn you,
if next year, you haven’t
give your grandmother, your
parents and me a grandson,
I'm going to blind you.
Okay, I will work hard.
He can't do it if you continue.
Okay, thank you everyone.
Let's go.
Remember to lock the door. -Shut up!
Here, sit down.
Did you hear...
Wait, you haven't tell me,
why did you lie to me?
I did remind you just now,
and I hope that both of
our life is full of surprises.
Secondly, I missed
the time when we first met
and the scene as well.
Most importantly we
have the same memories now
as our basic and stem
over a new life.
But I regretted when
I was being kicked
off into the sea.
If I found out that
I loved you, you
don't need to suffer.
Help! The wolf is coming!
I'm the big wolf, I want to eat you.
I want to eat little Red Riding Hood.
No!
Don't stop!
I want to be eaten.
I want to be with
the wolf forever.
Wait a minute...
Did you hear...
Did you hear anything?
What sound?
The true wolf is here!