THE WAVE
Making sure the kids
don't smoke in the yard, huh?
Hi, honey.
Hey, rocker!
Teachers are lazy, remember!
Just doing some copying.
You seen Mrs Kohlhage?
No, why?
She was looking for you.
Better see what she wants.
Autocracy?
I'm teaching the anarchy class.
Mr Wieland showed me his outline.
It's well thought-out.
- I'd have done mine this weekend.
- A bit late.
Wieland? Wieland doesn't have
a clue about it.
I studied in Berlin.
I squatted in Kreuzberg for five years.
May 1st demonstrations.
I'm an expert.
If it's that important,
ask Mr Wieland to trade.
Couldn't you...?
Work it out between yourselves.
Mr Wieland?
Mr Wenger.
- About the project subjects...
- What?
Could you trade with me?
I'm doing autocracy.
Alea iacta est.
The die is cast.
You know I wanted to do anarchy.
A bit too much!
Project week
is for showing the students
the virtues of democracy.
How to make Molotov cocktails
belongs in chemistry class.
If at all.
I loved you. You betrayed me.
But I haven't forgotten
my dream of life, love and trust,
the dream that once was real.
I will build it with my fortune
by destroying you.
Hey, thanks for the daisies, babe.
They'll look great
when I'm lying in the box.
He's making a fool of himself.
Know what I'm sayin', babe?
"I'll take you
to Capri in your coffin..."
- He's saying it wrong.
- It's what I want to say.
Ferdi, can't we do it right through
for once?
You're the one who stopped.
First stage rule:
The show must go on!
Aren't we applying the play's
criticism of capitalism to today?
That's why I'm updating
the dialogue.
OK, but don't make a joke out of it.
He can't assert himself.
Yeah, we're doing Dürrenmatt,
not Saturday Night Live.
Thank you for the wreaths,
chrysanthemums and roses...
dear sir!
That sounds like shit.
No way I'm saying that.
Forget it.
If Ferdi doesn't stick to his lines,
I can't do it.
I've had enough.
Are you coming?
It's a pity
they're not taking it seriously.
It's no use
if everybody does what they want.
Coming to the game today?
Lisa and I have to study for Spanish.
Not all afternoon?
What did you sign up for?
Sign up?
Project week.
- Are the lists up already?
- Sure.
- I was thinking of autocracy.
- Me too.
Gotta go.
- Will you sign me up?
- For what?
- Whatever you take.
- OK.
See you later.
I wanna see some grit.
Go and dominate!
Watch your defence
and counter man to man. Got it?
Eight minutes left. We can do it!
Marco,
that goes for you too.
Play as a team.
Let's go!
Mogli, move the ball up!
Nice, Marco!
Marco!
Sinan's wide open!
- Marco!
- Go for it!
Sinan's free!
What are you doing, damn it?
Sinan was wide open!
Don't you want to score?
Martin, you tell me...
What are we supposed
to rebel against nowadays?
Nothing means anything anymore.
We all just want to have fun.
What our generation lacks
is a common goal to unite us.
That'd just be the Zeitgeist.
Look around.
The most Googled name
on the Internet
is Paris Fucking Hilton!
No shit.
Stolte.
You got the dope today?
Sure I do.
- This is the real thing?
- Sure is.
A buddy brought it from Holland.
Are you nuts,
carrying that much dope?
Cops have to catch me first.
What do you want for it?
- Nothing.
- What?
It's free for you.
You're my homeys.
MONDAY
Baby.
The water's great.
60 degrees.
Don't you want to go for a swim?
It'd do you good.
Maybe later.
How's your shoulder?
It's OK now.
Don't overdo it.
Yeah, sure.
Coffee?
Sure, thanks.
Morning.
What's up?
- OK, Rainer?
- Yeah.
- Morning, Rainer.
- Sinan.
I have to say
I'm surprised so many of you
are interested in autocracy.
I'd have chosen anarchy.
- Lame Wieland?
- Your words, not mine!
So...
Autocracy. What does it mean?
Come on,
you signed up for this topic,
you must have certain expectations.
No hassles, I hope.
Jens, what do we mean
by autocratic government?
- Stuff like monarchy, I guess.
- Not necessarily.
Ferdi, what can you think of?
Autos that are crass!
That was pretty lame.
- Lisa, don't let me down.
- Dictatorship, maybe?
That's part of it. Karo?
I think autocracy is when
an individual or group
rules the masses.
Right.
Autocracy comes from the Greek
and means self-rule.
From auto, "self",
and kratia, "power", "rule"...
In an autocracy,
the ruler or rulers
have unlimited power
to change the law as they like.
Can you think of any examples?
Come on, a dictatorship!
- The Third Reich.
- Not again.
I didn't pick the topic,
but we have to get
through this week together.
I printed out some things for you.
All that stuff again?
It's an important topic.
The Nazis sucked.
All right, we get it!
And it's never gonna happen
here again.
What about Neo-Nazis?
We can't feel guilty forever.
We're not talking about guilt.
It's a historical responsibility.
Me a Turk, man!
- OK, we all know!
- What do we know?
Except
for some idiot East Germans...
Hey, I'm from the East!
You know. Skinheads.
- Can't we do something else?
- Like?
The Bush administration.
Wait, this is interesting.
You think another dictatorship
would be impossible in Germany?
We're way beyond that.
Marco, what do you think?
Beats me.
We'll take a ten-minute break.
What's the deal?
I changed the seating.
Now there's more room for everyone.
Fortunately, we can do
whatever we want during project week.
I propose we loosen things up a bit.
Any objections?
Very good.
What are the requirements
for an autocratic system?
Dennis?
- An ideology.
- Good. What else?
- Control.
- Surveillance.
You're getting
ahead of yourselves.
Unhappiness.
Interesting.
What does every dictatorship need?
We already mentioned it.
A Führer, man!
A Führer?
A word with lots of baggage.
But every dictatorship
has a central figure.
Let's go through this.
Who would that be here?
- You, the teacher.
- Me?
Who else?
One of you, for a change.
I'll be the leader.
No way! Rainer, you do it.
Let's vote.
Who wants me as your project leader?
- What is this?
- Play along.
Who's against? Any nays?
Abstentions?
- Good.
- Heil Rainer!
Of course, a leader deserves respect.
So you'll address me as Mr Wenger
for project week.
- Mr Wenger...
- Is he a megalomaniac now?
We just voted on it, didn't we?
- East German commie!
- Get with the programme!
Don't tell me what to do, bitch!
Watch your mouth, scumbag!
Quiet!
Clear off your desks.
From now on,
no one talks without permission.
- Yes, sir!
- Did I give you permission?
If you want to speak,
you'll stand up first.
- Isn't that going a bit far?
- Mona?
Isn't that going a bit far,
Mr Wenger?
- Feel anything?
- What?
Standing up gets your circulation going.
It's blood pressure.
If you stand up,
you wake up
and your concentration improves.
Sit down again.
Marco. You're tired from training,
but try sitting up straight.
Straighten your spine,
place your feet parallel
and breathe deeply.
Feel the difference?
Marco.
Yes, Mr Wenger.
It's better.
That's right,
you can breathe better.
Let's all do the same.
Everybody get up.
- Come on!
- What is this?
Breathe deeply.
Up you get.
Breathe in
and out.
- What's with you?
- No way!
Then leave, please.
No one's forcing you to stay.
Attendance is voluntary.
- Rainer, be cool.
- Mr Wenger.
Kevin, it's very simple.
Either play along or leave.
Well?
This is weirding me out.
Come on, Sinan.
Later daze!
You can sit down again.
What else is important
for a dictatorship?
- Discipline, Mr Wenger.
- Very good, Tim.
Discipline is power.
Let's go shoot some pool.
I've got a better idea.
Dude, what's that?
What happened to your M-class?
It's my mom's.
An anniversary present.
V-8, 250 bhp, 150 mph.
Wanna take this baby
for a spin on the Autobahn?
What's with you?
- I'm not coming.
- What do you mean?
I'm going back.
Have you totally lost it?
I've already failed twice.
You know what happens
if I don't graduate?
You're no honours student either.
I'm glad you changed your mind.
Have a seat in the back.
Thanks... Mr Wenger.
We were discussing
which social conditions
favour a dictatorship.
Lisa?
Which social conditions
are necessary?
Could you speak up, please?
Well, like, if there's injustice.
And, like, people don't know...
I mean, no jobs. And stuff.
Hey, Jens, what's the big idea?
Lisa, have a seat.
Take a deep breath.
Think what you're going to say.
Keep your answer short.
You can do it.
Try it again. OK?
High unemployment and social injustice.
Excellent. High unemployment
and social injustice
certainly would favour
a dictatorship.
Tim?
High inflation, Mr Wenger.
Good. Inflation.
- Political disillusionment.
- Very good, Karo.
Nationalism.
We saw it during the World Cup,
there were German flags everywhere.
But that was great!
I thought it was revolting.
That's what rocked
about the World Cup!
If Germans can't be proud
of their country, like anyone else,
itjust leads to the reverse,
to hatred of everybody else.
I think Mona means extreme nationalism.
Can we agree on that?
That was awesome today.
Thank you.
Mr Wenger?
After class call me Rainer again.
I really enjoyed it today.
Keep up your contributions.
Yes sir, Mr Wenger!
Watch it!
Why don't you watch it?
Be nice to your sister.
Just gimme a light!
- You shouldn't smoke.
- My dad says I can.
I've got a light.
Torsten just said it's up to you.
None of your business, anyway.
Ignore the little weirdo.
- Retard!
- You're the retard!
Don't you have a home
of your own?
Hi, hon.
Hi, sweetie.
You thirsty, too?
Aren't you going to ask me
how it went?
How did it go?
It was totally fascinating.
Mr Wenger taught us
how to sit right.
Upright, with your spine straight.
You know when you stand up quickly
and your vision goes all blurry?
That's because your pulse is low.
More roast?
Now we have to stand up to speak.
It's good for your circulation.
And keep our answers to the point.
Good. Why don't you, then?
There was this bizarre energy.
Everybody was caught up in it.
"Bizarre" is right.
What's that supposed to mean?
"Discipline is power"...
Karo, honey,
that's not how we raised you.
Maybe you should have.
Leon could use a bit of discipline.
He needs to learn his own limits.
It doesn't work for everyone.
Why?
I kicked Kevin out of class.
I'll kick your ass!
Get off it! Rainer's cool.
- You traitor!
- I'd have kicked you out too.
Besides, Rainer didn't kick you out.
Mr Wenger did.
He's always dissed me
'cause I'm not
in his faggy water-polo team.
What do you guys do there?
We practise hard.
I don't know why we're losing.
We have to beat Ernst Barlach High,
or we'll lose our league standing.
Come by sometime.
When's your next game?
Marco, let's go to my room.
We're watching the race.
We can watch it in my room.
We have our project assignment.
- What assignment?
- Are you coming?
Sorry, Torsten.
You go do your project assignment.
Hey, my little honeybee.
What say we do
our own "project assignment"?
I hear role-playing
can be pretty stimulating.
I thought we were going
to do something else.
Here, check this out.
Here's where we'll go.
The hippest part of Barcelona.
Only seven stops to the soccer stadium.
Isn't it a bit far?
Seven stops?
Barcelona.
It's beautiful. Right on the sea.
An artist's city.
Wouldn't your family miss you?
They get on my nerves.
Torsten and Bine are cool.
Sometimes they're too cool for me.
Stop whining.
Come here.
I'm not in the mood.
You're not moving tomorrow.
What's the hurry?
I have to sign up soon.
Then sign up.
Come on. Don't go yet.
I've got practice.
Wait.
Not here. Come on.
What the hell was that?
What the hell's wrong with you?
- Listen, man...
- Leave me alone.
Let's play together. Everyone
will expect you to hog the ball.
I'll swim into the clear on the left
and pass back to you, OK?
Get out! Sülo, you play.
Nice, Marco!
That's better.
That was a real play.
Finally!
Hi, sweetie, I'm home.
What's going on?
I just want to print something.
Those two get old real fast.
A real couple of teachers.
Are we like that too?
What's all this for?
Just a few ideas
I want to try out tomorrow.
I have a few ideas too!
Only if you put on
your nurse costume.
We'll see.
How about an injection?
I've got an injection
that's all ready to go!
Really?
Let's see it, then.
TUESDAY
Here he comes.
Morning.
Good morning, Mr Wenger.
You're making fun of me, huh?
No.
Everybody stand up, please.
Now do as I do.
These are a few warm-up exercises
to loosen up your muscles.
Especially the legs.
And now in unison.
Left, right...
What's the big idea?
I want to show you something.
Good.
You feel it?
We're becoming a single unit.
That's the power of unity.
- How long do we keep this up?
- Until we're in step.
You know that from dancing, right?
Left, right...
A rhythm like this
can cause bridges to collapse.
- Kaschi, you're out of step.
- Chill, man!
I think we get it, Mr Wenger.
No, you don't.
- This exercise has another purpose.
- What's that?
Wieland's anarchy class
is below us.
I want the plaster to fall
off the ceiling onto our "enemy".
Excellent!
Have they gone crazy?
Unity is power.
You want to know
why I rearranged the seating?
To break up your usual cliques.
You all have your friends and groups.
That's important.
You can't
get through life all by yourself.
But together,
we are much, much stronger.
The new seating has a method to it.
Do you know what it is?
Anyone?
Karo, why are you sitting
next to Jens and not Marco?
Because Marco and I
distract each other?
Oh, do you?
Wieland down there
wants to foster his students
by making them Ione warriors.
You know what I mean.
No one letting the other copy.
I say that leads
to social Darwinism.
I'm convinced if we pull together,
we'll be much stronger.
So we can copy from each other?
If it means better grades, yes.
That's why I'm checking your grades,
and seating the good
next to the bad.
I want you to help each other.
That's total bull!
I don't believe it.
Please stand up.
You wouldn't embarrass us like this.
All the poor students
are lined up like ducks in a row.
I never said anything about
poor students. Just poor grades.
There are no poor students.
You're good in my class,
but you struggle in math.
Lisa, however, is a math whiz.
You can help each other.
And there's another advantage.
The whole class would do better.
Better than the anarchists downstairs.
I know it's unorthodox.
But why not try something new?
Hey, Tommy. Pretty loud, huh?
How's it going with Wieland,
our Bavarian?
I thought anarchy would be interesting.
But he just blows.
He's such a jerk.
If you guys hadn't raised hell,
I would've dozed off.
What was that?
A little calisthenics
to wake them up.
Calisthenics?
I thought the building
was going to collapse.
My students are outraged,
and justly so.
Can I help you kids?
We wanted to ask if we can switch
to the autocracy group.
Right away, if possible.
We were talking about group unity.
What are the signs of group unity?
Team spirit, Mr Wenger.
Good. But I meant visual signs.
- Dress, Mr Wenger?
- Correct.
A common way of dressing.
Uniformity, you could say.
Uniforms suck.
Dominik?
I mean,
uniforms are totally fascist.
Not necessarily military uniforms.
There are all kinds:
McDonald's, stewardesses, meter maids...
Even business suits
are a dress code.
Your outfit
is a kind of uniform too.
It indicates your social group.
Lisa?
Uniforms can serve another purpose.
They eliminate social differences.
But they eliminate individuality too.
Mona, would you stand up, please?
Lisa, would you explain that to us?
Well, I mean, we all stress out
every morning over what to wear.
If we all wore a uniform,
we wouldn't have to.
In Hamburg they're talking
about reintroducing school uniforms.
Does that make sense?
Sure, but they'd have to be
cheap enough for everyone to afford.
Marco, why don't you tell everybody?
I was saying...
The Knicks' Stephon Marbury
developed a basketball shoe
that costs $14.98,
the "Starbury One".
He's a ghetto kid and wanted a shoe
kids could afford,
instead of expensive Nike Airs.
A good example.
How can he market them so cheaply?
Because they're made
in Chinese prison camps.
No, they just do
without expensive ad campaigns.
Nike spends
hundreds of millions on ads.
David Beckham
got 80 million from Adidas.
What say we adopt a school uniform
for the duration of project week?
Like what?
A pair ofjeans, a white shirt.
Everyone has that.
- I don't have a white shirt.
- Then buy one.
I'm not spending money for that.
Come on, how much can it cost?
Jens, stand up, please.
I've got two.
You can have one of mine.
That's what I call team spirit!
Good for you!
It's decided, then.
- Two of the same?
- Right.
You already bought one.
That'll be 110 euros.
Thank you.
- Receipt?
- Don't worry about it.
These must really be hip.
That'll be 45, please.
Excuse me, but my things
may be in here, too.
Where are you going in that?
Why?
You look like a nun.
Well, I like it.
Where's your white shirt?
WEDNESDAY
I didn't like it.
- Why not?
- I just don't look good in white.
So that's it. Pure vanity again.
I don't have to explain
why I don't want to wear a dumb shirt!
That's just what Mr Wenger
was talking about.
Pure egoism.
Karo, we agreed.
Mind your own business!
She doesn't look good in white.
Good morning.
Mona has switched classes.
More newcomers.
We're definitely full now.
Go ahead and find a seat.
Jules and Frederik
wanted to join us too.
Full means full.
Now that we're so many,
we need a name, don't we?
Excellent. That was my next topic.
Any suggestions?
Terror Squad.
Serious suggestions only.
Visionary Club.
- The Wave.
- You would say that!
It's great. It fits.
True. Tim?
Tsunami.
That's overdoing it.
The Base.
The Pact.
The White Giant.
The Inner Circle.
The Risen.
- The Centre.
- That's good too.
Anyone else?
No one?
The Changers.
The Changers?
That's quite a few.
I'll write some down.
OK, last suggestion...
The Changers.
We have a winner.
From now on we are The Wave.
That's really good.
Helps me concentrate.
Honest.
I like it.
Why not design a logo for us?
- For real?
- Yes.
You design our logo.
That brings us to the next step.
Action is power.
What's the use of great ideas
if we don't actually do something?
I want everyone to contribute
to The Wave, for the greater good.
I'll set up a profile
on MySpace for us.
Great.
- I wanted to do that.
- Do it together.
No. I'd rather do something
on my own.
Why don't you make a website?
We can make buttons with the logo.
My aunt has a machine.
We could have tattoos. On our arms.
Postcards to hand out...
Hey, what's up?
A friend of mine is out of stash.
I heard you can get dope.
Hey, my money's good.
Go buy it on the street.
What's going down over there?
They're shaking down Stoltefuss.
I don't sell dope
to anarchist freaks.
What's that mean?
Check out his pretty shirt.
Mommy buy it for you?
Leave me alone, you fucks!
Hey, take it easy.
Everything's cool.
Is there a problem here?
- Two more weirdoes.
- What?
This a gang thing?
If you hassle Tim,
we'll kick your ass.
All right.
Fucking fascists.
Those anarchist freaks
tore my shirt.
Don't let those scumbags
push you around.
- You got my back.
- If we're not here?
Tim, listen,
let me give you my number.
If those fags hassle you,
you gimme a call, OK?
Sure.
What was that earlier?
I don't know,
she's angry about something.
I can't get through to her.
I've noticed that too, recently.
It bothers me
when she tells me what to do.
She makes plans
without bothering to ask me.
Why should I even follow her
to Spain?
Ten months from now
she'll have some guy
named Juan or Miguel
or whatever.
I'm scared I'll lose her.
Karo, this is Dennis. Where are you?
It's total chaos.
Call me back
when you get this message, OK?
- Voicemail.
- Like I said.
But she knows
we're rehearsing today.
No big loss.
I bet she's pissed off because
nobody voted for "The Changers".
I'm not sitting around all day
waiting for our little princess.
I'm with you.
Hey, wait a minute.
Lisa, I'm going too.
If you leave now, we can bag the play!
Is that what you want?
I think we can produce
something really great.
A play that means something.
Notjust entertainment,
but a message.
But not without Karo.
You wanted her to play the lead.
I was against
that consensus rule.
I thought we should have
real auditions.
We never really voted on it, anyway.
Could you all be quiet for a moment?
Let's do it the way I say.
Just once.
Your big break, Maja.
You're Claire Zachanassian.
Cool.
- And Lisa, you play Maja's role.
- Me?
Sure. You know the part.
Just go for it.
And Ferdi, stick to the text
and don't clown around for once, OK?
Man, I'm glad that day's over.
Rainer was doing
cool stuff with us.
You should join up again.
The Wave needs you, man.
How will that look?
You don't have to come to class.
You can still join.
Hey, let us have a go!
- What do you want?
- To skate!
You're that bitch Karo's brother.
- Got a problem with that?
- She's a cunt.
So what else is new?
The pipe belongs to The Wave.
You want to skate, you have to join.
... sits /n the forest for the /ast time,
fu// of cuckoos and how//ng winds.
Tonight, the congregation
w/// assembie.
Dennis said I was really good.
And now Maja has my role?
Well, it was just to try it out.
Where were you?
I wasn't feeling good.
And Ferdi's sticking to the text?
Dennis finally put his foot down.
You're all against me,
in your white shirts.
- Bull!
- But it's working now!
Just because we voted
against your name.
Excuse me?
You rub people up the wrong way.
Are you nuts?
Has it ever occurred to you
Marco may not want to go to Spain?
- Why do you say that?
- He told me.
What else did he tell you?
How often we make it?
You suck, you know that?
I suck?
What if I talked
to your boyfriend like that?
I don't have a boyfriend.
In case you hadn't noticed.
It's all about you.
You know what?
Maja was much better than you.
But you don't care about that.
You're pissed off
because you're not top dog in The Wave.
A shitty feeling, isn't it?
Get used to it!
Hi.
I want to show you something.
Look.
Here.
- What is it?
- Know what a slacker Kaschi is?
He made us a MySpace page.
Cool, huh!
Way cool!
- Honey.
- Yes?
Kaschi's totally psyched.
The kids are changing.
Sure, like all wearing white shirts!
OK, I forgot to change.
The faculty are talking about you.
Haven't they always?
Since when do you care?
I'm just saying.
- That's our sign.
- Cool.
We'll roll over the town
like a wave.
That looks rad on a wall!
My respect.
What's he doing here?
What's your problem, retard?
Be glad you're in.
Peace, guys.
Anyone can join The Wave
who believes in the cause.
Tim's right.
Kevin bailed.
Why the change of mind?
Chill!
Kevin had 5,000 stickers printed.
That shows he's worthy.
Sure, sponsored by daddy.
I think Mr Wenger
should decide if he can join or not.
Mr Wenger taught us about unity.
United we stand.
I bet your Mr Wenger wouldn't like
us tagging the whole town.
You're getting too uptight.
I thought we were here to have fun.
Well?
OK, grab the stuff and let's go.
Everyone got stickers?
What's going on?
Hey, guys!
What's wrong, retard?
Cover up the anarchy clowns' scribbles.
Righteous!