Resync to 720p Bluray version by OlyOrvablé™
[Crowd Noise]
King Chulalongkorn:
She was the first Englishwoman
I had ever met,
and it seemed to me she knew more
about the world than anyone,
but it was a world Siam
was afraid would consume them.
The monsoon winds had whispered
her arrival like a coming storm.
Some welcomed the rain,
but others feared a raging flood.
Still, she came,
unaware of the suspicion
that preceded her.
But it wasn't until years later that I
began to appreciation how brave she was.
And how alone
she must've felt.
An Englishwoman,
the fiirst I'd ever met.
[Shouting
ln Siamese]
Mother, come look.
I think they've killed someone!
Louis, do take care
about the railing, honey.
Beebe, Moonshee,
gather your things.
It's time we went ashore now.
Come on, Louis.
I still think that we should wait
until someone from the palace arrives.
Yes, well, if they were coming,
they would've been here already.
- Besides, the ship is leaving.
- My point exactly.
Good-bye, Mrs. Leonowens.
Uh, watch your step.
Louis?
[Arguing ln Siamese]
Louis.
Pardon me.
Louis, come along,
darling.
- Mother?
- Yes?
Why does this king need you
if nobody here speaks English?
Because the ways of England
are the ways of the world.
It's a wise man
who knows that.
Memsahib,
in less than an hour
the Newcastle sails,
not to return
for another month.
Tonight, we shall all sleep in our
own beds in our own home, I promise.
Ah, madam, madam, madam,
a carriage? Where, a carriage?
Wait, wait. Ah...
[Stumbling ln Siamese]
This way, darling.
This way. Come on.
What do you suppose he's like,
this King Mongkut, hmm?
Now, I've heard that people
used to be forbidden
to even look
at his face.
They revere him
as a god.
You mean like Jesus?
No, hardly.
But I suppose
if he wishes his son
to be tutored
in the ways
of the west, then...
I should be
quite honored.
But why couldn't he
just send him to London?
Then you wouldn't have the chance
to learn Siamese, now, would you?
Gracious me! Are we sure
this is the right road?
How would we know?
If you are not
the lead elephant,
the scenery never changes.
Mother, look
at those statues.
[Soldiers Drilling]
Mem Leonowens, kawrub.
Mrs. Leonowens,
His Excellency
Chao Phya Kralahome,
the prime minister of Siam.
[Speaking Siamese]
Have you any friends
in Bangkok, sir?
No. I know
no one here.
Sir is married?
A widow.
Can you please
explain to me
why you call me
"sir"?
Women do not stand
in the presence
of His Excellency.
[Interpreter
Speaking Siamese]
How long are you in possession
of dead husband?
23 months.
How did he die?
Can you please convey
to His Excellency
that my purpose here
is as tutor to
the king's eldest son,
that it is not necessary
to ask any more
personal questions.
Please.
In Siam, sir...
it is custom
to first ask questions
ofpersonal nature
to be polite.
[Speaking Siamese]
Mr. Prime Minister,
I meant
no disrespect.
However, getting here
was something of a challenge.
Sir will be shown
to palace quarters.
Mem?
I beg your pardon?
The king promised us a home
outside the palace walls.
It's what
was agreed upon.
In Siam, sir,
you will learn
everything
has its own time.
[Monks Chanting Sutras]
Don't bother unpacking, Moonshee.
It's only for one night.
We shall all be settled
to our satisfaction,
or we'll be leaving
as soon as possible.
Thought we didn't have
any money.
That is correct.
but at the moment,
I do not need
to be reminded ofthat.
[Chanting]
Sounds like we're
living in a beehive.
In the morning, I shall
go directly to the king.
A monarch who refuses to keep his word
is uncivilized, unenlightened,
and, frankly,
ungrateful.
There are principles
at stake here.
Having a proper British
household with some privacy
is one of them.
I don't think Siam
agrees with you, Memsahib.
Mother, how can it be
a proper household?
You haven't lived in England
since you were a little girl,
and I've never
been there at all.
India is British, Louis.
That's what being colonized
is all about.
Father would've put him
right in his place.
I'm very sorry
I'm not the man
your fatherwas.
I'm sorry, Louis.
This is a good opportunity
for us, hmm?
I shall just...
try to look
at the positive side.
Assuming there is one.
Your father would've.
He was
a brave man...
wasn't he?
Yes. Very.
And most considerate.
Which is more than
I can say for this king.
Shall we go
find your bed?
Yeah.
[Woman Keening]
Kralahome: Unfortunate
your meeting so delayed, sir.
King's obligation reach
into every corner ofSiam.
Anna: Well, it
has given me the time
to think of many things,
Your Excellency,
including why
you pretended
not to speak English.
I have learned it wise
to be cautious.
Then I will assume
that our speaking now
is a great step forward.
Best not to assume
too much.
Hmm.
When presented
to His Majesty,
you and son
will remember to touch
forehead to floor.
Your Excellency,
although we have become
better acquainted
with your customs,
we have certainly
not forgotten our own.
Then how
will you greet him?
With the utmost respect.
[Man Speaking French]
Mother,
are those men
- speaking French?
- Yes?
Apparently, a warship's run aground
where it shouldn't have.
[Speaking Siamese]
Leroi vous
remercie, monsieur.
It appears
sir must wait
to meet His Majesty
another day.
No. I do not think so.
Come along.
Kralahome:
Mem Leonowens.
Mem Leonowens!
Mem, wait!
Please!
Your Majesty...
I am Anna Leonowens.
I'm a school--
- Stop!
- Aah!
Who? Who?
Kralahome: Your Majesty,
Mem Anna Leonowens
and son Louis.
Anna: Your Majesty...
we have been kept waiting
for nearly 3 weeks.
And although I appreciate
that you have issues
of...great importance,
I would imagine that your son's
education would be far more--
Silence!
You...
are teacher?
Yes, Your Majesty, I am.
You do not look
sufficient of age
for scientific
teaching.
How many years
have you?
Enough to know
that age and wisdom
do not necessarily go
hand in hand, Your Majesty.
I doubt
you would say same
for being bold
and English.
They are rather inseparable,
I'm afraid.
His Majesty has not
dismissed you. Follow him!
Come along, Louis.
Up, up, up. Quickly.
Anna: Uh, pardon me.
Pardon me.
You articulate
logical answer
under pressure,
Mem Leonowens.
That is very kind
of you, Your Majesty.
But irritating superior attitude,
King find most unbeautiful.
However,
it will serve you well,
given decision
I now make.
First impressions can
often be very misleading.
Along with
my eldest son...
you shall now teach
all my children.
Come.
[Children Playing]
King Mongkut:
The royal family.
23 wives...
42 concubines...
58 offspring,
and 10 more on the way.
Each one unique,
each one my hope
for the future.
I understand your surprise.
Not as many
as emperor ofChina,
but he did not spend
half of life
in monastery.
King making up
for lost time.
Mother, what's
a concubine?
Shh.
[Gong Sounds]
Presenting
original pupil
and heir apparent
Prince Chulalongkorn.
This, my son,
is your new teacher.
It is a great honor,
Your Highness.
He doesn't look
too happy about it.
This is a necessary
and practical gift
I give to you,
and you must never forget
to honor
your renowned teacher
Mem Anna Leonowens.
Ahem! Uh...
[Speaking Siamese]
Oh. Must not forget
head wife
the Lady Thiang.
It is my pleasure
that you help make her
fine scholar also.
Lady Thiang.
Welcome,
Mem teacher.
Prince...
Thongkon Yai.
Prince Suk Sawat.
Princess Kannika Kaeo.
[Laughter]
and Princess Fa-ying.
I'm not princess.
I'm monkey!
Ha ha!
My deepest apologies.
[Speaks Siamese]
I study her
in English myself.
Well, Your Majesty,
I am most flattered
by your welcome,
and I find the opportunity
to be in school
an exciting one.
Such devotion to progress
is to be commended.
[Coughs]
Reform is vital for
my country's survival.
As tiny feet change,
so, too, will Siam.
But being in a country
with so many unique customs,
If l am to raise my son
to be like his father,
which I very much hope
he will be,
then I must feel free to
follow our own traditions.
As a father,
I understand.
Good. Then His Majesty
will appreciate
why having a home
outside the palace walls
is of such
great importance to us.
A home which...
had been promised,
but so far has not
been provided.
It is my pleasure
that you live
in the palace.
But it is not mine,
Your Majesty.
You do not set conditions
of your employment.
And you shall obey!
May I respectfully
remind His Majesty
that I am not his servant,
but his guest!
A guest who's paid.
Education
begins tomorrow.
He sounds absolutely dreadful,
ifyou ask me.
Did unnerve me,
I must say.
Louis: Moonshee,
why does the king
have so manywives?
That is
an excellent question...
foryour mother.
Mother...
I heard you, Louis.
Well, uh...
Siam is a monarchy,
just like England,
and one way
that a royal family
maintains its control
in the face ofwar
and disease
is to have as many
children as possible.
So he needs
a lot ofwives
to take care
ofthem.
A keen observation,
darling.
Time for bed.
Come give us a kiss.
Does he love all of them?
In a way.
Like you loved father?
Things are very
different here, Louis.
Even love.
Go on. Off to bed.
Mother, why doesn't
Queen Victoria
have a lot of husbands?
Together:
Good night, Louis.
Presenting
royal school, sir.
Is anything wrong, sir?
No. No, no.
Nothing at all,
Lady Thiang.
Louis,
that'll be
your desk.
Yes. Well, I suppose
class is now in session.
Sit down.
Greetings, Mem Leonowens.
My father wish
to give sir this
to put on path
of good teaching.
Well, I shall...
certainly bear that
in mind, Your Highness.
Uh, may I complimentyou
on your English?
Siam...
population
6 million,
spreading across 49
bountiful provinces,
from Burma in west
to Cambodia in east.
Presided over by
King Maha Mongkut,
Iord oflife,
whose strength and power
reach everywhere.
Not in my house,
they don't.
Son of teacher
is forgetting
I am son of King.
Son of teacher
couldn't care less.
You will sit
somewhere else.
I will not.
Louis, remember
what I told you.
I'm sorry,
Mother,
but he
started it.
In my country,
man never tell woman
he is sorry
about anything.
Ever.
If you had father,
you would know that.
You don't have
a father!
You have a map!
Louis.
Is forbidden
to touch royalty!
I didn't touch you!
I shoved you!
Why don'tyou get
one ofyour slaves
to shove me back?!
[Children Yelling]
Anna: Let me through.
Excuse me.
Stop. Stop.
That's enough.
Why?
Prince insult memory
of boy's father.
Louis: 997...998...
999...
1 ,000.
Finished.
You may go home.
Aren't you coming?
Not until
Prince Chulalongkorn
finishes his task.
[Dishes Clattering]
I'm sorry,
Lady Thiang,
but supper
will have to wait.
The prince has not
yet been dismissed.
His Majesty,
King Mongkut,
afraid school teacher
might get hungry
during long night ahead.
He send food...for one.
Why does my father
humble me?
Well, he wants
what's best for you.
For the moment,
that includes me.
Why?
Most people do not see
the world as it is.
They see it as they are.
And a good king
needs a broaderview.
[Woman Lamenting]
Stay here, Your Highness.
[Woman Crying]
[Crying Continues]
[Crying]
What is that smell?
She has been chained
outside for 6 weeks.
And all because she tried
to buy her own freedom?
Mem Leonowens,
JaoJom Manda Ung is daughter
of very influential family.
Yes, and when La-ore
offered her the money,
she took it.
Her mistress took it.
And then she
accused her of ingratitude
and chained her
like an animal
where the prince and I
found her last night.
Heir to throne must
never be involved
in issue of bond-servant.
It will resolve
itself in time.
Like my house?
You are learning.
I've been been doing
much thinking, Mem teacher
on why some in this life
are masters,
IikeJaoJom Manda Ung,
and others, slaves.
Well, that is something that
you need to ask your father.
But you are teacher.
Teach.
Um...
This was written
by an American woman,
Harriet Beecher Stowe,
who asked the same question.
Perhaps you should read her,
and then we might
continue our discussion.
A woman?
Yes.
"Uncle Tom's Cabin. "
I shall read it
at once, Mem.
Anna: Come along, Louis.
Quickly, darling.
Don't want to be
late for school.
Were you not commanded
to leave slave issue alone?
Your Excellency,
I'm fully prepared to obey
His Majesty's commands
within the obligation
of my duties.
Beyond that,
I promise no obedience.
You will follow!
La-ore purchased her freedom
once, Your Majesty.
And I believe, had I given
this woman my ring first,
she would have
simply taken it
and continued
to hold La-ore captive.
King's commitment
to noble families
must not be compromised.
In your letter confirming
my employment, Your Majesty,
you claimed you wanted
Siam to take its place
among the nations
of the modern world.
You spoke of
building something
greater than yourself,
a country where
no man is above the law.
Which is why
I chose to come here.
School teacher
has outstanding memory.
Kralahome...
if you would please
honor Jao Jom Manda Ung
with an explanation
of the law.
[Splash]
Why did you
interfere?
My conscience
demanded it.
In boys' fisticuffs?
I beg your pardon?
I suppose since you must be
both mother and father to son,
tendency to overprotect
is strong.
Louis can fend for himself,
Your Majesty.
It was your son
I was protecting.
Thank you
for the supper.
Although I do not
think it was necessary.
I know my son.
You would still be there.
Perhaps.
But then my point
would have been made,
Your Majesty, not yours.
I am King.
Yes, and I am
his school teacher.
Which lesson do you
think he learned?
To respect
his classmates
or to fear
his father?
Husband must have been
very understanding.
My husband was
never threatened
by my ideas
or my opinions.
And because I am also such,
I will allow you
to always stand upright
in my presence,
providing head shall
never be higher than mine.
Thank you,
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
I believe there's
been enough insult
caused by this woman...
who believes herself to
be the equal of a man.
Not the equal of a man,
Chao Phya...
the equal of a king.
I make this for you
tomorrow.
Why, thank you,
Fa-ying.
It's beautiful.
These are monkeys
at summer palace.
Oh, and this must beyou.
Well, I shall hang it
on my wall at home.
I'll make another
for you yesterday.
Then I shall
wait for it tomorrow.
Lady Thiang.
Good morning,
Mem Leonowens.
This is
Lady Tuptim.
She's new in palace,
also like yourself.
[Greets ln Siamese]
I wish...
also to learn
writing of English
to--to please His
Majesty, King Mongkut.
Yes, well, certainly.
But I should hope that it would
please Lady Tuptim as well.
And this is for you.
Make sure all
of your books are open.
Who knows the next letter
in the alphabet after " E"?
Pupils: " F."
" F."
Who can tell me
which words start with " F"?
King Mongkut:
Fa-ying loves the river.
Hmm?
Yes, she told me all about
her journey to Ayudyha.
How it is the center
of the universe.
It is home to ancient ones
and their many legends.
I told her that
in England we have Camelot.
And a big round table.
Yes, that's right.
Everyone should
have legends, I think.
It allows us to dream.
You're an interesting
mix of fact and fancy.
I suppose it's because I'm
always surrounded by children.
Teaching theyoung is
fulfilling endeavorment.
I didn't have
a choice, really.
Buddhists believe
all life is suffering.
Take away pain
of husband's death,
takes away
Mem's chance to grow.
I might have preferred
a different lesson.
Yes.
But unique opportunity
to change world
would have passed
to someone else.
Louis.
Do try and stay
in the boat, darling.
Yesterday he asked me
about your flag
and the significance
of the white elephant.
I had no answer.
Louis Leonowens.
Uh, yes, Your Majesty?
I am teacher now.
The flag of Siam.
- Red is for?
- Courage.
- White?
- Compassion.
The white elephant
is Siam's most rare
and honored creature.
Perhaps onjourney
to rice festival,
we will all see one.
Rice festival?
Louis: Mother!
Mother, look!
There's Moonshee
and Beebe.
King Mongkut: I trust
you will find ample space
for engaging
in English traditions,
even for growing of roses.
Out of curiosity,
is this because
of our agreement,
or are you simply
trying to get rid of me?
Yes.
Moonshee:
A little soap and water,
and we will have
a fine house, Mem.
Shall I make us
some tea?
Yes, that
would be lovely.
[Boatmen Chant]
Tuptim: I remember
my first rice festival.
People come from
everywhere to see King.
He bless all crops,
and it began to rain.
I think he was a god.
And now?
He is also a man.
Well...
I feel very fortunate
that we were invited.
One cannot see
Siam's beauty
Iiving
in Bangkok, Mem.
Mountains
are so green,
and the skies
are more blue
than even your eyes.
I must find Louis.
Louis?
May I ask
a favor, Mem?
Yes, certainly.
To send this.
I wish family to know
how happy I am here with King.
I'll tell Moonshee to find
a messenger straightaway.
Thank you.
Mem?
May I ask a question?
Yes.
How did husband die?
In my arms, actually.
How did Mem survive?
Just as you will,
one awful day at a time.
Teacher,
Louis is teasing me!
He say in England,
coldness fall from sky
Iike tiny feathers.
Why would
I lie about snow?
Please, Mem,
it is too hot.
Can make some now?
Just because your father
can make it rain,
doesn't mean
I can make it snow.
King Mongkut: At last,
I discover her limitations!
I have many,
Your Majesty.
Father,
will you make
it snow, please?
Even for you,
I cannot.
But I've seen photographs
of such phenomenon.
Blankets of it.
Up to here.
Louis, smoke?
Me?  Jolly good!
No. No!
But, Mother,
he's the king.
And father smoked, too.
Yes, but
your father was a man
who had already achieved
his full height.
I have been smoking
since age 6.
And some believe me
to be a giant among men.
Yes, in intelligence
as well as stature,
Your Majesty.
Which is why, Louis,
I'm sure His Majesty
was only teasing.
I believe now is good time
for all children
to spread amazing concept
of snow to cool off court.
Yes?
Children: Yes!
I simply meant
to open conversation
in controversial fashion
Mem is so fond of.
I do have my opinions,
Your Majesty,
but they're merely that.
I wish to compliment you
for enlightening children
to open minds and taste life.
However, at this time,
I shall not
offer cigar to your son,
and you shall not teach
this book to mine.
Chulalongkorn
has many questions,
but one cannot plow new fields
in Siam overnight.
I understand,
Your Majesty.
[Siamese Music]
Anna: Honestly, Louis,
I leave you alone
for 5 minutes...
It was his idea.
Now just because
Prince Chulalongkorn
jumps off a bridge
doesn't mean you must as well.
How can anyone
smoke those things?
Well, your father
certainly enjoyed them.
Is that
why you like him?
The king, I mean.
'Cause he reminds
you of father?
I think that cigar has
clouded your brain, young man.
Go on, go to sleep.
Kincaid: You drag me out
in the middle of the night
and turn down
5 pounds a bushel!
Siamese Merchant:
French offer 7.
What is the matter
with you people?
You seem to have
a very high opinion
of the quality
of your produce.
That is the best price
you're gonna get!
Not gonna offer
any more!
No more concessions!
That's it!
[Speaking Siamese]
[Shouting]
[Gunfire]
Now, we all know
that this egg
will never
fit into this bottle.
It's a fact.
It's the truth.
And we rely on truth to
make judgments, don't we?
What if our judgment
is wrong,
even when we know for a fact
that it must be right?
Do we rely on our eyes?
Or do we believe
in the impossible?
You see, one way
to achieve the impossible
is to change the climate.
[Clattering Of Desks]
The French say
I am uncivilized ruler.
I, who has spent
entire life
attempting to
teach selfhistory,
Iiterature, and science.
Why would they print
such things, Your Majesty?
You are English.
You should not
be so surprised.
Well, I can
still be appalled.
More importantly,
do you, as a foreigner,
see me in this light?
I do not know all
that you are, Your Majesty.
But I believe
I know what you are not.
And you are not
what they say.
Thank you, Mem,
for humble validation.
I have decided
to give self
anniversary dinner
and invite important English
nobles and diplomats.
I don't understand.
French lndo-china
grows stronger
and more aggressive.
But if l improve
our foreign intercourse
with your queen's
special envoy,
French will think 3 times
before trying
to undermine Siam.
That's very clever,
Your Majesty.
As if to sound English
bugles in own defense.
You shall take charge
of all formalities,
as Mem is obvious choice
to make certain guests
feel at home.
But the anniversary is when?
3 weeks from yesterday.
3 weeks!
That's impossible.
Mem?
The egg...
is in the bottle.
[Speaking Siamese]
Half a glass.
[Smashing Glass]
Ah.
Your Majesty, we cannot
have the servants
bow every time somebody
walks into the banquet.
I understand.
[Speaking Siamese]
Just...for one night.
Thank you,
Your Majesty.
Sorry for nervousness.
This is first time
in Siam history
that King allow everyone to
stand up in his presence...
but only for tonight.
Your country and mine have
much in common, Your Majesty.
Rich cultures,
long histories.
And now, it seems,
Mrs. Leonowens.
Yes,
my children's horizons
keep expanding
under her tutelage.
Ah.
[Laughs]
My husband and I
have been stationed
all over the Orient.
But I must say,
I've never seen anything
quite like this.
Extraordinary,
isn't it?
Grand palace born from
the mind of King Taksin,
first man
to unify all Siam.
Our country owes
its creation
to a man they
declared insane.
Well, these roof tops
are a little nutty.
He endeavored
to build an empire,
but the nobility
that ran Siam
for generations
had grown tired
of his wars...
and replaced him with
Mongkut's grandfather,
someone they
could influence.
Taksin they put in
a velvet sack,
beaten to death with
a sandal wood club
and buried somewhere
in palace.
Oh, dear.
It sounds as though
you admire him, General.
I admire vision,
Lady Bradley,
in all its forms.
Forgive me, Your Majesty.
I believe the sun set
a little earlier today.
Mem, you arrange
all this to influence
positive future
of Siam.
And now, you steal
attention away from it.
Oh.
Well, that was not
my intention, Your Majesty.
Mrs. Leonowens,
what a delightful surprise,
encountering such
an enchanting countryman...
and so far from home.
Lord Bradley, this is
indeed a great honor.
I'm half-crazy
All for the love of you
It won't be
a stylish marriage
I can't
afford a carriage
But you'd look sweet
upon the seat
Of a bicycle
made for two
[Applause]
Gracious ladies, kind sirs,
on behalf of 68 brothers
and sisters,
we thank you immeasurably
and bid you
most gracious evening.
Your son bears
a striking resemblance
to his father,
Mrs. Leonowens.
I had the good fortune
of serving with him
a few years ago.
He was a courageous
soldier, ma'am.
Well, thank you,
Captain Blake.
Fa-ying: Father, may I
please kiss good night?
If l may beg indulgence
for not wishing to break
family tradition.
Ah.
I will be there
in your dreams,
as you will be
in mine.
Good night.
You have a remarkable
family, King Mongkut.
A remarkably...large one.
Hardly seems fair.
All these women
for one man.
Makes me wish I were
Siamese myself. Ha.
Mycroft Kincaid of
East lndia Trading Company,
correct?
Guilty as charged,
Your Majesty.
Mr. Kincaid's company
is merely one of the ways
we try to foster
economic relations
with other countries,
Your Majesty.
Also, I think, to arrive
at forefront of world
in wealth and power, yes?
Still, progress
through commerce is logic.
King find most practical
and excellent topic
for discussion.
All due respect,
Your Majesty.
It is a little
far-fetched to think
that commerce alone will bring
progress to your people.
Especially when they're
awash with, uh, superstition
and fear, like your
lovely concubines here
with their talismans,
worn, no doubt,
to protect them from us
foreign devils.
A friend once said,
Mr. Kincaid,
English also have
fantastical beliefs.
Or am I mistaking
your country
for being land
of Merlin and Camelot?
Ah. Point taken,
Your Majesty.
However, there's no arguing
the superiority of the English.
And in the light of
these dreadful massacres
up and down your border,
it's no wonder
you're seeking our favor.
Superiority,
Mr. Kincaid?
I do not recall anyone
being given the right
to judge whose cultural
customs are superior.
Especially
when those judging
have frequently done so
at the point of a gun.
Would you not agree,
Your Majesty?
Quite.
[Sighs]
Lord Bradley:
Well, the evenings here
are certainly warmer
than in London.
Hear, hear.
A night made to order
for anniversary party.
Especially for a king
who is most...
charitable and forgiving.
To our host,
a true gentleman,
generous in everyway.
May history mark
this occasion
as the first step
towards forging an alliance
between our two countries.
His Majesty.
All: His Majesty.
And in honor of our
most distinguished guests,
a waltz,
as is European custom
of dancing after dinner.
I--I must tell you,
Your Majesty,
that I have not
done this in some time.
And, well, seeing as
the evening has gone so well,
we wouldn't want to end up
in a heap, now would we?
I am King.
I shall lead.
[Orchestra Plays A Waltz]
I never danced
with an Englishwoman
before, Mem.
Nor I with a king.
I want you to make
promise, Mem,
to always tell King
what you think...
no matter what,
Iike the man from
East lndia Company.
I always have.
[Whispering]
[Laughing]
[Humming]
Mem, you're humming.
[Laughs]
Yes, I suppose I am.
As alarming as
this may sound,
I'm feeling rather
at home here now.
What charming
people, hmm?
You remember when
this market place
used to terrify us?
Like it was
yesterday.
I was afraid that dinner
might unsettle you,
all those Englishmen
in uniform.
Yes.
Thought it would make me
miserably homesick.
Quite the opposite.
I rather enjoyed myself,
even the dancing.
Should we get
some of these?
[Speaking Siamese]
Um...uh--uh--
And how did His Majesty fare
amongst all your countrymen?
He was charming,
absolutely charming.
Ha. I don't think
I'll ever forget
how he stood there,
holding his hand out
to me as ifl was--
One of his 26 wives.
Well, thank you, Beebe.
I hadn't thought of it
in that way.
Well, perhaps you should.
[Speaking Siamese]
I have a surprise
for you.
How--How did you?
Well, I'm not quite sure
actually.
Thank you, Mem.
My family,
it's very important to me.
I shall leave you to
enjoy every word, then.
Your Majesty.
You sent for me?
Ah, yes.
But here, look.
Ha.
Ah ha.
Something tells me
my little monkey
did not go to bed
night of anniversary.
Yes, I know.
I've been presented
with drawings of couples
dancing ever since.
Ah ha.
Come.
Sit, please.
[Clears Throat]
Perhaps you
should simply say
what it is you are
trying so hard not to.
I share this with you,
Mem,
because I believe you
to be trust worthy.
Events are happening
which I now believe
to be of Burmese origin,
and I fear that military
action is unavoidable.
But Burma's British.
Yes.
Then it is
not the French
that you were
worried about, was it?
I see.
On table, Mem,
is small gift of appreciation
for your many efforts
at anniversary party.
Mem's hand has been
lonely without such.
It is most kind,
Your Majesty.
It's very beautiful,
and though I am
terribly grateful--
It is custom
to bestow favors
for those
who please King...
and Mem has done so.
I'm sorry.
I cannot accept
such generosity.
[Bugling]
I hardly think 10 days rain
warrants the call
to battle, Louis.
Moonshee:
May I suggest a retreat?
Mother, I think
I should have a topknot
Iike the other boys.
I think you've gone
a bit daft, darling.
With all this rain,
it's no wonder.
I don't see why
I have to miss school.
Because your classroom's
underwater,
and I cannot
have you ill.
Balat:
" My most precious Tuptim,
"I know you will understand
why I must write this to you.
"When you were torn
from my heart,
"I was left with nothing
but my faith.
"Which is why,
if l am to live,
"I must devote my life
to Buddha,
"for only
he can give me peace.
I will never forget you."
[Wind Blowing]
[Shutter Banging]
Kralahome: Fa-ying
was found in the garden,
riddled with fever.
Difficult even for a grown man
to survive such.
Cholera always in world,
but still hardly at all
in Bangkok.
Is there nothing
you can do?
Well, they have
already begun. Listen.
Phra Arahan.
Reminding soul to go
to heaven and not lose way.
[Chanting]
It is why Mem must not
be heard weeping,
as her soul will
attach to sadness
and remain
to comfort living.
His Majesty is grateful.
The little one has made
frequent mention
of sir's name.
[Speaking Siamese]
[Praying ln Siamese]
Your Majesty...
being as the rain
has stopped,
the children hoped
you might join them
for a picnic.
Mem, I will always remember
your feelings for my daughter,
and you shall never forget...
you are not here to teach King.
The children miss you
terribly, Your Majesty.
You cannot shut
the world out forever.
Believe me, I've tried.
When my Tom died,
I thought that my heart
would never mend,
but then
there was Louis.
He was my salvation,
you see.
And yet, you still
refuse to live.
I beg your pardon?
A mother,
a teacher, a widow,
but you're
never just woman.
That is not fair.
In spite of all you say,
Mem is not accepting
passing of husband.
It is why you so protect son
and why you devote all time
to books and issues
and why you
cannot accept gift.
Why are you doing this?
Because you lie
even to yourself.
So do not lecture me
about living.
You are not qualified.
[Monkeys Shrieking]
[Speaking Siamese]
[Laughs]
These hours
are meant for sleep.
Ha. You startled me.
I thought it wise
to do so.
May I ask what His
Majesty is doing awake
at such an ungodly hour?
Gazing at the moon.
Yes, it is beautiful.
As the sun rises,
she will surrender the night,
but she is always with him,
even when he cannot see her.
It must be
a great comfort to him.
Yes.
Ah.
[Clears Throat]
This come from Bangkok.
You may find it
of some interest.
It's from--
Yes.
Please, to read...
as monkey has stolen
King's spectacles.
"Your Majesty,
"The United States
sincerely appreciates
"your generous offer to help
end this tragic conflict.
" Unfortunately, our country
does not reach a latitude
"which favors the elephant.
"We are, however,
"highly grateful for
this indication of friendship.
Your good friend,
Abraham Lincoln."
I admire this man
for what he is trying
to do for his people.
They say, at
the battle of Antietum,
70,000 men killed
each other in one day.
And each one
of those soldiers
has a father
who grieves.
I'm father
to all of Siam.
Mem is not wrong
about moving on.
Neither were you,
Your Majesty.
[Clears Throat]
When we return,
it is time for teacher to teach
Chulalongkorn and others
any subject she wish,
as long as King know first
so can be prepared
for consequences.
I will do my best,
Your Majesty.
And I was always believing
English women...
slept in hats.
Heh Heh. Ha.
Wonderful!
King Mongkut: I have
been wondering, Mem.
Hmm?
When it's my son's time
to become King,
will he be a good one?
Ah, he's still a boy,
Your Majesty,
but a keenly
intelligent one...
with a warm heart,
sympathetic soul--
qualities, I believe,
of a great king.
I want to thank you
for bringing me here...
to Siam. I cannot
imagine anywhere
I would rather be.
Were you happy in Bombay?
I was never unhappy.
I find myself traveling
from place to place
wondering where it is
that I belong exactly.
And I find myself here.
Your path is
as it should be.
My mind has taken me
down many roads oflate,
all of which lead
absolutely nowhere.
What would Buddha
say of that?
That roads are
for journeys, Mem...
not destinations.
Don't your wives
ever get jealous?
I do not understand
significance of question.
Forgive me,
I was prying.
Oh, no, no,
please, continue.
Well, most of the world
believes that...
a man and a woman
should share a relationship
which is sacred only
unto themselves.
Heh heh.
Each one of my wives
believes same about King.
Not everyone can marry you,
Your Majesty.
Good thing.
King need his rest
sometime.
[Horse Whinnies]
[Gunshot]
You said my
instincts were good.
And what are they
telling you?
That you're not
drinking, either.
[Choking]
Aah!
[Moaning]
[Grunting]
All the bodies were stripped
and left to the sun.
I fear Prince Chowfa
and Alakwere cremated
with the others.
May their souls
rest in peace.
You couldn't
have prevented
your brother's
death, Your Majesty.
Send my armies north.
If Burma wants this war,
they shall have it.
Lord Bradley?
Lady Bradley.
Mr. Kincaid.
If l might have
a moment of your time.
I'm afraid, Mrs. Leonowens,
a moment is all we have.
We are leaving
on the next boat, my dear,
and so should you.
My life is here,
Lady Bradley.
Kincaid: Nasty business.
All this sabre-rattling.
Not good for trade,
I can tell you.
But the king's brother
is most likely dead,
as is his general.
I would hardly call
his action unprovoked.
What can I do for you,
Mrs. Leonowens?
Are the British behind
these attacks on Siam?
Kincaid: Puh!
Stick to teaching,
Mrs. Leonowens.
It's obvious you know
nothing about politics.
Burma would
not make a move
without England's blessing,
that I know.
Precisely.
But if this crisis
isn't resolved soon,
and a country
under our protection
is threatened,
we will have no choice
but to defend our interests.
Our protection?
Our interests?
The ways of England
are the ways of
the world, my dear.
They are the ways
of one world, Lady Bradley,
one that I ashamed
to call my own.
You forget
yourself, madam.
Now, ifyou'll
excuse us.
No, I will not.
You raised
your glass to him.
You commended him
for his vision,
and all the while
you were waiting
to take his country
from him.
How the empire
conducts its business
is really
none of your concern.
Last time I inquired,
Lord Bradley,
I was still
a British subject.
A fact you would do well
to remember, madam,
next time you're cheek
to cheek with the king.
Anna: What is it?
Oh, my dear girl,
what have you done?
What I have done
is not a result of King
or intention to dishonor.
A concubine's heart is
of no consequence to King
consumed with matters
of a whole universe.
Oh, but, Tuptim, why
did you not come to me?
The king might have
understood.
You simply can't
do this to him, not now.
If love was a choice,
who would ever choose
such exquisite pain?
This is what I need
His Majesty to know,
if such does not
compromise you.
I will tell him
anything you wish.
I thank Buddha
for giving me direction.
And now,
with Mem before me,
I thank him for
giving me true friend.
[Soldier Yelling
ln Siamese]
[Soldier Giving Orders
He wrote to me
to bid me farewell,
believing I was lost
forever to the inside,
so committed his life
to monastery.
[Crowd Murmuring]
Aah! Aah!
Stop it! Stop it!
Do you hear me?
Don't you dare
lay another hand
on that woman!
She has done nothing
but to try and fiind
some happiness!
I will go to the king!
He will put an end
to this savagery!
[Gong Rings]
[Door Opens]
Thank you for seeing me,
Your Majesty.
I was told
by your prime minister
that this was
none of my concern.
King Mongkut: It is
none of Mem's concern,
and King
is seeing you now
to tell you same
himself.
Forgive me,
Your Majesty, but--
I do not wish
for you to talk more
on this matter,
to King or anyone.
Well, I was
only trying--
Tuptim broke law!
By loving someone.
"Sacrifice your life
for truth."
" Persecute no man."
Are these not
the teachings of Buddha?
I am King,
and I say enough!
You asked me to always
tell you what I think.
What you think,
and what you do,
and how, and when
you do them
are not the same thing.
If you believe I wish
to execute this girl.
But now, because
you say to court
you can tell King
what to do,
I cannot intervene
as I had planned.
Intervene after
they're tortured?
Yes!
But you, a woman
and a foreigner,
have made it seem
King at your command!
You have made me
appear weak
and impossible
for me to step in
and not lose face!
But you are the king.
And to remain such,
I cannot undermine
my ability
to command loyalty,
which I must have
to keep country secure!
You have the power
to lead your--
Now is not the time
to change the way
that things are done!
Well, ifnot now,
then when?
How many more
people must die
so that you might
save face?
Go home, Mem.
You help enough
for one day.
[Crowd Chanting
AndJeering]
[Drums Beating]
For the life of me,
I don't know
how you people
can stand this heat.
You have 5 minutes,
Mr. Kincaid.
I suggest you
not waste them.
I don't suppose I could
have a glass of water?
Right. Then, I'll come
straight to the point.
As you know,
I do a lot of business
with the Siamese.
Many of whom
have ended up dead
in recent months.
Which,
as I've discovered,
is all part of
some elaborate plot
to make you think
we British are the villains.
Well, I happen
to know we're not.
The acquisition
ofa particular little
piece of information
has cost me
a small fortune,
but the fact is,
when all is said and done,
I make more money
with Mongkut on the throne.
So, I think
I'm about to become
your best friend.
Your Majesty,
Alak will not stop
until all
of your children
are
in velvet sacks.
Kincaid said
he'll blame
the coup on Burma,
then launch
a full-scale attack
using your troops
already protecting
the border.
Alak seeks to finish
what Taksin only dreamed of.
Taksin was insane.
No. He was betrayed...
as we are now.
How long before Alak
reaches the city?
A week, maybe less.
And my armies?
They will never reach
the palace in time.
Then he has already won.
I will evacuate
the royal family
at once.
No. Recall the army
and announce
to the people
we have just received
glad tidings.
Glad tidings,
Your Majesty?
[Crowds Cheering]
Man: Chahngseekao!
Mother, doesn't
chahngseekao
mean
white elephant?
Do you think
they found one?
Yes.
A white elephant
in Prachin Buri.
The entire village
has seen it.
The first
in 20 years!
Mind Louis, Moonshee.
I'll see to our tickets.
I don't want to go,
Mother.
I don't want
to leave my friends.
The king has done
good things, too.
Your mother has much
on her mind, Louis.
You said the Siamese people
are just like us.
And what about
Chulalongkorn?
Doesn't he matter
anymore?
Believe me, darling.
I wish this
could all
be very different.
It's
the right decision.
We must go.
Sir, you of all
are most aware
there are
certain boundaries
I cannot cross,
one being
to contradict King.
Yes, and God help him.
Excuse me.
Passage for 4
on Newcastle.
Thank you.
There is
no white elephant, sir.
King invented sighting
at Prachin Buri
so he could
escort royal family
to greet imaginary beast
as in tradition.
I don't understand.
There is a traitor
marching on palace.
Deception's
only purpose
is to hide children
in monastery
in village
of Nong Khai.
Please, Mem.
My king believes
you are wise.
You are only one
who can persuade him
to stay
with children
until army returns
to Bangkok
and palace is secure.
Please, Mem?
I have
just been informed
of the nature
of your expedition,
Your Majesty,
and, um,
I would like to ask
a few questions
about the dangers involved,
as I've heard,
at times,
wild elephants
cannot be reasoned with.
I am surprised
the Kralahome
took time to arouse
such curiosity,
rather than
make sure Mem
not miss her boat.
We have already missed
our boat, Your Majesty,
so that I might
speak with you now.
King cannot
miss his boat.
If it would not
be inconvenient,
we should like
to go with you.
Jungle is no place
for proper
English teacher.
No, it is not,
Your Majesty,
which is why the presence
of one in your cortege
might help
ensure your display.
Something I feel,
for many reasons,
I would very much
like to do.
When a woman
who has much to say
says nothing,
her silence
can be deafening.
I wish to
thank you, Mem,
for your courage.
I thought I never wanted
to see you again.
I had a vision of
young Tuptim and of Balat.
I think by touching us all,
they have fulfilled
their destiny
and attained
eternal peace.
Through birth
and rebirth,
we Buddhists hope to learn
from our mistakes.
You told me once
that I had never
accepted the loss
of my husband.
I had no right.
No, no.
That was true.
I now realize
that it is not enough
to just survive,
that life is precious.
Especially if you're
a Christian
and only
allowed to have one.
Why did you come back?
Because I could not imagine
a Siam without you.
[Horse Neighs]
[Elephant Trumpets]
What has happened?
You and the children
must go on to Nong Khai
without me.
I will meet you there.
I can see it
in your eyes.
Something awful
has happened.
Was not to
be this way, Mem.
Alak's army
has found us.
If he crosses
the bridge,
everything
I love will die.
But they're
only children.
Yes.
And each one
heir to throne.
Now, you must hurry.
What will you do?
Blow up the bridge.
Will that stop him?
It will, if he's on it.
Your Majesty,
promise me.
Promise me that
I will see you again.
If your Bible
is correct,
whole world created
in 7 days.
Therefore...
possible handful of men
can stop an army.
But, Father, never has such
an expedition excluded royal children.
My son,
there are many things
you will come to understand
when you're older.
Then, why can't
I stay with you?
Because I need you
to lead our family
to the monastery.
There is no white
elephant, is there?
Come. Come.
[Horses Approaching]
Yah!
Mother, come look.
The king is waiting
on the bridge.
What?
And there's
hundreds of men
on the other side.
Wait. Stop the carriage.
[Bugle Playing]
Ugh!
Ahh.
[Bugle Plays]
You.
Why did you not
go to monastery
Iike King order?
Because I lost one man
to thejungle, Your Majesty.
I was not about
to let that happen again.
Mem Anna not fully
to blame, Father.
After all, you did
put me in charge.
To sound...
English bugles
in own defense.
Yes.
When king say
handful ofman
could save all Siam,
he was most
unusually incorrect.
Prince Chulalongkorn:
And it be then
that all ears hear
what all eyes
suddenly see.
Great white beast
in infinite splendor.
[Children Chatter]
[Laughing]
Um, great white beast.
Children: Ooh!
[Laughing]
And as people rejoice
with overwhelming joy.
[Children Cheering]
Most excellent conclusion
to expedition echoed
in every corner ofSiam.
The end!
[Applause]
Perfect. Wonderful.
Very, very good.
You did very fine jobs.
Mem?
This is play
to commemorate
monumental occasion,
and we make fools of selves
because of insufficient practice.
I understand truly,
Your Highness,
but the celebration
was tonight.
We were duty-bound,
were we not?
Children: Yes.
Were we not?
I want you all
to imagine next year,
when you've had time
to perfect things.
Then your father will be
even more proud of you
than he already is.
And you, Mem?
Will you be?
I will always be
proud of you, my children.
[Music Box Playing]
[Crying]
I, uh, ordered this
some time ago
for the children,
and, uh,
it's a fine example
of scientifiic
thinking,
as music is mathematical
in nature.
Chords, constructed
from notes
in intervals of thirds,
and so on, and so on.
Precisely.
I would
like to know why,
if science
can unravel something
as beautiful as music,
why it cannot
posit a solution
for a school teacher
and a king?
The manner in which
people might understand
such new possibilities
is also
process of evolution.
Everything in Siam
has its own time.
Even if King is also
wanting it to be different.
I still must go,
Your Majesty.
So, where is it
you will be going?
England.
Home.
This is good, Mem.
Very good for Louis
as well.
What?
Am wondering if,
given circumstances,
it is appropriate
for King to ask...
Anna...
to dance?
I have danced with
a king before, Your Majesty.
And l...
an Englishwoman.
Until now...
Madam Leonowens,
I did not understand
supposition
man could be satisfied
with only one woman.
I was only a boy,
but the image
of my father
holding the woman
he loved
for the last time
has remained with me
throughout the years.
It is always surprising
how small a part of life
is taken up
by meaningful moments.
Most of them, they are over
before they start,
although they cast
a light on the future
and make the person who
originated them unforgettable.
Anna had shined
such a light on Siam.
Cannot touch
Cannot hold
Cannot be together
Cannot love
Cannot kiss
Cannot have each other
Must be strong
And we must let go
Cannot say
What our hearts must know
How can I not love you?
What do I tell my heart?
When do I not want you
Here in my arms?
How does one waltz away
From all of the memories?
How do I not miss you
When you are gone?
Cannot dream
Cannot share
Sweet and tender moments
Cannot feel
How we feel
Must pretend it's over
Must be brave
And we must go on
Must not say
What we've known all along
How can I not love you?
What do I tell my heart?
When do I not want you
Here in my arms?
How does one waltz away
From all of the memories?
How do I not miss you
When you are gone?
How can I not love you?
Must be brave
And we must be strong
Cannot say
What we've known all along
How can I not love you?
What do I tell my heart?
When do I not want you
Here in my arms?
How does one waltz away
From all of the memories?
How do I not miss you
When you are gone?
How can I not love you
Subtitled by: Biot!