You know how blind I am without them.
Howard, don't cry.
Murder.
Good luck, John.
- Any contractions?
- Only the ones you give me.
Okay, Jad, what's coming?
Red Ball, double homicide,
one male, one female.
Killer's male, white, 40s.
Agatha nailed the time frame
at 8:04 a.m.
The twins are a little fuzzy on that,
so we'll need confirmation.
Location's still uncertain.
Remote witnesses are plugged in.
This will be case number 1108.
Good morning, detectives.
Case number 1108,
previsualized by the Precogs,
recorded on holosphere
by Precrime's q-stacks.
My fellow witnesses
for case number 1108 ...
are Dr. Katherine James
and Chief Justice Frank Pollard.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
Will the witnesses preview and
validate number 1108 at this time?
- Affirmative. I will validate.
- Go get him.
- Stand by.
- Time of murder, 8:04 a.m.
That is 24 minutes, 13 seconds
from now.
This is a Red Ball.
You know
how blind I am without them.
All right, Howard Marks,
where are you?
Howard? Howard, breakfast!
"Four score
and seven years ago ..."
- He looked familiar.
- Who?
A man standing in the park across
the street. I've seen him before.
How can you even tell? You know
how blind you are without your glasses.
Where are your glasses?
I must have left them up
in the bedroom.
You are running out of time.
You know how blind I am ...
I show eight Howard Marks in the
District. Sorting by race and age.
Run their license and registration.
See if I can capture an address here.
You are running out of time.
You know, I was thinking maybe
I'd play hooky, stay home today.
- What about your meeting?
- I've been working too much.
- Can you grab that?
- It's unclear.
I got six licenses.
Where do you want them?
Over here, please.
I'm very sorry.
You know how blind I am without them.
Got him in the Foxhall,
4421 Gainsborough.
Send a DCPD blue-and-white.
Set up a perimeter,
and tell them we're en route.
You know, I was thinking maybe
I'd play hooky, stay home today.
"We have come
to dedicate a portion of that field ..."
- What do you think?
"as a final resting place ..."
- What about your meeting?
- I'll reschedule.
I've been working too much anyway.
"is altogether fitting and proper
that we should do this."
- "But in a larger sense ..." Good.
- We could have lunch together.
- What do you say?
- "We cannot consecrate.
"We cannot hallow this ground."
- Any place you want.
- I would love ... I would love to.
"The brave men, living and dead ..."
I have an open house
at the Ressler place.
"have consecrated it far above
our poor power to add or detract."
I guess that's why you look so nice.
Chief!
We got a problem with our location.
- It's no longer there.
- Shit.
- Time frame?
- Thirteen minutes.
Investigator from the Fed's here.
Yeah, I don't need some twink
from the Fed poking around right now.
John, I wrote it down on your calendar.
I left you a message at your house.
Check in with the papers.
They had it forwarded.
See if the neighbors knew
where they went.
- Check all relations.
- Checking neighbors and relations.
- But, John ...
- Fletch, just get him some coffee.
Tell him some stories
how I save your ass every day ...
and you can't live without me.
- I got coffee, thank you.
Danny Witwer,
the twink from the Fed.
Whoops. Gum?
Sorry, Danny, I'm gonna have to give
you the full tour some other time.
The Markses moved
a couple of weeks ago,
nobody knows where. Still
searching for family and employer.
Time Horizon, 12 minutes.
All right. What he's doing now,
we call "scrubbing the image,"
looking for clues
as to where the murder's gonna happen.
Original running bond brick pattern,
streamlined early Georgian details ...
The brick has been re-pointed.
- And, "That this nation ..."
- "This nation ..."
- "under God ..."
"shall not perish from the Earth."
Victims are pronounced here,
killers here.
Beyond that and the date of the crime,
all we have to run on are the images
that they produce.
I show a cop on horseback.
- Near the Capitol?
- No Maglev system.
The Mall?
Georgetown.
The Precogs can see a murder
four days out. Why the late call?
Well, we call it a Red Ball.
With crimes of passion
there's no premeditation,
so they show up late.
Most of our scrambles are
flash events, like this one.
We rarely see anything
with premeditation anymore.
- People have gotten the message.
- Uh-huh.
Oh, this is good.
I show a match for Dwight Kingsley,
18th-century architect.
He did two dozen houses in D.C.
- Time Horizon, 10 minutes.
- Ten minutes.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Look at this kid. In this one, he's
on the left side of the man in the suit.
- Yes, so?
- This one he is on the right.
Merry-go-round.
It's a park!
Tell me there's only 16 of these
old merry-go-rounds left in the city.
Two in Georgetown,
one in Barnaby Woods.
The other's in Woodley.
Woodley's all Victorian.
It's gotta be Barnaby Woods.
- Evanna, flight time?
- The way I drive,
three minutes after wheels up.
- Clear.
Time Horizon, six minutes.
Let's go to bed.
Let's do it in here.
- The bed is soft.
- I'm soft.
Shit!
Which one is it?
- Don't stop!
- Not the bed!
- Come on, come on.
- I don't want to be on the bed!
Time Horizon, one minute. Chief,
we're catching up to the future.
Shut up, Evanna. Jad?
- Jad?
- Go ahead.
- Did he close the front door?
- What?
Did Marks close the front door?
Front door.
I didn't want to be on the bed.
Negative. The front door is open.
- The front door is open.
- Time Horizon, 30 seconds.
- I forgot my glasses.
- Oh, Howard!
No, no, no, Howard.
You know how blind
I am without them.
Howard, don't cry.
Marks!
Look at me. Look at me.
Positive for Howard Marks.
Mr. Marks, by mandate of the
District of Columbia Precrime Division,
I'm placing you under arrest ...
for the future murder of Sarah Marks
and Donald Dubin ...
that was to take place today,
April 22nd, at 0804.
No! I didn't do anything.
- Sarah!
- Give the man his hat.
Oh, God.
Don't put that halo on me! Sarah!
- Put your hand on your head!
- Help me!
I wasn't gonna do anything!
Officer Scott, I'm with the
Precrime trauma Response Unit.
I want you to sit here a minute
and listen to me.
Your husband is being arrested
by officers from Precrime.
Oh, God, Howard, no!
Howard, don't cry.
Howard, please don't cry.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
I thought they stopped the murder.
Well, that's just an echo,
a Precog déjà vu, if you will.
The really bad ones, the Precogs
see them over and over again.
Wally, erase the incoming.
Imagine a world without murder.
- I lost my best friend.
- I Lost my aunt.
- I Lost my dad.
- I Lost my father.
I Lost my wife.
Just six years ago,
the homicide rate in this country ...
had reached epidemic proportions.
It seemed that only a miracle
could stop the bloodshed.
But instead of one miracle, we
were given three, the Precognitives.
Within just one month
under the Precrime program,
the murder rate in the
District of Columbia was reduced 90%.
They were gonna be waiting for me
in the car.
He was gonna rape me.
- I was going to be stabbed.
- Right here.
Within a year, Precrime effectively
stopped murder in our nation's capital.
In the six years we've been conducting
our little experiment,
there hasn't been a single murder.
And now
Precrime can work for you.
We want to
make absolutely certain ...
that every American can bank on
the utter infallibility of the system,
and to ensure that what keeps
us safe will also keep us free.
- It works.
- Precrime, it works!
On Tuesday, April 22nd, vote yes
on the National Precrime Initiative.
What's the matter? Can't sleep?
- I just need a little clarity.
- True, true, true, true, that.
You want the customary clarity or
the new-and-improved kind of clarity?
Just give me the new stuff.
New and improved. New and
improved clarity, clarity, clarity.
Yes, indeed, clarity.
Come on, come on.
I just want a hit.
Look, don't bust my balls.
You just gave me four,
and some of these are duds.
Sweet dreams, Chief.
Don't worry none,
your secret's safe with me.
Besides, I could use a little juice
on my side.
What do you think you know, Lycon?
It's like my daddy used to say,
"In the land of the blind,
"the one-eyed man is king."
I'm home.
Overhead.
Wall screen.
- Sean!
- Hi, Daddy.
Can you teach me how to run faster?
'Cause all the kids in my class
run faster than me.
No. That's good.
Look, keep your knees up.
Keep your knees up like that. Good.
- Like that.
- Like that. High. High. Like that.
- Like that. High.
- See, you're a natural runner.
- Gotta keep running!
Gotta keep running.
You gotta keep running.
Will I be as fast as you someday?
Oh, I think you'll beat me someday.
You're gonna beat everybody.
I think you'll beat everyone someday.
- I gotta go. Bye.
- No, no, no. No, no, no. Wait, wait.
- You gotta give me a kiss.
- Not on the lips!
Only Mommy kisses me on the lips.
Yeah. All right,
all right, all right.
I love you.
- I love you, Sean.
- I love you, Daddy.
It reminds me of Rosarito Beach.
Remember?
Yeah, we had those ... We had $20,
and waiting in the van so the
sun would shine on our vacation.
John! John.
John, put the camera down. Look,
I'm ... I'm all ready for bed.
What ... What is this? No.
Put it away. It's time
to put the camera to sleep,
and time to come
and take care of your wife.
Sweetie, why don't you
put the camera down ...
and come and watch the rain with me?
No? I promise I'll make it
a memorable moment.
Look, put the camera down,
or you're not getting anything tonight.
A gentleman at Justice wants
to take all this away from us.
You understand a week from now
people are going to vote ...
on whether or not
what we've been doing down here ...
has been
some noble-minded enterprise,
or a chance to change the way
this country fights crime.
- I understand, sir.
- John.
Watch this Danny Witwer,
the observer from Justice.
- Yes, I met him yesterday.
You can let him look around,
answer his questions, but watch him.
- Yes, sir.
- And if there's any problem,
make sure we know about it first.
- I understand.
When the Precogs declare
a victim and a killer,
their name is embedded
in the grain of wood.
Since each piece is unique,
the shape and grain is unique.
The shape and grain
is impossible to forge.
I'm sure you all understand the legalistic
drawback to Precrime methodology.
Here we go again.
Look, I'm not with the ACLU
on this, Jeff.
But let's not kid ourselves.
We are arresting individuals
who have broken no law.
- But they will.
- The commission of the crime itself ...
is absolute metaphysics.
The Precogs seethe future,
and they're never wrong.
But it's not the future if you stop it.
Isn't that a fundamental paradox?
Yes, it is.
You're talking about predetermination,
which happens all the time.
- Why'd you catch that?
- Because it was going to fall.
- You're certain?
- Yeah.
But it didn't fall. You caught it.
The fact that
you prevented it from happening ...
doesn't change the fact
that it was going to happen.
You ever get any false positives?
Someone intends to kill his boss or his
wife, but they never go through with it.
How do the Precogs
tell the difference?
The Precogs don't see what you
intend to do, only what you will do.
Then why can't they see rapes?
Or assaults or suicides?
Because of the nature of murder.
"There's nothing more destructive to
the metaphysical fabric that binds us ...
"than the untimely murder
of one human being by another."
Somehow, I don't think
that was Walt Whitman.
It's Iris Hineman.
She developed the Precogs, designed
the system and pioneered the interface.
Speaking of interfacing,
I'd love to say hello.
- To Hineman?
- To them.
Cops aren't
allowed inside the temple.
Really? You've never been inside?
We keep strict separations so that
no one can be accused of tampering.
So, I'll be the first one
to go in, then?
- Maybe you didn't hear me.
- If it's a question of authority ...
No, there is no question.
You don't have any.
I have a warrant in my pocket
that says different.
- Show it to me.
- Sure.
This investigation of Precrime
and its personnel ...
is being conducted
under the direct supervision ...
and express permission from the
Attorney General of the United States.
I'm here as his representative,
which means you're now operating
under my supervision.
Seems you've been
left out of the loop, John.
All right, we're ready. Let's go.
Hold it right there. Hold it.
Not cleared for access.
Eye-dent, John Anderton. Approved.
- Wally.
- No, no, no, no.
It's okay. This is Danny Witwer.
He's from Justice.
We're to give him the run of the farm.
I can't touch you.
- Don't touch him or anything else.
- John, you can't be in here ...
I understand. Just answer his questions
and we'll get the hell out of here.
Tell me how ...
- They're sleeping.
- Sorry. Tell me how all this works.
The photon milk acts as both
a nutrient supply and a liquid conductor.
It enhances the images
that each of them receive.
We call the female Agatha.
The twins are Arthur and Dashiell.
We scan by way of optical tomography.
White-light pinpoints pulse along
the entire length of the headgear,
and they're reread after absorption
through their brain tissue.
In other words,
we see what they see.
They don't feel any pain.
We keep their heads pretty well stocked
with dopamine and endorphins.
Plus, we maintain careful control
over their serotonin levels.
Don't want them to drift off
into too deep a sleep.
They can't be kept too awake, either.
It's better if
you don't think of them as human.
No. They're much more than that.
Science has stolen
most of our miracles.
In a way, they give us hope,
hope of the existence of the divine.
I find it interesting that some people
have begun to deify the Precogs.
The Precogs are pattern-recognition
filters, that's all.
- Yet you call this room "the temple."
- Just a nickname.
The oracle isn't
where the power is, anyway.
The power's always been
with the priests,
even if they had
to invent the oracle.
You guys are nodding like you actually
know what the hell he's talking about.
Well, come on, Chief. The way
we work, changing destiny and all,
I mean,
we're more like clergy than cops.
- Jad?
- Yeah?
Go to work. All of you.
Sorry. Old habit.
I spent three years at Fuller
Seminary before I became a cop.
My father was very proud.
What does he think
of your chosen line of work?
I don't know. He was shot
and killed when I was 15 ...
on the steps of our church in Dublin.
I know what it's like
to lose someone close, John.
Of course,
nothing is like the loss of a child.
I don't have any children of my own,
so I can only imagine
what that must have been like.
To lose your son
in such a public place like that.
At least now you and I have
the chance to make sure ...
that kind of thing
doesn't happen to anyone.
Why don't you cut the cute act,
Danny Boy, and tell me ...
exactly what it is you're looking for.
- Flaws.
There hasn't been
a murder in six years.
There's nothing wrong with the system.
It is ...
Perfect. I agree.
If there's a flaw, it's human.
It always is.
John.
Wally.
Can you see?
John, what the hell just happened?
Her ACTH levels
just shot through the roof!
- What did you do to her?
- She grabbed me.
Grabbed you? That's impossible.
The Precogs aren't even aware of us.
- In the milk, all they see is the future.
- She looked straight at me.
It could have been a nightmare.
Sometimes they dream
about the old murders.
- She spoke to me.
- To you?
- What'd she say?
- "Can you see?"
You the Sentry?
Yes, sir! I'm Gideon.
You're Chief Anderton.
The music relaxes the prisoners.
Say, I don't ever see
any of you Precops down here.
- I'm not in trouble, am l?
- Not yet.
- I'm interested in a murder.
- I got plenty of those. Kill type?
- Drowning.
- That narrows it down.
Not too many in here for that one.
- Victim's Caucasian, female.
- This about the Justice Department?
I'm supposed to spruce up for a
tour they got planned for tomorrow.
Told me to wear a tie.
You like this one?
Stop.
Roll back.
There.
She's a golden oldie. One of our
first. Probably before your time.
This is the official composite
of the three Precogs?
That's right! A combined data stream
based on all three previsions.
Just show me Agatha's data stream.
For that,
we go for a ride.
My God.
I'd forgotten there were so many.
And to think they'd all be out there
killing people if it wasn't for you.
Look at them.
Look at how peaceful they all seem.
But on the inside, busy, busy, busy.
Okey-pokey! Now that is one bad man.
He drowned a woman
named Anne Lively out at Roland Lake.
The killer's a John Doe.
Never identified.
Why is he still a John Doe?
Why wasn't he ever ID'd
from the eye-scan?
On account of those are not his eyes.
He had them swapped out
to fool the scanners.
You can get it done on the street
for a few thousand bucks these days.
Okay, so you want
just the female prevision.
That's right.
We don't seem to have her data.
Try again.
This is odd.
See? We have the two previsions.
We got what Art saw,
we got what Dash saw,
but Agatha's isn't here.
Probably just a glitch.
Tell me about the intended victim,
this Anne Lively.
Looks like she's a neuroin addict,
like our John Doe here,
but I show an address history
that includes the Beaton Clinic.
So she cleaned up.
So where's she now?
I guess glitches come in twos.
You finally crawl your way out
of one hole just to fall into another.
No.
I can't let you take that
out of here, Chief.
It's against the rules.
Anything else going on in here
that's against the rules?
Careful, Chief. You dig up
the past, all you get is dirty.
And then you said the third prevision
was, what, kind of fuzzy or something?
No. No, the third prevision,
Agatha's prevision, wasn't there.
That's not all.
I spent a few hours down there,
and there are a dozen more cases
with missing previsions.
You'd think we'd have found a cure
for the common cold by now.
- It's stress.
- What's this?
Herbal tea with honey.
I hate herbal tea,
almost as much as I hate honey.
Just drink it before
I pour it in your lap.
- Can I get you anything, John?
- No, thank you, Celeste.
Witwer's scheduled for a Containment ...
Tour of Containment tomorrow.
Yeah, give him a tour.
- Lara called me.
- What?
She's worried about you.
Quite frankly, so am l.
I'm fine.
I understand you've been spending
a lot of time in the sprawl.
- I go running down there.
- In the middle of the night?
What if Danny Witwer
came to you right now ...
and insisted on a full chem run?
- Lamar, I'm fine.
You understand, John,
the minute Precrime goes national,
they're going to take it away from us.
We won't let them.
No? How's an old man and a cop
on the whiff ever going to stop them?
My father once said to me,
"You don't choose the things
you believe in. They choose you."
There's a reason you are here, John.
Had Precrime been in place
just six months earlier,
the loss you and Lara suffered
would have been prevented.
Remember the eyes ...
The eyes of the nation
are on us right now.
And we both know I'm not the
generation anyone listens to.
But people trust you, John.
When you speak
of your absolute belief in Precrime,
they know it's a belief born of pain,
not politics. I always understood that.
And I may have even encouraged it
to help with the cause.
But now, your pain is hurting both of us.
They're not gonna take it away from us.
I won't let them.
Bingo.
- Hi, Daddy!
- Hey, little buddy.
- I made up a club.
- Yeah?
- We're called the Crescos.
- The Crescos.
- We made up a soccer team ...
- Yeah.
and we practice at school.
Yeah?
Do you practice with Connor?
Daddy's in a lot of trouble, Sean.
Wait.
Jad, how come you're not out there
with Father Witwer?
We're in motion on something.
Now, from what I can see,
we got a white male victim,
about 5'10", approximately 170.
He takes a round in the 10-ring
and goes out a window.
- Red Ball?
- Nope, Brown Ball.
- This one's premeditated.
- Amazing.
There's someone within 200 miles
actually dumb enough to still do that.
Well, the victim's name is Leo Crow.
This is case number 1109.
Time of occurrence,
Friday, 15:06 hours.
Start a location run and a contact
search for future victim, Leo Crow.
Case number 1109,
previsualized by the Precogs,
recorded on holosphere
by Precrime's q-stacks.
My fellow witnesses
for case number 1109 ...
are Dr. Katherine James
and Chief Justice Frank Pollard.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
Are the witnesses ready
to preview and validate number 1109?
- Ready when you are, John.
- Standing by.
Oh, I love this part.
I've got no address,
last known or otherwise,
no tax returns for the last five years.
Check NCIC, maybe he's got a record.
And send a protection team
as soon as we lock location.
Looks like federal housing.
Concrete, glass, egg crates.
Ouch.
About 1,000 of those in the District.
Fractured images coming in.
Numbers nine ...
Nine and six.
Female, senior. She's smoking a pipe.
She's laughing.
Okay, now inside a room.
Window panes, aluminum extrusion.
Two figures resolving in the room.
Wait!
Looks like we got a third party,
wearing sunglasses,
just out of the window.
You're not gonna kill me.
Goodbye, Crow.
- Goodbye, Crow.
- Anderton, wait!
Wait. Wait.
- You say something, Chief?
- No.
I'll get this one.
We got time on this one, Jad.
Mind going down and getting me a piece
of cake they're eating down there?
- I'm starving.
- Sure, Chief.
I think I'll get one for myself
while I'm at it.
Take your time.
Chief Anderton,
what is this that I'm seeing?
I'm confused about ...
- Anderton, wait!
- Goodbye, Crow.
Wait! Anderton, wait!
Anderton, wait!
I like you, Chief.
You've always been nice to me.
I'll give you two minutes
before I hit the alarm.
Hold that, please.
Thanks.
- You're in a lot of trouble, John.
- You set me up.
I'll write the paranoia off to the
whiff you've been doping on all night.
- Easy. Easy.
- Seems I found a flaw.
What are you gonna do?
Possession alone will cost you
six months, not to mention your badge.
I guess we won't be working
together after all.
Now, put the gun down, John.
I don't hear a Red Ball.
Lamar? Lamar?
- Lamar?
- John, what the hell is happening?
- It's Witwer! He set me up!
- What the hell is happening?
- He set me up.
- Stop. Just wait.
- Who ...
- He set me up. Witwer. It's Witwer!
Yeah, who's the victim?
- Somebody.
- Who?
- Somebody. Leo Crow.
- Well, who is he?
I have no idea!
I've never heard of him!
But I'm supposed to kill him
in less than 36 hours.
Ah. But how could Witwer
have access to case files?
Can you fake a cerebral output?
- Why would anyone want to?
- Can you?
- Well, I doubt it very much.
- Well, would Hineman know?
- Listen. Come in.
- What?
Well, I'll keep you safe until
we get to the bottom of this, John.
No, Lamar, Listen to me. Listen.
Talk to Wally, see if Witwer's gone
inside the temple again.
Then ask Jad for any off-hour
eye-dents into the analytical room.
Just tell me, who's Leo Crow?
Security lockdown enabled.
Revised destination, office.
Lamar, they found me.
Is there any way to override
the lockdown?
- No. No. No.
- No?
I'LL meet you anywhere you say.
You can come to my house, John.
You know I can't. They'll get me
there. I'm not gonna get haloed.
You can't run, John.
Everybody runs.
- Oh, my God.
- Hey, hey.
Oh, my gosh. Are you okay?
Don't worry, sir.
I'll bring him in, unharmed.
Actually, Gordon,
you're not gonna do that.
- I'm taking control of the team.
- What?
Witwer, Fletcher is second
in command. It's his show to run.
If you want, you can observe. Do it.
Find him.
Yes, sir.
He came to see you the other day,
right before he was tagged.
- What did you talk about?
- The Mets.
John doesn't think they have a deep
enough pitching roster this year,
and I'm inclined to agree.
- Why are you protecting him?
You knew he was doping,
yet you did nothing about it.
- The man lost a child, for Christ's sake.
- Six years ago.
- What did you two talk about?
- None of your damn business.
Oh, it's all my damn business now,
Lamar.
Investigation of a supervising
officer for a capital crime ...
falls under federal jurisdiction,
so as to rule out
any possibility of conspiracy.
- He's my suspect.
- He's my subordinate.
Shall we call the Attorney General?
I'm sure he'd be happy
to clarify the issue for you.
I don't want John Anderton hurt.
I'm gonna enjoy working here.
A road diverges in the desert.
Lexus.
The road you're on, John Anderton,
is the one less traveled.
- Good evening, John Anderton.
- John Anderton.
John Anderton!
You could use a Guinness
right about now.
Stressed out, John Anderton?
Get away, John Anderton.
Forget your troubles.
He's been eye-dented on the Metro.
The train makes two stops,
at 20th and 33rd.
Send units to each location.
- They'll never make 20th.
- Have faith.
Fire them up!
- Hey, Fletch.
- Hey, John.
- That was a rough landing.
- Yeah.
- You have to work on that.
- It's that old, shit knee of mine.
- Yeah.
- Don't do it.
Hey, don't do this.
John? Don't run.
You don't have to chase me.
You don't have to run.
- Everybody runs, Fletch.
- You know we'll catch you.
Everybody runs.
- It doesn't have to be like this, John.
- Everybody runs.
Get your sick-sticks ready.
Everybody runs, Fletch.
Slow down, Chief. Just take it easy.
No sudden moves, Chief.
John, it's okay.
- Fletch ...
- Easy does it, Chief.
- Got a grip? Got a grip?
- Yeah.
Chief! Chief, no! Chief!
Anderton!
Go away! Get out of my kitchen!
Get that thing out of my house!
Get out of my house! Get out!
Anderton, stop!
Pull him off me, Fletcher.
Get him off me.
Do something! try to get them out
of here! What's the matter with you?
- John! Stop!
- Get out of my house now!
By mandate of the
District of Columbia Precrime Division,
I'm placing you under arrest ...
Go to sleep.
Just stay with me.
Dr. Hineman?
You're trespassing.
I don't have visitors.
Oh, I'm afraid that would be
from the Doll's Eye, the vine.
The baneberry that scratched you
during your illegal climb over my wall.
It's not a true Doll's Eye, of course.
It's a little hybrid of my own design.
It's quite something. Once the poison
gets into your bloodstream,
you will start to see
what I can only describe ...
as the most extraordinary display
of blue objects.
This just isn't your week, is it,
Chief Anderton?
I'm not a killer.
You better drink this.
Soon you won't be able to swallow,
and then you'll be totally buggered.
All of it.
Okay, now take a minute
to right yourself.
Just what is it you think
I can do for you?
You can tell me
how someone can fake a prevision.
How would I know that?
Because you invented Precrime.
What's so funny?
If the unintended consequences
of a series of genetic mistakes
and science gone haywire
can be called invention,
yes, then I invented Precrime.
- You don't seem all that proud.
- I'm not.
I was trying to heal them,
not turn them into something else.
Heal who?
The innocents we now use
to stop the guilty.
You're talking about the Precogs.
You think the three in the tank
come out of a test tube?
They are merely the ones who survived.
I was doing genetic research
at the Woodhaven Clinic,
treating children of drug addicts.
This was 10 years ago,
when neuroin first hit the streets.
It was an impure form of the drug,
not the engineered cocktail ...
that became so popular
among the more educated.
All of these kids were born
with severe brain damage.
Most died before the age of 12.
Those few, those precious few
who survived, they had a gift.
I call it a gift. For them,
it was more like a cosmic joke.
They would wake up in the night,
curled up in the corner of their rooms,
screaming, clawing at the wallpaper.
Because when these little children,
you see, closed their eyes at night,
they dreamt only of murder,
over and over, one after the other.
And it didn't take long for us to
realize that the real nightmare ...
was that these so-called dreams
were about to come true.
These murders
were actually happening.
You say some of the children died.
So many of them,
despite what we did for them.
Or maybe because of what we did
to them. But it doesn't matter.
It's a perfect system now, isn't it?
I'm not going to commit murder.
I've never met the man
I'm supposed to kill.
And yet a chain of events
has started,
a chain that will lead you
inexorably to his murder.
Not if I stay away from him.
How can you avoid a man
you've never met?
So you won't help me?
I can't help you. Nobody can.
The Precogs are never wrong.
But occasionally,
they do disagree.
What?
Most of the time, all three Precognitives
will see an event in the same way,
but once in a while, one of them will
seething differently than the other two.
Jesus Christ.
Why didn't I know about this?
Because these minority reports
are destroyed the instant they occur.
Why?
Obviously, for Precrime to function,
there can't be
any suggestion of fallibility.
After all, who wants a justice
system that instills doubt?
It may be reasonable,
but it's still doubt.
Are you saying
I've haloed innocent people?
I'm saying that every so often
those accused of a Precrime ...
might, just might,
have an alternate future.
Does Burgess know about this?
About this minority report?
I used to joke with Lamar that we were
the mother and father of Precrime.
Well, in my experience,
parents very often see their children ...
as they want them to be,
not as they are.
Answer my question.
Does Lamar Burgess know
about the minority report?
Yes, of course, he knew.
But at the time,
he felt, we both felt,
that their existence
was an insignificant variable.
Insignificant to you, maybe,
but what about those people that
I put away with alternate futures?
My God, if the country knew
there was a chance ...
The system would collapse.
- I believe in that system.
- Do you really?
You want to bring it down.
You will bring it down,
if you manage to kill your victim.
Why, that will be
the most spectacular public display
of how Precrime didn't work.
- I'm not gonna kill anybody.
- Hold that thought.
Why should I trust you?
You shouldn't.
You shouldn't trust anyone.
Certainly not the Attorney General,
who just wants it all for himself.
And not the young federal agent
who wants your job.
Not even the old man who just wants
to hang onto what he created.
Don't trust anyone.
Just find the minority report.
You said
the minority report's destroyed.
The record is destroyed.
The original report still exists.
I designed the system so that
whenever a report occurred,
it would be stored in a safe place,
but not declared.
What safe place is that?
The safest place there is.
Where is it?
Inside the Precog who predicted it.
All you have to do
is download it, darling.
That's all, huh?
Just walk right into Precrime,
get in the temple,
somehow tap into these Precogs,
and then download this minority report.
- If you have one.
- And then walk out.
Actually, I think you'll have to run out,
but, yes, that is what you have to do.
You're insane.
Or you think I am.
I'll get eye-scanned a dozen times
before I get within 10 miles of Precrime!
Sometimes, in order to see the light,
you have to risk the dark.
As a policeman ...
Oh, excuse me, as a former policeman,
I'm sure that you know
all sorts of people ...
who can help you out in this regard.
It's funny
how all living organisms are alike.
When the chips are down,
when the pressure is on,
every creature on the face of the Earth
is interested in one thing ...
and one thing only.
Its own survival.
Find the minority report.
How do I even know which one has it?
It's always in the more gifted
of the three.
Which one is that?
The female.
All right, here's where we're at.
Three men in a room.
The victim is here.
John is here. And this
unidentified male, out the window.
Now, the adjacent building
suggests public housing,
but I can't make out the location,
which means ...
There's thousands of units
like this one.
Yeah, they're everywhere.
But he doesn't go there to kill Crow
for another 22 hours.
Excuse me,
this is Chief Anderton's space.
Casey, he's okay.
- You can't sit in his space.
- He's not here anymore.
- He'll be back.
- I doubt that.
- What happened to you?
- It's okay.
In the meantime, I'm betting
he's somewhere in the sprawl.
Anderton's smart enough to
go where electronic billboards ...
and other media can't ID him
to pick his pockets.
There's fewer consumers there, which
means fewer scanners to target him.
- Why won't he just run?
- Because he thinks he's innocent.
We concentrate on the sprawl.
Do flyovers in shifts
with two spyder teams on the ground.
Thermal scan the entire area, read
anything with eyes and a heartbeat.
Where is she?
This damn cold!
Don't worry.
You see, I could cut open your chest
and sew a dead cat in there,
you would never get an infection.
Not with the spectrum of antibios
I'll be shooting into you.
That's comforting.
You do understand
I can't just give you new irises.
Please don't touch.
Because the scanners will read the
new scar tissue, alarms will go off,
and large men with guns will appear.
What was that? What was that?
It's anesthesia.
It's all gonna be downhill from ...
You always sneak up
on your patients like that?
You wouldn't break the hand
of a violinist before the concert.
Please, relax.
All I'm trying to tell you is that I'll
have to remove your eyes completely.
I know.
And I'll have to replace them
with new ones.
I know that,
but I wanna keep the old ones.
Why?
Because my mother gave them to me.
What's it to you? They're no good
in the secondary market anyway.
Whatever you say. It's your money.
Let me introduce my gorgeous assistant,
Miss Van Eyck.
- This is not a lot of money.
- It's all that I could safely move.
What did you give me?
Smile medicine. Tell you what,
since you and I go way back,
why don't I just give you my
"old pal" discount? What do you say?
You don't remember me, do you?
- We know each other?
- Oh, yes, we do.
From where? D.C.?
- Baltimore. East side.
- Baltimore?
- Yeah.
- How do we go way back?
Solomon P. Eddie, M.D.
I was a plastic surgeon.
You remember? I specialized
in burn victims, mostly women.
- I put you away.
- Oh, yeah. You did.
You made those tapes.
They were performance pieces.
- You set your patients on fire.
- I put them out!
Some not as quickly as others, but
let's change the subject, shall we?
The future is so much more interesting
than the past, don't you think?
Miss van Eyck,
I'm afraid she's already smitten.
She only has eyes for you.
I know what you're thinking, John.
How can I do what I do now?
Well, let's say that I did spend an
awful lot of time in the prison library.
Now that was a great way ...
to avoid some of the more unpleasant
aspects of prison life.
Confinement was a real education,
a real ...
eye-opener.
I mean, for true enlightenment, there's
nothing quite like, well, let's say,
taking a shower while this
large felon with an attitude ...
you can't even knock down
with a hammer...
whispers in your ear,
"Oh, Nancy. Oh, Nancy."
Now, that was a lot of fun.
Thank you so very much, John,
for putting me there.
Thank you so very much
for giving me the opportunity ...
to get to know myself so much better.
And now, to return the favor.
- This your work?
- Yes.
I like it.
Thanks.
You take anything in your coffee?
- Cream and sugar.
- I don't have any cream. Sorry.
Just sugar, then.
You and John ever come here?
- We used to, every summer.
- He's not here now, is he?
I had to ask.
You know,
I don't have any sugar, either.
Thank you.
- He hasn't tried to contact you?
- No.
You ever heard him
mention the name Leo Crow?
No, but then I don't talk
to John that much anymore.
So you haven't seen his apartment?
- That was our apartment.
- Have you been there recently?
It's full of these.
How long has he been doping?
- Since right after we lost our son.
- You mean after he lost your son.
It was nobody's fault.
But John was with him
at the public pool.
You said in your divorce papers
that John tried to kill himself.
It wasn't a suicide attempt.
- I regret ever saying that.
- Then what was it?
The FBI found something that
belonged to my son, a sandal.
Anyway, John was upset. He ...
He took out his gun and sat down
and watched his home movies.
- He shot ...
- This is all in your statement, Lara.
He shot a hole in the damn ceiling.
So what?
You lose your son,
let's see how well you handle it.
Lamar Burgess thinks you left John ...
because he lost himself
in Precrime instead of you.
I left him because every time
I looked at him, I saw my son.
Every time I got close to him,
I smelled my little boy.
That's why I left him.
And now you can leave.
Don't take the bandages off
for 12 hours.
If you take them off before then,
you'll go blind. Understand?
In the fridge there's milk,
and Greta made you a sandwich.
Make sure you drink a lot of water.
How do I find the bathroom?
The bathroom?
Now that's your right hand.
The kitchen is your left.
Don't scratch. Never scratch!
Seeing as we're being old pals and all,
I'm going to give you a bonus.
It might come in handy.
This is a temporary paralytic enzyme.
You're gonna shoot this baby
up there, right under your chin.
What is this?
It's gonna turn your pretty face
into mush.
People won't even
recognize you, okay?
In 30 minutes,
it'll tighten up again,
but it's gonna hurt like
nothing you've ever felt before.
Gonna put this in your goodie bag,
together with your leftovers.
I'm setting up a timer.
When it rings tomorrow,
you can take off the bandages
and get the hell out of here,
but not before then, or you'll ...
- Go blind, I know.
Don't scratch.
A little something
from a mutual friend of ours.
Don't take the bandages off
for 12 hours.
If you take them off before then,
you'll go blind. Understand?
25.16 seconds. That's a new record.
Is that a world record?
Is it a world record?
It's a personal best.
Okay, now I want to time you.
You wanna time me?
You gotta be kidding.
'Cause there's no possible way
I can beat 25.16 seconds.
How long can a whale
hold its breath underwater?
A whale can hold its breath for
about 20 minutes.
- So we gotta beat the whale.
- Okay.
We gotta beat the whale.
Here you go.
Now, that's gonna be 20 minutes.
You sure you don't want to go
for an ice cream or something?
- No.
- Because you know,
you know I'm going to beat that whale.
- Yeah.
- Okay, give me the count.
- Ready?
- Give me the count.
- Three, two, one, go.
Sean?
Sean!
Have you seen ...
Sean! I'm looking for my son.
Have you seen a boy
in a red bathing suit?
Sean!
He's wearing a red bathing suit.
Sean ...
Jad, we are now in position
and ready to begin thermal scan ...
on all residences on North Powell.
I'm thinking you must
really like me, don't you, Fletcher?
That's why you asked to partner with
me on this little sortie, isn't it?
I think you're swell company, Knott.
It's not that you don't trust me
to be alone with the Chief, is it?
That you think I might futz
with him if I had the chance?
No, I just want to watch him use your
body to sandblast another building.
That's all, Jeff. Evanna, go.
I show 27 warm bodies.
Roger that. Confirm 27 warm bodies.
What do you think? Four spyders?
One per floor?
Let's do eight. I gotta eat.
Residents of 931 Powell,
residents of 931 Powell.
This is Officer Fletcher
of D.C. Precrime.
Under authority P.C. Section 6409,
we are deploying spyders
into your complex.
- Go, go, go, baby.
- Mom, I'm scared.
Mommy, I'm scared. Mommy.
Come on, it's gonna scan you.
Keep your eyes open. Just stay still.
Stay still, baby. Open your eyes.
It's okay.
- I don't like it.
- Stay still, stay still.
Come on! You can't just come
barging in here like that! Come on!
You have stepped out on me
for the last time.
I told you where I was!
Now get off my back!
You're a no good liar! I know
you was with that ho last night.
- Leave me alone!
- Get out of here!
We lost one.
Roger that. Maybe it was a cat jumping
through a window or something.
- That's an awful big cat.
- Fletcher.
I'll go check it out.
They're crying their eyes out.
You terrified them. They're
absolutely terrified right now!
You don't want your kids to know
terror, keep them away from me.
Wait a minute. The big cat's back.
What do you guys think,
a drunk, maybe can't wake up?
Yeah, some guy
who doesn't want to get read.
Folks, please be quiet.
Close your doors. Go back inside.
Be quiet and close the door!
We got an ID. It's not him.
Standing down.
Let's eat.
Anderton, wait!
Fletcher, take a look.
There's four people in this room,
not three.
Four? There's Anderton, there's Crow
and there's the man with sunglasses.
Here's the man with sunglasses
outside the window.
There's also someone here,
in the mirror.
Yeah. Definitely female.
The Precrime Program began in the
year 2046 with a federal grant.
And now, nine years later,
the District of Columbia is
the safest city in America.
Why? Because Precrime works.
Precrime has eliminated the need
for conventional detectives,
so most of what happens now ...
is the verification and the protection
of the future victim.
Can we see the Precogs?
Well, the Precogs have
such a powerful gift ...
that they have to be kept
in peaceful seclusion ...
so as not to be distracted
from the outside world.
But this display is to give you some
idea of what their daily life is like.
The Precogs get over eight million
pieces of mail every year,
more mail than Santa Claus gets.
Each Precog has their own bedroom,
television and weight room.
It really is wonderful
to be a Precog.
My mom's new boyfriend
came over again last night.
He's just not a
very intelligent person.
My mom wouldn't let me go upstairs
and eat in my room.
She made me sit down there
the entire time,
having to listen to him
go on and on and on.
Shit! Shit, shit, shit.
Eye-dent, John Anderton.
Approved for entry.
I want to get a new dog.
Which I told her
I should be able to do
because I'm so good
at taking care of you guys.
But she thinks that I'll be
irresponsible, which is ridiculous.
No, no, no, no! You can't be in here!
No, no! What are you doing here?
No, no, no, no!
Easy there, old-timer. Who cleared you?
You are not supposed to be in here.
- Listen, Wally.
- Do I know you? Who are you?
I like you, Wally. So, I don't want to have
to kick you or hit you with anything hard,
but only if you promise to help me.
Hi, John.
Who does that look like to you?
I don't know.
It's Agatha.
He's coming here to get her.
- Are these all of her previsions?
- I'm rewinding her right now.
I don't need to see all these.
Just take me to the Leo Crow murder.
I'm looking.
They're not coming out in any order.
I'm just getting them as she's giving.
Can you see?
- He's inside.
- He's got some kind of mask on.
He sealed the door from the inside.
Shit! Nobody fires a weapon
inside the temple.
Use only bindfoam or your sick-sticks.
Is there another way out of there?
We've got all the doors covered.
There's no way he's getting out.
John, move away from the tank!
Move away from the tank, John!
No, no, no, no, no. No!
No! No, no, no, no, no!
- What does he want with the Precog?
- What do you think?
So he can kill whoever he wants to
without anyone knowing about it!
But there's still the other two.
Wally! Wally!
The other two can still function, right?
You don't understand.
They're a hive mind.
It takes all three for their
predictive abilities to work.
Are you telling me
they can't see murders anymore?
Maybe if he'd taken one of the males,
but Agatha, she's the key.
She's the one they listen to,
the one with the most talent.
She takes care of the other two.
Jesus. Agatha.
Please, bring her back.
Find out where that pipe leads.
I want every team underground, now!
It doesn't matter, he wins.
No, no. I'll send my men to EVAC.
We'll stop him in the reservoir.
Gordon, she's in the room with him
when he kills Crow.
She's already a part of his future.
Jad, put everything you've got
into finding that room,
and we stop a murder.
- How much time have we got, Gordon?
- We've got 51 minutes, 30 seconds.
You cold?
Can you understand me?
Are you cold?
The shivers,
it's the drugs we gave you.
It should wear off soon.
I'm sorry. I need your help.
You contain information.
I need to know how to get at it.
Can you just tell me who Leo Crow is?
Can you tell me if ...
- Is it now?
- What?
Is it now?
Yes, this is all
happening right now.
We've gotta take you
some place in public,
which means I've gotta get you
something else to wear.
I'm tired.
I'm tired of the future.
Hello, Mr. Yakamoto.
Welcome back to the Gap!
How'd those assorted tank tops
work out for you?
Mr. Yakamoto?
Hey, Miss Belford,
did you come back ...
for another pair of
those Shimmy Lace Ups?
If he's ransoming her,
where's the damn note?
It has nothing to do with ransom.
It has to do with the information
that's inside of Agatha.
He's trying to prove his innocence.
But he can't download her
without a lot of technical support.
Well, your average consumer
can't buy any of this stuff ...
because it's been assembled
and scrounged ...
from spare parts made to order.
Assuming Anderton ordered this,
who put it together?
Who's Rufust. Riley?
What's your pleasure?
We got it all here.
We got sports fantasies.
We got what I like to call
"Look, Ma, I can fly" fantasies,
which encompasses everything
from bungee jumping ...
to soaring like an eagle
over the Grand Canyon.
We got guys coming in wanting
to experience sex as a woman.
We got women coming, wanna get laid
by their favorite soap star.
Or just some good, clean fun.
Yeah.
It's a big rush, but you come out
the other side without a heart attack.
I want to kill my boss.
Uh-huh. Okay.
You got some images I can work with?
Rufus!
Yeah, being concert master for the
Philadelphia Symphony Orchestra ...
is one of our most popular choices.
No, no, no. I want to kill my boss.
You sick bastard!
You're the kind of person that
makes this a terrible world to live in!
Detective, nice of you
to come down here,
seeing how every cop in the world
is looking for you right now.
I need your help.
Why did you have to come
all the way down here?
Chief, I make house calls.
You know that.
- I need your help with her.
- Well, hello there, honeypie.
I'm impressed, Anderton.
You're on the lam,
and you still have the time and energy
to slice off a little jerky for yourself.
- She's a Precog.
- Yeah. Okay. She's a Precog.
You brought a Precog here.
Jesus Christ.
- Are you reading my mind right now?
- Get up.
I'm sorry for whatever
I'm going to do,
and I swear I didn't do
any of that stuff I did.
She's got information inside of her.
I need you to get it out.
No way, man. No.
I wouldn't even know where to begin.
Those thoughts about my cousin Elena,
they were just thoughts.
You've been busted twice
for felony hacking.
- So?
- So, I need you to hack into her.
I tell you what. I do this,
I get to keep whatever images
I get from her head.
They don't belong to anybody.
Take her to RadioShack.
Rufus, you gotta help me.
Agatha, I need to see. I need to
see what's going to happen to me.
And then we'll go.
- Wow. She works.
- Slow it down.
How do I slow this down?
I should hit her on the head?
- Are you recording this?
- Shit.
Yeah, recording.
I know this already.
Come on, move on.
Goodbye, Crow.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
- I ...
- Where's the rest of it?
- I guess that's all of it.
Where's my minority report?
Do I even have one?
- Do I have one?
- No.
- What?
What? Agatha, what?
- Can you see?
- See what?
Anne Lively.
You want me to see
who killed Anne Lively.
Are you recording this?
Yeah, but look,
it's pouring out of her backwards.
I like my life. Everything is good.
They're inside.
Who?
All your old teammates.
Get in, left chamber.
- Hey, close the door!
- Negative!
Thank you, I don't deserve that.
I'm gonna cry.
- You are the man.
- No, you're the man.
- No, you are the man.
- You are the man.
Can you see the umbrella?
Take it!
A man in a blue suit.
He drops his briefcase.
You see a woman in a brown dress.
She knows your face.
Turn in here.
Let's go.
Wait.
- No, we can't stop here.
- You see the balloon man?
Wait.
What are we waiting for?
Wait. Wait.
Wait.
- Please, Mommy, can I have one?
- All right.
Wait.
Thank you.
- Anybody got an ID? Anybody?
- Negative.
All right.
Scott, Ramos, take the east end.
Everyone else, follow me. Let's go.
He knows. Don't go home.
We've got eyes on.
They're working,
but they're standing on it.
- Please! Please! Have you got a coin?
- Drop some money.
Can't you put it in my hand?
May the Lord bless you.
May God take care of you.
Damn!
That's the guy. The man in the window.
Hey. Hey.
- Rooms are $95 a night, plus tax.
- Mind if I look at the registry?
Yeah, I mind.
How about now?
Help yourself.
He's here.
Anderton, leave.
You have a choice. Walk away.
Do it now.
I can't. I have to know. I have to
find out what happened in my life.
Please.
Agatha, I'm not gonna kill the man.
I don't even know him.
- What room is Crow in?
- 1006.
Come on. Come on.
Wrong room.
Leave. Leave.
Oh, God.
This is Sean, my son.
Every day for the last six years,
I've thought about only two things.
The first is what my son would
look like if he were alive today,
if I would recognize him
if I saw him on the street,
and second is what I would do
to the man who took him.
You're right.
I'm not being set up.
You have to take me home.
No. No.
You said so yourself.
There is no minority report.
I don't have an alternate future.
I am going to kill this man.
You still have a choice.
The others never saw their future.
- Leo Crow?
- Who the hell are you?
Six years ago, Baltimore,
you grabbed up a kid ...
at Francis Public Pool
in the West End.
Did l? I don't know.
I don't remember
anything about that place.
Who am l? Who am l?
Do you know who I am?
- You're somebody's father.
- His name is Sean!
Sean!
I told him I was a policeman.
I told him I needed his help.
It wasn't so bad. I sang him a
song. I bought him a pretzel.
I bought him a pretzel.
He was happy. He was happy.
Is he alive? He's alive.
Where have you got him?
Is he all right?
Tell me, you fuck, where is he?
I put him in a barrel.
I sunk him in the bay.
He floated back up.
I took him out.
I was gentle. I was gentle.
I was gentle.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm so very sorry.
How could you do that to my ...
I'm sorry.
You can choose.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say or do can be
used against you in a court of law.
You have the right to an attorney,
now and during any
further questioning.
If you can't afford an attorney,
we will appoint one.
Do you understand these rights?
You're not gonna kill me?
- Do you understand these rights?
- You're not gonna kill me?
If you don't go through with this,
my family gets nothing. Okay?
You're supposed to kill me.
He said you would.
He? Who's he?
I don't know.
He called me in my cell.
He told me I'd be released
if I went along,
and my family would be taken care of.
- If you did what? If you did what?
If I acted like
I killed your kid. Okay?
If you killed my kid?
Look, you don't kill me,
my family gets nothing. Okay?
What about the pictures?
They're fake.
He gave them to me. Okay?
Now, listen to me. You ...
You tell me,
who was it that set this up?
I don't know.
- Come on.
- I'm asking you again.
- Who was it that put you up to this?
- I didn't see his face.
I tell you who it was,
and my family gets nothing.
- Who made you do this?
- Kill me.
- You can do this. Kill me.
- Tell me.
- Kill me. Kill me.
- Give me the gun.
Leo, let go of the gun.
Let go of the gun. It's okay.
Let go of the gun. That's it.
Let go of the gun.
You're not gonna kill me.
- Goodbye, Crow.
- Anderton, wait a ...
No!
- Hey, did you see it?
- Stay back!
What's happening down there?
Murder!
It doesn't make sense.
If you were a child killer,
you took these pictures,
would you leave them on the bed
for anyone to find?
They may have been put away.
Anderton might have found them.
- What kind of cop were you before this?
- Treasury agent. Eight years.
This would be
your first actual murder scene?
Yeah.
I worked homicide
before I went federal.
This is what we call
an orgy of evidence.
Know how many orgies I had
as a homicide cop, Gordon?
- How many?
- None.
This was all arranged.
Today we saw the first murder in the
six years of the Precrime experiment.
Sadly enough, this failure was human.
The protection team simply didn't
get there in time to stop the murder.
But the murder itself happened exactly
as the Precogs predicted it would.
I think that today's event put
a human face on the Precrime system.
Danny Witwer's on the phone.
He says it's important.
Lamar?
- What?
- Lamar, there's something ...
terribly wrong.
We're chasing the wrong man.
What?
I don't wanna say over the phone.
Meet me at Anderton's.
We recovered that
from Leo Crow's hotel room.
I remember when I gave this
to him, back in Baltimore.
Please, sir.
Tell me what you have.
This is the murder of a woman
named Anne Lively.
Yeah, John told me about this.
You got this from Containment?
Yes. this is from the twins,
Arthur and Dashiell.
Agatha's stream was missing.
Now this one is from the cyber parlor.
Anderton downloaded this directly from
Agatha, and Rufus Riley recorded it.
- It's the same prevision.
- Not quite.
Look at the surface wind
across the water. Watch the ripples.
Moving away from shore.
Now the second image.
This is the one from Containment.
It's what Art and Dash saw.
Watch the water.
The wind's changed.
The ripples are moving the other way.
This murder's taking place
at two different times.
According to the Sentry,
Anderton was watching this ...
at Containment
right before he was tagged.
Well, I know. He came to me, told
me about the missing data stream.
He was concerned
that you might find it.
Well, he was right. I did find it.
It was inside of Agatha the whole time.
So the question is, why would someone
want this erased from the data file?
Danny, just tell me
what you're thinking.
I'm thinking someone
got away with murder.
How?
Well, Jad told me that
sometimes the Precogs see ...
the same murder more than once.
- It's called an echo.
- Jad called it "Precog déjà vu."
Well, we teach the techs
to identify them and disregard.
Yeah, but what if a technician only
thought he was looking at an echo?
What if what he was
really looking at ...
was a completely
different murder altogether?
I don't understand.
All you'd have to do is
hire someone to kill Anne Lively,
someone like a drifter, a neuroin
addict, someone with nothing to lose.
Precrime stops the murder
from taking place,
haloes the killer, takes him away.
But then, right then, someone else,
having reviewed the prevision
and dressed in the same clothes,
commits the murder
in exactly the same way.
Technician takes a look, thinks he's
looking at an echo, erases it.
Of course,
it would have to be someone ...
with access to the previsions
in the first place.
Someone fairly high up.
Do you know what I hear?
Nothing. No footsteps up the stairs.
No hovercraft out the window.
No clickety-click of little spyders.
Do you know why I can't hear
any of those things, Danny?
Because right now,
the Precogs can't see a thing.
Can you see? It's beautiful.
- Where are we going?
- Someplace safe.
- Burgess.
- Lamar, it's Lara.
- Yes, Lara.
- You have to help him.
- Is he there?
- Yes.
Has he got the Precog with him?
- Keep them there. I'm on my way.
Please. Please don't tell Danny Witwer.
I don't trust him.
I won't say a word.
You just don't let
John leave, all right?
He's no killer, Lamar.
I know.
It's cold.
Lara, this is Agatha.
You remember when I would read
Tom Sawyer to you and Sean?
He got so scared when Tom and Becky
were lost in the cave.
I gotta sit down.
I gotta figure this out.
They used Sean.
They wanted me to
think Crow killed him.
But he didn't.
He didn't.
Why would they set you up?
Because I found out about her.
About who?
- How could I not have seen this?
- Seen what?
Anne Lively.
Agatha.
Dr. Hineman once said, "The dead
don't die. They look on and help."
Remember that, John.
- Agatha.
- Sean.
He's on the beach now,
toe in the water.
He's asking you
to come in with him.
He's been racing his mother
up and down the sand.
There's so much love
in this house.
He's 10 years old.
He's surrounded by animals.
He wants to be a vet.
You keep a rabbit for him,
a bird and a fox.
He's in high school.
He likes to run, like his father.
He runs the two-mile
and the long relay.
He's 23.
He's at a university.
He makes love
to a pretty girl named Claire.
He asks her to be his wife.
He calls here
and tells Lara, who cries.
He still runs across the university and
in the stadium, where John watches.
Oh, God. He's running so fast,
just like his daddy.
He sees his daddy.
He wants to run to him.
But he's only six years old,
and he can't do it.
And the other man is so fast.
There was so much love in this house.
I want him back so bad.
So did she.
Can't you see?
She just wanted her little girl back.
But it was too late.
Her little girl was already gone.
She's still alive.
She didn't die, but she's not alive.
Agatha?
Just tell me, who killed your mother?
Who killed Anne Lively?
I'm sorry, John,
but you're gonna have to run again.
What?
Run!
I love you.
- Okay. You're okay.
- No, no.
- You'll be fine with them.
Stay with me. Stay with me.
- John, no.
- Don't talk.
John Anderton.
By mandate of the
District of Columbia Precrime Division,
I'm placing you under arrest for the
murders of Leo Crow and Danny Witwer.
That's it.
That's my girl.
I was so worried about you.
Did he hurt you?
I missed you so much.
It's okay.
Wally's here. Wally's here.
You're a part of my flock now,
John. Welcome.
It's actually kind of a rush.
They say you have visions,
that your life flashes before your eyes,
that all your dreams come true.
This is all my fault.
There was nothing anyone could do.
Lara ...
I thought you might want to have those.
I haven't worn this in years. I just wanted
to make sure it fits before tonight.
You look great.
I knew he was having trouble for some
time, and yet I did nothing about it.
Excuse me.
The guy from USA today is here.
Tell him not now.
- He just wanted a few minutes before ...
- Not now!
- I thought you were retiring.
- Well, I was.
But this incident with John made
me realize the fragility of all this.
This is John's legacy
as much as it is my own.
Now I have an obligation
to protect that.
Lara, I know how
difficult this is for you.
But maybe you can find
some closure in the fact that ...
John finally found the man
who killed your son.
Who's Anne Lively?
- Who?
- Anne Lively.
John was talking about her
right before they took him.
I don't know who that is.
John said something about him being
set up because he found out about her.
- Well, we know why John was tagged.
- He also said Crow was a fake.
And Witwer?
He was killed with John's gun ...
inside John's apartment.
- Lamar, do you know the reason ...
why John came here to work for you?
- Sean.
- Yes.
He came here to work for you
because he thought ...
if he could just stop
that kind of thing from happening ...
- I understand.
- No, I don't think you do.
Sir, they wanna start
the press conference in two minutes.
Lara, John was the best cop
I ever knew,
and, in some ways,
also the best man.
But the scars he carried around ...
Well, I know he'd want us to honor the
good things we remember about him.
And I also know why he married you.
You're as stubborn as he is.
Lamar ...
Lara, do you know
how to tie one of these?
Could you please give me a hand?
I'm all thumbs, you see.
Listen, I'll tell you what I'll do.
First thing Monday,
I'll look over the Witwer evidence.
And I'll have Gideon
run the Containment files,
see if anyone drowned a woman
by the name of ...
What did you say her name was?
Anne Lively.
But I never said she drowned.
- Sir, the press conference is starting.
- I'll be right there.
We'll talk about this later.
Perhaps tomorrow
I'll come by the cottage.
I'd like a word with my husband.
You're not authorized.
How did you get in here?
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, Lamar Burgess,
director of the new National Precrime.
On behalf of your staff, we would
like to present you with this.
- Congratulations, sir.
- My God.
How did you get this?
I padded your expense account
for six months.
Revolvers like this one ...
were given to generals at the end of
the Civil War by their troops.
The cylinders were loaded
with five gold-plated bullets ...
to symbolize the end
of the destruction and death ...
that had ripped the country apart
for five years.
Ladies and gentlemen,
with Precrime going national,
maybe we can all look forward
to a time when none of us ...
will have to discharge
another firearm ever again.
Now enjoy yourselves.
Enjoy yourselves! That's an order.
Does this mean we can finally use
the lake house on weekends?
I hope so.
Hello. Yes. Right away.
Excuse me. Excuse me. So sorry.
- Sir?
- Yes.
Sir, you have an emergency call
on your private line.
All right. Thank you.
Yes, this is Burgess.
Hello, Lamar. I just wanted
to congratulate you. You did it.
You created a world without murder.
Sir, everyone wants your name on
a hat. Can you sign these for us?
And all you had to do
was kill someone to do it.
A-room. Jad.
Jad, it's Lara. John needs a favor.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
I'm talking about Agatha's mother,
Anne Lively.
Just a junkie who had a kid once
and had to give her up.
But surprise. She cleaned herself up
and she wanted her daughter back.
She wanted Agatha.
Jad, you getting this?
It's a single stream from the female
only with no time or incident data.
Whatever this is, it isn't the
future. It already happened.
The problem was, without
Agatha, there was no Precrime.
She's always been
the strongest of the three.
You knew without Agatha,
you had nothing.
Without her,
you wouldn't be where you are now,
standing there, signing autographs.
Jad, what are you doing?
Jad. Jad, what are you
doing with that?
What you up to, big man?
Jad, Jad, let's think
before you send that.
Slow down.
So now you had to get rid of
Anne Lively. You had to shut her up,
which presented a problem.
How can you kill her
without the Precogs seeing it?
Simple. Use a system
you control against her.
So you hired someone
to kill her for you,
knowing full well
the Precogs would see that murder.
You lured Anne Lively
out to the lake ...
with the promise
of reuniting her with her daughter.
Where's my daughter?
Where?
Run.
Run!
And then, when you were all
alone, you killed her yourself,
in the same way the Precogs predicted
your John Doe would kill her.
You made the real murder
look like an echo,
knowing the tech would do what
he was trained to do. Disregard it.
Anne Lively became
just another missing person.
So, what are you gonna do, Lamar?
What are you gonna do?
We got a Red Ball!
Think about the lives
that little girl has saved.
Think about all the lives she will save.
That little girl could have saved Sean.
Don't you ever say his name!
You used the memory of my dead son
to set me up.
to set me up!
That was the one thing you knew
that would drive me to murder.
- What are you gonna do now, Lamar?
- How are you gonna ...
- Shut me up?
Forgive me, John.
Lamar, it's over.
The question you have to ask is,
what are you gonna do now?
No doubt the Precogs
have already seen this.
No doubt.
You see the dilemma, don't you?
If you don't kill me, Precogs were
wrong and Precrime is over.
If you do kill me, you go away,
but it proves the system works.
Precogs were right.
So, what are you gonna do now?
What's it worth?
Just one more murder.
You'll rot in hell with a halo, but
people will still believe in Precrime.
All you have to do is kill me,
like they said you would.
Except you know your own future,
which means you can change it
if you want to.
You still have a choice, Lamar,
like I did.
Yes, I have a choice.
And I made it.
Forgive me, John.
Forgive me.
Forgive me, my boy.
Lamar!
In 2054,the six-year Precrime
experiment was abandoned.
ALL prisoners were unconditionally
pardoned and released,
although police departments kept watch
on many of them for years to come.
Agatha and the twins were transferred
to an undisclosed location,
a place where they could find
relief from their gifts.
A place where they could
live out their lives in peace.