You know how blind I am without them.
Howard, don't cry.
Murder.
Good luck, John.
- Any contractions?
- Only the ones you give me.
Okay, Jad, what's coming?
Red Ball, double homicide,
one male, one female.
Killer's male, white, 40s.
Agatha nailed the time frame
at 8:04 a. m.
The twins are a little fuzzy on that,
so we'll need confirmation.
Location's still uncertain. Remote
witnesses are plugged in.
This will be case number 1108.
Good morning, detectives.
Case number 1108, previsualized
by the Precogs,
recorded on holosphere by
Precrime's q-stacks.
My fellow witnesses for
case number 1108
are Dr. Katherine James and Chief Justice
Frank Pollard.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
Will the witnesses preview and validate
number 1108 at this time?
- Affirmative. I will validate.
- Go get him.
Stand by. Time of murder, 8:04 a. m.
That is 24 minutes, 13 seconds
from now.
This is a Red Ball.
You know how blind I am
without them.
Alright, Howard Marks,
where are you?
Howard? Howard, breakfast!
Four score and seven years ago...
- He looked familiar.
- Who?
A man standing in the park across
the street. I've seen him before.
How can you even tell? You know how
blind you are without your glasses.
Where are your glasses?
I must have left them up
in the bedroom.
You are running out of time.
You know how blind I am...
I show eight Howard Marks in the District.
Sorting by race and age.
Run their license and registration.
See if I can capture an address here.
You are running out of time.
You know, I was thinking maybe I'd
play hooky, stay home today.
What about your meeting? I've been
working too much.
- Can you grab that?
- It's unclear.
I got six licenses. Where do
you want them?
Over here, please.
I'm very sorry.
You know how blind I am
without them.
Got him in the Foxhall,
4421 Gainsborough.
Send a DCPD blue-and-white.
Set up a perimeter, and tell them
we're en route.
You know, I was thinking maybe I'd
play hooky, stay home today.
We have come to dedicate
a portion of that field...
- What do you think?
- ...as a final resting place
- What about your meeting?
- I'll reschedule.
I've been working too much anyway.
...is altogether fitting and proper
that we should do this.
- But in a larger sense... Good.
- We could have lunch together.
- What do you say?
- We cannot consecrate.
We cannot hallow this ground.
- Any place you want.
- I would love...I would love to.
The brave men, living and dead...
I have an open house
at the Ressler place.
...have consecrated it far above our
poor power to add or detract.
I guess that's why you look so nice.
Chief!
We got a problem with our location.
- It's no longer there.
- Shit.
- Time frame?
- Thirteen minutes.
Investigator from the Fed's here.
Yeah, I don't need some twink from
the Fed poking around right now.
John, I wrote it down on your calendar.
I left you a message at your house.
Check in with the papers.
They had it forwarded.
See if the neighbors knew
where they went.
- Check all relations.
- Checking neighbors and relations.
- But, John...
- Fletch, just get him some coffee.
Tell him some stories how I save
your ass every day
- and you can't live without me.
- I got coffee, thank you.
Danny Witwer, the twink from the Fed.
Whoops. Gum?
Sorry, Danny, I'm gonna have to give you
the full tour some other time.
The Markses moved a couple
of weeks ago,
nobody knows where. Still searching for
family and employer.
Time Horizon, 12 minutes.
Alright. What he's doing now, we call
scrubbing the image,
looking for clues as to where
the murder's gonna happen.
Original running bond brick pattern,
streamlined early Georgian details...
The brick has been re-pointed.
- And, That this nation...
- This nation...
- under God...
...shall not perish from the Earth.
Victims are pronounced here,
killers here.
Beyond that and the date
of the crime,
all we have to run on are the images
that they produce.
I show a cop on horseback.
- Near the Capitol?
- No Maglev system.
The Mall?
Georgetown.
The Precogs can see a murder four
days out. Why the late call?
Well, we call it a Red Ball.
With crimes of passion there's
no premeditation,
so they show up late.
Most of our scrambles are flash events,
like this one.
We rarely see anything with
premeditation anymore.
- People have gotten the message.
- Uh..huh.
Oh, this is good.
I show a match for Dwight Kingsley,
18th-century architect.
He did two dozen houses in D.C.
- Time Horizon, 10 minutes.
- Ten minutes.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Look at this kid. In this one, he's on
the left side of the man in the suit.
- Yes, so?
- This one he is on the right.
Merry-go-round.
It's a park!
Tell me there's only 16 of these old
merry-go-rounds left in the city.
Two in Georgetown, one in Barnaby Woods.
The other's in Woodley.
Woodley's all Victorian. It's gotta be
Barnaby Woods.
- Evanna, flight time?
- The way I drive,
three minutes after wheels up.
- Clear.
Time Horizon, six minutes.
Let's go to bed.
Let's do it in here.
- The bed is soft.
- I'm soft.
Shit!
Which one is it?
- Don't stop!
- Not the bed!
- Come on, come on.
- I don't want to be on the bed!
Time Horizon, one minute. Chief, we're
catching up to the future.
Shut up, Evanna. Jad?
- Jad?
- Go ahead.
- Did he close the front door?
- What?
Did Marks close the front door?
Front door.
I didn't want to be on the bed.
Negative. The front door is open.
- The front door is open.
- Time Horizon, 30 seconds.
- I forgot my glasses.
- Oh, Howard!
No, no, no, Howard.
You know how blind I am without them.
Howard, don't cry.
Marks!
Look at me. Look at me.
Positive for Howard Marks.
Mr. Marks, by mandate of the District
of Columbia Precrime Division,
I'm placing you under arrest
for the future murder of Sarah Marks
and Donald Dubin
that was to take place today,
April 22nd, at 0804.
No! I didn't do anything.
- Sarah!
- Give the man his hat.
Oh, God. Don't put that halo on me!
Sarah!
- Put your hand on your head!
- Help me!
I wasn't gonna do anything!
Officer Scott, I'm with the Precrime
Trauma Response Unit.
I want you to sit here a minute
and listen to me.
Your husband is being arrested
by officers from Precrime.
Oh, God, Howard, no!
Howard, don't cry.
Howard, please don't cry.
Oh, God. Oh, God.
I thought they stopped the murder.
Well, that's just an echo, a Precog
déjà vu, if you will.
The really bad ones, the Precogs
see them over and over again.
Wally, erase the incoming.
Imagine a world without murder.
- I lost my best friend.
- I lost my aunt.
- I lost my dad.
- I lost my father.
I lost my wife.
Just six years ago, the homicide rate
in this country
had reached epidemic proportions.
It seemed that only a miracle
could stop the bloodshed.
But instead of one miracle, we were
given three, the Precognitives.
Within just one month under
the Precrime program,
the murder rate in the District
of Columbia was reduced 90%.
They were gonna be waiting for me
in the car.
He was gonna rape me.
- I was going to be stabbed.
- Right here.
Within a year, Precrime
effectively stopped murder
in our nation's capital.
In the six years we've been conducting
our little experiment,
there hasn't been a single murder.
And now Precrime
can work for you.
We want to make absolutely certain
that every American can bank on the utter
infallibility of the system,
and to ensure that what keeps us safe
will also keep us free.
- Precrime, it works.
- It works.
- Precrime, it works!
On Tuesday, April 22nd, vote yes on
the National Precrime Initiative.
What's the matter? Can't sleep?
- I just need a little clarity.
- True, true, true, true, that.
You want the customary clarity or the
new-and-improved kind of clarity?
Just give me the new stuff.
New and improved. New and improved
clarity, clarity, clarity.
Yes, indeed, clarity.
Come on, come on.
I just want a hit.
Look, don't bust my balls.
You just gave me four, and
some of these are duds.
Sweet dreams, Chief.
Don't worry none, your secret's safe
with me.
Besides, I could use a little juice
on my side.
What do you think you know, Lycon?
It's like my daddy used to say,
In the land of the blind,
the one-eyed man is king.
I'm home.
Overhead.
Wall screen.
- Sean!
- Hi, Daddy.
Can you teach me how to run faster?
'Cause all the kids in my class
run faster than me.
No. That's good.
Look, keep your knees up.
Keep your knees up like that. Good.
Like that. Like that.
Like that. High. High. Like that.
Like that. High.
See, you're a natural runner.
Gotta keep running!
Gotta keep running.
You gotta keep running.
Will I be as fast as you someday?
Oh, I think you'll beat me someday.
You're gonna beat everybody.
I think you'll beat everyone someday.
- I gotta go. Bye.
- No, no, no. No, no, no. Wait, wait.
- You gotta give me a kiss.
- Not on the lips!
Only Mommy kisses me on the lips.
Yeah. Alright, alright, alright.
I love you.
- I love you, Sean.
- I love you, Daddy.
It reminds me of Rosarito Beach.
Remember?
Yeah, we had those...
we had $20,
and waiting in the van so the sun
would shine on our vacation.
John! John.
John, put the camera down. Look, I'm...
I'm all ready for bed.
What...what is this? No.
Put it away. It's time to put
the camera to sleep,
and time to come and take care
of your wife.
Sweetie, why don't you
put the camera down
and come and watch the rain with me?
No? I promise I'll make it
a memorable moment.
Look, put the camera down, or you're
not getting anything tonight.
A gentleman at Justice wants
to take all this away from us.
You understand a week from now
people are going to vote
on whether or not what we've been
doing down here
has been some noble-minded
enterprise,
or a chance to change the way
this country fights crime.
- I understand, sir.
- John.
Watch this Danny Witwer,
- the observer from Justice.
- Yes, I met him yesterday.
You can let him look around, answer
his questions, but watch him.
- Yes, sir.
- And if there's any problem,
- make sure we know about it first.
- I understand.
When the Precogs declare
a victim and a killer,
their name is embedded
in the grain of wood.
Since each piece is unique, the shape
and grain is unique.
The shape and grain is
impossible to forge.
I'm sure you all understand the legalistic
drawback to Precrime methodology.
Here we go again.
Look, I'm not with the ACLU
on this, Jeff.
But let's not kid ourselves.
We are arresting individuals
who have broken no law.
- But they will.
- The commission of the crime itself
is absolute metaphysics.
The Precogs see the future,
and they're never wrong.
But it's not the future if you stop it.
Isn't that a fundamental paradox?
Yes, it is.
You're talking about predetermination,
which happens all the time.
- Why'd you catch that?
- Because it was going to fall.
- You're certain?
- Yeah.
But it didn't fall. You caught it.
The fact that you prevented it
from happening
doesn't change the fact that
it was going to happen.
You ever get any false positives?
Someone intends to kill his boss or
his wife, but they never go through
with it.
How do the Precogs tell the difference?
The Precogs don't see what you intend
to do, only what you will do.
Then why can't they see rapes?
Or assaults or suicides?
Because of the nature of murder.
There's nothing more destructive to
the metaphysical fabric that binds us
than the untimely murder of one
human being by another.
Somehow, I don't think
that was Walt Whitman.
It's Iris Hineman.
She developed the Precogs, designed
the system and pioneered the interface.
Speaking of interfacing,
I'd love to say hello.
- To Hineman?
- To them.
Cops aren't allowed
inside the temple.
Really? You've never been inside?
We keep strict separations so that no
one can be accused of tampering.
So, I'll be the first one to go in, then?
- Maybe you didn't hear me.
- If it's a question of authority...
No, there is no question.
You don't have any.
I have a warrant in my pocket
that says different.
- Show it to me.
- Sure.
This investigation of Precrime
and its personnel
is being conducted under
the direct supervision
and express permission from the Attorney
General of the United States.
I'm here as his representative,
which means you're now operating
under my supervision.
Seems you've been left out
of the loop, John.
Alright, we're ready. Let's go.
Hold it right there. Hold it.
Not cleared for access.
Eye-dent, John Anderton.
Approved.
- Wally.
- No, no, no, no.
It's okay. This is Danny Witwer.
He's from Justice.
We're to give him the run of the farm.
I can't touch you.
- Don't touch him or anything else.
- John, you can't be in here...
I understand. Just answer his questions
and we'll get the hell out of here.
Tell me how...
- They're sleeping.
- Sorry. Tell me how all this works.
The photon milk acts as both a nutrient
supply and a liquid conductor.
It enhances the images that
each of them receive.
We call the female Agatha. The twins
are Arthur and Dashiell.
We scan by way of optical tomography.
White-light pinpoints pulse
along the entire length of
the headgear,
and they're reread after absorption
through their brain tissue.
In other words, we see what they see.
They don't feel any pain.
We keep their heads pretty well stocked
with dopamine and endorphins.
Plus, we maintain careful control
over their serotonin levels.
Don't want them to drift off
into too deep a sleep.
They can't be kept too awake, either.
It's better if you don't think
of them as human.
No. They're much more than that.
Science has stolen most
of our miracles.
In a way, they give us hope, hope
of the existence of the divine.
I find it interesting that some people
have begun to deify the Precogs.
The Precogs are pattern-recognition
filters, that's all.
- Yet you call this room the temple.
- Just a nickname.
The oracle isn't where
the power is, anyway.
The power's always been
with the priests,
even if they had to invent
the oracle.
You guys are nodding like you actually
know what the hell he's talking about.
Well, come on, Chief. The way we work,
changing destiny and all,
I mean, we're more like clergy
than cops.
- Jad?
- Yeah?
Go to work. All of you.
Sorry. Old habit.
I spent three years at Fuller Seminary
before I became a cop.
My father was very proud.
What does he think of your
chosen line of work?
I don't know. He was shot and killed
when I was 15
on the steps of our church in Dublin.
I know what it's like to lose
someone close, John.
Of course, nothing is like
the loss of a child.
I don't have any children of my own,
so I can only imagine what
that must have been like.
To lose your son in such
a public place like that.
At least now you and I have
the chance to make sure
that kind of thing
doesn't happen to anyone.
Why don't you cut the cute act,
Danny Boy, and tell me
- exactly what it is you're looking for.
- Flaws.
There hasn't been a murder in six years.
There's nothing wrong with the system.
It is...
Perfect. I agree. If there's a flaw,
it's human.
It always is.
John.
Wally.
Can you see?
John, what the hell just happened?
Her ACTH levels just shot
through the roof!
- What did you do to her?
- She grabbed me.
Grabbed you? That's impossible. The
Precogs aren't even aware of us.
- In the milk, all they see is the future.
- She looked straight at me.
It could have been a nightmare.
Sometimes they dream
about the old murders.
- She spoke to me.
- To you?
- What'd she say?
- Can you see?
You the Sentry?
Yes, sir! I'm Gideon.
You're Chief Anderton.
The music relaxes the prisoners.
Say, I don't ever see any of you
Precops down here.
- I'm not in trouble, am I?
- Not yet.
- I'm interested in a murder.
- I got plenty of those. Kill type?
- Drowning.
- That narrows it down.
Not too many in here for that one.
- Victim's Caucasian, female.
- This about the Justice Department?
I'm supposed to spruce up for a tour
they got planned for tomorrow.
Told me to wear a tie. You like this one?
Stop.
Roll back.
There.
She's a golden oldie. One of our first.
Probably before your time.
This is the official composite
of the three Precogs?
That's right! A combined data stream
based on all three previsions.
Just show me Agatha's data stream.
For that,
we go for a ride.
My God. I'd forgotten
there were so many.
And to think they'd all be out there
killing people if it wasn't for you.
Look at them. Look at how peaceful
they all seem.
But on the inside, busy, busy, busy.
Okey-pokey! Now that
is one bad man.
He drowned a woman named Anne Lively
out at Roland Lake.
The killer's a John Doe.
Never identified.
Why is he still a John Doe?
Why wasn't he ever ID'd
from the eye-scan?
On account of those
are not his eyes.
He had them swapped out
to fool the scanners.
You can get it done on the street for
a few thousand bucks these days.
Okay, so you want just
the female prevision.
That's right.
We don't seem to have her data.
Try again.
This is odd.
See? We have the two previsions.
We got what Art saw, we got
what Dash saw,
but Agatha's isn't here.
Probably just a glitch.
Tell me about the intended victim,
this Anne Lively.
Looks like she's a neuroin addict,
like our John Doe here,
but I show an address history that
includes the Beaton Clinic.
So she cleaned up. So where's she now?
I guess glitches come in twos.
You finally crawl your way out of
one hole just to fall into another.
No.
I can't let you take that
out of here, Chief.
It's against the rules.
Anything else going on in here
that's against the rules?
Careful, Chief. You dig up the past,
all you get is dirty.
And then you said the third prevision was,
what, kind of fuzzy or something?
No. No, the third prevision, Agatha's
prevision, wasn't there.
That's not all. I spent a few hours
down there,
and there are a dozen more cases
with missing previsions.
You'd think we'd have found a cure
for the common cold by now.
- It's stress.
- What's this?
Herbal tea with honey.
I hate herbal tea, almost as much
as I hate honey.
Just drink it before I pour it
in your lap.
- Can I get you anything, John?
- No, thank you, Celeste.
Witwer's scheduled for a Containment...
Tour of Containment tomorrow.
Yeah, give him a tour.
- Lara called me.
- What?
She's worried about you.
Quite frankly, so am I.
I'm fine.
I understand you've been spending
a lot of time in the sprawl.
- I go running down there.
- In the middle of the night?
What if Danny Witwer came
to you right now
- and insisted on a full chem run?
- Lamar, I'm fine.
You understand, John,
the minute Precrime goes national, they're
going to take it away from us.
We won't let them.
No? How's an old man and a cop on
the whiff ever going to stop them?
My father once said to me,
You don't choose the things you
believe in. They choose you.
There's a reason you are here, John.
Had Precrime been in place
just six months earlier,
the loss you and Lara suffered
would have been prevented.
Remember the eyes...
The eyes of the nation
are on us right now.
And we both know I'm not the generation
anyone listens to.
But people trust you, John.
When you speak of your absolute
belief in Precrime,
they know it's a belief born of pain, not
politics. I always understood that.
And I may have even encouraged it
to help with the cause.
But now, your pain is hurting both of us.
They're not gonna take it away from us.
I won't let them.
Bingo.
Hi, Daddy!
Hey, little buddy.
I made up a club.
Yeah?
We're called the Crescos.
The Crescos.
We made up a soccer team...
Yeah.
And we practice at school.
Yeah?
Do you practice with Connor?
Daddy's in a lot of trouble, Sean.
Wait.
Jad, how come you're not out there
with Father Witwer?
We're in motion on something.
Now, from what I can see,
we got a white male victim, about 5'10",
approximately 170.
He takes a round in the 10-ring
and goes out a window.
- Red Ball?
- Nope, Brown Ball.
- This one's premeditated.
- Amazing.
There's someone within 200 miles actually
dumb enough to still do that.
Well, the victim's name is Leo Crow.
This is case number 1109.
Time of occurrence, Friday, 1506 hours.
Start a location run and a contact search
for future victim, Leo Crow.
Case number 1109, previsualized
by the Precogs,
recorded on holosphere by
Precrime's q-stacks.
My fellow witnesses for
case number 1109
are Dr. Katherine James and
Chief Justice Frank Pollard.
Good morning.
- Good morning.
Are the witnesses ready to preview
and validate number 1109?
- Ready when you are, John.
- Standing by.
Oh, I love this part.
I've got no address, last known
or otherwise,
no tax returns for the last five years.
Check NCIC, maybe he's got a record.
And send a protection team as soon
as we lock location.
Looks like federal housing. Concrete,
glass, egg crates.
Ouch. About 1,000 of those
in the District.
Fractured images coming in.
Numbers nine...
Nine and six.
Female, senior. She's smoking a pipe.
She's laughing.
Okay, now inside a room.
Window panes, aluminum extrusion.
Two figures resolving in the room.
Wait!
Looks like we got a third party,
wearing sunglasses, just out
of the window.
You're not gonna kill me.
Goodbye, Crow.
- Goodbye, Crow.
- Anderton, wait!
Wait. Wait.
- You say something, Chief?
- No.
I'll get this one.
We got time on this one, Jad.
Mind going down and getting me a piece
of cake they're eating down there?
- I'm starving.
- Sure, Chief.
I think I'll get one for myself
while I'm at it.
Take your time.
Chief Anderton, what is this
that I'm seeing?
I'm confused about...
- Anderton, wait!
- Goodbye, Crow.
Wait! Anderton, wait!
Anderton, wait!
I like you, Chief. You've always
been nice to me.
I'll give you two minutes
before I hit the alarm.
Hold that, please.
Thanks.
- You're in a lot of trouble, John.
- You set me up.
I'll write the paranoia off to the whiff
you've been doping on all night.
- Easy. Easy.
- Seems I found a flaw.
What are you gonna do?
Possession alone will cost you six months,
not to mention your badge.
I guess we won't be working together
after all.
Now, put the gun down, John.
I don't hear a Red Ball.
Lamar? Lamar?
- Lamar?
- John, what the hell is happening?
- It's Witwer! He set me up!
- What the hell is happening?
- He set me up.
- Stop. Just wait.
- Who...
- He set me up. Witwer. It's Witwer!
Yeah, who's the victim?
- Somebody.
- Who?
- Somebody. Leo Crow.
- Well, who is he?
I have no idea! I've never heard of him!
But I'm supposed to kill him
in less than 36 hours.
Ah. But how could Witwer have
access to case files?
Can you fake a cerebral output?
- Why would anyone want to?
- Can you?
- Well, I doubt it very much.
- Well, would Hineman know?
- Listen. Come in.
- What?
Well, I'll keep you safe until we get
to the bottom of this, John.
No, Lamar, listen to me. Listen.
Talk to Wally, see if Witwer's gone
inside the temple again.
Then ask Jad for any off-hour eye-dents
into the analytical room.
Just tell me, who's Leo Crow?
Security lockdown enabled. Revised
destination, office.
Lamar, they found me.
Is there any way to override
the lockdown?
- No. No. No.
- No?
I'll meet you anywhere you say. You can
come to my house, John.
You know I can't. They'll get me there.
I'm not gonna get haloed.
You can't run, John.
Everybody runs.
- Oh, my God.
- Hey, hey.
Oh, my gosh. Are you okay?
Don't worry, sir. I'll bring him in,
unharmed.
Actually, Gordon, you're
not gonna do that.
- I'm taking control of the team.
- What?
Witwer, Fletcher is second in command.
It's his show to run.
If you want, you can observe. Do it.
Find him.
Yes, sir.
He came to see you the other day,
right before he was tagged.
- What did you talk about?
- The Mets.
John doesn't think they have a deep
enough pitching roster this year,
- and I'm inclined to agree.
- Why are you protecting him?
You knew he was doping, yet you
did nothing about it.
- The man lost a child, for Christ's sake.
- Six years ago.
- What did you two talk about?
- None of your damn business.
Oh, it's all my damn business now,
Lamar.
Investigation of a supervising officer
for a capital crime
falls under federal jurisdiction,
so as to rule out any possibility
of conspiracy.
- He's my suspect.
- He's my subordinate.
Shall we call the Attorney General?
I'm sure he'd be happy to clarify
the issue for you.
I don't want John Anderton hurt.
I'm gonna enjoy working here.
A road diverges in the desert.
Lexus.
The road you're on, John Anderton,
is the one less traveled.
Good evening, John Anderton.
John Anderton.
John Anderton!
You could use a Guinness
right about now.
Stressed out, John Anderton?
Get away, John Anderton.
Forget your troubles.
He's been eye-dented on the Metro.
The train makes two stops,
at 20th and 33rd.
Send units to each location.
- They'll never make 20th.
- Have faith.
Fire them up!
- Hey, Fletch.
- Hey, John.
- That was a rough landing.
- Yeah.
- You have to work on that.
- It's that old, shit knee of mine.
- Yeah.
- Don't do it.
Hey, don't do this.
John? Don't run.
You don't have to chase me.
You don't have to run.
- Everybody runs, Fletch.
- You know we'll catch you.
Everybody runs.
- It doesn't have to be like this, John.
- Everybody runs.
Get your sick-sticks ready.
Everybody runs, Fletch.
Slow down, Chief. Just take it easy.
No sudden moves, Chief.
John, it's okay.
- Fletch...
- Easy does it, Chief.
- Got a grip? Got a grip?
- Yeah.
Chief! Chief, no! Chief!
Anderton!
Go away! Get out of my kitchen!
Get that thing out of my house!
Get out of my house! Get out!
Anderton, stop!
Pull him off me, Fletcher.
Get him off me.
Do something! Try to get them
out of here! What's the matter with you?
John! Stop! Get out
of my house now!
By mandate of the District of Columbia
Precrime Division,
I'm placing you under arrest...
Go to sleep.
Just stay with me.
Dr. Hineman?
You're trespassing. I don't have visitors.
Oh, I'm afraid that would be from
the Doll's Eye, the vine.
The baneberry that scratched you during
your illegal climb over my wall.
It's not a true Doll's Eye, of course.
It's a little hybrid of my own design.
It's quite something. Once the poison
gets into your bloodstream,
you will start to see what
I can only describe
as the most extraordinary display
of blue objects.
This just isn't your week, is it,
Chief Anderton?
I'm not a killer.
You better drink this.
Soon you won't be able to swallow, and
then you'll be totally buggered.
All of it.
Okay, now take a minute
to right yourself.
Just what is it you think
I can do for you?
You can tell me how someone
can fake a prevision.
How would I know that?
Because you invented Precrime.
What's so funny?
If the unintended consequences
of a series of genetic mistakes
and science gone haywire
can be called invention,
yes, then I invented Precrime.
- You don't seem all that proud.
- I'm not.
I was trying to heal them, not turn them
into something else.
Heal who?
The innocents we now use
to stop the guilty.
You're talking about the Precogs.
You think the three in the tank
come out of a test tube?
They are merely the ones who survived.
I was doing genetic research
at the Woodhaven Clinic,
treating children of drug addicts.
This was 10 years ago, when neuroin
first hit the streets.
It was an impure form of the drug,
not the engineered cocktail
that became so popular among
the more educated.
All of these kids were born with
severe brain damage.
Most died before the age of 12.
Those few, those precious few who
survived, they had a gift.
I call it a gift. For them, it was more
like a cosmic joke.
They would wake up in the night, curled up
in the corner of their rooms,
screaming, clawing at the wallpaper.
Because when these little children, you
see, closed their eyes at night,
they dreamt only of murder, over
and over, one after the other.
And it didn't take long for us to
realize that the real nightmare
was that these so-called dreams
were about to come true.
These murders were actually happening.
You say some of the children died.
So many of them, despite
what we did for them.
Or maybe because of what we did
to them. But it doesn't matter.
It's a perfect system now, isn't it?
I'm not going to commit murder.
I've never met the man
I'm supposed to kill.
And yet a chain of events has started,
a chain that will lead you inexorably
to his murder.
Not if I stay away from him.
How can you avoid a man
you've never met?
So you won't help me?
I can't help you. Nobody can. The Precogs
are never wrong.
But occasionally,
they do disagree.
What?
Most of the time, all three Precognitives
will see an event in the same way,
but once in a while, one of them will see
things differently than the other two.
Jesus Christ. Why didn't I know
about this?
Because these minority reports are
destroyed the instant they occur.
Why?
Obviously, for Precrime to function,
there can't be any suggestion
of fallibility.
After all, who wants a justice system
that instills doubt?
It may be reasonable,
but it's still doubt.
Are you saying I've haloed
innocent people?
I'm saying that every so often
those accused of a Precrime
might, just might, have
an alternate future.
Does Burgess know about this?
About this minority report?
I used to joke with Lamar that we were
the mother and father of Precrime.
Well, in my experience, parents
very often see their children
as they want them to be, not as they are.
Answer my question.
Does Lamar Burgess know about
the minority report?
Yes, of course, he knew.
But at the time, he felt, we both felt,
that their existence was
an insignificant variable.
Insignificant to you, maybe,
but what about those people that I
put away with alternate futures?
My God, if the country knew
there was a chance...
The system would collapse.
- I believe in that system.
- Do you really?
You want to bring it down.
You will bring it down, if you
manage to kill your victim.
Why, that will be the most
spectacular public display
of how Precrime didn't work.
- I'm not gonna kill anybody.
- Hold that thought.
Why should I trust you?
You shouldn't. You shouldn't
trust anyone.
Certainly not the Attorney General,
who just wants it all for himself.
And not the young federal agent
who wants your job.
Not even the old man who just wants
to hang on to what he created.
Don't trust anyone. Just find
the minority report.
You said the minority report's
destroyed.
The record is destroyed. The
original report still exists.
I designed the system so that
whenever a report occurred,
it would be stored in a safe place,
but not declared.
What safe place is that?
The safest place there is.
Where is it?
Inside the Precog who predicted it.
All you have to do is
download it, darling.
That's all, huh?
Just walk right into Precrime,
get in the temple,
somehow tap into these Precogs, and
then download this minority report.
- If you have one.
- And then walk out.
Actually, I think you'll have to run out,
but, yes, that is what you have to do.
You're insane.
Or you think I am.
I'll get eye-scanned a dozen times before
I get within 10 miles of Precrime!
Sometimes, in order to see the light,
you have to risk the dark.
As a policeman...oh, excuse me,
as a former policeman,
I'm sure that you know
all sorts of people
who can help you out in this regard.
It's funny how all living organisms
are alike.
When the chips are down,
when the pressure is on,
every creature on the face of the Earth
is interested in one thing
and one thing only.
Its own survival.
Find the minority report.
How do I even know which one has it?
It's always in the more gifted
of the three.
Which one is that?
The female.
Alright, here's where we're at.
Three men in a room.
The victim is here.
John is here. And this unidentified male,
out the window.
Now, the adjacent building
suggests public housing,
but I can't make out the location,
which means...
There's thousands of units like this one.
Yeah, they're everywhere.
But he doesn't go there to kill Crow
for another 22 hours.
Excuse me, this is Chief Anderton's space.
Casey, he's okay.
- You can't sit in his space.
- He's not here anymore.
- He'll be back.
- I doubt that.
- What happened to you?
- It's okay.
In the meantime, I'm betting he's
somewhere in the sprawl.
Anderton's smart enough to go
where electronic billboards
and other media can't ID him
to pick his pockets.
There's fewer consumers there, which
means fewer scanners to target him.
- Why won't he just run?
- Because he thinks he's innocent.
We concentrate on the sprawl.
Do flyovers in shifts with two
spyder teams on the ground.
Thermal scan the entire area,
read anything with eyes and
a heartbeat.
Where is she?
This damn cold!
Don't worry.
You see, I could cut open your chest
and sew a dead cat in there,
you would never get an infection.
Not with the spectrum of antibios
I'll be shooting into you.
That's comforting.
You do understand I can't
just give you new irises.
Please don't touch.
Because the scanners will read the new
scar tissue, alarms will go off,
and large men with guns will appear.
What was that? What was that?
It's anesthesia. It's all gonna
be downhill from...
You always sneak up on your patients
like that?
You wouldn't break the hand of a
violinist before the concert.
Please, relax.
All I'm trying to tell you is that I'll have
to remove your eyes completely.
I know.
And I'll have to replace them
with new ones.
I know that, but I wanna
keep the old ones.
Why?
Because my mother gave them to me.
What's it to you? They're no good
in the secondary market anyway.
Whatever you say. It's your money.
Let me introduce my gorgeous assistant,
Miss Van Eyck.
- This is not a lot of money.
- It's all that I could safely move.
What did you give me?
Smile medicine. Tell you what,
since you and I go way back,
why don't I just give you myold pal
discount? What do you say?
You don't remember me, do you?
- We know each other?
- Oh, yes, we do.
From where? D.C.?
- Baltimore. East side.
- Baltimore?
- Yeah.
- How do we go way back?
Solomon P. Eddie, M.D. I was
a plastic surgeon.
You remember? I specialized in
burn victims, mostly women.
- I put you away.
- Oh, yeah. You did.
You made those tapes.
They were performance pieces.
- You set your patients on fire.
- I put them out!
Some not as quickly as others, but
let's change the subject, shall we?
The future is so much more interesting
than the past, don't you think?
Miss van Eyck, I'm afraid
she's already smitten.
She only has eyes for you.
I know what you're thinking, John.
How can I do what I do now?
Well, let's say that I did spend an awful
lot of time in the prison library.
Now that was a great way
to avoid some of the more unpleasant
aspects of prison life.
Confinement was a real education,
a real
eye-opener.
I mean, for true enlightenment, there's
nothing quite like, well, let's say,
taking a shower while this large felon
with an attitude
you can't even knock down
with a hammer
whispers in your ear, Oh, Nancy.
Oh, Nancy.
Now, that was a lot of fun.
Thank you so very much, John,
for putting me there.
Thank you so very much for
giving me the opportunity
to get to know myself so much better.
And now, to return the favor.
- This your work?
- Yes.
I like it.
Thanks. You take anything
in your coffee?
- Cream and sugar.
- I don't have any cream. Sorry.
Just sugar, then. You and John
ever come here?
- We used to, every summer.
- He's not here now, is he?
I had to ask.
You know, I don't have
any sugar, either.
Thank you.
- He hasn't tried to contact you?
- No.
You ever heard him mention
the name Leo Crow?
No, but then I don't talk to John
that much anymore.
So you haven't seen his apartment?
- That was our apartment.
- Have you been there recently?
It's full of these. How long
has he been doping?
- Since right after we lost our son.
- You mean after he lost your son.
It was nobody's fault.
But John was with him
at the public pool.
You said in your divorce papers
that John tried to kill himself.
It wasn't a suicide attempt.
- I regret ever saying that.
- Then what was it?
The FBI found something that belonged
to my son, a sandal.
Anyway, John was upset. He...
He took out his gun and sat down
and watched his home movies.
- He shot...
- This is all in your statement, Lara.
He shot a hole in the damn ceiling.
So what?
You lose your son, let's see
how well you handle it.
Lamar Burgess thinks you left John
because he lost himself in
Precrime instead of you.
I left him because every time I looked
at him, I saw my son.
Every time I got close to him,
I smelled my little boy.
That's why I left him.
And now you can leave.
Don't take the bandages off
for 12 hours.
If you take them off before then,
you'll go blind. Understand?
In the fridge there's milk, and Greta
made you a sandwich.
Make sure you drink a lot of water.
How do I find the bathroom?
The bathroom? Now that's
your right hand.
The kitchen is your left.
Don't scratch. Never scratch!
Seeing as we're being old pals and all,
I'm going to give you a bonus.
It might come in handy.
This is a temporary paralytic enzyme.
You're gonna shoot this baby up there,
right under your chin.
What is this?
It's gonna turn your pretty face
into mush.
People won't even recognize you, okay?
In 30 minutes, it'll tighten up again,
but it's gonna hurt like nothing
you've ever felt before.
Gonna put this in your goodie bag,
together with your leftovers.
I'm setting up a timer. When
it rings tomorrow,
you can take off the bandages
and get the hell out of here,
- but not before then, or you'll...
- Go blind, I know.
Don't scratch.
A little something from a
mutual friend of ours.
Don't take the bandages off
for 12 hours.
If you take them off before then,
you'll go blind. Understand?
25.16 seconds. That's a new record.
Is that a world record?
Is it a world record? It's a
personal best.
Okay, now I want to time you.
You wanna time me? You gotta
be kidding.
'Cause there's no possible way
I can beat 25.16 seconds.
How long can a whale hold
its breath underwater?
A whale can hold its breath for
about 20 minutes.
- So we gotta beat the whale.
- Okay.
We gotta beat the whale.
Here you go. Now, that's gonna
be 20 minutes.
You sure you don't want to go for
an ice cream or something?
- No.
- Because you know,
- you know I'm going to beat that whale.
- Yeah.
- Okay, give me the count.
- Ready?
- Give me the count.
- Three, two, one, go.
Sean?
Sean!
Have you seen...
Sean! I'm looking for my son.
Have you seen a boy
in a red bathing suit?
Sean!
He's wearing a red bathing suit.
Sean...
Jad, we are now in position and
ready to begin thermal scan
on all residences on North Powell.
I'm thinking you must really like me,
don't you, Fletcher?
That's why you asked to partner with
me on this little sortie, isn't it?
I think you're swell company, Knott.
It's not that you don't trust me to
be alone with the Chief, is it?
That you think I might futz with him
if I had the chance?
No, I just want to watch him use your
body to sandblast another building.
That's all, Jeff. Evanna, go.
I show 27 warm bodies.
Roger that. Confirm 27 warm bodies.
What do you think? Four spyders?
One per floor?
Let's do eight. I gotta eat.
Residents of 931 Powell,
residents of 931 Powell.
This is Officer Fletcher
of D.C. Precrime.
Under authority P.C. Section 6409,
we are deploying spyders
into your complex.
- Go, go, go, baby.
- Mom, I'm scared.
Mommy, I'm scared. Mommy.
Come on, it's gonna scan you. Keep
your eyes open. Just stay still.
Stay still, baby. Open your eyes.
It's okay.
- I don't like it.
- Stay still, stay still.
Come on! You can't just come barging
in here like that! Come on!
You have stepped out on me
for the last time.
I told you where I was!
Now get off my back!
You're a no good liar! I know you
was with that ho last night.
- Leave me alone!
- Get out of here!
We lost one.
Roger that. Maybe it was a cat jumping
through a window or something.
- That's an awful big cat.
- Fletcher.
I'll go check it out.
They're crying their eyes out.
You terrified them. They're absolutely
terrified right now!
You don't want your kids to know terror,
keep them away from me.
Wait a minute. The big cat's back.
What do you guys think, a drunk,
maybe can't wake up?
Yeah, some guy who doesn't
want to get read.
Folks, please be quiet. Close your doors.
Go back inside.
Be quiet and close the door!
We got an ID. It's not him.
Standing down.
Let's eat.
Anderton, wait!
Fletcher, take a look.
There's four people in this room,
not three.
Four? There's Anderton, there's Crow and
there's the man with sunglasses.
Here's the man with sunglasses
outside the window.
There's also someone here,
in the mirror.
Yeah. Definitely female.
The Precrime Program began in the year
2046 with a federal grant.
And now, nine years later,
the District of Columbia is the safest
city in America.
Why? Because Precrime works.
Precrime has eliminated the need
for conventional detectives,
so most of what happens now
is the verification and the protection
of the future victim.
Can we see the Precogs?
Well, the Precogs have
such a powerful gift
that they have to be kept
in peaceful seclusion
so as not to be distracted
from the outside world.
But this display is to give you some idea
of what their daily life is like.
The Precogs get over eight million
pieces of mail every year,
more mail than Santa Claus gets.
Each Precog has their own bedroom,
television and weight room.
It really is wonderful to be a Precog.
My mom's new boyfriend came
over again last night.
He's just not a very intelligent person.
My mom wouldn't let me go upstairs
and eat in my room.
She made me sit down there
the entire time,
having to listen to him go on
and on and on.
Shit! Shit, shit, shit.
Eye-dent, John Anderton.
Approved for entry.
I want to get a new dog.
Which I told her I should be able to do
because I'm so good at taking care
of you guys.
But she thinks that I'll be irresponsible,
which is ridiculous.
No, no, no, no! You can't be in here!
No, no! What are you doing here?
No, no, no, no!
Easy there, old-timer. Who cleared you?
You are not supposed to be in here.
- Listen, Wally.
- Do I know you? Who are you?
I like you, Wally. So, I don't want
to have to kick you or hit you with
anything hard,
but only if you promise to help me.
Hi, John.
Who does that look like to you?
I don't know.
It's Agatha.
He's coming here to get her.
- Are these all of her previsions?
- I'm rewinding her right now.
I don't need to see all these. Just
take me to the Leo Crow murder.
I'm looking. They're not coming out
in any order.
I'm just getting them as she's giving.
Can you see?
- He's inside.
- He's got some kind of mask on.
He sealed the door from the inside.
Shit! Nobody fires a weapon
inside the temple.
Use only bindfoam or your sick-sticks.
Is there another way out of there?
We've got all the doors covered.
There's no way he's getting out.
John, move away from the tank!
Move away from the tank, John!
No, no, no, no, no. No!
No! No, no, no, no, no!
- What does he want with the Precog?
- What do you think?
So he can kill whoever he wants to
without anyone knowing about it!
But there's still the other two.
Wally! Wally! The other two
can still function, right?
You don't understand.
They're a hive mind.
It takes all three for their predictive
abilities to work.
Are you telling me they can't
see murders anymore?
Maybe if he'd taken one of the males,
but Agatha, she's the key.
She's the one they listen to, the one
with the most talent.
She takes care of the other two.
Jesus. Agatha.
Please, bring her back.
Find out where that pipe leads. I want
every team underground, now!
It doesn't matter, he wins.
No, no. I'll send my men to EVAC.
We'll stop him in the reservoir.
Gordon, she's in the room with him
when he kills Crow.
She's already a part of his future.
Jad, put everything you've got
into finding that room,
and we stop a murder.
- How much time have we got, Gordon?
- We've got 51 minutes, 30 seconds.
You cold?
Can you understand me? Are you cold?
The shivers, it's the drugs we gave you.
It should wear off soon.
I'm sorry. I need your help.
You contain information.
I need to know how to get at it.
Can you just tell me who Leo Crow is?
Can you tell me if...
- Is it now?
- What?
Is it now?
Yes, this is all happening right now.
We've gotta take you
some place in public,
which means I've gotta get you
something else to wear.
I'm tired. I'm tired of the future.
Hello, Mr. Yakamoto, welcome back
to the Gap!
How'd those assorted tank tops
work out for you?
Mr. Yakamoto?
Hey, Miss Belford, did you come back
for another pair of those
Shimmy Lace Ups?
If he's ransoming her, where's
the damn note?
It has nothing to do with ransom.
It has to do with the information
that's inside of Agatha.
He's trying to prove his innocence.
But he can't download her without
a lot of technical support.
Well, your average consumer
can't buy any of this stuff
because it's been assembled
and scrounged
from spare parts made to order.
Assuming Anderton ordered this,
who put it together?
Who's Rufus T. Riley?
What's your pleasure?
We got it all here.
We got sports fantasies.
We got what I like to call Look, Ma,
I can fly fantasies,
which encompasses everything
from bungee jumping
to soaring like an eagle over
the Grand Canyon.
We got guys coming in wanting to
experience sex as a woman.
We got women coming, wanna get laid
by their favorite soap star.
Or just some good, clean fun.
Yeah.
It's a big rush, but you come out the
other side without a heart attack.
I want to kill my boss.
Uh..huh. Okay.
You got some images I can work with?
Rufus!
Yeah, being concert master for the
Philadelphia Symphony Orchestra
is one of our most popular choices.
No, no, no. I want to kill my boss.
You sick bastard!
You're the kind of person that makes
this a terrible world to live in!
Detective, nice of you
to come down here,
seeing how every cop in the world
is looking for you right now.
I need your help.
Why did you have to come
all the way down here?
Chief, I make house calls.
You know that.
- I need your help with her.
- Well, hello there, honeypie.
I'm impressed, Anderton.
You're on the lam,
and you still have the time and energy
to slice off a little jerky for yourself.
- She's a Precog.
- Yeah. Okay. She's a Precog.
You brought a Precog here.
Jesus Christ.
- Are you reading my mind right now?
- Get up.
I'm sorry for whatever
I'm going to do,
and I swear I didn't do
any of that stuff I did.
She's got information inside of her.
I need you to get it out.
No way, man. No. I wouldn't
even know where to begin.
Those thoughts about my cousin Elena,
they were just thoughts.
You've been busted twice
for felony hacking.
- So?
- So, I need you to hack into her.
I tell you what. I do this,
I get to keep whatever images
I get from her head.
They don't belong to anybody.
Take her to Radio Shack.
Rufus, you gotta help me.
Agatha, I need to see. I need to see
what's going to happen to me.
And then we'll go.
- Wow. She works.
- Slow it down.
How do I slow this down? I should
hit her on the head?
- Are you recording this?
- Shit.
Yeah, recording.
I know this already.
Come on, move on.
Goodbye, Crow.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
- I...
- Where's the rest of it?
- I guess that's all of it.
Where's my minority report?
Do I even have one?
- Do I have one?
- No.
- What?
What? Agatha, what?
- Can you see?
- See what?
Anne Lively.
You want me to see who killed
Are you recording this?
Yeah, but look, it's pouring out
of her backwards.
I like my life. Everything is good.
They're inside.
Who?
All your old teammates.
Get in, left chamber.
- Hey, close the door!
- Negative!
Thank you, I don't deserve that.
I'm gonna cry.
- You are the man.
- No, you're the man.
- No, you are the man.
- You are the man.
Can you see the umbrella?
Take it!
A man in a blue suit.
He drops his briefcase.
You see a woman in a brown dress.
She knows your face.
Turn in here.
Let's go.
Wait.
- No, we can't stop here.
- You see the balloon man?
Wait.
What are we waiting for?
Wait. Wait.
Wait.
- Please, Mommy, can I have one?
- Alright.
Wait.
Thank you.
- Anybody got an ID? Anybody?
- Negative.
Alright. Scott, Ramos,
take the east end.
Everyone else, follow me.
Let's go.
He knows. Don't go home.
We've got eyes on.
They're working, but they're
standing on it.
- Please! Please! Have you got a coin?
- Drop some money.
Can't you put it in my hand?
May the Lord bless you.
May God take care of you.
Damn!
That's the guy. The man in the window.
Hey. Hey.
- Rooms are $95 a night, plus tax.
- Mind if I look at the registry?
Yeah, I mind.
How about now?
Help yourself.
He's here.
Anderton, leave.
You have a choice. Walk away.
Do it now.
I can't. I have to know. I have to find
out what happened in my life.
Please.
Agatha, I'm not gonna kill the man.
I don't even know him.
- What room is Crow in?
- 1006.
Come on. Come on.
Wrong room.
Leave. Leave.
Oh, God.
This is Sean, my son.
Every day for the last six years, I've
thought about only two things.
The first is what my son would look like
if he were alive today,
if I would recognize him if I saw him
on the street,
and second is what I would do
to the man who took him.
You're right.
I'm not being set up.
You have to take me home.
No. No.
You said so yourself. There is
no minority report.
I don't have an alternate future.
I am going to kill this man.
You still have a choice. The others
never saw their future.
You still have a choice.
- Leo Crow?
- Who the hell are you?
Six years ago, Baltimore,
you grabbed up a kid
at Francis Public Pool in the West End.
Did I? I don't know.
I don't remember anything
about that place.
Who am I? Who am I? Do you know
who I am?
- You're somebody's father.
- His name is Sean!
Sean!
I told him I was a policeman.
I told him I needed his help.
It wasn't so bad. I sang him a song.
I bought him a pretzel.
He was happy. He was happy.
Is he alive? He's alive. Where
have you got him?
Is he alright? Tell me, you fuck,
where is he?
I put him in a barrel. I sunk him
in the bay.
He floated back up.
I took him out.
I was gentle.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm so very sorry.
How could you do that to my...
I'm sorry.
You can choose.
You have the right to remain silent.
Anything you say or do can be used
against you in a court of law.
You have the right to an attorney,
now and during any further questioning.
If you can't afford an attorney,
we will appoint one.
Do you understand these rights?
You're not gonna kill me?
- Do you understand these rights?
- You're not gonna kill me?
If you don't go through with this,
my family gets nothing. Okay?
You're supposed to kill me.
He said you would.
He? Who's he?
I don't know. He called me in my cell.
He told me I'd be released
if I went along,
- and my family would be taken care of.
- If you did what? If you did what?
If I acted like I killed your kid. Okay?
If you killed my kid?
Look, you don't kill me, my family
gets nothing. Okay?
What about the pictures?
They're fake. He gave them to me.
Okay?
Now, listen to me. You...
You tell me, who was it that set this up?
I don't know.
- Come on.
- I'm asking you again.
- Who was it that put you up to this?
- I didn't see his face.
I tell you who it was, and my family
gets nothing.
- Who made you do this?
- Kill me.
- You can do this. Kill me.
- Tell me.
- Kill me. Kill me.
- Give me the gun.
Leo, let go of the gun.
Let go of the gun. It's okay.
Let go of the gun. That's it.
Let go of the gun.
You're not gonna kill me.
- Goodbye, Crow.
- Anderton, wait a...
No!
Hey, did you see it?
Stay back!
What's happening down there?
Murder!
It doesn't make sense.
If you were a child killer, you took
these pictures,
would you leave them on the bed
for anyone to find?
They may have been put away. Anderton
might have found them.
- What kind of cop were you before this?
- Treasury agent. Eight years.
This would be your first
actual murder scene?
Yeah.
I worked homicide before I went federal.
This is what we call an orgy of evidence.
Know how many orgies I had
as a homicide cop, Gordon?
- How many?
- None.
This was all arranged.
Today we saw the first murder in the six
years of the Precrime experiment.
Sadly enough, this failure was human.
The protection team simply didn't get
there in time to stop the murder.
But the murder itself happened exactly
as the Precogs predicted it would.
I think that today's event put a human
face on the Precrime system.
Danny Witwer's on the phone.
He says it's important.
Lamar?
- What?
- Lamar, there's something
terribly wrong. We're chasing
the wrong man.
What?
I don't wanna say over the phone.
Meet me at Anderton's.
We recovered that from
Leo Crow's hotel room.
I remember when I gave this
to him, back in Baltimore.
Please, sir.
Tell me what you have.
This is the murder of a woman
named Anne Lively.
Yeah, John told me about this. You got
this from Containment?
Yes. This is from the twins,
Arthur and Dashiell.
Agatha's stream was missing.
Now this one is from
the cyber parlor.
Anderton downloaded this directly from
Agatha, and Rufus Riley recorded it.
- It's the same prevision.
- Not quite.
Look at the surface wind across
the water. Watch the ripples.
Moving away from shore.
Now the second image.
This is the one from Containment.
It's what Art and Dash saw.
Watch the water.
The wind's changed. The ripples
are moving the other way.
This murder's taking place
at two different times.
According to the Sentry, Anderton
was watching this
at Containment right before
he was tagged.
Well, I know. He came to me, told me
about the missing data stream.
He was concerned that
you might find it.
Well, he was right. I did find it. It was
inside of Agatha the whole time.
So the question is, why would someone
want this erased from the data file?
Danny, just tell me what you're thinking.
I'm thinking someone got away
with murder.
How?
Well, Jad told me that sometimes
the Precogs see
the same murder more than once.
- It's called an echo.
- Jad called it Precog déjà vu.
Well, we teach the techs to
identify them and disregard.
Yeah, but what if a technician only
thought he was looking at an echo?
What if what he was really looking at
was a completely different murder
altogether?
I don't understand.
All you'd have to do is hire someone
to kill Anne Lively,
someone like a drifter, a neuroin addict,
someone with nothing to lose.
Precrime stops the murder
from taking place,
halos the killer, takes him away. But
then, right then, someone else,
having reviewed the prevision and
dressed in the same clothes,
commits the murder in exactly
the same way.
Technician takes a look, thinks he's
looking at an echo, erases it.
Of course, it would have to be someone
with access to the previsions
in the first place.
Someone fairly high up.
Do you know what I hear?
Nothing. No footsteps up the stairs.
No hovercraft out the window. No
clickety-click of little spyders.
Do you know why I can't hear
any of those things, Danny?
Because right now, the Precogs
can't see a thing.
Can you see? It's beautiful.
- Where are we going?
- Someplace safe.
- Burgess.
- Lamar, it's Lara.
- Yes, Lara.
- You have to help him.
- Is he there?
- Yes.
Has he got the Precog with him?
- Keep them there. I'm on my way.
Please. Please don't tell Danny Witwer.
I don't trust him.
I won't say a word.
You just don't let John leave, alright?
He's no killer, Lamar.
I know.
It's cold.
Lara, this is Agatha.
You remember when I would read
Tom Sawyer to you and Sean?
He got so scared when Tom and Becky
were lost in the cave.
I gotta sit down.
I gotta figure this out.
They used Sean.
They wanted me to think
Crow killed him.
But he didn't.
He didn't.
Why would they set you up?
Because I found out about her.
About who?
- How could I not have seen this?
- Seen what?
Anne Lively.
Agatha.
Dr. Hineman once said, The dead don't die.
They look on and help.
Remember that, John.
- Agatha.
- Sean.
He's on the beach now, toe in the water.
He's asking you to come in with him.
He's been racing his mother
up and down the sand.
There's so much love in this house.
He's 10 years old.
He's surrounded by animals.
He wants to be a vet.
You keep a rabbit for him,
a bird and a fox.
He's in high school.
He likes to run, like his father.
He runs the two-mile and the long relay.
He's 23.
He's at a university.
He makes love to a pretty girl
named Claire.
He asks her to be his wife.
He calls here and tells Lara, who cries.
He still runs across the university and
in the stadium, where John watches.
Oh, God. He's running so fast,
just like his daddy.
He sees his daddy. He wants
to run to him.
But he's only six years old,
and he can't do it.
And the other man is so fast.
There was so much love in this house.
I want him back so bad.
So did she.
Can't you see?
She just wanted her little girl back.
But it was too late.
Her little girl was already gone.
She's still alive.
She didn't die, but she's not alive.
Agatha?
Just tell me, who killed your mother?
Who killed Anne Lively?
I'm sorry, John, but you're gonna
have to run again.
What?
Run!
I love you.
- Okay. You're okay.
- No, no.
- You'll be fine with them.
Stay with me. Stay with me.
- John, no.
- Don't talk.
John Anderton.
By mandate of the District of Columbia
Precrime Division,
I'm placing you under arrest
for the murders of Leo Crow
and Danny Witwer.
That's it.
That's my girl.
I was so worried about you.
Did he hurt you?
I missed you so much.
It's okay. Wally's here. Wally's here.
You're a part of my flock now, John.
Welcome.
It's actually kind of a rush.
They say you have visions,
that your life flashes before your eyes,
that all your dreams come true.
This is all my fault.
There was nothing anyone could do.
Lara...
I thought you might want to have those.
I haven't worn this in years. I just wanted
to make sure it fits before tonight.
You look great.
I knew he was having trouble for some
time, and yet I did nothing about it.
Excuse me. The guy from USA Today
is here.
Tell him not now.
- He just wanted a few minutes before...
- Not now!
- I thought you were retiring.
- Well, I was.
But this incident with John made me
realize the fragility of all this.
This is John's legacy as much
as it is my own.
Now I have an obligation
to protect that.
Lara, I know how difficult
this is for you.
But maybe you can find some closure
in the fact that
John finally found the man
who killed your son.
Who's Anne Lively?
- Who?
- Anne Lively.
John was talking about her right
before they took him.
I don't know who that is.
John said something about him being set up
because he found out about her.
- Well, we know why John was tagged.
- He also said Crow was a fake.
And Witwer? He was killed
with John's gun
- inside John's apartment.
- Lamar, do you know the reason
why John came here to work for you?
- Sean.
- Yes.
He came here to work for you
because he thought
if he could just stop that kind
of thing from happening...
- I understand.
- No, I don't think you do.
Sir, they wanna start the press conference
in two minutes.
Lara, John was the best cop
I ever knew,
and, in some ways,
also the best man.
But the scars he carried around...
Well, I know he'd want us to honor the
good things we remember about him.
And I also know why he married you.
You're as stubborn as he is.
Lamar...
Lara, do you know how
to tie one of these?
Could you please give me a hand?
I'm all thumbs, you see.
Listen, I'll tell you what I'll do.
First thing Monday, I'll look over
the Witwer evidence.
And I'll have Gideon run
the Containment files,
see if anyone drowned a woman
by the name of...
What did you say her name was?
Anne Lively.
But I never said she drowned.
- Sir, the press conference is starting.
- I'll be right there.
We'll talk about this later.
Perhaps tomorrow I'll come
by the cottage.
I'd like a word with my husband.
You're not authorized.
How did you get in here?
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, Lamar Burgess,
director of the new National Precrime.
On behalf of your staff, we would
like to present you with this.
- Congratulations, sir.
- My God.
How did you get this?
I padded your expense account
for six months.
Revolvers like this one
were given to generals at the end of
the Civil War by their troops.
The cylinders were loaded with
five gold-plated bullets
to symbolize the end of the destruction
and death
that had ripped the country apart
for five years.
Ladies and gentlemen, with
Precrime going national,
maybe we can all look forward
to a time when none of us
will have to discharge another firearm
ever again.
Now enjoy yourselves. Enjoy yourselves!
That's an order.
Does this mean we can finally use
the lake house on weekends?
I hope so.
Hello. Yes. Right away.
Excuse me. Excuse me. So sorry.
- Sir?
- Yes.
Sir, you have an emergency call
on your private line.
Alright. Thank you.
Yes, this is Burgess.
Hello, Lamar. I just wanted to
congratulate you. You did it.
You created a world without murder.
Sir, everyone wants your name on a hat.
Can you sign these for us?
And all you had to do was kill someone
to do it.
A- room. Jad.
Jad, it's Lara. John needs a favor.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I'm talking about Agatha's mother,
Anne Lively.
Just a junkie who had a kid once
and had to give her up.
But surprise. She cleaned herself up and
she wanted her daughter back.
She wanted Agatha.
Jad, you getting this?
It's a single stream from the female only
with no time or incident data.
Whatever this is, it isn't the future.
It already happened.
The problem was, without Agatha,
there was no Precrime.
She's always been the strongest
of the three.
You knew without Agatha,
you had nothing.
Without her, you wouldn't
be where you are now,
standing there, signing autographs.
Jad, what are you doing?
Jad. Jad, what are you doing with that?
What you up to, big man?
Jad, Jad, let's think before
you send that.
Slow down.
So now you had to get rid of Anne Lively.
You had to shut her up,
which presented a problem.
How can you kill her without
the Precogs seeing it?
Simple. Use a system you control
against her.
So you hired someone to kill her for you,
knowing full well the Precogs
would see that murder.
You lured Anne Lively out to the lake
with the promise of reuniting her
with her daughter.
Where's my daughter?
Where?
Run.
Run!
And then, when you were all alone,
you killed her yourself,
in the same way the Precogs predicted
your John Doe would kill her.
You made the real murder
look like an echo,
knowing the tech would do what he
was trained to do. Disregard it.
Anne Lively became just another
missing person.
So, what are you gonna do, Lamar?
What are you gonna do?
We got a Red Ball!
Think about the lives that little girl
has saved.
Think about all the lives she will save.
That little girl could have saved Sean.
Don't you ever say his name!
You used the memory of my dead son
to set me up.
to set me up!
That was the one thing you knew
that would drive me to murder.
- What are you gonna do now, Lamar?
- How are you gonna...
- Shut me up?
Forgive me, John.
Lamar, it's over.
The question you have to ask is,
what are you gonna do now?
No doubt the Precogs
have already seen this.
No doubt.
You see the dilemma, don't you?
If you don't kill me, Precogs were
wrong and Precrime is over.
If you do kill me, you go away,
but it proves the system works.
Precogs were right.
So, what are you gonna do now?
What's it worth?
Just one more murder.
You'll rot in hell with a halo, but people
will still believe in Precrime.
All you have to do is kill me,
like they said you would.
Except you know your own future,
which means you can change it
if you want to.
You still have a choice, Lamar,
like I did.
Yes, I have a choice.
And I made it.
Forgive me, John.
Forgive me.
Forgive me, my boy.
Lamar!
In 2054, the six-year Precrime
experiment was abandoned.
All prisoners were unconditionally
pardoned and released,
although police departments kept watch
on many of them for years to come.
Agatha and the twins were transferred
to an undisclosed location,
a place where they could find relief
from their gifts.
A place where they could live out
their lives in peace.
SubText: NoRMITA.326