Another hard jolt by Clay...
and once again the cut
over Mountain Rivera's left eye opens up.
Mountain moves away, giving ground,
but Clay lands another left.
Follows it with a slicing right.
A sudden hook by Mountain
drives Clay against the ropes.
He follows it up with a series
of staggering rights and lefts.
The old pro won't quit, even though
his blood's splattered all over Clay.
Now Rivera's left eye is completely closed
as he leans on Clay, barely hanging on.
With time running out in Round 7...
Rivera tries desperately
to get his bloodied eyes in focus.
Get away from him! Get away!
Go back!
Three... four...
five... six...
seven... eight...
nine...
ten.
Doctor.
Come on.
Ladies and gentlemen...
Take him to the dressing room.
Dr. Gilbert will look him over.
...and 13 seconds of the seventh round...
winner by a knockout, Cassius Clay.
Great fight, kid. You were great.
Cassius, when did you really know
you had him?
A guy like Mountain can explode anytime.
I rocked him in the second,
and I figured I had him from then on.
Help me with him, will you?
Thanks a lot, Charlie.
Maish, hang on to him.
Mountain, listen, you're all right,
you understand?
Pretty cute, Maish.
Mountain, be careful.
Be careful, Mountain.
Mountain, listen, you're okay.
You're okay, Mountain.
Yes, boss.
Get out of here.
Sit down.
Mountain, can you hear me?
Mountain, where are you?
I'm in Pittsburgh and it's raining.
You're in New York,
St. Christopher's Arena.
New York.
Yeah, that's right. I'm in New York.
Maish...
this boy's fast, man.
It's okay, pal. It's all over.
Gotta stop him!
Stop it!
He'll be all right.
He'll come out of it all right.
Now put him on the table.
Gently.
You had no business in there, Maish.
- You hungry or something?
- What do you mean, hungry?
In 1952, he was number five.
1952?
When was that, Maish? Last Thursday?
You take a look at the eye.
Now look at this eye.
You see the pupil? You see the tissue?
That's known as sclerotic damage.
The inner structure shows
it could lead to a detached retina.
A couple of good rights to that eye...
you can buy him a tin cup
and some pencils.
Or maybe it doesn't have to happen
that way, Maish.
Maybe some day he'll bang his head
on a bathroom door and bleed to death.
Either way, Maish.
It could happen either way.
No more. This is it.
- What are you talking about, no more?
- No more.
That'll be my recommendation
to the Commission.
I got nothing scheduled for him.
He can rest.
He can rest up the rest of his life.
What's the matter with you?
He's 17 years in this business.
Suddenly he gets a cut
and I gotta put him out to pasture?
It isn't one cut and it isn't suddenly.
It's 17 years of cuts.
- How long do you expect him to go on?
- He looks good in the ring.
He's sharp. Sometimes he's plenty sharp.
He's a pro.
That's probably what kept him alive.
Hey, Doc,
you got any of those ammonia things?
You apply some strips to his upper lid.
You let me know
if there's any change in his condition.
You got any more big, fat suggestions?
Tell him to buy a scrapbook.
Don't fight!
I know, I know, but don't fight!
You okay? Come on now.
Come on now.
Take a good deep breath.
That's right. Inhale.
He stopped me good.
Forget it.
You were beautiful.
He just happened to throw a lucky punch.
Your boy caught it tonight, Maish.
That's very interesting!
My eye feels funny.
Mountain!
He must have caught me good.
You all right now? Come on, let me see.
What's the matter with my eye?
My eye feels funny.
No, don't touch it!
- It's deep?
- Deep enough.
I got a nice clear view into your head.
Go take a shower. You'll feel better.
Take a deep breath.
- I'm gonna go straight in.
- No slipping.
There's something wrong, ain't there?
Something wrong? What's going on?
Where were you when the lights went out?
I lost a boy tonight. Get with it.
- Besides that.
- "Besides that" nothing.
- I saw Greeny giving you the eye.
- I told you to forget it.
All I got to do is go hunting and pecking
and find myself another boy.
- Maybe I'll try a lightweight this time.
- Another boy? What about him, Maish?
Let him do what you did,
become a cut man or something.
Maybe he's lucky at that.
At least he walks away with his brains.
That's more than most.
That's very funny.
Seventeen years. At least he's lucky
if he walks away with his brains.
It's a great sport.
Sport? Are you kidding?
If there was headroom,
they'd hold these things in sewers.
- Come in here. Could you get me a shirt?
- Yeah.
I feel better after the shower.
My eye feels kind of funny, though.
Sit down.
What did he catch me with?
- He caught you with an uppercut.
- Uppercut.
Sucker punch.
That kid, a couple of years ago...
My legs get tired lately.
But I can take that kid.
Maish, I want to fight that kid again.
I want you to get me a rematch.
I got something to tell you.
The doc was in here.
He says you got to quit. No more fights.
What do you mean, I got to quit?
He feels you've had it.
What are you talking about?
You got to quit, Mountain.
You can't fight anymore.
Why? Because I got knocked out?
Don't everybody get knocked out?
Louis, even Patterson?
That's crazy!
All right, maybe I think it's crazy,
but that's what the doc says.
Go fight the Commission.
So you're gonna take
some lousy horse doctor's word?
Listen...
the doc said if you take a couple
more bangs on that left eye...
you'll end up selling pencils.
You got sclerotic damage.
So what do I do now?
A guy's got to do something.
All right, so you do something.
Do something you like.
All I know how to do is fight.
I've been with you guys for 17 years.
Why don't you go back home
to New Mexico or something?
Why, what's back there?
I wouldn't remember nobody
and nobody would remember me.
Maish, maybe we can try
in some other state?
If you don't pass muster
in New York State...
you don't pass muster anyplace else.
You know that.
What about some club fights,
tank towns, unofficial?
You got to face up to it, Mountain.
You can't fight anymore.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Maish...
I'm sorry about tonight.
I'm sorry I lost.
You don't have to feel sorry.
As far as I'm concerned,
you were number one.
That's what you were.
Don't give it another thought.
I took a bath tonight, Maish.
I don't want this complicated.
Don't make no long speech, just tell me...
didn't you phone me
and say your boy wouldn't last...
more than four rounds?
Didn't you make a personal guarantee?
He was up against Clay.
Two rounds, three rounds,
at the outside, four...
but never seven rounds, Ma.
Never seven.
Last question, Maishy.
Didn't you have us put up a bet
for you of $1,500?
And then on your word,
we put up a bundle of our own?
Aren't you gonna pay us back now, Maish?
Certainly, I'm going to pay you.
I'll give you the $1,500.
I just need a couple of months.
This was a bet, not a bank loan.
The bundle, and in cash,
by the first of the month.
Cash for your $1,500, cash for our bundle.
And Maishy...
you had better be ready.
Just one little last reminder,
so Mr. Rennick don't forget.
Wait a minute. Wait...
Yeah?
Hey, Maish. What...
You know, he was worried about you,
you know?
Okay.
I'll tell him.
Okay. All right. 'Bye.
Mountain, that was Maish on the phone.
- Is he all right?
- He's fine.
He hung one on last night.
He's got a head like a balloon.
I was worried.
- He never stayed out all night before.
- You don't have to worry about him.
Where are you...
Where are you going to go first, Mountain?
- No, the one over here, with the circle.
- Right.
"Wanted: Movie ushers.
No exp. Necessary."
- What does it mean, "exp."?
- Experience.
"Uniforms furnished."
- Can you imagine me in a uniform?
- Yeah.
You'll look like a general.
- No experience necessary.
- Yeah.
How much "exp" do you need to "ush"?
The same as a butcher needs to "butch."
Wait, Mountain! Wait!
- Here. That's it.
- Thanks.
- Say, that's a wild tie you got there.
- Yeah.
- Listen. Maybe there's a better tie...
- No, I want to wear this.
Maish gave this to me two years ago
for good luck.
Hey, good luck!
Yeah.
Size 40? Step over there, please.
No. I'm sorry, nothing for you.
Can I see your hands, please?
No, I'm sorry.
38? Step over here, please.
Size 40? Step over there, please.
Size 40.
40? You look more like a 46.
I could probably squeeze into a 40.
No, I'm sorry.
We don't have a uniform your size.
You didn't say nothing
about no sizes in this ad.
- Lf you were looking...
- Mountain!
You're too big for the job.
I like TV better, anyway.
38? Step over here, please.
36? Step over here, please.
Look, George, would I be asking you
unless it was something serious?
Whenever you came to me I had it for you.
I'm in a bind, that's why.
Look, George.
George?
Mr. Oakland?
Wait, where are you going?
- Let's get out of here.
- What do you mean?
- I've been waiting a long time.
- I don't care.
- We got to wait.
- We went to 20 of these places last week.
- Ain't nothing gonna happen.
- This will be different.
There's questions
I don't know how to answer.
If you don't know how to answer it,
you don't answer it, that's all.
- Come on, I'll buy you a beer.
- No, no.
- Mr. Rivera?
- That's you.
- Mr. Rivera.
- Right here, ma'am.
- Room 3, please.
- Room 3.
Room 3.
- Come on.
- No. No!
No.
Sorry, the man...
- Sit down. I'll be with you in a minute.
- He had no business firing me.
Last Thursday, I walked into his office
not five minutes after 8:30...
I'm awfully sorry about the whole thing,
Mr. McNulty...
but our concern here
is finding a job for the applicant.
I've got some rights in a situation like this.
You know, I'm going to have a word or two
with your supervisor.
May I look at your form, please?
Thank you.
Lewis Rivera, age 37.
Place of birth: New Mexico.
Now, your education.
You left that blank, Mr. Rivera.
- Education, you mean like school?
- Right.
Sixth grade.
- Sixth grade. And then you left, is that it?
- That's right.
Now...
past employment record.
You have nothing written down here,
Mr. Rivera.
Who have been your past employers?
You see, all I've been doing
for the past 17 years is fighting.
You know, in the ring.
In the prize ring.
- You mean a prizefighter?
- That's right, a prizefighter.
- A professional prizefighter?
- Yeah, I'm a heavyweight.
That sounds like interesting work,
Mr. Rivera.
Well, it's a living.
- Excuse me.
- Sure.
Miss Miller.
Hello, Cathy.
Yes, I am, but go ahead.
No, I wasn't kidding. I had a lovely time.
Not to me, he didn't.
He was an absolute gentleman.
Well, you know him better than I do.
Cathy, I can't talk now.
What? I didn't hear what you said.
No, of course I won't say anything.
I'll see you. 'Bye.
I'm sorry.
Now, where were we?
Past employers.
- You're a prizefighter.
- That's right.
It would be rather difficult to place you
in any kind of related field.
Well, I need a job,
so anything you've got is okay.
You know, dishwashing...
maybe a bouncer,
or even maybe a day labourer.
But, you see, we have to take
into account past experience.
What else am I supposed to know
how to do besides fight?
See...
Like that question, there.
You know,
"Why did you leave your last job?"
What am I supposed to write down?
The doc...
I mean the doc said, "No more."
He looked into my eyes.
You can't see it, but he looked in and said
one or two more and I might go blind.
- I see.
- I mean...
No! Well, it's just a bum break, that's all.
You know, in 1952,
they ranked me number five?
I'm not kidding you.
They ranked me number five.
That was no easy year, either.
I mean, there was Marciano...
Walcott and Charles still around.
But they had me up there, number five.
And Maish thought that, maybe...
with a little more experience...
Maish? Who's Maish, Mr. Rivera?
He's my manager.
Now, where does that leave him?
That's a nice thing to do to a guy
who's kept you going for 17 years...
and all of a sudden you stop cold on him.
It's not fair to...
I'm sorry, Miss.
I shouldn't have blown up like that.
But, you know, sometimes...
You should kick me out of here, Miss.
Honest, you should.
Well...
as long as we have your address
written down here...
- we'll contact you if anything comes up.
- Sure, sure.
Mr. Rivera.
Right after the war,
I did a lot of work with...
disabled veterans.
- Go on.
- Well, I meant...
I meant you'd be surprised at
the different openings that come up for...
- You mean, for cripples and guys like that?
- No, I didn't mean just that.
I meant for people
who have special problems.
Miss.
Miss, I got no special problem.
To you, I'm a big, ugly slob
and I look like a freak...
but I was almost
the Heavyweight Champion of the World.
Why don't you put that down
on that paper someplace?
Mountain Rivera was no punk.
Mountain Rivera was almost
the Heavyweight Champion of the World.
Mr. Rivera!
Going down.
Will you stop with that "bum-bum"?
I'm trying to concentrate.
Jack of clubs.
Jack of clubs. Gee, the jack of clubs.
That's what it looks like, don't it?
Eight of hearts.
Eight of hearts. That's good to know.
That is very good to know.
All right, stop with that,
"It's good to know."
Everything is good to know to you.
Just play the cards.
I'm going to knock with three points.
You caught me with the store.
I've got two kings, two queens, two nines,
a jack, a ten and two fours.
That's good to know.
What's the matter with you?
He's lost, Maish.
I don't know what to do.
Him and me, both.
Except he's doing it for you, Maish.
Everything for Maish.
Hello?
Yeah.
No, Perelli didn't call yet.
Tell him to call me here. Well, I'm here.
Okay.
You want to lodge a complaint?
Perelli handles wrestlers.
You've got the longest nose
in the business.
So! So!
So, okay.
So, for kicks, Army,
we let the kid wrestle a few.
Not Mountain.
Why not? They pay good for that stuff.
Just like they pay actors.
We could work up a routine for him.
Like Gorgeous George
or that nut on the coast, the Mad Baron.
- What's wrong with it? It's money, ain't it?
- Sure. What kind of money?
What difference does it make
what kind of money? Money's money.
A guy like him
don't take to getting laughed at.
What are you talking about? A guy like him?
What is he, a prima donna?
All of a sudden he's sensitive?
Since when does a guy like him
get sensitive?
- Since we've known him!
- Then you tell me what is for Mountain.
Go ahead, you tell me.
You say he wants to help me?
Well, let him start right now.
But not this, Maish, not this.
We got no time
to give him aptitude tests, Army!
I've run out of time, Army.
I was too busy stitching him up
so he could show the next week.
I was on my hands and knees...
pleading with promoters to use him
so we could get groceries.
Now, I've run out of time to carry
those poor sensitive boys in my lap.
Maish.
You stink.
You wanna know who owes who, Army?
You want to know who owes who?
I'll tell you.
Just check the records.
Look at the wins and losses.
Mountain comes out on the short end.
He owes me.
I figure it's as simple as that.
And what am I asking him to do?
To step in front of a train?
I put it to you, Army,
what do I ask of this guy?
To stick on a costume,
make people laugh a few times?
What is that going to do,
curdle his sensitive insides?
All right, wise guy...
so I'm selling his soul on the street.
You weep for him.
Go light a candle for him.
Maish...
I want to say something, and I want you
to hear me good, understand?
I love this kid
like he was my own flesh and blood.
And if I don't weep and worry for him,
no one else will.
Least of all you. Why? I don't know.
If anything happens to him, you be careful.
You understand?
You just be careful, Maish.
Yeah?
Hello, Ma.
I'm right here.
Don't worry about that.
I'll have the money.
I know what date it is, Ma.
When I make a deal with Ma Greeny,
I keep it.
As a matter of fact, I got something...
Hello?
- Lf I would have hit him...
- Joe Louis would hit you with a left...
Hey, look at this.
- I was looking for...
- Excuse me, Miss...
- unescorted ladies ain't permitted.
- I was looking for Lewis Rivera.
The man at the desk
told me I might find him here.
Lewis Rivera?
The Mountain, you mean.
Excuse me.
Hello, Mr. Rivera.
- Hello, Miss...
- Miss Miller. Grace Miller.
I tried to phone you.
- You're a hard man to get hold of.
- I don't know why...
- They told me at the desk you were here.
- I usually am.
Can we sit down?
Yeah, sure.
Hey, the round's over.
- Take a rest.
- Sorry about that.
That goes on all the time around here.
Maish calls this a graveyard.
He says these guys
spend their time dying in here.
That's not for you, though, Mr. Rivera.
I think you've got a lot of better things
in store for you.
I do?
Have you ever thought
of working with children?
- Children?
- Yes. You know, in athletics.
I never gave it much thought.
Well, I like kids.
- Yeah, I like kids all right.
- They're staffing summer camps now.
I know a couple who run a camp
in the Adirondacks.
They're in town now
getting their people together.
Would you be available if I could set up an
appointment for you to meet them tonight?
Tonight?
They have to leave town tomorrow
and I told them all about you.
You mean, they'll have to see me?
You know, I just got over this fight.
You mean, I'll have to talk to them?
But they're excited to see you.
They're looking forward to it.
I told them you were ranked number five.
You know, you're a hell of a sport.
I mean, you coming in here.
You're a real sport.
Thank you.
- Then you'll see them?
- Sure, if you say so.
How about it, Mr. Rivera,
can I have a beer?
A beer?
- In here?
- I kind of like it in here.
Sure, you can have a beer.
- Hey, Charlie!
- Coming.
- Charlie. Two beers.
- Two beers.
- How about some music?
- Music?
Don't you like to listen to music
when you drink beer?
I never gave it much thought.
Sure, you can have music.
Hey, Mountain.
Play Lover, Come Back to Me.
- Two beers.
- Charlie, how about a glass for the lady?
A glass?
Fancy-shmancy!
That's pretty.
Yeah, it is pretty.
- Them are violins.
- Beautiful.
I don't pay much attention.
I don't have the time.
What is that?
That's music. Just plain old music.
The only music I know by heart
is The Star-Spangled Banner.
- You don't go much to fights, huh?
- No.
They play that before the main event.
There was Smiley Collins.
Who's Smiley Collins?
He was a fighter and he played the violin.
A fighter playing a violin.
He used to play the violin? Seriously?
Real serious.
I don't know about his violin playing...
but he had a right hand,
he could knock down a wall with it.
What about his violin?
He fought Willie Floyd,
and he had 20 pounds on him.
Willie Floyd had 20 pounds on him.
That's okay, keep the change.
They don't get many ladies in here...
that's why Charlie forgot
to bring the glass.
Thank you.
"Drink hearty!"
That's what Maish always says.
Drink hearty, Mr. Rivera.
You think a lot of Maish, don't you?
He's number one.
He was your manager?
Excuse me.
For 17 years.
He's not just my manager.
He's my best friend.
When we were first getting started...
he used to stake me to, you know,
the chow and clothes...
Why aren't you married?
Should I be?
You should be.
You're pretty.
You're not just pretty, you're beautiful.
Thank you.
You know...
I once fought a guy named Jazzo.
Elmer Jazzo.
You know what?
He looked just like my old man.
He was the spitting image of him.
So I couldn't hit him.
So the second round, I go out
and I'm just jabbing away kind of easy...
and all of a sudden...
he comes at me strong.
He's got me up against the ropes
and he's giving me the elbow...
giving me the legs,
and he's biting me, and I just cover up.
I notice every time he shoots his left hand,
he drops his right.
So I go...
I knocked him out.
What?
How's the beer?
Fine.
Mountain.
Them are violins.
Drink hearty, Mountain.
Drink hearty.
It's a garden, ain't it?
Where are the flowers?
Right here.
I've had a real good time.
So have I.
Two beers. My!
When we were coming out of the bar,
I heard Charlie say...
that I had a pretty date.
Thank Charlie for me.
You don't mind
that he thought you was my date?
I suppose in a way I am.
I don't think I've had a real date
in all this time.
I mean, someone...
I liked.
You know...
someone I wanted to be with.
I think that's a compliment.
Yeah.
I feel like I'm walking on eggs.
Why, Mountain?
Well...
you know what my old man used to say?
He used to say, "Lewis...
"when you're out with a lady,
you should act special."
You have.
I've enjoyed this evening very much.
I haven't talked too much, have I?
One thing I wouldn't want to do
with a lady like you, is get out of line.
You've been a perfect gentleman.
You know what?
One thing I'm sorry about...
is that I don't know music.
Why?
Well...
I feel like singing.
There's a cab, Mountain.
Hey, cab!
I'll go back to my place
and phone the Reardons...
and set up an appointment for you
for tonight.
- Then I'll call you at your hotel.
- Sure, fine.
Hey, buddy...
here.
- No, Mountain, please.
- No, it's all right, it's all right.
You take the lady where she wants to go.
When you tell them about me,
don't build me up too much.
Tell them I had 111 fights
and never took a dive.
I'm kind of proud of that.
Of course you are, Mountain.
You must be very proud.
You're somebody very nice.
Thank you.
All right, buddy. Good night.
Hey, Maish, look at this.
Solid.
Where's Mountain?
We're waiting for him.
You know Perelli.
Yeah, I know him.
So where's your boy?
I've been here a half-hour.
He'll be here.
I ain't got all night, Maish.
Maish, I got some great news.
The lady from the employment agency...
she's getting an interview for me
with this guy that runs a camp.
That's very nice,
but wait till you hear about the deal...
All you need to work with kids is instinct.
Dandy! We'll talk about it after.
She says I got to start something new...
on account of I blew my wad in the ring.
I said, "What does a guy like me
know about kids?"
Mountain, I want you to meet Mr. Perelli.
He promotes the wrestling matches
at the Manhattan Arena.
- Glad to see you.
- Likewise.
I said, "What does a guy like me
know about kids?"
- She says, "It's instinct."
- Let's get on with it.
She says, "Instinct."
Mountain, come here. Listen to this good.
It's a beautiful thing.
Sit down, gentlemen.
I think we got something.
Maish thinks you might be a good draw.
Your name's pretty well-known.
I've seen you fight a lot myself.
I think I can wind you up with matches.
It might be worth both our whiles.
Didn't Maish tell you?
I'm not supposed to fight no more.
This has nothing to do with fighting.
I told you, he promotes wrestling.
I don't know how to wrestle.
He don't know how to wrestle,
you get that?
Rivera, you don't have to know how.
Couple of hours, you learn the holds.
Only two things to learn in my business:
How to fake it, make it look real...
and how to land
so you don't hurt yourself.
I don't get it.
What do you mean, you don't get it?
He's laying it out for you.
Maish, you know I've got a funny idea.
We dress you up
in one of them Indian costumes...
with the crazy feathers and everything.
Hey...
we give him a peace pipe,
and he'll blow smoke in the referee's face!
I got it!
We match him off against a cowboy.
You get it? Cowboys and Indians!
I don't think he goes for it, Maish.
What are you talking about,
"He don't go for it"?
What do you say?
Maish, I'd lose you a lot of money.
I can't wrestle.
I don't think I could win a match.
He couldn't win a match! I'll die!
What do you mean?
This whole thing is a setup.
You win one night,
the next night the other guy wins.
It depends on who plays the heavy.
Tank job.
Will you talk sense?
This is an entirely different thing.
- It's part of the game.
- I never took a dive for nobody!
I won 111 fights.
I never took one single dive.
Mountain, it's like Maish says.
These ain't exactly dives.
You guys talk it over.
Give me a ring, Maish.
I got to know definitely by tomorrow.
- I'll call you in the morning, Perelli.
- Sure.
Nice seeing you, Mountain.
I figure you owe me.
What do you figure?
I guess I do.
Then there's no more to it.
Maish...
I was almost
the Heavyweight Champion of the World.
And you'll remember that.
You were almost
Heavyweight Champion of the World...
and I was your manager.
Maish, I'm no stumblebum!
Why do you want to make me out
some kind of stumblebum?
Hello?
Yeah?
Who's calling?
Yes, he's here.
Hang on, just a minute. I'll get him.
Hey, Mountain? It's for you.
It's a Miss Miller.
That's the lady
from the unemployment agency.
Hello?
Hello.
You did?
They do?
The hotel St. Moritz?
I know where that is.
What are their names?
Reardon.
All right.
Miss Miller...
thank you.
Hey, Maish...
that appointment's for tonight.
These people run this camp
in the Adirondacks...
and they want to see me.
Maish...
come on...
you don't have to worry
about no wrestling deals no more.
No matter what I do,
you've still got a third of my action.
My son, the counsellor.
Just make sure those brats don't hit you
over the head with a hockey stick.
Hey, I got to change.
Like you said, you, me and Army,
we're the Three Musketeers.
He wins, I lose.
Go get some sandwiches.
You mean that, Maish?
Can I stop him if he wants
to sit around a campfire?
Get some sandwiches.
Why don't you break open that jug
and we'll have a couple of belts, too?
Have you seen Maish around, Steve?
He left about ten minutes ago.
He says, "I'm sorry, buddy,
but I don't give blue stamps."
That's great.
Look at the birthday cake.
The girls are having a birthday party
and I've got to play host.
Excuse me, please, I'll be right back.
Come back, Jack.
Remember when I was 22?
I remember the night you were 22.
You fought a guy named Rocky Rocco...
and you took him in three rounds.
You were very strong that night.
And how about that birthday party
you gave me?
With the assorted friends.
Yeah!
And you gave me that tie.
That tie.
You're never going to get rid
of that crummy thing, you'll keep it for life.
That's my lucky piece.
Those were the great days.
We travelled first class.
All the training camps were after us,
bidding for us.
You were on your way up.
Waiter! Bring us another.
Hey, look who's here.
Sit down and have a drink.
Mountain...
weren't you supposed to be
someplace by 10:00?
Didn't you have an appointment
someplace?
10:00?
Oh, yeah.
The Reardons, at St. Moritz, that's right.
Never mind. Forget it.
I'll call Miss Miller and cancel
the appointment, make it for tomorrow.
- You are in no shape to go now.
- What do you mean?
- Listen to me.
- I got to go, I got an appointment.
Anybody ever tell you
what a prince of a guy you were?
Mr. Reardon...
there's a gentleman down here.
Says he has an appointment with you.
His name is...
Rivera.
Rivera, sir.
All right, Mr. Reardon, I'll send him up.
They're expecting you, Mr. Rivera.
Room 1006.
Take the elevator across the lobby.
I'm going to be a counsellor
at a boys' camp.
I'm delighted, Mr. Rivera.
It's a big break.
Going up, please.
Tenth floor.
I'm going to see Mr. Reardon.
He runs a summer camp.
You have any boys, lady?
This is my only child.
I like animals.
I like all kinds of animals.
Is that a dog?
Why certainly, she's a champion.
Hey, you a champ?
Thank you.
Listen, I forgot something.
I forgot the...
Hey!
Mr. Reardon!
Mr. Reardon?
Yes?
My name is Mr. Rivera.
Are you Mr. Reardon?
No. Please, go. Get out.
Do you know where he lives?
Mr. Reardon?
Mr. Reardon!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I couldn't see where I was going.
I was looking for someone.
Mountain?
Down, please.
Mountain!
Come in, it ain't locked.
Maish, is that...
Hey, Miss Miller.
- What are you doing here?
- I had to see you.
I tried to follow you when you left.
There didn't seem to be much
to talk about.
I think there's a great deal to talk about.
You want to come in?
Can I take your coat?
Thank you.
Why did you get drunk, Mountain?
Maish and me...
I guess I was kind of scared
about meeting those people.
Maish and me, we had a few,
and before you knew...
I was potted.
You... Sorry.
- Want me to run and get you a beer?
- No, thanks.
Can you guess who that is?
That's me.
You know, Miss Miller...
one thing I'm sorry about is...
I didn't want to make a fool out of you.
That's not the point.
You lost a job tonight.
You threw it away, and I don't know why.
Will you tell me?
I guess I realised...
I was just kidding myself.
I couldn't be no counsellor. Look.
That's my old man I was telling you about.
Your father?
He's a good-looking man.
He was a big guy.
You know, Miss Miller,
about that counsellor job.
That's for them good-looking kids
with white sweaters.
I don't sound so good.
I mean...
I sound like an immigrant off a boat.
Anyway...
I already got a job.
You did! That's wonderful!
I'm going to be a wrestler!
A wrestler?
Yeah. You know.
I put on this Indian chief costume and...
one night I win,
next night the other guy wins.
It's like in the movies.
The good guys and the bad guys.
Is that what you want to do, be a wrestler?
I never figured to wind up like this.
You're ashamed of it.
You're ashamed. Then why do you do it?
I got to do it for Maish.
For Maish.
You do everything for Maish.
You keep him in a shrine.
For 17 years, you've prayed to him
as if he was your personal god.
And now he wants to strip off your skin
until you're chewed to death!
It's not true, you don't know him like I do.
A long time ago, in Scranton,
I fought Marciano on his way up.
He was a tough kid. He cut me up bad.
I was out of shape and he knocked me out.
But as I was being wheeled down the hall
in the hospital, I looked up...
and there was Maish.
He was crying for me.
Do you hear that?
Maish was crying for me.
Because of that, you'll do anything for him?
What's so bad about it?
Wrestling is like fighting,
only by different rules.
Why don't you see yourself as I see you?
Look at me.
Boy, am I ugly.
- You're not ugly.
- What am I, beautiful?
These are scars. They ain't medals.
You know why I talk so funny?
Because I've been hit a million times.
For a while...
you had me thinking...
it could be different.
But, Mountain...
I want you to believe it can be different.
You know...
the time would come when...
The time would come when...
What would you do then, Miss Miller?
I don't know, Mountain.
You better go.
Hey!
Hey, Miss Miller!
You forgot your scarf.
Thank you.
I appreciate your trying to help me.
You understand that it wasn't...
It wasn't...
I was out of line.
I belong with dirty towels in locker rooms.
Oh, Mountain.
- Give me my key.
- Mountain's already up there.
And there's a girl with him. A Miss Miller.
Excuse me.
Are you Miss Miller?
Yes.
And you are?
Maish Rennick.
Do I have a fighter now
or have I got a counsellor?
He's whatever you want him to be.
You got him drunk, and were successful.
He didn't get the job.
That's just too bad.
That's how the world goes, honey.
The rich get richer and the poor get drunk.
Now you can go out
and find yourself another charity.
Charity?
You don't give a damn about him!
But you do?
You're old friends.
All the way back to last Tuesday.
Let me tell you something,
and you'd better dwell on this.
You don't understand the breed.
You think when you put clothes on an ape
you make him a dancing partner.
I'm sorry.
You want to help him?
I'll tell you how you can help him.
Leave him alone.
If you got to say anything to him,
tell him you pity him.
Tell him you feel so sorry for him
you could cry.
But don't con him.
Don't tell him he can be a counsellor
in a boys' camp.
He's been chasing ghosts so long
he'll believe anything.
Any kind of a ghost.
Championship belt.
Pretty girl.
Maybe just 24 hours without an ache
in his body.
It doesn't make any difference.
It all passed him.
I just thought that...
maybe the next thing he wanted,
he ought to get.
That would only be fair.
I wish to God it was something
I could have given him.
You see!
I'll die. I swear to God, I'll die.
He'll knock them dead in that thing.
Where's the photographer?
I've got to get some pictures
of him in that thing!
Hey, Joe!
Maish!
I hear you're in action again.
Maybe we can still do some business?
I want you to meet Maish Rennick.
The wisest man in the business.
I heard you were looking for a fighter.
I can start anytime.
He's anxious, it's a good sign.
- Get out of here.
- All right, don't get hot. Come on, kid.
I'll just take my cut
when the kid starts to work, okay?
You don't have to wear that thing long.
Get into the ring, walk around
a couple of times and you take it off.
Maish, don't make me.
What do you mean, make you?
Am I your father?
You don't do what you don't want to.
If you don't think you owe it to me, okay.
Anything he owes you,
he's paid you back 100 times.
If he wants to walk, let him tell me.
I'd do anything for you, anything.
But don't ask me to play a clown.
You cross me now and I'm dead.
Hey, Indian.
Come on, put on the Indian hair!
We'll take some funny pictures.
I don't want to be no clown!
What are you trying to pull?
He's taking a walk, ain't he?
What is he trying to pull?
You're in deep trouble.
Ma Greeny's going to know about this.
Will you get these guys out of here
and I'll straighten it out?
I'll get them out of here,
but you'd better straighten him out.
Let's go, everybody, out!
You better take care of it.
You better!
I mean it.
My life is on the line.
You cross me now and I'm dead.
Like I told you...
I'll do anything for you.
Anything else, but...
But it bothers you?
It didn't bother you last week...
in the ring, with your hands
at your side for seven rounds...
and let Clay beat your brains out.
That didn't bother you!
It didn't bother you that I had
every last nickel I have on that table...
saying that you wouldn't go four!
Maish...
you bet against me?
Why, Maish?
Why did you bet against me?
Would it have made any difference,
Mountain?
Would it have made any difference...
if I had gone out and hocked my left leg
to bet on you?
You're not a winner anymore.
There's only one thing left.
Let's make some money from the losing.
You fink!
You dirty, stinking fink!
You know, Maish...
in all the dirty, crummy 17 years
I fought for you...
I wasn't ashamed of one single round.
Not one single minute.
Now you make me ashamed!
Where are you going, Hiawatha?
Ma...
punchy's gone wild.
Listen, Greeny...
if this punk don't show,
Maish, you don't get paid.
That means you're out in the cold, you dig?
So what did you do?
You beat up two bums?
That ain't going to help.
I got a whole regiment.
And what did you win for Maish,
an extra eight minutes?
Get these bums out of here.
I'm going to see to it you don't get
a license to walk a dog from now on!
You don't think I will? Just try me!
Maishy, darling...
take a good look at yourself
in the mirror...
then say goodbye to what you see.
Where do you want it, here or in the alley?
Let them do it slow, Ma.
Let them do it nice and slow.
I want to watch.
Come on, Maish.
Hey, Perelli...
pay that lady off.
For what? Your good looks?
I pay cash for services rendered,
and so far you ain't rendered nothing.
Put me on next.
You mean you'll go?
Eight matches, starting tonight?
- With an option for 16 more?
- Yeah, sure. Anything you say.
Makes me happy.
Now everybody's happy.
Have a good match, boys.
I owe you, Mountain.
I owe you for this.
I swear I'll pay you back.
We don't have to break up now.
We'll get that kid.
He's a good, fast kid.
Army, you saw him.
We can make a champ out of this guy.
The three of us.
Be partners like we used to be.
Make a lot of dough.
The kid could be a champ.
He could take over where you left off.
Look, I like you guys.
Mountain.
Army.
Don't let it break up like this.
What do you say, Mountain?
Army?
Mountain?
Next match. Two out of three falls.
From Morrilton in Arkansas...
weighing 620 pounds, Haystack Calhoun.
And his opponent, weighing 196 pounds...
former heavyweight contender,
Big Chief Mountain Rivera.
Mountain, don't forget this is make-believe.
Don't get carried away and belt him out.
Come on, Mountain,
get this show on the road.
Come on, Mountain.