THE RESTLESS
(Subtitle: Ninjutzu)
In the be ginning of mid school
I wrote a list of my dreams.
Many kids,
a house by the sea...
World peace, family...
Me a gainful work...
Not to hurt any one...
A woman to love,
to be happy...
It's been a while
since I wrote the list.
Some dreams have come true,
some haven't. Some don't matter.
My life's empty.
Nothing feels like any thing.
I feel nothing.
The passenger is ok.
-Does it hurt?
Am I going to die?
-No.
Can you move your legs?
Your hands?
What happened?
-His heart. He fainted.
Sinus rhythm.
-Good. No panic.
Excuse me.
Would you like to fuck me?
-Yeah.
See you.
It's alright, Mother.
I'm here.
Score!
What's up, pretty boy?
Oh, shit! Stop it!
I'm gonna puke!
Don't bother
taking off the condom.
We've got the same VD's.
Some mornings I feel empty.
Someone said
you get used to anything.
I was okay,
but I was hoping for a change.
Hey hey!
Sorry, I shouldn't laugh.
You can borrow my towel.
-No thanks. I'm almost dry.
No, take it. It's clean.
Thanks.
I'm Ari.
-Tiina.
Pretty warm
for this time of the year.
Thanks for the towel.
-No problem.
Would you like some coffee?
If you're not in a hurry.
No...
I'm not in a hurry.
Typical...
What do you do,
besides fixing girls' bikes?
I go to work.
-What do you do?
I'm a doctor. -I'm working on
my Master's thesis. On literature.
What do you do for fun? -I go
to movies, sometimes to a bar.
With your friends?
-I live here.
Are you sure it's not
too much trouble? -Yeah.
This won't take long.
Nice place. -I've only
lived here a little while.
My place is dumb.
It's ok ay, really...
Thanks for fixing my bike.
No one's ever done
that to me before.
What's this?
-It's a long story.
Who are you calling?
-You're calling me.
What are you thinking about?
-My Mom.
She's dying.
It could take weeks or months.
I don't get it. How'd it happen?
I just went for it.
He's a doctor.
Did you score?
-Twice.
Was he good?
-Take a guess.
Are you still going on about
the gigolo on the beach?
And you tamed him?
-Stop it. He's a regular guy.
Really cool that you made it.
Doctors are usually so stuck up.
You're not.
Go on, answer it.
-No.
Is it an old flame?
-Kind of.
How come you don't answer?
Is she an ugly cow?
No, I just never date.
In a minute!
Never?
-I don't want to hurt any one.
Dad!
Attack!
Smile!
Look over there.
Is this an 8?
-Yeah.
Hi! We have news for you.
-We decided to get married.
Congratulations!
Look, my colleagues
gave us this game.
''Test your relationship.''
-Let's play.
We're five.
You need even pairs.
Let's play cards instead.
Any cards in the boat?
Stop it!
There's still some left.
Answer!
Why don't you date occasionally?
Just for the hell of it.
The skins are the best.
How come?
-They're good for you.
What's your sign?
-What's yours?
Didn't God give us
a wonderful gift?
God gave us the gift of sex
as part of marriage.
Thousands of young people
have made a commitment -
to abstain from sex
before marriage. Join us.
True love waits!
-Thanks.
Do you want some dry clothes?
-A dress would be nice.
How about this?
-Let's see...
I made some coffee.
I really like to be with you.
-But what?
Are you spoken for? Married?
-No.
Gay? You have aids?
Then we're okay.
-I don't feel anything.
What?
-Nothing at all.
Don't you like me?
I'll make you unhappy.
Let me worry about
my happiness, okay?
I have to go.
-You're not going any where.
More...
Morning!
-You can tell he's got a new girl.
Doesn't let him sleep!
You'll soon be on vacation.
You can tend to
her night and day then.
Did she give you a blow job?
Did she give you a blow job,
blow job...
Did you use a condom?
Did you do it doggy style?
Sorry.
-Again. You could've called.
I am sorry.
-Yeah, right.
I'd love to do this
when I'm old.
Give me candy.
How long has it been?
-Three weeks.
Should we check him out?
And try him out.
-Don't stay long if you do.
We won't come.
We've seen it all before.
You haven't seen him before.
What if he's not home?
-Leave the cake outside his door.
Does my ass look big? -You have
the prettiest ass in the world.
Is this too romantic?
-Go on!
Congratulations!
Why?
-It's your birthday.
Do you have coffee?
-Wait...
Hello.
-Hi.
Well, you two can have the cake.
-Thanks, but I really have to go.
She's Päivi.
I hope you're not allergic
to almonds. -No.
Have fun.
Does she mean something to you?
-No.
Do I?
-I don't know.
I told you this would happen.
-Oh, you said so.
Then it's okay, right?
I was warned.
Do you care?
-I do.
Do you want to be with me or not?
-I can't.
Fine, whatever...
-Tiina!
I want all of you!
Let me know
if you change your mind.
Change your stupid mind, you idiot!
Sorry.
-It's okay.
Better it should happen now
than after 15 years of marriage.
He's not worthy of you.
-It's not that simple.
He's not totally bad.
-Yeah, right!
How come you ain't dancing?
-I rarely dance.
You're not thirsty, either?
I could be.
Come in.
This is Pera.
This is Ari.
Did you mean to fuck my wife?
Yes.
Go ahead, then.
Don't just fucking stand there!
Never mind him. Come on.
Why are you doing this?
-Come here.
You'll make a fine husband
for someone.
A man can kill his own dog, right?
Was she a good fuck?
Hi.
What happened to your head?
I changed my mind.
Sit down.
Careful now.
Hello! This is Ari.
Stig. -Ari.
I'm Riku.
I'm Ilona. Nice to meet you.
-Like wise.
Hanna-Riikka owns the boat.
Ari's a doctor.
-I knew it.
I knew you'd say that.
It's harder to guess in advance.
-Not if you know how to look.
Can Ari guess what
I'm studying? -No.
There's a psychologist,
an archaeologist -
a priest and an economist.
-And one autistic person.
And one literary historian.
-Midsummer of the nerds.
Literature -
economy, archaeology -
psychology.
Psychologists are quiet.
Priest or autistic?
Priest.
-Pretty good!
You got the archaeologist and the
psychologist wrong. -No big deal.
I've never understood
her weird jokes.
Score!
-I've never called a 999-number.
You'll catch up.
I've never ordered red wine
in a restaurant.
I've never eaten shit.
-Yuck!
Zero points.
Why would any one do that?
I've never used a seat belt.
Score.
I've never met
this wonderful Ari before.
My points never count!
M... I... D...
..S... U... M... M... E... R,
Midsummer!
Happy Midsummer!
Let's party!
We're done with traditions now.
What's the tattoo?
-I lost a bet when drunk.
I've never lost a bet.
-Score!
It's a game called ''I've never''.
If you've never done something
all others have, you get a point.
The biggest wimp gets points.
-Or the smartest.
The wimp, that is.
-Fine.
Try it.
I've never hit a woman.
-Me neither.
Did Tiina tell you?
-Tell me what?
I hit Ilona once. I was drunk.
I've never regretted
anything so much.
I've never heard about it.
You get a point.
-Congratulations, your first!
I've never believed in God.
Point for Riku. What does Ari say?
I've never used drugs.
-Me neither.
I've never swallowed sperm.
-Yuck. Who has?
I've never
broken a bone in the Alps.
I've never cursed
in front of my Dad. Or Mom.
I've never bought tax-free beer.
-Unbelievable. Point.
I've never drank
a whole cup of coffee.
Incredible. Point!
I've never been
any one's only best friend.
I've never gotten breakfast in bed.
I've never seen my Dad.
I've never cried in front of
someone as a grown-up.
Me neither.
I've never been this happy.
-Accepted.
I've never...
Go on.
I've never been in love.
I've never liked Midsummer.
What's wrong with me?
Nothing.
I always fall for the wrong guys.
You just don't feel wrong.
I'll bet he's not around
in a few weeks.
Bullshit, he's a good guy.
You're always judging people.
It's unfair.
I have a right to do so,
I'm a priest.
Hey, I'm joking!
-Which part was the joke?
The bottom.
You know what?
I've got flowers
under the pillow.
Look.
I'll dream about
my future husband now.
Did you throw?
-Hit in the side.
Come to papa!
You sure slept long.
-Can I help?
You can wash the potatoes.
-I'll do it.
Watch out for snakes.
Are you having fun?
-Sure.
I've never been in love either.
-That messes up the scores.
No, really.
Why are you with Stig then?
-Why are you with Tiina?
Maybe you just get
used to having someone.
We're getting married in the fall.
Love is not all that matters.
-No.
Then again, how would I know?
-You don't.
Dinner time!
Come and eat!
Bread and wine.
Will you say a prayer?
-No.
Why did you want to be a priest?
-Why did you want to be a doctor?
Nice job. Good money.
-Blood and bowels.
Are you specialized?
-He's an ambulance doctor.
Ambulogist.
-I wanted to be a paediatrician.
Do you want to help kids?
Isn't it obvious?
I used to think so, I guess.
-People spend 90 % of their time -
continuing with something
they once started.
Someone said that.
-For me that's 100 %.
Why? Do you think there's
anything good and true in life?
The right answer is Jesus.
Christianity is the
whole damn answer for me.
What is it to Ari? -Not all
people believe in something.
Yes they do,
or they're not human.
I must be a monkey then.
Did you lock up?
-Oh, me? I guess so.
Is my jacket there?
-Yes.
Mom...
Mom.
This is Tiina.
She can hear us.
Sorry I'm late.
-For a change. Where's Ilona?
I don't know.
Did she call? -No.
They cancelled my study grant.
I can't pay my rent anymore.
Can't you move to Ari's place?
-I don't know what he wants.
Ari speaking.
Hi.
Didn't you go to the concert?
Yeah, I'm interested.
Hello. -Hi.
Nice room.
Do you want a drink?
-Do you?
I wasn't sure you'd come.
-Well, here I am.
Second thoughts? -No.
This doesn't make any sense.
-Should it?
Is Tiina on top when you fuck?
Do you like that?
Do you feel good?
-Yeah.
Here you go.
Dry your pants.
Hi. -Hello.
It was a great concert.
Too bad Ilona missed it.
You have juice? I'm thirsty.
-Yeah, help yourself.
I brought you coffee.
You're beautiful.
I've been thinking...
Do you want to get married?
-What?!
Would you like to marry me?
Would you?
-I asked you.
I'm not against it.
-That's no reason to get married.
Do you want to?
-I'm asking you.
I feel stupid.
I just want to be with you.
You can move in here if you
want to. -Do you want me to?
I've got nothing...
-Don't say that!
What do you want?
It hurts me when you don't talk.
I can't move in with you
if you don't care.
Looks like I lost the bet.
I made a bet that your
thing wouldn't work. -Sorry.
It's okay
as long as Tiina wins.
At least I'm moving in here
in record time.
What time is it?
Seven.
Do you like me touching your ass?
I think it's fun.
-Good.
Hello.
-Hi.
We're going out.
I'll just take a shower.
Did you go to the store?
-No. I'll go later.
How are you?
-Good.
Tiina's unhappy.
-How so?
She's not showing it to you.
-She does to you?
I can tell.
She's my best friend. I love her.
You're not serious with her.
You pretend.
Or maybe you're scared.
Isn't every one?
-No.
Are you serious about Riku then?
-Yeah.
But that's different.
-Why?
Because we're talking
about you and Tiina.
What do you want me to do?
-Think logically.
Why logically?
I don't care if you think with your
dick, but Tiina deserves happiness.
You should know that happiness
doesn't need to be deserved.
There are different views within
the church. -What's yours?
That happiness
doesn't need to be deserved.
You'd be easier to hate
if you weren't so smart.
The doctor checks the ear.
It's fine.
-Good.
Time to fight the dragons!
This is good practice for you.
When's the wedding?
You've gotten a ring,
haven't you?
Something's bothering you.
What is it? -I don't know.
Am I too pushy?
Should we split up?
Are you happy?
About what?
-Everything.
No. I don't know
what to do with Stig. -Marry him.
Sure, we're doing just fine...
What am I to you?
A friend.
Who's available, right?
What was that?
-I'll start again.
You blew it. I slapped twice
and you continued.
No, I didn't.
-Yes, you did.
Take your hand off!
-Are you gonna hit me?
Ilona!
She hates everything about me.
-Sit down. This is an island.
At least she won't run
to another guy.
Except for the trolls with five-foot
dicks. -We weren't supposed to tell.
If your friend was cheating
on his partner, would you tell?
It's their business.
-Whose?
Their. -How can it be their business
if only two know about it?
Let every one deal with
their own lives. -Forget it.
Let's finish the game!
You still got only one hand!
Shall we play?
-What?
The truth game. We ask 3 questions
and the answer has to be the truth.
What if you lie?
-We don't lie.
One: why are you with Tiina?
-I want her to be happy.
Two: why are you
fucking Ilona then?
Three, was I right?
Ilona is nice.
-Are you nice?
That's the fourth question.
-Liar.
I don't lie much. Tiina doesn't know
and she doesn't need to.
But I do and it hurts.
Soon you'll be hurting, too.
It'll hurt e very time
Tiina touches you -
and every time you screw Ilona,
you'll be thinking of Tiina -
who thinks you're at work
or something.
Do they teach that to future
priests? -I'm self-educated.
I learnt my lesson
a long time ago.
Are you happy?
-Irrelevant.
My turn. Are you happy?
-No.
I knew it! -Do everything right
and you'll feel fine.
If you do everything wrong,
you'll feel bad. -Stop it.
Girls always fall for
such god dam cowards!
Including you?
My second question.
We're like a family.
Don't fuck it to pieces.
Hey.
-Hi.
Don't ruin others' relationships.
-I'm tired of your bullshit.
Wait, let's talk about it.
-What?
Let's talk. -Go fuck yourself,
you hypocrite dyke!
What do you wanna do?
-This makes no sense.
I want to end this.
-Okay.
It's not what you think.
We just...
Go on, get out.
I should hit you in the face.
-I'd better go.
Is this a ringing in my ears?
This wouldn't happen
if we had a sex life.
Hello.
-You're late.
Why didn't you tell me?
I didn't wanna hurt you.
-What?!
I warned you.
-Stop saying that!
I've just moved in.
This is me!
You don't love any one!
Go fuck my best friend,
but don't fuck me after that.
What are we gonna do now?
Go to hell!
And don't come back,
you bastard!
You bastard...
How's Tiina?
She took it pretty bad.
-So did Stig.
This can't be forgotten.
I hope he'll forgive me.
I'd like to try again.
It's best we don't see anymore.
Take care.
We had fun, didn't we?
Yeah.
See you!
You sure it's okay
I spend the night?
Sure. I can't sleep.
I'd kill my self if I dared.
-Stop that.
I'm the biggest asshole in town.
How's your vacation?
Awful. I've been drunk all day.
-Why?
Pia's been mad.
-About what?
About the drinking.
Now she's gone for good.
She's not gone.
She's out back, sulking.
Really?
-Yes.
You mean that?
Do me a favour, go get her.
-What do I say to her?
Tell her to come back.
-Why don't you go?
You have a way with women.
You know how to talk to them.
Do you want me to shoot her?
-No.
I just don't want to keep it here
when I'm alone.
And hey...
Get me more beer, too.
Come on.
-Why should I?
Because Roope loves you.
You don't know what it's like.
-To be in love?
To have kids.
-No, I don't.
Please, don't do that.
Let's see...
The result is positive.
-What does that mean?
You're pregnant. Congratulations.
Thank you.
It's a big change.
-Yes, it is.
Hey.
I just called because I haven't
heard from you in a while.
Where do you live now?
-Nowhere, really.
That's too bad.
-Yeah.
When are you going back?
-I don't think I can.
But it's your place.
Have you called her? -No.
You can stay with us until
you get your things sorted out.
What will it be?
-Two beers, please.
God bless.
-Hi honey.
Ari!
What's up?
-Just watching TV.
No beer for me?
-I'll get you one.
Where's the spare key?
Ari will stay here a few days.
I can't remember.
What's a few days?
-You won't be here!
I don't trust him.
-You're wrong.
Hello.
Where's Riku?
He went to a congress.
He'll be back in a few days.
Does it bother you that I'm here?
Want some tea?
-No.
Why is everything so complicated?
-I don't know.
What do you want?
-I don't know, sex.
I'd like to find the answer.
To which question?
-I don't know. All of them.
What are you doing?
-What are you doing?
Completing the series, huh?
-No.
Next you'll be touching
Riku and Stig. -I doubt it.
Are you serious?
I'll be damned...
You don't care about me.
Yes, I do.
-''Yes, I do.''
May I kiss you?
-Shut up.
Shit...
You only fuck your
friends' girlfriends, huh?
I didn't force any one.
-Good night.
This is my childhood hero,
uncle Fedja.
A serious boy
who left home when he was eight.
He sits on my shoulder now.
I see.
Don't get any ideas, ok?
-What?
Last night meant nothing.
I just tried it out.
To measure up with my friends.
What happened?
-Nothing.
You were
quite a disappointment.
Now get the fuck out of here.
Hello. -Hi.
I came to get some stuff.
I've been trying to call you.
It's important.
They called last night.
Your Mom's dead.
I see...
"Merry Christmas, Ari. Dad."
I should become forting you.
-I should get a place.
You already have one.
Just move in. -Where will you go?
I'll stay until I find a place.
I'll sleep on the couch.
You're confused, Tiina.
I don't want to be alone.
Find another guy.
You've only known Ari for 3 months.
-It's not that simple.
Cut the bullshit.
-What bullshit?
What's wrong with you?
-Nothing.
I need you on my side.
-It's not gonna work out.
You know that too.
You always tell people
to love and to believe.
I do like hell.
Don't curse in here.
Fuck you.
The body that is sown is perishable,
it is raised imperishable.
Jesus is resurrection and life.
Good night.
-Good night.
What if I came over there?
Go ahead.
No strings attached.
I missed you.
I don't know. It hurt really bad.
I'm really sorry.
A toast to us!
Ilona and Stig are still together.
The y're getting married.
Hanna-Riikk a
will perform the ceremony.
I'll be Ilona's bridesmaid.
We have made up.
Where are you going?
-Out for a while.
Hi.
-Hello.
I'm sorry about your Mom.
-Thanks.
Do you wanna get wasted?
Sure...
Can we join you? I'm Erja.
There's a party at the
nursing school. Interested?
Yeah, because... I'm sick.
Go fuck yourself.
-I just wanna talk.
Let's share a cab, I'll pay.
-But I've moved.
Where?
-I've moved alone.
Hanna-Riikka left me.
Why don't you answer my calls?
Because I can see who's calling.
It's weird that my best friend's
boy friend calls me at night.
I'm not with Tiina.
-Don't lie to me.
How are you?
-Good and bad.
Why do you ask?
Why did you leave Riku?
I wanna do
what's right in this situation.
It seemed
the right thing to do.
Why?
-Why?
Don't...
Do you think you could love me?
You'd have to change.
Did you have fun?
You're a little late.
I've been thinking...
I should have said this before
but I didn't know how.
I think...
-Ari.
I'm pregnant.
-What?
We're having a baby.
I know what you are.
But I love you any way.
I'll be a good mother.
I want this child.
I can care for it alone.
We can live together,
as friends.
I won't ask any questions.
You live your life and I live mine.
We'll take care of the child
together.
We don't have
to be like every one else.
I'd like to stay
if it's OK with you.
We can give it a try.
-I want to be a father to the kid.
Look how small it is!
Nice to work with you again.
How was the holiday? -Okay.
I'm glad it's over.
I got sober again.
Things are better at home.
How are you doing? -Okay.
You can be saved
from meaningless sex!
You, too, can find true love.
True love waits.
Let us pray.
Black humour.
I could come late.
Oh, call Riku.
Congratulations. You're
going to be a dad. -Thanks.
I didn't tell Riku anything,
you know.
I think about you all the time.
You missed the train.
-Right.
Hanna-Riikka! Are you coming?
See you in hell.
I know where we are.
The smell is so bad.
Fuck, did you get us hookers?
-You'll see.
Is it human or animal?
It's hard to tell...
-If it's a lamb, I won't fuck it.
What a surprise...
Let's move on.
It's a big change.
I'm glad I didn't hit you.
I've learned something about life.
I used to take things for granted.
I should thank you.
-You're welcome.
I'm proud of not hitting Ilona.
Tell us how you feel, Ari.
-Let's forget all this.
Is this the end of the party?
We could come up
with something else.
Ari, you're a real bastard!
Have fun!
-Shit, no... guys!
Don't leave me!
This is not funny!
I'll be...
Bulls eye!
Come on in, girls.
-We can go to a hotel.
We won't hurt you.
Are you a hockey star or something?
-Yeah. Come, I'll show you.
I know all the right people.
Stig, tell me something.
How old are they?
They said they were 16.
Are you happy?
-At the moment, no.
Shit! I've got hair in my mouth.
Well, maybe 80 % happy.
Or 78.5 %.
Ari, would you be my best man?
Isn't Riku the best man?
-Let him take care of the music.
Our marriage
is more your department.
A friend gave it to me
to throw away. -Never!
You can have it
if you promise not to shoot any one.
Wake up!
Turku is a great place
to live and prosper.
We had fun.
Ilona was quite drunk
and Hanna-Riikka puked.
How about you?
-A small party.
Stig asked me to be his best man.
Good. We can plan
the wedding together then.
Will the guests fit into one boat?
-Hope so.
Did you invite
any of your colleagues?
Don't exhaust yourselves,
tomorrow's a big day.
You're not putting all that?
-Count your own rice.
Who, me?
Are we gonna be like this
when we're 60?
Let's play. I've never
kissed a woman. -Score.
I've never liked being single.
-Me neither.
I've never worn a seat belt.
You've said that before.
-Not on this trip.
This is boring,
nothing new comes up.
I've never had an orgasm
during intercourse.
That's settled then...
Let's continue.
No one has to do anything.
-Can we at least try?
I'll do it.
I wouldn't go to Iceland
on my honey moon.
It must be cold out there.
This is wonderful.
It'll take a while
before the sauna's ready.
I like mild heat.
-It's really mild.
Where are the others?
-At the store.
How does it feel to become a dad?
-Weird.
It's hard to imagine.
I want you one more time.
Tomorrow I'll be a decent wife.
In the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Ghost.
We are gathered here -
for the wedding of Ilona and Stig.
I've known them both
for a long time.
We'll stop here.
Why are you doing this?
-I don't know.
Till death do you part?
I do.
In the presence
of this congregation -
I ask you,
Ilona Helmi Ilmarinen -
will you take
Stig as your husband -
to love and cherish
till death do you part?
I do.
With the powers vested in me -
I pronounce you
husband and wife.
In the name of
the Father, the Son -
and the Holy Ghost. Amen.
Well done, Tiina!
Any unmarried men?
Come here.
Someone could propose to me now.
I'd like to talk to you.
-Now?
We're fooling ourselves.
We can't live like this.
I agree.
I think we should be together.
I think we shouId split up.
-Why?
I can't do it.
Yes, you can. I love you.
I'll be there for the baby
but I can't live with you.
I don't love you.
I see...
Don't drink.
-Don't talk to me.
Did you have fun with Ari?
Go home if you can't behave.
-Slut!
You don't know
what you've done!
I know what you've been
doing behind my back!
Knock knock.
-Who's there?
Oh, it's postman Petskin.
I brought you something.
Why are we here?
Stop shooting, will you?
Stig...
Give me the gun.
Fuck, let's drink
to Ari the hero!
To the best man who
fucked the bride yesterday.
And our sacred priest -
who fucked my man!
A preaching whore!
Aren't you ashamed?
Stop!
What?
-Stop.
Sometimes you have
to go far to see clearly.
Take some distance.
Every thing's still unclear,
but in a different way.
People fear death.
They don't want to face it alone.
But we are still alone.
It's just nicer
to be alone together.
Let's drink some water.
Any questions?
How high is the church?
Can any one guess?
-Me!
130 meters.
-No.
500 meters.
-Look carefully!
Come on, let's play.
-Are you sure?
Yeah.
-Go on, play.
Good morning.
We'll continue
with yesterday's theme -
the importance of the sagas
in archeology.
Translation: Ella Hagfors & Miira Lähteenmäki
Subtitle: Ninjutzu