For unexplainable reasons
my son Ken-ichi and l
have been estranged for 10 years.
There is a profound chasm between us
which hurts me deeply.
I want us to be close again.
I have learned that
Ken-ichi is in the hospital.
His wife Rie has asked me to visit him.
She has suggested to me
that it would be an opportunity
for Ken-ichi and I to speak to each other
and to improve our relationship.
Hence I have come to Tokyo.
You must be surprised at the changes
in Tokyo over the past 10 years.
Ken-ichi has been unwell for awhile.
He's suffering from stomach pain.
It often disturbs him at night.
He hasn't been diagnosed yet.
Excuse me.
Give me a moment.
I'll tell Ken-ichi you're here.
He doesn't know that you've come.
Father is here to see you.
Why don't you let him in?
He's come a long way to see you.
Why should I see him?
Who asked him to come?
Did you?
I never said I wanted to see him.
Please don't talk like this.
Enough, I don't want to see him.
Father.
Please wait.
Father
he's sick and in great pain.
Don't take his words to heart.
Forgive him.
Let me talk to him.
This tape
was made by Ken-ichi in China.
It was broadcast as part of a TV special.
Please have a look at his work.
Make sure you watch it.
Please.
Mr. Takata, it's ready.
Thank you. Would you like a drink?
No, thank you.
I have another appointment.
Do you know how-to use a VCR?
Yes.
Let me introduce
an expert in oriental folk arts
Mr. Ken-ichi Takata.
He is widely published on the subject.
We have some footage
shot by Mr. Ken-ichi of a mask opera.
This opera originates from Yunnan Province.
This is Mr. Ken-ichi Takata
from the faculty of Oriental Folk Arts
at the University of Tokyo.
He's here to see you perform.
Thank you.
This is Mr. Li Jiamin.
He's our lead singer.
This is amazing.
You are incredible.
He says you are incredible.
I could be better. I have a cold today.
Come back and I'll perform
Riding Alone for Thousands of Miles.
I'm not familiar with this particular opera.
It's a mask opera about Lord Guan.
Oh...I see...the Lord Guan...
from the story
The Romance of the Three Kingdoms?
He actually knows
who Lord Guan is.
Riding Alone for Thousands of Miles
is the greatest of all mask operas.
I'm the greatest singer of it.
Then, this is a rare chance.
Can't you sing a little for me now?
My voice is not up to it today.
Ken-ichi is leaving China tonight.
Then, some other time.
It's a deal.
I'll come back to Yunnan next year.
I promise you an unforgettable performance.
How's the catch today?
Nothing much.
This is Takata.
Father
I've been calling and calling.
Have you been fishing?
I've received Ken-ichi's diagnosis.
Cancer of the liver.
It is terminal.
I haven't told Ken-ichi yet.
I don't think...I have the courage.
He thinks
he will be discharged soon.
I've always hoped...in my heart
that our family could enjoy a meal together
Father
Ken-ichi
and l.
Now I'm not sure
that's going to happen.
I need to find
the singer Mr. Li Jiamin.
I don't know what is out there
and I'm not good at dealing with people.
However
I feel compelled to go.
I need to do something for my dying son.
Mr. Takata.
Do you want to rest in Kunming
or go to Lijiang immediately?
Lijiang, immediately.
Fine.
LIJIANG
Rie?
It's me.
I'm at Lijiang
in Yunnan Province, China.
Yunnan?
What are you doing there?
I'm filming "Riding Alone for Thousands of Miles".
You want to film it
for Ken-ichi?
Actually
I gave you that tape
so you could learn more about him.
Father
please come back.
No.
The travel agency has arranged everything.
Please don't be worried about me.
Just don't tell Ken-ichi
what I'm planning.
Please.
LI VILLAGE
Mr. Takata.
This is Lingo. He's a village tour guide.
He speaks a little Japanese.
Lingo.
Remember Ken-ichi was here last year?
He promised to film the mask opera.
This is his father.
So you're Ken-ichi's father.
His father.
Ken-ichi is...my friend.
He's a very...good friend.
Lingo, how is everything going?
Just a second.
Are you Li Jiamin?
No.
Lingo, I told you we only wanted Li.
It doesn't have to be Li.
Other actors can also play Lord Guan.
No way. Mr. Takata only wants Li Jiamin.
If he insists on Li
there will be no show today.
Why not?
Look, Li enjoys a drink or two
which is usually fine.
Then, during a rehearsal
a stage hand mentioned
he had a bastard son.
This upset him so much
that he grabbed a wooden dagger
and stabbed the guy in the face.
He was arrested
and sentenced to 3 years in prison.
Please tell him
it doesn't have to be Li Jiamin performing.
All the actors are very good.
Once the mask is on
it doesn't matter who is behind it.
No-one can tell the difference.
Even a native can't tell
the difference between the voices.
So how could a Japanese person?
Does it really have to be Li?
His son wanted to film Li.
He is making this film for his son.
No-one else will do.
But Li Jiamin is in prison
for 3 years.
Even if he behaves well
and becomes a model prisoner
he won't be released for a year or two.
Takata should come back.
There will be other chances.
The show is always playing.
Jasmine
please help me.
Mr. Takata, this is not about money.
I'm in a difficult position.
I'm just a tour guide.
How can I get a foreigner
permission to film inside a prison?
It is impossible.
Please help me.
I really want to help.
But this is beyond my ability
and my job description.
Please forgive me.
My contract is only for 3 days.
I've been assigned other jobs.
I'll see you off at Kunming Airport.
I'm sorry.
Jasmine
please ask your boss
if I could employ another interpreter.
Hi, Boss. This is Jasmine.
That Japanese tourist
Mr. Takata, who arrived 2 days ago
is asking for a new interpreter.
Mr. Takata
my boss cannot help with your plan
to film inside the prison.
He also says
he doesn't have another interpreter available.
Please forget about this idea.
Mr. Takata.
Is that actor, Mr. Li, so important
to your film?
Excuse me.
Please turn around.
Turn around.
Jasmine
he wants to go back.
The opera is
Riding Alone for Thousands of Miles.
Lord Guan traveled a thousand miles
to help a friend
which is a big deal.
A man must be loyal.
I can't understand what they are saying
but I need their help.
Without them, I can't go anywhere.
For the first time, I feel helpless.
I wonder if Ken-ichi would feel the same way.
Mr. Takata
about your plan
Jasmine cannot help you
but I am able to.
Much obliged.
Thank you.
No problem.
There are no costumes
or props in the prison.
We'll have to take them.
Excuse me.
There are no props and costumes at the prison.
He's getting them.
Mr. Takata
I must confide in you.
Lingo is my friend.
He is very enthusiastic
but he really doesn't know much.
So, let me tell you
the basic procedures to follow.
First, go to the Office of Foreign Affairs.
Tell them why you want to visit the prison.
Office of Foreign Affairs.
If they approve
then go to the Bureau of Justice.
Bureau of Justice.
If they approve
then all's well.
Bureau of Justice...approves
If you have any difficulties
or Lingo can't properly translate for you
please call me.
I'll translate for you over the phone.
You have my phone number.
I'll leave this car for you
and charge it to your account.
You need to sign this form.
It's your request to change the interpreter.
Please sign here.
OFFICE OF FOREIGN AFFAIRS
Director Li is in a meeting.
He's been briefed on your situation.
He will be available soon.
He won't be long.
We have to wait.
Lingo, are they all...thank-you banners?
Yes.
This means "Thank you".
It's calligraphy.
A Chinese tradition.
Tradition?
Lingo
Please.
Write them down?
Please sit down.
No need to get up.
I've checked the files.
Indeed
there was a Japanese man named Ken-ichi
who traveled here frequently.
He enjoyed our mask opera immensely.
He also visited Li Village.
You are...?
I'm a tour guide from Li Village.
I'm Lingo.
He is my client.
This is Ken-ichi's father.
Welcome.
Please have a seat.
Lingo, can you translate
everything I am saying?
My Japanese is not very fluent
but I can take notes and translate later.
Okay, I'll talk and you take notes.
Okay.
You see
to let someone film inside a prison
is very difficult.
His request is totally without precedent
which makes it even more difficult.
You know
for a foreigner to visit a prison
is not a straightforward matter.
Even if it was
the procedures are complicated.
It may seem simple, but it's not.
It is very complex.
Okay, okay, I'm coming.
So, that puts an end to it.
Lingo
please explain these difficulties to him.
He doesn't have to visit this prisoner.
Many singers can perform this opera.
They could be even better than Li Jiamin.
I advise him to stop trying.
All right?
Mr. Li said
this is
too difficult.
Because
a foreigner
I'm a foreigner.
Law
Law is
difficult.
Because
Difficult?
Time
no time.
Dictionary
Check
Please check.
Law
Law?
Difficult?
Difficult law.
Easy for the Chinese
but for foreigners
very, very difficult.
Government...Law.
Hello.
Hello, Jasmine.
Sorry to bother you.
I need you to translate for me.
This is Lingo.
How did it go?
It was a disaster.
Get him a ticket and send him home.
That's the end of it.
Let me explain this to him.
Mr. Takata, telephone.
Mr. Takata
I'm sorry. Your request was refused.
Lingo will book you on the next flight.
Thank you.
Mr. Takata
goodbye.
Please return to Japan.
Because...government policy.
My Japanese
is not good.
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
You want silk banners?
Which one?
The best one.
These are the best. What size?
This one.
Director Li.
Lingo.
I've been waiting for hours.
We had a long meeting.
I forgot about the video.
Let's have a look at this tape.
Let's go in.
Why does Mr. Takata
want to use this tape
to talk to me?
Lingo
we don't understand Japanese.
No problem.
I have a Chinese version.
Jasmine translated it
and faxed it to me.
That's complicated.
Of course it is.
I've been practicing for hours.
Let's see it then.
Why isn't he talking?
Director Li
Forgive me for speaking to you like this
but I have no other option.
A long time ago
a long time ago
I hurt my son Ken-ichi deeply.
He has never forgiven me.
Recently
my son was diagnosed with cancer.
He may not have very long to live.
He has a deep passion for
Chinese folk operas.
He promised to return here this year
to film Li Jiamin's performance.
I don't know at this point
what else I can do for my son.
Maybe filming "Riding Alone for Thousands of Miles"
is the only thing I can do for him now.
Director Li, please help me.
Please.
Director Li
please.
I apologize for calling you so late.
Please help me.
If you think it's possible
I'll report it to the Bureau of Foreign Affairs
and ask them
to liaise with the Bureau of Justice
to resolve this.
Can you help me with this?
PRISON
Reform our ways.
Redeem ourselves.
Become new people.
One, two, three, four.
Are you his interpreter?
Yes, but my Japanese is not good.
I'll make notes first
and get someone to translate later.
Let me explain our protocol.
Foreigners have filmed here
in the past
but then complained publicly about conditions.
This gives our country a bad image.
Tell him this.
Yes.
Troublemakers like that are not welcome.
I have nothing against him personally.
You only want to film one prisoner?
Yes.
Prisoner Li Jiamin?
That's right, Li.
Mr. Li Jiamin.
Just to film him singing?
Yes, nothing else.
Which opera?
Riding Alone for Thousands of Miles.
It sounds like an excellent way
to promote Chinese culture.
After all, Lord Guan is not a state secret.
No, he's not.
He's certainly not.
I'll give it the Bureau's stamp of approval.
We can film it now.
Testing, do you hear me?
Yes.
Perfect.
This is the venue.
It is our recreation room.
The prisoners
use the room
on weekends and public holidays.
It's a place to relax.
Can you hear me?
Yes.
You can begin now.
Thank you, Warden Chen.
You're welcome.
Report for duty.
Come in.
Prisoner Yang and the band
reporting for duty, Sir.
Take your places.
Yes, Sir.
Lingo.
This is the prison band.
Some were professionals
others learnt to play here.
They are extremely popular
performing every year for festivals.
Please tell him.
Thank you. Thank you.
Reporting for duty, Sir. Come in.
Prisoner Li Jiamin
reporting for duty, Sir.
Li.
Can you sing “Riding Alone for Thousands of Miles"?
Yes.
What you need to do
is this
Repent of our sins.
Reform our ways.
Redeem ourselves
become new people.
Li.
Relax, don't be nervous.
You should be captured on film at your best.
You know all the pieces, right?
Come on, don't be nervous.
Band members, once again.
Ready go.
What's the matter with you, Li?
Why aren't you singing?
Li.
What's wrong?
He is waiting for you.
He came all the way from Japan
just to film you singing.
He's Ken-ichi's father.
The Japanese guy who visited you often.
Please sing.
Ken-ichi is sick.
Please sing for him.
Come on.
Why are you crying?
I'm not in the mood for singing.
I just can't.
I'm thinking of my son.
I can't stop thinking about him.
I envy Li.
He doesn't hide his feelings.
It is a blessing
to be able to express one's emotions.
If I could reveal my feelings like this
my relationship with Ken-ichi would be different
Lingo.
I don't think
we can film the opera today.
Li cannot sing.
Tell Mr. Takata to come back.
Let me know well in advance.
Please tell him.
Mr. Takata.
Stop crying, Li.
We know you'd like to see your son.
This is Takata.
I don't understand what's going on here.
Can you please help me?
Are you at the prison?
What happened?
We couldn't film the opera.
Li couldn't stop crying.
As the music started
he began to cry.
Why?
He's upset about his son
who he's never seen.
He longs to meet his son.
The warden stopped everything
when he saw Li crying.
What will you do?
He couldn't sing.
Li wasn't like that before.
He is a different man in prison.
Please pass the phone to Takata.
I'll explain to him.
Mr. Takata, your phone.
It's me.
Jasmine.
This is Takata.
Mr. Takata.
Sorry to disturb you so late.
I've been thinking.
I've decided to bring Li's son to him.
You want to bring the boy to Li?
Yes.
Please reconsider, Mr. Takata.
Li was over emotional today.
Warden Chen said
he'd be fine in a few days.
The boy lives in Stone Village.
It is in a very remote place.
This detour will only delay your plan.
I've made up my mind.
Mr. Takata.
Isn't making the film for Ken-ichi
the most important thing?
Both are of equal importance now.
I'm sorry.
Please call Lingo now
and ask him to take me to Stone Village tomorrow.
Please, I'm sorry.
All right.
Lingo.
Good evening. May l?
Please.
What is it?
Good night.
Goodbye.
Hello.
Is this Mr. Takata?
Sorry to bother you again.
What did you say to Lingo?
Why did he
return the money to me?
Will he still help me tomorrow?
Mr. Takata.
Let me explain.
Lingo and I feel very sad
about Ken-ichi's illness.
I apologize
for not helping you earlier.
Forgive me.
Never mind.
I understand.
Lingo doesn't feel right
about taking your money
when your son is so sick.
He will still take you
to Stone Village tomorrow.
Really?
Thank you both.
I'm happy that Ken-ichi
has friends like you.
Does he have many friends in China?
Actually...I don't know Ken-ichi.
Lingo doesn't know him very well either.
Lingo said that
Ken-ichi hardly has any friends in China.
Really?
Lingo said
Ken-ichi seldom spoke to anyone.
He would stay alone in Lijiang for months.
Sometimes he just stared for hours
at the mountains.
He seemed very lonely.
I may have said too much.
No.
Please
tell me more about my son.
Mr. Takata, I'm afraid that's all I know.
I am sorry.
Never mind.
I'm sorry it's so late.
Thank you, Jasmine.
Good night.
There's road work ahead.
STONE Village
Yang Yang's mom died a week ago.
He has no other family to care for him.
The villagers are taking care of him now.
The village chief said
the boy is now being raised by everyone
in this village.
That's right.
Li was told about this.
That's why he broke down in prison.
This was the reason.
We know why you have come here.
Our committee has already made its decision
I cannot give you the details straight away.
Why not?
Before I explain
I must clarify some things.
Please translate what I say.
Of course I will.
He's my client.
Please continue.
I want to say two things.
Firstly
Yang Yang is Li's son
born outside of wedlock
but we all accept that.
We all agree.
This is the first point.
Secondly
After 8 years, Li has now decided to claim his son.
We don't have a problem with this.
You'd better translate now.
Why don't you simply say "yes" or "no"?
So I can give him an answer now.
Yes or "no"?
You haven't translated a single word to him.
You should translate everything I've said.
You should make yourself clear before I do.
I doubt you speak any Japanese.
Ridiculous. Of course I do.
This loud discussion is going on for a long time.
I suddenly feel like an outsider.
I realize
in a foreign language environment
you can feel very isolated.
I'm slowly
beginning to understand
why Ken-ichi often visits here.
You're supposed to be a translator.
I wouldn't need you if I spoke Japanese.
I know how to translate.
I beg to differ on that.
No signal.
There's no signal here.
I know where you can get one.
He's calling a translator.
Let's go outside.
Why are we going to the roof?
You can get a stronger signal.
My son has made calls from up here before.
Who is Mr. Takata calling?
Jasmine, a translator from Kunming.
Isn't that your job?
Are you sure you speak Japanese?
Of course I do.
The issue is so important
we need to get a true professional.
Jasmine.
I'm sorry.
I don't understand what is being said.
Can you translate for me?
Thank you.
Ms Translator.
I want to make two points.
Firstly, Li didn't register a legal marriage
before his son was born.
We all accept that
Yang Yang is Li's son.
This is point one.
Secondly
at 8 years of age the boy
now finds he's got a father.
Li's sudden interest is hard to believe
and is confusing for everyone.
Please translate this for him.
It's me.
I totally understand
their reservations.
I never said "no" on this matter.
Lingo can't speak a word of Japanese.
Mr. Takata needed to know
our feelings on the subject.
Now he really understands
we are very relieved.
We have no more issues.
After much discussion, we give our consent
to let the boy go. Not for Li's sake
but for the sake of our Japanese friend.
Yang Yang can visit his father
with Mr. Takata tomorrow.
Yang Yang.
This is Yang Yang.
You are going to town tomorrow.
Get him some new clothes.
Could you ask the Chief
if Yang Yang wants to see his father?
Chief
he asks
if Yang Yang wants to see his father.
No problem.
Of course he does.
Sure?
Yes.
One moment.
I have to take a call.
This is Rie.
Father, please don't be upset.
I've told Ken-ichi
about your trip to China.
He didn't say a word the whole night
after he heard this
but he looked different.
I could see a change in his eyes.
Father
he never expected that
you would do such a thing for him.
Ken-ichi told me today
this particular piece of mask opera
is not that important to him.
He was only being polite to Li.
So, Father, please come back.
Father
can you hear me?
I am listening.
Father
please come home.
Ken-ichi said
your trip to China
is the most wonderful thing
you've done for him.
Did Ken-ichi say that?
Yes
these are his exact words.
Thank you.
Standing here today
I'm not sure
if Ken-ichi has uttered these words.
If he has
it is the first compliment
from my son in many years.
Seeing this large banquet
prepared by the villagers
for me a total stranger
I am deeply touched.
I will never forget this.
The sight of such generosity
and kindness from the villagers
makes me want to believe
that Ken-ichi has said these words.
What's wrong?
The tractor's broken down.
Broken down.
Really?
Yes
Can you fix it?
I think so. Let me try.
Yang Yang!
Lingo!
Yang Yang! Mr. Takata!
Yang Yang!
Mr. Takata!
Yang Yang.
What's the matter?
Why did you run away from us?
Do you know your way home?
Going home?
Your home.
Why are you running away?
Yang Yang.
Do you know where you're going?
Yang Yang
are you going home?
Is this the right direction?
Hurry up everyone!
It seems like hours.
All I can do is to follow Yang Yang around.
I'm one step behind. I think
the way I'm chasing after him
is the way I chase after my own son.
I don't know
which path to take
or what direction to go.
I have no idea.
Yang Yang.
We've been here before.
The trail looks the same.
Do you see?
Yang Yang.
We are lost.
We are very lost.
We can't keep going like this.
Let's wait for someone to find us.
All right.
Let's find a place to rest.
Let's wait here
and stay out of the wind.
Yang Yang.
What are you doing?
Having a poo-poo?
I thought you were running off again.
Don't look.
I can't do it if you watch.
Go away.
I don't believe this.
I'm not leaving.
I'll stay here.
Go away.
Stop doing that!
Yang Yang.
Hold on
Let's split into two groups to search.
That would be more efficient.
All right, let's do it.
Lingo, how do you pronounce his name?
Mr. Takata.
Are you sure?
Of course. It's a simple name.
Can you teach everyone to say it?
It's pronounced as Mr. Takata.
Repeat with me.
Mr. Takata.
Say it louder. Mr. Takata.
Mr. Takata!
All right.
You lead them that way.
We'll go this way.
Keep yelling out their names.
Let's go.
Mr. Takata!
Yang Yang!
The moon is bright in the sky.
Don't be afraid, Yang Yang.
I'm sure they'll find us.
We have to get their attention.
They might not see us in here.
Lingo!
Here, I've got a boat whistle.
Well done.
Well done, Yang Yang.
No, you keep it.
Blow it again.
Well done.
Sitting here all night
waiting to be found
I'm holding Yang Yang tightly in my arms.
I don't remember
if Ken-ichi and l
have ever held
each other like this.
Yang Yang
has no idea what his father even looks like.
I wonder
what kind of father I am to Ken-ichi?
His blood pressure is normal.
You will be fine.
Thank you.
Not at all.
I need to check the boy.
Give me your hand.
Jasmine
could I talk to the Chief please?
I am sorry for causing all this trouble.
No problem.
May I ask
why Yang Yang ran away yesterday?
He often wanders away.
I am not so sure.
Shall we ask Yang Yang?
Maybe he doesn't want to see his father after all.
There is no need to ask.
We'll make the decision for him.
What the hell does a child know?
He has to do as we say.
She can't translate if you're all speaking at once
Shut up. You can't speak Japanese anyway.
I can't? Can you?
You know I can't. Neither can you!
They're arguing again.
We should ask Yang Yang what he wants.
Okay, let me ask him.
Yang Yang, come.
Sit over here.
Let me ask you something.
Do you want to meet your dad?
Do you?
Come on. Yes or no?
No.
Why not?
Don't be naughty.
I am not going!
Why?
Tell me why not?
You must do as the adults say.
I'm telling you to go.
Go now.
He's not my dad.
I've never seen him before.
He is your dad no matter what.
I'm not going.
Why don't you want to see your dad?
I just don't.
Why don't you want to see him?
He's your dad.
Don't be naughty.
Yang Yang doesn't want to go.
You must do as we say.
I will not go.
Why not?
Tell me.
Could I speak with the Chief?
Chief, could you please come here?
Let's talk over there.
Don't cry Yang Yang.
We are not going.
Don't cry.
Chief
everyone
I'm sorry for causing you any trouble.
I've decided not to take Yang Yang to the prison.
Yang Yang
might not be ready
to meet his father yet.
Although he is just a child
I think we should try to understand
and respect his wishes on this.
All right.
Yang Yang will not go.
Who will raise Yang Yang now?
Tell him not to worry.
The village will keep caring for Yang Yang.
Li will be released in 2 years.
We'll arrange a meeting then.
The boy will be united with his dad.
We will take care of it.
Jasmine, one moment.
Yang Yang!
Mr. Takata
what do you want to do now?
I would like to visit the prison again.
If possible
I'd still like to film Li's performance.
Could you contact Warden Chen
to see if Li would be willing?
You may have to wait a few days for an answer
I'll wait.
All right.
Father.
Father
I've been trying to contact you for hours
but I couldn't get through.
Ken-ichi
passed away
Last night.
Yesterday during the day
Ken-ichi
was in high spirits.
He talked about you
and wanted to write you a letter.
He spoke. I wrote it down.
I wrote down...every word he said.
Shall I read it to you?
Do you want to listen to it now?
Please, read it to me Rie.
What do I want to say?
What should I say to my father?
I'm asking myself.
I deeply regret refusing to see you
when you came to the hospital.
This feeling of regret
torments me more than my illness.
I've been blaming you
ever since Mother's death.
Without any explanation
you moved away to a remote fishing village.
I thought then
you were trying to avoid facing reality.
To be honest
I've been trying to escape it as well.
When you came to the hospital
I couldn't face the distance between us.
People have never understood
my obsession with folk opera.
I've been drawn to them
because they mirror my life.
I've come to realize
that I'm the actor behind
the mask.
I've tried to fool myself
and everyone close to me.
My true feelings
have eluded me until now.
I have not allowed myself
to acknowledge them.
Father,
it's not the opera that is important.
I now see
that loved ones
should not mask their true feelings for one another
I eagerly wait for your return.
Father
I want us to embrace each other once again.
Mr. Takata. Lingo.
Jasmine?
Hello Warden Chen.
Mr. Takata.
I'm sorry that last time
Li couldn't sing.
I've organized more people this time
to create a crowd to cheer him on.
I hope it will go well today.
Li.
Yes, sir.
Tell Mr. Takata what you want to say.
Mr. Takata, I'm sorry about last time.
I'll do my best this time.
Warden Chen
thank you for arranging this.
It's very kind of you.
Today, however
I am not here to film the opera.
I've waited for two days
just to meet Mr. Li.
May I have a few words with him?
Of course.
Mr. Li
I've been to Stone Village.
I've met Yang Yang.
You saw Yang Yang?
He is a good boy. He really is.
Warden Chen
I've taken some photos of his son.
May I show him?
What photos?
Photos of his son and the village.
Photos of his son?
Please show us.
That's all.
Sorry these are all I have.
Li
Mr. Takata traveled a great distance
to take these photos for you.
Your son is a bright boy.
Everyone would agree with me.
He is really delightful.
You should thank Mr. Takata.
Thank you, Mr. Takata.
Can you perform?
I'll sing to the best of my ability.
There is really no need to perform.
I didn't come to film the opera today.
Mr. Takata
I've arranged the band
and the crowd.
A lot of men in our region
can sing mask opera.
I've picked some good ones
to accompany him.
I hope you stay for the opera.
There's really no need for me to film it.
Let me put it this way.
You don't have to film it.
We invite you to be our audience.
We'll perform the opera.
Please, will you sit here and watch?
Mr. Takata
thank you.
You are a very kind man.
So is your son, Ken-ichi.
I'll perform well.
Please film my performance
and show it to Ken-ichi.
Please tell him
to visit us again.
Mr. Li
I will film your performance.
Ken-ichi would be very pleased.
Thank you, Mr. Takata.