A wave of riots
has swept U.S. prisons.
Within 20 months,
riots have occurred in 35 states.
It began in Trenton, New Jersey...
moved quickly
to Jackson, Michigan.
Here at Michigan Penitentiary
for five days...
the world's largest walled prison
is torn to pieces by maddened convicts...
who destroy everything
they can put their hands on.
Damage is estimated
at $2 1/2 million.
Then, in Pennsylvania,
inmates seize...
five guards as hostages
in Western State Penitentiary.
Damage runs high,
as we can see...
in this view inside one
of the wrecked cell blocks.
At almost the same time...
231 convicts carry out
a similar rebellion...
in Rahway, New Jersey,
at the state prison farm.
Here, bed sheets,
scrawled with slogans...
are hung from broken windows.
The convicts hold out
for 4 1/2 days...
before submitting to authority.
In Menard Prison
at Chester, Illinois...
state police are called.
Ten guards are held
as hostages...
three of them by prisoners
in the psychiatric division.
Here, the inmates
insist on speaking...
only to the governor
about their grievances.
These riots, costing millions...
and millions
of taxpayer dollars...
have aroused
great public interest.
Mr. McGee,
what, in your opinion...
is the reason
these riots occur?
I would like to paraphrase the report
of the American Prison Association...
on riots and their causes.
The recent widespread occurrence
of prison riots...
is almost always
the direct result...
of the shortsighted neglect
of our penal institutions...
amounting to
almost criminal negligence.
Who is responsible
for this negligence?
Public leaders, such as governors,
legislators and others...
who must share
the responsibility for prisons...
as well as for
other branches of government.
And that neglect
includes the public?
Yes, indeed. In the final analysis,
especially the public.
One final question:
Do you look
to further riots in the future?
I abhor riot and disorder...
but until something is done
to correct the situation...
we will not see the end
of prison troubles.
Thank you, Mr. McGee.
All over America,
prison officials wonder...
"Where will the next riot occur?"
- Mac, you ever been
in the punishment block?
- No.
Keep your nose clean,
or we'll leave you in there.
Well, how's it doing
after a couple of weeks?
I like it. Still can't help but feeling
sorry for these guys, though.
You'll get over it.
Okay with the crosses.
What's so different
about these guys?
X marks the wild animal.
Must be Thursday.
Hey, you gonna feed
or ain't you?
You know what
you can do with that garbage?
Take it.
This is Honest Hal, folks, bringing you...
the greatest value
in used cars.
We're actually giving
these cars away.
Ha! If I'd have knew that,
I wouldn't be here.
Now, I want you to rush
right down here to 2730 Main Street -
Get that? 2730 Main Street -
right away.
- I'm a-comin', boss!
- Now, don't wait.
The right car
for the right price for you.
Thanks.
♪ Ask me if it's true ♪
- ♪ Am I in love - ♪
- I got to find out about my kid.
- Put it in writing to the warden.
- But -
♪ Can't you see the answer ♪
- ♪ In my eyes ♪
- Colonel?
- Yeah, Frank?
You're up for parole
consideration, aren't you?
- That's right.
- Do me a favor.
When you get out,
find out if my little girl's still sick.
Well, I'm not out yet.
I gotta find out.
I ain't heard in almost two months.
- Your wife will write you.
- Naw, she won't write.
That's the reason
I'm in here.
I thought I told you
to take that bush off.
Yes, sir.
Uh, 63.
Gotcha.
- Barrett speaking.
- Block 11, 238.
Hold it a minute.
- Go ahead.
- Block 11, 238.
Eleven, 238.
Okay, you're in.
- Barrett. Go ahead.
- Block 4, 637.
Four block, 637.
Okay, you're in.
- Go ahead, 5.
- Block 5, 433.
Five, 433.
Okay, you're in.
"O Lord, God of my salvation...
I have cried day and night
before thee.
Let my prayer
come before thee.
Incline thine ear unto my cry...
for my soul is full of troubles...
and my life draweth nigh
unto the grave.
I am counted with them
that go down into the pit.
I am as a man that hath no strength,
free among the dead...
like the slain
that lie in the grave...
whom thou rememberest
no more...
and they are cut off
from thy hand.
Thou hast laid me
in the lowest pit...
in darkness, in the deeps."
- Dummy up, will ya?
- Knock it off!
- Somebody slug that creep!
- Mother?
Mother?
Monroe!
Monroe, 48!
Yeah?
What do you want, Schuyler?
They're moving me to a new block
tomorrow, and I got a present for Gator.
Would you give it to him now?
Yeah, sure.
- How'd you make it?
- I got Monroe.
Good. Now for the others.
There's only four screws tonight.
- We got to grab 'em all.
- Snader's mine.
No cuttin', Carnie. We're gonna
keep 'em alive. That's my plan.
Snader.
Open your trap,
and we'll cut you a new one.
- You're not supposed
to have this, Snader.
All right, drag him out.
Acton!
Sergeant!
Hey! Monroe! Snader!
Hey! Monroe!
Snader!
Go ahead.
You'll have your brains out!
Schuyler, keep that screw
away from the phone!
Come on, hurry up.
Come on! Let me free!
- Hurry up!
- Let's go, Vito!
- I want out!
- Let me at the screws!
- Open up the cells.
- Hey, let me out, Dunn!
- Let me out of here!
I can't believe it's happening!
- Let 'em out!
- All right! Let's go!
Let's kill all screws!
- Where are the screws?
- Let's go!
Barrett speaking.
This is Dunn. We've got 11 block
and four of your guards.
- You've got what?
- Get the warden down here
or we're gonna kill every one of 'em.
Riot in cell block 11.
- What's up?
- What's the sirens for?
I don't know,
but I'll bet it's 11.
Sure, it's the guys in solitary.
It's a break!
Those guys have got
guts enough to try anything.
- Well, here we go again.
- Yeah, and all for 50 bucks a week.
Captain Barrett?
I've got your open line
to the governor's office.
Yes, sir.
I'll monitor all calls from 11.
Here's the armory, sir.
Armory, how many men
have checked in?
Second watch is coming in now.
Good. Speed 'em along.
Here's the way I want 'em dispersed -
two in 1 block,
five in 3 block...
two unarmed in 4 block.
Those to be armed
get rifles and tear gas.
And tell 'em
not to get itchy fingers.
All right, boys, come on.
Hurry up.
Watch those itchy fingers.
Captain's orders.
Hello.
Get me through to Barrett.
Well, cut in on him!
Hello? Hello, Barrett?
This is Ambrose. What's up?
A riot in 11 block.
The warden's on his way down.
- I'm at the gate. I'll wait for the warden.
- Right. I'll meet you in the yard.
Take it easy, fellas!
All right, take it easy!
That's enough!
Dummy up! Shut up!
Knock it off!
All right, cut it out!
Quiet down!
All right, pipe down!
If we're gonna win this,
we've gotta have discipline!
Now, Carnie here and me
are runnin' the show.
We all know
what's wrong here.
We're gonna ask for changes,
just like they did in the other prisons.
If they don't give it to us,
we'll make 'em a present
of one dead guard!
Or maybe four!
It may take all of 'em,
but they'll listen!
Me and some of my friends
are only in here...
because there ain't no room
on any other block.
We don't want no trouble.
Lay off!
You're either in or out, okay?
- You all covered?
- Yes, sir.
- All posts set?
- First thing I did.
- Doubled up in your building?
- Yes, sir.
Who did they grab in 11?
Snader, Acton, Monroe -
Monroe? Who assigned him
to that block?
- It was my suggestion.
- That was a mistake.
I figured him pretty green.
That block takes six guards.
It's tough enough to dig up four.
You know how short we are.
All right, Dunn, I'm here.
I want your word, Warden,
that I'll have safe-conduct.
I promise you no harm will come to you
during this conversation.
Guards, these are
my instructions:
Dunn is to be allowed
to come out into this yard...
and to return to 11
without interference.
- How about it, Dunn?
- Sure, Warden.
When he's ready, 16,
open the gate.
- Want me to go with you?
- No.
Just Snader.
I gave you my word, Dunn.
Hold that gate.
I believe you, Warden,
but I don't trust your screws.
You gonna open up?
- What do you want?
- I want the press here tonight.
Inmates never win a riot.
You know that.
That's my worry.
Release the hostages.
I'll get the press.
I can't bargain with you
as long as you're holding these men.
I wouldn't stand a chance
without hostages, and you know it.
Give me your word
you won't harm the hostages...
and I'll get the press.
- I can't hold my boys too long.
- Couple of hours.
Okay.
- Attaboy, Dunn!
- That's tellin' him!
- That's tellin' him.
- Good work.
- How's it goin', Carnie?
- We're waitin'...
but we ain't sleepin'.
- Tony, make a list of all this stuff.
- I can use that wire.
What do you want to do,
blow us through the roof?
Hey, I got something to show you
that's terrific. Come on.
Hey, what's that?
Learned how to mix
that cocktail in Normandy.
Now, watch this.
This is a real beauty.
Hey, that's all right.
Fasten that to the bars of the window,
you can knock their brains out.
Make some more.
There we are.
It's finished.
- How does that work?
- Here, lend me your neck a minute.
Slip it over a screw's neck -
How's it feel, screw?
- That's all right!
Holy smokes!
Right, Governor.
I've got to have authority...
to bargain with Dunn
and send for the state police.
I warned you
we were due for a riot.
I've even got 'em sleeping
in the corridors of block 4.
You're always talking about overcrowding,
old plant, insufficient personnel.
I don't want to argue that now.
Right now I've got
a riot on my hands.
Give me the authority to act
before this thing spreads.
Warden, I can't let convicts
dictate terms to the state.
I'll send Haskell right away.
Yes, sir. Haskell!
I don't know what that politician
will do here. These men can't vote.
Monroe's wife.
Yes, Mrs. Monroe?
Is it true
my husband's in block 11?
That's right.
He is in the block.
He'll be killed!
We're not going to let anything happen.
I promise he'll be all right.
Yes. Good-bye.
Tell the operators not to put
any more of the guards' wives through.
Just tell 'em they'll be okay.
That's all I can tell 'em anyway.
I got four guys on the front gate,
two on the roof.
Yard's all clear.
Captain Barrett's
got nothing on you, Gator.
- You working out demands?
- Well, we got a pretty good start.
Why don't we get
the Colonel in on this?
I've been thinking about that.
We could sure use him.
Well, then, use him.
Yeah.
Hey, Colonel...
you're the only guy here besides me
who could lead this riot.
You gonna help us?
I had to hit that boy to show
these gunsels who's boss.
In the street they think we're wild animals.
Tonight you proved it.
What chance do we have
if we don't stick together?
This place is bad enough.
Don't you make it worse.
We're trying to work up
some demands.
I'm asking everybody
for their beefs. What's yours?
The same as everyone else -
the whole setup.
The bloody cages,
the idleness.
- But this riot won't change it.
- What will?
Maybe nothing.
We're forgotten.
Colonel, you've got
education, medals.
You're used to handling men.
Help us with the demands.
Count me out.
- I don't get it.
- There are a lot of reasons.
For one thing,
I'm up for parole consideration.
You're strictly for you.
All right, you control the boys.
I'll help frame the demands.
Hey, Carnie.
- Monroe here wants a cigarette.
- No.
Sure.
What's the difference?
Give him the lighted end.
Here.
Take it.
It's all right.
Thanks.
What are they doing out there?
They're not gonna kill us, are they?
You'll be all right for a while.
It's not me. It's my wife.
We're gonna have a baby.
How can you afford a kid
on your salary?
I got two jobs -
this one and one in town.
If I could get in touch with her -
Hmm. Now you know why the boys
fuss so much over letters.
- If I could let her know I'm all right -
- They've got wives too.
Y- You got a family?
Sure. Wife and a kid.
It's tough
any way you look at it.
I figure too good.
I figure all the time,
but it don't add up.
- I'm an accountant, a good one.
- Embezzlement?
Nah, robbery.
I'm out for a while,
then I take something I don't need.
Grocery, department store -
it doesn't matter.
- You mean you don't need the stuff?
- No.
Just got to take it.
Like some fellas have to take a drink.
You belong in a psycho ward.
You shouldn't be here.
You're - You're different.
"Different"?
Take Ray in 26.
Armed robbery.
Do you think all that happens...
is that he says to himself, "I want
something" and then goes and gets it?
Nah.
It's not as simple as that.
There's something wrong
with him too.
You - You mean
they're all nuts?
Including the guards.
- Whose side you on, Mac?
- Well, of course I, uh -
I need glasses to see...
but not to think.
I can't put you through to the warden,
Mrs. Snader. The press just arrived.
Tell him I've got to talk to him.
All right, Mrs. Snader.
I promise.
No, I'm sorry. The warden's
with the press. I can't cut in.
What's a rookie guard
doing in the hole?
We don't have enough men,
and they're not good enough.
Most have to have
other jobs to make a living.
- Any idea why this started?
- Who's this Dunn?
Here.
Armed robbery, third offense.
Murder, second degree.
Medical report says he's homicidal -
dangerous and unbalanced.
He should be
under psychiatric care.
- When do we get to see him?
- We're waiting for Commissioner Haskell.
He's on his way here.
Here's another one.
Crazy Mike Carnie.
In for life. Dunn's pal.
Transferred to us
from the state mental hospital.
I've been trying to get him
transferred back - with Dunn.
- No luck.
- Are they all psychopaths?
Oh, no.
We've got all kinds here.
Good and bad,
just like on the outside. Here.
Vetter, known around here
as the Colonel.
He is a colonel too.
Brilliant war record.
Got drunk, fight in a bar,
manslaughter.
He's up for parole
consideration.
Should be out soon.
These men aren't here forever.
Ninety-five percent
of them will be released.
Not men like Dunn.
He'll be living around you
and your family.
And 65 percent of them
will break the law again.
Sixty-five percent?
That's a pretty high figure.
A figure that proves
we're not doing the job.
Isn't that the same speech you gave
the state legislature last summer?
It's the same speech he's been giving
for the last nine years.
- Hello, Warden. Hello, everyone.
- Hi, Haskell.
Well, let's get going, boys.
- Hello. How are you?
- Hi, Commissioner.
- Hi, Jack.
- How are you?
- Nice seeing you, Bill.
- Barrett.
- Mr. Haskell.
It's a fine mess you've gotten us into, Reynolds.
Let's clean it up fast, huh?
All right, Dunn, here's the press.
Let me see your hands!
These are used on the inmates.
Drop 'em,
or you can't come out.
Come on, hold up that chain.
Now look fierce.
Show a screw with a chain.
Come on,
show us how the chain works.
Sure, on you!
I'm coming out.
All right, 16, open the gate.
You gonna give us a statement,
or do we ask questions?
We got beefs we want to bring
to the attention of the public.
There's no work program.
Most of the guys are just sitting,
waiting for their time to run out.
- You're asking for work?
- Yeah.
- You think the public cares?
- They ought to. It's costing them dough.
- Your paper gonna print this?
- You know what we're interested in.
Yeah.
Mad dogs running wild.
- This place is badly organized.
Everybody's
all jumbled up together-
mental cases with kids.
We understand you've threatened to kill
the guards if your demands are not met.
- Is that true?
- You heard right.
Isn't that murder-
in prison or out?
This state will be responsible
for their deaths.
We understand the guards are married.
Some have children.
- So have we.
- You're not being killed.
- We're rotting to death.
You know Mr. Haskell is here
as the governor's representative.
If you can get together,
will you call off the riot?
If we can get together.
You heard Dunn, Mr. Haskell.
I'd appreciate reading
something like what I've said.
I heard. His charges
are without foundation.
Isn't it a fact that
the federal government says...
that prisons of over 1,500 men
are unmanageable?
This prison was built to house 4,000 men.
It cost the taxpayers $26 million.
You want us to tear it down?
What's the cause of the riots,
in your opinion?
I'll give you a full statement
after I've talked to Dunn.
In a case like this,
either the cons run the prison...
or the prison runs the cons.
- I wouldn't try to prove it tonight.
- You gonna get the state police?
If I need them.
We gotta feed
that Haskell a guard.
This is just the beginning.
Take it easy.
Reynolds, this thing can spread.
We can't let it.
We have to settle it tonight.
Okay, Haskell, what you got?
I want you
to release the guards.
I bet you do.
- What do you want?
- What are you gonna do for us?
If you don't give up,
I'll see that every one of you hang.
Haskell, get away from me.
- Dunn!
- Haskell, come back!
Dunn!
- There's our statement, boys.
Oh, that's real brilliant, Carnie!
You gave 'em
just what they wanted!
So far,
the guys are behind me...
but for how long?
Some look up to you,
and they'll follow you, not me.
Throw in with me,
and we sew up the block.
I told you I would help organize
the demands. That's what I'm doing.
I want you to do more
than fix the language.
Check with the men so they'll know
you're for the demands.
I'm for the demands
but against the riot.
Maybe that's because
you used to be brass.
Maybe.
I don't think so.
Look, Colonel...
every newspaper and radio
in the country is watching this riot.
We'll never get a chance
like this again.
Yeah, I know.
If we could just get across
that anyone could land in prison...
just like that!
I'm just gonna serve my time
and get out.
- And never come back?
- Yeah.
And never come back.
Still think you're different,
don't you?
No.
But once you put this uniform on,
you not only look like a con...
you feel like one.
Yeah.
Even if you don't come back...
you'll always be an ex-con,
so why not come the whole way?
I can't, Dunn. It's like mutiny.
I just couldn't go for that.
If you only had three years on the street
since you were 14, you'd know how I feel.
We're wasting time.
I'll do the best I can on the demands.
Let's hope we can win some.
"Some"?
We've got to win them all.
Jeff...
if 11 can make it, so can we.
Don't rush it.
Yeah, I know. We're all tired.
But the guards have to stay
at their posts until further notice.
This is Mr. Russell
of the New York Sun. He just flew in.
Hello, Warden.
How's Haskell doing?
Just a flesh wound.
Excuse me, Warden.
Kitchen crews have reported...
they're ready with breakfast,
no incidents.
Good. Feed the blocks one by one.
Start as usual.
Right now we're trying
to feed 4,000 men.
Pardon me.
I have to check the yard.
- Bring him up to date.
- Sure. How about some coffee first?
Fine.
Yeah, what about
the leg irons and chains?
- Yeah, what about 'em?
That's covered in number three.
You'll see when it's finished.
- Finished yet, Colonel?
- Almost.
That's another thing.
Kids should be separated
from guys like that.
from what?
You heard me.
From guys like you.
Rub your nose
out of my business!
Don't get too big
for your britches, sonny.
Mickey! Drop it.
- Commissioner, how do you feel?
- All right, thanks.
What's going on?
We've fed 1, 2, and 3.
- Let 4 go, Barrett.
- Yes, sir.
Delmar, Barrett speaking.
Send 4 through.
Yes.
Isn't it risky letting those men go past 11
on their way to the mess hall?
It is. The only other
way to do it...
is to try to feed
4,000 men in their cells.
That has dangers too.
Don't know if I could spare enough guards
for that and still maintain security.
Okay, keep moving.
Barrett, 18.
It's Dunn.
Yeah, Dunn?
Warden, we'll be ready
in about 15 minutes.
Hold the phone.
- Dunn is ready to bargain.
- Tell him you'll call him back.
I want to get
this thing over with.
I'm not going to jump
the minute he's ready.
Let him stew a while.
Time is on their side.
The longer we let this go,
the more explosive it's going to get.
Tell him you'll call him back.
I'll call you back.
Just don't take too long,
Warden.
He'd better not take too long.
Seven's still in business.
Sure wish I was with 'em.
This slop is rotten!
Attention, all towers.
This is the warden.
Listen carefully.
Don't do any shooting
unless they hit the wall.
- Cell block 5.
- Yes, sir?
- Have they started yet?
- Yeah, they're on their way.
Get 'em back. Block 4
has broken out of the mess hall.
Get yours back,
whatever you do.
Yes, sir. We gotta get 'em
back in their cells.
- All right. Come on back.
- Hold it! Back in your cells!
Back in your cells.
Come on.
Come on, get a move on there.
Come on back.
Grab a cell. Into your holes!
Hit your drum!
If they lock you in, you're dead!
They'll shoot you in your cells!
Let's go!
X-14 to 1734. Ready now.
Come in.
State police, come in.
This is Lansing.
Hello, Captain.
This is Warden Reynolds.
- Standing by, Warden.
- We need you right now.
- As many men as you can spare.
- Yes, sir.
How soon can you get here,
Captain Lansing?
- I'm on my way.
- Good.
Barrett, can you put any guards
down in the yard?
I already have every man
placed on 24-hour duty.
They've gone crazy.
I'm getting scared.
Everybody's scared.
Toolhouse is on fire.
Fire Department.
Fire in the toolshed.
Fire in the toolshed!
Let's go!
It's Roberts in cell block 5.
Roberts?
- Lifer.
- Roberts?
- Yeah.
- You can get death in this state
for leading a riot.
I've done 20 years
of hard time, Warden.
Tell those guys in the gun walk to lay off
or we bring these guards through.
- Wait. You tell him.
- Warden...
these men mean
to kill us!
Gun walk.
Gun walk...
don't do any shooting
when the men come out of 5.
Nineteen.
Nineteen tower.
The men are
coming out of 5.
They have hostages.
Let 'em go.
They want me to open up
and let 'em into 11.
Yes, sir.
Hey, the state police are coming!
Why don't you bring
the army too, you bunch of freaks!
Yellow-bellied rat!
Lousy dogs!
Scram, you lousy cops!
Men, this is the warden speaking.
The state police have orders not to shoot
if you go back to your blocks.
Go back to your blocks!
- I appeal to you for your own sake -
get back into your blocks, men.
Get back into your blocks!
Give me the okay, Warden,
and we'll break this up.
Take over, Captain.
Lieutenant Wilkinson,
proceed with plan B.
Dunn on the phone.
Yes, Dunn?
Warden, I'm giving you
fair warning.
If any inmate is killed,
one guard for each inmate.
Pick up the man
who was shot.
Break 'em up into two groups.
Damage estimated
at over a million dollars.
That includes the mess hall,
fire in the toolshed -
Once they arrived,
it didn't take long.
Nobody killed,
quite a few injuries.
State police
handled themselves well.
The warden's policy
is to avoid bloodshed.
No, it's far from over.
Eleven's still holding out.
Now they have nine hostages -
five guards from block 5.
No report on any of them.
Presume they're still alive.
Haskell seems to be
the boss around here.
- Yard's clear, Warden.
- Good.
Barrett, 18.
Warden, Bacon's dead.
Let's have the doctor
hold his report for 24 hours.
We won't release this
to the press, huh?
- There's 11 again.
Yeah, what is it?
- I hear Bacon got it.
- It was an accident.
Give it to me straight.
He's dead. Gunshot.
Okay, it's like I said -
one for one.
Carnie, get one of the screws
and bring him here.
- Snader?
- Snader.
- It's a pleasure.
- Dunn? Listen, Dunn, are you there?
It was an accident.
We didn't kill him.
One of the state policemen did.
We're sticking to our end
of the bargain.
Yeah, but Bacon's dead, isn't he?
Our deal was one for one.
They're going to kill Snader.
Hold it, Dunn.
I'm coming right down.
Dunn!
We're ready to listen
to the demands.
Okay, Warden, I'm ready.
I want to talk
to the whole prison.
First let me see Snader.
- Okay.
Have a good look.
We of 11 block...
know that we represent...
the entire inmate population
in these demands.
We are bargaining
for all of you.
Here goes.
Eleven block
must be remodeled.
Give us room to breathe...
and more light to see with.
The nuts ought to be separated
from the rest of us...
and put some place where
you can do something for them.
Get rid of the leg locks, chains...
and brutal guards like Snader.
Teach us a trade...
so that when
we get out of here...
we'll be able
to hold down a job.
Are you sure you didn't write
these demands yourself?
The whole thing sounds
exactly like your yearly complaints.
"Remodel block 11, turn -"
Look, the state commission
condemned that block two years ago.
Inmates read too.
And last...
no reprisals...
against any ringleaders...
or participants of this revolt.
That is all.
Well, you may let them get away with it,
Reynolds, but I promise you...
I'll have these men
brought to trial.
If it weren't for these guards,
I wouldn't sign anything, and you know it.
- Warden, what do you think?
- Those demands are awfully sharp
for a bunch of cons.
These are intelligent men,
Dunn in particular.
If he's so smart,
what's he doing in here?
He's also a psychopath,
like a lot of brilliant men on the outside.
Are you going to recommend
acceptance for the governor?
In the main. After all...
most of them have been
my demands for a long time.
- Looks like this time
you might get 'em.
I want you to sign,
and I want the governor to sign.
I'll sign, but I don't know
about the governor.
When will you know?
Give me six hours.
Sure, Warden.
- Throw him in one of the cells.
Carnie! Carnie!
Carnie!
No. No.
Dunn! Carnie!
That's enough of that!
This punk tried to take over.
Throw him out.
Gator, get me Barrett
on the phone.
Take care of him.
Come on,
let's put him in a cell.
He's badly hurt.
- Easy with him, Al.
- I've got him.
Oh, leave me alone.
- Far as I can tell, nothing broken.
- My neck's stiff.
Lucky that pipe
just glanced off your shoulder.
You don't look so hot
yourself, Al.
- I figured you on Mickey's side.
- You figured wrong.
Yeah, and you figured wrong
when you put Carnie in charge.
If you want the job,
it's yours.
Then shut up!
- Yes?
- We're throwing Mickey
out the front gate.
I'll right. I'll send a stretcher
for Mickey. Who's this?
Mike Carnie.
- Where's Dunn?
- I'm in charge now.
That was Crazy Mike Carnie.
He's taken over.
- They've almost killed one of the inmates.
- What happened to Dunn?
- He won't say.
- Crazy Mike - who's he?
"Crazy" is the nicest thing
you can say about him.
- Dispensary.
- Yes, sir?
Send a stretcher
to 11 block gate.
What's the matter, Snader?
Don't think I like you, huh?
You're wrong.
I'm gonna do you a favor.
Wanna say good-bye
to your wife?
I'll let you write her
a farewell letter.
No.
All the other screws
are writing letters.
How will your old lady feel
if she don't get one?
Of course,
if you don't wanna -
I'll just leave
the pencil and paper.
Change your mind, just rap on the door.
Schuyler will pick it up.
Wait till the wives get those letters
and start to phone the warden.
You'll see some action.
What a lot of tripe.
"Good-bye forever."
Get me the operator.
This is Carnie.
I want to talk to Mrs. Monroe.
The operator says
Carnie's calling Mrs. Monroe.
Tell 'em to put the call through.
I'll monitor it here.
Put the call through.
We'll cut in.
- Find out what this guy's up to.
- Yes?
- Mrs. Monroe, this is inmate Carnie.
- Mike Carnie?
I got a farewell letter here
from your husband.
No! No, he's not dead!
Not yet.
"Dearest Sue...
I feel responsible
for everything."
- Get me the governor.
Operator, get the governor.
Urgent.
"They tell me I gotta
say good-bye to you and the children.
I don't know how,
because I can't believe it."
Convinced?
- Just a moment, sir. Ready.
- Governor, have you signed yet?
No, I haven't.
These men's lives
really depend on it.
We can't trust Carnie.
Governor, if you're going to sign at all,
will you please do it right away?
I must consider
very carefully.
If I sign, it'll be an open invitation
to the inmates of every prison in this state...
to grab guards
and dictate their own terms.
Governor...
I don't want you to take the responsibility
for the murder of nine men.
Every minute counts.
He hasn't signed?
Not yet.
What happens if we break
into 11 block?
That block is as hard to break into
as it is to break out of. Harder.
Some of my men will be killed.
Well, suppose we blast a hole
in the block, only inmates get killed?
The casualties will be high.
- Including the guards on the inside.
- Maybe.
Haskell, the moment
you give the order...
to blow up that block,
you're in complete charge.
I'll have to take that risk.
All right, Captain, let's get started.
Hold your head up a little.
Colonel, do you think
us guards should be killed?
- We haven't done anything.
- Hold quiet.
I never treated the men bad.
No, you just
lock up the cages...
and help throw the food
to the wild animals.
I never hit nobody.
Didn't play no favorites.
Yeah, you treat us
all the same -
like a bunch of cons.
Each man in here
feels different inside.
We all fight for our identity.
And you help destroy that.
That's the prison.
I'm just a guard here -
Yeah, I know.
That's what we got
against you.
Schuyler.
Get me Snader.
We'll start with him.
- I thought I told you -
- Take off.
And keep your eyes open.
I don't think
we should kill 'em.
God would approve.
How's Al, Tony?
Feeling better.
Talk to him. See if he and his friends
will stand up against Carnie.
- I don't want trouble.
- You can't have it both ways.
If you don't want the guards killed,
you have to put up a fight.
Go on.
Hand him over, Schuyler!
What do you guys
think you're doing?
I'm willing to let you
run this riot, Carnie...
- but you can't kill Snader.
- Gator, boys, come on!
Now, wait a minute!
- Let's let Dunn decide this!
All right. Get him.
What's the matter?
You guys goin' chicken?
- I want to see Dunn.
- Carnie said no.
I said I wanted to see Dunn!
Dunn. Dunn!
- Hey, take it easy.
- Carnie's gonna kill Snader!
- What for? What happened?
- Nothing. He's crazy.
- If you don't stop it,
we'll all end up in a bucket.
I told him no cutting!
All right, break it up.
Break it up.
- Break it up. All right -
- Hold up.
Break it up, now.
Break it up.
All right, break it up.
Break it up, now.
They're gonna
blow up the block!
What?
I been standing guard, and I seen
these cops coming across the yard.
- They're not planting flowers.
- Where?
- By the end of the block.
- Lock Snader in a cell.
All right, dummy up.
Dummy up.
- It's a double-cross.
They're gonna blow
a hole in the block.
Carnie, get the screws.
We'll tie 'em up here.
Right.
Gator, you three, come on.
Will you wait
for the governor to sign?
And if he won't sign?
We've tried your way. It's no good.
It started with four hostages, now nine.
Tomorrow it may be 20.
You've never tried it my way.
The legislature's never given me
the money I need.
If they had, maybe I wouldn't have
a riot on my hands.
I disagree.
I think this riot is a direct result...
of your policy of compromise
with the convicts.
That's why I'm against signing.
I'd never sign.
Your way would only make
this place harder to handle.
You'd have thousands
of angry, desperate men...
and they'd take it out on the public
when they're released.
They may be angry,
but they'll be scared too.
They'll know
we mean business.
They'll think twice
before they riot again.
No.
You'll never stop riots
by treating the prisoners worse.
You stop them
by treating them better?
Line up! Line up!
Get back in your cells!
Get back in your cell -
- Popped his buttons.
- Yeah.
- I'm calling the warden
to tell him we're giving up!
- I'm running this show, Colonel.
They blow this cell block, they'll not only
kill the guards, but we'll go with them!
- All right, cut it out.
- Put that bum in there.
That's what anybody else gets
who tries to sell us out.
- You all set?
- Say the word.
- This is Dunn. What's up?
- The warden's on his way
down to the yard.
Yeah, but what about
the dynamite?
Nothing's going to happen
if you release the guards and come out.
The governor signed
the demands.
Hey, the warden's in the yard.
They say the governor
signed the demands.
- It's a trick, Dunn.
- Well, I'm gonna find out.
I've signed it.
So has the governor.
You wouldn't be
playing tricks, Warden?
Like maybe planting
a little dynamite?
- All the reporters here?
- Yes.
Okay, let's give them
their headlines.
All right, Dunn.
Start filing out, one by one.
After I see
the morning papers.
They'll be here at 7:30.
Fine.
- We did it!
All right.
Let the guards out first.
I gather from what you say
you feel you've won a victory.
- That's right.
- Congratulations are in order.
I'll say they are.
- Tom! Tom!
I never thought
I'd see you again!
Hey, Colonel!
Yeah, Dunn?
I can't understand
why we haven't heard anything.
What do you think they're doing?
- Well, it's only two weeks.
- Yeah, but nothing's happened.
They're in no rush.
Sure, you forced them,
but they don't like it.
They signed.
It's still in the papers.
What's in the papers?
That you led a riot?
That you beat up the guards?
That you destroyed property?
Yeah,
and the headlines say I won!
Yeah. Well, don't expect
any medals.
All right, Dunn,
the warden wants to see you.
It's about time!
I hear the warden's got
the blueprints for the new 11 block.
- Here he is now.
Wait outside.
What's it all about, Warden?
Dunn, you're going
to stand trial...
on charges of leading a riot
and kidnapping guards.
But I don't get it.
No reprisals - the agreement.
There is no agreement.
State legislature repudiated
the governor's signature and mine.
- They what?
- Canceled it out.
Said we had no right to make
an agreement with convicts.
But Warden, you signed it.
You gave us your word.
I don't like it, Dunn...
but that's what happened.
What'll I get?
If you're found guilty,
probably 30 years.
Thirty years?
And for what?
For nothing!
What'll Carnie get,
and the colonel?
Carnie is being sent
to the state mental institution...
where he should have been
a long time ago.
I'm signing
the colonel's parole.
And I get 30 years.
Warden, you know I didn't do it
to bust over the walls.
I did it just so people would know
what it's like in here. But 30 years?
I was never able
to transfer Carnie before.
The colonel may not have gotten his parole,
even though he deserved it.
Try to realize, Dunn...
that good does
sometimes come out of evil.
That's awful little good
for 30 years.
Well, the public
has learned more...
about the inside of a prison
in the last few weeks...
than they did in my 15 years
of making speeches.
Why do you think that is?
Because we got
in the papers.
And you're still news...
with or without
an agreement.
Haskell wants me to resign.
There's gonna be
an investigation.
But this time, the public
will listen to my side of it.
And they're your only hope.
They're the only ones
who can help.
I sure hope so.
I've been in and out
of these joints all my life.
And who cares?
That ain't right, Warden.
In other states after their riots,
changes were made.
The inmates won.
Yeah, I won - 30 years.