Annie Freelinghouser.
Did your lordship reply to this ?
I did.
Accepting ?
Accepting.
Have you ever seen anything like this in your life ?
I'm afraid not, milord.
It's ridiculous.
What is it, you suppose ?
It said Insect Man on the box.
Insect Man !
This is an amazing country, Ransome.
Hello.
How am I going to smoke with this thing ?
What am I going to do about drinking ?
It doesn't seem very convenient
in any part of the costume.
Hm ?
Oh, I see what you mean now.
The car for Mrs. Freelinghouser is waiting.
Very uncomfortable.
Your antennae.
My...
Oh, yes, of course. Thank you.
Couldn't we take the head off from the torso ?
No we could not. It's fixed on to the body.
It's a pity, milord.
It's a great pity, Ransome.
Is this Westbury ?
No, this is West 70th Street.
We pick up a lady here.
Charming.
Celeste !
Who are you ?
The car for Mrs Freelinghouser.
Oh, so you're the car for Mrs Freelinghouser.
Well you'll have to wait.
Celeste come here. I'm going mad.
There's something missing from this costume,
I can't go like this. I'm half naked.
See if you can find it.
What's it supposed to be anyway.
Does it say on the box ?
It calls itself a Lady Skybug.
Celeste, you're on something.
It's gonna fall to pieces.
It's never gonna last the night out.
See if you can find where that goes.
Oh, will you go. or stay, or laugh or do something.
There's a gentleman waiting in the car.
What's he like ?
He said he was an Insect Man.
A what ?
Celeste, did you send for an Insect Man ?
You're a funny fellow, aren't you ?
No, I'm not funny. It's a gentleman from the Ritz.
A Mr. Lord Rexford.
Tell him to come up. Never even heard of him.
Tell him to come up and have two or three drinks.
I'm gonna be hours.
Celeste, if you prick me again I'm gonna scream !
Let me take a look at this.
What a contraption.
That Annie Freelinghouser must be insane.
What are we all gonna look like anyway ?
Aren't there some instructions or something ?
I know I haven't got the thing on right.
Yes, here they are.
Oh.
I have to be painted.
Isn't that just dandy ?
Yes. There's a box of paint and a brush.
They didn't forget a thing, did they ?
Will you answer that ?
It must be the Insect.
Oh, I'm going crazy.
Hello.
Hello ?
What ?
Oh, hello.
No, not tonight. I'm going to that Freelinghouser ball.
No, I stood her up once before.
I can't do that.
What ?
I know it's insane, but it might be fun.
My costume is beginning to fall off already.
I think everyone else's will too.
So you see, I might meet some dinos after all.
Well, that's all she wants, the dirty old...
Oh, my God !
What is this ?
What ? No...
Something just came in.
No, it's pretty awful.
Who ?
No, tell him no.
No, no, no. Tell him to jump in the lake.
Bye, sweetie, bye.
Ooops !
My dear.
Listen, you turn your head, will you ?
I'm sorry, I can't. It's fixed onto my body.
Turn your body then,
unless you want to get a load of mine.
That's pretty awful. What's it supposed to be ?
I'm an insect man.
That's right, so your friend said.
For your information, I'm a Lady Skybug.
An insect's eye enlarges the image it sees.
So what ?
I was trying to be funny, but I can't.
Mu humor's completely gone. I...
Would you mind something awfully ?
Awfully what ?
Would you do with a very great
kindness of going to this affair alone ?
I'm awfully sorry. I simply can't go through with it.
It is too absurd, too unsane.
You remind me, Mr Bug, I want to thank you.
How do you do ?
Thank me for what ?
For saving me from going too.
Listen. I tell you what. We go up to my sister Sylvia's.
There's some fun going on up there.
Do you like mad parties ?
Well, yes, I think I do, thank you very much.
Good. What's your name ?
Rexford.
Where do you live ?
Ritz chambers.
Well, you run along home and get on a nice evening dress
and pick me up in an hour. How's that ?
Right.
Right. No, wrong. I'll pick you up.
That'll be quicker. And step on it.
Yes, I'd better, before somebody steps on me.
The lady, milord.
Thank you.
Milord.
Milady.
Is he kidding ?
Are you a lord ?
I'm terribly sorry, yes.
Are you really the beetle ?
I was the beetle.
How do you like
picking up a lady to go to a ball ?
Adored it.
Lucky, wasn't it ?
Most fortunate.
You could be cavorting around a hot room
with some fat old sheep tick or even a flea.
Now here you are on the threshold of trouble
with someone who happens at the moment to be very unattached.
The gods be praised.
Just how unattached are you ?
Free as the air.
We haven't differed on anything up to now, have we ?
No, I know.
I think it's a good sign.
From home.
How did you know I wanted a highball ?
Just instinct.
Sweet.
And you too.
Fun, isn't it ?
From out of nowhere.
It's where the best things come from, nowhere.
Glad ?
Thrilled.
May I ?
If you want to.
Old beetle.
Are they blowing that whistle for us ?
No, the French lines
are very sympathetic about a thing like this.
How sweet.
Come with me to my stateroom.
No, no. That boat's my enemy.
It's taking you away from me.
But only for a while.
You think so ? No.
Forever, I'm afraid.
Darling, do you know why
I can't stand you leaving me ?
It's been so perfect up to now.
Too good to be true, hasn't it ?
And it's everything a woman thinks of love.
I'm not over it yet, but I will be eventually.
Marry me.
Will you marry me ?
Oh, darling.
How sweet of you to say that.
That's perfect, but...
I wouldn't do such because I loves you too much.
Kipling.
Oh, why not ? Why not ?
No, we're entirely different people.
You're completely you and I'm...
well, I don't know what I am.
I don't see we're so different.
Don't you ?
You would when you came out of the ether.
It's been a beautiful spree.
And I mustn't let you
be swept of your feet, you see ?
I just want you to think of me once in a while.
Come on.
Oh, thank you, Ransome.
I'd almost forgotten these. For you.
It looks expensive.
Oh, you haven't !
Pearls.
But why ?
Round your neck. Why not ?
I thought pearls...
Oh, darling, pearls have nothing
to do with the way I feel about you.
No, you haven't money enough
to buy what you have already given me.
A very bright little corner of the city in all my life.
Oh, my sweet.
I suppose it was rather odd of me.
Not at all.
Now get on that boat
that's taking you thousands of miles away.
This time even you are going too far.
Be happy, Mary. All your life.
And all yours, Philip.
Let's not have one regret ever, never one.
No.
Would you like the message
delivered personally, madam ?
Darling !
Your boat.
There are lots of boats.
Only one Mary.
Your baggage ?
Gone.
Gone ? I can't believe it.
Do you know some place where
they can accept a nice
respectable lad without luggage ?
This is a very hospitable city we have here, sir.
Darling, I suddenly couldn't leave you. I simply couldn't.
Mary, this is it.
What ?
Us.
You mean...
Me Lady Rexford ?
Yes, dear.
Oh, darling.
After all those things I told you about me ?
Think now. Think hard.
I have thought. It's all forgotten.
Or isn't it ?
Oh, yes, if you say so. Buried and forgotten.
Only you in the world.
Are you sure you can forgive it all ?
Forgiven.
Forgiven ?
All right, from now on a ring in the nose
and a beating every Saturday night, please.
Yes.
I remember distinctly what I said.
How I hate you in this mood.
You always crabby after lunch.
Why do you go if you don't have to ?
Because Philip happens to be going to America today.
And he knows I'm in town.
Isn't he very dull ?
No sense of humor whatever.
They say the little American girl
he's married is full of ginger.
I invariably laugh with Americans.
But she can't be very amusing,
or she'd never have married Philip.
You'll laugh. You always do.
Oh, his father was such a gay old buck.
The naughty old devil.
Now, please don't start
a long old story of reminiscence.
We're nearly there.
You cheeky little brute.
How I hate London. I hate it !
Why did I ever come back ?
Tell me, why did I ever come back ?
We'll go to the Riviera tomorrow.
And you told me to close the Villa.
And I closed it.
Very well, then it stays closed.
We can go to the Carlton Hotel.
Now understand,  tomorrow morning we start.
Oh, I've got a pain.
It's the lobster.
Not at all. It's not in my tummy, it's in my heart.
It's because you're so cruel to me, Bertie.
David !
Yes, Mary.
Is the captain on th bridge ?
Yes, he is.
What are the chances ?
Very slim, I'm afraid.
Did you put in a word for me.
My dear, I'm only a secretary.
I'm only a wife.
You know how he is when his mind's made up.
I've never known him
when his mind isn't made up.
Bad as all that ?
Not so bad but very stubborn.
Here goes for a good row.
Never known him to.
What ?
Row.
Here's one now.
Am I accompanying my husband
to America or am I not ?
Not, I'm sad to say.
Oh, darling.
Five years and we haven't been apart a week.
And now just because someone you work for says no women,
as though women were trunks or something...
Oh, darling, I can hurry, I can rush,
I'm not an old frump like Mrs. Parrish.
Really, you should have insisted.
I could scream.
Go on then, scream.
How's that ?
Oh, Mary, you are making me feel such a swine.
I don't mean to.
I know you can't take me.
I'd most likely be an awful nuisance.
No, no, it really isn't so tragic.
Aren't you glad I think it is ?
Oh, yes.
You know, sometimes I get the absurd idea
that you might think New York isn't
quite the place for me again.
You don't think that, do you ?
What on earth do you mean ?
Oh, you know.
No I don't, really.
Well, I'm glad.
'Cause I can't remember New York
without thinking of us, can you ?
You know what I mean ?
Yes.
I wasn't exactly your wife then, was I ?
Or don't you want to remember that ?
You're my wife now. Don't talk like that.
That doesn't have anything to do
with your aunt taking me, does it dear ?
Of course not.
I think I'll leave a card. They're probably busy.
How do you do, Lady Riversleigh ?
How do you do er...
Who are you ?
I'm Lord Rexford's secretary.
Oh, really, how nice.
This is my secretary, Bertie Davis.
What's your name ?
My name's David Fenwick.
Oh, is it.
How do you do ?
That's Philip's valet.
What a distinguished face he has.
And I'm talking to the servant.
I'm so confused.
I'm sure it's a bad day to call.
I think I'll leave a card.
No, please, I know they're both expecting you.
Oh, they changed the hall. Painted it white.
Looks like a railway station as it is.
It's Lady Riversleigh.
I'm counting out my cigarettes.
Bertie go to the car and get them there.
Aunt Hetty, how are you. I haven't seen you for years.
Mmm... and donkey's ears...
Oh, how nice.
You're looking so well.
I wish I felt as well as she looks.
This is er...
Mary.
My dear, you're divine.
I heard on all sides how attractive you were.
Well, I've been waiting for years
to see what I'm really like.
Why ? Americans are so amusing.
What does she mean ?
When I ran a little naughty, they'd always say:
"Oh, you're just like Aunt Hetty.
At my age, I'm really flattered.
You shouldn't be.
How sensible of Philip to marry
a nice healthy girl full of Mmmmmmm!
Zimmm.
Oh, I like that.
You have that Mmmmmm.
I had it too when I was a girl.
I was full of Mmmmmm.
Joie de vivre.
You still have.
Philip, did you hear the nice
compliments Aunt Hetty is paying me ?
What are they ?
She says I have er....
That sounds fine. What does it mean ?
Don't you know what that means ?
That means this.
She's getting pottier and pottier every day.
I beg your pardon, sir.
Every day.
yes, sir.
Look what I found out here, please.
This is Pamela.
Four years old and weighs a ton.
My dear, not a ton.
Why I only weigh a ton and a quarter.
What a nice little bit.
And look. She has mother's twinkle in her eye.
Aunt Hetty, forgive me for rushing away.
Goodbye and good riddance.
I'm going to stay here and talk to your lovely wife.
Aunt Hetty, you will excuse us for a moment, will you ?
What a lovely little girl.
Oh, Bertie, where have you been ?
There are your cigarettes.
Well, don't throw them at me.
What's the matter with you ?
Come on, darling. Daddy has to catch a train.
You pick her up.
Goodbye, my angel girl.
I expect to find you
a whole inch taller when I get back.
You promise me ?
Here, Clark, you better take her.
I've a little tear I don't want her to see.
Oh, Mary, my Mary.
Telephone me sometimes, will you ?
Of course I will.
I shan't be able to tell you any
more than I cn tell you now.
Say it, darling.
I love you, I love you.
Do you ?
Sometimes I wonder if you do.
Darling, how dare you.
Please take care of yourself.
Men.
So they've gone.
How nice it is when people go.
The house seems so quiet.
Oh, Aunt Hetty, I wanted to run across
that square after that car and bring him back again.
A little girl in love.
You're right, darn it.
But why should I be left here all nights ?
Oh, my dear, talking nights...
Have you any wine that's cold ?
I have a little sinky feeling at this time of day.
Have you ? Well I'm sinky too.
What about a bottle
of cold champagne for two little girls ?
That's a marvelous idea.
Bollard, bring some champagne.
Big cocktails, you like cocktails, don't you ?
I adore cocktails. And don't forget
the Angostura and the sherry, Bollard.
Yes, milady.
And make sure they're cold.
They must be cold, my dear, we mustn't tell him.
Aunt Hetty, you're very naughty.
Of course I am. Why not ?
Why not ? I was once.
I'm sure you were,
with that molted twinkle in your eye.
And does Philip know ?
Hm-hm.
Since you were married ?
Before ?
He caught you red-handed ?
Oh, no, I told him everything.
Oh, my dear, you foolish girl.
It isn't that I don't adore Philip, I do.
And I'm not a neglected wife, don't think that.
I think as I please,
you're telling the story, I'm listening.
It's just that I don't seem
to amuse him these days.
He's like the conductor of an orchestra in a theater,
who doesn't laugh at the poor comedian's jokes any more.
No sense of humor. He never had any.
He looks at me in that funny dry way of his
and I feel more like crying than laughing.
I seem to have developed an unconscious fear
of displeasing him somehow or other.
My dear girl, come with me to Cannes.
What ?
Come and stay with me at Cannes.
That sounds divine, but...
You need sunshine, and laughter and a coat of tan.
Get thee behind me, Satan...
You need music.
Hi to yourself.
Lovely, gracias señorita.
Thank you, Brooklin, New York.
I must say...
Oh, do your best. Go and find Tommie...
Look at you.
My dear, I'm furious I'm living !
You know, you're missing all the fun.
The heartlessness of youth !
Now what's the matter ?
Have you forgotten Nina Pourtalès' mad party tonight ?
You were invited.
A mad party ? Why aren't we there ?
This is a mad party right here...
Oh, but where is Tommie ?
He's upstairs in bed.
Who's in bed ?
Tommie Trent.
Tommie what ?
Tommie, you know...
He's from New York, so are you, aren't you ?
Am I ? And do I know Tommie ?
Why, the old slouch, where is he ?
In bed with his miseries.
With whom.
No names, please. Even among cads.
He's in bed with his sorrows, his miseries,
he won't see a doctor, he won't even take a drink any more.
He says he's world weary.
Poor Tommie. Misery and too much fun.
He promised faithfully. We must get him.
Dynamite wouldn't get him out of bed tonight.
He has skull pains up to here. No kidding.
I bet I could get him out of bed, we're old friends.
My dear, I promised Nina Pourtalès.
You know that Tommie can make any party.
Yes, so I've heard.
I'm gonna get him.
No, no, then you won't come.
Tommie can bend anyone to his will.
I'm not bending this season.
Come on you, chaperone me. I'll get him out.
He looked my way once in New York.
Lucky you.
Now what does that mean in American ?
That means making a pass, my darling. Making a pass.
Come on, what's your name ?
You tell me yours first...
Easy, easy.
At's all the ice balls, there ain't no mo'.
Well, go and get some more ice.
Yessum.
Don't slam the door.
Tommie, I have a lady to see you.
Tommie ! Peek....
... a-Boo !
What, no Tommie.
Tommie.
Where's the lovely heir ?
Tommie ?
See if he's in there.
Thomas.
Tommie !
Not in bed.
I think he's gone out.
He must be here, the music's still on ?
Here Tommie, here Tommie....
What ? No Tommie.
Perhaps he's out on the balcony.
Tommie Trent, you old son-of-a-gun !
Madam, these old eyes fail me somewhat.
But that voice has a ring...
... that brings back memories of better days.
Take a look stranger, Mary Watts, New York City.
Collonade, 21. Man who hit on my roof and went to sleep
and woke me up in the middle of the night
when it started to rain. Who ?
Who ?
No one but you-hoo.
Madam, pray be seated.
Come on, Hetty is furious.
You've stood her up and kept the old gal waiting.
Erskine, you in your rude sound shattter me.
You're playing on my one raw nerve.
Leave me, Erskine, leave me.
I'm so sorry, sire.
No, now, don't you go.
You're going to a party.
What ?
Yes. That's what I said. Now wait a minute... wait...
this is mad...
Madam, I am glad to see no one, but from afar
pilgrims do come to dip their fingers
in the magic fluids of my dome.
And what must I do ?
What can I do but submit ?
It got to you at last. I knew it would.
Listen, I'm going, you're frightening.
Call me up when you come out of it, will you ?
Mary.
Well, that's something like it.
Mary, darling, I'm glad to see you.
How are you ?
I'm a little hung over, but I'm glad to see you.
You're just a teddy bear with a sore head.
What is this I read about you in the newspapers ?
Are you a duchess or something,
or is that just a press stunt ?
You guess.
Corn in Egypt, oasis in the desert,
but you are a sight for sore eyes.
Very touching, but we're going places.
Erskine, come on let's get some clothes on him.
You're going to a party.
Whither thy goeth, so will I follow on.
Allez, tout de suite, vite, marche !
I will be bathed, perfumed, dressed, earled...
What shall I wear ?
Something quite simple and a small hat.
A tuxedo ?
My old lace.
See that the lady has nothing she wants, Erskine.
I'll return in a jiffy.
You'll never be missed.
He's a scream.
See these gray hairs ?
Try living with him for a week.
Might be stimulating.
Look at me. I'm stimulated.
Is that what you call it ?
Nobody swiped them.
For me !
For you.
Will you introduce me ?
That's George.
Charming little fellow, George.
Here's to George.
George.
Have you ever seen anything
quite as mad as that Rexford girl ?
She's awfully pretty, isn't she ?
She's quite drunk.
Did you see her on the floor with those men just now ?
Shocking !
That was fun.
Mary. Don't do that. Mary !
It's full of water !
Mary.
Mary !
You're not gonna swim again, are you ?
What, this ? No, it's just for effect.
My hair is soaking.
Well friend Thomas, what now, what now ?
What now, Lady Mary, we are outcasts.
What now ?
Please, what makes you think
you can get away with that ?
You said please.
Now you've spoiled everything.
All right, now wait a minute.
Have a little drink. I mixed it all by my little self
over at the little bar.
Drink up.
Good.
Oh my, oh my, oh, my.
What an age, what a world.
What's wrong with it ?
I find it a very pleasant world.
It's all part of the coming of the great catastrophe.
What is ?
When girls like you turn out to be prudes.
What ?
What's gonna become of men like me,
that's what depresses me.
What do you mean, prude ?
You're pretending to be one
and you're being pretty convincing about it.
Just because I didn't let you...
You're crazy.
Where is she ?
With Tommie.
He's on an edge for days.
Give him a break.
Something must be done.
We must find them.
Bertie, they'll be all right.
Hetty's responsible for her.
Oh, Bertsie. You have no romance.
No. Come.
I'd love to.
You must admit that
if there wasn't a certain reason
for your saying no...
... that this moon, this place, this moment,
me, might not be quite so...
... repugnant.
Did I say anything about anything being repugnant ?
If it had been, I'd have left.
Then why the pose ?
What pose ?
A leopard cannot change its spots.
No more can you, ducky.
Can't a woman forget a past whatever it's been
when she marries and settles down ?
You settled down, all right.
That's an insult.
All right, be insulted then.
I am.
Bushes ? Tommie never goes in the bushes.
One of us must keep our senses.
Hetty goes absolutely pottie.
No thought of tomorrow, only thought of today.
I'm going to get up.
What will it look like if you do ?
Let's keep on looking.
I f we don't find them,
at least we shall have done our duty.
Not that there's anything wrong.
I've always had a feeling that I could sleep better
after having done my duty.
I wouldn't trust that Tommie with my old Buick.
Tommie, too much Vermouth.
I'm furious.
You've ruined my evening.
What do you think you've done with my evening ?
What ?
Here I was contemplating a nice juicy suicide,
everything getting darker and darker...
... when you blow in with a lot of trumpets full of electricity,
inflame us and whoa !....
up on top of the world again.
Will you keep quiet.
How did I spoil your evening ?
I don't know.
Don't take me too seriously, dear.
I was wrong. Let's just be friends.
From your standpoint you weren't wrong, I guess.
That's very sweet of you to say that.
Perhaps I did take too much for granted.
I probably encouraged you a bit.
Let's just be real pals. Real buddies.
We'll go over to St. Tropez tomorrow
and have a real hearty lunch and watch the sea.
No, no, I don't think that would be such a good idea.
You see, Tommie, I'd love to, but...
All right, all right. Don't explain.
Tonight's been perfect.
You're sweet.
You really are.
Mary...
Mary, I could marry you.
I've never said that to any woman before.
I've never thought it about any woman before.
You're mad. You're beautifully batty.
You're always reaching out
for something, somewhere, somehow...
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Aren't we all ?
This whole human setup is just grab, grab, grab,
and I'm getting very sick of it.
I think human biengs are the most unfortunate
of all animals, all the reptiles and all the birds.
Tommie, you're a fool, but a nice one.
You know, you have a funny sense of truth in you...
And so have you.
If only you'd be true to yourself.
Listen.
Listen to those birds up there.
They don't have to drink to be gay.
They don't have to doll up
and gab a lot of nonsense.
Listen to that row back there.
Now listen to him.
He's a happy little fellow, isn't he ?
We could be happy too, Mary.
Two people like us.
I am happy.
No. I mean two kindred spirits like you and me.
How ?
They could sleep all day...
They can get up just when the evening was gonna get gay...
... and they could dance,
and take long walks into the moonlight.
... then back and change,
and out with the horses and riding into the dawn.
Just when everybody else was waking up to face the day.
They could be flitting in and out of warm shower baths...
... and pulling down the blinds on trouble,
and bores and telephones.
Then they'd be up in the evening
and drink steaming hot coffee...
... and pull up the shades
and let that old moon in again.
It would be paradise, wouldn't it ?
They'd be children of the night.
Satan...
See me sometimes, Mary.
Just like this.
Forget all that solid routine they call living.
Spread your wings and flutter with me sometimes.
I've forgotten how to flutter.
I can teach you. Wouldn't it be fun,
wouldn't it be marvelous ?
Think of the thrill of knowing that just around the corner
there was fun and laughter....
... waiting to hold you....
... like this....
... and say...
hello, Mary darling.
It's perfect, isn't it ?
Nearly.
Why not perfect ?
I'd like a drink.
All right, I'll get you one.
Don't want you to get cold.
I'll be back in just a second.
First a little gin.
Now a little... a little gin.
Oh... Mary.
Mary, I will disguise this
so that you will never know.
A dash of bitters...
Ice... pardon my fingers.
Oh my, what a moon, what a moon.
Mary, look at...
Mary.
Mary !
Where is she ?
There she goes.
Mary !
Hello there, Tommie.
Good morning.
Mary !
These Americans...
Mary ! Mary !
Mary, you can't do that !
I'm sick of being thrown out of hotels.
Mary, you said that you would wait. Now, Mary...
Mary, open the door !
Mary !
Monsieur, vous ne pouvez...
Oh, mon Dieu. Venez avec moi...
Slick, I smell trouble.
What you smellin', Mr. Grey ?
Mary !
Ce n'est pas juste, Il y a d'autre monde qui dorme...
Mais, non, regarde quel heure est-il.
Mary !
Every time I find something that I really like
away it pops.
But she's married.
So was Cleopatra.
How do you know ?
Go to bed, Slick.
Get in here.
All I needed was that girl.
Listen to me, you can write her off your
next year's income tax as unavoidable loss.
She trembled. She fluttered.
I know, but she'll flutter
just as well tomorrow.
No she won't. Not her.
She's got conscience written all over her face.
At this moment she is cooling off
like some beautiful volcano...
... that has decided not to wipe out
a lot of Italian villages.
Why don't you be a good boy and go to beddy-bye ?
Why ?
So I can go to beddy-bye.
That's her room over there.
Mary !
Tommie, now wait a minute.
What are you gonna do ?
Mary !
Don't make an ass out of yourself.
Leave me alone.
If you fall will you leave me the big car ?
Yeah, I'll leave you my ermine coat too.
Shh. What's your name ?
Mary !
Tommie !
Have you sent for a doctor ?
Yes, I've sent for one.
Lady Rexford ?
Yes.
Do you speak French, madame ?
I do, but I'm not in the mood.
What is it ?
Tonight, madam, you had here a visitor.
A gentleman.
He comes, perhaps, for a little chat.
A little drink.
Why, no one was here.
Je vous avez bien dit que vous aviez tort.
Madame was alone ?
That's what I said, yes, why ?
Then, madame, how is it that this Trent...
Trent ?
Thomas L. Trent.
What about Mr. Trent ?
They say he must have thrown
himself from your balcony.
Then it was Tommie who jumped.
Tommie jumped...
What happened ?
Tommie wasn't even up here tonight.
My dear, I didn't tell you when I came in...
Silence, please.
Madame should know.
I don't know what you're talking about.
You did not quarrel with Mr. Trent tonight ?
Of course not.
You did not perhaps,
in resisting him, push him out ?
Don't be ridiculous.
What's happened to him ? Is he hurt ?
We don't know. He's at the hospital.
What hospital ?
Hospital Ste. Madeleine.
Thank you very much.
What's he doing there ?
Mr. Clegg, please, this is a private matter.
I know, I know.
Tommie Trent attempted suicide from this balcony.
What ?
Come on now. Who is the lady ?
Who are you ?
My name is Clegg.
Clog ?
Clegg ! Excelsior News Service.
Are you the Lady Rexley, is it ?
My name is Rexford.
Perhaps we can have a
little chat when the visitors leave.
Take him away.
You have taken your picture, Mr. Clegg.
It's a private matter.
Can't you sort this thing out ?
And what is your name, please ?
The dowager duchess of Valhalla Gotoblazes.
I accept the apology. Taken.
Tommie, you poor kid.
Mary,
Mary, you pushed me.
Fool.
Mary, I can't see you very well.
They've pumped me full of junk.
Why did you do it ?
Why did you run away from me ?
You were grand.
I was going crazy for weeks.
Then you came along and...
cured my blues,
then you ran away and locked me out.
And I couldn't bear it.
You might have been killed,
I suppose you know that.
Would you really care ?
Really ?
Of course.
What do you think I'm made of ?
Rainbows.
Well, I wish there were
something I could do for you.
There is.
What ?
Would you...
Would I what ?
I can hear a lot of violins playing.
And it's all very fine and very wonderful.
And your eyes are full of stars.
Tommie, what was it
you were gonna ask me ?
Kiss me.
Will you go to sleep and be quiet ?
Yeah.
Thank you very much.
Excuse me, sir, please.
Take the big stuff round the back.
Just a moment before you go in.
Yes, dear ?
Are you terribly angry ? You haven't kissed me yet.
Yes, I have.
Oh, but such a silly little kiss.
I have so much to tell you, dear.
I'd rather not talk about it now, Mary.
I'd rather not discuss it now.
All right, dear.
Anyway, it's wonderful to have you back, darling.
Wait a minute, do I hear a little mouse somewhere ?
Yes, I do hear a little mouse somewhere.
My angel.
We've gained three pounds.
Have you ?
Oh, no, not me.
It.
Such a very pink rose.
I'm so sorry, but these fellows
really do want to make the morning papers.
All right, my sweet, you run along.
What is that ?
How can you have a horse without a tail ?
You sillybilly.
You know, you've stayed up
much too late as a matter of fact...
... as a special treat tonight on account of daddy.
She just loved to see her daddy again, milady.
I know. I was just a little bit j-e-a-l-o-u-s.
You're too smart, too smart for a little girl.
Is that all you want ?
Yes, thank you very much, sir. Good day, sir.
Good day.
Remember me to Mr. Warmington, will you.
Yes, sir. He's had a bit of a cold but he's much better now.
That's good. Bye
Hello, how are you ?
Good afternoon, Lord Rexford.
I think the others are after general news,
but I'd like to ask you something more personal.
I see, yes, what ?
We've held up a story from America
about the possibility of a divorce.
Oh really, have you ?
Haven't you anything to say to me at this time ?
No, most certainly not.
Nothing at all ?
No.
Thanks.
David !
Shut the door.
What's the matter ?
Any of the other fellows talked
about Mary and the Cannes business ?
No, why ?
What a filthy thing to come home to.
I thought you'd decided to wait.
You've covered up your
feelings beautifully until now.
I've been watching you and I've been watching Mary
and she hasn't taken her eyes off you.
It's all so unfair.
How could she put me in such a position.
May I suggest...
What ?
... that you hold your horses.
Why don't you see these other people
and get your bath and change your clothes
and then talk it all over with Mary after dinner ?
You know she won't lie to you.
You know if anything were wrong,
really wrong, you wouldn't have
a smiling Mary to meet you.
Knowing Mary.
All right, David, I'll try.
Shall I send them in ?
Yes, I suppose so.
Oh, thank you.
Coffee, dear ?
No, I don't think so.
I've nerves.
I think I have nerves too.
No coffee, Bolly.
Let me know when Fenwick gets back, will you ?
Yes, milord.
Darling, you're not going to run away ?
I think I ought to.
Cross ?
No.
Just a little ?
Darling, I'm so sorry.
I've been terribly worried.
How could you get mixed up
with a fellow like Tommie Trent ?
Darling Tommie Trent.
He's a fool. I just happened
to know him in New York.
You did ?
That's one of the things
the American papers omitted.
I knew him very slightly.
He's always been very amusing and...
I know.
He's quite mad and...
Yes. That the papers did infer.
Darling, it's been horrid for you.
Those awful things in the papers...
I knew they'd exaggerated.
They never let down.
They kept building up in headlines.
One would have thought
another war had been declared.
You poor dear.
Then, just when I thought it was all over,
out came the Sunday Supplement
with special features...
"Mr. Tommie Trent and some
of the women he's supposed to..."
Darling, please.
Your picture was there
with a question mark over it.
And next there was a perfectly horrible one
of me with caption underneath it saying...
"Burning". Me, burning !
Darling, I'm so ashamed.
And I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry too. I...
I didn't mean to blow up.
I made myself promise myself I wouldn't.
I don't mind. You should blow up.
I want you to blow up.
Darling, you never thought for a
moment that I was one of...
Tommie Trent's adventures, did you ?
I didn't permit myself to think.
Look at me, you couldn't.
There must have been something.
What made him think
he could come to your room ?
Two or three bottles of champagne, I suppose.
Nothing else ?
If there had been anything else,
I'd have been the one to jump from the balcony.
Why don't you tell me the truth ?
The truth.
I went to a party with Aunt Hetty.
A party given by a woman called Pourtalès.
Countess Pourtalès, to be precise.
It was all a little hectic.
We didn't even get there till 2 in the morning.
Fun.
It was fun, Philip.
Well, go on, darling.
Don't say darling like that, darling.
Well ?
There was a big full moon...
I didn't put it there...
... and a soft warm wind full of mimosa,
and trouble and we were talking.
You and the Mr. Trent.
Yes, He's terribly funny.
We were talking a lot of bosh and
nonsense about birds and people.
Sounds interesting.
Well, and he kissed me.
Yes ?
It all seemed very silly and trivial
until I got back to the hotel... safe...
... a little frightened. The next thing I knew he'd fallen off a balcony.
I naturally went to the hospital to see how he was.
And now I've told you the truth, judge.
The whole truth and
nothing but the truth, so help me...
I suppose it is amusing.
It makes me a little ill.
Well.
You might have had gone for a divorce.
Exactly what I was thinking.
Philip. Slap me in the face, shout,
knock me down, but don't keep this up.
I was wrong, I know it.
But I'm intact, if that means anything to you.
You make it sound quite remarkable.
Darling...
Don't be so...
Philip, haven't you ever...
Ever what ?
Nothing.
Have never what ?
Felt temptation.
So you were tempted then ?
For an instant yes, I was.
Tommie Trent didn't tempt me, the moment did.
I wasn't myself if you like,
that's possible isn't it ?
It was a bad moment. It opened my eyes
to something inside of me that frightened me.
Darling, don't go away and leave me again.
I belong to you.
I'm not so sure of myself anymore,
and I'm so sure of you.
Take care of me darling, I love you.
I love you too, that's the trouble.
If you mean that, nothing
can ever happen again.
Forgive me.
I have forgiven you.
No.
No, you haven't.
If I could only feel inside of me that you have.
How can you expect me to believe
that all this ended with a kiss ?
Why not ?
I'm reminded vividly of New York.
What about New York ?
It didn't end that way once before.
I think I see what you mean.
And you will still say that after 5 years,
these five years in this house
with you and the baby ?
In New York you were the kind of a
girl that wouldn't stop at a kiss.
I always knew that one day you'd say that.
Philip, you're angry.
I don't blame you for being angry.
But this !
Won't you believe me ?
I don't know.
You don't...
Then you really believe me guilty.
I... don't know.
Philip, I demand to know where I stand.
I've told you the truth.
Why don't you believe that ?
Lady Rexford expects me.
The name, sir ?
Hm ?
The name, sir, please.
Tommie. What's yours ?
I beg your pardon, sir ?
Come, come, the name.
Albert, sir.
Tommie.
Tommie, this is serious. Come here.
Present.
I want you to do something for me.
It may seem a little silly
and embarassing to you, but...
I want you to do it.
Mary, don't look so worried.
It doesn't agree with you.
But I am.
I can't help it, I'm nearly out of my mind.
I'd do anything in the world for you, you know that.
The account of your accident was
published all over America with the
most amazing suggestions attached to it.
I know. I got a very charming letter
from my father about it.
I suppose your husband is...
I've explained evrything to him
and he won't believe me.
Does he believe the papers ?
He won't believe me.
Tommie, this is what you could do.
Will you see him for me ?
And tell him that there was nothing.
Nothing at all.
If he won't believe you,
why should he take me for a Gideon Bible ?
I don't look like one, do I ?
Tommie, don't joke, please. Be serious.
Will you do it for me ?
Yeah. Of course I will.
Thanks.
Mary, where is the nearest hospital ?
I brought my violin but no first-aid kit.
Philip. May I disturb you ?
Of course.
Philip, this is Mr. Trent.
My husband.
Good evening.
I telephoned Mr. Trent
and asked him to come to see you.
Why ?
I'm doing everything in my power
to try to convince you that you're wrong.
Mary asked me if I would
come over and explain.
You see, I drink a bit
and I'd known Mary in New York...
Yes ?
Yes.
And when I met her down in Cannes I was...
just a little bit lit and...
one laugh led to another and...
I remember being a little bit fresh
and naturally Mary ran away.
And I went skylarking on those balconies
and over I went.
I'm sorry to report that I wasn't killed.
I should have been.
You know thay say that children and drunks all...
Is that all ?
I was solely to blame.
Thank you.
Well, that's all I can say, Mary.
Not at all.
Call on me any time.
I've told you that before and I still mean it.
Goodbye.
Bye, Tommie.
Didn't you say that was all ?
Yes, yes, good night.
Good night.
Are you completely mad ?
I've never known anything
in quite such bad taste.
But Philip, I wanted to convince you.
You have.
What more can I do ?
I don't know.
So Mister Jeremy Fisher
invited his two friends to supper...
... Sir Isaac Newton and Alderman Ptolomy Tortoise.
Mr. Tortoise brought salad in a string bag...
Mr. Jeremy Fisher made some butterfly sandwiches
with Ladybird sauce which frogs
consider a great treat,
but I think must have tasted pretty nasty.
Clarke, what time is it ?
Half past six, milady.
Think somebody's pretty sleepy.
Daddy !
Let's hide, Come on.
Isn't he coming ?
I'm afraid not.
So the captain is on the bridge.
Yes, very much on the bridge.
A kiss for daddy.
Good night, sweet angel. Sleep tight.
Sweet dreams, darling.
All right, Clarke. Good night.
Good night, milady.
Oh, Mary.
What's the matter ?
David, I'm sorry. I can't help it.
I guess I should make myself scarce around here.
Why ?
He's avoiding me.
He waited until I left the room last night
before he came up and kissed her.
I know.
Well ?
I've been sent to apologize.
To tell you he's working. He really is.
He's dining out.
So men must work and women must... what ?
I don't know.
What I do know...
I think some women are splendid.
They have such courage. They have such patience.
Oh, David, thank you.
I know how he feels, you know.
If I could only see him
and talk to him about it.
What is it, Curtis ?
Mrs. Theodore Wilson on the telephone.
My sister Sylvia.
I haven't seen her since she got back to town hardly.
Here it goes.
Hello.
Hello there kiddo, how are you ?
Oh, I know.
What do you mean highbrow ?
Listen, darling, I can explain.
Where are you ?
Sounds merry.
I hear music.
What club ?
Toad in the Hole. Yes.
No, I'm afraid I can't.
I don't know, but I simply got to see you.
Toad in the Hole is an
awfully merry little spot.
Sylvia... I'll be over.
Yes, where is it ?
Brooke Street.
Yes, I'll find it all right.
I'll be over. Listen, I need a laugh.
And besides, I'm dying
to see that old face of yours.
So hold everything.
Right.
David, if the captain asks for me,
I say if he does...
... tell him I'll be at that jolly little spot.
Good for you, Mary.
You say her ladyship went out ?
Yes, milord.
She went with her sister to the Toad in the Hole.
Toad in the what ?
Toad in the Hole, the club.
My nerves are going pop.
I'm awfully sorry,
naturally I can't help noticing...
What ?
I beg your pardon, sir.
That's all right.
Where is this place ?
Brooke Street.
Oh, Philip.
Philip, this is Robbie Grey
and this is cousin Suzie...
And that's Charlie Clark.
And this is his wife Rosie.
How do you do ?
Philip, will you have a drink ?
No, not just now...
Hello, Lord Rexford,
it's awfully good of you to look us up...
I'm Major Mills, I run this little business.
I'll make you an honorary member.
Thank you very much.
I didn't expect you, dear.
I want to talk to you.
Anything serious ?
It's a bit late tonight and I'm off first thing in the morning,
yes it's quite serious.
Tell me, what is it ?
No, not here.
Major, have you got some place
where we might go and talk ?
There the little office of mine...
It's entirely at your disposal.
That's very kind of you.
Will you forgive us ?
And keep that.
Don't let her get it.
Don't worry.
All right, Philip.
So what ?
Mary, I can't hurt you any more.
But you are hurt too.
I know. But I've decided what to do.
What ?
We can't go on.
Before I went away you had
settled down into being a normal, decent wife.
Thank you.
But the moment my back was turned...
Oh, don't start that again, Philip, I can't stand it.
Very well.
Since I've been back, all I can find is a
restless, jumpy, affected woman.
That's not fair.
But it's true.
I suppose I shouldn't have come here.
I didn't say that.
No, but you're thinking it.
Well, I had to do something.
I couldn't keep following you around the house
on my knees waiting for you
to come out of this coma.
Am I not to be cruel to attempt
to keep you away from this atmosphere ...
... which obviously you thrive on ?
Is this Cannes again ?
Cannes, or here, all of it. It's a sort of...
It's a color of life that seems essencial to you.
That's not true. But go on.
I'm seeing Farrington tonight.
Your lawyer ?
You mean...
Yes.
Divorce.
So you don't want me anymore.
Don't put it like that.
Philip, give me another chance.
We've had our chance.
We've failed.
I adored you so.
I would have died for you.
Nothing you could ever have said or done
could have changed that.
I'm being honest.
I'm protecting us both.
Pardon me you two,
but a certain fellow here wants to chip these.
And I think it's a good one, at least I hope so.
I can't take any money from the bar,
it upsets the barmen.
So I keep a little here for people in distress.
Will you have one of these ?
They're rather special.
No, thank you very much.
By, the way, Lady Riversleigh...
... Mr. Trent, Mr. Brown, tho whole gang at the bar...
I took the liberty of introducing
them to your rather amusing sister.
I told them you were here.
They said when you'd finished
would you come to the bar and have a talk.
Aunt Hetty and Trent...
I didn't know they were here.
I had no idea they were coming.
My dear, it doesn't matter any more.
Don't you see, it doesn't matter.
Oh, it doesn't matter.
How different we are.
You stand for everything that's good and chivalrous and right,
I know that.
You don't need kindness, and tenderness and forgiveness.
You're so sure, so strong...
You can detain and control lives with words and divorces...
You've got the strength to take everything in life that I want.
Well, I've got the strength to tell you: take it.
You're right. it doesn't matter anymore.
Oh, there's Mary.
Hello, Aunt Hetty. How are you, dear ?
I've just met this charming, amusing sister of yours.
You know Americans always make me die of laughter.
Hello stranger.
Hello there, how are you ?
Where's your husband ?
He's gone.
Oh. Have a drink ?
Love to.
Name it.
French 75.
Same here, French 75. Boom !
Boom yourself and everyone else.
Atta girl.
Thine eyes like limpid pools, baby...
It's the smoke.
Sorry, Mary.
My name is Nightingale.
I'm the butler.
I'm speaking from Riversleigh Hall.
Lady Riversleigh's residence.
The place is on fire.
All right then, hurry.
The old wing !
Hurry ! I've been trying
to get you for the last half hour.
Well, Bertie ?
It's started in the old wing.
I'm really glad. I hate the old place.
Are any of the guests in the old wing ?
Lady Rexford is in the old wing,
the Foxtons are in the old wing...
You'd better go to the old wing and tell them.
They probably don't know there's a fire.
No, I'll go. I'm the hostess.
You'll get yourself scorched.
The captain must stand by the ship.
Keep the dog there.
I think somebody must take charge.
I'm in charge here.
Is there anything I can do to help ?
Suppose you take charge.
I'll take care of Hetty.
General, general.
I've just rescued these two angels.
Aren't they divine ? I've never had so much fun.
Don't you love it, General ?
I hate this place. It smells so stuffy.
Oh, dear. We didn't know a thing about it.
This wing is seldom used.
Shhh. Darling. Don't make a sound.
Why not ?
Go and answer the door.
Wait a minute. Hold your horses.
Think.
Something has be going on downstairs.
Smells like a bonfire.
It's probably your sister
giving them a good American barbecue.
Mary, do open the door
or you might burn to death.
Do you mind.
Not a bit. I was just thinking of you.
Don't bother. It doesn't matter any more.
I'm still thinking of you.
Oh, Mary.
Aunt Hetty, what is it ?
Oh, my dear, there's been a fire raging.
We didn't know a thing about it.
Lady Hetty probably saved all our lives.
We heard something going on downstairs,
but we thought it was a game.
Tommie, come on out, there's been a fire.
We didn't here any firebells.
Oh, we should have had some bells.
Bertie run along downstairs and ring some bells.
We've been talking.
And so were we.
You know, you might all have been burned to death.
I don't mind telling you that I heard
confidentially that the whole thing is over.
But I didn't say a word to anybody
because it's the only excitement
we had over the weekend.
Now come and have some bacon and eggs.
And I have sweet pickles on toothpicks...
Well, it's happened.
Now what ?
I haven't been in St. Moritz
since the days I was a lad...
... studying Law at Cambridge.
Ah, those were the days.
Winter sports in Switzerland every year.
Life is different now, somehow.
Very different.
Very mild on the Riviera just now.
Well ?
It's Cannes I came to see you about.
I've been down there on your case.
What on earth has Cannes got to do
with Mary getting a divorce from me ?
Didn't I make myself clear ?
Didn't I tell you how I wanted the matter handled ?
I think you should understand,
a little pardonable caution
on the part of your lawyer.
You know, this type of lady
has been known to be a trifle difficult.
What do you mean this type of lady ?
Well...
As in the case of Webster versus Webster
where the husband tried to do the decent thing
when he had absolute proof.
So you went to Cannes for proof.
I wanted us to be protected
in case she became unreasonable.
And you found it.
On the contrary. Not a shred of evidence.
Of course I went personally because
I knew you wanted the matter to be kept
as private as possible.
And I interviewed policemen, chambermaids,
hotel managers, hotel detectives...
And you found nothing.
Nothing.
The night manager of the hotel
stated very clearly that on the night in question,
he together with other employers of the
hotel had to remonstrate with this Trent fellow...
... he then being intoxicated, for knocking
on the door of the suite occupied
by your wife and your aunt.
The door then being securely locked.
I got a statement from Lady Riversleigh.
She said that your wife...
I resent your making these inquiries.
They're unnecessary and humiliating.
Where's Mary now ?
As far as I know, staying quietly
with Lady Rivesrleigh in the country.
And you could think for one moment
that I should be the one to bring suit ?
Well, I'm afraid you've got no case
if attempted divorce.
What made you think that I wanted a case ?
Do you believe her innocent ?
Oh, yes, I...
I do, I do, I...
I really see... I believe that now.
Farrington. Do nothing more.
I really have been out of my mind.
Go carefully, Philip.
You married her impulsively,
you threw her aside impulsively.
Now do think.
I have thought.
I was wrong. I know I was wrong.
I do believe her.
All right, supposing subsequently you find
she has been unfaithful to you ?
I can't think that.
I wouldn't answer for the consequences.
What are you going to do ?
Take her back ?
Will she take me back ?
Wanna play ?
Yes, come on. I'll beat you.
Aren't you drinking ?
Me ? Never.
What ?
I don't need to anymore.
You fool, you fool...
Come on, double.
Don't cheat yourself.
Hello.
Hello, yes.
No.
Lady Rexford ?
Oh, yes. A telegram ?
Why don't you send it ?
The telegraph boy's a fireman and he's here
Oh, it's all very confusing.
Will you read it to me ?
Yes, I have paper and pencil here.
Yes.
To Lady Rexford...
Essencial we should talk.
Can you come here to me at once ?
Don't fail. Waiting.
All love. Philip.
Yes, I've written it all down.
That's all right.
Where is it from ?
St. Moritz.
Oh, yes. Thank you.
It's as if he's on her trail.
A bit late.
Why not ?
Mary, can I speak to you ?
There's a telegram for you.
I copied it out. It's private.
I'm a fraid it's not private any longer, darling.
What does she mean ?
Well ?
Go on. Your move.
No, it's your move.
What are you gonna do ?
Well... oh yes.
I'm going.
Pretty cold in St. Moritz right now.
Perhaps.
Seriously, Mary, you can't go.
Why not ?
Mary, darling, you can't go now.
You're gonna tell him the truth ?
Are you afraid ?
No.
No, I'll go with you.
We'll tell him together.
No.
You couldn't.
No ?
I'm going.
We have the epidestra.
The convolvuli and a
very large type of rhododendrum.
Flowers.
Blooms, blossoms.
Oh, I see.
Personally I prefer the carnation to any other flower.
Oh.
Carnation, you know. Carnation ?
It's hardly the same thing, do you think ?
That's why I prefer them.
Oh, so infinitely more.
He whistles for you and you go scampering.
He wants to see me.
And you want to see him,
but I'm not gonna let you go alone.
No man is gonna let me
or not let me do anything ever again.
Celeste, pack. We're leaving for London imediately.
We can pack there again,
catch the Golden Arrow to Paris at 11 o'clock.
We'll take a night train
out from Paris to Switzerland...
... St. Moritz, warm clothes and no nonsense.
Gotta make those connections.
You'll have to step on it.
I'm gonna step on it,
how I'm gonna step on it.
I never packed so much in my whole...
Oh, stop mumbling to yourself.
Mary, I thought he'd called it a day.
He did.
And now something that was
apparently dead has started up again.
I'm gonna stop it at once for his sake.
It was dead and it's gonna stay dead.
You still care for him, don't you ?
As a friend only.
No more, no less than anyone.
Tommie, go on.
Will you go now ? I have to dress.
You're unfair, inconsiderate,
you're behaving like a hysterical ...
Oh, Tommie...
I've heard all that too.
Yes, I know. I'm sorry.
Will you go now ?
When will I see you again ?
When I get back.
When will that be ?
The instant I've told him the truth
and closed that chapter.
Take care of yourself.
Hm-hm.
For me.
Mary, I love you.
Oh, Mary, my Mary.
Hello, Philip.
Sweet of you to come so quickly.
I came at once because I had something
to tell you that I couldn't write.
That I ...
There's lots of time...
So much that could be said, but...
Well, whatever it is,
we can discuss it quietly as friends,
can't we ?
Friends...
Are those waiters
going to stand there forever ?
I'll throw them out.
Would you two gentlemen mind
holding your meeting outside ?
Philip. Listen to me.
No, Mary. Hear me first.
A criminal is entitled to a hearing.
I never said...
Mary.
People, just people can get married,
actually married, in a few minutes.
But sometimes it takes years
to marry their natures...
... to come to a perfect understanding, each for each.
... to give and take,
to find that divine adjustment when
you can look at each other and say...
This can go on forever.
If you'd only held me for a moment.
One look, one word.
Love's a cruel thing.
You can get angry in love.
You want to drive it out
because it becomes agonizing in anger.
And then at the moment it's leaving you...
you die inside you.
With such pain, and such a longing
to undo things we may have said.
I died, Mary, inside me.
I can't go on without you.
Oh, I do trust you.
Please, please forgive me.
Philip !
You're making it so
difficult for me to tell you what I must.
No, not another word.
You do.
Please, Philip.
I don't want to hear anything.
Tell me you forgive me.
There's somebody in the other room.
You have, Mary.
Would you go and see who it is.
It's you, Celeste. What is it ?
I wouldn't bother you, I...
I was just borrowing one of
your sleeping powders...
I can't sleep. It's the altitude.
I've got an attack of nerves.
I tried to get everything right.
I forgot half the things
I should have brought.
Let me get you some brandy.
No, it'd make me sick.
I'll be all right.
I know I rushed you off, you poor girl...
What is the matter, Celeste ?
You mustn't get so upset.
Get to that telephone.
It's London. Lady Riversleigh.
Why didn't he put it through ?
She said I was to get you alone.
It's urgent.
Hello.
Hello ?
Yes, I'm in London now.
Yes, my dear.
Tommie Trent has just left.
He's as drunk as a fool.
He's insane. He says he's going to
take an airplane and come
to St. Moritz at once.
Well, stop him, can't you ?
Have you said anything to Philip ?
No, no, I don't know.
I can't explain.
Stop him if you can. Yes.
All right. Goodbye.
Thanks.
Mary. You've been hours.
I've been trying to gather my courage.
So have I. I was thinking...
Philip, will you hear me ?
Yes, dear.
You know, the last time we saw each other...
in that little room in the club, remember ?
Yes...
You said that I'd failed you...
I hadn't then...
I never really believed in my heart...
Mary I couldn't have believed
that you were untrue to me.
If I had believed it
I would have killed you and myself too.
If I could only tell you in words...
Last night...
I wrote to you
things I haven't been able to say.
Do read it, Mary.
I thought I'd lost you forever.
Tell me one thing.
You do love me, don't you ?
Do you love me ?
Before God I do.
Philip, wait a minute.
Once you told me
you couldn't put your arms around me.
And I understood you then.
Now...
... please just don't hold me, will you ?
Let's go.
All right.
Good night, Mary.
Good night.
Yes.
I have Mr. Trent here on the line.
Will the lady speak now ?
No.
Hey, Tommie. Get this.
Lord and Lady Rexford return
from St. Moritz to their London residence.
You'd better check out that romance, my boy,
or the shooting season'll star early this year.
Is she there ?
Ask her if she could say er...
Good morning, Tommie.
Aw, come on, just one little word.
Wait a minute. I'll ask her.
It's Tommie.
He wants to talk to you. Just a word.
Sylvia, no, I can't.
Well, you're out of luck.
She won't speak.
He wants to come around. Is that all right ?
No, of course not. Sylvia, please tell him.
What ?
What's the matter ?
Where ?
In the lobby ?
Hold on.
Who ?
Are you kidding ?
Please don't joke.
Who ?
He isn't kidding.
Philip's over there at the Ritz right now.
Hello.
What ?
Oh, no, please don't see him.
Don't see him, will you ?
All right.
Listen, Mary. I've gotta see you.
Hetty tells me
you're gonna have lunch with her.
I'll see you there at lunch time.
I've gotta see you.
All right, I'll see you there.
Now, you won't see him, will you ?
No.
All right.
Just tell his lordship that I am not home.
I'm you, you know, out.
Out.
Slick !
Yo.
Bath, shave, massage,
hot towels, blue suit, white flower...
A weddin' ?
No. I don't know. Who knows ?
I'm in love. I'm in love.
Mary, he's on the wagon, high and dry.
Why, he even telephoned his father
in New York this morning to tell him
he wanted to go to work and settle down
Sylvia, my problem is here with Philip.
I almost lost him once
and I'm not going to lose him again.
Mary, you watch your step.
With that state of mind you're in
he'll find it out any moment unless you can
begin to forget, and apparently you can't.
I can forget it.
I do forget it until I hear his voice...
... till I look into his eyes.
Till I see him watching me
with that tender inquiring sort of a look
and I want to ask him what he's thinking about.
I'm terrified that he suspects something.
What can I do ? I've...
... I've avoided his arms and his kisses, but...
... that can't go on.
What am I going to do ?
What ?
Mary, what's this thing about
conscience and cowards ?
Lady Rexford.
Hello, Hetty.
Hello, dear.
Hello, Mary.
Hello, Sylvia.
Hello, Tommie.
Hello, stranger.
You look better, Mary.
Do I ? I feel fine.
Had a lovely walk across the park.
It was nice and fresh.
You do look well.
Whatever you're doing is doing you good.
Is the twinkle still there ?
I don't know. Is it ?
Let me see.
Yes, it's still there.
Way back in here eyes where Mary lives.
How pretty.
I wonder what's at the back of my eyes.
Rose pink clouds at sunset for you dear.
I like the rose pink, but why the sunset ?
I'm not setting, it sounds like a hen.
That's awful.
Well, Mary, what are we gonna do now ?
Tommie, I'm going to stay
right where I am, if I can.
Oh...
In the old ancestral home.
Yes
You haven't told Philip anything ?
She has not.
And no one else is going to tell him anything either.
How can you stop them, Mary ?
I may not be able to stop them,
but I can deny it.
Mary, do I warrant any consideration ?
Of course you do, Tommie.
But my first consideration is Philip.
I should have thought of that before
but I didn't.
All right, but there are
certain facts that should be faced.
Tommie, those facts must be forgotten.
Nonsense.
You can't keep gossip like that quiet.
Of course you can't.
That is true, Mary.
Don't you think I know what a fool I've been ?
I haven't closed my eyes for nights.
I've been trying and trying
to tell Philip the truth but I simply can't.
I'm afraid.
Not afraid for myself, but I'm afraid for him.
Mary, if you remember, in the country...
Tommie
So much has happened since then.
If I had only known before.
If I had only known how deeply,
how truly I do love him.
It's just a case of love at second sight.
I've made up my mind definitely to one thing.
There is something more sacred than truth.
That's protection.
To protect someone you care for from pain.
This thing would break him.
I realized that at St. Moritz.
He must never know. Never.
Fair enough, but Mary...
I'll lie, I'll fight, I'll do anything.
But there's never gonna be
anything else to lie about, ever.
Lord Rexford.
Philip.
Hello, dear.
Hello, Mary. What is it ?
Anything wrong ?
No, dear.
What a surprise. You'll stay to lunch.
Mary, why didn't you tell me he was coming ?
I didn't know.
I didn't know myself.
Well, I'm very flattered.
I had no idea I was in your better graces.
What made you suddenly make up your mind to look me up ?
I wanted to see Trent.
Yes, I heard you called.
Can I be of any service ?
Oh, yes, you can.
Well ?
I want you to stop annoying my wife.
Philip !
Philip, what do you mean ?
Dear, I'm asking him to refrain from annoying you.
That's simple enough, isn't it ?
No, I don't understand you.
Mr. Trent tried to phone you at St. Moritz.
Now I find him conveniently lunching here,
still intruding himself upon you.
The last thing that I wanted was to intrude.
Mary, was my telephoning you an annoyance ?
Well, it annoyed Philip, apparently.
As a matter of fact, Tommie wasn't lunching here.
He simply came by to pick up Sylvia.
We'll have to keep an eye on these two.
It's the third time this week
that they've lunched together.
What did they say of the corner table at The Embassy ?
Yes, but I've arranged...
Don't be a killjoy.
You want to be alone, don't you, Tommie ?
Oui, madame.
When I telephoned this morning
your man told me you were lunching here.
He's crazy, that man.
Aren't we all ?
Mary, did you expect to meet Trent Here ?
No. I did not.
It was just a coincidence ?
Yes. What's so strange about that Philip ?
Don't you believe me ?
I don't understand you.
It's only fair you should understand me.
It's probable I'm making a fool of myself
and it's just as probable
my suspicions are unfounded.
Philip, I don't know what's on your mind,
but wouldn't it have been fairer if you
had told me about this this morning ?
I intended to tell you after I'd seen Trent.
Do let us have lunch.
Come on, Tommie, let's go.
Goodbye, Mary.
Goodbye, Tommie.
I won't annoy you again.
I promise not to call you up even to inquire
the state of your health.
Although you know I'll always be interested.
Thank you, Tommie.
Have a good time.
No, I can't promise you that.
What's all this ?
Still jumping off balconies ?
As a matter of fact I could for Mary.
You see, I happen to love her.
No, Tommie, please.
Yes ?
I've asked her to leave you and marry me.
Tommie, what are you saying ?
Is this true ?
Do tou want to leave me for him ?
No, Philip, no.
Have you told him that ?
Yes, I have.
And he persists.
Yes, but I told him it's impossible.
Now what right have you...
Every right. I love her. I've seen her suffer.
Stop, Tommie, stop !
Mary, haven't I the right to...
No, that's not true. I beg you.
Tommie, please.
What are you all trying to hide ?
Philip, there's nothing to hide.
I came here to help you out of an embarassment.
Loving you and trusting you, Mary.
And what do I find ?
Nothing but a lot of hedging,
and dodging and denials.
That's your own imagination and your own jealousy.
But why wouldn't I be jealous ?
Yes if you have grounds, but...
You, your eyes, I've been watching you.
If you have anything to tell me, tell me now.
There's nothing.
Even he had the decency
to come and tell me to my face
that he's asked you to leave me.
Has he the right to ask ?
Have you given him the right ?
I don't know what you mean.
You do know what I mean.
You can't answer me, can you ?
Yes, I...
Mary.
You came back to me in St. Moritz.
You came back living a lie.
I didn't know anybody could be so...
I should have known what to expect.
I could answer so much.
But nothing I could say would justify what you've just discovered...
... and this time happens to be true.
I did try to lie to save you.
But lies, truths, faithful, unfaithful, right or wrong...
...our real tragedy is that
our love for each other isn't big enough...
... isn't strong enough as you said,
to overcome everything.
And neither of us is quite big enough.
So this time, Philip...
... it must be divorce.
I never knew that a punishment
could be so just and terrifying.
I know I must go, but...
I'll tell you the truth now.
If there was only one place that I ever really wanted to be...
... that was by your side.
This has been a horrible business.
She must be a very erratic woman.
No, not at all. She's enchanting.
Well, she'll be here. She's left her hotel.
Good.
Now I understood that the money
mentioned here is outside the original agreement,
... it's a gratuitous gesture.
To buy the child from her,
I think she has been punished enough.
Punished ? A clear name ?
And a handsome income.
What's happening ? Is she coming ?
Yes, she'll be here in a moment.
Well, we are ready for her.
Good morning, Sir Geoffrey.
I understand your client is sailing today.
Yes, so I understand.
It's all very confusing.
Thank you, I'll keep it.
Yes, milady.
No, Clarke. I can't see her possibly.
Couldn't trust myself.
Tell me...
How did the little birthday party go ?
Quite nice, milady.
We missed you.
I gave your present and read your little note.
Did you tell her I had gone away
on a great big boat ?
Yes. She doesn't quite believe it, though.
She asks for her mother
every morning and every night.
Does she ?
Couldn't you see her for a moment, milady ?
How could I ?
I guess I'd never let her go.
You shouldn't have to, milady.
It's a crime.
I thought for a moment I'd seen her hiding.
What was it ?
Something I wanted to ask you.
Oh, yes.
You might steal a couple
of those snapshots for me, would you ?
You know, the ones from last year by the sea.
Celeste couldn't find them when we left.
There's one with me running with her
and another one in the water. Remember ?
Yes, I know, milady.
Clarke.
Now, wait a minute... don't.
It's all right.
Hello, Mary.
Hello, David.
Philip.
Mary.
Sir Geoffrey.
I'm afraid I'm not
a very cooperative client, am I ?
Your maid said you had a cold and I believed her.
That was very sweet of you.
Mr. Farrington.
How do you do ? You know my brother, my partner ?
Yes, yes.
Well, Sir Geoffrey, what is it ?
You said it was important.
Yes. There is an agreement they want you to sign
taking your baby from you
and giving an income in return.
Well, I have an income.
Please don't be silly. You'll need money.
Philip, I want nothing.
You might regret this, Lady Rexford.
You've been awarded this baby and I'd be very happy...
That's very kind of you, Sir Geoffrey, but no.
Shall I read this ?
Couldn't I just write a simple note,
would that be all right ?
David, why don't you take it down ?
Yes, I will.
Dear Philip...
... Pamela stays with you...
... her father,
I have no claim on you or her whatsoever.
You have behaved most generously,
and I appreciate it.
All through your charming anxiety for my future.
Now, would you hurry with that, David,
so I can sign it before I go.
Yes, I'll have to hurry.
I doubt the legality of that note.
It's enough.
All right, if Lady Rexford won't change her mind.
I won't.
I believe you, Lady Rexford.
Come on.
I want to talk to you a minute outside.
There is nothing I can do for you before you leave ?
No, thank you. You have been very kind.
Well, what will the address be in New York ?
700, Park Avenue.
Will you see Pamela now ?
No, Philip.
Hurry up, David.
I want to sign that letter
before I go for your peace of mind.
You don't have to.
Why do you trust me ?
I'm sorry, Philip.
I didn't mean that to be a joke.
Well.
No, I couldn't say goodbye to you, Philip...
... any more than I could say goobye to Pamela.
I see.
You've been fine about that, Mary.
It's the least I could do for you, isn't it ?
When she grows up to be a big girl, I...
Funny to think of it, isn't it ?
Don't let her think me too bad, will you ?
No, I won't.
Thank you, Philip.
You made a pretty good job of it this time, Mary.
Anger, doubts, tears all have gone.
Just two polite little people.
Friends, though, really.
Oh, yes, of course.
When are you sailing ?
Tonight some time.
Would you mind if I come and see you off ?
Why, Philip ?
I don't know. I'm like you.
I find it rather hard to say goodbye too.
But we mustn't.
It's just a moment.
It's been every moment through it all.
Philip, you don't...
You don't mean that.
Here all these lawyers and people, hard at work,
all the machinery for parting us...
Even ourselves.
It can't be done, Mary. Can it ?
Can it, Mary ?
No, Philip.
Pam, my baby ! Pam, my girl !
Oh, my darling.
Oh, my sweetheart.
Here we go. Here we go.
Oh, my darling.
My darling !