DoReMii Fansubs and Intangible FS Presents
Why Why Love - Huan Huan Ai
Episode 8 brought to you by DoReMii Fansubs
Vist doremiiscale.blogspot.com to support us!
Get this for free @ d-addicts.com!
Over the mountains, over the oceans.
Over the obstacles, facing the dangers.
I still have to catch up, I still have to fly.
I am not afraid no matter how dangerous it is on the way.
Before dawn, I have to be ready.
Going forward on the roads. Being able to see my destination.
I won't regret. I am definitely right.
I want  an exciting  tomorrow.
Because of you, I will not back away.
I want to see my achievement progressing slowly.
Because love can make a dream fly.
No matter how much longer the road ahead of me is, I will overcome it all.
Every time I close my eyes,
I can only think of you, smiling at me.
I have surpassed it. Everything went smoothly.
Just need one more step, and I can reach my destination.
Translators: Sweetnocturne, debbie
Spot Translators: soph_iie, connie
Editors: rothedoe, rage, weimel
Timing: tipsytoto
Qc'in: tipsytoto
Sayings of the ancient people
really come true,
in life, 8 or 9 times out of 10.
The more the Good Family Virgin Girl doesn't want to see Miss Elegant,
the more likely it is that they'll meet.
How strange!
The master is not here,
yet you still come without notice.
Your suspicions are out of control again.
Not going to wait for Huo Da?
Leaving in such a rush
makes it seem even more suspicious.
Feels like you're sneaking around.
Are you trying to say
that I am a thief?
Jia Di isn't.
Precious Ah Xin,
why are you here?
Huo Da, you're back.
Were classes tiring this morning?
Yan Shu has already helped me find
a really good tutor.
Oh! that's great.
I came today
to render the last of my services.
Let's just say I accepted your three good deeds.
I'll give you some advice.
What advice?
Student Liu has arrived.
You still can be saved.
Good luck.
Bye.
Huo Da,
I helped you find the class' top student
to assist you in taking the exams.
Huo Da,
you're so popular.
At first, I thought that I was getting lucky with my love life...
Please help! Please!
But her coming to find me...
Was it also because of you?
With the support of the King of Awards,
I think you'll do fine on your exams.
Work hard!
I can return these to you.
Thank you.
Thanks for opening the door for me.
No problem.
What did you borrow his notes for?
Bo Zi,
don't you ever dare to
randomly let strangers in.
Let's not have this happen again.
But Liang Jia... Di
isn't a stranger.
Student Liu,
until the exams are held,
I'll leave Huo Da in your care.
No problem!
"What are the four P's in advertising?"
"If you can't even answer this question,
you don't have the right to watch TV."
Playing while working isn't bad,
but make time for both models and studying
so that you can succeed in both.
Writing these,
probably took a long time.
Getting my house all covered with these,
it looks awful.
Wow, doesn't she need to study for exams?
She used all her time on you!
And these are my notes from the whole semester.
She copied them all out,
and didn't even miss a single word.
"Studied this page?"
"You're very serious."
"Continue working hard!"
Huo Yan,
I'm at Huo Da's place.
I have already solved his problem.
How so?
The top student in Huo Da's class,
will start to tutor him from now on.
Being in the same class,
will make it more beneficial.
As for this Ms.Tong,
I've already talked to her.
What did you say to her?
I spoke truthfully.
What does that mean?
From the very beginning,
I haven't trusted her.
You don't have to make it sound so serious.
I don't ever want to see that girl again.
She's like a cockroach,
continuously interrupting our lives.
She didn't.
The relationship between Huo Da and her is very pure.
The one making me worry isn't Huo Da...
-Thanks. -It's you.
I cannot stand
the fact that you and Tong Jia Di
have this special thing going on.
I helped Huo Da find a tutor,
just to avoid seeing her again.
I don't want her to find any reason
to appear beside you again.
Huo Yan,
everything I've done
isn't for Huo Da.
It's for you.
Huo Da.
Don't misunderstand this.
Classmate, sorry for wasting your time today.
But,
because I am
naturally evil,
sitting beside you is very uncomfortable.
So?
So clean your things up,
drink a bit,
and leave.
-But... -There's no buts.
Didn't you hear me? Just Leave!
Even god wants to diffuse my anger.
This rain,
I don't think it'll stop anytime soon.
Let me entertain myself.
From this point on, the 10th guy who walks past,
I must...
I must go under his umbrella,
and have him take me to the station.
That Devil and Xiao Nan have
trained me to become so oblivious to humiliation.
I could even withstand
Miss Yan Shu's suspicions.
The 10th guy.
Hello? Jia Di?
It's me.
I know.
The 10th guy.
Let me tell you,
you probably won't have to worry, as
your brother will do fine on his exams.
This is because Miss Yan Shu
helped him find our class' top student to be his tutor.
That guy is really good!
If I were Huo Da,
what I would really need isn't some top tutor.
But rather someone who
would care for me as a friend.
This...
Miss Yan Shu can do this better than me.
Because...
I can only use silly methods.
I tried really hard
to get your classmate, Liu to help tutor you.
And you just kicked him out.
When will you be able to
understand other people's feelings?
When then, will you be able to
understand the feelings that I have for you?
We've known each other since childhood,
you're just like my little brother.
Our relationship is that of good friends,
caring for you,
being good to you,
it's a given.
Plus Huo Yan is so busy,
so taking care of you,
is also helping him.
Must the relationship between us
always include Huo Yan?
Don't force me.
This question has no answer.
To me,
you and Huo Yan are both equally important.
It's different.
In front of Huo Yan,
I am just a tool that you use to get closer to him.
In front of me,
Huo Yan becomes your protection.
Some feelings are true,
just like those of Precious Ah Xin.
Other feelings are fake,
and carry ambition.
Why?
Even our precious memories from childhood,
you use them for your own ambitions.
Huo Da!
Not studying?
What are you calling me for?
I should be asking you what you're doing!
I...
I'm eating Pork Rice.
Eating a lot.
To celebrate the end of our exchange coupons.
Hey. Listen up.
If you fail on your exams,
I'll teach you a really big lesson!
Pork rice, is it good?
It's very good.
It smells nice too.
Fool.
You must pass.
Once you pass,
if you call me a fool,
people will believe you.
I will for sure.
You better.
Don't suddenly give up half way.
I'll laugh at you if you do.
Like this
Hahahaha...
So humiliating.
Are you full?
If you're full, I'll come pick you up.
What for?
Why aren't you focusing on your studies?
Picking me up,
it's a waste of time.
Don't talk so much nonsense.
Hello? What a jerk.
Are you full?
If you're full, I'll come pick you up.
What for?
Why aren't you focusing on your studies?
Picking me up,
it's a waste of time.
Don't talk so much nonsense.
Hello? What a jerk.
Why are you treating yourself like this?
Look, your hands are so cold.
Get in the car.
I'll give you a ride home.
I thought
you already left.
Why did you let yourself get soaked like this?
Ever since we were children,
you've been like my little brother.
Being good friends,
caring for you,
taking care of you,
It's always been this way.
Now,
you even refuse
my sincerity,
mistrusting me.
In your eyes,
there is a lot of suspicion.
Why has it come to this?
Who is the one changing?
I'm not your little brother.
Saying I'm your little brother,
is just an excuse.
But I won't just stand
pretending and lying to myself.
Friendship, relationship,
they're all your perfect protection.
Protecting yourself,
and yet wanting to have this confusing bond with me.
Huo Da, you...
I refuse to continue acting like this.
From now on,
please don't question me,
or in front of others,
show that you
care for me.
Because,
either,
I get all of your feelings.
Or,
the relationship between us
is zero.
To me, you
are very important.
-But if there was no Huo Ya... -There are no ifs!
I accept zero.
I understand.
If that is your decision...
I'll try to accept it.
CEO,
thanks for driving me home.
Jia Di!
Huo Yan,
everything I've done
isn't for Huo Da.
It's for you.
There are no ifs!
I accept zero.
If that is your decision...
I'll try to accept it.
I knew that a rotten strawberry like you
would turn crazy while studying,
and try to destroy your books.
The strong rubber band won't allow you to deny my existence!
I'm very smart.
I demand you to pick up those books in 10 seconds,
and apologize sincerely to it.
Say "I'm wrong" three times,
Or else this house
will automatically explode.
10...9...
The fool skipped 2.
Facing a tough situation,
and want to drink beer like you usually do?
Please think again before you open the fridge!
There are only 2 choices.
Milk will allow you to drink and fight again
or beer will allow you to drink and get confused.
This is a once in a lifetime choice...
Please make it wisely!
My dear master,
please let me live a day longer!
Once you've passed your exams,
then with your cute tutor,
drink me ,and celebrate together.
A fool a million times over.
Work hard!
Precious Ah Xin.
Why are you back?
Study!
I must use the best of my abilities
and the best of my skills
to raise your exam battle energy
up to 100%!
Work hard!
Huo Da work hard!
Spirits of the heavens, spirits of the earth...
isn't it funny?
There's the Devil inside, no entrance for sleep.
You pig!
Wake up!
I knew you couldn't last until this page.
I... think I just had a dream.
This is the last of my notes.
Don't waste your life.
You can't waste any of it.
All of us humans,
are working hard to live.
You, who views life as garbage,
probably feels very lonely.
But inspite of your loneliness,
I can still see through you.
Because,
I have seen in you before,
the one who loves to race,
the one who seriously loves Miss Yan Shu,
and even...
the one who makes me smile,
and helped me wipe away my tears.
I believe that,
there are still things that are worth you being serious about.
This world,
probably isn't that bad,
right?
So...
this time, be serious for yourself
okay?
Winter holidays!!!
Whoah! So many things happened
to you in one day.
The 10th guy stayed at your house for the night.
And then?
Spill it!
I thought I already told you,
it's not possible between the 10th guy and me.
Did you?
I really don't understand.
The 10th guy is already
so great to you.
Tong Jia Di,
what on earth are you so frustrated about?
-I don't like the 10th guy anymore. -Liar.
I didn't.
Then why are you blushing?
I...
It's from yesterday's fever.
Right.
The fever burnt your head.
Why don't you like the 10th guy?
Right...
why?
After that night,
what happened?
I really want to know too.
That time...
I realize...
I think I fell in love with you...
Devil.
Was I dreaming,
or did I really say something like that?
The fever has really fried my brain.
If you don't give me a reason,
I won't allow you to not like the 10th guy.
If I don't like him, then I don't like him.
That's not true.
You're just running away again.
Whether you permit it or not,
I've already said my goodbyes to those two brothers.
Tong Jia Di,
don't go overboard.
When I said I liked Devil,
that's the time when I ended it with the 10th guy.
Even if it was only in my dream.
I'm okay.
Whatever it was,
At least I had some really great memories.
That's really awesome!
If I think about it,
it was really happy.
What memories?
If it's past, then they're memories.
The story hasn't ended yet.
Take it?
What?
"Happiness" Exchange Coupon.
Tong Jia Di, you have to be happy.
If that isn't enough,
"Forever Smiling" Exchange Coupon.
"God, Give me Love" Exchange Coupon.
"Moon God plus God of Love,
West-East combined together" Exchange Coupon.
"Bravery" Exchange Coupon.
Love really needs bravery
to face fake rumors.
Only your eyes make sure
that when I have love, it's worth it.
Xiao Nan,
you're so good to me.
Having you is enough.
Don't be like this.
This "friendship" Exchange Coupon
is only for when every other Exchange Coupon doesn't work,
then we use the ultimate secret weapon.
You're exchanging it too early.
I don't care.
I want to exchange it now.
Jia Di,
promise me,
try using these exchange coupons.
If working hard isn't enough,
I'll be here by your side.
I...
Well...
I don't like the 10th guy,
it's because I think...
What?
How to say it?
Listen.
My heart beats rapidly,
and I am not thinking right anymore,
it is all messed up.
The universities now are so open.
It's really messed up.
Listen.
My heart beats rapidly,
and I'm not thinking right anymore,
it's all messed up.
The universities these days are so open-minded.
That is what is really messed up.
Yeah.
They are so open that
even dirty-minded people like you
can enter.
Your sticky-notes,
were actually pretty useful.
Really?
So you passed your exam,
and won't get kicked out!
If the notes you copied for me were correct.
Even though the credit goes to Miss Yan Shu,
at least,
everyone is satisfied with the results.
I believe that your brother will be very happy also.
I worked so hard,
yet you only care about whether Huo Yan's happy or not.
Of course.
The reason why I'm happy
is because "everyone" is happy with the results.
Thank you.
Until the very end of the exams,
you chose not to give up.
You did something really great.
You're not that bad after all!
Thank you!
Because you reached your goal,
so...
So...
I can say goodbye to you without any hesitation.
What do you mean?
There are no endless parties, and
no endless exchange coupons.
So...
here right now, I have to say goodbye to you.
Great!
I don't have to be bothered anymore.
Right!
From now on,
there's no need for us to see each other again.
I can finally escape
your stupid girl annoyances.
Jia Di can finally escape
the torture from a Devil like you.
You, big noisy horn,
why are you talking so much.
I really want to celebrate.
Celebrate what?
Celebrate that your mouth is so big
that I could fit my fist in there?
You're so evil.
Jia Di, let's go.
Don't ever let those
stupid exchange coupons
appear again in my house.
And if you
break a leg,
go hungry,
or have unwashed underwear,
don't call me.
Let's go.
Don't talk to him.
Stand still.
I don't want to see
arrogant people walk away from me.
If someone has to leave,
I'll leave first.
"I realized,
that I have fallen in love with you,
Devil."
Mr. CEO.
Sorry, please continue.
Did you take a look at the plan I e-mailed you?
That your computer,
needs your fingerprint to open it...
I have some thoughts about that.
You want to look at the secrets on my computer?
Just kidding.
Last time you were at the hospital,
no one could turn on your computer.
There's so much information on your computer that we needed
that your secretary went crazy trying to find it.
In the end, I re-did everything.
Last time it was a car accident.
I promise,
if I leave one day,
I will copy all the information for you,
so you won't be frustrated.
The plan you sent, I received it already.
I'll take a look at it.
Mr. CEO,
the VIP party we held last time,
had a very good response.
Then I will leave the arrangements for the,
upcoming spring events to you
Organize some events that will captivate our customers.
Cai Juan.
Sorry, you come and visit me,
yet you still have to help me out.
We're good friends, don't say things like that.
If you talk like that, I won't talk to you,
and go back to Taipei.
Yu Hua, are you alright?
It's nothing.
Just a minor illness,
it'll be fine soon, it's nothing.
If I didn't come to visit this time,
I wouldn't have known that your health had become so poor.
Why is it that everytime you come to Taipei,
you won't let me know?
Why are you worried about me?
You're the one suffering more.
I'm only one person.
You have to take care of two children.
At least let me know
when you are sick.
Then I can be the one visiting you.
So you won't be the one visiting
me in Taipei everytime.
Actually...
actually I went to see my son.
Did you get back together with your son?
I just...
just quietly went to take a look.
As long as I can see him from afar,
it's enough.
He's living really well right now,
very handsome.
My original decision,
to send him away,
was indeed the right one.
It was right.
Right.
Devil!
What are you doing?
Are you crazy?
That was really dangerous.
Let me ride around for a little bit.
You haven't ridden a bike for ages,
can you manage?
How long has it been since you last dated?
It's been about...
two years since I have dated.
Then can you do it?
Can you?
Hey, there is no need for doubts.
Combine your question with your answer.
The way the Devil changes his gears
is still not smooth.
There are no endless parties and,
there are no endless exchange coupons.
So,
I'm here to say goodbye to you.
How was it?
Was it smooth?
Felt really bad.
It wasn't smooth at all.
Careful with the displays.
During holidays,
many professionals get their bonus and
go on a shopping spree.
For the upcoming two months,
every division should put in their best effort.
Especially the fashion section,
I think they should increase their outlets
Is there a problem?
No.
But...
increasing decorated outlets
means we need to add more salespeople.
We can mainly hire part-time students.
Yes, Manager Yang.
Hey Bo Zi,
No matter how I calculate,
I don't know where we can find this money.
Even if we save money
for two months.
Now,
we don't even have one-fifth of the fund.
How can we ever compete?
What are you talking about?
Nothing.
Didn't say anything.
You don't want this wealthy Devil
to know you guys are in straits.
This means
you guys are overly proud.
Don't use that face.
I'm not using money
to buy your fortitude.
Then don't care about it.
That's right.
You're wealth is your own business.
But your business is my business.
At least
this piece of the dream,
you will let me join, right?
So much crap.
After this is exposed,
you would still give us money.
Then do you want to reject me
or the money?
After knowing Taiwan A Shin,
for the first time towards money,
I have a different perspective.
Money is money,
what's different about it?
What's money?
What is it?
It's just a tool.
If it can't let the people I care
to have a meaningful life
but if I horde my money
and not help others,
then it is the same as being poor.
Devil Boy,
I think you have been enlightened by
Good Family Virgin, so you have a Buddha's heart now.
Even though
I don't want to use your money.
I don't want to reject your heart either.
When you go back,
quickly phone to find people.
Yes.
Group leader Lin,
I'm pregnant.
So starting next week,
I want to have two months of maternity leave.
There are already not enough workers.
Okay...
When I find a replacement,
I'll let her take over.
Thanks group leader Lin.
Xiao Ru,
remember to find experienced workers.
Or else when we're busy,
we'll need to train them.
Yes.
Okay, get back to work now.
Hello Xiao Nan,
This is group leader Lin from Huo Shi department store.
I'm not going.
But I've already promised her.
Since it's winter break now.
Ok,
then you go.
I can find another job.
I've told you already,
I don't want to be related with those two brothers anymore.
I'm...not going to Huo Shi.
But...
I'm going to the office to make a phone call.
Ken, why are you here?
Have you told Tong Jia Di yet?
Hey, I was having an exam before,
so I forgot to tell you...
Where are you? So loud.
Where's mom?
How's Auntie Xin?
What is it?
I'm telling you
that our uncle's loan
has already been paid.
You and mom can come back.
Let me stay here longer,
then I'll come back.
Where's mom?
Let her pick-up the phone.
Hey, the phone signal is weak,
I'll call you later.
What's up?
You still have to report to your parents when you come out?
Of course not!
Why would I care about them?
The batteries ran out.
Your phone call has been transferred to voicemail,
a fee would be charged after the "beep" sound.
If not, please end the phone call.
Speed message is after the "beep" sound...
Since you're already
friends with everyone in this Agency,
we will get you a job.
Don't worry.
Thanks.
I've already given all my money to you.
Then get Tong Jia Di to lend me some more.
But...
Jia Di has her own difficulties back home
Then are you saying that she is more important than your boyfriend?
Ken,
the love between us,
other than money,
what's left?
I think that the answer to this question
should be answered by you.
Ken!
Don't go!
Don't be like this.
Listen to me.
Ken!
Taiwan A Shin,
I'm not gonna annoy you anymore.
I'm going home.
Xiao Nan is $3000,
$5000,
$4000,
$7500.
The total amount that I owe her is $24 500.
My salary from the gas station,
has reduced due to money I loaned Uncle.
There's not even $3000 left.
That kid doesn't look too bad.
We can make some money from him.
Why do you need this money?
Because Bo Zi is going to a national competition,
and they need the fee expense.
There are no "free lunches" in this world.
Other than your daily expenses,
I am not responsible for giving you anymore money.
I knew you wouldn't give me money easily.
What do you want me to do?
Why do you need this money?
Because Bo Zi is going to a national competition,
and they need the fee expense.
There are no "free lunches" in this world.
Other than your daily expenses,
I am not responsible for giving you anymore money.
I knew you wouldn't give me money easily.
What do you want me to do?
You should know.
Dad has mentioned many times,
that you shouldn't waste the winter break.
During my first year in university,
dad had arranged for me
to be trained in the company.
Isn't this just to monitor me?
Huo Shi Department store doesn't need me at all.
It seems like
you don't need the money.
Are you threatening me?
Should I say that you are awesome
or despicable?
Which division?
My general manager office,
or Yan Shu's marketing planning department?
Or do you want to ask dad for suggestions?
I can make my own choices.
During this time, it is as busy as the holidays.
Unless you have an emergency,
you cannot skip work.
There are three shifts.
I will explain your jobs,
now that you are used to the area.
In the employee manual,
there are things that you need to be aware of.
If there are any questions,
check the employee manual.
Or you can observe how others work.
Basically it is because you two are experienced.
So,
I hope you will be able to handle the workload without instruction.
Welcome!
Elevator's going up.
Standing for a whole day, so tired.
Elevator's going up!
Which floor are you going to?
My throat has completely dried up.
You two are wearing uniforms.
Does that mean you are working here?
Yes, Yan Shu.
please give us lots of advice in the future.
I'm really impressed.
I think your sentence isn't finished yet.
If you're impressed with Jia Di,
there should be a reason.
It is because she found so many means
of approaching Huo Yan.
Exchange coupon,
birthday wish, wanting his phone number,
becoming his nurse,
study partner.
Now you are an employee in Huo Shi.
You've really tried hard.
You got the wrong person.
You should be impressed with me.
All of the things mentioned above
were my brilliant plans.
These are all my merits.
So you should admire
Jia Di for having such a good friend!
I don't think so.
Mostly I have my own opinions.
I don't need friends who believe they are intelligent.
Ms. Yan Shu.
Although I really want to be impressed with myself.
I have to tell you that all of those incidents
were purely because of the destiny they share.
Even though you have known the 10th guy for a long time,
and grew up together.
But,
Jia Di and him are truly destined to be together.
This is not true.
Yan Shu,
I've never had such intentions.
It's okay.
The fact that you so vehemently defend youself,
makes me more suspicious.
In retrospect,
I feel that your friend
is more honest than you.
Your personal life,
I have no need for an explanation.
Because I don't even want to listen to it.
That's wasting my time.
In your job,
please do what you should be doing.
Or else,
it is also wasting time.
Even a peacock isn't that proud.
Wasting time...
you are wasting my air!
This is a washroom.
Oh yeah,
didn't you say you didn't want this job
just because you didn't want to see them?
Really?
I said that?
Although in my life,
I have many principles that I follow,
if there are larger issues at play I
am willing to overlook them.
Then what are these larger issues?
Of course it is getting over my money issues.
Right.
Money...
is very important.
Group leader,
thanks for hiring me as a substitute.
But,
I need to get part of my salary in advance.
If you need us,
Xiao Nan and I can come help.
Get your salary in advance?
You have so many requests!
Fine.
Thank you group leader!
At least we are already here.
Let's strive and make money!
Cheer up!
Xiao Nan, my angel!
This is destiny!
Why are you here?
Not only me,
also...
You...
I'm working in your family's department store.
Because of Huo Yan,
you've really sacrificed yourself.
What?
Whatever.
I don't care what you think.
Want me to help you,
future eldest sister-in-law?
You...
I'm working in your family's department store.
Because of Huo Yan,
you've really sacrificed yourself.
What?
Whatever.
I don't care what you think.
Want me to help you,
future eldest sister-in-law?
I just want to work here.
That is my only purpose.
Devil Boy,
first it is Yang Yan Shu,
then it's you.
You guys are continuously mass-criticizing Jia Di.
What is the deal?
Do you have to be this insulting?
It's me that made him misunderstood.
I think it is because,
there are so many places in Taiwan that are hiring people.
But I chose here.
If you really think I have something else planned
and cannot distinguish between personal and business matters,
I can leave.
You want to show off your strength of spirit again.
Boring.
Even if someone cannot distinguish what's personal and business matters,
it's not you.
It's him and Yang Yan Shu.
Do you know
your face looks like
it deserves a beating
right about now.
Beat me if you dare.
I'm not the same type of person as you.
Good girls won't fight with a Devil.
I'm going back to work.
Xiao Nan!
Go away Si Da Bo.
If you don't want to be killed in Huo Shi,
just buzz off!
Xiao Nan, let me and you...
Go away! You're so annoying!
Don't be like this.
Go away!
Xiao Nan.
So annoying!
At least this is the back stairs.
If this was a window,
We would have fallen off the building.
You're so scared that Yan Shu might see you.
Then you could just treat me like air
or an invisible person.
You sure?
I'm sure!
Then, we will not mind each other's business.
Just what I wanted.
I can make you regret now.
You could still flatter me now.
I will be a salesperson,
and you be your Huo family Devil.
We are not related at all.
Why should I flatter you.
Because I could help you.
I could help you woo Huo Yan.
Even you think that I work here
to get his attention.
Good Family Virgin,
you're good enough!
Are you an unsalable product?
You're an excessive person!
Criticizing me,
make fun of me,
laughing at me.
That is what makes you feel balanced right?
Why wouldn't I be balanced?
You like Ms. Yan Shu,
Yan Shu likes the general manager.
So you're venting your rage on me!
I'm not.
I'm treating Yan Shu like...
When I see her,
my heart is...
beating impulsively!
Why are you giving suggestions
about my relationship with her?
Then stop spouting nonsense in front of me!
Stop it! Let go!
You...
The person who likes Yang Yan Shu
shouldn't be grabbing my hand.
It's not because of her!
It's not because of her?
You like her!
If you don't shut up then I'll kiss you.
The person who likes Yang Yan Shu...
It's so easy to befuddle the senses of a Good Family Virgin.
You almost fell into the trap.
Why should I kiss you when I don't like you?
It's so fun playing with you.
So I won't treat you like air.
I don't care if there's no exchange coupon.
I have already figured it out.
You can't get rid of me.
Good Family Virgin's miserable life
is an extremely a sorrowful story of
being tortured by the Huo Da Devil.
Welcome!
Elevator's going up!
Excuse me,
which floor do you want to go to?
General manager,
I have some business matters
to report to you.
What can I do for you?
I think
the general manager should care more about the lower level employees.
What do you think I should do?
All of the solutions
are written on this paper.
"Can the General Manager please care about the lower level employees."
"Jia Di is working in the women's fashion section."
Devil,
so my angel, Xiao Nan is working here!
Then what about this,
tell your brother
to let me work here
as payment for the fee.
Don't even think about it.
He just wanted to make me feel controlled, don't you get it?
I finally have this chance.
Help me think of a way.
I'm just the same as you.
What's the same?
Having the advantage of being close to somebody.
Didn't I tell you already
I've already spoke to Yan Shu
clearly about it.
Her answer was a "zero" relationship.
I'm not talking about her.
What does that mean?
Did you really not realize?
When you saw Jia Di,
your facial expression
changed almost 300 times in one second!
Anxious and nervous,
astonished and delighted.
Continuously ever-changing.
Who's listening to you talking crap?
It's true alright?
A whole complicated face.
Young Huo Da's worries...
You idiot!
How can it be possible?
Fine, if you don't admit it.
The main point is me!
Please help me.
Have the advantage of being close to somebody.
When I say it three times.
Then it's true.
Bye bye bye.
Fine...
To be honest,
help me if we're friends.
Can you hear me? Have the advantage of being close to somebody.
Hey~this is the scene of Why Why Love
Huo Shi department store.
The part that we're screening is
the first day that Huo Da is going to work.
Let's see what's happening now!
Actually today I am...
Today I have about 8 scenes,
and I have a lot of lines to memorize.
So...
I am a little distraught.
Is that because of your flu?
There are a lot of lines.
Oh, yes.
Since I took pills already,
I am feeling really dizzy now.
Now we are waiting for this...background music.
We can only shoot after the music's turned off!
The background music is a large distraction
to the shooting.
But during this time, Chuan Yi
started dancing.
Then what about Xiao Mei who is standing aside?
What would I do if my family had a department store?
Don't need to work.
Don't need to work, everyday like this.
You don't need to act in dramas anymore.
No, I would still act in dramas.
Then many people would say:
"He Jun Xiang, lend us your family's department store to shoot a drama!"
Yes, yes, ok!
Xiao Mei, you really know how to imagine!
Then Chuan Yi
suddenly started shopping!
Do you like it?
*Acting cute*
Are you inspecting?
Because I need to cultivate the feeling of
being a general manager.
Xiao Mei and Cheng Lin are a
pair of enemies who like to argue.
Actually, outside of the drama,
they are also the same,
and really like to argue.
Good Family Virgin, you're good enough!
Are you an unsaleable product?
You're an excessive person!
If he's excessive then you should beat him!
Raise your hand and slap, then
-slap and then... -You're an excessive person!
*It smashed into pieces!*
Then the hand was smashed.
You could still suck up to me now!
*Shaking*
What are you doing?
I'm shivering.
These two
when they are rehearsing,
looks like they have great tacit understanding.
But...
Good Family Virgin, you're good enough!
You're an unsalable product!!
You're an excessive person!!
Cut!
What are you grabbing?
Grabbing what?
I grabbed her sleeve.
Good that it was long (the background).
Great...
What are you grabbing?
Sorry!
Director! By saying that,
Xiao Mei's pose now
looks like
grabbing..."Just like the touch of a salty pig hand"~ (salty pig hand=perverted man)
It's not because of her!
It's not because of her?
You like her!
If you don't shut up then I'll kiss you.
*Shyness*
Idiot!
Then I'll say
why would the person who likes Yan Yan Shu want to kiss me?
So annoying, I'm so immature~
Why would the person who likes Yan Yan Shu want to kiss me?
*Acting in a pettishly charming matter*
Aiya!
Aiyo, both of them even kissed before,
why would they be so shy
after saying this line~
So immature!
Why would the person who likes Yan Yan Shu
*Xiao Mei, what kind of face expression was that?*
Ho ho ho...
It's so easy to cheat on a Good Family Virgin.
You almost fell into the trap.
Why should I kiss you when I don't like you?
It's so fun playing with you.
*He's crazy!*
So I won't treat you like air.
I have already figured it out.
I don't care if there's no exchange coupon.
You can't get rid of me.
Good Family Virgin's miserable life
is extremly a sorrowful story of
being tortured by the Huo Da Devil.
An extreme sorrowful story.
Why should I kiss you when I don't like you?
It's so fun playing with you.
Sorry!
Forgot your line?
Yeah, forgot the line.
It's so fun playing with you.
Someone forgot their line!
You just recorded it
just because you're lucky.
I rarely forget my line.
Mostly it's her that forget lines.
How could I?
I'm the queen of memorizing!
I'm a memory master!
You're the wrong memory master.
I'm a memory hunter!
Ha!
Those two started to argue because of NG.
Also, the arguement continued to
the next scene.
-I've already memorized it at home. -Who is it?
-It's not your business. -Who is it?
Don't need to record him.
Don't record... don't record him.
Everyone is getting their script booklet here.
Okay?
You always get it and give it to the people in your company.
I don't have people in my company~ So you know.
I've already memorized it all at home!
I'm recording!
She doesn't have people in her company right?
Here, I'm recording.
I'm recording, people in her company, you see.
At last, Xiao Mei who's recording
was blamed by Cheng Lin again.
He Jun Xiang doesn't have any abilities!
He can't even record with a video camera!
I'll forgive Yang Cheng Lin today
just because of that thing coming.
Fine.
Even when they love to argue,
the director also should be responsible.
Because director
really likes to create arguements for them.
Would this be to make them act more realistic in the drama?
Director: At this time you can see them looking at each other,
and we went into a trance.
When you chop me with a knife, I'll slash you with a sword!
I thought you were professional.
When you see them in the NG...
Oh yes~ excuse me.
It's Cheng Lin's fault.
I hope so!
-Because her mood affects the whole team's mood! -Because my shadow is too beautiful!
-Her coming would affect the whole team's mood. -You really don't...
Do you have to tell the whole world about this?!
Jiu gao su quan...
Quickly sing!
Singing is his weakness.
He can't sing.
Even in the elevator,
they can continue to argue!
*Hurts~(in Japanese)*
It really hurts~
Violent person.
Quick! Take revenge!
Hey~ If you do that she'll feel uncomfortable.
He is bullying me.
After seeing how you treat
money as your purpose in life,
my perspective and personality have changed.
I have decided that I want to improve myself,
so during this winter break,
I'll be getting a job.
The job that I will be taking on is...
Huo Shi department store's management employee.
You don't need me to remind you
that since you're working here,
you should be aware of your actions.
I hope that you can meet our standards.
I think that you're worried that I am causing trouble.
Don't worry.
I know I'm really handsome.
but I won't flirt with others.
But it works both ways,
I would like to see if you can pull off the same thing.
I know that you wouldn't be
dating with the
company's employees.
Of course I won't.
I hope so.
Why would Xiao Nan and the Devil be hugging together?
Why would Xiao Nan look at me like that?
What happened?
You may want to fire Jiang Xiao Nan,
but I don't agree.
I hope that today's incident
can teach you a lesson.
You should now realize
that if you are working,
you can't just fool around,
and do whatever you want.
It would only affect more innocent employees,
or potentially make them lose their job.
The person who is cutting jobs here
is you.
Correct.
But before I do so,
there is a person who gets them into that situation.
That accomplice is you.
My lips curl into a smile unknowingly
Are these the symptoms of bliss?
My heart starts to pound.
Thinking of you, I become breathless.
I start to blush and breathe unnaturally.
Are these the symptoms of bliss?
I become breathless, again.
Spring arrives slowly, bit by bit.
The moonlight shines, but can't see the sadness.
In the field in front of the merry go round.
Love starts to blossom.