PRESENTED BY - Big_A_Little_A
DOWNLOADED FROM  - Extratorrent.com
SEEDED BY - Novalayer.net
Good luck, General Yin.
A man must do or die.
Mr Ho, before I left,
Lord Cheng is concerned about you.
If he can strike back with his army
and defeat the tartars,
credit for Canton will be yours.
One must sacrifice for one's country.
The 6 brothers arrested by tartars
were tortured but have so far
refused to make a confession.
This is most admirable.
If I fail,
I wouldn't even get arrested.
General Yin...
Mr Ho, please.
Sirs,
when Inspector-gen.
and Gen. Tien Ta
arrive, please say a good word for me.
Don't worry, Mr Magistrate,
General Tien Ta ordered us
to capture the 6 traitors.
The Inspector
will supervise the execution.
Yes, yes.
Tang San-yao, it's almost 12.30.
Don't forget the General's command.
The Inspector-general is here.
Make way.
We're trapped!
General Yin, I knew you'd be here
to "Welcome" the Inspector-general,
but he has not yet reached Canton!
Stop.
Your skill is comparable to a general.
Let's have a fair fight:
A General to a General.
Let me try you out.
Good, I need a substitute.
Let me fight you single-handedly.
Quiet down,
the teacher's here
The teacher's here, hurry up...
Mr Ho.
What's it?
What's happened to Mr Ho?
Mr Ho.
Please have some tea, Mr Ho.
Mr Ho, why are you so late?
Did you watch the execution?
Leave me alone!
Isn't it enjoyable to watch executions?
Lin Zhen, it depends on who it is.
If it is the tartars who invaded us,
of course it is gratifying.
But today's convicts are patriots.
They are all Han's martyrs.
Do you still think it is enjoyable?
I...
Yesterday, I taught you sacrifice
for the sake of a righteous cause.
Do you all understand?
Yes.
Hurry up...
It's here.
Is he dead or alive?
He's so stiff, of course he's dead.
He's a hero.
What did you say?
I...
- Arrest him.
- Yes.
You're an accomplice.
Lord Tang... Listen to me.
This student is not a bad man.
He's the son of a seafood shop owner.
Son of a shop owner?
Yes, exactly.
These are his classmates.
Yes, we're his classmates.
Where are you studying?
They all study in Chong Wen College.
Are you vouching for them, Mr Wang?
Yes. Apologise to Lord Tang.
I...
You're young and ignorant.
Always causing trouble.
Do you know who I am?
I do. Tang San-yao, Lord Tang.
Yes, let's go, quickly!
- Uncle Wang, we didn't do anything wrong.
- Yes, I know.
Tang San-yao's notorious
for his craze after money and women.
You mustn't antagonise him.
As the saying goes, "One must..."
"...humble oneself under enemy's rule."
Mr Ho... please open the door!
Who is it?
Mr Ho.
Open the door, Mr Ho.
Mr Ho!
What's wrong?
I...
There's something we don't understand.
So we've come here even at this hour.
Humble oneself under enemy's rule.
Do we and our children have to
humble ourselves forever?
I'd say, we'd be beheaded if we didn't.
If we fear not death we don't have to.
You're right. It's well said.
One brave man alone is not enough,
but unity is strength.
The tartars are well-armed.
We...
Man owes allegiance to his country.
Lord Cheng is recruiting in Taiwan.
He's become tartar's biggest concern.
The Manchurian emperor has ordered
coastal residents to move away
and to be on their guard.
Mr Ho, I wish Lord Cheng could use us.
The day will come.
Don't you all want to help?
Yes.
Good. Come here.
Secret documents will arrive by sea.
I need a way to bypass customs.
Liu Yu-de, doesn't your pa
run a seafood shop?
Yes.
Open sesame.
Shut sesame.
Mr Ho sent us here.
Good.
Little brother, you're a brave fellow.
Lock it up...
Yes, hurry...
Pa, has San Li's abalone arrived?
The abalone... Go, go now!
It has... The sea cucumber has too.
Te, what are you doing?
A big order for abalone was placed.
I am showing them some samples.
So you're in business now?
- Te, you can't take the whole case.
- I'm in a hurry to deliver it.
Hurry?
Do you know the market price?
The quality's high.
Raise the price.
- Open it.
- Yes.
Excellent kung fu.
You'll find that at Shaolin Temple.
Mr Ho, we could invite them to...
Yes.
They don't involve in worldly matters.
If Shaolin taught kung fu to laymen,
people could fight the tartars.
That would be great!
Yue Shan, South gate... here.
General Tien,
Arise.
Come over here.
Lately, we've suppressed rebels
and found this on their leaders.
Zheng Cheng-gong's edict.
Look, what have you been doing?
There must be many of Cheng's men
hiding in Canton.
We must capture the rebels
and kill them to scare them off.
Who's that?
No idea. He's secretive, maybe a spy.
I'm innocent.
I'm a delivery boy.
I've brought dried fish.
Look!
Shut up.
Lord Zheng, notorious rebels...
- Who told you to bring this here?
- No... no use to ask me.
Kid, we'll take you away
and torture you one after another.
See how long you will hold your silence.
I'll talk... Don't torture me.
I... I say, there is someone.
Go on with the torture if you like!
I saw a squadron of Ching troops
of over 100 patrolling our alley.
Mr Ho, what shall we do?
We must keep calm and be on the alert.
Yien-pin, let them hide in your home.
Mr Ho, what about you...
- Mr Ho, Mr Ho.
- Go quickly, go!
- What about you?
- Hurry up, quick.
Master, look!
Please have mercy.
Please talk to them.
- Please ask them not to...
- Quiet!
General's order: No dried fish.
Then...
What's your relationship with Liu Yu-de?
He... he's my son.
Bring him here.
He's not home... What do you want him for?
We've uncovered many spies recently.
One's a teacher, another's his pupil.
Liu Yu-de's a pupil of that school.
We'll capture him and torture him!
Master, our young master won't...
Please have mercy.
How do you know he wouldn't?
Let's talk it over.
Pa...
Yu-de, run quickly... Yu-de.
Young Master, run, run quickly.
Run quickly, Young Master.
You want to rebel?
Yu-de, run quickly, run!
He's innocent! My son!
Liu Yu-de, come up quickly.
My son is innocent, my son!
- Change your clothes at once.
- I...
All wearing school uniform will be arrested.
Wonder what's happened to my home?
Try to find a hiding place first.
We can find out later.
Right, let's go now.
What has happened to my home?
Your home...
Tell me.
All the houses in the neighbouring street
to your home have been cordoned off.
What about my father?
Pa...
Don't be sad.
It's the same for mine.
I wish I had learned kung fu
instead of studying,
so I could fight them.
Studies teach us right from wrong.
What's the use of that?
We can't talk sense with the tartars.
We can't stay in this town anymore.
The martial arts headquarters is...
Shaolin Temple.
We're lucky we made it.
Let's go straight on.
Did you see a group of men riding by?
Why don't you answer me?
Let's go!
- Dismount and chase them.
- Yes.
These two must be traitors.
One watch the horses, others chase.
Yes.
Hurry up.
Let's go.
Liu Yu-de, mount it.
Liu Yu-de?
Liu Yu-de, escape now. Go!
Don't let him get away.
Liu Yu-de, good luck!
Please give me some water.
Thank you, uncle.
How far is it to Shaolin Temple?
It's not far, only up the mountain.
But it looks like you wouldn't make it.
I can... even if I have to crawl there!
Sit down. I don't think you can.
A few Shaolin monks buy food here everyday.
Their cart is over there.
Hurry up... Do it orderly and quickly.
Get going, go!
Why is it so heavy?
Yes, I don't know why.
Go. You'll be punished if you're late.
Let's go, quick!
Push harder, harder, go!
Hurry up, park the cart there.
Come and lend a hand, everybody.
Why are you standing there? Come here.
Take this to the kitchen. Be quick.
Why are you so slow? Hurry up...
What's the matter?
What's that man doing there?
Stay calm, he can still be saved.
Bring him inside. I'll tell the abbot.
Sir, the abbot would like to see you.
Thank you.
This temple is not a sanctuary.
You're spiteful and emotional,
unfit to stay in the temple.
You're recovering, please leave soon.
I had so much difficulty coming here.
I won't leave.
Don't be rude.
Splendid. We believe in fate,
and we believe fate has brought you here.
Brother, you mustn't make a precedence.
He arrived here in a coma
but woke up after 10 days.
Perseverance to Buddhism
warrants his admittance.
Dharma also came to the east
with such perseverance
and laid the foundation of Shaolin.
What are your opinions, brothers?
You're right, brother.
Thank you abbot.
Morning, sir.
- Morning, sir.
- Morning.
San Ta, San Ta.
Morning, sir.
How long have you been here?
Over a year.
Are you unable to endure destitution?
No, not that, but...
Don't hide anything from the Buddha.
Before I came here, I heard
Shaolin's the headquarters of kung fu.
But for the past year, I have only cleaned.
I haven't seen any kung fu.
You can learn kung fu if you want to.
As long as they want to, any monk
can learn from the 35 chambers.
If you don't tell us, who would know?
Why do you want to learn kung fu?
Honestly, sir,
before I came here, I saw the people
oppressed by tyrannical rule.
If they were able to learn kung fu,
they could defend themselves
and combat enemies. Therefore...
Good, good, San Ta.
Buddhists shouldn't bear such thought.
Don't mention it again!
I won't abandon such a desire.
Whatever the outcome, I won't dare complain.
Sir.
Can I still learn kung fu?
There're 35 chambers in Shaolin.
Which chamber do you want to start with?
Which is the most advanced?
The top chamber, of course!
Then I'll start from the top.
Sir.
Behold, the Buddha says:
"Emptiness is the Eternal Five."
No sight, sound, smell, taste, sense.
The five flavours dull the taste.
The five tones deafen the ear.
The five colours blind the eye.
It can also not be seen,
but it won't pass away.
Being at one is eternal.
But all things will come to you.
Without wisdom... without...
Leave!
No wisdom, no gain.
Gaining is not continuant.
All men will come to me once.
For there lies rest
and happiness and peace.
It's invisible and inaudible.
And it's inexhaustible.
Can you hear the sound of bells?
The heart is calm. We hear nothing.
How often do you recite the sutras?
I... I...
Go away!
Sir, I came to learn martial arts.
Get out!
No one learns martial arts here.
This is the most advanced field.
You won't understand it.
I'm willing to start from the bottom.
Cross the pond to enter dining hall.
Yes.
Brother, this is the 35th chamber?
Shut up. You starve if you're late.
A pure body is light, steps stable, stance is firm.
Don't enter the hall if you're dirty.
How dare you enter this dining hall?
Sir, I want to...
Have congee?
Come with me.
Stand on the wood.
Jump.
Turn around!
Eat!
Get up, you're hopeless.
Clean all the pottery and cutlery.
Wall is low, power of Buddha is high.
He's fallen into it.
Don't laugh, he's only a novice.
- Enter the dining hall.
- Yes.
San Ta, you're terrific...
Concentrate. You'll find a way.
Keep practicing day and night. Go!
Stop!
Wood drifts, its buoyancy is limited.
The harder you step, faster it sinks.
- San Ta.
- Yes.
Throw the plate hard into water.
The plate sinks in water.
Just like the wood you stepped upon.
I keep the plate in motion, balanced.
Power takes you forward.
Firmness balances the body.
Uniformity of mind
focuses power.
You must keep this point in mind.
Power, balance, speed.
Power, balance, speed. Right.
Sir, I...
Go!
I beg you to teach me, master.
The 34th chamber focuses
on training arms' strength.
Fist, palm, knife, sword, pole, spear.
All depends on the arm's strength. Look...
This is the basic process.
Carry the water up the slope.
Pour it down to keep it flowing.
Remember, arms must be straight.
You should carry water everyday
to build up arm strength. Go now.
Yes.
I didn't think you'd make it so soon.
Don't help others when they practise,
it'll only ruin them.
Yes.
You've violated our rule. Leave...
Sir.
Go to the 33rd Chamber.
Thank you, sir.
This chamber is comparatively easier.
Whenever you hear me knock the wood,
strike the gong.
Sir, I'm here to learn kung fu, not...
Don't belittle the bamboo poles. Ji Wei.
Yes.
The hammer weighs 10 catties.
It is fitted into a 12-ft pole.
With a foot-long pole,
hammer weighs 10 catties.
With the pole extended,
it now weighs 120 catties.
How much can your wrists bear?
I'm willing to try.
Add on 2 more feet.
Ready...
Keep practising.
My respects to the abbot.
You've left the Wrist Room?
Yes, the overseer said I could leave.
Good. Starting today,
as a reward for your diligence,
you'll be in charge of Sutra Room.
Thank you, abbot.
Brother, San Ta is ambitious.
He's not like our Buddhist brothers.
It's peaceful here in this temple,
but outside it's turbulent.
We may need someone like him.
Please guide me, sir.
Stand between the two burning incense.
Yes.
Anyone practicing martial arts
must be sharp-eyed. Watch the flame.
When the flame oscillates,
your eyes should follow.
But remember,
your head must not move. Start.
Told you not to move your head. Again.
Right, the target has disappeared.
But still, the eyes shouldn't move.
Eyes be bright, limbs be agile.
This is the way to do it.
Yes.
Turn around.
San Ta, hit the reflecting poles.
You're my most outstanding pupil.
Thank you, sir.
Head Chamber
Continue.
Don't lower your head. Stand up.
Hands on your waist.
Use your head to hit the sand bags,
then burn incense before the Buddha.
Yes.
Again.
Get up.
Sir, I...
Collapse so soon? Get up now.
Continue. Go on.
Sir.
San Ta. Were it not for 2 years' hard work,
you might not even take one step into this alley.
San Ta, head is the most important
and the last phase in the training.
After going through it,
you can learn fighting and weapons.
Offer the incense.
Use your strength to hit it. Get up!
Come on, get up!
You've set a new record.
You've completed the basic skills
of the 10 chambers in 25 months' time.
I can't do it without the teachers.
You can now practise boxing,
knife, baton and other skills.
Yes.
Justice Officer.
I'll make him head of Dharma House.
San Ta, greet these two abbots.
Yes.
Stop!
Continue!
San Ta!
Leg Chamber
Sir.
San Ta, not bad, not bad.
Sword Chamber
Turn around faster.
Good fellow.
San Ta.
San Ta, it's commendable of you
to master all 35 chambers' kung fu
in only 5 years.
Now I'll make you deputy overseer of
any of the 35 chambers.
Brother, San Ta's post is high enough.
He's been promoted 8 times in 5 years.
With his present skill,
he's qualified to be deputy overseer.
Shaolin arts has existed for 1000 yrs.
We mustn't make a hasty decision.
In my opinion.
Let him fight me with any weapon.
If he wins, he can be an overseer.
You heard what he said.
What do you think?
I dare not.
It's my idea. If you win
you can take charge of any chamber.
Excuse me then, sir.
Watch out.
Thank you, sir. I've lost.
You may challenge me any time.
How many times have I tapped you?
17 times.
I could've hurt you with the blade.
You're right.
I'll continue with my practise.
Brother, I think he'll never win.
Not necessarily.
What weapon is San Ta using?
A three-jointed stick invented by himself.
Good, that blow was not bad.
Go on!
Sir, are you alright?
San Ta, I still have my weapons.
Excuse me.
Abbot,
San Ta can take charge of any chamber.
San Ta, you can choose to take charge of
any of the 35 chambers except
the Top Chamber. Your Buddhism
attainment is not advanced enough.
Abbot,
I've not yet made up my mind.
Never mind. I'll give you 3 days.
Thank you, abbot.
There're only 35 chambers in Shaolin,
there isn't a 36th chamber.
I know. I'd like to create it.
This 36th chamber is...
It's a pity Shaolin martial arts
is confined solely to the temple.
It should be taught widely to all.
That's my idea for the new chamber:
to teach martial arts to laymen.
We don't involve in worldly affairs.
Nor do we admit secular pupils.
Forget it.
Abbot, this affects the handing down
of Shaolin martial arts to posterity.
Please let me enrol promising youths
and train them in the 36th chamber.
Nonsense, how dare you talk back?
I don't mean to...
Shut up!
I must ask you to reconsider, abbot.
Justice Officer.
Yes.
Our pupil San Ta should be punished.
San Ta, you've violated our rule.
You have to collect contributions.
Don't return unless the book is full.
Yes. Abbot, I deserve punishment.
Leave tomorrow morning.
You want to pray for Chiang Tai?
They all died.
They were buried in East cemetery.
Go there and pray for them.
Uncle Wei, may you rest in peace. We will
complete your mission
and restore the Ming rule.
Hung Hsi-kuan.
Hung Hsi-kuan, I knew you'd be here
to bury your accomplices.
Run!
Go!
See if you can escape.
Good! I'll kill you one after another.
Go ahead and try.
Tang San-yao, you're so malicious.
Your vice will be punished.
Scram, bloody monk.
Master, please stay out of this.
So you're an accomplice.
Tang San-yao, remember 7 years ago,
you confiscated my school and my shop
and kill my whole family?
You're Liu Yu-de, a fugitive! Get him.
- Go help your brothers.
- OK!
You're a Buddhist, show mercy.
Even Buddha has to conquer evil.
A monk should not kill.
A monk cannot but I can. I'll do it!
Tang San-yao, you've killed my men.
I'll stab you 1,000 times!
Amitabha Buddha.
Thank God. Today, our martyrs
can see you lying dead here.
Master, I want to learn martial arts.
Please accept me as your pupil.
Good. I've come from Shaolin
to enrol promising youths.
Hsi-kuan, is Tien Ta still in Canton?
Yes.
His hand is stained with Han's blood.
We must eliminate him at all costs.
We'll plan well.
Find a hideout first.
Don't act rashly.
Do you know of other hot-blooded youths?
Yes, Tung Qian-jin is another.
Tung Qian-jin, Commander's orders.
Make a batch of wheels.
Deliver them within one month.
I can't, it'll take one year.
One year? Are you turning me down?
Do you want to join the dead?
Want my help?
I'll teach you to be smarter.
Beat him up!
Are you going to do it or not?
Not over my dead body.
It is better to use the haft.
Help!
Do you still want the wheels made?
No, no!
Damn you!
Good! Good!
Master, Master!
Master... Let me follow you.
Why?
I admire you. Please accept me as your disciple.
Please take me as your pupil.
Tung Qian-jin, what's wrong with you?
You said you won't submit to anyone
and will challenge even the Gods?
Why are you kowtowing to a monk now?
What do you know? He's not a monk.
He's a Bodhisattva.
He only said several words.
And I scared the tartars away.
So he's a living Bodhisattva?
I'm only a monk from Shaolin Temple.
I taught you to avoid direct conflict.
They've learnt kung fu, you haven't.
Using a heavy weapon slows you down
and puts you at a disadvantage.
Right.
Lu Ah-cai, are you convinced now?
Master, it makes sense.
Lu Ah-cai, can you move?
Lu Ah-cai, don't make hasty moves.
Master, I'm convinced.
Are you sure now?
I am, I'm convinced.
Master, please come in for some tea.
Master, I'm really convinced.
How did Tang San-yao die?
You still haven't found out yet?
He was chopped by a knife.
I only want the man who chopped him.
Yes, we're investigating.
Kill all suspects.
Yes.
You must be on the alert.
This is General Tien Ta's residence.
He patrols the city every day,
and he must pass through this street
when he goes to the city gates.
Shops on both sides of the street
made it difficult for us to get him.
Any households on this street?
Yes.
There is a rice-miller's shop.
Back to back with the General's residence.
- Are there many people living there?
- There seems to be only one person.
Sir...
Amitabha Buddha.
Sir, I...
No one would come for offerings this late.
What are you doing? Go away.
What do you mean by that?
Sir, please excuse me.
What do you want?
May I know your name, sir?
My father died
without telling me my name.
So I have no name.
I started milling rice when I was six,
so they call me Miller Six.
I'm San Ta. I'm from Shaolin Temple.
People say that monks from Shaolin
are excellent at kung fu. No wonder...
I've practised for several years.
Having milled rice for many years...
I also have a pair of strong feet.
Do you want to try them?
I've drunk a bit too much today.
But your footwork's not bad.
Let's go in for a drink. Let's go!
You can't stay here much longer.
Why not?
Very soon, something big will happen
in the General's residence.
What is it?
General Tien Ta's going to die here.
How can you say something like that?
Aren't you afraid of being executed?
I beg you to leave here at once, please!
I don't care whether you came from,
Shaolin or Linshao Temple,
please just leave. I beg you.
The Ching tartars killed so many people.
Don't you want to fight back?
I'm only a rice miller. Even if I did,
what good will it do? I'd rather drink.
People continue to suffer because
too many people have that attitude.
You'd put it more plainly.
I want to borrow your place.
No... lf you do,
I won't be able to stay here anymore.
Don't worry. I'll take you to Shaolin.
Go away...!
Come here, on your knees...
Lord Cheng, we caught them
near the cemetery.
Kill them all!
Yes.
Stop!
Lord Cheng, I killed Tang San-yao.
Not them!
You?
How did you kill him?
With this.
- Take him.
- Yes.
Where did you learn it?
In Shaolin Temple.
Report to the General! Quick!
Yes.
Master, we're outnumbered.
Yes, there're so many of them.
Everyday they wake me up early.
Will you please calm down?
No, I can't.
I'm Miller Six.
This is flour.
Commanders Tang and Cheng are famous.
Their failure this time is because...
If more monks were here
there might be a rebellion in Canton!
Yes...
Tomorrow I'll bring some men to capture him,
even if I have to go to Shaolin.
Go, go at once... Run!
Give me a sword.
You, a monk, joining the rebels!
A Buddhist has to conquer evil.
How many lives have you taken?
I've killed many, but never a monk.
Stop!
The sweeping tail of the dancing dragon.