Eve, just tell them what they want to know.
-Who was she dating?
-We already told the Savages.
-The Savage brothers?
-They were here yesterday.
Good, now try us out.
Who was she dating?
No one special.
You guys were having
a goodbye dinner, right?
-What?
-She was leaving town, wasn't she?
-Going to Las Vegas?
-How do you know?
She closed her bank account,
she had hotel phone numbers.
She wanted out of this dump.
She wanted to start a new life.
Well, a 19-year-old girl
doesn't go to Las Vegas alone.
So who was she going with?
Come on, girls.
Who was she going with?
Brendan.
Excuse me?
-Brendan.
-Brendan Harris?
Brendan Harris, yeah.
You got an address?
Hey, Dave.
Hey, Jimmy.
Sorry, I came out for a smoke.
Go ahead, sit down. Sit down.
I haven't had a chance
to talk to you all day.
How you doing?
What happened to your hand?
This?
I was helping a buddy move a couch.
I slammed it in the doorjamb.
Ways you can manage
to hurt yourself, right?
It's good to see you.
Yeah?
How are our girls holding up?
They're doing okay, I guess.
That Celeste, she's a godsend.
You thank her for me, will you?
It's nice, isn't it? Just to sit out here.
Yeah.
I couldn't stand looking through the fridge
to find room for all that food...
...we're gonna throw away
in the next few days.
-Lot of waste, huh?
-Yeah.
I just can't let anything get fucked up
in these next few days.
Because it's all anybody
will remember about her.
One thing you could say about Katie,
even when she was little...
...that girl was neat.
When I got out of the joint...
...you know, after Marita died...
...I remember, I was more afraid
of my little daughter...
...than I ever was of being in prison.
I loved her...
...most...
...because when we were sitting in that
kitchen that night...
...it was like we were the last two people
on Earth. You know, forgotten.
Unwanted.
And it's really starting to piss me off, Dave,
because I can't cry for her.
My own little daughter,
and I can't even cry for her.
Jimmy.
You're crying now.
Yeah, damn.
I just want to hug her one more time.
She was 19 fucking years old.
Do you want me to leave you alone?
No, just stay here for a minute,
if that's cool.
Yeah, sure. Jimmy, it's cool.
When was the last time
you saw Katie Markum?
-You don't think I'd hurt her do you?
-She isn't hurt. She's dead.
-I didn't kill her.
-Again, when's the last time you saw her?
About 8--
Saturday night, about 8:00.
About like 8, Brendan, or at 8?
It was about 8.
We had a couple slices at Hi-Fi,
and she had to go meet Eve and Diane.
Yeah. Why doesn't Jimmy Markum
like you?
I don't know.
But he told Katie he never wanted her
to see me or any other Harris.
What? That thief thinks he's better
than our family?
-He's not a thief.
-He's a thief! A scumbag burglar.
Daughter probably had the same bad gene.
You count yourself lucky, Bren.
So Katie had some brochures for Vegas.
We heard she was going there with you.
We were gonna leave Sunday.
We were gonna get married
when we got there.
Well, that was the plan, right?
You were gonna leave me?
Without a word?
-Ma, I was gonna tell you.
-Just like your father, huh?
That's my brother, Ray,
and his friend John.
-Hey, boys.
-Hey.
He don't speak.
Father couldn't shut up, but his son's
a mute. Oh, yeah, life's fucking fair.
They're here about Katie. Why don't you
go watch TV or something.
So where were you between 12:30
and 2 a.m. on Sunday morning, Brendan?
I was asleep.
Can you confirm that, Mrs. Harris?
I can confirm that he closed his door
at 10:00.
He came down for breakfast at 9.
I can't confirm that he didn't open
his window and go down the fire escape.
Okay, we're gonna ask you to take
a polygraph. You think you'd be up for that?
I loved her so much.
I'm never gonna feel that again.
It doesn't happen twice.
Doesn't happen once most times.
Celeste.
-Sorry, Jimmy. You surprised me.
-What are you still doing here?
I don't know.
I don't know, I just....
Did Annabeth get to sleep?
Yeah, I convinced her to take a pill.
-Could I get one of those?
-Yeah.
One for the road and then home.
Jimmy, I can stay over if you want.
Sit up with Annabeth.
You've done enough.
To you and Dave for being here for this.
Okay, Jimmy. I'll be back.
I'll be by first thing tomorrow.
See you first thing.
Good night.
-Good night.
-Yeah, good night.
Hello?
Christ. Lauren, say something.
"Okay. Hey, Sean, how was your day? "
Oh, me? I'm tired of wishing things
made sense.
I'm tired of caring about some dead girl, and
there's just gonna be another one after her.
Sending killers to jail is sending them where
they've been heading all their lives.
The dead are still dead.
Jesus, l...
...can't do this tonight.
I just....
I can't do it.
Bye, baby.
Because...
...sometimes the man wasn't a man at all.
He was the boy.
The boy who escaped from wolves.
An animal of the dusk.
Invisible.
Silent.
Living in a world...
...the others never saw.
World of fireflies.
Unseen except as a flare
in the corner of your eye.
Vanished by the time
you turn your head toward it.
I just gotta get my head right.
Catch a nice, long sleep.
And the boy will go back to his forest.
Back to his fireflies.
Is he asleep?
How's Jimmy and everybody?
Okay.
It's weird.
Took something like this for me and him
to become friends again.
Dave? Dave.
There's still nothing in the paper.
About what?
I don't know, honey. Maybe I didn't
hurt him as bad as I thought.
He's a mugger. He's not going
to the hospital.
Yeah.
Right.
Anyhow, it doesn't matter, does it?
I mean, Katie Markum is dead.
That seems more important right now.
I know in my soul I contributed
to your death.
But I don't know how.
Brendan Harris aced his polygraph.
Good. I didn't like him for it,
nor want him for it.
Yeah. Poor fucking kid.
Ballistics will be back in a while.
Meantime, we got a list of bar patrons.
All people who, I'm certain,
are dying to cooperate.
Considering the crime, maybe.
Dave Boyle?
Hey, is that the guy you were friends
with as a kid? The car guy?
Could be.
He's a guy to talk to. He knows you.
He won't treat us like cops.
-Clam up for no reason, huh?
-We'll see.
Hey, Boyle!
-What's it been, seven, eight years?
-Yeah.
Yeah. How you doing?
This is my son, Michael.
Hey, Michael. How you doing?
My name's Sean.
I'm an old buddy of your dad's. Hi.
-So you still with the staties?
-Homicide. This is my partner.
-Sergeant Powers. How are you?
-So you got a minute?
-We'd love to ask some quick questions.
-I was just gonna walk Michael to school.
-I can be back in a few minutes.
-Tell you what, we'll walk with you, okay?
Sure.
So you look good.
-I hear rents are rising.
-Yeah, the yuppies are coming.
They're cutting my dad's old house up
into condos.
We walked by there the other day.
Must be something we could do
to stop them.
A friend of mine says the other day,
he says:
" Neighborhood needs a fucking crime wave.
Get property values where they belong."
Young girls keep getting murdered up in Pen
Park, Mr. Boyle, you might get your wish.
Dave. Call me Dave.
You said the F-word, Dad.
Yeah, I know. Walk on up ahead, Michael.
Us guys need to talk. Go on.
-So, what's up, Sean?
-Yeah, you heard about Katie Markum?
Yeah, I was at Jimmy's yesterday.
Celeste is there now.
-Who's Celeste?
-My wife.
-How's Jimmy doing?
-It's hard to tell. You know him.
-Yeah, so the reason we came by--
-Listen, I saw her.
Katie. I don't know if you know that.
At McGill's, the night she died.
That's what we wanted to talk about.
They were at a couple of bars that night.
Your name turned up for McGill's.
They put on quite a show
dancing on the bar.
-Pretty drunk, huh?
-But it was harmless.
They weren't stripping or nothing.
They were just 19.
What time did they leave?
I left at 1. They must've left
15 minutes before me.
-So we'll say 12:45?
-Sounds about right.
You see anything unusual
or anyone--?
Michael.
-Like what?
-I don't know.
A guy watching the girls?
A guy with hate in his eyes?
A woman-hater?
No. No, if they hadn't danced on the bar,
it would've been business as usual.
-See you later, Dad.
-You got your milk money?
Fuck, I hated school.
What?
Yeah, me too, Sean.
Just one more thing, Mr. Boyle.
Where did you go after you left McGill's?
-Home.
-Home by 1:15, would you say?
-Roughly. Sure.
-All right.
Yeah, well, thanks a lot, Dave.
We'll grab a beer sometime?
-Yeah, I'd like that, Sean.
-All right.
What?
What happened to him in that car?
Can you believe this?
Man, it's the same as Dunkin' Donuts.
It costs 15 times the price.
You know, you take away love,
money or hate as motives...
...you're not left with a whole lot.
Well, if this Markum thing's random,
I mean, shit.
Yeah, tell me about it. But the old lady,
Prior, she doesn't hear a scream.
Hears a gunshot,
before that a "hi"...
...which tells me the girl is either
friendly or she knew him.
She turns into the curb, not too fast or she
hops it. Foot's off the clutch. She stalls.
-She says, "Hi." He shoots her.
-She slams the door into him, takes off.
What makes her swerve
without hitting the brakes?
-I don't know. Something in the street.
-Maybe.
This Markum girl couldn't have
weighed more than what, 110?
-She hit hard enough to get a jump on him?
-Maybe he's knocked back on his heels.
Your pal Dave strikes me as a guy
permanently back on his heels.
Wait a second, how did we get to
Dave Boyle all of a sudden?
-We just got to him.
-He's a guy who was in the bar.
The last place, Seany,
the last place she was at.
The guy is wrong. You saw his hand.
Yeah, I saw his hand. You seriously
want to take a look at Dave Boyle?
Just a little one.
I'd recommend two sets of visiting hours,
from 3 to 5, and 7 to 9.
-Sure.
-Good.
-Have you thought about flowers?
-I'll call Knopfler's this afternoon.
Good.
And the notice?
Notice?
Yes, the obituary. We can take care of it
if you give us her basic information.
Or if you prefer donations
in lieu of flowers?
Where's my daughter?
Downstairs, in the basement.
I wanna see her.
I'm gonna find him, Katie.
I'm gonna find him before the police do.
I'm gonna find the man,
and I'm gonna kill him.
Did you say something, Mr. Markum?
The notice.
It should read: "Katherine Markum...
...beloved daughter
of James and Marita, deceased...
...stepdaughter of Annabeth, sister to--"
"Sister to Sara and Nadine."
-You guys again?
-Yeah. We're like two bad pennies.
-You dropping in on Jimmy?
-Yeah.
Do you have some kind of, what,
break in the case?
No, just paying our respects.
Where you off to?
Annabeth got a craving for cigarettes. I'm
gonna go get some. See you in a minute.
By the way, Mr. Boyle, what happened
to your hand there?
Garbage disposal. It jammed, I stuck
my hand in, it started again.
-Stupid.
-Painful.
Garbage disposal. Bullshit.
Yeah. Well, it doesn't mean
he killed anybody either. Come on.
-Heard you could use one.
-Thanks.
-I quit 10 years ago, you believe this?
-Whatever you need right now.
Come on in, I'll get Jimmy.
I got a couple errands I gotta run.
I'll be back in an hour.
You don't have to come back, Celeste.
I'll be fine.
-Sure?
-Celeste Boyle?
Yeah.
I'm Sean Devine, an old friend of Dave's.
This is Whitey Powers.
-Mrs. Boyle.
-Nice to meet you.
Look, I gotta go.
Oh, damn it.
I left my report pad in the cruiser.
-You better go get it.
-Yeah.
Come on.
Hey, Celeste, could I ask you
a quick question?
-Me?
-What time did Dave get home on Saturday?
-What?
-It's a little thing.
We're running a time line on everything
involving Katie. I'm sure...
...Dave told you he saw her
at McGill's.
You think Dave killed Katie?
Oh, no. God. I didn't say that.
Why would I even think that?
-I don't know.
-No, no. It's just that we could figure out...
...what time she was on the road
if we knew what time Dave got home.
See, it's 5 minutes from your place
to McGill's...
...and Katie left 15 minutes
before Dave did. You see what I mean.
I was asleep.
Saturday night, when Dave came in,
Okay. Well, thanks.
Bullshit.
No, he was dating Katie, Jim.
They were gonna elope to Vegas.
We found tickets under their names.
Brendan Harris confirmed it.
Remember what you said?
How she looked at you on Saturday like
she was preparing to never see you again?
-Did Brendan Harris kill my daughter?
-No.
You're 100 percent sure?
Passed his poly with flying colors, plus it
seemed to me like he really loved her.
Jimmy, I'm just curious, man.
Why are you so dead set
against that kid?
He said Katie told him you'd disowned her
if she ever dated a Harris.
I knew his father. They called him
"Just Ray" Harris.
Why is that?
There were so many Rays
in the neighborhood.
You had "Crazy Ray" Bucheck,
" Psycho Ray" Dorian.
The cool names were taken,
so he got stuck with "Just Ray."
We never got along.
I flat out didn't like him.
And he cut out on his wife when she was
pregnant with that little mute of hers.
I don't know.
I just figure the apple doesn't fall
far from the tree.
I didn't want Brendan or any other Harris
dating Katie or any other daughter of mine.
I can't believe we're talking about
Just Ray Harris.
How about this? We've interviewed
witnesses...
...canvassed people
who were in the bar.
We've run into more than a few of them
who were questioned...
...before us by one or more
of the Savage brothers.
-So?
-So the Savages are not policemen, Jim.
-Some people don't talk to policemen, Sean.
-With all due respect, Mr. Markum.
...and just so we're clear,
this is our case.
-How long?
-How long what?
How long before you catch
my daughter's killer?
You bargaining with us?
Bargaining?
You giving us a deadline?
We'll speak for Katie, Mr. Markum.
If that's okay with you.
Just find my daughter's killer, sergeant.
I'm not standing in your way.
The last thing we need is Jimmy Markum
and the Savages putting the fear of God...
-...into the neighborhood.
-We grew up terrified of them.
Eleven months apart, like their mother ran
a loose-cannon factory.
Fucking knuckleheads.
Hey, Guys. Ballistics are in on the Markum murder.
-Yeah, you got a match?
-You're gonna love it.
It's a perfect match.
Gun was a.38 Smith.
Part of a lot stolen from a gun dealer
in New Hampshire in 1982.
The same gun that killed Katherine Markum
was used in a liquor-store holdup in 1984.
-ln Buckingham.
-The Flats?
Rome Basin. Place called Looney Liquors.
I pulled the file.
It was a two-man job.
They fired a warning shot into a wall.
-That's where the bullet got pulled.
-Nice work.
Thought you'd like that.
It's okay, Ray.
Don't worry about it.
Ma said that?
That I'm better off?
I loved her! You know what that's like?
Huh?
I'm sorry.
No, you're wrong.
I won't ever feel that again.
Right there. Went in through a bottle
of Jack and stuck in the wall right there.
-Scary, huh?
-Scarier than a glass of milk, right?
So take me through it.
These two guys come in....
In rubber masks.
They came in through here.
That's the storeroom.
There's a door back there
that leads to a loading dock.
I always keep that door locked.
So they must have had a key.
A key? So, what you're saying
is that it was an inside job?
It had to be. One of them, at least,
worked for me at some point.
The only reason they fired that goddamn
warning shot was they must have known...
...I kept this under the counter.
-And you told the police that at the time.
-Yeah.
Sure, they went through
my employment records.
Questioned everybody
who used to work for me.
-Never made an arrest.
-Still have a copy of those records?
Yeah, it's in a box in the office there.
But I know who did it.
Oh, yeah?
This guy I fired a couple
of weeks before.
Son of a bitch came in here
a few days after the robbery.
He had this fucking goddamn grin
on his face.
And I just knew.
Go tell a grin to a jury, right?
You remember his name?
Do I look senile to you?
-No, sir.
-Name...
...was Ray Harris.
We used to call him "Just Ray."
You say they used the same gun
for another crime?
-That's correct, sir.
-Thanks for your help, Mr. Looney.
Where you been?
Out.
What you watching?
Some vampire movie.
Guy just got his head torn off.
Where'd you go, Celeste?
I was sitting in my car...
...down by the channel.
You know...
...thinking about things.
-What'd you think about?
-Oh, you know....
No, actually, I don't know.
Things. You know, the day.
About Katie being dead.
And poor Annabeth and Jimmy, you know...
...those things.
Those things.
Know what I was thinking about, huh?
Vampires.
What about them?
They're undead...
...but I think maybe there's
something beautiful about it.
Maybe one day you wake up
and you forget what it's like...
...to be human.
Maybe then it's okay.
What the fuck you talking about, Dave?
Vampires, sweetie. Werewolves.
You're not making any sense.
You think I killed Katie?
-Celeste.
-What--?
-ls that the sense we're making these days?
-Where'd you come up with that?
You've barely looked at me since you found
out Katie was dead.
In fact, you seem repulsed by me.
-Dave!
-What?
I don't think anything.
I'm confused, okay?
Even your friend Sean
asked about--
He's not my friend, if you didn't know.
He asked me about you.
What time you came home.
-What'd you tell him?
-I said I was asleep.
-That's good thinking, baby.
-Jesus Christ, Dave!
-Why don't you tell them about the mugger?
-The mugger?
The mugger! I see how
your mind's working. I do.
I come home with blood on me
the same night Katie's murdered.
I must have killed her, right?
Fuck!
Henry....
What? Henry?
Henry and George.
I never told anyone that before.
Those were their names.
Isn't that fucking hilarious?
At least that's what they called themselves,
but...
...they were wolves, and Dave...
...was the boy who escaped from wolves.
What are you talking about, Dave?
I'm talking Henry and George.
They took me on a four-day ride.
They buried me in this ratty old cellar
with a sleeping bag.
And, man, Celeste...
...did they have their fun.
And no one came to help old Dave then.
Dave had to pretend to be somebody else.
You mean, all those years ago...
...when you were a little boy?
Dave....
Dave's dead.
I don't know who came out of that cellar,
but it sure as shit wasn't Dave!
You see, honey--
Fuck!
It's like vampires.
Once it's in you...
...it stays.
What stays?
Did you know there were child prostitutes
in Rome Basin?
What?
Fuck!
I can't trust my mind anymore, Celeste.
I'm warning you...
...I can't trust my mind.
I gotta go out,
try to get my head around it.
Okay.
-The gun sends us in a different direction.
-I don't see it that way.
What does Just Ray's gun
have to do with Dave?
These things get passed around.
Just Ray may have blown town,
but his gun never did.
I say we talk with Brendan Harris
in the morning.
And I say Dave Boyle. The hand story.
The wife, she's definitely scared.
They're hiding something, but Dave Boyle's
as much a killer as Brendan Harris.
Boyle fits the profile, a fucking T.
Mid-30s, white, marginally employed...
...sexually abused as a kid.
On paper, this guy should be in jail already.
Katie Markum
was not sexually abused, see?
In that equation,
sexual emission is part of the deal.
You were friends when you were kids.
This makes you a fucking liability.
He's not my friend.
Turns out you're right, I'll have my cuffs
off my hip faster than yours.
Hey, Jimmy.
You're out late.
Yeah, you too.
It's cold, huh?
Yeah, I guess.
You know, l....
I been sitting out here...
...over the last few years...
...waiting on Katie to get back
from someplace.
About midnight, I'd say to Annabeth,
"I'm gonna go sit on the porch for a while."
Weird thing is...
...it seemed to bring her back.
I saw her, you know.
Saw who?
Katie. I was at McGill's Saturday night.
-You saw Katie Saturday night?
-Never got around to telling you.
Did you talk to her?
Just nodded hello at one point.
Next time I looked up, she was gone.
But...
...Jimmy...
...she looked...
...happy.
I got more walking to do.
Good night.
-You stole his car.
-His car was officially towed.
-From the front of his house.
-No! It was abandoned in Rome Basin...
...adjacent to the parkway.
Lucky for us, the parkway's state
jurisdiction. Some kids jacked the car...
-...they took it for a joy ride....
-What? Why'd you do it?
After I left you last night, I decided to talk
to Boyle myself, put some fear into him.
I get to his house, I decide to look in
his car, see what he's got. I find blood.
-Blood?
-Front seat of Dave's car. B-negative.
-How much?
-A bit. Found more in the trunk. A lot more.
Type O, same type as Katie Markum.
Wait, Katie Markum
never got in anybody's trunk.
She was chased through the park
where she died.
-It's enough to ask questions.
-Your search is gonna get tossed out.
No, found and abandoned in state
jurisdiction, for insurance purposes.
-ln the best interest of the owner.
-Get a physical search, file the report.
Bingo.
You wanna talk to him,
or should I send him home?
-Dave's here?
-I've had him in the box for an hour.
Sent two of my biggest, ugliest troopers
to pick him up.
Come on, Mr. Boyle!
We know you didn't get that swollen hand
sticking it in the garbage disposal.
-Oh, yeah? How do you know that?
-Why's your wife afraid of you?
She know what really happened
to your hand?
How about a Sprite or something?
How about you tell us what really happened
Saturday night, Mr. Boyle?
You lied.
That's your opinion,
which you're entitled to.
-Hey, you think this is funny?
-No, I don't. I'm tired, I'm hung-over.
Not only was my car stolen last night,
but now you won't release it to me.
Okay.
All right.
Tell us, Mr. Boyle,
how did you get the blood in your car?
-What blood?
-Let's start with the front seat.
What are you looking at him for?
Hey, you think I could get
that Sprite, Sean?
Sure.
Oh, I get it.
You're the good cop.
How about a meatball sub
while you're at it?
I ain't your bitch, Dave.
Looks like you'll have to wait.
Yeah, but you're someone's bitch,
aren't you, Sean?
The blood on your front seat, Dave.
Answer the sergeant.
We got a chainlink fence
in our back yard.
Me and my kid play Wiffle Ball
every afternoon after school.
He's getting good, so most of the balls
are on the other side of the fence.
So I climb it.
Except I slip...
...slice myself where the links curl in,
right here.
Bled like hell.
Ten minutes later,
I gotta pick up Michael at school.
Probably was still bleeding
when I got in the front seat.
What blood type are you?
B-negative.
Yeah? That's the match we got.
-Well, there you go.
-Not quite.
Blood in the trunk of the car
wasn't B-negative.
I don't know anything
about any blood in the trunk of the car.
No idea how half a pint of blood
got in the trunk of your car?
-None.
-This is not the way you wanna go, Dave.
How is that gonna look in court?
You not knowing how someone else's blood
got in the trunk of your car?
Gonna look fine, I suppose.
You filed the report.
What report?
The stolen-car report.
The car wasn't in my possession last night.
So whatever the thieves used it for,
you should find out...
...because it sounds like they
were up to no good.
Things looking any better
on the Sprite, Sean?
Well, you just got too fucking smart.
The car is inadmissible.
Anything in there, his lawyers say
was put by the car thieves.
-I can break him.
-You just kicked their asses in there!
You still think your old buddy Dave
wouldn't hurt a fly--
-ls that the point? No.
-What is the fucking point?
We can break this open on the gun.
It's the gun.
Okay. Maybe.
So, what do we do with Dave?
Fuck it. Kick him loose.
Maybe a Celtic cross.
That's always a popular choice.
Or this lovely red marble here.
Or a figural.
That one.
Very good. Nice and simple.
Hey, Jimmy!
Annabeth said you were here.
We been asking around, like you said to.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Jimmy, this ain't about the two-year bit
you did for me.
And it ain't about me missing your brains
running things.
Katie was my niece. Not by birth, but
she was part of our family, we loved her.
I don't question you, Val.
What's up?
Cops are all over this. Doing their job
for once. Bars, street trade, everything.
Every hooker we talked to, bartender,
already been questioned.
-The fucking law has descended, Jimmy.
-What about Just Ray's kid?
Quiet as a mouse.
Kid's no trouble to anyone.