You're late!
Well, I could not come earlier.
Well I've only come because
you like this music.
Sarge caught me running
and I had to lose him.
Come on!
Watch out, man!
What do you think?
Oh, well... not bad, a little noisy...
- What shall we do tonight?
- Have not we done?
- We have to do something else.
- Oh no, I can not.
My parents will be
hysterical if I late again.
Fuck them!
Okay, here we go.
Hello!
I was cleaning.
Listen, it does not give
me the last 2 innings.
You close this thing and
see the movie for free.
I do not like flying saucers.
There is a movie of dishes... is a warning.
I do not like warnings and...
I like you either.
- Sure you do. - No... seriously.
If you do not treat me
right I will not ask out.
I do not want to date you.
Goodbye, baby!
It nixer... accelerates,
accelerates before we see.
Come, we gonna catch.
- Do you have to make supplication?
- Hey, I already had a point!
Would not she the one who had to point?
- Just below the navel. - What?
Since you run off to boots.
Hey! Have you seen the sci-fi movie?
Do we have to bear it, Dude?
The only opinion I need is yours.
Try some aliens, who steal their
soul to humans while they sleep.
There's a guy with his girl,
trying to escape human monsters
to warn the world of what happens.
How does it end?
The girl falls asleep and
becomes one of them.
Will run at night?
Yes, I'd say about aunt, aunt's passing.
Because I had to warn the world.
And an aunt is not more
important than the world.
Wait... What if I wanted to? What
if she was for all the world?
That if, if she was his whole world
had to stay with her, right?
The hell!
- I thought you left me.
- We're out, baby... Do not you see?
Va, come darling.
Why do not you come down here, nixer?
See you later.
Hey Dude!...
Look who's coming.
Hey!... but if it Dude...
The human anteater.
Is today the catechesis
the released them before?
Look at his girlfriend... Dude do you do?
To go girls across the Mexican border?
Shut up, asshole!
Oh, speaking Spanish ons!
You're jealous because
I speak two languages.
Better stick with the Spanish,
because your English bites.
So bitch!
You look beautiful tonight, Sister Teresa.
The largest I have your head.
Shut up, fool!
Hey, that's my sister, largemouth!
I'll kill you!
Let's go.
Hey!... To!... You hair is burning!
You hair is burning!
And now, where we're going, Dude?
This is very romantic, very romantic...
take me home.
- That... take her home. - Come on, Donna.
Shit!
Hey, you have fallen!...
brake!, have fallen!
Fuck.
I'll upload the bastard!
Go!
Give me a kiss.
Within
You can see your parents.
What do you say? They are sleeping.
Apparently not.
Very timely, as always.
I have brought the
newspaper a little early.
I had to have given the kiss here.
Anyway, Donna.
Pussy!
Setting
- Have you noticed the hand? - Damn, right!
See? Do you see how carefully
covers it with the bread?
Watch as changes bread texture.
My particular theory... is partly
due to the fat of the sausage,
and partly to the sweet
angelic touch of their hands.
My mom makes them every day
since it enters the body.
And taught me...
to bring a spare in your pocket.
God bless you!
What if I need a snack to get by.
Ten!
We do not yet
First I want the smell.
You have to learn to use something
other than the eyes and ears.
He showed it to all my new teammates.
Tricks of the trade.
Only that...
anyone will tell...
if you know the tricks...
know the trade.
Sink your teeth!
Damn, that woman has great hands.
Slip this into your pocket.
Ehm... Listen to me carefully...
Those guys are no longer the same.
You know who is to blame?
The Rock'nRoll.
That music makes the guys
in a gang of werewolves...
love sex, beer and car racing.
There goes that Dude!
Let's get that son of a bitch!
How much noise coming, officer?
What a show the last night, Dude.
Yes, you should be more careful...
Someone could get hurt.
Hey, do not get smart, boy.
What do you have eaten?
Eh! He has made his mother, blockhead!
Do you cook in a pigsty?
Out of the car!
Hands on the door.
These thugs need to be careful,
have switchblade knives.
Does wearing today, blockhead?
- What?
Do you carry knife?
Why not sign up to your own son?
Regístrale pockets!
Regístramelos good puppy.
You may find dog biscuits
which makes his mother.
Hey, his mother makes
them especially for him.
I'm certain you have.
Do you know?
One of these days I'll kick your ass.
Why do not you do it now
and saved the wait?
No... When I give you...
be for something that you
can not escape happily...
rabbit with that smirk.
I'm so close to beat you
up nearly'm seeing.
Would you aroused just
thinking about it, eh?
Listen, I can lock up when
I damn well, but surely...
that the prison is too
good for a guy like you.
This is my city.
No one rides their own laws in my city.
Take care of yourself, kid. Right?
Hey, can you look your Uncle
Charlie, talk alike, but it is not.
Half the people in town are aliens...
and the other half is about to be.
They are all like zombies.
Van following the usual
routine without any emotion.
What are hell are you talking about?
"The Invasion of the Body Snatchers"
It's a movie, JT. You shut
up and kitchen, will you?
We talk about a movie.
Shut up fool, or I spit on the burger.
Go ahead...
not be more disgusting.
- What time is spent? - Keep it up, nixer!
At 9. but starts at 9 and 10. There
are 3 developments and news.
Well, look... not a true story, is a movie.
You must see it.
- Sorry. -'s Burning!
JT, do you fill it again?
Do you... have a rag?
Yes, I have 40 wipes.
Well give us 30.
Take this.
Only one. Oh, and Sign me up this thing.
And now I want to refill.
If you would not mind.
A pair of doubles!
Shut up.
Get out!
I've burned all the hair
my girlfriend, Dude.
Pussy!, Now has to wear a wig.
It seems an old!
I thought it was your old.
Do one thing...
bring it here...
Take off the wig...
and daddy will make bald spit shine.
If you want you can kill...
but what will you do in my place, okay?
And now let fooling...
before I get to make fresh meat patties.
Sit Dude!
Sorry, JT.
Tonight...
on the cliff...
at 9.
Does the cliff? Uncle Jo!,
That site is dangerous...
Shut up, asshole!
No, do not you remember Teddy?, Now
have to take my sister to skate.
Fuck him!
Dude, I've promised!
As compensation for having burnt hair.
Do you skate? Hey Teddy...
beware do not go wrong with
the likes of the skirt.
We see the faces... Dude.
Sure thing.
"Hello?"
Hi, Donna.
Dudi!
Oh, do not call me that.
Hey, sorry about last night.
He had to have known they would be raised.
Now they want to be home for dinner, sorry.
Bah, anyway, just want to
tell their side of the story.
Get out of here!
When I see you again?
Want to go skating tonight?
Would you take me to skate?
Why do not you?
Well... but I can not
believe you want to go.
Of course I want, for my Donna anything.
Pick me up at 8.
Best at 9.
All right, bye.
Shit!
To see if you aim!
Have not you ever had one of those
days where the jet is divided into two
and goes to the two sides of
the urinal and hit them all?
Si. Be more careful!
With a little will suffice.
Duel.
At last.
It's okay Julie, it looks great.
The hell!
It takes getting used to.
- Julie is here.
- If... and also Teddy. That strong, right?
- Coincidence? - Sorry, Donna.
Oh!... I thought you were
going to get to skate.
We skated.
It's time to dance in pairs.
And here's a song dedicated to Julie.
She devotes nixer.
Let me crash head on my wall...
Of Hasil Adkins.
Wait a minute.
Going out in the newspapers.
Fuck you in the ass.
Are you satisfied?
Care... sliding.
Sorry Donna, compensare you, I promise.
Come on, you hear this.
- What?
"What do you want?
What I tell you?
I was caught off guard.
Then you have a problem.
And if you want to be a man have to solve.
And do not come to me for help.
I will resolve it.
Yes
For now do nothing but
look like an asshole.
I've never made a fool!
We'll never
You have to take these tough fumes
and then sew it to hosts to kick his ass.
Have not I taught you anything?
If I ever catch you doing that
in public, hit a beating...
the hit you as if you were nobody.
Can you hear me?
That does not look like
I have a son asshole.
Be a man.
I'll show you who's the asshole.
There is nothing good in that radio shit.
I have an idea.
Ten... touches your something.
If you do not like the music I play.
You touch something.
Why do not you play in a band?
I do not like playing the most.
But there must be someone you admire.
I do not admire anyone.
To no one.
No, no.
No one, no?
Link Wray's fine.
Link Wray...
Is it famous?
No... make it right.
If it was so good...
seriously famous, is not it?
But what do you do? Oh, my God!
If the good is because he's
famous, you can all go to hell.
But, what are you doing girl?
Come on, play something sweet.
This is sweet.
You do not give bad.
It sucks.
If I could see your father!
You have given me.
You will... when you
came and you found out.
You think you're funny, right?
It's a good comic, Sarge.
Do you like hot dogs, Sarge?
You can bite mine.
Hey, you should not talk like that,
unless you want Donna's mother finds out
what were you doing last
night at Marphis Point.
I have nothing to hide, boss.
Really?
Well check this out...
if you have nothing to hide, as
you've deleted the name, huh?
Do not you know that's against the law?
The name does not matter.
Oh, forget it lieth me to
mourn and a time to another.
You asked for it.
What happens Dude? Your dad didnt want you?
Dont you showed love and understanding?
I thought you had to be sensitive you
to the problems of today's youth.
And we are... I'm sensitive.
But you, son, you're a lost cause.
Do you know?
Just like your father...
Your father... had some funny ideas
about how things had to be resolved.
And I take from here to kicks. He
left with his tail between his legs
And if you're still so shit that
history will repeat itself.
Take care, Delanney!
Ah, this bumper.
I mean you Johnny without a lead
guitarist it will not work.
Who played guitar?
I'll tell you who touch her.
The touches me.
- But if you have to play the saxophone.
- Also I'm going to play.
Does it look bad?
No, what you say, Johnny.
- Ready, Tommy? - Sure, Johnny.
Ok
Do not go man.
Now, Johnny!
Very good guy.
Give!
And then going nixer and says: Come
on baby, you know that I'm good.
It's weird.
Tell me, going all night. He wants to
give you free tickets or something.
Go, go, go! Are not you something
north of the border, miss?
Where is your hero? Is not that
going to your side, right?
They are a chihuahua... and a giraffe.
I think we will make a stop here.
I do not understand... If it is Mexican?
How is it that their parents are white?
Ah... I had reductions in Mexico?
Son of a bitch.
Mamma Mia! I think I'm in
love with corn pancake.
We got screwed.
Any suggestions?
I'm just the drummer, Johnny.
Well, okay.
It will not work. We got screwed!
- Well, come on, let's go man.
- Now twice as fast!
How'd it go last night with that girl?
Bah... sent me gargle.
You had to have done the tea bag.
Is the tea bag?
What's that?
Consists put him and pull his
tongue over and over again.
- I have to talk to you, Dude.
- Do it again.
- Want to go to the movies tonight?
- No, I have to study.
Leave that shit the study and
come to the movies with me.
Why do not you go with him? I like more.
Come Dude, I have to talk, really.
- Come I want to see...
- Shit... there is Teddy.
"What happened?"
I enjoyed our walk in the park, Donna.
Trying to tell you.
Did you do something?
I have an idea.
Promise you will not do anything.
What did he do?
We'll have a party.
And Donna can make piñata.
The so-called
tried to kiss me.
So everyone will have their part.
Have you got the shotgun shells?
Please do not do anything stupid.
He just wants to piss you off.
Dude.
If I'm doing something stupid.
See you later, Donna.
Come Dude... as if there were
lots like her out there.
- What's the matter baby? Dont you like it?
- Forget what I said, Dude.
Want a tamale with that shake?
Hello, JT.
Sarge...
What do I owe you, JT?
Thank you.
JT, do not give special
treatment to this thug.
Are you a business,
or you take it as a business,
or you were in the street before
resorting to the Ministry of Health.
My thing is to feed people, Sergeant,
keep the thugs at bay is up to you.
You better be devoted to each his own.
That's the spirit, JT!
You shut up!
Yes
Got a minute?
Sure.
Well, you might seem a
little sudden, but...
I want to say that I like what you do.
Thank you.
How did you do that?
Fact what?
Well, that... I mean...
that the world is not very easy for those
who want to do things differently.
Well I started playing, and went with it.
Nothing special.
- Do you smoke? - Yes... yes
Look at this, JT.
From here... to Eternity is
the time before I was born.
And from here to Eternity...
is the time after I die.
And this... is all the time that I have...
to use it.
You do nothing.
You'll spend the rest of
your days here in this town.
And you will die here...
with my burger in hand.
And nothing more.
I want you to know that in my group
have good news and bad news.
We have signed a record
label to take on tour.
- And the good news?
- That's the good news.
- Ah... well... what's the bad?
- Gone is the guitarist.
- Why?
- Because it was not the time or something.
Did you say you play?
If you think we can help,
you should do a test.
If it goes well you could do the tour.
There is a lot of money.
Enough for 2 people to live?
Sure.
Hey, I think you do because you know
that everyone is covered in shit.
If... I'm sick of all these people
who have success being a real shit.
Look, I want to make music...
to affright staff.
If... I understand.
That same train came to
me long ago, and I lost.
This time will not go without me.
Our last show is tomorrow.
Come if you think you can fill the gap.
Okay... thanks.
Uncle!, A record... a tour.
Forget all this...
I never have an opportunity like that.
Girls... women... fame and fortune.
If... not say anything to
Donna, yet nothing is certain.
It might be jinxed.
No... I do not want to get your
hopes up, in case it does not work.
Well... if you need rep
or something... not...
someone to help you... and if
I have other commitments...
Shit... I will not go without you.
- Do you want to go see that movie tonight?
- I can not.
Is it Donna?
Are you sure you want to
date someone like Dude?
Yes
It's that one day his father was caught
and we are scared to do the same.
Donna, just think about your future...
as good parents.
And with no one to guide him,
we fear that it can not give
everything you expect from a man.
Dude I know things you do not
know any of your friends gossip.
Like what?
As it is a good musician...
going to have a group going
to sign a record deal,
and earn so much money that will suck.
Well, if that happens you
will have our blessing.
I already said.
But if not, I want you to be
prepared to look at other options.
- Oh!... This will look that good. - If...
Go body!
I assure that you'll get later I can.
Ah... this jumps a lot, right?
It is good idea but jumps every
time we caught a pothole.
Well... What we do tonight?
Whatever you want, Donna. I like the dark.
I want to go see... a movie.
Want to watch a movie with me?
For my Dudi whatever.
What do you want to go see?
Thank you, Donna.
How many times have you seen this movie?
15.
Why do not you tell me that
you had left your father?
Never tell me anything.
There is nothing you have to know
about me that I have not counted.
I want to hear about your father.
From my father just got a thing.
What?
Better not to know.
Fight,... in the park... tonight... at 9.
Where children play, Teddy?
They will not miss.
I love to jump rope with you,
but I have an appointment.
It's settled, goes to your appointment.
I already atizare other day, not tonight.
With that hot chick got that quote?
Surely not this whore with which you.
With this Mexican whore.
We are
Like the music, right?
The cockroach... cockroach...
Is a Mexican song, right Donna?
Did you know that you
were throwing a cockroach?
Leave her out of this.
Why? You would have burned my
girlfriend's hair, so bud!
You think I'm going to
leave you alone like that?
Fuck you in the ass!
Tonight...
at 9...
At 9.
I'm sure you are.
Are you are going through a bit, is not it?
- What have been those now?
- Teddy wants to dance.
I thought that was the police.
Yeah right... is the police, but...
Do you not understand?,
Can not trust anyone.
They've taken over the entire city.
How the hell warn others if there's no one?
Fuck!, You can not even
trust his girlfriend.
Well,... and when he learns
that the girl is one of them?
When she kisses him.
Whenever you hear well, right?
When it's late... So are they... girls.
Listen to me, guys.
I have lived much longer than you.
Do you think a child dreamed of
making burgers for scum like you?
You have to know you want to do.
And above all... when.
Because the time is important.
If not, you realize, as
the guy in the movie,
that... fuck... it's too late.
We ask you something.
What do you think it gives impression
that the son of Sergeant...
is the village idiot? Huh?
I'll tell you.
People say that you can skip the laws.
You know... my laws.
Because apparently you can not
handle a thug dirty and disgusting.
- I told you I will. - Yes?, How?
I challenged him to a fight tonight.
I have the kids ready if
comes up with something.
Everyone knows it's a hook.
You'll have to work hard to fuck at all.
Listen...
Not because I had a problem
with his father long ago.
Got it?"
I have my reasons for putting a broth.
You know, son? If excuses
were worth cents...
you'd be a fucking silver dollar.
Do not forget to put this
in my hand when I'm dead.
"Who knows what the devil
looks in the human heart"
"The Shadow knows"
- Dudi? - Hey, baby!
Come here, I have to talk to you.
- What happens? - Sit.
You know that group you like?
They are looking for a guitarist.
- Yes, I have heard some comment.
- Is our chance!
- What do you mean?
- Have signed a record deal.
And are your style, do not
touch anything sweet.
Now!, But I have to think about my mother.
Listen! If you had wanted to go
somewhere ask me to leave my parents.
Yeah, well... but not the same,
they are not your real parents,
are not your own blood.
Do not go to the fight
tonight, Dude... please.
Come to the club, show them what you do.
Worth a try. We will not have
another chance like this.
Please... You promise you're going to try?
"Please!
I promise you.
Ready to machacarles?
Yes, very well.
Teddy has gone too far.
I spoke to the club.
I was talking about the fight.
Did not you hear anything I said JT?
Yes, I... an uncle very deep.
Dude, fuck the fight,
the only chance to get out of here.
Why waste it with Teddy?
My father never faced with
anything in his sad life.
One was dedicated to flee.
And I'm not going to flee.
Neither Teddy nor pig of his
father, or anyone else.
Do you have the brass knuckles?
- Oh, yes.
Do you think it will?
At least that appears with this Donna.
You know that I like fair fights.
Meddle not, assholes... is all mine.
Lately you have not hit very hard.
Want to see how you swallow that comment?
Just saying... Apparently
that made you all a cocoon.
You were lucky.
And the hair of my sister?
Then what are you gonna do, Teddy?
Would you let your face like a
finely chopped raw hamburger?
If... that and much more.
Its true that I do nothing of myself, but
I dont get in trouble.
People do not want to
know anything about you.
It's exactly what I want,...
so do not bother me.
Look, Dude... have forced me to be.
And you have forced... give me one.
You'd fuck not no crabs in a whorehouse.
Oh, very well.
Ten reflections!
Sorry, Dude.
- It's okay. - But...
Stay away!
This if... which is stronger!...
We're here waiting asshole face.
That guy is not going to appear.
Hey, where are you going?
It's too chicken to come... we go.
I love it when you play out of tune!
Quarter's 11!
I know you hate this city,
you hate Teddy, I also...
But I also know how you like your music.
Fight for what you like...
not for what you hate.
Well, what are you gonna do?
Clubbing... and machacarles.
Need a lift?
Hey, hey! They put a record spinning!
It is a fraud!, Is a fraud!,
A fraud!, A fraud!, Fraud!
You bastards!...
They were playing a fucking fag.
Music, Dude... it was just that...
just music.
A great fuck!
You did not have to, we had a
chance and you fucked up as ever.
You're selfish, Dude. I give
a shit about my dreams.
Those dreams are mine, not yours.
You get one.
Asshole."
Now your father if you're going
to be okay to broth, Teddy.
No, Teddy!...
yes
Here we are...
Cursed chickenshit.
It's time...
once you start.
Fuck off with your shotgun cartridges!
Do you really think I would
have to buy the chocolates?
But if you're too fat.
I think with the petunias enough...
and even perhaps
- Mustard? - Eh, sorry... what?
Do you want the dog
with or without mustard?
Sarge Con love the mustard.
Get in the fucking car...
we go!
But do not want to eat?
Get in the fucking car now!
Add all at once!
- Where are you going, Dude?
- Looking for Donna.
A Teddy something happened.
They say he is dead...
Take me with you, Dude.
You have to start following only your way.
What I do here? If I'm not
in trouble, I go crazy.
You spend what you better
looking than me mounting them.
What will you do?
Living in the streets,
with all the garbage...
People throw many good things.
They're hung...
What are you doing, dude?
Say you do not think we
will go skating, Donna.
I want to help.
No can help me.
I will not ever believed
that I am a problem.
I can not go with you, Dude.
It's all... you're better off without me.
What remained of me?
A dim image in a mirror...
Faster!... catch that son of a bitch!
Damn...
This time will not get away, you bastard!
We... to end this... now.
I should have fucking long.
I'm going to kill you, fucking asshole.
Check the brake! Check the brake!
About the camera a little.
To see wait a little, soon followed.
The mother who bore!
Sometimes it can seem as hard as you want!