About 140 years ago
in the turbulent Bakumatsu era...
There was an assassin
called Hitokiri Battousai.
Following orders of the
people of the anti-shogunate
movement he was acting behind
the scenes in Kyoto...
Being feared by many due
to his strength and
cool-headedness even in
the fiercest of fights.
It is now the crucial battle of
the Boshin Civil War...
[January of 1868]
[In the mountains of Toba-fushimi]
It's them! Shinsengumi!
Hitokiri Battousai!
Where are you? Where?
Saito Hajime, Captain of the Third Unit
of the Shinsengumi! Brace yourself!
It's time for the duel, Battousai!
We won! It's the Imperial Standard!
Now you're just a rebel army!
It's the victory of the
Satsuma-Choushuu Alliance!
So it's come...
The new age.
At last.
Himura Battousai!
Don't think it's the end of it.
Even if the world changes...
We have no other path but to
live by the sword and die by the sword.
Why?
Why have I survived?
What's with this sword?
It belongs to Hitokiri Battousai...
[1878 - the 11th year of Meiji Era]
[Tokyo]
Field marshal Yamagata Aritomo speaks!
Salute!
At ease!
10 years have passed
since the Revolution...
This country became unified!
It continues to develop using
the Western countries as a model.
Power of the new government
spread far and wide...
Bringing fortune and stability
to our country!
The age when fear and violence
were ruling came to the end!
Salute!
Humans are weak.
They long to talk about ideals...
But in the end three things make
them no better than animals...
Their well-being...
Money...
And pleasure.
Excuse me.
It's a success! You did well, Megumi.
Thank you.
This new sort of opium...
Turns human into a beast.
You may go.
One person who knows the way
of making is more than enough.
Which one should I choose? Says Kamisama...
[Japanese counting-out rhyme]
Thank you so much!
Damn it!
Let's go!
Leave him alone.
This guy...
I'll leave him to Battousai.
Banzai! Banzai!
How about delicious yaki-dango?
I'll take one.
Why don't you understand?
That's why I told you not to come closer!
Go away! There! Get it already!
[On the paper: The vindication
of slaying the evil.
Himura Battousai of
Kamiya Kasshin Ryuu]
It's the police officer who
were working undercover.
It is a warning then.
Again Hitokiri Battousai... Why there
is always an assassin's vindication?
It's a fake.
What?
A "vindication of slaying
the evil" is a list
of all misdeeds the
killed person committed.
But there's none...
It's not the Battousai's way of doing.
Oro?
[Wanted]
"Hitokiri Battousai"?
"Kamiya Kasshin Ryuu"?
You!
Who else would defy the law
and carry a sword?
Are you the rumored Hitokiri Battousai?
Oro?
Your wrongdoings will end today!
Brace yourself!
Wait a second, wait!
Don't play dumb!
You're mistaken!
Ororo...
This one is but a rurouni...
A swordsman travelling with
no destination.
I see you've realised it.
Why do you carry such a thing then?
This is a sakabato.
Sakabato?
Like this...
Blade is upside down...
Isn't it different form a usual sword?
You can't kill anyone with this.
Right?
Much obliged.
What's more important -
this discription of a person...
For last six months...
Proclaimed himself to be
one of my sword school,
he's been leaving
assassin's vindications.
Even though the age has
changed, he still...
Oro?
Kanryu-sama!
There is a guest.
And here I thought that the police
always come in a bunch.
How about one?
And what is this I wonder.
Police officer who worked
undercover was killed.
The killer calls himself "Battousai".
10 years have passed, yet
a ghost of samurai age
is brought back once again
to kill, is it not?
What do you have in Shinbashi's storehouse?
Oh, over there?
We are not using it now.
We planned to use it for
storage of imported goods...
But it didn't work out.
If you want to examine it all the same...
We shall insist on you coming
through all the formalities.
With all the respect, law is law.
This is the new age after all.
Don't get carried away.
This ghost of the samurai age seems to fail
to notice that the times have changed.
It's a meal!
Look at those people.
They all lost their livelihood
with coming of the Meiji era.
Descendants of samurais,
samurais, ronins.
I couldn't remain indifferent looking at them.
So I hired them as my guards.
It's for everyone's good
that I look after them.
As they're very capable, if you
just leave them alone who knows
what they'll do. No one can predict
whom a hungry dog would bite.
Well, by looking at you I can tell
that you were a samurai as well.
And still am.
As expected, we won't get along.
Be careful.
Police is all about "evidence and proof"
but I'm not.
Kanryu-sama, Megumi has disappeared.
What'd you say? Megumi's run away?
We were informed by the bribed policeman.
He told that she came to the police alone.
Damn it, Megumi!
No need to worry, I'm tellin ya!
If she tells them about the opium
she'll be charged for making it as well.
You're so stupid!
Can you imagine what will happen
if she get desperate?
What do you know about women?
What?! What the hell!
Shut up!
Bring the woman back. Now!
Don't you touch me.
What did you say?
I'll search for her.
What?
Don't kill her, Jin'e.
She knows the secret of
manufacturing "a spider's web".
With others do whatever
you want, "Battousai".
Isn't it you who asked for our protection?
If you don't explain the situation to us...
Can't be helped then.
What happened?
It's over there!
What's going on?
This way!
Get off the way!
Are you Battousai?
Quit your resistance!
What are you?
Don't move!
Stay where you are!
It's not a black magic.
It's Nikkaidou Heihou's "Shin no Ippou".
Human's heart is weak
being full of fears.
By striking this weakness
with strong spirit of
the sword I paralize all
victim's movements.
Is it painful?
The weaker heart is
the easier to strike.
Ah, it's a kitten!
Cute!
What's...
Stop right there!
Are you that Battousai?
For what reason do you murder people...
Proclaiming yourself to be one
of Kamiya Kasshin Ryuu?
Because of a scum like you, my father...
Kamiya Kasshin Ryuu left by my father is...
You father is what?
He teached the sword which brings
men to life. Sword that is not for kill...
Not for murder...
But for bringing men to life!
Woman with a wooden sword
has the guts to face me.
Shut up!
What can you do with this stick?
Only after it tasted blood
sword comes to life...
You'll percieve it in the next world.
You forgot this.
What? Who are you?
It doesn't matter.
So it's you the man who
calls himself Battousai.
This scar...
This speed...
You must be the legendary...
It doesn't work on you...
Run!
This way!
Brace yourself, Battousai!
Seems like there was a point
surviving in this boring world after all.
Get the rope ready!
Are you alright?
He's there! Battousai's there!
Catch him!
This way.
No, this one.
Oro?!
I have to thank you...
But just so you know
I'd be fine even without your help.
It's better to treat your wounds right now.
Acting master Kamiya Kaoru...
It was never a big school...
But still, in respect of my father
who passed away...
Many people have been practicing here.
However, six months ago...
Because of the commotion Battousai
started it's became like this...
I need to stop his wrong-doings
as fast as possible. Otherwise...
You should give up on him.
What?
He is far stronger than you, Kaoru-dono.
A swordsman must be honest
about his foe's skill and his own.
You must have realised already,
what will happen next time you face him.
Dignity of your school...
Such a thing is not worth your life.
Sword is not a tool to kill people with...
Kamiya Kasshin Ryuu sees as ideal
the sword that brings men to life.
For the school to be stained by
a sword that kills is unthinkable.
But just a mere rurouni...
Can't understand this pain!
The sword that brings to life...
Well...
Whatever your reasons
might be, it's impossible
to patrol at nights
with such a wound.
I'm sure your father
wouldn't wish his dauther...
To protect the name of the school...
With her own life.
Exuse me.
Such an awful murders!
Does he challenge us?
Rurouni?
Ah, it's just you...
What'd you mean "just me"?
Not satisfyed with Myoujin Yahiko-sama?
You're too noisy.
Where is my breakfast?
Be so kind to feed a poor starving child!
You're making too much noise.
Trainings first.
Kaoru: Start cleaning up already!
Yahiko: I don't want!
Who are you?
We come to get this dojo.
[He holds the dojo sign.]
What?
We'll give you a good price.
One noble man says he wants
to buy it for a lot of money.
For you... It's not a bad offer.
What are you talking about?
I'd never give away my father's
dojo just like that!
Hey, master!
You're quite a shameless woman, huh.
To talk like that after the cruel murderer
came right out of your school...
Battousai has nothing
to do with our school!
Don't get so worked up!
It seems noone comes near your dojo,
the dojo that trains murderers.
Do it, guys!
Stop!
Stop it!
What do you think you're doing?!
Yahiko!
What's with this brat?
I'm Myoujin Yahiko -
descendant of Tokyo samurais!
And I won't forgive bastards
who bully the weak!
Let go of him!
What are you doing?!
Talk big after you got strong not before!
Exactly!
This school is said to teach
the sword that brings to life...
How about bring yourself to life
with that sword?
Don't walk into with your shoes on!
Sword that brings to life... So naive!
Remove your shoes! Put off your shoes!
Our goal is violence,
the essence of our art is to kill!
This is the true nature
of swordsmanship.
Get it!
Won't forgive!
Rurouni...
Out of the way!
Who're you?
You are right...
Her words are the words of a person...
Who never soiled one's
hands with a killing.
Sounds like childish nonsense.
A sword is a weapon.
Swordsmanship is an art of killing.
No matter what pretty words you use...
This is the truth that can not be changed.
But in the face of such awful truth...
I prefer the naive words of Kaoru-dono.
Bullshit!
Don't run, you! Go face him!
Don't hide, you idiot!
I tell you to go and fight!
The style Hitokiri Battousai uses
is that of Hiten Mitsurugi Ryuu.
It's an ancient style
that pits one against many.
If not for this sword...
Many of you would be dead.
You bastard!
You are...
Kaoru-chan!
What've happened?!
He's dead!
What... What have happened here?
Is it him? He killed them?!
No, you're wrong.
They suddenly came to attack the dojo.
But it's okay.
No one has been killed,
they are just unconscious.
This way, this way!
What happened?
You what, haven't heard about
the law? No swords are allowed!
Bring them all in!
What happened here?
I'm afraid it's all my fault...
I'm rurouni and I'm to
blame for all of this...
It has nothing to do with this dojo.
Let's go!
Wait!
Rurouni-san...
What is it?
At least tell me your name!
Ororo!
Wait a second!
It is Himura Kenshin.
Off the way!
Kenshin...
The heart of sword...
Quiet!
Newcomer's here!
Move your legs!
Open the door!
A man with the scar
in a shape of character "ten".
Just as I thought, it's you.
Long time no see...
Hitokiri Battousai.
It's been almost ten years
since the Battle of Toba-fushimi.
I need to talk to you.
Come out.
Hitokiri Battousai, huh.
It's sure have been a while!
Where you have been hiding all this time?
Yamagata-san?
There've been rumors that
last ten years extremely
skilled rurouni has been
helping people around.
I ordered my men to investigate it.
What?
Ah, this guy?
In the past we followed different paths.
But both of us wanted
the same - the better country.
Now he is called Fujita Goro.
He works for me.
What do you want from me?
There is a bunch that sells it openly.
Goes by name "spider's web".
Outside it looks like normal opium
but content is absolutely different.
Makes people heavely addicted.
Opium will ruin the country.
Even the greatest Qing dynasty
couldn't do anything...
And the part of its territories
became a British colony.
I'm only a rurouni.
Why explain it all to me?
No doubt...
They are planning something bigger.
Help me...
Get a position in the military service...
And use these hands once
more for the sake of...
I don't feel like working
as hitokiri ever again.
"Hitokiri", huh?
It all was for the sake of Revolution!
Have you lost all strength of yours?
Why use such a ridiculous sword?
How are you going to protect anybody,
a hitokiri who doesn't kill?
Even with this sword...
I can protect the people within my sight.
Want to try it?
Before talking big how about
protect at least yourself?
I won't draw my sword.
As if I care!
Sword with a blade put upside down...
Will hurt you in the end.
Just like this.
Have you remembered that time?
As I threw my past away...
I don't kill people anymore!
That's enough!
I'm sorry for that.
It's nothing.
Release him.
Hey, Kaoru?
Kaoru!
Oh!
Sorry! Are you okay?
Help me, please!
I'm being chased!
I beg you.
Kaoru-dono...
You have nowhere to go, right?
Come to my place.
Because you saved me.
You must have already realised...
That I was a hitokiri.
I don't care!
The person I met...
Was a rurouni called Kenshin.
We all have things in our past
we don't want to talk about.
Right?
Here you are.
Take it!
Let's go!
Come on.
Come inside.
Exuse me for intruding.
Yahiko.
This is Myoujin Yahiko.
I teach him sword from time to time...
And he lives there most of the time.
She has no students at all
so I kindly come to visit.
He is rude but kind inside.
Shut up! I just want to become strong!
As you wish.
Kenshin will live here too from now on.
I'm your sempai then!
Take good care of me.
O..ok.
Introduce him to me too.
What? Who are you?!
She was soaking wet so I decided
to let her take the bath at least.
And you decided it all by yourself?
Who is that gentlmen?
W..wait!
This is rurouni, he's name is Kenshin.
Oh, so it's you!
I heard about you from the boy.
I'm Takani Megumi.
Nice to meet you!
Nice to meet you.
It's better to have
a change of clothes, right?
Much obliged.
Father was a big man...
Only his clothes from when
he was young will fit you.
Color...
Color may be a little bit flashy for you...
No, it's alright.
Sword that brings to life...
Welcome!
By the way...
Why are you even here?
Oh, looks like someone is jealous!
You are not from here, are you?
Where do you live? Where are you from?
Secret!
Mysterious woman is beautiful, isn't she?
Enough of this talk.
Here you are.
Thank you.
It's in a sign of my gratitude. So don't
be shy and eat as much as you want.
Then...
Delicious.
Right?
So hot!
Eat carefully!
I know!
Kaoru-chan...
I heard about what happened in the dojo.
Tae-san...
Don't give up.
We all decided...
That we won't sell our places
no matter what.
Welcome!
Ah, that's Takeda Kanryu!
He is a businessman who has
a mansion on the outskirts of town.
Where is the bathroom?
That way.
Kanryu-sama!
Excuse me for interrupting your dinner...
Is it you that brave man who alone
protected the dojo from ten thugs?
I am trading foreign goods.
Hey.
Let's go straight to the point.
I want to employ you with this money.
If you work for ten people you'll get
a payment tenth times bigger.
How about that?
Will you become our bodyguard?
I decline your offer.
Is this not enough?
I got it.
Eagles eat no flies, is that it?
Well, I don't mind.
However, in the Meiji era
money is everything.
Sorry to tell you that,
but now your pride is worthless.
Moreover, samurais who
continue to hold onto it...
Are falling low one after another.
As a result, nowadays
red-light districts...
Are full of wifes and
daughters of ex-samurais.
Look at the members of gangs...
All of them are samurais who broke down.
That's the world we live in now.
Forget about your samurai's past.
And start to learn...
How to enjoy...
Your life.
Exuse me.
No money, no hot pot.
I'll get that money then!
Sanosuke-san?
W-wait!
Hire me!
Who are you?
I'm fight merchant Sagara Sanousuke!
Just out of jail.
Have nothing to do.
Are you good enough...
For such a sum?
Want to try me out,
legendary hitokiri...
Himura Battousai-san!
What?!
If I beat him will you employ me?
We disturb people here.
May we go outside?
I've been waiting for it!
All go outside!
It's a fight!
This is a sword...
To cut riders with horses.
It's called zanbatou.
Was popular during the Ounin War.
Haven't been using it for ages,
so it's not sharp at all.
Still...
I can smash you down with it.
Wait!
Himura Battousai!
Warrior of Revolution
from Choushuu province!
Worked as hitokiri for 5 years,
since he was 14 years old.
But for the last 10 years
no one has seen you.
That was good!
Off the way!
I put my sword away.
Then bring it back and fight me!
I don't want to fight you.
Why is that?!
There is no reason for us to fight.
That man...
Are you going to use your talent for him?
What's happening?
What's wrong?
What are you doing, fight merchant?
Kill him already!
Shut up!
Don't you tell me how to fight!
Is it the end?
Well, let it be it then.
Don't want to end up in jail again.
Looks like I made some noise!
Go back, all of you!
It was just for show!
It's the end!
Let's go home.
Sorry for causing trouble.
Let's go back and eat.
Would be a waste not to eat it all.
He is the real thing.
Be careful with him.
We shouldn't make Battousai angry.
Got it!
Not enough blood!
Still not enough blood!
This is my way of doing!
It is me who is real Hitokiri Battousai!
Again work of fake Battousai...
Killed them, killed the police officers.
Who's side he is on.
Once you lose your humanity,
you can't go back.
Only then one can be called "hitokiri".
Please, go ahead.
What?
Let's go.
Wait!
I got it!
Those are guys who attacked the dojo.
Result would be the same
if you just killed them at the time.
But if you did it then...
Those police officers would still be alive.
Even your sakabato...
Can be useful.
Off the way!
Let me see!
Won't you work for us as an assassin?
For the sake of the new era.
[Fourteen years ago, Kyoto]
If in exchange for all sacrificed lifes...
The new era will come...
Where everyone will be
able to live happily...
At a time like this...
Marriage of all things!
I'm sorry.
Well, it's a good thing anyway!
Such a happy person!
Lucky bastard!
Wish I could too!
Who are you! Tell us your name!
You're the Battousai!
Satsuma-Choushuu bastard!
You jerk!
I can not die...
I have a person precious to me...
I must not die!
Can't die! Can't die!
I have someone dear...
Must not die...
Can't die, can't...
[Vendication of slaying the evil]
Can a murder of the young ones
who bear the future...
Be called the murder for the new age?
Is it really right to do what I am doing?
You are just a mere murderer!
Kenshin!
Kaoru-dono?
I was worried because
you didn't come back.
I thought you might have
gone somewhere...
I am starving.
Wonderful!
To imagine that such a
thing really existed!
So, what's about our plan?
All arrangements are done.
After destroying everything around
there I will build a harbour...
And send ships loaded with opium!
Send where?
Throughout the country!
No!
[America] [France]
Throughout the whole world!
[England] [China]
Money I got from all the people
who turned into beasts.
I'll spend on weapons...
And create "Empire of Kanryu"!
I'll replace the new government!
Time has come!
Awake, Battousai!
Megumi.
Who may have thought that
you were hiding at such a place...
You can't deny the fact that you
were the one manufacturing the opium.
You and we... No.
You and opium share the same fate.
You are one of us so I'll tell you...
Be careful.
Megumi prepared the rice.
Kenshin prepared the miso soup.
And Kaoru prepared...
The fish.
You'd better practice more.
Men prefers to marry the women
who is good at cooking.
So he might get taken by someone else.
Piss off!
You're getting on my nerves!
Could someone find me new student?
If I continue to practice with
such a weakling I'll lose my skill.
It's my line!
Kaoru-dono, Yahiko, both of you...
Let's just eat!
Kaoru-chan!
Is anybody here?
I need your help!
Her body suddenly became numb...
Breathing got harsh and then...
Have you seen the doctor?
No, since the last night all doctors
from the area have disappeared!
We don't know what to do anymore!
Hey!
Be careful.
I'll get this dojo!
Kaoru-chan! Kaoru-chan!
Help us!
Kaoru-chan!
Help!
What's happened?
She's been telling since morning
that her belly hurts.
She collapsed...
This way?
What's happening?
Is it a virus?
Hey!
Somebody, call a doctor!
If you need a doctor,
there is one right here.
High temperature and coma...
Most probably caused by poison.
What?
Poison? Are you sure?
We must get the poison out fast!
And water, I need water!
But not from the well!
There's a high chance that
wells were poisoned. What?
Come to the drug store,
buy some castor oil.
I also need a towel and a kettle.
And you!
You go buy as much water as possible.
Kaoru-san, can we get any
Chinese medicine in the town?
I'll write you the list,
go and bring it all!
We are dealing with a poison!
Time is everything! Quickly!
Got it! Yes!
I brought water! Who needs water?
It'll heal you.
You'll get better.
I won't forgive.
How dare he treat person's life like this?
Megumi-dono.
Wouldn't you tell me the truth at last?
You said "Takani-san"?
You mean Megumi-san?
You know her?
Know? There is no one
in the world of medicine...
Who doesn't know name "Takani"!
Takani Clan is a famous family...
That has been healing
people for many years...
However, during the Aizu War...
They all went to the front
and were killed in a battle.
Is it so?
Only one daugther stayed alive.
You were a hitokiri, weren't you?
How about to tell me about yourself...
Before asking me.
You must have killed many people
with those hands of yours.
And this scar?
To boast around?
Decoration of some kind?
This scar...
It was left by one young samurai...
While this one...
Was left by the woman who
was going to be his wife.
Countless lifes...
I took countless lifes.
I'm different from you.
I've no family. No relatives to rely on...
Kanryu found me...
And I've become his woman.
We just used each other...
He used me to get money
for the opium while I used him...
To survive.
To survive...
Give me some opium! Please!
Shut up!
Kanryu has over 250 guards...
And among them some are skilled samurais...
Who lost everything in the revolution.
I'll go with you.
Kenshin!
Kenshin, this...
Megumi-san has left.
It can't be.
I'll go too!
No.
The only master of
Kamiya Kasshin Ryuu must be safe.
But... It'll probably
take all night...
So prepare breakfast for
five people and a hot bath!
I'll go too!
Yahiko!
Even if you go, you'll
just be a hindrance.
Shut up!
Yahiko!
You'll stay at the dojo.
What?
I entrust Kaoru-dono and the dojo to you.
Of course...
I knew you'd come back.
You have nowhere to go...
But here.
From tomorrow you'll work hard...
I came back...
Not to make more opium...
What?
I came back to kill you!
Calm down...
We have the same fate...
I'll kill myself right after!
You morons, stop staring
and do something!
Stop being foolish!
It's my atonement!
You!
Ungrateful bitch!
Finally there...
It's him.
Takeda Kanryu!
Hey you! I'll beat the shit
out of you for free!
Come here right now!
Himura Battousai!
Megumi-dono!
Dare to break into others' house!
What a scum!
What're you talking about?!
Don't hold yourself!
Kill them!
Kill them right now!
Do it! I have money for all!
Look! It's the money!
I'll pay as much as you
want for their heads!
Kill them!
I don't get it!
Why? Why Battousai is doing it?
For what?
If he was a man who wants money or fame, he
could have been in the military top by now.
Warriors of the Revolution
are all like this.
What a clever dick!
Get it ready!
You mean "that" thing? But...
Don't you talk back!
It's an iron rule of the business!
Be double sure!
Bring the woman!
Can I ask you a favour?
Where that crazy glassess-guy went?
Probably upstairs...
Who's among you morons my opponent?
I'll be the one for you!
Hand to hand!
Time for fight merchants has come!
Go ahead!
Much obliged.
So you're the Battousai...
Where is Megumi-dono?
Is that woman even worth saving?
There is not a single person
not worth saving.
What a nice logic.
You tell me.
Why did you sell your soul to Kanryu?
Soul?
You also once belonged
to a samurai clan, did you not?
Stop talking nonsense.
Because I couldn't feed myself...
In that peaceful era you created.
Kenshin! Are you ok?
Die!
What's with this sword?
It's my vow not to kill ever again.
Sakabato.
Where do you think you're going?!
Wait a second! Wait!
What for?
Want to try it too? It's good!
Here!
I'm a vegetarian. Poor thing.
Drink it then?
Give it to me.
After killing so many people
it's too late for sakabato!
Cut the bullshit!
Fight is done!
By head!
It was fun!
Finally got serious...
What is the vow not to kill?!
You think you'll end this
fight without killing?
I will.
Come and try!
You've done him pretty hard.
Let's go.
Wait...
It's not the end of our battle yet!
Fight!
It is the end of it.
Too much fun!
Fire!
Sanosuke!
You'll let me smoke my cigar
slowly, will you not?
Huh? Look at what you've
done to others' home!
Bastards!
It's you who've done it all, idiot!!
Where is the legendary hitokiri?!
Don't understimate me!
I'll help you kill him.
Why are you here?
The brat from your place
came to the police.
Yahiko?
What've happened?
Look...
If this monstrous canon aims at one side...
Other side becomes a blind spot.
Come at me!
Welcome, welcome!
Come on!
I give up!
You won!
Don't shoot, don't shoot!
There's no way we could
defeat such a thing.
Right, Kenshin?
You come too, we can't win.
I surrender.
Put off your sword!
Apologize to me!
Cast yourself at my feet!
And put off your clothes!
Get naked!
Apologize on your knees, naked!
Don't get carried away!
Damn you!
This way! Shoot!
Shoot! Shoot! Shoot!
More! More!
Damn!
Do you see now
what thing money can't buy?
You're the one begging now...
It's a life.
Quit it!
That means now I finally
can beat the shit out of you.
It's my work from now on. Go!
Much obliged.
Megumi-dono!
Sorry for making you wait.
It's all right now.
Thank God you're safe.
Don't waste your time!
Kaoru-san's in trouble!
Looks like you're back to your senses.
Don't look at me like that.
I took you as hostage
because it'll enrage Battousai.
Rage will bring more rage and
he'll be back to Hitokiri he once was.
Looks like he'll be here soon.
Kenshin!
You are angry.
Yes, at you bastard who
involved Kaoru-dono.
And at myself who couldn't prevent it.
Kenshin?
That's good, Battousai
Get angry more!
Kaoru-dono!
Think you can kill me with such a sword?
Kenshin!
You read my moves well...
Untill my "backwards wheel"!
Kenshin!
Not yet!
You aren't the Battousai yet.
Not nearly.
Kaoru-dono!
I made Shin no Ippou stronger than usual.
Enough to stop her lungs.
She will last two minutes at most.
Jin'e!
You've no time to talk.
If you've something to say,
speak with that sword!
Very good!
If you do want to live...
Break the spell you put on Kaoru-dono!
I can't anymore.
There's only two ways...
She must either break it herself or...
My will must be shattered...
With my death.
Then...
It's time for our duel,
Himura Battousai
No more games.
Strike so that I can kill you.
Take this!
The stance of Battoujutsu, huh.
Hiten Mitsurugi Ryuu,
battoujutsu "Souryuusen".
I crushed your elbow
and severed your ligaments.
Your life as swordsmen is over...
And this...
Is the end of your life.
To save Kaoru-dono...
I will once again become the hitokiri.
Kill me!
Die!
Kenshin, no!
She broke the spell!
Kaoru-dono.
Don't become hitokiri!
You mustn't kill.
Don't kill him...
Kenshin...
You...
For the sake of people you killed...
Until now...
For the sake of people you saved...
Now people can be saved...
Cause now is...
Now is the new age...
Which...
Which was created by you, Kenshin!
Kaoru-dono...
We must end it, Battousai.
That's enough.
You can't win with only left hand.
It's not the end yet.
Inside you're the hitokiri as well.
I'm the hitokiri myself, I can tell...
No matter what hitokiri is hitokiri.
You won't be able to pretend
to be just a rurouni forever.
I'll wait for you in the hell.
Do you get it now?
What happens when you
go around talking about "justice"...
Pretending to be a rurouni
who would not kill...
When someone is killed, hatred is born...
The hatred brings another murder...
To break this chain...
Is a purpose of this sword
which does not kill.
How long are going to say these
fine but empty words?
Going to wander again?
The way of rurouni is
the way of weaklings.
Live by the sword die by the sword.
There is no other way for us.
There are lots of smuggled goods...
Don't let anyone get away!
Why won't you lead me to the harbor?
If you let me run away,
I'll pay you in abundance!
Money is in this pocket...
In this pocket!
There's money in it!
At least bring me other shoe, won't you?
Shut up!
It's so hard to walk!
I'll be back! You'll see!
Kenshin!
You're awake?
Where's Kenshin?
Eh? Ah, well...
What is it?
No, it can't be...
Wait!
Oro?
Kenshin!
You woke up, Kaoru-dono...
Listen to the end!
Kenshin promised to prepare dinner today.
I'm so hungry!
Welcome back, Kenshin...
I'm home.
Translation by Translator Sensei.
Edit and timing by Kateviardo.
Find us at:
Kateviardo.tumblr.com