(Claramount)
it happened in 1932.
Atanza!
(Crowd)
They killed us!
It happened in the election...
Of 1945 and 1950!
- They killed us!
- It happened...
In the one-candidate
election of 1962.
(Crowd)
They robbed us!
It happened
in the election...
- Where the winner kept changing.
- We need reinforcements.
(Claramount)
Even though the voting was
long since completely done!
They robbed us!
(Claramount)
And now, 1977,
and this time, we will not
stand for it anymore!
We will occupy this plaza...
Until there is a true election,
a free election!
Freedom, freedom, freedom!
Freedom, freedom!
(Man)
Everybody who's finished voting,
please get back on the bus.
Thank you.
(Father Morantes)
Alfonso, take care of
these two that never voted.
Let's go! Everybody
line up over there to vote.
Good morning.
Hey, Fernando, listen.
Pick up the bus
at El Paisnal,
and take it to San Martin.
There are 100 more voters
waiting for you. Hurry.
Come.
Look at them.
(Woman)
We need more voting
papers over here.
I cursed the rain.
I cursed the dirt.
But after the land
was saved,
I knew I loved it, too.
It was ours.
But now,
they came and said
we had to go.
We were only sharecroppers.
We had no rights.
When we wouldn't go,
they burned our homes.
They left us with nothing.
It's God's will.
Who says it's God's will?
I think God looks at
these things and vomits!
What's the matter?
Oscar, what are you thinking?
What are you doing?
I am not doing anything.
It is the people that
are doing it, at last.
Archbishop Chavez says
you are going too fast.
What do you think?
I've always believed in you
and your strength, your ideals.
But some are
even saying you're a...
Sub... subversive, an agitator.
Remember who else
they called such names.
Jesus is not somewhere
up in the clouds...
Lying in a hammock.
Jesus is down here with us,
building a kingdom.
Oscar,
what else can I do?
I cannot love God,
whom I do not see,
if I do not love
my brothers and sisters,
whom I can see.
[Church bells]
(Boy)
Father Grande!
They're stopping buses
on the road.
The voters can't get through.
Where?
On the road from El Paisnal.
[Gun shots]
[Screaming]
[Brakes squeal]
It's okay now.
Everybody out!
We have to get to
Auxiliaries to vote.
Tell that to the guerillas.
They're trying to
sabotage the election.
The road is closed.
Good afternoon,
lieutenant.
These people want
to get to the polls.
There are snipers shooting
at anything that moves.
The polls close in 3 hours.
I'm sorry, but I
cannot jeopardize...
The safety of all of these people.
They say the road
is too dangerous.
We'll take the risk!
These buses are not
going anyplace.
The lieutenant will not
let us drive to Aguilares,
so...
Shall we walk?
Yes, father!
(Father Grande)
Come, lieutenant,
you can protect us.
You don't need me.
No terrorist would dare
shoot at the church.
I'll see the jeep
gets back, Monsignor.
A little walk will do you good.
Martinez!
[Gun shots]
Keep moving.
Come on!
They've been trying
to kill these people.
First, they will have to kill us.
We walk in the
protection of the Lord.
Jesus was vulnerable.
Don't think we're not.
What should we be,
cowards?
Not cowards,
but not heroes either.
Just ordinary people
trying to do our job.
So are the soldiers.
You know, I think
that pretty soon,
they won't allow the Bible
into our country anymore.
All we'll get is the bindings,
because everything inside,
all the pages, will be
declared revolutionary.
Tilio, you should be the one...
Taking Archbishop
Chavez's place.
I’m not even a bishop.
But you can talk.
You know the people.
We need someone
who can change things,
before it's too late.
Rivera-y-damas
is a good man.
The worst
be Romero.
[Laughter]
Not even the Vatican
is that crazy.
(Father Osuna)
He'd fiddle while
El Salvador burns.
We won't let
El Salvador burn.
[Singing]
[Knock at door]
Come in.
Oscar.
Hello, Monsignor.
Are you all right?
I’m fine.
I’m just tired.
It's been a difficult day.
I have some
news for you.
Please sit down,
Monsignor.
I think you may
need to sit down.
You have been
appointed archbishop.
I'm not qualified.
The Vatican has
every confidence,
and I will support you.
Others won't.
It is not an easy time.
What should I do?
What God wants.
What is that?
He's a good
compromise choice.
He'll make no waves.
He's a bookworm.
The whole country
could be running wild,
and he wouldn't even notice lt.
The military will keep
a lid on things.
They might need to,
and you might get
another medal.
Perhaps.
Anyway, his health is delicate.
It always has been.
He won't last.
Yes, give him
a happy death soon.
Shhhh.
[Organ music]
I come from
a world of books,
and there is much
to learn in their pages.
But I have
much else to learn.
There is ferment and division...
Alive in our land.
Certain priests accept...
And express the most
radical ideas glibly.
But none of us can pretend
to know all the answers,
and demand that others
implement them.
We in the church...
Must keep to the center,
watchfully,
in the traditional way,
but seeking justice.
(Priest)
Monsignor, may I present the
president-elect and his wife.
(General Humberto)
Best wishes, Monsignor.
We seem to share victories.
Yes.
We hope more than that.
We must work closely together.
Yes, general.
Thank you.
Monsignor.
Monsignor, this is for you,
with the best wishes
of our family.
Thank you.
We have a house
in Escalon, too.
It would be our privilege
to offer it to you...
As a home, as a quiet
place to get away to.
I hope you will baptize our
daughter's new baby, Monsignor.
It would be my privilege.
Monsignor.
We had to bring you
a little something, too,
for all your books.
(Romero)
It's very beautiful.
After the reception, you must
have a quiet lunch with us,
just the three of us.
Will you excuse me
for a moment, please?
It's good to see you!
It's not so much.
It's nothing compared to...
but I brought you
something, too.
This is what
I really needed!
I know.
[Laughter]
Shhhh.
[Shoes squeak]
There.
- Like them?
- Yeah.
Everybody knows
you're coming.
Here's the archbishop.
[Laughter]
[El Salvadoran music]
[Clapping and singing]
- Body of Christ.
- Amen.
Santo, Santo, nuestro dios
Santo, Santo, Santo, Santo
Seoor de todas las naciones
Santo, Santo, nuestro dios
- Body of Christ.
- Amen.
[Clapping and singing]
[Engine sounds]
[Siren blares]
(Crowd)
Freedom, freedom!
You have five minutes
to disperse!
(Soldier)
The military commander
of San Salvador...
Orders you to clear the plaza!
You have five minutes
to disperse!
(Soldier)
Clear the plaza!
We order you to
disperse immediately!
Disperse!
[Clapping continues]
[Gun shot]
[Woman screams]
[Screaming]
[Gun shots]
Stop it!
[Hysterical screaming]
[Gun shots]
[Engine roars]
[Screaming]
[Music]
Lieutenant,
listen to me, please.
The signs are everywhere.
The unions,
the cooperatives,
the student and
campesino organizations,
everywhere.
Too many people
do not realize...
How high
the stakes are.
The basic freedoms
we take for granted;
our whole way of life.
And no government...
Can put a stop to it
alone, believe me.
Ah.
Ricardo, this is not one
of your business meetings.
It's a party.
But we're coming now.
We were just
looking at the house.
[Violin music]
Natalia is feeling
very uncomfortable.
She doesn't Know
anyone here.
She knows me.
I like her.
So do I.
So is she the one?
I doubt it.
Monsignor, I'd like you
to meet Ricardo Columa.
My warmest
congratulations, Monsignor.
Thank you.
Who is that?
I don't know how
to say this, but...
About an hour ago,
I was giving holy communion...
With Fathers Osuna
and Morantes.
Suddenly, the national
guard arrived.
Now there are perhaps
70 people... Dead.
I'll go at once.
It's too late.
Don't you see what's
going on around here?
Anyone who says
what he thinks...
About land reform or wages
or God or human rights...
Automatically is
labeled a communist.
He lives in fear,
they take him away, they
torture him, they kill him.
You don't
believe me, do you?
Goodbye, Oscar.
Where are you going?
Back to Aguilares,
to be with my people,
to serve them,
to work with them,
to strengthen them...
While they are still alive.
[Woman weeping]
(Father Villez)
"This is not the way God
wants his children to live.
"He cries out
to heaven for redress.
"Therefore, even at the risk
of being misunderstood...
"or persecuted,
"the church must lift
its voice in protest,
"when a society
is so permeated...
With injustice."
What does everyone think?
It is inflammatory.
The people will
take to the streets.
(Bishop Cordova)
But there is nothing but
the truth in this statement.
It must be said.
I believe it should be read
at all the masses this Sunday.
I'm not sure.
You asked for the
statement, Monsignor.
I know.
And now you want
to give it up?
No, just toned down.
It mustn't be incendiary.
That's it.
That's right!
(Bishop Flores)
An equitable solution.
The archbishop
and Monsignor Cordova
will amend the statement.
In favor?
Against?
Approved.
[Babies crying]
(Father Grande)
Fernando, I baptize you...
In the name of the father
and of the son...
And of the holy spirit.
[Baby cries]
Luis, I baptize you...
In the name of the father
and of the son...
And of the holy spirit.
[Car horn]
Fernando, can I
give you a lift?
Hello, take my hat.
Yes, the sun is very,
very hot today.
All right, off we go.
(Child)
Off we go!
La-lalala
la-la-la lee-ya-da-la-la
la-lalaya
[car horn]
(Father Grande)
Oh, my God!
Get down!
[Gun shots]
[Crying]
[Screaming]
You, get out!
Come on, let's go!
Get out of here!
You, get out of here!
[Moan]
[Gun shot]
You are very,
very sick.
Very, very sick.
(Girl)
You must rest,
and we will treat you,
and try to save you.
(Boy)
Treat you and
try to save you.
Am I going to die?
Your temperature is 1012.
Very sick.
Let me see.
That sounds a little high.
A hundred-and-one.
(Man)
Monsignor, it's for you.
Excuse me,
doctors.
Yes?
- I will give the homily.
- No!
The archbishop must.
The archbishop should speak.
He's here.
His presence is enough.
This is the time
when he should speak!
Excuse me,
fathers,
I'm looking
for my boy.
I'm looking for my Rutilio.
I must...
Take him home
to his mother...
To wash him...
And sit with him.
(Romero)
Yes,
but afterward, I would
like you to permit us...
To take him
to the cathedral.
I want them to lie
together for all to see.
This Sunday, there will not be
a mass in Aguilares...
Or El Paisnal...
Or Santiago.
There will be a single mass
in the cathedral.
And it will be...
For a...
A fine priest,
an old man,
and the boy.
(Romero)
They are equal,
and they are us.
(Romero)
They were murdered,
and we must not
let this happen again.
You cannot do that;
force everyone to go
to the same mass.
It's never been
done before.
Priests have not been
assassinated before.
The church's job is
to preach the gospel.
This is going to be interpreted
as a political statement.
I am not trying to make
a political statement.
I want to draw
our people together,
to mourn these deaths
and to express their outrage.
The church has always
been a stabilizing influence.
If we abandon
this role now,
what will happen?
Are you all against it?
Yes.
Yes!
I defer to your authority.
And you, Monsignor?
I don't know.
(FIores)
Not everybody could come.
Not everybody would come.
(Cordova)
There is no majority.
(Estrada)
It will deprive the people
of the sacraments.
(Cordova)
We must vote again.
May I help you?
Well, I was looking for
Monsignor Rivera-y-Damas,
but he is busy.
Is it a matter
of confession?
No, not exactly.
Not really.
How can I confess
what I did not do?
Please.
What, then?
Maybe you can help me.
How could I
possibly do that?
Everyone else is
giving me advice.
I'd like yours.
Mine?
You know about
Father Grande?
Yes.
What do you think
I should do?
Will I go to heaven
when I die?
It's so bad here.
Someone has to
take a stand.
I've got to have something
to look forward to.
(Romero over radio)
If this were...
An ordinary funeral,
I'd speak of my friendship
with Father Grande.
At crucial moments
in my life,
he was always there,
close to me.
Those times will
never be forgotten.
But this is a moment...
To gather from these
deaths a message,
for all of us who
remain on pilgrimage.
(Romero)
The liberation that
Father Grande preached...
Was a liberation
rooted in faith.
And because it is
so often misunderstood,
for it, Father Rutilio
Grande died.
Who knows?
Perhaps the murderers are
listening to these words.
So we want to tell you,
murderous brethren,
that we love you,
and that we ask for
repentance in your hearts.
(Man)
This is my wife, Maria,
on our wedding anniversary.
This is our house.
These are our children.
This one is Paco,
my son.
See his face?
Always into trouble,
and always good.
You know... a boy.
The soldiers came
and took him,
and now we can't find him.
He has disappeared.
We tried to find him.
We went to the police.
We tried everything,
but we can
find out nothing.
He has
disappeared.
Rafael always calls me
before he leaves the office,
so when he
didn't call me...
why, Rafael?
He works beside
his men in the fields.
He's the Minister
of Agriculture,
but he supports
agrarian reform.
We have some money,
but nothing to do with
political prisoners.
Have you told
the police?
You read the
ransom demand.
Have you told your father?
I am afraid of
what he might do.
I called you...
Because you are our friend,
and because you can
help us, can't you?
Please help me.
Good morning,
fathers.
Good morning.
Monsignor, what
brings you here?
I need to ask
your help.
Rafael Zelada
has been kidnapped.
Would either of you have
a way to find out...
Who might have
taken him?
I can't help you, father.
Father Osuna?
I can't, either.
You can't,
or you won't?
Here is your car,
Monsignor.
Hello, Monsignor.
How can I help you?
It can be dangerous to wait
on corners in El Salvador.
I'm trying to find a way to
get Rafael Zelada released.
Why should
I want that?
Money was demanded.
Money is just
icing on the cake.
The real issue is
political prisoners.
Free them, and you'll
find Zelada free.
Think of the family,
of what they're going through.
If I did, he
wouldn't be alive.
We must find other ways
to work these things out.
Excuse me,
Monsignor.
I’ve grown tired
of this conversation.
We'll let you off.
Take a look and
see what it's like,
how our people
are forced to live.
Monsignor.
Good morning.
Good morning,
Monsignor.
I have an appointment
with the president-elect.
Yes, Monsignor.
I am sorry, Monsignor,
but it's a pity.
The president-elect
has been detained.
I will wait.
The president-elect
expresses his sincere regrets,
but he will have to call you
and reschedule
the appointment...
At the earliest opportunity.
I will wait.
It may be hours.
He is coming back?
Yes.
Give him this.
Monsignor.
I'm afraid the president-elect
hasn't returned,
but he sent you
this note.
Good night,
Monsignor.
Good night.
I've done what they said,
exactly as they told me,
hours and hours ago,
and no word.
Waiting and waiting,
I don't know.
There's nothing to do,
and we're waiting.
What else can we do?
There must be something
else we can do.
There should
be word soon.
Soon?
How soon is soon?
I’m sorry.
I'm glad you're
here with me.
Of course I'm here.
I hear things,
Monsignor.
What things?
That you're only
sympathetic to the poor.
Not only to the poor.
To radicals.
I must minister to everyone.
To the men who
have taken Rafael?
You are brave,
but how could you think
I wouldn't find out?
Why didn't you
tell me?
This is
my doing, father.
We've done what
they asked.
We've saved him.
Haven't we?
(Arista)
He's going to be
all right, isn't he?
They asked for
political prisoners.
Perhaps you could...
I could do
no such thing.
If they harm him,
it will be our turn,
and there
will be blood.
That can't help.
You church people,
you live in your souls.
You don't understand
what we do;
producing, selling,
bringing dollars in.
Capital to develop
the country,
to create jobs, to build
a prosperous economy.
What does this have
to do with Rafael?
That is what affects people.
(Galedo)
But for that, we must
have law and order.
These priests of yours,
with all their talk about
justice and human rights,
organizing these people,
convincing them
they are God almighty;
they are responsible
for these problems.
And so are you, Monsignor.
But the...
The church is a whore.
(Galedo)
She'll spread her legs
to the highest bidder.
Bring him.
Bring him home.
You're a part of this.
[Knock at door]
Monsignor!
We are here to see
Father Alfonso Osuna.
Who?
He's not here.
I am Father Villez,
and I would like
to see Father Osuna.
Father Villez is
the Jesuit provincial,
and I'm Archbishop Romero,
and we would like
to see the father.
Could we have
a moment alone, please?
What happened?
I...
I was preparing to
celebrate the Eucharist,
and they came,
and they
blindfolded me,
and they brought
me here.
Why?
They said I was responsible
for Zelada's death.
They said I was in collusion
with the guerillas.
How could they?
I do know some of them.
But you are not?
You met with
a guerilla, Monsignor.
Does that make you one?
Because Zelada died,
is it my fault?
(Father Osuna)
Is it yours?
What did they do?
They used electricity.
I'm just glad I'm
a priest and celibate,
because I don't think I would
have a choice any longer.
[Crying]
Monsignor,
what are you
doing here?
We are here to get
Father Osuna.
Who let you in?
Why was this man
brought here?
He cannot be released.
I do not have the
authority to release him.
Who had the authority
to arrest him?
I was carrying out
instructions.
Instructions to
torture him?
(Aide)
Monsignor!
You need an appointment!
Please, Monsignor!
The new Swedish ambassador
will be at the embassy.
Hector, I would
like you there.
Monsignor.
How are you?
Fine, thank you.
Good to see you.
Come in.
Can I offer you an aperitif?
No, thank you.
Sit down, please.
Now, what can
I do for you?
I'm sorry to come to you
like this, general,
but this is a matter
of importance.
A few weeks ago,
Father Grande
was assassinated.
Yesterday,
a priest was tortured.
Today, I presided
at a funeral mass...
For Minister of
Agriculture Zelada.
This violence
is destroying us.
There is trouble on
many sides, Monsignor.
Even inside the church.
Elements have
gone astray.
The priests...
Must stay out of politics.
But there are political
implications to the gospel.
We will take care of those.
Now, in a week,
I will be inaugurated.
The archbishop
has always attended...
To symbolize
the church’s blessing.
We have not heard
from you, Monsignor.
It would be of great
help to all of us...
If you would be present.
How can I bless a situation...
In which innocent people
are disappearing...
Night after night?
Unfortunately,
I have found it
necessary...
To occupy Aguilares
and to close the church,
until there is order again.
You can't do that.
It is a tragedy,
but let's face lt.
This Grande...
we know what they
are doing out there.
We have proof.
Inciting the people,
agitating,
calling political meetings;
on the day you
became archbishop,
on the day he was killed,
he was a communist.
Father Grande
was here with me...
The day I became archbishop.
(Romero)
On the day
he was killed,
it was baptisms
he was performing.
You are a liar.
(Bishop Estrada)
You cannot count
on my support.
I will attend
the inauguration.
It is going to be
a magnificent ceremony.
I am military vicar,
and it is my function to go.
Who else?
I will go.
This is not an action I wish
to take, or take lightly,
but we mustn't do anything
to give the impression...
We approve of
what is going on.
There is no
persecuted church.
Don't you see what's
going on out there?
There are only sons
of the church...
Who have lost their way,
and put themselves
outside of the law!
Gentlemen, please!
I won't go.
Monsignor Flores?
I would like to support
the archbishop,
but I don't agree with him.
In fact, I seldom do.
In fact, I think he’s
become a Jesuit dupe.
Except...
Priests are getting killed.
Except I could get killed.
Except it's reprehensible.
So...
I'm not going.
This is a scandal,
these divisions,
ever since you became
archbishop, Monsignor.
Rome is going to be
very unhappy.
[Shouting in Spanish]
[Screaming]
[Bell ringing]
What are you doing?
Come on, let him go!
(Lucia)
You'll break his arms!
[Shouting in Spanish]
We are here to remove
the blessed sacrament...
While the town is occupied.
This is a barracks.
This is a church.
What are you doing here?
We are here to take care
of the Eucharist.
[Gun shots]
Now, get out of here.
Now!
(Master Sergeant)
Hey, hey, hey!
You again?
[Gun shots]
Turn around!
Move, move!
(Soldier)
Move! Get out!
Are you all right?
(Romero)
We are here today...
To retake possession
of this church building,
and to strengthen all those...
Whom the enemies of the
church have trampled down.
You should know that you
have not suffered alone,
for you are
the church.
You are the
people of God.
You are Jesus,
in the here and now.
He is crucified in you,
just as surely as he was
crucified 2,000 years ago...
On that hill
outside of Jerusalem.
You should know...
That your pain and your
suffering, like his,
will contribute to El Salvador's
liberation and redemption.
Buenos dias, padre.
Later we will play a game.
Arista.
You could have
come to my office.
I did, but there
were so many people.
Oh, this can be a bit
of a crazy house.
I hope it's
a sanctuary.
It's time to
baptize my baby.
It's past time.
It would be
my privilege.
I would like to
pick a date.
There are baptisms
every Sunday.
The choice is yours.
I think the first Sunday
in December would be fine.
That's a good week.
It's not so crowded.
I would like
a private baptism.
We have so many
to baptize now,
we don't have
private ones anymore.
Will you...
you will make an
exception, won't you?
I'm sorry.
You expect me
to baptize my baby
with a bunch of Indians?
You have deserted us.
[Bell jingles]
God bless you.
Bless me, father,
for I have sinned.
It's been a month since
my last confession.
Yes?
I am a believer in the
theology of liberation,
and I have worked in
the people's struggle.
That is no sin.
No, but I had a belief
in one single man,
and in no one else.
That is no sin.
Especially not
the archbishop.
I deplored him,
mocked him,
laughed at him.
How can I tell him...
I was wrong?
Just pray for him.
Let's make that
your penance.
I absolve you in
the name of the father...
And of the son
and of the holy spirit.
Amen.
Thank you, father.
[Applause]
(Romero)
I am a shepherd,
who with his people
has begun to learn...
A beautiful
and difficult truth.
Our faith requires...
That we immerse
ourselves in the world.
I believe economic injustice...
Is the root cause
of our problems.
From it stems
all the violence.
The church has to
be incarnated...
In those who fight
for freedom,
and defend them,
and share...
In their persecution.
[Footsteps]
No, no!
Help!
De colores se visten
Los campos en la primavera
De colores
De colores son los pajaritos
que vienen de afuera
De colores
De colores es el arco iris
que vemos lucir
Ypor eso
los grandes amores
De muchos colores
me gustan a mi
Ypor eso
los grandes amores
De muchos colores
me gustan a mi
Ypor eso
los grandes amores
De muchos colores
me gustan a mi
De colores
De colores, brillantes y vino
se viste la aurora
Do you wish to
see me, colonel?
I'm disturbed by
recent events, Monsignor.
I must speak to you
with all due respect.
The problems that exist
have not been solved,
and you are aggravating
the situation.
You are losing the people.
Who are those who come
to see me at the hospital?
Who come to my office?
Who fill the cathedral?
You are losing the people...
Whose support you need
to run the country.
My task is not
to run the country!
My task is to prevent
my priests and our people...
From getting killed!
Please,
Monsignor, have patience.
Step back.
Wait.
If we stop the wild talk,
things will cool off,
settle down.
It is your choice.
(Romero)
This past week,
I wrote a letter...
To the President of
the United States...
To send no more arms
to this country.
They are only being used
to kill our people!
[Applause]
Kneel!
[Gun shot]
[Gasp]
[Knock at door]
They were
demonstrating,
and driven into
the church.
There's been shooting,
and they have a hostage.
They asked for you.
Who's in charge?
Where do you think
you're going?
Inside.
They asked for me.
No, you're not.
I’m going to get
the hostage out.
He’s already dead.
Are you sure?
We heard noises,
Monsignor,
and screams.
They tortured him.
If I get the hostage out
and he's all right,
will you let the men
who hold him go?
No.
If I get him out,
and the men in there
lay down their arms,
will you let them go?
No.
What more do you want?
If they lay down their arms,
if he's alive, unharmed,
and if you're still alive
Do I have your word?
What did I just say?
[Gun cocks]
You, fathers.
Yes, Monsignor?
Is the hostage all right?
Yes.
They are holding
no one else?
They were only holding him
for their own protection.
What do they want?
A new government.
[Sigh]
This one is no different
from the last.
The powerful are still
allowed to organize,
and when the poor attempt it,
they hire off-duty
soldiers to kill them.
This is no solution.
Don't you realize
what is going on?
Last night,
they killed Lucia.
Before they raped
and killed her,
they cut out her tongue.
Somebody has to have the
courage to say, "enough."
[Engine sound]
(Loudspeaker)
If the hostage is not
released in five minutes,
we will storm
the church.
Tell them to let
the hostage go.
Show the national guard
that he's alive.
Have them put down
their weapons.
If they do, they've
agreed to let them go,
guaranteed safe passage.
And you believe them?
They gave me their word.
You have mine.
The hostage
is alive and safe.
These people have kept
their part of the bargain.
Who gave you the
authority to go in there?
They asked for me.
Who gave you
the authority?
I told you,
they asked for me,
and this man
and I agreed...
this man?
I'm in charge here.
The hostage is safe.
These men have...
arrest them!
[Shouting]
They were guaranteed
safe passage.
Who says?
He did! I did!
These people
are all terrorists.
We cannot
tolerate that.
This man gave me his word!
Arrest him, too.
Adolfo, cigarette?
[Father Osuna screams]
Stop!
Stop in the name of God!
[Father Osuna screams]
[Screaming]
We’re human beings!
We're human beings.
Monsignor.
Obviously, there has
been some mistake.
I will get you out
of here in no time.
You are all right?
You must take care
of yourself.
I worry for your safety.
You do not fear for your life?
You should.
Yes...
Like any other Salvadoran.
I cannot protect you anymore.
What if you die?
What will happen?
I am not leaving here...
Without Father Osuna
and the others.
No!
[Weeping]
Are you ready?
Are you ready now to accept
the way it really is?
You're a priest.
You believe in God,
in the power of love.
You used to pray.
I still do.
Then why are you
carrying a gun?
How can I not
carry one?
Am I going to
abandon my people
when I am
one of those...
Responsible for
opening their eyes?
A guerilla,
is that what you are?
A communist?
No.
I am a priest...
Who sees Marxists
and Christians...
Struggling to liberate
the same people.
Jesus is part of
that struggle.
He would not stand by
and watch his people
being murdered.
So you've become like the
military and the aristocracy.
You wage class warfare.
You become violent.
How can we continue
to speak against violence...
When they keep killing
the people that we love?
Even you admit we have
the right to defend ourselves.
You're not defending!
You're attacking!
And you’ll lose God,
just as they have!
What else can we do?
You think I want this?
To live like this?
With what you say,
there'll be no end
to the bloodshed.
I have no choice.
I can't.
You must.
I'm yours.
Show me the way.
Hey, a priest!
Bring him over here.
(Woman)
Monsignor!
Search him.
Nothing here.
Maybe he's got
something underneath.
Let's see.
Take his clothes off.
I have nothing.
Strip him.
It's all right.
But you are our voice.
You speak for us.
Let us begin a celebration
of the mass now.
In the name of the father...
And of the son...
And of the holy spirit.
Amen.
The grace of our Lord, Jesus
Christ, and the love of God,
and the fellowship of
the holy spirit be with you all.
And with you.
Lord, you created us
for freedom.
(All)
Lord, have mercy.
Christ, you made us
to live in dignity.
(All)
Christ, have mercy.
Lord, you strengthen us
in the struggle for justice.
(All)
Lord, have mercy.
(Lieutenant Columa)
We developed our country.
We penetrated its jungles,
planted coffee and sugar cane.
We are like the pioneers
of the united states.
We do not want what
doesn't belong to us.
We only want to have what
the North Americans have.
To live as they do!
[Cheers and applause]
Bravo!
(Romero)
The mission of the church...
Is to identify itself
with the poor,
and to join with them...
In their struggle for justice.
By so doing,
the church finds
its own salvation!
(Lt. Columa)
The new government
is riddled with communists.
The priests are working
with the guerillas.
All the unions are infiltrated.
(Lt. Columa)
Don't ever feel guilty...
For having fought
these subversives.
They have declared war
on our way of life.
Those who fight them,
they will be national heroes.
I hope that this call
of the church...
Does not further
harden the hearts...
Of the rich and the powerful,
but will move them
to conversion.
You are the principal
protagonists...
In this hour of change.
On you depends,
in great part,
the end of violence.
There is no clinging
to our feudal past.
This is a new age,
an age in which
all God's children...
(from radio)
May live in peace,
freedom, and dignity.
I'd like to make an appeal,
in a special way,
to the men in the army.
Brothers,
each one of you is one of us.
We are the same people.
The farmers and peasants
that you kill...
Are your own brothers
and sisters.
When you hear the words
of a man telling you to kill,
think instead
in the words of God!
"Thou shalt not kill!"
No soldier is obliged
to obey an order...
Contrary to the law of God.
In his name,
and in the name...
Of our tormented people...
Who have suffered so much,
and whose laments
cry out to heaven,
I implore you,
I beg you,
I order you,
stop the repression!
[Gun shot]
[Screams]
(Romero)
I have often been
threatened with death.
If they kill me,
I shall arise in
the Salvadoran people.
Let my blood
be a seed of freedom,
and the sign that hope
will soon be reality.
A bishop will die,
but the church of God,
which is the people,
will never perish.
---the end---