I still don't get it.
What?
Maybe you'll figure it out, huh.
- Woo! Nice take, nice take.
- Nice take.
I'm just saying, you an Swarek are solid.
Look, it is what is is.
Sucker!
Okay, good.
People stay together.
People break up. Whatever.
Well, you seem to be dealing pretty well.
What else am I gonna do?
I mean, I have the choice.
I either fall apart or keep moving,
and I choose to keep moving.
You know what?
With everything that
happened with Gail and Traci,
my romantic life is not an issue.
Yeah, it kinda puts it into perspective.
I'm getting over it. I'm fine.
♪ 'Cause it's a war zone out here ♪
Nice.
♪ There ain't no such thing as fear ♪
♪ and the end is always near
♪ so, baby, bring it on
Great workout,
although she totally
cleaned my stove. (Chuckles)
It was brutal.
- So you're taking me in, right?
- Absolutely.
Thanks again for lending me your truck.
Oh, that's no problem.
Must be a pretty big doctor's appointment.
I mean, if you're taking the whole day.
Not just doctor. Dentist,
optometrist, podiatrist...
I do 'em all, same day, once a year.
Optimization of transportation.
(Chuckles) Okay.
You coming?
(Keys jangle) Right behind ya.
Just gotta grab my coat.
(Clicks tongue) (Jangles)
(Horn honks in distance)
(Beeps)
Hey. It's me. I got the truck.
Be there in 20.
(Woman) ♪ and every
time you touch me right ♪
♪ it's like, oh, oh
Really? That's what we're gonna listen to?
Yep. I mean, you're the one who
wanted to pick me up, remember?
Oh, so that means you
get to choose the music?
Fine. Let's see what you have on preset.
(Changing radio stations)
(Chuckles)
(Turns off radio) Whoa! Good
God, man. How old are you?
I'm old enough to know what I like.
Yeah, well, we gotta
get you with the program,
because you are a virile young man.
(Chuckles) We need to get you set up here.
Hey, you know I don't actually
need a ride to work, like,
every single day, right?
(Turn indicator clicking)
Dude, I'm good.
No, I know. I just... I like the company.
Oh.
And the sparkling conversation.
Okay. (Turns on radio)
Ohh.
(Man) ♪ yeah ♪ (Woman) ♪ all night
♪ well, these are the facts
(laughs)
♪ ... from scratch, oh,
she likes my raps ♪
♪ oh
I can't lose you right now, Callaghan.
I'm already short a detective.
You've got Nash starting back today.
She can take over some
of Jerry's case files.
You're in a rush to get
out of here. I get it.
I didn't say that.
Project Dakota?
Heard about it at headquarters.
It's a big deal. Congratulations.
No idea what you're talking about.
(Chuckles)
(Lowered voice) Well, we should figure
out who you need in terms of people.
Major task force on organized crime.
We got the best of the best right here.
Yeah, I'll keep that in mind.
What? You'll keep that in mind?
You spent years in this building.
Where's your loyalty?
(Lowered voice) Look, Frank,
15's in a rough patch, okay?
Your numbers are down.
It's not your fault that a detective
was killed in the line of duty.
Our numbers have nothing to
do with abilities or talents.
I understand that, but
people are starting to notice.
Getting any of your people on
a major task force right now
would be a tough sell.
(Clatters)
(Indistinct conversations)
Why are you in uniform?
Already cleared it with Frank.
(Frank) All right. Listen up.
As of today, we're
putting the past behind us,
which means we're moving forward.
Officer Swarek, "back to basics"...
what does that mean to you?
It means hit the streets.
Foot patrols, traffic stops.
That's right.
Talk to ten people. Make two arrests.
Back to basics, people. I
want to see results today.
McNally, Collins, Anderson, Pearce,
I want you guys at Jarvis,
Sherbourne, and Carlton.
Get out of your cars. Get on the streets.
Be proactive.
(Lowered voice) I guess
numbers are down again.
(Lowered voice) You think?
(Indistinct conversations,
telephone ringing in distance)
Nash?
Can you come here a second?
(Radio chatter)
What's going on?
Frank didn't tell you?
Tell me what?
(Clears throat) It's my first shift back,
and I just thought that...
I should start on the street,
you know, get back on the horse.
How long?
Look, Nash, I've been
saving files for you.
I'm dealing with Jerry's
entire caseload on my own.
I just need a couple of days.
I... I know you've been through a lot,
but you've been off a month already,
and this detective job...
this is a training rotation,
so if you can't do this,
you need to let me know,
because I gotta find somebody who can.
It won't even... it'll be,
like, unintentionally all...
Hey. McNally, how ya doin'?
Good. Fine. You?
Ready to get back to basics?
Yes, sir.
Hey, hey. Hey, wait. Wait up.
(Radio chatter)
Hey. (Sighs)
Uh, I want to talk to you about something.
Okay.
Um... (Sighs)
uh, my keys, um, to the truck.
I just, um, it's my only other set.
I should probably get those back.
Keys. Yeah. Uh...
I think they're in my locker.
I can go grab 'em right now for you.
No, no. Later's fine.
All right. Have a good shift.
You, too.
Diaz, come on! Let's go!
(Chuckles) You got that right.
See ya.
Back to basics. I love it.
(Siren wailing)
(Door opens)
Hey, did you check your weapon?
Yes.
And your radio's turned on?
Yes, Gail.
Hey, who knows what kind of bad habits
you picked up at the D's?
I mean, this is real policing right here.
(Radio chatter)
(Horn honks)
There you are.
(Sniffles, voice breaking) Hey.
I was looking for you inside.
I thought you might have gone in...
Yeah, no. I'm, uh, I'm
a keener, so... (Sniffles)
(Seat belt buckle clicks) You okay?
(Sniffles) Yeah, I'm fine. Why?
Let's get to work.
(Starts engine)
(Sniffles)
(Exhales deeply)
(Radio chatter)
Disobeying a traffic
light, improper Lane change,
failure to signal,
taillight or headlight out...
today nothing escapes our notice.
(Radio chatter)
So you've been doing all right?
I mean, considering
everything that's happened
and... and you and Andy breaking up?
- Diaz.
- Right. Yeah.
If you don't want to talk
about it, that's cool, too.
Red Corolla up ahead. Notice anything?
Busted taillight. Nice.
(Radio chatter)
You know, my worst breakup, I
cried every day for two weeks.
No, but I did buy a motorcycle
and joined the army, so...
I don't know.
And then I grew a mustache.
(Chuckles) (Chuckles)
You know how some guys
look really good with mustaches
and some guys just do not?
Well, I do not, and I went to Afghanistan,
and all these guys were
like, "I cannot believe... "
"good riddance: How to ditch
that loser and keep smiling."
Wow. Okay. You definitely win.
Yeah. My mom got it for me.
She thought it would help me.
So did it?
I don't know. I haven't
read it all the way yet.
(Sniffles)
(Keypad beeping) I don't know.
Guy seemed kinda frazzled.
Couple of baby seats in the back.
Maybe we should cut him a break.
Two priors for domestic assault.
Beats his wife.
We let him off 'cause
she won't press charges.
Turns around, beats her again.
Okay, but right now all we
got is a busted taillight.
Good thing we're back to basics.
(Radio chatter)
(Sighs)
(Radio chatter continues)
Not a good day for you, my friend.
You rolled right through that stop sign
when you made your turn back there.
Uh, your rear marker, the
little light over the top
of your license plate... not illuminated.
Failure to sign your
vehicle registration in ink.
You used a pencil.
That's a separate offense.
Failure to produce insurance documents,
and you have a broken taillight.
Five tickets? Are you serious?
You're gonna give me five tickets?
We don't make the rules, sir.
Oh, forget it! I'm not paying these!
Please step out of the car, sir.
Oh, come on!
(Seat belt buckle clicks)
Over here, sir.
- I want your badge numbers, both of you.
- We're just doing our job, sir.
Yeah? And I pay your salaries, jackass.
Never heard that one before.
Do you write your own material?
Screw you.
And that's called "assaulting an officer."
- Here we go.
- Ohh! Hey.
- Sir, I need you to hold still.
- Ow!
(Handcuffs click)
"Rule number 3... do not
talk to your ex for 60 days."
Ooh, well, good thing you
guys don't work together.
Okay, you don't have to read it out loud.
It says here you need a breakup buddy,
rule number five... "someone
who will kick your ass
and make sure you follow the rules."
Skipping it.
Oh, my God.
You want me to be your breakup buddy.
Andy, I am touched.
(Laughs) Shut up.
(Radio static)
(Woman) 1520, we've got a vehicle fire
at Queen and Cowan at St. Julian's Church.
Please attend. Fire has
been dispatched. (Static)
1520. Show us responding. (Static)
(Receiver clicks, siren wailing)
(Indistinct conversations,
flames crackling)
(Static) 1520.
Vehicle is indeed on fire.
Put a rush on the fire
department. (Static)
(Extinguisher spraying)
Whoa! Whoa!
- Hey! Move back! Get back!
- Hey! What are you doing?!
- Hey, come on!
- I got ten crates of tomato sauce in there. Come on!
Okay. Come on, sir. Let's go, please.
Come on. Come on!
- Come on. Move back.
- Get against the building.
Back up against the building.
No, all four of you.
Is that your car there?
(Speaks indistinctly)
(Sighs)
I was unloading stuff into the kitchen.
Two minutes I must have been down there.
When I came back up, the van was on fire.
You didn't see anyone around it?
No.
No one running away?
Nobody.
Is there anyone you can think of that
might want to hurt you? (Siren whoops)
I'm a priest. Who would
want to hurt a priest, right?
Well, someone's trying
to send you a message.
Probably some junkie I pissed off.
I got one rule... you show up high,
you get nothing. No exceptions.
So you think a junkie
set your van on fire?
It could be. I mean,
it's pretty easy, right?
A beer bottle half-full
of gas, stuff a rag in it.
It's pretty simple. Takes two minutes.
(Radio chatter)
Hey, you mind if I get in there?
I may be able to salvage something.
Uh, no. Sorry, father.
Crime scene, right?
Well, it's all a write-off, anyway.
Just 'cause something's damaged don't mean
you gotta throw it away.
Let you know when we're done.
Mm-hmm.
(Traci) None of these kids
was outside when it happened.
(Gail) Yeah, but what about the priest?
Well, he says he didn't see anything.
- But...
- Well... (Sighs)
I don't know. I met this guy before.
He doesn't miss a trick.
What does he have to hide?
He runs a program for street kids.
He gives 'em a safe place to sleep.
He feeds them. He tries
to get them off drugs.
Maybe he's protecting one of his kids.
Yeah, it'd be a priest-like thing to do,
turn the other cheek.
Well, either way, it's a death threat,
so we have to take it seriously.
You coming?
Maybe we talk to one of the locals,
see if they saw something?
Let's do it.
(Grunts) Let me guess. Brick collection?
(Closes door) Textbooks. (Chuckles)
Listen, Dov, thanks for helping
me move on such short notice.
I just... I just didn't
have anyone else to call.
No, I told you, whatever you need,
but... along with all these books,
you're also gonna need some furniture.
First time moving out,
maybe your mom will
spring for a new couch.
She's helped enough with med school.
Yeah, I know, but once she sees
how empty your apartment is.
I don't want her help.
Besides, I don't think
she's gonna be coming by here anyway.
Okay. None of my business.
That's right. (Sighs)
But if it were, I might ask.
My mom found out I was talking to you.
That's why you're moving out?
It's... it was my decision.
It's not a big deal. I left.
So are you gonna help me move or what?
(Traci) Nobody's talking.
Yeah, what a surprise.
I almost forgot how hard it was.
See, this is exactly my point.
It's not exactly a cakewalk out here,
and you spent all that time
training to be a detective.
Just don't want you to throw it away.
I'm not throwing it away.
I'm just trying to figure out where I fit.
Here we go. 1:00.
So those are the corner guys,
the ones taking the orders?
Yeah, except I think we
might be cramping their style.
(Police radio chatter)
Where are the runners, the
kids who deliver the drugs?
(Children speak indistinctly)
(Radio chatter continues)
God, look at them. They could
care less that we're here.
As long as they're under 12,
they're practically immune.
Hey. You kids want to have a chat?
Hey!
- Ow! Let go! Let me go!
- Oh, d... don't be so dramatic.
This is total brutality!
You just hit me in the
face with a slushie.
Okay, you little punk? So guess what?
You can go for a ride in my squad car.
You okay?
Like I said, it's not exactly a cakewalk.
Last three months, church
been vandalized six times...
broken windows, graffiti...
(Knock)
Hey. You got a minute?
No.
Father Jean Pierre Solaine.
Five years for armed robbery.
Three for aggravated assault.
Got out of prison in 2006.
So he wouldn't be the first
guy to find God in jail.
(Nick) Think he knows
who set the van on fire.
'Course he does. He's not gonna tell you.
Look, people confide in
him, tell him their sins.
One honest conversation with this guy,
I could probably close 18 cases.
Curtis Payne.
(Keyboard clicks, beep)
Local dealer.
Hires the neighborhood kids.
Father Jean Pierre's been
pushing back for years.
Your van fire probably has
something to do with that.
Well, it sounds like the
priest is doing something right.
Look, if you want to get
any traction with this,
you're gonna need an eyewitness,
somebody who can put Curtis at the fire.
If you can get Curtis Payne on this...
Then we can trade up
and get to his suppliers.
Back to basics.
Curtis Payne is no joke.
He's dangerous, okay?
Andy, I'm serious.
Curtis buys them anything they
want... running shoes, iPod...
he even takes 'em to hockey games.
Yeah, that's what these
kids want, is attention, huh?
That's why nobody snitches on him.
Curtis just sucks them into
the life, and they're lost.
They end up in jail or dead.
The father tries to make
sure that doesn't happen.
He did the same thing for me.
I used to work the streets.
Hey, you want to give me a hand with this?
Sure. Where's this going?
Downstairs. Cory will show you where.
- Lead the way.
- Follow me.
Got something for you, too.
Okay.
And there we go.
(Police radio chatter)
See, I knew you guys
were good for something.
(Police radio chatter)
- We're good to go.
- Yep.
Here's fine.
Just make a pile.
All right.
Sounds like father Jean
Pierre's doing pretty good work.
Yeah, I guess.
Hey, Cory? Any idea who might
have burned the van today?
It was Curtis, for sure.
Oh, yeah? You saw him?
No.
Oh. Father Jean Pierre
taught you not to lie, huh?
Father's a smart man.
(Gunshots, glass shattering)
(Andy) Cory, get down!
- (Nick) Don't move!
- Cory, are you okay?
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Stay there!
1520, 10-33, Queen
and Cowan. Shots fired.
(Police radio chatter, tires screeching)
(Holsters gun) What happened?
It's called a drive-by.
- Everyone okay?
- I'm good.
You take care of her.
Hey. Father. Come on. Let us handle this.
Let you handle this? Are you serious?!
You're the reason we're
getting shot at, officer.
It's your fault!
(Sirens wailing in distance)
Watch yourself there, pal.
Big step forward, all right?
Got a cruiser coming
in. Come on. You guys?
I need you on the other side
of the street, all right?
So the bullets hit up here,
taking out the windows,
and father Jean Pierre was down here?
Mm-hmm. Guess they
didn't have very good aim.
Or they're just sending a
message, trying to scare him.
I met this guy a few times before.
I don't think he scares that easy.
Callaghan, you want to give
me the tag, I'll run it down?
We didn't get the license plate, actually.
By the time we got out
here, they were gone.
I'm sorry. So you were
both inside the church?
Yeah. Father Jean Pierre
asked us to bring in some gear.
What kind of gear?
Tomato sauce.
So you were unloading groceries
while the priest was out here
getting shot at. Is that right?
Did anyone see the vehicle?
Well, far as we can gather, gold S.U.V.
Full size, maybe an Escalade.
I'll see if I can find any gold S.U.Vs
registered in the neighborhood.
(Sam) Genius. Why don't you two
talk to father Jean Pierre again,
see if he remembers anything else?
Mm-hmm.
Some, uh, fantastic
leadership there, Sammy.
You want to take a shot at me next?
Good to have you back, Callaghan.
Keep saying that.
Always a pleasure.
How many times I gotta tell you?
They came out of nowhere,
started shooting at us.
It happened so fast.
So you didn't recognize the car?
Once again, it was a S.U.V.
I didn't see anything else.
It was Curtis Payne, wasn't
it? Why is he shooting at you?
Maybe 'cause we talking to the cops.
Okay, did you get a look at
any faces? Driver? Shooter?
Nothing.
Carlene, did you see anything?
We didn't see anything, and we're fine.
Can we go back inside, please?
Hey, Father. Hey. You all right?
(Jean Pierre) Yes.
I'm gonna get these two officers
to stick around and keep
an eye on things, okay?
That's not necessary.
Thank you. We're good.
They're not gonna get in the way.
All that's gonna do is upset the kids.
Well, I'm sorry.
After today, I'm not,
uh, I'm not really asking.
(Police radio chatter)
(Man) All right. Pull that
squad car out of here. (Sighs)
(Buzzer, beep) I know the rules. If
you're arresting me, I get a lawyer.
You're not under arrest.
Then why am I here?
Whoa, hey, now.
I was just standing
there, minding my business.
You assaulted an officer.
Please.
Okay, why don't you just
calm down? Have a seat.
She said, sit.
Okay, you need to tell us your name.
Jordan.
"Jordan" what?
Look, Jordan, we need to get
in touch with your parents.
You know a guy named Curtis Payne?
Never heard of him.
You don't work for him as a runner?
No. I was just hanging
out with my friends.
What is this?
Let go! You can't touch me!
Now you're sure you don't want
me to hook anything else up?
I mean, uh, DVD player,
TV, lamp, clock radio...
Shh.
Okay, so, there's barely
any water pressure,
one of the windows won't
open... (Banging in distance)
and judging by that banging sound,
there's a ghost in my closet.
Well, th... that's good news.
Means you'll always have company.
No, you know, I think
I'm gonna like this...
you know, living on my
own, you know, my own music,
my own mess, no one
asking where I've been...
So, uh, when did you plan
on filling me in on all this?
What? It's not a big deal.
I just, like, found the
apartment on Craigslist,
called the guy up,
made an offer... simple.
Crystal, you know what I'm talking about.
Look, my cousin saw us together.
He told my mom, and now
my family won't talk to me.
Were you going to tell
me about any of this?
Dov, I don't care what they think.
They'll get over it,
or else it's their loss.
So what, you're just never gonna go home?
Why? Do you want me to?
No, I... I don't know what I want.
♪
All right. (Beeps)
I found a gold S.U.V.
with a flag on the record.
It's registered to a business,
the Skyline restaurant,
and guess who the owner is?
Who?
Curtis Payne.
No kidding.
Yeah. Yeah, 1426 Queen Street.
Should be right about...
here. You... you knew that already.
I had a hunch.
(Siren wailing in distance)
(Police radio chatter)
(Car door closes)
(Hip-hop music playing)
Boys, what's the lunch special?
Closed.
Shouldn't you kids be in school?
Hey. Can I see your gun?
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey, let me call you back.
(Beep, cell phone clatters)
Can I help you, officer?
You know why we're here, Curtis...
drive-by at St. Julian's, gold S.U.V.
- Yeah, we heard about that. Word travels.
- Yeah?
Doesn't have to travel very far
when you're the one who did it.
And who might your witness be?
I don't need a witness. I know it was you.
I guess you don't have
any evidence, either, huh?
Is this what it's come to?
Taking shots at a priest?
Look, I've been sitting here all morning,
talking to these gentlemen.
My vehicle's been parked out back all day.
♪
(Groans) Officer Diaz. Subject
had his hands in his pockets.
You know what we call that?
Threat cue.
That's right.
Put it away.
(Curtis chuckles)
(Sighs) Kids and their phones, huh?
Officer Swarek, if he
doesn't have anything,
I think we're done here.
(Sighs)
Curtis? Stay away from the church, huh?
(Exhales sharply)
Unless you're there for confession.
♪
Nice seeing you, too, officer.
Have a nice day.
(Telephone rings in distance)
How'd you get the burn marks, Jordan?
(Sighs) I don't talk to cops.
Look, it's a simple question.
(Sighs) It was an accident.
I was cooking bacon.
Cigarette burns in a pattern.
Might be some kind of initiation.
Need to contact child and youth services.
Mm-hmm.
She needs to be
interviewed by a detective.
(Police radio chatter,
telephone rings in distance)
Well, no firebombs or gunshots
in the last hour and a half.
Things are looking up.
Okay, so rule number six...
we have to make a good riddance list.
So what are Swarek's
least likable qualities?
- Okay, we really should be working.
- We are.
Padre hasn't left the church
since we've been here, so...
"Selfish"? Is he "stubborn"? "Arrogant"?
(Sighs)
Oh, come on. Help me out.
- I'm just trying to be a good breakup buddy.
- "Stubborn."
Write that down.
Okay, great. What else?
"Overbearing," "insensitive"...
What about "selfish"?
You know that we have been
together for almost a year,
and he has not once told
me how he feels about me?
Well, some guys are just
too cool for feelings.
Yeah, well, you know what?
That gets a little thin
for the rest of us, who
are working really hard
trying to figure out what
the hell you're thinking...
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Don't look at me.
I'm not too cool for anything.
You know, I didn't want
to admit this, but...
I'm actually someone's breakup buddy.
(Chuckles)
Okay. So the mantra.
(Whispers) Mantra.
(Both) "I, Andy McNally,
am still a kick-ass person,
and just because my
relationship failed... "
- "Does not mean I'm a failure."
- "Doesn't mean I'm a failure."
Just means you're unlovable.
(Thump) (Laughs)
Whoa. Heads up.
(Police radio chatter)
What are they doing?
Looks like we're gonna find out.
Oh, no. Oh, no. No.
No, thank you. No. No, th...
whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa, no! No!
Car wash, sir?
(Engine starts) Stop.
Stop! No! We don't need anything!
Get away from our car! Stop!
(Nick) We're fine! Thank
you! Step off the car!
Watch it with the squirting, okay?
(Tires pealing) Back off. Up against
the fence. Up against the fence.
(Groans)
Curtis Payne is a major
player in this neighborhood.
Intimidation, violence...
he's a suspect in seven
different assaults.
In, like, six years, we
haven't been able to touch him.
All the more reason we
need to play it by the book.
Informants, undercover
buys... none of it's worked.
He's too careful. Best we
can do is rattle his cage.
Speaking of which...
All right, gentlemen. Let's
go. Hands against the wall.
(Man)... Talking about, man?
What did I just say?
Hands against the wall.
- (Man) Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- (Man) Hey, man! Man!
What are you doing?
What do you think we're
doing, Officer Diaz?
We're arresting criminals.
Arresting them for what?
You didn't see 'em selling
drugs? I saw 'em selling drugs.
They just seem like a
bunch of kids hanging out.
No, no, no. Let's take a closer look.
(Thud)
(Police radio chatter)
Dispatch is gonna put a lookout
on Father Jean Pierre's car.
Is he gonna get in trouble for taking off?
No, he's not. We are
trying to protect him.
We don't want anybody getting hurt.
I already told you, I
don't know where he went.
Okay, well, did he talk
to you about what happened?
Father J.P. doesn't talk about that stuff.
Oh, come on, Carlene. You
know exactly what's going on.
Van fire, shooting... same day.
(Sighs)
Um, Curtis and the father...
they've been having
this war over the kids,
and then this whole thing with Thomas...
it just set it all off again.
(Andy and Nick) Who's Thomas?
Totally amazing kid. He was a
scholarship winner last year.
He used to hang out here all the time...
and, uh, then, a few days ago,
Father J.P. went out and found him.
He was working the corners.
On his arm right here,
it was all infected.
Someone burned him with a cigarette.
And father Jean Pierre freaked out.
So the shooting... had
something to do with Thomas?
Carlene.
He was in the car.
Thomas was? You saw him?
He wasn't the one with the gun,
but he was there in the back seat.
Curtis was making a point.
I think Father J.P. might
have gone out to find Thomas.
Where does Thomas live?
(Door buzzes and beeps)
Jordan Lewis.
I called Child and Youth
Services, and it turns out
there's not that many
Jordans in the neighborhood,
so didn't take long to pull your file.
You've been in foster care
since you were 2 years old.
12 different families.
That must have been tough.
Do you ever talk to your real parents?
No. They don't need me. I don't need them.
I don't need anyone.
How old is this kid?
- (Traci, filtered voice) I get it.
- 11.
You feel like you're all
alone, but what about Curtis?
I mean, he must be like your family now.
What's he like? Is he a nice guy?
'Cause I know he's generous.
I know he gives you guys...
What's with the new clothes?
Sorry?
You were in uniform. Why'd you change?
Did you think I'd like you better?
Actually, I did.
You're still a cop. I hate cops.
Put me in jail, I don't care.
Hey. You guys need to see this.
- (Traci, filtered voice) Jordan, you're not going to jail...
- What is it? What's wrong?
Come on. You, too. Let's go.
(Radio chatter)
I was going through that
girl's phone, looking for, uh,
looking for somebody to
contact. I found this.
(Key clicks)
You ready, Thomas?
Ready?
Give me your arm.
Come on, man.
Do it.
(Sizzle)
(Screaming)
(Children speak indistinctly, clapping)
(Curtis) That's it, little man. It's over.
It's over. Welcome to the family.
(Boy) Yeah! Welcome to the family.
- Aren't you proud of your brother?
- Whoo! Yeah!
Make some noise. Come on, guys.
Yeah!
(Key clicks)
(Woman) Thomas isn't here.
Well, we're actually looking
for Father Jean Pierre.
Do you have any idea
where he is right now?
You need to tell me what's going on.
Well, somebody drove by the church,
and shots were fired
at Father Jean Pierre.
Is he okay?
Yeah, he's fine,
but we think Thomas was
in the back of the car.
Andy? Traci forwarded me
something you should see.
Oh.
Ms. Young, is that your son?
What's happened to him?
Curtis Payne.
Looks as though he burned Thomas.
J.P. came looking for
Thomas about 20 minutes ago.
Why is he so desperate to find Thomas?
Jean Pierre... h...
he's Thomas's father.
Sir, I don't think these guys are dealers.
We don't know that.
I only found one joint in this bag,
and none of them will tell me whose it is.
Well, I guess we're gonna have to bring
'em all in, then. (Cell phone rings)
(Ring, beep)
McNally?
Hey, Sam.
Listen, we think Jean Pierre's
going after Curtis Payne.
What? Why?
Because Curtis has his son... Thomas.
He was in the car when
the shots were fired.
I'm sorry. The priest has a son?
Yes, from a previous life.
Look, I will explain all of this later.
We're heading to Skyline right now.
We're gonna see if we can catch up
with Jean Pierre before anything happens.
All right. We'll meet you there.
Listen, we know Curtis is armed,
so do not go inside without us.
(Beep)
Pearce says he can take
a couple of these guys.
He can take 'em all. We
got someplace else to be.
I gotta go. All right?
(Car door closes)
Thought Swarek said to wait.
Screw Swarek.
God bless the program.
Ready?
(Laughter in distance)
- (Man in distance) Come on, son.
- (Speaks indistinctly)
Father, you shouldn't be in here.
(Chuckles)
That's Curtis Payne back there.
Dude is so untouchable.
Nobody comes after him, right?
That's right. (Chuckles) Until today.
When he comes out that door,
with God looking over me...
Gun.
I'm gonna kill him.
Father, put the gun away.
All these years on the streets,
not knowing if I'm doing any good.
(Whispers) This right
here... this would be good.
That's not true.
(Normal voice) Yes, it is true.
That is not true. That's not how it works.
One bullet... one...
and I save lives... kids' lives.
Who's getting it done? You? You?
Let me do what I came
here to do, and after that,
you can read me my
rights. I'm good with that.
This isn't up to you. You
don't get to decide that.
You're not God.
You damn right, and I'm-a
deal with the good lord
when this is all over with.
Hey, how you doing, man?
Hey, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Father, put the gun down. Put it down.
That's the look I was waiting on.
You like that, Curtis?
Put it down.
Walk away.
This is between me and Curtis!
You know we can't do that.
Just say you came two seconds too late.
That's all you gotta do.
You gonna let him do this?!
Yo, Curtis, shut up.
"Thou shalt not kill."
That's what you teach the kids, right?
(Holsters gun)
Ten simple rules.
What are they gonna think
if you break number six?
What about Thomas? What's he gonna think?
Thomas is the reason why I'm here.
You are a good man.
Are you really willing
to throw everything away?
If you do this, you're
gonna lose your son forever.
He's gonna find out you did this.
He is.
What if he can't forgive you?
What if he can't forgive himself?
(Whispers) Don't.
(Normal voice) Come on.
(Clatter)
Come on. (Speaks indistinctly)
Hands against the wall.
You, turn around.
(Curtis) You're cuffing me?
I gotta search you. Turn
around. Turn around. Arms up.
I told you to wait till I got here.
I heard you.
(Police radio chatter)
Turn around.
(Handcuffs click)
It's okay.
(Handcuffs clicking)
(Whispers) Forgive me Father,
for I have sinned. Forgive me.
You can save it.
I'm not saying nothing till my
lawyer gets here. (Door closes)
That's cool. You don't
have to say anything.
Just wanted to show you
we recovered this from the
premises of your restaurant.
We're just waiting on
the ballistics report,
which I'm almost positive
is gonna match the slugs
we pulled from the mortar at St. Julian's.
Well, you know, a lot of people
come and go from my place.
You know, that could belong to anybody.
That's true,
but that's why we're looking
at you for something else.
(Curtis) You ready, Thomas?
Give me your arm.
(Boy) Come on, man.
(Boy) Do it.
(Thomas yelling, children
speaking indistinctly)
Whatever. Just some people messing around.
Well, what you call,
"messing around," we call,
aggravated assault of a minor.
Carries a pretty serious charge.
And jail time.
Assault of a minor?
Yeah, child abuse?
Child abuse... what's that
gonna do for your reputation?
I guess you could carefully explain it
to your fellow inmates.
Maybe eventually they'll
see it like you do,
that you were just "messing around."
Or you know what?
You could just give us some names...
you know, a couple
players, your suppliers.
Maybe then we could talk
about a different charge...
lighter sentence.
(Door buzzes and beeps)
We'll give you some
time to think that over.
I give him till his lawyer
arrives before he cracks.
Nah, it's not gonna take that long.
Good work on this.
You're wondering what
else you could have said.
Not to Curtis... the girl.
You didn't get through to
her, and that bothers you,
so you're already planning what
you'd do different next time.
How'd you know?
Because I'm a detective, too.
(Door opens)
Thomas is here. He says
that he let you down.
He wants to apologize.
Does he know?
I mean, did you tell him?
No.
It's between you and his mother,
but if it were me, I'd want to know.
Hey.
So what's new?
Lots of things.
Okay, so this woman... she's
from Child and Youth Services,
and she's gonna help you find
a new home, a new family...
it's gonna feel like a fresh start.
Jordan. You don't fool
me, not even for a second.
Your whole tough guy
act... I just don't buy it.
So I want you to have my card.
I want you to hang onto it,
and if anyone ever hurts
you or makes you feel afraid,
I want you to call me,
okay? That's me... Gail Peck.
(Clatter)
(Keys jangle)
Hey.
Here's your keys. (Keys jangle)
Thank you.
(Bag zips)
Just finished releasing
those guys we picked up today.
Whole lot of paperwork for nothing.
(Lock clicks) Sends a message.
You know, I gotta think
it's police work like today
that makes kids not trust cops.
Diaz, you get 'em for
what you can, when you can,
'cause that's the job, even if
you have to push it sometimes.
No. It's not. Not for everybody.
Look, I know you and
Detective Barber were friends,
and I know this thing with
you and Andy's gotta be tough,
but whatever you're going through,
you need to deal with it, soon.
(Door opens)
(Door closes)
(Keys clatter)
Thanks to Curtis Payne, 15
division just made 8 arrests.
Should help boost your numbers.
That is true.
(Keys click)
So who would you recommend?
For the task force. Say I
was looking at people from 15.
Who would you recommend?
(Telephones ring in distance)
Well, I think it's safe to
say you earned this today.
What's that?
Just a little tear-out diploma
I found in the back of the book.
Oh, you just ripped it
right out, hey? No scissors?
Uh, not just yet. Still
have to do number ten.
Final cry. Come on. It's your
last chance to let it all out.
What if I don't need it?
Sure about that?
Yeah.
I think I'm good.
Well, then, congratulations. You graduate.
Hey, Nick.
Are you driving me or what?
Want a lift?
No. No, no, no, go. It's
a nice night. I'll walk.
Thought you said you didn't need a ride.
I changed my mind. I'm cold.
Two words... high maintenance.
Five words... boring-est person
I've ever met ever. (Siren whoops)
Well, that was six. How'd
you get into the academy?
Shut up.
♪
Can I get one of each? Thanks, T.
Thanks to Curtis Payne,
we made eight arrests.
Yeah, I heard. Congratulations.
Actually, can I get two of these?
(Woman) Yeah.
(Clatters)
You want some advice?
Uh, no.
You're an idiot.
If you don't figure that out soon,
you're gonna lose Andy for good.
Take it from me.
(Siren wailing in distance)
(Both stammer)
Um, yeah. (Chuckles)
(Door opens and closes)
(Grunts)
(All grunting) (Thuds)
(Pants)
That one's for Tyler Markes. (Grunts)
You stay away from his
sister, you hear me?
(Man) Go.
(Tires peal)
(Tires screech)
(Pants)
synced and corrected by chamallow
www.addic7ed.com