Hey, baby, what's going on there?
Oh, hi!
Miss Golightly!
Someday... Someday!
You take off for the powder room.
That's the last I see you.
- Now, really, Harry...
- Harry was the other guy.
I'm Sid. Sid Arbuck.
You like me, remember?.
I protest!
Darling, I'm sorry, but I lost my key.
That was two weeks ago.
You cannot go on keep ringing my bell.
You disturb me!
You must have a key made!
It does no good. I lose them them all.
- Come on, baby, you like me.
- I worship you, Mr. Arbuck.
- Good night, Mr. Arbuck.
- Wait! What is this?
You like me. I'm a liked guy.
You like me. I picked up the check for five people...
... your friends. I've never seen them before.
When you asked for change for the powder room
I give you a $50 bill.
That gives me some rights.
In 30 seconds, I going to call the police!
All the time, a disturbance!
I get no sleep!
I got to get my rest! I'm an artist!
I going to call vice squad on you!
Don't be angry, dear man, I won't do it again.
And I might let you take those pictures.
When?
Sometime.
Anytime.
Good night.
I'm sorry to bother you.
But I couldn't get the downstairs door open.
I guess they sent me the upstairs key.
I couldn't get the downstairs door open.
I said, I guess they sent me...
Uh, upstairs key.
I couldn't get the downstairs door open.
Sorry to wake you.
That's quite all right.
It could happen to anyone...
Quite frequently does... Good night.
I... I hate to... uh...
I hate to bother you, but if I could ask
one more favor... could I use the phone?
- Sure. Why not?.
- Thank you.
Well, this is a...
... nice little place you've got here.
You just moved in, too, huh?
No. I've been here around a year.
The phone's over there.
Well, it was.
Oh, I remember.
I stuck it in the suitcase.
Kind of muffles the sound.
I'm... sorry.
Is he all right?
Sure, sure, he's OK.
Aren't you cat?
Poor old cat.
Poor slob.
Poor slob without a name.
I don't have the right to give him one.
We don't belong to each other.
We just took up one day.
I don't want to own anything,
until I find a place where me and things
go together.
I'm not sure where that is,
but I know what it's like.
It's like Tiffany's.
Tiffany's?
You mean the jewelry store?
That's right.
I'm crazy about Tiffany's.
Listen...
You know those days when you get the mean reds?
The mean reds? You mean, like the blues?
The blues are because you're getting fat or it's
been raining too long. You're just sad, that's all.
The mean reds are horrible.
Suddenly you're afraid,
and you don't know what you're afraid of.
- Don't get you ever get that feeling?
- Sure.
When I get it, what does any good,
is to jump into a cab and go to Tiffany's.
Calms me down right away.
The quietness, the proud look...
Nothing very bad could happen to you there.
If I could find a real-life place,
that made me feel like Tiffany's, then...
Then I'd buy some furniture
and give the cat a name.
I'm sorry. You wanted something
Oh, the telephone.
I'm supposed to meet somebody.
Isn't this 10:00 thursday morning?
I just go off a plane from Rome,
and I'm not too sure.
Thursday... Is this thursday?
- I think so.
- Thursday! It can't be!
It's too gruesome!
Well, uh... what's so gruesome about thursday?
Nothing, except I never remember
when it's coming up.
Wednesdays I generally just don't go to bed,
because I have to be up to catch the 10:45.
They're so particular about visiting hours.
Be a darling and look under the bed
for a pair of alligator shoes.
I've got to do something about
the way I look.
A girl can't go to Sing-Sing with a green face.
Sing-Sing?
I always thought it was a ridiculous
name for a prison. Sing-Sing, I mean.
Sounds more like an opera house, or something.
Black, alligator.
All the visitors make an effort
to look their best.
Actually, it's very touching,
all the women wearing their prettiest things.
I love them for it, and I love the kids.
It should be sad seeing kids there,
but it isn't.
They have ribbons in the hair
and lots of shine on their shoes.
As I understand it,
we're getting you ready
to visit somebody at Sing-Sing.
You could always tell what kind of a person
a man thinks you are
By the earrings he gives you.
I must say, the mind reels.
- May I ask whom?
- Whom I'm going to visit?
I guess that's what I mean.
I don't know that I should discuss it.
He never told me not to.
Cross your heart and kiss your elbow.
I'll try.
- You probably read about him, Sally Tomato
-Sally Tomato.
Don't look so shocked.
They couldn't prove he was in the Mafia,
much less head of it.
They only proved he cheated at his income taxi.
Anyway, he's a darling old man.
He wasn't my lover or anything.
I never knew him until after he was in prison.
I've gone to see him every thursday
for seven months.
I'd go even if he didn't pay me.
- Shoes.
- I could only find one.
- He pays you?
- His lawyer does.
If he's a lawyer, which I doubt.
He doesn't have an office.
Only an answering service.
He always wants to meet at hamburguer heaven.
There you are, you sneak. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Dress... Dress...
Here we are... Bag.
And a hat, too. There we are.
Anyway, about seven months ago,
this so called lawyer, Mr. O'Shaughnessy,
asked me how I'd like
to cheer up a lonely man
and pick up a hundred a week.
I told him: "Look darling,
you've got the wrong Holly Golightly."
I do as well on trips to the powder room.
Any gentleman will give $50
for the powder room.
And cab fare... that's another 50.
Then he said his client was Sally Tomato.
Sally had seen me somewhere,
and had admired me 'á la distance'.
So wouldn't it be a good deed
to visit him once a week?.
How could I say no?
It was wildly romantic.
How do I look?
Very good.
I must say I'm amazed.
I could never have done it without you.
- Bag...
- Call me anytime.
I'm just upstairs, or I will be
as soon as I get moved in.
Bye, cat.
Uh... you mean he gives you $100
for an hour's conversation?
Mr. O'Shaughnessy does when I meet him
and give him the weather report.
It's none of my business,
but it sounds like you could get in trouble.
Hold this for me.
And what do you mean weather report?
Just a message I give Mr. O'Shaughnessy,
so he knows I've really been up there.
Sally tells me things to say like, uh...
"There's a hurricane in Cuba"...
"Cloudy over Palermo"... things like that.
You don't have to worry.
I've taken care of myself a long time.
Taxi!
- I never could do that.
- It's easy.
Paul.
I'm late. I know it.
Where you locked out?
Didn't you get the key?
Oh, darling, I'm sorry.
No, I got the key, all right.
Miss Golightly, my neighbor, kindly let me in.
Miss Golightly on her way to Sing-Sing.
Just visiting, of course.
Miss Golightly,
Mrs. Falenson, my... decorator.
- How do you do?
Oh, darling. Let me look at you.
- Are you through?
- Was the flight absolutely ghastly?
Grand Central Station.
And step on it, darling.
Is it really only three weeks
since I left you in Rome?
Seems like years.
- You seen the apartment?
- Not yet.
It was wicked of me, but I couldn't resist.
I fixed it up without you.
I think it's darling,
but if you absolutely hate it,
we can rip everything out and start from scratch.
Hey, baby! Where you going?
come on, baby. Open the door.
Aw, be a pal.
You're breaking up a beautiful party.
Come on, baby, open the door.
Hey, the band's swinging!
Aw, come on, baby.
Miss Gorightly!
Once again I must protest!
If you don't stop that phonograph now,
I'm going to call the Police Department!
Yeah. That more better.
What's the matter, baby?
Aw, come on. You're a great kid.
Open the door.
Come on, baby. I'm waiting for you.
- It's all right, it's only me.
- Uh, wait a minute. Miss, uh...
Golightly. Holly Golightly.
I live downstairs.
We met this morning, remember?
Yeah.
It's all right. She's gone.
She works late hours for a decorator.
There's the most terrifying man downstairs.
He's sweet when he isn't drunk, but...
Let him start lapping up the 'vino'
and, oh, golly, 'quel' beast!
It got so tiresome, I went out the window.
You can throw me out if you want,
but you looked so cozzy in here
and your decorator friend had gone home,
and it was getting so cold
on the fire scape.
And I always heard people in New York
never get to know their neighbors.
Well, how was Sing-Sing?
Fine. I made the train and everything.
And what's the weather report?
"Small-craft warnings,"
"Block lsland to Hatteras."
Whatever that means.
You know, you're so sweet.
You really are
And you look a little like my brother, Fred.
- Do you mind if I call you Fred?
- Not at all.
300. She's very generous.
Is that by the week, the hour, or what?
The party is over. Out.
Oh, Fred.
Darling Fred, I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to hurt your feelings.
Don't be angry.
I was just letting you know I understand.
I understand completely.
Stick around. Make yourself a drink.
- Or throw me my robe, I'll make you one.
-Stay where you are.
You must be absolutely exhausted.
I mean, it's late,
and you were sound asleep and everything.
I suppose you think I'm very brazen
or 'trés fou' or something.
You're no fouer than anybody else.
Yes, you do. Everybody does.
And I don't mind.
It's useful being top banana
in the shock department
What do you do, anyway?
- I'm a writer, I guess.
- You guess? Don't you know?
OK, positive statement.
Ringing affirmative.
I'm a writer.
The only writer I've been out with
is Benny Shacklett.
He's written an awful lot of TV stuff,
but 'quel' rat!
Tell me. Are you a real writer?
I mean, does anybody buy what you write
or publish it or anything?
They bought what's in that box.
Yours?
All these books?
There's just one book,
12 copies of it.
"Nine lives" by Paul Varjak.
- They're stories.
- Hmm... Nine of them.
Tell me one.
They're not the kind of stories
you can really tell.
Too dirty?
Yeah, I... suppose they're dirty too,
but only incidentally.
Mainly they're angry, sensitive...
intensively felt,
and that dirtiest of all dirty words...
Promising.
So said The Times Book Review
October 1, 1956.
- 1956?
- That's right.
This is kind of a ratty question,
but what have you written lately?
Lately, I've been working on a novel.
- Lately, since 1956?
- A novel takes a long time.
- I want it exactly right.
- So, not more stories.
The idea is I'm supposed to not fritter
my talent on little things.
I'm supposed to be saving it
for the big one.
Do you write every day??
Sure.
- Today?
- Sure.
- It's a beautiful typewriter.
- Of course.
It writes nothing but sensitive,
intensely felt promising prose.
- There's no ribbon in it.
- There isn't?
No.
Something you said this morning
has been bothering me all day.
What's that?
Do they really give you $50
whenever you go to the powder room?
Of course.
You must do very well.
I'm trying to save,
but I'm not very good at it.
You know? You do look
a lot like my brother Fred.
I haven't seen him since I was 14.
That's when I left home.
He was already 6'2".
It must have been the peanut butter
that did it.
Everybody thought he was dotty,
the way he gorged himself on peanut butter.
But he wasn't dotty,
just sweet and vague and...
terribly slow.
Poor Fred.
He is in the Army now.
That's really the best place for him
until I can get enough money saved.
- And then?
- And then Fred and I...
I went to Mexico once.
It's a wonderful place for racing horses.
I saw one place near the sea that...
Fred's very good with horses.
Even land in Mexico costs something.
No matter what I do, there's never
more than $200 in the bank.
It can't be 4:30.
It just can't.
Do you mind if I just get in
with you for a minute?
It's allright. Really, it is.
We're friends, that's all.
- We are friends, aren't we?
- Sure.
OK, let's don't say another word.
Let's just go to sleep.
Where are you, Fred?
It's cold.
There... There's snow in the wind.
What is it? What's the matter?
Why are you crying?
If we're going to be friends,
let's just get one thing straight right now.
I hate snoops.
- Yeah.
- Lucille, darling?
I've been trying desperately to reach you.
Bill just got back...
A day early, the beast...
So, I'm afraid I'll have to beg off.
You'll explain to the rest of the girls?
You are a darling.
Maybe we can have a long lunch tomorrow.
- I'll phone you in the morning.
- Whatever you say.
You'll manage to survive without me tonight?
Sure. I might even take
a wild boyish flying at writing.
- Good night.
Got yourself stuffed,
huh, Polly, baby?
Serves you right, bigmouth.
'Buon giorno'.
Aren't you drinking?
You have pockets there or something?
What do you go by?
What's your name? What do you call yourself?
- Irving.
- Oh, yes. Perfect, perfect.
That's wonderful.
I'll be right back, Irving, baby.
Kid's still in the shower.
You expected?
I was invited. That what you mean?
Don't get all tense and soft. Come in.
It's a party.
Lot of characters come who aren't expected.
I'll buy you a drink.
- You drink?
- Yeah.
- Then I'll buy you a drink. - OK.
Hey, honey, your skirt's split here.
- What do you drink?
- Bourbon.
- Bourbon... on the rocks?
- Yeah... No, with water.
- You want rocks first?
- Yeah. Not too much.
All right. That'll set you free.
- Know the kid long?
- Not very. I live upstairs.
Look at this place. What a place
It's unbelievable. What a dump!
What do you think?
- About what?
- Is she or isn't she?
Wait a minute. Hold it.
- Harriet!
- Hi, J.B.
"J.B."? What's that?
- You know Gil.
- Yeah. How are you?
- How about a drink?
- In the kitchen. You'll find everything you need.
So... Oh, honey, that is you.
Fred, darling, I'm so glad you could come!
I brought you a house present.
Something for the bookcase.
Oh, you're sweet.
Doesn't that look nice?
Give me a cigarette, O.J.
-Sure, sure...
- O.J.'s a great agent.
He knows a lot of phone numbers.
What's Jerry Wald's phone number?
Come on, lay off.
Darling, I want you to call him and
tell him what a genious Fred is.
Stop blushing, Fred.
You didn't say it, a genious, I did.
So, quit stalling, O.J. Just tell me
what are you going to do to make Fred
rich and famous.
Let Fred and me settle that.
Huh, puppy?
OK, but just remember... I'm the agent.
He's already got a decorator.
I'm the agent.
Hold it.
Hi, boys. Come on in.
Everything you need's in the kitchen.
So, listen, Fred, baby... What...?
- No, it's Paul, baby.
- I thought it was Fred, baby.
- No.
- Oh, it is. I thought it was Paul, baby...
- Answer the question. Is she or isn't she?
- Is she or isn't she what?
A phony.
I don't know. I don't think so.
You don't, huh? Well, you're wrong... She is.
But on the other hand you're right,
because she's a real phony. You know why?
Because she honestly believes
all this phony junk.
Now, I sincerely like the kid. I do.
I'm sensitive, that's why.
You got to be sensitive to like the kid.
You know what I mean.
It's a streak of the poet.
You know her long?
I discovered her, I'm O.J. Berman
She was just a kid...
Lot of style and class, you know...
- Lot of what?
- Class. Yes, she had a lot of class.
But when she opened the mouth you didn't
know what she was talking about...
Whether she was a
hillbilly or an okie.
- Know how long it took to me
to smooth that accent?
- No.
- I'll tell you how long.
One year. Know how we did?
We gave her french lessons.
Figured once she could imitate french,
she could imitate english.
Finally, I arranged
for a little screen test.
Well, the night before the screen...
I've got to kill myself...
The night before the screen, the phone rings,
I pick it up...
"This is O.J., speak" and she says: "Hi, this is Holly"
"Holly, you sound far away".
And she says: "I'm in New York."
"you can't be in New York.
You have a screen test tomorrow."
She says: "I'm in New York because I've
never been in New York before"
"Get yourself in a plane! Get back!"
She says: "I don't want to."
"What do you mean?
What do you want?"
She says: "That's what you want."
And she says: "when I find out, I'll let you know."
Bang!
- So look, Fred, baby...
- It's Paul, baby.
Sure.
Don't tell me she isn't a phony.
Irving, honey, where you been?
Mike, darling, I tried reaching you
all day long.
Your answering service doesn't answer.
That's the trouble with answering services...
Well, I guess that's... and after all that she said...
- Time, darling.
- What?
Time?
- You have a watch?
- No.
- Oh, let's see. 18:45.
- Thank you.
Really, was that necessary?
This is some party.
Who are all these people, anyhow?
who knows? The word gets out.
You don't mind, don't you, darling?
Reinforcements.
Right in there.
Holly?
Holly, darling!
- What's that?
- Mag Wildwood.
She is a model, believe it or not,
and a thumping bore.
But just look at the goodies
she brought with her.
He's all right,
if you like dark, handsome,
rich-looking men
with passionate natures and too many teeth.
I mean the other one.
- the other one?
- He's Rusty Trawler.
The ninth richest man in America
under 50.
Now, that, indeed, is a remarkable piece
of information to have at your fingerprints.
I keep track of this things.
- Excuse me. you owe me 47...
- Hold this a minute, darling.
Mag, darling, what are you doing here?
I was upstairs working with Yunioshi...
Easter stuff for The Bazaar.
then these two nice boys came
to pick me up.
It was a mistake, of course.
My wires get crossed somewhere.
They were both very sweet about it.
May I present
José Silva Pereira?
He's from Brazil... Miss Golightly...
Very kind of you, Miss Golightly,
to allow me to attend your party.
I'm so interested in north-american culture.
I've been already to the Statue of Liberty
and to the Restaurant Automatique.
But this is the first time
I am in a typical north-americansom home.
Wouldn't he just melt in your mouth?
And this is Mr. Rusty Trawler.
You're not vexed at me for bringing him?
- Of course not, darling.
- I'm glad.
Now, who's going to bring me a bourbon?
- O.J.
- Yeah.
Would you get Miss Wildwood a drink?
which one's Miss Wildwood?
Mr. Berman, we haven't been formally introduced,
but I'm Mag Wildwood from Wildwood, Arkansas.
That's...hill country.
Now, you just make yourself righ at home.
Oh, don't trouble yourself.
I'm contented to observe the customs
of your country.
OK, you do that.
Now come along, Mr. Trawler.
Let's see what we can find
to amuse you.
I wasn't supposed to pick you up.
You said you would...
Miss Golightly?
This time I'm awarning you!
I am definitely this time
going to call the police!
Good evening!
Is it something important?
No. Just the guy upstairs complaining
about the noise.
He's angry?
He did mention something about
calling the police.
Oh, the police... The police?
That i cannot have. I'd better look
for Miss Wildwood and go.
To think I'd find a beau of mine
mousing after a piece of
cheap Hollywood trash.
Mag, darling, you're being a bore.
Shut up!
You know what's going to happen you?
I'm going to march you over the zoo
and feed you to the yak...
Just as soon as I finish this drink.
Timber!
Sorry.
- Oh, good evening, Ed.
- It's Paul, baby.
You remember Irving, don't you?
- This is José.
- Nice to meet you.
Wonderful seeing you.
Jewel thieves.
Sally helps me with my accounts.
I have no head for figures at all.
I'm trying desperately to save some money.
I just can't seem to.
He makes me write down
everything in here.
What I get, what I spend.
I used to have a checking account.
He made me get rid of that.
He feels, for me, it's better to operate
on a cash basis, taxwise.
Someday Mr. Fred, you take this book,
turn it to a novel.
Everything is there.
Just fill in the details.
Would be good for some laughs.
No. No, I don't think so.
This is a book would break that heart.
"Mr. Fitzsimmons...
powder room, $50."
"Less $18... Repair one black satin dress."
"Cat food, 27 cents."
Sally, darling, please stop.
You're making me blush!
But you're right about Jack Fitzsimmons.
He's an absolute rat.
But I guess, of course,
I don't know anybody but rats.
Except, of course, Fred here.
You do think Fred is nice, don't you?
For you... I hope he is.
Give me a kiss, goodbye, uncle Sally.
Till next week.
Goodbye, uncle Sally.
Goodbye, and don't forget to send that book.
I won't.
Oh, what about the weather report?
Oh, yes.
"Snow flurries expected this weekend
in New Orleans."
Snow flurries expected this weekend
in New Orleans?
Isn't that just the weirdest?
I bet they haven't had snow in
New Orleans for a million years.
I don´t know how he thinks them up.
- What you doing?
- Writing.
Good.
Well, hello.
- What's wrong?
- I don't know.
It's probably nothing.
I wnat to see if he's still there.
See if who's still there?
What are you talking about?
Look.
See?
I noticed him yesterday afternoon.
I didn't say anything.
I didn't want to sound neurotic, but...
- When he's there again today...
- Who do you think he is?
It could be anybody, of course,
But what crossed my mind was...
Suppose Bill's having us watched, huh?
OK, I'll take care of this.
No. No, don't. Please.
If that's what it is, you'll only
make everything worse.
I'll be careful. Wait here.
Darling, please don't.
I don't think you should.
Now, take it easy.
I just want to find out
what this is all about.
All right, what do you want?
Son, I need a friend.
That's me, that's her,
that's her brother, Fred.
You are Holly's father?
Her name ain't Holly.
She was Lula Mae Barnes,
was till she married me.
I'm her husband, Doc Golightly.
Paul Varjak.
I'm a horse doctor. Animal man.
Do some farming, too,
near Tulip, Texas.
Her brother Fred's getting out
of the Army soon.
Lula Mae belong home with her husband,
and her children.
children?
- Them's her children.
- She's got four children?
Now, son, I didn't claim they was
her natural-born children.
Their own precious mother...
Precious woman...
Passed away July 4th,
Independence Day, 1955.
The year of the drought. When I married
Lula Mae, she was going on 14.
You might think the average person
going 14 wouldn't know her own mind.
But you take Lula Mae,
she was an exceptional person.
She just plumb broke our hearts
when she run off like she done.
Just plain had no reason.
All the housework was done
by our daughters.
Lula Mae could just take it easy.
That woman got positively fat,
while her brother, he growed up into a giant,
which is a sight different
from the way they come to us.
A couple of wild young'uns, they was.
I caught'em stealing milk
and turkey eggs.
They'd been living with some mean,
no-account people
about 100 mile east of Tulip.
She had good cause to run off
from that house.
Never had none to leave mine.
What about her brother?
Didn't he leave too?
No. We had Fred with us till
the Army took him.
That's why I come.
I had a letter from him.
He's getting out in february.
That's why I come to get her.
Lula Mae's place is with her husband
her children, and her brother.
The prize from the cracker jack.
Want it?
Never could understand
why that woman run off.
Don't tell me she weren't happy.
Talky as a jaybird, she was,
with something smart to say
on every subject.
Better than the radio.
The night I proposed,
I cried like a baby.
She said: "Why are you crying?
Of course we'll be married."
"I never been married before."
I laughed and hugged and squeezed her.
"Never been married before."
Listen, son, I advise you,
I need a friend,
'cause I don't want to surprise her
or scare her none.
Be my friend, let her know I'm here.
Will you do that for me, son?
Yeah, sure, Doc.
If that is what you want.
Come on.
All right.
Coming.
Oh, darling, I'm on my way out.
I'm half an hour late.
Maybe we can have a drink tomorrow.
Sure, Lula Mae...
If you're still here tomorrow.
Oh, please, where is he?
Honey, don't they feed you up here?
You're so skinny.
- Hi, Doc.
- Gosh, Lula Mae...
Kingdom come!
What's the matter? You all right?
I guess so... No, I'm not.
Will you help me?
- If I can.
- Come to the bus station with Doc and me.
He still thinks I'm going back.
- I can't play the scene alone
What can I do?
- He's your husband.
- No, he's not.
- He's not?
It was annulled ages ago.
He just won't accept it.
Please, Fred.
I'll say you're seeing us off.
Don't say anything.
Just meet us out front,
in about an hour. Please?
You wait right here, honey.
I'll get the bag.
Why don't I get some magazines?.
Please, Fred, don't leave me.
Attention, please...
Leaving from platform 5,
through coach to Dallas...
Philadelphia, Columbus,
lndianapolis, Terre Haute,
St. Louis, Tulsa,
Oklahoma City, Denison, Dallas.
Come on, Lula Mae. That's us.
Doc, I'm not coming with you.
Come on. Let's walk quietly.
I'll try and help you understand.
Help me, Fred.
I appreciate you want to help, but
it's between Lula Mae and me.
Sure, Doc.
I love you, Lula Mae.
I know, and that's the trouble.
It's a mistake you always made...
trying to love a wild thing.
You were always lugging home
wild things...
A hawk with a broken wing,
a full grown wildcat
with a broken leg...
- Remember?
- There's something...
You mustn't give your heart
to a wild thing.
The more you do,
the stronger they get
until they're strong enough
to fly into a tree,
then to higher trees,
then to the sky.
There's something I got to tell you.
Excuse me.
Couple of weeks ago,
I got a letter from Fred.
From Fred? He's all right, isn't he?
Yeah, he's fine, I guess.
He's getting out of the Army
in february.
In february?
Well, that's only foor months.
So, see, you got to come back,
your place is with us.
Doc, you've got to understand.
I can't come back.
You got to understand what I'm saying.
I don't want to pressure you,
but it got to.
If you don't come
I'll have to tell young Fred
he better sign up for another hitch.
Don't do that.
Don't write that to him.
I'll write him and say I want
him with me.
I'll take care of him.
You're talking crazy, Lula Mae.
Doc, stop calling me that.
I'm not Lula Mae anymore.
All right, Lula Mae.
I guess you know what you're doing.
Keep an eye on her, will you, son?
At least see she eats something
once in a while.
Sure, Doc.
So skinny.
Please, Doc. Please understand.
I love you, but I'm just
not Lula Mae anymore.
I'm not.
You know the terrible thing,
Fred, darling?
I am still Lula Mae...
14 years old, stealing turkey eggs
and running through a briar patch.
Except now I call it
having the mean reds.
Well, it's still too early
to go to Tiffany's.
I guess the next best thing
is a drink.
Yes, I very much need a drink.
- Buyme one, Fred, darling?
- Sure.
Only promise me one thing...
Don't take me home until I'm drunk...
Until I'm very drunk, indeed.
Do you think she's talented?
Deeply and importantly talented?
No. Amusingly and superficially
talented, yes...
But deeply and importantly talented, no.
Gracious.
Do you think she's handsomely paid?
Oh, indeed.
Well, let me tell you something.
If I had her money, I'd be
richer than she is.
- How do oyu figure that?
- Because I keep the candy store.
Old Sally Tomato...
That's my candy store.
I'd always keep Sally.
That's why I'd be
richer than she is.
We'd better get a little more air.
Tom, Dick and Harry...
No. Correction.
Every Tom, Dick, and Sid...
Harry was his friend.
Anyway, every Tom, Dick,
and Sid sinks...
Thinks if he takes a girl to dinner,
she'll just curl up in a little
furry ball at his feet, right?
I have by actual count
been taken to dinner
by 26 different rats in the last 2 months.
27, if you count Benny Shacklett,
who's in many ways a super-rat.
- I forgot my key.
- Nevermind. I just buzzed Yunioshi.
Do you want to know
something funny?
In spite of the fact most of
these rats fork up $50
for the powder room
like little dolls...
I find I have $9 less
in the bank account
than I had six months ago.
So, my darling Fred,
I have tonight made
a very serious decision.
And what is that?
No longer will I play the field.
- Congratulations.
- The field stinks...
both economically and socially,
and I'm giving it up.
This time I'm calling the police,
the Fire Department
and New Yorks State Housing Comission,
and, if necessary, the Board of Health!
Quiet up there.
You want to wake the whole house?
As Miss Golightly was saying
before she was so rudely interrupted.
Miss Golightly further announces her intention
to devote her not
inconsiderable talents
to the inmediate capture,
for the purpose of matrimony,
of Mr. Rutherford...
Rusty, to his friends, of whom,
I'm sure he has many... Trawler.
- Who?
- Rusty Trawler.
You met him at a party.
He came with Mag Wildwood,
not the beautiful latin type,
the other one...the one that
looks like a pig.
Remember?
The 9th richest man
in America under 50?
Do I detect a look of disaproval? In your eye?
Tough beans, buddy, 'cause
that's the way it's going to be.
Hi, cat.
- Holly, you're drunk.
- True.
Absolutely true.
True, but irrelevant.
What are you doing?
So I think we should
have a drink,
to the new Mrs. Rusty Trawler... Me.
Hey, take it easy.
What's the matter?
Don't you think I can do it?
Tell me, I'm interested.
Don't you think I can?
You heard the Doc.
My brother gets out in february.
The Doc won't take him back.
It's all up for me.
I don't know why you don't understand.
I need money, and I'll do
whatever I have to do to get it.
So... This time next month,
I'll be the new Mrs. Rusty Trawler.
I think we should have
a little drink to that.
It's all gone. Isn't that too bad?
Got any whiskey upstairs?
But you've had enough.
Go ahead. Get the whiskey.
I'll pay you for it.
Holly, please.
No, no, you disappove of me,
and I do not accept drinks
from gentlemen who disapprove of me.
I'll pay for my own whiskey.
Don't forget it.
Holly.
I do not accept drinks
from disapproving gentlemen.
Specially not disapproving gentlemen
who are kept by other ladies.
So take it.
You should be used to taking
money from ladies by now.
I I were you, I'd be more
careful with my money.
Rusty Trawler is too hard
a way of earning it.
It should take you exactly 4 seconds
to cross from here to that door.
I'll give you two.
Hi. I wanted to talk about
the other night,
then I saw the paper, and...
Well, actually, I'm kind of
embarrased about it,
but since it oncerns you,
I thought I should talk
about it in person.
- What?
- what?
Oh. The earplugs.
I can't go through the whole thing again.
It's sufficient to say,
I've come to make up.
As an added inducement,
I have all kind of news.
- Can come on in?
- I guess so.
Just a  minute.
Do I have a nightgown on?
No, I don't.
Would you turn around for a second?
Never mind. That's corny anyway.
I'll turn around myself.
Come in.
Have... you seen the paper?
Mmm. Rusty, you mean?
Yes. I know all about it.
Certainly had him...
Pegged wrong, didn't it?
I thought he was just a rat,
but he was a super-rat all along.
A super-rat in rat's clothing.
You don't even know the best part.
Not only was a super-rat,
he was also broke.
Broke! I mean, but not a farthing.
His family has money, of course,
but he personally is broke.
It turns out he owes $700,000.
Can you imagine anyone owing $700000?
$43, yes.
Anyway, that's why he decided to
marry the queen of the pig people.
I'll tell you one thing, Fred, darling...
I'd marry you for your money
in a minute.
- Would you marry me for my money?
- In a minute.
I guess it's pretty lucky
neither of us is rich, huh?
Yeah.
Oh, Fred, darling,
I'm so glad to see you.
What have you been doing?
Writing, mostly.
Sold a story.
Just got word this morning.
Oh, that's marvelous!
It really is.
Only how does your decorator friend
feel about it?
Aren't you supposed to be
saving yourself?
You know something?
I haven't got around to
telling her yet.
Look, why don't we go have a drink
or take a walk to celebrate?
All right. There's some
champagne in the icebox.
- Why don't you open it while I get dressed?
- OK
I don't think I've ever drunk
champagne before breakfast before.
With breakfast on several occasions,
but never before before.
Well, I've got a wonderful idea.
We'll spend the day doing things
we've never done before.
We'll take turns. First something
you've never done, then me.
'course, I can't think of anything
I've never done.
I've never been for a walk
in the morning before.
Not in New York.
I've walked up 5th Avenue at 6:00,
but I consider that still night.
- Do you think it counts?
- Sure, it counts. Now we're even.
- Don't you just love it?
- Love what?
Tiffany's.
Isn't it wonderful?
See what I mean, how nothing bad
could happen to you in a place like this?
It isn't that I give a hoot about
jewelry, except diamonds, of course.
Like that.
- What do you think?
- Well...
Personally, I think it would be tacky
to wear diamonds before I'm 40.
Well, you're right, but meantime
you should have something.
I'll wait.
No, I'm going to buy you a present.
You bought me a typewriter ribbon
and it brought luck.
But Tiffany's can be pretty expensive.
I've got my check and $10.
I wouldn't let you cash your check,
but a present for $10 or under,
that I will accept.
Of course, I don't know what
we'll find here for $10.
May I help you?
Perhaps. We're looking for
a present for the lady.
Certainly, sir.
Is there something special
you have in mind?
Well, we've considered diamonds.
And I don't to offend you but,
the lady feels that diamonds are tacky for her.
Oh, I think they're divine for
older women,
but they're not right for me,
you understand.
- Certainly.
- In fairness, I ought to explain
there's also a secondary problem,
one of finance.
We can only afford to spend...
a limited amount.
- May I ask how limited?
- $10.
That was the outside figure, yes.
- I see.
- Do you have anything for $10?
Frankly, madam,
within that price range
the variety of merchandise is
rather limited.
However, I do think we might have...
Let's see...
Strictly as a novelty,
you understand...
For the lady and gentleman
who has everything,
a sterlingsilver telephone dialer.
That's 6.75, including tax.
A sterlingsilver telephone dialer.
Yes, sir. That's 6,75 dollar,
including Federal Tax.
Well, the price is right,
but I must say
I'd rather hoped for something slightly more...
How shall I say it...
Romantic in feeling.
- What do you think?
- A sterlingsilver telephone dialer?
I certainly think it's handsome,
but, well, you do understand.
Well, we tried but...
We could have something engraved,
couldn't we?
Yes, I suppose so. Yes, indeed.
The only problem is, you'd have
to buy something first
in order to have some object upon
which to place the engraving.
You see dificulty?
Well, we could have this engraved,
couldn't we?
I think it would be very smart.
This, I take it, was not
purchased at Tiffany's?
No. Actually, it was purchased concurrent with...
Well, actually it came inside a...
- Well, a box of cracker jack.
- I see.
Do they still really have prizes
in cracker jack boxes?
- Oh, yes.
- That's nice to know.
It gives one a feeling of solidarity,
almost of continuity with the past,
that sort of thing.
Would Tiffany's really engrave it for us?
They wouldn't feel it beneath
them or anything?
Well, it's rather unusual, madam,
but I think you'll find that Tiffany's
is very understanding.
If you would tell me the initials,
I think we could have something
ready for you in the morning.
Didn't I tell you this was
a lovely place?
What is this place anyway?
You wanted to sit down.
It's the public library.
- You've never been here?
- No. That makes two for me.
I don't see any books.
They're in there.
See?
Each one of these drawers
is stuffed with little cards.
Each little card is a book
or an author.
I think that's fascinating.
- V-a-r-j-a-k.
- Really?
Look. Isn't it marvelous?
There you are...
Right in the public library.
Varjak, Paul. "Nine lives."
Then a lot of numbers.
Do they really have the book itself?
Live?
Sure. Follow me.
Number 57. That's us.
57, please.
"Nine lives" by Varjak, Paul.
Have you read it?
It's marvelous.
- I'm afraid, I haven't.
- You should. He wrote it.
He's Varjak, Paul, in person.
She doesn't believe me.
Show her your driver's license
or Dinner's Club card
or something.
He's really the author.
Cross my heart and kiss my elbow.
Would you kindly lower your voice?
Autograph it.
Wouldn't that be nice?
Sort of making more personal?
really, Miss...
Go ahead. Don't be stuck,
signera den.
Vad ska jag skriva?
Någonting sentimentalt,
autograph it.
What shall I say? Stop that!
You're defacing public property.
Well, if that's how you feel,
come on, let's get out of here.
I don't think this place is
half as nice as Tiffany's.
Did you ever steal anything
from a 5-and-10
when you were a kid?
No. I'm the sensitive, bookish type.
Did you?
Yes, I still do now and then
sort of to keep my hand in.
Come on. Don't be chicken, you've
never done it, and it's your turn.
I can't see.
Hi, cat. Lady of the house at home?
Bu!
You're crazy. You know that, don't you?
But I love you anyway.
- Tooley?
- Yeah?
I've... got to talk to you.
All right.
You want a drink?
If this is going to be
a serious discussion...
and suddenly I'm terribly
afraid it is...
you're going to have to take off
that ridiculous mask,
or else I'll have to wear one too.
Tooley, look, please.
What's the matter? Girl trouble?
Is that it, darling?
Oh, I see.
Well, that's not too serious.
As a matter of fact,
I've expecting it.
I can't say I like it,
but I've been expecting it.
Who is she?
Hasn't got anything to do with her.
This is between you and me.
Oh, then it's serious.
Well, now...
Tooley, you're a very stylish girl.
Can't we end this stylishly?
- End it?
- Yes.
Well... I do believe love
has found Andy Hardy.
Let's see... a waitress?
A salesgirl?
No. She'd have to be someone rich,
wouldn't she, Paul?
Someone who could help you.
Curiously enough...
She's a girl who can't help anyone,
not even herself.
The thing is, I can help her,
and it's a nice feeling for a change.
All right.
I understand.
I'll tell you what, Paul.
I'm very stylish girl.
- What are you doing?
- Writing a check.
Don't look so bewildered.
Surely you've noticed me
writing checks before.
Pay to the order of Paul Varjak...
$1,000.
Take her away somewhere
for a week.
You're entitled
to a vacation with pay.
Simply a matter of fair
labor practice, darling.
If you were really smart,
you'd get the boys together
and organize a union.
That way you'd get all
the fringe benefits...
Hospitalization, a pension plan,
and unemployment insurance
when you are...
How shall I put it...
between engagements?
Thanks for making it easier for me.
Don't be ridiculous, darling.
Take the check. And call your girl.
No, thanks. I've got a check of my own.
When you get yourself a new
writer to help,
try and find one my size.
That way you won't have to even
shorten the sleeves.
- Oh, what are you doing?
- Excuse me.
Uh, I... I'm sorry.
You look just like a girl
I know, named Holly.
Really?
I'm sorry.
Hi.
What do you want?
I want to talk to you.
I'm busy.
- What are you doing?
- Reading.
"South America:
Land of wealth and promise"?
It's very interesting.
Let's get out of here.
I said, let's get out of here.
I want to talk to you.
What's the matter with you anyway?
What's happened?
Fred, will you please just
leave me alone?
I love you.
- Where are you going?
- To the ladies room.
- What's the matter with you?
- Let me go.
- No.
- Fred, let me go.
Let's get something straight.
I'm not nor have I ever been Fred,
nor am I Benny Shacklett.
My name is Paul, Paul Varjak,
and I love you.
- Let me go.
- Not till we settle this. What's
about all this jazz about South AmericaVar?
I thought if I'm marrying
a south-american,
I'd better find out something
about the country.
- Marry? What south-american?
- José.
- Who the hell's José?
- José de Silva Pereira.
Who the hell's José de Silva Pereira?
Darling, you met him, I know you did...
Mag Wildwood's friend.
He came to the party with Rusty.
Well, my dear, you won't believe this,
but not only is he handsome and rich,
he's absolutely cuckoo for me.
- You're crazy.
- Do you think you own me?
That's exactly what I think.
That's exactly what everybody thinks,
but everybody happens to be wrong.
Look, I'm not everybody.
Or am I?
Is that what you really think?
That I'm not different from
all you other rats and super-rats?
wait a minute.
If that's it...
If that's what you really think...
There's something I want to give you.
What's that?
$50 for the powder room.
the place is in such a mess,
I couldn't face it alone.
- Ah, you have a message.
- No.
Olé.
Good evening, Mr. Yunioshi.
- Oh, good evening, Paul.
- Good evening.
Good evening.
Please, you must help me.
Let me go. No!
No! No!
- What did you do to her?
- Nothing.
There was a telegram, and then this...
Crashing everything and acting like
a crazy... It's appalling.
I can't have a public scandal.
It's too delicate...
My name, my position, my family.
Will there be the police again?
I don't see why. There's no law
against busting up your apartment.
- Where is the telegram?
- There it is.
"Received notice young Fred killed..."
"in jeep-accident, Fort Riley, Kansas."
"Your husband and children
join in the sorrow"
"of our mutual lost.".
"Letter following. Love, Doc."
Her brother Fred.
This brother, was she very
close to him?
Yeah.
What can one do?
Try to help her.
I tried,
It didn't do much good.
You got a ranch or
something in Brazil?
Yes.
that's good. She'll like that.
Well, you better get in here.
- Hi.
- Hello. Got your wire.
How did you know where to reach me?
Oh, I tried everything...
Called people, asked around,
and suddenly I thought of the phone
book. Anyway, I'm glad you came.
You look fine.
I'm fat as a pig, and I haven't
had my hair done,
but I'm happy, really happy...
It probably shows.
You look 'trés distingué' yourself.
I've got a job.
I've been writing a little.
I've read three of your stories...
Two in The New Yorker
and one in that funny little magazine.
- Won't you sit down?.
- Thank you.
- I've taken up knitting.
- So I see.
It'll probably look, uh... very nice
once it's finished.
I'm a little nervous about it.
José brought up the blueprints
for a new ranch house he's building.
I have this strange feeling that
the blueprints and my knitting instructions
got switched.
I may be knitting a ranch house.
really, darling, I can't tell
you how divinely happy I am.
What is that, anyhow?
Portuguese...
A very complicated language.
4,000 irregular verbs.
Hmm. Very impresive. What's it mean?
I believe you're in league
with the butcher.
Holly, what's this about?
Why did you want to see me?
José's in Washington for the night,
so I thought I'd ask you over,
adn, well, I've said goodbye to
everyone else I care about.
- You're going somewhere?
- I'm going to Rio, tomorrow.
I've got the plane ticket and I've
even said goodbye to Sally.
- José's flying down with you?
- We're going on separate planes.
He doesn't think it looks right
for us to travel together.
His family's important down there,
so he worries about things like that.
Anyway, I thought I'd show off
and cook dinner for us.
Did I tell you how divinely
and utterly happy I am?
Yes.
You're getting married, then?
Well, he hasn't really asked me,
not in so many words.
Four, you mean?
Well, that's how many words it takes...
Will you marry me?
Oh, we'll get married, all right.
And in church and with his family there.
And that's why he's waiting till
we get to Rio... Probably.
Do you think it's trying to
tell us something?
I hope you like chicken and saffron
rice served with chocolate sauce.
It's an east indian classic, my dear.
Three months ago I couldn't
scramble eggs.
Oh, are you all right?
Oh, golly, darling,
I did so want to impress you.
Look, I'm not much for chicken
with sauce anyway.
Why don't we go out somewhere?
Let me buy you a farewell dinner.
Oh, that would be fun, as long as
I can go like this.
Years from now, years and years,
I'll be back...
Me and nine
brazilian brats.
They'll be dark like José, of course,
but they'll have bright green,
beautiful eyes.
I'll bring them back, all right,
because they must see this.
Oh, I love New York.
Then, why are you leaving?
What's in it for you?
Look, I know what you're thinking,
and I don't blame you.
I've always thrown out
such a jazzy line,
but really, except for Doc and yourself
José's my first non-rat romance.
Not that he's my idea of the
absolute finito.
He's too prim and cautious
to be my absolute ideal.
Now, if I could choose from anybody
alive, I wouldn't pick José.
Nero, maybe, or Albert Schweitzer.
or Leonard Bernstein.
But I am mad about José.
I honestly think I'd give up
smoking if he asked me.
Come on, darling, let's eat,
It's getting late.
I'm leaving tomorrow and
I haven't even begun to pack.
Didn't want José to think
I'm a girl who loses her key,
so I had 26 of them made.
Wait. I got a better idea.
Kind of a farewell gesture.
Somebody must have tripped the lock.
Ah, crafty devil, that Yunioshi.
Wake up, wake up! The british are coming!
Or, in this case,
the brazilians.
Exactly.
Ooh, I've still got to clean up
all that rice.
Hey, you know...
There she are who did it!
The wanted woman! There!
Groenburger. Narcotics squad.
- What do you mean?
- What's going on?
- Why don't you ask your boss?
- What boss?
Sally Tomato. Ask him. Come on.
Look around for narcotic!
They got plenty narcotic in there.
- What's your name?
- Varjak.
Hold it down over there!
Paul Varjak. V-A-R-J-A-K.
Hey! Get lost!
Get out!
I'm a writer.
W-R-I-T-E-R.
I can't answer all your questions.
One at a time. One, please. Good.
One at a time, please.
Knock it off!
- Now darling why don't you star?
- Did you carry messages
from Tomato in code?
Of course not.
I'd just give Mr. O'Shaughnessy
the weather report.
Simply do not ask me what this is all about.
'Parce que je ne sais pas, mes chers.'
- You did used to visit Tomato?
- Every week. What's wrong with that?
Tomato's part of the narcotics syndicate.
He never mentioned narcotics.
These wretched people keep
persecuting him.
He's a deeply sensitive person,
a darling old man.
- Then, you're innocent.
- Of course, I'm innocent.
- What are you going to do about it?
- What do you mean?
- Well, who's your lawyer?
- I don't know.
Mr. O'Shaughnessy, I guess.
- Mr. O'Shaughnessy!
Hey! Get out of here!
All right, come on! OK, move.
- Aw, shut up!
- Get in there!
- Hello.
- Mr. Paul Varjak?
Yeah.
Ready with Mr. Berman in Hollywood.
Kindly deposit $3.00 for the first
3 minutes.
Hello? Hello?
O.J. Berman here.
Who's calling?
- Mr. Berman, this is Paul Varjak.
- Nice to talk to you, kid.
Varjak. V-A-R-J-A-K.
I'm a friend of Holly's.
We met at a party, in New York.
- Who?
- Paul. Paul Varjak.
V-A-R...
Mr. Berman, this is Fred.
Oh, Fred, baby, huh?
You're calling about the kid, huh?
Everything's under control.
You just relax.
I spoke to my lawyer in New York.
I told him to take care of everything,
send me the bill, keep my name anonymous.
- What?
- I don't want any part of it.
You sound like you're in a tunnel.
It's this executive phone I have.
- What?
- Executive phone!
Thay only got her on 10,000 bail.
My lawyer can get her out at 10 A.M.
I tell you what to do.
You bust into that dump she lives in,
collect all her junk,
go down to the jail, get her out,
take her to a hotel under a phony name.
Try to keep her away from the reporters.
- Will you do that?
- Sure, Mr. Berman.
I can't tell you how much
I appreciate...
Forget it.
I mean, I owe her something.
not that I owe her anything,
if you really want to get right
down to it.
but... she's crazy.
She's a phony.
But she's a real phony.
Know what I mean, kid?
Yeah, I know what you mean.
Thanks, Mr. Berman. Thanks a lot.
Right!
Why don't you behave?
'Quel' night.
I did a little housebreaking
while you were away.
Clayton Hotel. 84th and Madison.
O.J. thinks it would be a good idea
if you stayed out of sight for a while.
I got your stuff here, including cat.
Hope he's all right.
Hi, cat...
Poor no-name slob.
Listen, darling,
did you find that plane ticket?
- Right here. We can cash it in.
- Cash it in? Are you kidding?
- What time is it?
- A little after 10:00.
Good. Idylwild airport, driver.
- Never mind. You can't do that.
- Why not?.
You don't understand.
You're under indictment.
You jump bail, they'll
throw away the key.
Don't be ridiculous, darling.
I'll be married
to the future president of Brazil.
That'll give me diplomatic inmunity,
or something.
I wouldn't be on it.
What is it, darling?
I have a message for you.
Oh, yes, I see.
Did he bring it in person, or was it...
just there, shoved the door?
A cousin.
Hand me my purse, will you, darling?
A girl can't read that sort of thing...
Without her lipstick.
You read it to me, will you, darling?
I don't think I can quite...
bear...
Are you sure you want me?
"My dearest littel girl,"
"I had loved you,
knowing you were not as others,"
"but conceive of my despair"
"upon discovering in such a
brutal and public style"
"how very different you are
from the manner of woman"
"a man of my position could
hope to make his wife."
"I grieve for the disgrace
of your present circumstances,"
"and I do not find it in my heart"
"to add my condemn..."
"to the condemn that surrounds you,"
"so I hope you will find it in your
heart not to condemn me."
"I have my family to protect
and my name and..."
"I'm a coward where these
institutions enter."
"Forget me, beautiful child,"
"and may God be with you."
"José."
Well...
Well, at least he's honest.
It's kind of touching.
Touching! That square-ball jazz.
He says he's a coward.
All right!
So he's not a regular rat,
or even a super-rat.
He's just scared little mouse,
that's all.
But, oh, Golly... gee! Damn!
Well, so much for South America.
I really didn't think
you were cut out to be queen
of the Pampas anyway.
- Clayton Hotel.
- Idylwild.
What?
The plane leaves at 12:00,
and on it I plan to be.
- Holly, you can't.
- 'Et pourquoi pas?'
I'm not hotfooting it after José,
If that's what you think. Oh, no.
As far as I'm concerned, he's the
future president of nowhere.
Only why should I waste a
good plane ticket?
Besides, I've never been to Brazil.
Please, darling, don't sit there
looking at me like that.
I'm going, and that's
all there is to it.
All they want from me are my
services as a State's witness
against Sally.
Nobody has any intention of
prosecuting me.
To begin with, they don't
have a ghost of a chance.
This town's finished for me...
At least for a while.
There are certain shades of limelight
that can wreck a girl's complexion.
They'll have the rope up
at every saloon in the town.
I'll tell you what you do for me
darling.
When you get back to town
call up the New York Times
or whoever you call.
Mail me a list of the 50 richest
men in Brazil... The 50 richest!
Holy, I'm not going to let you do this.
- You're not going to let me?
- Holly, I'm in love with you.
- So what?
- So what? So plenty!
I love you. You belong to me.
No.
People don't belong to people.
Of course they do.
- Nobody's going to put me in a cage.
- I don't wanna put you on a cage.
I want to love you!
- It's the same thing.
- No, it's not! Holly!
I'm not Holly.
I'm not Lula Mae, either.
I don't know who I am!.
I'm like cat here, a no-name slob.
We belong to nobody, and
nobody belongs to us.
We don't even belong to each other.
Stop the cab.
What do you think?
This ought to be the right kind of place
for a tough guy like you...
Garbage cans, rats galore.
Scram! I said take off! Beat it!
Let's go.
Driver...
Pull over here.
You know what's wrong with you,
Miss whoever-you-are?
You're chicken.
You got no guts.
You're afraid to say:
"OK, life's a fact."
People do fall in love.
People do belong to each other,
because that's the only chance
anybody's got for real happiness.
You call yourself a free spirit,
a wild thing.
And you're terrified somebody's
going to stick you in a cage.
Well, baby, you're already
in that cage.
You built it yourself.
And it's not bounded on the west by Tulip,
Texas or on the east by Somaliland.
It's wherever you go.
Because no matter where you run,
you just stand up running into yourself.
Here, I've been carrying this
thing around for months.
I don't want it anymore.
Here, cat!
Cat!
Where's the cat?
I don't know.
Here. Oh, cat!