Sonjusha, you're bitter about
my imprisonment, and ask,
"How is it that some people
may decide the life of others?"
The entire history of civilization is based,
on decisions on the life
other people lead,
which has its roots deep in
material living conditions.
Only a new, painful development
can bring change.
You ask: "What's it all for?"
You can't question life and all its forms.
I don't really know why there
are bluetits in the world,
but their existence is a joy, and
it's a sweet consolation to hear,
their tweets from a short
distance over the wall.
Sonitshka, stay happy
and calm for my sake.
You'll see that it'll all turn out.
Regards to you, Karl.  Hugs, Rosa.
Quick, help me up!
- One of them's Brodna.
- Kaminski and Kozinski, I don't know the other one.
Murderers! Executioners!
Aim!
Fire!
Anna Matschke.
Murderers.
- How long are you going to wait for it, honey?
- I want to see it bloom.
It sleeps at night just like you do.
Tomorrow you'll see a flower, Rosa.
Blindfold off.
It was a mistake, madame.
Which doesn't mean that you
won't be shot one day.
Sit down.
- Have you got anything to tell me today?
- No.
Why not?
For the same reason as before.
I don't know anything.
There's one thing you know.
Your name isn't Anna Matschke.
Prussian authorities were very helpful.
You seem to be of the same
value to the Tsar authorities.
Luxemburg is an important name in
the movement of German Socialism,
and international socialism.
She incites passion to move
from words to actions,
in other words, to annul
the existing social order,
by way of revolution, whatever the means.
Good work, eh?
Now we don't need to find
out the name of the man,
who was arrested at the same time with you.
My name's Anna Matschke now.
Tell your comrades who I am.
We use agitation, not weapons.
- What does Leo say?
- Weapons are intended only for defense.
- We must protect our own.
- Agitation is of course important.
It's dangerous to shake up the
government with group appearances.
Tsarist administration discarded Socialist agitation.
We're not throwing bombs
or wounding the police.
Agitation will pave the way to a
general strike and street revolt,
which will extend the revolutionary
turmoil to the countryside, villages ...
- You're forbidden from coming here.
- You can't keep me out, Leo.
I'm a party member of the council, too.
You're more useful in
Berlin than in Poland.
I was, as long as you were
sending information regularly.
Lately, I've had to beg downright.
- Now I get it from the top myself.
- I don't want you to stay.
What use am I in Berlin, when
there's a revolution in Russia?
You can't leave me out of an
important historic moment.
I'm no longer that student
who you can boss around.
Give me a hug, I've missed you.
Not: "the so-called reasonable
people consider socialism,"
"the product of a sick imagination,"
but: "the so-called sensible people
maintain socialism as an illusion. "
- That's too dry.
- Comprehensibility is the main thing.
You spoil everything with your fussiness.
And stop creeping around my back
all the time. It makes me nervous!
Once again the contents suffer
because of your temperament.
- I'm the one who writes the article.
- It goes to press in only one week.
What is needed are dialectics and a
groundbreaking idea. Do you understand?
Groundbreaking ideas require time
to grow. That's the dialectic.
Time will tell who understands more
about it, even if it's a monkey.
Your answer is better
than your article.
"What we need ..."
Are you the author?
Among other things it's about
the freedom of the press.
The right of everyone to express their
views in speech and in writing.
Everyone can have an opinion,
but not a printing press.
That's why we came to you.
In the end, I'd prefer to
publish my own opinions.
Anton. Prepare this.
Open up! Police!
It seems that you don't know
who you have living here.
Did you publish this?
This is a mistake, we're German journalists.
Names?
- Anna Matschke and Otto Engelmann.
- Come with us.
Wait outside, we have to get changed.
Hurry up!
I don't want the family to
blow this out of proportion.
My imprisonment doesn't mean
you have to take care of me.
Not a single petition of amnesty or
any help from the German consul.
Those gentleman can wait until I
ask for protection and rights myself.
More preferably I'd like
to get solitary confinement,
I must convey to Germany
what I've heard and seen.
They could court-martial you!
If you keep speaking
German, this visit is over.
Those months in Warsaw have
been the best in my life.
I'm worried about you, my sister.
We live in times of violent
change, all ready to collapse.
It's absurd to sit in jail for
something that might not happen.
It only seems that way to you!
We need patience, Josef. And good spirits.
Your time's up.
I'll come again.
Your freedom.
I was probably only let out
because of my bad health.
Have you heard about Leo?
The German Press revealed him.
He was prosecuted.
The charge read:
"Company of armed insurgency overturned
against the monarchistic administration,"
"prescribed in the Russian constitution. "
The same prosecution is expected for
you, too, if you don't leave quickly.
- Will you say goodnight, Aunt Rosa?
- Of course I will.
- Are you staying with us now?
- I need to return to Berlin.
Why?
I work in the German Socialist Party.
It's the largest and strongest
labour movement in Europe.
Are you coming back?
I don't know.  I'll write to you a lot.
- Will you put flowers inside?
- Lots of flowers.
Sing something.
Valleys, the valleys.
The valley of a small creek.
Why do not you love me?
Was I not nice?
Valleys, the valleys.
The valley of a small meadow.
Why do not you love me?
Am I just a toy ...
Dziodziu, you kept your promise!
- Take me in your arms.
- You're too heavy, Rosa.
Please, come on.
Just for a minute. You know I like it.
So you're going to
be a terrorist, huh?
I want you to love me,
without fear of confession,
that you humiliate yourself with.
You want to hear that you're the most
beautiful and the smartest woman I know.
I am the best! I am a better human
being, so I submit to you.
I wish that we would start living
together as man and wife.
We've lived together for a long time, Rosa.
I mean in our own apartment,
our own furniture, a library.
We can work in peace
together, take walks.
We can go to the opera sometimes,
have a trip in the country once a year.
Good evening, August.
This is Leo Tyszka. August
Bebel and his wife.
- Nice to meet you. Do you speak German?
- Not very well, a little.
We'll meet again later.
- Well, what a wonderful time.
- You wanted to dance.
It's the best way to make acquaintances
without any formalities.
Leo Tyszka, a friend from Poland.
Hans and Luise Kautsky.
- Nice to meet you.
- It's my pleasure.
Luise is my best friend and we
almost never talk about politics.
- What about you?
- It's sometimes on my mind.
- Where's Carolus Magnus?
- Over there. He doesn't dance.
Leo Tyszka, teacher
and master from Poland.
Karl Kautsky, my teacher in Germany.
Ignaz Auer.
- Have you come directly from Poland?
- No, Zürich.
You emigrated?
- Will you stay long in Berlin?
- I don't know yet.
So you're a member of the Polish Socialist Party.
Yes, I'm the founder.
The same man who had a
dispute with Plekhanov?
Interesting.  Can I ask you
a couple of questions?
- Clara, how nice to see you.
- Good evening, Rosa!
Let me introduce my sons.
Maxim and Kostja.
I didn't know that your
children were so grown up.
Visit Stuttgart sometimes.
- We'll certainly get along well.
- Of course.
- May I?
- I don't want to dance with you, Comrade Bernstein.
We're not in the party now. A
celebration is a time for enjoyment.
I can't have fun with you today
or have any connection tomorrow.
It's a wonderful party!
Rosa gave him the brush-off.
Bernstein has something
to complain about again.
He mixes up humour and
opportunism. His nature.
- When will you expel me too?
- I don't expel anyone, I go my own way.
Come on Leo, let's dance!
- What impression did you get of Karl?
- He doesn't know Poland, at least.
He's let me write about it until now.
You should pull a few
strings with each of them.
That method works in a Polish puppet show,
but not the majority of the party!
Happily, proudly and confidently,
the class-conscious proletariat
moves into the 20th century.
One century has gone, I hope the
future century is one of fulfilment.
Progress has been magnificent,
and even better, it's continuing!
I've had a bad few days, therefore
I'm unhappy, therefore I'm unwell.
Now I promise that I won't
listen to my inner demons.
Of course I'm unhappy sometimes,
because I always see from a distance,
see and hear about what
means life and happiness.
I swear while I'm here I'll learn
self-patience and gentleness.
- Luise!
- Rosa!
Erna is even prettier than before.
Here, this is for you, and
this is for the children.
- Let me see you.
- I'll take off the apron, you hate it.
You don't know how much I've
missed that apron, leave it on.
I would've returned to Berlin
earlier, with a passion,
but I was afraid I'd get taken again
at Germany's border to the castle.
Oh, Luise, how I've missed this.
How are the children?
Bendl has been asking about you
and Karl wants to draw with you.
And Leo? What's happened?
He was sentenced to
several years of hard labour.
- Without precautions the same would've happened to you.
- What precautions?
What precautions, Luise? Tell the truth.
- I thought you knew. Bebel ordered it.
- Ordered what?
Your brother spoke about your condition and
that you'd be released against collateral.
For god's sake, Rosa, it was the only
way to get you out of there.
Against my specific will!
I don't want to be indebted
to the party leadership!
- Siberia would have killed you.
- How I hate all this patronizing!
As my friend you should have stopped it.
You don't know me at all.
You didn't do wrong, Lulu.
The most important thing is
that we're together again.
And that I can put a little
life into this complacent place.
This careful reticence. You have
to force yourself to read it.
Instructive, dry.  How
laboured you've become.
- Like there's no blood in your veins.
- Not like Russians.
What did the comrades
say about my article?
For some, parliament is a place that's more
important than strikes and street battles.
Trade Union Leader Legienin believes
that strikes are the worst threat.
And others with words like him
press the party more and more.
Russia's trade union movement
is a child of the revolution.
Before the revolution there wasn't a
trace of professional organization.
You have to believe that it grows
from peaceful conditions.
- I don't think so, Rosa.
- I wrote a booklet about it in Russia.
In prison? How'd you manage that?
There are courageous people
in the Tsar's jails, too.
They smuggled articles to you.
- How much space do I get?
- As much as a return to discipline allows.
Now I present to you
Dr Rosa Luxemburg!
Directly from Warsaw, where
she has been risking her life,
working for the Russian revolution.
Comrades!
I've just been introduced as
a martyr of Russia's revolution.
I'd like to start off on a note of protest.
You probably have a completely
wrong picture of the revolution.
Russian right-wing press presents
abroad a huge sea of blood,
and immense human suffering.
That's a vision of the bourgeoisie,
not the proletariat class.
The people of Russia have
yielded for centuries.
Russia has lived for centuries
in the yoke of monarchy.
Has anyone ever asked,
how many thousands have
died of starvation or scurvy?
How many thousand proletarians have
fallen in work, on the battlefield?
How many infants have
died of malnutrition,
before the fulfilment of
their first year of life?
These countless victims,
compared to this pain,
of the present suffering is trivial.
Before the nation survived and suffered
with no hope of anything better,
but now it knows for what
it falls, suffers and fights.
Everyone knows they are participating
in the freeing of their people,
for the sake of their
children and grandchildren.
Could I trouble you a moment,
it's a personal matter.
I should decide whether or
not to get married now.
Is marriage a thing of the past,
a trifling thing or what?
- That depends on you.
- I've studied the matter.
If I were you, I'd take the simple approach.
Thanks for the advice. My girlfriend
expects a child, she's also a comrade.
We didn't know whether marriage
was a bourgeoise conceit or not.
- Thank you very much, Doctor.
- I wish you all the best.
If you were pregnant, I would've
liked your speech even more.
You need to decide if you want to
be a mother or a revolutionary.
- Both.
- Impossible.
Why?
- A baby will make you timid.
- You don't love me.
Your mission is to bring ideas into
the world. Those are your children.
- Will you come again tomorrow?
- As often as you want.  Good night.
Your health, Rosa dear.
To your return.
To the revolution.
Oh, dear Auer.
We'll be stubborn mules if we don't take
a lesson from the Russian revolution.
- Before you said that Russia was learning from us.
- And now I don't say that.
The East is now the heart of revolution.
History is progressing in leaps and bounds.
That's too big a leap.  Russia
can't be compared to Germany.
Every step forward in
parliamentarism is a leap.
I know that a revolution isn't something
you can just take command of.
It's about what Socialists can do:
knowingly participate in historical development.
You see? Rosa's come back from
Russia as a radical extremist.
When the revolution comes to Germany
she'll be on the left, and I'll be on the right.
But we'll hang them, they
won't ruin our good times.
You don't know yet who hangs who.
August, I love you all.
I'd like to say a few words
about Bebel's speech.
I'm just not sure I
understood him correctly,
because he sat on the left and
talked about too much about the right.
He talked about what Germany
could do and what should happen,
if we have a war with Russia
because of Prussian intervention.
I don't know if I understood correctly,
but I think he meant to say,
that if we are on the brink of
war, we can't do a thing about it.
Nonsense!
I dare not ever doubt it,
the party leadership maintains.
As a pious member of the Party
I will state after the management:
Credo quia absurdum!
"I believe, because it is absurd."
That interpretation of Bebel's speech
would be embarrassing for our French friends.
You see, local comrades say:
rather an uprising than a war!
Men of the French proletariat
make themselves heard! I hope,
that we also have the courage to
say: not a war against our will!
In connection with the war a
general strike has been considered.
The International Conference on
The Brussels Congress of 1868,
refers to the practical
measures to prevent war.
Namely, that society really can't operate,
if production is stopped for some time.
That the working classes, which are
almost exclusively recruited into war,
just need to suspend their work,
in order to interrupt the monarchical governments
which only advocate their own interests.
Bebel said:
"Do you think the party council is
able to carry out a general strike? "
"No! The masses must put
pressure on the party council."
Otherwise, if a party council
doesn't understand its role,
it will be pushed!
I ask you, therefore, to
vote for Kautsky's proposal.
- I think that hat fits you better.
- No, it suits you.
- There isn't one for August.
- He seems to be angry with me.
- Because of the Mannheim speech?
- He offered money but I didn't care.
You and your Polish friends need it.
- There's other things.
- How so?
- You'd do exactly the same, as always.
- I don't know. I haven't been short of money.
Let's get it written.
- Dearest August.
- No, 'Dear August'.
Too common. Dear Party Council,
my beloved August.
- We need to get a grip.
- Yes, while there's still time.
I can only get this boisterous
with another German.
- To your freedom in Weimar.
- To life.
I often went rowing with Leo
when I was studying in Zurich.
"We'll stay far from the Germans,"
I wrote to him from Berlin.
"There are no conditions for
happiness for any pair in the world."
May god grant me to keep him.
I've done a lot of work.
I don't always wish for success.
German Marxism is a gouty
old man who is afraid of fresh air.
- Have you buried your ridiculous idealism?
- Not at all.
I'm just not a conscientious donkey
any more, who toils for others.
At least you show that temperament
alone is not enough.
Yes, and so can a monkey.
- Don't you want to talk about your travels?
- We have work, Rosa.
Yes, yes, business.
But I'd like to know.
Well, do I know the people
who you were hiding with?
- Were they friends?
- Yes.
- Was there a woman there?
- Rosa, don't go into this.
Was she beautiful?
It's certainly more enjoyable
to hide with a beautiful comrade.
Did you sleep with her?
- No.
- Swear.
Rosa, forget about it.
I just want to know the truth.
Answer me, Dziodziu.
- You loved her.
- I wouldn't have come back to Berlin if I did.
- You slept with her but didn't love her?
- Yes.
Why did you lie then ...
How can someone be with
another without loving them!
- You can't compare it to us.
- Why not?
There are higher things.
- So that's why we work together?
- One of the reasons why.
- Did you work with her?
- Of course, she was in the party.
So you loved her, you only know
how to love someone through work.
If it calms you down or makes you
feel better ... then I loved her!
- No, it doesn't calm me down!
- We're not talking about this any more.
I want you to leave.
What should I do?
I don't want to live with you any more.
I'm serious, Leo.
Just because of some trifle?
Have you lost your reason?
If you love someone, it's not a trifle.
Loving for better or worse.
I only came to Berlin because of you.
You came to Berlin because you
were forced to leave Poland.
- I couldn't work underground.
- So, you operate more efficiently here.
And you'd pass over any
woman for your work.
- Do you need anything else, Doctor?
- No, you can take the evening off.
- Thank you, Doctor.
- Forget the 'Doctor' business.
When is Dr Kristallowitsch coming?
He isn't coming here again, Gertrud.
Good night.
You overestimate my maturity.
My inner balance and fortune fall,
with even the slightest shadow blow.
I suffer unspeakably.
It's characteristic of me
to be dumbfounded.
Finally! We'd feared the worst.
We were too close to the
soldiers' firing exercises.
They would have aimed more carefully
if they'd known you were standing there.
Indeed they may have been hit.
We should have made a memorial.
- Two large women have left us.
- While remaining forever unforgettable.
Here lie two noble, brave women,
whose struggle for progress, peace and justice,
will always be our model.
Or here rest the last two men
of the German social democracy.
We've achieved more than many
other countries' political parties.
We have influence.  We're not
working underground any more.
We can have an effect officially.
Within certain limits, of course,
but the number of votes has
increased in all the elections so far.
Yes, Rosa knows this.
Which is therefore more to lose!
Rosa doesn't take it into account.
What you have achieved?
That the unions decide and
the masses aren't asked.
The masses have a voice.
They've had enough parliamentarism.
The party must be ahead of
events, not dragged behind.
A general strike can't be declared
before it's necessary.
We'll use that method as
soon as the situation is ripe.
At the moment, impatience
would be a loss, not a victory.
You mess up moderation at your convenience.
You have composure, but others are divided.
For example, the women's franchise.
- Why does the party support it only formally?
- That's not the issue here.
Clara's absolutely right.
I've always asked you to take
care of more women's issues.
Such an intelligent and argumentative
woman should devote herself to her sex.
- And leave the big things for men.
- Go ahead, if they're capable of it.
- Rosa isn't argumentative, just courageous.
- We don't deny it.
Courage itself is not a virtue.
Courage is needed at the right time.
It will be found, I promise you, Rosa.
And I promise to remind
you of your promise, August.
I've given you permission to
work here, but not on Sunday.
- I want to talk to you about us.
- We are no longer talking.
"My only Dziodziu.  Our lives are
better than those of others,
because I know that our souls
are richer than most people."
Burn them, they are no longer relevant.
"Precious one. How I need
you, we need each other.
There is not such a task in life
as that of a single pair,
to make a human being of each other.
It brings upon itself all the conditions of happiness."
Do you remember what you wrote back?
Pages of trade reports
on the work of the party.
Not a shred of normal life.
I had no lack of your abysmal scribbles.
When did we allegedly live?
We just talked about it.
- What about Zürich?
- That was a long time ago.
What about Warsaw?
- Warsaw!
- Don't shout, Kostja's asleep.
Who's Kostja?
Kostja Zetkin. Clara's son's here in Berlin.
Clara asked him.
Good day.
- Has that pup fallen in love with you?
- None of your business.
I don't think Clara will be
very happy about that.
- I'll kill you, and him too.
- You're not that childish.
Do you want me to grovel
on the floor in front of you?
I just want you to leave me alone.
Please.
You won't get that from me.
I won't ever leave you alone.
Battling for the party doesn't
suit your character.
It's a disservice that's a
constant of all human beings.
You should stay in a spiritual job.
Philosophy, economics, history.
Or start writing. I'm sure
you know how to write well.
Listen, a great tit.
You haven't yet experienced
how animals help people.
- When are you going to London?
- In three days.
- Can't you skive off this time?
- Oh, Bubu.
Party affairs aren't like schooldays.
- Will Leo Jogicheskin be there?
- Of course.
All the Russian and Polish Social Democrats.
What if he threatens you again?
I've gotten a small pistol.
Listen.
Let me explain to you ...
- Is there anything you can't explain?
- No.
Why do you love such an ungainly duck?
You find it hard to accept our friendship.
- He tried to hide it from me.
- I asked him to.
Why?
I thought it would upset you.
If I were your friend I would've
earned your confidence.
You know how hard it is to
talk about private affairs.
Love isn't a private affair,
it applies to me too.
I'd be the worse off if
Kostja chose between us.
My son must be happy that
he met a woman like you.
- Why not publish my article?
- For some time,
I've clearly expressed that
publication would be a mistake.
Particularly now, when elections
are around the corner.
We mustn't spoil the chances of
rising to be the strongest party.
We can improve them!
Strengthen the party in battle.
My opinion is that groups
are not ripe for revolution.
Karl, it's not even an
issue of revolution now,
but that of a strong mass movement
from the Democratic Republic.
And you just close up,
let the groups decide.
Our task is to present
reasons for and against!
Your article would require my
dissenting opinion as a balance.
The situation's the same as in Russia in 1905.
Demonstrations in Berlin
grow, mines go on strike.
The party shuffles behind events
and doesn't go ahead of them.
- The party's majority does not support you.
- You mean the party on the Council.
I imagined that we agreed on key issues.
Now it seems that your
Marxism just gives up on you,
when a revolutionary situation arises.
- After another 20 years you'll think the same.
- I don't ever intend to think like you.
Karl himself is accused of
extremes now.
That's not a reason to back off.
Right now, when the German monarchy
falters for the first time,
and the Democratic Republic
would really be possible.
What are you going to do?
If the Party Council silences me
I'll turn directly to the groups.
I'll talk in a dozen towns, I'll
get 50,000-100,000 listeners.
Hopefully my voice will hold out.
Oh, Luise.
Your husband's cowardly. He
doesn't deserve a wife like you.
He's not so bad.  Put yourself
in his shoes, for once.
If you want to see me,
you'll have to visit me.
- I won't stay in this house now.
- That's being hard on me.
It's hard on me too.
This noise is a narcotic to my sick heart.
It's probably my only medicine.
I would preferably live only with you, Mimi.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Recently, many of us have been reminded,
that we have 40 years of peace behind us.
It was concluded that we are
heading towards the times,
when peaceful development would be possible.
This illusion of growing peace has evaporated.
Those who remembered
the 40 years of peace,
forgot about the wars that
have taken place outside Europe,
and in which Europe was involved!
The classes which support the threat of war,
are reponsible for the buildup of
madness on borders and seas,
under the guise of peace-keeping!
And the liberal parties also,
who have renounced all
suppression of militarism!
It is said that fighting
is part of human nature.
We can't equip ourselves without
hurrying from the danger of our neighbours.
We disagree. People can,
and they must live in peace!
The dominant think they have
the right to make decisions,
while ignoring public opinion
of such vital issues.
I ask you:
Can we allow a war we don't want,
to be instigated without impunity?
If we are required to raise
a weapon of murder,
against our French brothers,
or any other, we will shout:
We do not agree!
My stomach hurts.
It is surprising the accused has in recent years
known how to keep making
inflammatory speeches,
without being guilty of
committing a crime.
It is a sign of a rare intelligence.
She is known for her sharp words.
It isn't for nothing that she
is called "Red Rosa".
The submission of the accused to punishment,
corresponds to her role in the past,
and a very hostile state of mind.
I will come to the essence of the charge.
The prosecution concludes as follows.
Because I agitate against militarism
and want to prevent a war,
I obviously did not know a better
way than to say to the soldiers:
When you are told to shoot, don't shoot.
Is not that right, honoured council?
What superior logic in the
convincing conclusion.
Let me say, however, that
this logic is the result of,
the prosecutor, not perceptions
of social democracy.
We don't think,
that the outbreak of war
and the final result,
will be solved by the army, superior
orders, and blind obedience,
but the solution is integrated
deeply within the people.
If the vast majority of the
people reaches the belief,
and awareness of the campaign that
the Social Democrats have made,
if the majority reaches the belief,
that wars are deeply immoral and base,
an impossible phenomenon,
then people will react against it.
- Thank you, Paul.
- For what?
- For coming here with me so I'm not alone.
- Look around, you're not.
I didn't mean that.
People love you.  Even the
right-wing press respects you.
- Respect for "Red Rosa"?
- They call Bebel "The Emperor's Contender"!
In front of you stands a major criminal
proclaimed an outlaw by the state,
a refugee from the prosecutor,
a condemned woman.
I wouldn't switch with the prosecution
for what is in their homeland.
I have a bigger and dearer homeland.
What else but the Fatherland, and
crowds of working men and women?
Remember what Wallenstein says
in Schiller's play on that night,
when he examines the stars,
to interpret the future course of events.
"Day is near, and Mars is dominated by the moment."
That's still suitable today.
Mars, the god of bloody war,
still dominates the moment.
Still the ones who fall back on
weapons of murder have the power.
Still wars are prepared, still
parliaments are subjected.
Still proposals for military expenditure
are made, but Wallenstein said:
The day is near. Our day.
So approaches the day
when we will stand up.
We will not carry out the image
of massacre in the prosecution's timid eyes.
No, with our jurisdiction we
can create a social order,
which is worthy of the human race.
Society in which neither exploitation
nor genocide is known.
Society, which implements the ideas,
of the oldest relgious founders
and ideals of major philosophers!
In order to make that day
dawn as soon as possible,
we shall be subjected to
forces to the extreme,
in defiance of all the prosecutors,
all military power.
Dear Lulu. I have become
a vulnerable human being.
I tremble from every
shadow that touches me.
Do you know what thought
persecutes and scares me?
I imagine that once again I
must step into a crowded hall.
The glaring lights, the noise of the crowd.
The roar of applause when I
make my way to the podium.
And it seems to me that I
could escape from this place.
Liebknecht and Levi are here.
Your attorney's very fond of
you. Do you like him?
When will you learn to keep our
work and my private life separate?
You didn't want to keep
them separate before.
Before I thought we needed each other
in order to become good human beings.
Is that what's become
of us?  Both alone?
- Karl, it's a pleasure to have you as an ally.
- The pleasure's all mine.
Hello, Paul.
- Are you feeling better?
- Much better. How wonderful...Gertrude!
Good day.
Mathilde Jacob, I'm a secretary.
Have you read the "Forward" paper?
It borrows from the right-wing press.
"The behaviour of this
presumptuous woman must stop".
- The authorities prick up their ears.
- The appeal is pending.
Rosa's not healthy, and she's
needed outside of prison.
Would you get the tea, Leo?
Is it ready?
Come and sit, Mathilde.
Is it possible that the social democrats would
vote against the government if war breaks out?
Only if they put pressure on the
representatives in public so strongly,
that they no longer dare act
against the will of the people.
I've prepared a text which
I'd like to discuss with you.
What is the proletariat?
It is a group of people and community,
who loves peace and hates war.
A number of frenzied patriots however,
revels in the massacre of war.
But when your own head
bears the risk of conflict,
when wars devour bourgeoisie
and workers alike,
they will remember their allies
and try to quell the storm.
However, the terrain of these
gentlemen has been mined.
In the face of the initial enthusiasm,
and the initial euphoria of fighting,
they manage to sweep the
masses along with them.
But when typhoid decides
to do the work of grenades,
when death and misery strike,
so men of reason,
in Germany, France, Russia and Italy,
will demand their leaders' accountability
for the number of bodies.
And released from its shackles,
the revolution will answer them:
"Go and ask for forgiveness
from god and man. "
It is my pleasure to welcome a
brave woman, Rosa Luxemburg,
whose thoughts shine in the
hearts of the German proletariat.
- Over to you, madame.
- I can't.
- You would have to remain silent.
- Leo, you weren't there.
If only you had seen. The
atmosphere in that hall.
The workers shouted out that
they dare not start a war,
- And that we have the Socialist International.
- That's true.
I'm afraid of the death of the Socialist
National and the victory of nationalism.
War's going to come.
The majority of socialists will march along.
I know it.
Was I supposed to pretend
to believe in the future?
No. You're right.
Dziodziu ...
I've never been so
desperate in my life.
They all voted in favour. War
loans have been approved.
- What about the minority?
- It bent to the party line.
Haase talked to the group.
"In a time of distress the love of one's country
shouldn't be left to the responsibility of the right."
"The workers wouldn't understand it."
If August were here this
never would've happened.
I was shouted down as unpatriotic.
- What about Kautsky?
- Two of his sons have been called into service.
Right now everyone's going to
have to shoulder their own cross.
We'll show that the Socialists also
know how to die for the Fatherland.
If brigands are attacking my house,
I wouldn't speculate on
humanity, but shoot.
And the same to the Socialist International, huh?
The workers were in favour of
war. What else could we do?
Abstentions would've made
us enemies of the fatherland.
It wouldn't be good for
the future of the party.
- I've got to go.
- I'll see you this evening, Karl.
Don't go inside.  It's all
been for nothing, Sonja.
- Let's go home.
- Karl probably needs me now.
- We'll never see each other again, Rosa.
- What are you talking about, Kostja?
War won't last that long, you'll see.
When hunger comes, the mind changes.
Everything that was alive in
in the hearts of young people,
sinks into the dirty swamp of nationalism.
They're all sacrificed.
There's no party for us anymore,
Rosa. We ought to resign.
Oh, Clara. Do you intend to
separate from humankind too?
- I've thought of that too.
- And me.
But who'll do the work if we don't?
First, set up Mehring with the magazine.
Liebknecht will try to organise meetings.
I'll send telegrams to party
agents in the opposition.
Your only answer will be
pretexts and cowardly denial.
They've spoiled the joy
of Christmas for us, too.
This is for you, yes, here you are.
And this is for me. For you? No.
Oh, Mimi.
A book should be written
about these events,
which would affect the whole of
humanity like the blow of a club.
Our time's running out, Mimi.
Quickly, if you may.
Ask Miss Jacob to notify
the lawyer immediately.
Don't forget Mimi. She
has her favourite chair.
Don't worry Mimi, I'm going to write
an anti-war treatise in the castle.
And clear accounts with
those accursed cowards.
- Take them off.
- I've already been inspected today.
It's best to be sure.
Faster than that.
Keep going.
And the rest.
Turn around and bend over.
Cell 45.
You'll get your belongings tomorrow.
- What about my nightgown?
- Tomorrow.
- I could at least have a book.
- The censors have to look at them first.
House, houses.
- What 's smoke ...
- Smoke.
Here are Ala and Ola.
Ala stands and Ola stands.
You're doing really well, Nana.
Ola's doll stands.
What are you doing here? You
should be back at work in the kitchen.
- How are you?
- Reading's more important than potatoes.
- You're just indulging Nana.
- I want to be a teacher.
- Are you on your feet?
- Not today. Could you take care of my letters?
So many! Wouldn't it be better
for them to be answered verbally?
It's fun when they come, but
letters must still be answered.
Karl! How did you get here?
- Through the integrity of lawyers and MPs.
- Sit down.
I brought a nightshirt,
comb, soap, eau de Cologne.
The little things of life. Sonja
got them, regards from everyone.
Mathilde's taking care of Mimi, Leo's taking
care of the organization, I'm campaigning.
However, I'll be in the military
service in France for a while.
- What about integrity?
- It's difficult.
There are dates when I have leave.
- There are less and less of us.
- Leo's handling it.
I'm worried about him, he can't get
any food coupons without a passport.
- Mathilde can help him.
- Leo pretends he doesn't need help.
- You have to trick him.
- Mathilde can manage it.
You need this for the article.
Sonja will come next time.
Any message for Leo?
- How did you ...
- I've had a lot of time to practice.
- Do you have any name in mind for the group?
- Spartacus.
Is that a slave in history
or a woman who's resisted?
Ask Clara.  She invents someone
in case of emergency.
Five more minutes.
- Have you heard anything about Clara?
- We got some bad news.
The house is guarded, the phone
is monitored, mail is opened.
Comrades in the village go into war.
Even the old and unfit for service.
- Was I supposed to hide that from you?
- No!
I hate it that I'm shielded away.
I am of course sick, I shake all over.
Sometimes I feel
I'm not a real person,
but a bird or an animal in
unsuccessful human guise.
Deep inside, I'm more at home among the
bumblebees in a garden or a meadow,
than in a party conference.
I can tell you this. You do not immediately
smell the betrayal of socialism.
But I hope to die in my rightful place,
fighting on the street or in prison.
However, my innermost self belongs
more to fieldmice than comrades.
Are you really Polish?
Yes.
Why are you in Germany,
then? Or am I too curious?
I thought Germany's social democracy
was a strong international force.
- You don't think that any more?
- Have you heard the phrase,
- "Proletarians of all countries, unite"?
- Yes.
Now it reads: "Join together in peace,"
"and cut each others throats in war."
That doesn't make sense.
- What's your name?
- Elisabeth.
Could you send a letter for me?
- For you, I'd do it.
- Thank you.
Lulu!
Oh, how funny!
Don't fret, Lulu. I know that
your mind is full of sorrows,
but after all, it's only sighing over all that
goes wrong in the history of the world.
You were right. The Socialists have failed miserably.
Ebert and Scheidemann pushed through war loans.
But we can't just sink down
to moan about the present.
People hardly have any food. You
might not be quite up to date.
It's irrational to rage against
the whole of humanity.
My garden.
The only action I've taken in
prison is making this garden.
See how the violet seeds are doing.
I like to sit there, too.
Lulu. It seems to me
that this whole madhouse,
this moral mire in which we now crawl,
can in an instant, as if by magic,
be changed into something great.
Dear friend, don't live in this
country like a trodden frog.
I came to cheer you up and
you're the one doing it.
Embracing is forbidden. Your hour is up.
Filthy spy!
What else can you expect from that?
Elisabeth!
- Have you read the book to the end?
- I cried three times over.
It's always nice to read something.
- Could you lend me something else?
- Sure.
How about Tolstoy. Have you heard of him?
The greatest of the Russian
writers. What can I give you...
You'll like this.
Everything from Russia
is prohibited now.
You shouldn't care about such nonsense.
Anna Karenina.
It's painful to enjoy such beauty alone.
I'd like to shout over the wall: please
note today is certainly a wonderful day.
Do not forget it. In the middle of your hurry,
lift up your heads, look
up at the silver clouds.
Feel the air, which the flowers in
the linden trees breathe passionately,
behold the days of luxury and beauty,
because today will never return.
It was given to you like a
rose that has come full bloom,
and expects you to pick it
and press it to your lips.
There's not enough room for books here.
No light for plants.
Books can be stored
in the adjacent cell.
- How do I get them from there?
- Knock on the door.
Or make a request to the commandant.
Mail.
Thank you.
It's unbelievable. First Mimi died, and now ...
Don't, Luise.
I can't ...
- If nobody's talking, the visit will be suspended.
- No, please don't.
Should I tell you something?
All kinds of things happen to me,
but when something happens to
someone else, I lose all my strength.
Sonitshka, I had a
painful experience here.
One day, a cart loaded with
sacks drove into the courtyard.
The load was so big that the
oxen couldn't get through the gate.
A soldier, the brute, was beating them,
until one began to bleed.
After unloading, the animals stood silent, exhausted.
There was the expression of a
child with eyes ready to cry.
I stood near the animal
and it looked at me.
Tears flowed from my eyes.
They were its tears.
When I saw its silent pain
it reverberated in me,
as if in front of your beloved brother.
We both stand here in silence.
It's a common pain, helplessness, yearning.
Sonitshka dear, stay calm and happy.
Life must be accepted as it is.
Without being discouraged I probably
smile bravely. In spite of everything.
There's a visitor from Berlin,
Mrs Sonja Liebknecht.
Sonitshka.
I know you suffer from the
fact that the years roll on,
without any room to live.
But still we live on and
experience it all.
Sometimes I think that the
war will go on forever,
and you and Karl will never be free.
I want you to drown
in the ectasy of life.
I'll defend your right
to do so, unwaveringly.
First, we'll see the old
world sink little by little.
Maybe it'll all sink away forever.
I think about the story of the heroic mole.
It digs and digs until its
whole reality is hollow.
Look.
A country mole succeeds in reaching
the light even in a prison yard.
Germany is a parliamentary
democracy beginning from today.
The Social Democrats have
been voted into the government.
The new government has presented
a Peace and Ceasefire request,
to the American president.
This means a defeat and surrender for Germany.
You can read about it in
the papers, there's one each.
Has your wish come true now, Dr Luxemburg?
Your party's in power.  That's what
you've been waiting for, for 20 years.
I'm afraid of Ebert abusing his power,
and deceiving the workers again.
- Hello.
- Hello, Director.
Political prisoners were pardoned on October 12th.
I should've been released three weeks ago.
Amnesty only applies to prisoners
who've been convicted.
You're in preventative detention.
The government's afraid of me
speaking publicly against the war.
The war's over.  What does the
government need to be protected from?
- Revolution.
- Liebknecht was released two weeks ago.
One radical is enough for them.
I can't exempt you
until I get a warrant.
Can I ask one thing?
Do you love or hate Germans?
Germans are like children
who don't know freedom.
Director, Breslau is far from
the centre of operations,
When an army demobs, trains and
phone lines get overloaded.
Couldn't you contact Berlin
and ask them about me?
You've been a model prisoner.
You haven't created any disturbances.
How did you get your name "Bloody Rosa"?
Frankly, your patience has surprised me.
I've kept the forces inside me
alive, waiting for this moment.
To make sure I'm returned to my rights.
Freedom is my right!
Rosa!
You've taken care of me
so dearly for all these years.
- God, what misery.
- You don't seem that healthy.
Don't talk about me, I think there's
been enough talk about that already.
- We can't go to your house yet.
- Why not?
- I've been waiting to get home.
- You've got to be careful.
We've gotten old.
You can't see your wrinkles, Leo.
Breslau was your ninth prison.
That's one score I've beaten you on.
Well, what's to be done?
We've gotten the weight of
requisitioning from Leon's proposal.
- Like Warsaw in 1906?
- Like that.
The paper's called "Red Flag".
The first issue came yesterday.
You manage the delivery.
Leo organises it, but it's
still at your disposal.
I'll go to the people on the
street, but of course still write.
Can I see today's one?
Will we succeed?
We're not as fast as the
young radicals want.
Don't talk like a grandfather.
You see revolutionaries. Yet
they're just obedient soldiers.
If we'd won the war,
they still would be.
- Isn't their obedience enough?
- You've been gone a while.
Spartacus is not as powerful
as we'd like it to be.
People change, soldiers change.
And Germany changes.
It's wonderful to have a real bed.
I'm sure I'll have a good night's sleep.
In the beginning,  I collected a small,
courageous band of victimised comrades,
and hurled it against the fervour of war.
We were shouted down,
persecuted and imprisoned.
When I said out loud what no-one
else at that time dared to say,
namely that the German political and
military leadership was guilty of war.
I was branded a traitor who called
for the destruction of Germany.
It would have been easier for us,
if we'd remained silent or joined
in with the jingoistic chorus.
When we raised our voice again
to show the German people,
the only path to freedom
and peace lay in disaster,
the same people who had
suppressed the truth, and us,
once again began their old
campaign of lies and slander.
Rage and shout!
We follow the revolution and
the direct path of socialism!
The great task for which we have
prepared so long is now needed.
The revolution is here!
We don't want to make a road to violence,
or bloodshed, as our opponents believe.
We call upon the revolutionary
readiness, the assembly of forces,
to take into our hands the
rebuilding of the world!
Either we sink back into the mire of the past,
or continue to fight for mankind's release
from the curse of slavery!
Long live the world revolution! Spartacus lives!
- You spoke like a preacher.
- But not against my conviction.
I don't think we should cheer
ourselves, but criticise.
Self-criticism doesn't lend wings to the
people. Now we need wings of inspiration!
- You've got to strike while the iron's hot.
- Still, you shouldn't appear too sure.
Remember that the bourgeoisie which has
been wounded is fighting for its life's blood.
- Was my speech so ambiguous?
- It's a bit misleading.
I'll write tomorrow's article on the way.
We'll meet later.
We're at the front of the biggest
task ever set for humanity.
- Where's Karl staying tonight?
- He's visiting colleagues in Neukölln.
I've got to see him! I
need tomorrow's article.
- He'll send it tonight.
- Your blanket, Rosa!
Rosa! Sandwiches!
Tell me why I always go on,
as if I never had the
slightest desire to live.
Don't fool yourself.
If you lived any other way
you wouldn't be any happier.
- Papers.
- Okay, no need to worry.
- What is it?
- Spartacists are fighting in Ullsteinin.
They're being fortified
with the "Forward" magazine.
- Did you know?
- I was afraid of this.
Go through!
- Don't go out there, they're shooting.
- I need to talk to them.
This is not the place for a woman, Doctor.
Suppose that you succeed,
and Berlin is ours.
What happens in East Prussia,
Hamburg, Bavaria, the Ruhr?
- The Bavarians will be roused last.
- We don't have a uniform organization!
It has to be either the whole
of Germany or no-one!
- It wasn't the whole of Russia and they still won.
- This isn't Russia.
- Victory can only be reached with casualties.
- Your life shouldn't be the price!
- This way, you can only lose!
- Karl Liebknecht says otherwise.
Everybody against everybody without
order.  The forces are not ready!
That's theory, Rosa. Reality
has its own dynamics.
You're accelerating it artificially.
There's no revolutionary majority
yet.  We need time, Karl.
It's just a pointless bloodletting,
not a revolution!
- The Proletariat marches, it's a revolution!
- This is nonsense!
The Socialists also understand the reaction.
Little fragments taken from articles!
You always stand aside, you and
Leo, who always know everything!
- We don't stand aside, but we're not fanatics!
- So I'm a fanatic?
You'll have to answer to posterity
if you don't stand by me now!
If we don't submit to your ideas
then we're traitors, eh?
The typesetters are expecting a
leading article, they can fit three columns.
Blood has flowed for four years in genocide.
Now every drop must be carefully protected.
- Why haven't I head anything from Luinen?
- He's probably scared of you.
Before the political differences of
opinion didn't separate us.
Continue.
The unhesitating revolutionary energy
and humanity alone are the real spirit of socialism.
The world must be revolutionised,
but every shed tear wiped away,
is an accusation.
It's a poor human being,
who carelessly mentions such crimes,
that's a miserable coward.
Quick, come here!
That's the second time today.
She asks too much from herself.
You'll have to go somewhere else, my husband's
diabetic and he can't take this strain. I'm sorry.
We could go to Bremen. It's
safe, there's comrades there.
When did you start becoming afraid?
We didn't run away in Warsaw.
Don't get sentimental, Rosa. You're still needed.
What could happen? In the worst
case, a couple of years in the castle.
BEAT YOUR LEADER TO DEATH!
KILL LIEBKNECHT!
You're not packing me off to Berlin.
If Karl's staying here, so am I.
- They won't be looking for you here.
- Neukölln would suit me better.
There's a message for you.
Karl, All is forgiven. R.
We're not beaten yet, Rosa.
We'll endure and we'll win.
If only we're still around
when that happens, Karl.
My article for tomorrow.
The waves hit high.  We are
accustomed to the risk of plunging,
into their crests but our ship runs
steadily and proudly to harbour.
Perhaps we won't be living there when
it reaches, but our programme will.
It guides the world to free
mankind, in spite of everything.
Read the last sentences.
"Order reigns in Berlin." You stupid
henchmen. Your order is built on sand.
Tomorrow the revolution will already
raise itself with a rattle,
and announce with fanfare, to your
horror: I was, I am, I will be.
Could you play a little piano?
I went so long without music.
Is there anything to eat?
Someone's told them the
address. You have to get out.
- Where are you going to go, Bremen or Frankfurt?
- Neukölln.
The paper must go on. We'll show the
comrades we're not going to be silenced.
- May I?
- Please, comrade.
Take care of yourself, my treasure.
And you, Rosa.
- Over there, the old whore!
- And the cavalier!
Spartacists!
Are you Mrs Rosa Luxemburg?
- You should be, according to your picture.
- If you say so.
You'll probably refuse to make a statement.
- Depends what you ask for.
- Your impudence is not acceptable here, Dr Luxemburg.
We are a state authority,
not your crippled allies.
History is proving the opposite.
Aren't you going to lock me up?
- Where are you from?
- Bremen.
- Got any brothers or sisters?
- Yes.
You're not allowed to talk to me.
Come on.
Don't shoot.
Subbed by Badge