BEST ACTRESS - CANNES 1999
Come to my office
I said come to my office!
Did you tell them I’m always late?
- That’s not the issue!
- Yes or no?
I said it was 'cause of the bus
That’s not important
Come to my office.
Why’d you say she said that?
That’s not why you were fired!
Am I a good worker?
Then why fire me?
Because your trial period is over
- Why me, if I’m a good worker?
You’re the only one on a trial basis.
Now change and come to my office
Come on!
Stop it!
Leave or l’ll call the
Calm down!
Open this door!
You have to leave!
You have no right!
I did my job well.
Everyone says so!
l’ll force this door open!
That’s enough now
Let me go!
Shut up
Any mail?
- No.
There’s a fox on the prowl
Don’t leave food out.
Why are you planting all that?
We’re not staying here
What’s this?
It wasn’t me.
I don’t even like that brand
How’d the cork get here?
- I don’t know.
You reek of beer
He brought you booze
so he could fuck you, right?
That’s not true. I’m your mother!
Don’t talk to me that way!
Swear it’s not true
That’s my tub
Leave me alone
- Go dry out.
Where’d you get that?
Someone gave it to me.
- Was it him?
From where I got the clothes.
You’ve been begging
- They gave it to me!
- Why didn’t you say no?
I don’t turn down mending
That’s different!
You mend clothes and I sell them
Throw it out
We’re not beggars
Not this one either
Why?
They’re summer clothes
l’ll take this dress
Nothing else
That’s 450 francs
You need a salesgirl?
- Not right now.
"The Grand Canyon"
Is that your address?
Is that a cafe?
A fairground?
A fairground
I can’t put you down
as unemployed.
- I worked.
Not long enough
Go to window 8.
You may be eligible for welfare
Why won’t you take them?
They’re out of season.
I have dozens from last summer
The whole bunch for 500 francs
- That’s still too much.
Name a price
Four hundred
Three hundred
Three fifty
All right, 350
One waffle, three beers,
and three nonalcoholic beers
Did you take that girl’s place?
Hello.
No problems?
I’m leaving 2,000 in the till
- Okay.
Sir, are you looking
for anyone to sell waffles?
Or anything else?
Not at the moment
Sorry
What did you talk
to the boss about?
You looking for work?
Get me some water
When I used to get that
- I don’t care.
- Let me tell you at least
You tell me every time. I’m not you
Hold the glass for me
It’s not 6:00 yet.
But you’re home
’Cause I got fired,
not so you could go drinking
Give it back!
Give it to me
All you think about
is drinking and fucking
Let me have one
Get out of here
Why do you bring her alcohol?
- Just one drink.
You know she’s trying to stop
- Give it back!
Leave her alone!
Give it back!
You owe me 120 francs!
Go to a whorehouse
if you want to fuck!
My mother’s not a whore!
Leave her alone!
Who told you I lived here?
There’s an opening.
The boss fired someone
Okay, now we add
two quarts of water
Get the measuring cup down there
and set it here
Hold tight here,
and careful with the pressure
A little more
Good
Pour it in
No, always back
where you got it.
Now four sacks of flour
I’ll show you how to carry them
Slide it onto your knee
and grab it like this
Lay it over the edge of the bowl
Pull on the string
and move around the bowl
as you pour it in.
Then back this way
Now I’ll add 200 eggs
Six trays of 20 each.
You get the other sacks of flour
You forgot to stamp my form.
I did?
They said I was entitled to miss work
You can’t fire me.
They’re wrong
You know my baby’s sick
- Not ten times a month!
It’s caught under the wheel
There
Anyone here?
- I’m coming.
Wanna go for a drink?
I’m off at 4:30.
Then see you tomorrow
- See you tomorrow.
Look.
That’s good
You wanna take it to him?
Tell him he can’t turn it off
without telling us first.
Get out
The 500 francs
A receipt
Turn the water on first
Pay and l’ll turn it on
I’m here to pay the rent,
not to get the water back on
I don’t see the difference
- I do.
Brush your hair
Get up
And put your shoes on
Where’s your ID card?
In your box?
I don’t want to go!
Let me go!
Come on
It’s the only way you’ll make it
They’ll take care of you.
I don’t care if I make it!
Come on
I’ll try to get you a sewing machine
when you come back.
What’s a used one cost?
Mom!
lt’s all muddy!
Come in.
How’d you know I lived here?
- I asked the boss.
You can put your cooking stuff there
and there’s water there.
You can plug a heater in there
I don’t think she’s asking much
- How much?
Less than what I pay.
Less than 5,000 francs
There’s a shower over there
Needs a little work.
I could fix it up for you
Could I have those boots?
- What boots?
Down there
You make waffles?
No, it’s just a waffle iron
I’m trying to fix.
Want a beer?
- Just water.
Give me the boots
Did you win that?
Yeah
I was a champion
in floor gymnastics
Well, provincial champion
Wait
You been doing it long?
- Doing what?
Your scam with the waffles
From the start
What did you come
behind the stand to tell me?
Nothing
Nothing?
I wanted to watch you work
More to drink?
- Yeah.
A beer
More French toast?
- Yeah.
Thanks
What music do you like?
- What?
I don’t know. Anything
Wanna hear some drums?
- Yeah.
lt’s me playing some stuff
I tape it to get better.
You play in a group?
- I’m starting to.
I practice on a friend’s set
You play anything?
It’s pretty bad.
I’ll turn it off if you want
This part I do okay
This is the same stuff
with my group.
Not bad, huh?
Wanna dance?
I don’t know how
Doesn’t matter
Come on
lt’s easy
Hold my hand tight
Keep your arm firm
Hold on
That’s where I mess up
Watch my feet.
That’s the basic step
What’s wrong?
Rosetta, what’s wrong?
I forgot the boots
You want a ride home?
I don’t want to go back
to the trailer tonight.
Good night
Your name is Rosetta
My name is Rosetta
You found a job
I found a job
You made a friend
I made a friend
You have a normal life
I have a normal life
You won’t be left by the wayside
I won’t be left by the wayside
Good night
You’re replacing me?
- It’s just temporary.
Where am I gonna go?
If a job opens up, it’s yours,
but I have nothing right now
Where are you going?
Why are you taking my job?
Calm down!
He can goto some other school!
It’s my job!
I’m the boss here
Settle down!
Okay? Just calm down!
Get up, you big lump
How can I make it any clearer?
It’s only been three days
You can’t do this.
I wish my son
wasn’t a fuckup, but
He messes up
and he gets a job
But I’m out in the street!
Give me that sack
l’ll give you severance pay
- No, I’m staying!
It’ll just be a few weeks
I want a job and a normal life
like everyone else!
That’s enough now
Give me that.
Give it to me
Give it to me!
- No, sorry.
Maybe later on?
Anyone on a trial basis?
- We have a waiting list.
If you need help,
you can tell me.
I’m looking for work
We only hire
the long-term unemployed
What about cleaning your offices?
Volunteers do that
I’m sorry.
Good-bye
Thanks.
Thanks. Good-bye
Maybe his son will hate it
Or maybe he’ll hire you for the counter
He has 12 stands.
A waffle, please.
Forty francs
- Here’s 40 francs.
Don’t worry about it
See you tomorrow
- Hold on.
I’m catching the bus
- Hold on!
Wanna come to my place tonight?
Want me to come
by the campground?
You still mean what you said?
- What?
- If a job opens up, it’s mine?
Yeah. But the light’s changed
But will I have a job?
I don’t know.
I can’t say in advance!
The entrance
Is on the other side.
What do you want?
If you need money,
I can lend you some
- No need.
You sure? What about the apartment?
I don’t care about the apartment
What are you doing?
I thought you were the attendant
I threw my lines in.
- Your what?
My lines, with my trout traps
I caught one
Gimme that
Give me your hand
I’m sinking!
Rosetta!
I’m sinking
Grab hold!
Ouick! I’m sinking!
Ouick!
Pull!
I slipped
Wring it out more
If you want, you can come
dry off at the trailer.
No, l’ll change at home
- Didn’t you see me?
I didn’t think it was open
Want some coffee?
Come on
You coming?
Come inside
Come on
It’s hot.
It’ll do you good
You could make
the batter for my waffles
I sell ten a day.
Comes to 15,000 francs a month
You’d have a job
Working under the counter
isn’t a real job.
At least it’s something
You open?
In five minutes!
You can keep it all
You interested?
No, I want a real job
Is the boss in?
Yeah.
In the back, in his office
I came to see
if you had any news
It’s too soon
I said I’d write you.
I have your address
That’s my old address
Okay.
Give me your new address
The Grand Canyon
- The campground?
252 Floute de Marche
Fliquet’s ripping you off
What?
He’s selling his own waffles
- How?
He has a waffle iron at home
How do you know?
- I saw it.
His waffles are under the counter
If I come, he’ll know I told you
- He’ll know anyway.
Hello, boss
Where are they?
- What?
Cut the crap.
Where are they?
Where are your waffles?
Right here
What’s this?
Why’d you do it?
Give me your apron
Come on. Give it to me
Pick it up
You owe me three days’ pay
- Go on.
You owe me three days’ pay!
You gonna pick it up?
Pay me my three days!
Get out, you fuckin’ little thief!
Beat it!
Put this on
Let me go!
Why’d you do it?
Go on, hit me!
I wanted a job
Let me by
Let me by!
I wasn’t going to help you
out of the water!
But you did!
Let me by
That’s 40 francs
Have a nice day
A waffle and an Ice Tea.
- Coming up.
Here you are
That’s 75 francs
Two waffles, please
- Coming right up.
Thanks. Good-bye
Eighty francs
A waffle.
A beer
One waffle, please.
- Right away.
That’s 40 francs
Thanks. Good-bye
Two beers, please.
- Coming right up.
Here you are
- Thanks.
Thank you. Good-bye
Help me
Sit down
Hello. ls the boss in?
This is Rosetta
I won’t be coming back to work
A canister of gas