Subtitle by: Footsoldier
The evil Japanese warlord Lord Godless desires to conquer China. He threatens the General in command to surrender,
takes the emperor captive and subdues a large number of martial arts masters using his special poison.
Among the captives are Cloud who surrendered out of concern for Chu Chu, and the Mou Lam legend Nameless.
Lord Godless gives them two choices, they can either surrender and work under him, or they will be executed. None of the masters accept the offer.
Your Emperor has already handed the throne to my father,
Juewu Shen (Lord Godless)
Those willing to surrender, The gift is the poison antidote
and enjoy the central plains together
Xun zhe chen, Nie zhi wang!
Nameless, surrender your secret 1000 swords skill
and you will conquer the central plains with me
Since hundreds and thousands of years, Central Plains has already survived so many enemy attacks.
Now still do not fall
With the power of you alone, you want to conquer the central plains?
Only in your dreams
Since you rejected this offer, kill!
These are the Ma Xiang poison antidote
Heart!
Know nothing of your limits
Wind and Cloud together, are vulnerable
Today, I will use my immortal body armor
to break the myth of your 1000 swords skill
From now on, I am the myth
FY-II
The Storm Warriors
Master, how can you hurt so badly?
Toxicity had not entirely ceased
He was seriouly injured when confronting the Lord Godless
Based on my current injury
It is hard to recover Within a short time
Brother Wind, Where are you going?
I can't stand people to die because of me
Brother Cloud
Do not act rashly
Otherwise, the sacrifices of the other masters will be useless
Cloud, based on you and Wind potentials
you will need to enhance both of your skills in order to defeat Lord Godless
At this moment, only Piggy King's elder brother, Lord Wicked (xie huang)
can be skillful enough to defeat the Lord Godless
That guy is strange
he might not be willing to help
Someone is chasing behind
We split into two ways, I am responsible to divert the pursuing soldiers
Brother Piggy King, you bring Wind and Cloud
and go find Brother Xie Huang for help
Ok
Heart
Bring back Nameless
Eradicate others
Those who disobeyed, will die
Only he is capable of defeating Lord Godless
He has strange behaviour
Do not care about anything
Hope that this time, he can help
Len Lao, long time no see
See you working day and night, you shoud take a rest
If anyone is like you, how can there be any fun in life
Lord wicked! I have came to see you, come out and meet
Lord Wicked
Me, wind and with Brother cloud, come under Nameless command,
Hope that Lord Wicked can help and defeat Lord Godless
He occupied the territory of Central Plains and we kill martial art masters and innocents
These are dangerous and hard times, hope you can help
Long have I ever question any world matters
with Nameless
Lord Godless will retreat sooner or later
All of you go
Because Nameless was defeated by Lord Godless, suffering from serious injuries,
therefore we come and find you
Now that Central plains is under the enemies hands, do give some opinions
Brother Cloud
Sir, to show our sincerity
We will kneel here
Until you are willing to offer your help to defeat Lord Godless
Lord wicked, this is enough, stop being incapable of being satisfied
Hey, have one, taste very nice
Brother Wind, Brother Cloud. Both of you haven't been eating for the past few days
Please have a little
It's ok, ZhuZhu. Thanks for caring.
How about Brother Wind?
Lord Wicked, I am Second Dream
Requesting to greet you
Dream, Why did you come here?
Piggy King, such big event
I come, hoping to help Brother Wind and Cloud
Good timing, please help persuade Lord Wicked
Lord Wicked, I am Second Dream, please come out
So, you no longer care about me
Then I follow Brother Wind
Kneel before you until you come out
(Sigh) You have already grown up, how is your father?
Lord Wicked, my father is fine
He even said he wants to have a duel with you
You are still that pure
Lord Wicked, what happened to your hands?
I got curious, and went to learn a demonic skill
Hoping to master it
However, the result is uncontrollable behaviour and had done terrible things
Few years ago, due to fear of this behaviour happening again, i cut down my two arms
Now my skills are not as powerful as before
Learning any other skills cannot be done in a short time
According to the present situation, seems not possible
Lord Wicked, is there another way?
Learn the demonic skill, therefore increases termendous strengths
After learning the skill
it will be dangerous
However, it is the only fastest way to defeat Lord Godless
Who is willing to try?
Me
Lord Wicked, do think carefully, are there any skilled masters?
Would it be better to ask for their help?
Open both of your hands
Cloud
You are too impatient and irrational
Learning demonic skill will only worsen it
Wind
You have a calm heart
Hope that after you learned the skill
There is a chance of survival. Just like me, repent and be saved
Cloud, be patient, wait until i mastered this skill
We will fight Lord Godless together
But there is one thing I want you to promise me
If started to lose consiousness after i learned this demonic skill
Killing innocents
If that occurs, then I have to trouble you.
Brother Cloud, for you
Thank you for your help
I wont bother you anymore
Thanks
Any martial arts
cannot be learned in a short time, even with a superior master
I understand that haste makes waste
Rehabilitation is hard, learning demonic skills are easy but with major side effects
Takes a long time to learn a skill, but lesser time with demonic skill
To enhance life-long skill
Then must wholeheartedly willingly to learn, will you regret?
No, I have already considered this thoroughly
Your blood, must mix with the demonic lake
in order to become a demon
We have finally met
Brother Wind
The letter you wrote me, I have been keeping it with me
I have been cherishing it
Cloud, Lord Nameless has invited you to come
Just now you can counter my ultimate skill
And in a short time, you can turn it into your own use
Sufficient to prove that you have the ability to save this disaster
I intend to pass on to you my skill
I think you misunderstood
I have no ambition to be a hero
I am willing to kneel before Lord Wicked
Only to hope that after learning his demonic skill, i can fight for the sake of myself
I am now left with only one power
In order to defeat Lord Godless, there must be unity between Wind and Cloud
And I feel that this unity
will have a remarkable power and force
and will continue to increase in power
The demonic water
This is the method
On this map, the mentioned holy spine/treasure
is hidden in the Central Plains of the Dragon empire
within the emperor's palace of a restricted area, a cave
The cave is connected to the emperor's palace
Only the Emperor knows the way
If lost, there is a possibility that we will be lost forever
King is already in our custody
When found the Dragon Tomb
No one can stop us from sharing the central plains
Remember, central plains cannot be shared
Lord Godless, with Nameless
and Wind and Cloud
Rumors that they share extraordinary potential
Nameless has underestimate the power of the Ma xiang poison, it has not been cleared from his body yet
The forced use of his 1000 swords skill will only kill him
As for Wind and Cloud, I don't even mind about them
But when both unite
The one who has the capability to find the Dragon holy treasure
Can share great treasures with me
Yes, Father
Lord Godless, Nameless is under recovery
Wind and Cloud went to the Mountain
Send Messange to the my comrades
to defeat Nameless
Also, bring my best warrior to the Mountain
Yes lord
Let's go together and find the holy treasure
together with the emperor
My Son
Understand
Bring us to find the holy treasure
My father will guarantee you and your family safety
and enjoy lasting wealth
Wealth I have already obtained
This country has always belong to me
I have been in vain
Stop your nonsence!
Most people stay here
Others follow me
Walk
Can't believe at this short period
You can master this skill in such high level
Master, all this effort
All thanks to you
I hope you will name for this new skill of mine
Since the skill you learned is special in this world
I am afraid, not a word can be worthy of it
Or this one ...
Cloud, next time you will name this skill of yours as this
Master, there are so many odd words in this world
Forgive of my stupidity, but i've never seen this word
This word might not existed in this world
This is my new creation
Neither a cloud nor cloud, Neither a sword nor sword
that this word implies
You can read it as "Tyrants"
"Tyrants"?
What are you doing? What are you sweeping?
I am enough of you
There's nothing for you to sweep
Do persuade him
He's wasting his time
Be patient
I told you to self-cutivate, have you done that?
Time has passed, Wind has gone to the final stage of his demonic training
Must not be disturbed
Otherwise, he will die
Cloud, when will you be back ...
Cloud, the skill you learned, has not been completed yet
Still unable to express to the tipping point
Once completed, the power is unimaginable
Rush to the Mountain immediately, see how are they
Which hole is the Dragon Tomb?
This Central Plains will not escape from my reign
Sir
What happened? Where is Wind?
In order to save Second Dream, Brother Wind has been forced to come out
without finishing his demonic training
Actually, I am confused
The training has not finished
Those people learning it cannot intefere the process
If intefered at the last minute,
That person will go mad/crazy
and die on the spot
Unless Wind is somewhat different
With the present situation
as long as he can wake up from his uncontrollable and unfinished demonic power
Most likely he will return to the correct path
That means Wind still has a chance
Where is Wind at this moment?
Cloud, you went with Nameless for such a long time, what did you do?
He teached me his ultimate skill
Even guide me to invent my own skill based on his
Please note that the Emperor is under custody by Lord Godless
and went after the Dragon tomb in search for the holy spine
In the Dragon Tomb,
there is a hidden material that according to legend, possession of the material will enhance skill and wisdom
It must not be fallen to Lord Godless possession
Cloud, take haste and stop him
Lord Godless has indestructable body armor
Based on my opinion, his weak spot
is hidden in his strongest defended area
I will remember what you have said
When I have finished, I will return immediately
I think I know where Brother Wind has went
Really magnificent
Where is the Dragon Tomb?
This is the land of the dragon tomb?