I'd love to hire you, honey. But you've
come out of step with the season.
We just cut 3 girls.
The last one goes
back to school tomorrow.
- Tried anyplace else?
- Yes'm. They's all half shut-down,
or they're not hirin'.
Well, like I say,
your timing is way off.
It's now or never.
Mrs. Chambers,
I've done retail before
and I work real cheap.
What is your name?
Gissing.
Ruby Lee Gissing.
Ricky is slime.
He'll come onto you sooner or later.
He came after me, once.
And he ain't even a liberal.
You know, even Mrs. Chambers
knows her son is a true bastard,
but, see, admittin' it would be a
confession of her own, now wouldn't it?
All bosses are scumbags.
Is that why you left... wherever?
Manning.
Tennessee.
My Mom passed and things
kinda went bad all-around.
There's more to life than workin'
at Uncle Jack's store
and takin' crap from men.
You are a dreamer, ain't you?
Right here, moving up
in the world, and all?
I got out of Manning without
getting pregnant or beat up.
That's sayin' somethin'.
Well. Speak of the devil.
Ain't he a mess.
Works his mama's books upstairs
and God-knows-what on the side.
- Must be a drug dealer.
- Hardly.
Real estate, stocks,
that kinda stuff.
He's one can make money
when all the news is bad.
- It's a good trick.
- Yeah, for him, maybe.
I was here once when
I was 10 years old.
Only vacation I can remember.
Yeah. Summer's fine.
On the other hand, this
time of year's kinda bleak.
Seems fine to me.
If you like ghosts, maybe.
It'll be like this
pretty much 'til Spring Break.
This year they're expecting
thousands, hundreds of thousands.
Sounds impossible.
Well, just the same,
that's what they're sayin'.
You know, most of the locals try to
stay clear, but sometimes it's fun.
The clubs have great music and
everybody just goes a little bit crazy.
Last spring, Billy, my boyfriend,
he just about got himself killed.
What?
Well, he didn't get hurt, I mean,
we were leaving this club, see?
When these four rednecks pull up
and start shouting they don't
want us niggers on their beach.
And they were drunk, you know,
wild and up on us before we knew it.
So club security,
they got there in a flash.
It was a good thing, too, 'cause see,
Billy was, he was kickin' behind.
And the club, they gave us some
passes and a round of drinks,
and I got a story to tell.
And Billy?
Billy goes to school in Atlanta, and...
We're supposed to get married,
and all that good stuff.
Knock on wood.
- Where's that club at?
- Just up a ways.
My God.
Tomorrow, World Geo and Accounting 201.
Yeah.
We agreed that you weren't gonna
make these kind of deals without
telling me about it first!
- I tried, but I had to act,
and I couldn't find you!
- And out of my account?
I don't like being told
that I can't write a check.
Selling short and all the rest of this
stock market crap makes no sense, Ricky.
You're betting on losing money; why don't
you just throw it away at the dog track?
I only made 4 Grand in 3 days!
What'd the store net last week?
This store has been very, very good to you.
If you spent half the time here
that you do on your deals,
- it could be even better.
- How many times do we
have to go through this?!
Yes, this store has been great to me.
No, I will not come in,
because there's no
future in retailing!
- I don't see us hurting.
- Look, I want my own deals.
You know, one day, one of your
hunches is gonna backfire.
- I've gotta be able to trust you, Ricky.
- I'm not going anywhere, Mother!
And I'm sure as hell not gonna
bite the hand that so generously fed me.
- You don't have to get nasty about it.
- I don't have to get anything about it!
I'm late.
You and Rochelle get all those
T-shirts marked down?
Yes, Mrs. Chambers,
they're all priced on the shelf.
Well, next time, make more noise
when you come in.
I'm gonna be away for
a week starting Monday.
Ricky will be in to open up
and cover the upstairs.
There's one rule I have
for all my employees:
They don't date my son.
You understand that?
Yes'm.
It's so great being out of high school.
When I saw all the other kids
going back last month,
I felt like I was out of prison.
It's amazing how much you grow
in a couple of months.
Drive wild, Jimmy!
Jimmy's an artist.
Does airbrush. Shirts and stuff.
It's a glory to watch.
He's gonna teach me so that
I can do it next summer.
- Did you know Jimmy in school?
- I knew Ed.
It's his night to cook,
but I always help.
We all get along just fine, you know?
We're very liberated.
That's a neat old rocker.
Thanks.
It was my Granny's.
- You knew your Granny?
- Both of 'em. Grand-daddys, too.
Wow.
I barely knew my Ma.
Where the hell you been?
- Did you run out of gas?
- No, not this time. Come on.
Debrah Ann?
Guess what I got?
Nothing fancy here.
Just try to put down
my thinking over time.
Maybe figure out the why's of
running off, of coming here.
"Back home".
Seems strange to say that.
Seems strange to write that.
It was "Do this, do that."
Now it's up to me,
to what I want to be.
I got some idea about inside,
feelings and stuff.
But about the outside,
the acts and looks of things,
of me,
I am not so clear.
Wonder if I'll ever feel
just what I am.
No...
No, you're right, you're right,
it may never be the same.
Those little bastards love nothing more
than to make trouble for business.
Uh-huh. Leeches is what
they are, worthless.
No! No, no.
It shouldn't affect the deal.
Thirty dollars and
seventy-three cents, please.
No. Not at this time, at least.
Hey, I'll keep you informed, okay?
Here you go. Your receipt.
Listen, JB, if I'm gonna meet
Justine in a half-hour, I gotta go.
JB...
Five bucks says I take you by 3.
Oh. Okay, buddy. You're on.
- See you later.
- Are you leaving?
- Huh. It's dead.
- But I--
- The store needs two people.
- No, no you don't.
Trust me.
- So how about tonight?
- Excuse me?
Dinner, dancing?
This is a resort town you moved to.
You need to resort.
What do you say, Ruby?
- For one thing, I say you're about
as appealing as day-old roadkill.
- Roadkill?
And for another, your mama says that
the help stays clear of the boss' son.
My mama tries to protect me
from opportunists, but uh...
I can take care of myself.
Can you?
Come on, we might as well
get this out of the way.
Who knows?
I dare you.
- 8:00, where do you live?
- I'll meet you here.
Okay.
So far, fun has been nothing but work.
Ricky was right:
get it over with.
Morning. Sorry I'm late.
Here.
It's for those lonely nights
when we can't be together.
I really enjoyed our evening.
We'll do it again sometime.
I'll get the cash drawer.
Another day, another dollar.
I hope.
Do something with that towel display
when you get a chance.
And the sidewalk needs sweeping.
Glad you could come. Had to know how
you were doing with Freddy Krueger?
- Who?
- Slick Rick, the hunk in the trunk?
Alright, I guess.
Mrs. Chambers has been on vacation.
So you've been alone with the masher?
He come onto you yet?
I keep him at arm's length.
Besides, half the time
he's not even there.
That's good, see, cause he's the kind
you give an inch and he owns your butt.
He could care less about the store.
How's school?
Mmm. I'm on what they call
a pre-business track.
Just junk, mostly, buying and
selling, like Mrs. Chambers.
Mama wanted me to be a teacher,
but I said forget that no-money crap.
A blue volvo and job security
will make me a happy camper.
My worst nightmare is
I turn into another Ricky.
Oh, well.  Tchk.
As one of my professors says,
"Necessity has always been
our easiest excuse."
What would you teach?
I mean, children.
How to survive.
With your soul intact.
Yeah. I guess that's it.
Today, lunch with Rochelle.
I don't know what I'm doing here.
Call it an experiment.
Folks do this crap and a whole
lot worse without battin' an eye.
After all,
why slave your life out
when you can just take?
Are there any real reasons
for livin' right, anyway?
Mama always thought so, and they
held to her like a moth to light.
With the hopes of earning
everlasting peace and glory.
"This life and the next"
she used to say.
It was all a bloody mean trick.
I don't want none of it.
Get away from Ricky.
Ruby? Come on back here a sec, would you?
- Welcome back, Mrs. Chambers.
- Well, thank you, Ruby.
- How's everything been?
- Fine. Real nice.
Yeah, the store looks good.
You know, usually I'm afraid
to come back after a trip,
but you did a good job.
I'll ask you to do the
cash drawer, if you don't mind.
Surprise!
How about tonight, we could
meet at the Driftwood?
- I don't think so, Ricky.
- Last time was wonderful.
It was fantastic, I don't
wanna lose that momentum.
It was real nice, Ricky,
- but your Mom's back, and
I just think it's too risky.
- Don't worry about that.
And I didn't come all this way
to be your chippy.
Ricky? Ricky! It's for you.
There in a second, Ma.
I'll give you a few days,
and we'll work it out.
It was fantastic.
Fantastic.
That's right, Tom. Now might be a good time
to cover your plants and bring in the cat
because we're expecting the first
severely cold weather of the season.
As you can see, there is quite
an extensive Canadian front
draping into the Southeast this hour.
Behind it, some parts of the
Tennessee Valley are already reporting
record low temperatures, they're experiencing
blizzard conditions in some areas.
Here in Northwest Florida, we'll be
feeling the effects of that cold front
by early tomorrow morning.
There's also a small craft
advisory in effect tonight.
If you have to be out on the gulf,
do exercise extreme caution.
We'll have a look at current conditions
and the extended forecast
right after this message.
"Do exercise extreme caution."
"We'll have a look at current
conditions and the extended forecast
right after this message."
It's snowing back home.
They don't need snow here.
Here, you could get washed out to sea,
and nobody'd ever even know where to look.
- How's the jade?
- Excuse me?
You came in here a while back,
bought a little jade plant.
Part of a set of cuttings I did myself.
Fine. Plant's fine.
That's why I'm back.
Right.
You know, uh...
Most of the nurseries around here,
they-they buy their stuff,
but we grow almost
everything ourselves.
Huh.
Now in, uh, California, jade there
grows as big as garbage cans. Bigger.
But out here, outside, it wouldn't
make it to Thanksgiving.
- Thanks, I'll remember that.
- But now, uh,
you need to know about
your new companion here.
I get off in 10 minutes. 5.
I'm a good guy.
You've seen where I work...
Okay, you tell me where you work and
I'll come by and visit you there.
Chambers' Beach Emporium,
but I'm not allowed to have visitors.
Is that a fact?
That's too bad.
Well, I was just thinking, you know,
everybody's gotta eat sometime.
Would you promise not to say
another word about plants?
What's a plant?
They'd come from all around
but I was old enough to figure out
she had something special going on.
I'd spend all day in the kitchen.
I didn't know people from
Tennessee liked oysters.
Everyone I know.
Thank you.
It's so funny to me. My aunts didn't
care about how great she cooked,
they never tried to learn.
I met a new guy, Mike McCaslin.
He can talk your ear off about anything.
But he's a good listener, too.
I guess I've been needin' that.
We've seen each other a few times now.
His great-great-granddaddy
helped settle Panama City.
and Mike says he knows
everything about this place.
Like how the Indians lived,
and where the Spanish first landed.
And how things started going wrong
almost from the start.
Mike was real involved once, in
trying to make things better.
But now he says
he sees there's no point.
My granddaddy and I, we used to
fish off this bridge here.
Ain't nobody gonna be fishing
off this bridge.
Always seems like people have to
tear something down to make
themselves feel alive.
Then we run around scared to death of
whatever's gonna take us out in turn.
Like cockroaches or big-mouth bass.
Right.
Anyway, this whole place'll be
under water in 100 years or so
that oughta slow us down some.
Why wait?
Why not just end it all now?
It's pretty, isn't it?
It's kinda dirty.
You know what these are for?
Neither do I.
Mike can get morose,
that is no lie.
But most often he just
seems glad to be here.
Like a tree, he says.
That's his job.
That and keeping the record straight.
Looks like you live next to a junkyard.
That's Jimmy, Ed, and Debrah Ann.
They're alright.
You want to come in?
Next time.
I'll fix you something.
It's been a long time since
one kiss made my lips hum.
I can still feel it.
Must be all that bike riding.
Gotta watch it with Mike.
Be careful, now.
There. Beautiful!
- So what's this all about?
- Our second season. You'll see.
Y'all got enough stuff now?
So I like selling stuff, okay?
Is that good?
Five days of one thing for two
of something else.  Fair enough.
Anyway, the weeks are
moving faster now.
Sometimes I see Rochelle.
...some course you could take.
Finance, marketing, management ...
so you can run the business
one day. Or general education...
She says I should set my sights
higher, go back to school.
It's the only way to get ahead.
But Mike doesn't see much point to it.
You just need a guide,
to aim you in the right direction.
- And here you are.
- At your service.
Mike says there's a whole
new way to see the world.
Low-impact living, he calls it.
Getting unburdened,
giving nature a chance.
Sounds fine.
What I can make of it.
And yes, we've gotten it on.
All tender and romantic.
I'd been here almost three months
and hadn't gone swimming.
Mike said that was long enough.
Canadians go all the time,
but God it was miserable cold.
We sure had fun.
That gulf water can wake you up.
Good morning.
I've never seen so many books
in a house.
That's 'cause only fools read anymore.
You can have anything you like.
Whatever looks good.
For somebody who doesn't see a point
of school, how do you figure all these...
It's something else.
More like a... vain addiction, really.
I only read I had to, like the Bible.
Lot of good it did me.
I guess you think I've missed something.
Now that...
That may be a little bit tame for you,
but it's a great choice.
"No one who had ever seen
Catherine Moreland in her infancy
"would have supposed her
born to be a heroine.
"Her situation in life, the
character of her father and mother
"her own person and disposition,
were all equally against her."
Those are my odds.
"Her father was a clergyman
without being neglected or poor,
and a very respectable man..."
- Go on.
- I don't think so.
Well, take it, then.
You can join my fools' reading society.
Meetings nightly,
after lovemaking.
Lot of good it's done you.
Saved me from evil,
restored my soul,
brought peace
to my troubled mind,
and joy to my broken heart.
I'm not sure what Mike's gettin' at,
but I liked this one.
All that fuss over finding a man
isn't all that different now.
Who's it gonna be, and when.
And why.
Never got around to it.
You don't want to let mother catch you.
She, uh... She might wonder what
you're doing on the job.
Take care.
Ricky is 100% of something
I would like to forget.
Isn't it wonderful the way Austen
seems to dwell on the superficial
and the comic
and yet, all the while,
revealing the contradictions
and value systems
of an entire society?
I don't think there's been anyone
so subtle and elusive.
- What do you think?
- It was a neat story.
And Mike, I always feel good around him.
He's like that red and blue sweater
I had when I was 13.
So perfect.
I wanted to wear it all the time,
even when it got hot.
But sometimes...
Not always a pleasant feeling.
- This is crap, let's go.
- This is a good part.
It's braindead, come on.
- Hey, Mike, I don't see
why we have to leave.
- This is garbage.
- What good does that do?
Can you tell me?
- It's just a movie.
It's bullshit.
It takes over your brain with
stupid fantasies that have
nothing to do with being alive.
Next thing you know, they're just
gonna wire you up and set you spinnin'.
- No screen, no popcorn, no nothing.
- Maybe sometimes that's okay.
- What gives you the right to know?
- Because it's so clear.
Well, to you, maybe.
It's not to other people.
They have to make up their own minds.
- Perhaps it's all they need.
- Do you really believe that?
I don't know, and I'm not deciding
right now, so don't press it.
- You wanna go back inside?
- And sit next to you when
I know you're miserable?
Morning.
So how's our #1 and
only salesperson today?
Fine, Ricky. And yourself?
I'm in the mood for
a night to remember.
I think we oughta
give it another go.
Not a good idea.
Least not right now.
Most people are only 2 paychecks
from the streets, did you know that?
I'll keep that in mind.
I didn't mean that, Ruby.
It's just, I can't
get you out of my mind.
I'm going to Bimini for a few days.
I'd like you to come with me.
- Why won't you just give me a chance?
- Ricky, that hurts!
Now's just not a good time.
Maybe after the holidays.
Yeah.
Yeah, we'll work it out.
Sorry.
I don't know why I just didn't tell him
right there I was seeing someone else.
Maybe I didn't want that to mark me,
to be what I was.
"Hands off,
I'm some other man's lady."
Get out! Get out.
You never stay around
long enough to ask.
Oh, really? I'm here now!
What do you say about it now?
No! No!
Eddie, can't you stop him?
Eddie? Eddie's my friend, darling.
His old lady can't do a thing about that.
I'm sorry to ask this.
But is it alright if I stay the night?
No problem.
Thanks.
Thanks, Ruby.
I'll be alright tomorrow.
I've grown so much
in the last two weeks.
You'll see.
Messes.
I've sure been there.
And if I'm not careful...
Everybody's fantasy...
Tender unions,
precious ties...
I wonder how many folks
get anywhere near.
Mike's boss at the nursery
has a family.
Everything is perfect.
But from what I've seen, it's the woman who pays most for the dream of...
security and belonging.
Still, for some, there must not
be any charge at all.
Like it comes without effort.
Like breathing.
Lord help us
if we don't fit that mold.
Especially when we're all so willing
to buy in every chance we get.
Suckers for the tender, cozy life.
You all done?
No.
I put up with your garbage.
Now it's time for some inspiration.
And move away from the selfish claims
of our wills and desires.
Oh, I know. Our pride objects.
Our petty spirits rebel.
But he knows we seek
limits to our lives.
That we are happy
only when we yield...
Don't you love it? Just enough
truth to keep the sheep in line.
No. I don't love it.
You go ape over a dumb movie, and then
you put up with this, this kind of crap.
It's how most folks make do.
Is it how you make do?
I guess.
Way back, somewhere. I figure
there's a God out there.
But gentler, without the
harsh threats and the misery.
You can't have that kind of comfort
without the hell threat coming somewhere.
What?
So clear and bright,
like a crystal beacon lit
2000 years ago and still shining.
Obey and be saved in love.
Turn away and be damned for all eternity.
My family bought it all.
Hook, line, and sinker.
I grew up with the security and
certainty of living in the law.
I also know the guilt
and shame it can bring.
Nothing is ever gonna get
that kind of hold on me again.
My poor, tormented rebel from the law.
I'm not your poor anything.
I didn't mean any harm, Ruby.
Honest.
- Merry Christmas.
- Same to you.
- Can you get the light?
- Yeah.
Emily. Mike's Emily.
Strange words.
Too many thoughts, but I
thumbed through the pages.
"To ache is human, not polite.
"The film upon the eye,
"Mortality's old custom,
"Just locking up
"to die."
- Wish I had a set of these.
- Let's see the price.
Woody, I'll take a dozen
of each of the trays.
You keep all of this in your head?
Well, most of it doesn't change,
just the numbers.
and what you think
you can sell this year.
Ms. Chambers,
I need to know something.
Am I doing a good job?
Well, you still have a lot to learn.
But you're earning your money,
if that's what you mean.
I see.
Are you all packed?
- I'm all set.
- Good.
I'm glad we did that.
It's always good to go back to the
floor a second time on some things.
Especially,
with this new stuff.
But two days of it is enough
for any human being.
I've been coming to these things
for 20 years, I'm still afraid
I'm gonna forget something.
I'm gonna let you start driving.
I gotta take a nap.
Ruby!
Ricky. You scared the
damn hell outta me.
I'm sorry.
Can I come in?
It's really late.
I'm mighty tired.
Here.
Happy Valentine's Day.
Aren't you a little early?
Yeah. That's right.
Come in.
You want some coffee?
No, thanks, Ruby.
I'll be alright.
I've missed you
so much, Ruby.
More than I ever
thought possible.
Your mom and I just got back from Tampa.
I guess you've been to a lot of trade shows.
Not since I could say "no".
Your mom spent $6,000
in four hours on the floor.
Then we went to a big meeting about
tourism, and ate in a fancy restaurant,
and got some sleep before hitting
the floor again this morning, then
drove straight back through
so you can see how I'm real worn out.
Ruby!
I ain't seen anybody since you.
I got feelings, don't you understand?
I just need you to set them free.
And everything'll be all right.
Back, or I scream!
Get out of here, Ricky.
Ruby...
Ruby, Ruby, Ruby...
A man offers you his heart,
and look at you.
What's in this for you,
Miss Gissing?
If you're not careful, you're gonna
end up one lonely, cock-teasing bitch!
I should've known.
I don't wanna see you around.
In fact, don't even bother coming in
to work, 'cause you're fired. Terminated.
I'll send your last check here.
I think it's for the best, don't you?
I don't ever want to see you again.
I mean it.
Driving along the road once,
I swerved trying not to hit a rabbit,
and ran smack over a skunk.
I'm sorry, Ricky.
Guess nothing good can come
from being a fool.
Goddamn Ricky and his line about folks
being 2 paychecks from the streets.
Just make this right, here, and you'll
get back on that main road.
I met a family
from near back home.
Either that, or you want to take this...
Everything they owned
was in their car.
Out of work and on their way to Mobile
to stay with a cousin.
I don't think the mom
was countin' on much.
I gave them $10 for gas.
Can't meet up with any more.
Not for a while, at least.
Not until I'm settled again
and unbeholden.
- Hey.
- Hi.
- How about a movie?
- I'm not feeling so good.
I think I've got the flu.
Really?  I'll come in and
make you some soup, then.
I think I should just sleep.
All right. You call me, alright?
Yeah.
Like a ghost,
I'm gonna haunt you.
No.
Well, I can do just about anything,
right there, I bet.
- No, I don't know.
- Are you sure? 'Cause there
are plenty of people in here.
I'm sure that you can add me right in,
and I can do something just fine for you!
Good afternoon,
may I help you?
No, um...
I was supposed to meet someone.
I guess he's not here.
No problem.
Did you know you're not
supposed to be here alone?
I sure didn't.
We'll be seeing you around.
Impressive stuff.
To flaunt it in front of
paying customers.
The ultimate merchandise.
Maybe that's all there is.
We're all selling.
Forget what's inside.
It's all in our skin...
and in what touches it,
what covers it, what hides it.
And what it can do.
Too close to feeling gone.
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
It was my problem,
I wanted to work it out myself.
Didn't you just tell me Old Lady Chambers
said you were doing a great job?
Why-- Why'd she fire you?
There was no traffic in the store.
She had to.
Typical. Money's tight,
forget the worker, save your own ass.
Not even a week's notice.
You'll get another job. And if you
need some money to see you through...
- It's all right.
- Ruby, you could always move in here.
Stay as long as you like.
I'll take real good care of you.
It'd be wonderful.
Every girl's dream.
Right.
Well, you think about it.
For now, I'll just settle for
what you got in that pan.
Saved it.
Okay. Welcome.
You take the top part of the sheet,
with the longest piece of hem...
you put it all in one hand,
you draw it out
and you set it in that basket.
The first day is always
the toughest, but you'll make it.
Though, none of us plan
to be here long, do we Wanda?
But sometimes...
What you been doing?
Sales. I've been in sales.
Much better choice.
The talkative one is Wanda.
I'm Persephina.
Ruby.
Well, Ruby, don't forget
to eat your Wheaties.
Don't worry. Pretty soon,
you won't feel a thing.
Why'd you wait
so long to tell me?
Didn't I warn you about that man?
Didn't I warn you?
Are you really mad or sad, Rochelle?
I could always join the Navy.
Sure. Or marry a preacher
and have 15 babies.
It's not your style, I'm afraid.
- I've got 50, 60 dollars maybe...
- No...
Yes. 50 would help.
Thanks.
You'll get it back.
On the edge of the edge,
a dream.
Everyone I'd ever known was there.
living on a beautiful mountain.
We all did our share.
We all felt joy in being alive.
Wild and free,
without harm, without sorrow.
Beyond reality.
Beyond fantasy.
Only there.
Ruby ...
Are you awake?
Yeah, come on in.
- You okay?
- Yeah, I've just been keeping
some late hours, is all.
I brought you some chest pie.
It's the only thing my ma ever taught me.
- Debrah Ann! You coming back
today sometime?
- Coming, Jimmy.
I'll see you later.
"What's that thing between Daddy's legs?"
She says "Well, she's old enough to mind",
so she says, "That's how you get babies."
"You put Daddy's thing together with
Mommy's thing, that's how you get babies.
The girl, she's a little confused, she says:
"Mom, I was looking through the keyhole
and I saw Daddy's thing
in your mouth."
And she says
"Girl, that's how you get jewelry."
I heard that.
Looks like you're
getting the hang of it.
- I don't think so.
- Well, that's good.
Don't lose your mind.
Hello, Ruby.
Is it alright if I come in?
Thank you.
- Can I get you some tea?
- Oh, no thanks.
I paid for that.
I would never have
thought otherwise.
Ricky told me that you came by the store
with the car loaded and left for home.
Some emergency, he said.
I was furious and hurt that
you hadn't even said goodbye.
It wasn't until Rochelle called,
that I found out what really happened.
My son is a lot like his
long-forgotten ass of a father.
But I still have some hope for Ricky.
I know that must sound crazy.
But you've got more pressing
concerns at the moment.
I like mysteries.
Ones with women detectives.
I'd like to try one.
You know, when you first
came in the store,
I didn't really need anybody.
But I had a feeling about you.
You reminded me of something,
you were hungry.
There was a rage, and a...
fury that I recognized
from a long time ago.
A lot of good it's done me.
Most of us learn to lay low.
Sounds like dying.
Come on back
to the store, Ruby.
You're doing fine, and I need
an Assistant Manager with
energy and good ideas.
Besides, I'm thinking of opening
a second store, up the beach a ways.
Lord knows, the way this
country's going, maybe nobody's
ever gonna buy anything again, but...
Still, memories and dreams
are important.
And, so are beach towels, swimsuits,
and suntan lotion. We gotta be ready.
We'll have fun.
And Ricky will leave you alone.
All right, Mrs. Chambers.
Mildred.
- Mildred.
- Great.
And now I think
I would like that tea.
You going to wash in your dress clothes?
No.
I just came by to turn this in.
I got my old job back.
Just when you were getting
the knack of it.
Chambers Beach Emporium. Come by,
I'll give you a real good deal.
- Wanda?
- Yeah.
I dream about that room.
And Wanda, and Persephina.
Am I up to remembering that
we're all in the same world?
I don't know. I hope so.
I know it won't be easy.
Well, keep it up, girls. After this,
we're gonna tackle the upstairs.
At this rate, it's gonna take us
10 years to get the store restocked.
Y'all got enough stuff now?
I'll get the door for you.
Y'all come back now, y'hear?
Thanks a lot.
Tell your friends about us.
Thank God for spring.
And the "Best Buns on the Beach"
contest continues!
Ladies in the house, can you make some noise for contestant number 6, Jeff.
Is that you? Go do your duty, man. Ladies,
make some noise! Get this guy movin' for ya.
Wiggle it.
Not just a little bit.
Ladies, are you at Party Spring Break?
Make some noise!
Where's the party at?
Give it up!
Let's rock the house!
Shock the house!
It's Spring Break, y'all, time to
cut loose, on Panama City Beach.
How many people need sex on the beach
while you're here this weekend?
Safe sex, safe sex.
I'm gonna send out two girls right here
with some more t-shirts, guys.
Safe Spring Break party.
Don't drive while you're drunk.
Put your sunscreen on
and be sure...
to be safe with sex
on Panama City Beach.
The 3 big S's of Spring Break. Who needs
a t-shirt? My ladies have'em for ya.
You gotta make some noise, guys!
Where they goin'?
Spring Break capital of the
United States, Panama City Beach.
If you guys are feeling good,
make some noise!
- Not the most gorgeous shade of blue.
- Yeah, but one size fits all.
You got the other side?
- Okay.
- Let's go to work.
These knobs set your price, look through
the little window and make sure it's right.
Give it a good, hard squeeze,
and then just roll it..  on like that.
On someplace flat. Alright?
You wanna try?
Ruby...
Never mind.
- Rochelle ...
- Yes, Mrs. Chambers?
- Has the new stock been priced yet?
- The new girls are putting it on the floor.
Great, thank you.
It's nothing like when I first started.
You wouldn't believe the
inventory that we're moving.
We get all this stuff,
and the next day, it's gone.
Mildred says it's a buying frenzy.
Like it's contagious, or something.
What do you think about all this,
Rochelle?
It's what we're gettin' paid for, isn't it?
When the fish bite, enjoy.
- Like lemmings to the sea.
- What?
Nothing.
Beats not working.
There were other options.
What do you mean?
No matter how much they mess things up,
there's always the ocean.
Yeah.
Polluted and dying.
There it is.
I'm glad you finally called me. I was
beginning to think I was a leper or something.
I got caught up in gettin'
the store ready for spring.
It can't mean anything,
going back to the selling game.
It doesn't mean anything
It can't be the reason you're here.
It's a game whose rules I understand.
And for a while, at least, that's
just gonna have to be enough.
What are you really
trying to say, anyway?
It's better than
having no game at all.
You and all of your
gloom and doom crap, man.
Do something about it
or leave it alone.
Just please stop looking down
at the rest of us.
You're absolutely right.
I'm sorry.
Me too.
That's when I started
seeing less of Mike.
We go to movies and stuff,
but we get uncomfortable if
we stay together for too long.
He's working on something.
One of his causes again.
But he won't say what.
May be afraid of losing it.
I understand.
I hope we keep in touch.
Somewhere I heard that "Hell is
when all your dreams come true.
Maybe it's because you find out,
they won't all go together.
Or that there's always sides you
can't see when you're dreaming away.
I won't be staying long.
I just wanted to tell you
how much I regret what happened.
I'm in counseling now.
"Getting in touch with myself,"
they call it.
Becoming a new man.
I just wanted to apologize,
that's all.
Maybe I'll see you around?
Business is booming.
While we have a free moment...
Thanks, Rochelle.
It was a real help.
Oh, yeah.
I'd forgotten. Almost.
By rights, Mildred should
have made you Assistant.
Nah, after this summer, Mildred
won't be able to afford this one here.
Billy finishes school in December.
And I'll have my degree, and...
we'll be straight.
I hope.
Hello.
- Did you used to work over at Porter's Court?
- Oh, my uncle's place.
I still do.
He and my father just bought this complex,
and we're fixing it up.
- Do you live here?
- Yeah, I do.
- Would you like to have some tea?
- Sure.
What about that song?
Prayers to Shiva,
who is everything.
Everything?
When my family came here,
we were skin and bones.
I mean it, we were skin and bones.
But four years later, and look at me now.
I'm so healthy, don't you think?
- Don't you miss your home?
- This is home now.
- Everyone wants to be here.
- It doesn't make it right.
It is, for now,
the great dream of the world.
Whether it's right or wrong,
that's always much harder.
It really is a beautiful song.
Maybe you'd like to learn it?
- Good morning, Mr. Roberts.
- Mornin'.
Suppose it means more.
Making it in some
big great city somewhere.
But this is the world I found.
And I guess the questions
stay the same.
Mornin', Ruby.
Like, where does caring come from?
Can we ever know our true desires?
And why are we, all of us,
so often lonely and afraid?
The answers are probably
real simple and real close.
Smiling somewhere, quiet-like.
Waiting, for us.
Mornin', everybody.