Here.
What are you doing?
(5 minutes before Dong Hyuk came to Young Ae's rescue)
There's someone I know.
- Please begin.
- All right.
Blowfish is fibrous.
You have to slice the fish as thinly as possible.
Isn't this so thin?
We didn't order this.
Your boyfriend ordered it before he stepped out.
He said it's one of your favorites.
Boyfriend?
Ms. Lee, are you in a relationship?
I guess your boyfriend stepped out.
You'll introduce me to him when he's back, right?
Gosh, I'm really curious what kind of man you're seeing.
What? Why are you leaving? Where are you going?
You didn't even finish the food.
Well, something came up.
What's the rush?
Where are you going in the middle of dinner?
My gosh. Look who's here.
You have to finish the food.
Sit.
What is going on?
Does this mean...
Mr. Cho is...
your boyfriend?
Yes.
I'm her guy friend.
Her male friend.
Aren't I right?
Yes.
We're friends, you know. We went to elementary school together.
So you two are just friends?
My gosh! Mr. Lee, what brings you here?
Well, I was just...
We should get going. Let's go.
Come on. Enjoy your dinner.
- All right.
- Bye.
Mr. Lee.
Don't you think there's something going on between those two?
They're saying that they're just friends,
but they got all flustered and ran away...
Where did he go?
When did Mr. Lee leave?
Goodness, every single thing he does irks me.
(Episode 5: A Jealousy-filled Day)
Hey, wait!
What happened?
Why did you show up...
Aren't you two dating secretly?
What?
How did you know that we're dating?
Young Ja, did you tell him?
No, why would I?
At the last work dinner you guy had,
I saw you two holding hands together.
I see.
Mr. Cho and you are not on good terms.
I wanted to help because I didn't want it to affect the project.
I see.
Thanks.
- I better get going now.
- Bye.
See? I told you that we shouldn't stay in the neighborhood.
Dong Hyuk saved us.
Young Ja, were you and Mr. Cho close?
No, I didn't see him for 30 years.
I couldn't even recognize him at first.
Really? I'm surprised.
He helped you even though you guys aren't close.
He doesn't look like the type to do that.
He said he helped because of the project.
Gosh, I left all the shrimp sushi because of Mr. Cho.
What a waste.
I'll buy it for you again.
(She pulled an all-nighter!)
Young Ae, I'm coming in.
She's not here.
Is she in the bathroom?
Why is her room so messy?
Is this what she's working on these days?
What are you doing in my room?
I'm sorry. I came in to speak to you about something.
Young Ae, I got a project for you.
What?
My friend came to see me to sell me insurance,
and I got him to get promotional materials done through us.
Seriously?
I'm impressed.
You sold our service to a salesman.
I used the skills I learned from you to persuade him.
I said, "Your promotional materials are so ugly."
"I can't trust your service because of them." Then he placed an order.
Right.
You got us many orders when we were in Jeju Island, too.
You have a great sense of humor. You look friendly as well.
I know.
Looking back, those were the fun times.
Don't you agree?
You're right.
You and I were...
such a great team.
You designed, and I took care of the sales.
We were.
Speaking of which,
why don't we...
I have to get dressed and head out for work.
Sure.
He must want to work with me again.
But I couldn't take him to Nakwon Printing.
Should I have told her straightforwardly...
that I want to work with her again?
Why can't she take a hint?
You've been staying at home for six months now.
Why can you still not even cook rice?
(Her husband gets on her nerves from the morning.)
Close the lid and push the "start" button.
Then it'll say "It starts now."
It doesn't?
Did you lock the lid?
You have to turn the lock.
There's only one thing you can turn.
You're driving me crazy.
Hang up.
What are you doing?
After peeping at my text,
now you're listening to me talk on the phone?
I didn't mean to.
You were just speaking too loud.
Let me tell you again.
I don't want others to talk about my family matters.
So...
if you say anything about my husband losing his job,
I'll lock your mouth with this.
I get it. Don't worry.
Seo Hyun regrets getting to know about Mi Ran's family matter.
Among the revised versions,
which is your favorite?
Are they really revised versions?
They all look the same to me.
Is this a "spot the difference" quiz or something?
Can't you tell the differences?
I stayed up all night working on it.
Is your eyesight getting bad?
She worked on it all night. They can't look the same.
This one is like this.
That one is like that.
They all look the same to you as well, right?
Ms. Lee, are you sure you worked on it all night?
They're all the same.
That's not true. They're all different.
This one has a bigger belly.
This one has a bigger horn.
This one has more hair.
This one has bigger nostrils.
I like the first one the most.
Really? That's my favorite, too.
I can see why you're a designer.
I wonder why Ms. La couldn't tell the differences.
I did.
I pretended because I wanted to cut Ms. Lee some slack.
What are you talking about?
Ms. Lee is not a slacker like you.
I'm not a slacker.
I'm so proud of you, Ms. Lee.
You revised it in a day.
You even had a date yesterday.
A date?
- With who? - That's right.
I saw Mr. Cho from the bar with her yesterday.
It was just a dinner.
Don't start a false rumor.
I have to stop by at the print shop.
She had dinner with Mr. Cho yesterday?
Yes.
They had dinner just by themselves at an expensive Japanese restaurant.
They looked so close.
Right. You saw them, too.
They looked like they were just friends.
That's not true.
Including what happened regarding the poster,
he's always been taking Ms. Lee's side.
I'm sure there's something going on between them.
They went to the same elementary school.
Could they be each other's first love?
Like in "Autumn in My Heart" or "Rain Shower."
I've never seen such an unattractive heroine in my life.
I've never seen such lazy employees in my life as you.
Cut it out and go back to work.
What was that? He usually takes the employees' side.
(Hyuk Kyu is wearing a suit. Something funny must happen.)
What's taking him so long?
Hyuk Kyu is asking around for a job.
Yong Ju! I'm here.
Hyuk Kyu came to meet Yong Ju after a long time.
You can't show up at my workplace on such short notice.
I don't have so much time as you do.
Yong Ju doesn't seem happy to see Hyuk Kyu.
I'm sorry.
By the way, your office is so cool.
Of course. I went to a nice university, and I'm good at English.
I quit working at the government...
to come to this company.
You're right.
Yong Ju, have you had lunch yet?
Why don't we have lunch together?
- I have something to tell you.
- I'm busy. Just say it now.
I see.
The thing is, Yong Ju,
can you ask around for a job for me?
- What?
- You worked in the government,
and now, you work at a big company. You must know a lot of people.
Hey, you're as stupid as I remember you used to be.
Why would they want you?
What?
Isn't that too harsh?
Did I say something wrong?
I have some important business to take care of.
I have to go.
Hey.
Mr. Lee.
I asked you to get some cigarettes for me. What are you doing here?
- Well,
- Cigarettes?
I'm on my way right now.
You were so fast when Mr. Park asked you.
Do you look down on me because I'm from a mediocre university?
That's not true. How could I look down on you?
You're...
this much ahead of me.
I mean this much.
- Gosh.
- No.
- This...
- Yong Ju!
Yong Ju!
Help.
What should we eat?
I'm not sure.
- What about some stew?
- That sounds good.
- Let's have fermented skate.
- Fermented skate?
I don't think so.
What do you want to eat, my...
What do you want to eat, Ms. La?
I want to eat pasta.
Buy me pasta, Mr. Lee.
I was just playing along.
He's becoming weird after getting a girlfriend.
I know.
Gorae Caress Bar has started serving lunch.
- Why don't we try it? - Sure.
Ms. La, I'll have to buy you pasta some other time.
All right.
- It's only five dollars.
- It's cheap.
Gosh.
Let go.
Your exam is only a few days away. How can you skip classes?
The teacher said I should rather go home.
What did you do to make her say that?
It hurts.
Isn't that a bit too violent?
I know. Stop it. You'll hurt him.
My goodness.
Are you taking your nephew's side?
Is it because you'll be his aunt?
That's not it.
Please help me.
He'll kill me.
Soo Hwan.
- Come here, will you?
- I won't.
You're a professional fighter.
A professional fighter?
Were you an athlete?
Didn't you know?
My uncle was a famous mixed martial arts fighter.
He even won a championship once.
He won a championship?
Shibasaki.
(Cho Dong Hyuk Won by Choking Shibasaki)
It's unbelievable.
He won against him?
In the UFC 2007, he won against Shibasaki,
who had a much higher rank than him.
I thought Shibasaki was a curse word.
How do you know all that?
Girls usually don't like mixed martial arts, but maybe you do.
I remember it because it was a match against Japan.
Fagayaro Shibasaki.
- Fagayaro?
- I see.
I've never seen a mixed martial arts champion in real life.
It's an honor.
You do have extraordinary muscles.
Oh my. It's so hard.
Oh my goodness.
- Enjoy your food.
- Okay.
Ms. La, don't touch Ms. Lee's boyfriend's arms.
Mr. Cho seems embarrassed.
Stop teasing me.
Hello, Mr. Kim.
Yes.
Anyway, Ms. Lee is so lucky.
A man in mixed martial arts is the manliest man possible.
On top of that, he's handsome.
You're right.
His bar is doing well, too.
He's reserved and earnest.
Even as a guy I can tell that he's a good catch.
This seafood soft tofu stew is just as good.
Good? No way.
It's salty.
No, it's perfect.
I eat my food bland.
This is salty. It's too salty.
- My goodness.
- What are you doing?
Hey.
That's better.
Thanks to Seung Joon's jealousy,
Nakwon Printing staff had to eat extremely bland stew.
Yes, Sir.
Not at all.
A little. It's just a little scratch.
Yes, I can get back to work tomorrow.
Yes, Sir.
They said you have a fracture. You have to stay here.
How will you go to work?
Just tell him you'll take a few days off.
What if someone replaces me? Are you going to be responsible?
A low-ranking staff like me...
is more than replaceable at a big company like that.
I'll crawl to work if I have to.
You used to boast about yourself all the time.
You really changed.
The world changed, so I should, too.
It doesn't matter what university you went to,
and how fast you passed the civil service exam any more.
What can a man like me do, then?
Here is your dinner.
Thank you.
- Give it to me.
- That's an early dinner.
Yong Ju, let's eat dinner.
Forget it. How can I eat right now?
I have reports due tomorrow.
You should eat and get energy to get better.
Come on.
Jangjorim and rolled omelet?
Hospital food is pretty good.
You really won't eat it?
If you're going to throw it out, I'll eat it.
You're right. I should eat and get better as soon as I can.
If I can't get out of bed, someone else will take my place.
I'm going to eat.
I'll eat...
and go to work.
Bottoms up.
(You can act like you worked overtime in the winter.)
No one's there to greet me at home.
Do you want to go for soju?
Is your wife still at your in-laws'?
Gosh, life is so easy with my mother-in-law babysitting.
Well? How about it?
I'm not sure. I think I have to go on a date.
Young Ae.
- Do you have a minute?
- What is it?
I need to talk to you about the night market.
Sure. Let's go.
- You guys go ahead.
- Okay.
Okay.
What was that? Was he waiting for her to get off work?
That's what I'm saying.
Right?
Let's go home and drink soju.
I thought you had a date.
I said I thought I might. I never said I did.
My girlfriend texted me and said she's busy.
Let's go!
Okay.
Why is he taking it out on us?
I'm not sure.
It's not our fault she's busy.
I'm sick of this.
- Are you going to quit?
- Are you crazy?
This should go in the fridge.
(The working mom's day never ends.)
Here, eat this. Here.
Good. Good girl.
All finished.
I thought you were tired from working. What are you doing?
We ran out of baby food for Hae Jin.
Leave it. I'll do it later.
It's okay. You were babysitting all day long.
I'm home.
- Are you back?
- Yes.
- Honey, are you home?
Dad.
Hae Mil, did you have fun today?
My goodness.
I told you to take Hae Mil back and forth from day care.
Where have you been all day?
I went to see a friend...
to ask him for a job.
Do you remember Yong Ju? He tutored Young Min.
Yong Ju?
Sure, the graduate from Yonsei University?
Yes. He's working for a big company.
And?
Did you ask for a favor?
Pardon?
Well...
He's in a sticky situation, too.
Really? Why?
Of course he is.
Birds of a feather flock together.
He's your friend, so of course he's not doing well.
Mom, don't be so harsh.
I agree.
Did you eat?
We just finished.
Of course he ate.
Yes. Of course I ate...
Hyuk Kyu doesn't dare say...
that he hasn't had a meal all day.
(Let us introduce you to Mr. Yoon's pet.)
All right, let's eat.
Gosh.
What about the saury stew? Is it still boiling?
Right.
- Gosh. - What? What is it?
Are you adding something?
Why are you putting in water? It was perfect.
Gosh.
Didn't you just see Mr. Lee at lunch?
He's in a bad mood. We should cheer him up.
Let's see.
It's so bland.
It's perfect.
It tastes like you did laundry with kimchi.
Gosh.
Young Ja, what are you doing? Are you done yet?
No.
The night market is coming up, so we have a lot to discuss.
- Should I just look at these? - Sure.
Are you still at his bar?
All right, good luck.
I thought it was going to be quick.
She's working, so I can't say anything.
This is so annoying.
I can't take it.
- Mr. Lee.
- Mr. Lee, try the stew.
I made it just for you.
Here you go.
What is this? Do you have diabetes?
This is so bland.
- Are you leaving? - None of your business.
I thought he liked it bland, so I made it bland.
Gosh.
You're right. If he wasn't going to drink with us,
why did he ask me to come?
Gosh.
Do you have a dip for this?
Why did I ask him to move in?
It's so tiring.
You're right.
What are you doing? Get me a small saucer.
Okay.
Seriously, he should be nicer since you're doing him a favor.
That's what I mean.
I will never let anyone move in again.
Why do I have to be uncomfortable at my own home?
Hey.
What are you doing? You got it all over me.
- My goodness.
- I'm sorry.
Gosh.
This might stain. Hurry up and wash it.
- Gosh. - I'm sorry.
My goodness.
Hold on a minute.
You should know your place.
You always come over because your place is far.
These are my pants. Why are you overreacting?
Go. Go home.
- Just go home.
- I should eat the stew.
I don't have any for you.
I'll give it to a dog. Go.
Then everything else is good to go...
as long as I add a talent show in the list, right?
Yes.
I'm sorry I called you so suddenly.
It's okay. People change things the day before all the time.
Young Ja.
Mr. Lee. Why are you here?
Why do you think? I came to drive you home.
You didn't have to.
Of course I should.
I should take care of my girlfriend.
Young Ja, are you tired? Drink this.
Give it to me.
That was easy for you because I already did all the work.
- Let's go, Young Ja. - Okay.
Young Ja, shall we stop by the diner for a bowl of udon?
You know the diner we go to all the time.
Shall we?
See you around.
See you.
Let's go!
What was that about? What's with him?
(What time is it now?)
(It's about time I get very hungry!)
I should've just had dinner earlier.
I can't sleep because I'm too hungry.
Is there anything I can eat?
It's braised ribs.
They must've had braised ribs for dinner.
Wait a second.
Young Ae likes this style of braised ribs with radish.
Mother might get mad at me if I eat this.
I shouldn't touch this.
Is there anything else I can eat?
What are you doing in the middle of the night?
You woke up.
I'm hungry, so I'm cooking up some food for myself.
Gosh, just eat whatever we have. Why are you cooking at this hour?
It looked like you're saving the braised ribs for Young Ae,
so I'm just using the leftover vegetables in the refrigerator...
to make some fried rice for myself.
Leftover vegetables?
You're making fried rice with these vegetables?
They're for Hae Jin's food.
Sorry? Well...
These are ingredients for Hae Jin's food?
Yes.
You should've just had the braised ribs.
Why are you using the ingredients for your baby's food?
Young Chae spent so much time to chop all those vegetables.
You get nothing right.
Are you ignoring me right now?
I'm sorry. I didn't want to burn the rice.
You annoy me so much.
You're worried about burning your fried rice,
yet you're not worried about making my blood boil.
Do you study how to make me angry or what?
Why do you have to be like this, seriously?
Hyuk Kyu is hungry, uncomfortable, and sad.
Hyuk Kyu, what are you doing here?
Aren't you cold?
I'm not cold at all.
Our place feels a lot colder.
It feels as cold as Siberia in there.
What's wrong? Did something happen at home?
The same thing as always.
I feel so incompetent and uncomfortable because I'm jobless.
Cheer up.
You'll be able to find a job soon.
Can you...
get me a job?
What?
Let me work with you.
You saw how good I am in sales when we were in Jeju Island.
I also got you a project this morning.
But...
I can't help you right now because my situation isn't ideal.
My situation is a lot worse. I really cannot stay at home.
Just give me something to do. I'll work very hard.
Just pay me whatever you can. Please?
I'm sorry, Hyuk Kyu.
I'll keep my eyes open for a good position for you.
I'm going in.
Young Ae, Young Ae!
I practically begged her.
Have some mercy, seriously.
- Really?
- Yes, I'm serious.
(A few days later)
Why do I have to work at the market on my precious weekend?
That's what I'm saying.
Isn't Mr. Cho going overboard to win the organizers over?
Yet it's always us who do all the work.
Hey, you opened a booth there.
You have to be there anyway.
Stop whining already.
By the way, why isn't Young Ae here yet?
She went to the market early in the morning...
Mr. Yoon. That's what you told me earlier, right?
Pardon me?
I said that?
Yes! Are you becoming senile already or what?
I must say, Young Ae looks like a newly-enlisted soldier these days.
She has been working so hard lately.
You haven't served in the army. What do you know about being a soldier?
I don't have to taste night soil to differentiate it from doenjang.
You totally sound like a Korean. It's giving me goose bumps.
Oh, hello.
- Hello. - Mr. Cho.
Why are you dressed in a suit?
You look dashing.
There will be high-up officials including the chief of the borough.
I have to look presentable, you know.
Hence, I thought I should dress up.
Oh, my. It looks like you also got your car cleaned.
- It looks like a new car.
- Hey! Hands off!
I spent 60 dollars to get it hand-washed.
I even got it polished.
How dare you try to touch it with your grimy hands.
I'm sorry.
I'll meet you guys there.
Don't be late.
- Okay. - Okay.
Goodness gracious.
My hands are clean. That was so mean.
Your hands are grimy.
Look at your dirty nails.
- Whatever. - Open the door.
(They designed this banner.)
I must say, the character is so cute.
Young Ae did a great job.
Yes, it looks great.
Why do you keep taking photos of Food Monster?
Just because.
He wants to record everything about Young Ae's first character.
Hey, shouldn't you be offering help even if you don't mean it?
I'm sorry.
My hands are tied.
It looks like Ms. Lee met up with Mr. Cho using work as an excuse.
They're actually on a date now.
Next to Mr. Cho who is a big guy,
Young Ae looks dainty and delicate like Kang Susie.
She won the lottery.
Meeting a guy like Mr. Cho, that is.
Mr. Cho, enough with your corny jokes.
But this one was actually funny.
- Yes. - I know, right?
She won the lottery.
- You made it.
- Yes.
You two are working so hard.
Young Ae, the leaflets are here. Take a look.
- Oh, sure.
- Nice.
- They're finally printed. - Oh, my.
- Let me see.
- Here.
The leaflet looks amazing, too.
Really? Is the design okay?
Not really. It's not okay.
What's wrong? Is there an error?
The talent show segment is missing in the event details.
- What? - Seriously?
You're right.
What happened?
I gave you the revised design.
I guess I printed the first design. I'm sorry.
- You forgot because of your booth.
- Gosh, seriously.
Sazal, you're useless!
I'm sorry.
No, it's okay. I should've double-checked.
- I should go design a sticker...
- No, it's okay.
We already posted a notice on the website...
and received applications from the merchants, so it'll be fine.
But still, if the talent show is missing on this leaflet,
people who just come here won't know about it.
They'll gather when they hear it going on.
Don't worry and just get other things done.
I'll go tell people at the association.
I'll go with him and apologize to them.
All right. Go on.
Mr. Cho is so sweet.
I thought he was going to get mad at her, but he comforted her instead.
I know.
"Don't worry and just get other things done."
He's such a heartthrob.
- Don't do that, please.
- What is this?
- Let's go.
- Where is this supposed to go?
Hello, Sir. Thank you for coming.
Hello, Mr. Cho.
Mr. Lee, what are you doing? Say hello.
- Your business must be going well.
- Yes.
- Thank you for coming.
- Hello.
There are many delicious snacks inside. Please check them out.
There is a photo zone over there. Don't forget to take a picture.
There's a talent show taking place at 7pm. Please participate.
Please feel free to browse around.
Come try our traditional cookies. They're delicious.
Where is Sazal's booth? What's he selling?
I didn't ask.
He'll probably sell Korean food, right?
I'm curious.
Try tasty Indian curry.
Have some tasty Indian curry.
Sir, ma'am, try it.
Try some tasty Indian curry.
Mr. Yoon and Mr. Jeong.
Is this your booth?
You're not from India. You're from Bangladesh.
We eat curry in Bangladesh, too.
You've never made it for us.
Do you even know how to make it?
Hey.
What's the big deal?
These days, instant curry tastes quite all right.
Try some tasty Indian curry.
Gosh.
There you are. I've been looking for you.
I thought you were with Mr. Cho.
He can't stop flattering people.
I had to leave him.
Aren't you hungry? Let's get something to eat.
Try some traditional Indian curry.
Are you selling curry? What happened to your pronunciation?
- Wait.
- We shouldn't eat it.
We could have had Sazal's food.
Something smells so good.
I think it's the skewers.
It must taste great. There are so many people.
It looks so tasty. Let's have it.
That's Mr. Cho.
That was why there were so many female customers.
He's so good-looking.
Look at that.
It's not the skewers that are burning.
It's the ladies' hearts.
Shouldn't Ms. Lee drive them away?
Why is he selling skewers?
Is it because Ms. Lee loves skewers?
Maybe. Are they really going out?
I smell something fishy between those two.
It's not from those two.
Your mouth stinks.
Keep your mouth shut. Stop talking.
What is he talking about?
Does it smell bad?
Are you not brushing your teeth with your wife away?
Gosh, that almost killed me.
Take a picture with Food Monsters.
(Work like there's no tomorrow.)
Please attend our talent show, too.
Okay.
The pictures turned out great.
My chin hurts a bit, though.
Her chin hurts?
It feels okay.
What's wrong?
What are you doing?
It's nothing.
Wait, Dong Hyuk.
What?
Help me. My face got stuck.
Really?
Let me see.
Take it easy.
Try not to damage the print.
We could just cut it.
- No, we can't.
- Fine.
We need to say hi to those in high positions.
Why do you keep disappearing?
You're doing fine without me.
(They're dressed like people from the countryside.)
Wait.
What's going on?
Mr. Lee, look at that.
Why? Did you spot someone important?
What are those two doing?
Oh my.
They look so sweet.
To me, it just looks like he's trying to get her face out.
- Sorry? - We should help.
Leave them alone. Let them have some fun.
Gosh.
- Hey.
- What?
Can't you make your face smaller?
How could I make my face smaller so suddenly?
That hurt.
It worked.
Oh my.
It's "Love and the Night Market."
Mr. Lee, did you get what I said?
You've heard of the drama, "Love and Ambitions," right?
It's a parody of that.
"Love and the Night Market."
Do you understand now?
Where did he go now?
Gosh, that brat.
Gosh.
Why does Mr. Cho keep linger around Young Ja?
I wish I could stop him.
(It's hard to stay reasonable when you're in love.)
Hey, did you see that man who's selling skewers?
His arms are so big.
- Where is he? - Over there.
He's so good-looking.
- Let's take a closer look.
- Okay.
It's not tasty.
- Sorry?
His skewers are way too salty.
Try Indian curry instead. Don't eat his skewers.
- Let's go.
- Don't have the skewers.
What are you doing?
Why do you spread a false rumor?
I didn't.
I said it because it is salty.
You haven't even tried it.
I can tell just by looking at it.
Do you have something against me?
Why would I?
I know you're trying to make me look like a petty person.
Your skewers do look salty.
He's blinded by jealous.
That was so salty.
Those skewers are so salty.
Seung Joon has become too childish.
What can you do if I have something against you?
Gosh.
What's going on?
They're participating in the talent show...
to win 50 dollars from Ms. Lee.
What do you mean?
She left out the information about the talent show in the leaflets.
She probably felt bad that not many signed up.
Ms. La, it's our turn soon.
I live near here. I hope no one will recognize me.
Let's go. Let's get ready.
Oh my.
I'm impressed by Ms. Lee. She's spending her own money.
Where is she?
Ma'am, go next.
I don't want to do it.
Everyone seems to know that you love to have fun.
Please do it for the sake of the night market.
I don't think I can do this.
You can do it just like that.
(A fantastic collaborative performance)
(Night Market Talent Show)
What are they doing?
They're humiliating our company.
Can't you stop the music?
Why?
Those important guests seem to be loving it.
Is that right?
Should I have signed up, too?
No.
That would have really humiliated our company.
What did you just say?
Encore!
Really? Okay.
Ms. Lee, I'm sorry.
- I don't think I can do it.
- Pardon?
I have a huge group coming in.
Wait, it's your turn now.
I'm sorry. I have to go.
Wait! Ma'am!
What do I do? My goodness.
Our next contestant, please come up.
- What's taking them so long? - Next up, she's from Aunty Jokbal.
Aunty Jokbal, are you here?
(You can always trust in Young Ae.)
What is this?
Why does the owner of Aunty Jokbal look like Ms. Lee?
No, she doesn't look like Ms. Lee. That is Ms. Lee.
What?
You're right, it's Ms. Lee.
She was looking for participants, so she went up there herself?
Young Ae is working hard to pay back for her mistake.
Young Ae is so good. The crowd is loving her.
Those VIPs at the front are all laughing.
Really?
What is this? She told us to go on stage,
then she goes after us?
Who cares. All we need is the money.
I've never seen anyone look so good...
with pig's feet in her hands.
Why does she have her stomach out like that?
Ms. Lee, put that belly fat away!
They look like her own hands.
They're a part of her.
What's wrong with him? Why is he smiling at Young Ja?
She used to be so shameless during childhood. She's still the same.
- Go, Aunty Jokbal.
Thank you for such a passionate stage.
Please give her a round of applause.
Next up, we'd like to invite Mr. Shin over...
- Are you here?
- Hey.
Yes?
Your armpits are ripped.
What?
It's okay. It's hardly visible.
Right, can I borrow your truck to move Food Monsters later?
What?
That punk.
All right. For the success of the night market.
- Cheers!
- All right.
- Okay.
Gosh.
Curry doesn't go well...
with rice wine at all.
It's what Sazal had left over from his stand.
It's so watery.
It's disgusting.
I know that.
There's no need to tell me again.
- Gosh.
- My goodness.
You must have worked hard to prepare the night market.
We didn't do much.
We just did what we ought to.
Especially Ms. Lee. Great job.
Not at all.
Thank you for trusting us.
The ward official seems very pleased with you.
He was complimenting your work.
Please keep up the good work.
- Of course.
- All right, then. Good night.
- Enjoy.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
Ms. Lee, you should treat us.
Shopping District Association and the ward office all like you.
You're right.
After this is over, Lee Young Ae Design...
might take over all the work.
That won't happen.
Ms. Lee. Didn't you say that you got rid of...
your Seoul office when you moved to Jeju Island?
Pardon? Yes.
Do you have to find a new office?
Office rentals are expensive these days.
I looked into some, but they were all expensive.
What do you think about sharing office spaces, then?
Pardon? The Nakwon Printing office?
Yes.
We have to keep working together on the night market.
It'd be good to work in the same space.
Really?
I'm not sure. Let me think about it.
What's there to think about?
Yes, Dong Hyuk. What?
I can't hear you. I'll call you back.
She wants to talk to her boyfriend...
in secrecy.
Are they really dating?
I think so.
I saw his eyes fixed on Ms. Lee during the talent show.
He has such strange taste.
Here's another person with weird taste.
Ms. Lee, isn't acorn jelly weird with curry?
No. They taste good together.
Do you want to try it?
That's disgusting.
- Sazal, you should've made jelly.
- Eat slowly.
Really? How long do you want me to wait?
Wait for what?
What's wrong?
The job is done. Why are you asking her to wait?
I can't bear to see you with Young Ja any more.
You better be careful.
What's wrong with him?
Mr. Lee, what are you doing?
- What did Dong Hyuk do? - Dong Hyuk this, Dong Hyuk that!
I thought you guys weren't close. Why do you keep saying his name?
You still call me Mr. Lee when we've dated for a year.
That's because I met you as my boss.
Are you jealous?
Yes, I am! What are you going to do?
How can I not be jealous?
People keep saying that you two look good together.
I keep seeing you and him together because of the night market.
How can I just walk around laughing?
We have to work together, that's why.
Then why did he whisper into your ear?
Whisper?
Right after the talent show!
I saw everything.
I saw him talk into your ear.
That's...
See, see, see? You can't say anything because there's something.
There isn't anything.
He told me my armpits ripped while I was dancing.
Here! Look! Happy?
Gosh. I didn't want to tell you because I was embarrassed.
Then why did he ask you to wait?
That's... I asked him to move Food Monsters with his truck.
I need to edit something on it.
Then why did you ask him and not me? I can move it for you.
- How can you carry this?
- I can do it.
Like this. See?
- What are you doing? Put it down. - Let me carry it to the office.
You don't think I can do it? I'll show you I'm capable.
Don't try to stop me.
Seriously.
What was that, Young Ja?
You're so cute, Mr. Lee.
I only have you, so please don't worry.
Okay?
Okay, I understand.
She's shameless to no end.
Just throw out that curry.
I'll get going, then. My boyfriend is picking me up.
Bye.
- Bye.
Gosh, my kids have to go to school early tomorrow.
Do you want to give this curry to your kids tomorrow?
No, thanks. That curry isn't even good. I don't want it!
- Bye, everyone.
- Take a little bit at least.
- Bye, Ms. La. - Good night.
Well, I called a designated driver.
- You guys should get going.
- Okay.
All of you better come to work on time tomorrow!
- Of course.
- Good night.
Get home safely.
Can he let us come in a little late tomorrow?
Cho Deok Jae, that piece of...
Darn it!
What's wrong, Mr. Cho?
Who did this?
Who did this to my car?
- Pardon? What happened?
- What's going on?
- My gosh!
- Oh, no. This is...
Gosh, it looks like someone bumped your car from behind.
Mr. Cho.
Did the driver leave a note anywhere?
No!
This is certainly a hit-and-run case.
Who did this? What kind of jerk did this to my car?
Mr. Cho, is there a black box in your car?
That's right!
It must've recorded everything that happened here.
Exactly.
I didn't buy it to save money.
Darn it!
If he had a black box,
it would've recorded us kissing here earlier.
I know. We would've been caught.
Wait a second.
Mr. Cho's truck is right there.
The black box in his car must show this area.
- You're right!
- Yes.
What should we do?
I don't know. This is crazy.
Mr. Cho.
Show us your black box footage.
Pardon me?
What for?
A prick hit my car from behind and ran away.
The whole thing must've been recorded in your black box footage.
What are you talking about?
There's no black box in his car. Aren't I right, Mr. Cho?
What are you saying?
That thing with the blinking light. That's your black box, right?
Gosh, he is saying that he doesn't have one.
- Let go. What's your problem?
- I'm just...
- My gosh!
- Oh, no.
- Gosh!
- Are you okay, Mr. Cho?
What was that about? Goodness gracious.
I almost broke my back because of you, Ms. Lee!
Why are you trying to stop me?
He's saying he doesn't have a black box, but you're not listening.
He has it! Stop being so annoying.
Mr. Cho, show me your black box footage.
- Mr. Cho, please be careful. - I don't have a black box.
What?
What are you talking about?
There's a holder for it right here.
I used to have it, but I got rid of it recently.
I don't have one now.
That can't be. I saw a light blinking earlier.
Hold on a second.
Did you do it, Mr. Cho?
Is that why you got rid of it?
That's probably why Ms. Lee tried to stop me.
Mr. Yoon and Mr. Jeong. Go find it.
- Okay. - Okay.
- Search the truck. - Okay.
Where did you hide it? Where is your black box?
What? You're not holding it.
Where on earth did you hide it?
Thank you.
Where is it?
Young Ja, thanks for all of your hard work today.
- It was my pleasure.
- Good night.
Let's go for a meal with Mr. Cho next time.
I'll buy the most expensive black box for him.
What?
You had steam coming out of your head because you were so jealous.
Well, that was just because of a misunderstanding.
I actually think he's a great guy.
- Get home safely. - Thanks.
Oh, Young Ja. You forgot this.
See you!
My goodness.
There have been many ups and downs in Young Ae's life,
but she now wants to be successful in both work and love.
The greedy Young Ae's love story will be continued...
Will it be continued?
Rude Miss Young Ae's risky love story...
will be continued in the next episode.
(Rude Miss Young Ae)
So Mr. Lee Seung Joon was the creditor?
You're turning 40 soon. How can you date secretly?
You must be looking for a place to live together.
It looks like your boyfriend wants to get married.
Have coffee with me.
Promise me
It looks like you're seeing someone seriously. Why didn't you tell me?
We broke up.
I wanted to marry her,
but she didn't feel the same way.
- Gosh, seriously.
- My goodness!
Mom.