Heard it Through the Grapevine
Episode 29
Is there something wrong
in Yi Ji's room?
Well, ma'am...
It's not her room.
I was just checking to see
if the walls are damp around here.
Good job.
Big Missus is going up.
Are you sleeping?
Are you here, Yi Ji?
Yes, what is it?
What are you doing here?
I'm picking a book to read.
We thought you were sleeping, ma'am.
I was just going through
some winter clothes.
Are you not sleepy?
It's not that late.
Why do you want me to sleep so early?
Aren't you going home?
I was helping her. It's not like I have
anything to do at home anyway.
Why?
You must go on a date with Mr. Dok.
I can't do it every day.
Collect all In Sang's clothes
and sell them to the shop.
Mom...
I'm sure he had other plans when he decided
to run away without anything.
Do as I say.
Yes, ma'am.
Good night, ma'am.
Get rid of that.
Yes, ma'am.
[Silence]
President Han said he'll be home late.
Okay.
All washed up, Jin Young?
Feeling great?
It's chilly!
Let's get dressed!
How cute!
Come here!
You're hungry, aren't you?
I'm home!
Okay.
Just a moment, please!
You can either come in or leave.
Is someone else here?
My friends.
It's me!
- Hello!
- Wow, it's the baby!
We carried around In Sang's luggage
in my car the whole day.
I had to lie to my chauffeur!
Thank you!
I was worried because we don't have
enough money to buy new clothes for him.
Come on in.
Shall we sit down?
We have guests!
I figured you might be concerned
if I told you in advance.
So I just brought them.
That's fine.
You have everything you need!
Quite wondrous, isn't it?
It looks like a movie set.
How do you have a sex life here?
Do you even have one?
Do you play music and muffle
each other's mouth?
- Guys...
- Sit down.
Sit.
You must thank me.
She says she was very direct
with In Sang's mother that day.
That's why she gave up.
Don't try to take credit for
what you didn't do.
You're the one who
thanked me that day.
I thank you for telling her
the truth...
But she hasn't given up yet.
Really?
Even though you're living like this?
I guess she's waiting to see
how long he'll last.
Frankly, I'm the same.
Wouldn't he get sick of this life?
Don't let go of In Sang.
I loved seeing the mothers being speechless.
It sounds like you're using us.
That's right!
She wants you to be on her side.
Please use us frequently!
I will.
You all have the spirit of evil!
We must make her give up completely!
I wonder if that's even possible.
We must make it possible.
What if you can't?
Yi Ji is quite smart.
She knew exactly what we needed...
Yes.
I told her to bring me the things
that I used to use.
Is that okay?
Of course it is!
I don't want to offend
your generosity...
You're not offending anyone!
It'd be great if I can buy you
everything brand new, but...
We can't give you anything
monetary...
But we can give you our hearts!
Yes, of course I know!
We're glad that you know.
You're only getting compliments these days!
I'm not sure if they'll be able to live on.
His parents won't give up so easily!
Well...
It'd be great if they can
visit each other and stuff...
but the problem is that they're all out
to cut ties with each other!
Look at this cutie!
I can't cut ties with this cute one!
It all depends on your father, Jin Young!
Just stop caring!
He'll come back sooner if
we don't show any lingering affection.
Don't call him, and
certainly don't go to see him!
Of course.
Go home.
The spinach soup is good tonight.
Okay.
Almost done.
That's not necessary.
I'm done with my classes early today.
I'll be back around two.
Can you come over here?
Why?
Is something wrong?
No.
Don't try too hard.
You can't wear yourself out too much.
Okay.
See you later.
I'm leaving!
- Goodbye.
- Take care!
Okay.
Hello!
I assume your graveyard shift
is pretty tiring!
No, I'm fine.
I've used the bathroom outside already.
You don't have to leave early because of me.
You care too much about everything!
Just don't fall asleep during class!
Okay, goodbye!
Come up!
I'm coming!
I don't know if the owner is making any money
after hiring two part-time workers.
The owner has another job.
And the store is paid off too.
It'd be difficult for him to survive
if the store was his only source of income.
A lot of convenience stores
are closing these days.
But the new ones keep popping up.
That's what's so crazy.
I guess you're curious about
how laypeople survive.
Yes...
Now that it has become my problem...
But I'm concerned.
Both of you should continue your studies.
I've applied for a part-time job
at my school.
There are not many openings
these days though...
But a job there will be better
than the job at the store.
Bom will be able to take a break too.
Wouldn't it be great if the government
takes care of all that?
They should support student parents!
That'll encourage people to have more babies!
That's right.
I don't know if such day will come.
You must be tired because of Jin Young.
Don't be sorry.
I may be tired, but he's still cute!
How cute!
We're sorry for your parents.
Only we get to enjoy his cuteness.
They must be missing him.
There's nothing I can do.
I'm being very cold.
But why is there no response?
Be honest.
Yes, sure...
I'll pinpoint two mistakes
of you and your husband.
First, the fact that you tried to
secretly give money to your in-laws.
Second, the fact that you changed
the content of the contract.
Those were very dishonorable...
I'm sorry.
Those were a bit extreme.
Figure out a time for that place.
Okay.
Be careful.
They might resort to foul play.
There used to be a time when
the whole country got riled up...
by the smallest moral indeficiency
of the prime ministerial candidate.
But now...
people don't expect everything to be perfect
about the candidate.
People don't care about shady real estate
transactions or military service problems!
Because that's what everyone in the
top one percent of this country does...
everyone wants to do them too
instead of getting angry at them.
Have you ever heard?
"Enlighten! By that, people will
fall into deeper sleep."
The people who used to be intoxicated by their
shallow knowledge of how this world works...
are now all sleeping!
I don't have to try so hard.
There's no need for me to pay a lot of money
for your informational reports.
So you finally feel threatened by me.
I thought you've become completely
desensitized.
I like to see that.
What should I give you
as my final gift?
Don't rush it.
You should stay at least until
the confirmation hearing is done.
Let's see if I'm right or wrong
together.
I will.
You're not allowed to join them
to prepare for the confirmation hearing?
That's right.
He has transferred your work
to Secretary Yang.
I know.
Apparently there has been a deal.
President Han will turn a blind eye
to Secretary Yang's slush funds.
You often tell me juicy things.
I've done my time in this place.
Thank you.
I hope it'll be helpful.
I'm sure it wil be.
So all these are the new facts
that we just found out?
Yes, sir.
They must be added to the
list of things you know already.
I'm sorry to say this...
but he's a complete package
of corruption.
His son dodged the military draft
by coming up with a fake excuse.
His wife is involved in real estate
manipulation along with tax evasion.
His brothers-in-law and sisters-in-law...
How astonishing!
Why is everyone in the gutter?
I can't look at these anymore.
They studied law to join the
top one percent of Korea!
Then they should have known their limit!
They should have some sense of
social responsibility left in them!
I'll prepare a mock questionnaire.
His conscience gets covered up because
people like us keep protecting him!
I urge you to focus on the goal, sir.
Right.
Let's forget about my emotions,
for bigger things.
I think this is about everything.
Send a copy to the candidate.
Tell him to bring his PR man
to the rehearsal.
Yes, sir.
- He's here, sir.
- Bring him in.
- I'll take my leave, sir.
- Go ahead.
Welcome, sir!
I heard the preparation is done.
Yes, sir.
I'm sorry to cause you all this trouble.
Not at all.
Please sit down.
You must be busy.
Now I have to find a person
who'll ask questions during the rehearsal.
It seems like you've used
your last card.
I had no other choice.
The man is a piece of garbage,
but we must get him confirmed.
I bet.
I'm sorry that I've taken your work away.
But do you know what I did
in the past 32 hours?
I lived with the candidate in his house
and made him tell me everything.
I didn't see the need to do an investigation
like you.
Like what President Han often says...
"Tell me everything."
"One who confesses shall be
exempted from punishment."
No one will know our sins
better than ourselves.
I guess it'd be easy to prepare
for the answers.
As long as he doesn't do something stupid.
I'm still nervous even though
you're spoon-feeding me.
There's something special about that seat.
I haven't done an interview since
the time when I took the bar exam!
There'll be some sort of aggression.
The opposition has a part
they must play too.
I am aware of that.
Well...
Here's to your prompt confirmation!
We should meet up with Prime Minister Song
before he leaves office.
Yes, sir.
Wasn't he quite insistent on
leaving his son alone?
I'm afraid...
we must reconsider that problem.
Song Jae Won hasn't left the country yet?
I don't think it'll be necessary
to get him involved.
How?
Is there something else?
I'm afraid that it might
do us more harm.
It'd be the best to carry this out
as quietly as possible.
Indeed!
I'll do my best to block this issue
as soon as I become prime minister.
Everyone is involved!
I believe in you.
It can't be more perfect than that.
He'll say everything himself and the preparation
team will make excuses for his shortcomings.
I don't think the right questions
will be asked at this rate.
Everyone thinks he'll be confirmed anyway,
so there's no point in asking sharp questions.
President Han is hypnotizing
the committee.
We should still make some noise!
But this is making me angry.
I can't believe he said
everyone is asleep.
Does the opposition party members
have a similar report as that of Joo Young?
Or do you think they're being careful because
they don't want to reveal anthing either?
Three of the committee members
are relatively clean.
His chief of staff went to the
same college as me.
Let's try it.
Let's be more safe.
Try to poach the three staunch
members of the opposition.
It won't be difficult.
Meet me first.
I know that much at least.
You can't meet that woman first!
I'll be right there.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Change first!
Here.
I'll change in the taxi.
That's very uncomfortable!
Would you like to eat this?
Great!
I haven't eaten yet.
So, how did you manage
to come here in the morning?
I have the afternoon shift today.
Meeting a man like that
can be extremely risky.
I think so, too.
Or you can take
a bigger risk for a bigger reward.
Look here, Jin Young!
Good, Jin Young!
One more!
You too, Bom!
My heart is aching.
You can sit down now.
I was told to take
as many pictures as possible.
How's everyone doing?
Depressed.
The whole house feels empty.
How pretty!
Big Missus would like to see Jin Young.
I'm sorry, but you will have to
talk to Jin Young's parents.
- Grandma, come here!
- Okay!
What if he gets tired?
Smile!
Mommy!
Grandma!
Do you want to just go crazy
and beg for mercy with my brother?
My parents have soft spots too.
Forget it.
Whatever that might come after begging
will be the real problem.
You know it.
There's just no good way out of this.
Just think of this as
the way out.
Okay.
Enjoy your life while you can.
I'm sure my parents will
change their minds eventually.
How could you be like that?
Like what?
You know everything.
Bad girl.
You must look at him from afar
as I've told you before.
Why must I?
I've explained it to you
more than enough times already.
I'm good at that too.
I agree, but...
I can't blame anyone else but
In Sang's stupidity.
But you and your husband
provided the original reason.
His mother did!
The person in charge has gone
to a meeting at the district office today.
The facility looks pretty good.
See if this nursery can be connected to our
firm's corporate social responsibility program.
Yes, sir.
I've contacted the head of this nursery.
Why don't you look around for now?
Is it going to take a while?
She said she'll be here
as soon as possible.
He's just showing off!
I can show off too!
Why are you doing this?
What do you mean?
I thought he's usually here at this hour.
Should I look for him?
Be careful, he might resort to
foul play.
He is here to see if he can be of any help
to this nursery...
in regard to Hansong's new
corporate social responsibility initiative.
Yes, sir.
Why are you alone?
Where is the baby?
Jin Young is with my mother.
Let's talk, since I'm here already.
I...
believe there's a serious deficiency
in your motherly instinct.
A concern is that as Jin Young's mother, you have
no idea what you're doing to him right now.
The normal thing to do here is
showing me Jin Young right now.
You wish your son to
not know his grandfather?
It's because you did not
keep your promise.
You'll be able to see Jin Young again
only when...
In Sang and I believe that you're
trustworthy again.
And you'll be the judge of that?
He's not leaving.
Why?
There's a world of difference between
what you can offer Jin Young...
and what I can offer him!
Do you agree?
No.
What's your reason?
Aren't you aware of the time
that we live in?
I'll tell you honestly since
there seems to be no one watching us.
What are you going to tell me?
I'm sure it'll be very fortunate for a kid to
grow up with the best of everything.
But if people like you can use your power
positively to create a system in which...
the kids who are less fortunate can
still grow up to be good citizens...
What I mean is...
I hope the kids without rich grandparents
can become successful too...
A man will think he's done something generous
every time he does something for others.
But the system doesn't think like that.
Are you saying that I show off
my generosity?
I'm sorry.
Delusions are worse than epidemics.
I hope your symptoms won't get any worse.
Goodbye.
I'll be watching you.
First floor.
The door is closing.
I didn't tell him that you were here.
What should I do about her?
How could she show absolutely
no sign of repentance?
I'm not sure...
You're certain that she didn't see me, right?
Do you think her mom will tell her?
I'm not sure about that either.
I'm worried.
We must lay down some rules.
That would be pointless.
To them, they make the rules.
They should've just said
they miss Jin Young!
Did they think I'd ignore
their feelings for Jin Young?
If anything, I understand that they probably
miss Jin Young as mush as I used to!
That doesn't seem to be the case.
Let's go home!
Okay.
Everyone including the district chief
was surprised to hear that you paid a visit.
So what did you tell them?
That it was just a tour.
Good job.
I heard you went to somewhere today.
Yes.
Where?
Tell Secretary Lee to go home.
Okay.
So you're the only one who
knows the whole thing!
Dad is the only one who doesn't know!
What are they doing over
this cute thing?
I guess they can't help
but to be attached to their blood!
Doesn't that mean that they should be
willing to give up their pride for him?
How handsome!
How's the preparation for
Mr. Kim's confirmation hearing going?
Well.
People are talking about it.
They'll get quiet soon.
Everyone has the brain of a bird.
What kind of brain do you have?
I saw you leaving empty-handed
after making all those calculations.
I did?
From where?
Forget about it if you don't know
what I'm talking about.
Did you see me?
I told you not to go there.
Tell me if you saw me there!
In Sang is very much like you
when it comes to being stupid.
What?
I connected you since
you applied for it...
But I still don't understand.
Why a guy like you would apply
to be a part-time tutor.
A guy like me?
Everyone knows that you're studying
for the bar exam...
with the help of the star tutor,
Mr. Dok.
Well...
I've put it off due to
personal reasons.
What personal reasons?
Changing your plans?
I'm thinking about it.
Are you not confident?
I guess your father also passed it
with flying colors.
I assume the pressure on you
is quite high.
I've written this down
on the application form too...
But I'd like to teach kids
that pay well.
Okay, I'll accommodate.
Even though I don't understand.
Look here.
A 10th grader who needs help
with homework in Math and English.
You can see the parents
at their home.
The pay is the highest, but the mom
can be quite picky.
I'll go see her.
But what's your reason?
Do your parents know?
No...
It doesn't matter if they know.
But...
Nice to see you.
Hello.
Thanks for coming.
Not at all.
I must thank you.
Please sit down.
Tea?
The school has confirmed your identity...
I see that your father's an attorney?
Yes.
At a law firm?
Or a private office?
The latter.
Where is the office?
Near Gwanghwamoon.
I saw that your address was
One Hangang Street.
Is that an apartment building?
No, it's a private house.
You heard that you'll be helping out
with the schoolwork, right?
Yes.
How did you study
for your classes?
I did it my way.
Then you must know very well.
The classes for English and Math
will be on Saturdays and Sundays.
I want you to go over the day's materials
before each class...
and help with the homework.
The tutoring sessions will start
at 11 p.m. and last for two hours.
Would that be possible?
Yes.
Since it'll be late, I'll pay for
your taxi rides home.
There'll be a set regular pay,
but on top of it...
there'll be monthly incentives dependant
on the schoolteachers' opinion.
Somewhere between 100,000 won
and 150,000 won.
It felt so weird.
She was my mom's age, but normal.
A war like atmosphere, no? The competition for
college entrance is just beginning.
People like you who are willing to pay
anything for a tutor has created this phenomenon.
Giving false hopes to parents.
It's not my fault...
But I do feel partially responsible.
I think you'll be very uncomfortable.
I don't think you should tutor kids.
She's right.
I'm not going back to the academy.
The bar exam format will be reformed too.
Then what will you do?
I guess the marriage comes first.
- What?
- With who?
She's right there.
Hello.
How have you been?
- We just heard.
- Congratulations.
How embarrassing.
There's no need!
Why would you be embarrassed?
We already have a kid!
That's a successful life!
Do your colleagues know?
Of course they do.
How about my mom?
We'll tell her soon.
Then...
I'm quitting.
What?
Both of us want to do something else.
That's right.
You don't have to be so formal with me.
What do you want to do?
You're very interested in jobs
these days, aren't you?
I suppose I am...
May I ask if the two of you are
going to continue with your studies or not?
Are both of you stopping?
Or are you both continuing?
Or is one going to support
the other?
Tell us once you make the decision.
That'll be 19,000 won.
Please sign here.
- Do you need the receipt?
- Yes.
Thank you!
Goodbye!
So what do you think?
You?
I really want to do it now.
I'll pass the exam and walk
a completely different path than my father.
I told him the same thing too.
To whom?
Your father came.
What?
He stopped by to take a brief look at
Jin Young but I ran into him.
Then I told him straight.
I told him that I don't know what he means
when he says he's doing things for Jin Young.
That if I could, I'll create a place in which
kids can succeed without rich grandfathers.
His way of thinking is indeed different.
So he cares for Jin Young,
but still insists on being that 0.1 percent.
Isn't that scary?
Shouldn't everyone live together happily?
It'd be great if we can study together, no?
But there's no guarantee.
Look, we can barely get 1.4 million won by
working here 6 hours a day, five times a week.
And for you, you can only study if
your mom looks after Jin Young!
It's just impossible for
the both of us to study.
We'll have to consider ourselves dead
for a year and a half.
If we have to choose one...
wouldn't you have a better chance than me?
Why?
On that mock test, you got more
difficult questions right.
That's an advantage.
That's not a good indication.
Should we decide by rock paper scissors?
That's fair.
We'll reach a conclusion once we put
some more thought into it.
I hope so.
I hope that I will be able to extinguish every
single piece of doubt out there about me...
So I promise to answer
with only the truth.
I'd like to talk about this
"Supernova" rumor.
I know nothing about it.
Those accusations that my brother-in-law
made two billion won with 100 million won...
is groundless.
Do you think that makes sense?
What kind of idiot would only invest 100 million
won in a scheme that would twentyfold his money?
They need to turn off the microphone...
I'm sorry, I couldn't control my emotions
and said something inappropriate.
If I may say this again...
I don't have anything to do with
that rumor.
I've never heard anything about it,
and know nothing about it.
This is a conspiracy against me.
That's not true either.
If I do say so myself...
I hate white collar finance criminals
the most.
Mr. Kim Jin Seong has been confirmed
as the next prime minister of South Korea.
I hate white collar finance criminals
the most.
Mr. Kim Jin Seong has been confirmed
as the next prime minister of South Korea.
The Parliament's vote, which happened
at 3 p.m. today...
showed 198 yeas and 80 nays
out of 281 total members.
It seems like 50 out of 130 members
of opposition voted in favor of Mr. Kim.
The other party let its members vote based
solely on their personal convictions
and this is the reason why the confirmation
process has ended very smoothly.
Now that he's confirmed, the president will
meet with Mr. Kim tonight...
to talk about reshuffling the cabinet.
Mr. Kim start his official duties as
prime minister tomorrow.
You must be relieved.
Well done.
Let me shake your hand.
It's my honor, sir.
So I guess the Han Trust won't be
mentioned for a while.
You and your brother will be safe too.
All thanks to you, sir.
Go home early and get some rest.
Thank you, sir.
Well done, ma'am.
Congratulations.
That's not necessary.
I was worried that your brother
might become the scapegoat...
once the Han family's foreign bank
accounts get revealed.
Indeed.
I gave my everything to this
because I can't let that happen.
You've managed to protect your brother.
Yes, I have.
You must be happy.
Yes.
I think it'll be prudent of you to refrain from
showing your happiness in front of Joo Young...
It's fine.
This isn't the end.
Is that so?
There's Yang Jae Hwa, who wants to
safeguard her money.
Then there's Min Joo Young, who
wants to recover her brother's tainted name.
We'll see who might be the stronger one.
Don't be like that.
It's scary.
This is why people laugh at us.
They did not use any of our questions.
How could everyone be so easy on him?
It was a comedy show!
Yang Jae Hwa did well.
She showed the members what she
knows about them.
The times when they frequented
massage parlors and saloons...
when they got into fights with people,
their overdue loans...
We can't reveal a corruption case
that's 100 times bigger than those...
because people are afraid that those
petty things will be found out.
Hello.
How's the runaway life?
I guess you can come back now.
What?
How are you in Korea?
If I tell you how I managed to stay in Korea
and continue to enjoy my Seoul life...
would you change your world view a bit?
I said one thing to President Han.
That changed the scapegoat.
Do you think I would ever
pledge my alligence to that guy?
I just promised him to fill his
empty forehead.
I introduced him to my doctor
who specializes in hair transplants.
You can't beat him.
You can't even afford to be his enemy.
Selecting the judging panel
might be random...
but everyone defers to him!
All the judges want to go to places
like Hansong once their retire!
How can you expect them to rule
against corporations then?
Don't waste your time and energy.
Let's just blind ourselves
and live happily.
I'm sorry, but I have a happier life.
And your hair joke was very bad.
Song Jae Won?
Yes.
He used to treat criminals very well.
It was all possible because he had
those safety nets like that.
How are you friends with him?
Figurine collections.
You're quite something.
When I go to his bar, I get to find out
more about the elite class of this country.
Everything about President Han's
family too.
So, did President Han get
a date for the surgery?
Of course!
He said he'll do it at the end of this month
and treat it like his summer vacation!
How fortunate!
But who's the new scapegoat?
Secretary Yang's brother is the head
of the Han Trust.
Wow!
It seems like it'll pass without
a problem...
But it seems like Secretary Yang told
President Han to arrest her own brother...
if things come up to the surface.
She's so loyal!
I'm sure he'll be compensated well
if he does a year or two in prison!
I bet he wouldn't do any prison time!
This is how it should've been
from the beginning.
He didn't have to tell you
to leave the country!
I thought I'd be dead.
There's no better place to hang out
than Korea!
That's right.
I can't stay at the same place for more than
a month no matter how nice the place is.
So be careful from now on.
Stop startling us!
Of course.
Let's call up Yeon Hee.
I think you should wait.
I think she's still uncomfortable with me.
Why?
It was the kids' doing.
It's not entirely about the kids.
Everyone got embarrassed,
but she moreso than I.
This might be a good thing.
They might become too relaxed by
this new victory.
How could you be so positive?
Our goal is to continue
until the very end.
We'll connect the Han Trust and the
presidential election and the foreign accounts.
I like the attitude.
I'll go.
Probably the paralegal applicant.
I'm Park Gyung Tae.
I sent you an email.
For the paralegal opening?
- Yes.
- Come in.
Welcome.
I'm Yoon Je Hoon.
This way.
It's nice to meet everyone.
But is this the interview right now?
In a way, yes.
- Here.
- Thank you.
How did you find out about us?
I'm sure you know Han In Sang.
I see...
Yes.
His running away from home has given me
an opportunity to switch my career.
So you came here knowing everything.
Yes.
You're Ms. Min Joo Young...
Yes...
I'm Seo Bom's uncle.
Nice to see you.
We met several days ago
with In Sang.
Right.
He has a class at ten o'clock today.
Did he have breakfast?
Should I call him and tell him
to go to school?
Leave him alone!
He looks so tired.
Missing a day won't do anything!
Anyway, I'm leaving now.
He might still be asleep
when you come home.
I'm telling you in advance
so you don't get startled when you get home.
Okay.
We've contacted everyone
in this line.
Those will be sold soon.
How much per household?
I'm thinking 1.5 times higher
than market price.
The new construction is still being
planned out...
But you must sign a contract that binds you
to vacate the unit within a certain timeframe...
as soon as you sign the
general sales contract.
So when would that be?
I'm not sure.
If you'll vacate the place before that,
please give me a call to that number.
I don't think that would happen.
I'm not forcing this on you.
I'll get going then.
Goodbye.
I shouldn't have sold it back then.
You had to sell it!
You couldn't even afford the interest.
If I had managed to keep the property,
the kids would be living much better lives!
It pains me to think about it.
Excuse me...
Why didn't you go to school?
I overslept.
I'm on my way now.
A hard worker!
Not that...
How we live has exceeded your
wildest imaginations, hasn't it?
We sometimes have very
startling moments too.
Why?
I'm curious about that too.
You should study hard and teach me!
I'm just kidding.
You should get going.
Yes.
You're up!
Are you okay?
Yes, why?
I came because I was worried.
I'll be back.
One of us must make money.
Just go!
Likes attract like.
I'm sure it's upsetting for you.
But you must respond logically.
Are you scared?
Or do you want me to be scared?
Of course their next steps
are very obvious.
They'll have no regard for politeness and just
continue to create noise in every way possible.
But everyone will be sick of that soon.
I don't even care about being sick of them.
They're just annoying.
- I'm coming in
- Yes, ma'am.
What happened to Mr. Park?
Well...
Is In Sang still meeting up with him?
If that's the case, I'll really disown him!
Secretary Lee!
Yes?
Is Mr. Park seeing the kids?
You must know.
Well...
I don't think this is the appropriate time...
[Resignation Letter]
What is that?
It is only natural for Secretary Lee
to leave too.
Are they dating?
You can only go after I leave.
Where are you going?
Study abroad.
I'll go when she goes.
Then the sides will become too obvious.
The sides?
Be responsible!
We won't stop you.
But you can only leave once you find
your replacement and train her.
- That's how we'll process it.
- Yes, sir.
- Everyone...
- Come down from there.
Don't lord over us.
Darling...
This is a betrayal, right?
Subtitles by DramaFever
You ran away from your home
to hinder your wife like this?
We must think again to see
if our life goal is really that.
You must come up with a strategy.
No need to look back.
Once you have an opportunity...
Will you be okay?
Go with me.