I'm going to bed.
- You drink one glass of wine and you fall asleep.
- It was two.
You'll get your masters,
Miss. 3-day student.
- Do you think it's an accident?
- Who would want to kill princess Dy?
She's so young and so beautifull!
I'm going to sleep.
Jony, don't forget to feed kitty.
Kitty, kitty, dinner time!
Turn the music down!
Kitty, kitty, dinner's ready.
Kitty!
Kitty, kitty, dinner is ready.
Kitty, dinner's ready.
Why didn't you feed the cat, already?
Hey, shut that damn cat off.
What is your name?
Chainy. Kates.
And the deceased was your sister?
Her name is Jony.
We are twins.
Were you able to see
who did this?
Just a glimps.
It was dark.
I'm not certain.
It is my opinion as a forensic psychiatrist
that John Forster is a serial psychopath.
If allowed to remain a free man in our society,
he will rape ang murder again.
Will the defendant, please, rise.
We, the jury, on this day, November 9th 1998,
find the defendant John Forster guilty
of murder in the first degree.
Oh, I've seen that outfit before.
I can't remember when.
Last night. Last night!
These things do return.
God, my head is still
pounding like a drum.
You party hard.
Yeah, well, you don't
look worse than I am.
I didn't drink as much as you.
History of my life, Sara.
Psychiatrist by day,
party animal by night.
I thought you've told
me you were a lawyer.
I'm not, yet.
Excuse me.
Yeah. Hey, Jack. It's Shelly.
I've been calling all morning.
You OK? I'm Ok. What's up?
I was worried.
You worry too much,
Shelly. What's going on?
Frank Parks is been calling. He
needs to speak with you immediately.
Pass him through.
I had fun last night, Miss. Pollard.
Me too.
Thanks for the wine tasting, Dr. Gramm.
Jack.
Hey, Jack, I've got
Frank Parks. Go ahead.
Hey, Frank. Jack.
We got another one.
Oh, no. The same?
Every detail.
Right down to the lateral laceration.
It's the Seattle slayer again.
Where are you now? Look, Jack.
There's a tape.
You're gonna wanna see it.
Jack, are you still there?
Yeah.
Meet me at my office, okay?
Sure, Jack.
Where to?
114 Western, please. Quickly.
Welcome back, Seattle.
We're continuing our
interview with John Forster...
Who was convicted for the death
of Janie Kay, nine years ago...
Based on the eyewitness testimony
of her twin sister, Janie Kay.
John Forster was dated to die at
midnight, at Walla Walla Penitentiary.
Do you mind changing it? John Forster.
What's your reaction to the State...
Thank you.
Congratulations!
For what?
I was referring to the hottie that
you left with the party last night.
She was a quite piece of ass.
Remember her name? Yes, I do.
Sara Pollard.
Is that a cut on your nose? You
didn't have that before I left.
I fell out of the bed. FBI hit here yet?
Yeah, 2 minutes in the
conference room. Okay.
Any calls?
New York Times,
Washington times, Newsweek.
They all wanna know if you have
a quote about Forster's execution.
What else is new? Kim
Cummings called twice.
She was worried about you
too. Kim knows this procedure.
Apparently not. She's in your office.
Jack Gramm Associates.
I put those case reports you
wanna me to look at on your desk.
I thought Lauren and Leeza
showed real insight and ability.
The others were pretty
much working the math.
Yeah.
Don't you have Federal
Agents waiting for you?
Yeah.
I' see you in class.
I'll take them trough
today's work if you run late.
Thanks.
Thank you, Kim. Bye.
Janie Keith came by
to give you a present.
Dr. Gramm.
I'm sorry. I don't know
if this is appropriate...
I just wanted to...
I just wanted to mark the day.
Thank you, Janie.
I'm glad that my sister Janie
hasn't been forgotten. Thank you.
For everything. You
went out of your way.
You are busy, so I'm just...
I'm gonna get out of here.
We did good, Janie. We did good.
All right.
Thanks.
Can I help you?
You are one of my students?
Hi.
Jack. Yeah.
I'd like to introduce you to Jeremy
Goober, with attorney general office.
Jeremy is in charge of the
Seattle slayer task force.
Dr. Gramm, it's so good to meet you.
This is a really big honor for me.
Sorry about the...
Oh, this is such a beautiful
conference room too.
And this special agent
MacTire from the FBI.
Dr. Gramm.
Pleasure. Have a seat.
Hey, big fellow?
Yes.
Jeremy.
Seattle slayer task force.
Well, okay. I'm sure you
have a lot of questions.
I'll do the best I can to
answer them, but first I...
No. First I think we
should all have a cookie.
These are from Janie Kay, whose sister,
Janie was murdered by John Forster.
Jeremy? Sure, thank you.
Frank? No, thanks, Jack.
No?
Mr. MacTire?
You are a good sport, Jeremy.
A little milk maybe, what do you think?
Shelley, we got milk, don't
we? Bring in three glasses.
Nothing for me, Jack.
All right, make that two.
No, make it three.
Maybe you have a change of heart.
So, let's see...
I can assume...
That last night crime scene...
Was very much like Forster's
previous crime scene, right?
They totally match, yeah.
What totally matches?
I have in here...
Halothane on the breath.
Subdued by Halothane.
Rape. Yeah.
The body was hung up side down.
Yes.
And...
Slashed throat.
And where this takes us?
Looks like a copy cat.
It could be. Maybe Could be? Maybe?
Maybe. It's a stage scene. Maybe what?
Maybe, and this might be far-Fetched...
But what if the perp
worked with Forster...
And these stage scenes were intended to
throw some doubts on his guilty verdict?
Go with it. Possibly providing him...
With a stay of execution
or even a new trial.
Goal star, Jeremy. Big goal star.
I mean, that's exactly what
I think is happening here.
No, I'm sticking with copy cat.
Of course there is another possibility.
Yeah? Forster is innocent.
Wrongly convicted. No!
The task force is aware...
That your expert opinion was
critical in convicting Forster.
But then why he walked his first trial?
Procedural error.
Why is he never been tried in any of
the other five pending murderers...
That you've attributed to him?
You realize that it is the dude of my
office to ensure that an innocent man...
Is not executed tonight.
You do understand that?
Look, Jack. If you have any
reconsideration of testimony...
Or anything new you
wanna lay on the table...
Now it would be the time.
Would you say it was
fair to characterize...
Your attitude towards John Forster...
As a personal vendetta? Lf
we're been fair, yeah, sure.
It's a personal vendetta. I have a
personal vendetta against Ted Bundy...
And Gacy and about 10 or
15 other serial murders...
That are on the streets
right now. Jack, please.
That's helpful.
There is one other issue
that we need to address.
Milk maid.
What's going on here?
Do you know a woman named Dale Morris?
Yes.
How?
She's a student of mine.
She's just a student of yours?
Dr. Gramm, we're federal agency
here. You don't wanna be lying here.
We had a relationship. You've
been very cryptic right now?
He had a professional relationship,
not a sexual relationship.
About a year ago her father
died. She was very troubled.
I treated her as psychiatrist.
I don't sleep with my
students, Mr. Goober.
Neither I sleep with my patients.
Now what does this have to
do with anything? Anyway.
Jack.
Dale Morris was murdered last night.
She's the third and latest victim.
When was the last time you saw Dale?
Well...
I saw...
I saw her last night.
To our impossibly difficult professor.
We say thank you...
For making our lives miserable.
The pleasure is all mine.
We're celebrating.
You're celebrating
Forster's pending execution?
No, we're celebrating his
conviction, not his execution.
It was an overturn so we're happy about that.
We worked hard on this case.
We have a tape that was
left on the crime scene.
We're gonna play it for you now.
This message is for Dr. Jack Gramm.
You got the wrong man.
Forster is innocent.
Please, don't hurt me anymore.
Don't hurt me anymore.
You gonna let me go, right?
You said you'd let me go. I've
read what you want me and...
Jack, it goes like that for
about an hour, before she dies.
Why do you think she was reading
you that message, Dr. Gramm?
Dr. Gramm?
In Dr. Gramm own words...
He analyzes a mental puzzle.
So they're no actual
tangible pieces per say.
He made a guess based
on what happened to Kate.
A guess based on his
intuition, a personal bias, ego.
And he sold that fiction lock,
stock and barrel to the jury.
What is it?
The girl that was killed last night...
Was Dale Morris. Dale?
Oh, my God.
Okay, let's see...
We have our investigators
coordinated with the FBI...
I wanna know everything Dale
Morris did on the last 24 hours.
I wanna know where she
went, who she talked to.
Can you please have Dr. Gramm's
car ready, please. Thank you.
Thank you, Shelley.
For what?
I don't know. For everything.
I hate when you do this, Jack.
Every time you o this, I
think you gonna end up dead.
Just don't ask me to marry you again.
Why not? We're perfect for each other.
Yeah, yeah. Except that I'm
gay and you're commitment phobe.
That's why we're perfect.
Thanks, baby.
Dr. Gramm is a world known
expert in forensic psychiatry.
What is forensic psychiatry?
I mean, is not the same profession
that destroyed MacMorton's life...
By conjuring up images
of child molestation?
None of the charges were ever proved.
And the accused, though innocent...
Was public crucified.
Jack, look. Look at the kite.
Jack, come here.
Yeah?
Hello?
You have 88 minutes to live.
What?
You know how long 88
minutes can be, don't you?
That's 11:45 am. Who is this?
Tic-Tac. Who the hell is this?
Tic-Tac.
What were you saying?
Jack Gramm Associates. Shelley?
I want you to set a trap
and and a trace on my cell.
What's going on?
I want you to contact
a wireless carrier...
And have them find out who
made that last phone call to me.
Jack, I could be more
helpful if... Just do it.
Just do it. I need it, all right?
And call me when you get it.
John Forster was an Eagle Scout, which
counts for his facility with ropes.
He also worked in a veterinary office...
Where he had experience using the
animal tranquilizer Halothane...
Witch he's used to subdue his victims.
Halothane. Sorry, I'm
late again. Thank you, Kim.
I see that the size of our
class is dwindling once again.
It could be because you
keep booting everyone.
My favorite student, Mike Stempt.
Okay. The legal distinction between
sanity and insanity rests upon what?
Free will. The concept of the free will.
And what is the most important thing...
One should remember when
entering a court-Room?
That insanity it's a legal concept.
It's not a medical or psychiatric term.
But despite the fact that
insanity is a legal concept...
It doesn't mean that
someone is not sick.
Yes, Lauren.
Of all the serial killers that
I've interviewed and studied...
Witch include our boy
Bundy, Dahmer, Gacy...
None of them was legally insane.
This is not saying
that they were normal.
I could argue that they
couldn't help themselves...
Precisely because of
their mental disorder.
Well, if you wanna argue, Mike...
School of law is across campus.
Come on, Dr. Gramm.
It's ingenuous to pretend that our
presentations are not arguments.
We create a narrative of
the crime and the criminal.
Narrative is based on
facts. Based on logic.
We don't walk into a court-Room
and advocate set scenes, do we?
We don't take sides. We
check our views at the door.
You mean you want us to pretend
we don't have an opinion?
We have opinions, Lauren, but
we just keep them to ourselves.
Share them with your
dog, if you have to.
Not with your parrot,
because it talks back.
It is that kind of logic that's gonna
get you in a law school across campus.
I've been there. I've done that.
Well, my condolences.
So, where is...
Dale Morris? She's
absent. I don't see her.
That's her first.
I didn't take her for a quitter.
Anyone who has her phone number,
please, contact me after class.
Okay.
Excuse me.
Shelley.
Tick-Tack, doc. You have 83
minutes to live, Dr. Gramm.
Tick-Tack, doc.
So where was I?
Bundy versus Forster.
What? Bundy versus Forster.
Thank you, Lauren.
You're welcome.
What we're gonna explore today is the
similarities and dissimilarities...
Say, from Ted Bundy's motives, let's
compared them to John Forster's.
Dr. Gramm, your phone is ringing.
Jack, are you there?
Shelley. What's going on?
The call was made from a cell phone.
One of those you buy
and pay minutes for it.
Registered to whom?
Look, I know you're in class,
but... Yes, who is registered to it?
A Kate Gramm.
Jack, it's a common name. It
doesn't have to be your sister.
It's just a coincidence.
It's not a coincidence.
Jack, I'm loosing you.
Shelley? Goddamn it!
Shelley?
Have you found out who my
phone is registered to by now?
Poor Kate. If it was Kate,
you'd like to call her?
I'm gonna find you, you here
that, you son-Of-A-Bitch?
You're barking up the
wrong tree on this one.
I'm gonna find you.
She suffered for such a long time.
You remember how long, don't you?
You still feel guilty about her?
You feel guilty about
falsifying the evidence?
For lying under oath?
Tic-Tac, doc. You have
79 minutes to live.
Do you find this funny, Albert?
Who were you calling on your phone?
Let me see your phone.
I was just...
Let me see that goddamn it phone.
I was just checking the Mariners score.
You were what? I was
checking the Mariners score.
Okay, what is the score?
The score.
What's the damn score?
It's 3 x 1 Mariners. B1.
Oh, my God, I can't believe it. What
does it mean? What's the problem?
Look.
What?
What's going on here?
It says that Dale Morris
was murdered last night.
Is that true, Dr. Gramm? Yeah.
You knew it? You knew it
and you didn't tell us?
You knew and asked for Dale's
number? Is it the slayer?
It could be. It could be?
Well, the police haven't
released any information yet.
Are we all in danger? I can't
believe you didn't tell us.
Dr. Gramm? Lynn Johnson.
Someone just called a bomb threat.
Everyone is to evacuate the
building immediately. Thank you.
Come on. Grab your stuff.
I'll get your papers
of presentation, Tom.
I got the slides, Kim.
All students, faculty and staff
must evacuate the building.
I repeat. Everyone must
evacuate the building.
All students, faculty and staff
must evacuate the building.
I repeat. Everyone must
evacuate the building.
Please, remain calm e do not run.
Proceed to the door to
the end of the campus.
I repeat. We must evacuate the building.
Jack? What are you doing? Get going.
All students, faculty and staff
must evacuate the building.
What was that on the screen?
Some student playing
a joke or something.
You of all people know that it breaks
school laws to proceed by a threat...
You need to report this to the
campus security immediately.
Carol. I get threat like this,
three or four times a year.
Your incredible arrogance will
slap the shit of you, Jack.
I wish you'd disclosure your
true feelings about me...
Before we became such good friends.
Maybe you should stop hiding behind
your assessments about other people...
And start assessing yourself...
Cause you need to get over your
past and go on with your life...
Cause what you're living isn't one.
It is not what you tell your patients?
Gum? Thank you.
I'll call campus security and
let them know you're on your way.
Where did you go last
night? When you left the bar.
Home.
Were you alone?
Screw you.
Roger. We're on it.
Yeah.
The press got a hold of Dale's
name. It's all over the news.
Yeah, I know that.
And Forster's attorney is going
to the court and try a stay.
A stay? On what grounds?
They're claiming that these...
Murders prove that the real killer
have never been brought to justice.
Nonsense. They're just trying
to buy time. They're desperate.
They're also claiming that you falsify
testimony and concealed evidences.
Well, it's all loose. Goddamn it.
Who is that guy?
What about Dale Morris?
Did we find anymore of her?
She was murdered in her apartment...
Between the hours of two and six am.
Any sign of force entry? No.
Does Forster still have that
group visiting him on prison?
He's like a goddamn rock
star. Website and all.
I want you to pull a background
check on all my students...
And get back to me.
Damn.
Oh, no.
Okay.
Kim? What are you doing here?
I'm getting my car, it's parked here...
Like it's every day
I come to the campus.
That was really horrible. Just
horrible what you did in class...
It's was little low for you. I
was looking for potential suspects.
That's what I was doing. What did you
do after you left the party last night?
I didn't end up drunk in
bed with an strange like you.
You left the party with Dale Morris,
the girl that was murdered, didn't you?
Yes, I did. So what did
you do? Where did you go?
You're not seriously considering...
Where did you go?
We went to the Hickory Stick.
We had a drink, two drinks.
And then? And then I went home alone.
You have anyone that can verify
that? No. No-One can verify it.
Come on. I've been your
teaching assistant for two years.
I'm your friend. I'm here
to help you, if you let me.
Follow me.
Who did that?
What does that mean?
According to a anonymous phone call...
That means I have 72
minutes left to live.
Can I borrow your cell phone?
I've broke mine.
These are my car keys.
Can you take that around front
and meet me there in ten minutes?
I have to go to the
campus security. Okay.
Call me on my Blackberry
if you run late.
Okay.
Shelley. You gonna have to
reach me on Kim's cell phone.
What happened to yours?
I broke it. What?
You have her number, don't you?
Yeah, I do.
Listen, just forward all the
calls, okay, to Kim's cell.
Please, thanks.
Dr. Gramm.
Hey, Mike.
Everyone is pretty upset about Dale.
Yeah, well, that's understandable.
Considering the circumstances.
I have a question about John Forster.
Yeah? What?
Well, I've been going through the
trial transcripts in Kate's history...
Why would you do that?
To understand your process better.
How you come to your conclusions.
And?
What?
Is it possible that Forster is innocent?
No.
You won't even consider the possibility?
You're completely convinced the scenario
you put together is the only one?
First of all, I didn't
put together a scenario.
I recreated the crime scene. Second...
I didn't convict Forster. A jury did.
But the evidence was circumstantial.
No DNA, no murder weapon.
Nothing directly linking Forster to
the crime, except your narrative...
And Janie Kay's testimony.
What's your point?
Just that your testimony
was very convincing.
That's my job.
To be convincing.
I thought it was to be right.
Help!
Somebody, please!
Lauren. Dr. Gramm.
What happened to you?
He's wearing a leather
jacket. He's out there.
I bit his hand, it's bleeding. If
his hand is bloody, you can get him.
You're okay? Go get him now! I'm fine!
Watch my car! It's a police action!
There's been an assault.
I wanna see your hands. Back off!
Roll the window down. No!
I'm a forensic psychiatric
with the FBI. Here.
Okay? Open the window now.
Yeah. See? Well, roll down the window...
And let me see your hands.
Let me see your hands.
If you have nothing to
hide, you can show me.
Look, I'm trying to go home. What?
Okay, sorry.
Excuse me.
There's been an assault.
I wanna see your hand.
Okay. Be cool now!
There's been an assault.
I gotta check your hands.
I'm a forensic psychiatric with the FBI.
Sorry.
I couldn't find him.
Here.
This is stupid.
I'm so stupid.
How I could be so weak? Such a
wimp. It's not your fault. Come on.
I can't believe I let him get away
like that. I should've fought back more.
Stop beating yourself
up? What exactly happened?
He came from behind. He put this
rag over my mouth and I bit his hand.
The rag had an odor? Something sweet...
It's Halothane, right?
Yeah. He's the one.
Probably.
I let Dale's murderer get away.
Stop beating yourself
up and tell me something.
Tell me something. Could you
identify him if you saw him again?
He came from behind, I didn't see him.
Let's go to the campus security,
you'll tell the everything.
Hello.
This woman has just been attacked.
Are you okay?
I think so.
What's your name?
Lauren Douglas.
And who are you?
Jack Gramm.
The famous Dr. Jack Gramm?
Then Johnson Fonsen
have you be coming in.
Is there someone to interview
Miss Douglas now, please?
Jimmy? Yeah.
You wanna check out
this girl? Wait a minute.
Right this way.
What's going on here?
The person who attacked her
may still be on the campus.
What the hell you guys doing?
We got all these guys
out on the bomb squad.
Excuse me for one moment. It's
a little crazy around here.
Jimmy, get off the phone and
interview Miss. Douglas, please.
I'll be right there.
Why won't you seat here?
Okay, you okay?
Jack Gramm Associates.
Shelley? Get Frank...
And pass him through
when you get him. Okay.
Okay, thank you.
I don't want you going back to your
apartment until the locks are changed.
I don't have anywhere else to go.
After you talk to the officer here...
Go back to my office. Shelley
will find a place to stay.
Okay.
Come on. It's gonna be all right.
Sorry for all the troubles I caused.
Miss. Douglas. Right this way.
Right in here. I'm sorry.
Yeah? I left a word for Frank.
Okay. There's been another incident.
The Forster's case
it's your thing, right?
Wrong, it's not my thing.
I saw your testimony on Court TV.
Yeah, right?
Fill those out.
Yeah, I follow the big crime cases.
They fascinate me.
When Dr. Jack Gramm takes the stand.
You come up with things
I didn't think off.
This here, this is just a job until...
Until you pass the police's exam.
See? How did you know that?
Just a guess.
That's the thing about you.
You know how to put two plus
two and you make it four.
Or five.
There are times that you know.
I'm not gonna be a campus cop
to a bunch of snob rich kids.
Especially these rich bitches...
My car is been analyzed.
The window was smashed.
There's a number on
the body. Look into it.
Dr. Gramm?
This is Johnny D'Franco,
from campus security.
Can you get me Lynn Johnson?
Jack Gramm Associates. Shelley?
Did you find Frank? No, not
yet. What the hell is going on?
Well, I received a threaten phone
call saying I have 88 minutes to live.
11:45h this morning, and my time is up.
Pull out my risk assessment file.
Anybody rating "e" and above...
I want you to cross
reference against Forster.
And when you find Frank...
Ask him if Sara Pollard or any of my
students ever visit Forster in prison.
Sara Pollard?
She's the girl I met
at the party last night.
Call Wong Lee...
And have him make a list
of all the phone numbers...
Forster called on the last 72 hours.
Where should fax the list?
My apartment.
And run a check on Kim.
Kim?
Yeah, just do it, okay? Hello.
Jack.
Damn it. The car is out front.
Drive Squaid. Good.
You're okay? You look
a little freaked out.
Yeah. You have...
A battery for your phone? Yeah, I do.
What the hell is this?
What are you doing?
Goddamn it, what is this?
What are you doing with
a gun in your purse?
Jesus, why don't you just
announce to the world?
I don't think they've heard
you in English Department.
Why the gun, Kim? For protection.
Where did you get it? I have
a permit. My dad is a cop.
Why you need a gun? I
don't. My dad thinks I do.
Why?
I have a crazy ex boyfriend, okay, Jack?
Oh. Jesus. God.
Yeah, I really know
how to pick one or what?
The judge said if he threats
anyone he goes back to jail.
Back to jail? What jail?
Prison, actually. Walla Walla.
That's where Forster is.
Come on, let's go.
Special Agent Parks.
Frank, it's Jack.
I'm at the university
campus. We got a problem here.
Someone attacked one of my students and
tried to knock her out with Halothane.
That's the Seattle
slayer. I know, hold on.
Give me a second.
Yeah. There's a security guard on
this campus, his name is D'Franco.
I don't like him. He's suspicious.
I want you to take him
in for questioning, okay?
Also get a warrant and search his place.
Jesus Christ, Jack.
You know I can't just get a
warrant without sufficient grounds.
Just get a warrant, Frank, come on.
Do you think he is the slayer?
To link Forster on the
outside? It's possible.
Listen, I checked the names
that Shelley, of the students.
And there's no record of Lauren
Douglas, Kim Cummings or Sara Pollard...
But you gonna love this.
Mike Stempt visit Forster four
times over the last six weeks.
Mike Stempt. What was his reason?
Research. He had written permission.
No, no, no. I didn't
give him any permission.
Written or otherwise.
Well, it's your signature,
Jack. I got a copy right here.
Hold on. That... Hold on a second.
That ex boyfriend of
yours. What is his name?
Guy LaForge.
Run a check on a parole
named Guy LaForge.
He served time at Walla
Walla with Forster.
And I'll call you back
when I get to my apartment.
All right.
Do you think that Frank
is working with Forster?
Someone is.
I got you Johnson. Yeah.
They've found a backpack
in your lecture hall.
What? With a bomb in it?
No. A photo, dynamite, and a
time with a note addressed to you.
What did it say?
Tic-Tac.
What does it mean, Jack?
I call you back.
You are okay? Yeah.
What the hell was that?
Probably somebody trying to scare us.
Who do you think would
do something like that?
Does your boyfriend drive a motorcycle?
Yeah.
Except he's not my boyfriend anymore.
How does it feel to know you
won't live through another night?
56 minutes.
Tic-Tac, doc.
Let's go.
Guy LaForge.
He isn't a boyfriend, is he?
The only thing that got me out
of Texas was my books marks.
And when I left for college,
I had that, but not much else.
So I tried to fit in. I drank too much.
Thought too little.
And I met Guy.
And he was this English...
Working class rock star wanna be.
And I fell for him.
And I married him...
When I graduated.
He didn't take to well to my
aspirations for higher education.
In fact he didn't really want me to
leave the house. And when I disobeyed...
He got filthy drunk and he beat me.
That's when he got
arrested and I divorced him.
I've been trying to make
up for lost time ever since.
You know, Forster is trying to
kill me. Forster is in prison.
Yeah, I know. He's got someone
on the outside trying to...
To do the job.
He's gonna kill me.
If I don't get him first.
Whoever is working with
Forster must be close to you.
A friend even. I don't
have many friends.
That's a plus.
It's a real pleasure to look at everyone
you know as your would be murderer.
Paranoia is a normal state of mind, huh?
Where is Errol?
I don't know. I'm a
temp. The agency sent me.
Dr. Gramm?
There's a package for you.
How did you know my name?
I don't. It was a question.
Yeah.
There's no returning
address on this? No.
Who delivered it?
A carrier. But there was another
person here at the same time...
Iooking for you. Who?
What was his name? No, I didn't get it.
When he walked in I was on
the phone with the plumber.
He said he would be right back. Okay.
You wanna me pull the
surveillance tapes?
That shouldn't take more than an hour
to get someone up here with the keys.
I don't have an hour. No?
Hey, you know, he was also wearing
leathers. He had a motorcycle helmet.
That's Guy. He was here.
If he comes back, don't
send him up to my apartment.
Yeah.
Hi, Dr. Gramm. Hi, Eva.