Subbed and Timed by the Chinese Hero Zhao Zi Long Team @ Viki.Please do not reuse or reupload our subtitles.
A Hero's Tears - by Sun Mingyu
♫ Endless nights, not afraid it may seem like only a dream. ♫
♫ Others will understand my undertaking of loyalty and gallantry. ♫
♫ Moving with great ease to hoofbeats of horses, ever-victorious with swords, spears, saber and halberd. ♫
♫ clouds over the imperial pagoda, an ode to good reputation across the world. ♫
♫ A hero's tears, can only fall within the heart. ♫
♫ Glory and emotions, remain within lifelong military metier. ♫
♫ Sever the grief and joy of separation and reunion, fill the world with heroic pride. ♫
♫ The mottled years, fill the world with heroic pride, the fight for justice. ♫
♫ It is the ambilight, it is a solitary roc flying thousands of miles, it is a legend in the vast land. ♫
♫ Let principled courage envelope your body, Write in a great number of ancient stories, reminiscence. ♫
♫ A hero's tears, can only fall within the heart. ♫
♫ Glory and emotions, remain within lifelong military metier. ♫
♫ Sever the grief and joy of separation and reunion, fill the world with heroic pride. ♫
♫ The mottled years, fill the world with heroic pride, the fight for justice. ♫
God of War, Zhao Yun.
Episode 3
Elder, Elder, Elder... Elder!
Elder, it's me.
You two again, you're asking for trouble.
This is good wine that I personally made,
requesting Elder to accept it.
Subbed and Timed by the Chinese Hero Zhao Zi Long Team @ Viki. Please do not reuse or reupload our subtitles.
Something's not right, you gave me good wine for no reason. I'm afraid this is a trick.
No, no, not a trick. The other day, we scared Miss Fei Yan.
Today we are here to apologize.
You actually came to this. There's probably another reason.
You still won't tell the truth?
I'm Zhao Yun, Zhao Zi Long.
I'm Liu Shen. We are here to learn from you. We hope you can accept us as your students.
Once in awhile there will be people knocking on my door.
But, in the end, they all quit after realizing the difficulty.
I won't talk in circles with you.
Tell me first, why do you want to learn martial arts?
...
the brilliance of martial arts is in having a benevolent heart.
And to use one's own expertise in martial arts to stop another's violence and provocations.
This can enable benevolence to exist between heaven and earth.
Define benevolence.
Help the weak and fight the strong is kindness.
To forget about oneself is justice.
Look, he spoke so nicely.
He is definitely a scholar, not a martial artist.
You should go to the capital and take the scholar tests.
Don't bother me here.
Father, it's not a sin that he's educated.
Fei Yan, you--
Also, a true hero is physically strong and well educated.
You are right
Miss Fei Yan
Shut your mouth!
Do you think just because Fei Yan is helping you out that I will accept you as my disciples?
Whether or not you are the right material, we will only know after dueling.
As long as Elder is willing, even if it's just to give me a chance out of courtesy.
If I can not pass, I am willing to be banned outside closed doors and to never disturb you again.
Right, right, right. You give the quests, we will definitely get it done.
To stump you is very easy.
This jar of wine, I will keep it
To enjoy this wine, it must be accompanied with meat.
How about this, the both of you go into the mountains. If you can kill a tiger bare fisted
and deliver it to me before noon tomorrow, I'll consider the both of you to have passed the test.
Fierce tiger and on top of that, bare fisted!?
Aren't you making things difficult for us on purpose?
Yes, I did it on purpose.
If you can't do it, then let's forget about martial arts.
Senior, If it's over a kind of test, then I'm willing to even go through fire.
But if you want me to go up into the hills to kill a tiger, that I'm afraid I can not do.
Truth be told, on this mountain there is a white tiger that is very dear to me.
Wah, to even have ties with a tiger seems like something out of the ordinary.
Who are you exactly?
Since you asked, I won't hide it from you.
My father was the former General. Zhao An.
I as a mountain person only knows about three acres of a land.
Whether great generals or officials of the court, it has nothing to do with me, so I don't care.
Zi Long, just admit it.
The Iron Masked Hero who killed the bandits and saved the maiden that other time, is none other than him.
As for this iron something, I did hear some rumours about him.
Hence,
I presume you do have some martial art foundation
How about this, if you can receive 3 blows from me, I will accept you as my disciple. What do you say?
You junior is willing to try.
Don't rush to agree. In these three stances, I will use all my strength.
If I kill or cripple you, don't blame me for being ruthless.
Senior, after you.
How about this, within 3 blows if you do not step out of this circle, I will consider that as your victory.
After you.
Zi Long, are you alright?
That punch just now, I have yet to use my full strength.
On the second one, I shan't hold back anymore.
If you are going to back out, it's still not too late now.
The words "give up" don't exist in my mind.
Good!
Lad, think it through.
I have thought it through.
Zi Long!
Zi Long, are you alright?
What are you doing?
Giving a hand, doesn't count. Let him get up on his own.
Zi Long, let's forget about acknowledging this master.
It's not worth it to get killed in the process.
If you want to master powerful kungfu, then you must be able to withstand being punched.
Just two blows and you're throwing up blood. Your constitution is too weak.
Why don't you go back.
Father.
I, Zhao Zi Long, from young
until now, there is no such thing as giving up halfway.
Do consider it once more.
This last blow, even if not lethal
is highly possible to cause you to become a cripple.
Whether, death or crippling,
it's by my own choice, I won't blame anyone.
Come!
Father, look at him wavering.
Why not change to another day for this entrance exam.
It's not like I'm forcing him.
Zi Long are you alright?
My wine!
I really can't stand the temptation of this wine.
How about this, come back tomorrow to receive three blows from me!
Fei Yan!
- Father! - Where are the beans in our house?
Hurry and look for them!
Zi Long, what are you acting tough for?
If this blow connects, you would have become a cripple.
Let's go.
(crowd noises)
(crowd murmurs)
- Look! - Look at him!
You men go to the East Gate.
Understood!
Move!
Zi Long, isn't this new magistrate coming after you?
Here is the medicinal ointment. Hurry and apply it.
I can still do it myself. No worries.
Look at you!
This master of yours did not even acknowledge you yet and here you are about half beaten to death.
What are you plotting exactly?
I tried my best to receive his blow. It's not only about my ability.
All the more, this proves that
his punches and my father's are exactly the same.
Then why did he not make himself known?
Nowadays, Dong Zhuo's henchmen are increasing daily.
The new magistrate that came for duty, that Gao Ze!
Even though he looked quite refined,
but in actuality, we don't know.
What if he is extremely sinister?
Coming up next, what are we going to do about his next move?
This won't do, I've got to go out to investigate.
General Gao, the Iron Mask Hero...
There's no rush to make our move. Let's find out the Iron Mask Hero's vital spot and strike it hard.
Oh by the way, do we have the Iron Mask Hero's protrait?
Yes we do, I already prepared it in advance.
These few days, I will have to trouble General Pan to cast a few duplicate Iron Masks.
Qing Er is still the best.
Until I reconcile with my Teacher uncle, I shall get a nice silver hairpin for our Qing Er.
You still remembered? I thought you just said it as a passing remark and then forgot about it
Along with me, growing up together. My bare arse good buddy, how could I forget.
Growing up together bare arse?
You... you
You think of me as just a good buddy?
That's right. Isn't that right?
You are heartless! Not even on the same par as a beast!
Where are you going?
Let me tell you Zhao Zi Long, I'd rather feed a tiger than you.
This...
Hold on a second!
The white tiger actually knows to strike only after being provoked!
He is so formidable.
Inaction, and deceit.
Report! General Gao!
The skilled exponents that we sent to your district, only one returned.
The rest were all killed.
How did they die？
Gong Sun Zan, after receiving the order from the Imperial Tutor,
not only did he disobey, but instead raised his voice to curse and swear.
Just when the skill exponentials came together to attack Gong Sun Zan outside the gates and
just when they are about to succeed...
Jia! (horse command to move faster)
Jia!
Stop harming my father!
- Justice is here- Till death we follow
- Heaven is looking, - White horses our witness
Raise the chains!
Miss!
Gong Sun Zan! Drop your weapon and surrender.
Otherwise, I will kill your daughter.
Stop your obscenities or I will rip your body to shreds.
Jia!
Bo He Brother, Xuan De(Liu Bei) is here!
Xuan De, you came just in time.
Kill all these villians.
I didn't think that Liu Bei, ZhangYu and GuanYu, these three brothers, were so highly skilled.
Fortunately that day, we didn't make a move or otherwise the consequences would have been dire.
Now that military strength is so strong.We no longer require Gong Sun Zan's assistance.
Locating the two swords is more than enough.
How is the casting coming along for the iron masks?
They will be finished tomorrow
It's our turn to strike. Iron Mask Hero, be prepared to receive my move.
You are indeed courageous.
Are you ready?
I am going to strike.
Ready to receive your teachings, Senior.
Not too bad lad.
You actually didn't go down.
Three Strikes!
You are good lad!
Zi Long... Teacher please accept Zi Long's kowtow.
Forget about becoming my disciple, I would never accept.
Are you going back on your word?
Why?
As long as I accept a disciple,
I would have the bear the responsibility of being a master.
With you two young lads,
who knows when you are going to cause earth shattering trouble for me.
I would be in deep dung.
Senior, I am in awe of your martial arts and character,
but how can you go back on your word.
Father, backing out of a promise made to someone isn't appropriate.
Senior, you should admit to your loss.
Look, even Fei Yan has spoken up on our behalf.
If you are still going to be like this, then it isn't very appropriate of you.
Who said I'm going back on my word?
You have only heard half of what I was going to say.
But you guys are chattering non-stop in disapproval.
Who says I'm going back on my word.
(As I was saying) I won't accept disciples, just in case in the future you lads are unfilial
and drag me into the trouble you caused.
So I'm going to teach you Martial Arts and on top of that I will give additional supervision.
Teacher, at the very least accept a kowtow from us.
"Teacher" this word...
if you like just use it for now.
Let's have an agreement first.
I did not accept you lads as disciples.
Alright, we know.
Then we shall return now to prepare. We will come again tomorrow.
Tomorrow?! You've got to start practising now!
If you want to learn martial arts, we've got to have a sense of urgency. I wouldn't waste my time to teach you empty tricks.
Now I will impart a few useful stances to you.
Great!
Is it just to borrow grains?
Just in time, not long ago I went on an expedition to Xian Bei
and got my hands on those rations, I shall share some of them with you.
I give my thanks on behalf of the people of PingYuan country.
You have my gratitude Brother Bo Gui.
You and I are of the same rank, there is no need to be formal.
Sit.
But I have a favour to ask as well
Please go ahead.
Bao Yue.
- BaoYue!- Coming!
Father.
My daughter prefers to make knives
and I use the smelter.
But I am unable to impart to her spear mastery.
Therefore, I would like Brother Yun Chang
to give her a few teachings.
What do you say?
Great!
Bao Yun is the kind of smart and quick witted girl I will teach.
What are you still here thanking me, hurry up and thank Second Uncle Guan.
Alright.
My respect to you Master.
Please rise, Princess.
The important aspect of using a sword is when your heart has no sword.
Forget all about the sword.
Using your mind and breath. That's the most powerful.
Zi Long!
Pay close attention in practice. Gao Ze's people must definitely have put his hand onto something.
Yes, I know.
How much is this one?
This is 12 coins. You see this one is good. How is it?
How about this one?
This one is 3 coins.
The Iron Mask Hero is coming.
Good, good, good.
Jia!
I'm the Iron Mask Hero!
Iron Mask Hero is coming!
Today, I'm teaching everybody a new character.
This character is read as 'yi'. The 'yi' as in the word justice.
Little children, can you tell?
This "yi" character is a sheep. When it's on my back,
it's like, when a friend is sick.
So I will bring food to visit them.
It shows the character of selflessness.
This "yi" character uses "I" as the base.
It's like, when you are chasing justice, it all begins with yourself.
Do you understand?
We understand!
Teacher! Teacher! Teacher!
Little Hu Zi, what happened?
Teacher, the Iron Mask Hero took my school bag away.
Okay, Xiao Hu Zi. Stop crying first.
Go back there and sit down.
The Iron Mask Hero is breaking the law and committing crimes!
General Gao Ze will occupy a post temporarily put a stop to it on behalf of others!
In a few days, the Iron Mask Hero will be apprehended alive. The people need not worry.
General Gao!
The son of Zhao An still has't shown his face.
Has he already left for Mount Chang?
The distance from here to Zhuang village isn't far,
If he wanted to flee, he would have fled already. But then he went to save people as the Iron Masked Hero,
so he still has important matters in Chang Shan.
Then would he refuse to come out?
I've heard Zhao An's family at the Zhao family villa have a reputation for generosity.
They usually lend a hand when others are in trouble.
Zhao An earned a worthy death by defending the neighboring county.
I think this lad has his father's guts and boldness.
Come out! Everyone come out!
Hand over the Iron Mask Hero!
Capture the Iron Mask Hero!
Open the door!
Zi Long, their method is ridiculously obvious.
Using such a heinous way of forcing you to go down, you can not fall for this.
-  Come out!   - That's right.
They say they want to capture the Iron Mask Hero or monster.
But the peasants don't know who Zhao Zi Long is.
At most, we'll just change your name.
A name can be changed at any time.
But they're so persistent. How could I bear it?
Open the door!
They just want chaos, so just let them whine.
After they think it has nowhere to go,
they'll naturally stop.
They wouldn't protest for no reason.
Previously our family dragged the Zhao family down with us,
my heart is full of guilt. This time, I can't do the same thing.
Then let's depart ourselves,
make a fake Iron Mask Hero, and finish it.
We can't.
Gao Ze would find someone else.
Furthermore, even if we're strategic and kill Gao Ze,
Dong Zhuo will still order people to come here.
And it will get stronger and more uncontrollable.
That's right. That's my biggest fear and inability.
Come out, Iron Masked Hero.
Are you still not opening the door!?
This won't do, that won't do. So what do we do?
Come out, Iron Masked Hero.
Come out, come out!
It seems I need to try this Gao Ze.
You want to fight against Gao Ze?
But would you be able to defeat him?
And there are many people with Gao Ze!
That's right!
Zi Long, you once said that I was impulsive with my actions.
But this time, you can not be impulsive.
Gao Ze is forcing me so closely. I can't even hide.
But isn't this obviously asking for death?
This time, it will be a fight to the death.
I'll find a way to fight with my wits, not my muscles.
I want to see what kind of person Gao Ze is.
Come out!
Open the door!
Come out, Iron Mask Hero!
Since you've already decided, bring this.
In a crucial time, it can protect you.
Right! Bring the golden steel sword!
It's useless. The golden steel sword is useless when facing a master.
Bringing it will create even more of a hassle.
Come out, Iron Mask Hero! Open the door!
Open the door!
Don't create trouble for me! That piece of clothing is for my father!
Look at you, you don't want to snatch anything else. But you want to snatch clothes?
I said this wasn't yours!
Young hero!
Here!
Thank you!
Take him away.
Let's go.
Get up! Let's go!
More force!
Can you see this?
Take this. Continue.
General Gao, someone is complaining about injustice again.
It looks like there's another case for you.
Stop crying.
Now General Gao is following orders.
If you have any grievances, please say them now.
War Practice Ground.
Stop!
What are you doing?
If you dare disguise yourself as me, you're dead.
You are the Iron Mask Hero?
That's right! I am the Iron Mask Hero you're looking for.
What is happening?
General! The Iron Mask Hero is here!
Gee up!(Same as Jia)
Come! Get on the horses! Chase him!
Hurry! Hurry!
Gee up! Hurry!
Gee up!
Carry him inside!
Yes.
War Practice Ground.
Could you please stop crying?
What is wrong? Can you explain clearly?
Stop crying!
You!
General Gao! The Iron Mask Hero has appeared!
What?
Wake up! Wake up!
You are...
I am the Iron Mask Hero you're looking for.
Stop! Stop!
Hurry! Hurry!
Giddy up!
Stop! Stop!
That's enough, stop crying!
General Gao no longer has time to attend to you.
Come testify tomorrow.
That's enough. Exit the court.
Zi Long should have arrived in the backyard.
My goal is achieved.
Zi Long, you must be careful.
Careful.
You do look like the painting
You are indeed Zhao An's son. You have some guts.
You also broke into by yourself! What's your purpose of breaking in?
- Are you here to surrender the Qing Gang sword? -I came here to tell you,
in 10 days you will have three occurrences of blood baths.
I decided to spare you three times.
Spare me three times!?
You're full of confidence.
An ignorant child's mouth cannot be shut. I don't blame you.
If you're here to give me the sword then fine. If not
then I will make you bleed all over!
If you kill me, you definitely won't receive the sword.
Then what do you want to do?
Let's have a fight to the death.
Betting your head
and that sword.
It's very simple. Within ten days,
I'll spare you three times.
So you won't bother the local peasants.
You'll clear the Iron Mask Hero's name,
and you must tell me who caused the death of my parents.
Letting you off is true,
I won't bicker with the ignorant child any longer.
How about this,
within ten days, I'll spare you three times, and you hand over the sword.
If not, in my anger,
Tai Shi might send more mercenaries to flatten Zhen Ding Town and Mount Chang!
Then I won't have any other options.
Okay. Two bets, dueling together.
Subbed and Timed by the Chinese Hero Zhao Zi Long Team @ Viki
Just based on your three legged cat's skills you still dare break into the government house?
Other than your guts, there is nothing else...
These few strokes were to your sleeves,
the next few will be to your arm!
Brother!
I just saw Dong Zhuo's people
each a master of martial arts. Can Zi Long escape?
Don't worry. He's bright and won't have any trouble.
This--
Let's go.
Go.
♫ Passing the ashes of spring, only to sigh at summer's end.♫
♫ Unable to burn through the loneliness of fall, nor the swan song of winter.♫
♫ Light breeze flows, a cup of wine, dreams stray behind.♫
♫ Past memories like lotus flowers mirroring in the water.♫
♫ Soft rains, broken winds, much to worry about in a foggy, drunken state.♫
♫ To only sigh, but still holding on.♫
♫ Misty moon, guarding love, falling into an embrace.♫
♫ The fear of love, the thoughts of woe.♫
♫ Lalalalalalalala...♫
♫ Once was there familiarity, tears fall, song sang.♫
♫ The promise of espousal after incarnations never changed.♫
♫ Unwilling to disturb the past.♫
♫ Lalalalalalala...♫
♫ The heroes of the past oft were melancholic.♫
♫ After the rise and collapse, the success and failures, still remembering her visage..♫
♫
♫  Lalalalala...♫
♫ Parting after a single song ♫
♫
♫ The promise of espousal after incarnations never changed.♫
♫Unwilling to disturb the past♫
♫ The heroes of the past oft were melancholic.♫
♫ After the rise and collapse, the success and failures, still remembering her visage.♫
♫ Remembering past dreams, a scene of painful separation.♫
♫ Painful separation...♫