In reykjavík, Iceland today,
Bobby fischer failed to show up
for his second game
against Boris spassky.
Unpredictable Bobby fischer
stayed in bed today
rather than show up
for game 2
in his world title match
with chess champion
Boris spassky of Russia.
The match between the world's
chess champion, Boris spassky,
and Bobby fischer
took a strange turn
when fischer failed to show up
at the scheduled time
and forfeited game 2.
The entire world seems
to be asking the same question:
"What will Bobby fischer
do next?"
Half the witnesses
they call are communists.
The other half are Jews.
If you're both,
do you testify twice?
- Go ahead.
- Make jokes, Mr. liberal.
Your entire family
wasn't gassed
at the camps.
Mama.
Mama!
Not now, Bobby.
I have to talk to you!
Bobby, it's past
your bedtime.
Joan?
There's
a car out there!
- What car?
- You told me to tell you.
A red 1952 Chevy.
Bobby,
you remember
what I told you?
There are
bad people out there
who wanna intimidate us
because we represent something
very threatening to them,
to the status quo.
You remember
what that is?
Revolution.
Yes. And sometimes
these bad people wanna
know about our work.
So they spy on us.
So... if someone comes up
to you in the street
and asks you questions
about me or mommy's friends,
what do you say?
"I have nothing
to say to you."
That's my big boy.
Yuck. Joan. Joan.
Joan. He's got mustard
on his shirt.
He's gotta wear that
to school tomorrow.
- Would you soak it for me?
- Love to.
- And put him to bed.
- Bedtime for bonzo.
I'm carmine nigro,
and I'm told
you are a chess player.
Our church-- all colors
and creeds welcome.
Bobby.
Choose.
Let's see
what we got here, eh?
Most young people
don't have the concentration
to play at a high level,
so please don't get
your hopes up.
Ha! He's beaten everyone
he's ever played.
My hopes are he will
give up on the damn game
if someone beats him.
Okay.
It's your move.
Do you like baseball,
Bobby?
- Hmm? Jackie Robinson?
Pee wee Reese?
- Mm-hmm.
Bobby, have you
ever been to the moon
on the subway?
- Mm-hmm.
If I take the pieces away,
he just keeps playing
in his head. Day and night.
Took him to a shrink.
He said to come here.
Well, his game is good.
Not exceptional though.
Hmm.
- Who taught him
to move like this?
- He taught himself.
Bobby, shall we
call it a draw?
Hmm?
He hates draws.
Check.
Mate.
I'm officially
the 25th best chess player
in New York City.
I can tell you
he has great potential.
Come here.
Come--
again.
Carmine,
it's your move!
I know
it's my move.
Come on!
I'm thinking.
Come on, carmine.
It's your turn.
Bobby, I know
it's my turn.
Just go.
-  Come on!
- Bobby, I still have time
on the clock, okay?
- Let me think.
- Fine.
There's a rising star
in the chess world,
and he's only 12 years old.
His name is Bobby fischer.
Today he played
American master Donald byrne
and beat him in what
is already being described
as the game of the century.
So, Bobby,
what's next for you?
It's either I beat them,
or they beat me.
You know?
With an impressive string
of five victories,
Bobby today became
the youngest ever
United States chess champion.
Ooh.
Oh, you're back.
And you won.
Congratulations.
Every night
i hear you two screw.
Bobby,
put those down.
Bobby.
Shut up, size 12.
You live in my house,
and you're not my father.
Okay?
Bobby.
- Where is my father?
- Come on.
I was born, right?
What did you do with him?
Is he on earth?
Does he even exist?
Honey, that was
a long time ago.
So what?
You can't remember?
Where is he?
Gone.
- Gone where?
- It doesn't matter.
It matters to me.
You know what?
Get the fuck out of here.
You know wha--
go-- go back to Moscow
with your commie friends.
I am studying
day and night.
And I'm gonna be
the next world champion.
Do you understand me?
I need silence.
Do you understand?
I want silence.
Mom says
you're staying
at the chess club.
It's quiet there.
And what
about high school? Hmm?
Huh.
Yeah.
She still there?
She fixed up
the apartment.
Even got
the hot-water heater
working.
She won't be
living there anymore.
She's going
to do politics
in California with cyril.
You mean king Kong.
Mate.
Mom was worried.
She thought
if they went away,
you'd go home,
sleep in a bed.
That's what
she told you? Huh?
And you bought it?
She's running away
with some nutcase
bigfoot communist.
Oh, oh,
and you know what?
It's for Bobby's benefit.
You said
you wanted quiet.
You won, Bobby.
Be happy.
In portoroz, yugoslavia today,
American chess prodigy
Bobby fischer
became the youngest
ever grandmaster
in the history of the game.
Congratulations, Bobby.
Where do you go from here?
Well, uh, I wanna play
the Russians.
They're the best in the world,
and I'm gonna beat 'em all.
Having won the interzonal,
he is the odds-on favorite
to win the candidates
tournament
and gain a match against
the current world champion.
How are you feeling?
I'm ready.
It's my time.
Mr. spassky,
a quick chat, please.
This is ridiculous.
King to rook three.
Knight to king six.
Pawn takes queen.
Bishop to knight seven.
It's over.
The Russians are
drawing games on purpose
to save their strength
and they're dumping games
to pad their points,
making it statistically
impossible for me to win.
Mr. fischer, your complaint
has been lodged.
There's nothing we can do.
Of course there's
something you can do.
They're playing a team game.
It's five guys against one.
Against me!
Can we go back inside?
No, I'm not interested.
Bobby, don't--
what the hell are you
doing about this anyways?
All right.
Come here. Gather around.
I got something to say.
I wanna make this very clear.
The Russians are cheats.
Everybody knows
what's going on.
The corrupt federation
does nothing to stop it!
There can be
no legitimate world champ
if I'm not playing.
And I'm not gonna play,
because this is unfair.
It's unjust.
It's immoral!
I quit.
I don't just quit
this tournament.
I am quitting chess.
Move. Move.
Bobby.
Bobby, wait.
We'll go back inside
and apologize.
You can
still place well.
What are you talking about?
This was it!
What do you think I've been
working the past 10 years
of my life for?
I was gonna be the youngest
world champ in the history
of the game! That's over now!
They stole it
from me, carmine.
They took it!
That was today! Today!
- English.
- This is America.
Ah, the American boy
who hates us, but cannot
resist our magazines.
Spassky is becoming
the new Messiah.
They say he won't
ever lose a match.
Someone left this
for you.
A lawyer.
You are in trouble,
maybe?
Do you want a game?
You think
I'm stupid?
So you know who I am.
Yeah,
i know who you are.
I've been trying
to reach you. You don't
answer your phone.
Oh. You're--
you're that lawyer.
What'd I do?
Nothing.
You did nothing.
You do nothing.
That's why I'm here.
I read your article
in sports illustrated.
You told the truth
about the Russians.
Yeah, that's right, I did.
Did you see this?
"Soviet invasion
to hit California surf."
"World's greatest
chess players to visit us."
Yeah, I saw that.
They say it's just
a game... for fun, hand of
friendship, all that crap.
You know the truth.
They're laughing at us.
They think
their chess dominance...
Proves Soviet
intellectual superiority
over the decadent west.
I don't really care
about politics.
They're using chess
to say "screw America."
I'm about the game, you see.
Two guys at a board,
one makes a move,
the other makes a move,
and that's it.
I'm a chess fan myself.
I'm also
hopelessly patriotic.
I take an interest
in people like yourself,
creative people.
I create the wherewithal
that allows them to do
what they do.
Ask Jimi Hendrix.
Ask the rolling stones.
If I can help them,
i can help anybody.
I'd like
to represent you,
Mr. fischer.
So you're out
to make a buck.
No, I don't need the money.
I'd be doing this for free.
Pro bono.
You're the one man
in this country
who could put up a fight.
Maybe even
beat them.
I'd like a front-row seat
when the good guys win.
If I went back to competition,
there'd have to be
some real changes.
It's got to be fair.
If you're serious
about playing,
I'll see what I can do.
That is if you
still wanna play.
Call me.
He's very excited
about this.
I'm only a selector
on the committee.
You see, he apologizes
to the federation.
With profanity
on the first line.
Ah. Well, he's--
he's nursed a grudge.
Mm-hmm.
For a long time.
He's studied
how the Russians play.
Every day.
Eighteen hours a day.
For four years.
Mm-hmm.
For him, uh, Vietnam
and the Beatles
never happened.
I'm guessing he still
has his opinions
about the Soviets?
Well, you'll promise
the committee, we'll
keep him out of trouble.
The piatigorsky
was organized to build Bridges,
not to burn them.
Well, so we lose 12-0,
and that's a bridge?
He asked for you.
Wants you
to be his second.
He respects you.
You're the only one
who ever beat spassky.
We were young.
He'd destroy me now.
And...
You've beaten Bobby.
That was a long time ago.
Bobby has problems.
So did Mozart.
He might crack.
Bobby won't crack.
He will explode.
Bobby?
Bill's here.
Oh.
Hey, Bobby,
how you doing?
Against petrosian in Zurich,
you sacrificed
your king's pawn.
You know that's the thing
that got you, right?
You always play too cautiously
and you go crazy
in the other direction.
That's--
that's a real weakness.
-Hey, if I criticize
a priest, do I go to hell?
-Depends if you believe in hell.
Yeah.
All right.
- I'm gonna show you how you
could have won in 13 moves.
- Huh.
Castle, pawn,
knight, bishop, rook.
That's you.
All right.
King goes there.
Pawns.
All right.
Now, here-- here's
where you screwed up.
You got greedy, and you
traded knight for bishop.
- And you sacrificed
your pawn, right?
- Mm-hmm.
Now, what if you'd
done this instead?
You see, the Russians
are like boa constrictors.
If you do nothing,
they strangle you to death.
But if you confuse him,
you attack him
from everywhere.
Then all they
can do is react.
Now, here, you see,
i got my machine gun lined up,
bearing down on the king.
Now, he tries
to defend himself.
I sacrifice my rook,
and now the real attack begins.
Check.
Check. Take.
Hey, Bobby, you know,
this tournament's
about... diplomacy.
No, this tournament,
like all tournaments,
is about winning.
So--
okay, well,
the rook takes bishop.
Of course.
Now, he thinks he's safe,
but I've been developing
a plot to kill his king.
You see, my rook
is sitting there waiting,
forgotten about
in the background.
I bring him into the hunt.
Now, the king flees.
Even his beloved queen
can't do anything.
She's just sitting there,
watching.
Mm-hmm.
As the noose tightens.
And finally,
he sees the end.
Holy shit.
Hey. I didn't know a priest
could use bad language.
I like this guy.
So, uh, we going
to California?
This is 93 khj Los Angeles.
Don't be fooled
by the warm weather, kids,
because the cold war
just blew into town.
The Soviet chess team
arrived today in la
for a goodwill tournament.
With them is
the current world champion,
Boris spassky.
The comrades are booked
into the Beverly Hilton hotel.
So much
for working-class values.
If you're listening, guys,
welcome to the free world
and enjoy the sunshine.
It's really hot in here.
What's going on?
Repair guy didn't show.
You know,
you promised hotels.
This place is a real dive.
Are you a rock star?
He acts like a rock star.
You realize I have
to prepare, right?
- Right?
- Yeah.
- Well, you know what?
- What?
- I ain't stayin' here.
- Bobby.
These are
improved accommodations?
This is improved.
Staying at a roach motel.
Somebody else
is paying for it.
Yeah, well, where are
the Russians staying?
We don't have
their kind of money.
Didn't we invent money?
- We rely on private donors.
- Yeah, right.
The Russians, they get
whatever they want,
because they know
what it takes to win.
And I end up staying
next to route 66.
All I want is some quiet!
So stop yelling.
Yeah. Yeah. Right.
Sorry.
- What's your name?
- I'm Donna.
Oh, well, uh--
yeah, I'll see you later, Donna.
I'm going for a walk.
Want some company?
Uh, sure.
Wait.
I'll be right there.
Uh--
and he hasn't even
started playing.
You walk pretty fast.
This all you
wanted to do?
We could sit down.
Oh. Okay.
So, what do you do,
Donna?
I screw people.
- Yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
Oh. So do I.
Hmm.
Listen. Uh, I was thinking
about getting rid
of my virginity.
- Is that right?
- Yeah, that's right.
Bishop to queen three.
Bishop to knight five.
Knight
to knight five.
Uh, king rook to queen one.
Uh, queen to knight four.
Ah.
Yeah, that's not even me.
It's, uh, morphy
versus anderssen.
Pawn to queen rook four.
Queen to king seven.
Queen takes queen.
Rook takes queen.
Shit!
Hey. You ready?
Yeah.
Background
on the Soviets.
You're kidding, right?
Uh--
yeah, I know every game
every one of these guys
has ever played.
You know,
they're sitting by the pool
at their fancy hotel,
laughing, having drinks.
They have no idea.
You guys coming?
I think he's ready.
Yeah.
Bobby's disappeared.
He'll be here.
If he's not seated
in three minutes,
he forfeits.
He'll be here.
Yeah? A little prayer
wouldn't hurt.
I pray
for his opponent.
- Bobby, you here?
- Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
What the hell?
You've got, like, seconds
to take your seat.
Great. If my mom comes,
would you give that to her?
Yes.
She lives in California now,
so you never know.
She might show.
Bobby, you've drawn Ivanovich
in the first round.
Hey, whatever you do,
don't let her get in.
It screws up my game.
I told her she could
listen on the radio.
Bobby, Ivanovich is
officially the third
best chess player in the world.
Fourth.
If he doesn't make
his move in 60 seconds,
the game will be forfeited.
Adjust.
Americans don't
beat Russians at chess.
But it happened today
in Santa Monica.
And when American
chess sensation
Bobby fischer's around,
it just keeps on happening.
We have
a problem.
...are going
to be here any minute.
Look at this place.
Mr. fischer?
Yeah. I've decided
I'm not playing again
until all my conditions
are met.
What, uh, conditions?
First off, I wanna arrive
in a big black car,
you know,
just like the Russians.
Uh, limousines
cost money.
Number two-- you know
i was on the front page
of the la times today?
Ticket sales
are through the roof.
Mm-hmm.
A thousand people
are paying $5.00 apiece
just to see me play.
That's $5,000.
Mm.
I want 30%.
That's 1,500.
- Uh, Bobby--
- no. Money's respect, Paul.
And number three--
i want at least five feet
between me and the audience.
You know,
i can smell their breath.
It's almost like I hear
their thoughts, you know.
- My thoughts need
to be on the board.
- Is that all?
- Well, why don't you
have someone check
and make sure our phones
aren't being bugged.
The rest
is on the list.
Hey. Hi.
So, uh, I heard you won.
So congrats.
Oh, thanks.
What's wrong with the phone
in your room?
Oh, I heard
this click-click.
I thought maybe, you know,
my phone was bugged.
Who you calling?
Uh, hold--
hello. Operator?
I'm looking for a number
for Regina fischer.
Um, I don't know.
I thought maybe, um--
well, I don't know.
Somewhere near the beach.
I'm in Santa Monica,
so-- I don't know--
maybe somewhere around here?
I'm making sure my mom
doesn't come tomorrow.
She can be distracting.
And I'll say hello
to her and--
hello?
Uh--
oh, okay.
Well, never mind then.
So, you wanna lose
your virginity tonight?
Oh. Uh--
well, I haven't forgotten
about our arrangement,
and I am looking
forward to it.
But, uh--
but I gotta stay
focused tonight.
I slaughtered
one of them today,
so tomorrow
they're gonna come
at me like banshees.
Okay.
All right.
Uh--
well, good luck.
See you later.
I passed up having sex
for this.
Passed it up
for 20 years.
- Patty melt.
- Got it.
So, Boris, it looks
like Bobby has improved
his game.
What do you think?
Tomorrow,
a record crowd will watch
the American, Bobby fischer,
as he faces Russian
world champion Boris spassky
in the final match.
Fischer, whose demands
for more money have infuriated
tournament promoters,
has won a remarkable
eight matches in a row.
But tomorrow will definitely
be his greatest test.
Pawn to king three.
Queen to king one.
Knight to rook four.
What?
Uh--
I, uh-- I like to play
the king's Indian,
but he's an expert
on the sãmisch, so, uh--
who?
Uh, spassky.
So I thought
maybe a grünfeld,
but-- but then I have
to find an answer
to pawn bishop four.
You know, I was wondering,
did you reach your mom yet?
I bet she'd be proud.
Uh, I need
to go through this.
I need to work--
work through this,
so I thought maybe--
uh--
sure. Yeah.
Well, that was great
for me too.
Thank you.
Oh, yeah.
How you feeling?
I'm fine.
Did you eat?
You mind not talking?
That's good.
Okay.
Thanks.
Bobby, how does
it feel to lose?
That's a stupid question.
How'd he beat you, Bob?
Would you understand
if I answered that?
He was playing to draw.
Bobby, no one
expected you
to beat spassky.
I did.
They're waiting
to give you
the runner's-up medal.
No thanks.
At least, uh--
ah, forget him.
Talk to
the TV people!
Forget him.
He's disappeared.
He'll be back.
What makes you
so sure?
It's all that matters to him.
Without chess, he doesn't exist.
You think
he can ever beat spassky?
Hypothetically,
what would it take
to make him world champion?
The desk clerk asked
why we were making
so many calls to DC.
I haven't
been calling DC.
Who have you
been talking to?
People in high places
who take an interest
in any confrontation
between us
and the Soviet union.
State department? CIA?
White house?
Bobby wants limos,
he gets limos.
And they'll throw
in honorariums
for each victory.
Paid for by whom?
Are you a patriot,
father?
Mostly.
Bobby may be
a little off,
but he understands
this whole thing
better than you.
We're at war.
Only it's not being fought
by guns and missiles.
Not yet, at least.
It's a war
of perception.
The poor kid from Brooklyn
against the whole
Soviet empire.
The perfect
American story.
So your interest in this
is ideological.
But what's in it for you?
There's such a thing
as doing well by doing good.
And you haven't answered
my question.
Bobby fischer--
Bobby fischer
is the second best chess player
I've ever seen.
He's also got
severe problems
in his head.
Which need
to be understood
and managed.
Managed?
Bobby?
You ever hear
of Paul morphy?
1855.
Greatest player
this country ever had.
Before Bobby, that is.
But by 21,
he'd beat every master
in Europe.
But then...
Things started to get
a little weird.
He started
having visions
and became convinced
that people were trying
to poison him,
and he quit...
At 26.
And eventually
killed himself
in a bathtub
surrounded by 12 pairs
of ladies' shoes.
So... this game--
it's a rabbit hole.
After only four moves,
there's more than
300 billion options
to consider.
There's more 40-move games
than there are stars
in the galaxy.
So... it can take you
very close to the edge.
Could he win?
If-if Bobby were
to go for the title,
it would mean traveling
around the world playing
tournaments for three years.
In my opinion,
he might not make it
that long.
It's your job
to see that he does.
If we can ever find him.
Holy shit.
They following me?
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Hey! Over here!
You guys following me?
Hey!
You're soft!
You got your guys!
You're a stooge!
I got nothing!
Hey!
Where you going?
I'm talking to you!
Hey!
Where you going?
I'm coming for you!
I'm coming
for you!
This is BBC news.
Today in Hungary,
American Bobby fischer returned
to international competition
by defeating
the number-five player
in the world, Viktor korchnoi,
and declared his intention
to become world champion.
And so begins
the grueling challenge
of defeating the grandmasters
who stand between fischer
and the newly-crowned
world champion, Boris spassky.
Bobby, you dominated
the competition.
How do you feel?
I feel good.
Uh, you know, these--
these guys didn't
offer me much competition.
I see this
as an obstacle course
to the world championship,
and then, uh--
then they'll have to agree
to the conditions I want.
Over here, Bobby.
- You think the Russians
are worried about you?
- Oh, yeah.
They've been worried
about me ever since
i started playing chess.
You know, I'm kinda picking
these guys off,
but, uh, they've
been preparing for me,
so you never know
what's up their sleeve.
Bobby, over here!
Think anybody can beat you?
The tide of history
is changing, friend.
God's plan
has left them behind,
so they plot to take
the world away from god.
They seek to destroy
our great Christian nation.
As it is written
in revelations 18,
he will use one nation
what are you listening to?
To punish another nation.
He will take vengeance
on this modern devil.
You mind closing the door?
And they will do anything
in their power to destroy us.
Sure.
Theirs is
an international conspiracy.
Mossad, kgb,
the military
industrial complex
and an unholy cabal
of Jewish banks.
Joanie,
joanie, joanie.
I'm between
three airports and hell.
I have 10 minutes in New York
to see my wife, kiss my kids,
talk to you.
How the hell you been?
You're looking great.
I have to see him.
Every time I call,
they say his phone
is broken.
- That happens.
- You mean he breaks them.
I wanna take him
to see a doctor.
Ah, well, that just
won't be possible.
He's already
in Vancouver.
These.
Every week,
his letters, they--
they get more cra--
more crazy.
Take a look.
Go ahead.
Um, they're private letters
to you, Joan.
I, um--
I respect his privacy.
I showed them to
a psychiatrist friend.
He said that Bobby
is displaying signs
of, um--
uh-- of paranoia
and delusional psychosis.
Well, you know, uh,
chess is a crazy world.
Some of the things he says
about the Soviets are true.
In Tunis, we found
listening devices
in his hotel room.
"The communists...
Infect my mind with words
that just keep repeating.
The Jews are
helping them too.
The Jews wanna keep
the chess federation
all to themselves
just like
they own New York
and own and control
most governments
in the world."
We-- we--
we are Jewish.
Bobby is Jewish.
What do you people say to him
when he comes out
with this trash?
He doesn't listen to me.
He doesn't listen to anybody.
Joanie, look, I swear,
this isn't just
about the title anymore.
It's about the kind
of games he's playing.
Out of all
the crazy stuff,
such...
Unimaginable beauty.
A Da Vinci,
they're saying,
from Brooklyn.
Once every what,
500 years?
Grandmasters
are watching Bobby play
with tears in their eyes.
Joanie, look,
I'll take care of him.
Okay?
I'll make sure his life
doesn't get too crazy.
There he is! There he is!
Bobby, right here.
You've never beaten
spassky before. Why do you
think you can beat him now?
Bobby, look at me.
This is BBC news.
Today, Bobby fischer
beat Russian grandmaster
tigran petrosian...
In the semifinal
of the world chess
championships.
Fischer will now face
the current world champion,
Boris spassky.
Bobby, with this win
you're guaranteed a shot
at the championship.
How does it feel?
It's about time.
I always said I was the best.
Everyone said,
"oh, he's an arrogant,
terrible, conceited person."
But now it's just an
obvious fact I'm the best.
You've never beaten spassky.
The Russians are saying
you don't have a chance.
I don't care two cents
about him one way or the other.
He's just another guy.
What's this
about the Russians
spying on you?
Oh, yeah, sure. Yeah.
They, uh--
I've seen them following me.
They bugged the phones
in my hotel rooms.
I heard they can even listen
through the fillings
in your teeth.
- You're kidding, right?
- I'm not kidding.
Go see your dentist.
Petrosian said
he wasn't well.
He's the second Russian
to get sick playing you.
They're all getting sick.
Bobby!
Wide world of sports
is already offering
a segment.
Yeah.
Cavett wants you, and--
are you ready?
Are you sitting down?
Mike Wallace called.
60 minutes, Bobby.
Well, it's about time.
You know, I don't wanna
get distracted doing
a bunch of press though.
No, this is-- this is not
ordinary press, Bobby.
I know, I know.
I'll-I'll do the big ones.
Great.
That is great.
Only, um--
hey, I'm starving.
Let's get some food.
When we do
these shows,
yeah.
Just go easy
on the bugging
and the teeth.
What are you
talking about?
I'm just--
I'm just saying
what's on my mind.
I know. I know.
I'm telling the truth.
There's nothing wrong
with what I'm saying.
I know.
And people like that.
You need to be careful.
Some things you say,
they can be misinterpreted.
People get worried
when you talk like that.
What are you saying?
"People get worried."
Who? What people?
No one.
You're talking
about yourself.
No one.
Which of these interviews
do you wanna do?
Now, wait a second.
What did you mean,
"people begin to worry"?
What are you talking about?
Doesn't matter.
I think cavett
is a great idea.
Why do you keep
changing the subject?
I'm not changing--
I'm asking you a question.
You said people get worried.
What people?
Uh, Joan.
Joan? My sister?
How would you know that?
Did you talk to her?
I was in New York.
We, um-- we had
a cup of coffee.
You met with my sister?
Without telling me?
Wha-- why would you do that?
She called me.
What were you guys
talking about?
Were you
talking about me?
Well, I was looking out
for your interests.
That's my job.
Don't lawyer me, Paul.
I'm not trying to--
don't lawyer me.
You're talking
with my family
behind my back.
Did I ask you to do that?
What were you doing?
You're spying on me?
I was trying
to help you, Bobby.
I don't understand
why you thought
that was a good idea.
There are
a hundred more of you
just right behind you,
waiting in line
to be here.
Hey, pull over.
Um--
- stop the car.
- Wait a minute.
Bobby. Bobby.
We're about
to get everything
you've ever wanted.
Stop the car!
Pull over!
Stop the car now!
Bishop, bishop six.
Uh, king to queen four.
Rook, rook five.
Pawn to king five.
So?
- He's back in his room.
- Is he okay?
He's in there listening
to those tapes of his.
Isn't that, uh,
some kind of god squad?
Those people know
as much about god as you do.
I'd have thought
you'd approve.
Should we try to get him
to see someone?
A psychiatrist?
Never gonna happen.
Concierge told me
he asked to have the TV
removed from his room
'cause he thinks
the Russians are watching him
through the screen.
Maybe they are.
He also believes
they're gonna try
to blow up his plane.
What good would a doctor do?
Give him a diagnosis.
Hmm.
Uh, give him a pill.
That would be like
pouring concrete
down a holy well.
Bobby fischer,
the United States
chess champion,
has challenged
world champion Boris spassky
in a 24-game series.
...playing Boris spassky.
Are you afraid?
I'm not afraid of him.
He's afraid of me.
Last time we played,
a couple people said
they saw him trembling.
Fischer, the first
American in history
to reach the finals
of the world championship,
is the latest arrival
in our growing culture
of celebrity.
But who would have thought
that a chess player
could suddenly become
a rock star?
My next guest
is prepared to take on
the Russians single-handed.
And he may win.
Will you welcome
a bright boy from Brooklyn,
Mr. Bobby fischer?
All right.
Do you honestly think
that you probably are the
world's greatest chess player?
Yeah. Yeah, right.
You know
what life magazine said.
"Bobby fischer is
single-handedly changing
the face of chess,
making it
the fastest-growing sport..."
And what's the moment
of pleasure for you?
Is it when you see
the guy in trouble?
Where's
the greatest pleasure?
What would correspond
to hitting the home run
in baseball?
Greatest pleasure?
When you break his ego.
That's where it's at.
Really?
- Yeah.
And when does
that occur?
When he sees
that he's finished?
When he sees it coming
and breaks all up inside.
Their goal is nothing short
of world domination.
And unless they are stopped,
that goal soon will be
within their grasp.
Look at the godless
Soviet union
and their relentless march
across eastern Europe.
Look at the illegitimate
state of Israel
whose expansionist
ambitions have usurped
palestine from its true heirs
in the kingdom of Judah.
Indeed, the people of Israel
are not even the real Jews.
That tribe was taken captive by
king nebuchadnezzar of Babylon
in 600 bc.
Bobby,
turn the music down!
He doesn't want
the Russians to know
what plane we're taking.
And I want the food
to travel with us
on the plane, Paul!
You got it, Bobby!
We have some issues.
Well, the plane
leaves in two hours.
With the traffic--
- and make sure
there's enough oranges!
- Check!
There's never
enough oranges!
Uh-huh.
He wants all
the food flown in and
prepared in front of him.
Okay.
He also wants $46,875
in his bank account
before he plays.
He'll pick up the rest
when he wins.
Well, that's not
going to happen.
Yeah,
otherwise he's not going.
Which is what
he wants anyway.
What are you guys
whispering about
in there?
Just talking travel plans,
Bobby.
Who's traveling?
You're really serious
about all this?
They gotta give me what I want.
Mm-hmm.
And if they don't?
Well, we can play
in this hotel room.
I like it here.
Let me get this straight.
You're willing to throw all this
away for money and oranges?
That's right.
I don't need to play.
I know I'm the best.
I think you're scared.
And I think
you're overwhelmed.
Is that, like, um,
pop psychology?
Yeah.
You've got the passports,
right? You've got them?
Yeah.
I want my passport.
You-- you're not leaving
for a half an hour.
Yeah.
Yeah. Maybe I'll take
a later flight. Or not.
Okay.
That's kind of funny,
seeing a priest get mad.
I'm getting on the phone
right now.
I'm gonna
make this work.
I don't mind either way.
I really
got nothing to prove.
Well, what's the issue, Bobby?
I don't know.
Something's not right.
We settled too low.
I oughta get 30%.
Bobby,
we agreed on 25%.
Well, it's 30 now.
We agreed.
Well, I changed
my mind, Paul.
I understand that.
But, Bobby,
you just can't change
your mind like that.
We're here.
We're at the airport.
What am I supposed to do?
I don't have to get
on the plane.
I don't know.
You're not gonna
get on the plane?
Now?
What is this, Paul?
I told you!
No photographers!
Move it!
Move out of the way!
All right, fine.
Bobby!
Where to?
Just go! Drive!
Another bizarre turn today in
the world chess championships
when Bobby fischer
failed to appear
for the opening ceremonies.
Meanwhile, Bobby's opponent,
Boris spassky,
arrived in reykjavík today
to the excitement
of all of Iceland.
Three-day adjudicator
Wolfgang schmid,
had this to say.
I am honored, but confused.
I was always led to believe
that chess needed two people
for a game.
Unfortunately,
our American friends
have managed to lose
a famous Mr. Bobby fischer.
One hopes they are
not so careless
with their nuclear weapons.
Mr. tremblay,
is Bobby not showing affecting
Iceland relationships?
Is it true
he denied two million dollars
to come to reykjavík?
I love chess.
The world loves chess.
We are here
to celebrate chess.
Excuse us, please.
Still no sign of Bobby fischer,
the American chess player
who thinks he's the best
in the world.
Fischer today was supposed to
be in reykjavík, Iceland
to start playing Boris spassky
of the Soviet union
in what promises to be
the super bowl
of the chess world,
if it ever comes off,
and that's a big if.
Fischer is still believed to be
in New York City, where he was
last seen in public...
Mama?
Yeah, baby.
There are men
on the lawn.
Today the international
chess federation said
come here.
If fischer is not in Iceland
by noon on Tuesday,
he will be disqualified.
In other news, the white house
refused to comment
on the recent break-in
at the Watergate headquarters
of the Democratic
national committee.
Hello? Hello?
Bobby, is that you?
Yeah. I, uh--
they promised me
no photographers and
a bunch of them showed up,
so I had to get
out of there.
Where are you?
I'm-I'm here.
I'm at home.
I was going to the airport, and
they promised no photographers,
and a bunch of them showed up,
so I had to get out of there.
I had to
show them,
Joan.
They told me
no photographers.
They keep doing this to me,
everywhere I go,
all the time.
People keep
doing this to me.
Yeah.
It's not fair.
Bobby,
are you okay, huh?
Well, you know that 727
that went down?
You know, they said
the fuel tank exploded.
Yeah, well that seemed
kind of funny to me.
Right?
You know, they don't
tell us everything.
Yeah, no, they don't.
That's true.
And the kgb,
they kill people.
They do.
Th-th-that's real.
They put poison on the tips of
their umbrellas, crazy things.
You understand?
Yeah.
Baby, you stay there, okay?
I'm going to come over.
These people,
i wouldn't put
anything past them.
Who-who people, Bobby?
The Russians.
You believe me.
They would like it
if I dropped dead tonight.
You hear that?
Shh, shh, shh!
-  Do I hear what?
Shh.
I don't know. There's
a noise on the phone.
Do you hear it?
No, I don't hear anything.
Bobby?
We have a NATO base out there,
and I asked for the marines
to guard me.
They said no to me.
They said no, Joan.
With all the prestige
i am bringing
to this country.
I'm the most famous man
in the world.
Do you hear that?
They put stuff
in my food to mess
with my mind, you know?
I don't know.
Bobby, you stay there.
I'm-I'm gonna come over.
No, no, no, no, no.
Listen.
Joan, listen to me.
I'm trying to
tell you something.
I keep-- I keep
thinking about this.
I keep going over it
and over it
and over it in my mind.
I can't figure out
what's next, Joan.
Do you know what I mean?
Yeah. Yeah.
Do you understand?
I understand, baby. Yeah.
- Bobby--
- shh! Joan.
Goddamn it.
Do you hear that?
There's a noise.
Joan.
I'm gonna
get off the phone.
Bobby, you--
uh, who's there?
Hey, pal, you in there?
Hey, can I come in?
Got big news.
Yeah, what's that?
You wanted more money?
I just got you
an extra 130k.
Some English chess nut
wants to see you play so bad.
Is the money real?
It's real. It's good.
It's secure.
May I use your phone?
Let folks know you're okay?
- Hey, who's that?
- That's, uh, security.
They've fixed it
for us at the airport.
We can go straight to the plane.
No press.
Yes. Hello?
I found him.
It's Henry kissinger.
Pretty amazing,
huh?
Hello?
Dr. kissinger's on the line.
Hello. This is the worst
chess player in the world
calling the best chess player
in the world.
We just want you to know,
the president and I,
that we are thrilled that
you will be going to Iceland
to play for the usa, Bobby.
Yeah. Yeah.
I, uh-- I decided to play.
This is
the BBC world service.
American chess grandmaster,
Bobby fischer,
is believed to be finally
on his way to Iceland for
his match with Boris spassky.
This is how we used to
get Jagger out of here.
After months of negotiation,
fischer will now face
the current world champion,
Boris spassky.
What do you think of Bobby?
I don't know.
Uh, least there's
one reason to feel good
about America.
- A bit impolite.
- Fischer is to chess
like Ali is to boxing.
He's tedious. He's arrogant.
He's inconsiderate.
At long last, Bobby fischer
arrived in reykjavík today
after months of speculation
that he wouldn't appear at all.
Yeah, well the Russians have
been telling lies about me
since I was a kid.
- How do you like Iceland?
- Iceland?
Yeah, I'm happy to be here.
I feel like a viking,
ready to conquer.
Come in.
Take a look around.
Yeah.
There's good.
It's, uh,
five bedrooms.
Place even
has a sauna.
All right.
I'm gonna check out the rooms,
see which one I want.
Go for it.
Yeah.
Huh. Hey, uh,
what are you doing here?
I took a little time.
All right.
You want to work?
Want to analyze
some positions?
Nah, maybe later.
What's wrong? You sick?
I'm just taking a break.
Okay. I'll check up
on you in a few hours.
It's good to see you, Bobby.
Yeah, sure.
Couldn't stay away, huh?
Well, I get it.
Yankees are playing
in the series, you want
a seat in the dugout.
Can I get one of these?
Billion people
around the world
watching two guys play chess.
Nixon's put a TV
in the oval office.
Oh, yeah?
Mmm.
World war III
on a chess board.
We lost China.
We're losing
Vietnam.
We have to win this one.
This is abc's
wide world of sports,
bringing you live
coverage of the
world championship of chess.
Best of 24 games.
Each win is worth a point.
Each draw is half a point.
It's the chess version
of a 15-round heavyweight
prize fight.
And the noise from the crowd
tells us that Boris spassky...
...in what will surely be
an historic confrontation.
Where is he?
If the press could please
take their seats,
we will now come together
for the drawing of the colors.
Mr. spassky?
Mr. fischer, choose.
Mr. fischer chose black.
Mr. spassky will begin.
So far, so good, yeah?
Mmm. They're playing
a variation on a nimzo.
A draw would be fine
for our side.
Is that bad?
No, no.
It simplifies the game.
Your cameras are making
too much noise.
It's distracting.
I'll be back.
From
the cameras?
Yeah, they're going like--
come here.
Do you hear that?
It's just a camera.
Yeah. Well, you've got
to move it back.
What?
Move the camera back.
Move it back.
-You've got to get the audience
under control too.
-What's wrong with the audience?
They're making too much noise,
and you're not doing anything.
That's your job.
All right?
Do your job.
Mr. spassky's made his move.
It's good.
Yes, yes.
Herr schmid,
Mr. schmid,
he's trying to
upset my player.
You see,
the camera was making noise.
We just moved it back.
- He is upsetting my player.
- Yes, it's fine.
If you could just
take your seats, please.
Thank you.
You don't look well,
Robert James.
First game
goes to Boris spassky.
Bobby!
- Hold on a second!
- Don't yell at him.
I'm not yelling at him.
Bobby!
It's just one game.
One point.
You'll take
the next one.
Twelve and a half points
is-is a long match.
The reporters
will go after spassky.
We could slip out
another way.
You all right?
You hear that?
It's quiet in here.
Boris! Boris!
How did you feel?
How you doing, Bobby?
- I'm not
going to do it anymore.
- Do what?
Play with
all these distractions.
It's like a circus.
It's not
what we agreed to.
You know, they've been
doing this to me for years.
Making me
all these promises.
They all turn out to be lies.
They've been doing it to me
since I was a kid.
You know,
i would get stuck in Europe
with huge hotel room bills
when I was 15 years old.
The federation would
raise money off of my back
and funnel it to reshevsky.
Another Jew, by the way.
I don't know
what I did to them.
And they're all out to screw me.
The Russians and the Jews--
they got their dirty
little fingerprints
all over everything.
What are we
talking about?
The Jews.
Ah.
You made a stupid mistake,
and you got your ass
handed to you.
No. I am not going to submit
to their game.
- If you don't get
your head in the game--
- we're going to play my way!
You're not just
gonna lose!
No audience, no distractions!
Humiliated in front
of billions of people!
You guys brought me here
under false pretenses,
and you're going to fix it!
This is how I play!
You know,
his mistake is that
he didn't see this bishop.
Unless the rest of the games
are played without an audience
and without cameras,
he isn't going to show up.
He won't continue unless
the games are played
in the ping-pong room?
That's the only place
that's quiet, he says.
He also wants
a different board.
Makes too much noise
when he puts the pieces down.
He prefers wood.
It's like morphy.
It's destroying his brain.
No, chess
isn't destroying him.
Why all the demands?
It's like he wants them
to say no.
I think he's afraid of
what's gonna happen if he loses.
No. He's afraid of
what's going to happen
if he wins.
If the press could
please take their seats.
The match was scheduled
to begin at 5:00.
We will now start the clock.
Mr. fischer failed to show.
Mr. spassky
wins by forfeit.
According to federation rules,
Mr. fischer has 24 hours
to indicate in writing
that he wishes to continue,
otherwise Mr. spassky
will be declared world champion.
The match between Boris spassky
and Bobby fischer
has taken
a decidedly disappointing turn.
News in reykjavík, Iceland
today,
Bobby fischer failed to show up.
...the match is spassky's,
regardless of what happens now.
A two-point advantage
is considered
practically insurmountable.
Unpredictable Bobby fischer
stayed in bed today
rather than show up
for game 2
in his world title match
with chess champion
Boris spassky.
The future of the match
now is clouded in doubt,
although game 3 is still
scheduled for Sunday.
Bobby?
I have messages from people
all over the world who
want you to open this door.
Bobby?
The president
of the United States
called three times.
Three.
Uh, well,
he's been trying to reach you.
In Moscow,
brezhnev opened his only bottle
of 1868 Louis roederer,
left over from the revolution.
You know why?
Because he heard you quit.
There are boys
your age in Vietnam
giving their lives right now
in the fight against communism,
and all you have to do
is play a game of chess.
Bobby, I've been arguing
on your behalf all night long!
I-I've been
threatening them for you.
I have cajoled.
I have begged them!
Now I'm begging you.
Please, please, please.
Go back in there and play.
You're one of them,
aren't you?
- What?
- Who got to you?
- Kgb? CIA?
- Are you serious?
This is BBC news.
The world chess championship
looks to be ending
in humiliation
for the American
Bobby fischer
whose demands that the game
be held in a rec room have
led to widespread ridicule.
Huh?
Ah.
Stop here.
Thank you.
Oh, hey.
You won't believe it.
Spassky's agreed to play
in the ping-pong room.
Yeah. Right.
Wait.
Where are you going?
Only one camera.
It does not move.
It makes no sound.
Good?
Good day.
Thank you.
So please, gentlemen.
If we can remember,
the world is watching.
Did Nixon
really call you?
Game's starting.
What's he doing?
I don't know.
He's playing the benoni.
Black, two games down.
He thinks it's suicide.
Is it suicide?
Yeah.
- What's happening?
- He's exposing his king.
He's going to end up with
doubled-up pawns. He wants him
to take it with the bishop.
Uh-huh.
Yeah, shit.
Oh, my god.
He's threatening mate in one.
He's going to force
the exchange of these knights.
He hates draws.
- He takes him.
Check.
- Yeah!
Bobby fischer beat Boris spassky
today in the third game
of the world chess championship.
Bobby fischer
won his first game ever
from Russia's--
Boris spassky
resigned today's game
on the 42nd move.
Fischer mania is taking
the country by storm
as news of Bobby fischer's
first victory
over Boris spassky
has captured
the public's imagination.
Bobby,
i love you so much.
I know you're
going to do amazing.
And win it for usa!
- Go usa!
- Number one!
Bobby! Bobby!
A chess craze
is sweeping the nation.
You can find it being played
in every living room,
park and classroom.
And the young man
from Brooklyn, little known
until about a month ago,
is quickly becoming
the most famous celebrity
in the world.
You can't imagine the tension
involved in a head-to-head match
like this.
Excuse me?
Spassky took
Bobby's bishop.
Yeah, well,
i took his virginity.
Oh, wait.
Bobby's making a move.
Excuse me.
They drew game 4 last night,
you know?
Yeah, we know, asshole.
We're watching the rerun.
Hmm?
Schieße.
Game 5 goes
to Mr. Bobby fischer.
Mr. spassky.
An electrical engineer examined
the lighting fixture and made
an astounding discovery.
Inside, he found this.
Two dead flies.
Bobby fischer's
comeback
in this match.
That's historic in chess.
Certainly, Jim.
And at this stage it looks as
though whoever wins this game...
Will most likely go on to
take the entire match.
This one game, game 6,
will determine the outcome?
I certainly think so.
Well, now we'll just
have to see what happens.
Fischer has agreed to return
to play in the main hall.
Press could
step back, please?
Thank you.
What's he doing?
We all can't quite
believe it up here, Jim,
but in this,
the pivotal game of the match,
fischer has abandoned
his trademark sicilian opening.
All of spassky's careful
preparation is suddenly
out the window.
Grandmasters are shaking
their heads in confusion.
Fischer's moves are
unprecedented in chess history.
No one seems to be able
to decipher what he's doing.
Bravo.
Grandmasters never applaud
an opponent's victory,
but I guess this is something
no one has ever seen before.
- Bobby?
- Can I get you anything?
Oh, no, thanks.
It'll be light soon.
Yeah, it's never
really dark here.
You know, Bobby,
the chess you've been playing
is really inspired.
It's almost all, um,
theory and memorization.
People think there are
all these options, but...
There's usually
one right move.
Of course, in the end,
there's no place to go.
The United States is based
on lies. It's based on theft.
Look at all I've done
for the us. But now
I'm not useful anymore, you see?
The cold war is over, and now
they want to put me in prison.
I'm not sure, but if I know
the Jews in the us,
they may come at me
with some attack I don't expect.
Life is like that, and people
are living in a dream world.
It's not really paradoxical.
Chess is, uh, basically
a search for truth, right?
- Right.
- So I'm searching for the truth.
Fixed & Synced By MoUsTaFa ZaKi