How far back do you want me to go?
College?
I was totally outgoing.
A real people person.
In high school, I felt like that mouse
that gets dropped into the snake cage
and just kinda sits there,
frozen, trying to blend in.
I guess I remember being happy
when I was a kid.
Back when you just naturally expect
good things to happen.
Before my mom died.
Now I just expect the worst
and try not to get my hopes up.
Which is why I'm here.
Does that answer the question?
Usually people just say where they're from
and where they worked before.
Great. I'm already overqualified.
So, in your previous experience,
can you give me an instance
in which you went above and beyond
the call of duty for a customer?
No.
I get it.
You think you're too good for this.
Why are you even here?
No, I'm sorry...
I really need the money.
I live at home,
I work my ass off at this internship.
- I just...
- Yeah, it's not gonna work out here.
I can tell your type.
You're just not a quality hire.
Wazzup?
No, I don't want the prepubescent look.
I want a woman.
We don't retouch at Seattle Magazine.
We're journalists.
No, not there. An intern.
Yeah.
That's what I'm saying. We respect women.
Don't put that there.
That goes in the utility closet...
- I know...
- And then refresh all the bathrooms.
I was just giving you this change.
Yeah, this is my job now.
It's like spelling things out for interns.
Fuck! Okay.
Writers, ideas.
It's idea time again. It's that time.
What have you got?
Does anybody have an idea? Or a story?
Are you guys here?
Can you hear me? Anyone?
- Top 10 dog parks in Seattle.
- No.
Summer activities for winter people.
Not interested. Jeff?
All right. How about this time travel ad?
What have you got?
Yeah, somebody e-mailed it in
from the classifieds.
He's looking for somebody to go
back in time with him.
Do a little tongue-in-cheek investigation.
Find this guy, see if he
thinks it's real or if it's a prank.
Not bad.
The guy says, "You'll get paid
when you get back.
"Bring your own weapons.
"Safety's not guaranteed."
And he's only done this once before.
See if maybe he believes in this stuff.
I don't know. I think it could be funny.
You wanna do it? All right. You got it.
Can I get a couple interns?
- Help me with the research?
- I'll do it.
- Do some heavy lifting...
- Me, too, please. Me.
All right. Give me the lesbian and
the Indian, and I got a story.
We sent a letter to the address in the ad
and asked them to get back to us.
And I called the local paper,
but they're really uptight about giving
out information on people that take out
ads, so...
I fucked Bridget.
Yeah. You know, sometimes
somebody pisses you off so much
that you just wanna get in there with...
Did she like criticize your technique
the whole time?
Like boss you around? She did, right?
Maybe a little.
All right, we should go.
Let's go to Ocean View.
We can just find whoever put up the ad
and stake him out.
We? What do you mean "we"?
I mean we, the three of us.
Nowyou don't wanna go?
- That place sucks.
- That place does not suck.
I had the best summer of my life
in Ocean View.
I'm not going.
- Yeah, you are.
- No.
It seemed like I was asking,
but I'm actually telling as your boss.
You're coming.
Dad, I'm going out of town for a few days.
- Out out?
- No, it's just this work thing.
Yeah, I think it'd be great if you went
out, did a little social stuff.
Get out of your funk.
I have no funk. I'm totally funkless.
Going out and being with your friends.
I think it's a great idea.
What's wrong with me?
Well, you're sad.
I don't know how to describe it.
It's like there's a cloud following you.
- You're antisocial, and you're a virgin.
- What?
I don't ever see you with any guys.
I don't remember the last time
you brought a guy home.
Yeah, well, how do you know I'm not
on Craigslist having casual encounters?
Or when I was away at the dorms?
You weren't there.
I talked to Amy.
Why are you talking
to my college roommate?
We're Facebook friends.
Oh, my God! How do I eject?
Why do you have flames on your laptop?
It's a gaming laptop. It's really fast.
What time would you go back to?
- If you could?
- I don't know.
- I'm fine here.
- I would definitely go back.
Everything cool is gone.
The Aztecs.
People killing themselves for each other.
You wouldn't wanna see the dragons
and the elves
fight each other in the magical forest?
- Come on!
- No. That wasn't a time.
- Yeah. Okay.
- Yeah.
Get in, retards.
So, here's what I'm thinking.
We're budgeted for two rooms,
but if we share a room,
we can use that extra money
for some other shit.
- What, drugs?
- That's exactly right.
Easy, Arnau, we're messing with you, pal.
We're talking about using it
for buffets and shit.
You never done coke or anything
when you're studying for an exam?
Cocaine? Are you crazy?
- What is it you study?
- Biological and life sciences.
Makes sense. So what are you doing
interning at a magazine?
Diversity looks good on an application
for grad school.
We got to get you laid on this vacation.
That's what needs to happen.
- Vacation?
- All right, work trip, whatever.
It's freezing here.
It's got bite, don't it?
Reminds me of going back to school.
Yes. It's all one long school year now.
No start, no finish.
Except for this guy.
How many years till you graduate, Arnau?
Total, including doctorate
orjust undergraduate?
Forget it.
How're we doing the beds?
We'll do me in one, interns on the other.
- Okay.
- No.
Cool. Me and Darius.
Fine. I hope you moisturize, Arnau,
'cause I cuddle.
Tomorrow morning first thing,
we hit the post office.
Let's hope our boy checks
his P.O. Box every day.
There she is.
What?
"Wanted, someone to travel
back in time with me,
"this is not a joke.
"P.O. Box 91 Ocean View, Washington.
"You'll get paid after we get back.
Must bring your own weapons.
"Safety not guaranteed."
Hey, here we go.
No way. He's too old to be time traveling.
Come on. That's the time traveling demo.
White beards, spectacles, pipes.
- Close.
- Wait, what about this one?
Yeah. She wants to stop whoever
gave her that haircut from being born.
Yo! Yo! It's him. It's the guy.
Him? Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure. Box 91. Get in.
- Wait, what are you doing?
- Following him.
What about Jeff? You should call him!
That's pretty amazing stuff, man.
I'll tell you about the cat in the
box theory, it'll blowyour mind.
It's like I'm the only one who
really gets it. You know?
I started this dialog with some
big shot theoretical physicist online,
and I'm like, "Do the rules of quantum
mechanics allowfor alternate histories?"
And he just blasted me.
You know, people are just so convinced
it's a fixed thing,
but they're just, like, looking
at this little sliver of time,
that's all people can see.
It's not a fixed thing, Shannon.
You know, it's on and on in both directions.
It's like a "V," you knowwhat I mean?
I gotta do a bathroom check, brother.
Yeah, you knowwhat I'm saying.
I'd like to fill out a comment card
on one of your employees, Kenneth.
What's his last name?
Sorry, ma'am, he's a little...
No, no, it's a positive comment.
It's like complimenting him.
Good. Kenneth Calloway.
Calloway.
Thanks.
Hit the thing that says I have
a new message.
"Liz confirmed you on Facebook."
Here. No photos, that's a drag.
Okay, good. She still lives here.
She lives in this town.
Who is Liz McHollis?
She was a girl I had a fling with
when my family used to come here
over the summers.
She was this really smokin' hot blond.
She was my first blowjob.
If there's one girl
that I still think about, honestly.
Here she is. Look at you,
you went all rogue.
What did you get?
- Got his name, where he works.
- Great.
What did you guys get?
She accepted, but no photo,
so I'm not really sure.
What?
He came here to hook up
with an old high school girlfriend.
Seriously? That's what you've been doing?
Well, I've been doing other stuff too, but
maybe this will change your attitude
a little bit.
That's her when she was 18,
I used to see her naked.
So?
So I'm coming back
to try to see her naked again.
I'd be weirded out if some guy tried
to track me down after 20 years.
I'd be weirded out too
if some guy tried to track you down.
- Why?
- Who would do that?
Tomorrow morning, I'll go in.
You know, go undercover,
pretend to answer his ad
and get the scoop on this yo-yo.
- 991 Mallory. This is definitely it.
- What a piece of shit.
All right, I'm goin' in.
- How do I look, Arnau? Good.
- Good.
- Can I go in?
- No, you did good last night,
but I'm gonna handle this.
I don't wanna overwhelm the guy.
All right? Wish me luck.
So...
Do you go out a lot back home,
like clubs and stuff?
Not really.
You know those really tight leggings
that girls wear,
do you ever wear those?
No.
I think you would look nice in them.
Hello?
Kenneth?
Kenneth? Kenneth Calloway, right?
Is that right?
My name is Jeff.
Look, I sawyour ad in the classifieds.
I wanna know if you need a partner.
- What's your mission?
- What do you mean what's my mission?
What's your reason for going back?
Well, who wouldn't want to go back?
It's an amazing opportunity.
To go back in time, you know?
See gladiators and watch dinosaurs
with my own eyes.
Have sex with a pilgrim.
Fun stuff, that's all I want.
I wanna go back. It's neat.
Who wouldn't want to go back, Kenneth?
You wanna go back.
Why do you wanna go back?
Well, do you need a partner?
- Can you look fear and danger in the eye?
- That's an odd question.
Have you ever stared
fear and danger in the eye
and said, "Yes"?
- Sure.
- Get off my porch.
Let's start over.
Come on, we could be pals.
Let's go back in time.
Man, that smile...
What is that smile?
- You don't know pain.
- I don't know pain?
- You don't know regret.
- Yeah. All right.
- You don't know...
- Okay.
Well, it was really nice to meet you.
That's what I thought.
So, what'd he say?
Well, he's the real deal.
That ad is no prank.
He's not like retarded,
but there's something wrong with this guy.
Definitely didn't like my ass,
I'll tell you that.
- So, what, that's it?
- Oh, no, this just got good.
What makes you think
he won't slam the door in my face, too?
'Cause you gotta be sincere
and charm him, okay?
He's used to assholes like me
coming and making fun of him.
Also probably none of the other people
were beautiful girls.
- Easy, Arnau.
- What?
But he's right. Use that, too.
There's something off about this guy, okay?
So you gotta go slow,
like you're trapping a skittish animal.
You know, lure him, play coy.
Girls know how to do that shit.
You're dangling my vagina
out there like bait?
What if this guy's a murderer?
What if he cuts me up into little pieces
and eats me?
Then the story's even better.
Do you sell guns here?
- What kind of guns?
- I don't know.
Something sexy and affordable
with killing power.
You should try C&R Guns in Wilkins.
The state of Washington does not allow
the sale of firearms in the business
premises of a grocer.
What about those thingies
with the spiky ball
at the end of the chain things?
You know, with the... Do you have those?
What exactly is the intended use?
Is there a pest problem, or hunting?
Well, if your ad had been written properly,
I may have a better idea of what I need.
- My ad?
- Yeah.
- It's pretty sloppy.
- Excuse me?
You heard me.
I hope you worked harder
on your calibrations.
My calibrations are flippin'
pinpoint, okay?
There are people after me.
How do I knowyou don't work for them?
Because I've never worked
for anybody in my life.
You ever faced certain death?
If it was so certain,
I wouldn't be here, would I?
This is a bad place to talk.
I get off in like 15. Rendezvous?
See you in eight.
- Get down!
- What's going on?
- Just get down! Don't let him see you.
- Wait, is he coming?
- Yeah.
- What the hell is he doing?
I don't know. He's all freaked out.
He thinks people are following him.
We're gonna rendezvous.
He's taking me to a secure location.
Get down!
If this guy's taking you to some
sex bunker, he's gonna be freaked out
when me and Arnau pull out of this thing
like it's a clown car.
- Hey, what's going on out there?
- Get down!
Shit! He's coming!
Don't let him see me,
it'll blow everything for you.
- What am I supposed to do?
- I don't know! Do something!
We're being followed!
Go! Get in your car! Go!
What the hell is this?
- Oh, shit!
- Git! Git! Go! Get out!
- What the fuck?
- He's got a gun!
- Just get out.
- Where are we?
I don't know. Just get out.
I'll come get you when I'm done. Come on!
- I don't know.
- Yeah. Fuck that.
- Are you guys racist?
- It's complicated.
- Hello?
- It's too hot here right now. Can't talk.
Look, my gut tells me you're not with them,
but I have to be absolutely certain.
I'm gonna do
a quick background check on you.
If everything is good,
I'll be in touch, okay?
Yeah, okay.
All right, over and... Good night.
Hi, is Liz around?
And it's not necessarily...
It's not a false relationship,
but she's so charismatic.
She's such a beam of light.
All the reporters are saying that.
Also, what I'm reading from...
I don't know. She was big, and like...
And like your age? Yeah. Gross.
It was more like...
I don't know, like the years
have not been kind to her, you know?
They pretty much took a shit
all over her face.
- So, did your dude call yet?
- No.
Maybe we should do a background check
on this guy,
you know, make sure he's not a psychopath.
- He seems pretty harmless.
- Don't worry, Darius, he'll call.
I'm sure your weird mojo clicked with
his weird mojo and you got it in the bag.
- C'mon!
- Ready, hike!
Hi.
- Thanks.
- Listen, I'm sorry about the noise level here.
But we need to maintain cover.
I'm certain I'm being recorded,
I'm certain I'm being followed.
So, who are we dealing with here?
I'm not sure yet.
Government agents maybe. Probably.
But the joke's on them.
The technology I've invented
can't be understood by the average mind.
So, what are the means of transportation?
Just hold it in your holster
for a second, okay?
I'm still making up my mind about you
as a potential partner.
I have to be absolutely certain
that I can trust you
before I include you in certain
information.
Well, I just don't wanna be jerked around.
You know, jerking around is forjerks.
God, I remember this smell.
The smell of grass.
I used to play a little bit,
back in the day.
- I think you should give Liz
another chance.
- Oh, you do?
That sucks to spend all that time
thinking about her,
and you're finally here
and you don't follow through with it.
I think it's sad that you're a 22-year-old
virgin with those creepy glasses,
but I don't bring it up.
You knowwhat? Actually, Arnau,
there are lots of hot chicks here, man.
You could kill in a place like this.
You should run game.
Arnau, Arnau, Arnau, be cool, run game.
- She's in high school.
- I know!
I know she's in high school
and you're in college.
Who do you think that girl wants to fuck?
You!
- Could you, please!
- What?
So what's the year? Where are we going?
- 2001. Is that gonna work for you?
- It's perfect.
I will need to know the timetable, though.
There's a critical step soon.
I need to obtain certain materials
to facilitate the travel.
I plan to execute this step
within the next week.
Why 2001? What are you going back for?
Like I said, certain information
will have to wait.
Knock him on his ass, he's a bum!
- Right there, these two.
- All right. Let's go.
Why? Sit down. We're not going anywhere.
Tell me why. Why?
You're drinking alcohol
at a high school game.
You're damn right I am.
United States ofAmerica.
Drinking a beer at a football game.
Don't get tough on me, big guy.
Let's not do this.
Wait a minute, I know him.
He came to my house.
I think that guy
is recording our conversation.
Is there somewhere else we can go?
Let's get out of here. Come on.
- Stay close. Yeah.
- Are you okay?
I really would have messed that guy up
if I wasn't trying to keep such a
low profile.
I'm glad I got to see your qualities,
though.
I think you're ready for the next step,
some basic training.
The heat's moving in.
That's all for tonight.
I'm leaving. I'm walking out!
I'm leaving by choice. By choice.
- Seriously?
- This place is a dump.
Let's get out of here.
Fuck.
Pretty good. You might be a one
arm shooter.
- Okay, I'll try it.
- Let's just loosen it up.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
- Yeah! You smoked him!
- I smoked him.
Come on!
I think I'm getting better than you.
Hey, let's not get ahead of
yourself here, okay?
It's one thing to hit a target
that's standing still,
but think about it when the
heat's moving in.
Smoke it!
Double smoke!
- How are your hamstrings holding up?
- Real good.
You're pretty impressive with a handgun.
It's a superlative performance
under simulated pressure.
Our chemistry is starting to build.
I really like your intensity.
You're, like, no-nonsense.
There's no sense in nonsense.
Especially when the heat's hot.
Exactly.
I like your intensity, too.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. You've got good moves.
Nobody's seen my moves before.
Haven't brought a candidate
this far into the training process.
Really?
We'll be learning from each other
from now on.
Good.
We still have to discuss your reason
for going back.
That's classified information.
I can appreciate that, I respect that,
but I have a certain responsibility to
keep as the leader of this mission.
Then I have to tell you that it's personal.
Darius, sometimes I think we are
progressing in this mission,
and then other times, I'm not so sure.
I'm going back to stop my mother
from dying when I was 14.
How'd she die?
She was killed by some guy.
Just some guy at a gas station
took her and killed her.
- Oh, man. Just some random thing?
- Yeah.
Well, no, actually.
She was driving home. It was really late,
and she called me to tell me
she was coming home, and I...
I asked her to stop
and get me chocolate milk.
Because I had to have chocolate milk.
So like five minutes later, she called me
to tell me that she got the chocolate milk
and she was coming home.
And her voice was like,
really excited, like she was really happy.
And I was, like, okay, whatever.
I wasn't even nice.
That was the last time I talked to her.
That's not your fault.
Yeah. That's what they tell me.
All right, Darius.
I think you're ready. I trust you.
Good.
You should.
- Jeff! Hey!
- Hey. Liz, it's great to see you.
- Look at you.
- So, this is where you live.
- This is my house.
Well, look, I wanna say
I'm sorry about yesterday.
I was gonna come,
but work's getting crazy and...
I was sad 'cause you got me
thinking about you on that Facebook.
- I never thought I'd see you again.
Oh, God, excuse me. Would you come in?
I'd love to.
Your hair's red.
Yeah.
It's different.
Yeah. I changed it.
It's just about the only thing
I've changed.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Kind of. What about you?
A lot has changed. Almost, like,
everything.
- Tell me.
- The car... I got an Escalade.
And my job's going really well.
Got a great condo.
Tell me about your life.
I just did.
- I've got to read this magazine of yours.
- Oh, don't.
- That is so exciting.
- It's not that exciting.
You knowwhat?
I always thought you'd do something
special with your life.
If you knewwhat it was really like,
you wouldn't say it was special.
Oh, come on. What...
- What's wrong with your neck?
- Sorry I'm doing that.
It's just I got this shooting pain.
I have to share a bed with a male intern.
And I don't feel like
rubbing asses with him, so...
- Let me see.
- You don't have to do that.
- You need to put some heat on that.
- I do?
- I have pies in the oven.
- You make pies?
I made some pies.
I made peach, apple, strawberry rhubarb.
Which one do you want?
Yeah.
Liz, that is unbelievable.
You bake pies, you give these massages,
and you're not married?
I don't get it.
I was married. He was a ball player.
And I was the good little wife,
baking cookies for the team.
Oh, my God, you bake cookies, too?
Cameron got traded,
and when he went up to the Marlins,
he started making money
and started messing around
with those Miami girls.
Well, I can say this honestly,
Cameron's an idiot.
Yeah, well, we were young.
Hey, do you have one free night
while you're in town?
Because I would like to make you
a homemade dinner.
I wanna eat that homemade dinner.
I'm just gonna press "record." Okay.
So, Kenneth,
why are you looking for a partner?
I feel like
the world is mostly full ofjankholes,
but I believe that there are
purists out there,
and that's why I put that ad in the paper.
It's my hope that
if you're watching this video,
something incredible has happened.
I do believe that martial arts
are for self-defense only.
While I would like to maneuver through
this world with an open heart and mind,
sometimes that doesn't gain you favor.
So I just need to be equipped
with the necessary skill sets,
guns, training, weapons, fighting,
in case I encounter any obstacles
that need to be defeated.
- The area is clear.
- Oh, my God!
Mission accomplished.
- Wow! Man, that was intense.
- Task completed.
The mission has to do with regret
and the mission has to do with mistakes.
The mission's also about love.
I'm already saying too much.
Aren't you interested in some of
this equipment or something?
Can we talk about something else?
So it's very important that you and I
do not abuse the power
that will come with our knowledge
of the future.
No matter how tempting
it will be to gain personal fortune
or notoriety by say,
being the first person to list
the Contra code for up, up,
down, down, left-right,
left-right, B-A-start.
Or to say, "Hey, leave your Star Wars
figurines in the box
"'cause they'll be worth like hundreds
more if they are super pristine."
But what about if it's, like,
for the betterment of future society?
Absolutely not.
We have to stick to the plan.
So when do you fill me in on the plan?
Pretty soon. The action's getting hungry.
I can't eat here.
- Why?
- See that kid? He's like a mutant kid.
Hey, there's something on your ear.
- It's fine, it does...
- Are you okay?
- It looks like it's falling off or something.
- No, no, no. It's fine. Don't worry about it.
Shit! Sorry. It's off.
- Kenneth!
- The mission's off, I'm sorry.
Forget it. You're not the right one.
Hey, what's wrong?
It's fake.
- What's fake?
- My flipping ear is fake.
They used to make fun of me,
all the other kids.
My parents could only afford one prosthetic,
so I had to wait until I was fully-grown.
- You know that's not a big deal, right?
- Yes, it is!
No, it isn't.
People used to make fun of me, too.
Yeah, right.
I shave my arms and wax my upper lip, okay?
- You're saying that to make me feel better.
- I'm serious.
I had a freaking mustache until I was 14.
Okay, we can still do this,
but you have to promise me
we're never, ever gonna talk about
my ear ever again
for as long as you and I both shall live.
- Okay. Okay.
- Forever.
- But can I say something?
- What?
I think it's kinda cool.
- Get in.
- Okay.
So then, what did you tell him your reason
for going back to 2001 is?
I just made up some story.
Yeah? What's the story?
I told him that I was gonna go back
and stop my parents from getting divorced.
Arnau, you son of a bitch. Smash him!
What are you doing?
Whatever I'm doing,
I'm feeling fan-fucking-tastic doing it.
Did you just have sex with that girl
you came here to stalk?
No, I didn't, actually.
We shared a nice conversation.
And you know the truth is,
she's not that fat.
I don't know, a girl's beauty,
it's in the eyes, you know?
And that doesn't go away with age.
So, anyway,
can we please just focus on the article
and figure out what's wrong with this guy,
like low I.Q.,
or emotional disorder, or whatever it is?
What makes you think there's something
wrong with him?
'Cause he thinks he can go back in time.
Was there something wrong with Einstein
or David Bowie?
Not the same.
Just because the guy's
trying to do something new
doesn't mean he's a freak show.
So you think this is normal?
I don't know. Is it normal that your
interns do all your work for you?
- Is that normal?
- Right.
Is that how all your articles get written?
It's him. I have to go.
Okay, this is it.
There's technology inside this building
that I need to complete the machine
that will take us on ourjourney.
I'm gonna breach the outer perimeter,
gonna disable their security measures,
penetrate the target,
locate and secure the package,
then we'll rendezvous at the getaway point.
You got it?
Rendezvous at the getaway point.
- I've been watching this place for weeks.
- Yeah, got it.
- The security's full of holes.
We'll be fine.
- Okay.
- Fuck!
- Stay focused.
What am I doing? Why am I doing this?
Let me see those keys.
Shit!
Okay.
Come on!
Excuse me?
Hey! Hey! What is that? What are those?
- Lasers.
- Lasers?
- Those are real lasers?
- The mission's been compromised.
Hey. Where are you going?
Let's get out of here! Drive!
- Floor it!
- Sorry.
What do we do with the van?
Leave it. I stole it from the lot.
Hey, you didn't hurt anyone, did you?
Like, you didn't...
No, no, no, no. Look, it's a fake.
- No casualties. Here. Take it.
- Okay.
- You okay?
- Yeah.
Take this. It'll make you feel better.
You're shaking.
It's just adrenaline from the infiltration.
It's good.
- You ready? Come on, let's go. Come on.
- Yeah. Yeah.
Go. Go.
We gotta stick to the back roads,
we can't be seen out here.
Oh, my God! Okay.
- Damn it! We're getting off the road.
- Why?
Those are government employees.
They'll blow our cover.
We gotta wait it out.
Kenneth, it's fine. They won't tell.
No. We can't have any witnesses
that will connect my car to the van.
The people that are after me
are gonna be on full alert.
They'll put the pieces together.
Totally unprofessional!
It's okay.
It's just...
It's a girl.
My reason for going back is a girl.
- Who was she?
- She's my first girlfriend.
Her birthday was the exact same day
in April as mine is in October.
We ended up working at the same restaurant.
She was just so nice to me.
She would make me special food
and after work, while all her friends
were getting ready to go out,
she would just hang out and talk with me.
She was really pretty.
What happened to her?
She died.
Some jerk,
some a-hole jerk in a band got drunk
and crashed his car into her living room.
I should have been there, you know.
People tell you that
there are other girls out there,
you know, and
it's not just about a girl, it's about...
It's about a time and a place.
Do you have a favorite song?
Would you tell me what it is?
- It's stupid.
- What is it?
Over the Rainbow.
It's a really beautiful song.
It's that time and that place
and that song,
and you remember what it was like
when you're in that place,
and then you listen to that song,
and you knowyou're not in that place
anymore and it makes you feel hollow.
Can't just go find that stuff again.
I like your reason for going back.
It's really nice.
Thanks.
- Fucking lasers?
- What kind of lasers?
I don't know,
I'm not a frickin' Stormtrooper.
This guy's awesome.
He's over there right now
thinking he's building
a frickin' time machine.
Hey, Arnau, what are the chances
he can do that with these lasers?
- Howwould I know, I'm not a...
- He doesn't know.
He's not a frickin' Stormtrooper either.
Stormtroopers don't know anything
about lasers or time travel,
they're blue-collar workers.
I gotta see this shit.
- Isn't this like violating his privacy?
- Don't worry about it.
I can't see much. Looks like an engine.
What are you building in there, Kenny?
Who's this asshole?
Oh, my God, there are people
following him.
There are really people following him.
We're doing this.
Stay back. Don't spook him.
- Stay back. Don't scare them.
- This is fucking intense.
We're going fifteen miles an hour.
Shit. He saw us.
Oh, shit, they're onto us.
Onto what?
Shit.
Don't let him see you! Duck!
Stay down!
What the hell, did you see those guys?
They look like government agents
or something.
- He's really being followed.
- Holy shit! Is this guy for real?
- Kenneth? Are you okay?
- I can't talk right now, okay?
- Just watch your back.
- Okay.
- Stay low and lay low.
- Yeah.
Go to the beach, I'll pick you up.
It's almost time, Darius.
This is totally crazy.
- Who do you think those guys are?
- I have no idea.
Maybe he's not totally insane, maybe he
really thinks he's doing something and...
I don't know.
What? Why are you looking at me like that?
I don't know. You got a thing for this guy?
What?
No! I'm talk...
You saw those guys.
Can I ask you a question?
Do you mind, as a reporter?
What?
What is it that you two weirdos
do when you're off alone?
I'm getting information.
What are you doing when you're off alone?
I'm seeing an old friend.
Just take me to the beach. I have to meet him.
All right, this is it.
It's pretty obvious they see a threat in
me possessing this kind of power.
It's not clear yet what entity
they represent.
Their presence here
definitely accelerates the plan, though.
They're gonna
have one of their guys at every door,
but you should be okay.
I don't think they've ID'ed you yet.
- Got it.
- Good luck.
Wait!
Go! Go!
Shannon?
I'm supposed to give this to you.
This is from Kenneth.
Kenneth said to give this to me?
My wife, she's...
You tell him...
Tell him I hope he gets wherever
he's goin'
and it all works out like he wants.
I'll tell him.
All good?
Yeah.
What?
Nothing.
Yeah, we're getting
some really great stuff, Bridget,
I'm gonna need a couple more days.
Bridget, I'm doing an interview right now.
Yeah, I'll send you an e-mail
with all the information,
and I'll paint you a real picture.
Okay. I have to go right now.
That all seems so dangerous.
Her running around with this guy...
She'll be fine. You got any more of
that leftover pie? That was pretty good.
I was thinking about you
and the time we spent together.
I was pretty ripped back then.
Top of my game back then.
- You were not ripped.
- Yes, I was.
Why don't you feel me now?
You look great.
- Are you familiar with cryptography?
- Yeah. Of course.
Yeah. Well, I prefer
the St. Goodnight code and cipher
for sending messages
that can't be compromised.
It's just 4-4-3-1-4 and then you
just reverse the whole thing, okay?
Yeah. Got it.
Learn it. Practice it.
Hey!
If I showyou something, will you promise
not to tell anybody else about it, ever?
Yeah.
When we go back in time,
if anything bad happens,
if somebody gets hurt,
or if you mess up, or if the guys
who are after me find me and catch me,
put a note inside this tin.
I'm gonna do the same thing.
If anything goes wrong,
we go back and we fix it.
Okay.
So far so good.
So that's been there since 2001?
Since I was a kid.
I used to come up here
and camp with the Boy Scouts
near here when I was little.
Do you knowwhat Star Wars is?
- Yes.
- Yeah.
So, when I was younger, I used to
bring my Star Wars figures up here,
'cause I didn't wanna leave 'em back
at the house 'cause they'd get lonely.
And some of the more cynical kids
would make fun of me,
- they would throw them in the fire
and stuff...
- Really?
This was before my martial arts training,
of course.
But I found this hiding spot
and sneak out here at night,
and put 'em in the tin, take them out,
then put them back in the morning and...
Anyway...
I wish I could see you
when you were a little kid.
I was not as impressive as I am now,
I can assure you.
- What?
- Yeah.
Okay.
- Wanna see something cool?
- Yeah.
Come on.
That was the best sex I've ever had.
And I've had a lot of sex.
That's what you said about the
roast chicken.
That was the best roast chicken
I ever had.
You don't know
how long I've thought about this.
You've become this, like, character
in my head that's like,
it feels like you're from a fairy tale,
and you're like this purity
that's just not in my life.
You are so cute.
Hey. This is gonna sound crazy.
I want you to come to Seattle with me.
- What?
- Yeah.
It's crazy, but I want you to come...
Jeff, the minute you drive out of this
place, you are not going to want to
be with me.
That's just not true. That's what I'm
saying, I mean, do you not feel this?
- You're not in your right mind right now.
- I'm absolutely in my right mind.
This is the clearest I've been
in a long time.
I've done this before.
- You haven't done it with me.
- No, I've done this before
and I'm too old.
We're the same damn age.
That's perfect.
That's unbelievable.
Unbelievable. Okay. Great. This is good.
This is perfect. I'm glad you said that
'cause this was a mistake.
You're right. You knowwhat?
I open up my heart to you and...
Thank you,
because my head was turned around...
- Jeff...
- But it ain't anymore.
I think you're being a little
crazy about this.
Yeah. I think you're crazy for saying no.
Please go.
I'm goin' by choice.
Why are you sitting here?
Why would you be sitting on your computer?
You are a young man.
You got the whole world ahead of you.
I'm asking you to be a man and try.
Are you ready to have a crazy night
with me? 'Cause I'm ready.
- Say you're ready. Say you're ready.
- I'm ready.
My man. Good answer.
Let's do something stupid!
Stay here.
You guys ever partied in an Escalade?
Here we go. Here we go. Drink. Drink.
You drink. Open that up and start drinking,
I didn't buy it for nothing.
Good girl.
Go. Go.
Drink, drink, drink.
Arnau!
This guy's getting laid tonight.
He's my best friend!
Arnau! Pay the son of a bitch!
You warm enough?
This is all your stuff?
Well, I just kind of set up here,
the Boy Scouts don't really
come up here after September, so
it's kind of like having a second home,
come to spend some nights
and clear the head.
Okay. This is for you.
I circled the location on the map,
this way you'll always know
where to find the truck and this campsite.
- Don't get lost.
- Okay.
What's that? Is that a guitar?
No, it's called a zither.
Can you play this?
Not very well at all.
My dad had one, he was really good.
Belinda really liked music, so...
I always wished I could have
played her something,
so I've been writing her this song
for when I see her again.
Will you play it?
- It's...
- Please?
No, it's not finished
and it's really just not very good, so...
Well, I'll tell you if it's good or not.
Okay.
It's only halfway done, so it's just like...
Stand straight
Fall back in line
Comb your hair
Get to work on time
Everyone in the big machine
Tries to break your heart
And pull you underneath
Maybe I'm wrong
And all that you get is what you see
Maybe I'm right
And there's something out
there to believe
Everybody's talking in their sleep
They push a lot of air around
But don't say much of anything
Except when they laugh at me
Like ghosts under a sheet
Everybody's talking in their sleep
I messed up a bunch of parts,
- but that's basically what it is.
- No, it's so good.
Shut up.
So good.
Thanks.
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Anyway, you cold?
Trust me. Trust me.
Now, feel this.
It works, right?
What are you doing in the lobby?
Are they still in there?
Yeah, that's the point.
She's still in there.
- You go.
- What do you mean I go?
I didn't want to hang out with these three.
I did it for you!
I don't think so. It's fine. You go.
- Are you gay?
- What? No...
- Is that what this is?
- No.
I'm asking you seriously,
I'm not judging you.
You don't know this about me,
but I don't care about that stuff.
No, Jeff, I'm not gay, no.
This is set up perfectly.
Do you not think she's hot?
- You're acting like it's so easy.
- Because it is so easy.
- No, Jeff. It's easy for you, not for me.
- Why not?
Because I'm not you, Jeff.
Do you just wanna see me get embarrassed?
No!
Arnau, come here, man. Come here.
Fucking come here.
I'm not pranking you, man.
You're not gonna get this opportunity
very much longer.
You're not always gonna be 21, young man.
I promise you fucking that.
I don't know. I don't knowwhat to...
How do I start?
First of all, take these pedophile
glasses off
and don't wear these,
they make you look like a weirdo, man.
I'm gonna put these on you. Holy shit!
Look at that killer.
That dude right there crushes chicks.
I would take a photo of you and showyou
how good you looked right now,
'cause you look fantastic.
- You look like a damn pilot.
- Okay.
Like a cool pilot who drives jets.
Pop this shit.
Act like you've been there before.
You're not gonna be your age forever.
One day, you're gonna be the old dirtbag.
All by yourself.
This is the moment you live for.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Okay.
Hey, Halloween, you smoke?
- Yeah.
- Jeff, what the fuck?
It's so early, Bridget.
Yeah, I'm working here.
Isn't that what you're doing down there?
Yes. That's what I'm doing.
I've been going over the notes
that you've been sending in.
This Belinda St. Sing, the
ex-girlfriend he said died in an accident.
Is that her name?
Yeah, that's right. Why?
You're past curfew.
- Were those girls with you?
- 100%Arnau.
Hey, you know that girl your boyfriend
was going back in time to save, Belinda?
Yeah?
Well, she's alive and well.
Lives about an hour away.
How? What do you mean?
Bridget called and set up an interview.
I think your little boyfriend
is seriously nuts.
Yeah, I know, he's totally nuts.
He's completely crazy. I know.
So she's alive. Okay.
- I wanna do the interview.
- That's fine.
You sure you got this, kiddo?
Yeah?
- Darius?
- Hi.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
Come on in.
I've never been interviewed
by a magazine before.
He worked at Anderson's,
which was the restaurant I waited at
all throughout college,
and he was really nice.
Different just than the typical guys,
I guess.
So how long were you guys together?
Well, we were never really together,
together.
You never dated?
I mean, I wouldn't call it dating. He was...
He was one of those guys, who
you kind of know has a crush on you,
but he's really nice
and so you're really nice back.
But he wasn't the type of guy
who you could easily
fit into your life, you know,
with your friends and everything.
He was
weird, I guess we've all
had one of those guys, right?
Yeah. Yeah, I knowwhat you mean.
So, then what happened?
Do you guys still talk?
After that, I started dating Rob,
who was my last boyfriend
before I met my husband,
and then Kenneth quit the restaurant.
I didn't see him for a while after that.
Then there was the accident.
Accident?
Kenneth ran his car
into my boyfriend's house.
There was a big dent
under the kitchen window.
My God!
So I convinced Rob to just let him go
and we...
We told the police it was a hit and run.
I haven't seen him since then.
But you said you've seen him recently.
How is he?
He's good.
Excuse me. Darius?
Can we have a moment of your time?
Nothing to be alarmed about.
We'd just like to ask a few questions
about Kenneth Calloway.
Guys? We're from Seattle Magazine.
We're just here doing a story on this guy.
We're not involved
with what he's involved with.
What do you want with him?
He's been contacting government
scientists on the Internet,
asking questions about
our particle accelerator in Berkeley.
We've been investigating Calloway
for a couple of years now
and we suspect him of being an agent.
He can't be a spy.
He was arrested in Colorado for breaking
into a nuclear physics laboratory.
And then there was the recent robbery
at a medical research center here.
Oh, yeah? And what did he take?
Are you sure it was him that
broke into the medical research place?
You have evidence?
We're confident.
He hasn't been back to his house
in the past 24 hours.
Give us a call if you hear from him?
Will do.
- Thank you.
So, what's your story about?
The story.
I don't know anymore, actually.
You all right?
You sure?
Yeah.
Wake up, Sleeping Beauty.
Kenneth?
Kenneth? I'm coming in.
Darius?
Hey. What are you doing here?
Everything's set.
We move the machine to the launch site.
Departure is at 5:00 p.m.
How'd you get in here anyway? The spooks
are all over me. It's crazy out there.
I had to sneak in through the back.
Hey, we need to talk.
About last night. I know.
Last night
was a thunderbolt.
But I realize
our working relationship
became complicated,
so for now, maybe we just
re-focus and concentrate on the mission.
Whose house is this?
It's my house. My parents left it to me.
Where are the lasers?
Can you show me the lasers?
What's wrong with your voice?
- Where's the time machine?
- The time machine is at the launch site.
Oh, right, it's at the launch site.
Darius.
What are you doing?
I talked to those guys who are
following you.
And they told me
that you stole those lasers because
you're some kind of spy or something.
That's perfect. Let them think that,
it works in our favor. It's better.
Seriously.
I also talked to Belinda.
- What?
- Yeah.
- You did not talk to Belinda.
- Yeah, I did.
I talked to Belinda.
I was just at her house.
No! No!
What are you doing?
She's alive! She's alive! Okay.
This is good. Okay.
This means the mission must have
been successful, and we have saved her
- and we've come back to the present...
- Hey, hey...
Hey, you can be honest with me, okay?
- I really like you.
- Okay.
Yes. But this is the thing.
It's a complicated science
and cannot be measured by our brains...
You can't time travel!
This is all crazy. Okay, you lied to me.
- Listen to me.
- What else are you lying about?
Hey, hey, listen to me.
You come to that launch site at 5:00 p.m.,
you take my hand
and I'll showyou who can't time travel.
Oh, shit!
All right?
Darius! They're right behind the house!
- Wait...
- They're right behind me.
Wait, you're with that guy?
- Are you...
- No.
- Were you making fun of me?
- No, I would have never...
Nobody was making fun of you, Kenneth.
We are writing an honest piece
about you for a magazine.
Magazine? Darius, don't...
- We're not making fun of you.
- Get out of my house!
- We're on your side. We're here to help.
- No, I'm leaving tonight!
So is he really building
a time machine or what?
Why did you make me do this?
I didn't make you do this.
You wanted the story.
You don't care about the story!
You don't care about him.
You just came here
to hook up with old girlfriends.
- What's going on?
- Hey, guys, check this out.
It's open.
Watch your head.
I knowwhat they were looking for.
I saw it, it was like a,
like a jet engine or something.
It's gone!
Darius, have you seen this stuff before?
What the hell was he building in here?
I don't know.
You don't think he actually built it,
do you?
Holy shit!
Move!
Darius!
Kenneth, I'm sorry.
Were you making a joke of me
the whole time?
No.
I promise.
I lied about the story, but everything
else was real, okay? That was really me.
Then get on.
Come with me.
The mission's been updated.
I'm going back for you now.
All right. You trust me?
Come on.
Take my hand. I knowwhat I'm doing, okay?
Flip that switch. Do it. Flip it down.
Are you ready?
Go!
...to go it alone or to go with a partner.
When you choose a partner, you have to
have compromises and sacrifices,
but it's the price you pay.
Do I wanna follow my every whim and desire
as I make my way through time and space?
Absolutely.
But at the end of the day, do I
need someone when I'm doubting myself,
and I'm insecure and my heart's
failing me?
Do I need someone who,
when the heat gets hot, has my back?
- So, do you?
- I do.
THE END
Subtitles by: