?? [ Orchestra ]
[ Low, Masculine Voice ]
? It's a cold and an empty feeling ?
?Just staring endlessly ?
? At a cold
and a faceless ceiling ?
? And wondering where she'll be ?
[ High, Feminine Falsetto ]
? And at last when I think he's found me ?
? At last my time has come ?
? Other women are all around me ?
? And I'm back where I started from ?
? But here's some news ?
[ Maintaining Female Voice ]
? I'll make it plain ?
? Friends, you haven't
a thing to lose ?
?Just forget all the old taboos ?
? You've got
really much more to gain ?
?Just get closer to ?
? The one you're close to ?
? And that needn't be ?
? The one you're supposed to ?
? Cast out your fears ?
? Chase them away ?
? You've been waiting around for years
Now it's time that you shifted gears ?
? Why be glum
when you could be gay ?
? Once around ?
? Should suffice ?
? If you'll just slip a little versa ?
? Into your vice ?
? I could die for
the sweet things you do ?
? Yet any fool can see ?
? You've got eyes for Marlene
For Lulu ?
? But not a glance for me ?
[ Low, Masculine Voice ]
? How it hurts when I feel you near me ?
[ High, Feminine Voice ]
? So near, but yet so far?
[ Masculine Voice ]
? And I start seeing things more clearly ?
? Seeing things
just the way they are ?
[ Feminine Voice ]
? So here's some news ?
? I'll make it plain ?
? Friends, you haven't a thing to lose
Just forget all the old taboos ?
? You've got
really much more to gain ?
[ Masculine Voice ]
?Just get closer to ?
? The one you're close to ?
? And that needn't be ?
? The one you're supposed to ?
[ Feminine Voice ]
? Cast out your fears ?
? Chase them away ?
? You've been waiting around for year’s ?
?  Now it's time
that you shifted gears ?
? Why be glum when you could be gay ?
? Once around ?
? Will suffice ?
? If you'll just slip ?
? A little versa ?
? Into your vice ??
[ Applause ]
?? [ Ends ]
Heil Hitler!
Heil Hitler.
It's on, Wallenberg.
At last. When?
A question of days.
A blitzkrieg!
And we're going to win!
The Führer was definite
as to how long it will last.
- Guess.
- A year?
Six months?
Two months at most.
We'll scarcely have time
to enjoy it.
We'll enjoy the postwar periods,
Herr Obergruppenführer.
Gentlemen, to the war.
To Germany and the Führer.
Sieg heil.
[ Boot Heels Click ]
?? [ Piano ]
?? [ Continues ]
[ Man Farts ]
Wallenberg.
I'll need about 20 girls.
I know that for you
this is an easy task,
but this time, they must not only
be beautiful but intelligent...
and, above all,
good  National Socialists.
Go through Germany
with a fine-tooth comb.
[ Movie: Hitler Speaking ]
Every region, every city,
every village.
Inspect farms,
factories and universities alike.
Do not omit any social background,
from the bourgeois to the working class,
from housewives
to office employees.
Be they virgins or married,
inspect them thoroughly,
but do not forget to base your selection
principally upon their political faith!
[ Speaking German ]
And have fun, Wallenberg.
[ Audience ]
Heil Hitler!
[ Crowd Shouting ]
These three cadavers
will give ample proof...
that our racial theories,
which are a very important part
of our German ideology,
are based on
indisputable scientific facts.
Uh, the vices
and, uh, corruption...
of, um, the inferior race...
are transmitted from
generation to generation
by the chromosomes.
Uh, the pigmentation
of this black man...
bears a direct relationship
to the bestiality of his race...
and the impossibility
of its members
being educated.
He died, uh,
in a drunken stupor...
after a gunfight with the police.
Cover him.
[ Flies Buzzing ]
Now, this prostitute,
on the contrary--
this prostitute,
who died sitting up
while attempting an abortion,
is of pure Aryan stock,
and in spite of the vices
of her profession
and the corruption of her life...
this cadaver preserves, even now,
uh, all the intrinsic characteristics
of her superior race.
Any questions?
Professor, is it true...
Jesus Christ was the son...
of a Roman prostitute...
and a German mercenary?
Oh, without a doubt.
There is not the slightest trace
of Jewish characteristics
in Jesus Christ.
He was blonde, he had blue eyes--
typical signs
of his Germanic origin.
Can you tell me who
was the first man in history...
to recognize this
and make it known to the world?
That's easy, sir.
Our great Führer, Adolf Hitler.
?? [ Piano Continues ]
[ Squealing ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Squealing Weakly ]
?? [ Continues ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Pigs Snorting ]
[ Snorting Continues, Fades ]
[ Flies Buzzing ]
He promised he'd free us...
from communists
and labor unions in six months...
and, by God, he's done it.
Today, German law
is the most advanced of all socially,
far more than the Fascist code in Italy.
[ Giggles ]
It's so Italian!
I admire the Italians, Mother.
And so do I, darling,
for Mediterraneans.
[ Man Burps Loudly ]
I'm sorry.
- Mmm.
- [ Clears Throat ]
Yes, for Mediterraneans
they're most handsome.
A little too exotic for my taste.
Too colorful.
Perhaps, but our dear Führer
suffers from a certain lack of chic.
All those brown shirts--
such a dull color!
And his manners, my dear.
The way he holds a teacup
with his little finger raised.
[ All Laughing ]
You forget, Mrs. Henckel,
just as my mother and father
sometimes do,
that the  National Socialists can't afford
to lose time studying etiquette.
They're too busy
trying to rebuild that order
which you fail to defend...
by drinking tea
without raising your little finger...
and your very chic taste in colors.
Don't you realize?
[ Flies Continue Buzzing ]
You're a dead generation.
What?
[ Clearing Throat ]
Good night.
Yes, well, um,  National Socialism
has a great hold over the young.
Well, after all, that's what we were hoping
when we backed Hitler in '33, isn't it?
The most important thing
is to be on the winning side.
That's the side of history,
my dear.
Prosit!
[ All Responding ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Laughing Fades ]
[ Clicking ]
[ Clicking Continues ]
From each of you,
the Führer asks this--
that you wage war
to the best of your ability...
for the triumph
of National Socialism...
and of Germany.
It would have been easy enough
to have chosen professionals,
but the Führer has greater confidence
in political faith than in technique.
Where there is goodwill,
technique can be quickly learnt.
It is rather like killing.
The first time one can feel remorse,
vomiting, even insomnia.
But then the third time
one sleeps easily...
and from the fifth time on
one goes to dinner
with a healthy appetite.
It becomes exciting, a thrill!
For you too it will be like that.
- Heil Hitler.
- Heil Hitler!
Kameraden,
remove your uniforms.
[ Whistle Blows ]
You are about to undergo group testing
with S.S. men of the Third Reich.
It will help you
to get rid of your inhibitions...
and will give naturalness
to your performance.
The most qualified will be given
a second examination,
more detailed, more specific.
The test has been tailor-made for you
by our psychosomatic center.
Your duty is to refuse nothing--
coitus, anal coitus,
masturbation and fellatio.
Ready,
Herr Obergruppenführer.
Enjoy yourselves, kameraden.
Use your imagination.
This is also a way to serve the Führer
and the Fatherland.
Heil Hitler.
Heil Hitler!
[ Speaking German ]
Ready!
[ German ]
Right face!
March!
[ German ]
Left, right, left!
Two, three, four!
[ German ]
Keep your distance!
Left, right, left!
Two, three, four!
[ German ]
Left!
Ready!
[ German ]
Halt!
Right face!
[ German ]
Stand straight!
?? [ Piano, Instruments: Fanfare ]
[ German ]
Group 1 , men.
Group 2, women.
?? [ Upbeat March ]
[ German ]
Group 3, men.
Group 4, women.
[ German ]
Group 5, men.
Group 6, women.
[ German ]
Group 7, men.
Group 8, women.
[ German ]
Group 9, men.
Group 1 0, women.
?? [ Continues ]
?? [ Band Members Singing In German ]
?? [ Singing Continues ]
?? [ Ends ]
[ Officer ]
Ulrika from Luebeck.
[ Wallenberg ] Perfect.
Splendid capacity for adaptation.
[ Speaking German ]
Olga from Hamburg.
[  No Audible Sound ]
No.
[ Speaking German ]
Martha from Danzig.
[  No Audible Sound ]
Rejected.
Margherita from Leipzig.
Approved.
Lela from Düsseldorf.
[ Speaking Italian ]
What is he?
[ Italian ] A gypsy.
[ Wallenberg In Italian ]
Weak. Mediocre.
No sense of race.
[ Italian Continues ]
Are you sure she's Aryan?
Yes.
[ Italian ]
How embarrassing.
Susan from Berlin.
[ Italian ]
Courageous, determined,
fearless in combat,
steadfast faith
in  National Socialism.
Approved.
Is that the lot?
Jawohl,
Herr Obergruppenführer.
I wanted to ask,
what about the rejects?
The girls will be sent
to the disciplinary
and educational sections.
The men--
Well, my dear Rauss,
we can't have bodies around that can talk.
I thought they still might be
of some use in the labor camps,
or for Dr. Schwab's experiments.
You have one failing, Rauss.
You always want to show that you have
thought things out better than the others.
I repeat, get rid of them!
- Heil!
- Heil Hitler!
[  No Audible Sound ]
?? [ Piano: Classical ]
Hey!
Who are you looking for?
?? [ Continues ]
[ Elevator Door Closes ]
[ Doorbell Rings ]
?? [ Continues, Louder ]
?? [ Continues ]
?? [ Ends ]
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
What frightens you more--
what you see, or what you don't?
Nothing ever frightens me.
The paintings
were removed from sight.
They were degenerate art.
Expressionists.
French stuff.
Jewish culture.
No, thank you.
I'd rather have tea.
Tea?
[ Chuckles ]
The decadent habits
of the upper class.
No, on the contrary.
The bourgeois drink--
Oh, I don't drink, like the Führer.
Your damned snobbish pride.
You haven't changed.
You're the same
as when you were born.
I believe in  National Socialism.
Believing is not enough.
To be a real  National Socialist,
you have to deny yourself, your origins.
You must accept
total compromise.
You must destroy yourself
to be...
reborn.
[ Door Opens ]
You may go.
Good-bye.
It was nice meeting you.
How can I destroy myself?
By humiliation.
How?
Take off your panties!
Quickly!
Pull up your skirt now.
Higher.
Higher!
Higher. Higher!
On your knees.
On your knees!
On all fours and then... crawl.
Faster.
Fast! Fast!
Come here!
Do you see?
You're nothing.
A dog...
trained to obey my commands.
[ Groans ]
I like the way you fight back.
I like your dignity.
I like your pride.
Share that with me...
and I'll share my power
with you.
Do I repulse you?
Kiss me. Kiss me!
Do something, for God's sake!
I'm not part of your world, am I?
You're in a far more
splendid world.
[ Radio: Hitler Speaking German ]
September 1 , 1 939
Declaration of war on Poland
[ Radio: Hitler Continues
Speaking German ]
[ Hitler Continues In German ]
Free round for the war!
Heil Hitler!
[ All ]
- [ Radio: Crowd Cheering ]
- Max! Franz! Rudolf!
Champagne for everybody!
It's from Kitty!
I'd love to kiss everyone,
all of Germany!
[ Kitty Speaking German ]
Let everybody drink!
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughing, Chattering ]
That is the price
of the mutilated soldiers too, Kitty?
Oh, shut up-- Ohh.
Please.
But they already exist,
the charming victims
of an equally charming war.
Beautiful and mutilated.
More than mutilated--
doomed to suffer agonizing death
within their charging tanks...
instead of on white stallions
along the river banks.
[ Italian ]
Nice heroic poetry, right?
Dino,
if there weren't any dead,
it wouldn't be a war.
Then Germany couldn't win it
and rule the world,
and we wouldn't be here tonight
drinking champagne and the fun
of this party wouldn't exist!
Right you are!
Cliff is much more amusing
than you, my dear Dino.
[ Laughing ]
And more logical too,
as America is farther from Berlin
than my Italia!
[ Chattering, Laughing Continue ]
Gentlemen! Girls!
Friends!
Uh... play something hot, Wolfie,
immediately, or you are out of a job!
?? [ Customers Singing
"Deutschland über Alles" In German ]
?? [ Continues ]
Madame.
[ Laughing ]
Madame Kitty.
Madame.
?? [ Singing Continues ]
Madame!
?? [ Continues ]
Don't be such a wet blanket.
Come and join us.
There's free champagne.
I know the girls don't interest you,
but surely the champagne does.
Sorry, Kitty, I can't.
I've got a thousand things to do.
I'll send you a car.
What shall I put in the car--
girls or champagne?
Just you.
[ Laughs ]
I appreciate the compliment, darling,
but I gave up house calls a long time ago.
Come if you like, and if you don't,
stay in your office with your pretty ass
glued to your headquarters.
Good-bye!
Rauss!
?? [ Orchestra: Introduction ]
[ Kitty ]
? They say that all things ?
? Must have an end ?
? That broken bones
and broken hearts ?
? Take oh, so long to mend ?
? You've heard it so often ?
? It must be true ?
? Will you believe it ?
? When it happens ?
? To you ?
? Your morning coffee ?
? Won't taste the same ?
? A fix won't help ?
? For that you've only got
yourself to blame ?
? Your bed's so empty ?
? Your words so black ?
? Is there no joy ?
? Is there no love ?
? Is there no turning back ?
? Your life's in pieces ?
? What can you say ?
? As you light yet
another cigarette ?
? Thoughts far away ?
? With sleepless eyes
you realize ?
? It's not the same world anymore ?
? On the morning after?
? The night before ?
?? [ Orchestra Continues ]
? Your life's in pieces ?
? What can you say ?
? As you light yet
another cigarette ?
? Thoughts far away ?
? With sleepless eyes you realize ?
? It's not the same world
anymore ?
? On the morning after?
? The night before ??
[ Applause, Cheering ]
[ Applause Stops ]
[ Customers Murmuring ]
It's the Gestapo.
Gestapo.
[ Kitty ] Have you gone mad?
To have me brought here
by Gestapo agents to tell me this?
You've got to deport my girls
because they are foreigners?
I have to close down?
Your party needs my house?
[ Kitty Screams ]
I'm not responsible.
Who is responsible?
Himmler? Von Ribbentrop?
They are all my clients,
except for Göring.
Have they gone mad too?
I'll call them all right now!
One after the other.
On a day like this?
Kitty, war has just been declared.
[ Scoffs ]
What the hell does war
have to do with my work?
Are we going to put on chastity belts
because war has been declared?
Are we all going to join the Red Cross?
[ Sighs ]
[ Laughing ]
Haven't you learnt anything
from the Roman Empire?
You must laugh and sing
if you want to conquer the world.
Do you want my girls
to give singing lessons?
Thank you very much, Kitty,
but for the greatness of Germany
our brave soldiers are musical enough.
Don't you think
our brave soldiers...
would like to have half an hour in bed
to come before they go?
Hmm?
Naturally.
But remember,
most of them are married.
[ Laughs ]
Wives are for breeding, not for fun.
A soldier has to shoot off his own gun,
not only government issue.
Oh, Wallenberg,
sometimes I have the feeling
you don't know what it's all about.
Just because I'm not interested
in your whores?
But that's not the point.
There's nothing
to be done about it.
Sorry, Kitty.
You have to close down.
You meddling bastard.
You can't ruin me like this.
Give me half a year.
Three months!
Mm-mmm.
Not even one day.
I told you-- the party
needs a building right away.
But I can help you.
I'll see to it that your girls are replaced
by beautiful German females
of good Aryan stock.
And I know of a spacious villa
in the Grunewald that could be
made available to you.
Thank you, but Kitty has always
been in the center of Berlin.
Fresh air makes me dizzy.
I prefer champagne.
Kitty, you're making a mistake.
The villa is bigger,
independent, isolated.
The whole neighborhood
would be yours.
It's quiet, discreet...
and, uh... very high class.
I could even get you
a good price on it.
And if I refuse?
I wouldn't if I were you.
It wouldn't be very wise,
and you wouldn't only lose your license.
You obviously
don't know me well enough,
Herr Untergruppenführer.
If I have to,
I'll go to Hitler himself!
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
Still. Everybody still.
Smile!
I'll miss this.
I'll miss this view.
Charlesey, I don't give a damn
about changing the address.
Love smells the same everywhere,
thank God.
I'm not changing my profession.
I'm not changing you.
[ Stifled Sobbing ]
After all, this isn't a home.
It's just a whorehouse.
Are you crying?
[ Sobbing Continues ]
I don't know why!
I swear I don't know why.
I'm so stupid!
[ Laughing, Continues Sobbing ]
For heaven's sake, relax, girls!
You're not in the army,
you know.
Pretty, bring some drinks.
Something strong.
It's freezing cold in this place.
Oh, mm-hmm-hmm,
they certainly stand at attention
in a charming way.
I won't deny that, Wallenberg,
but here it's not enough.
They look like amateurs.
Take her, for example.
She'd be great for a Sunday picnic,
but not for a customer
who wants a decent screw.
And her--
Put a baby in her arms...
and give her a pair
of knitting needles and see.
You've got the ideal hausfrau.
No fire!
She looks constipated.
She even makes me feel uncomfortable.
Imagine a poor, nervous client.
She'd be more at home
in Sunday School than here.
We need warm, soft girls,
always ready...
and able to laugh and to live it up,
no matter what happens.
Technically,
they are perfect.
I hope they don't salute the clients
when they come in.
You know, with my own girls,
at least,
I was sure I knew they could give
a dying man a hard-on.
All right,
loosen them up.
After all, it's your business,
not mine.
I'm told you used to be phenomenal.
Teach them to be the same.
[ Kitty ]
Ach!
[ Exhales, Scoffs ]
Ah.
No!  No!  No!
They are all perfect!
Too damned perfect.
They are boring.
They look like color postcards
to send home to mama.
I need specialists, girls able to--
to satisfy any request,
the most complex perversions.
The men who come
to Salon Kitty have fantasies.
If one of the girls doesn't work out,
just let me know.
After all, they're here for your--
Ach! Shit!
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
That it should come to this.
Us teaching kindergarten.
[ Sighs, Inhales ]
Ahh!
[ Laughs ]
[ Glass Shatters ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
[ Giggling ]
?? [ Orchestra: Introduction ]
? We're told for what it's worth
that God created life on earth ?
? That's what we're given
to believe ?
? It's also written in the book ?
? That on the day that Adam
took his first long look at Eve ?
? He eyed her tenderly
and though his thoughts were pure ?
?  Noting her gender, he
remarked one thing's for sure ?
? I'm going to get me some of that
I'll be the first man to be gassed ?
? But Eve, nobody's fool ?
? Said there are things, my friend
I think that you should hear ?
? About the things
that I'm not going to take ?
? I'm not for free, my friend
and if that's not quite clear?
? Why don't you go
try it with that freak ?
? Well, Adam must have seen
there's no real choice between ?
? A love affair
with beauty or the beast ?
? So he wrote fig leaf checks
for prehistoric sex ?
? He must have learned at least ?
? There is a debt account ?
? In very large amounts ?
? Don't tell me
you're just finding out ?
? What it's all about ?
? Mister, you just got here
from the moon ?
? In the best bank accounts ?
? It's still the gift that counts ?
? It may be sad, but yet it's true ?
? It's something all of you ?
? Would-be lovers
must look out for true ?
? Philosophers and sages
writing wisdom of the ages ?
? All agree and leave no doubt ?
? That if you want to play the boss ?
? You'd better plan to come across
or else you'll do without ?
? Why, even Romeo
found out to his dismay ?
? The lovely Juliet
would not come out to play ?
? If all he offered her was beaches ?
?Julie had the brains to know
that each is all his very own ?
? She said, Look here, my friend
I think it's time for you ?
? To learn a few things
you will never see ?
? Oh, there's not much, my friend
A girl is going to be ?
? For just some words
beneath her balcony ?
? Well, there's a moral here
By now it should be clear ?
? By now it should not come
as a surprise ?
? You pay for what you get
All free for Juliet ?
? A girl who realized ?
? When the champagne is out ?
? That's when it really counts ?
? Because champagne has to be iced
It can never be ?
? A drink to more than
from a Wofford cup ?
? It's strictly guests and gowns ?
? In very large amounts ?
? So, mister, all you got to do
is bear in mind that you ?
? Done enough
You'd better get it up ??
[ Applause, Cheering ]
?? [ Ends ]
- Hah!
- [ Applause Continues ]
Hey!
Bravo.
Perfect.
So, Wallenberg,
this is your battle station.
Work carefully, hmm?
And patiently.
To trust is good.
Not to trust is better.
I want to compare the recordings
with the girls' reports personally.
Is that clear?
?? [ Kitty Singing ]
Carry out my orders meticulously,
as you're quite capable of doing.
And have fun, Wallenberg!
Hmm?
And what's your name?
Susan, Herr General.
What's wrong?
Why are you staring like that?
You look at me
as if we'd already met.
All Germany knows you,
Herr General.
You're the conqueror
and subduer of Poland.
Conquer and subdue
my body as well, Herr General!
[ Laughing ]
Let's leave Poland out of this.
The war is too sacred and far too immense
to speak about in a whorehouse.
Put on my boots.
[ Laughing ]
Jawohl, Herr General.
Can you sing?
Then sing to me
and march!
?? [ Singing In German ]
Like my song,
Herr General?
?? [ Singing Continues ]
Help me out of my trousers!
Jawohl, Herr General!
Don't call me Herr General!
Call me... Clarita.
[ Gasps, Laughing ]
[ Headset: General ]
Tell me you like.
[ Woman ]
Oh, yes!
[ Man Speaking Italian ]
Tell me how it burns!
[ Headset: Man, Italian ]
You're splitting open.
[ Man, Italian ]
Take it!
[ Man Continues Speaking Italian ]
Yes, take it! Become a comrade of the Axis.
[ Moaning ]
[ Italian ]
An official of the Duce.
Tell me you like it.
[ Italian ]
Tell me how it burns.
You're dying.
[ Italian ]
You're splitting open.
Say it.
[ Moaning Continues ]
[ Italian ]
Tell me you're dying. Tell me.
Tell me you're dying.
[ Italian ]
You're splitting open.
You're hurting yourself.
[ Gasping, Pleading In Italian ]
Give it to me! Give it to me!
- [ Italian Continues ]
You're killing me!
- Say it!
[ Italian ] You're dying.
[ Italian ]
I'm dying. Give it to me!
[ Headset: Italian Continues ]
Say it! Say it!
[ Headset: Moaning, Pleading Continue ]
[ Screams ]
[ Woman Speaking Spanish ]
Yes! I like it!
[ Spanish ]
More! I'm the woman from Masada.
Yes!
[ Spanish ]
More!
[ Whip Continues Cracking ]
[ Spanish ]
Later on!
I like it!
[ Headset:
Officer Speaking Foreign Language ]
[ Foreign Language Continues ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Foreign Language ]
[ Translating Into Italian ]
[ Translating Into English ]
You'll see whether I'm talking nonsense...
or telling the truth, my little jockey.
In Oslo and Copenhagen,
we'll be speaking English,
my lovely asshole.
[ German Continues ]
A lovely tongue, English--
a tongue worthy of your cunt.
Rauss, type up the report.
Use the exact words.
Send the first copy
and the recording to the chancellery...
and a second copy
to Reich Führer Himmler--
top secret and urgent.
Without having it
checked first by--
Rauss! How many times
do I have to tell you not to be so zealous?
[ Wallenberg Shouting ]
I take full responsibility
for this operation...
personally.
?? [ Orchestra ]
[ Applause ]
?? [ Continues ]
Well, frankly, I was skeptical.
Raw material coming
from God knows where.
Girls who knew nothing.
For days I sweated blood over them.
I was sure they were going to be a disaster.
But now business is booming,
sold out every night!
I can tell from the champagne.
It's impossible to find it
anywhere else but here.
And there is plenty more
where that came from.
Von Ribbentrop is a friend of mine.
Ribbentrop also gives you--
[ Sniffs ] Huh? [ Laughs ]
?? [ Continues ]
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Moaning ]
Have you been at the front?
Uh-huh.
You made love
as if you hated me.
No, it's not true.
Do you still want it?
Always.
So do I.
Why? Oh, yeah, sure. Sure.
It's your job.
Too bad.
Too bad you don't know
what it means.
Why are you in Berlin?
On leave?
Don't you want to talk?
I want to fuck.
But if you don't want to--
I want to.
That's not true.
Why do you say that?
It's not true.
But why should I care?
Why should I give a damn?
Just spread your legs.
I feel like it too.
Not like that.
Without anger.
With tenderness.
Relax.
[ Gasps ]
[ Whispers ]
Margherita.
[ Margherita Gasping,
Moaning Intensely ]
[ Margherita's Voice ]
Margherita, report number 48.
Name: Hans Reiter.
Rank: Hauptmann.
On leave from the front.
Unwilling to talk.
He only wanted to make love,
an act which he completed
several times.
You are lovely.
Making love with you
is just beautiful,
even if you are a whore.
Life has taught me to hate,
but with you
I remember when I didn't.
Are you in Berlin to get a medal?
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
I, uh, wear it on my back.
Will you fight again?
I don't think
I'm a good soldier.
When do you leave?
Soon. In 1 0 days.
An eternity for making love.
[ Sighs ] Yeah, an eternity
which ends right away.
I wish I could
take you with me...
to make love to you
whenever I want.
It's so good with you.
You're exaggerating.
Do you mind?
No.
But you mustn't exaggerate.
It's not right.
Would you mind
if I fell in love with you? Hmm?
[ Giggles ]
Just a little.
[ Chuckles ]
Would it seem ridiculous?
Love is a word you can always say
when two people are in bed together.
Mmm.
Yeah.
[ Giggles ]
[ Hans, Margherita Laughing ]
[ Air Raid Siren Wailing ]
- Air raid!
- It's an air raid! An air raid!
[ People Shouting, Chattering ]
- Come on!
- [ Kitty ] Get to the shelter!
Hurry! Hurry!
Look alive!
[ People Continue Screaming, Chattering ]
Turn the lights down!
[ Siren Continues Wailing ]
Hilde! Come down here!
Hilde!
[ Cork Pops ]
[ Siren Continues Wailing ]
?? [ Piano: Jazz, Slow Tempo ]
Mmm!
[ Siren Winds Down, Goes Silent ]
?? [ Continues ]
Good luck.
Good luck to me
to have found you.
A gift before going back to war.
Oh!
Uh, I saw light coming
from under the door.
Aren't you afraid?
British planes
will never fly over Berlin.
Göring himself
has promised us that.
- That's no reason to get drunk. Even you.
- [ Laughs ] Well, have a drink with us.
Thank you.
Today is
an important anniversary.
What of?
Well, it's exactly a week
that Margherita and I have met.
Mmm. Many happy returns.
To you too, Margherita.
[ Laughs ]
?? [ Continues ]
I don't like anniversaries.
I only like drinking
champagne with him.
Not even with him.
I just like the champagne.
Too many good wishes
bring bad luck.
[ Margherita Laughing ]
[ Shouting ]
Why, Hans?
Tell me why.
Hans.
Why?
[ Woman On P.A., Speaking German ]
Train departing for Grunewald
from Platform 1 .
[ German ]
Train departing for Grunewald
from Platform 1 .
- Come on! Hurry up!
- [ Whistle Blows ]
[ Man Shouting Marching Orders In German ]
[ Woman Continues Speaking On P.A. ]
Next train for Grunewald departs
in 20 minutes from Platform 1 .
[ Man Speaking German ]
Left, left, left, two, three, four.
[ German ]
Man, you are not doing it right.
BLACK OUT
Why, Hans? Why?
The entire country's floundering
knee-deep in human blood,
and it's far from being over.
From Warsaw to Leopolis,
as far as you can see--
gutted houses, burnt fields,
dead horses rotting in the sun,
carrion for the vultures,
heaps of men, women and children--
terrifying silent minds.
Defenseless people, gunned down
by nose-diving Messerschmitts.
I, too, have killed them.
I thought I was born
to build places to live and love in.
[ Sighs ]
Instead, I've become the architect
of a horrible cemetery without graves,
without coffins.
No!
No!  No!
Margherita.
Margherita!
MEN
[ Crying ]
[ Crying Continues ]
Love me, Hans.
Love me again.
[ Whimpers ]
[ Hans ]
Do you realize now
what your sadness means?
It's our last day.
Stop talking.
I'm getting out of this slaughterhouse,
together with you.
But you're a soldier.
It's your duty to fight.
I know.
And until yesterday,
I accepted it all.
But now I've made up my mind.
I'm going to fight against Hitler,
against his madness,
against the violence
which is corrupting us all.
[ Margherita's Voice ]
Hauptmann Hans Reiter
came again today.
What can you do?
When I get back to my base,
I'll simply defect to the other side
with my aircraft.
That's treason!
[ Margherita's Voice ]
He rarely spoke--
only fragments of thoughts.
He's introverted,
but he seems honest,
sincere and secure...
in his National Socialist faith.
Margherita,
man belongs to humanity,
not to a nation or a race
or to a religion.
My conscience is clear.
[ Margherita's Voice ]
He constantly made love to me,
which is only right
for a soldier preparing
to return to the front.
[ Hans's Voice ]
Margherita, man belongs to humanity,
not to a nation or a race
or to a religion.
My conscience is clear.
In the report, the girl
has surely given the officer's name.
Jawohl,
Herr Untergruppenführer.
Hauptmann Hans Reiter.
Precise and faithful.
He is going back
to his base today.
Take care of him.
Right away.
Jawohl, Herr Untergruppenführer.
[ Door Closes ]
Hauptmann Hans Reiter.
You fell in love with him.
No.
Drink it.
I'm sure you've also learned
to love champagne.
You saw him every day
for two weeks.
He asked for me at the salon.
[ Door Opens ]
And...
you just spread your legs.
I told you to come in
only if I called you.
- Get out.
- Good-bye, miss.
I am Helga Wallenberg.
I married her
a long time ago.
She's an excellent wife.
Discreet and faithful.
Get out.
No. Wait.
Pretend she is Hans Reiter.
Show me what he liked.
You didn't write that down
in your reports.
What is it? Is your pride
still getting in your way?
Stop that!
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Glass Clatters ]
[ Grunts ]
Get out!
I didn't think you'd get involved
with this sentimental nonsense.
I overestimated you.
Why? Who am I
in your opinion?
What you are your Hans
will never understand.
Anyway, he has nothing
to offer you.
Do you?
Look at this!
It's all mine now.
And look here. Look.
Look at this.
And this-- it's mine too.
Things others dream of,
I already possess!
I want you, too, in my private dream.
You need another ghost,
like your wife?
It's my wish, but your duty.
You want me to lose my body,
my very being?
Would you rather stay
as you are now'
with your pitiful love affair?
My aims are higher.
That's why I'm a National Socialist.
I have a goal: power.
And with you,
it would be complete.
Compared with all this,
what does your pilot's
ridiculous love mean?
It's not love.
Here. I have a letter from him.
I could destroy him.
[ Hans's Voice ]
Heinsberg, the 25th.
My darling, I have just arrived.
Not even an hour has passed
since I got here,
and already I feel
a deep, deep need for you.
I got the letter through
without its being censored.
Not one but you
has read it.
You see, I can do
anything I want.
I know.
You manipulate emotions...
as I manipulate things
through willpower.
That's how I want you--
with my will.
Now you belong to me.
You're mine.
I want you to say
you're my accomplice.
[ Moaning ]
Say it.
Say it. Accomplice.
[ Gasps ]
Say it.
[ Hans's Voice, Indistinct ]
...a deep-- a deep need for you.
[ Moaning ]
...deep need for you.
...need for you.
...for you.
Oh, please, ladies, give it back.
[ Women Laughing ]
You're all being so mean.
Oh! The lonely butterfly.
I don't find this
clowning funny.
Oh, you must be sort of special.
The neurotics like it.
If you're clever,
you can get rich in no time.
Money. That's all you think about.
Of course, dear.
That's all any good professional
should think about.
And when you've made your bundle,
you quit.
Money's the only thing
that gives freedom a respectability.
You think like a servant.
You have no ideals.
You're not
a National Socialist.
[ Laughing ]
Ah, my dear child.
First and foremost,
I am a madam above ideals.
Just as, despite Hitler, your husband,
your child and your party,
you are a whore-- a whore.
I am not! I am not!
I am not! I am not a whore!
I'm not a whore!
Stop it!
Ladies!
No, no, don't!
[ Man ]
Kitty, are you all right?
Oh, my God!
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
Being a whore is an easy life--
a luxurious life, so they say.
They let themselves
get fooled into it,
and then it's too late.
[ Sighs ]
Liebe, Hilde, liebe Hilde.
Why don't you undress?
Do you like my stockings?
Go over there and lie down.
I want you over there.
Put out the light.
?? [ Fanfare ]
[ Speaking German ]
[ Hitler Continues Speaking German ]
[ Crowd Cheers ]
Open this.
What is it?
It's pastry.
You like pastry?
Mm-hmm.
It's for the two of us.
It comes from the finest
bakery in Berlin.
Huge, isn't it?
Put it between your legs.
Go on.
Spread your legs wider.
But make sure you keep it
straight up.
I want you to make me believe
it's your cock.
Big. Such a beautiful
big dick.
[ Crunch ]
[ Screams ]
[ Screaming ]
[ Grunting ]
What's wrong with you?
Heil Hitler!
[ Shouting Marching Orders ]
Lie down!
Lie down, I said!
Heil Hitler!
[ Shouting Marching Orders ]
Help! Help me!
[ Shouting Marching Orders,
Screaming ]
[ Speaking German ]
[ Crowd Cheering ]
[ Crying ]
[ Moaning Softly ]
[ Moaning Continues ]
[ Kitty ]
The poor girl.
It was a mistake.
I shouldn't have told you.
I should not have let you
destroy her this way!
[ Wallenberg ]
Calm yourself.
I trust there will be
no further incidents of this sort.
If there are,
call me immediately.
I'll take care of everything.
As you did today?
As I did today.
[ Shrieks ]
[ Gasping ]
What are you staring at?
Go away while you still can!
This is a lousy life!
A life full of shit, vomit,
jizz, pricks, cunts and idiots!
Go away! All of you!
[ Shrieks ]
You. Especially you.
What need have you
to be humiliated by men?
You're so beautiful, so gentle.
Save yourself.
Anything is better than this.
Save yourself, Margherita.
[ Moans ]
How did you manage
to hide it until now?
By wearing a corset.
The men, well, they never
notice things like that.
But now my child shows.
You should have
informed us immediately.
Why didn't you?
I want to have the baby.
I've never heard
of anything so ridiculous.
[ Woman ]
It's mine.
- And the father?
- It's mine.
Do you mean to say
you'd consider having a baby...
without proper state control?
Have you forgotten
that you are still an S.S. woman?
One of our auxiliaries?
It's mine.
Psychologically,
this girl is finished,
so far as her mission
is concerned.
We can't have a whore like her
walking around.
She knows too much.
Doctor, the solution
is up to you now.
- Heil Hitler.
[ Screaming ]
Your must be Margherita,
Hans Reiter's girl.
We were in the same squadron.
[ Urinating ]
He told me about you.
Yes, I know him.
He's been here.
Do you know
he was in love with you?
It happens.
Fortunately,
he got over it quickly.
I don't think he did.
[ Toilet Flushing ]
That's too bad. A man should never
fall in love with a girl like me.
[ Chuckles ]
Why?
I'm a whore.
Hmm.
Where is he now?
Don't you know?
He was hanged
a few days after he got back.
For defeatism
and anti-patriotism.
Ah. There was
an S.S. report from Berlin.
He was planning to desert.
He was going to defect
to the enemy, the swine.
We thought he was
a good comrade, the shit.
In public he defended
National Socialism,
and in private
he called us murderers.
He was a goddamn coward.
No balls.
Fortunately, he gave himself away.
They hanged the son of a bitch
on a meat hook.
I got a kick out of seeing
that bastard hanging up there.
[ Chuckles ]
Like a stuck pig.
I even had the satisfaction
of spitting on his corp--
[ Doorknob Rattling ]
[ Kitty ]
Margherita! Margherita!
[ Knocking ]
Ohh!
Get me Wallenberg's office, please.
Wallenberg? It's Kitty.
We've had some trouble here.
An officer shot himself
in the shower.
When are you
going back to Berlin?
I don't know, Mother.
Darling, are you
on sick leave or what?
Yes, I am.
A sort
of nervous breakdown.
From overwork,
let us say.
[ Flies Buzzing ]
And what about them?
Do they approve?
They? They who?
What do you know about it?
You don't know
what I do.
You just noticed
that one day I left home.
You never gave a thought
as to what my work might be.
Well, you never gave me permission--
[ Margherita ]
Neither did I give you permission
to make me join the  National Socialist Party.
To bear a grudge
is childish.
I don't bear any grudge.
You despise us!
I do.
I despise your hypocrisy,
your refusal to face the truth.
You hide in silence
behind your law and order.
And our tradition!
A fine tradition.
Look at yourselves.
Two mummified insects.
Why should people
like you be saved?
Today's youth isn't concerned
about the past or the future,
so it is up to the elders
to preserve our--
Preserve what?
Your hide?
Your property?
[ Doorbell Rings ]
With your eyes closed
so as not to see, not to think?
-A few months ago,
you sang a very different song.
- Mm-hmm.
- It's for you, miss.
- Who is it?
Madam Kitty Kellermann!
Kitty?
[ Margherita ]
Tell her I'm not at home.
Say you don't where I am.
No, wait.
Show her to the winter garden.
Margherita, what kind of work
do you do in Berlin?
Invent something, Father.
Whatever makes your conscience
sleep in peace.
[ Kitty ]
I understand you, darling.
At your age,
I would have done the same thing.
But I can't keep
on covering for you.
Wallenberg wants you back.
So now you're pimping for Wallenberg.
I don't pimp for anybody,
especially not for a politician
like Wallenberg.
But don't forget
that a German officer
was killed in your room.
It's not only stupid
but dangerous
to fight a man like him.
Are you blackmailing me?
Well, I don't give a damn.
Go ahead and tell him.
Tell him I blew his brains out.
Tell him I killed that pig to avenge Hans.
Did you really love him
that much?
You don't have
to come back tomorrow
or the next day. Take your time.
Meanwhile,
I'll try to smooth things over.
There's nothing to smooth over.
I'm not going back.
Don't bother to lie.
Write the report yourself.
Margherita is leaving
Operation Kitty!
What operation?
The one that gets people
hanged on meat hooks.
What the hell
are you talking about?
The operation you run, Kitty.
The nest of spies
who drink champagne and fuck...
and report every secret they learn
back to Wallenberg.
It's not true.
There's not a word of truth
in what you say.
Stop it, Kitty.
Stop playacting with me.
I don't ask you to justify yourself.
I don't give a fuck
if you're in partnership with Wallenberg.
Me? Partnership
with that S.S. captain?
You've all been spying.
Spies! Spies! Spies!
In my house! In my honest,
clean, beautiful house!
I hate you!
The whole lot of you!
I never dirtied myself
with all that political shit.
[ Sobs ]
People can do
whatever they want in there.
Sex is clean.
[ Sobbing ]
Now I understand everything.
He changed the house.
He changed the girls.
He thought he could
change Kitty too.
But I'll show that bastard Wallenberg.
I'll get him. I'll destroy him.
I'll go to Himmler.
I'll go to Hitler.
[ Sobbing ]
And this time, I mean it.
Forgive me, Kitty.
Don't cry.
I suspected you.
I thought you were in on it with him.
Me? Oh, you idiot.
You must be out of your mind.
[ Sniffles ]
Forgive me.
But then,
how could Wallenberg know
every single word Hans said,
as if he'd been there?
We were alone,
absolutely alone.
How did they know
what Hans felt?
His decision to defect?
That's why they killed him.
How did they know?
You put that butcher's hook
into him.
No. Hans?  No.
I never wrote a word
of what Hans told me-- not a word.
I didn't want to admit
that I loved him.
But now I know.
I also know what he meant
when he said,
"I'm going to get out of this slaughterhouse,
together with you."
He knew that I, too,
would begin to think, to understand.
Kitty.
Don't you want to be
on my side?
No. On that side, never.
I need your help.
I feel I'm waking
from a nightmare.
When are you going
to wake up too?
I don't understand
anything anymore.
Not a thing.
Well, neither do I, Kitty.
But don't you see?
Now we must help each other.
Let's try.
What do you want to do?
Let's go back to Berlin...
and find out how Wallenberg
knows everything we do
and everything we say,
all the time, in every room.
I want to clean up my house, Margherita,
whatever the cost.
I want it clean like it was before. Clean.
?? [Jazz ]
[ Vomiting ]
?? [ Continues ]
?? [ Trumpet ]
I go. I piss. I come back.
?? [ Humming ]
Kitty.
?? [ Humming Continues ]
"Brutus is a man of great honor."
No. "Brutus is an honorable man."
Ciao, Kitty.
Have you come to feast your eyes?
[ Laughing ]
I have known many men in my life,
but you-- How can I resist you?
It takes a strong woman.
Huh. What's going on?
Are we making the famous Salon Kitty
into some den of iniquity...
like the decadent past
of ancient Roma, huh?
Get yourself a sheet, Kitty.
We have to talk to you,
if you can stop clowning
for a moment.
I obey. What's up?
I found out why Wallenberg
forced me to move here.
We are being spied on.
The girls are all S.S. agents.
Every day they report
all the nonsense you men
are foolish enough to say in bed.
Le ragazze sono delle S.S.?
Mm-hmm.
Oh, shit.
You mean they're not only whores,
but bitches too? Sorry, Margherita.
That's not all.
The rooms are bugged.
No. The bathrooms aren't.
[ Italian ]
Ah, indeed.
[ English ] They couldn't hear anyway
because of the water.
Ah, but if they could.
Don't believe that those Nazi bastards
are democratic or kind enough
to let us piss in peace.
Which reminds me.
We need your help.
[ Toilet Flushing ]
What for?
To destroy him.
Well, it's a bit unusual
to conspire in a bathroom,
even for an Italian.
But when a problem is that shitty,
you discuss it in a shithouse.
[ Man ]
Hoorah!
Paris is ours!
[ Chattering, Laughing ]
I drink to the German soldiers...
who are marching
under the Arc de Triomphe!
Heil Hitler!
[ All ]
[ Man ]
Once again, everybody!
Sieg heil!
Heil Hitler!
[ Glass Shatters ]
?? [ Accordion, Up-tempo ]
Vive La France!
[ Speaks German ]
- Vive La France!
- [ Speaks German ]
- [ Woman ]
Vive La France!
- [ Shouting In German ]
[ Whip Cracking ]
Vive La France!
Heil Hitler!
[ Shouting In German ]
Vive La France!
[ Speaks French ]
Madame, mademoiselle, monsieur!
Le Can-can!
[ Whip Cracks ]
?? [ Begins ]
[ People Clapping Rhythmically ]
[ Hooting ]
At last. What happened?
Where are you?
[ Dino ] In Paris.
The French are delighted
to have been liberated by the Weimar.
As you know, my Italia
has now joined forces with Germany--
just in time for history
to put us in the books of major triumphs.
The big brass decided
I'm the best war correspondent.
I couldn't refuse the honor.
And what-- what about me?
You have forgotten me?
Ah, no. You know your kisses
are unforgettable, cara.
Pretend that I'm still there
with you as always.
I do, but it doesn't help.
I miss you terribly.
Thank you for calling, darling.
No, darling, just a minute.
I had to call you anyway.
Remember in Margherita's bathroom?
I forgot to turn off the shower.
The bathroom will be flooded.
You'd better go up, huh? Capito?
Turn it off. Capito?
Margherita's bathroom.
But hurry. Presto. Capito?
You know you can't call
the plumber after 1 0:00.
Understand, huh?
I miss you.
[ Smacks Lips ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Laughs ]
Excuse me.
Aren't you feeling well?
I feel fine, thanks.
Don't worry. I know everything.
Dino asked me to bring you a present.
It's a new kind
of radio transmitter.
A great little gadget.
It'll relay everything
up to half a mile.
Oh?
It's quite simple.
You just turn it on, and I'll record
whatever you want me to.
[ Margherita ]
I see you so rarely.
?? [ Classical ]
?? [ Continues ]
Why don't you say something?
Are you angry with me?
?? [ Continues ]
[ Sniffing ]
Speak to me. Say something.
?? [ Stops ]
You like that, don't you?
Slave and master.
Oh, God, but I've wanted you.
[ Glass Clatters ]
Drink it.
I despise whores.
They are paid to let us.
What am I then?
Even if I don't do it for money,
I'm still a whore.
You're my creation.
I invented you.
You're my accomplice.
Do everything you want, anything.
God knows when I'll see you again.
Very soon.
Wait.
I want to make it last
as long as possible.
Your wife?
I've sent her away.
Even the servant
has the day off.
She's still your wife.
Soon I'll be powerful enough
to get rid of her.
Kiss me. Please kiss me.
This house is no place for illusions.
They're not illusions.
Look!
My wife's grandfather was a Jew.
If they find out,
that could be dangerous,
even for you.
Not when I have the power I deserve--
the power of Himmler.
You're mad.
I have in my hands the bedroom secrets
of everybody in Germany--
Ribbentrop, Goebbels,
Keitel, Jodl,
even Himmler himself.
I know the weak points of...
every single one of them.
The cocaine they take,
their impotence, their perversions,
their thieving, their betrayals,
their rivalries.
Defeatist cowards.
What do your superiors
think about it?
[ Wallenberg ]
They won't have time to think.
- [ Margherita Moaning ]
- The original idea wasn't mine, I admit,
but I know how I can get rid of them all,
at my convenience.
You have illusions
about your power.
No, no, no.
Every word is true.
It's true!
Get that through your head!
I don't give a damn
about National Socialism,
just as none of our leaders
give a damn!
It's a means to an end-- power!
There are no ideals, no faith.
You are the one
with illusions, Margherita--
you and the millions of other Germans
who believed in us.
It's a way to get you all
under our thumb.
You, a bourgeois,
under the thumb of a pimp.
To have you and what you stood for,
I got you down to my level.
Just like all the others.
Reduced to
a world of gangsters.
We made criminals
out of all of you.
Murderers, thieves,
corrupted accomplices...
and slaves.
I believe you.
But let's not talk about that now.
Touch me here.
Make me come.
Let me feel your power.
Whore.
I made you, a whore, into one
of the first ladies of the Third Reich.
Pimp.
Whore.
A whore and a pimp
who salute each other in public.
Heil... Hitler.
[ Gasps ]
No one knows anything about us.
Only I.
Heil--
[ Moans, Speaks, Indistinct ]
[ Moans ]
[ Cliff]
What's the matter, honey?
Are you getting tired
of all this?
I'd like to see you at it--
my legs spread all day long.
It's no fun anymore.
Why don't you quit?
If only I could.
You're sweet, you know.
I like you.
Take me to America with you.
Would you?
Sure. If you put
some clothes on.
I'll get my things together,
and we'll go.
Listen.
I'll be back in a minute.
Get ready.
Roosevelt's waiting for you.
[ Door Closes ]
- [ Door Closes ]
- Shh.
[ Toilet Flushes ]
[ Woman ]
Cliff!
In a minute!
[ Gasps ]
[ Screams ]
[ Shrieks, Gasps ]
[ All Gasping ]
She hanged herself.
Son of a bitch.
[ Sobbing ]
[ Sobbing Continues ]
Jesus God.
Untergruppenführer Wallenberg
is not here!
I haven't come to see him.
I've come to charge him with treason.
Wallenberg?
[ Shouting ]
Do you realize
what you are doing?
I do. I am a National Socialist.
I know that traitors must be crushed
without pity, no matter who they are.
Do you have any proof?
This is my report.
You will recognize Wallenberg's
voice on this recording.
How did you find out?
I'm his mistress.
We shall look into it.
We shall listen.
Listen to it
and take action immediately.
Mine is a professional accusation.
If you don't feel you can handle
the matter, just say so.
I'll go directly
to Reich führer Himmler.
I'll take care of it immediately!
Don't worry, kamarad!
Heil Hitler.
Heil Hitler!
[ Knocking ]
Come in.
A report and a recording!
Very urgent!
Top secret,
Herr Obergruppenführer!
[ Tape Whirring ]
[ Wallenberg's Voice ]
Look!
My wife's grandfather was a Jew.
[ Margherita's Voice ] If they find out,
that could be dangerous, even for you.
[ Wallenberg's Voice ]
Not when I have the power I deserve--
the power of Himmler.
[ Margherita's Voice ]
You're mad.
[ Wallenberg's Voice ]
I have in my hands the bedroom secrets
of everybody in Germany--
Ribbentrop, Goebbels,
Keitel, Jodl,
even Himmler himself.
I know the weak points of...
every single one of them.
The cocaine they take,
their impotence, their perversions,
their thieving, their betrayals,
their rivalries.
Defeatist cowards.
[ Margherita's Voice ]
What do your superiors
think about it?
[ Wallenberg's Voice ]
They won't have time to think.
Heil Hitler!
The original idea wasn't mine, I admit,
but I know
how I can get rid of them all,
at my convenience.
[ Margherita's Voice ]
You have illusions
about your power.
[ Wallenberg's Voice ]
No, no, no.
Every word is true.
It's true!
Get that through your head!
I don't give a damn
about National Socialism,
just as none of our leaders
give a damn!
It's a means to an end-- power!
There are no ideals, no faith.
You are the one
with illusions, Margherita--
you and the millions of other Germans
who believed in us.
It's a way to get you all
under our thumb.
You, a bourgeois,
under the thumb of a pimp.
To have you and what you stood for,
I got you down to my level.
Just like all the others.
Reduced to a load of gangsters.
We made criminals out of all of you.
Murderers, thieves,
corrupted accomplices...
and...
[ Margherita Speaking Italian ]
I believe you.
[ Italian ]
But let's not talk about that now.
[ Margherita Continues Speaking Italian ]
Touch me here.
[ Italian ]
Make me come.
Let me feel your power.
[ Wallenberg Speaking Italian ]
Whore.
[ Wallenberg, Italian ]
I made you, a whore, into one
of the first ladies of the Third Reich.
[ Margherita Speaking Italian ]
Pimp.
[ Margherita, Italian ]
A whore and a pimp
who salute each other in public.
[ Margherita ]
Heil... Hitler.
[ Animal Shrieks ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Airplanes Droning Overhead ]
[ Airplanes Continue Droning Overhead ]
[ Explosion ]
[ Laughing ]
[ Kitty ]
? They say that all things ?
? Must have an end ?
? That broken bones and broken hearts ?
? Take, oh, so long to mend ?
? You've heard it so often ?
? It must be true ?
? Will you believe it ?
? When it happens ?
? To you ?
? Morning coffee ?
? Won't taste the same ?
? A fix won't help a lot ?
? You've only got yourself to blame ?
? Your bed's so empty ?
? Your world's so black ?
? Is there no joy ?
? Is there no love ?
? Is there no turning back ?
? Your life's in pieces ?
? What can you say ?
? As you light yet another cigarette ?
? Thoughts far away ?
? With sleepless eyes, you realize ?
? It's not the same world anymore ?
? On the morning after ?
? The night before ?
?? [ Violin Solo ]
? Your life's in pieces ?
? What can you say ?
? As you light yet another cigarette ?
? Thoughts far away ?
? With sleepless eyes, you realize ?
? It's not the same world anymore ?
? On the morning after ?
? The night before ??