The International Union
Miners ...
... and Workers
Metal presents:
SALT OF THE EARTH
The scene is
New Mexico, ...
... the land of the
Free US ...
... which inspired
this film ...
... and the home of the brave
they performed ...
... most of the papers.
How shall I begin my story
that has no beginning
My grandfather raised cattle
in these streams ...
... before they got
Anglos.
our roots
go deep in this place
... deeper than
the pines ...
... or mine.
This is my town.
When I was small,
was called San Marcos.
Anglos put him
Zinctown.
Zinctown, New Mexico, ...
... United States.
This is our home.
The house is not ours ...
... but flowers
yes they are.
My name
Esperanza Quintero.
I am the wife of a miner.
My husband has spent
18 years at this mine.
Half life in darkness,
with dynamite.
The land where
Mine is ...
... Grandpa belonged
my husband.
Now belongs
to the Company.
Who can say
when my story began?
Yo no lo sé.
But I remember that day
as the beginning of the end.
It was the day of my holy.
Moreover, met 35 years ...
... a day of celebration.
She was pregnant
7 months of my third child.
I remember that day
I made a wish.
It was a sin,
one evil.
I prayed to the Virgin to ask
forgiveness for my thoughts.
I wanted ...
... my son did not come ...
... to this world.
Are you ill, mother?
Are you sad?
Are we going to church
to confess?
Later, when
end boards.
Did you come back to fight
with Anglo children?
- They think very hard.
- Promised not to fight anymore.
Dad says do not let
make fun of me.
Ignore him.
¡Be still!
Does it hurt?
- And that cake?
- Forget the cake.
Go find your father
When your turn ends.
Tell him to come home
directly.
I have been told that you had
problems with a detonator.
You're alive, what
is the problem?
Ya know, this new standard
to work alone.
Let's see the supervisor.
It is negotiating
with your committee.
- All the better.
- Wait.
He dictated that standard,
It will not help.
Well, I'll stop boring.
With your contract?
Have someone read it to you.
He said nothing of helpers.
This mine is
bloodstained.
The blood of my friends
working alone
They were crushed because
anyone watched the detonator.
Nobody sounded
alarm.
That is the task
shift foreman.
He wants to extract mineral.
We want
everyone out alive.
You will work only.
If you work overflows,
I'll find another.
To a squirrel?
At an American.
Do not say anything on the cake.
Will strike?
I do not want to worry, but
in the shop told me ...
... that if we do not pay another
within the radio, ...
... will they take.
Only owe a month.
I tried to convince them.
That's not right.
Is not it good?
And is it OK to buy
this artifact?
But you wanted.
You had to listen
radio.
I hear at night ...
... when you are you
in the bar.
"No entry
in easy installments. "
Diré you something:
Deadlines are the curse
of workers.
- Where are you going?
- A talk with peers.
The water is cold again.
- Sorry, the fire was extinguished.
- Forget it.
They forget!
Short firewood five times
day, I can not forget.
Do not forget that miners
Anglos have running water ...
... and toilets at home.
Do you think I like
live like this?
What can I do?
... ask for better conditions ...
... would have to demand
decent plumbing.
We did, but we
to resign.
- What?
- All at once can not be.
Now we requirements
most important.
What's most important
that healing?
Safety at work
is more important.
This week has been
five accidents ...
... to increase
production.
You are a woman and do not know
anything in the world.
First we have to get
equality at work.
Then we will
the rest.
- That's a guy thing.
- I understand.
Men do strike
by your demands ...
... but you leave for later
what we women.
Do not start again
to criticize the union.
What have you done for me
your union?
Remember what it was like
before the union, ...
... when Estela sick and
we could pay the doctor?
We founded the union
for our families.
Okay, you will have
your strike.
I'll have my son.
The hospital will not admit me
being the wife of a striker.
Store fail to rely
and children will go hungry.
We can not pay
deadlines ...
... and the radio will be.
What all you care
is this radio?
Just think of yourself.
I do ...
... because you never
think of me.
Never.
Basta!
We are seeing
children.
Be resolved
the problem.
The company always
says the same.
For a miner, is
dangerous work alone.
Nobody works alone
in other mines.
Anglos work
in pairs.
And I have to risk
life because I'm Mexican?
- We have already asked.
- We are negotiating.
We have not achieved anything in
three months of negotiations.
Even with the help of
Barnes, International.
Ni increases,
nor old ...
... nor safety.
Have a drink.
We must act now.
Do others think
like you?
Speak for everyone.
What if employers
want to strike?
Do not want, and less
contract with the Army.
then
Why refuse?
They have agreed with other
sections of the union.
But here most
We are Mexicans.
We want equality with
Anglo miners.
The same pay,
the same conditions.
Exactly, but employers
do not want this equality.
His only argument against
the Anglo sections is:
"We give more than
the Mexicans ".
So what? discrimination
Anglo hurts ...
... but me.
And I'm sick.
If you declare strike
when they want, ...
... will crush the union.
Wait till you can win.
Employers do not expect.
No running water,
my children sick.
The doctor did not expect.
Cobra cash.
We must within
the radio.
The store does not hold:
"Pay or we get along."
Why such a hurry
Shop employers?
They want to scare us
so that we do not protest.
Want us to conform
with what we have.
But I am not satisfied,
I'm not afraid.
I'm sick.
What are you doing here?
- Is something wrong with your mother?
- Have you forgotten?
- Forget what?
- Today is the holy mother.
He's a great guy,
It is in everything.
Today is the holy
my wife.
I would like to ask you
viniérais to haunt.
- At this hour?
- The later the better.
Why sing?
Sing to me.
Can we turn
candles?
We can now turn them on.
Happy Birthday!
He never wanted to mourn.
Why do I cry,
if I'm happy?
I'm an idiot.
No, you're not.
Was very expensive beer?
I invited Antonio.
Forgive me for saying
ever think of me.
I'd forgotten.
Luis reminded me.
I spent a week thinking that round
Never had such a nice holiday
It was a song that filled my being ...
and mitigated the harshness of everyday work
One, two three.
forget all our problems ...
... even Ramón
That night I could not dance ...
... because of my state ...
... but I was jealous when he danced with the other
It was wonderful to see you smile again
one morning, was hanging laundry
We were chatting
when they arrived ladies.
Formed a kind of delegation
They spoke of health facilities
Anglo miners had
sinks with hot water
Why not us?
I know, talk about it
Ramon
... just a week ago
He says the union it has
removed from their demands
We need to raise awareness
men about this.
Teach the banner
"We want health,
non-discrimination. "
We and many more
take you to the mine
While it is trading at the office ...
Arrive in groups to take the site
Both parties see that
we mean
- A squad of Women?
- Why not?
count me in
We should form a union
of woodcutters
We cut wood for breakfast,
to wash their clothes ...
... for washing for laundry,
to make dinner ...
... and when you come home
night, says:
Have you spent the day
reading comics?
Come on, Esperanza
we have to
I can not.
If Ramon found out of
I'm in a pinch ...
Do you fitting?
It is Mr. Kalinski
Hurry.
Carefully.
I want to see!
- I want to see him now!
- He'll be fine, Mrs. Kalinski.!
I want to see him now!
How did this happen?
He entered the gallery
they were dynamiting
I warned, this occurs
because we work alone.
- Why did not they tell you?
- I had to do the foreman
When I looked there was no
It would be sleeping.
Not come down to the well, Kalinski
I saw you at the office
Pancho lie.
You're a dirty ...
Enough!
Do not lose control.
There is a wounded man.
I'm sorry too, you know?
Accidents hurt us all
But the company
No reason to stand
like party
Back to work.
The party is over,
all to work.
What do they say?
Not "know".
Barnes, tell your men
back to work
No work for me,
I work for them.
Luis.
What you decide, comrades?
"We want health,
non-discrimination. "
That night, there was a
union meeting ...
... to give official appearance
Did not take long.
The strike was approved
by 93 votes to 5.
Teresa said it was
the time to introduce.
I did not want.
Never been in a
union meeting.
But others said:
"If you are one, we all."
When we arrived, the meeting
I was about to end
Charlie Vidal outlined the situation.
Said the strike
had one goal.
Equality.
But employers do anything ...
... to avoid them to get equality.
Try to divide workers ...
... between Anglos and Mexican-Americans.
Who sold it to his brother
would be rewarded.
Women ye
make a statement ...
It is not a statement
- Women want ...
- Higher!
Consuelo, speaking from the podium
Women have spoken
sanitary facilities.
If you want to achieve equality ...
... as you say, ...
... you should ask
the same equality ...
... sanitary facilities
Reivindicadlo also
the strike.
We have also thought ...
... we could create a
female auxiliary section.
We want to help in any way possible.
I think I speak on behalf
of my colleagues ...
... to thank the women
offering us their help, ...
but it's late and I suggest postponing the issue.
The board will accept a
motion to adjourn.
- I presented it.
- The seconded.
Who is in favor?
Who is against?
Approved.
You need to plan
Why did not you defended?
You are worse than others.
Teresa, can not be forced
Therefore the situation.
Ye you force us to accept
unfair conditions.
Why not consult me?
It was embarrassing!
At least you did not ridicule
as Consuelo.
It's not a bad idea;
should demand better health.
- But honey ...!
- Put a notice on the door ...
"No dogs allowed
or women. "
"We want equality
with other miners. "
"We are guided by the union."
"Less talk and more money."
So it all started,
and other strikes.
The company said
not negotiate ...
... until the workers
back to work.
But the ploy
will not work for them.
They hired strikebreakers
of other peoples.
But his mind was cooled ...
... when they saw the size of the picket.
The sheriff and his men
They were always there ...
... wearing their weapons.
But men just marched ...
... day after day ...
... week after week.
At first, women
we stayed at home.
The union brought food
We tried and we ...
... feed our families.
One morning mrs. Salazar
He went to the picket line.
Her husband had died in a
strike for many years.
She wanted to be there.
No one remembers how it happened.
One day Mrs. Salazar
he joined the march.
And it was not separated from them.
Several women began
bring coffee to their husbands ...
... and tacos, because
Men have just ...
... tired and hungry
acting on picket.
It was then that
the union decided ...
... that should be set
a female auxiliary section.
At first I did not go with them.
Soon give birth.
In addition to Ramón did not like.
But Ramon loves
good coffee ...
... and swore that of
other women appeared ...
... dregs of zinc.
So, one day I made the coffee.
"They did not move."
"Solidarity with the miners."
Three days ago I do not see him
Ramon, listen to this.
The foreman gave me last night
me shift manager ...
... if I am the first
returning to work.
"Jenkins, why are you doing
For these Reds?
I replied that the Reds
I like every day.
Two scabs managed to pass
- We stopped to rest.
- Les ye searched?
They were Anglos other peoples
But they were not miners,
they would not know the zinc.
Good job.
Go to tomer coffee.
Ramon comes the supervisor.
- Good Morning
- How is here?
We picked up the types
to you. hired ...
... and we came in trucks
this morning.
When they saw the picket
they turned
Not seem so scary.
Mr. Hartwell, some
They are brave men.
Especially the leader
the picket line.
How is it called?
Raymon, or something.
Yes, I know him.
This is the main picket.
They have another on secondary road ...
... and patrol the area.
The land is in the company.
Why not throw them?
Everything is of the company,
Mr. Hartwell.
The shop houses ...
... everything.
Where would miss them?
And who would?
Do we let go?
Sooner or later.
Just want to impress
with his power.
Why do not you let go
these gentlemen?
Do you know who will
in that car?
The cashier brings us
Moscow gold.
No, it's the president
of the company.
Comes to appoint Jenkins
Managing Director
Come on, let him go.
How childish!
They are like children
Sometimes you have to pamper them,
... other must scold
... and others have to punish them without eating.
Here comes my saying.
It is quite a character.
He claims that his grandfather
owned land mine.
Want to go to your office
Mr. Alexander?
Sure, I have not stopped
for coffee.
To that we can invite.
No thanks.
Men want to know who is
this gentleman.
- It is not his business
- Leave it, it's not a secret.
My name is Hartwell,
work in the offices of this.
- In Delaware?
- No, in New York.
By any chance are you
the president of the company?
- no
- What a shame.
The man always wanted
see President
He could resolve the strike.
Is that possible?
Yes, negotiating.
Is a union spokesperson?
Not exactly.
I wish it were.
Know more of mines
puppets with whom we associate.
Seriously, I've seen
your personal record.
I was going to promote you to foreman
when the strike began.
You had future in the company.
You've been swept by these red ...
... but you will betray.
When awaken, Ray?
Your name is Ray, no?
Call me Quintero.
Mr. Quintero.
Are we allowed to pass or I
to call the sheriff?
Nothing stops him.
I was wrong, do not want to
Jenkins CEO.
I want my!
You should have heard
to that liar.
Foreman said he would appoint me.
- What's the matter?
- It's nothing
just a cramp.
Dad, come here!
What makes Luis here?
Another time playing hooky?
Come back here!
We have seen two scabs
They have hidden there.
Wait, fellas.
You three, accompany me.
The others follow
in line.
Luis, come back!
They go by.
Ramon, listen,
for God's sake.
You!
I would have expected from an Anglo.
I needed the job.
You, Judas!
leech
It was for my kids!
Do not eat enough.
Do you think mine itself?
Dirty Rat.
I know I did wrong
but do not hurt me.
Do you think I'm going to hit you?
I would not mess with you hands.
There comes a child,
warns women, fast!
Why are we stopping?
Tell us why agrediste
that boy.
That's a lie.
Do not talk to
a white.
Go back and then produce a
blanket to move it.
Did not you say this torero
had much stamina?
No one would say now.
The chile gives
much energy.
Like as it prepares
your "tiny" Pancho?
We need a doctor soon,
that woman will give birth
Do you take me for the driver
an ambulance?
Notify your physician of the company.
Nobody here has a car.
The company doctor will not attend
Picket anyone.
No time to take her home,
Put it in there
Raise your head Pancho,
that's no way to sit.
Do not you go out with
your pigs.
You like what you have searched.
OMG!
Forgive me for having desired
my son was not born
Have mercy on my son.
Do not let me die.
OMG!
Ramon was in the
hospital a week.
... and one month in prison ...
... charged with assault and resisting
authority.
I decided to postpone
christening ...
... until Ramón out
from jail.
We christened
the name John.
That night there was
double celebration.
Christening Juanito
and the return of Ramon.
Children to bed
in the bedroom ...
... as always ...
... and men occupied
the living room, ...
... as usual.
- Five thousand dollars.
- Too much for me.
- Ascend to ten thousand.
- I'm going, what do you have?
Three aces.
Come to Daddy.
Do bailiffs
Vicente arrested?
Yes, there have been many
provocations.
Assume that locking up
leaders on false charges ...
... were able to end the strike.
Do they let play poker
all night?
- I want to dance?
- With the husband from whom?
With either,
even with mine.
If you dance with my husband,
will have to endure this.
Your attitude toward Anglos
It is unbecoming of a leader.
What attitude?
Do you distinguish between workers
and Anglo employers
To him I invited him to my house
Is not it?
Do you also suspect him?
perhaps
Has much to learn
on our people.
Still, say it all.
You are the organizer.
Strategy plan
and you hit almost always
You think of everything
we do the rest.
We do not have
to think about anything.
Do you think that laziness us
prevented from taking the initiative?
You know not.
Maybe not, but there is more.
Tonight on entering,
I hear you ask your wife ...
"That man is your grandfather?"
Is Juarez, Mexico's father.
If I did not recognize
George Washington ...
You'd take me for a stupid Mexican.
It never fails.
You try to advise Ramón
and you respond with an insult.
He's right. I still
much to learn.
Well, settled matter.
Who gives the cards?
Be comforted, even listening
women less.
What do they talk?
Their weaknesses.
Did you have?
Now it criticize Ramon.
If we exclude women
the union struggle ...
Come on, bet!
Let's change the game.
There are housewives,
They are our companions.
They deserve to be treated
as equals.
Look who's talking.
The defender of women.
Enough, Ruth.
I follow him everywhere.
The miners organized,
village after village ...
... in Montana, Colorado
or Idaho ...
... but never thought
in organizing women.
Women also have
Angles in sections.
Nor do I approve as
Ramón treat your woman.
Dr. Barnes has his remedy
for women ...
... but have not tried
at home.
It is breastfeeding her child.
Goodbye to the game.
I'm glad. Consuelo,
up the volume.
Top Dad.
Standing.
Look at him!
He is a fighter.
Born fighting ...
... and hungry.
Chupa Juanito.
You'll never be so happy
as now.
Yes, it will be happier ...
... someday.
What did they say to you?
I make you suffer.
Suffer if you're in jail.
In this cell
I could not sleep ...
For bugs, heat
and the stench.
And he told me:
"Think of something beautiful ..
... into something beautiful. "
And I thought of you.
And I felt my heart pounding ...
... of love for you.
Not only Juanito ...
... you too will be happy.
The strike will triumph.
Why are you so sure?
If we lose, we lose
more than a strike.
Lose the union
and men know.
If we win, we will win
more improvements.
We will win something ...
... much more:
hope for
our children.
Juanito need
more than milk.
- Do you live here Quintero?
- What do you want?
- We come to garnish.
- What about the warrant?
- Also have.
- We do not want problems.
Just took the radio.
sorry to interrupt
the party ...
... but the owner of the radio
has achieved a garnishment order ...
Do not touch.
We do not seek problems
Mr. Quintero.
We order
repossess the equipment.
I said do not touch it!
- Let them take her
- Passing over my dead body
I do not want your corpse,
or see you in jail.
It is yours and not
they carry.
If you resist will
an excuse to lock you up.
Gladden those faces.
We have real music!
But the strike continued.
It seemed interminable.
They spent four months,
five, six ...
The company was
without wanting to negotiate.
They tried to turn against
Anglo miners us.
They said I had to send the
Mexicans back to their country.
How I can back
the place where it went?
The barracks where I was born
is now Company
Why would anyone sends
patterns his people?
Patterns so there would
throughout New Mexico.
- Hopefully we will see that day.
- Jenkins is not an employer.
In his ilk
They let them stay.
You can not give the desert
Oklahoma, it would be inhuman
I was born in Texas
That would be even worse!
He reached the seventh month
The company store
he refused to serve us.
Box resistance
It was exhausting
Several families could not stand it.
Nobody knows where they went.
The union decided that
desperate cases ...
... should apply for a job
in other mines.
This was done.
About getting employment
helped with their pay ...
... for others
they could eat.
Ramon was not a hopeless case.
Only had three
children to feed.
Still, employers us
they would have starved ...
... but we received support
International, Denver ...
... and other sections.
We thought that
anyone outside the county ...
... he was interested in
our problems.
We were wrong ...
"Solidarity with the miners.
Construction union. "
Letters came from our
Southeast compatriots.
From far:
Butte, Chicago,
Birmingham, New York ...
Messages of solidarity ...
... and crumpled banknotes
men working.
The women were helping ...
... not only as cooks
or making coffee.
Some men mocked ...
... but you had to do the job ...
... and allow us to do so.
Nobody realized
the magnitude of change ...
... until the day of the crisis.
The sheriff smiled.
We learned that brought bad news.
The company had achieved a
writ ...
... prohibiting mining
manifest in the pickets.
It was based on the law
Taft-Hartley.
Punishable by heavy fines
and a prison ...
miners who disobeyed
You had to make a decision immediately
Ignoring the mandate
or do not comply.
If we obey ...
... the strike will fail
The scabs come
as the needle was going
If we disobey ...
... the strikers will be
arrested
... and the strike will fail
anyway.
So things are
peers.
Employers are we
at their mercy.
I want to add something.
Whatever your decision ...
... I support the International ...
... as it always has.
We are a union
democratic.
The decision ...
... is yours.
Comrade President.
If we surrender now ...
... and to the odedecemos
Taft-Hartley rotten ...
... we are fools and cowards.
We can only do
one thing to fight.
- To fight and win.
- There would win anything.
We would be detained
The men discussed.
There were great speeches.
Apparently Barnes
was right.
The company had them
at their mercy.
Apparently the strike
had failed.
Companion president.
If you read the injunction
carefully ...
... you will see that only prohibits
manifest miners.
women
We are not miners.
We will relieve you
on the picket lines.
Do not scoff.
We have a
solution and you do not.
Quintero is right
saying that lose ..
... the achievements of 50 years
fight if the strike fails.
also lose
women and children.
So we promise ...
... relieve you on the picket ...
... to strike
not fail ...
... and scabs
I do not take the job.
Only union members
may submit proposals.
- I present.
- The seconded.
You heard the proposal.
Start the discussion
Light asked whether they preferred
hide behind their wives ...
... or humble themselves before
employers.
Comrades, we ignore
our women.
Employers or
even think about them.
They will show employers what now ...
... why there is no unity among men ...
... their wives
and her companions?
Carlota Sanchez said
the pickets ...
... were unfit
the ladies.
It was not right.
Perhaps even it were sin.
Give an opportunity to the women.
What do
when police ...
... hit our women?
We will not stay
idly.
We will have to intervene
and back to the top
Or worse,
more humiliated.
Companions.
I beg you,
You do not permitáis.
Let's vote.
Discussed the issue.
we all know
we voted:
The female section
will be responsible for the pickets
Raise your hand if
they favor.
President, I appeal to
regulation.
I do not understand
these discussions ...
... but the men
you go to vote ...
... what to do
or not women.
I think it would be fair ...
... that we allowed to vote.
Especially if we
to do the job.
Comrades,
would go against all rules ...
... allow women
vote in a union meeting.
If no objections ...
... postpone the meeting.
Wait.
We can continue as
assembly of citizens.
So we all adults
entitled to vote.
- I propose
- OK.
Hands up who
want to postpone the meeting.
Who is against?
Approved.
Now all adults
entitled to vote.
Returning to the original topic
Those in favor of
women formed picket ...
... to raise their hands.
Who is opposed?
Approved the motion
by 103 votes to 85.
Then came the women.
From Zinctown,
Hills ...
... and other mining towns ...
... traveling up to 45 km.
The we had never seen before.
They had no connection with the strike.
They had heard of
women pickets ...
... and going.
The men came too.
I think feared ...
... women
not abide.
Or perhaps feared
that we did so.
But not all women
joined the pickets.
some husbands
they banned it.
I was a
them.
It's unfair, I would
to be with them.
It was I who asked
they could vote.
The union does not send
in my house.
Those Anglo motivate you
and you do get ridiculous.
- I do not see them in line.
- Yo si. I see Ruth Barnes
The woman organizer?
Is your duty to be there!
no
It's there because he wants
I also see Mrs. Kalinski
And Jenkins? his wife
is not on the picket
There are also late Anglo husbands
- What did you say?
- Late
Can I download to animate?
- How small?
- He likes to wander.
This will throw the air ...
Do you wish to see my gun, girls?
Shut up!
Would you disobey fun
an injunction?
I'm not so sure
that violate the law.
The injunctive only
mentions miners
Which side are you on?
calm down, will rush
as chickens
Here we go, before
100 women come more
Forward guys.
- Use gas?
- It will not be necessary.
Back, do not intervengáis
Han run over
my wife!
Do not give them excuses
to shoot.
You will go to jail
Back!
- Stand back
- Do not be involucréis
Do not stay still.
Do something!
Calm down.
If we do not intervene,
there will be victims.
Do not get it wrong
Besides, you already have
hands full.
Let's go!
Now they go, gather
the banners.
It protects the union
We will not move!
Continue as a tree,
firm riverside.
They do not move!
- I'm hungry.
- Me too.
- And your mother?
- It was a meeting.
Did you see how he took
gun to the sheriff?
I never want to see you there.
- Are you okay?
- Sure.
Was it an unforgettable experience, right?
- I hope it does not recur.
- I Will go tomorrow.
- Could hurt you.
- It is possible.
If you think I'm going to deal
I child, you're crazy
Wear all day
caring for them.
I will care for
born.
Tomorrow I will not
stay with them.
So tomorrow ...
... come with me to picket.
I returned the next day ...
... and every day
for one month.
Juanito remained
in the gatehouse.
If you did good day
and no disturbances ...
... pulled the cradle
Outdoor.
Estela playing with small ...
... and Luis was ...
... at school.
Ramon came every
day to observe.
Women ...
... Ramón criticized by
not stay with the children.
The sheriff left us
in peace for a while ...
... but his men insulted us.
We said terrible things.
And he began again.
They returned to using gases
harnessing the wind.
we disperse
as planned.
I put the little one safe
They failed to break
our ranks.
They could not break
We have tried everything
less fusilarlas.
Have you tried locking them?
Do you want the
stop all?
No, only the organizers ...
... which stand out and
those with many children.
Where is the boy?
Hey you! Come over.
Well, girls
You can choose ...
... among returning home
or go to jail.
No buts.
Dissolve the picket
or you will be arrested.
Okay ... What?
This is the ringleader,
Teresa Aguilar.
Under arrest.
Do you prefer your home
or dungeon?
Follow-up
displayed based discipline
There will resist
authority.
Follow-up
The Ms. Salazar, old.
Chana Diaz,
the blue dress.
Luz Morales, that.
Ms. Kalinski, Anglo.
Ruth Barnes, women
Organizer.
And Ana Alvarez, the beauty.
And former.
- Does the child?
- Is the wife of Quintero.
He does not want to come
- Leave Juanito.
- Do not worry about it.
- Also take care to Estella.
- No, the child comes to me
Solidarity Forever.
The union makes us stronger
Solidarity Forever .;
Be quiet!
I told you ten times.
We have no food.
We have beds.
Baths have not.
So, please ...
... Shut
You can not take this milk,
you feel bad.
Not infant formula.
I should bring.
Do not worry.
Will succeed.
The child can not romar that milk,
we want the formula.
- What do you want?
- Formula.
We want the formula.
"Office of the Prosecutor
the district. "
Get to commit
to leave the pickets.
Or set a high bail
for them to stay in jail.
I can not keep
of my own pocket.
Mr. Hartwell,
I wonder ...
... how long this will last.
You. Not want to negotiate ...
What do you want?
The company has
other mines.
You have to see the whole picture.
If they get their way ...
What are you doing here?
Are not you sick of me?
I come to my children.
They are in their cells.
And has taken all
their triumphs.
Not all.
For example?
Profit not silence them.
Say something of a formula.
A special compound
for the small.
It is his son.
Hush, hush!
I have given milk
for the child.
What comes
fuss?
This milk is useless.
The child needs formula.
If you sick. It will
responsible.
This is not a pharmacy.
Guilt is only yours.
In one hour you would be
with your families.
You just have to sign
express to the waiver.
We will not sign anything, stinky!
We want the formula!
Where is that guy?
Come here, Pancho.
Where is the child?
And the girl?
Kids, get out of those baskets!
Three hours to heat water
just for laundry.
I assure you ...
... although the strike succeed,
which I doubt ...
... I will not return to work
if you do not put hot water.
The union had
I have demanded before.
Who do you tell?
Charlie according Vidal, there
Two types of slavery:
The wage,
and housewife.
It is the problem of
womanhood.
What problem?
The problem of what
do about it.
What does he do?
He says they deserve
equality at work ...
... equality at home
and also ...
... gender equality.
What does it mean
"gender equality"?
You know.
Charlie is a real organizer.
Oraganiza women
and disrupts their homes.
Can I go?
no meeting of the youth section.
We can help
in many ways.
You only get you
send to a reformatory.
- All help is easy.
- You'd have to help at home.
Mom did not make me
drying dishes.
You should help
without being asked.
- How are you?
- I'm fine
How did you sleep
these four nights?
We set the fuss
we brought bunks.
I almost ran hoarse.
And Estela? And the little one?
are sleeping
¿Firmásteis waiver
continue with picket?
never
we would have done.
If you continue,
They lock you again.
They are not, fed
of us.
The locos were returning.
The group of Consuelo
morning will rest.
- We the relieve you.
- Well, let's plan it.
We need to talk.
Later, now
we have a meeting.
We must organize
the picket tomorrow.
If you want, you can attend.
Let's see.
Who is available?
Chana's husband was
to the governor.
many men
they go hunting tomorrow.
They will be about forty,
their women can not come.
We will ask you
care of children.
What we do
with his attitude?
Still have not learned
The lesson?
our DELEGATION
I could talk to him.
This I have
I solve it alone.
I know someone who works
in the Ministry of Mines.
You know that saying?
That never again
to exploit this mine.
Is it possible?
He says the mineral
is exhausted.
All this is nonsense.
That mine is rich,
I know.
But that does not matter,
ever want to negotiate.
Look at this!
Him!
- President of the company.
- Let me see.
Hear this
"Mr. Hamilton Miller
distinguished gentleman ...
... it's banker, businessman,
director of Continental ...
... and president of
Delaware Zinc Inc. "
- Let me see.
- Wait, there's more.
"Amateur sport
and experienced hunter ...
... Mr. Miller finds time
for every year ...
... a safari in Africa.
Party this month
heading to Kenya ...
... where he hopes hunt
his thirteenth lion. "
I frame it,
Ramón look.
Must see
complete picture.
So that
will hunt lions.
Did you expect out
hunting rabbits?
Guys, would like to get
some deer.
For weeks
I tasted the meat.
What do you think of disappearing
for a couple of days?
Do not ask me
I do not direct this strike.
If you want permission
to take the field ...
To ask Him
female section
I waited lifted
until midnight.
Do not expect me.
The meeting lasted
just 10 minutes.
My first night at home ...
... and you go to the brewery.
What's up?
Do not endure this
aspect of me?
Shut up!
You wanted to talk.
Speaks.
We can not continue.
I can not go on living
thus you.
True, we can not
go on ...
... or we can return
our old life.
And what is your new life?
Do you think that entitles you
to neglect your children?
- Where are you going?
- A hunting.
- When?
- At dawn.
- Only?
- Do Not.
You can not leave.
Why?
I am not required.
You are.
And especially now, with so many
men absent.
You're the captain of the squad
booking.
Yes, we reserve
for the funeral.
What funeral?
We were not doing too badly.
We have not seen scabs
three days.
Because the company knows
which can starve us
Even if it takes other
two or three months.
For them it means nothing
The mine is still closed.
It means a lot,
would do anything to reopen.
They have other mines.
Do not see the whole picture.
They are millionaires.
They can outlast us
and they know it.
Are you willing to give up?
Who speaks of surrender?
I do not humiliate
to return to the company.
You want to lose with honor,
Is that it?
For I would not lose.
I want to win.
We are not weakening.
We are stronger than ever.
They are weakened.
They wanted to destroy our
pickets and could not.
To win, you have to
do something big surprise
Like what?
I do not know.
But I feel it in the air.
It is the calm prece
the storm.
Charlie Vidal says ...
Vidal Charlie Fuck!
Do not give me now
Charlie Vidal.
He is my friend.
I need friends.
Why are you afraid
to accept me as a friend?
I do not know what you mean.
True, you do not.
Have you not learned
none of this strike?
Why do you fear I
fight by your side?
Do you still think you can have
dignity if I do not?
You speak of dignity
after what you've done?
Yes, I speak of dignity.
Employers despise you
and that's why you hate.
You say "stay on your site
Mexican dirty. "
Why do I say to myself
I fall on my site?
Do you feel better
if someone inferior to you?
Calla, say nonsense.
Who do I have to tread
to feel superior?
And what good will that do?
Do not want anyone
you feel so inferior as me.
I want to get up and fight
for all along.
Are not you shut up?
If you do not understand,
you are stupid.
You can not win
this strike without me.
You will not gain anything without me.
That would backtrack.
Do not ever try.
Never again.
I'm going to bed.
Sleep anywhere ...
... but not me.
They have only tested a while
the lives of women ...
... And run away.
Ramon is right.
I downloaded all my bitterness ...
... And he felt hurt.
You learn so
that causes suffering.
These changes come with pain.
Also for other husbands ...
... Not only for Ramon.
Are you willing to give up?
You want to lose with honor
Why is that?
For I would not lose.
I want to win.
We are not weakening.
They are weakened.
Have not you learned anything
this strike?
I can feel it in the air.
It's the calm before
the storm.
They wanted to destroy our pickets
and they could not.
To win have to
surprise and quickly.
Companions!
We should go back.
Where is Ramon?
Was hunting with the others?
Do you know where we can find?
¿Hunters?
They're deserters.
Something wrong?
Speak, Charlie.
The company has a
order of eviction.
Eviction!
Where?
Do not worry, Quintero
has gone hunting.
Vacate your home
and the rest will be easy.
Let the neighbors see it
to see if escarmientan.
Can we do something?
Back girls.
What's up?
They are evicting Quintero.
We are going there.
Let alone children
Come back here and finish the job.
Ignore
Continue with the rest of the furniture.
It's what we were expecting.
What do you say?
This means that waive
to end the picketing.
Now we can fight together.
Women back to enter it all.
Quintero, these women
obstruct justice.
Oblíguelas to behave.
I can not do anything.
You. I know, no longer obey
men.
Wants to return
to confine them?
Do you really want enclose?
Do not enter!
Look, the boys from the quarry.
And the crusher.
Any other ideas?
I do not decide policy.
I'll talk to New York.
I think you better ...
... Solve this.
Yet.
We did not know then
we had won.
But our hearts
were radiant.
Ramon said:
Thank you ...
... Colleagues.
Esperanza, thanks for your dignity.
You were right.
Together we can rise ...
... And move forward.
I knew then that we learned
something we could never take away.
Something that could bequeath
Our kids.
And they, the blood of the earth
they would inherit