Thank you.
FOUR NIGHTS OF A DREAMER
FIRST NIGHT
Leave me alone!
Don't touch me.
Don't stay there.
Quick!
What's wrong?
Give me your hand.
I'll take you home.
I'll be there, same place.
under the statue,
tomorrow, same time.
I'll have to.
I could not help it.
SECOND NIGHT
Do you know why I came?
No...
We have to be
very clever...
I've never done anything
as clever.
I don't know you. Sit down
and tell me your story.
My story?
I have no story.
I see no one,
I speak to no one.
STORY OF JACQUES
I live at 6 rue
Antoine-Dubois.
A loft on the
third floor.
How many times
I was in love!
How is that? With whom?
With no one, an ideal,
the woman in my dream.
That's stupid.
Yes. And God sends
an angel to show me...
To reconcile me
with myself.
In the park we walk
together, hand in hand,
hoping, losing hope...
The castle is strange.
She's there half the year
with her old husband,
Silent, boring,
who scares us a little.
But our love is pure
and innocent...
Is pure and innocent...
Pure and innocent...
I find her again in Venice.
Isn't it her, in this palace
of lights and music?
It is. She is dancing...
She is dancing...
She sees me. We leap onto
the balcony...
She tears her mask off
and whispers in my ear:
"Jacques, I am free!" ...
Ended are the sorrows
of the ancestral castle,
of the old garden,
of the old husband...
In the park we walk
together, hand in hand,
hoping, losing hope...
The castle is strange.
She's there half the year
with her old husband,
Silent, boring,
who scares us a little.
But our love
is pure and innocent...
I find her again in Venice.
Do you recognize me?
Yes...
The Art School.
Of course!
Craftsmanship is dead!
Chardin's brioche,
Manet's pivoines,
Van Gogh's chair and
godillots, it's over!
I am for a mature art,
open to its time,
which does not burst in
contact with Nature,
but simply is a meeting of
the painter and a concept.
Do you understand?
No thank you, really.
What's crucial is not the
object, not the painter,
but the gesture which lifts
the presence from
the object,
which is suspended in a
space which delimits it,
in fact, supports it.
Do you understand?
Not the object there,
not the painter there,
but the object and the
painter which are not there.
Their visible
disappearance
makes the canvas,
so sensually structured
as to form
a whole light source
which is specifically solid.
Do you understand?
Look at these spots!
Did you make them?
Yes. And the smaller
they are,
the larger the world
they define by suggestion.
One does not see
the spots,
one sees everything that
is not there. Perforce.
Thus, we're obliged,
we painters,
to re-think fundamentally
the problematics of art,
effecting, of necessity,
the process of its accretion.
You'll excuse me.
See you soon.
For sure?
For sure.
In the park we walk
together, hand in hand,
hoping, losing hope...
The castle is strange.
She's there half the year
with her old husband,
Silent, boring,
who scares us a little.
But our love is pure
and innocent...
I find her again in Venice.
Isn't it her, in this palace
of lights and music?
It is. She is dancing...
Is that your life?
Yes.
But yesterday, you
came straight to me.
I was happy yesterday.
I had been in the country.
You are not happy
every day?
Some days are horrible,
when it seems I cannot
go on living.
I see people in
a turmoil and a rage,
while my dream
becomes flat: a bore,
and realize that all that
was so dear to me
never existed.
There is nothing to regret.
What I have lost
is a perfect zero!
Stop it. I won't pity you;
give me a piece of advice.
STORY OF MARTHE
I live with my mother.
We barely exist on
my father's alimony.
Every year we rent out
a room next to mine.
How is he? Nice?
Pleasant?
What is that?
Books lent to us
by the boarder.
Confess that you want me
to marry.
Me, why?
Because you always
rent to a man.
Be careful. With or without
a pretext of marriage,
men know how to
manoeuvre girls.
When they've
had enought...
I know, mother, I know...
then drop them.
Are you the girl?
Let me go down.
What are you doing?
Do you wan to go
to the movies tonight?
You mustn't tell. We'll
go where you want...
Yes?
It's not nice.
It's tough!
THE BONDS OF LOVE
Who got you these seats?
Guess.
Him? ... Is he going too?
No.
Let's not go!
It's a nuisance.
He deprived himself
for us.
A film premiere is
a bore.
Not always.
We have fallen into a trap.
Let's go. Come on!
We can't!
A trap?
A trick! He wanted to
punish me...
Who did?
The boarder who got us
the seats.
Punish for what?
Not going to the movies
with him.
Do you think so?
He confessed it to
me later.
I thought we'd see him
more often.
But, mother, I never
saw him.
What, he's moving, and
you told me nothing?
I thought you knew.
Me?
Yes, I forgot.
Take me with you!
But...
You must take me with you.
Are you going?
Yes.
Far away?
To Yale, in America.
I have a fellowship.
I'm going.
I am bored here.
Let me follow you.
It's impossible!
Marthe!
Marthe, my dear.
How would we live?
I don't know.
But I swear to you,
when I return,
if I am fit to be married...
...and if you still love me...
Hey!
In a year from now...
here...
day for day... same time.
It has been a year...
He came back three days
ago, but not to me.
How do you know?
I know. It's the third day.
If I went and talked
to him?
Is it possible?
Not really. But write him
a letter.
I can't, and I don't
want to force him.
You have the right to.
He tied himself with
a promise
and left you
entirely free,
even to refuse.
How would you write
the letter?
Tell him... I don't know...
that for a year you lived
with hope...
that you were happy...
but that now the doubt
is unbearable.
Tell him:
"I don't accuse you, if
you have forgotten me."
Why the formal "vous"?
"I don't accuse you, if
you have forgotten me."
"But I know are incapable
of causing such pain
"to the one who loved you
so, and who loves you."
It's absolutely right.
Thank you, thank you.
It had been agreed that,
as soon as he'd arrive,
he'd let
friends of mine know.
I can't go there. Be kind
deliver my letter to them,
they'll forward it.
If there is an answer,
you bring it to me
tomorrow night.
But the letter,
you must write it...
It can't be done until
after tomorrow.
The letter... is there.
With the adress
for delivery.
Until tomorrow!
If it rains...
But it won't rain.
Marthe! Marthe! Marthe!
THIRD NIGHT
It's done! I delivered
your letter!
Do you know why I'm
so glad?
Why I love you so
much today?
I love you because you're
not in love with me.
You're so sweet!
When I am married,
we'll be more than
brother and sister.
I'll love you almost
as much as him.
You say that because you
are nervous and afraid,
you believe he will
not come.
If I believed that,
I would cry.
You are afraid!
We'll welcome
him together.
I want him to see how
much we love each other.
How much we love
each other!
You know what happened
to me today?
First I did what you had
asked me.
At home, I worked:
it was going well.
Then I threw myself on
the bed.
Suddenly, time stopped.
No more time!
And only one feeling,
one desire...
And then
a musical phrase,
heard long ago
and forgotten.
Soft, marvellous...
I felt it had been
waiting all my life
and that only now...
How can that be?
Eleven!
Yes.
Don't cry.
If he couldn't come and
he answers in writing,
his letter won't arrive
until tomorrow.
Tomorrow I'll go to your
friends and let you know.
You don't mind?
There are still a
thousand possibilities.
It's true. I hadn't thought
of that.
What a little girl you are!
It's because of you
that I cry.
Why isn't he you?
Not made like you?
You're more clever and
more kind than he,
but it is him I love.
Of course; I don't yet know
him completely.
How he looked at me
when I came to his room
with my bag!
You love him more
than anything.
More than yourself.
Maybe.
But why does a man always
have something to hide?
Why not just say what is
in one's heart,
as if afraid of
wasting feelings
by revealing them
too quickly.
There might be lots
of reasons.
You're not like the others
I feel that you give up
something for me.
How can I tell you?
It's silly. I don't know.
But I'd so much want
you to be happy!
What you've told me about
your dreamer is false.
You're very different from
what you pretend to be.
If one day you fall in love,
she will be happy.
I know it!
He will not come today.
It is too late already.
He will come tomorrow.
Now we are bound
together for ever.
Marthe! Marthe!
Tomorrow maybe.
Maybe.
FOURTH NIGHT
Still nothing?
He hasn't come
to see you?
He can do what he wants,
I don't give a damn!
Don't stay there. Come!
Don't tell me he'll come.
He will not.
And why? Why?
Was there anything
in my letter?
And to think I was
the one who went to him!
No, it's not possible.
We are mistaken.
He doesn't know yet. He
hasn't received the letter.
Or maybe someone spoke
badly of me.
Anyway, not
another letter.
Enough. I don't love him
anymore. I'll forget him.
You wouldn't have
behaved like that
with the one who had
come to you.
You'd think her unable
to defend herself
against her love
for you.
She is innocent.
She didn't do anything!
What's the matter?
I love you,
that's the matter.
I knew it, but I thought
it wasn't serious.
I can't help it.
It's not my fault.
Something tells me
I'm right.
Because I could never
hurt you.
I'll always be
your friend.
Sit down!
No. I'll go.
You were the first to talk
of love.
You're the guilty one.
Stay!
To say what?
Speak!
...I believed you didn't still
love him?
Even if you'd gone
on loving this man,
I'd have loved
you secretly.
What have you done
to me?
Let's go!
Listen, since he
abandoned me, forgot me,
although I still love him.
I won't cheat you...
Listen to me!
How could I have been
so blind and stupid?
Let's part.
I only torment you.
I want to leave.
One second! You can wait
one second!
Wait for what?
I love him. But it'll pass.
It must pass.
Tonight will end it...
I hate him, he doesn't give
a damn about me.
You love me.
He never did.
I love you as
you love me.
I had told you that before.
You remember?
If I love you, it's because
you are superior to him.
Let's go in!
I am not frivolous.
For a whole year
I loved him
and I never
was unfaithful.
He didn't respect it...
I don't love him
because I can only
love what I admire...
It's better than
if I'd been wrong.
and learnt later
who he really is.
Maybe my love was
only an illusion,
I was under my
mother's thumb,
and I wanted to get away
from home.
What I want to say
is that, although
I love him...
--no, although I
have loved him...
If you still can push him
out of my heart...
if you still love me...
as much as you do, today,
then...
Are you happy?
Let's go to
the Drugstore.
We must go now.
It's time.
Don't leave your loft.
But come. Be our boarder.
The room is free.
Look at the moon!
Look!
Is it you, Marthe?
Who is it?
It's him.
She sees me from afar.
She flies towards me.
The night is
luminous, marvellous,
the only such night
in a lifetime.
An enthusiastic cry!
All is forgotten:
separation, pain, tears...
Jacques, forgive me for
being wrong.
"I was blind.
"I hurt you
as I hurt myself.
I have suffered for
you a thousand deaths...
"but it's you I love."
I am astounded, elated.
What strength
makes your eyes
shine with such a flame,
lights your face
with such a smile?
Thank you for your love.
And be blessed for the
happiness you bring me.
She sees me from afar.
She flies towards me.
The night is luminous,
marvellous,
the only such night
in a lifetime.
An enthusiastic cry!
All is forgotten:
separation, pain, tears...
Jacques, forgive me for
being wrong.
"I was blind.
"I hurt you
as I hurt myself.
I have suffered for
you a thousand deaths...
"but it's you I love."
I am astounded, elated.
What strength
makes your eyes
shine with such a flame,
lights your face
with such a smile?
Thank you for your love.
And be blessed for the
happiness you bring me.
English subtitles
.:: Norgen (norgen@centrum.cz) ::.