Tomorrow you'll see your wife again.
Are you nervous?
It's been 3 years...
You know who arrived here
with the clown and his wife?
They were at Weger's then
Here, you say?
Yes. I was there. It was rather painful.
I'll tell you about it.
Poor old Frost!
That was seven years ago.
The garrison was run by the gun.
The officers were bastards.
They lay around drinking schnapps.
The troops were training hard at the beach..
That was the scenario!
Then, they saw Alma.
She still had
a queenly persona
though already a bit faded.
The chief greets you...
What is this honor worth to your chief?
Your wife?
My wife! and then?
She's bathing naked with the soldiers!
Be a man!
Have to kill her!
She needs a kick in the backside!
Load the guns!
She shouted
that we were killing her husband.
Strange, such a woman...
Nobody's paid any more,
and there's nothing to eat.
Only half of the costumes are left.
There are some
who don't have anything to do.
Your problemss are appreciated.
Rain, you can nothing about it.
Sure!
All the kids have worms.
My wagon is full of fleas.
I'll be running the menagerie!
There's the bear...edible perhaps.
If it were killed
before it dies of its own accord?
Rather kill you!
Or me... that'd be better.
Then, Albert!
How about that?
Good idea!
Afterwards, you feel stupid.
- In America...
- Ah! It's not like here!
Over there, they march through
the city in procession!
Music and elephants at the head,
everyone smiling...
to the cheers of the crowd,
a powerful voice shouts the program.
If you went by caravan
and our most beautiful costumes?
Those that were left behind?
Then, posters will be made.
Madam Ekberg'll perform,
and Anton 'll be the crier.
Not a bad idea!
I'll wear my green dress!
But no dwarf!
I'll be at the front to announce you!
Another idea! Actors from the
Sjuberg theatre are here on tour.
I'll ask them for some costumes
and this evening: The Grand Official Reception!
Followed-up by a supper of schnapps,
beefsteak, chateaubriand...
and caviar!
On the flower-covered hill, Hjalmar sang
acts of war of yesteryear...
Put on your yellow dress, quickly!
Curl your hair
and fix your make-up!
We're going visiting.
To the prefect's?
- No, to Sjuberg's.
The theatre people? Are you crazy?
Show me that!
Your ears are dirty.
You won't leave me?
What do you want to say?
If the circus is done for...
We'll know it.
You promise not to leave me?
Don't worry.
You'll see your wife.
And my kids... it's been 3 years...
I am afraid that you do not go back there.
Calm down, darling.
Can I shave?
One day we'll be successful.
You believe that?
Rich circus directors do exist!
They have a house, diamonds,
cars...
The only thing is...
they're in America.
There are still some costumes!
And umbrellas. So...!
What's up?
Nothing... why?
You seem anxious.
Me? Not at all!
It's up to me to speak to him.
You... you give him your most charming smile.
Pretty girls, that's what interests him.
Breathe deeply, so he sees your breasts.
If he wants to see your legs,
you needn't refuse.
I'll take care of you.
Just keep your mouth shut.
An innocent heart
is a woman's wealth
and will make him smother any temptation.
My dear father, your words
will bear fruit in my heart.
Madam your mother...
for Mister your father...
Mister my husband!
Who do you want?
- the director.
He's rehearsing.
We'll wait.
Who dares speak during rehearsal?
There's a gentleman and a lady...
They can go to the devil!
Here they come!
Wait! He wants to speak to you.
Some other day.
Hello, Mr. Sjuberg.
What a good weather!
I'm Albert Johansson,
owner of the Alberti circus.
and this is Anne, my wife.
Curtsy!
What can I for you?
Us... It's that...
A chair for Madam!
May I?
I', listening, Mr. Alberti.
Misfortune resulted in half...
our costumes...
being destroyed.
It occurred to me that
you could help us
by lending us
some capes and hats...
between fellow-theatricals...
And what if we catch your vermin?
Lice, the pox...
How would we tell?
I don't know this circus.
It's a serious risk!
I guarantee you...
How much will you pay me?
Eh well... I was thinking...
- How much do you want?
- Too much, I'm sure.
You insult me.
Yes...
Because you lot are tramps,
as much as us,
and because you go along with
my insults.
Your caravans are not even up
to our shabby hotels.
Your art is not Art.
The lowest here
scorns the best among you.
You only risk your lives.
We risk our pride.
I find your getup ridiculous,
and Madam would undoubtedly look better
without hers.
You don't dare laugh
at our false elegance,
our rouge, our accents.
Why not insult you?
I wouldn't...I don't understand you.
You're so forceful.
And costumes?
You'll have them.
But... how much?
Invite us this evening!
- What an honor!
- Most certainly.
Mr Blom will show you the attic.
Start the scene again!
Courage, my child!
An innocent heart...
You've made me insane!
I lost my head!
Do you want to marry me?
That old ass won't have you any more!
You divide his bed?
You whisper soft words
in his ear?
Come on! Don't make me suffer any more!
I love you!
I want you! Immediately!
I could rape you on the spot,
in front of your dopey director.
Let me go!
No, I won't let you go!
I'll do what I want.
Not that!
You shouldn't talk like that
about my husband!
Only with you, I'd beat you.
I'd rip your low resistance to shreds
like dirty paper!
Who are you going on about?
Don't play the bull.
I'm not your cow.
Deep down you have more choices to make a better deal.
What's your tariff?
I have a bit saved.
I should have started there.
You are too beautiful.
You have the air of a girl.
Do you want my opinion?
You've never fulfilled a woman!
Careful what you say!
You aren't so beautiful when you blush
If you goad me, I bite.
You'll hurt your mouth.
If I'm not beautiful,
you, you're beautiful!
Forget all I said!
Forgive me!
You must like me...
I beg you!
On your knees!
Face to the ground!
Down further! Harder!
I'll kiss you just once.
Only once.
Go away! You're turning me into a bad woman!
These costumes are fantastic!
This evening, the Alberti circus
is giving an official reception!
M. Blom is a friend!
It offered us schnapps!
You want some?
Listen, good people, and admire!
At great cost and sarifice,
the Alberti circus has come to you!
This evening, an unrivalled Gala performance!
Full of beauty, and excitement!
Not forgetting laughter!
Splendid scenes,
dazzling costumes!
Artists of world fame!
Quiet!
Don't you know this is illegal?
A little advertisement...
You have authorization?
But I believed...
The gentleman is a believer!
Everybody down! Onto the ground!
Go to the marketplace there, you are tolerated.
You'll see, species of monkey!
You want me to learn to you
to respect the law?
Down! Everyone down!
Died with the cows!
Uncouple the horses!
They will spend the night on our premises.
That will learn how to you to discuss.
On the way!
Heap of jokers!
You, you do that?
She'll not have anything to say!
And then I don't care!
You drank?
- You'll return early?
- Look at me.
You'd spend the night there!
It's 3 years since I saw my kids!
Now it's urgent!
You don't understand.
I know she's waiting for you...
waiting for your return.
You'll work in her shop.
The farm!
Don't contradict me!
You think of your retirement.
You're getting old, you're afraid.
I'll be back for the gala reception.
Stay here!
Don't go there!
I beg you!
- You're crying?
- Not at all.
- You're jealous?
- Does that astonish you?
And if you left for good?
You've had enough of the circus and me.
What would I do without you?
But I love you!
If it were true,
you wouldn't be going to her place.
I love you though.
- Liar!
- Good, good, we'll see about it!
You'll not find me here when you get back!
Where would you go?
Somewhere... you'll see.
So much the worse for you.
What do you want?
Don't you  recognize me?
No.
Wait...
What do you want?
- is Your mother there?
- Yes.
- Can I see her?
- She's having lunch.
I can await for her?
The weather is nice.
You are my dad?
Yes.
You are well?
And your brother?
He lost a tooth.
And you, you help your mother.
That's good.
How old are you?
9.
Would you like to join the circus?
No.
Here's mama.
Hello Agda.
I came to see you while passing through.
Are you hungry?
Do I look hungry?
Sounds like it.
Good, I accept!
Watch the shop.
I have only crepes.
Does that suit you?
Fine.
Is the shop doing OK?
Forsell sold up his to me.
I have the two tobacco shops in town.
You look after the other one?
Obviously!
Take off your jacket.
I'm OK as I am.
There's a button missing.
What about your shirts?
Don't you have have any newer?
Probably not.
Buy some!
I can't buy anything.
- don't shout!
- You aggravate me!
Then go away!
I can lend you some money.
Shameful!
Be civil!
It's none of your business!
Very generous of you, I don't want any.
You are too weak!
The thing is so simple.
Why refuse?
You feel strong! You are avenged!
Of what?
Don't be funny!
To have left me?
But I'm grateful!
What?
Now, I have peace.
You left, now my life belongs to me.
More than circus...
That disgusting circus
that scared me so much!
Screaming, swearing,
bickering,
vermin, filth!
Here, I'm happy...
and grateful.
Let's go into the drawing room.
You are an impressive woman.
Thank you.
- Us, things were good.
- How?
Us two,
before you had the shop.
I felt sorry for the kids.
You wanted to form them.
No, sincerely, it was hard.
- You followed me.
- I loved you.
No more?
Is there any point in talking about all that?
No, perhaps not.
My love had done nothing but grow.
But the shortly after your departure,
it had already died.
Odd.
I did not leave you.
You stayed here, me on the road.
Let's not talk about it any more.
You see everything so clearly!
For me, it's allmuddled.
You have money problems...?
What a question!
Your health.
And yours, and thank you.
Nothing changes, here.
Summer or winter, all is calm.
It is a quiet street.
The years go by, and nothing changes.
It is a ripening.
Not, it's a void.
I'm nothing but a clown
in this world of illusions.
The perfidy of a woman, her weakness,
her indifference even,
change my existence
from day in day, hour in hour.
Am I the Count
Badrincourt de Chamball?
Or I am the most miserable
of men?
Out, O dagger, from your hiding-place.
Seek the place
where your thirst will be appeased!
You are my mistress
whom I press to my heart.
The night will see our union
in this garden
where formerly, my cruel goddess
granted her favours to me.
Good-bye, cruel world!
Good-bye, my sovereign!
Your tears can
fall upon my grave.
I die.
Raise the curtain!
Everyone on stage!
The rehearsal is finished.
Quite a sad spectacle.
M. Blom is an idiot.
Thank you, he knows it.
I want to leave the circus.
Are you making fun of me?
I smile at you because you are beautiful.
You do not need to marry me,
you know.
You smell of the stable,
the bad perfume and sweat...
I'll lick you like a dog!
I'll teach you make-up.
Your mouth...
- I really smell of sweat?
- I said that as a joke.
My perfume isn't expensive.
I'll give you some. Wait...
Your hands are beautiful.
That must be expensive!
It's for you.
Nothing to do in the stable.
All here feel the same.
You put make-up on me?
What do you want with makeup?
- a present?
- Gently!
From a woman!
With its return: No more Anne!
No more rider for her ponies!
No more lady sawn into two
by a drunken magician!
Part, disappeared!
And if you get tired of me?
Then, I'll kill you.
If I don't commit suicide first!
Oh, I'm strong. Feel me!
Terrible!
I crack nuts with them!
You frighten me!
I also go full gallop,
without a saddle,
hanging on by my thighs.
You can do that?
No, I don't think so.
You're not strapping man.
You're well made, but a bit flabby.
What an affront!
I bet I'm the strongest!
You eat far too much.
Let me alone! I don't want it!
Let you go now?
I don't dare do it!
I don't want any more.
Give me the key!
How does one learn
how to dance with the bears?
Do you need hot irons?
Give me the key!
You hate me?
The key! The key!
Yes, you hate me...
and I still like you.
The key!
You'll get it afterwards...
We haven't finished playing.
This amulet is a valuable thing.
I received it from a grateful lady.
If you are good, you can have it.
By selling it,
you will be able to live for a year.
You will be able to leave the circus.
It will carry you to happiness.
You will sell it to a jeweller at face value.
Will that pay me ...how much?
Enough to live one year.
They are true pearls.
You swear to give me the key?
I swear it.
Will nobody find out?
I won't say anything to anyone.
Here, it's all I can do.
Thanks, that was kind of you.
Hello.
What do you want?
his monkey does turns for 5 öre.
5 öre, a lot of money, far too much.
Please, mama!
I'll give it to you.
You say thank you?
And now, off you go!
Tired?
This meal... and cognac...
Say, Agda...
I cannot too what say...
It is hard to express...
Then, don't say anything!
Don't get annoyed...
I'm not sure!
If, I promise you.
I want to stay with you!
I'm too old for the circus.
I want to share this peaceful life,
to see my boys grow up.
I'll help you with the shops.
I can be pleasant when it's needed.
You will not regret it.
I will not be left any more!
Do not play the beggar!
I am a beggar!
Oh, it's not because of your money!
I'll sell the tent, the costumes
and the horses which are with me.
The money will go to your business.
You talk too much.
You, you don't say a thing.
What can I say to you?
To remain.
Not, you will not remain here.
- There is someone else?
- So what does that matter?
I won't always live alone.
But nobody will force a life on me
and my peace.
Nobody, you hear me? Nobody.
- Where were you?
- Why do ask?
Does the question bother you?
You have funny voice.
I was out for a walk.
- Alone?
- And what else?
Nothing.
And you?
You know perfectly well.
I am unaware of the details.
Let's talk about you.
- You've nothing to hide?
- Less than you!
What do you want to say?
The shop windows, are forbidden?
The goldsmith's shop.
You spied on me?
No, but I saw you leaving the theatre
and to enter opposite.
So?
Why the theatre?
To see the rehearsal!
Is that a crime?
Who was there?
I don't know them.
- was Frans there?
- Perhaps well.
- You spoke to him?
- No.
- You are sure?
- Not a word!
Why did you leave very dishevelled?
A fall in the staircase.
You finished, yes?
Did you mislead me?
You are insane! You've no right!
- You're afraid?
- to be beaten, yes.
You have only to tell the truth.
Frans told me two words.
In his room?
- He took you there?
- Not! I swear you!
The truth!
Or I smash your face in!
You force me to make up things!
I want the truth
that I'll see in your eyes!
He gave me a jewel
supposedly valuable.
I showed it across the road.
- Showed!
- It was worthless.
- And for that, he had you!
- No.
You lie badly.
Don't shout. Nobody'll help you.
I didn't betray you!
I could kill you,
but that doesn't tell me anything.
If you want to lie, lie!
I lay with Frans!
He forced me.
He locked me in with a key.
I was afraid of being late.
He promised the key to me if I yielded.
I was too afraid of him to say no.
Say something!
You still lie!
I heard you speak, this morning.
You want my opinion?
You went to see him
because you're tired of the circus and me...
as I am of the circus and you.
Stop laughing!
We're well stuck in hell here!
This evening will be sensational!
Brass bands of cornets for the horny!
Trombo'es for the jumbos!
Your health, my brother! Skål!
When I really think about it,
I don't really hate anybody.
Not even the cop this morning.
Even not for Anne, who misled me.
We all make mistakes.
You, mistakes everyone,
you, me.
Me, I love people.
I cherish them.
They don't frighten me.
I won't be the idiot
of this poxy circus any more.
I'll be an honest middle-class man
with a bank account
and a faithful wife.
Anne, you'll never be
an faithful wife.
And I'll never marry you
because you misled me...
little wretch!
A little feeling, that made me feel good!
Poor Anne, poor Agda...
the poor little boys!
And you, poor devil,
and your poor wife!
It's a pity that people
are obliged to live.
It is a shame!
It is a shame to be Albert.
It is really a shame.
But I will do finally something
that is worthy of a man.
To kill by your own hand?
Do I have to say that?
I got it from Timba, the trainer.
You should shoot the bear.
It doesn't have a long time to go.
Good idea.
Don't forget to kill my wife too.
It would be pure charity.
One must kill all those who suffer.
Five or six, at least.
You, for example.
I have my poor father to look after!
I frightened you?
Not... If...
You are afraid of death?
Yes.
Me, I am not afraid.
You commit suicide, then!
It is hot here! Outside!
Open the door!
Look at this life which surrounds us!
I like it, this life!
Why did I need the truth?
To be cuckold without
the knowledge is nothing!
You are the new Othello!
I will strangle her,
I will ask him for forgiveness.
I will aask her to tell all.
All that they did.
I must be insane!
Do you understand me?
No, and I am of the insane!
Anne! So weak!
Such a woman! My child!
Why mislead me, the bitch!
I'll do the same!
You finished vomitting?
You, you are like an ice floe.
Get up!
Prepare the show!
One starts in one hour!
You, you little runt, I'll  kick out you...
if I don't commit suicide first!
Try to be funny!
Only, be decent!
It's a town.OK!
I think I'll leave them.
Happy birthday!
This act's gone on long enough!
Here, to close this evening,
A passionate Seniorita
on an Andalusian thorough-bred.
An unforgettable spectacle!
Always fresh and in top form!
Is someone back in saddle?
The plan is straightforward!
Reciprocal insults!
We will be judge and jury.
The director will crack his whip.
Snuffboxes and knives prohibited!
Go!
Kill him, Albert!
I'll get him!
Where is he?
The spectacle is finished.
Thank you for coming.
Open up!
Let me in!
Are you dead?
No!
You won't open?
Go to hell!
No, Albert! No!
Do we start dismantling?
Whatever you like.
Good gate!
Divide it between you.
Put a shoe on  Prince
before you leave.
- We're leaving?
- Obviously!
This afternoon, I had a dream.
I saw Alma, who said to me:
"You poor thing, you look tired and sad.
Don't you want to rest?"
I said yes.
"You'll be small like a foetus,
she said.
You'll sleep a long time
in my belly."
I lay down in her belly
and there, I slept
like in a cradle.
I got smaller and smaller...
as small as a seed,
and then I disappeared.
Hurry up! Come to bed!
She can't fall asleep without me.
Good night.