Thank you. There you are, guv'nor.
Hello!.
- How are you?
- And Barbara.
Barbara's going to be
a big movie star.
Good to see you.
Come on, darling.
Here we go.
Cigarettes?
I'm so glad I could come.
You're looking great, Bill.
I have to go. I'll call back.
See you soon.
Well, well, well.
- Who's this, then?
- He is a very wicked fellow.
- Wonderful show. Great fun.
- It's fun to do.
- You shone.
- I didn't have that much to do.
Didn't she?
Like a light, to the trained eye.
Dr Ward has the most
highly-trained eye in London.
Isn't that right, Stephen?
Care to dance?
She's upset, your girlfriend.
You must give me
your telephone number.
Impossible.
Nothing's impossible, not for you.
I've seen her on the telly.
She's on the telly, isn't she?
Except when she's flat on her back.
Oh, Chris, it's lovely.
it must've been ever so dear!
It's from Marshall & Snelgrove.
- Don't spend your money on me.
- Why not? I enjoy it.
Oh, it's lovely. I love yellow.
It suits you.
I don't know
what your father's going to say.
- How is he?
- He worries about you. We both do.
Well, you shouldn't.
I'm having a smashing time.
You can always come home,
you know that?
If...anything should happen.
Nothing's going to happen.
Oh, Lord!
- Who is he?
- I met him last week.
- He's a doctor.
- A doctor?
- An osteopath.
- A what?
He does people's backs.
All sorts of famous people.
Whatever next?
Christine! I was just passing.
This must be Mrs Keeler.
Delighted to meet you.
Well, very nice. Lovely setting.
Perfectly lovely. Looks a picture.
This is Dr Ward.
It's nice in the summer.
- How did you find me?
- It wasn't hard.
I'm a very determined fellow, my dear.
I'll stop at nothing, when aroused.
Stephen, it's wonderful!
You said a cottage.
It's just a little place
for weekends.
Bill lets me have it
for a pound a year.
- I let him cheat at bridge.
- Who's Bill?
Lord Astor. He's very sweet.
You'll meet him. Come.
- Are you married?
- Good heavens, no!
I was married once for 40 days,
years ago.
The worst mistake I ever made.
Come look at the gardens.
They're widely acclaimed.
You may have seen them
on the front of Country Life.
- Feels like a million miles away.
- It is.
This is all Bill's,
as far as you can see.
1 8th century.
God gave you beauty.
You're lucky. You should enjoy it.
You move like a racehorse.
You walk like a Derby winner.
Let me help you.
Introduce you to some friends of mine.
Some photographers,
film people, television people.
It's my vocation, you see. My vice.
When I see beauty like yours,
wild, untutored, elemental beauty...
...I long to liberate it.
It's my life's work, in a way.
I could do wonders with you, little baby.
I could shock the world.
I should be getting back.
Mum will be wondering.
No. Don't say anything.
I'm doing your lips.
So I tell Frank
and he has a bloody fit.
I said, "Look, I don't mind."
You got one,
you might as well have two.
it's only small,
but there's hot and cold water.
And the bathroom is a scandal.
You're out all night.
I'm in the surgery all day.
- What could be better?
- Where would I sleep?
You could always curl up with me.
- So, that's it.
- Don't be silly.
That's not what I meant.
You can if you like.
It's really up to you.
We're going to be friends.
Very good friends for a very long time.
- We must do something about that hair.
- You don't like my hair?
You'll be happy here. With me.
With my friends.
- You make it sound like a dare.
- Do l? Perhaps I do.
Never say no to a dare.
You never know what you might miss.
Wait.
Little baby.
Thank you.
Are you going to be in there forever?
Little baby!
That is wonderful.
- You don't like my eyelashes?
- I prefer your eyes.
It's wonderful.
Today's victory marks
an unprecedented third term
for the Conservatives.
Prime Minister Harold Macmillan
is understandably...
My lords, ladies and gentlemen,
you lucky people.
All together now,
you've never had it so good!
I'm sure I speak for each
and every one of you lucky people
when I call three cheers for
the Conservative Party and Macmillan.
I give you
the new Conservative government.
- Hip hip!
- Hooray!
For he's a jolly good fellow
He is indeed a man to watch.
Rising star of the Conservatives,
John Profumo is rumoured
to be the next Minister for War.
I always had a preference for what
the Americans call "heavy petting".
It's something I studied
at college in Missouri.
I adore the oh, so painfully slow
escalation of touch and caress,
the tiny nibbling kisses,
the sigh of silk on milk-white flesh.
I love the ache.
It can go on for hours and hours.
Stephen, you're such a tease.
But it's worth the wait.
When you come, it's like a sigh.
It's like a delicious drawn-out sigh.
Dr Ward is the son of a vicar.
He's a connoisseur of sin.
Rather fun, isn't it?
Clive picked it up in Copenhagen.
Where's Jennifer?
"A" deck. Popped up
to tuck the kiddies in.
They come in all shapes and sizes.
Bound to come in handy,
don't you think? For something.
Well!
All hands on deck.
- I'll just put a record on.
- Ayee aye, Captain.
Wet your lips.
You could have said something.
- Were you shocked?
- Just a bit.
- But you enjoyed yourself.
- It was funny.
That thing on the table.
I hated that Clive.
Nasty piece of work.
I'm told he killed his first wife.
It never came out, of course.
- Were you frightened?
- No, I was not.
You mustn't be. Nothing to be
afraid of. We're all flesh.
No harm in it,
so long as nobody gets hurt.
Everybody is afraid
to enjoy themselves
or they're too ashamed to admit it.
You're the doctor.
You won't leave me, little baby?
You won't run away?
- Would you run after me?
- I don't know what I'd do.
You'd find someone else.
Another racehorse.
I'd never find another Derby winner.
What's she doing?
Chris, this is Mandy. She's new.
She's in my place.
Tell her, somebody. She's in my place
- Tell her yourself.
- I'll sit where I like.
Move it.
Take all this rubbish and move.
She can't just barge in
like the Queen of bloody Sheba.
Do as she says. There's a space
next door. It's cooler.
Thank you.
Where's my top? Don't be silly.
Which one of you stole my top?
Don't worry. Nobody will notice.
Mandy! Where are you?
Hello, Mum. It's me.
I'm in London.
No, I'm all right, really.
Goodnight, Christine.
I've got a job.
I got a part in a West End show.
No, it's only a small part,
but if I do well, Mr Murray says...
He's the producer.
They're putting me up in a hotel.
Ever so smart, it is.
It's the Piccadilly Palace Hotel.
Right on Piccadilly.
Yes. Well, it's not really a theatre.
It's more like a nightclub, really.
Of course I miss you.
I miss you both.
You mustn't worry, really.
I'm a big girl now.
I've got to go.
There are people waiting for me.
I'll write to you, I promise.
All right. Bye-bye.
Fancy a drink?
Where will we go?
We could always try the bar
at the Piccadilly Palace Hotel.
Caught you!
Forty quid, Miss. Or it's the police.
- Bill, it was awful.
- What's happened?
I was so frightened.
Mandy's been caught.
We can't leave her.
She'll go to jail. She's only 1 6.
- What exactly has she done?
- She owes the landlady £40.
It's a bit steep, you know.
It is, honestly.
I don't mind giving you a lift.
I don't mind that.
You could have told me
you were doing a bunk.
It's really unfair.
I didn't want you to know.
I'm sorry. I feel awful, really.
I don't know why I do this.
I feel so ashamed.
Hmm. £40.
She'd better be worth it.
Peter!
Ex-boyfriend.
He's filthy rich.
Owns half of Notting Hill.
You like older men, don't you?
Christine.
- This is my friend, Mandy.
- Hello.
Peter Rachman.
What did he say?
He said he likes your tits.
Cigarette?
- Thank you, Peter.
- Ward.
Eugene lvanov. Peter Rachman.
- Peter disapproves of me.
- Not at all.
- He thinks I'm wicked.
- Are you wicked?
Not as wicked as Peter.
I did some sketches of Madame
Furtseva. Whatever became of her?
- Madame Furtseva?
- She's delightful.
She says that Khrushchev
eats with his fingers. Is that true?
Drinks straight from the bottle,
so she says.
It's good, this. Peter said
he'd take me to the opera.
Lucky duck.
I rather like opera. Mozart and that.
You've never been to the opera.
- How do you know?
- It's obvious.
- I've been to The Mikado.
- Where's the hairdryer?
Where are you going?
Where's Stephen?
- Where are you going?
- Dinner.
- Where?
- The 21 Club.
I know all about the 21 Club.
It's a knocking shop.
- Don't tell Stephen.
- He'll be furious.
Not if you don't tell him, he won't.
You can come if you like.
You don't have to do anything.
Not if you don't want to.
That's what Nicky says.
Nicky's on the game. She's a prostitute.
So? There's no harm in it.
- We're all flesh, you know.
- Not me.
- Gin and it.
- Champagne cocktail.
Don't look now. David Fairfax Jr.
He's even more smashing
than in the movies.
Here he comes. Wet your lips.
I'll take care of that, barman.
Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
Hi, girls.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Exciting?
You'll never guess who that was.
- Animal, vegetable or mineral?
- Fictional.
I give up. I never read.
James Bond.
What did he want? Let me guess.
A beautiful blonde
with her legs in the air?
- You think I'm joking, don't you?
- You're always joking.
Between you and me
and these four walls,
that was the voice
of British intelligence. Ml5.
Tie me down.
I think he had a spot of hay fever.
Hay fever. Good of you to come.
Not in the least. I'm always happy
to help if I can do something useful.
Your friend, lvanov, the naval chap.
- Is he a spy?
- No idea.
- What do you think?
- It crossed my mind.
You talk, discuss things,
exchange views.
I'm a curious fellow, Mr Woods.
Insatiable, in my way.
Interested in a fellow's point of view.
You know a lot of people.
A lot of young women.
Has he ever asked you a favour?
Took a copy
of Lady Chatterley's Lover.
If he should ask a favour...
...anything at all.
- I'll let you know.
- Do.
I will.
Good.
What a little baby!
What do you think, Eugene?
Come on. Come on, let's have it off.
It looks like something
my grandmother would wear.
Go on, let's have it off!
Oh, baby!
- Lovely to have you.
- It's been a cow of a week.
This Kuwait business.
The PM is chewing the carpet.
Terrible place, Kuwait. Stinks of piss.
- What's that?
- What's what?
- I heard a laugh.
- Laugh?
Get it off, girl!
Good girl!
Splendid, girl!
Hello, Bill.
Shameless hussy.
Got you.
Christine, meet John Profumo,
Minister for War.
You'll want this, my dear.
Golly!
Set.
Go.
And this is my favourite painting
of my favourite city.
That could be you and l
in the gondola.
The trees have such fine brushwork.
Do you agree?
It's lovely.
You have never made love until
you have made love in a gondola.
I remember a rowing boat once.
But never a gondola.
Hello, you two.
I can't take you home tonight.
I've got a slow puncture.
I've asked Eugene to take you.
You know what I see
when I look at this country?
- Doom, decay. A land without honour.
- It's not that bad.
You saw Profumo. He was walking
on the bottom at the shallow end.
- What kind of man is this?
- You're angry 'cause he beat you.
He cheated.
He was walking on the bottom.
He's a Cabinet minister
and he cheats at games.
Anyway, I bet you don't have
houses like Cliveden in Russia.
Cliveden is a museum. Russian
museums are open to the public.
Looks like rain.
Poor Eugene.
You look so unhappy.
Why don't you come up
and have a cup of tea?
Tea?
In Russia, we drink vodka.
Christine?
- Morning.
- Well?
- Well what?
- What happened?
- When?
- Last night.
- Last night?
- With Eugene.
You know Eugene.
He bellyached all the way back,
had a quick cup of tea and went home
to dream of Mother Russia. Coffee?
I know Eugene better than that.
I know you both.
Nothing happened, really.
I promise.
He was talking about his wife.
She's a teacher.
Look at me.
If you must know, it was awful.
Awful?
Why?
- He wept.
- He wept?
Aren't you going to answer the phone?
Hello?
- Wept?
- Practically.
Jack. Stephen Ward here.
I'm just about to go out.
Would you like to talk to Christine?
Jack Profumo.
Hello, Jack.
That would be lovely.
Hello, Jack!
Bye, Jack!
- Hello?
- Mr Woods?
Ward. Stephen Ward. I've just spent
the most enjoyable weekend.
i've been in the country
with some very interesting people.
- You've changed your hair.
- I just washed it.
- Eugene says you cheated.
- lvanov?
He says you were walking
on the bottom of the pool.
He's a liar.
What?
I've never been in a Rolls-Royce before.
I feel like the Queen.
is that all?
- That's all.
- He didn't touch you?
- He was shy.
- Shy? What's wrong with the man?
He wanted to talk. You know, chat.
I saw him at Cliveden. We all did.
He was all over you like a cheap suit.
Honestly, what did you expect?
Did you think he'd rip my knickers off
in the back of the Rolls
outside the Palace?
I expect too much, that's the trouble.
Don't worry. He'll ring again.
Do you think?
No, can't see anyone.
- Ask him.
- You ask him.
He'll never sell it to us.
He'll think we're from Scotland Yard.
Come on, Christine, be a sport.
Give her ten bob, old chap.
Good girl.
Y'all right, sister?
Looking for something?
I'm with some people. In the car.
They thought...
Well, they wondered... They thought
there might be some pot about.
Pot?
- You know.
- Yeah.
- I think she's got it.
- What's it like?
Pot? No idea.
Stiff Pimms, I suppose.
- This is Lucky.
- Hello, Lucky.
- He wants us to go to a party.
- Right now?
Right now. The Sound System.
I could think of nothing better.
The young sound of Jamaica.
I love it!
- Getting anywhere?
- Nothing yet.
Well, I don't know about you,
but I'd rather have a stiff bourbon.
Do you know what I like about you?
- My arse.
- Correct.
You're always so happy.
I don't know how you do it.
You make me happy, Jack.
I must dash.
You're always in such a rush.
I have an army to run.
You do want to be saved from
the approaching Russian hordes?
Paddington 5268.
i been looking for you, sister.
You're wonderful, marvellous.
You make me feel so...
- What are you doing?
- I'm a witch.
I'm keeping this to put a spell on you.
I'm going to be all yours, Jack.
Whenever you want me.
- I wonder for how long.
- As long as you want me.
And when I'm gone?
When I'm off being the Minister for War,
where will you be then?
I'm going to buy a present
for my mum. It's her birthday.
Here.
Buy her something from me.
It's so funny,
they were practically bumping
into each other on the stairs.
You know Mariella?
She's the best-bred harlot in town.
Her father's the
President of Czechoslovakia.
No, darling, my uncle.
But he's been dead forever.
He's the one with the big nose.
Mariella could teach you a thing or two.
She had a fling with JFK.
Stephen, can I ask you
a rude question?
Please do.
Why don't you take your socks off?
Cold feet.
Drink, madam?
- Bit warm.
- Warm, madam?
Don't you think?
Definitely a bit on the warm side.
If you say so, madam.
I do.
Thank you, madam.
- John Profumo.
- Never heard of him.
He's in the Government.
The Minister for War.
- What's he like?
- You'd like him.
- He gave me this lighter.
- Chris, it's terrific.
- It's from Asprey's.
- How do you know?
I've seen it in the catalogue.
I read all the catalogues.
- What does Stephen say?
- He thinks it's a scream.
He says it's quite a coup
that I've been out
with a Russian diplomat
and a minister for war.
Peter says he's a pimp.
"That ponce", he calls him.
Stephen's not a pimp.
He just loves the intrigue. He thinks
he's James Bond or something.
The sooner you get away from him,
the better.
You should talk to this agent I know.
You could do ads on the telly.
He wants me to get a flat. Profumo.
I hope you said yes.
I can't.
I can't leave Stephen.
He'd be lost without me.
I wish you wouldn't
smoke those things in the flat.
- It's only a roach.
- I won't ask you again.
Is he? A spy? Eugene?
Bound to be. All Russians are spies.
It's the way they're brought up.
Looks like an invitation.
- So, he is then?
- Well, I expect so.
Why not? It sounds like fun,
and there's a lot of money in it.
You'd be hopeless.
You'd be the worst spy in the world.
You can't keep your mouth shut
for five minutes.
Well, thank you.
What is it?
Someone's having a party.
- Where's your wife?
- lsle of Wight.
Fun, aren't they? Valerie bought them
in Vienna on our honeymoon.
The Queen was here
and made such a fuss of them,
I'll have to send them to the Palace.
- The Queen?
- But they're probably fakes.
Must be fun, chatting to the Queen.
What do you talk about?
Fox-hunting?
- Thanks.
- I'll phone you.
- If you like.
- Wait. Get in.
- What?
- Who is that? By the bins.
She lives here.
She owns the shop round the corner.
We can't go on like this.
You living here. Ducking and diving.
Let me find you a place of your own.
I told you, I'm happy as I am.
I can't see you
while you're living with Ward.
Don't be silly. He's not
my boyfriend. You know that.
Why don't you like him?
He can't keep his mouth shut.
He's vain and empty-headed.
That's not true.
- We must get you out of his clutches.
- He doesn't clutch.
I'm serious.
We can't go on seeing each other
while you're living with Ward.
Well, that's it, then.
Darling, please.
You must see. People talk.
People listen.
I have to be careful...
Be careful, then. Do what you like.
I'm not leaving Stephen for anyone.
I don't care
if you're the Prime Minister.
Come back!
Christine!
- Smart lighter.
- Jack gave it to me.
- Comes from...
- Asprey's. I know.
What's the matter? Why so pouty?
Nothing.
- You quarrelled?
- No.
- What about? Not about me?
He'll be back.
I don't care.
I don't like him, anyway.
- He'll phone.
- He better not.
It'd be a shame to lose him.
He could be Prime Minister one day.
You can't be serious.
He looks the part.
Youngest MP of his generation,
decorated in North Africa.
He's got a spotless reputation.
He wants me to get a flat of my own.
- I hope you said yes.
- That's what Mandy said.
What did you say?
Obviously, I made a mistake.
Never mind. It's all right.
He doesn't want to come here
any more. He doesn't trust you.
He thinks he's being followed.
- Followed?
- Watched.
- Watched?
- I don't know.
- You must ask him.
- You ask him!
You're the one
who's so bloody struck with him.
Ask him about the Queen.
You'd find that riveting.
I've had enough.
Stephen, I'm 1 8.
I want to go out dancing.
I don't want to be... I feel like...
I want to have some fun, for a change!
Christine.
Just give me my money.
Don't do that to me.
- Johnnie.
- What's the matter?
Take me home.
- Later.
- Not later. Now!
Keep it.
Don't fuck with me.
Come to me, now.
Lucky!
Why do you do this to me?
Come out of our house, man!
Fuck!
Christine!
Coffee?
It's all right, baby. You're at home, now.
It's all right, now.
Tell me about Johnnie. Was he huge?
You can tell me everything.
A chap in the Sudan had one
one and a half foot long.
I have a photo somewhere.
One and a half foot!
It was knocking against his kneecaps.
- You don't care.
- Yes, I do.
More than I can say.
Stephen.
Stephen! Stephen!
Mandy? Mandy!
- Guess what? I got it!
- Got what?
The Camay ad!
They said yes on the spot!
You don't use Camay, I do.
Don't be spoilt.
Let's go to the hairdresser's.
- I've got a headache.
- Take a pill.
You'll end up in a flat
full of black men smoking hash.
I'll have to walk home alone.
No, I promise.
I've finished with that.
- You're full of promises.
- I mean it.
Your agent lined me up
with another ad for next week.
£90 an hour. You don't even
have to take your clothes off.
You stand there and wet your lips.
Christine!
It's him.
- Who?
- Johnnie.
Christine!
- Go and look.
- You go and look.
Tell him I've gone
to the hairdresser's. Go on.
- What do you want?
- Where is she?
She's not here. She's gone.
I'm just gonna talk to her.
Just a few minutes.
- She's gone to the hairdresser's.
- Christine!
- He doesn't believe me.
- Johnnie.
- Open the door for me, now.
You must go away.
You'll get into trouble.
Open this door.
I've got a taxi waiting!
Johnnie, please!
Lucky Gordon's gonna kill me.
I got nowhere to go.
- I can't.
- Christine, please!
- Please!
Here. Take this and go away!
Bitch.
- You bitch, you see this?
- He's got a gun!
- Smashing.
- Ring the police!
Christine, you bitch, come now!
Johnnie? Listen to me.
Put the gun away.
Get me the police.
There's a man with a gun...
I'll kill you!
Dr Ward.
I just thought you should know.
There's a black man
shooting at your front door.
It's very kind of you to call.
He's gone.
Why are you laughing?
You think it's funny.
- Sorry. I can't help it.
- I can't stand it!
- There is a limit.
- I'm sorry.
There comes a point when I say,
"No, that's enough. No more."
I've said I'm sorry.
The Express was there.
The Mail. The Mirror.
They were all there
before the police were there.
I'm a doctor.
I can't have it, Christine.
I've got patients,
I've got a certain position,
I've got a reputation.
I can't have lovesick jungle bunnies
running amok on the front door
taking pot shots at the windows.
It's monstrous!
You took me down there.
You wanted to snoop round Westbourne
Grove at one in the morning.
I never wanted to go. You made me.
I'd never have met Lucky
if it wasn't for you.
I'd never have met Johnnie
or any of those people.
- It was all your idea.
- You go too far.
"Be a devil," you said.
"Never say no to a dare."
You took me to parties
and introduced me to everybody.
I'm yours, Stephen. You pull the strings.
I'm what you made me.
- I'll drop you.
- Where?
Wherever you want to go. Vicky's.
- I can't go there.
- Well, you say.
Let's go for a drive.
Please, Stephen. Take me home.
It's over, little baby.
It's over.
Good evening, Miss.
Miss Keeler? My name's Kevin,
from Sunday Pictorial.
Could we have a word?
Sit down. Cup of tea.
I know a place
not very far from here. Cup of tea?
It's all Stephen's fault. It was all his idea.
- Did he give you money?
- Who?
- Profumo. Did he pay you?
- I'm not a prostitute!
No, I'm sorry. I didn't mean it like that.
What I meant was a little gift,
a token of his affection.
He gave me this.
Did he ever write you any letters?
Maybe a couple of notes.
Notes? You kept them?
I put them away somewhere.
It was months ago.
Yeah, well, you should look for them.
It's all Stephen's fault.
- You got your gumboots on?
- Why?
This shit's deep. Run your little
West End shoot-'em-up tomorrow.
Say "West indian Held in West End
Shooting". Use a big picture.
But listen, that's not the half of it.
If what this tart has told me is true,
we are sitting on dynamite.
Here's the headline.
"The War Minister,
the Model and the Russian Spy. "
- Yeah? Great.
- I thought you'd like that.
Get her to sign something.
She must sign something.
Offer her money. Just get her signed.
All right, will do. i'll be there later.
Ted!
Thank you.
Isn't that the girl we saw
at Cliveden? The one by the pool.
Is it?
- You must remember.
- Yes.
Christine something. I'm sure it's her.
Keeler.
- Times, please.
- Times?
Well, well, well...
- lsn't that...?
- Yes, it is.
Well, that's torn it.
She must be stopped.
She's talking to everybody.
Yes. If it's a matter of money...
What Christine needs is a holiday.
Bit of sun on her back.
Somewhere quiet. Spain, Portugal.
- Just the job.
- lt'll do her good.
You don't think
she might...kick up a fuss?
Leave Christine to me. I dreamt
her up. I can make her vanish.
Who's that?
It's a cousin of mine.
I won't be a moment. Excuse me.
There was a letter. A note.
- I know.
- Silly of me.
Yes, it was rather. I'll see
if I can get it back, if you like.
There was nothing in it.
I've nothing to hide.
Come off it.
We all have something to hide.
What a rum life it would be
if we didn't.
I never touched her.
You know that.
Never laid a finger on her.
Goes without saying.
- Thanks, Ward.
- Not a bit.
What are friends for?
Stephen, all right?
Where's my cigarettes?
You want to wake up to yourself.
The papers have been ringing.
You could buy your mum a new house.
I feel sick.
You worked for it.
You deserve every penny you can get.
- There'll be trouble.
- What's to lose?
Look at me with Peter.
What have I got?
- Earrings.
You want to wake up to yourself.
What are you waiting for?
What did Profumo do for you?
He won't look after you
in your old age.
You and he might call it
a bit of fun.
I'll tell you what I call it. Theft.
- Stephen'll kill me.
- Stephen's a rat.
All he cares about is his own neck.
- That's not fair.
- He threw me out.
I paid a month's rent
and he threw me out.
You should hear
what he says about you.
"That Christine," he says.
He reckons you've ruined his life.
It's not true. He wouldn't say that.
Ask him. Ring him up.
- I'll ring him up, if you like.
- No.
He's no friend of yours.
You want to wake up to yourself.
It's lovely. Lovely stuff.
£1,000. There's a lot you can do
with a thousand smackers.
I need a break.
They're calling me back to Moscow.
Things will only get worse.
Today, it's my neck.
Tomorrow, it may be yours.
Don't worry about me.
No salt mines here.
They will be looking
for someone to take the blame.
In Russia, we say a "goose".
You mean a "goat". A scapegoat.
It'll all blow over, you'll see.
These things always do.
Next week, they'll all be talking
about something else.
Mr Profumo!
Do you know where Miss Keeler is?
Can't you do something?
Make them go away.
- What can I do?
- Do something.
Order.
The Right Honourable John Profumo,
personal statement.
With permission, Mr Speaker,
I wish to make a personal statement.
I understand that my name
has been connected
with the rumours about
the disappearance of Miss Keeler.
I last saw Miss Keeler
in December 1 961,
and I have not seen her since.
I have no idea where she is now.
Any suggestion that I was
in any way connected with
or responsible for her absence
is wholly and completely untrue.
My wife and I first met Miss Keeler
at a house party in July 1 961
at Cliveden.
I met Miss Keeler on half a dozen
occasions at Dr Ward's flat
when I called to see him
and his friends.
Miss Keeler and l
were on friendly terms.
There was no impropriety whatsoever
in my acquaintanceship
with Miss Keeler.
Hear, hear.
Order. The Estate Agent's Bill.
Second reading.
I beg to move that the bill
be now read a second time.
This bill concerns the profession
and others serving the public.
Get me Scotland Yard, please.
Thank you.
Mariella Novotny? Scotland Yard.
Lady Astor?
It is Lady Astor, isn't it?
i did the right thing.
i kept my mouth shut.
I'm in an appalling position.
I'm under investigation myself.
It's monstrous.
They've talked to all my friends.
You're hard to ignore.
You have so many friends.
It's monstrous.
You know such a wide variety
of people.
I'm on trial by hearsay.
I don't quite understand
what you're getting at.
Call off the dogs.
If the police persist in ruining
my reputation and livelihood,
badgering my friends and digging up
women I haven't seen for years,
then I have no choice
but to defend myself.
Firstly, I needn't remind you
that the police
are not under the jurisdiction
of the Conservative Party.
They do their business
as they see fit.
I am in no position to call them off.
You leave me no alternative.
Secondly, it would appear
that you are proposing
to blackmail the Government.
I must tell you
that would be most unwise.
I've always been a good friend
to Jack Profumo.
I like to think
that I am loyal to my friends
and that my friends are loyal to me.
I hope they are, Doctor.
You're going to need
all the friends you can get.
Christine!
Mum.
- Are you all right?
- Chris, look at you.
What have you gone and done now?
It's not me. It's everyone else.
Christine!
Hello? Just one moment, please.
A Dr Ward.
I'm sorry. There's nobody here
by that name. Quite sure.
- Paddington 5628.
- Stephen...
- Hello, Bill!
- Yes.
- I'm sick about this, Stephen.
- Cheer up. We'll all pull through.
- We all are.
- So long as we stick together.
- Cigarette?
- No, thank you.
How was New York?
Bronwen likes it.
The shops.
I'm glad we could meet and talk.
I've been thinking about the cottage.
- The cottage?
- Yes.
I've had a talk
to one or two of our legal chaps.
They seem to think
I should have it back off you,
with things as they are.
- Have it back?
- The cottage.
I'll fix you up for the improvements.
Bill, you're throwing me out.
You see what a spot I'm in.
I think it would be better all round.
I thought about £200
for the improvements.
You could pop the keys in the post.
Yes, of course.
You've been under a lot of strain.
I know that. I can tell.
You're worried sick. You're frightened.
You're frightened
you might go to prison.
I haven't done anything.
It was Johnnie Edge...
Piss on Johnnie Edgecombe!
You see my point?
Johnnie Edgecombe, Lucky Gordon,
they're bunnies.
The jungle's full
of bunnies like them.
Ward is a different class of animal.
Your ponce.
- He's not a ponce.
- I've known a lot of whores.
A lot of prostitutes.
I used to be at Mayfair North End.
I can smell them. Can't l, John?
- I can smell the pink Camay.
- I'm not a whore.
These clients of yours,
these gentlemen friends
that Ward introduced you to,
how much did you charge them?
Twenty quid? Thirty?
I'll bet you charged them
thirty quid at least,
a beautiful young girl like you.
- How much did you give to Ward?
- Nothing! I've told you.
I've told him. How many more times
must I say it?
I never gave Stephen money.
I chipped in for the phone bill.
I may have bought a tin of Nescafe.
We were friends, we shared.
He didn't keep me.
Tight, was he? Mean? I should think
you kept him, more like.
Why do you hate him so much?
Hate him? I don't hate him.
It's not my job to hate people.
My job's to root out the filth.
Cup of tea?
Thanks.
You can't save him. We know it all.
Profumo, lvanov, Rachman,
the man in the mask, the works.
Ward's for the drop. There's nothing
anybody can do for him.
Profumo's an MP. Astor's a lord.
Ward's just a jumped-up
little ponce from Torquay.
He's not even a proper doctor.
You don't understand.
I love Stephen.
He's the only man I've ever loved.
- Morning.
The Secretary of State for War
has written to the Prime Minister,
and the Prime Minister has asked
me to read that letter to you.
"Dear Prime Minister, you will
recollect that on March 22nd,
"following certain allegations
made in Parliament,
"i made a personal statement.
"i said that
there had been no impropriety
"in my relationship
with Christine Keeler.
"To my regret, i must admit
that this was not true.
"i cannot remain a member
of your administration
"nor the House of Commons.
"i cannot tell you
of my deep remorse
"for the embarrassment
i have caused to you,
"to my colleagues, my constituents,
"and the party i have served
for the past 25 years.
"Yours sincerely, Jack Profumo."
Sorry, that is the end
of the statement.
Of course it's a security problem.
Don't be so silly!
A secretary of state for war
can't have a woman shared with a spy,
or if he was a spy,
without a security risk.
The question is not
whether it was a security risk
but whether there was
any breach of security.
it's silly to make this
a party issue.
A scandal can arise in one party
and it can arise in another.
Let's recognise it
for what it is. A scandal.
A great party is not to be brought
down because of a squalid affair
between a woman of easy virtue
and a proved liar.
A party of great principles
and policy,
a party which believes things
about the country and the world,
that has great convictions,
does not depend upon squalid morals.
What we've got to do
is to clear up the facts,
establish the facts,
punish the guilty.
Thank you, Lord Hailsham,
Conservative Leader
of the House of Lords.
I've always been afraid of this.
Dreaded it. Nightmares.
I've always been afraid
that the day would come
when they'd throw me to the dogs.
Ever since I can remember,
since school.
There was a boy there who snored,
called Follet.
He slept in the next bed to me.
I know he suffered from asthma,
but he kept us all awake.
One night, one boy got fed up
and hit him. He didn't hit him hard.
He just slapped him across the face,
but it fractured his skull.
He had a weak skull, Follet.
He was in a coma for weeks.
You can imagine the hue and cry.
I knew who'd hit him, of course.
A few of us did.
But nobody would tell.
You just didn't do that.
So, because I was the nearest,
they picked on me.
They knew I hadn't hit him,
but they knew I knew who had.
But I didn't sneak.
You simply...
...simply didn't do that.
The house master dragged me out
in front of the whole school
and gave me a thrashing.
A few years later,
I met him at a wedding.
God knows why he was there,
and I asked him,
"Did you really think that
I was to blame?" Know what he said?
He said, "Someone had to have
a thrashing, Ward."
"lt just happened to be you."
It just happened to be me.
Well, not again. Not this time.
This time, I'll split.
This time,
I'll drag them all down with me.
I bet you don't.
Hello, Stephen.
Let's go back to the old in-and-out.
What about the man in the mask?
Did she tell you all about that?
Christine?
She told us the lot.
She missed out the best bit.
Yeah? What was that?
You tell us the best bit.
It really was rather extraordinary.
Mariella had this little glass jar
full of bees.
- Bees?
- Bees. Angry bees.
Somehow, she managed to screw
this glass jar on to his bollocks.
And you can imagine
what that was like.
She'd sprayed Chanel
on to his bollocks.
Apparently, bees can't stand Chanel.
Drives them mad.
You're for the drop, Ward.
You know that, don't you?
You're finished.
They've all dropped you. All your mates.
All your lords and ladies,
all your MPs, your royalty.
They're all rushing off to America
on urgent business.
Nobody wants to know.
You haven't got a friend in the world.
It's no use thinking your Ml5 mates
will come up the Thames
in a midget submarine.
This isn't your James Bond.
- I said, it's not your James Bond.
- No.
You stink, Ward.
You're a stinking little ponce.
And I've got 1 47 people
who say the same. 1 47.
Know how many witnesses we normally
interview on a charge of poncing?
Three or four. Five at the most.
And we generally get a result.
1 47, Ward.
That's 1 47 different interviews.
Me and John have been busy.
We've been at it round the clock.
You'd be amazed
at some of the people we've dug up.
Real filth, eh, John?
Real pox-ridden harlots.
Oh, dear. Look at that.
A prostitute is not necessarily
the kind of woman that one pictures
when one normally uses that word.
It is not necessary for her
to ply her trade on the street corner.
Prostitution, as a matter of law
and for the purposes of this case,
is where a woman offers
her body for sexual intercourse,
that is, normal sexual intercourse,
or for any acts of lewdness,
for money.
I swear that the evidence
I shall give shall be the truth,
the whole truth
and nothing but the truth.
How did you pay the rent
at Comeragh Road?
I didn't pay the rent
at Comeragh Road.
- How was it paid?
- By cheque.
- Whose cheque?
- Lord Astor's cheque.
- Had you met Lord Astor?
- Yes.
- Who introduced you to him?
- Stephen.
Did you have intercourse with him?
Not when he paid the money.
Two years later.
Were you having intercourse
with any other men at this time?
- Peter Rachman.
- Anyone else?
David Fairfax Jr.
- A boyfriend of mine.
In October 1 962, when you were
living with Ward at Wimpole Mews,
did you have sexual intercourse
with an lndian doctor?
- Yes.
- Did he give you any money?
Yes. Sometimes, he gave me £1 5,
sometimes, £25.
How much of this money
did you give Ward?
- I paid the rent.
- Apart from the rent?
Some money for the phone. About £25.
I paid for the food as well, you see.
This is not a laughing matter.
Miss Davies, is it not true
that you have been negotiating
with a number of newspapers
to sell your story?
I did, yes.
Does the value of your story not
depend on the conviction of this man?
No.
Do you realise
that because of the laws of libel,
your story will not have
the same value if he is acquitted?
I hope he is acquitted.
Are you still friendly with him?
No. But I know what it's like in jail.
Mr Burge?
You know that
before you came on the scene,
Lord Astor, an old friend
of the accused,
had lent him
substantial sums of money?
I did not know that.
Are you aware that Lord Astor
denies any impropriety
in his acquaintanceship with you?
Well, he would, wouldn't he?
Just a moment.
Mandy!
I hate this.
I don't know what to say.
Just tell 'em the truth.
It can't go wrong.
Nothing will happen to you
if you tell the truth.
What about Stephen?
What are they going to do to him?
That's his problem, isn't it?
Miss Christine Keeler.
Take the book in your right hand
and read what is on the card.
I swear that the evidence
I shall give shall be the truth,
the whole truth
and nothing but the truth.
When did you first meet
the defendant?
- When I was at Murray's Club.
- Did he take you out?
We used to go for a coffee.
- Did you go to the cottage at Cliveden?
- Yes.
Is it true that you never had sexual
intercourse with the defendant?
Yes.
Were you having intercourse
with Peter Rachman?
Yes, I was.
Were you paid anything by way
of money or presents by Rachman?
He looked after me.
Will you answer the question?
Did Rachman give you money?
Yes, he gave me money.
Did you introduce
Mandy Rice-Davies to Ward?
- Yes, I think I did.
- And to Rachman?
Yes, I did.
At Wimpole Mews, did you have
intercourse with any other men?
- Yes.
- How many?
Two or three.
- Did you meet Mr Profumo?
- Yes.
- Did you have intercourse with him?
- Yes, I did.
Did he pay you any money?
No. Once, he gave me money
for my mother.
- He gave you money?
- On one occasion, yes.
- Did you meet a man, lvanov?
- Yes.
- Did you have intercourse with him?
Did you ever
introduce girls to Dr Ward?
Yes, I did.
You say you were
highly influenced by him.
- Yes.
- What do you mean by that?
Dr Ward has
a very charming personality.
He had full control over my mind.
- And you left him from time to time?
- Yes.
- How many times, all told?
- Eight or nine.
Why did you do that?
Because I knew
he had control over me.
- You went back to him?
- Yes.
How did you come to go back?
He's a very dominating personality.
Mr Burge?
You know the prosecution
are endeavouring to prove
that Ward has been living
on the earnings of prostitution?
Yes, I do.
I would like to say that I am not
and have never been a prostitute.
While you were living with Ward
at Wimpole Mews,
is it right to say that you were
frequently hard up for money?
Yes.
And that Ward
gave you spending money?
Yes.
It is quite obvious
to anyone who has seen you,
if you wished to earn money
by selling your body,
you could have made
very large sums of money.
Yes.
But while you were living with him,
it was obvious you were not
making large sums of money.
Yes, that's right.
Was it not the case
that Dr Ward was anxious
that you should give up
smoking reefers?
No. He smokes them himself.
You have referred
to domination of the mind.
Dr Ward, you said,
had full control over your mind.
Is this not an expression
that appears in your memoirs?
Yes, it is.
That were written for you
by a journalist?
Yes.
In fact,
you've done pretty well out of this.
You sold your story,
on the most recent occasion,
to the News of the World for £23,000.
That's only for the local rights.
Not the international rights.
I had to think of my future.
Is it not the truth of the matter
that you have milked the notoriety
this sorry affair has given you
for every penny piece you can get
without a care in the world for
the only man who ever stood by you,
the man who picked you up
every time you fell,
a man whose only crime,
if crime it was, was to be your friend?
This is not fair!
Mr Burge.
I beg your pardon, My Lord.
But this...
...this is not fair.
Get back!
Make way, sir!
it's really more than i can stand,
the horror, day after day,
in the court and in the street.
it's not only fear.
it's a wish not to let them get me.
i'd rather get myself.
i do hope i haven't
let people down too much.
i tried to do my stuff.
But after Marshall's summing-up,
i've given up all hope.
Turn this way.
Once again. Just like that.
Smashing.
i'm sorry
to disappoint the vultures.
i only hope this has done the job.
The car needs oil in the gearbox,
by the way.
Be happy in it.
Seven, eight, nine,
1 1, 1 2, 1 3, 1 4, 1 5...