[Rosen]: I see a car in my rear view
mirror.
I hear footsteps behind me.
I turn around and they're gone.
Previously on "Scandal"...
She could be getting into something
possibly dangerous.
With work.
So Albatross, the mole,
the man who killed Wendy...
he's the one who leaked
their names to the terrorists.
(Olivia) You can't tell anyone
it came from me,
and you can't bring it
to the C.I.A.
An anonymous source sent them
to my office this morning.
That meeting isn't
on my schedule.
It's so late at night
and three times a week.
Who is it?
He's not cheating on me, Cy.
He's cheating on you.
The mole is not in the agency.
The C.I.A. Is clean on this.
Thank you, Osborne.
(Quinn) He can't know
we're on to him.
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
His name's Jake Ballard.
He's a naval intelligence
officer
with the Joint Chiefs of Staff.
Put him under the microscope,
see what you find.
- The more dirt, the better.
- It'd help to know why I'm doing this.
He sleeping with
your husband?
In a manner of speaking, yes.
So this source of yours...
The one who gave you
the fax transmissions
on the Kashfari hostages...
Yeah?
You think there's more
blood in that stone?
(Pouring) There might be.
Why do you ask?
I want you to look into it.
Me? Don't you have a building
in Langley that does that?
I do, but so far
all they've done
is rule themselves out
as the leak.
- You need some backup.
- I need some backup.
Someone I can trust.
Which these days...
it's a very short list.
And who knows?
If things go well,
maybe we find a place
for you here
that's a little more official.
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(Keys jangling)
(Clicks switch)
(Sets down briefcase)
(Object shattering)
(Rustling, door opens)
(Floor creaks)
(Exhales)
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
Scandal 02x17
Snake in the Garden
Original Air Date March 28, 2013
==sync, correction by dcdah==
for www.addic7ed.com
So I've been thinking...
about your family.
It's just it's been a while
since you had one
- to, you know, watch.
- Slow down.
What? The speed limit is like...
You have to keep at least
100 feet between us and them.
Slow down.
(Sighs)
Anyway, I just thought
maybe we could find you
a new family.
Look, I know they were
special, Huck,
but every family's special
in their own little way,
- don't you think?
- He's turning left.
Next street.
And don't forget to signal.
When you don't signal,
it draws attention.
(Clicks lever, signal clicking)
(Breathes sharply)
So, what do you say?
I say we've been following
Osborne for a week,
and he hasn't made a drop
the entire time,
hasn't been to
the dry cleaners even once,
and he's driving
a new route tonight,
which is very, very strange.
So, what do you see?
Osborne's on his way
to a new drop?
Mnh-mnh.
- We've been made?
- We've been made.
We haven't been made. What makes
you think we've been made?
You see that apartment
building up ahead?
- Yeah. Wait, isn't that...
- Olivia's.
- We've been made.
(Chimes)
(Rustling on TV)
(Clatters)
(Knock on door)
(Sighs)
Director Osborne.
To what do I owe...
- Who hired you?
- Excuse me?
You're having me followed.
Unless you have a crush on me,
I assume there's a reason.
What's the reason?
Director Osborne,
all due respect...
Who hired you?!
(Static blips)
Do you really think we don't
have a file on you?
The woman who's had her finger
in every pile of dirt
that gets dumped on this town? It's a
damned encyclopedia. (Phone clicks)
Yes, I'd like to report
a break-in.
I asked you a question,
and I am waiting for an answer.
Check my file.
Half my clients have
your pay grade or higher,
which means half my clients
would happily intervene
on my behalf and kick your ass
in whatever special way
their office allows,
which is why I suggest,
Director Osborne,
you leave my apartment
immediately.
This isn't over.
(Exhales)
(Knock on door)
(Sighs) - Oh...
- Are you okay?
Yeah. (Sighs)
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
- Wow.
- Yeah.
Really? Nowhere else to put him?
He's safest here.
Oh, come on!
David walked into
someone ransacking
his apartment last night.
Oh, God, is he...
Fine. Shaken but fine.
Do you think it was Osborne
looking for the flash drive?
I think Osborne sent someone
else to do his dirty work,
because last night the man was
too busy threatening me.
- So he's on to us?
- He's on to us.
- So what next?
- We lie low. We back off.
We don't take on the director
of the C.I.A.
without solid proof
he's the mole.
In the meantime,
we have a client coming in.
(Harrison sighs
and clears throat)
- Who's the client?
- You've been on an all-night stakeout.
Why don't you go home
and get some sleep?
I'm not tired.
I can work.
Wait... who's the client?
(Door opens)
I'd apologize for being late,
but, hell, I'm not that tardy, and
I ain't that sorry. (Door closes)
Darlin', if you'd do me
the kindness
and rustle ol' Hollis up
a coffee black as Texas crude
with three sugars sweet as you,
I'd be much obliged.
This is my favorite ex-wife
Debora.
All he would tell me is you're
a bunch of specialized lawyers.
Don't think for one second I'm
renegotiating the divorce contract.
You deserve every penny,
Honey.
I'm afraid we got a whole other
cat to skin.
Please, daddy.
(Crying)
Just do what he says or he
swears he's gonna kill me.
(Crying)
He wants you...
he wants you to wire
$20 million
to this routing number
and account number...
(Train passing faintly
in distance)
Or he swears you'll never
see me again.
(Sobbing)
He says...
he says if you go
to the police,
you'll never see me again.
He says if you do anything
other than what he's asking,
you'll never see me again.
(Sobbing)
Please, daddy.
I'm so scared.
I just want to come home.
Just do what he says,
or else he'll hurt me!
Help...
(Static crackling)
Only thing she forgot to do
is thank the damn academy.
What is the matter with you?
Y'all weren't buying
that little performance?
That there is nothing more
than the fruits
of the six years of film school,
acting class, scene study,
and whatever in hell else
Maybelle wanted to take
and I was a damn fool
to pay for.
I had myself a good ol' laugh
when I got it in my mail
last night.
You have been sitting on this
since last night?
Our daughter, our... baby
has been kidnapped,
and you waited 12 hours
to tell anyone?!
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking) Maybelle Doyle, 25,
youngest of Hollis'
eight children
and only daughter with his
fourth ex-wife,
Manhattan power player
Debora Clarkson.
Apple fall far from the tree?
Evil tree, rotten apple.
Imagine a pretty, young,
spoiled Hollis Doyle
on pills and coke and speed.
Darlin', our baby
is a drug addict,
a user who's trying
to bleed me dry,
and the only way left since
I cut her off without a cent
after that... what was it now?
Fourth?
No, fifth stint in rehab.
So you don't believe
your daughter was kidnapped?
- No, sir, I do not.
(Debora) - How can...
You saw that video.
She's not lying.
She's terrified.
Hollis, I advise you take
a moment to fully consider.
Ain't nothing to consider,
ponder, or cogitate on.
That child has bled me dry
her whole life.
Now she's just at it again,
on a bigger scale
with fancier dramatics.
After getting kicked out
of Georgetown for cheating,
daddy bought her a big, fancy
penthouse next door
to keep her out of trouble...
And it worked for a while.
Then Maybelle met Justin
Turner at a club.
Just as rich,
just as useless.
They started dealing,
forging checks, stealing cars.
Think Bonnie and Clyde
on pills and coke and speed.
Even it wasn't a hoax,
I got me eight kids
with five wives.
If I paid up, they'd just
come take the rest.
Pretty soon I'd be stuck
working the drive-thru
at Gettysburger
just to pay ransoms.
This is not hypothetical.
This is happening.
This is our daughter!
Miss Pope, please.
Our hands are tied if we
can't go to the authorities.
We'll do our best to get
your daughter home safely,
but I'm gonna need you
to cooperate.
Hollis, I need your full
participation in this.
Oh, don't get me wrong.
- I want y'all to get my Maybelle back.
- But?
But... it'll be a cold day
in hell
before I pay one red cent
for that gal's heinie.
- We have a men's room.
- Same pipes. What's the difference?
I really need to explain to you
why you spitting your plaque
and your food bits all over
my kitchen is a problem?
You need to explain to me
why the devil
- is suddenly our client.
- He needs help.
Why not help the murderer
you rigged an election with?
It's the Christian thing to do.
- Gladiator.
- Suit. (Breathes sharply) Yeah.
Yeah, I know.
- What the hell does that mean?
- Watch and learn,
rosen, watch and learn.
("Flash Light" by Parliament
playing)
What does this tell us?
- Looks like a warehouse.
- Please, daddy...
Plaid curtains. Could be
it was converted to residential.
- Swears he's gonna kill me.
- Ooh. The angle of that sunlight.
The window must be facing west.
♪ flash light ♪
- What else?
- That's everything in the frame.
(Typing) ...To this routing
number and account number...
- Close your eyes.
- Or he swears you'll never see me again.
(Inhales) ♪ flash light ♪
(Train passing faintly)
- Metro.
- He says...
I hear the Metro.
It only runs above ground
in a few places,
so we can narrow down
the warehouse locations
based on that, right?
Let's pull up the maps.
(Typing) ♪ da hada hada da da ♪
♪ oh, it's no use ♪
You look at the ex-boyfriend?
This sort of crime's
always the ex-boyfriend.
Thanks for the heads-up.
The boyfriend Justin's
been M.I.A. six months,
- ever since he left lockup.
- No sign he was here.
None of the prints
I found matched his.
He could have been
wearing gloves.
Plus, I mean,
look at this mess.
- Signs point to a struggle.
- Could be she's just messy.
Rich people take things
for granted.
Not shoes.
Not these shoes.
I didn't know you kept up
with fashion.
I keep up with girls
who keep up with fashion.
(Both laugh)
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
- Well?
- I don't know anything yet.
(Sighs) Oh...
He is spending his evenings
with a soldier,
a man you and I have
never met or heard of.
I'm looking into it,
but right now... (Sighs)
- There's a snake in the garden, Cy.
- I don't know anything yet.
A garden that we planted
and we cultivated
- and we harvested.
- I do not know anything yet.
Do I have to take care
of this myself?
I don't know anything yet.
Yet. Yet!
(Sighs) (Lowered voice)
I'm simply saying
I realize that you are not
in the best position
- with him right now.
(Lowered voice) - Yes, I am
currently on the outside looking in.
(Sighs)
My nose is pressed up
to the glass of life
right now, and I want
to thank you for that.
I do. Because, you know,
it reminded me never
to let my guard down,
not when something Mellie
this way comes.
But don't you worry about me.
I will once again
be his warrior.
I will once again sit at
the right hand of the father.
I'm on it, my guard is up,
and as a friend of mine
likes to say, it's handled.
He says the kids are
coming down this weekend,
which is funny, since
the Secret Service
doesn't have any travel
for the kids on their roster.
That feels like a thing
you should be taking care of.
Did you need something?
I am, um, heading to bed.
Good night.
You know,
I wanted to mention...
it might be hard for Jerry
and Karen to get away
- from boarding school this weekend.
- It'll be fine.
We put in the request
a month ago.
No, I know, just...
with classes.
Karen has a paper,
and Jerry has Lacrosse,
and they were just here
for the holidays,
and before that to see Teddy...
We are going to play tennis
all weekend.
Well, they are.
I'll coach.
Can't very well play tennis
and hold the baby
at the same time.
Tennis. That sounds...
You don't have to worry
about it.
No one expects you to join us.
Family activities aren't
your thing, I know.
(Olivia) Director Osborne.
To what do I owe...
- Who hired you?
- Excuse me?
You're having me followed.
Unless you have a crush on me,
I assume there's a reason.
What's the reason?
Director Osborne,
all due respect...
Who hired you?!
(Static blips)
(Rewinding)
(Pressing button)
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
What about Alexandria?
There's some warehouses near the
King Street stop.
Good idea.
We'll check there
after Greenbelt.
Or, just thinking
outside the box,
you could save gas and time
and maybe this girl's life
if you get the F.B.I.
to look for you.
First of all, we're so much better
than the F.B.I. at this. (Door opens)
Secondly... here's your
fourscore, extra bacon,
and your hushpuppies,
of course.
And here's the rest
of the mail...
mostly invitations
to fund raisers...
Have we ruled out Takoma Park?
It's too residential.
And it doesn't look like
there are any stops
on the Red Line that go near
a Warehouse District.
- This package came for you.
- My hands are awful busy, darlin'.
Well, that's all right.
Wouldn't be the first time
you leant your boss a hand,
right, Trixie?
This warehouse is like
a needle in a haystack.
The police have software
that can location map
everything down to a crack
in the sidewalk.
And that would take three days.
She'd be dead by then.
Have we pulled up maps...
(Trixie screams)
(Screams and gasps)
- What's going on?
- Oh, my...
- I touched it!
- Is that...
(Huck) - That's an...
- I touched it!
Ear.
This is Olivia Pope.
I'll be negotiating
on behalf of the Doyle family.
(Maybelle on speaker)
Daddy, why didn't you pay him?
You saw what he did to me!
(Olivia) You're gonna
have to talk to me, Maybelle.
Whoever has you, you tell them
you're only talking to me.
He cut off my ear!
Afraid I'll need
to see some proof.
Proof? Are you insane?
Maybelle, we're going
to need proof.
He's saying... (Panting)
He... he says...
Maybelle, what does he say?
(Sobbing) He says that you
need to pay up in 24 hours,
or else I'm going to lose
something less cosmetic!
(Sobbing)
Once the money is wired
into his account,
then he'll call and he'll
tell you where I am.
(Sobbing) Please,
daddy, please.
This time, just listen to me...
(Line clicks, dial tone)
(Beep) (Gasps and sobbing)
I'm telling y'all
that's not her ear!
- Wh-where would Maybelle get a human ear?
- Addicts are resourceful.
Hollis, you have to consider
the risk if you're wrong.
I tell you what.
Get me a D.N.A. test.
A D.N.A. test takes
48 hours minimum. We have 24.
That's y'all's problem.
I don't pony up any money
till I have proof
that's her ear.
You just killed our daughter.
Are you happy?
You just killed our baby!
Our daughter's nothing more
than a spoiled brat
who wants to get her hands
on my money!
If you think I'm gonna
give it to her,
- you're crazier than she is!
- Charming family.
- Okay.
- Seriously.
Not trying to sound like
a broken record here,
but isn't this the time
to call the police,
bring in the F.B.I.?
We're dealing with a class "A" felony.
(Laughs)
(Huck) - It's just math.
- Math?
You hire us, we negotiate
the ransom,
make an untraceable payment,
retrieve the victim
safe and sound.
We've never lost a client,
not once.
You call the cops,
you get a rescue team,
dogs, body armor, the works.
Now, you don't spend
any of your own money,
but the victim's chance
of survival drops to 50%
in a rescue scenario.
So, if I wanted to see
my loved one alive,
I wouldn't call the cops,
I'd call us.
Every time. (Hollis and
Debora arguing indistinctly)
Hey, Liv.
Let me ask you a question.
Why are we helping Doyle?
Why is the devil our client?
Because even the devil
loves his kids.
Ma'am.
(Sighs)
How can I help you today?
I'm going to need you to change
Fitz's schedule this weekend.
Oh, no need to worry,
Mrs. grant.
I have already completely
cleared it
so he can spend time
with the children.
That's lovely.
And thoughtful.
But now I need you
to unclear it.
- Ma'am?
- He's a busy man.
He runs the greatest
nation on earth.
Surely he has things
he could be doing.
Well, he always has things
he could be doing...
Put them on his schedule
this weekend.
Yes, ma'am.
(Lowered voice) Are you
keeping bad news from him
in an effort to stay
on his good side?
(Lowered voice)
I would think you have
enough problems of your own
to worry about
without meddling
in our private family affairs.
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(Phone chimes)
(Clicks and beeps)
Cyrus, I can't talk.
Why not?
Because Hollis Doyle's
daughter's been kidnapped.
Karma.
You are a bad man.
Just take a moment to feel
the karma.
Good-bye, Cyrus.
(Clicks and beeps)
(Chimes) (Sighing)
Jake, how are you?
I was just wondering
what you were up to.
I thought maybe we could
grab some lunch.
I'd love to, but I can't.
I'm in the middle
of something at work.
Maybe later, when I'm home?
Yeah, maybe later,
when you're home. (Beeps)
(Clicks)
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking) (Clatters)
(Camera shutter clicking)
(Clicks)
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(Opens drawer)
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(Beeps)
These documents came from
a flash drive that,
until very recently, I believe
was in Osborne's possession.
The level of security clearance
required to access
this information belongs
to a handful of people...
You, Secretary of Defense,
the Vice President,
and Osborne.
Why do you assume it's Osborne?
Because I saw him
threatening my source.
You're not gonna tell me
who the source is, are you?
No, sir, I'm not.
I know this is a big gamble.
But consider the damage
a guy like Osborne can do,
especially if we drag
our feet on this.
You trust this source?
They brought home
the hostages, didn't they?
You asked me to do a job.
I did it.
And I am telling you,
Grayden Osborne is your mole.
(Train whirring)
So?
- Not the kidnapper's building.
- And why?
It doesn't match the video.
The windows don't open.
Very good.
(Door opens) Hey...
How about them?
They live in an apartment.
So? Nice families
live in apartments.
Ah, no yard, no dog.
They got a little dog.
It doesn't need a yard.
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(Scoffs) That is not a dog.
You're never gonna find
the perfect family.
Perfect families don't exist.
(Musical ringtone)
Hey, new message!
And there's an attachment.
Pull it up on the TV.
(Typing)
(Gasps) Oh, God!
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(Debora gasps)
Well, it was definitely
her ear.
(Panting)
(Huck) Plaid curtains,
Western sunlight,
electrical transformer
across the street.
Just like in the video.
So where's Maybelle?
I don't know, but she was
definitely here.
Pay 'em.
Pay 'em. Pay 'em
whatever they want.
- It doesn't work like that, Hollis.
- You hear me?
Pay them son of a bitches,
get my baby back here now!
We're all set up to wire
the money
via electronic transfer
to the account number.
However...
(Turns off TV)
- We're only sending half of it.
- What?
If we give him
everything he's asking for,
you'll never see Maybelle
again.
He's already proven
he means business with the ear,
and it's a cleaner getaway
if there aren't any witnesses
- to testify against him.
- So what do we do?
To get her back?
What do we do?
Pay half up front,
then wire the rest of it
only when we see she's alive
and we can assure her safety.
I say we wire the whole
enchilada, get this over with!
With all due respect,
I'm not looking for your advice
on how to handle this.
I'm telling you
what my associates and I
think the best way forward is.
Is it risky? Yes.
Welcome to kidnapping.
Do it.
(Typing continues)
It's done.
$10 million.
(Voice breaking)
What if he doesn't call?
He will.
Just wait.
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
Is he dirty? Dirty? I don't know.
But I think I figured out
how he and the president
know each other.
What happened in Iran?
What are you talking about?
Operation Remington.
It was '91,
the end of the Gulf war.
Your plane went down
over Iranian airspace...
Mountains west of Nurabad.
You were rescued.
You've been looking into me?
Mission report is redacted,
even for my lofty level
of access.
What, are you looking for dirt
on me so you can keep your job?
Maybe it was a simple
extraction.
A handful of special forces
and a couple of black hawks,
and you were tucked
into your bunk
just a few hours later.
Or maybe... you got caught
in a village
and had to fight your way out.
Maybe it was My Lai, Iranian style.
(Sighs)
Maybe things got ugly.
- You want to stop playing games?
- I'm not playing any games.
You want to know what happened?
I'll tell you what happened.
I don't care what happened.
I don't need to know.
Point is, you did things.
(Breathing heavily)
Things you can't talk about.
Heroic things you can't
put in your memoirs
because it would endanger
our military operations,
things that might even endanger
the foundation of the Republic.
Who knows?
Well, guess what.
(Breathes sharply)
So did I.
And just because
my battleground was in Ohio
and not the Persian Gulf
doesn't make me
any less of a patriot
or make my service
any less valiant.
And just like you, I can't
talk about that service,
that operation,
because doing so
would endanger the Republic
for which we stand.
But still,
I can be proud of it.
I am proud of it,
just as I hope you
are proud
of Operation Remington.
You are equating
what you did in Defiance
with national security issues?
I'm saying the right side
and the wrong side...
(Breathing heavily)
Are determined not by me
and not by you...
but by history.
History makes the heroes
and the villains, sir.
You and I, we're just players.
(Exhales)
Sit down.
Sir?
Have a seat, Cy.
(Exhales)
I've ordered the F.B.I.
To raid Grayden Osborne's
office and home
to seize any and all
communications.
Why?
Osborne's our mole, Cy.
I received some documentation
with some highly classified
intelligence
that only he and the Secretary
of Defense would have.
(Typing)
- No call?
- No call.
(Sighs)
(Sniffling)
(Door closes, bottles clink)
Drink?
For the life of me,
I can't remember...
when it happened.
Even how.
One day she's the love
of my life,
my little sidekick,
my partner in crime.
Just like that...
she's my enemy.
Can only assume
the worst of her.
(Breathing unevenly)
I let her down.
(Voice breaking)
I let my baby down.
(Musical ringtone)
(Beeps) Maybelle, it's Olivia.
(Maybelle on speaker) He says
he doesn't have all the money!
Where's the rest of the money?!
Maybelle, tell him he'll get
the rest
upon confirmation of life.
That's non-negotiable.
Okay.
He says that's okay.
But no surprises, or...
(Sobbing)
Oh, God, please don't hurt me! Please!
Aah! Don't you touch her!
Proof of life, and we wire you
the second $10 million
on sight.
- I'll give you the location where...
- No!
He says he chooses
where we go.
Okay.
Give me the address.
(Exhales)
Maybelle, I need an address.
There's an old gas station
on Route 50
between Aurora Pike
and Stemple Ridge Road.
(Pants) He says...
He says you have 20 minutes.
This is it.
(Olivia) Here we are!
No authorities!
As promised!
Now it's your turn!
(Rattling)
Send it.
So she's there?
(Taps key) She's still alive?
Yeah. It's done.
You have the money!
Now let her go!
- He could have a gun on her.
- He could have a gun on us.
Maybelle, it's okay.
Walk towards me.
No one's gonna hurt you.
He has his money.
You're free now.
Walk towards me.
Let me go in.
Easy, Huck. Come on.
It's okay. You're free.
I can get this guy.
Not our job.
Let me take...
Huck, no! Come here, Maybelle.
(Tires screech)
If you want to, we can
still call the police.
No, no.
I'm just glad to have
my baby back.
(Monitor beeping)
I can't believe
Justin did this to me.
I can't believe he took
your money.
You're home safe now.
That's all that matters.
(Softly) Thank you.
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(Sighs)
(Phone chimes)
(Beeps)
- Cyrus.
- I'll be there in 20. I was thinking
a nice Napa red with a side
of stovetop popcorn.
- We'll go old school tonight?
- I can't.
I'm... I have plans.
Is it a date? Who is he?
You wouldn't know him.
I don't even know if I know him.
There's something...
not quite right there,
but I'm going with it,
because God knows,
when it comes to men,
my instincts haven't exactly
served me well.
So I'm jumping.
This is me jumping.
Why is everybody cheating on me?
You don't mean...
Not James, of course not.
My other marriage.
(Sighs)
But I think I'm back in.
Now I just have to get rid
of the competition.
Fitz is getting advice
from someone else?
- Yep.
- Who?
You don't know him.
Go for the jugular.
I always do.
How is he?
You have a date
with a new guy, remember?
(Exhales) Good-bye,
Cyrus.
Good-bye, Liv.
(Sighs)
(Phone beeps)
(Exhales)
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
Well, you look incredible.
A little underdressed
for a 5-star
dining experience, but...
- I tried to call you.
- I know.
I ignored the call.
I don't think
I'm going to go.
Two steps forward,
one step back.
I have a lot of work to do,
and I'm really tired,
- and I just...
- You are afraid.
Of me. Of the unknown.
Of what this is.
You seem like a really
great guy,
and maybe I'm just...
I had a relationship
with a man I thought was...
(Breathes sharply)
and I'm not over it yet.
I don't know how to judge
anymore what's good,
what's bad, if I...
someone mentioned him to me
on the phone five minutes ago,
and I...
I think about him.
I worry about him.
I wouldn't be on a date
with you. I...
H-he's in my head
all the time. (Chuckles)
Close your eyes.
Wh-what?
- Close your eyes.
- Why?
You don't know me.
I might be the worst guy
in the world.
Or I might be the best.
Whoever I am, I like you.
I like you a lot.
I like how you say "What?"
When you answer the phone.
How you always seem to be
wearing white.
How wine seems to be
a food group for you.
I like that you know
who you are,
and that you fix
everyone around you.
But you seem...
sad to me, Olivia.
I like you,
but you seem sad.
And if you let me,
maybe I can help you
not be so sad.
Because whatever
happened to you...
Whoever happened to you...
already happened, it's done.
So maybe I can help you
start fresh.
Maybe...
I'm your do-over.
(Stifled chuckle)
'Cause you deserve
a do-over.
So close your eyes.
Close... your... eyes.
(Exhales)
Are you still thinking
about him?
(Softly) No.
Good night, Olivia.
Good night, Jake.
(Door opens)
(Door closes)
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
(Rustling)
Really? We eat in here.
Huck, throw it away!
- Shh! He's working on something.
- Come here.
(Abby scoffs)
Really?!
Huck, what are you working on?
Finally got a call back
from my source at Justice.
Turns out Maybelle's
ex-boyfriend's been sitting
in a Thai prison
for the last two months.
Customs caught him trying to poop out
a shampoo bottle full of heroin.
No one knew he
was there until now?
- Rich parents kept it hush-hush.
- So he's not the kidnapper?
No, she is.
The frayed edge...
If a kidnapper
had cut off the ear,
he would have pressed on
Maybelle's scalp for leverage.
It would have been a clean cut.
But this isn't clean
because she couldn't get
the necessary leverage.
She had to saw through it.
She did this to herself.
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
Maybelle kidnapped herself.
Dulles airport.
(Beeps)
We reversed the deposits
to your father's account
and called the police.
Of course you did.
(Scoffs)
You always find a way
to screw me.
How can...
Do you realize
how worried we were?
How sick we were
when we thought s...
How do you do
that to yourself?
How do you cut yourself?
How do you hurt yourself?
I needed the money.
How could you do this to us?
We love you...
What do you want, mom?
I want you to come home.
I want to make it right.
Whatever we did to make you...
Hate us like this...
(Breathes sharply) I...
I... I want to
make it right.
You can't. It's too late.
Poor little rich girl.
Excuse me?
What was it?
He worked late,
she missed your dance recitals,
they threw you
in reform school, rehab,
they tried to buy your love
instead of earning it?
Whatever they told you
in therapy,
whatever sad cliche you're
still holding on to
after all these years,
it doesn't matter.
No one feels sorry for you,
not anymore.
You're being offered
a fresh start,
a clean slate, a do-over.
That doesn't happen.
No one gets that. Ever.
And if you don't take it,
you're not just spoiled
and selfish,
you're stupid.
You need to make
a choice, May.
Because your mom and I...
she can't go through this
again.
So you need to make a choice.
You want the money...
Or you want your family?
You're offering me $20 million?
You take the money,
you don't come back.
What's it gonna be?
Money... or family?
I...
Money.
I'll wire it to you tomorrow.
Go on.
Get!
(Sobbing)
(Door closes)
(Sobbing continues)
Hey, dad, it's me.
Lindsay. Again. Uh...
I'm not sure if you've
checked your messages.
I've left you about ten.
I just...
I wanted to say
"Happy Birthday" to you
instead of to a machine.
But you're not picking up.
Okay, well,
Happy Birthday... again.
(Beeps)
(Sighs)
Tell me this isn't happening!
(Door slams) Tell me
those men in my office,
those men in my house...
The ones putting my entire
life into boxes and bags...
It's happening.
I am not the mole, Cy.
I did not leak those documents.
No?
(Softly) No.
(Normal voice) I have spent
my entire adult life
serving this country.
I never went to any
of my son's soccer games.
I missed my daughter's
high school graduation.
I haven't been out to dinner
with my wife in years.
Why? Because I have always
chosen the Agency
above anything else.
Not because it was my job.
Because it was my duty.
I am not your mole.
I am not a traitor!
Tell me that you do not
actually believe
that I betrayed my country.
The president has decided
he no longer needs
your services.
And I serve at the pleasure
of the president.
(Sighs)
You wanted to see me?
Lauren tells me you asked her
to change my schedule
this weekend.
You had several important
meetings she was going to cancel
because of the children's visit,
and I thought it was simply best
to cancel the children's
visit and...
What is wrong with you?
Fitz, I was just
trying to be helpful.
They're our kids!
You shipped them off
to boarding school
the minute they were
old enough to go,
and now, on one of their
few free weekends,
one of my few free weekends,
you cancel on them?
These are our children!
I get it.
You don't have the mother gene.
You don't want to be
bothered to raise them
or take care of them, but I'd
think you'd at least love them.
I love them.
You're cold.
I'm not cold!
Or maybe you just did it
to hurt me, I don't know.
(Clatters)
I've been looking forward
to this visit, and you just
cancel it without even
asking me?
Are you punishing me?
(Sets bottle down)
I'm not... what about them?
Did you even think about
how this must make
Jerry and Karen feel,
how rejected they must feel
by their own mother
who cancels their visit
at the last minute?
They didn't want to come!
What?
(Sighs)
They didn't want to come, Fitz.
They have called me
every single day
since you summoned them to
the White House for this visit
begging me to cancel this trip.
Oh, please. If you think
I'm gonna buy that...
You are different.
Ever since... (Sighs)
You're different.
And they are not babies.
They are not Teddy.
They are teenagers,
and they know their father's
not their father...
I am their father!
You stink like scotch.
They can smell it
on your skin all of the time.
You are lubricated
all of the time now,
which makes you mean.
You're mean, Fitz!
Karen hates tennis,
and you know that!
You used to make it fun
and funny for her.
The last time they were here,
you yelled at her
the entire time she played.
And when you weren't
forcing her to play tennis,
you were firing
political questions at her.
And Jerry...
He is shy and he is gentle,
and you know that,
and now... (Sighs)
He's afraid of you.
It's you.
You're different.
And maybe I'm cold,
and maybe I don't have
the mother gene,
and maybe a thousand other
things that make me
such a horrible villainous
bitch in your book,
but in Jerry and Karen's book,
I'm still their mom.
I haven't changed.
It's you.
You're not their father
anymore.
And it's not because
you found out about Defiance.
That's the thing
that is so... (Sighs)
It's because you found
your precious Olivia
doesn't have the secrets
of the universe
tucked between
her magical thighs,
that she is just a person
like everybody else,
and that she is capable
of using you
just like everybody else.
And suddenly you're devastated
and you stop being
their father.
You're not their father
anymore.
And you are not Fitz anymore.
You know who you are?
You know who you've become?
You're big Jerry.
You're your father.
Everybody
in this White House...
Cyrus and me included...
tiptoe around,
trying to figure out
how to get on your good side,
but you don't have a good side!
You've turned into your father!
So... you should understand
how your children feel,
considering how much
you hated your dad.
They didn't want to come.
And so I told them
they didn't have to.
Deal with it.
(Scoffs)
Put another glass of scotch
on top of it and just...
deal with it.
(Door opens)
(Door closes)
(Turns off engine)
This is it.
This is it?
Where's the mom?
Dad's name is Dave.
Daughter's Emily.
Mother died a few years ago.
Cancer.
Uh, since then, Dave's
been running half-marathons.
Emily loves to paint.
Watercolors, mostly.
They're doing a lot better now.
This isn't what you wanted
at all.
No. No, they're not for me.
(Exhales)
(Breathes deeply)
(Plate clatters, rustling)
Hey, turn that up.
The "Times" is reporting
that C.I.A. Director
Grayden Osborne...
(Abby and Harrison) Olivia! Was
found dead earlier this evening,
the victim
of an apparent suicide.
A body found inside a vehicle
in rock creek park
has allegedly been identified
as that of Osborne.
The Central Intelligence Agency
has yet to make a statement.
(Sirens wailing,
police radio chatter)
(Camera shutter clicking)
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)
- Hi. You mind?
- Yeah.
(Sighs and rubs hands)
Chilly tonight, huh?
Supposed to drop
even more tomorrow.
Hmm.
So it's done?
It's done.
And the police believe
it's a suicide?
Hook, line, and sinker.
I have to say,
it was staged perfectly.
And now everyone thinks
that Osborne is the mole.
- Hmm.
- Or was.
Well... you stay warm now.
Yeah, you, too.
==sync, correction by dcdah==
for www.addic7ed.com
(Projector and camera shutter
clicking)