Production Funding Kim Woo-Taek
Funding management Jung Tae-Sung
Produce Lee Seung-Jae
When the woman saw that
the fruit of tree was good for food
And pleasing to the eye and also
desirable for gaining wisdom
she took some and ate it.
she has offered her husband.
With some fruit and
he ate it as well
Temptations are fun
You have no idea
what fun they can be
They always begin
like games
Why avoid them?
The Scarlet Letter
HAB Suk-gyu
LEE unjoo
SUNG Hyun-ah
UHM Ji-won
Written and Directed by
Daniel H. BYUN
Shush!
Shut up for 8 seconds
You know what Pace means?
Peace! Huh?
God, give us peace!
Dead with a smashed head?
That's no peaceful way to die
Are you in peace?
Wow, On this great day huh?
Think I'm in peace on my way
to see a smashed head?
By the same token
whoever smashed his head
wouldn't be in peace either
Fuck!
- HAN Studio...
- Captain
Found any clues?
- Good morning Captain.
- Hey
- Captain
- Huh?
- Its this way
- Okay
It's only been a few hours
The body is still stiff
A murder weapon?
Something hard like a brick
- Did you look for it?
- It's gone
- You sure?
- Sir?
- When I got..
- Take a note
Okay
'A murder weapon rarely
leaves the crime scene.'
I will find some uniforms
to search the area
Tell them to pay extra attention
to trashcans and manholes
AH N, who found the body?
His wife
Should I sit there?
Did you kill your husband?
Taking the fifth won't
do you any good
When I got back
I found him on the floor
- Where did you go?
- The market
What did you buy?
Didn't you go to the market...
to buy things?
- Some bean sprouts.
- For how much?
- 2 dollars.
- You have a lover, don't you?
Were you cheating on him?
Never
You have a criminal record
March 1999, at the mall...
I tried on a pair of shoes
and I forgot to pay
I was gonna Pa)'
But they didn't trust me
A cup of coffee?
Shit
That's enough
Come sit
I'm out of aftershave
- Already?
- Yeah
You use it for body oil, or what?
Damn, the deposit rate has
dropped again
- Here.
- Thanks
The doctor's appointment is
at 2 today, right?
- It's tomorrow.
-huh?
Wait. Come here
Hold still
Let me listen to my son
Puﬂe He was our patron.
A fine gentlemen
Any domestic problems?
Did they have issues?
They seemed fine
He was loaded...
and wasn't a womanizer
They didn't have a child.
Then again...
A little bird told me
he wasn't shooting blanks
What do you mean?
She got so many abortions
behind his back
That's what I heard
Yeon- shim?
She's so clumsy!
Get these gentlemen
some snacks
She bought bean sprouts
around 4 yesterday
- Do you remember?
- Think hard
- I can't
- She bought them from you
- Can't you remember?
- I don't remember anything
- Leave me alone.
- AHN!
- AHN, that's enough.
- Go away!
Recoil
Recoil spring
Magazine, End, slide... Check!
21 seconds
shit!
What's the point?
We hardly use it
CHO
you know what lured me
into the police academy?
This! huh?
Sig Sauer P- 226
This was what
They sell these at the marts
in America though
- Checked the insurance?
- Yes
He bought a policy recently
- Life policy?
- Yes, for half a million
- The beneficiary is his wife?
- Bingo!
This is almost too easy
It's so obvious
Take a note
'They never smash heads
like that just for money.'
These days...
they cut fingers off
for a few hundred bucks
- Aren't you writing it down?
- Sure
What about the wife?
She helped her husband
with the studio
She must be seeing someone.
Check into it
Put one of our men on her
AHN is out there
Get your ass out too!
Listen to the baby's heartbeat
Head, trunk, Feet...
This is the spine
The baby is moving a lot
Fantastic!
Looks like an alien
- Nurse?
- Yes?
Thank you very much
Congratulations, Su- hyun
Here's the prescription
- Just a second.
- Sure
- Did you see the baby on sonogram?
- Yes
When?
Come on, tell me quickly
What?
Okay
- Keep an eye on him.
- Okay
This is the list of food to avoid
during the pregnancy
You don't drink, do you?
Another abortion isn't good.
Take care of yourself
Excuse me!
Who is it?
Turn off the water, will you?
It's leaking downstairs
Did you turn it off?
Fuck!
KIM Hyuk-ju!
Shit
How much did you get?
From whom?
The lady from the studio!
She'll pay you the rest later?
You bought that?
What the fuck!
I didn't get anything!
We have pictures, punk
Bullshit!
You're writing a novel
Playing tough?
- Look here.
- Don't hit me!
You're messing with the wrong guy
Whatever!
You lay your hand on me again,
and I'm so suing you
Listen
Didn't I tell you to make it quick...
so we could eat?
Four prior convictions
A month out of the joint...
and you don't get it?
Your prints were found
at the crime scene
We have pictures of you
taking money from her
Tell us how much she promised you...
for killing her husband!
Motherfucker!
- Captain.
- What?
Any orders for me?
What orders?
This is no restaurant!
Let's give it a change
Make it two-five time
Okay?
These are all the unpicked- up ones
in the period of one month
You can tell a lot
from them
This one
This family took a trip
for the first time in a while
I think it's the youngest
taking pictures
Maybe this one
Her big brother must be on leave...
from the army
This girl is... his girlfriend?
She's not part of the family
considering she's dressed up...
while the others have shorts on
I don't watch TV
- This is more fun.
- Ms. JI Kyung- hee
Aren't you curious
how your husband died?
It was a heart attack
He appeared to have died
due to the smashed head
But there's more to it
Had the impact affected the brain...
an apnea would've resulted...
As the right part of his head
got smashed
the artery popped
which led to hemorrhage
It seems that he tried hard
to breathe
or kept spitting out words...
for help
Not only was there
blood on the floor
but his mouth to his lungs
were filled with blood too
That caused the cardiac arrest
In other words, a heart attack
That's the cause of death
You don't find it interesting?
Did you guys get along?
We were okay
You're married, you must know
Problems are often overlooked...
to keep the marriage together
How come no children?
I've call you back soon
I learned you'd had abortions.
Quiet a few times
Why?
How'd he find out?
It's me
I told you I'd call you back
I'm busy tonight
Yes
Do I have to tell you?
No, I'm not home
I've call you back later.
Bye
Who is your lover?
What do you mean?
You know KIM Hyuk-joo right?
How much did you offer?
Did you offer fair split?
What is this all about?
KIM Hyuk- soo confessed it all
What? He threaten me
Ah, there must be somebody
responsible for murder
Are you always like this?
Why did you give him the money then?
My husband promised to do so
That money was mean to be his
Then you should've told so before
I did not want to be
involved in a mess
Well, investigations will tell the truth
If I have to go to the office
I will
Will you...
be easier to confess for
your crime at the office?
You're not doing your lover...
any good by keeping quiet
Tell me
Have you ever hated your wife?
No particular reason
You'rejust sick of her
I thought it would pass
For 5 years
But it never did
I've get back to you
- Call.
- I will
Not me
The lady you talked to earlier
She must be waiting...
...for your call
- Come in
- Hello
- Bean sprouts please.
- For how much?
- 2 dollars please.
- Okay
Su- hyun
Most people put them
in boiling water
But I do it differently
Over bean sprouts...
I pour boiling water
This way they stay fresh
Here you go
Let's see
It's a killer!
Try it
- What you heard at the clinic...
- What?
I will get it
Hello?
Hey, CHO
What's going on?
I guess my cell phone is
out of battery
We'll talk tomorrow
Bye, CHO
He...
I'm sure he's innocent
He would come quite often.
Once a week
Keep 90mg
I think...
He had a crush on me
I'm sorry.
Are you okay?
Sure
I was just testing my camera
You have my apology
It's okay
Why'd you take pictures
of your feet?
His feet?
His own bare feet
The whole roll
I thought they were pretty
That was the beginning
Hands at first
Then the shoulders
Maybe...
That's how he hits on girls
You know what?
It's quite boring
sitting alone at the studio
He started keeping me company...
and I was glad
Even thankful
Thank you. Bye
Bye!
- What was it?
- Me
- Who took these?
- You told him?
No, I couldn't
I have no idea
why I'm in those pictures
That was the last roll
from him
I was gonna develop them
when my husband was gone
Kyung-hee, I love you
Did he see this too?
He got furious
What's going on here?
Who the hell is he?
Don't you know?
They're from customers
It's the same goddamnjerk!
What's wrong with you?!
Why'd he take your picture?
I don't know!
I really don't!
But he didn't believe me
When I got back from the market...
- How do I look?
- Gorgeous!
Su- hyun
Look who's here!
Ka- hee, it's been so long
hi,
hi
You were fabulous
Here. Come on
Go ahead
You haven't changed a bit
Same old you from college
Look at Su- hyun
Who would think she's married?
Once she becomes a mom,
it'll be a different story
Gosh, are you expecting?
Congratulations!
That's really great
- Congratulations.
- Thanks
One, Two, Three
What's up, CHO?
Amen!
Sorry, Father.
I have to take this call
- See you at church.
- Sure. Bye
To you who are loved
and to myself who's become
an intruder
Where are you?
Five o'clock!
- What do you say?
- What?
If a familiar song is heard
when you don't expect it
you feel exhilarated
like having an orgasm
Did I give you that tonight?
I remembered
What?
Do you remember
when we went to the opening
of this wine cafe?
But it was under construction
with nobody around
- It was then.
- What?
Hesitating whether to leave
we did it on the stairway
One side of the wall was glass
And you said...
"Having sex looking down
at people outside,"
'It feels like doing the treadmill
at the gym.'
I did?
- It was that night.
- What about it?
I'm positive
When I got home that night
my cat cried hard into the night
Until dawn...
What's your point?
I'm 4 weeks pregnant
This is like a celebration party
for me
Why follow me?
Take your precious wife home
- What's going on?
- What?
That you're here
Why? I wasn't supposed to be?
Don't forget.
Su- hyun and I are friends
- Should I come with you?
- Where?
The hospital
I can't believe
I got knocked up at this age
Silly me, huh?
Should I keep it?
What do you say?
Some babies are blessed
from the womb
And others have to fear...
What do you want me to do?
Nothing!
Keep living happily with her
as you have
I'm not a home wrecker!
If I minded sharing you
I would've left you...
when you decided to marry her
Stop it, God damn it!
You think I'm happy?
What is it you want?
The baby?
Keep it then!
What is this?!
Are you trying to screw me?
- How Long?
- Sir?
How long since the murder?!
5 days
You know it's considered unsolved
past a week's mark
Solve it within this week!
- Hey, Captain Lee.
- Sir?
- You only have 3 days.
- Okay
Get moving!
JUNG Myung- sik is in Japan?
Yes, the school confirmed...
the seminar was set long ago
He's coming back tomorrow?
Right, arriving at 10:40
Tomorrow morning...
Captain
Yeah?
Reporters are talking
We can't hold KIM Hyuk-ju forever
Release him
I don't wanna see you
Ka- hee...
Let go! I'm showering
I got you something
- Ka- hee...
- Let go!
- Ka- hee, I am...
- Let go! Let go!
I'm sorry
Hands off, you bastard!
Listen to me!
How could you tell me
to abort...
Why'd you come to the concert?
- I'm sorry.
- Let Go!
It's all my fault
I'm SORRY, okay?!
I'm sorry
I love you, Ka- hee
- I love you.
- I do too
I love you too
You're all mine!
I own you!
- I love you.
- I love you too
I love you so much
So much!
I love you.
I love you
Done. Left foot
Wish I had a son like you
To cut your toenails?
Fine, I've cut your toenails
for the rest of your life
Sleep over
You come and go
whenever you feel like
What's my place,
a rest stop along the highway?
And you don't pay me
- Money? How much do you want?
- What?
Your money is no good
What do you want then?
- Leave your heart with me.
- My heart?
Give me your hand
Here. My heart
- Ki- hoon.
- What?
You need to gain weight
Are you sure you're a cop?
You have no muscles
Don't rub it in!
- Come on in.
- No way!
I'm cold
Wait up, Ka- hee
Do you love Su- hyun?
I do
She loves me too
Are you sure?
You think you know her well?
She's not like us
nus'?
You think we're the same?
She's just different
Have you interrogated her,
Captain LEE?
Assuming she loves you...
because she fits into your life...
Isn't it too dangerous?
I'm not seeing you
cause I have issues with her
While I see you
I do my best to her
You do?
In what sense?
Fucking me hard
and keeping a beautiful family
with her?
Then...
Should I tell her?
What?
That you sound like a cat
reaching an orgasm
That you like me from behind...
Want some water?
No thanks
Smoking right after sex?
You're so bad
Su- hyun, sleeping?
My Heart
Hello?
Yes?
Captain!
Yes, we picked him up
at the airport
Yes
This picture.
You took it, didn't you?
It was found at the scene
And you left the country
And you left the country on the same day
This belongs to my son
who goes to primary school
He wrote it on the ground
and asked me to shoot it
for his girlfriend in class
And my trip was scheduled
last semester
You took pictures of JI Kyung- hee
- Who?
- The female owner of the studio!
- You took her pictures.
- No
Don't play hard ball
You took her pictures!
She asked me to
Cut the crap!
She brought us pictures you took
and told us everything
She asked me to!
She was so serious I agreed
It wasn't porn
I took nude pictures of her.
Is that a crime?
Nude?
You took nude pictures of her?
So you're telling me
JI Kyung- hee
asked you to take pictures
of her in the nude?
Look, Detective
I have a family
Honestly, it's embarrassing...
to even be here
Kyung- hee, right?
I think she had a crush on me
I'm sorry
I was testing my camera
Why didn't you tell me?
I could've been your model
Anything wrong?
You memorized my name
and phone number!
Of course you come
every week!
Why'd you take pictures
of your feet?
Of all the pictures
she showed so much interest
in my nude ones
Why'd you keep going back?
You're a man.
Put yourself in my shoes
She's pretty and mysterious
It's not a bad thing for a girl
to be aggressive
So I kind of enjoyed it
You play at a concert hall
and I sing at a basement cafe
We've turned out so differently
- Tomato juice?
- For her
Coffee is mine
Thanks
Why not drinking it?
It's pretty good.
Try it
You're seeing Ki- hoon lately?
Change the subject
I've had enough
With what?
- Ka- hee, please...
- Please what?
Tell me
You like the way you live?
Didn't you tell me?
Taking pictures frees your soul...
...like a little boy
Please
She said her husband was
out of town
and asked me to take pictures
of her in the nude
I thought it was too much
so I refused at first
Then again, I sometimes hire
a professional model
and she was volunteering
So you did?
Mind giving me one?
Don't you like the thrill?
I do
Getting there...
is more fun than being there
Don't you have that experience?
Fucking is good
but the feeling after you come...
I didn't sleep with her
- Talk to me.
- Yes Sir
It's true he was at the library.
His library card confirms it
What if he lent it to someone?
Keep digging for witnesses
And check out his wife too
- Yes Sir
- Okay
What now?
You know what?
It's quite boring
sitting alone at the studio
He started keeping me company.
And I was glad
Even thankful
That was the beginning
Hands at first
Then the shoulders
What do you think
it meant?
Maybe...
He wanted to sleep with me
Tell him about our rule
One more for the loser!
- Cheers!
Come on!
You lost! One more shot!
Sorry about that
Give it here
- Captain
- What?
Let me drink
just beer
Shut up
You don't mix liquor
But once you do,
you go all the way
Take a note!
1 . You don't mix liquor
2. Shut up and drink
Whoever finishes last
gets one more
- Okay
- Sure
Ka- hee
It's me
Finger on the pad please
Try again please
What the...
Ka- hee!
It's me! Open the door!
It isn't easy for me either
I can't even buy you
the ring you want so badly
Su- hyun got an abortion
without me knowing
So open the goddamn door!
Open it!
It's me!
- Su- hyun, I...
- Please
I want a divorce
19 seconds
Gosh, you waited...
for too long.
I'm so sorry
Let me
I'm so sorry.
Just so many customers!
What kind of style...
- Sister.
- Yes?
Where's Hyuk-ju?
Who is...
I don't know. I swear!
Where can I find him?
I really don't know
I miss him too!
Name's OH Yeon- shim.
They met at the bar
Hyuk-ju is crazy about her
Where can I find her?
I'm not sure
I heard she works at a cafe
called Purte
I met the studio owner
through my boss
He offered to buy me...
an apartment if I gave him a child
It wasn't killing a baby,
but giving life to one
But Hyuk-ju completely lost it
when I told him
I didn't get it.
I'd be carrying the baby, not him!
What the fuck.
It seems there is
nobody that she meets?
What about the photos then?
Kyung- hee I love you?
I have all the evidences
You fuck- head!
Can't you do anything right?
I was trying to be nice
on you for Yeon- sim
Shit- heads like you...
and a hoe Yeon- sim,
that bitch...
you are all
retarded assholes
I met him later that day
Watching 'Kisses' on TV,
he said out of the blue...
I smashed his fucking head
Yeah.. No...
Didn't you used to run the show
in the morning?
I see
Thanks
Estimated time of death?
The line is busy...
Should we break up?
God damn it!
Let's eat out tonight
I'm getting off early
Let me have some of yours
Oh this!
Shoes for our baby
They're pink
I think I want a girl now
I bought you a doll but...
forgot to get it out of the trunk
You'll like it
Bye
A Letter of Commendation This
commendation is for your determination...
with patriotism and commissions to...
control violence and drugs
crimes in the country
You look great in uniform
- You look good too.
- Thank you
- Congratulations, Captain.
- Thanks
- Uh...Captain?
- Yeah
Should I take one of you?
Oh, he's Detective CHO?
Hi, the real Detective CHO
Sometimes, I'm Detective CHO too
Mind taking a picture?
- Of us together.
- Sure
One, two...
Pretty good
Wanna go in there?
Motel
We need to talk
You got a commendation.
It's your day
Let's not waste it
in a dim motel room
I have something to tell you
It's my birthday
Don't say anything to ruin it
Happy Birthday
You didn't remember!
Happy Birthday to you
Happy Birthday, Dear Ka- hee
No birthday present?
- What'd you do that for?
- I don't know...
- This is fun.
- Come on, it's not
- Stay still!
- Does it hurt?
- Move your leg a bit.
- Okay now?
- A little more.
- There?
Lucky it's not so cold
It would be terrible
if it was winter
We won't die in here
like this won't we?
Don't talk like that
We are not far away
from the main road
What would people say
when they open up the trunk?
Your trousers are half open.
And my skirt is up to the waist
What is this?
Should I strip you?
Stay still
- Keep still
- It hurts
Can you move your legs?
You see anything?
Never been in here before
Hold this for me
Fuck! Its hot!
What for?
You gonna shot?
What's this?
I can't breathe
God damn it!
He stayed out last night
No, not a single word
Okay, thanks
Recoil...
If we're found dead
we'll make the news, won't we?
What would they call it?
The end of a dirty liaison?
Magazine...
No
Some might think
we chose to die together
- Slide...
- Dearest Captain...
Commits double suicide with a singer.
Ka- hee
Do me a favor
Move your hand
'Kisses' 4:05
Estimated time of death?
What about 'Kisses'!
So after killing HAN,
hyuk-joo went into the motel.
And saw 'kisses' with yeon- sim
that's 4:05!
But estimated time
of death is at 5!
We have to get out
Can we?
I am going to
We have to!
Don't wanna die like this?
Don't worry
The world will pity us
Not everyone can die
this tragically
Stop talking about dying!
Su- hyun will come through
as if nothing ever happened
Even if we die together
she'll manage to be so calm
What's wrong with you?!
Stop talking about dying!
This is nice
Ki- hoon, are you hurt?
- Let me see.
- Please leave me alone
Let me see...
I think it's morning
How nice
I finally got my wish
That I woke up with you
in the morning
Ki- hoon, are you okay?
Are you aright?
Ka- hee?
Ka- hee, are you home?
Did anybody come?
Su- hyun! What are you doing here?
Have you guys met?
She's Su- hyun.
We went to high school together
He is...
A friend of mine.
Name's LEE Ki- hoon
Are you happy with Su- hyun?
Are you happy with her?
She loves me
Does she?
I---
I love you too
Everybody that I love...
They all have rings on
As if...
As if they'd been born
with one on
Does she have the same ring...
as yours?
I have to get out of here
I have to get out of here!
She's waiting
She's waiting!
She's waiting?
Yes, she's waiting
- For whom?
- Please let me out
Didn't I tell you?
You don't know her
I---
...loved...
...my friend
When it began...
I don't remember
One thing I know is...
I initiated it
No, I loved it
It's been a happy time
Even if my life had ended then...
I wouldn't have been unhappy
When I met you
a whole new world opened
My life took a different course
but Su- hyun...
I was afraid...
that will leave me
if she get married
Yeah you choose
Su- hyun
Su- hyun is the funny one
By marrying that man.
I wanted to keep Ka- hee
Should I move to America
and raise the baby?
In fact, I've already named the baby
It's Jin-ju
Jin-ju
Tacky?
It means 'Pearl' in English
Like that...
ingle mom's girl in
'The Scarlet Letter.'
I've raise her like an angel
where nobody knows us
In the forgotten memory
The thought of you
Too painful to remember
Look how lonely I am
See how empty...
Ki- hoon, look at this
I'm bleeding
I'm bleeding from down there!
Oh God!
My baby!
Get me out of here!
M)' My Poor baby! baby!
I have to get out!
Shut the fuck up, you skank!
I'm scared
I'm so scared
I wish I could die in my sleep
Will you help me do that?
- Please kill me.
- What' s wrong?
My stomach hurts too much
I don't like the pain.
Please kill me
- Please end my pain.
- I can't
You do it.
You brought this on yourself
Leave me alone
You peed and shitted in your pants
and still wanna live?!
You fucking bastard!
You got us into this mess.
It's your fucking fault!
Please kill me.
I don't like the pain
I'm so scared
I'm scared like hell.
Please kill me
Ka- hee, don't!
I'm sorry!
It's my fault!
- I've kill my self
- No, don't kill yourself!
I've be scared alone!
- Don't cry.
- Don't die
It's okay. Don't cry
- Don't..
- No, No
Don't cry. Don't cry...
It's okay
It's all my fault
I could've met someone else
if I had wanted to
I'm sorry
But I couldn't
Eating something delicious,
I thought of you and cried
Waking up at night,
I missed you like crazy
'Please let me stay with him
for the rest of my life.'
I prayed every day and night
I'm sorry, Ka- hee
- No.
- I'm sorry
It's okay. Don't worry
I don't wanna get any lower
No! No, Ka- hee!
I couldn't be happier.
So please do it for me
It's okay
- It's okay.
- No!
That punk...
Please... Please let me live
Captain?
Captain!
CHO, get over here quick!
It's me AHN
Hurry up, CHO!
Captain!
Hang it there!
Get clothes for him!
I'm sorry
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry
It's my fault
- Are you okay?
- It's all my fault
Captain!
Captain! Captain!
AHN!
Come on, Captain!
Captain, stop it!
Let Go!
The gun! Get the gun!
Take the gun from him!
Shit.
Captain!
Two days...
I had spent two more days
with Ka- hee
The smell of her blood...
In the mean time
I told the police
she had killed herself
Nightmares haunt you forever
When do you wanna move by?
The faster, the better
It might take a while
to find a buyer
with the economy so sluggish
- I'm counting on you.
- Sure I've give you a call
- Okay. Bye.
- Bye
I'm selling the studio
I can't run it alone
I've left the force
I can't believe
I put away the wrong guy
Then again, he's been injail.
He'll do just fine
Sorry I brought it up.
It's all over
Is this called
'Our Lady of Grace'?
Different names
for different postures, right?
Tell me
What can I do?
Kyung-hee, I love you
You said it wasn't for me
I checked with the school
his son goes to
No girl named Kyung- hee
in his class
It doesn't matter now
JUNG Myung- sik...
Did you love him?
If I loved him...
If I loved him, I'm forgiven?