Subtitles provided by MBC
I wish I were dead.
Sungnyang.
I wish I had died
on the Isle of Daechong.
Why are you here?
To speak with Your Majesty.
To laugh at me?
To say I brought it on myself?
To tell me this is what I get
for betraying you?
Go ahead. Laugh.
Just like in Koryo.
I'm a fool,
I'm worthless, say it!
Don't get your hopes up.
I will do nothing for you.
For you... nothing.
My Liege.
My Liege, you're needed
at the inquisitor's office.
They're planning the examination.
Take her.
What is this?
Answer me. Unhand me.
My lady, my lady.
Episode 13
You don't look well.
Should you be up and about?
You're worried about me?
Thank you.
She's not
an easy woman to break.
Just wait.
After the examination...
she'll be a nun,
shaved head and all.
His Royal Majesty.
Why is she
being examined here?
A fake pregnancy
cannot be investigated in private.
We'll learn who put her up to it...
even if it means
skinning her alive.
Doctor, examine her.
Report. Is she pregnant?
M-my lord...
Spit it out.
You other doctors,
examine her.
She is with child.
The slippery pulse,
without question.
Explain.
It can't be.
She had the powder
and the tonic both.
What? Remove the licorice
from her tonic?
Her ladyship
is urinating far too much.
It may be from laurel powder.
Laurel?
Then Her Majesty's purpose
in ordering the tonic...
To cause a miscarriage.
My lady!
Well?
The child is well.
Fortunately Yonhwa only slipped her
a small amount of powder.
Go tell them
she'll agree to the examination.
Not yet.
Not yet?
This is our chance to have
the Empress fall in her own trap.
You...?
This fight will never end
until one or the other falls.
We have to end it here.
Please don't.
Don't?
Her clothes
were soaked through with sweat.
I will check
the pulse on her wrist.
- Do so.
- Yes, Your Majesty.
What is it?
I can't find the slippery pulse.
Mother.
Congratulations
on the forthcoming child.
Congratulations are not enough.
My Liege, the royal house
has been held up to ridicule.
Her Majesty must be held accountable
for spreading such malicious gossip.
First I have a question for her.
Why were you so certain
the pregnancy was faked?
Ah, well...
Her crime is clear.
She foolishly listened to gossip.
And so brought shame
on the imperial house.
She must answer for that.
How will she do that exactly?
Groveling for mercy should do it.
Father.
Groveling isn't nearly enough.
We must make
an example of the instigator...
Your Majesty.
The traditional groveling
is my only offer.
Surely you don't want her exiled?
Or do you?
Enough.
What is this?
You can fool others but not me.
You're behind all this.
I'll have you...!
You know what this is?
What?
My written promise
to send you from the palace.
Your seal, if you please.
Wha...?
The letter is enough.
How dare you?
It's fine.
I'll seal anything if it means
getting rid of Lady Pak.
Sungnyang, you...
You wanted me dead?
Fine. Let's see
which of us dies first.
I'll scream.
You don't want
Her Majesty's treason made public.
Little fool.
You would make us enemies
to avenge your king?
This is not about the king.
What then?
You killed my mother.
She died by your arrow.
If you want to be rid of me...
send me out of the palace.
I'd be glad
to never see you again.
I can't...
I can't really...
be falling for her?
Your Majesty, it is time.
- Your Majesty.
No tears.
Your Majesty.
I am the Yuan Empress.
I can take the jeers of others
behind my back.
But I will not have my retinue
pity me in front of me.
Your Majesty.
Lead the way.
I will call on the Emperor.
My Liege, the Empress is here.
My Liege, I am to blame
for all that happened.
Forgive me.
My Liege!
My Liege,
forgive your unworthy Empress.
It will never happen again.
Have mercy, My Liege.
I can't take
much more of this.
I'm taking her inside.
- No.
- Father.
Leave her.
Sometimes you must lose
an arm to save the head.
She must observe custom.
It must be done.
Tell her it's enough.
No, My Liege.
It's raining.
If she should fall ill...
First make Lady Pak
an imperial consort.
Mother, we pushed El Temur
as far as we can.
Influence ages.
Just as people do.
Influence cracks with age.
Make her a consort
and if she bears a son...
the court will flock to our side.
Influence is fickle.
It favors the young.
It is the nature of power.
Do not expect me to cry,
My Liege.
I will not cry...
until I have paid out
those who did this to me...
a thousand times.
I will not...will not...
- Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
- Wake up, please.
Majesty!
- Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
Well? Take her inside.
Lady Pak, hear and obey.
Lady Pak is an honorable woman,
an example to the Inner Court.
- Your Majesty.
- She bears the Emperor's child...
...and so the mandate of heaven.
I, the Emperor,
make her a consort of the fifth rank.
Hear and obey.
At your service, My Liege.
Tanasiri?
She fainted.
Lady Pak is an imperial consort.
I'm sorry.
This is all my fault.
Moron!
Your weakness disgusts me.
Have you forgotten
you are the eldest son of our clan?
Never show weakness.
Not even to me.
Understood?
Understood, father.
Why are you here?
General Talahai
sent me with a message.
Report. How goes the war?
I regret to report...
A total loss.
What? Total...?
Talahai alone survived.
Bayan and Wang Yu
were killed.
Why is it so quiet?
Our attack must have failed.
Talahai wouldn't
leave us here otherwise.
Talahai may not
have led the attack last night.
Not Talahai?
Which begs the question
of who it really was.
Well now.
Look at you.
Well, Yom the... Scum.
Long time.
You like my new hairdo?
Wang Yu's 'dead' men.
What did I tell you?
Don't trust them, I said.
Where's Wang Yu?
Why? Does baby miss him?
Open the door. Now.
'Open the gate. Now.'
Have it your way.
Begin!
They mean to kill us.
General...
Where are you taking us?
If we're to be killed...
What's all this then?
My men want you dead.
Proof that those
with whom we served...
are worse than any enemy.
Batolu was after the horses,
not the men.
A fact you well knew.
Did you plan this all along?
You used us as bait.
I merely did the same to you.
This is mutiny. Treason.
Have you already forgotten
who showed me the way?
What?
Survive?
Dream on.
It's impossible
to kill all the Turks.
And for either of us,
that is the
only way out of here.
Our real enemy wasn't Batolu.
It was him.
Enough chatter.
Kill us.
General.
Give them horses.
We ride for the Capitol.
There is no reason to spare us.
Why are you doing it?
In my place, you would kill us.
But the men
of Koryo are not Mongols.
And I am not you.
Satisfied?
And Batolu?
The body.
Why are you helping me?
The only reason
we're fighting is the Mongols.
The enemy
of my enemy is my friend.
Friend, you say?
Yes. Friend.
The present doesn't matter.
The future does.
For us there is no future.
Nor for Koryo.
Since we have no future,
why not build one together?
The Yuan control the seas.
The only thing they
do not control is the Silk Road.
We are in this together.
The Silk Road will give
us breathing space.
I wanted to state my case.
I don't expect an answer.
My name is Yon Feisu.
Mine is Wang Yu.
Wang Yu.
We will meet again soon.
Chunsim, Onnyon,
the imperial kitchen is a disgrace.
Once more
and we'll dock your pay.
Hongdan, you're doing well.
Are you always on the rag?
Sir?
Why else would you
be scowling all the time?
Of all our rules, pleasing those
we serve is the most important.
Nyang, take off your uniform.
And put this on.
This...
You serve in the palace now.
Nyang, congratulations.
I'm so jealous.
Good for you.
Congratulations.
Your new quarters.
Your serve in the palace now.
Your behavior and demeanor
must reflect that fact.
What about Sungnyang?
Sir, your orders.
Never show weakness.
Not even to me.
Understood?
Kill her.
Yes, sir.
For my father.
For my house.
I won't
be sorry to see you dead.
Sire, I can
leave the palace now.
Wherever you are,
I will find you.
Nyang.
Nyang?
Still awake?
What is it?
It's late.
The head eunuch wants you.
What for?
How should I know?
He said hurry, so hurry.
Nyang.
My lord.
Come with me.
The head eunuch wants me.
As does the Emperor.
Did you find Her Majesty's letter?
It was not in her quarters.
Search her.
Give it back.
Anything but that.
My Liege.
No.
My Liege! No!
My Liege!
What? She was
taken to the Emperor?
Kill me, sir.
And your man?
The one you ordered to kill her?
You need not worry, sir.
Wake him.
No...
He killed himself
by swallowing his own tongue.
Killed himself...?
Get him out of here.
I won't have this.
Start Sungnyang
in the imperial palace tomorrow.
My Liege.
I've had enough
of my so-called Empress.
I'm going to her chambers.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty,
the Emperor is on his way.
Lie down.
You still have a fever.
My mirror.
Mirror?
The doctor said you
should rest till the fever subsides.
The Emperor
can't see me like this.
Make-up and robes.
Go.
My Liege.
How is she?
Waiting inside.
Welcome, My Liege.
Please.
Why did you do it?
It was beneath you as Empress.
So why?
You really need to ask?
I'm asking aren't I?
No. Let me ask you this.
How could you treat me this way?
What way?
I'm always alone.
There hasn't been a day
since I came here...
that I wasn't lonely.
You made me this way.
You see?
So you're still not sorry.
Sorry?
Look, you ran to me,
did you not?
You're here talking to me,
looking in my eyes.
I have prayed for this day.
Why would I be sorry?
Empress!
But this is not
quite what I prayed for.
Without rancor.
A soft look.
A kind word, that's all.
I resent my father
for sending me here.
And I resent you.
You are to attend the Emperor.
Do as you're told.
Always be within
three paces of his presence.
Well, answer.
I understand.
My Liege, Nyang.
Enter.
Come closer.
Closer.
There.
I'm going to draw you.
No blinking,
no sneezing, no talking.
- My Liege...
- I said don't move.
Why didn't you find me
when you came here?
Why hide that you're a woman?
Did you hate me so much?
Were you scared
I'd see you as a woman?
That I would be attracted to you?
Send me from the palace.
- My Liege.
- No talking.
The moon over
Egret Island shines all day
To speed travelers on their way
The wind blows,
the ships set sail
I long to share
one last cup of wine
But to no avail
That's sad.
But then,
parting is always sad.
Let me leave the palace.
Again? That again?
I did everything you asked
on Daechong Island.
Please do this for me.
Why are you so eager to leave?
To find my King.
You still serve him, even here?
Listen to me.
You're here now, with me.
He isn't your lord. I am.
My body may be here.
But I have only one lord.
Everything changes in life.
Your circumstances
have changed and so as your lord.
A chick imprints on its mother
when it breaks out of its shell.
It never changes after that.
He is my lord first,
last and always.
Enough! No more.
I don't want to hear any more.
- My Liege.
- That's all for today.
El Temur has you marked.
You're dead if you leave me.
You're safest with me, you idiot.
Your lord is the King of Koryo?
He's dead.
He's what?
Your lord is dead.
That can't be.
He's not
one to die so easily.
Ask Lord Zhang.
We have word
that he was killed in action.
Treat the Emperor like that again
and you'll have to deal with me.
Sire.
Wang Yu is dead?
Not just him.
Bayan and Tal Tal as well.
How did they die?
Lord Zhang
didn't have the details.
Does Sungnyang know
he's dead?
Yes.
She must be heartbroken.
I will live
and come back for you.
Stay alive for me.
That's an order.
Understood?
Sire.
You were what gave me hope.
How can I go on?
Why should I?
Sire.
She's barely eating anymore.
Does she miss
her king so much?
Test His Majesty's food.
Wait.
Nyang will do it from now on.
My Liege, custom dictates...
Custom or not...
that's how it is.
I'm starving.
Go on then.
Well? Go on.
Eat more than that.
How else can you tell
if it's poisoned?
And this.
Test this too.
More than that, go on.
Well?
It's fine.
Enjoy.
Here, my favorite.
Test to see that it's all right.
Go on.
I'm paranoid.
You have to test
everything for poison.
I swear, take a real bite.
Wake up.
You can't follow a dead man.
Don't worry about me.
You are my servant.
You need my permission to die.
I told you,
stay within three paces.
Did you forget?
Sungnyang.
Nyang.
Nyang... EEP!
You scared me.
Was that a smile?
It's cold out.
Come along.
Daidu is just over that rise.
It will be dark soon.
We should make camp.
I agree.
At least to rest the horses.
You camp here.
We'll go on.
You haven't slept for two days.
No one is chasing us.
What's in Daidu anyway?
What's his rush?
It's Sungnyang.
Sungnyang?
He's in the Capitol?
Not he. Her.
A girl.
A girl?
It's late.
We'll have to wait till morning.
Wait a moment.
Jombak is finding us
suitable quarters.
It's him.
Sire.
Did you find something?
There's a
courtesan house, but...
But what?
Wang Ko is staying there.
Wang Ko?
Scum!
How dare you?
Sire, please.
They dare reject me?
Even courtesans
are looking down on me!
You've had enough.
Silence!
I don't need you.
Leave, I don't care!
Sire.
So they're watching me, eh?
Follow them.
Sire.
S-Sire.
Wang Yu.
Wang Yu is alive.
If you're a ghost, go away.
If you're Wang Yu, join me.
If you're a drunk, go away.
If you're Wang Ko, join me.
What did I tell you?
I said he's not easy to kill.
You stole salt,
swore allegiance to El Temur...
and this is what it got you.
Look here.
You lecturing your uncle now?
The palace is scarier
than any battlefield.
Doze off
and you'll lose your neck.
You made it back.
Be on your guard.
If it means bowing
and scraping like you...
I wouldn't have bothered
coming back.
Good luck with that.
Nyang.
Nyang?
Nyang has taken ill.
Nyang!
Nyang... Nyang...
She's burning up.
The imperial physician!
My Liege, for a servant?
Get him now!
My Liege.
Nyang.
Sungnyang.
Sire... Sire!
Sire!
Stay with me.
Sire...
Sire!
S-Sungnyang.
Sungnyang,
that's right, I'm here.
My Liege.
I've been
looking all over for you.
What is it now?
General Bayan is alive.
He's here?
He's not dead?
No, My Liege.
He has returned victorious.
And...
Wang Yu?
What about him?
He rode back with him.
He survived?
Sire...
Sire.
Subtitles provided by MBC
You've seen Sungnyang?
Not another word.
Unless you're reading.
The late Emperor
wrote a petition in blood?
You thought it was suicide?
One little sip,
drift off to sleep...
and wake in a better world.
I will do what I want,
how I want.
My Liege.
Would you act this way
if I were Wang Yu?
His Majesty
will be waiting near the pavilion.
Sungnyang,
whats keeping you?