Hey!
Man.
Hey! Hey!
Yaah!
God!
Damn it!
Evil women and whiskey
Surely drive me
to my grave
Evil women and whiskey
Will surely drive me
to my grave
Wherever I go
Trouble seem to follow
Shit.
What's going on?
I don't know, man.
Think it just died.
Holy shit.
Come on.
Oh, my God.
What is it?
It's like angel-hair pasta
in here, brother.
Um...
here. Try it now.
Anything?
Nothing.
Okay.
Oh, this is terrible.
All right.
So...
Um...
Why do we even bother
to pop the hood?
I thought
I heard something.
Yeah, well, unless there's
a flashing neon sign
that says,
"Here's your problem,"
what the hell
do we know?
Fuck, that's hot.
Careful.
What you got?
I got no service.
What about you?
I hardly get
service in the city,
let alone the desert.
Yeah,
I got nothing, man.
Where the hell
are we, anyway?
Uh...
let me see.
Okay.
We, um--
We passed this dot...
about an hour ago.
I think we're
in here someplace.
That's like
60 miles back.
Wow.
It's like a hundred miles to the next dot.
What the hell are you doing driving
us through the middle of nowhere?
We're taking the scenic route,
remember?
Yeah, by scenic,
I was thinking--
I don't know, more trees,
mountains, people,
dots a lot closer
together.
By scenic,
I meant rarely seen.
I'm gonna get you
a dictionary when we get back.
Okay.
Holy shit,
it's hot out here, man.
It's gotta be,
like, 115 degrees.
I know.
Not even noon!
No wonder
the truck died.
Something
probably melted.
Have we even
seen any cars?
Ow. No,
but, uh,
it's a road, right?
I mean, someone'll
be along soon.
Well, we got about
20 jelly beans
and 6 ounces
of melted ice.
That should last us
10 minutes.
Oh, good.
It's pretty.
Yeah.
It's beautiful.
Ohh!
What flavor is this?
Bacon and margarita.
Oh, my God!
I saved those two
just for you.
Tastes like that cake
you made with the onions.
Remember that shit?
Yeah, I remember.
I think that
brings your total
of veiled references
to things I did with Karen
up to three,
so feel free to stop, please.
You never think about her,
man? Ever?
I probably
think about her
about as much
as she thinks about me.
Well, she thinks
about you a lot, dude.
I ran into her
last week, and, uh,
you were all
she can talk about.
She said she was floored
to hear you had a wife and kid.
Yeah, well, it floors me
sometimes, too.
You all right?
Yeah.
Don't overexert
yourself.
I can't believe
you got us out of roaming.
Huh?
Never been out of roaming.
That even possible?
Where are you going?
What are you doing?
I'm gonna go up here and
see if I can get a signal.
No! Let's sit,
and let's wait
a few minutes, man.
Well, why?
I don't know.
We'll hang, and we'll wait
for a car.
No, you sit and wait.
I'm gonna go up and check.
Ah, shit.
You remember last time
we drove cross-country
and we went, like,
200 miles out of the way
because we were
so into whatever we were talking about?
Yeah, and now neither one of us can
remember what it was.
Might have been when, uh--
Might have been when
you claimed that art can reach a point
where its quality
became fact rather than opinion.
That sounds
like a couple hours of my life
I'd like to have back.
Or it might have been
better defense,
'85 Bears
or Steel Curtain?
Ah, that's
hardly debatable.
Bears.
Yeah.
Well, there hasn't been
much of that this time.
What?
Pointless conversation?
Any conversation.
How are things
in high finance?
Ah, put it
this way--
there's this
motivational poster in my office
with, like,
this eagle
soaring out
of the sky and shit.
Yeah.
I'll spend some days
just staring at it,
trying to decide
whether or not
I'm more suicidal or
homicidal that day.
Nice!
So quit.
Quit? And do what?
You ever do that thing when you
were in second grade,
where you,
like, drew a picture
of--of what you wanted
to be when you were adult, you know?
Like, I heard that that's
the truest reflection of what you really want.
Like, if you're doing
what you drew back then,
then you're probably
really happy.
Yeah? And what'd
you draw?
Me?
I think I drew
a fat, unemployed writer,
so I'm killing it.
Come on.
Nothing.
So Joanne didn't like
your music, huh?
We just have
different tastes.
More likely,
she has taste.
Well, I liked it.
Karen liked it.
Would you stop that?
What, man?
I mean--
Joanne didn't
like your music,
and she made you
get rid of your guitars.
I'm just trying
to get up to speed here.
No, she didn't
make me do anything.
It became clear
that I wasn't
gonna have a lot
of chances to play,
so I got rid
of the stuff.
You know, she's not
a music critic.
She's a receptionist.
She's my wife,
Carter, my wife.
I'm just saying.
I know exactly
what you're saying,
and I'm telling you
to stop.
Davey said he saw
you guys at the store,
but you just kind of
walked right on by.
Yeah? Well,
tell him I say hello.
Why don't
you tell him?
You live less than, like, 10 miles
away from the guy.
Yeah, we're pretty busy.
Well, he thinks that
your wife hates him.
No.
No?
She's just not much
on gatherings, that's all.
What about
your parents' house?
There's never less than
a hundred people there.
Ah, we don't
visit very often.
Okay.
Uh, so no Davey,
no family.
Sounds like the list
of people she does like
is kind of short.
I hope you're on it, buddy.
Seriously,
would you knock it off?
You don't even know her.
You're right, man.
I don't know her.
Every time I come
to visit you guys, you're too busy.
I'm surprised she
let you get away to do this thing with me.
Here we go! Here we go!
Oh, thank God.
Come on. Here we go.
Whoa. Wait a minute.
Oh, shit. Wait. Wait.
Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait!
God damn it!
Agh! Ow!
Dude, are you okay?
Hold up!
Hold on!
Shit!
Wait. Wait!
Hey! Wait!
Hey!
Hold on!
Yo.
Whoa. Whoa.
Hey.
Car trouble?
Yeah. We, uh--
We broke down
a few minutes ago.
Well, I-I'm not
much good on cars.
I'll give you
a lift into town.
That would be great.
Thank you so much.
Just let me grab my bag.
Hey! Look, a ride.
Wait! Wait!
Sorry.
Hold on.
We don't need it.
What do you mean
we don't need it?
Sorry, sir.
Nothing
to worry about, son.
I-I'm harmless.
No, it's not--
No.
I, uh--
No, it's all right.
It's not that.
It's just that the--
The truck,
it's not broken.
What do you mean
it's not broken?
It's--
I took a wire out.
It's not a big deal.
What are you talk--
Um...
One second.
What are you
talking about?
I thought that we
were gonna have some good conversations
like the last time,
you know?
But instead I got
cellphones and freeways
and motels and
fucking sports radio.
And, uh, I mean,
I tried to get off the beaten path.
You just decided
to go to sleep,
so I thought this would give us
a chance to catch up.
Thank you, sir.
Are you out
of your f--
You sure everything's all right?
Yes. Oh, yeah.
I--I am
definitely sure.
Okay.
Ta-da.
All right, thank you.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Wait. Wait! Wait! Wait! Wait!
Put it in.
It's no big deal,
man.
Put it in!
I want to see it start.
It's just a wire.
Sorry about this.
Just give us a second.
It's just a wire, man.
Look.
Okay.
Here.
Happy?
You boys good?
Yeah. Yeah.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
I appreciate it.
Have a good day.
Sorry.
Thank you for stopping.
Are you insane?!
Huh?
You stage
a breakdown
in the middle
of the desert
so that
we can talk?
Yeah, and we've had
our longest conversation in the whole trip.
I guess that's
a coincidence.
I could have broken
my neck falling down that goddamn hill.
I told you not go up there.
We could have had
a perfectly good talk sitting right here...
Talk?!
but you had to go up and
climb a fricking mountain.
That was not a talk.
That was you stopping us
a hundred miles from nowhere
so that you could spend a few
uninterrupted minutes
bashing my wife and job!
What kind
of a ring was it?
What?
The engagement ring.
What kind was it?
What do you mean,
what kind?
Was it a diamond?
Why does that matter?
Why won't you answer?
Fine. I got her a diamond.
So what?
"So what?"
So you just forgot
all about
the gumball doctrine?
The gumball doc--
Oh, my God.
You gotta be kidding me.
Has nothing happened to you
in the last 10 years?
So you do remember?
Yeah, I remember it
as something cooked up
by a couple of losers
who had nothing better to do on a Friday night.
Uh-uh. Uh-uh.
I didn't cook it up.
You did. You're the one.
You're the one that said
that you would never
buy an engagement ring
that didn't come
from a gumball machine.
You're the one that said
the poorest people on the planet
are hacking off
each others' limbs
to give you something
to spend 2 months' salary on.
Look, just because you took
some conversation we had
over beer and macaroni
and decided to make it your religion
doesn't mean the rest
of the world gives a shit.
Okay, fine. So you
gave up on diamonds.
Okay. Who gives
a shit, man?
You give up on
your music, your friends and your family,
and for what,
the rebound girl?
Come on.
The rebound girl?
Yes.
Really?
Yes, the rebound girl.
I was there.
I saw you
and Karen together.
You were insane
for the girl.
And--And when
she left, you know--
You were messed up.
Okay? People get that.
But 4 months later,
and you're engaged to the secretary?
Listen,
take a step back,
and see that
for what it is.
I fell in love.
You panicked.
Why do you insist
on listening
to the words you're
putting into my mouth
rather than the ones
I'm actually saying?
You got a goddamn dog.
So what?
You're allergic!
Take a pill.
What's the dog's name?
Sun--Fuck you.
No.
No, "Fuck You"--
No, "Fuck You,"
I would believe.
"Fuck You" is exactly
the kind of name
that you
would name a dog.
No, but your dog's name
is Sunshine.
Fucking Sunshine.
Are you gonna
look at me with a straight face
and tell me that
your opinion was actually considered
in the decision
that resulted in an animal
you're allergic to
being named after a Care Bear?
Oh, my God, you're right.
I didn't get to name the dog.
My life is a sham.
No, no, let me just get
this straight, okay?
J-Just for me.
So the love
of your life leaves.
Okay? And, um,
less than a year later,
you're married
to a secretary
who loves dogs and hates
your fucking music.
I think it's reasonable
at that point to have some doubts, right?
to email your good friend Carter.
You remember that?
"Hey,
what the fuck, man?
What am I getting into?
Did I make a mistake?"
And before
I can hit reply, you buy a fucking house!
That's great!
I understand.
Right. Okay, fine.
You're--
Focus on--
You want to focus on
fucking square footage,
rather than the fact
that you have nothing in common.
That's okay. You--
It's marriage counseling
by HGTV.
I get it, man.
I get it.
And now, you know,
after all this home improvement,
you realize, you know,
you haven't improved
a goddamn thing.
And now you got
no distractions.
"What am I gonna do?"
Oh, yeah, I forgot.
It's the next chapter
in the off-the-shelf life plan
you got
from Home Depot!
Right. Procreate!
That's the job
that's never finished.
"Keep my face down.
Keep my nose
to the grindstone."
Just focused
on the kid,
and maybe you can go
the rest of your life
ignoring the fact
that you fucked up, man.
You made
a colossal mistake,
and you married,
literally,
the first chick
to come along.
What--Hey, hey.
Come on. Come on. Fucking--
I'm not saying anything
you don't know already.
Just swallow your pride,
and you'll see how true it is.
You ever talk
about my family like that again,
I will kick the shit out of you.
You hear me?
Okay. All right.
Listen, I'm sure
that Cole is great.
I'm sure he's the best thing
to ever happen to you,
but he's not a substitute
for loving your wife.
Joanne was right.
You're nothing
but a piece of shit.
Okay.
That's okay.
Get in!
I'll get in when I'm--
I'll get in when I'm
good and fucking ready.
That's when
I'll get in.
So it's you and Joanne
against the whole world.
That's all right.
That's okay.
You know,
you're so scared
to admit that you
made a mistake,
that you just keep on
making it over and over and over again.
But that's fine.
That's fine.
You want to keep on believing
your own bullshit,
we'll get you home,
get you back to your
perfect little life
and your
"motivational posters,"
and you
can tune back out and--
and try to forget
all about the fact
that your life is
a complete shit hole.
Then maybe,
maybe you can call me in 20 years
when you've
fucking lost your hair
and you've come
to your senses.
I don't think we'll be
talking much anymore.
Whatever.
Stupid motherfucker.
It probably just
came loose, man.
Are you insane!
Calm down!
Why are you--Calm down?
You want me
to calm down?!
You go fucking around with
the electrical system
in a 30-year-old
piece-of-shit truck
in the middle of the desert
with no food and no water,
and I'm supposed
to calm down!
I didn't fuck around with it.
I disabled it, briefly.
You should be thankful
that I'm willing to go to these...
Thankful!
I should be thankful?!
lengths to try
to help you.
Who the fuck are you
to be giving me some sort
of life intervention, huh?
You're unemployed!
You're homeless!
Yes, and you
hate your job,
and you have a house
that's apparently too small for a guitar!
This is so typical.
You're constantly
doing something for you
and then saying that
it's for everybody else.
You don't like my wife,
we don't get
to hang out anymore,
so you want me
to get divorced,
right,
for my own good...
Yeah.
because I can do better,
but it's all bullshit.
You want me
to find somebody you like better.
It's for your own good.
Fuck. Fuck. Shit.
I got a good job.
I make good money.
I have a house, a family,
and it kills you,
because you're
a 30-year-old failure who lives in his car.
Right.
So you turn your anger on everybody else
and try to make us feel
like our achievements aren't worth a shit
because we
didn't draw a picture
of ourselves doing them
in the second grade.
You actually
think that if I quit,
took up music
and actually made it,
that you'd be
happy for me?
Mm.
Fuck that. You would be
just as blind with jealousy
then as you are now.
You'd probably--
I don't know--
run me over with
your car-slash-house...
Probably.
and then tell me
that it was for
my own good, right?
Yeah.
This is not about me.
You don't give a shit
about me.
This is all about you
and how everybody else
can accommodate your failure.
Hey, I'm not
a failure, okay?
I could have everything
you have and more,
but I decided long ago
that it would be better to follow my dream
rather than try to buy enough shit
from fucking Pottery Barn
to be comfortable
with the idea of being
a meaningless,
lever-pulling, button-pushing cog!
I was a day away from--
From law school.
No, no.
We all know
the story.
Fuck!
You took a test.
You blew it away.
You had your choice
of schools,
but walked away
for the sake of art, right? Right?
I followed my dream
instead of a paycheck.
Yeah. No, no, no,
no, no. Enh! wrong.
You're a scared and
insecure little freak
who couldn't get
anywhere with writing
and so desperately
needed somebody to approve of you,
to say that you were
still intelligent,
still capable...
Come on.
that you took
a fricking test.
You know
what you should do?
You should tattoo
that test score on your forehead.
That way, when somebody says, "Wait a second.
You live in your car?"
You can say,
"Yeah, but look.
I chose to be a loser,
so its okay."
You think you've
got the rest of us pegged, right?
You got the rest
of us pegged,
and it's your job
to make sure we all face reality?
The reality is
your writing sucks.
You're not gonna be famous.
You're not gonna sell a book.
You are wasting
your time.
You're the one that needs
to face facts, pal.
But every time
those facts get too close,
you just hop in your car,
and you run off.
Well,
here are the facts.
A 30-year-old loser
living in his car
is about the last
person that I'm gonna be looking to
for advice
on how to fix my life.
So unless you want to put out
a book of don'ts
based on all the ways
you screwed up,
which is the only thing
you're ever likely to publish,
you should probably
just shut the fuck up.
Are you done?
Fuck!
Shit. Shit.
Shit. Sh...
Someone'll come along.
You make me sick.
Hot enough for ya?
They say the nights
kill more people than the days.
Okay.
I'm so thirsty.
My tongue feels
like a two-by-four.
Here.
Eh...
Man, finish it.
How long can you go
without water?
2 days?
I don't know.
It doesn't matter.
I'm going for help
in the morning.
Oh, 60 miles is
a pretty long walk.
That's only if
I don't see a car.
I think I saw some cones
on the way in, man.
I don't know.
Hey, I know it--
I know it doesn't really change
anything, but, uh...
I'm sorry.
It was definitely
not your brightest idea.
I mean I'm sorry
about what I said.
Are you sure you
don't want to apologize
for getting us stuck?
I'm not freezing to death
because you insulted my wife.
I'm sorry about
the whole goddamn thing.
You really think
my writing sucks?
It's--It's not bad.
It's just...
all--all your characters
get, like, cancer and die.
Don't all get cancer
and die.
In that one thing,
I'm pretty sure
about 75%
of the people die--
That was about
an oncologist.
Yeah, and that other one
with the woman
who was high and her baby
crawled out the window.
I mean, it was
good writing, but...
kind made me
want to kill myself.
Look, that shit really
happens, all right?
It's just hard to get the message out
if nobody reads the book.
The idea that
"I might not have it,"
it's--it's not news.
It's just that...
you go your whole life
with everyone
yelling at you to follow your dream and
then to never give up.
But to be honest,
if everyone followed their dreams,
we'd just be a planet
of pro athletes and--
and astronauts.
You know, there's gotta
be someone there
to clean the toilets,
am I right?
It's like you said,
you know.
Sometimes it's better to go after
something you care about
than to be handed something
that you don't, right?
Really?
What if
my lifelong dream
was to be point guard
for the Lakers?
Would you tell me
to keep chasing that?
No.
Exactly.
Because "Never give up"
looks a hell
of a lot better
on a coffee mug than
it does in real life.
Because failing...
daily failing,
it's--it's just--
it's a lonely...
miserable business.
Look man, if I thought you should quit,
I would say so.
But sometimes, you know,
inside all that other stuff,
sometimes...
you'll say something
in just a few words
that I realize I've
been thinking for years.
And that's not just
you reading my mind.
That's you
reading a part of it
that I never would have
known how to express.
Now, that's not
just some fat kid with no jump shot.
That's--
There's something there.
Some of the things
you put out there, man...
I think a lot more of them
stick than you realize.
I cheated on Joanne.
Are you kidding me?
No.
6 months ago
at this conference.
Just--
just sort of happened.
We're freezing our asses
off in the middle of the desert.
You think you're
gonna get away with,
"It just
sort of happened?"
It was just--
It was this woman--
Girl, really, 21, 22,
somebody's intern.
Long brown hair,
these long, skinny legs,
and she had
this huge smile.
And she walks up to me,
and she introduces herself,
asks what firm I'm with, blah, blah, blah.
And I said, like,
"Listen, if--if you're looking for a job,
I'm the wrong guy,"
and she goes,
"No, I just think you look interesting."
And she says, "Would you
like to have dinner?"
And I realize that
I've had my hands in my pockets this whole time,
so she has no idea
that I'm even married.
Mm-hmm.
And suddenly I get
this feeling, you know,
like I told you I get
with books and movies,
like I--I finally had
a chance to escape,
to be somebody else
for a while.
So I go back up to my room,
and suddenly I feel
this wave of guilt,
like the spell breaks,
and I start thinking
this is crazy.
Then all of a sudden,
my phone rings,
and it's Joanne.
And I answer, and I say,
"I'm so glad you called,"
because I was.
"I miss you, and I wish
you were here right now."
And she says, "Well, I wish
I were there right now, too,
"because the disposal's
broken again.
"Do you want me
to call a repairman,
"or do you want
to try and fix it?
"Oh, and did you ever
talk to our neighbor
"about whether or not
they stole our recycling bin?
Because it's getting
a little awkward walking with--"
And she goes on like this
for, like, 5 minutes.
So when I hung up,
I practically ran
to the elevator.
And Annie--
her name was Annie--
we have this whole dinner,
and you know
what we talked about?
College football.
Mm.
No car insurance,
no day care,
no gossip about other parents
I don't even know.
Just simple, effortless conversation.
I've never--
The first one that
I've had in a long time.
Scale of 1 to 10?
10.
Plus the fact
that she was 21,
makes her, like,
an eleventy-zillion.
Hello.
Don't get me wrong.
Joanne is
very attractive.
And this is gonna
sound shallow, but...
pregnancy is bad
for a body.
You know, sometimes
I'll catch myself
staring at her thighs
or belly,
and I'll be like...
whatever happened to the
woman I married, you know?
You do realize you're
the one who made her like that.
I know. That's why
I feel like an asshole even saying this.
I feel like an asshole
even thinking it.
And don't get me wrong.
Cole is the best thing
that's ever happened to me.
It's just
he's the worst thing
that ever happened
to our sex life.
I used to look at Joanne
and just want to jump her,
but now I look at her,
and sometimes--
And this is embarrassing,
but sometimes
I have trouble...
getting ready for her.
And Annie?
I could be ready
just thinking about her.
I was ready
when she asked my name.
I guess
when you get married,
you're supposed to say
that the relationship
goes beyond tight thighs
and a skinny waist
and that,
when all that goes,
the rest of it
will sustain you.
Well, it just
isn't phrased that way.
But if--if it was,
would you still have married her?
Yeah, of course, but...
you just don't realize
how much you'll miss things,
you know, little things,
like kissing.
Y-You don't
kiss Joanne anymore?
Yeah, we kiss
all the time,
but it's habit.
It's like a handshake.
You don't even
think about it.
But when Annie kissed me...
fuck.
It was like the hairs on the back
of my neck stood up.
It's hard to say, but there's more in that
first kiss with someone new
than there is
in the whole shebang after 4 years.
That's how everything was.
It was just exciting,
you know, touching her,
taking her clothes off
for the first time.
And then the--
the rest of the weekend at--at the conference,
I'd be sitting
in some stupid speech,
and all I could
think about was those tiny, little legs
and those little
black panties,
and I just--I felt like
I was going fucking crazy.
So then, at lunch,
I found her...
and we blew off
the rest of the conference,
just blew it off.
Did it 4 times
on Sunday...
once an hour before
we went to the airport.
Now, you have
to understand,
if Joanne and I do it
four times a month,
it's a fucking miracle.
But it's like I knew
that it was gonna disappear forever,
and I just--
I couldn't get enough.
And did it
disappear forever?
Yeah, we email
sometimes, but...
nothing serious.
But every time I see
her name in my in-box,
it's like my heart
doubles up, man.
Are you gonna
see her again?
Why? That would just
ruin it, you know?
Everything I felt for Annie,
I used to feel for Joanne.
So, what, I just run off
with this gorgeous little football fan. Then what?
Next thing you know,
talking to Annie is like talking to Joanne,
kissing Annie is like
kissing Joanne. It's--
That's just
what marriage does.
You asked if I ever mention
the music to Joanne.
Well, I have.
Hmm.
I do.
It's like clockwork.
Every couple of months,
I'll wake up,
freaked out that my life
is meaningless.
She'll try on some clothes,
have a breakdown,
swear she's gonna
lose 20 pounds, swears off food.
I swear that I'm gonna turn in
my tie for a guitar strap.
We both say, "Good for you, honey.
I'm with you,"
not believing a single fucking word
the other person's saying.
That's the problem
with marriage. You--
You can't do it
without learning to lie
to the one person
you're supposed to trust.
Can I ask you something?
What?
And I don't--I don't
mean to upset you.
Um...
if it's so bad,
why don't you get out?
Let me see your keys.
I told you, I tried
a million times.
Just--Just let me see 'em.
It's not gonna work,
brother.
That's it?
Two keys?
Yeah, why?
Jesus.
Yeah.
It's like you
mugged a locksmith.
Yeah, I know. It's, uh--
Okay, there's my--
my house keys.
I got my gym locker.
I've got my toolshed.
I've got my boat keys.
I don't know what the hell
that one's for...
Jesus.
or that one.
I mean, it's like--
You know when people say
they're gonna
put down roots?
Well, that's what
it looks like.
Shit.
You know what
I always wanted?
What?
Mohawk, fucking Mohawk,
just like that dude
from--from "Taxi Driver."
Travis Bickle?
The nutcase?
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
But I could never do it.
Why not?
Well, because my parents
would have killed me.
Then when I got to college,
I was working.
Then I was working
as soon as I got out of college.
Then of course I got married
and had a kid, so...
So?
So you don't see
many responsible parents
or functioning members
of society with Mohawks.
So?
So forget about doing
something crazy
and life-altering
like quitting my job
or leaving my wife.
I can't even get
a haircut anymore
without thinking
about the keys,
and the keys,
they don't like Mohawks.
Well, how long do you have to listen
to the keys exactly?
U-Until you retire?
Until Cole goes to college?
Oh, I'll probably
be bald by then.
Exactly.
You know, I used
to have something on my key chain,
but it kept
falling off.
Do you know
what this is?
This is a multi-tool.
And do you know what
one of the tools is?
Shing.
Mohawk?
Dude, put away
the multi-tool.
It's not happening.
Why not?
Because I just told you
two pounds of why.
So what, man?
Nobody's here.
We're freezing
our asses off
in the middle
of the desert.
There's not a soul
to stop you.
Whoa.
Mohawk!
It's not something that
I think Cole needs to see,
is his old man
with a Mohawk.
So what? You'll--
Man, you'll--
you'll prove to him
that--that it's good to be your own man.
What about Joanne?
Joanne's probably
as bored with you as you are of her.
You're probably one Mohawk away from
fucking like rabbits.
Okay, well...
Mohawk! Mo--
Come on.
Just say fuck it, man.
Fuck it. Fuck the keys.
Do it for you.
Oh, God, you don't--
You're
pulling on it.
Just re--Just relax.
Don't be a pussy.
There we go.
Whee.
That's looking good, man.
Here we go.
Ow!
Yeah, that's gonna
leave a mark.
Are you
fucking kidding me?
Is it straight?
It's fairly straight.
Yeah? Does it look
like Travis Bickle?
Heh. You look
pretty crazy.
What do you think?
Oh, no.
Do you love it?
Yes.
Oh, my God.
I'll give you 100 bucks
if you let me come to work
with you on Monday.
You don't have $100.
I know!
I'll sell something.
You gonna sell a book?
Something of value,
like my kidney, maybe.
God.
Oh, my God.
This look is never gonna make it to work.
Oh, come on, man.
This is new Mitch coming through.
Oh, my--I can't
believe how many times you cut me.
The lacerations will fade,
but the memories
will last us a lifetime.
Oh, we can't say
nothing happened on this trip, huh?
God.
Yeah.
What?
Have you ever
been this thirsty?
No.
Really?
It tastes like water.
Gimme.
Yeah, tastes like water.
It's blue and soapy.
Yeah, well,
it's washer fluid.
What do you expect?
That's horrible.
I don't...
I don't
want any more.
All right.
I don't like it.
Well...
I-I'm gonna save
mine for tomorrow,
in case I have
to go for a walk.
Yeah, well,
we should pro--
We should probably
get some sleep...
Yeah.
in case you do, huh?
Holy shit.
Hold on. Hello.
Hello? Hi. Oh, God.
Thank you. Wait.
Hi. Hi.
Hold on. Hi. Hi.
How--How are you?
It's so good to see you.
We had--Ow.
Okay, don't
go anywhere.
Um, we had a...
problem last night.
It's so good to see you.
I'm sorry. Um,
oh, my God.
We had a bit of an issue with the engine.
I guess I tampered with it,
or--I didn't really
dismantle it.
It's fine.
It's all good, but, uh,
God, we were here
all night,
all day and
all night last night.
Maybe you have food
or water or something?
Just--Just anything?
A ride, you know?
We--We'll...
Wait! No!
Where are you going?
Wait! Wait! Wait!
Oh, God.
What the fuck
are you doing?!
I--I thought she was
gonna take us with her.
She was!
Until you scared
the shit out of her!
You couldn't wait
one minute to get into the car, man?
Come on!
I don't--I don't know.
I thought she--
I thought that--
You look like a goddamn fucking
horror movie extra!
Let's remember
why I look like this.
This--This was your idea!
What am I afraid of?
What can it hurt? Well, there you go.
That is exactly why
you can't have a Mohawk in the real world.
I gave you a haircut,
not a lobotomy.
I don't feel well.
Ahh.
Maybe it has something
to do with the fact
that I spent a day
in the oven and the night in the freezer
with nothing
but fucking washer fluid in my system!
I told you not to drink
that shit, man.
Oh!
It tasted like soap!
Okay, so this is
all my fault.
I got us stuck
in the desert.
Well, you certainly
got us stuck for another 20 hours.
Hey, do me a favor.
If you see
any more cars coming,
try not to be
such a fucking moron!
This is exactly
what happens
when you let a homeless person
cut your hair!
Don't worry.
I'm gonna call Joanne for you.
I'll tell her you're just fine,
you'll be home soon,
but you won't be able
to get it up looking at
her fat fucking thighs...
Hey!
unless you think about
your girlfriend Annie.
Hey, You better keep
your mouth shut!
Then maybe she'll give you
that divorce you're
so scared to ask for.
Then you can give
those keys you love so much to Cole's new dad!
Hey!
You fucker.
Aah!
Oh, shit.
Hey.
You son of a bitch.
Come here.
Hey!
Come here!
Hey! Hey!
You son of a--
You--
You just broke my nose!
Fucking--
Yaah!
Damn it.
Hyah!
Come on!
Aah! Oh, my eye!
Time-out!
Are you all right?
Damn it!
I think you broke my nose.
Now I'm going
to have two casts
and a fucking Mohawk.
Hey, quit
fucking around, and get up.
Come on. Get up!
Carter.
Carter?
Hey.
Get up!
C--
Hey.
Hey! Come on.
Come on.
Carter.
Oh, shit.
Oh, man.
I'm so sorry.
Carter, come on, buddy.
Wake up.
Oh, my God.
Carter, come on, buddy.
Get up. Get up.
Get up!
Oh, fuck. Oh, fuck.
Oh, my God.
H-Hey...
Ah, fuck.
What the--
It's gonna be okay, buddy.
It's gonna be okay.
You know, I was
thinking about it,
and it's really funny.
We should have
thought about it sooner.
We scared
that old lady, man.
We scared her.
I mean, look at me, right?
I'd be scared of me.
I'm--I look fucking crazy.
But that's okay.
That's good. That's very good,
because she probably
went straight to town
and told somebody
about it, right?
She probably went
to the first house
or store or whatever
and was like,
"Ohh, you gotta help me.
"Some crazy guy
with a crazy haircut
tried to get in my car."
But I wasn't trying
to get in her car.
I was just--I was just
feeling it, you know.
I was just trying to
make sure it wasn't one of those, what, mirages,
like in the cartoons,
you know?
But that's okay.
That's good.
That's very good, because
she probably told somebody,
and they're gonna come
out here and check it out.
They're probably
sending somebody right now.
They're probably--
They're probably
sending the police.
The police are probably
coming right now.
Carter.
Carter, hey,
I think the police
are coming.
Carter, I need you
to wake up, buddy.
I need you to wake up!
Carter!
The police are coming.
The police are coming!
I need you to help me
make them understand how this happened.
Carter, come on!
Come on!
Hello!
Do you hear me?
'Cause if you
don't help me explain,
they're not gonna
understand, Carter.
Come on!
You remember my keys?
Do you remember my keys?
I got a lot of things
to worry about.
Come on, buddy. Wake up.
Wake up!
Fucking--I am sorry.
Carter?
Carter.
Holy shit!
Holy shit! You're alive!
You're alive!
Carter! Oh. Okay.
J-Just wait here.
Just--You're okay.
You're okay.
You're okay. You're okay.
Everything's gonna
be okay. All right?
What's happening?
You scared the shit
out of me!
That's what's happening.
Ow, my head.
Ohh. Oh, my God.
Quit it.
I can't believe it.
I have the worst
headache I've ever had in my life.
Okay. All right,
well, just--
Just stay
right there, okay?
We'll get you
taken care of.
Oh shit. Oh, fuck.
Um...
is this all mine?
Yeah. Yeah, mostly.
Ohh.
Jesus.
What the fuck
happened to you, man?
You.
Wow.
Okay, just--
Keep breathing.
Breathe in.
Breathe in. Breathe in.
Okay.
There you go.
All right.
Good job. Good job.
I hope I don't look
as bad as you do.
Let's just say
we're tied.
Let's just...
Um...
what the fuck
happened to my hand?
Oh.
Uh, it...
looks broken.
Yeah. It looks
really broken.
Yeah.
Look, I'm just--
Look, it d--
It doesn't matter, okay?
I'm just happy that
you're alive and okay.
W-What the fuck
happened here?
W-We were arguing.
You don't remember?
No.
It really hurts
to think, actually.
Well, then don't. Just--
Just sit here. Rest.
It doesn't matter anyway.
It's over.
Oh, my God.
It's almost dark.
Yeah.
And nobody's come?
No. I hoped that lady was
going to send somebody,
but she, uh...
Just take it easy.
I-I'll keep lookout.
Oh, watch out.
Oh, God.
Maybe
I just need to--
No, no. You stay.
Just stay--
I just need to sit up
for a second.
What the hell is that?
Uh...
Well, it...
What the fuck is that?!
You don't understand.
I thought you were--
What the fuck is that?!
Listen. Listen.
Stay back!
Listen.
Get away from me!
Come on, Carter.
I thought you were dead.
I thought you were--
Stay back!
I--I didn't
feel a pulse.
I checked your--
And there was no pulse.
I didn't
know what to do.
So you were just gonna fucking
bury me in a hole?!
No, no. It's not like that.
Listen.
Are you fucking crazy?!
We were fighting,
and you pulled the knife on me!
You broke
my fucking nose!
You get the fuck back!
You bit
my fucking cast!
What was I supposed to do?
Come on. Just--
You tried
to fucking kill me!
I wasn't trying
to kill you, buddy. Just--
Where you going?
What are you--
Stay the fuck back!
Okay!
Okay, okay. Listen--
I'll kill you.
I didn't know.
I panicked.
I panicked, okay?
I didn't know what to do.
I wasn't feeling
all right.
'Cause I thought
you were dead.
You thought
I was gonna do it.
Didn't you? Didn't you?!
You thought--
You thought I was gonna do it,
I was gonna fuck up your--
your perfect little life,
and so you were just
gonna--gonna bury me,
bury me out here
in the middle of nowhere.
Your stupid, loner,
novelist friend...
No.
who no one would ever miss.
Hey, hey. Hey.
I didn't.
You stay the fuck
away from me!
All right.
Where you going?
Get back!
Where are you going?
I'll kill you!
Okay, I'm--I'm sorry.
Don't follow me.
Hey. I'm--
Please don't go!
Carter.
Carter?
Quit fucking around, man.
You're freaking me out.
Ah, fuck!
Get out of here!
Hey, Mitchell.
I'm not well.
It'd be so fucking easy.
I just pull this
right across your throat,
and I cover you
in this hole, Mitchell,
and leave you
in this godforsaken hellhole forever.
You'd have to be
out of your mind.
No. That happened
a while ago...
and I still can't do it.
Why are you in the hole?
Because it's warmer.
We're in here.
You--Do you
hear something?
I would have
done things differently.
I'd have made changes.
Yeah. Me, too.
You know, It wasn't
that bad of an idea.
It's just we--
We just
didn't do it right.
Well...
next time.
There's gotta
be something.
Carter.
Carter. Carter.
Can you walk?
Look.
I found another dot.
That might not
even be a town.
Well, then, what is it?
It might just be a dot.
Y-You can't have a dot
if there's nothing there,
can you?
I don't know.
Okay look,
the sun set over there,
so that's west,
so we got--
Never eat shredded wheat.
Okay, so it's--
I-It's southwest,
so we--we gotta
go that way.
What if we get lost?
Or eaten or--
or something?
Okay, no,
w-we use the sun
to make sure that we
stay in a straight line.
Okay? I figure
in this condition,
we could probably go,
like, a mile an hour, okay?
That's one day
to get there.
We should just stay
near the road,
and then s-someone
will come for us.
Okay, we haven't seen
a car since that lady.
And what if you're right?
What if--
What if this road was
closed down like you said?
I can't--
I can't keep doing this.
I can't do it.
Look, if we're
gonna go out...
if we're
not gonna make it,
I want to go out trying,
all right?
Okay.
You go.
What?
You go. I can't.
Shut the fuck up.
I'm not going without you.
I'll be fine.
No, you're not fine.
You're lying
in a fucking hole. Come on!
We got 3 hours
until the heat rolls in.
You can do it.
This is our best shot.
I won't make it.
Yes, you will, Carter.
You remember the Grand Canyon?
Remember that?
When you tied the rope to me
and you pulled me up?
Mitchell.
Do you remember that?
I lost a lot
of blood, okay?
You go.
Come on. Get up.
Get up!
Come on. Get up!
Ow!
Come on.
Wait. Wait.
Wait.
Fuck you.
Come on.
Help me up.
I'll carry your ass.
Come on.
Come here.
What?
I hear something.
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
I tell her
that I loved her
And lived with no regret
Oh, Laura
You just look away
Just look away...
No! Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Oh, Laura
You just look away
Just look away
Oh, nothing
Will get you to stay
Forward or backward?
Hmm.
Hey. Hey.
Got you something.
I got you something.
Hey. Hey.
I found something.
Heh.
I saw something.
See?
Look. They go
to the town, probably.
Oh, my God.
Jesus.
Come on.
We good?
Yeah. Let's go.
After you.
All right.
Let's just--
Is it heavy?
Yeah.
Heh.
Answer it.
Hello.
Hello. Hello!
Ah, you remember
Uncle Carter? Huh?
Hey, doggie.
Ha ha. Hey, what's up?
How are you, man?
Oh, I'm good.
Remember Uncle Carter?
Real good.
Hey, Cole.
Hi.
Low five.
This is everything.
Yeah? That's it, huh?
Yeah.
Are you sure
about this?
Hey, Cole.
Yes?
Why don't you show Uncle Carter
his new room, huh?
Yes.
Yes?
Good boy, Cole.
All right.
Let's do it.
Thanks.
You got it.
So is this it?
This is it.
All right.
All right, buddy,
let's go.
There you go.
You ready?
Are you sure
you're okay with this?
Are you kidding me, man?
It's the least I can do.
Besides, it'll give me a chance to
knock out a big chunk.
Yeah.
I'm proud of you, man.
Well, it's just
flowing from me now.
How long is it
gonna take you guys
to circumnavigate
the world?
Uh, you know,
we're gonna stay
with the parents for a couple days,
and I'm still not entirely sure we're
gonna get through that,
but if we do,
the tickets are open-ended,
so we'll just pick
a continent and stay until we get bored
or, you know,
run out of money.
You know,
she's--she's not...
what I thought,
you know?
I mean...
I never really knew.
Yeah, well, she said
the same thing about you.
Yeah.
All right,
come here, you.
All right, man.
See you.
Be good.
All right.
Be safe.
Hello.
Hey.
I wake you?
No, I just--I'm finishing
some stuff up.
What's going on?
Eh, you know,
I just wanted
someone to talk to.
I'm feeling...
weird.
Has it occurred to you that maybe
you need some sleep?
I guess...
I thought that
I was past the point
where I really believed
that people could change, you know?
At least, the point
where I thought that I could.
Sounds like
a pleasant surprise, no?
Yeah. Absolutely,
but I'm just not sure
I believe it.
Believe what?
That I'm really
doing this.
Well, what exactly
is the alternative?
Well, this is gonna
sound a little crazy.
Imagine that. You called me
in the middle of the night
with something
that sounds a little crazy?
Part of me
believes that...
we never made it
out of that desert...
that we're just
lying there, overcome...
and this is
just all part of our imagination.
I told you this was
gonna sound crazy, but--
And you didn't
sell it short.
A-Are you telling me
that you're not at all suspicious
that things have
gone so smoothly?
Suspicious? No.
I'm stunned,
I'm impressed,
but I'm not suspicious.
Well,
maybe you should be.
I mean, think about it.
Things may be
just a little too good to be true,
you know what I mean?
Believe me, if I
was making this up,
there'd be a lot more
lottery winning and supermodeling.
Well, at least
convince me that it's probable,
you know,
that life really
can turn on a dime,
that you really can--
I don't know--
reinvent yourself.
Which is harder
to believe,
that things are finally going the way
you always wanted them to
or that the only way
it could be this good
is if it's all
in your head?
I don't know.
You don't have
an opinion on that?
Well, I don't
know about you,
but this better
be reality for me,
because if we're still
out in the middle
of the desert somewhere,
I just finished
an imaginary book.
Wow, that's--
That's really, really fast.
So tell me how it ends.
Well,
that's the funny thi--
Carter?
Piece of shit.