(music playing)
(women vocalizing)
Alert. C.I.C. to Khara-22.
Prepare for combat.
(music continues)
KHARA: Moving target spotted,
bearing 07-02, 200 markes.
Assumed to be a Briga cruiser.
Colm 201 squadron,
move to confirm.
KHARA: Colm 201 Alpha, copy.
(automatic weapons firing)
Kiakra C.I.C., pursuing target.
Request permission to engage.
Permission granted.
OPERATOR: Colm 201,
sending Colm 202 and 203
for reinforcement.
SECOND OPERATOR:
Commander, unidentified vessel
confirmed as a Briga
escape shuttle.
Why would a Briga
pursue another Briga?
Capture the shuttle.
Top priority.
FIRST OPERATOR: Colm 201 Alpha,
Briga escape shuttle priority.
Colm 201 Alpha, copy.
(music continues)
(chorus vocalizing)
(music ends)
(explosion echoing)
(wind whistling)
KHARA: Kiakra C.I.C.,
Khara-22 hit.
Airframe damaged.
FIRST OPERATOR:
Copy that, Khara-22.
Activate auto-return mode.
KHARA: Auto-return mode
activated.
(yawns)
Khara-22, killed in action.
Body can be renovated.
Let's consolidate casualty data
and begin transfer.
(music playing)
NARRATOR:
Around its blue parent planet,
Gaia circles Annwn,
a world at war.
Once this world was controlled
by eight tribes
called the Garm...
Briga, Wurm, Basse, Seta,
Borzoi, Zenen,
Kumtak, and Columba.
Each tribe had
its own form and language
based on its function,
and they served
the god who created them.
However, Danaan, the Creator,
left this world one day,
and these tribes
who were left behind
began to fight each other
for supremacy.
After a long period
of conflict,
the atmosphere
has been contaminated
and the surface
left covered in ruins.
Of the eight tribes,
only three,
the Briga, Columba, and Kumtak,
now remained.
And even the Druids,
said to convey the word of God,
have died out.
The Briga have established
dominance of the surface
with their military might.
The Columba rule the skies
by deploying mechanized units.
The Kumtak have
barely managed to survive
by offering their superior
information technology to Briga.
The Briga and Columba, the two
great tribes of land and air,
were about to begin battle
of dominance over Annwn.
- (music playing)
- (chorus vocalizing)
(woman vocalizing)
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
KIAKRA COMPUTER:
Data consolidation complete.
Thank you for your brave service
to the Kiakra, Khara-22.
New identification code
for the squadron is Khara-23.
INTERROGATOR: Type, Kumtak.
I.D. code unknown.
INTERROGATOR 2:
Accessing auxiliary brain.
Infiltrating memory hive.
INTERROGATOR 1:
Function, system analysis
and interrogation,
also information management.
Consistent with the Kumtak
information officers
serving the Briga.
Scan the Garm
terminal access log.
INTERROGATOR 2:
Last access, minus-3716 sen.
His breach
was minus-2517 sen.
You're telling me he's been
off the Garm network
for over a thousand sens.
INTERROGATOR 2: He must be
operating as a stand-alone.
What about
that other individual?
INTERROGATOR 2: Type, unknown.
Function, unknown.
INTERROGATOR 1:
There's a powerful firewall
in the subject's
auxiliary brain.
Could be a trap.
Auxiliary brain manipulation
is a Kumtak specialty.
Try the Kumtak's
memory nest again.
See what he knows
about the other subject.
INTERROGATOR 2:
Scanning. Extracting.
INTERROGATOR 1: Type, Druid.
I.D. code unknown.
- A Druid?
- Impossible.
For the sake of argument,
let's say it is a Druid.
The more important question
is not one of existence,
but of action.
What would drive a Kumtak
to flee the Briga?
If the terminal access logs
are correct,
he's been on the run
for some time.
We've no choice
but to interrogate them directly
if we're to learn
anything of substance.
INTERROGATOR 2: Wait.
Trace data detected
in the type-Druid's headgear
and secondary buffer.
Extracting.
Is that...
Danaan?
(yawns)
KUMTAK: Are you
the Columba pilot
that died trying to save us?
What if I am?
WYDD: Thank you.
I was just following orders.
WYDD: Maybe so,
but it seems like someone else
would like to thank you.
You seem entitled
to receive a blessing,
although that would be
for a Gula to decide.
(Gula groans)
(whimpers)
Garm in this ship
restrict a Gula's movement?
To be touched by a Gula
is to receive a blessing
of great fortune and protection.
To the best of my knowledge,
Nascien is the only one
the Gula's ever blessed.
Would you care to try?
(Gula grumbles)
(whimpers)
(grumbles)
(brakes squeal)
Hmm.
(machinery humming)
(platform whirring)
Where is the Gula?
A Gula is always searching
for someone or something.
(music playing)
(whimpers)
(grumbles)
How did you get down here?
Gula!
Interrogation will commence.
Kumtak, who is that individual
you fled the Briga with?
My dear interrogator,
you are aware of the existence
of the Sage of the Trees,
those who convey all the words
of our creator, Danaan?
If by the Sage of the Trees,
you mean Druids, then yes.
We are familiar with both
their existence and extinction.
WYDD: Yes, along with
the Wurm, the Basse,
the Seta, the Borzoi,
and the Zenen,
all extinct
after years and years of war.
Now with the Kumtak
near extinction,
only the Columba and the Briga
remain
in any significant numbers.
Your point, Kumtak?
Every Garm knows this.
These are keystone memories
of our collective database.
Yes, but just because
you commit something to memory
does not make it a fact.
In our collective memory,
the last of the Druids
were killed off long ago,
but the truth is, one survives.
Druids are said to have
access to tremendous power,
and if that power
could be harnessed,
then total systems dominance
could be achieved.
That, at least,
was the thinking of the Briga.
The Briga tried to use
the power of the Druids?
That sounds like
something they would think of.
There are stories that a Kumtak
once tried to use Druids
to gain the power of Danaan
and challenge the Briga.
But that Kumtak's ambitions
brought great shame to his pack,
and he was ousted from the clan
as a heretic.
Surely there's no need
to follow in the footsteps
of that Kumtak
who played with systems
beyond his comprehension
and ended up a pariah.
WYDD: No matter how much
the Columba boast
of their speed and mobility,
the Brigas' mighty warships
and armored forces
remain as great
a threat as ever.
Would you not call
attacking a powerful enemy
the very height of foolishness?
So why have you come to us?
The Briga and the Kumtak
have been united
for countless cycles.
Enslaved, not united.
So you've come to offer us
the power of the Druids
against the Briga
in exchange
for your tribe's freedom?
If that is what you want,
then, yes,
that is what I'm offering.
(barks)
Gula.
(Gula whimpers)
(grumbles)
- (barks)
- Gotcha.
LEAD INTERROGATOR: Kumtak...
you say
that by combining our power
with that of the Druid,
we can destroy the Briga.
How do we know
that what you say is true?
WYDD: If you allow me access
to this ship's
information core,
I will combine it
with the Druid's,
and you will see firsthand
the true power of the Druid.
Don't be ridiculous, Kumtak.
You'll trigger an overflow
and destroy the braincase.
Sir, you aren't
seriously considering
giving him access, are you?
The Kumtak are notorious
for their skills
at manipulating data.
How do we know
what this Kumtak says is true,
that it's not all
some elaborate trap
by the Briga, sir?
Give the Kumtak access
to the Kiakra's main core.
Sir!
There is a Druid
standing before you,
a Druid.
Don't you understand
what this means?
Give the Kumtak access now.
INTERROGATOR 1: Yes, sir.
Port opened
in the staging area firewall.
Thy right hand
shall teach them to fear thee.
See for yourself
the power of the Druids.
(machinery whirring)
(chorus vocalizing)
Danaan, you make yourselves
known to us only in visions.
We only speak to you in dreams.
Stop it!
Cut her off! Cut her off!
(energy crackling)
Behold the power
of the Druids!
(laughing)
(music playing)
All right, listen up.
Our primary objective
is to take back
the Kumtak and the Druid alive.
Ignore the Gula.
Any Columba, you kill on sight.
Team one, take care
of the sleep hive.
Team two, hit the hangar
and ground
as many Six-Wings as you can.
Now the rest of you, follow me.
OPERATOR: Illegal access
into the ship's information core
detected from the Kiakra.
OPERATOR 2: Air-traffic control
section isolated from system,
connected directly
to information core.
OPERATOR 1: Fire-control section
isolated, too!
OPERATOR 2: Shipboard
security systems offline.
OPERATOR 1:
Navigation and control systems
integrated
with information core...
(grunting)
Set the C.I.C.
to autistic mode now!
COMPUTER: Share combat
information center.
The system merges
all of the main building.
KHARA PILOT: Colm 301
to Kiakra C.I.C. Come in.
Air patrol to Kiakra C.I.C.
Multiple Briga warships
approaching.
Kiakra C.I.C.
KIAKRA COMPUTER:
Air-to-ship combat alert.
Prepare to launch aircraft.
(chorus vocalizing)
(muffled explosions)
(woman vocalizing)
(vocalizing ends)
I was wondering how I was
gonna get this thing open.
Don't even try, Kumtak.
We're taking you
and your little doll
back to Briga command.
(automatic weapons firing)
(chorus vocalizing)
(energy hums)
(muffled explosion)
SKELLIG: Contact the Rosmerta.
Objective secure.
Now let's move.
(music ends)
PILOT: Six-Wing
closing behind us.
SKELLIG: Lose them!
PILOT:
They're coming in too fast.
(Skellig grunts)
(turret whirs)
(silence)
(fire crackling)
(gasping)
(groans)
(winces)
(metal scrapes)
(coughs)
(groans)
(music playing)
(rifle whines)
(music continues)
(sniffs)
(wind blowing)
(thunder crashing)
(woman vocalizing)
- (tube hisses)
- (grunts)
(panting)
(women vocalizing)
(music, singing ends)
(seabirds calling)
(Gula barking)
(whimpers)
(barks)
Kumtak!
Is this some kind of joke?
The Torc Sea,
where the corrupted land
of the Garm ends
and the sacred land
of the Druids begin.
You said this was
the way back to Briga command.
I have no intention
of returning to the Briga.
(both grunting)
(groans)
(gasping)
(panting)
- (yells)
- (barks)
(whimpering)
Kumtak,
get this Gula out of the way.
(Gula barks)
Even an obstinate Briga
like him knows it's a grave sin
to kill one
who's been blessed by Gula.
(grumbles)
(yawns)
(seabirds calling)
WYDD: You used manna.
It makes you faster, stronger,
allows you
to heal more rapidly
than if you were
in your sleep hive.
But there's a price to pay.
If you use too much at once,
your body will destroy itself
from within,
accelerating your metabolism,
aging you, wearing you out.
You talk like you know
more about the Garm
than they know about themselves,
like you've forgotten
you're one of us.
Have you ever wondered
what it truly means
to be a Garm?
Our core memories
are so limited.
Think. Your weapons,
the Columba carriers,
the Briga cruisers,
the systems
that operate them all,
nothing was created
by the Garm.
How long have they existed?
No matter how hard
we trace our memories
or how we trace the records,
the answer's the same.
Nothing is created by the Garm.
They've existed
from the very beginning.
The Garm don't create.
We maintain.
If we don't know
where we came from,
how would we know
where we're going?
(seabirds calling)
KHARA: Heresy.
What you're saying is heresy.
A Garm fulfills his mission.
That's all.
Is it?
Do you know where you are?
Do you know what that is?
The Torc Sea.
Danaan, our creator, made it
to separate the Garm
from the lands of the Druids.
Those lands are
forbidden to Garm like us.
Only there can I follow
the memories of Danaan,
who vanished from these lands.
Danaan?
(sighs)
Don't you?
Don't you want to know
why our creator left us?
WYDD: Once we cross
the Torc Sea,
Nascien will lead me
to Dual Grund,
where I can gain access
to the upper-level systems
of the Druids.
That is where the truth
behind Danaan's absence lies.
And what about me?
And the Briga?
You just expect us
to follow you?
Cut off from your packs,
Garm like you will die
wandering in the wasteland.
Your memories
will not be downloaded.
You will not reawaken
in your sleep hive cells.
But in Dual Grund,
you may find another fate
waiting for you.
What, I cannot say.
But cut off from your pack
as you are, the choice is yours.
The tide is rising.
Are you coming or not?
(beads rattle)
SKELLIG: Where do you think
you're going, Kumtak?
Across the Torc Sea
to Dual Grund.
(sighs)
You're not going anywhere.
My mission's to take you
back to Briga command.
You can die now
or later on your own
out in the wasteland,
but we're going to Dual Grund.
SKELLIG: You're not gonna
make it across on foot.
Get on.
Why should I trust you, Briga?
'Cause if I could kill
a Garm blessed by a Gula,
you'd already be dead.
I've come too far to let this
crazy Kumtak just walk away.
You wanna go to Dual Grund?
I'll take you.
Once your business there
is finished,
I'm gonna take this crazy Kumtak
and the Druid
back to Briga command,
and the Gula could do
as the Gula pleases.
Deal.
SKELLIG: So you do have
some sense, Columba.
It's Khara, Khara-23.
(Skellig chuckles)
You're telling me
your generation code?
(laughs)
That information's
only shared within a pack.
I am Wydd, Wydd-256.
The Druid is Nascien-666.
You're kidding me.
I'm Skellig...
(sighs)
Skellig-58.
(tank whirring)
NARRATOR: These people
who have all lost their packs
miraculously meet and begin
their pilgrim's journey
to the holy land
in search of the memories
of the Garm.
(women vocalizing)
(chorus vocalizing)
(singing ends)
(music ends)
(rifle fires)
(barking)
Not bad.
Funny.
A Gula can live where birds are,
but we can't.
How much manna
do we have left?
Uh, three selmas,
if we're strict
with rationing.
And there'd be even less
if the Druid didn't seem
to be surviving off her...
connection with these stones.
Even if we make it
to Dual Grund,
if there's no manna there,
we're finished.
You're regretting
your decision?
(chuckles)
A Briga never regrets
his actions.
You remember that.
- (sighs)
- (whimpers)
(chuckles)
(sighs)
I came to relieve you.
I'm fine.
Go back to sleep.
I can't sleep when Wydd
sleeps so soundly.
What does he know that we don't?
I thought you trusted him.
(scoffs) Hardly.
I can't shake the feeling
that he had something to do
with the disaster
that brought down the Kiakra.
Well, if you can't trust him,
what makes you think
you could trust a Briga like me?
We have a deal.
(chuckles)
Unbelievable.
If you're a code 23,
that means you have a long
service record as a warrior.
A Garm without a pack
tends to throw caution
to the wind.
If that's true,
I'm not the only one.
(sighs)
It's not the same thing.
I have my mission.
You made a choice.
Out here,
is there really a difference?
Go get some rest.
If I need relief, I'll...
I'll come and wake you.
I told you I'm not tired.
(sighs)
Do you, um...
What did it feel like,
to be touched by a Gula?
Do you feel...
Do you feel any different?
It's just...
I don't know how to explain it.
She drools a lot.
Is it, um...
Was it sticky?
I felt something warm and soft
when she touched me...
not on the outside,
but on the inside,
if that makes any sense.
And her scent...
I feel like I've smelled it
somewhere before.
I don't know.
Your Briga pack
didn't have any Gulas?
We used to.
I never saw one, no.
Gulas are short-lived,
eh, and clones are forbidden.
Skellig,
what's your first memory?
Uh...
uh, target practice maybe?
Mission briefing?
No, back further.
What's the first thing that you
can recall ever experiencing?
For me, I think...
the first thing that I ever saw
was light coming in
when my sleep hive cell
opened up.
Your first memory isn't
something similar to that?
So what if it is?
We're Garm.
We fight. We die. We download.
(chuckles)
Being around the Druid's
going to your head, Columba.
"What is your first memory?"
Why is it any more important
than your third
or your tenth or your last?
Skellig,
why are there no young Garm?
Gulas give birth to pups.
Even birds at the Torc Sea lay...
raise chicks from eggs.
Why is it just the Garm
that have no young?
Danaan created us that way.
Why would Danaan create
the Garm to be like that?
What was the point?
Is that why
you wanna go to Dual Grund?
What, to... to find answers?
I don't know.
(scoffs)
You asked if something changed
when Gula touched me,
and something did.
I don't know what,
but something
inside of me changed,
and if going to Dual Grund
tells me what that something is,
then so be it.
(sighs)
You should go.
Go.
SKELLIG: Visibility's shot!
I can't see anything,
just this fog.
It's too dangerous
to keep going.
We're stuck.
KHARA: Wait.
I think the fog's thinning out.
Skellig, there on the left.
SKELLIG: Distance, 390 nortes.
What is that, a hill?
(distant birds squawking)
KHARA: I've heard the birds
can travel from this world
to the other using their wings.
WYDD: The place
where the world ends
and the world begins.
Dual Grund.
This is the place,
the exact vision that Nascien
projected in my sleep.
In your sleep?
You mean you dream?
I thought only the Gula
were blessed
with the ability to dream
until I met Nascien.
I've never doubted
or regretted my decisions,
and yet...
coming to the holy land,
it could bring disaster
to the Briga.
There's no turning back now,
not for us,
nor for the world.
If we are the harbinger
of things to come,
what lies ahead?
If that was not the case,
then why would a heretic like me
and Nascien have turned up?
And you can't say that Khara
willingly left her pack.
Neither did I, I suppose.
Perhaps we'll have
a more different future
if Danaan's curse is lifted.
The future.
That's such an absurd concept.
Briga, all we have
is the future.
Ah, Kumtak.
Guess there's
no turning back now.
(birds squawking)
(chorus vocalizing)
(singing ends)
(barks, grumbles)
(whimpers)
Cold feet, Skellig?
Only way forward's on foot.
Someone's gotta be backup,
and I'm the only one that knows
how to work this thing.
You keep your com channel open.
You run into trouble,
just say the word.
(Gula barks)
Khara...
What?
It's the first time...
It's the first time
you called me by name.
(sighs)
What about you?
I, um...
I don't need
as much manna as you.
Besides, I got my pal here
if anything goes wrong.
You said there was something
you wanted to find out
at Dual Grund.
Go find out.
Go find out if there's a future
waiting for us, for the Garm,
something that's different
than this.
Go.
(water splashing)
(sniffing)
(grumbles)
(ticking)
(rumbling)
KHARA: Skellig,
there's something in here.
80 markes ahead.
Do you see it?
SKELLIG: I see it.
I'm picking up two more
on your left and right as well.
Look out. They're moving.
KHARA: I'm going in
for a closer look.
SKELLIG: Be careful, Khara.
Whatever's out there, it's big.
(rumbling)
(chorus vocalizing)
(metal creaks)
KHARA: Skellig, it's a Giant!
It's moving!
Wydd, stay low,
and stay out of the way.
Skellig, fire! Keep firing!
SKELLIG: Don't worry about him.
Worry about the other two
on your flank!
KHARA: Got it.
Something must have
been triggered
when Nascien
accessed the system.
Anything else
you forgot to tell us?
These Giants have a weakness.
They're not like us.
They require physical connection
to the... to their network
in order to identify
and attack an intruder.
Cut the connection, and that
should stop those Giants.
Skellig, did you get that?
SKELLIG: Loud and clear.
Cut the cable, kill the Giants.
Skellig,
you keep them distracted.
I'll find the cables.
(engine grinding)
SKELLIG: Anytime now, Khara!
Found it!
(creaking)
SKELLIG: That's one down, Khara.
- (tube hisses)
- (grunts)
SKELLIG: Be a decoy,
and flank the Giant!
(grunts)
(creaking)
Nice shooting, Skellig.
WYDD: Khara, can you hear me?
Wydd, go ahead.
WYDD: We found an access point.
Nascien's going to try
to disable the defense system,
but it will take time.
Can you keep
the remaining Giants distracted?
KHARA: Just hurry, Wydd.
SKELLIG: I'll take the big one.
You take the little one.
KHARA: Big one? Little one?
(distant gunfire echoing)
(women vocalizing)
(singing ends)
(gasps)
What happened
to "the big one"?
SKELLIG: They're all big ones.
(energy crackles)
(grunts)
Skellig!
(gasping)
Skellig, run.
- (grunts)
- Skellig!
(yells)
(yelling)
(panting)
WYDD: We've disengaged
the system.
We're safe now.
Khara, do you read me?
We've located the position
of the central terminal,
the core of Dual Grund.
Nascien will show you the path.
KHARA: We have to help Skellig.
Forget Skellig.
Nothing could've survived
that explosion.
Khara, if you want to know
the truth, forget Skellig,
and follow the path
that Nascien reveals.
(fire crackling)
(silence)
(footsteps approaching)
(grumbles)
NASCIEN: You have
served me well, Kumtak.
Nascien.
(groaning)
(panting)
(overlapping voices)
I am Malakh,
messenger of the Gods.
Nascien is only the shell I wear
when I walk in your world.
Garm type, Druid, you call it.
I have come to this place so I
may fulfill my lord's bidding.
(rumbling)
(chorus vocalizing)
WYDD: I found you.
I protected you.
I killed for you.
For what?
Tell me.
Tell me, what have I done?
(metal clanking)
Malakh.
(groans)
Speak not my name.
Listen well, Kumtak.
My name is Wydd,
Wydd-256.
NASCIEN: Time had
stood still for the Garm,
but by your coming here,
it has begun to flow once more.
The time of the Garms'
extinction has begun.
(groans)
Your body
will still prove useful to me.
The braincase of a Kumtak
will be able to freely access
the central Garm network.
I shall make free use of it.
However,
all other central memories
will be deleted from it.
I am Wydd,
Wydd...
256.
I am Wydd,
Wydd...
2-5...
NASCIEN: How peculiar.
It would appear
that the few thoughts
remaining
in this body's braincase
do not wish its memories
of you to be deleted.
I have placed here
a flaming sword,
which turns every direction
to guard the way
to the Tree of Life.
(automatic weapon fires)
(splash)
(clicking)
(grunts)
KHARA: Give it up.
There's no way out.
You're trapped in there.
My name is Khara-23.
Now tell me, why do we fight?
What meaning does the Garms'
endless fighting have?
Answer me.
(overlapping voices)
The owner of this body
already appears
to know the answer.
Then tell me.
(thunder rumbling)
(rain falling)
What was is and ever shall be.
I form the light
and create darkness.
When this world
was not yet formed,
They came from far, far away.
Then They divided this world
into heaven and earth
and filled the space between
with living things.
- (clanking)
- (chorus vocalizing)
Finally They created the Garm
and bequeathed unto them
a portion of their technology
that allowed the Garm
to control this world.
The Garm
were separated into tribes
according to their abilities.
Eventually
they named themselves...
Briga, Columba, Kumtak.
And they named the individuals
that formed the tribe
and went on to name
every living thing
that filled this world.
To name something
is to show dominance over it.
And when They
were named by the Garm,
They abandoned the Garm
and left this world.
They forbade the Garm
the power to create new life,
for They feared the Garm
and their reckless desire
to conquer all
that was in their world.
And since that time,
the Garm have had no future,
only a present.
And now the Giants will rise
and burn Annwn to ash.
What was is and ever shall be.
I form the light
and create darkness.
Wait.
What do you mean,
"Ever shall be"?
Who are "They,"
and where have They gone?
They've already begun
their next experiment
in the place
closest to this world.
That's why this world
must be destroyed.
You keep saying, "They."
Why don't you say their name?
Even now, you ask their name.
(sighs)
They call themselves...
(alien language)
(sighs)
It means "jealous,"
for They are a jealous God.
(chorus vocalizing)
(crying)
(singing, music end)
(music playing)
07-01...
36...
Message from
early warning craft.
Two echelons Danaan
from bearing 01-09...
- 06-03...
- 04-07...
- Three echelons...
- 02-07...
03-02...
- Prepare to launch...
- Two echelons...
Number increasing.
(chorus vocalizing)
Task force 11 in battle array,
ready to deploy.
Task force 12
Third formation,
bearing 02-07.
(overlapping chatter)
Fifth assault ship
force ready.
(vocalizing continues)
- Strike force 103 ready.
- Formation 08-05.
(overlapping chatter)
(vocalizing continues)
NARRATOR: The invasion
by the reawakened Giants
marks the end
of the so-called Old Cycle
and the dawn
of a new era on planet Annwn,
an era of heavy warfare
between Garm and Malakh.
(vocalizing ends)
(energy hums)
(drums beating)
(music playing)
(woman vocalizing)
(women vocalizing)
(chorus vocalizing)
(vocalizing ends)
(women vocalizing)
(Gula whimpers)
(yips)
(grumbles)
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com