presented by
Next Entertainment World
world sales Finecut
a Haemoo Co., Ltd. production
executive producer
KIM Woo-taek
producers
BONG Joon-ho, CHO Neung-yeon, Lewis Taewan KIM
co-producer
YU In-soo
KIM Yoon-seok
PARK Yu-chun
HAN Ye-ri
MOON Sung-keun
Of course you break it,
if you get drunk and step on it.
Told you to look at it before
we left port.
Ho-young!
Roll them up separately!
That's what I'm doing!
Rolling 'em up separately.
- You have to flip it.
- Okay.
Watch the spark!
Look at this part.
Feel how smooth it is.
Be careful!
Temperature in Yeosu will be similar
or slightly lower.
Relatively calm at sea with
the wave 1m high maximum.
A good day for fishing.
Overcome the IMF crisis...
Oh, Lee Dae-jin is pitching!
cinematography
HONG Kyeong-pyo
Please let the catch be worth
a lot of money.
And let it be a full haul.
The blade is all nicked.
Ho-young!
They're not anchovies!
They're pomfrets!
Get moving!
Let's get those pomfrets!
Kyung-koo!
Call out the engineer!
Dong-sik! Don't stand around.
Go help with the net.
You mean this?
What the hell?
- He's caught!
- Turn off the drum winch!
You have to be shitting me.
- It's stuck!
- Hold the net tight!
Just turn off the damn winch!
Holy shit.
The winch is jacked up.
How the hell did you check
the equipment?
You're lucky to be alive.
Iine producer
HAN Sang-bum
screenplay by
SHIM Sung-bo, BONG Joon-ho
directed by
SHIM Sung-bo
HAEMOO
Yeosu, 1998
Hello, Captain.
Still no fish.
They better catch some soon.
That one.
That one looks good.
That one there.
Already back before the tide?
We missed a school of
pomfrets...
The drum winch got jacked up.
We should do a complete
overhaul of the boat.
Need to fix the radiator too.
Why spend money to fix
that piece of junk?
The government is reimbursing
old fishing boats now.
They're even turning in
boats that are in good condition.
Don't even joke about
giving away my boat.
For people like me,
that's like denying your family.
A load of crap.
You can't give away the Junjin.
Never.
Loan me some money
to feed my crew.
You gotta be shitting me.
Hey, Captain.
Why is your sorry ass
is still a captain?
It's thanks to us!
You know what?
We're turning in that boat,
get our money in the bank!
Bank interest is good money now.
Under the lMF crisis.
Excuse...
That rotten...!
You little!
You going somewhere?
Why're you back so early?
We returned with a full load.
Heard it's tough these days...
Your captain must be good.
Yeah.
Nana. Were you at the
market again?
No.
Told you not to work.
I can earn for both of us.
How can I stay home when
my baby's working out at sea.
You're home early.
Done fishing?
Excuse me.
The restaurant and the house
are a complete mess.
And you're here doing it
with that guy?
Better than you.
If you don't like it,
make yourself available.
Or bring home some money.
Husband my ass.
The door is jammed.
Where's the....
Can't even pay for a motel?
You're so cheap.
Shut up!
Push up closer!
Okay!
It's so dark.
- Mind the gap.
- What's going on?
Kyung-koo brought a girl.
With a call girl again?
Not again.
Oh, hello boys.
I can't wait.
Think of this as my yacht.
To your left and right.
4 beds total.
Take your pick.
You guys sleep on
bunk beds like kids?
What the...
Thought you were going out
on the town tonight.
What for? I live here.
Okay, whatever.
- I got a better place.
- Really?
Follow me.
What's your name, baby?
Huh?
We have to improvise.
Let's try the captain's bed.
Real comfy.
- Really?
- You don't trust me?
Hold tight.
There you go...
Oh!
How dare you bring a girl
on board!
Kyung-koo, get a room.
- Was the captain here?
- I didn't know either.
Was he here all along?
Is he sleeping on board
instead of home?
- Wait up!
- I'm leaving.
He's worried about the boat.
Are they really selling the boat?
It's burning. Flip it.
Okay.
Why do you need a big loan?
I'm getting my boat back.
Buying that piece of junk?
Its value is practically nothing.
Captain Kang.
Your income last year
is a total mess.
Your savings account is tapped out,
and you used up your loan.
- Restaurant is mortagaged.
- What?
Your wife's name is
Kim Jae-hwa, right?
It's going to be difficult.
It's not like the old days
for trawler captains.
The red tide's been bad
for business, huh?
It's not the red tide.
It's my luck running out.
Trawler captains used to spend money
like spoiled princes.
Didn't you spend 2 million
in one day at a bar?
It's become a legend here
in Dolsan Harbor.
Even now you can fool around
with these girls all day.
and still it doesn't cost 2 million.
- Go outside.
- Okay.
Guess times have really
been tough for you.
Even coming to see me.
Look...
Do you still take those jobs?
From China.
Of course.
You made a wise decision.
Didn't you hear about
Captain Hong?
He now became a construction
worker in Soonchon.
He's hauling bricks
for Christ's sake.
When I heard that,
it just broke my heart.
Who are we?
We're sailors, aren't we?
Sailors should make a living
at sea!
Enough bullshit.
Just give me the coordinates.
Captain. This is where the
money is now.
Aren't you curious
what you're shipping?
I just deliver.
Isn't it gold watches?
I just got this job.
Smuggling immigrants.
Not crates. Immigrants...
Smuggling in
Korean-Chinese people.
They call it 'croaker fishing'
in lncheon.
The government started busting,
so it came down south.
Now it's here in Yeosu.
Here, the coordinates.
Technically it's smuggling,
but we're doing
a great service for our country.
Without their cheap labor,
the economy won't sustain.
For you and your wife.
Call it a deposit.
This fake crap worth shit?
Are you kidding me?
Trust is important in this
line of work.
Let it be a symbol of
our mutual trust.
This is the actual deposit.
What if we get caught?
Just bring them over
in the fish hold.
What if we get caught with them
on the boat?
That's the Junjin crew's business.
That's a given
when transporting cargo.
Name check
for the departing crew.
Bos'n.
- And you, Kyung-koo?
- I'm on drum winch duty.
- I'm Dong-sik.
- Dong-sik.
- Where's Chang-wook?
- He's in the engine room.
Chang-wook?
Here.
You' re the engineer?
Yeah, so?
You?
That asshole.
One, two, three, four, five.
How come the crew is so small
these days?
The catch isn't so good.
That's why.
The weather forecast
doesn't look good.
We can't just sit around.
Gotta at least try.
I hope you catch enough
to cover the gas.
Wan-ho, this should stop.
Are you going to hide forever?
For as long as I owe money.
I'm a sailor. I'm fine as long as
I end up on a boat.
What's with the oil
on your face?
Here, let me help.
I look cool, right?
You know l...
Kyung-koo.
...fixed up the engine room.
Get everyone in the the cabin.
I have something to say.
If we get caught,
don't we all go to prison?
Of course.
Smuggling immigrants ain't a joke.
How much are we getting?
Forget the money.
How can the captain decide
without telling us?
Imagine why he'd go to
that snake, Yeo.
It's cuz he cares about us.
Still! Transporting people
won't be easy.
Then there'll be chicks among
the immigrants, right?
Sit, sit.
Bos'n.
This is an advance for all.
Once we unload the immigrants,
you get the rest.
So let's not screw up.
Okay?
Wan-ho, let's do a complete overhaul
on the engine room.
- But...
- Come on!
Eat.
Let's go eat.
Heavy rain is expected,
so stay cautious.
At sea, waves up to 4 meters
are expected.
Wave alert in effect tonight
all across the South Sea.
But should be calm tomorrow
once the rain stops.
Colder temperatures,,,
- Captain. Your dinner.
- Come in.
What?
Have you ever...
smuggled in people before?
Don't tell your grandmother.
You got that?
- Yes, sir.
- Go on.
Yes, Captain.
It's raining hard.
You think it's okay?
Don't worry.
It's gonna pass.
How many are we boarding?
Bos'n! Ho-young!
- Yes, Captain!
- 1 0 o'clock.
I see a boat coming.
Go take a look.
Chang-wook!
Dong-sik!
Dong-sik.
You watch this side.
Chang-wook!
Do you see anything?
It's too dark.
I can't see anything
cuz of the rain.
1 0 o'clock.
Up ahead in the distance.
I know! I'm looking.
It should be a small boat.
Keep a close watch!
- It's here!
- Where? Where!
9 o'clock.
- Over there.
- Where?
Turn on the searchlight!
Wait.
Need to make sure.
If it's the right one,
they'll signal.
That must be the right boat.
What is this? A game?
- What the fuck?
- It's a freighter?
Attention!
Let's get ready!
Load them up quick.
- Is this the Junjin?
- Yes.
Bring the boat closer!
Be careful!
- What?
- Throw the rope!
Boat closer!
- Pull it!
- Sending your way!
Throw the bags!
Jump, jump!
It's okay.
It's okay. Jump!
Now!
Watch where you jump!
Whose bag is this?
This is a complete mess.
Hurry up. Jump!
Go to the back!
Hey, sit down!
Please help these women.
Shit! That's bad luck.
Women on my ship...
- Hold on!
- I got you.
I want to do it.
Let me!
Here.
Come to me!
- Stretch your arm!
- I got it!
- Now!
- One, two, three!
Watch your step.
Hey, you.
Come to me!
I'll grab you. Over here!
Do you want to get caught?
Hurry up!
Haven't got all night.
Over here!
It's okay! Trust me!
Give me your hand!
Don't look down!
Here.
Untie the ropes!
Dong-sik, put these away!
No, no!
Someone fell in the water!
Dong-sik!
Son of a bitch.
Turn on the searchlight!
Chang-wook! Quick!
- Where'd he go?
- Dong-sik!!
Captain Kang,
turn on the lights!
Dong-sik's going to die
out there.
That crazy son of a bitch.
- Dong-sik!
- Where are you?
Hold tight.
We have to do
mouth-to-mouth.
She needs mouth-to-mouth.
- What the hell is wrong with you?
- What?
She needs it.
Dong-sik!
Are you crazy?
Waves can swallow you up!
You think it's a joke?
Let's all gather over here!
Don't go in there!
Keep everyone out of
the engine room!
Are we supposed to
give these out?
You ignorant bastard.
Never been on Korean Air?
Meals are served right after
take off.
Like you've been on one.
Now...
each person take one ramen.
- Take just one.
- Water is limited, so take what's given.
Oh, no...
You' re all wet.
Which do you want?
Thank you.
Chang-wook. Chang-wook!
What are you doing?
Look at that guy sitting
dangerously on the anchor line.
Go stop him!
- Come out of there!
- Sorry, no more water.
Oh, no.
You're all wet...
Here, this will warm you up.
Haven't I seen you before?
Open the thermos.
Sure we haven't met?
You have to put this away.
Why did you?
That's your food.
You really meant for us
to eat it?
Is this boat going
straight in?
Yeah, of course.
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
Why're you so suspicious?
Then why hand these out?
This is to put us
in the fish hold for days,
so we can shit here.
What? Why shit in that?
There's a bathroom.
There's a bathroom back there!
Is this your first smuggling job?
Why?
Listen up!
Don't eat it. Salty food will
only make you thirsty.
This is our toilet.
- What's his problem?
- We're only trying to be nice.
Don't sit on the net.
- You shouldn't be here.
- What?
Come, It's cold out.
Watch your feet.
What are you doing?
It's okay. Go inside.
Watch your head.
Where're you taking me?
This is the engine room.
Never seen one before, right?
It's a little noisy,
but it's nice and warm.
What are you waiting for?
Watch your head.
I can go by myself.
- Come here.
- Let me go.
- Let me go!
- Stay still.
This is the best for
seasickness.
What are you doing?
You have to rub the arm
and circulate the blood first.
My grandma just shoves
the needle right in.
Your grandmother is wrong.
Here...
Too late for that.
Hands off!
Thank you...
for saving my life earlier.
That was nothing.
I'm a sailor, you know.
Sit over there.
Do you remember
what happened in the water?
Yes.
You squeezed my neck so tight,
I thought it'd break.
- Really?
- Yeah...
What's your blood type?
Why do you ask?
I'm a type O.
Hey! You're not nauseous
anymore.
- Hold on a minute.
- Where are you going?
Just wait a sec.
Captain Kang.
Why'd you stop the boat?
We're on standby.
It's too risky to go in now.
They're going to call us.
We'll just have to wait.
Going to keep them out like that?
What if someone sees?
There're no boats at this hour.
Don't worry. I'll put them all
in the fish hold.
The fish hold.
You should get some sleep,
or something to eat.
Dong-sik just took
the last ramen.
You can't pamper him
cuz he's young.
He has to learn the work.
Why did the boat
suddenly stop?
Probably nothing. Maybe just to
meet the schedule.
Have you ever tried this
in China?
Of course.
This is 'fanbeimei'.
What?
Pang-gah-mae.
Pangahmae.
Guess that's what you call it.
You have it in China too?
I've never
had this kind before.
It's 'cup'-pangahme.
It's probably ready.
Careful, it's hot.
Look at me.
I forgot the kimchi.
No, it's okay.
Do you want some?
No, you go ahead
and eat.
Can I have a sip?
It's good.
You made it...
Right.
Actually, this isn't the
real deal.
To cook the real pangahmae
that we fishermen eat,
you start with the seafood.
Crabs, sea squirts, octopus,
sea cucumbers, oysters,
and turban shells.
You put these in.
Then the sliced up hot pepper.
That's a real pangahmae fit for
a Yeosu fisherman.
You wouldn't know.
By the way, how old are you
to keep talking down?
I'm...
twenty-six.
- Born in 1 974?
- Yeah.
Never mind then.
What's your name?
I'm Dong-sik.
You?
I' m Hong-mae.
Hong-mae.
Hong-mae...
How'd you end up on a
boat like this?
I' m going to Korea
to find my older brother.
He's been gone for 6 years,
but we haven't heard from him.
What's your relation to
this brother?
You don't know what
a brother is?
Course I know.
Your real brother?
- Yes.
- Oh!
It's just that in Korea, girls have
many kinds of brothers.
So... where is your brother?
In Seoul...
Oh, no!
It's all wet.
#247-6 Guro 3-dong.
Guro 3-dong.
Guro Gongdan Station.
On subway line #2.
I've been there. The subway
runs above ground.
- Then it's not a subway.
- No, it is.
It just runs above ground.
Then they should call it
an aboveground train.
I should go up to the deck.
You can stay here.
I'll talk to the engineer.
I can't stay here when
everyone else is in the cold.
Thank you for the ramen.
Have you already been to
the engine room?
Sorry?
I saw everything.
What did you do there?
What are you talking about?
A woman on a smuggling boat's
engine room, it's obvious.
Get yourself a marriage certificate
as soon as we arrive.
Then you'll be a Korean citizen.
You won't get deported.
I'm not interested.
Stop it.
He looked cute for a fisherman.
Nice little face and all.
You're unbelievable.
Why did you come back out?
It's warm in there.
Go back in. Come on.
Cover her feet too.
It's cold.
Anyone else hurt?
Can I get a Band-Aid?
What are you doing?
Nothing, nothing...
I'm sure we met before.
What on earth are you
talking about?
Come here.
Did you drink the water
I gave you?
- Are you warm now?
- Not warm enough.
I better take you to a
warmer place then.
Well, if you insist.
Watch the ropes.
Can I sleep here?
Of course.
Do you have leftover blankets?
Blankets?
We'll have nice, soft blankets
on the floor.
Can I stay here until
we arrive, huh?
That's exactly what I want.
You can stay for a
thousand years.
We can fool around
all we want.
Hey!
What the fuck?
- Pull it out, you little shit!
- Hold on!
Told you not to do it
on the boat! It's bad luck!
I was almost there.
- Get out!
- I'm staying!
Get a grip!
I didn't do it!
- Get out!
- I'm going!
Get over there!
Asshole.
Careful not to catch a cold.
Thank you.
Can I ask what you do? How can you
read a book in the middle of all this?
I was a grade school teacher.
Oh my...
A school teacher on
a boat like this.
We can make 1 0 times more
working in Korea.
You know that.
No one here is going there
to stuff his own belly.
They're all going for their
families back home.
It's the same for us.
What is that?
My wife and daughters.
Your daughters are very pretty.
Wake up.
Boat approaching.
Wake your asses up!
There's a boat coming!
Sit down, sit down.
Listen closely.
A boat is coming,
so get in the fish hold.
If they see you, we get
in trouble.
Dong-sik, open the hatch.
And get the ladder.
Hurry up and help him.
Be careful!
Move out of the way.
Use the ladder to go down.
Be careful.
It's deeper than you think.
Don't push!
To the engine room.
No, I won't go.
Want me there instead?
Come here.
Hurry up with the ladder!
Come on!
Come on, hurry.
Out the way.
Careful. Hold my hand.
Move out the way!
Move!
Poor thing.
It smells bad, right?
- Do I have to go in there?
- I know, it's horrible.
Not on the net.
I knew this would happen.
I'd better give you the
acupuncture remedy again.
Come here.
It's the smell.
That's what we fishermen
smell like.
Dong-Sik!
Fetch the mop!
- Go inside.
- Again?
Stay in the engine room
until we arrive.
No, it doesn't feel right.
I can't stand you being in
the fish hold.
Hey!
Are you going to put us
in there again?
That fish hold is no place
for people.
It's meant for fish.
There's nowhere else to hide.
Just hang on.
You'll get used to it
after a couple of times.
It can be several days.
Let us in the cabin or
the engine room.
Put us somewhere else.
The engine room?
Yeah, right.
Why didn't you just take
Korean Air then?
We paid a lot to be
on this boat.
Didn't you get your cuts?
How can you treat fellow Koreans
worse than the Chinese?
Don't you agree?
Yeah! He's right!
Fellow Korean my ass.
Do you know what lMF is?
These are rough times, pal.
Fellow Koreans?
It's hard enough cuz of
the lMF crisis!
Give us our money back!
You low-life scumbags.
Sit down!
Sit down. Sit.
You South Korean scumbag!
I'll fucking kill you!
Captain!
You have to save him.
He could get killed!
Then you stay in the
engine room?
Captain Kang!
Stop! That's Dong-sik!
- You'll kill him.
- Yeah, it's enough.
Bos'n.
- Yes, Captain.
- Throw him in the water.
Are you deaf?!
Move over!
No, no!
- One, two, three!
- No!
You motherfuckers!
You fucking assholes!
Listen up!
On this boat, I'm the president,
the judge, and your freakin' father!
Your life is in my hands.
Understand?
Please forgive us.
Please help me!
- Please help! Help!
- Let's go inside.
- Please save me!
- Dong-sik, go help him.
I want to live!
Fucking South Korean scumbags.
Fuck!
Try to bear the smell a bit.
I'll keep the hatch open.
Thank you. See you later.
How could you...?
This wasn't the deal!
- It's the bos'n.
- Hey, Kyung-koo.
You go help Dong-Sik
with the rope.
Yes, sir.
Asshole.
Go fuck yourself.
Let me help you with
your bag.
Get off me.
- Let me help you go in.
- Hey! What is this!
Get up.
It's nice in here, right?
Once I put this blanket here,
it'll be like first class.
This blanket's clean.
You just sit back and relax.
Wait a minute.
Are you trying to take
advantage of me?
No way.
Never.
I'm not capable of doing
such a thing. Really!
I mean...
I can do it cuz I'm a man.
Healthy and all...
But I'm not the kind
who'd treat a lady like that.
Yeah...
That's what I meant.
When I go to Seoul,
I'll invite you to Guro 3-dong.
- I promise.
- Really?
Seoul is very far away.
You can take a few days off.
True... Will you let me sleep
at your place?
We always have days off when
we return from sea.
Promise me you'll come?
Dong-sik?
Are you in here?
Yes?
What are you doing?
Get up here.
Wan-ho!
What?
Come here.
Is it okay if Hong-mae
stays here?
Stay here where it's comfortable.
I'm the engineer.
In here, he's the king.
Even the Captain respects him.
This is the Taechang.
Patrol ship is making its rounds.
This is the Junjin.
Where exactly?
What brings you all the way
to international waters?
International waters?
What's wrong, Junjin?
Catch some endangered fish?
Get ready to fish.
Cover the fish hold
with the net.
Hurry!
Wan-ho, hide inside.
Stay absolutely still,
and don't make a sound!
- Will they be okay in there?
- lt'll be fine. Act natural.
Junjin!
Turn off your engine, hah?
Bring me closer to the boat.
I know these guys well,
so wait over there.
Don't just stand around.
You look younger every time.
What's wrong with your hair?
And you must be new.
Wan-ho!
Still hiding from debt collectors?
Come out!
Get up.
- Dick caught in the net, huh?
- What are you doing?
What did you catch?
Covering it all up.
We didn't catch shit.
We haven't even started.
Why are you sitting out
in this cold?
Let's go upstairs.
I'm busy today so let's have
a quick drink out here.
What are you, the Mafia?
Why are you standing around?
Dong-sik, go get the
leftover sashimi.
Get ready to cast the net.
I have something to discuss
with Chief Kim.
Measuring my mesh size?
Getting strict on me now?
Can't help it.
This is bureaucracy.
My men are watching.
I have to do it right.
- You can go now.
- Yes, Captain.
Seems like the mesh is
a little too small.
It would have been nicer
on the bridge.
So sweet.
This is the perk of being
a fisherman.
What was that?
Wait...
Did you hear that?
Is it coming from below?
Is Wan-ho fixing something
again?
Oh... Wan-ho!
He's fixing the radiator, sir.
It's an old boat.
The radiator is rusty.
Radiator?
It keeps breaking down.
Shit.
You won't find anything on
an old boat.
So go catch the big fish.
What time is it?
Let me see.
Heard these are quite popular
in Yeosu nowadays.
What are you talking about?
Come on.
Think you can fish these
without cutting me in?
I'm a sailor too. Need to make
a living out in the sea.
I've no idea what you're saying.
We'll miss the fish.
You should go.
We have to start working.
Damn it.
Do you want me to open this
to make my point?
What the hell are you doing?
If you're really a sailor, mind your
freakin' manners on my boat.
Who the hell are you?
Threatening to open my fish hold.
Get down here!
Open it!
It'll be your grave!
Such a temper.
Let's not do this
in front of the boys.
Asshole.
See you at Yeo's office.
I'm leaving.
Hey!
Hey! He's leaving!
Looks like a sea fog is
creeping in!
See you back on the
golden shore!
Sea fog my ass.
Kyung-koo!
Put this away.
- Open the hatch.
- Yes, sir.
What are you waiting for?
Are they asleep?
Must be sleeping.
Guess they got used to it here.
Sleeping on top of each other,
not minding the smell anymore.
Are you okay?
Hey!
Hey?
Get up.
Come on. Get up!
Anybody awake?
Get out.
The gas leaked.
- Gas?
- Don't breathe!
Dong-sik, come out.
Come out!
- Don't close the hatch.
- What's wrong?
He says the gas leaked.
Shit. Wan-ho!
Wan-ho!
- What happened?
- What is it?
It's Freon gas.
The freezer must've exploded.
- They' re all dead...
- Look!
He just moved.
He's still alive, Captain.
You guys, get back.
Go away.
Dong-sik.
Open the hatch
and let the gas out.
Guys, get the ladder.
Go down there once it's clear.
- Bos'n.
- Yes, Captain.
Bring all the bodies
up to the deck.
Sir?
It's better...
that they're all dead.
Dong-sik.
I think that's all of them.
- Right?
- Yeah...
Move!
What are you doing?
We have to draw the blood.
It'll attract the fish.
Better to be fed to the fish than
be bloated corpses.
If one of them
washes up ashore,
we're all finished.
Got it?
Wan-ho, you want to be in prison
or with your daughter?
You too, bos'n.
Make sure it's done properly.
Are we really doing this?
We have no choice.
It's the captain's orders.
We have to obey.
- Here.
- That's right.
Why're you standing around?
You're in your work clothes,
aren't you?
They're all dead.
It's not like it's going to
hurt, right?
Look, they're fine...
They're dead anyway.
We're doing them a favor.
Wan-ho, don't just stand there.
Dong-sik, you too.
Dong-sik, you go in.
He's just a kid, who went to
a marine science magnet.
What the hell?
He gets excused just cuz
he went to marine science high?
- You fucking...
- Stop it!
It's no time to fight.
Dong-sik, get to it.
What's your problem?
Goddamn it. Stop fighting
and get back to work!
There's no time.
Look at all the bodies!
See, chop the big ones up
into smaller pieces.
Otherwise they might surface.
Got it?
There was another girl
besides this woman.
Chang-wook,
what are you mumbling about?
Let's get to it.
We should hurry up.
- That one's big.
- Look, like this.
Look at him go.
Not shy after all.
With the small ones,
just draw blood and throw over.
Should be fine, right?
The intestines are
spilling out of this one.
What? I can't hear you.
Yeah, that's what I meant.
Here it is.
What the hell are you
mumbling about?
I'll let them know.
Really?
Let's see. It's hot...
Okay.
I'll let them know.
Is someone in here?
Anyone?
Kyung-koo!
You have that girl,
don't you?
The little one
Turning silent cuz I'm here?
I'll tell the bos'n.
- Chang-wook!
- Holy shit!
- Scared the shit out of me.
- What are you doing there?
Why?
Hurry up. The bos'n called
a meeting.
Come on.
Son of a bitch.
Creeping up on me.
Don't push.
- Hold still.
- You asshole!
Don't move.
Kyung-koo, did you see
that young chick?
How the hell should
I know?
- Should've had that woman.
- What're you saying?
You had her,
but I never got my turn.
Out of your minds?
What the hell?!
Get your shit together.
Listen up.
Nothing happened on
this boat today.
- No, no!
- What?
We can keep this a secret for
the rest of our life, right?
To be honest,
why should we care?
Captain ordered the smuggling
and chopping the bodies.
What?
If I tell the police,
the captain goes to prison.
What the fuck is wrong
with everyone?
We're all in the same boat.
It's literally a boat.
We're all in it!
- Bos'n.
- What?
Once the fog clears,
we're heading for shore, right?
That's right.
Then it's all over.
Hong-mae.
I know...
It's your last wish.
Wan-ho?
Stop doing this to me.
I should've listened.
Watch your head!
It's so hot.
They're burning.
Wan-ho, are you okay?
Hong-mae.
You can come out now.
I brought real ramen,
the pangahme for you.
- We didn't have hot pepper.
- Will you kill me too?
What?
I saw everything.
What are you talking about?
It's not what you think.
Don't come near me.
You have to be quiet.
Yeah, I know.
Take your filthy hands off me.
- Where are you going?
- Have to go home.
- Can you hear me?
- Yeah.
Wan-ho!
- Okay, I got it.
- Wan-ho!
Come down from there.
What?
It's scary up there.
Wan-ho, what are you doing?
My god, you were right.
It must have been so hot.
What are you doing with
dead people's belongings?
Look. Here it is.
Why did you take that out?
We have to burn it.
Why'd you fucking take it out?
This man...
wants me to tell his family
where he is.
I should take this
to the police station, right?
What? Are you saying
you'll turn us in?
We need to ask the police
for his address.
Forget the police.
This was an accident!
It's cuz the boat was so old!
You know that too!
Kang Chul-joo...
Let's just stop.
It's all my fault.
Wan-ho.
Where are you going?
Let's talk about this.
- Talk about what?
- Let's talk over a drink.
Where's the bottle of soju
you stashed away?
They're already dead.
What's the use!
Let's have a drink together.
What we did today.
Can't keep it just
in our heads forever.
Poor thing.
I'm sorry...
I'll send them the news.
Rest in peace.
I'll follow soon...
Even if I lose my life...
I'm taking you to the shore.
We're going to Guro 3-dong.
Kyung-koo, shine it my way!
The sun is up.
Can't even see in broad daylight.
You!
Where have you been?
Wan-ho's not
in the engine room, right?
Shit.
Where the hell is he?
Kyung-koo!
- Yes, sir.
- Shine it that way!
It's no use.
We can't see anything.
I definitely heard it.
Someone fell in the sea.
- Wan-ho!
- Did you hear anything?
Wan-ho's been acting strange
since yesterday.
Talking to himself and everything.
Can't see a thing.
Wan-ho!
Shit.
Your new place.
What are you doing here?
Can't you see?
Think they know
anything about the engine?
I'm the only one.
So...
you're going to stay down
here now?
What the hell are you doing
in the engine room?
Isn't it weird that
Wan-ho just disappeared?
Wan-ho? Don't remember
anyone like that.
I'm the engineer now.
What are you two doing here?
You two dating?
Move over.
I know Wan-ho used to
stash his...
Dong-sik.
Don't dare tell anyone,
you asshole.
You're keeping it all?
Fuck off.
You can be the engineer.
This is mine.
Kyung-koo, hold on.
Let's split it in half.
- Cut me off some.
- You idiot.
Damn! That's supposed to be
my money!
I'm the engineer.
Do you think there's
anything else?
What else would there be?
Should've looked for
the cash first.
That could have been mine.
Do you smell that?
What?
Chang-wook.
Don't you think Kyung-koo's
been acting weird?
What about?
He keeps taking stuff
and bringing it somewhere.
Like now. He took the money
and went somewhere.
Like he's going to
see someone, a girl.
- Girl?
- Let's follow him.
Kyung-koo, that asshole.
Chang-wook.
Chang-wook!
There she is!
Huh, nothing.
There's nothing here.
Let's just go. Come on.
She's here!
The girl, she's here!
The girl is here!
See? I told you!
Told you there's another girl.
Yeah, she's the one.
The little one.
Don't move.
Stay right there.
Chang-wook, come here.
Let's keep her hidden.
We'll keep it a secret.
Between you and me.
Fine, but she's mine.
I found her.
Also...
imagine Kyung-koo finding her.
No way!
She's all mine.
I'll be the only one
havin' her.
What now?
Let's go up for now.
People will get suspicious.
I want her now.
She'll be here, right?
Hurry up and get over here!
What the hell were you doing?
You lazy asses.
Chang-wook!
You tend to the net.
Dong-sik! On that side.
We're fishing?
- Dong-sik! Unwind anchor.
- Seriously?
What the hell's the point?
In a situation like this.
What situation? Huh?
Cast the net, catch fish,
then we go home.
Let go all lines!
Engine room get ready!
Engine room!
Turn on the generator
and get ready to cast the net.
Get the fuck off her!
Dong-sik, please!
Huh?
"Dong-sik, please"?
You already did her,
haven't you?
You already did.
She's fucking mine.
When did you do it?
What are you two doing?
Captain!
He's hiding a girl.
He's been hiding her
all along.
Captain.
She really doesn't know anything.
She's been here the whole time.
I don't know anything.
What would I know?
And... when we get to Yeosu,
I'm going to make her
my bride.
We're going to get married.
Even if she knows something,
I'm her husband.
She couldn't possibly tell
the police, right?
So she did see something.
Captain.
I'll be responsible for her.
Stupid fuck. If she tells anyone,
we're doomed.
No.
Dong-sik!
She's not your problem.
He's going to snitch on you!
- You crazy asshole.
- Kyung-koo's going to snitch?
Kyung-koo's part of
the Junjin crew.
- Am I right?
- Yes, sir.
Dong-sik, you're part of
the Junjin crew, right?
Yes, sir.
What about her?
What is she?
- Dong-sik.
- What about Wan-ho?
If we're all part of the crew,
why did you kill him? Why?
You must be out of your mind.
Bos'n.
Make sure she's
properly taken care of.
So she doesn't float.
- Dong-sik!
- What are you doing?!
Kill me instead!
- Dong-sik.
- Hong-mae!
- Dong-sik!
Bos'n! This is murder!
I know.
- Hong-mae!
- Dong-sik.
Get your shit together.
You don't even know her.
Are you going to risk the crew,
our families,
and the Junjin
just because of that girl?
She's nothing!
Captain...
I haven't done it with her yet.
Can't kill her yet.
- I'll be back.
- What the hell...?
Hong-mae.
Hong-mae!
No!
You freakin' bastard!
Hong-mae!
You bastard!
Enough is enough!
Where's Hong-mae?
Where are you fuckers?
Hong-mae!
Where's Dong-sik?
Son of a bitch.
Hit the same place twice?
Where's Dong-sik?
Did you get him?
Captain,
Hong-mae went...
- What?
- No... Shit!
Son of a bitch lost his mind.
Kyung-koo!
Shit... Bos'n!
The bridge!
Coast Guard!
Junjin to Coast Guard!
What are you doing?!
- Door's locked!
- 1 27 degrees east,
33 degrees north.
Out of the way!
Did you copy?
Junjin to Coast Guard!
This is the Junjin!
1 27 degrees east...
You ungrateful piece of shit.
Get him out.
Come here,
you son of a bitch.
Where's Hong-mae?
You know where she is, right?
Let me go.
Coast Guard to Junjin!
- Coast Guard can't do shit.
- Have you hit a reef?
Calling nearby vessels
to the rescue!
Coordinates are useless
in a sea fog.
127 degrees...
Get inside.
In there, you piece of shit.
Kyung-koo, I'll find the girl.
Stay here.
Look closely.
Dong-sik, you stay put!
Coast Guard patrol is
on its way!
Junjin, there are a lot of freighters
in your area.
It's dangerous cuz of the sea fog,
so stop your engine and wait.
Hong-mae!
Hong-mae...
Hong-mae.
It's me, Dong-sik.
I' m sorry. So sorry.
I have to go home.
I need to go home...
We will.
We' ll go home.
We'll go home together.
Coast Guard will be here soon.
Just hang on for a bit.
Hong-mae...
I hate it here.
There, there.
You're with me now.
Hong-mae's in here, right?
Couldn't find her
anywhere else.
Did you do it with her again?
Did you?
Look at our little Dong-sik.
You're scary.
You were doing her,
weren't you?
What the fuck?
How many times, huh?
Hong-mae, Hong-mae!
You little...
Now that you're up close,
your skin is so fair...
You!
You again!
You! Trying to do it
all by yourself again!
I didn't even get to do it.
You two already took turns.
Are you okay?
Hong-mae, you okay?
Let's do it here.
Gosh, it smells in here.
Hong-mae.
Hong-mae!
Where are you taking her?
Wait here. I'll take care of
everything from here.
You're not going anywhere,
right?
I'm not going anywhere.
That son of a bitch.
Completely broke the engine.
Dong-sik.
If the Coast Guard finds us...
we all go to prison and
she gets deported.
Deported.
Got it?
If we shut her up...
Lay a hand on her and
I'll kill you first!
You son of a bitch,
do you really want to die?
You damn bitch.
What are you?
What the hell are you?
Are you a person
or a witch?
What the hell?
There's a hole?
Get up.
Shit!
The ship's leaking!
Kyung-koo!
Chang-wook!
Shit!
Stop right there!
Dong-sik!
Dong-sik! Hurry!
Ho-young!
Hong-mae!
We have to untie this
to use the buoy.
Help! Help!
Who is that?
Chang-wook, is that you?
Yes! Captain!
Captain, the ladder!
The ladder!
Who is that?
Kyung-koo!
Go to the engine room.
The hull is punctured,
so go and plug the hole.
- Or the boat may sink.
- Lot of holes here too.
Did we hit something?
Captain! The girl!
Don't kill her!
Plug the hole!
Useless fools.
I'm the only one
who hasn't done it yet!
She's mine!
Bos'n!
Where'd you all go?
Dong-sik!
We have to save the ship.
I can't stop the leak.
Let me out.
I'm scared!
- Dong-sik, you bastard!
- Go up.
What are you doing?
The boat is about to sink!
You crazy son of a bitch.
I'll throw that bitch.
Throw her in the ocean.
Come here!
- Let me go!
- Don't touch her!
- You've gone insane!
- I'll kill you!
Dong-sik!
I'm the captain of this boat!
We have to...
at least save the boat.
Come on, Dong-sik.
You're no captain.
You are a murderer.
Murderer!
Let's throw the anchor in
the water together.
Wake up.
Our boat is done for!
This is the Coast Guard patrol!
Junjin, we have poor visibility!
Sound your horn!
Dong-sik,
it's the Coast Guard.
- Hong-mae.
- Junjin! Junjin vessel!
It's time to go home.
Sound your horn!
Junjin!
Sound your damn horn!
We can't see you!
Sound your horn!
We have to throw all this
over board.
It's too heavy.
It' ll sink the boat.
Guys, the boat...
We can save the boat.
Dong-sik...
Dong-sik.
Dong-sik!
We have to go home...
Go home...
It's okay.
Hong-mae.
Dong-sik.
Thank you...
6 years later
Hey, Kim!
How about some pork barbeque
with soju?
- What about Guro-dong Dongpo pork?
- Dongpo pork?
- Where?
- Where we went last week.
Nah, it wasn't good.
Let's go. Pork barbecue or
Dongpo pork, whichever.
What would you like?
Ramen with rice cake.
One ramen with rice cake!
Got it!
Ma'am.
Do you have hot pepper?
- For the ramen?
- Yes, please.
Can you chop one up
for me?