SEASIDE
Summer
You got to sleep in the end?
Yeah, sort of.
- Hi, Pierre.
- Hi, Paul.
Here on holiday?
Yes, we just got here.
We haven't seen you for a while.
I don't have much time to come.
So...
How's the job going?
Pretty good. I'm pleased.
We saw some of your photos
in a fashion magazine.
You know...
those models are hot.
Well, not bad anyhow
How about you?
I'm working as a lifeguard.
I should be on holiday
but I like it...
and the sea's nice too.
Here for a while?
Yes, you'll probably see me around.
See you.
Coming, Lilas?
Did you have a good night?
I already told you.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Did I say something wrong?
Hey, she's pretty.
True, Marie is pretty.
Go and have some fun.
I like to watch people dance.
Want another one?
Excuse me.
I'm sorry...
Mum's here.
- She's here?
- I'm really sick of it!
I'll deal With it.
What a bloody nerve!
Go home right now, please.
Let go of my arm.
You're hurting me!
Let go or I won't go home.
The pain in the ass!
A real pain in the ass!
She'll get her three lemons
one day.
Let me finish my cup.
It's ridiculous.
Let her have a bit of fun.
I'm going home.
- Want me to come?
- I have to be up early.
I'll see you home anyway.
I'll be fine.
See you.
I dreamt I was flying.
For the Taoists,
the ultimate freedom
is being a butterfly
Oh yeah?
Albert, your mum will be upset
if you don't pick her up.
Tell her I'm working.
It's a pity.
It's going to be sunny
Albert, Blanchard's here again.
The joke's gone on long enough.
Make sure he doesn't come back.
I'll try but he'll be back anyway
You don't know the locals.
Don't piss me off, okay!
Blanchard,
you're on early retirement.
There's no work for you any more.
You signed the paper
It's too late now.
Why don't you go for a swim?
Your dad’s never have allowed it.
Fives, please.
Just a second.
You smell nice.
Seen Marie this morning?
I saw her ride by.
She seemed to be thinking of you.
- How was she?
- I only saw her ride by.
Do you ever talk to her?
Yeah, sometimes.
Do you ever talk about me?
Marie's not like that.
That's true.
Paul!
Mum! Casino!
I hear you!
She should get herself banned,
like any big loser.
At roulette, not slot machines!
Know what I think?
If I didn't work there,
I'd try to get the place closed.
Three in a row! I got it!
Ten thousand!
I'm quitting now It's over.
I promise.
I'm quitting.
I can do oysters as a starter.
It's a bit much with scallops.
You can't open oysters anyhow
I thought I'd dropped my purse.
A bit off-color, isn't he?
- He should stop smoking.
- He works too much.
And doesn't eat properly
A week here will do him good.
I'll do sole tomorrow.
Pierre loves that.
What do you do in Paris?
Actually...
all kinds of odds and ends...
I'm still looking for myself.
Do you study?
Not much.
We call it Little Siberia.
Have you been coming here
on holiday for long?
Since forever.
A hundred years ago,
it was a very select resort.
My grandparents came every year.
I'm not in Paris right now
but it's not a problem.
I can be there in the morning.
Ah...
It's weird,
people in swimsuits on a beach...
- Are you staying all summer?
- Sure.
- Don't you fancy traveling?
- We can't do it all.
Can't you stop smoking?
When I work, I don't have time.
Do you fancy oysters for dinner?
Really?
I was going to get scallops.
Pity you're leaving so soon.
Coming?
What is it?
A pebble quarry
For souvenirs?
I've no idea.
When I was a kid,
I'd count pebbles to get to sleep.
Haven't you ever done photos here?
In the fashion business,
you travel far away
to be taken seriously.
This seems far away.
Hi, Marie.
Hello.
On your break?
Okay? Not too hot?
We could have dinner or lunch
some time.
Whatsit you tell your wife?
The truth.
- Meaning?
- That I'm seeing a colleague.
We're not colleagues.
We don't get the same pay
I expected Albert to come.
No, Odette. He's working.
You look really rested anyhow
I'm as white as a sheet!
That tunnel...
Crossing the Channel does me in.
It's horrible being under the water
Really?
Personally, I like the idea
of burrowing into the earth.
You still don't smoke?
Me?
I left my cigarettes on the train.
..It. ...too late...
to go back for them now
How's Albert?
He's okay.
A carton of Dunhill Reds, please.
It's a while since we saw her.
She's certainly got class.
- So you say.
- Exactly.
- At least She gets to travel.
- We worked, Denise.
We didn't play the tart.
If the boss had fancied you,
you wouldn't have said no.
Marry the boss!
Are you feeling all right?
Show a bit of respect.
That old goat! Honestly..
At least my husband
had a bit of class.
Still, I think she has a good life.
Had a good holiday?
London's so expensive now.
I stayed at the M,ridien.
Good service, nice and comfy.
I didn't want to bother your brother
Is he well?
Lovely kids...
How's your work going?
Okay.
You're home late.
Your dad worked a lot
but he was always home by six.
The plant went bankrupt.
He couldn't invest.
The machinery was old,
he had too many workers...
- But the site was a goldmine.
- So you rented it out.
He'd have done the same.
Is it that hard for you to hug me?
Don't be absurd.
This is a sight for sore eyes.
These journeys exhaust me.
I'd never have done dinner for myself.
The pleasure's mine.
Don't worry. She's a dreamer.
I'm not worried.
Let's go to the beach.
Don't you think he sees
enough of the beach?
Let's sit down.
I don't like
the bathing huts at night.
A dog'll pee on you one day!
I want to live with you.
What for?
Just say yes or no.
I can't go on like this.
Winter
Did you sleep well?
Think I'm fat?
You're my sister.
Have you seen mum today?
- We need to see to her heating.
- 500 francs won't kill us.
Cold, isn't it?
We used to freeze on the sorting bench,
your mum and me.
Paul!
Is Rose all right?
Yeah, she's okay.
It can't always
have been easy for her.
No, it's okay.
If there's anything I can do...
Give them this
to keep the bailiffs away.
I'll see to the heater myself.
Why don't you ask Odette?
Rose?
It's Odette.
You're being stupid now
It's been so long, Rose!
Exactly! What's got into her?
She's like my dog.
He knows when I'm not happy
Go now
or you'll miss your soap.
Total absence...
State corresponding to a total absence
"of real particles."""
In four letters.
I respect your mother.
She fought for your job
when we bought your father's firm.
You don't seem happy here.
My great-grandfather
founded this firm.
World leader in sea pebbles
from father to son.
Why did you choose this job?
Out of heredity
No, I don't know.
Out of politeness.
Does my contract end
in three months or now?
Now, I think.
Another guy will be happy here.
- You've found someone?
- Yes.
Make it three months.
Blanchard's in the yard.
What's new?
I'd like to go away with you.
- I'm leaving my job.
- you always say that.
You know,
your mother doesn't need you.
You can waste your whole life
on others.
So why do you stay with me?
Because I love you.
I wait for you to change but you don't.
We're all waiting for something.
She's mortgaged her house.
Now your pension's gone,
you had to gamble the house away?
We keep telling you
no one ever wins!
I just thought I was bound
to hit the jackpot in the end.
Casinos are for the rich.
Play if you can afford to lose
Whatsit you do now?
I'll find a place to rent.
What With?
You're broke!
Don't look so grim!
It's not that serious.
We don't have a dog.
She can sleep on the couch.
What's up?
Are you crazy too?
It's nothing. It happens.
It's all so serious with him.
It's not because of you.
200,000 francs in slot machines!
Just think!
Early retirement's driven her
round the bend.
She doesn't like TV
What else can she do here?
Right, I have to get back.
Maybe I'll come to see you.
Hey, Albertine! You know what?
You look like a star!
The dresser will look good
at your sister's.
One more house to sell in Cayeux.
That's your inheritance gone.
You should have thought of that.
No more gambling now
I'm sick of it.
You think it's funny!
I had a few drinks with your sister
It cheered us up.
They're doing fashion photos!
We're going to see.
Maybe I'll join you.
It's a tough life,
always on the move.
Not many of them make the big time.
Not the prettiest either.
Wow, it's pretty dead here.
When I was a kid,
it felt like the moon.
- Twenty years, right?
- Yes, twenty.
Already?
Time flies
and we're not getting younger
I hope I'll get the champagne.
After twenty years,
I got the champagne,
a nice bouquet of flowers
and an envelope.
I hope I get all that too.
I think so.
Okay?
Did things change
when the firm was sold?
Not for me because I kept my job.
No one cares when an old family firm
gets swallowed up.
A boss is a boss.
The bonuses aren't any better
You're drinking, Lucille!
It warms you up, right?
What's wrong, mum?
Nothing.
- How's the plant?
- I won't be staying.
Really? Why not?
There's a new albumen bearing.
It's a 100%-sure grinding agent.
There are always some impurities
in pebbles.
It's a lot more expensive now
but the costs will soon drop.
You believe that?
Raw material costs are down.
Aluminium is worth nothing.
You know your brother
has a new apartment?
He has? That's great.
What a success!
What a success...
I wanted you to have
a good education,
and go to university
After, you were free.
- Want some coffee?
- No.
It's a good idea
to look for a new job elsewhere.
Spring
Work: problems to sort out,
deal with the most urgent now
The rest will fall into place.
Romance:
old feelings return to the fore.
You thought it was all over
but the heart is a surprising hunter
"Health: migraines possible."""
Coffee with milk, please.
- Are you well?
- I'm okay.
How's your son?
I'm going to be a grandmother
That's nice.
I can still see the two of you
paddling in the water all day
We were only little.
It was long ago.
It feels like yesterday to me.
Good bye.
You've got a nerve,
staring at people like that!
I'm sorry?
I caught too many.
We'll give the rest away.
Does it hurt?
It's nothing.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
- Has something upset you?
- No.
You're not coming?
My head's spinning.
Can I help?
I don't feel well.
I'm going home.
Take your things with you.
What are the pebbles used for?
To make washbasins, I think.
Things like that.
Bathroom fittings...
- Ceramics?
- That's right.
What do you do exactly?
Basically,
we take the unsorted pebbles
and the machine sorts them.
Then the girls sort them again.
Some pebbles are no good?
They wouldn't need us otherwise
Some are oxidized or broken
so we dump those.
- Where?
- Back in the sea.
The tide brings them back later
The oxidized ones can get cleaned.
If the oxide's not too deep,
the friction can clean them up.
But not all of them.
There you are...
Where do all the pebbles go?
All over the world.
Asia, I think. Italy.
Everywhere, in fact.
I've been coming here
since I was a baby and I didn't know
It doesn't matter.
I'm seeing you everywhere today.
It's not hard in a place this small.
True.
I felt like taking a walk...
Not very cheerful, is it?
Ever thought of leaving?
The shrimp turns pink
when it hits the boiling water
Are you hungry?
Do you remember Marie?
The girl who used to play with Pierre?
She works at the pebble plant.
She's a worker.
Really?
If one gets out alive,
we'll call him Super Shrimp.
He), grandma!
Lost your sense of humor?
You piss me off with your shrimps!
The stones are tough.
Sometimes, I was fit to drop.
Turn the fuckingT\/ down.
We're chatting
and we didn't even notice.
When it's not him, it's her
There's always something wrong.
It takes guts and sex
to keep a relationship going.
Maybe they just need to be alone
for a while.
Why don't you come back home?
Or go and see Odette.
She could easily afford the house.
It's a lovely hotel.
Very relaxing.
They wait on you hand and foot.
And it's very young...
- a very young atmosphere.
- I'm not sure, okay.
Why don't you book the tickets
then decide
whether to come or not?
You can do what you like...
but South America gets booked up fast.
Cheers.
Have you found a new job?
I'm not really looking.
You don't really need to work?
I'm taking the time to think.
Careful,
thinking can give you a headache.
You're not at the plant?
I felt sick earlier.
Feeling better now?
Sort of.
Actually, everything's the way
I don't want it to be.
Lucille's at work.
Amiens was dull enough
but this place...
is deadly.
We have the sea.
You'd need to clear the beach.
Tourists won't come to this dump.
Except for yobs.
A beach
is an expanse of sand.
You need to be able
to walk on in it heels
and an evening dress
like a movie star!
We had some English buyers today
I've run you a bath.
Can you watch the pasta?
Marie?
Are you with Marie?
Have you been at the casino?
No, I went to see Denise.
Where are you going?
Three?
Seventy-eight?
Where were you?
- She was asleep.
- No one asked you.
It's true, I was asleep.
Two hours I've been looking for you!
Maybe, but I was asleep.
You could have told me.
You were bound to find me
if I stayed put.
That's what we thought.
Right, Rose?
What are you playing?
Lotto.
I'm serious. I was worried.
You should have looked upstairs.
I was asleep.
Now you piss everyone off
and make me look dumb!
You've never trusted me anyway.
Get out of here.
Go on, piss off!
You're both so complicated.
My woman...
Have you seen her?
- Who's your woman?
- Marie.
I've seen no one.
He's an odd bloke.
It can't be easy for him.
I'm not going to pity him.
Summer
Attention, please!
No swimming allowed.
No swimming today.
Really? Why?
There's a shark in the bay.
A shark?
A shark? Here?
It's for safety's sake.
If I was Paul,
I couldn't talk to her
After what her son did.
Don't you agree?
She isn't her son.
What did she say?
Nothing. Not a word.
You'll be busy
with a thing like that out there.
Are you helping me?
You and your bloody knitting!
You should try it.
It keeps you busy.
What a lovely day...
Are you okay?
Fine, yes.
Have you had sharks before?
Not that I know of.
I'm scared enough without them.
Did you see jaws?
It's been on TV a lot.
It made me too scared to swim out far.
I stay in the shallows.
I wonder if it's instinct
or because of the film.
When you can't see things,
your imagination runs wild.
Can I sit up there?
Okay?
Sorry.
There are reports of a shark in the bay.
Lovely, isn't it?
Hey...
That's good.
He's seeing girls again.
Yes, but...
What's going on here?
Deep-sea fishing, huh?
What do you mean exactly?
- How far gone?
- Six months.
No, you go-
- have you had a fight?
- No, not at all.
She just wants to be alone.
Funny isn't she?
That's a nice costume.
Yes, I like it.
Okay up there?
Fine, thanks.
Were you born here?
It's funny...
Where's that girl
who was with you last year?
She's not here.
Well...
She left.
No one's heard from her.
I mean, I just don't get it.
- What if She came back?
- They drove each other mad.
Where's your daughter again?
In Brittany.
A pity she's missing the shark.
Maybe it'll be here
when she gets back.
You never go away?
She's right. Why don't you?
- Hello, Odette.
- How Are you?
- And yourself?
- very well. you look fantastic.
We were in Antibes.
- For long?
- Two weeks.
Two weeks, that's good.
- How's it been here?
- Oh, I like it.
I keep out of the sun, you know
- I'm allergic.
- It can be bad For you.
- Come to dinner on Saturday
- Lovely. see you then.
How are you?
I'm fine.
And yourself?
A bit of circulation trouble
but I can't complain.
It comes from working standing up
all those years.
So they say.
Any news from your son?
He's traveling at the moment,
I think.
Do you know...
if the girl's with him?
Yes, I think so.
Actually, I'm not sure.
I'd like to know how she is.
If you hear, let me know.
It's odd, my daughter-in-law
well, my ex-daughter-in-law,
stays in touch.
She's found a good job in Paris.
I'm glad she's happy
Have a nice day, Rose.
You too.
It scares me, you know.
You're young. That's good.
In any case, she loves you.
So try not to spoil it.
Why do you always have to say things
that piss me off?
I just want you to be happy
- How Are you?
- Can't complain, and you?
Fine, thanks.
Heard about the shark?
You bet I have.
Everyone's talking about it.
We've come to see it.
Like in the film!
It's probably harmless.
Whites, blues, hammerheads...
Not many are dangerous.
- I saw some... from a ship once.
- It's probably a basking shark.
They're not the same on TV.
The liver's their weak point.
They've been on earth
400 million years.
I think bees kill more people.
Really?
- It's 7 feet long.
- It's huge!
Shit!
You can't stay here sulking like this.
What?
You'll get over it.
I'm fine.
Don't worry about me.
She needed to be taken away
I was too dumb to see it.
Did you want to leave too?
What's on your mind?
I'm thinking.
What about?
This place.
And?