Previously on "Second Chance"...
Disgraced sheriff Jimmy Pritchard
took his own life today.
You're the first to
journey all the way back,
to get another chance.
I know you. You're one of
those rich computer twins.
Otto recoded your white blood cells
to fight the cancer in my blood.
You brought me
back to save you?
He's stronger than predicted.
Why does he think he's my father?
Because he is.
I'm here about finalizing the merger.
I need to know you'll take care of Otto.
After me, you're the only person he trusts.
I'll take care of Otto.
What's wrong with him?
The glitch did not exist in
the subject's original code.
His genetic code is evolving.
His own body's rewriting it.
Mary.
The numbers from your
most recent blood labs,
they're improving.
His blood is making you better.
For some reason that defies
me, she connects with you.
She will be a beautiful monster.
I'll be back in a few hours.
Bury the other girl outside while I'm gone.
Make sure the hole is deep enough.
Sleep.
Let the drugs hold you down.
How many are we going to have
to bury before he gets one right?
Where is she?
Damn, lady!
Monsters! They're monsters!
What a day, Otto.
The kind of day that makes you feel young.
Well, I am young, but still.
You know the kind of day that just makes
you want to grab it with both hands?
No.
You don't look out there and
think there's just a world
of trouble I can't wait to get into?
No.
Well, you wouldn't. But... where's Mary?
I got the supercharger
hooked up to the Riviera.
Maybe she wants to celebrate her
remission by taking a ride up the coast.
Throw back a few clams
and pitchers of beer.
Mary doesn't throw back clams or pitchers.
And, anyway, she's in a hotel
having sex with Connor Graf.
She's where, doing what?
She's in a hotel, having sex...
with Connor Graf.
Who the hell's Connor Graf?
Connor Graf, age 34, C.E.O.
of Incentric Biosystems.
Estimated net worth... $1.2 billion.
Interests include artisanal
small-batch Bourbon,
rock climbing, French
new wave cinema.
That bothers you?
No, I just didn't know
she was seeing someone.
Connor's the man she has sex with.
I don't believe she's seeing him.
Hmm. I guess I'll just take a
ride up the coast on my own, then.
Before you do, you might
be interested to know
that there should not be
another glitch in your code.
Good to know.
I replicated the code in these.
Uh...
Any further changes should
show up in these subjects first.
Actually, I'd like to
draw some blood from you
and run a quick series of tests
to ensure that you and
the rats are all lined up.
I needed that.
Needed that or needed me?
You know what I mean.
We need to talk about the merger.
I-I don't want you to
worry about that, all right?
Your company and Otto are
in safe hands, I promise you.
You have enough to deal with,
so I don't want you to worry about that.
Okay?
When we first started
discussing the merger,
I'd just been given six months to live.
Mm.
I needed to make sure
Lookinglass was in good hands.
Yeah.
That Otto's place there would be secure.
You know...
But...
...I have more than six months to live now.
What? Remission?
Not fully, but improvement.
My numbers are better.
That's great.
Well, we-we need to celebrate.
We... we need to go somewhere.
- We-we need to...
- Connor...
the merger.
I don't want to plan for my end anymore.
I need to call off the merger.
I know it was a lot of work.
Look, don't... don't even mention it.
It's all lawyer stuff. One
phone call, it all goes away.
Mm!
That's perfect. So Davos or Rio?
Neither. Work.
I feel good. And I want to work.
Bitch.
Yeah, what do you have?
She said she woke up on a table.
There were three people in the room, but
she only got a good look at one of them.
Can she I.D. him?
I think maybe you should go
ask her that yourself, sir.
I'm in the middle of something.
All right, what you working
on? You need any help?
No. I have to go now, all right?
Are you, uh... you, Grace, and
Helen still coming to Peng's later?
Look, Gracie's away on a class trip.
Mm, right. Yeah, she is.
Uh, you and Helen, then...
Pritchard family dinner.
Sounds good, right?
I'll do my best.
Is that police radio?
Are you on a crime scene, Duval?
Duval?
That was definitely a police radio.
What are you doing, Duval?
Agent Duval is currently
investigating a kidnapping case.
Well, now we're talking.
Artie, do any of the deputies
on the scene have those, uh,
body cams?
Artie, if you weren't some
creepy little kiddy cartoon,
I'd kiss you.
Oh, they've got cadaver dogs.
I love cadaver dogs.
Means they're looking for a dead body.
Turn it up.
Helicopters.
Ma'am?
What the hell's going on out there?
I'm Agent Pritchard, FBI.
You said you got a good
look at one of the men.
Not men...
monsters.
- Monsters?
Sir?
You should come and see this.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Stay with her, okay?
Arthur, what's that address?
How did you find out
about this? Lookinglass.
What, the radios?
Body cam?
Yeah. Look, I heard what happened.
Why don't you let me work
this one with you, huh?
This means something to you. Why?
I heard what the witness said.
And I've never seen a real monster before.
And you're not going to now.
Look, if what she thinks she saw is real,
these people need to be
stopped, and it's what I do.
So just let me stop them.
There is nothing to do.
What, why? You already caught them?
Them? There are no them.
There's nothing out there.
There never was anything out there.
It's empty. Clean.
No DNA. Luminol shows no blood.
No body.
And certainly no surgical
table or instruments.
What we have are the drug-induced
delusions of a party girl
who works part-time for
a high-end escort service.
Test her blood?
Mm-hmm. Positive for MDMA.
She was high, and she saw monsters.
Okay, well...
I'll let you get back to
whatever it is you were doing.
All right.
Uh, dinner at Peng's, though, right?
Yeah, dinner at Peng's.
Great.
You another agent come to
say you don't believe me?
I'm not with the FBI. I just
work with them sometimes.
I, uh, heard your statement.
That I'm some whore,
high on Molly, seeing things?
You know, that house was empty. It's...
You know what? Screw you and screw this.
There were monsters, they were
real, and they were after me.
And now no one's gonna stop them.
Ma'am, I can drive you home now.
Hey, I... I think I can help you.
I'm not asking anyone for any more help.
If what you saw is real, you
might want to rethink that.
You live here?
Yep.
Okay, so exactly what kind of
FBI consultant has this home?
It's not his home.
You can't have people here.
Oh, yeah? Why?
I assume you know why, and you're
baiting me with that question.
What does he mean, not your home?
- He's joking.
- I'm incapable of joking.
Who is she, and why is she here?
That's my business. Nothing
to do with you or Mary.
It's my business, Otto, and if you
don't mind, I'd like to get back to it.
My sister lets you go out
because she thinks you need it.
_
That was twinspeak.
Why do you live with Otto Goodwin?
I work for them sometimes.
Them? Does Mary live here, too?
Jilly, let's just talk
about last night, huh?
What's the last thing you remember?
I went for a run, and I
ended up in that house.
This monster you saw, describe it to me.
Why?
I've seen enough things in my life to...
believe you.
Artie?
May I help you?
Artie, she's gonna describe something
to you, and I want you to make a sketch.
Okay, Mr. Pritchard.
Whenever you're ready, Jilly.
Um, he...
it...
it had an oval-shaped face.
And a shaved head.
Horns, little ones.
No, under the skin.
Is this everything?
- Yes.
- From the house?
We watched the Feds from up in the hills.
There's nothing of us left to find.
They think the girl was just tripping.
Good.
We'll get someone else for you to work on.
Can't be someone else.
I chose her. It has to be her.
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
He had dark eyes, piercings, I remember.
On his nose and above his eyebrows.
I...
I don't think I want to do this.
You... you're doing great.
Come on, you got this.
Keep going.
His ears were pointed.
Hi.
I just came back to
change in between meetings.
- Everything okay?
- Yes.
I'm working, and Pritchard's
upstairs with a prostitute.
Initiating
facial-recognition software.
Oh!
It really happened.
You must be the...
Jilly. This is Jilly.
You were gonna say "hooker."
Just a word. Go ahead, say it.
Jilly's in trouble. I'm helping her out.
Is there a problem here?
I'll just give you some space.
Can I ask, if she's in trouble,
why the police aren't handling it?
They don't believe her.
For some reason, you do believe her?
She's in trouble. I brought her home.
I mean, this is my home, isn't it?
If I want to be with someone, I
can bring them back to where I live.
I don't have to sneak off to a hotel.
Wait, are we talking about me now?
Those the same clothes you wore last night?
- What has gotten into you?
- Your brother's code.
Oh.
Sometimes I forget you're...
What?
What am I?
You're one of a kind.
You must get lonely.
You must get scared.
Facial recognition matched.
Caleb the Widowmaker.
That's him.
He's real! That's him!
Arthur, what am I looking at?
I matched this sketch to a photo from an
underground body modification website.
A what?
Body modification is the deliberate
altering of the human physical appearance
for aesthetics, sexual enhancement,
or rites of passage.
Nice.
And this Mr. Widowmaker, any
idea where I could find him?
He works at a bar
called the Inkwell.
Jilly, you sure this is the guy?
I'm gonna go take care of something.
Jilly's gonna stay here till I'm done.
Look, I didn't mean to mess up
whatever situation you have going here.
I really do respect you.
A strong woman in a man's world.
Would you like some tea?
Yes.
But tea with wine and no tea.
Good idea.
And maybe a change of clothes.
First time alone with an escort?
I think so.
Yes.
Well, he seemed to know his way around.
With escorts?
Yes, I believe he's had
some experience from before.
Before what?
Before he came to live here.
Just so you know, uh, he
and I didn't do anything.
That is none of my business.
We're not in a relationship.
So he's with your brother.
Otto?
No. Why would you say that?
Just the way you both were real
unhappy that he brought me back here.
I figured he must be
with one or both of you.
What do you think of him?
I think he's a badass.
But...
But what?
Something else.
He's kind of an old soul, you know?
Caleb the Widowmaker?
Do I know you?
This is you.
I'm just wondering is
"the" your middle name,
or is "the Widowmaker" your last name?
Where do you think you're going?
Just want to ask you a question.
I know what you did to
Jilly in that house, Caleb.
Well, he said he'd be here.
He says a lot of things.
Maybe we should just go ahead and order.
Look, he grew up not knowing us.
Imagine what it was like for him
knowing we were his family
and not being able to see us.
I mean, he's... he's a bastard, Duval.
Yes, Helen, he is a bastard.
If he wants a Pritchard family
dinner, I think he should have one.
Well, if he wants a Pritchard family
dinner, then he should show up for it.
Duval, Helen.
Well, three siblings. Here we are.
Should we order drinks?
The man Jilly saw, he's real.
Who's Jilly?
The escort he drove off with
from my crime scene last night.
Well, you're not a very
good boss to let that happen.
He's not my boss. We work together.
He's not a monster, either.
He's a man, and he works at the Inkwell.
You went after him, didn't you?
I'm guessing he's either in the
trunk of your car or long gone.
I did lose him.
But I have this.
Oh!
Now it's a Pritchard
family dinner. That's...
He has some kind of elf ear on him.
The don't use their real names in
there, but with this, we could find him.
You want me to get a DNA sample
of the blood from an elf ear?
No, he tried to grab it back.
I want you to run this
bloody fingerprint right here.
Swelling's gone down nicely.
Now, don't be surprised if someone
mistakes you for your daughter.
Oh!
Dr. Lesueur, a patient keeps calling.
I told him you were in a consult,
but he says it's an emergency.
I'll be right back.
I told you never to come here.
Some Fed came to the bar asking questions.
What did you tell him?
Nothing. I swear it.
I got away.
Looks like it hurts.
Meet me at the garage, I'll make
everything better, all right?
Okay, that fingerprint is
a match to a Caleb Hammond.
First offense.
18 years old, killed his neighbor's dogs...
with a garden trowel.
Caleb at 21. In for possession.
Caleb at 24. Now in for assault.
Can you connect him to the
house they found Jilly in?
Bank owns that house.
It's been empty for the past six years.
Caleb's last known address
is here... with his wife.
You pay him a visit.
You can flash him your
badge, ask him some questions.
I'll just stay out of it.
I will. I'll just stay out of it.
Thank you.
Are you leaving?
Yeah. I got to get back to my life.
Which isn't here, you know?
James wanted you to stay. Are you sure?
I have a cab waiting.
I thought he brought
me back here to save me.
And don't get me wrong...
he was the only one who believed me.
Why did he bring you back here?
To show you he was saving me.
Although, him being a man, it's
50-50 if he even knows that.
See ya.
We have nothing on the guy who lives here.
Well, he is a dog-killing monster.
Hmm.
Took you long enough.
Come on, the sink's this way.
You're not the plumbers.
No, ma'am. FBI.
It's about Caleb?
I threw him out last year when he
started calling himself the Widowmaker.
So whatever he's done, you're gonna have to
go ask whoever it is
he's making miserable now.
Is this the, uh, sink
that's giving you trouble?
- Yeah.
- Ew.
Well... lucky for you, I made sure
Duval knows his way around a J-trap.
Remember the house on Elm when you stuck
a toy soldier down one of these things,
some kind of crazy rescue mission?
Your mom had guests over
and it was gonna be...
Well, don't just stand there.
Ask the nice lady where a
wrench is or find a bucket.
You have a wrench or a bucket?
It's about time. It's throbbing like crazy.
All right. Well, sit down,
and we'll get started.
I thought you liked pain.
Only when I ask for it.
Can you tell me why you
asked your husband to leave?
He got too weird.
How did Caleb get weird?
He'd go on about beauty,
how some beautiful people are monsters,
they just don't know it.
But he was gonna show them.
Caleb had some bad times.
He had it rough as a kid.
But he was putting it all behind him.
All behind him until...?
Until he started hanging
out with this cutter.
Cutter? What's a cutter?
The illegal doctors who do
the more extreme modifications.
Like horns?
Yeah, horns, branding,
scarification,
penis-splitting, you know...
W-wait, what was... what was the last one?
These cutters, they use
surgical tools, right?
- Yeah, they do.
- You have the name of this cutter?
No names.
That work they do is so illegal.
Caleb was always so
freaking Voldemort about it.
Okay, good. Well, what can
you tell us about Voldemort?
He's kidding.
Oh.
You're paralyzed, but
I know you can hear me.
I want to thank you for
all you've done, but...
it's all about Jilly now.
You've been in love, you understand.
When she looks at you and
knows you for who you are.
You see, I... I can't risk getting caught.
And that Fed knew you, and you know me,
so I'm gonna push this blade
in deeper, and you will die.
Now, I know you only like
pain that you ask for,
so don't worry, my dear
and sweet Widowmaker.
It won't hurt.
Caleb Hammond, A.K.A. Caleb the Widowmaker,
came under the influence of a
cutter who uses surgical tools.
Surgical tools is what Jilly
says she saw at the house.
This is real, Duval.
Yeah. Okay.
First thing we do is
get Jilly somewhere safe.
I didn't exactly like that talk
about Caleb showing beautiful people
how they're really monsters.
Well, she is somewhere safe. I
left her at the Goodwin house.
Thanks for coming to get me.
Of course. My pleasure.
You just let her walk out the door?
She's a grown woman.
What was I supposed to do?
Did she tell you where she was going?
Did she give me the name of the
man who is going to pay her for sex?
No.
So tonight, the usual three hours?
Yes. Why don't you go run a bath,
and, uh, I'll get us some drinks?
That sounds really nice.
I can't find her phone.
You sure you gave me the correct number?
Yes, I'm sure.
Even if it's off, you should be able
to push through and find it, right?
Even if the battery's out,
we should be able to find it.
Well, what the hell does it mean?
Who was the last person she contacted?
Jilly got a text before she left.
Did you pull it off the cloud?
Yes, from a disposable phone.
He must be a regular
client, someone she trusts.
If he's the cutter,
then we got to find him.
I've got a more low-tech idea. Let's go.
_
I have something to ask.
What is it?
Will you marry me?
It's beautiful.
Just like I always knew it would be.
What happened? W-why'd you stop?
No, I'm just... I'm having a little
trouble getting into it tonight.
Do you mind just giving me a
minute and we can start again?
- Sure, yeah.
- Okay.
A-are you okay? You, uh...
you seem distant.
I had this thing happen to me.
What? Were you hurt?
No.
But it made me feel like I
couldn't take care of myself.
And I've spent my life taking care of me.
No one's gonna take that from me.
Good for you.
That's important.
Hmm. What's in this?
I know that taste.
Pharmaceutical MDMA.
That's what I put in your water bottle
before you went for
your run the other night.
What?
After I left, they said that you cut
yourself free and you... you ran for it.
You can take care of yourself.
That only makes me love you more.
We are gonna be so happy together.
- You were there, behind the light.
- Yeah.
You were the man behind the light.
Ohh.
Oh!
My friend Mr. Widowmaker around?
No, not since you beat the crap out of him.
What do you want?
Oh, uh... I'll take a cutter.
Cutter? Don't know what that is.
Sure you do.
The cutters are the ones
who do the extreme work.
Like penis-splitting.
Okay. Why don't you act your age?
Hmm? Yeah.
We just want to have a talk with him.
Listen, I can't help you.
We don't mention their names for a reason.
They make all this possible.
We turn them in, we go
against our community.
Even if one of them is a killer.
We don't say their names. Ever.
There he is.
Hey, you know, why don't you just let
me show you a little old Seattle, huh?
Maybe you'll learn something.
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Y-you're FBI.
You can't do this!
No, turns out he's not FBI.
Then what is he?
Oh, you'd need a science
background to understand it.
I just want to show you something.
This is the hospital.
I'm having a little trouble figuring out,
you know, who I am, where I fit in.
But I feel like in this alley,
I fit right in, don't you?
I can't give you a name. Please.
You see, this guy...
this is the morgue.
You got a pen?
That's how you used to do it?
I'm a monster. I know.
The things that I've done.
Now, I know you saw one of my mistakes.
Right? There were others
before you, I admit it...
weaker women.
See...
I was looking for someone strong, like you.
Because no one deserves to be alone,
even a monster like me.
And you said you'd be mine.
You took my ring over and over
and said that you'd share my life.
So if I'm a monster and you love me...
you must be a monster, too.
I promise you, Jilly, I will
make you a beautiful monster.
But monsters...
don't have soft, pure skin.
See, some monsters have leathery skin.
Some have scales.
Some monsters...
well, some monsters
are covered in feathers.
Black feathers.
We'll tattoo the feathers, then
I think we'll implant the claws.
Then we'll take that face of
yours off and give you another.
All right.
Pritchards?
What... No! Wait, no,
you can't go in there!
Mary, I tried to stop them.
They barged.
It's okay, Alexa. You can go.
This is about Jilly?
These are the driver's license
photos of the six cutters
that we got from the
bartender at the Inkwell.
We need to know if any of them
has spent any time with Jilly.
So use your facial-recognition software
that I'm not supposed to know about
to see if you can put any of them with her.
No.
What?
I'm not a monkey that jumps every
time you say "solve a puzzle."
Get on your machine right now.
I'm not gonna ask you again.
_
- _
- Otto!
I'll do it myself.
Arthur?
Yes, Mary?
No. Arthur is mine.
No, Mary.
Implement my override.
Override implemented.
Should I use Lookinglass
facial recognition
to associate any of
the photos on your desk
to the woman who was
in our house yesterday?
Yes, Arthur.
Go ahead and do that.
That was taken last year. He's
wanted her for a long time.
Now I'm making this official.
You need to go home.
What? Go home?
Your gut was right.
Now let the people with badges finish this.
We'll get him. You go on home now.
He's wanted in Florida
under a different name.
Eight dead prostitutes,
all surgically altered.
The coroner said they all
died during the process.
We're gonna hit his apartment, his office,
and any other known residence.
Clear!
Check the bedroom, over here.
Place is empty, sir.
They waited six hours for him to show up
hoping he'd lead them to Jilly.
But she's not in there.
And now he knows the FBI is on to him.
Yeah.
What about her?
Jilly?
I'll tell you what I used to tell my men.
Sometimes you do everything
right and the bad guys still win.
I used to hate giving that speech,
some deputy trying his best not to cry.
You're saying the words but, you know
full well that there are bad men...
I mean, real bad men out
there just laughing at you.
The best thing about my
last few years in this chair
is I didn't have to
give that speech anymore.
You don't have to be the sheriff.
Oh, then I wouldn't know what I was.
It's all I have left of me.
I solved it because I couldn't help myself.
So you might as well know.
Solved what, Otto?
She said they used a light.
The previous location the doctor was using,
the house in the woods,
was owned by the bank.
The banker handling it...
is a client of Dr. Lesueur's.
I compiled a list of the other bank-owned
properties handled by the same banker.
They total 136, all empty.
But Jilly said they used a light.
So I had Arthur check to see
if any of those abandoned properties
are now pulling power off the grid.
And we found one.
The hard part comes next.
There's always so much blood.
Shh.
Oh, no.
Where is she? She was the one!
She loved me! Where is she?!
I'm right here.
Aah!
You think killing him
will make this all go away?
It's a start.
I get that, I do.
But if you kill him...
it will change you.
There's no coming back from that.
It's up to you.
It's your choice.
Those tattoos, what he did to you...
...you can get them removed.
These feathers are me now, not him.
It's what I've been through...
how strong I can be.
You need to go with him now.
Okay?
What am I gonna find in there?
Just a couple of guys
who thought they were bad.
But you showed them, didn't you?
Now that the merger's off,
I'm not going to be able to get Otto.
I can't do the science without him.
I-I can't make this work without Otto.
You're gonna have to work harder.
I tell you everything they tell me.
I need you to get me
Otto's lab work and notes.
If I can't have Otto, I
need his work, all right?
All of it.
Well, that's inside their house, then.
I'm the only person Mary trusts there.
You're a good person.
And you hate to violate her trust.
But this is how we get what you want.
Don't forget what you want.
I'm home.
Did you have a good day?
Yes.
What is it, my dear?
Do you think you can do the wrong things
for the right reason?
I used to have a scar on this ankle.
This body doesn't have it.
The scar you got in the tank is
the only one that doesn't heal.
Each time you go back in the tank,
you're restored without imperfections.
I got that imperfection
climbing over a fence
separating me from a secret swimming hole.
I proposed to my wife that day.
The other day, Duval told me to go home.
I came here.
This is your home...
...if you want it to be.
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com