Subtitles by DramaFever
[Episode 15]
If I like you too...
Will you still think love is absurd?
You didn't know?
Have you no sense at all?
I like you.
You like me too.
Hey!
There's no need to be so surprised.
Water... you need water.
Hold on a minute.
Yang Dong Chul! Get water!
Okay!
Thanks.
Ra Yoon Young... Oh, hey!
If I like you too...
Will you still think love is absurd?
If you like me, you should like me.
Why are you avoiding me?
Did it stop?
Did it?
Yeah.
Why did you say such nonsense
and make me get hiccups?
What?
Did you know that I got divorced?
Did you hear from Yoon Young?
Why does it matter who I heard from?
You knew everything, and you were
just watching over me?
You sure know how to embarrass a person.
I knew you'd need time to put things
in order after the divorce, so I waited.
Where are you trying to run off to?
You're saying you like me?
That alone is funny.
But you think I like you too?
Who says so?
Ha No Ra...
I don't.
- You don't?
- I don't!
Don't back away because of cliches
like your divorce and your son.
It wouldn't be like you, Ha No Ra.
Whether it's a cliche or not
the fact that you think
I'm backing off is a cliche.
I told you that I don't like you,
didn't I?
Do you think everyone is into you?
This is just too much,
I can't stay here any longer.
I'm going now.
This is nonsense, total nonsense!
Cha Hyun Suk must be crazy.
Oh, Yoon Young.
I hear you and Cha Hyun Suk just
played out a scene from a romance movie.
Yoon Young, how did you know?
I'm already in my car.
I'm more amazed by you than Cha Hyun Suk.
How long has it been for you?
Since when did you have Cha Hyun Suk
in your heart, Miss Ha No Ra?
It's not like that.
What do you mean?
Dong Chul heard everything.
He told me the exact lines
of the romance scene.
"If you like me, you should like me.
Why are you avoiding me?"
Hey...
Must you lie to me?
I'm so happy about it.
You're happy about it?
Of course.
Ha No Ra, you're a human being now.
A bear ate mugwort and garlic and became
human in a hundred days. (Korean folklore)
You now know how it feels to
like a person for the first time.
That's the one good thing about this.
Just being able to feel these feelings...
Excitement, heart-pounding, and
always thinking about that person.
I realized that this is how it feels
to like a person.
That's right! So enjoy those feelings.
Cha Hyun Suk is completely right.
Why are you denying it and running away?
What could I do with him
that I would enjoy it?
A single woman and man like each other.
What's the issue?
Am I in a position to feel that way
and play around?
I have so much to think about.
What should I do after I graduate?
I have to find a new place to live,
and work all my part-time jobs.
Even the Bluebird Theater job...
Hyun Suk set that up for me.
He has some sort of need
to save and protect me.
This isn't some sort of...
self-condemnation, is it?
No, just accepting reality.
- Have a nice day.
- Okay.
I'm out front.
Bring your bag and come out.
Out front?
What's with him?
Hey, friend.
What is it?
Friend, I guess you couldn't sleep either.
Your eyes are red.
What was on your mind all night?
Actually, I slept very well.
I couldn't sleep last night
because my mind was racing.
I just can't accept what you said.
What can't you accept?
That you don't like me.
Why does that seem like a lie to me?
It's not a lie!
Why don't you believe what people say?
I said it, didn't I?
So, I'm just a friend to you?
Yes, I consider you a very good friend.
An old friend that I'm very grateful to.
Then show me proof that you
consider me just a friend.
You want proof?
I couldn't forget you for 20 years.
You have to prove to me that you consider
me just a friend so I can let you go.
Isn't that the very least you ought to do?
As a friend?
Am I right or not?
Think about what I did for you
and your grandma.
How am I supposed to help?
I'm going to do all the things
I've always wanted to do with you.
While we do, you'll have to prove to me
that you don't like me.
Are you not up to the task?
Then you should admit it now.
No, I'm up for it! What should I do?
Hey, come next to me.
Why are we walking separately?
What kind of friends do that?
The path is narrow. That's why.
Oh my!
This isn't a bike path, you know!
Here.
What is it? Is it difficult to eat?
Should I show you how?
I can do it on my own.
You can do it like this.
Eat it like this.
I'll do it on my own.
Eat.
Thanks for breakfast.
Wait.
You're overreacting.
I was going to undo the seat belt.
I can do it myself.
Do you think I'm doing it for you
because I think you can't?
Then hurry up and undo it.
A loan for school expenses
is possible for all four years?
Yes, as long as you apply
for student loans.
However, you have to take 12 credits
every semester and maintain a C average.
A C average?
I wish English could be an enjoyable
course for you like Satoori.
But in Korea TOEIC is very important.
A. The books have been arranged in piles.
B. The bookshelves have fallen over.
C. The cart has been turned on its side.
D. The files have been stacked on
the bookshelf.
B. Matt is holding some reading material.
C. The shopper is picking out clothes
from the rack.
D. The man is folding the merchandise
on the table.
Ha No Ra.
You startled me.
Seriously, Cha Hyun Suk!
I waited a long time,
but you came out last.
You think holding onto the test longer
will improve your chances?
What now? What, what?
You want me to prove something again?
- You think everyone is into you?
- What?
Look at you... you must think
I'm thinking about you all day long.
Then why are you here?
I came here because of work.
I'm going to a site today,
and I need my assistant.
I didn't think you were thinking of
using our theater.
I thought you'd use a big theater,
Producer Cha.
It's for a show that will have
a very limited audience.
What do you think about the atmosphere
of this theater?
The audience will mostly be people
that sent in their stories
so I think it's good.
I think the acting will be relayed
well to them, as well.
Bingo.
Who is she again?
She's the woman that I like.
- Really?
- Yes.
But she says she doesn't like me much.
Oh! I came here with Danny.
How did you know it?
Telepathy?
I suppose I told you about all sorts
of things, didn't I?
Why are you copying Danny?
All date spots are basically the same.
But I did bring something different.
What?
Let's lie down and read comic books.
Romance, action, comedy...
which one do you want?
Lie down here and read comic books?
You said we were friends.
Why? You don't think you can?
Who says I can't? Let's do it. Do it.
What is it? Is it funny?
Huh? Yeah.
Let's read it together.
Move over.
You read this then.
I'll read a different one.
Turn the page.
Don't mind me, just keep reading.
Oh, my arm hurts.
Be a pillow for me, okay?
Why leave your car and take the subway?
We've never done this before either.
We should do it before it's too late.
It's not time to get off yet...
You sit here. I'm doing what I want to do.
You have to prove to me
that you consider me just a friend.
You were really tired, right?
You were anxious and tense.
Only because we were out all day long.
Mom?
Oh, Min Soo!
Who...
Oh, that couple from before...
You know Hye Mi and my Min Soo?
So you were No Ra's son.
Nice to meet you. My name is Cha Hyun Suk.
He's my classmate from high school.
Nice to meet you. My name is Kim Min Soo.
I'm working at his office right now.
Did you not make up with your girlfriend?
What's with the beer?
No, I was going to drink it with my mom.
Have a nice night.
See you again next time.
Let's go.
This is the first time I've had drinks
with my son.
What's going on that you wanted
to drink beer?
My mind is so complicated lately.
I don't remember why I decided to work
for a large corporation.
What do I want to do,
and how do I want to live?
I've never even thought about it.
Because you were so busy studying.
Just like Dad told me to.
Once I graduate and get a job,
I have trouble picturing my life.
You can start thinking about that now.
Don't be too impatient.
What do I want to do,
and how do I want to live?
I've never even thought about it.
I'm out front.
I'll be waiting, so come out.
Again?
I don't want to prove my feelings
to you anymore.
I don't know why I have to.
Then are you admitting that you like me?
No! No! No, no!
I'm saying I don't want to spend time
with you having to prove that I don't.
Why?
- Because I don't...
- like you?
When you eat your toast,
you're afraid to get ketchup on your face.
When you jumped out of the way of the bike
and when I undid your seat belt,
you were nervous.
When I'm near you you can't breathe,
and you can't even look me in the eye.
Is that how you act towards a friend?
Even if we are friends,
you're still a man and it is awkward.
Do you know how you treated me
in high school?
When we worked on our dance routine
and it went well, you'd hug me.
You'd always put me in a headlock
and tease me.
You truly treated me like a friend then.
Now, you care about eating in front of me
and my touch.
You can't lie down and relax.
That's because you said you like me.
It's become uncomfortable.
That's right! I like you... a lot.
Hey! Please stop saying things like that.
It's been 20 years.
It took 20 years for me to have an
opportunity to say I like you.
Why are you telling me not to say it?
Because it has been 20 years.
You... your eyes are stuck back in
the past, 20 years ago.
That's why you still see me as that pretty
and precious person.
I am really thankful for that.
But, you need to stop that.
Am I asking you to marry me or something?
We can eat together, have coffee, fight,
get mad, and make up.
I just want to spend time together.
We can do that as friends.
- So, even as friends...
- I can't be friends anymore.
We're a man and woman who like each other.
Why would we be friends?
Stop saying we like each other.
I told you that I don't.
I just don't like
getting stuff on my mouth.
If I can do it on my own like seat belts,
I don't like others doing it for me.
I especially don't like it
when people touch my waist!
- Ha No Ra...
- Most importantly...
you are not my type.
I like men with big faces,
thick double eyelids, and no dimples.
So... give it a rest now.
Ha No Ra, you are a good liar.
It's not a lie.
I would like it if you no longer
made things uncomfortable.
All right.
All you want is for me to leave you alone?
Yes.
Then that's what I'll do,
and I'm going now.
Yes!
I'm really going.
I said go.
Hye Mi.
Let's skip class
and go have fun somewhere.
What?
You wanted to go on a trip with me,
didn't you?
Kim Min Soo, why are you suddenly
acting like this?
When I insisted on going,
you kept saying no.
I suddenly wanted to go... with you.
If you don't want to go...
I might just go on my own.
Let's go.
One, two, three!
I won! You're buying the meal.
Hey, Oh Hye Mi.
Why do you keep giving it to me?
You eat some too.
Come here.
You're cold, right?
This is the best date we've been on.
This was what you've always talked about,
wasn't it?
A date where Kim Min Soo is focused on
Oh Hye Mi one hundred percent.
But, I'm very sad too.
Does this mean you don't think you'll be
able to do this for me in the future?
Is that why we're doing everything
all at once?
Yes, I can't do it yet.
Yeah... that's what I thought.
I thought a lot about what you said.
Right now, I need time.
You are so sure of the life you want.
I'm not that way.
I only found that out now.
So... I need some time for myself.
It's not because I don't like you.
I need to know who I am,
and what I want to do in my life...
I need time to found out who I am.
Even if we continued to date,
we would have continued fighting.
I still want to live my 20 year old
life with ease.
I'm sorry I can't be with you.
I'm sorry that I couldn't try
to be more understanding.
You know what?
Later on, you're really going
to regret today.
You might cry every night
because you miss Oh Hye Mi.
Yeah, I think I might.
I think I'll regret it.
Me too.
Let's...
Let's do everything we want to do,
so that we regret it a little less.
Is there anything else you want to do?
One, two, three.
I only divorced so that we could
start over again.
Kim Woo Chul...
Let's start a proper love triangle now.
Did they break up?
Kim Yi Jin must be quite traumatized.
Oh my, Sang Ye!
How do I look?
Is it strange?
No, you look so pretty.
I've never seen you
look so feminine before.
I just brewed it.
Thank you.
What's the occasion, by the way?
Is today a special day?
There is...
Yes, it is.
I remembered what I said to you
that day that I was drunk.
What?
Ah, you remembered?
- Were you surprised?
- No.
Well, I guess I was.
But you were very drunk that day.
I found out why people say they find
their answers while they are drunk.
Since my feelings have been revealed,
I'm going to make a confession to Senior.
A confession?
Since I'm dressed like this, do you think
he will finally see me as a woman?
Of course. You look so pretty.
Once he gets here,
please give me some support.
I will.
Wow, who is this? Is that Shin Sang Ye?
I thought it was someone else.
I look odd, don't I?
It reminds me of the past.
You dressed like that in college.
Ah, I guess I ruined you
when you became my Assistant Producer.
Senior has a good memory, right?
He does.
Sang Ye, I'll be in the office.
Can you tell Ha No Ra to bring the latest
version of the actors list?
What? Why don't you tell her yourself?
Also, tell Ha No Ra
that I'd like a cup of coffee.
Yesterday, I slept over
at Ha No Ra's house.
What?
She even made me pollack stew
in the morning.
Hey, Shin Sang Ye...
Eating that stew tasted like I was
getting over my last remaining feelings.
I'm sorry you had to find out about
my feelings, Senior.
All right...
I'm not going to feel sorry towards you.
But...
I don't feel good about it.
Then... set me up with someone.
Professor Kim Woo Chul...
Can he remain at Woocheon University?
Oh, when did she come and go?
Sang Ye, let's go now.
Okay.
We need to head out.
Sang Ye.
Tell No Ra she can go once she shreds
files and organizes the meeting notes.
The two of you slip back in time to
18 years old whenever you meet.
- Please do as he asked.
- I will.
Tell Professor Cha Hyun Suk,
"I understand".
Let's get going, Senior.
Shin Sang Ye, you're all grown up.
Getting all dressed up for a blind date.
Only because you're vouching for him.
Also, I had another purpose.
What do you mean?
Ha No Ra believes that I'm on my way
to confess my feelings to you right now.
What?
I wanted her to be jealous.
I was just a little upset for you.
Hey kid, why did you do
a useless thing like that?
Right now, jealousy would have
a negative effect.
Goodness, you just don't get women.
It sure didn't seem useless to me.
Yeah?
Oh right.
The department chair wants to know
your plans for next semester’s courses.
What should I say?
I'll take care of it.
Since my feelings have been revealed,
I'm going to make a confession to Senior.
Pull yourself together. Come on.
Do you think he will finally
see me as a woman?
[Ra Yoon Young]
Oh, Yoon Young.
Where are you?
Let's go to see the Yeonam-dong store
right now.
Why?
One of my students parents owns
a business consulting company.
I want to take photos and show it to them.
Business consulting?
Whether you go to school or not,
how long can you do part-time work for?
They are trustworthy consultants.
We can just look into it.
Oh... are you the new owners?
Pardon?
Even though there are new owners,
I still have time left on my contract.
I can extend it automatically, can't I?
What do you mean, new owners?
[Min Soo's Mom]
Yes, Min Soo's Mom...
By any chance, did you sell
the Yeonam-dong store?
What? How did you find out?
I came here with Yoon Young.
Oh that... don't misunderstand.
I didn't have a place to stay,
so I sold it in a rush.
Ask him why he'd do that
without consulting you about it.
You should have told me beforehand.
With the final exams, I was so busy.
I made a mistake.
In return, once our apartment get rented
you can keep the deposit money.
We'll talk about that when it gets rented.
I'll come by to talk about it.
It looks like I'll be going
to Jahcheon University.
You can attend school comfortably.
All right.
What is he saying?
The deposit money is larger,
and he's telling you to keep that.
And he sold off the store that he was
supposed to give you.
Do you think he's up to something?
He wouldn't do that.
We have Min Soo, after all.
That's the last boat out.
- Let's go.
You must be going to class.
Oh, Sang Ye.
You know that auditions start the day
after tomorrow, don't you?
When you get the script from the printers,
can you check it for any errors?
I'll do that.
Did you have fun yesterday?
Yes.
It was much better than I thought it'd be.
Ah... that's good.
I have a report to write.
Gosh, she's taking it too well.
That's not how it's supposed to go.
[Resignation]
I'd like to see you.
I have something to talk about.
Who is it?
Hello.
A man out in the hallway
asked me to give this to you.
Okay, thank you.
What is this?
How did this photo get taken?
[Kyung Dae Nam]
Yes?
Hey, Kim Woo Chul.
Is something going on with you?
What do you mean by that?
I just heard from Doctor Cha.
Jahcheon University heard there's an issue
with you, and you'll be getting cut.
What are you saying? Why would I?
Woocheon is planning to dismiss you soon.
You didn't know?
Dismiss me?
This was a setup from the start.
I fell into a trap.
Dismissing me from Woocheon University...
Who would do such a thing?
I even made you
a Woocheon University professor.
Yi Jin?
I wanted to ask you one thing.
Just one thing?
You must be curious about many things.
I wasn't sure it was you...
But Jahcheon is acting strange.
Was this your doing too?
Yes.
I did it.
How could you, Yi Jin?
How could you do such a thing?
Someone so pure like you...
This is the punishment
for someone who betrayed that purity.
For the crime of making me
a laughingstock.
And what about the money I paid them?
Did you take that too?
Take the money?
I have no interest in money.
When you hit rock bottom,
you're going to need all that money.
Then, why blackmail me for money?
It was bait
in order to get this picture of you.
Bait?
Then did you orchestrate Choi Kyu Won's
bribery scandal, as well?
According to some, you're the one
who orchestrated it.
Yi Jin, you made a mistake.
I have a contract with that student's
fingerprint on it.
If I report it, that student will be
caught right away.
And once she is caught,
everything about you will be revealed.
Take that contract and go to the police!
That contract is evidence that you did
orchestrate the Choi Kyu Won scandal.
"I, Kim Woo Chul, ordered the girls
to take photos of Choi Kyu Won."
"That is why I got blackmailed."
"That is why I paid and told her
not to threaten me again."
Once they find the student,
this matter will be over with.
If you can find her, that is...
What was the purpose of taking this photo?
As for that...
you'll find out tomorrow morning.
Are you all right, Kim Woo Chul?
Yes, hello.
What's with him?
This is why people say
no matter how quickly you regret,
it is still too late.
Producer Cha!
Oh my, who has upset you so much?
Many people enter
without announcing themselves, like you.
What brings you by?
I wanted to let you know that I won't
be teaching at Woocheon next semester.
Why are you telling me?
You should tell your own department chair.
You were the one who first came to me
to become an adjunct professor.
Ah, that's right. I did.
Thank you for all your work.
You're not going to stop me?
Is it because you think you can't stop me?
Or is it because you don't want to?
You do know that I'm not going to fall
for your tricky words again, right?
Goodbye.
"No matter how quickly you regret,
it is still too late"?
Senior, look at this.
What is it?
There is a post on Space Host that a
Professor K got hired through connections.
On the list on potential professors,
Kim Woo Chul is listed.
Kim Woo Chul?
Take a look.
This is a picture taken
at Woocheon University.
In the background, Professor Choi is seen
receiving a cake box from his student.
Netizens realized that there was no cake,
but crumpled newspapers in the box.
Sang Ye.
When was
the Professor Choi Kyu Won scandal?
I think it was before first lecture.
Can you find me the picture
of the students and some new videos?
Okay.
Yeah, Ra Yoon Young.
Hey, Cha Hyun Suk.
I'm calling because something is off.
Look into something for me.
What is it?
He sold the store in a hurry?
No Ra doesn't know that I called you.
I just can't trust Kim Woo Chul.
Thanks for coming right away.
Professor, what was so urgent?
Do a part-time job for me.
A job?
What kind of job?
You'll find out tomorrow morning.
Tomorrow morning...
Tomorrow morning, she said.
What should I do?
I told you I have somewhere I need to be.
This isn't right.
- Come back tomorrow...
- It will be too late tomorrow.
Too late? What is it?
Kim Woo Chul, Ha No Ra, Kim Yi Jin...
and me, Cha Hyun Suk.
It's something that involves
the four of us.
Those people no longer matter,
nor have anything to do with me.
Kim Yi Jin, you're very smart, so focus
and listen carefully to what I'm saying.
I saw a very interesting post
on Space Host.
The Professor K list.
What does that have to do with me?
It was like deja vu.
It reminded me of
Professor Choi Kyu Won's scandal.
Everyone knew Professor Cho Kyu Won
was pathetic and took money from students.
But how was it discovered?
It was because of this picture.
One day, this picture happened to be
posted on social media.
And amazingly, Professor Choi Kyu Won
is accepting bribe money behind them.
Ah, and amazingly another person
pointed out...
"Oh look! It's Choi Kyu Won."
And said, "I think it's money in there."
Someone else poured
more gas onto the fire.
This was on the news, I know it already.
Why are you telling me?
Because all of it was constructed by you.
What did you say? Why would I do that?
Ah...
Because Professor Kim Woo Chul got
hired after Choi Kyu Won was dismissed?
That was your plan.
So, No Ra had no idea her husband
was coming to Woocheon University.
And Professor Kim Woo Chul did everything
he could to stop No Ra from attending.
Don't talk about that couple
in front of me!
These students... Choi Soo Hyun
Business Major, Class of 2013.
And Ko Mi Ran, Youth Education Major.
Class of 2013.
What about it?
Choi Soo Hyun put up the post
about Professor K.
Ko Mi Ran put up the reply
mentioning Kim Woo Chul.
I couldn't contact either of them.
They are both from the rural area.
Both of their parents think they're away
on a working holiday.
This has nothing to do with me.
I can find out where they went.
You know that, right?
I've lived in Russia and Europe.
I've traveled all over the world too.
But, I won't bother looking for them.
It takes too much time.
Instead, I'll put up one post
on Space Host.
"Kim Yi Jin, the only daughter of the
Chairman of the Board and Congressman..."
"had an affair
with Professor Kim Woo Chul."
Do you have evidence?
What will you say if I told you
I have CCTV from the Massa Maren theater?
If the reason you're trying to make
Kim Woo Chul hit rock bottom
is because of your anger at him for
having unresolved feelings for Ha No Ra...
Just step on Kim Woo Chul alone.
Don't harm No Ra and No Ra's son.
So this was all because of Ha No Ra?
This overreaction from you.
The son of the man you once loved
attends Woocheon University.
Did you even think of that?
If you do crush Kim Woo Chul,
what will you get out of it?
Letting off steam
for the betrayal of your pure love?
No... you were not pure.
You had the most out of the four of us,
and you didn't lose anything.
Take down that post right away.
Before No Ra and Min Soo see it.
If you take care of it too late and
something happens to Kim Woo Chul...
you know what I'll do.
You did love him once.
If you do that to him,
how many days will you feel good about it?
Three days? Two?
One day?
Hello, this is Bluebird Theater.
Hello, this is Ha No Ra who was supposed
to start pre-performance work next month.
I'm really sorry, but it turns out
that I can't do the job.
I'm sorry.
Since my feelings have been revealed,
I'm going to make a confession to Senior.
It was much better than I thought it'd be.
Hello.
This is the real estate agent.
Oh, has it been rented out?
Yi Jin!
What did you have for lunch?
I haven't eaten yet.
I ran over to eat with you.
What was on the cafeteria menu again?
Let's go.
How about hot, boiling Budae stew?
Budae stew?
That's what I wanted.
I wanted to walk together on this campus.
Come to our secret spot.
Yi Jin...
Why didn't you tell me earlier...
Why didn't you speak up!
"Sorry, I don't feel
the same way anymore."
Why didn't you say that
instead of making me this way?
I wanted to say that,
and I was about to text you to meet.
[Sale Contract - Yeonam-dong 250-9]
What...
What happened?
Cha Hyun Suk, who exactly are you?
What's with you?
Who! Who are you to help me?
We're rivals in love.
So why would you help me?
It wasn't because of you.
What?
If something goes wrong with you,
then your son will be unhappy.
If Min Soo is unhappy,
then No Ra will be even more unhappy.
Min Soo? No Ra?
Kim Woo Chul, you have to live well
in order for No Ra to live well too.
Min Soo, did you leave something behind?
I'm thankful that you didn't
change the pin number.
It doesn't mean you can
barge in here like this.
Don't worry. I won't be coming by again.
What's going on?
What's going on with Yeonam-dong?
And you don't look right.
It's because I lost to Cha Hyun Suk.
What do you mean you lost?
What does that mean...
He saved me.
He's trying to be cool.
Is he really that cool,
or is he just pretending?
What do you mean? He saved you?
Did something happen to you?
[Space Host]
It's deleted.
Gosh! Thank you, Kim Yi Jin.
Who is it?
- It's me, Ha No Ra.
- Ha No Ra?
What brings you here
so early in the morning?
I wanted to say thank you.
For what...
I heard that you helped Min Soo's dad.
No... that you saved him.
How... who did you hear that from?
Come in. Come inside and talk.
Don't grab me.
I'll talk from here.
Why are you being like this?
Why didn't you tell me?
He's my child's father, and my ex-husband.
I was just doing what I could for you.
I didn't want you
and your son to get hurt.
I know.
But, Hyun Suk...
It's so hard for me.
Thank you... thank you.
I've said thank you so many times
since I've met you again.
I'm saying thank you again,
and I have nothing else to say.
So, it's difficult for me.
Why is that difficult?
I didn't do that
so you would feel that way.
I didn't do it to show you anything.
My father passed away
when I was two years old.
And my mother left me
when I was five years old.
And it's like you're the person my grandma
prepared for me when she left.
So...
What are you trying to say?
Let me go.
Stop doing things for me.
I'm having a hard time.
A hard time?
It's hard standing in front of you.
It's hard having you look at me.
Is it so...
hard to be brave?
I don't want you...
by my side anymore.
[Cha Hyun Suk]
Let me ask you one thing.
Is time what you need?
No.
What about me?
Do you not need me?
I don't.
I didn't want to be with you
because you were my first love.
I love who you are 20 years later.
I've come to love you now.
The reason? I don't have one.
At first, I bothered you
because I was mad at you.
At times, I sympathized with you
when you were in trouble.
But... as I watched you change,
it just happened.
That's how I feel.
Don't look down.
Look at me.
Look into my eyes.
I know why you're holding back.
But, you also have to work on
narrowing the gap.
It's something you have to do.
And you're saying you can't, right?
I want to try living on my own.
Without anyone.
But, you should know this one thing.
There is no forever.
It's time for me to move on now.
I can't hold on to dreams
of my first love forever.
I can't live my life that way.
Yeah.
You should have done that earlier.
Yeah...
All right.
Let's stop now.
We had a first love
over a time span of 20 years.
Well, they say first loves never last.
I'm...
going.
Okay.
Thank you for everything.
Live well.
[Woocheon University]
Subtitles by DramaFever