What do you still doubt, Daegam?
Were you not approve this transaction?
Joseon era now, had only one person has been able to embed frills independence movement.
By reason of saving the nation cheats here and there.
How can I believe in you and provide military funding?
Do not equate us with the bastards.
In addition to getting what you want,
You can also contribute to efforts to liberate the homeland.
This is the counterfeit goods.
How dare you try to screw me?
Daegam ...
Yeonggam-nim, matamu sudah rabun ya?
Have been agreed on beforehand. Why even stalling?
Then why do not you meet the time we agreed together?
S
his
Sub
And under
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitle o
Subtitle ol
Subtitle ole
subtitle by
Subtitle by:
Subtitle by: ~
Subtitle by: ~ D
Subtitle by: ~ SU
Subtitle oleh:
~ SU
Subtitle by:
Subtitle by: ~ v
Subtitle oleh:
~ SU
Subtitle by: ~  Super
Subtitle oleh: ~ SuperS Damn!
Subtitle by: ~ Damn! SuperSU
Subtitle by: ~ Damn! Supersub
Subtitle oleh:
~ Damn!SuperSub I
~ SU
Subtitle oleh: ~ SU
Subtitle by:
~ SU
Subtitle by: ~ SU
Translated by: ~ SU
Kim Jang Ok, listen carefully!
You are surrounded. There is no chance for you to escape.
Put your weapons and surrender immediately!
How?
Really stubborn. Still insist survive.
It certainly was.
However, they are members of the core team Taksim.
I'll try to persuade him to surrender.
Here!
Kim Jang Ok!
Can you hear me talking?
I'm Lee Jeong Chul.
Do not shoot!
I try to check the area around here for a while.
In the meantime do not act rashly.
You're giving me orders?
Why could have thought if this is the command?
Kim Jang Ok apprehended alive is the order of Higashi Bucho.
Ringkus him!
Attack!
Right here!
Do not shoot!
I told you do not shoot!
Healthy!
Possible!
Backward everything!
Lee Jeong Chul!
Jang Ok!
I was Lee Jeong Chul.
Let's talk for a minute.
The door will be opened. Do not shoot!
They were on top of betraying the country and you betray your people.
Nighttime sleep so you can still asleep.
Hordes of traitors!
You think inibisa independent state?
This ship was already shaky.
Yes.
Ships already shaky. Fleeing first is a coward.
Out.
If you're out, you can still maintain your life.
At least you have to defend your life.
I would never conspire with traitors.
Put your weapon!
Daehan independent life.
Jang Ok!
-= The Age of Shadows =-
- = Joseon Chongdokbu, Dept. Police = -
Please sit.
This is the genuine article.
Looks like they need immediate funds can be disbursed.
Supposedly Kim Jang Ok arrested alive.
Unfortunately battle this time.
You guys are friends, right?
Not.
Yeah well.
In hard times like this it's hard to find friends.
People who reached out first, that's your friend.
Sotoku-fu have great expectations on you.
[Sotokufu - Japan Governor's Office]
The Buddha statue will bless you in finding Giretsu group.
I have entrusted to you.
Release him!
- = Sampantong professed = -
Joo Dong Seong mana?
They failed to capture Ok Jang Hyeong, only managed to catch Dong Joo Seong.
But a man named Lee Jeong Seong Dong Joo Chul freed recently captured a day ago.
Lee Jeong Chul?
The new man in the police. Joseon people.
Had served in the interim government in Shanghai.
And selling information to the Japanese government.
Because of his services that he managed to become a cop.
The evil and greedy.
Had served as a translator and far-flung connections.
And the purpose of these actions is to sell government.
In other words, Lee Jeong Seong Dong Joo Chul freed with the goal of making it as bait?
One moment! Lest this place has been discovered?
Impossible. When we brought him here twiddling twirling first.
No one is stalking.
How do I deal with Dong Joo Seong?
No matter what kind of beaten up remains willing to open his mouth. We also can not do anything.
Remove him from the organization from something unexpected happened.
Let's make it like this...
You've escaped from hell alive.
I really do not know what happened.
He told me to go, so I went.
Kan Lee Jeong Chul who sent this freedom?
No, Hyeongnim.
The existence Ok Jang Hyeong also leaked from where we are.
It's not me, Hyeongnim.
It's not me.
Bastard like you who suck the blood of your own countrymen!
Why? Why suspect me?
Who Lee Jeong Chul 'no I do not know.
Hyeongnim, I really do not know who it was Lee Jeong Chul.
Really do not know.
Plans night was just the three of us know.
How did the police know?
I'm going to count to three. You'd better confess.
If not, heads will bloom shell.
One!
Who leaked the secret?
I am innocent.
I brought a bomb with his life,
why are you even suspect?
Two!
Damn!
Why only me a suspect?
So you-you are here there is no possibility of a spy?
Hyeongnim!
Three!
Joo Dong Seong.
You do not know why the enemies of freedom?
If you have not tired of life, never appeared rod nose in front of me!
Immediately leave Gyeongseong!
[Gyeongseong / Keijo - Seoul called the Japanese colonial era]
Hyeongnim...
You also do not believe me?
It looks like the independence army is facing difficulties funding problems.
They started selling valuables.
You know who he is?
Yes I know.
SD friend Jo Hoi Ryeong.
The son of an artist.
His name is Kim Woo Jin.
Reportedly worked with Hyeong running a photo studio business and antiques.
Reportedly all funds will be collected there and then transferred to the top.
Why the sudden need of funds in the independence army major jumlahyang?
What are they planning?
Reportedly ...
... They're buying up explosives from all directions.
Based on info from Shanghai,
they are communicating with the bomb.
There is new information?
Yeah, it looks like I locate. The new plan-and Giretsu fundraising.
[Giretsu - Militant group name Uilyeol-and in B. Japan]
Chaired by Jo Hoi Ryeong along with Kim Woo Jin.
It looks like they are Giretsu militants who infiltrated into the capital after Kim Jang Ok.
Very good. Why do not you find out if there could be lobbied.
If they ask whether it permits the transport or funds, give the green light!
Because they sibukkan undoubtedly this is the case.
Ready to execute.
In the future you cooperate with Hashimoto.
Please guide me.
I will try as much as possible.
Both?
I...
Working closely with the Inspector Lee, we would not be defeated.
Please guide me.
Hashimoto was hunting Giretsu chairman and Jeong Chae-San.
Share information only.
Utilizing this opportunity both of you set up your feeds that could provoke Jeong Chae San exit.
It's time to show kebolehanmu already arrived.
In this sense Inspector Lee has worked very well.
Hashimoto, you need a lot to learn from him.
Good.
You've heard about Gye Yeon Soon coming from China?
Secretary Jeong Chae San is a female member.
There is information that says if he had some time ago arrived in Gyeongseong.
But unfortunately none of the people who know her face looks like.
By capturing these women, together with Chae Jeong managed to strangle San.
- = Studio photo Yeongsaeng / antique shop. = - (A secret meeting place Uilyeol militant groups-and in Gyeongseong)
What preparations?
You stay here, I'll get there alone.
Own?
This time you do not have to participate.
Wait until the goods I move here.
This latter state is less secure.
Dangerous.
You're worried about me?
Not worried, but worried comrades.
Companion in arms ...
What if you help photographing seperjuanganmu friend?
Why suddenly talking like this?
You do not ever take my picture.
I want a piece.
One two...
There affairs what?
Kim Woo Jin-ssi which one?
I'm Kim Woo Jin.
I have a valuables. Could you please briefly checked?
Well, go to the top floor.
You know the origin of these items?
Aslikah ini?
Let me see.
Looks like the old man in Jongno get a windfall.
The basis of the fraudsters.
What do you mean?
That this is fake goods.
Except that an expert like me, would be hard to distinguish.
Oh ya?
These things I get from the hands of people I can trust.
Just a moment please.
Where do you think the original?
It looks no different.
That the age of 200 years. The other is freshly made spring of this year.
I have a ceramic factory in Shanghai.
A potty kusulap wreckage could become a historic relic of the royal family 300 years old.
What? This Is not no different than the scams?
If there is genuine, there is definitely fake one.
Honestly, the demand is far greater than the supply of goods.
Your ability to reap tremendous profits.
Could not if only a little, should be plenty.
It makes people envious.
You're engaged in what area? Why should envy me that an entrepreneur?
Inspector Lee Jeong Chul Police Agency.
Aigoo, I was being presumptuous.
Allow me to introduce myself.
My name is Kim Woo Jin.
Fail to recognize the important figure.
But why do you have a position in the police Chongdok-bu why be jealous of a small businessman like me?
Paid work, not fun.
Far greater than with a small businessman like myself.
Lee Gyeongbu...
You have connections with Japanese police in Shanghai?
Arguably so. I worked in Shanghai for some time.
Oh ya?
If so, can I ask a favor?
I would like to import some goods from Shanghai.
I is not a fund-raiser for the Liberation Army, just an ordinary businessman.
But I suspect that simply can not import anything.
Trivial things like this
you want bayarin I drink?
Lee Gyeongbu, you are interested to find additional revenue?
The feeling is really fun.
How?
While having a drink we'll talk about the business together, how?
Now?
When again?
Come on!
It turns out there is an event like this.
Ok Jang Hyeong was a village with me.
Ok Jang Hyeong you and are good friends since they worked in the interim government.
Then you and I have little connection.
But at the time you become a translator for the interim government.
Why now could be the Japanese police?
His heart is unpredictable.
Perhaps he was being tortured themselves to death.
Bujang-nim are now specifically asked me to here. Keep ya I changed to be like this.
And Jang Ok I used contacts in Shanghai.
Arguably is a congenial friend.
After Jang Ok death, I raised my toes.
And feels very light.
It was in my mind there is only mind as well.
I knew this would definitely like.
You are not sadists. I knew from the beginning.
If it does not become a police officer, would have to be a poet.
Drink there!
Yes, I would drink.
Starting today, I'll call you "hyeong."
Whatever.
Not important.
Beware the stairs!
Today drank a lot.
Hyeongnim, thank you. Go home.
Be careful on the road.
Yes.
Be careful on the road, Hyeongnim.
Operator.
I was Lee Jeong Chul of Police Chongdok-bu.
Please connect me to the Police Agency.
Kim Sa Hee, do not have to go to the office tomorrow.
Sampandong to get the stuff you never talk about it.
This is important stuff. Should be extra careful.
- = Japanese police chase with very tight. Lee Jeong Chul, Joseon people who had been active in the interim government with its status as the Japanese police trying melobiku. If our organization is exposed, all members are encouraged to immediately move to Shanghai. = -
This is a copy of the conversation Inspector Lee.
Sampandong, at 7.
In other words if Uilyeol-and managed to infiltrate into the capital city,
they will act through this pathway.
Seongmoseongsim monastery.
Studio photo Yeongsaeng.
Kim Woo Jin bastard. I knew it would be like this.
This bitch is a whale.
The other is the path to be taken by the Union Rickshaw.
The problem is whether the path they take is in line with Kim Jang Ok.
This is why in the open?
You show it to others?
Kim Sa Hee!
Once out of the door, it turned out I had been awaited by Hashimoto Gyeongbu.
He said should exchange information. Therefore...
Bring the car to the front door!
Ready!
You to the photo studio!
Fast! Hashimoto had acted before.
Ready!
Seongsim convent!
Anu...
Claim!
Ya?
There was stuff inside. Could you please help lift into the rickshaw?
Good.
Lift alone, right?
- = Already exposed. Beware of Hashimoto. = -
I told you to be caught alive.
Sunyeo-nim, the Japanese police were in front of the gate.
Be careful!
Basic rice scoop!
Women who are hiding in the convent was not willing to arrest you?
Kuwanti already cautioned, the problem with this mission can not be told to anyone, even to your mother or your great.
You look is still worth you call yourself Japanese police?
Sorry.
Who is this person?
A - I was the informant of
Inspector umano-san.
Hashimoto Keibu.
. Anda Dicari Higashi Bucho
[Bucho - Kepala Bagian]
Why are not you screaming in the street alone
if you're a cop captured the independence movement?
Useless!
Already satisfied making a scene yet?
What do you mean?
If there are only two of us, talk to the Korean language.
Laboriously track them down and spread the bait ...
why should they panic and flee?
Is there a specific procedure in the army arrested the independence movement?
If you know so, should they be arrested before he could escape.
Not appropriate for you to ask me.
Supposedly you can keep track of how these police information to leak out.
Do you intend to defy me?
According to reliable information Jeong Chae San have been to Shanghai.
It seems to collect the explosives expert of Shanghai.
And it looks like all members Uilyeol-and had fled to Shanghai.
Antique shop owner Kim Woo Jin from since the morning have also been invisible bridge of his nose again.
All of this is caused by the aspect operasional--
No need to explain!
Catch them as soon as possible!
Take advantage of all the resources we have in Shanghai.
Head-and Jeong Chae Uilyeol San collect all explosives expert in Shanghai.
It's clear they are targeting Sotoku .
[Sotoku - government buildings]
We have to stop the entry of explosives into Gyeongseong.
Do not waste any more time! Immediately went to Shanghai!
High rewards that you have not seen the rest of your life is waiting.
Because everything we do is in Shanghai.
Hashimoto!
Ya.
You stay here. Collect all the news submitted by Hashimoto from Shanghai.
Report everything to me!
What if kulaporkan directly without passing Kim Sa Hee?
Information relating to the Chae Jeong San you report directly to me!
Ready to execute.
-= Shanghai, Jeongbu =-
Let me.
Woo Jin, how are you?
There are things I want to talk to you. A few more days I'm going to Shanghai.
I hope you can come and get me.
Lee Jeong Chul.
This place is not safe anymore.
I hope for a while, you hide away some time in Manchuria.
Now we're fighting an enemy that is invisible.
The situation really dangerous.
I also agree with the proposal Gye Soon.
What do you think about Lee Jeong Chul this person?
Can be trusted?
We both are Umpang thrown by anglers.
Including friends like?
I've heard Kim Jang Ok offend this person's name.
He said he was a close friend.
Just past.
Now we do not have the time or people.
Bite this feed.
Investigate sow discord.
For enemy spies to spy for us.
The most dangerous among the spy,
but also the most effective tactics to sow discord.
I do not agree.
Target enemy is you, nor-nim.
There is a risk?
Definitive nature of people like this, like the grass on the fence that was blowing in the direction of the wind.
We'll see this time he sounded direction.
Spies for both sides but only one true homeland.
And it certainly occupies a special place in his heart.
Let's help him open the door.
Inner struggle is the most frightening thing.
If we go down together, Kim Woo Jin would suspect.
You go out of there.
He has come. Smile a little!
No need to smile.
Aigoo, Hyeongnim! Long time no see.
Certainly busy, huh? I thought not even see you here.
As you ordered, had to find out.
Among the Hungarian anarchist very lack of professionals in this field.
It could be that they have received assistance from these people.
There are some external people who intend to fight for the independence of Joseon.
Why?
By helping a country to form a government, they will be successful and prosperous.
- If there is time to stop by the office. - Janggwan fuck is that?
In the eyes of Janggwan was just no money. Besides money, there was nothing he cared.
When are you going mempertemukanku with eye-matammu?
Since the incidence of leaking information on Gyeongseong,
Uilyeol members-and to be very careful and not act rashly.
Be careful that's their business, is not it?
And finding these people is our duty.
I believe in Uilyeol members-and there our spies.
Every gestures Lee Jeong Chul still under close supervision, is not it?
Shanghai experienced a tremendous change within the next few years.
I tuh want to stop working in the police and start a business here. Do you have any suggestions, Dongsaeng?
Finally Hyeong mind open as well.
Nice thought.
Job "selling" the country for a while are more relaxed.
But the guilt that plagued'll torture lifetime.
Once melodious singing.
In short, I've only been active in the interim government here.
It's been quite a long time I left Shanghai. Never was also in touch with the people in the interim government.
In addition to the Japanese people, I do not know the experts who are here.
I'm looking for someone.
Do not give out first! Let me guess.
You need the Joseon experts who have relations with the interim government.
New half the story you already know. You're the ghost huh?
Penyampaianku intelligent way kah?
The business name is half the capital half cleverness.
I already understand. Although I do not know who you're looking for.
But I will help you find an expert who is very close relationship with the interim government.
You've said you wanted to look around the ceramic factory, right?
Immediately there. The place is also not far from the residence.
Yes, let's.
You both need anything?
More recently there are foreigners who come to buy explosives in large quantities?
We do not sell explosives.
Do not lie! I'm here because it already knows.
Nothing like this. There! There!
Hei! Hei! Bos! Bos! Hei! Hei!
He said lately there was a fighter of the Hungarian revolution often here.
Hungary believed the poor were explosives experts.
He worked at the French pharmaceuticals.
But his wife is Asian.
You forgot this.
It's your husband.
thanks.
When I have time to stop by our house for dinner.
Bye.
Do not get into! Follow me!
Tomorrow eat French cuisine only.
Drink a glass before returning goods.
Today is a rest first. Still tired from the trip. Do not forget to request earlier.
What?
Forgot to mention, right? Goods enter Gyeongseong my art.
Sure, sure.
Be careful.
Sign in and rest.
Damn, eating only costly.
Who?
What's up in the morning?
Let's go eat breakfast!
This early?
Bird early risers will find many caterpillars.
Birds that get up early to be caught first.
Doenjang fragrant.
Hyeong, you must help me.
I told you I'll help.
Right now my head shell which will be at stake.
I am very scared.
Yes, should you be afraid. Because your heads will be at stake as well.
New invited to eat you had asked for my head is at stake?
How? In accordance with the tastes?
Fortunately. I was chairman Uilyeol-and, Jeong Chae San.
At the moment in a revolutionary organization Goryeo I've heard we Dongji offensive about you.
There are also many Dongji very grateful for the help of Lee Gyeongbu that time.
I want to see you, so I asked for help Woo Jin to introduce you to me.
I'm flattered.
You are welcome. If it was not thanks to Lee Gyeongbu, where there is a chance I
sit down and eat with a Gyeongbu of the police station.
But how can you trust me with the status of a police officer?
Why glaring at me? I did not say anything.
Danjang-nim hear his own time in Shanghai.
Eating together with the people of the village in a place thousands of miles away, why his speech was so long-winded?
Come on, let's eat.
Without alcohol, which arguably entertaining guests.
You seem to have made up his mind would make me rich.
Bring the highest rewards, Jeong Chae San front of me.
What do you want to do now? Old you are still green makes you not tremble to anything, so?
I had long forgotten what fear is.
Why? Fear?
Your goal is for these approaches me, right?
The person had been in front of your eyes, what are you waiting?
I could spend Jeong Chae San now.
Please try.
If I go now, you'll all fall in danger.
Lee Jeong Chul Gyeongbu of Chongdokbu staying up drinking together with Chae Jeong-and Uilyeol San chairman.
It certainly is widespread throughout Shanghai.
You're threatening me?
You do not know what situation you own now?
You really do not know?
After arriving here, Higashi been looking for you?
Why do you think the Japanese people who came with you about the Shanghai government hides from you?
Due to complete its mission alone.
I have often met with someone like that is to the left and to the right but eventually collapsed.
Actually this is not as much as expected.
While talking about home, drink as much.
Although I was a hyeong, but I'm not so strong drink.
When did you become hyeong?
Come on!
Come on, you are also drinking.
Come on, let's toast.
Cheers!
Here the glass.
Come on!
So fast?
Lee Gyeongbu.
You like fishing at night?
When depression fishing to make here is actually quite relaxed.
Sitting in the dark riverbank instead will make you forget the fear.
Do you feel afraid?
Of course.
I was the military who lost the state.
Wandering to and fro with the status of soldiers who fled.
I had the most confidence in the sense of alertness.
Who will stand on my side, and who is going to help sustain life,
the ability to determine.
I believe Lee Gyeongbu will help me.
I am a salaried police.
People who only know hunting gains already plastered on the front of the eye.
I can not guarantee my mind will change.
Lee Gyeongbu, push me into the water right now!
If really you want that, do it now.
Such an opportunity will not come again.
Why can not believe in yourself?
I can not believe what people say. I said anything I did not already own faith.
I only believe what I should do. What should be done by someone.
Because sometimes people will be in the moment in which he does not know. The moment in which the status of self must be disregarded.
Lee Dongji, I wish that my name recorded in the history books like this.
Later, I'll leave you my time Lee Gyeongbu.
Help us, we had to.
I think I want to crazy.
Indeed many bacotmu. What should I do?
We ... came to Gyeongseong safely. Just that.
But too many stumbling blocks.
The rest we complete yourself. We will not trouble you.
The decision is yours. I will not blame you.
I'm no different from the deceased Ok Jang Hyeong. Even ghosts have to be lonely,
also do not want to be a ghost coward.
I do not know the next time when we meet again I've turned into such things.
Did you know?
These are all false. I pretended not to know anything.
He opened a factory and so trust me.
Hashimoto!
These are all false.
I pretended I did not know anything.
He opened a factory and so trust me.
Kim Woo Jin wants to Tokyo. He filed a second sheet travel documents. Do you think he'll go with who?
It is certain to San Chae Jeong, Jeong Chae San.
Kim Woo Jin is the number two. Tomorrow they are going to the port. Hurry to apply for a warrant!
Your information is accurate?
Then the prize money I eat it yourself.
If you do not believe me, please find their own information out there.
You are Kang Jong Gye?
Here other than I was there someone else?
Jeong Chae San No?
Our target is to bring the explosives safely to the Gyeongseong.
Each disguise identities and hide explosives.
The most notorious in the box where?
Where are these people?
Even if there is something undesirable upon us,
This box should arrive safely at Gyeongseong.
Search carefully!
I will send more people to the port to Shanghai tomorrow.
The time had arrived.
Everyone departs from the station Gyeongseong.
After meeting at the last meeting which has been approved, the mission would end.
I and Heo Cheol Joo will bring a box containing explosives to Andong Station by train.
After the box arrived in Andong, stayed transported to the cargo section.
Well, we all have to meet at the station Andong in a state without lacking anything.
Done.
What is this? What happens is this?
Kim Woo Jin mana?
The entire pier had been searched, nothing.
What?
The entire pier had been searched but no.
How did you work?
What informer?
Content is the details were unclear because he is subordinate.
During this time you were using the informant useless like this?
Although no one in the upper layer, but due to worry about getting caught anniversary meeting reduced.
Should you tell me. Our actions as a whole should be planned carefully in advance.
You think this is my decision?
I'm just carrying out orders from superiors.
Bosses also ordered to excommunicate the mission this time?
This is an order from Higashi?
Lee Gyeongbu information can not be trusted. It is a fact, is not it?
You think I'm that fabricate information?
Your information is junk information! Rightly informer replaced, is not it?
The cost for the entertainment you used to?
What?
Not a ship, but the train.
Train?
Where are you going?
It seems like they go on their own and make a pact to meet each other in Andong then equally toward Gyeongseong.
Oh, yes? Sure?
Chae Jeong San risked their lives to go to Gyeongseong.
Are you sure?
Jeong Chae San participating in the trip or not I'm not so clear.
What? Now the most important thing is Jeong Chae San.
You even say it is not clear Jeong Chae San participate or not in the course of it?
Anu, if according to my informant
And Yeon Woo Jin Kim Gye Soon a team. They hid in a few places then meet in Andong.
Down from the car and you repeat your report, bitch! ß Basic rude!
What is the importance of his men to Gyeongseong or not?
Jeong Chae San ke mana? Jeong Chae San!
No information about it.
Who gave you this kind of information?
One of their members who participate in the quest to Gyeongseong this time.
Makes sense does not it? If indeed he was a core member should he know Jeong Chae San whither.
Reportedly in the organization Uilyeol-and no single member knows exactly where Jeong Chae San.
Actions to be taken are always kept confidential. At the time of the execution of new notified.
So I asked who it was, shucks!
Stop it. For now still can not be told.
You go find out where Jeong Chae San!
Good, let's get moving!
What if this information is false?
At that time Uilyeol-and, Jeong Chae San
did not work we ringkus, want to go back empty-handed and looking silly?
No, this time the information is reliable.
Informants this time one hundred percent trustworthy.
Rewards promised him this time is very seductive.
Kim Jang Ok hideaway also leaked by this.
Otherwise, we will not have the opportunity to approach Jeong Chae San, is not it?
Let's take action.
= The train with the aim Gyeongseong will depart within 5 minutes. =
= Train with destination Gyeongseong will soon leave. Passengers are expected to soon rise into the train. =
Let us scatter and search! You want which direction?
Gye Yeon Soon along the West should be in first-class carriage. Gye Yeon Soon I'll find.
Do you want to get the services of a self-selected for capture Gye Soon Yeon, would not you say?
What?
Then you're over there, I'm here.
But are you sure they are in this train?
S
his
Sub
And under
Subti
Subtit
Subtitl
Subtitle
Subtitle o
Subtitle ol
Subtitle ole
subtitle by
Subtitle by:
Subtitle by: ~
Subtitle by: ~ SU
Subtitle by: ~ Damn!
Subtitle by:
~ SU
Subtitle By:
~ Su
Subtitle by: ~ Damn! Soup
Subtitle by:
~ Su
Subtitle by: ~ Damn! Super
Subtitle by: ~ SU
Subtitle by:
~ Su
Subtitle by: ~ Su
Subtitle by:
~ Su
Subtitle by: ~ Su
Translated by: ~ to to ro ~
I'm out looking for some fresh air.
What happened? Why be here?
You've been caught. Gye Yeon Soon there where?
He was with the Caucasians?
True, they were in the first-class carriage.
Hashimoto was headed there.
What? The train journey is only our members know. Why can...
Anggotamu who were on the train is one of them is an informant.
Bastard was also leaked the existence of Kim Jang Ok.
Because you are now my position so little dangerous.
In short, Hashimoto should be prevented so he does not wander searched.
It let me think of something. You also have to find the best solution.
Anggotamu who were on the train is one of them is an informant.
Please keep stuff for a while.
Next door there is no?
It looks like nothing.
OK.
Hashimoto!
One moment!
You sit down here.
I think searched in this way would arouse suspicion.
Even if you've met, also have to be patient until arriving at Gyeongseong.
If you can not get caught everything, we must also consider their counterattack.
Therefore if Kim Woo Jin was found, or someone suspicious, watched silently.
After arriving at the new Gyeongseong arrested all of them. What do you think?
Makes sense.
Okay, then. Do not get too excited in the act.
Be like the passengers in general. Keep an eye secretly.
So you mean, no matter what the passengers must be supervised?
Yeah, right.
No, I mean I will act with caution.
Apprehended them all at once instead of making them to be vigilant.
I see what you mean.
You follow me rummage with the distance apart of the carriage.
Sorry, I just want to ride through.
Why is my diaper ...
It smelled really stung. Excuse me.
Pretended not to know me. Straight ahead.
Fifteen minutes, in between carriages.
Damn!
Hoi Ryeong!
The meeting place after arriving in Gyeongseong should be replaced.
I sensed if the location had been discovered.
Really? Hour and place ...
Hotel Hwanggeumjeonmog-in, jam empat.
I will tell them one by one. Avoid contact with others to avoid problems.
If there is something unexpected,
show license trip and said you were Westerners. They would not dare do anything against you.
Once we arrived at the station Gyeongseong, leave the place with carrying explosives
and is located at Jongno street Tongtaehwa in five hours.
Good.
Just a precaution, the location of the meeting in Gyeongseong will be replaced.
The new meeting location is
Hotel Hwanggeumjeonmog-ins.
Six hours.
Hotel Hwanggeumjeonmog-in, jam enam.
The meeting location has been changed. Hotel Tongtaehwa in Jongno street at four.
Hotel Tongtaehwa in Jongno street four hours.
Shop coat in Deokseung-dong, five.
Including Simsang-do. Do not tell it to anyone.
Good.
What is wrong? Frequently meet me in danger.
Listen carefully to what I would say from now on.
Just now I was met by my members individually and tell them about the change of plans.
Separately giving the time and location of the meeting different.
Before the train arrives at its destination,
The informant will pass this information to the informant Hashimoto.
That person was an informant. And he is the bastard who betrayed Ok Jang Hyeong.
I told you, we encounter extremely dangerous.
Enough you tell it to me. They must know the location and time.
Why should I interfere in your mission? Try love reason.
If they find out we've been working together, you will be in danger.
Think carefully, actually people who pass on information to the Japanese it was you.
Therefore, we can safely get into this train.
Disguised as one of you and melobimu is my job.
I was the informant. It was approved by the Higashi.
But you have to do a scary act Higashi unknown to us.
Damn, so see you play directly threatened.
The present situation does not allow to find another solution. Then you think I should do?
Detonate the bomb and die together?
Hyeong!
Keep us safe until the Gyeongseong.
I'll be waiting in the dining car. Hurry up there!
Damn!
How?
Either he was disguised as a parent or anything. Not met at all.
Then look again! How? You've found the informant Uilyeol-and-so?
Just now I met him.
It seems there is a new clue.
Here's our plan.
Informants we place in Uilyeol-and it
will deliver the core members such as Kim Woo Jin, Gye Yeon Soon and other members.
People Uilyeol-and no one knows if we are on this train.
Therefore they are going out into the train station this calmly.
Our men have surrounded tight all the way out of the train station.
Once they arrive at the train station, everything will be immediately arrested by our people.
So you're saying before arriving in Gyeongseong, they absolutely will not be tampered with?
Right, so just listen to your ideas
plus people Uilyeol-and it was by far more than us, there is a possibility the position we are in danger.
From now on we have to wait for the arrival of the Gyeongseong calmly.
Finally able to wipe Uilyeol-and.
The day on which Jeong Chae San'll be caught is imminent. So increasingly tense.
I want to have a beer first.
You want to come?
No, I do not like to drink. You go alone.
Yeah, too, had worked hard all day. Take a break. I went for a while.
What would you like to have?
Give me a bottle of beer.
Good.
I grab a towel for a while.
thanks.
Sorry.
Who are you?
Nothing.
It's okay, it's okay. Please be continued eating.
Do not look at you, I thought something happened to you.
Too stuffy in the cabin. So I went out for some fresh air. What news?
There is.
Where? What time?
Hotel Hwanggeumjeonmog-ins.
Four hours.
Think carefully! Do not acting on the train. We could all die.
From now on, you take care of yourself.
Do not come looking for me again.
Hey, Kim Woo Jin ... Our relationship is pretty up here alone.
Did not he want to break you in your seat?
Now that I think
I should accompany Lee Gyeongbu drinks.
A glass of beer.
Good.
Theatrics really convincing.
No one wants you to tell me?
These people face very similar to the person we are looking for. What do you think?
What are you talking?
From now on I gave the orders here. Fucking bastard!
I gave the orders. You just need to do it without a lot of snout.
I was a cop, show your identity card.
Wait a minute! Do not move.
Hei!
The identity card was in his wallet. Want me alone ...
You two listen good. One-one, you're going to die here.
Depending on who is calling the other party.
You have to think about it.
Kim Woo Jin.
Now!
Son of a bitch!
Move! Move!
When kunasehati, you do not want to hear.
I am a Japanese police from the police headquarters.
I'm on official duty. You all do not panic. Please return to your seat each.
Good.
Back to seat each!
You change your mind?
Not changed his mind. More precisely changed determination.
I've actually been a long time did not have the determination again.
I've long since given up.
Where can you just give up?
If we ever succeed once, I certainly would not like this.
If only by risking their lives by throwing some bombs seeds will be able to get independence.
I can not continually play dumb.
Even after arriving in Gyeongseong, there will not be any changes.
It is an impossible thing.
Even if this time I managed menghindar--
Evade? Who's with whom? You with me? With us?
If not that, you, you ... have long kubeberkan everything.
Because you are my friend, you are my family.
Should not you thank me?
I want to avenge Ok Jang Hyeong.
I'm not your friend. I do not have any feeling about you.
You want to tell this fucking kill Caucasians?
On behalf of Uilyeol-and, I execute enemy spies.
Woo Jin!
See you in hell.
After arriving in Gyeongseong, I do not know you anymore.
Take this out of the train station.
By the time we meet again, if you did not die then I live.
Or two of them died.
- = Station Gyeongseong = -
Like?
No, I'm not that person.
Get him!
Yeon Gye Soon!
Run fast!
Move! Move!
Get him!
Calm! Calm! Calm!
Let go of me!
Quiet!
Sorry.
How is your condition?
Could immediately behind the work.
After a shot and a jump from the train but you're only minor injuries.
Really lucky.
It is regrettable to lose Hashimoto.
But you also made a large contribution.
They say you can for the sake of great fishing, you throw a good bait.
You know who this is?
I know you're fluent in several languages. But it should be the most fluent Korean language, is not it?
Here was someone who could communicate with you in Korean.
Ask him where Kim Woo Jin.
Where Kim Woo Jin?
Wait a minute!
Which simply use it alone?
Kim Woo Kim Woo Jin Jin ... where? If you open your mouth, everything will be fine.
I do not know. I really do not know anything.
Lee Gyeongbu.
Bucho.
Do it!
Quick! Quick!
- Tell me! Quick to say! Fast! - Dont know.
- Fast! Quick to say! - Do not know! Do not! Do not!
Quick to say! Quick!
Please, quickly say, fast!
The skin looks pale face.
Not like that.
He said you two are very close to the time in Shanghai.
You're suspicious of me?
Everyone from the beginning has been suspect. But I do not.
Moreover, the work of an informant, due to the characteristics of his work, when carrying out tasks
Also questionable is not fair.
Terauchi Sotoku upon appointment once said so ...
"The Joseon choice is only following the orders of the Japanese or die."
Who told you were born so the Joseon?
Therefore, no matter what you've been doing,
I never disputed.
Bring Kim Woo Jin here!
U-turn!
Passport!
Seo Jin Dol!
By the way, when the new weather can be warmer?
Take him away!
Try reconfirmed!
Get out!
Can not do it like that.
Give me the damn passport!
I have a right to be here.
Police!
Quick escape! Quick!
Mother, I will travel far. You have to stay alive and waiting for my return.
Mother, you have to stay alive and waiting for my return.
Mother!
Still not want to go home?
Hei, Joo Dong Seong!
Woo Hyeong Jin came to the house looking for me.
He told me to look for Lee Jeong Chul Gyeongbu to forge an identity card.
He said you would help him.
Kim Woo Jin.
How are you all?
Gye Soon must have suffered.
Look at you. You used to be so confident.
Go, hurry!
This is a collier to Japan.
If you were to leave for Incheon, still trigger.
How are Hyeong-by?
Never seen it.
Then why here?
- Joo Dong Seong.
- Joo Dong Seong?
Did not you ask Dong Joo Seong looking for me? Identity card...
Over there! Quick chase!
Capture alive!
Shoot his legs!
Kim Woo Jin!
Lee Jeong Chul escape.
What?
Kim Woo Jin!
Lest you believe in Lee Jeong Chul?
The man who betrayed you is Lee Jeong Chul.
Where explosives?
Under your feet.
It seems to you too gentle treatment. You still look fierce.
Although I do not know how long it took, but quickly slow you'd open your mouth.
Such a thing would never happen.
Will never.
Gye Yeon Soon is your wife?
Want to hear an interesting story?
Do you think you were arrested because of information from informers?
But Yeon Gye Soon whose face has never been exposed can be caught,
because of Gye Soon Yeon picture this.
Photographed in the studio of your photos.
I want to see how long you can survive.
Never give up.
Start!
He bit his own tongue.
Explosives still not been found?
Bucho!
Lee Jeong Chul been caught.
Stand up!
Please sit.
The trial begins today.
The defendant presented.
Lee Jeong Chul.
Lee Jeong Chul...
Please come forward.
Please provide a statement.
I had to get the explosives from the hands of Kim Woo Jin
to be submitted to the police deliberately did not give information in advance.
His intention to wait after arriving at the central police station
The new all at once destroyed.
I always adhere to the work of the police.
If the mission is successful, I will be promoted to superintendent.
From before engaging in this mission, I'm sure.
I...
As the Japanese police, I just want to contribute.
I'm not a member Uilyeol-and.
I just wanted to take advantage of Kim Woo Jin.
We are not comrades, nor friend.
I am innocent.
Traitor!
You're going to hell, dog!
Unfortunately I can not kill you with my own hands.
Hey, Lee Jeong Chul!
- = A month later = -
Hei, Bisu!
Gye Yeon Soon died this morning.
Why so small?
The beautiful female prisoners.
Coming from China. Do not have friends, do not have a family.
There is no suitable place to bury them, also can not be thrown away.
There is no more time. Come on, quickly! Quick!
A bite untouched. Do not have an appetite?
Where are you going?
Higashi Bucho mana?
= Tonight there was a dinner appointment. =
= Tonight Police Department held a dinner at a Japanese entertainment clubs. =
Who are the guests at the party tonight?
= Japanese government officials, police officials and officials of Chongdok-bu. =
= Party of Japan overall pro. =
Hyeong!
Hyeong.
Please help me to secure these explosives.
I'll distract them. You hide explosives.
You crazy! Until the last second is still ...
We make an agreement.
If you get caught even have to die can not open his mouth.
To death also can not be admitted as members Uilyeol-and.
At least one of us has to stay alive.
With new so there is hope for our plan to succeed.
With so our sacrifices will not be in vain.
thanks. Without Hyeong no way I could come this far.
Kill him! Kill him!
Hei!
Semuanya, Higashi Bucho sudah keluar.
Cheers.
Street!
Police, police ...
The rumors were true?
Calm! Calm!
Hei! Hei, Si bisu!
Have you heard?
An explosion at a Japanese entertainment clubs.
Lots of people killed and seriously injured.
He said the atmosphere is chaotic. Like hell on earth.
But I heard he said the explosives were smuggled by Uilyeol-and from Shanghai,
half were not found.
It makes people more frightened.
Yes also, from being seized by the Japanese.
But there is one thing, if people found out I used my money to finance the military can bring problems.
You have to promise me. Before independence, it must be kept secret.
Do you think could be free, Yeonggam?
With the people like you, independence was only a matter of time.
Yeonggam, it costs how much?
These people, in Gyeongseong are more numerous than dogs are a medal of Chongdok-bu.
If so, try specify approximately how much it costs.
Amount you get by selling Kim Jang Ok.
Who said that? Jo Dong Hoi Ryeong or Joo Seong?
It kuhadiahkan you.
You're sure to be successful.
News Danjang-nim okay?
Yes, he was fine.
After hearing what happened with the mission this time, he cried for a long time.
Then he said something like this:
"Even if it fails, still persist."
"Hit the failure and keep going forward."
"It will eventually stand on higher ground."
There was to be conveyed to the Danjang-nim?
Will certainly meet again.
Although unsuccessful, still persist.
Step on the failure and keep going forward.
Will eventually stand on higher ground.
Thank you for using subtitle of: ~Su ~
SU
~ SU
~ SU ~
and look forward to our next work. ~