I bought some things Tiffany will need.
They're things she'll need right away.
I bought clothes a size bigger, too,
so she can wear them next year.
Tiffany is prone to colds,
so be sure to put a jacket on her in April.
You're flying out tomorrow, right?
Before you go,
can you let me see her one more time?
I'll get going now.
Areum.
You raise Tiffany.
Really?
Do you mean it?
Tiffany...
I can really raise her?
Go before I change my mind.
Thank you.
Thank you!
What happened?
Phillip...
Phillip said I could take her.
He said I could raise her.
What?
Really?
Tiffany, come here.
How did this happen?
It feels like a dream.
That I...
That I can raise my little girl.
I can't believe it.
Is this for real?
This is great. I'm so happy.
This is wonderful.
Tiffany...
Consent Form to Relinquish Parental Custody Rights
I know the way you love Tiffany
is different from mine,
but I know that it's real.
That's why you underwent
this surgery despite complications.
Thank you.
You did for Tiffany what I couldn't.
I...
I don't regret having met you.
Without you,
I wouldn't have Tiffany.
She is not only my daughter,
but yours, too.
I've been pushing you away too much.
I'm really sorry.
I acknowledge the fact that
you are Tiffany's dad.
So...
Please wake up soon.
I'm sure that's what Tiffany wants, too.
Myeonghwa, no matter
where Tiffany goes, she'll be fine.
So don't worry so much, okay?
Of course.
And America isn't as far as you think.
This goodbye isn't forever, so don't be sad.
Myeonghwa.
If you're tired, you should go to your room.
Yeah, you must be worn out from crying.
Let's go in and lie down.
Areum!
I'm back.
Areum, what happened?
Why is Tiffany...
You couldn't go to Phillip and just came back?
It's for the better. Good going.
That's not it, mom.
Phillip...
Phillip told me to raise Tiffany.
Are you... Are you serious?
Phillip said that?
Then, Phillip changed his mind?
Yes, dad.
Tiffany, come to grandma!
Oh, my darling Tiffany.
Thank you so much for coming back to us.
Thank you, Tiffany!
Thank you! Yes, yes.
You're a sweetheart.
They say life is full of ups and downs,
and it must be true.
What a pretty girl.
What a pretty little girl.
I sent Tiffany to Areum.
You got her to sign the consent form!
What are you saying?
I tore that up.
It means nothing now.
You...
I thought Tiffany would be happier
being with Areum than being with me,
so I decided to do that.
Please respect my wishes, father.
Oh, geez...
Unbelievable...
What about us going to the States?
We'll go as planned.
Let's leave tomorrow.
It must've been a tough day for Tiffany,
but she's still going strong.
Yeah, my family must have worn her out
from all the hugs and kisses,
but she's got energy left.
I can tell she's healthier.
Yeah.
It's been an eventful day for her, too...
From now on, I'll make sure
you never part with Tiffany again.
No matter what happens,
I'll protect the two of you.
If you weren't there for me,
I don't know how I would've gotten through it.
Forget all the difficulties.
Let's focus on being happy from now on.
I'll forget the hardships of the past, too.
From now on,
I'll live only for you and Tiffany.
I'll do that, too.
Who is it?
Are you going to answer it?
There's still time.
Go ahead.
Okay.
Don't disappear like last time.
I won't.
Where are you?
I'm at the airport.
I'm leaving soon.
Can I see you for a second?
You won't get to see Tiffany for a while,
so I thought I'd bring her to see you off.
No need to come all this way.
Hold her.
I'll keep you posted on how she's doing.
And whenever you miss her,
you can video chat with her.
You and I will be too busy.
Just send me some pictures.
I'll want to see her growing up.
Thank you.
I'll raise her well enough for both of us.
So that when you see her in the future,
you'll be proud.
I'll raise her to be a great person.
Cheon Seongun...
He seems like he'll make a good dad.
When Tiffany was sick,
he asked me to help save her.
He even knelt down in front of me.
With dedication like that,
he deserves to be Tiffany's dad.
I could never do that.
I should get going.
You won't be back for a while, right?
Probably not.
Then stay well, wherever you go.
And I wish you and Suji happiness.
Thanks.
I wish you the same with Seongun.
Seongun, there's a lot I should apologize for.
I won't ask you to forgive me,
but please take good care of those two.
Take care.
Tiffany.
Say bye to daddy.
Bye.
Let's get out, ladies.
Are you ready?
Yes, I'm ready.
Want something to calm your nerves?
No, thanks. I'm fine.
Let me have Tiffany.
Here we go!
Let's go inside.
He said he'd come with Areum,
but they're late. Should I call?
No need. I'm sure they'll be here soon.
President Cheon.
You won't oppose Areum this time, right?
What do you mean, oppose her?
I promised Seongun that I'd accept her
if the baby issue was taken care of.
Seongun.
I'm here, father.
Hello, President Cheon.
The baby...
You said Phillip took her to the States.
Well...
Areum regained custody of her.
Regained custody?
Yes, Phillip gave up custody of Tiffany,
so Areum can raise her again.
That's a relief.
That's great, Areum.
President Cheon, let's sit down and talk.
Have a seat.
Don't you dare.
I thought the child was taken care of,
so I said to bring Areum over,
and you bring the child, too?
Are you kidding me right now?
President Cheon.
You might as well accept them now.
Accept them?
I don't even know anymore.
You do whatever you want.
I think he's taken aback.
I'll talk to him later,
so don't worry too much.
Thank you.
Go up to Seongun's room.
I'll bring some fruit.
Thank you.
- Come on. / - Okay.
Sir.
You made Areum feel bad.
How could you go in here like this?
Is Seongun out of his mind?
I made myself clear to him before,
so he should get it right!
Sir.
I know you have a grudge against Phillip,
but the baby did nothing wrong.
And Seongun loves the baby so much.
Mom, grandma's here.
- She is? / - Yup.
She's here with her landlord.
Her landlord?
Why would he come with her?
Are you nervous?
Of course. It's the first time I'm saying hello.
You have no reason to be nervous.
We're just here to inform them.
We're not here to get permission.
Then I'll just trust you on that.
Mom, what are you doing here?
Hello, nice to meet you.
I'm Kim Seongcheol.
Oh, hello.
What brings you here...
This won't be brief,
so we should all sit down. You, too.
Mother, what's going on?
I came with Seongcheol to say something.
To say something?
Listen up.
From now on, Seongcheol and I
will begin a new chapter together.
What?
What...
Mother, are you saying you'll
marry this man or something?
No, we won't go all out like that.
We're just thinking about
moving in together.
What?
But you seem around my age...
And you'll be my father-in-law?
I suppose so.
If you want labels and such, I guess so.
Grandma, unbelievable...
No way. I won't allow it!
Brat.
I don't need your permission.
I'm not asking you to buy us a house.
We won't bother you, so don't worry.
Sir!
Sir, are you alright?
- I don't even know anymore! / - Dohyeong.
Everyone can move in together
or get married or whatever!
What?
This will drive me to an early grave...
We're so busy today.
I feel bad leaving you alone like this.
I asked my friends to come help,
so don't worry and go ahead.
Okay, just for today.
I'm late.
I'll be back. Sorry about this.
Please congratulate them for me.
Okay. Thanks!
You're not in your hanbok yet?
Oh, my gosh!
Pretty, huh?
You can't put on so much today.
Why not? It's pretty.
We're going for a reserved look today.
That's the concept.
Myeonghwa, hold on, okay?
Let me wipe the lipstick off of you.
I'll help you put it on again.
I like being pretty.
Eungmin might come today.
Eungmin?
Yeah, handsome Eungmin.
I don't know if he's coming today.
Myeonghwa, for now...
Let me wipe this off.
For now...
Myeonghwa, say ah.
Oh!
Okay, then you do that. Hold still.
Ah!
Look at you being silly.
You're so adorable.
Hold still.
You look pretty.
We'll put on your hanbok, okay? And wipe this.
I hope he comes today.
Eungmin.
Close your eyes.
Who's this beauty?
Are you an angel from heaven?
I had no idea you could be so elegant.
I like being pretty better.
You do look pretty.
He's right. You look great.
Really?
Really.
You look pretty.
Now that we're ready, let's get going.
Honey.
Seongho, you look great.
Dad, why isn't Mr. Jang here yet?
He's not here yet?
I'll call him.
Oh, geez.
Why are you here so late?
Sir, I'm sorry,
but I don't think I can attend today.
You can't? Why not?
If I go there,
I'll be a laughingstock.
I can hear people's laughter
ringing in my ears already.
What are you saying?
I was in such a rush
that I didn't double-check my clothes...
You are all kinds of trouble.
I thought I told you to lose weight.
I'm sorry, sir.
Get him a pair of my dress pants.
Okay.
Please get the biggest size he has.
You're here.
You got here first.
Haebang, watch your step.
Your feet will hurt standing around.
You should sit down inside.
What took you so long? You said you'd be here.
Don't even ask.
Haebang's fans wouldn't let her go.
We'll be late. Let's go in.
Let's go. Careful.
Bride, Han Areum
Congratulations.
Areum's going to get rich at this rate.
Are you jealous that she's getting married?
Of course.
I wonder when we'll be hearing wedding bells.
Just wait a bit longer.
I'll marry you as soon as I can make money.
You're too sweet.
Here you are, Jinwu.
Hi!
Here's my gift.
I'm giving it to the bride's side,
since the groom's side is loaded.
We should chip in where it's needed.
Thank you.
I hear you're doing really well for yourself.
Jinwu told me.
Thanks to Haebang,
I feel like I've hit the second peak in life.
Anyway, see you inside.
He must be doing super well.
He finally got himself a good singer.
Wow.
I hear the buffet here is amazing.
I hear the steak will melt in your mouth.
Really? Want to go eat right now?
I didn't have breakfast, so I'm starving.
We have to see the bride and groom enter.
- Let's wait. / - Alright.
Hey, kids! What are you doing on my turf?
Wow! You look amazing!
You look like a movie star.
Amazing!
Hey, I was born looking this good.
Go hang out over there.
I can't hang out.
Okay, see you later.
- Congratulations. / - Thanks.
Let's go.
Thank you.
Seongun, congratulations.
Father, you're here.
Stop smiling so much.
Congratulations, Seongun.
Thank you.
Yuni, what are you doing here?
I heard from our friends.
I'm hurt.
How could you not invite me?
Sorry.
You're marrying Areum after all, huh?
- Congratulations. / - Thanks.
Life in Jeju-do must be good.
You've gotten even prettier.
The air is great there.
Come visit me in Jeju-do with Areum.
I'll show you a lot of great places.
Okay, we'll go there.
See you in the wedding hall.
Don't get too nervous.
See you in a bit.
Thank you.
Honey, why...
Why is Shoe Man over there greeting people?
Shoe Man is marrying Areum today.
Oh, my.
Then Shoe Man
will be my son-in-law?
Yes. You like that, don't you?
You like Shoe Man.
I do like him.
Shoe Man got really lucky.
He gets to marry Areum.
Tiffany, you're all dressed up.
Don't you look so pretty?
What a pretty girl.
You like that?
Areum Han!
Louis!
- Congratulations, Areum. / - Congrats.
Thank you so much for coming.
Areum Han, you look really beautiful today.
Her face is glowing! How radiant!
This is how a blushing bride should be.
You look amazing.
I'll give you that.
What brand is the wedding dress?
That's not important.
She'd make anything look luxurious.
Yeah, I mean, who knew
you'd marry the heir of Winners Group?
Yeah.
When did you two get so close?
Let's hear that story another time.
Why don't we take pictures first?
Yes, pictures!
Tiffany, let me hold you!
Look pretty!
One, two, three, cheese!
Tiffany!
We'll get going now. See you in a bit.
How did you...
We came to see Tiffany and everything.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
Tiffany's gotten so big.
Can I hold her?
Of course.
Tiffany, daddy's here.
Let's go to daddy.
Here we go.
She's gotten heavier.
Are you well?
She is, thanks to you.
What about you?
Philip's well, too.
I've been taking good care of him.
I see.
Tiffany.
It's me. Daddy's here.
Daddy's here. Let me see you.
How adorable.
Hello.
Hello, Ms. Oh.
What brings you here?
Pardon?
I'm here because my daughter
is getting married today.
I see...
I'm here because my son's getting married.
Oh, my! Congratulations!
Oh, I see.
Thank you.
Mom, why are you over here?
Your seat is over there.
Jinwu, this man's son
is getting married today, too.
Mom, let's go over to that side.
Okay.
Goodbye now.
Are you not feeling well?
You don't look well.
I'm fine.
Why aren't they starting?
The groom will now enter.
He's so excited about seeing his bride
that he can't stop smiling.
I can tell he's going to be a fool for his wife.
And today's lady of the hour.
The beautiful bride will now enter.
Here comes the bride.
I can't believe I'm the officiator today.
Life leads you
to places you'd never imagine you'd be.
You become family with people
you'd never have imagined.
And we call that destiny.
If you find a kind person to be with,
they say you'll be happy for 30 years.
But if you find a dependable person,
you'll be happy for life.
Honey.
Isn't our Areum so beautiful?
She looks like an angel.
I didn't know our little girl was so pretty.
But honey...
Why do I keep crying?
Upon the green pastures
I'd like to build a lovely house
And live forevermore with my beloved
For 100 years to come
Sow seeds in spring
And watch flowers bloom in summer
In fall, we reap the bounty
And in winter, we're as happy as can be
Tall buildings may boast great heights
And living the trendy life can be nice...
I'll take the picture now.
Ready? One, two...
Wait!
Here comes Tiffany.
Our little Tiffany.
Tiffany.
Tiffany...
How adorable.
Tiffany.
Tiffany, go to daddy.
You look so pretty.
Are you happy?
Okay, I'm really taking the picture now.
One, two...
It's Eungmin!
Thank you for watching "Love & Secret"