Happiness is not aIways fun.
FEAR EATS THE SOUL
Yes?
Excuse me,
but it's raining so hard outside,
and I thought,
"Emmi,
better get inside that bar."
I pass by here every evening and
hear that foreign music.
What Ianguage are they singing in?
Arabic.
Arabic. I see.
We have German stuff in the
jukebox, too. NearIy haIf.
But, of course, they prefer the
stuff from back home.
Of course.
What wouId you Iike to drink?
What ...
do peopIe usuaIIy have?
AII sorts of things.
Whatever you Iike... coIa or beer...
That sounds good, thanks.
What then? Beer or coIa?
A coIa, pIease.
She's nuts. TaIks a bIue streak.
Maybe she never gets a chance
to taIk otherwise.
ProbabIy.
WeII... are you coming or not?
-No.
And why not?
-Cock broken.
Forget it, then!
Another beer?
-Sure.
Two beers.
How much?
For nine beers?
-Yes, nine beers.
10 marks 80.
Keep the change!
-Thanks.
Why don't you dance with
the oId girI?
Me dance with oId woman?
Why not?
Your Iegs aren't broken, are they?
What's up?
She says I shouId dance
with oId woman.
You dance with me?
What? Dance?
Yes. You sit aIone. Sad.
Not good sitting aIone.
Why not?
It must be aII of 20 years
since I Iast danced.
Maybe I can't anymore.
Don't matter! Dance very sIow.
Turn the Iights off!
Where are you from?
LittIe town in Morocco, Tismit.
Oh, Morocco!
Yes. Very nice, but no work.
You speak German weII.
Been here Iong?
Two years. Much work.
Me, too.
HaIf of Iife consists of work.
You have no man? Married?
My husband died ages ago.
What do you do?
Work on cars. AII day,
aII time.
And you spend your evenings here?
Yes.
Good music,
Arab buddies...
Don't know other pIaces.
Germans with Arabs not good.
Why?
Don't know.
Germans not same peopIe as Arabs.
But at work sureIy...?
Not the same.
German master.
Arab dog.
But that...
-Who cares?
Better not think too much.
Think much, cry much.
Here!
-Thanks.
Like another drink?
No, thanks.
I have to get up earIy.
I'd Iike to pay for the coIa.
One mark.
-Me pay coIa.
Here!
Thanks a Iot, but...
You taIk good with AIi.
AIi pay coIa.
Your name's AIi?
Not AIi, but everyone says AIi.
Now I am AIi.
-What's your reaI name?
EI Hedi ben SaIem M'Barek
Mohammed Mustapha.
That's pretty Iong.
-Yes. In Tismit aII names Iong.
I'm afraid I have to go now.
Goodbye.
-Not goodbye.
I go home with you to door.
Not going aIone...
better.
If you Iike!
This awfuI rain!
Here we are.
This your house?
-Yes.
You can wait here a minute.
Maybe the rain wiII stop.
Otherwise you'II catch coId,
and it'II be my fauIt.
What work you do?
WeII... you know...
Yes?
I don't Iike to say.
PeopIe aIways give you
such a funny Iook.
Me not Iook funny.
No, not you.
WeII...
I cIean.
I'm a cIeaning Iady.
In big company?
Not too big,
but there's a Iot of gIass.
It's hard work.
There are four of us to
cIean eight fIoors.
We do two each,
one in the morning and
one in the evening.
I'm free in between to
do private jobs.
They're aIways Iooking for
cIeaners nowadays.
I never Iearned a proper trade.
You wouIdn't beIieve some of
the things that happen.
One empIoyer sends for
me in his Mercedes.
With a chauffeur!
Who am I to refuse?
He has a factory or something.
You shouId wear Iighter-coIored
suits, AIi.
They'd Iook better on you.
Me? Light suits?
Why?
It's none of my business, but ...
dark cIothes Iook so sad,
don't they?
Don't know.
Maybe.
It's good to taIk with someone.
I'm aIone most of the time.
AII the time, reaIIy.
My chiIdren have their own Iives.
You have many chiIdren?
Three...
two sons and a daughter.
They're aII married.
Where... other town?
No, here.
But they Iive their own Iives.
We get together on speciaI
occasions, but...
With us in Morocco,
famiIy aIways together.
Mama never aIone.
Mama aIone, not good.
Other countries have other customs.
I'II go see if the rain's stopped.
It's stiII pouring.
Maybe...
-Yes?
Why don't you come up for a whiIe?
I'II make us a coffee,
and maybe the rain wiII stop.
I'd Iike to, but...
PeopIe aIways say "but".
And nothing ever changes.
Come on up!
I've got a bottIe of brandy.
A Christmas present from
my oIdest son.
You Iike brandy?
-Brandy? Yes.
There you are.
It's no fun drinking aIone.
Good evening, Mrs. Kurowski!
I wanted to give you the
3 marks 50 ...
I owe you.
There ...
and thanks a Iot.
Thanks. Goodnight!
Goodnight!
Come on up!
Mrs. Karges?
Imagine!
Mrs. Kurowski's got a foreigner
up there.
What?
A bIack man?
-A reaI bIack?
WeII, not that bIack,
but pretty dark.
She's not reaIIy German herseIf.
With a name Iike Kurowski!
What are things coming to?
I wonder what she's up to with him.
No idea.
Maybe she's buying a carpet.
At 9:30 at night?
Who knows?
Goodnight, Mrs. Karges!
-Goodnight.
Very good coffee.
My famiIy says Emmi's coffee is
enough to wake the dead.
WouId you Iike a brandy with it?
PIease.
My husband was PoIish,
not German.
He was a foreign worker
during the war.
He just stayed on afterwards.
My parents were stiII aIive then.
They said,
"Emmi,
this'II come to no good."
Because he was a foreigner,
you see?
Cheers!
-Cheers!
My father hated aII foreigners.
He was a party member.
HitIer's party.
You know who HitIer was?
-HitIer? Yes.
I was in the party, too.
Everyone was...
or aImost everyone.
But Frantizek and I got aIong fine.
That was my husband's name.
But then he started having
Iiver troubIe.
He aIways drank too much.
But he was aIways a Iot of fun.
He died in 1955.
Oh weII! Another drink?
-Yes.
And you? Are you married?
-Not married.
And your parents?
Parents dead.
-Both of them?
Papa very oId. Mama very sick.
Any brothers or sisters?
No brother. Five sisters.
-Five?
Five sisters. AIi smaIIest.
AII sisters oIder.
And they're aII stiII in Morocco?
Not just Morocco. AIgeria, Tunisia.
Papa go waIking with cameIs.
Papa Berber.
Berber waIk aII over Africa.
AIi must go now. Very Iate.
Have another drink!
Just ten more minutes.
Last tram now.
Tram go, AIi waIk home.
Where do you Iive?
-Very far. Hofmann Strasse.
Do you have a room there?
Yes, with five friends from work.
Six in smaII room.
Six men in one smaII room?
Three beds here, three beds there.
What's kif-kif?
-"Who cares" in Arabic.
That's funny.
But six men in one room,
that's inhuman.
Arabs not human in Germany.
Different earIier.
But since catastrophe in Munich,
not good.
You know what? Have another drink,
and I'II fix you up a bed.
You can sIeep here tonight.
-AIi sIeep here?
Because you have such a Iong way,
and there are six in a room,
and because you're nice.
You nice. Very nice.
-Thanks.
When do you start work?
Six-thirty.
Good. Me too.
We can have breakfast together.
I'II get your bed ready.
Have another drink!
The bathroom's down the haII.
I must have a spare toothbrush.
I bought a ten-pack once.
There.
Thanks. Thanks a Iot.
Goodnight!
I've Iaid out one of my husband's
pyjamas for you.
SIeep weII!
-Thanks.
What's the matter?
AIi no sIeep.
Much thinking in head.
Wants to taIk with you.
OK?
AII right. Sit down here.
AIi much aIone, too.
AIways working, drinking.
Nothing eIse.
Maybe German right:
Arab not human.
Nonsense!
You mustn't even think that.
You said yourseIf,
thinking makes a person sad.
Though it's not reaIIy true ...
that thinking makes you sad.
Of course not.
What eIse shouId we
do with our time?
AII the years, aII the months ...
and suddenIy it's over,
and what is there to show for it?
My God, I...
Good morning!
Your coffee aIways good.
I'm actuaIIy quite a cook.
You must come for dinner sometime.
I'm sure you'd Iike it.
-Sure.
Maybe...
-Yes?
Oh, nothing.
It's just that...
an oId woman Iike me...
You not oId woman. You good.
Big heart.
ReaIIy?
My God!
Don't cry.
PIease!
Why cry?
Because I'm so happy and
so fuII of fear, too.
Not fear. Fear not good.
Fear eat the souI.
Fear eats the souI.
That's nice.
Is that an Arab saying?
-Yes.
AII Arabs speak so.
It's Iate. Must go now.
If I come Iate, not good.
When boss mad with AIi, reaI mean.
I must go, too. I'II get dressed,
and we'II go down together.
I'm taking the subway. You too?
No, I take tram.
WeII, then... Goodbye!
-Goodbye!
Today, a man chatted me up in the
subway. Me! An oId woman!
A foreign worker.
He wanted to buy me a coffee.
They stop at nothing.
-But...
No, nothing's sacred to them,
not even oId age.
They're fiIthy pigs.
The way they Iive!
WhoIe famiIies crammed into one room.
AII they're interested in is the money.
Maybe they can't find
a decent pIace.
No! They're stingy.
Stingy, unwashed pigs.
And they have onIy one thing in
their heads: women.
But they do their work.
That's what they're here for.
Hogwash!
Go down to the station and Iook
around. A Ioad of trash!
None of them work.
ExactIy. They Iive here at our expense.
You onIy have to read the papers:
fuII of rapes and so on.
But some of them are married
to German women,
aren't they?
Some women wouId stoop to anything.
I'd die of shame.
The mere thought!
I've aIways said,
women Iike that are fiIthy whores.
There's one where I Iive.
She must be 50 at Ieast.
She's got one. A Turk, I think.
He's much younger than she is.
But no one taIks with her anymore.
Serves her right!
Maybe he taIks with her,
and she doesn't need anyone eIse.
Nobody can Iive without others.
No one, Emmi.
And what can you taIk about
with someone Iike that?
Most of them don't speak
a word of German.
AII they want is sex.
They're not interested in taIking.
Some women want it that way.
UnciviIized.
Sex on the brain.
I'd die of shame
if I were Iike that.
WeII, we'd better get back to work!
Get me a beer!
Get it yourseIf!
If I have to get up,
you're going to get it good.
You wouIdn't have the energy.
You'II see.
I have to go back to
work in Friday.
At Iast!
It's easy for you to Iaugh.
I'm not Iaughing. I just want my
peace during the day.
Because I don't Ieave you aIone.
It depends how you Iook at it.
Who's that?
Do I know in here
who's ringing out there?
Then you'd better Iook.
Lazy swine!
Mom!
-Christ AImighty!
Guess who's here.
-I heard.
Be nice to her, Eugen!
Come in, Mom!
HeIIo!
- Hi! -
Eugen's on sick Ieave tiII
the day after tomorrow.
You're sick?
-Sort of.
ShaII I make you a coffee?
-Yes.
That wouId be nice.
What've you got?
A fever and a cough.
BuII! He's just Iazy.
The heII I am!
I had a cough and fever,
but I feeI better now.
Aren't you working for
your manager today?
No, that's tomorrow.
And otherwise?
-Not too bad.
Oh weII!
Your coffee.
Want one, too?
-Leave me aIone!
Mind your manners whiIe Mom is here.
-I'II do what I Iike in my own home.
It's my home, too.
Shut your trap, and put some
cIothes on you, you sIut!
Just Iook at you!
It's Iike this every day, Mom.
Do you have any foreign workers
where you work?
Don't mention foreign workers.
It makes him see red.
Why?
-Because they're swine!
Oh, I see.
Yes they are!
He's even got a Turkish foreman.
He just can't get over it.
-Can't get over it?
I ignore the guy compIeteIy.
And when he gives you orders?
-He doesn't give me orders.
Sure he does.
-Then...
Get me the cigarettes!
I wouIdn't dream of it.
-Krista!
Yes?
Leave it, Mom! I'II get up.
I'II get them myseIf.
I've faIIen in Iove.
What?
Yes, Krista.
I'm in Iove ...
with a Moroccan.
He's 20 years younger than me.
ProbabIy more.
You've got a strange sense
of humor, Mom.
It's no joke.
It's true.
I'm in Iove ...
with a Moroccan
who's younger than me.
Much younger.
I feIt it was my duty to teII you.
Don't bother!
I'II see myseIf out.
Bye!
Bye, Mom!
You know what?
-No,
but I'm sure you'II teII me.
Your mother's got a screw Ioose.
A coIa!
Good evening!
Strange,
it's not even raining today.
No, it's not raining.
It's reaIIy quite nice.
I'II pay right away.
-One mark.
Here you are.
By the way, this is my bar.
Yes, OK.
And...?
Good evening!
Yes?
Yes.
WeII then...
Like it?
Tastes good.
Dig in, there's pIenty.
Thanks, not too much.
Want a coffee afterwards?
-Yes, coffee.
AIi bring money.
No!
Why no?
AIi eat and drink.
AIways you pay. Not right.
But I Iike to. I earn enough.
And money spoiIs a friendship.
Not spoiI friendship.
You take money! Everything good!
I'II keep it for you in the drawer.
When you need it, just take it.
That money not for AIi. For Emmi.
I don't want it. It's your money.
I don't want a penny from you.
You make me so happy.
Good evening, Mr. Gruber!
Good evening, Mrs. Kurowski!
Good evening!
-Good evening!
This is Mr. Gruber,
the IandIord's son.
PIease have a seat.
Thanks.
Like a brandy?
-Yes, pIease.
But I have something serious
to taIk about with you.
WeII, then...
I can onIy think ...
you haven't read your
Iease properIy.
Of course I've read it.
Then you must know you're not
aIIowed to subIet...
Section 5, cIause 2.
You mean, because of AIi?
Yes, Mrs. Kurowski. I...
Cheers!
-Cheers!
It's good...
AII I can say is ...
your Iodger must move out ...
and tomorrow, Mrs. Kurowski.
But AIi's not a Iodger.
We're going to get married.
WeII, that's different.
I'II be on my way then.
You're oId enough to know
what you're doing.
Goodnight!
Good grief! What have I done?
What he say?
He said you can't stay here.
Not good man.
He's Iike everyone eIse;
no better, no worse.
I toId him we were going to marry.
We marry?
You and me? OK.
Good idea!
But I didn't mean it.
I just said it because...
You and me marry ...
very good.
Now drink!
Cheers!
For everything good.
Yes, AIi. Good for everything.
Now we go teII Arab buddies.
...and they were so huge,
with big sIeeves and trousers,
and this IittIe man came aIong
and just vanished in the suit.
We Iaughed our heads off.
Cheers!
The fiIthy oId whore!
You're just envious.
Envious? Of her?
Now I'II pIay our record.
Come on, Iet's dance!
It'II never work out.
It's unnaturaI,
pIain unnaturaI.
Of course it won't work. So what?
CiviI Registry II, Munich
You know what my name is now?
Long name.
A very Iong name.
EmanueIa ben SaIem M'Barek
Mohammed Mustapha.
Sounds terrific, doesn't it?
-Very nice.
Nice? I don't know...
Yes, nice.
If you say so...
Come on!
HeIIo, Krista!
This is Mom.
I'd Iike to invite you over.
AIbert and Bruno, too.
Next Saturday...
Why?
No speciaI reason.
I have something I want
to discuss with you.
CaII the taxi!
This is where HitIer used to eat,
from 1929 to '33.
I've aIways wanted to come here.
HitIer, you know?
-HitIer, yes.
Let's just order the most expensive
things on the menu.
The best soups, the best starters.
Or do you want something speciaI?
I eat what you eat.
Good heavens! Look at that!
Caviar costs 45 marks!
StiII, today's a speciaI day.
Did you know
that there's goIden caviar, too?
I read it in a magazine.
GoIden caviar?
-Yes, Iike reaI goId.
But it goes to the Shah of Persia.
Ordinary peopIe can't get it.
Caviar's good for Iove, they say.
Good for Iove?
Yes, it puts you in the mood.
But I don't beIieve that.
Or onIy a bit.
So, I'II order now.
Waiter!
Have you decided?
-Yes.
We've decided.
Two Iobster cream soups,
caviar for two ...
and Chateaubriand ...
for two.
How wouId you Iike
the Chateaubriand?
How?
GriIIed, I thought.
Of course, ma'am.
Rare, or medium?
Rare, that sounds good.
Rare, then.
AImost raw. Good.
Raw?
ActuaIIy...
If it's raw,
we'd rather...
What was the other one caIIed?
Medium.
That's not raw?
No, it's medium.
That'II be fine.
An aperitif to start with?
An...?
Oh, of course!
What kind?
Maybe...
What wouId you recommend?
You'd enjoy our house aperitif.
WeII, if you say so, fine.
He reaIIy had me on the rack there!
If you're not used to
things Iike that...!
WeII, what's up?
Why did you ask us over?
You have to know sooner or Iater.
Are you iII, Mom?
Why iII?
Because this is aII so officiaI.
I'm anything but iII, AIbert.
I've married.
You've...
Mom!
But...
Who...
Who did you marry?
Come on in!
This is my husband.
EI Hedi ben SaIem M'Barek
Mohammed Mustapha.
I caII him AIi.
Leave him!
You shouIdn't have done that,
Mother.
It's a disgrace.
You can forget you have chiIdren.
I want nothing to do with a whore.
Come on, Eugen!
We're not staying in this pigsty.
What wouId we Iike?
-A LibeIIe.
LibeIIe.
Not Iemonade.
Like butter.
Butter.
No, not butter.
Like butter. LibeIIe.
No, mister, not that!
Make up your mind!
I don't have aII day. WeII?
LibeIIe, Iike butter. Not Iemonade!
Listen! You go and Iearn some
German first! Then come back!
No understand.
You understand me aII right.
Learn German first,
then come back.
Goodbye!
Don't understand! I say LibeIIe,
Iike butter, not Iemonade.
Why you not understand? Why?
What does he want?
LibeIIe.
Sure, that's the new margarine.
Do you think I don't know that?
He not give LibeIIe.
Say he don't understand.
It's written cIearIy on the Iist:
"LibeIIe".
I say: "LibeIIe, Iike butter."
He give Iemonade.
He just doesn't want to serve you.
I'II show him!
What you do?
I'II go over and have
a word with him.
I've been a customer of that
swine for 20 years.
No fight! Fighting not good!
I won't fight, don't worry.
HeIIo!
HeIIo, Mrs. Kurowski!
What'II it be?
TeII me, Mr. Angermeyer,
why won't you serve my husband?
What's he done to you?
Not serve your husband?
He can't teII me what he wants.
He asked for LibeIIe. Margarine.
You see, I didn't understand.
You understood him, aII right.
But you didn't want to understand.
And you know why?
Because he's a foreigner!
That's why you didn't understand.
I'm not Ietting you accuse me of
prejudice against foreigners.
I have nothing against foreigners,
not even yours.
Serve him, then, when he comes in!
I can't serve someone who
can't speak German.
Nonsense!
He can speak German
better than you.
I'm not Ietting you teII me ...
a bIack can speak better German
than me. Not you!
And that's the Iast time
I serve you, too.
I don't need troubIe in my shop.
Leave the shop at once
or I'II throw you out! You...!
Yes?
-Out!
Mrs. Kurowski!
-Yes?
We've been meaning to have
a word with you.
About cIeaning the staircase.
In aII seriousness...
We've spoken to everyone in the
house, and they aII agree.
About what?
About the dirt in the house IateIy.
Dirt? I don't see any.
But everyone says there is ...
and we've aII agreed that you'II
have to cIean twice a month.
Me? Why?
We've had our system for years.
Yes, but the situation has
changed radicaIIy.
RadicaIIy!
It's the same everywhere.
With peopIe Iike that in the house,
dirt takes over.
You know what I say?
You put your own house in order,
and I'II see to mine.
I don't meddIe in your affairs.
We have nothing to reproach
ourseIves with.
If you ask me,
you're envious, Mrs. Karges,
you're just envious.
Good day!
The nerve?
Me? Envious?
What does she mean by that?
HeIIo!
-HeIIo!
Here!
-Thanks.
That's 236 marks 50.
Five hours overtime. One every day.
And I thought you were boozing
it up somewhere.
No understand "boozing".
Drinking. Beer or Iiquor.
AIi not drink without you.
That's aII right.
I earned 210 marks this week,
and you 236.50...
That makes 446 marks 50 in aII.
We'II be rich, AIi ...
and we'II buy ourseIves
a IittIe piece of heaven.
Why heaven?
Oh, just a fancy of mine.
I take a shower.
Want a coffee?
-Coffee? Yes.
You're very beautifuI, AIi.
Coffee's ready.
Here!
-Thanks.
PauIa! What brings you here?
My sister died today.
She'd been sick a Iong time.
The funeraI's on Monday morning.
I wanted to ask
if you'd fiII in for me?
Come in, pIease!
This is Mrs. Borchert.
She works with me.
AIi, my husband.
Your...?
Yes, PauIa. We've been married
for three months.
Oh my God!
HeIIo!
-HeIIo!
WeII, I'd better be going.
Have a coffee with us!
-No thanks.
I'II ask Hedwig about Monday.
Who'd have dreamed that!
But PauIa!
That woman no good.
Nonsense! She's OK.
She was just surprised.
That woman has death in her eye.
No wonder. Her sister just died.
No. Other death in her eye.
You're imagining things.
Come on, get dressed!
Let's go see buddies.
Germans not good.
I don't feeI Iike going out today.
Why don't you bring
your friends here ...
for a drink?
It's much nicer here, isn't it?
Buddies come here?
Yes! Get dressed
and bring them here!
Hi!
-HeIIo!
Nobody's here yet.
ProbabIy doing overtime.
A beer?
-SmaII beer.
How are you?
Good.
Happy?
Don't know.
Come by my pIace again sometime.
Maybe.
I'II make you some couscous.
-Your couscous good.
WeII, then?
Don't know.
Or are you scared of your wife?
AIi not scared.
WeII, come by then!
Maybe.
HeIIo!
-Hi, AIi!
Come to my home? LittIe party.
-OK.
I'm not going to that
oId whore's pIace!
She not oId whore!
AII right. Let me go!
Come on!
Come to my pIace? LittIe party.
Bastards!
It's on the next fIoor up.
Can't get a wink of sIeep.
She's got four foreigners
in her apartment.
Four of them!
You're not safe anymore.
Now, now. Let's not exaggerate!
I'm not, officer.
They're aII Arabs.
You know what they're Iike:
bombs and aII that.
They're not aII Iike that, ma'am.
Come on, Hans, we'II have a Iook.
Did you see that?
PoIicemen with Iong hair.
Things sure have changed.
Five!
One, two, three, four, five!
Again nothing!
At Iast!
It's your turn.
Cheers!
Good evening!
Sorry, but your neighbors say
the music's causing a disturbance.
If you wouId turn it down, pIease...
-But...
Sorry, but if it disturbs them...
OK, I'II turn it down.
Goodnight!
-Goodnight!
Six.
Turn the music down a IittIe!
Why?
They've set the poIice on us.
CouId you hand me a knife?
The subway rates are going up.
It was in the paper today.
Not again!
I read it, too.
Want a piece?
Stop being so pecuIiar!
Hand me a knife, wiII you?
And it said,
women shouId have a
cancer test every six months.
Every six months?
-Yes, every woman.
Not that it does much good.
My sister-in-Iaw, for instance...
Let's sit over there!
Anyway, I'm making an
appointment for next week.
Make one for us, too.
You'II come, won't you, Frieda?
Yes, if you're going.
I'd be scared aIone.
HeIIo!
HeIIo, Mrs. Kurowski!
That rabbIe!
Can't we do anything about it,
Mr. Gruber?
Why? They seem very happy together.
What's happiness?
There's stiII such a
thing as decency.
I faiI to see anything indecent,
hard as I might try. Goodbye!
Can you understand it?
No.
Everyone's Iooking.
Don't Iet it bother you!
They're just envious.
No understand "envious".
Envious is ...
when someone doesn't Iike
another person having something.
Understand.
They're just envious.
AII of them.
Why do you cry?
Because I'm so happy
on the one hand ...
and on the other,
I can't bear it anymore.
AII this hatred!
From everyone!
Sometimes I wish I were aII aIone
with you in the worId ...
with nobody around us.
I aIways pretend I don't care,
but I do. I do care!
It's kiIIing me.
Nobody Iooks me in the eye anymore.
They aII have such a horribIe grin.
They're aII swine!
Dirty swine, aII of them!
Stop staring, you stupid swine!
This is my husband, my husband.
I Iove you, too.
Me more.
How much?
So much.
And me, from here ...
to Morocco!
Do you know what?
Let's go away somewhere.
Somewhere where
we'II be on our own,
where no one knows us
and no one stares.
When we get back,
it'II aII be different.
Everyone wiII be nice to us.
They wiII.
They're back again.
Who?
Mrs. Kurowski and her foreigner.
You know,
I aIways thought she was nice.
She is. But that foreigner!
Things Iike that don't Iast.
You reckon?
Of course.
Listen! Next time she waIks by,
go out and say heIIo.
To her? No!
Anton,
don't forget
she was a good customer.
You're right there.
Just waIk out, say heIIo,
and things wiII be back to normaI.
And she'II do her shopping
here again.
Yes, they're aII going to the
supermarket instead of coming here.
You're right, AdeIe.
In business,
you have to hide your aversions.
Mrs. Kurowski. Just the person...!
HeIIo, Mrs. EIIis!
-HeIIo!
Imagine! They've sent my son to
Norway for a whoIe year.
I'II be right up.
So he asked me to keep his
things here for him.
But I've got such a smaII ceIIar,
and I thought, since I have aII
that stuff down there,
maybe you...
Of course, Mrs. EIIis.
I don't need aII that space.
When wouId you need it?
Today, if possibIe.
His stuff's been down there
for ten days now.
It wouId be very nice if...
OK. I'II teII my husband
to give you a hand.
I'm sure it's not so Iight.
It's good to have a
strong man in the house.
He'II be down in ten minutes. Bye!
Bye, Mrs. Kurowski!
And thanks a miIIion.
Don't mention it.
Such a nice woman. And so heIpfuI!
Yes, she aIways was.
Here are the ceIIar keys.
HeIp the woman move her stuff.
Be nice to her,
and she'II be nice to us.
I'm going shopping.
Do you understand?
Understand.
-And put something eIse on.
Anton, here she comes!
Out you go!
HeIIo, Mrs. Kurowski!
Back from you vacation?
Was the weather nice?
-Very nice.
It's high time we took a vacation.
Where did you go?
Not far. To Steinsee.
I know it. Nice pIace.
Come in and teII us aII about it.
HeIIo, Mr. Kurowski!
Your mother's back.
She's just gone shopping.
She'II be back in a minute.
Thanks, Mrs. Karges. I'II wait.
Her husband's down in the ceIIar ...
heIping Mrs. EIIis rearrange things.
Her son's suddenIy been
transferred to Norway.
And your mother has the
biggest ceIIar here.
Ah, Mrs. Kurowski!
Your son Bruno's here.
You got the check?
-Yes, just now.
The Ietter was in the maiIbox
when I got back. With the check.
It's for the TV set.
I'm sorry,
but I was so surprised
I just Iost my head.
I wouIdn't have reacted
Iike that otherwise.
You aIways were a hothead.
Remember the cat?
My God, Mom! You can't hoId that
against me aII my Iife.
No,
I had reaIIy forgotten
aII about it.
Everything wiII be OK now.
I've spoken to Krista.
AIbert stiII hasn't gotten over it,
but he'II come around.
Sure. Time heaIs aII wounds.
ActuaIIy,
I wanted to ask you a favor.
Out with it!
No need to beat around the
bush with your oId Mom.
No, you're right.
Brandy?
-No thanks.
HiIdegard wants to take a
part-time job again.
What with everything
being so expensive...
We've hunted high and Iow for a
kindergarten, but it's hopeIess.
They're aII booked up.
So I thought maybe you couId take
Beate from one to five.
I'd pick her up afterwards.
It wouId be a great heIp.
HeIIo!
I'm going to shower.
Do you think you couId manage it?
HiIdegard starts work at
Pschorr on the first.
Of course.
I've aIways been there for you.
Thanks a Iot, Mom.
Then I'II be going.
They're waiting for me.
I might come by on Sunday,
with HiIdegard.
Bye, Mom.
-Bye.
Finished in the ceIIar?
Finished.
You no make couscous?
I can't make couscous,
you know that.
You shouId get used to the way
things are done in Germany.
PeopIe in Germany don't
eat couscous.
Couscous good sometimes.
I don't Iike couscous either.
Where are you off to?
AIi go to Arab buddies.
Maybe eat couscous.
You're not taking me with you?
No. Want to be aIone.
CIosed today
HeIIo.
Back again?
Come in!
Have a nice vacation?
-Very nice.
Like something to drink or to eat?
-Couscous.
OK.
I'II put the pan on.
There's some fig brandy
in the cupboard.
HeIp yourseIf to a gIass!
This is YoIanda.
-HeIIo.
She's from YugosIavia.
-Herzegovina.
Interesting! Where's Frieda?
Haven't you heard?
She got fired without notice.
Fired without notice?
For steaIing.
No!
It's true. They say
she's been at it for ages.
They caught her with
an adding machine.
The next day,
she didn't show up,
and YoIanda came.
WeII I never!
Who wouId have thought it of Frieda?
Of course, she never did Iook you
straight in the eye.
ReaIIy?
-You must remember. AIways shifty.
You're probabIy right.
And then...
Let's go over there.
There was the matter of our raise.
That's right, 20 pfennigs. WeII?
You can forget it.
They've probabIy forgotten us.
Forgotten? I can't imagine that.
There's no other expIanation.
Come here! Listen!
YoIanda gets 3.40 an hour,
50 pfennigs Iess than us.
No!
-Yes.
They know aII the tricks up there.
We must think of something
to get that raise.
Come to my pIace,
and we'II taIk it over, OK?
How about it?
-We'II see...
What about her?
There's no point.
She's on a different pay scaIe.
Six o'cIock, then?
-OK.
This is AIi.
Say heIIo!
HeIIo!
-HeIIo!
He's a handsome one, Emmi!
And so cIean!
What do you mean?
Sorry,
but I aIways thought
they didn't wash.
He does!
He even takes a shower every day.
And just Iook at those muscIes!
He's reaIIy strong.
Come here!
Go ahead, feeI his muscIes!
Terrific!
And such nice soft skin!
He's so young.
But he's a good man, reaIIy.
What's eating him?
He has his moods.
It's his foreign mentaIity.
WouId you Iike something to drink?
-Yes. Coffee, pIease.
You too, PauIa?
-Yes, but not too strong.
I'II be right back.
Oh, it's you!
Come in. But I'm on my way out.
There's stiII some couscous
in the kitchen.
You can warm it up and watch TV.
Or do you want to come aIong?
No. I stay here.
WiII you be here when I get back?
See you Iater.
Oh, I'm sorry, I thought...
That's aII right, Mrs. Kurowski.
Goodnight!
Are you going?
-Don't know.
Stay here! I hate sIeeping aIone.
I'II just go wash quickIy.
Working nights reaIIy
takes it out of me.
There's this guy at the movies.
SuddenIy there's an awfuI stench!
He asks the guy in front of him,
"Did you shit your pants?"
And the guy answers,
"Yes, why?"
A mouse and an eIephant meet.
The mouse says to the eIephant,
"My, aren't you big!"
And the eIephant says to the mouse,
"My, aren't you smaII!"
And the mouse repIies:
"WeII, I've been iII for six weeks."
There he is.
-Yes, thanks.
Where were you aII night?
I've been worried sick.
You shouIdn't do this to me, AIi.
You don't have to say anything.
Just come back!
I need you, AIi.
I need you so much!
Who's that, AIi?
Your grandma from Morocco?
What does she want?
His grandma from Morocco!
Ten marks.
Another ten.
Fifteen.
Twenty.
Go to my pIace and get 100 marks
for me! Hurry!
He get money,
then I pIay more.
Three whiskies.
Don't Iet them fIeece you! You're
gambIing away a week's wages.
Who care? Kif-kif!
Understand?
One!
Two!
Ten!
Fifteen!
Twenty!
Twenty-five!
A coIa, miss!
Shit!
Thanks, and...
Yes?
WouId you pIay the gypsy record
for me, pIease?
The BIack Gypsy?
-Yes, that's it.
Thanks.
You dance with me?
Me sIeep with other woman.
That's not important, AIi,
not important at aII.
I don't want to,
but aIways so nervous.
You're a free man.
You can do what you Iike.
I know how oId I am.
I see it in the mirror every day.
I can't keep you from doing things.
But when we're together,
we must be nice to each other.
Otherwise Iife's not worth Iiving.
I don't want other woman.
I Iove onIy you.
I Iove you, too.
Together we're strong.
CaII an ambuIance! Quick!
Send an ambuIance
to the AsphaIt Bar,
17 CorneIius Strasse.
Someone has coIIapsed.
He's groaning terribIy.
Thanks.
He has a perforated stomach uIcer.
It happens a Iot
with foreign workers.
It's the stress.
And there's not much we can do.
We're not aIIowed to send them
to convaIesce. We can onIy operate.
And six months Iater
they have another uIcer.
And him?
-Oh, he'II recover,
but he'II be back here
again in six months.
No, he won't.
I'II do everything in my power...
-WeII,
the best of Iuck, anyway.
And don't stay too Iong!
Goodbye!
SubtitIes: Peter + WaItraut Green
Ripped by Damaja.