a Chungeorahm Film Production
Showbox
Mediaplex,lnc. Presents
produced by CHOI Yong-bae
executive producers
CHOI Yong-bae, KIM Woo-taek
Plastic Surgeon, Noh Do-chul
Okay.
Are you ready?
Oh Ji-young, Psychiatrist
Broke up with boyfriend a month ago
Sleeping pilIs (Trazodone, Zolpidem)
And even cigarettes...
Mr. Suh Min-jun?
A business-like voice
yet high pitched
Physically sensitive, I bet!
Sometimes a proactive start
works well
Since her death a year ago,
I haven't slept well.
- There's a sleeping pilI I'd recommend...
- Trazodone?
Zolpidem?
Tried 'em, but no use.
KilI him with my pretty face...
I was just trying to drive on
when this huge truck
passed me by so fast
that I nearly jumped and...
Wrap up with extra cutesiness!
- I'm terribly sorry.
- Okay...
She said to me,
Don't get mad at me.
30 Won
is burning at your fingertips.
Are you hurt?
Oh no.
- Oh no.
- I'm okay.
Gosh, I'm so sorry.
Doctor.
You can erase the traces
but not the memories.
- Gosh, I'm terribly sorry
- That's okay. The car's just fine.
Ah, well, no problem at all.
Yeah, sometimes even I think
I'm too much
Anyhow, mission accomplished!
I'lI see you next time.
You're a great doctor.
Seduction is not a technique.
It's a science.
THE ART OF SEDUCTION
starring
SON Ye-jin and SONG ll-kook
directed by Oh Ki-hwan
Give me name-tag, in my heart.
Give me true love, in my soul.
If you truly, honestly
love me ,
Just hold me tight.
Let go and it breaks
Love is pain
Baby!
Gave my love, my heart
- Yes, come in.
- Good morning, Ms. Han!
You have an appointment
with Mrs. Park tomorrow at 3 p.m.
And as always Mr. Kang
has sent you flowers.
And as always throw them out.
Mr. Bong from Gangwon Province
is waiting outside.
Gangwon...
Bong?
That hick loaded with cash?
I mean, Mr. Bong?
Yes, he's been waiting for an hour.
Mi-jin, telI him I have
- urgent business to tend to
- Uh, well, he's...
Ji-won
Bong Bong Industries
You could've just wired the money.
Shouldn't take such trouble coming here.
You live so far away.
Nah, it's not too far
I get here in a jiffy on a chopper.
Here's the 300 million Won
I promised.
Stayed up alI night
countin' the bilIs twice.
How'd you bring
alI this money in cash?
And why is there soil?
Oh, I buried the money
in the potato field and dug it up.
The land is honest, you know.
- But I don't know what to say
- Why? Not feeling well, Ji-won?
No, just that the fund's rules have changed
to 1 billion Won minimum
Why do the rules change so often?
I came with 300 million
'cause you told me so last time.
I'm so sorry, sir.
I won't keep you from transferring
your account to another bank.
Oh, don't say that
I'm staying where you are.
- So, is 1 billion enough?
- Yes.
I'lI bring 1 billion next time
Don't you worry.
Just wait for me
I'lI have 1 billion ready.
WilI it be in cash again?
Yeah, it took three days
digging up 300 million.
So, 10 days for 1 billion.
You know, I keep my money
buried in my potato field.
How large is the field, may I ask?
Well, somebody told me
it's the size of a smalI city.
- Ji-won, you should come visit some time.
- Uh?
Of course! I will!
I'd love to see it
The field you've worked so hard on.
I'lI wait for you.
Well, Mr. Bong.
How is it?
WilI I'lI be alright?
I'm sorry.
You should prepare yourself.
You have a month, perhaps?
First, transfer this house
and the stocks to Ms. Jung's name.
Yoon-ho, I don't want it.
I don't need them, Yoon-ho
Don't need anything.
Sorry, but to my knowledge your house
is already put up for auction,
and your stocks in the company
went bankrupt last month.
They're not listed anymore.
There must be something eIse.
Your reaI estate took a bad turn
and it's worth nothing.
Oh yeah
I aIso saw in your mailbox
that the utilities bill
is five months overdue.
They'lI be cutting off gas
unless you pay the bilIs. I'm sorry.
Damn it
My life is worthless.
Yoon-ho, don't worry!
I'm here at least!
You have me, Yoon-ho!
I'lI stay by your side tilI the end.
Please, don't do this
He needs to rest.
Yoon-ho!
- I don't know what to do, Yoon-ho
- Please, he needs to relax.
I've been a doctor, an undertaker
I've been everything for you.
You should act your age.
- What did you say?
- I mean.
Dad, your heart is stilI young
It beats like a young man's.
Of course, boy
When you're my age,
heaIth is everything.
Yup, you have too much of it.
Anyway, I don't know what to do
with that woman.
Is she nuts or what?
Told her I'm broke and wilI die soon
but she stilI clings on.
- Because you're so sexy
- Cute, kid.
She looks okay
Why not just marry her?
I told you I've got you
from my marriage and that's enough.
I told you time and again.
When alI eIse faiIs
honesty works best.
Then she'lI get hurt, dummy.
You need to have
some respect for women.
Don't know if in your days such hoax
is considered respect,
but for our generation
honesty is respect.
I'm gonna go and take a shower.
Now that's my boy.
Ji-young, baby.
What are you doing
my lovely goddess?
Oh, Min-jun, please stop.
- Why? It's because I love you
- You're too much.
- My goddess, sleep tight
- You, too.
I'lI come to you in your dreams.
- Dream about me
- I'lI wait for you, sweetie.
She's loving every bit of it
Yeah, I'm stilI good.
Dad!
We're done, ma'am
- Thank you.
Min-jun!
Just a minute. I'lI be right out.
Okay.
- Is the director here?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Hey, who's that cutie outside?
- Not again. Not again.
I dunno, he comes here often
with different girIs.
I think he's a big player.
Yeah?
He's so hot
I'd like a bite of him.
Guess you're finished
with your new boyfriend Do-chul.
You know, he's handsome
And he's a rich doctor.
You should be gratefuI for having him
What's the problem now?
You won't believe it
Last night at dinner,
he kept calling his mom and sisters
asking them what they ate.
I just found out
he has six older sisters.
- And he has no younger sister?
- Of course he does.
His battery ran out before he could
ask her what she had for dinner.
Should've seen
how disappointed he was.
Oops, sorry.
Rotten girl.
Hey! It stinks!
- What did you eat for lunch?
- Spicy noodles.
I was starving and ate two bowIs
Guess that troubled my boweIs.
Keep sniffing and numb your nose.
She had salmon salad?
Maybe I should have some, too.
Mom, I'lI calI you back in a minute.
Almost done, honey.
I just wanted
to introduce you to my friend.
Sorry you had to get
an expensive faciaI 'cause of me.
1. Don't worry. I'm rich
Don't worry. I'm rich.
2. It's okay. Your friend is my friend
Besides, your friend is my friend.
3. Don't say that. I'lI get mad!
So don't say that. I'lI get mad.
4. Do you want one, too?
Hey, why don't you get one, too?
No thanks.
Noh Do-chul, age 31
and owner of S Plastic Surgery.
Kang Sung-mo, age 31
Shinsung Securities' HR Director.
What are you?
My father or something?
Why are you meddling in my business?
I can forgive you for dating casually
before our marriage.
You know me
I'm an open-minded person.
Really?
Honey, close your eyes.
Like this?
Honey.
- Come here and lay down
- Lay down?
- But this is... No, no, I won't.
- Don't open your eyes.
But, don't you think
this is too risque for the daytime?
And this place...
This is naughty.
Ji-won, you're a bad girl.
Relax, relax.
Hope you walk out of that room
a changed man.
Ji-won... Ji-won.
- Yes?
- Cut the deck, girlie!
Yes...
You!
- Very good! Very nice!
- Really? That good?
You're like a baby
who after ten starving days
has found his mother's breast.
You are in luck!
You're a good-luck talisman.
So keep her with you.
I told you we're perfect
for each other.
No, that's not it.
He's very lucky
- But you, girlie, no good.
- Sorry?
You've done him many wrongs
in your previous life.
But if this relationship
is good for him,
then shouldn't it be
good for me, too?
Yeah, you're smart, ain't ya?
Did 'you' come here
to do the fortunetelling?
While he's with you, he's gonna
strip you of everything.
That's your karma. Yup
Look. See this card?
It's alI black. That's your fate.
And you know
this card counts for double.
Double the bad luck.
It's sad. I feeI for you.
Listen, if you stay with him
you won't last tilI forty.
- I'lI die?
- Yup, before forty. Uh-huh.
This toad here is getting empty.
He's lost weight
His cheeks have shrunk.
What a loss.
But can't go on like this.
Good work, Doctor.
I'm so sorry
The surgery took too long.
- You must be tired of waiting
- No, it's okay.
Honey, I wanna take you somewhere.
Where?
Darling, let's pray.
Holy Mother, we kneeI before you
to make a vow of love.
We wilI love each other
no matter what hardships we face.
Let his eyes go blind
so that he sees no other women.
I wilI love him though he be blind.
I fear he may speak
sweetly to other women.
Let him go dumb.
I fear he may touch others.
Sever his two arms, dear Mother.
Break his two legs, Mother
so that he may stay by me forever.
Allow alI this to come true, Amen!
God is my sanctuary
Only one I can rely on
What hardships there may be
Do you believe?
I have peace in me
Our souI so barren
Give us new life
Grant us eternaI rest in you, My Lord
Together!
God is my sanctuary
Only one I can rely on
This is getting boring.
Let's be friends.
Love is no game
Love is truth
What the hell?
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
I was just trying to pass by,
but this huge car
suddenly zipped by me.
I nearly jumped and...
I'm terribly sorry.
1. Don't worry, I'm fine.
2. Are you hurt anywhere?
3. It's my fauIt for parking here.
4. How about a drink instead?
A huge car?
When?
Anyway, I'm very busy
Give me your business card.
Ms. Han Ji-won?
You know SeouI Hospital, right?
See you there at lunchtime.
Ah, sure.
To be honest,
my parents passed away
when I was a child.
Must I do this?
No, I'lI just pay up.
No way I'm doing this for money
darn it.
- You're here
- Yes.
You don't look so well.
Yes, I had to work late to make money.
Anyway, are you feeling better?
I got up in the morning,
and ouch
it does ache here and there.
But nothing terrible, I suppose.
Luckily, my friend works here
and I signed up for a check up.
Your friend?
Car accidents are like that.
You may seem fine now
but worse symptoms can come later.
What's invisible is the scariest.
ShalI we go?
Ms. Han Ji-won?
Here!
- Ms. Han
- Yes?
Go on in.
Go on in? Me?
Yesterday,
you seemed so out of your wits
to see if you were hurt.
So go on in. I've asked the doctor
to take good care of you.
So it's not you
but me getting a check-up?
I'm fine
Being too heaIthy is my problem.
Private banker?
This is uncharted territory
Interesting.
A famous architect?
Attractive. Quite a dish.
- The food is okay?
- Yes.
Excuse me.
Hello?
Hey, you promised me a birthday party
What's keeping you?
Oh, it's you, Yoon-ho.
How dare you calI your father
by the first name?
Ah, so you're with a woman.
Yeah, I'lI be there in awhile.
Hurry, boy! The girIs here are hot!
Okay, but be a good boy.
Don't drink
more than two bottles, okay?
You little prick. Okay, I got ya.
Bye, Yoon-ho.
I love you. Bye.
Yoon-ho's a physically-challenged kid
We're like brothers.
I used to visit him once a week
But lately I've been too busy.
- He really looks up to me as a brother.
- I see.
Physically challenged?
You're dead meat if you're lying.
Death to liars!
- Ah, yes.
- Hello?
It's me, Soo-jin.
Oh gosh, it's been so long.
You crazy bitch.
I saw you yesterday
What do you mean 'long'?
And what's with the fake voice?
I'm fine, too
So what made you call?
Anyway, where's the The Hot Motel?
Um...
Near Don't TelI Mama, the club.
How could you forget?
I told you a hundred times.
Come on, I can't find it!
Walk out the back door
of Don't TelI Mama.
Turn to the right at BY Motel
There's a karaoke bar, remember?
No? It used to be the Pegasus Motel.
Yeah, walk straight up the side street
and you'lI see The Twins'.
Next to that is the moteI with a sign
that says Love Chair Available.
Oh, my! A chair?
Doing it on a chair?
My friend
wants to try cross-stitching.
I gave her the directions to a place
but she can't find it.
I see.
Yeah right, cross-stitching?
Cut the hoax!
Playing the good girl!
Nah-nah.
What would you like for dessert?
- I'm quite full.
- I'm okay as well.
- ShalI we leave?
- Yes.
What's this?
Thank you for this evening.
One.
Two...Three!
- Ms. Han, just a sec!
- I knew it.
Yes?
I hope you won't think me rude
for saying this.
No, what is it?
I think you're wearing
your skirt backwards.
It was designed like this.
This is the latest fashion
Didn't you know?
Is that so?
That's strange
It looks very uncomfortable.
- Well, take care
- Yes, you, too.
How humiliating.
Mr. Suh Min-jun
so you want to put up a fight, huh?
I accept the challenge.
Suh Min-jun!
Born in 1976.
Graduated from Columbia
with a B.A. in Architecture.
Currently
CEO of his own construction firm.
- Phone number...
- So what?
Why are you harassing me
at my workplace?
Relax. Relax.
But, you know already.
That I'm very open-minded.
By the way
I have something to give you.
What?
Regardless...
She's adorable.
Come in.
I apologize.
My place is a mess.
No, it's quite nice.
Wow. You have a library here.
Come on, a library?
I had too many books,
and threw out most of them
when I moved here.
I'm addicted to reading.
I get nervous
when I'm not reading something.
I'lI just go
and get changed in a minute.
Sure.
Very impressive.
Simatiga
He actually reads this stuff?
Prince of Red Tea
Doolie's Book RentaI Shop
Yeah, yeah, I knew it.
What is alI this crap? It's alI fake.
What?
You really went out of your way.
Ji-won
I'lI be done in a sec.
Okay.
Today's special, Spaghetti Carbonara.
You might faint after taking a bite.
I haven't seen a woman who hasn't.
Min-jun.
By any chance
did you put apple vinegar in this?
Yes, what's the matter?
I knew it
I'm allergic to apple vinegar.
Allergic to apple vinegar?
I'm okay with persimmon vinegar.
Do I look that easy?
I can't believe this girl.
Is that so?
I didn't know that.
I'lI make you another one.
No, it's okay
I'lI just have the salad.
This is really good!
- Ji-won?
- Yes?
I put apple vinegar
in that salad, too.
It's okay when I eat it with veggies.
Excuse me.
Where are you, honey? I'lI wait untiI you come.
Your darling, Sung-mo!
What is it?
Is there something wrong?
It's nothing.
Nothing really. Excuse me.
Send me another message, you ass
and I'lI crack your skull!
I placed an order in India
to get this tea.
Imported tea usually lose their aroma
during the long distribution process.
Hot! Hot!
In Europe they say if you stir red tea
with a silver spoon
on a fulI moon night
a lovely fairy wilI appear.
But it seems tonight
that magic wilI not happen.
Since I already have
a lovely fairy next to me.
Min-jun.
Yes?
You must really love comics.
I've aIso read Prince of Red Tea.
And you borrow books
from Doolie's, it seems.
Looks like stainless steel
not silver.
The tea smelIs really nice.
Doesn't it?
But I'm really sorry.
I don't sleep welI on caffeine.
I'm a bit of an insomniac.
Do you have anything decaf?
Insomnia?
Come on
people would think I drugged you.
She said to me,
Don't be angry. 30 Won is burning
at your finger tips right now.'
What a bummer!
That woman was really uptight, huh?
So what happened next?
What did you say to her?
Well, then I just gave her
a knuckle rub on the head.
Good work. She deserved that.
Anyhow, she really sounds dull.
It's really nice
looking out at the sea.
Well, the problem
is getting back home.
I've stood up
two nights straight working.
Of course you can't drive
While being drowsy is dangerous.
- You think so too, huh?
- Of course.
That place looks alright
ShalI we relax just for two hours?
Be careful.
Ji-won, it's been so long
I almost forgot your face.
Thank you so much, Mr. Bong.
What's there to thank?
Your mother being ilI and all.
I only found out
a couple of hours ago.
And that man over there
Is he that famous?
The best cardiologist in Korea
Dr. Kim Sung-il.
I had a hard time getting him here.
Anyway, your mother
seems so ilI alI the time
it really breaks my heart.
And you, Ji-won
you're really a caring daughter.
It is only natural
for a daughter to do so.
My mother is waiting
I must go to her.
- I wilI give you a calI later
- Yes, I'lI be waiting.
Good-bye.
Dr. Kim Sung-il, come sit here.
Why are you sitting down there?
I'm fine here.
The bath and spa in that hotel
was superb, wasn't it?
Look, my skin's so soft.
- The men's wasn't so excellent
- No, you're too modest.
Your face is simply glowing.
By the way
do you always carry that gown?
It's my friend's.
I may not have a friend with a chopper
but I have many friends with gowns.
Ji-won, press the button
Ji-won, you know me.
I've always wanted to propose to you
in a speciaI way.
Please marry...
Kang Ji-won
You clean it up, you bastard!
What a nutcase!
Five.
Six.
Seven.
Eight.
Nine.
- Hello?
- Hi, Min-jun.
Hey, Ji-won. Just a sec.
No, not there!
Yeah, put it right there!
Okay, good!
Hello?
No, not busy at all.
Go on.
There's going to be a lingerie party
Can you come?
Pardon?
You sound surprised.
Surprised? No.
I've been to one in New York.
Don't worry. It'lI be mostly couples.
Sounds like fun.
Okay, sure.
Bye.
Suh Min-jun
How much are you worth?
I'lI buy you.
Hi, Min-jun.
How do you like it?
Pretty cool, huh?
Yeah, well...
But I only see women.
I know
It was supposed to be for couples.
But I guess Korean men
aren't ready for this kind of thing.
Sad, don't you think?
I should be thankfuI for the chance.
But, there is a problem.
What do you mean?
There aren't many things to put up
for the auction later.
Can you help out?
Is it something I can help with?
What kind of auction is it?
For personaI treasures or something?
Well, you see...
It's a slave date auction.
Slave?
Don't worry. It's for a good cause.
The proceeds wilI alI go to children
with heart disorders and...
I'lI make sure to buy you.
Up to 3 million Won.
3 million?
It'lI begin in ten minutes. Over there is a room.
You can wait there.
You promised to buy me.
Trust me.
This isn't right.
Min-jun, wait.
Have you been exercising?
You have such muscles.
Nothing to brag about really.
Maybe I should go to the ATM
and get more cash. I'm worried.
Nah, there are a lot of guys
with muscles like these.
- Over there?
- Good luck!
Great! Sold for 1 .5 million Won!
Now, now, next!
Guy No. 3, please come out!
Look, everyone!
He is the hottest item
we have tonight, Ladies!
Everyone, get ready and
500,000 Won!
You're quite in a hurry!
That's good!
- 700,000!
- 700,000! Anyone eIse?
- 1 million!
- 1 million? Ladies, it's getting hot here.
- 1 .2 million!
- 1 .3 million!
- 1 .5 million!
We have 1 .5 million! Anyone eIse?
One! Two!
1 .8 million!
2 million!
The top bid for tonight at 2 million!
No one higher, is there?
One! Two!
- 4 million!
- Amazing!
WilI we have
a 4 million Won slave tonight?
One! Two!
- 10 million!
- 10 million...
Anyone eIse?
One. Two. Three!
Sold to Mrs. Park for 10 million Won!
Have a great night!
Cutie.
How old are you?
Thirty, ma'am.
That's not good.
You calI me ma'am and it puts
such distance between us, no?
CalI me Ji-sook instead.
We've just met,
but I feeI so comfortable.
Could we have been lovers
in our previous life?
My, you are so adorable.
So very very adorable.
How could you be so cute?
What's your name, cutie pie?
- Suh Min-jun
- Suh Min-jun?
Yes.
Do you by any chance know Tae-hoon?
Lim Tae-hoon?
You're Tae-hoon's mom, aren't you?
Uh-huh.
Remember me?
I came over
and you cooked us dumplings.
They were really good.
Were they?
Well, dumplings is my best dish.
Min-jun.
- I beg you, please
- Don't worry, Mrs. Park!
I won't say a thing to Tae-hoon!
Okay.
Mr. Lee. Let's go.
Good-bye, Mrs. Park!
Han Ji-won.
Suh Min-jun
It's him again.
I'm totally screwed
If he catches me, I'm dead meat.
I might be sold off
to a shrimp-fishing boat.
What if he does?
You wench!
This is funny to you, huh?
Come on, wouldn't you laugh
if you were in my shoes?
Anyway,
could he have gone alI the way
with that hag?
I dunno. Probably.
Mrs. Park stopped calling me
and closed her account.
I'm dead.
You really like him, don't you?
Why?
If I don't like him
you want a shot at him?
No, not exactly that, but...
Hey! Give it up.
Our daily event at Tribeca!
Let's go nuts.
The Sexy Dance Contest!
Get off the stage! Out!
Look at her go.
What are they doing?
So vulgar. Lunatics.
What if their parents knew?
So disgraceful.
Why? It looks like fun.
Today's contestants are pretty bad!
Anyone eIse
who would like to take a shot?
Your prize is a flight to Europe.
What? Europe?
- I'm going!
- Again?
Do I have to do it for her again?
You dummy
you're trembling like a wet dog.
Satisfied now?
Wouldn't you be?
Ji-won!
It's Min-jun. I'm sick, okay?
What brings you here?
Got drowned or something?
No, I'm sweating
because I'm very ill.
She told me she was sick
but I dragged her here for a beer,
and she got even sicker.
How could you let her get so ill?
She could die from dehydration!
Ji-won! Ji-won!
She's losing it.
I'm taking her to the hospital!
What?
Ji-won! Ji-won!
Hang on! Ji-won!
Oh, my back.
Han Ji-won.
Ji-won! Ji-won!
Ji-won! Wake up!
Ji-won, wake up! Ji-won!
Yeah, you bastard
Just kilI me, wilI ya?
Ji-won, please wake up!
Ji-won, please wake up! Ji-won!
Please, calm down first!
- Check her blood pressure
- Doctor, please save her!
- 190/140! It's very high!
- 40.2 degrees.
But why is there so much water
on the patient's body?
It's sweat. Her sweat.
- Sweat!
She has severe dehydration.
Ms. Kim, a shot of Ativan
and get a 1 liter of D5W.
Yes, doctor!
Ji-won.
The doctor's going to give you a shot.
Two shots, in fact.
- Wait a sec!
- What's the matter?
- Is she allergic to something?
- No, that's not it.
Ji-won may be angry
to see needle marks
on her delicate arm.
Now you're talking.
Couldn't you give her
the shot on her rear?
Shit! He's asking for it.
- She seems heavier than I thought
- I'lI do it. Allow me.
Yes, sure.
Please step outside for a second
while I give the shot.
She's my wife.
Okay.
Spasm! Spasm!
- Hold her down!
- Down?
No, that's enough!
You'lI suffocate her!
I gave her a shot
so she'lI be better soon.
Thank you.
What's that smirk on his face?
That face...
Is he laughing at me?
How's that?
Ms. Han Ji-won's guardian!
- Yes?
- Please filI out this form.
No. Gotta hold on.
Suh Min-jun. Just you wait.
I'lI finish you no matter what.
There's no change!
200 joules. Three, two, one, shock!
StilI the same, doctor!
- What do we do?
- 100 joules higher!
Patient:Han Ji-won
Guardian:Suh Min-jun
- No change?
- None.
Did I go too far?
Did you know this?
Stir red tea with a silver spoon
on a fulI moon night,
and a cute fairy wilI appear.
Cute like moi.
- You haven't had sex lately, have you?
- No, why?
Then...then, why does your skin
glow like those really lucky girIs
who get a dozen orgasms
every single night?
Hey, sex is not
just making out naked.
I know that.
So, you pulI your top down
a bit just so...
And do oraI sex like this.
Stupid!
Making a man
want me so bad at times.
Just stealing
a look at his eyes or lips.
AlI that can aIso be sex.
- Are you a pervert?
- I bet Min-jun thinks the same.
Yeah, you weirdos
are perfect for each other.
I bet Min-jun is dying right now.
If my calculations are correct
by this weekend...
See?
- Hi, Min-jun. What is it?
- Hey, Ji-won.
Do you want to go
for a drive tomorrow?
Uh, sorry, but I have a seminar.
What? A seminar? On a weekend?
And, it's in Cheju Island.
Cheju Island?
Cheju? You're not going to...
Yeah, I'm disappointed, too.
It's gonna start at six
and end in one hour.
That's great. I can go to Cheju.
Really? You mean it?
You said it was just an hour
I can wait.
Well, if you say so, Min-jun.
I'lI see you at the airport at two.
What was Cheju Island about?
A seminar? On the weekend?
Yeah, right.
Don't wanna make the first move, huh?
Sure, of course
You have a reputation to maintain.
You should never go to him
Have him come to you.
He's coming to Cheju to see me.
That means I won and he lost.
Ji-won, I respect you
You are perfect.
- He's calling me again
- Really? Again?
Min-jun, what is it?
I'm sorry.
Something's come up
I can't make it tomorrow.
I ordered some crabs
on a home shopping channel,
and they're delivering
them tomorrow.
Uh-huh.
Uh, well, that's too bad.
I understand, bye.
Oh gosh.
His Dad is in a criticaI state.
I heard it all, dummy!
You got picked over crabs.
And I'm drinking tea with a loser
who's no better than a crab.
A shame.
Those crabs do look yummy.
Why am l, the hottest girI in town
home on the weekend?
It's Min-jun!
Hi, Min-jun.
Me?
It's no fun
You know how seminars are.
What? Where are you?
I'm telling you. I'm in Cheju.
Can't you hear the tides?
What do you mean why?
The crabs arrived in the morning.
I'm here to pick you up
after your seminar.
Where shalI I go?
I'lI calI you
after the seminar's done.
Okay, okay already!
Be patient, darn it.
- Yes, Min-jun?
- Ji-won, are you almost done?
- What?
- There's a problem.
We're waiting for some execs
to arrive from Seoul.
Can you wait a little bit longer?
I'm sorry.
This wilI take forever.
Darn it, how do I get out of here?
That's it.
Giddy up! Giddy up!
So Min-jun
you want a piece of me, huh?
Come and get it.
Stop calling me, damn it.
Hi, Min-jun. I'm on my way.
Where are you?
The lobby or the room?
What? Lobby?
- Room?
- Oh, it's you.
Thought you were someone eIse.
What the helI are you doing
with that bastard?
What I do and where I go with him
be it Cheju, Siberia or Alaska,
is none of your business!
Hello? Hello?
God of jealousy
show me what you're made of.
Giddy up!
Gimpo Airport
Flight to Cheju
Cheju Flower Shop
Flower B Set
Those beasts!
If it weren't for the seminar
we could be back.
I'lI calI the airport
you calI the Cheju port.
Yes, if not the airplane
we should take a ship.
No? Then how about Asiana?
- No? What?
- The number you have called is not exist or
- Because of the high tide?
- you cannot reach.
- No budget flights or light aircraft?
- Press 1 for daily weather updates.
If not, one of those
smalI fishing boats would be fine.
Yes, I understand.
Sorry, sir.
What? You have only one room?
And even that one room just became
available due to a cancellation.
Ji-won, what should we do?
I don't know
Let's check out another hotel.
I'm sure the situation
is similar in other hoteIs.
To get a room on a weekend
without a reservation
is nearly impossible.
Darn, what should we do?
I guess we have no other choice.
Give us that room
It's a twin room, right?
This room is a double.
But if you want we can give you
an extra bed.
- No thank you!
Sir, I'm very sorry
but is this your card?
Of course, why?
- It says it's a stolen card
- What?
That's impossible.
- Try this one
- Thank you.
No way.
That's okay!
- Here is my card
- Yes, thank you.
I don't get it.
It happens
with computer system errors.
Don't worry. It's probably nothing.
Ma'am, this too is a stolen card.
Impossible!
This is my card
See? It says 'Han Ji-won'.
That bastard blocked mine, too?
What?
Nothing. Never mind.
Exactly three minutes.
Let's eat! Yum, it looks good.
Instant noodles in a cheap motel?
Suh Min-jun, is this alI you've got?
Why aren't you eating?
You haven't had anything alI day.
I've lost my appetite.
Min-jun!
Heard of a fish
called saw-edged perch?
Saw-edged perch?
Raw saw-edged perch
is an exquisite treat in Cheju.
It's a bit pricey
but they say it meIts in your mouth.
It's a Cartier in cuisine
so to speak.
Really?
Su-jin told me
I should absolutely try it.
How sad.
I had this last night, too.
So you can't take ramen noodles
and a rundown inn, huh?
- Ji-won?
- Yes?
I'lI be back in a minute.
- Where to?
- Uh, to the restroom.
Be back quick. I'm scared.
I will.
- Hurry
- Just a minute, okay?
Yeah, it's about time
you showed me what you can do.
Darn it, I'm starving
and alI I get is a cup of noodles.
You bad boy and girl.
Han Ji-won.
Think you can get away from me?
You and your lover boy
are dead!
He's weird.
Mind your own business!
This is the captain speaking.
We wilI make an emergency landing
at Gimhae internationaI airport.
No! You can't land here!
Please, sir!
Sit down and fasten your seat beIt!
Don't touch me!
Don't you land here!
Go straight to Cheju Island!
It's very dangerous!
Please take a seat!
Dangerous?
Ha! You make me laugh.
Your face is far more dangerous.
How's that? One to zero, okay?
Here!
500,000 Won!
Come on
this is a very expensive watch.
Stop eating for a sec
and please take a good look at it.
400,000!
You know, this watch
is a Gio Monaco!
- Gio Monaco?
- Yes!
- So you know
- 300,000!
Look!
Gio Monaco is a very costly watch
Only three of them in Korea!
Where is the third one, I wonder?
Wait!
300,000! Yes, 300,000!
- Is it that good?
- Yeah, it's so very yummy yummy.
- You should have some, too
- I'm fine.
ShalI I give him a little prize
for his efforts?
Why are you sweating so much?
Look at alI this sweat.
Does it look like sweat to you?
But you're lovin' it.
So her highness
is giving me a prize.
Well, it feeIs good, I admit.
Okay, this is enough.
I'm so full.
Are you finished already?
Yes, true connoisseurs of raw fish
eat three pieces max.
Wish we could have a glass of wine.
Rain makes me want wine.
- Ji-won
- Huh?
I'lI be back in a sec.
Going to the men's room again?
You go too often, darling.
- You're right
- Don't be too long.
It's as good as they say.
The shelI is really good.
A glass of soju would be perfect!
Soju and raw fish, the best combo!
Goodness.
I didn't expect to find
such great wine in Cheju.
Isn't it a sweet surprise?
I feeI the wine alI over me.
Yeah, and I feeI the cold
coming over me.
Yes, it is such a sweet surprise.
Anyway, why do you keep coming back
from the men's room so wet?
Took a shower or something?
You'lI catch a cold.
Oops.
I dropped my handkerchief.
ShalI we move a bit farther?
You're very wet.
Let's go now!
So fast?
There's stilI plenty of wine.
I drink
only one glass at a time
before going to bed.
ShalI we go?
But what about the bill?
It must be quite a lot.
I ordered too much, didn't l?
Don't worry.
- Ji-won
- Yes?
Why don't you wait outside?
Now, Min-jun
what are you going to do?
Run! Run!
Oh goodness! My umbrella!
They won't chase us
alI the way down here, right?
No way!
- Oh, Ji-won, you were really fast!
- You should exercise more.
You could've gotten caught
running so slow.
Some nerve.
FeeI better now after running, huh?
ShalI we go in now?
I guess.
Let's go.
- Ji-won
- Yeah?
I have to run to the men's room.
You wait inside.
He does try so hard.
What took you so long?
I nearly died coming here
and that's alI you've got to say?
Are you nuts, boy?
Remember that time
when you owed me one?
- I got there in one hour!
- It was bright and sunny that day!
Today, I nearly flew to Japan
and came back 'cause of the current!
Whatever, just give me the stuff
I'm busy.
Boy, I truly despise you.
I love you, Dad.
Don't worry. I got everything ready.
Thanks, Dad.
- Gotta go
- Son, wait! I almost forgot.
Come on, Dad.
Son, this is my favorite kind
strawberry scent.
Dad, I don't have time for jokes
I'm in a hurry.
I'm not kidding
It really smelIs like strawberries.
Dad, hurry on to the wine bar
I'm gone! Thanks!
Bastard only thinks about girIs!
My love?
Is my sweet goddess there already?
Why don't you have
some of the wine I have in keeping.
I'lI be there soon.
Wait a little while, darling.
Yes!
Thank you.
This place is really classy.
You don't have any money
so how did you?
I dunno.
Ji-won, come on.
This is the outfit
for you to change into tomorrow.
These are some cosmetics.
And this is your underwear.
I got them for you
since I know you packed for a day.
Min-jun.
It was too late
and alI the shops were closed.
I had to beg to go
in some of the shops to get these.
So don't complain
even if you don't like them.
Of course I won't.
I'm sure I'lI like them
No, I do like them!
You are soaked.
You might catch a cold.
You're even wetter.
- You okay?
- I'm fine.
I'lI go take a shower first.
Suh Min-jun, you're no amateur.
I like it!
Bad boy.
Is he peeling off his skin?
What's taking him so long?
Darn it.
It's so steamy in here.
Min-jun, do you want a rub?
Min-jun!
Thank you, doctor.
Ji-won.
Yes? Feeling better?
I'm dizzy.
You look a lot better to me.
No, I'm ill. Very ill.
- I'm a patient
- You won't die. Don't worry.
FeeI better now?
Yeah, 'cause of you.
What do I do now?
Han Ji-won
what are you going to do?
- Well...
- I'm...
- You go ahead
- No, you can speak first.
You know, my dad wants to meet you.
No need to feel
uncomfortable about it.
He does? That's wonderful!
Since you've mentioned it,
I told my parents about you
and they're dying to meet you.
If it's okay with you,
they're thinking of visiting Korea
to see you.
No, we should go and visit them.
How about we go next week
during the holiday?
Sure.
This may sound really corny,
but my parents want us
to go to a fortune-teller.
That's not corny at all.
Listen to the elders and you'lI be
rewarded even in your sleep, they say.
- ShalI we go?
- Go where?
There's a really good fortuneteller.
No, I've actually reserved the best
Let's go!
How did you two come together?
You know who you are!
I don't know. Can't see anything.
What should I do?
I dunno.
Brother, my life's so difficuIt.
Why are you laughing?
Because you are.
Because I could tell
you were going to laugh.
- Well, take care
- Yes, you, too.
- Good bye, Min-jun
- Okay, bye.
Three months later
- Good evening
- Hi!
Well, this may sound a bit forward,
but feeI free to telI me
what you need,
be it money or land.
Money goes rotting in my closet.
- Yes.
- Please sit here.
- Nice place!
- Isn't it?
Damn.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing much.
See over there?
The rich housewife type of a woman?
I dated her a while ago.
Stop looking. She's gonna see us.
So what?
It's nothing
Just feeIs a bit uncomfortable.
Irish coffee, please.
Cow milk for moi.
Excuse me.
I need to go to the men's room
Sorry.
So humiliating.
Come on.
Darling, we meet
exactly ten minutes later, okay?
I got it.
But what do I say to him?
Well, just say some emergency
has come up at home.
Okay.
sweetly.
TelI me, am I the only one for you?
Of course, baby.
Wait.
You got something on you right here.
- Here?
- Yeah, you got beauty on you, baby.
You're a darling.
Wait a sec.
- Who's this?
- Who's...
Have fun
Those amateurs, how dare they try
little tricks before us masters?
Yeah, they're funny, huh?
Anyway, your taste for women
seems to have changed.
I mean that woman looked
old enough to be a teenager's mom.
Oh yeah?
When you walked in,
I thought you were giving
your old uncle a city tour.
Hey, I'm stilI a head-turner.
Last night at a club
they asked me for my ID.
Probably thought you were
a policewoman under cover.
Min-jun, I'm saying this
out of genuine concern for you.
Want me to fix you up
with a nice girl?
No need to be embarrassed.
Okay!
See that couple over there?
You are amazing.
That crazy bitch.
You turn me on!
Why the helI is she here?
Let's forget about them.
Yeah, let's.
How about them over there?
- Yeah?
- How many minutes?
Ten?
Whoa, don't strain yourself.
How about you?
It has to be fair. Ten minutes.
What's in it for the winner?
Let's see.
The loser grants
one wish whatever it is.
Sure, I have a designer bag I want.
It's been a long time.
What? Give up already?
Give up?
Ten minutes is too long for them
I can smoke one.
Yeah?
Do you realize that 300,000 Won
is burning at your fingertips?
Then, I'lI go first.
- What?
- It's me!
My new boyfriend has a son
who is a reaI stud!
He's supposed to be everything
you wished for and more.
Really?
Yes!
She's hotter than Britney Spears.
If you don't falI for her
in 10 minutes,
my pretty goddess
wilI take us out to dinner.
Is that so?
- Sure, I'd like to meet her.
- Min-jun. I've decided to take this.
Yes, Dad.
Alligator leather.
If only I hadn't smoked
that one cigarette.
- Satisfied?
- Yeah.
Sir, I'm sorry
but your card's registered as stolen.
What?
No way.
You fooIs.
Remember me?
Kang Sung-mo
is back.
Why do those damn rules
change alI the time?
Three more days of digging
and I'lI have 10 billion ready.
Ji-won, wait for me, darling.