Translated by Tobbeman
I have allways woundered:
If you hit a mime,
would he make a sound?
Well, now you know.
Ilostmyteeth.
What is he saying?
I don't know. Something about thiish.
w... w...
Ohh, he lost his teeth.
Terry...
Hey!
You sons of bitches ain't going anywhere.
I saw the whole damn thing.
I'm calling the police!
We are the police.
"Every depression leads to war."
Simone de Beauvoir.
It Prud'hon Pierre-Joseph,
The father of anarchism.
instead of Simone de Beauvoir,
feministka-ekzistentsialistka.
I bet you 50 bucks.
I will take that bet.
Hello, Uncle Terry!
How is it hanging Cesar?
A little early in the day Terry?
It's midnight in Tokyo.
Hi uncle Terry.
Hi little Bob.
Where is my x-box?
How the fuck should i know?
Ohh, you know what? It's up my ass.
You wanna go and see it?
It's in the dining room.
I hit your car Bob.
Again?
Yeah.
Is it bad?
We should take my car.
You had a nice swim honey?
My eyes hurt.
I told you Bob! You put too
much chlorine in the pool.
No no. I followed those instructions.
He has been up to something.
No I haven't.
No I haven't. Our little innocent little
lord fucking fartalort over here.
Stop.
- It has been itching all weekend.
- I am trying to digest over here.
When was the last time you had sex?
Thursday.
And when did it start itching?
Saturday in late afternoon, early evening.
It's thrush.
What is thrush?
I wore a condom.
It don't matter.
- What do I do about it?
- You go to a drog store.
They will give you some cream
or something. You will be fine.
What is thrush?
Thrush is a small to medium size song bird.
Now get the fuck out of here.
Can you guys not...
discuss his genital complaints
when I am trying to eat.
Is that too much to ask for?
This looks like dick and balls now.
See you later Delores.
See you later Terry.
- He has fucking broke it mom.
- No!
Ohh, you know what?
It is broken.
Mom!
Take it easy man. You make me look bad
in front of all my fucking white neighbors
Lets go fuck some scumbags.
Balloon Museum
ALBUQUERQUE
What are they doing now?
Looking at the exhibits.
Fuck you think they are doing?
So waste of time.
No it's not.
What do you think the web brothers are doing here?
Drawn in the Balloon Museum?
You think they are researching
the history of aeronautics? No.
Oh look at this guy point. You
are not fooling anybody body.
Do you think they gonna heist the place?
It's popular with the yo calls
but I recons it's just a meet.
- Ow! Hold it right there.
- Here, right here?
Yeah, the light is perfect.
Like this?
Yeah, that's really nice.
That's Jimmy Harris.
And his fucking jojo.
I thought he was sitting.
He got out some month ago.
Who is the other guy with the kid?
No idea.
What kind of criminal brings
his kid to a meet though?
Eyes here. Eyes here.
Why am I looking there?
There we go.
Hm.. The jojos where once...
They were banned in Damascus?
Ha, it was believed that they caused drought.
Look at all these fucking assholes working.
Suckers!
Welcome back, guys!
How was your vacation?
Very pleasant!
I masturbated a lot.
Forced vacation, I should say.
What?
Ok...
So the clowns are back?
Tweedledum?
Siegfried and Roy, Sacco and Vanzetti,
Abelard and Heloise ...
This quiz?
No it's not a quiz.
This is your last chance.
Ok?
This is it!
No more suspensions.
Great!
You will be kicked out next time!
Oh, that's not great.
You would have already been fired, if the authorities
were able to prove some rumors.
- Yeah, but you know what they say about rumors.
- Rumors are the engine of progress.
No, it's laziness - the engine of progress.
Rumors then?
Rumors are  ...
Silenzio!
Assault on a colleague -
is one thing!
Bribery and corruption charges against you
and that's it.
We were provoked.
Bob was provoked!
Same thing.
So, guys.
I agree with you
about the race issue.
I'm married to a "Ching" myself!
I have "Ching" kids.
Look at their faces.
Good looking boys.
I know how you felt Bob.
But that is not a reason for assaulting a fellow officer.
No matter what they say.
He called me a wetback.
He knows that I was born here!
He is a big racist pig!
Yes!
He is a big fat racist pig.
I agree!
No argument there.
But look!
This is the police department.
We are surrounded by big fat racist pigs.
So work with me here.
So,
What have we learned here?
Do not assault a fellow officer.
Even if he is a racist pig.
Yeah ... and?
Something about rumors.
No.
Chinese kids?
Bribery and corruption!
Yes!
Bribery and corruption.
And what about bribery and corruption?
Ohh, there is a part two..
Don't get involved with it?
Don't get involved with it
in any way, shape or form.
Bribes and corruption - bad!
Excellent!
Progress has been made.
Leave the scene.
Who is that ass who used to
hang out with Harris?
Negro gentleman.
Reggie Hayes.
But he changed it? Didn't he?
Changed his name.
He joined the "Nation of Islam".
Reggie X!
Who sings?
Glenn Campbell.
Cool song.
Masterpiece.
Do you see him?
Maybe hiding somewhere.
Thats what these criminal types do
Hiding.
Ah, there he is.
Reggie!
As-Salamu Alaykum.
He did not seem happy to see us.
What's wrong, guys?
You know how to read, don't you?
Egghead bastard.
Or not taught in school?
I'm actually dyslexia.
Ok?
And I find that statement to be offensive.
Are you an actor?
Dyslexia is only for movie stars.
The rest of us call it stupidity.
You know these bastards?
You shouldn't have done that.
And what will he do?
Tell Mom?
What the fuck?
I didn't do a shit!
What is that, Terry?
Certainly not origami.
You got to be kidding me
I think legally it is called
banned substance.
No!
Ohh yeah.
Definitely a banned substance.
And you found it on him, is that correct?
He hid it in his anus, your honor.
Oh, you filthy animal!
Filthy animal!
You are a dealer now, Reggie.
You two are fucked up.
You still homies with Jimmy Harris?
Not since back in the day.
Thought he moved on.
Not everyone can sell toasters, you now?
I work at the highest level!
I'm a designer of stolen toasters.
Yes, big fucking shit!
Fancy, shit.
Yeah, fancy shit! From Moschino!
Moschino doesn't make toasters!
But you're friends, right?
We know each other.
Have you heard that your
friend is back in town?
- I heard
- You did.!
We followed the webb brothers.
- Do you know the web brothers?
- Well, who doesn't know them?.
Already good progress!
They are up to something.
I mean, so our informants told us.
Where would we be without our informants?
Nowhere.
Exactly, dude!
So Jimmy Harris and the
Webbs are hooked up...
So...
- So ...
- "So" What motherfucker?
They are planning a fucking robbery.
Exactly!
Quietly, quietly.
We gonna fuck them up,
and you are going to help us.
Fuck!
The cops!
Shit! We are the cops!
For a second I forgot.
And I was like, "Fuck!"
And I was like, "Where... Where?"
If I don't help you..
You gonna bust me for possession?
Educated man, Terry.
Good coke!
There is more.
Where did you get this?
We fucked up a mime.
The race has begun!
Oh, Your Grace!
She is a three year old.
Beautiful filly.
Which would you like in the saddle?
I haven't ridden her yet.
She is playful.
Excuse me. One of my trainers.
Keep me informed about current envelopment.
Of course.
I hate champagne.
Why did I drink?
One of the unsolved mysteries of life.
How's my crew?
Or how are my crew? If I should
be more grammatically correct.
All set.
The Webbs just checked in.
The other thing?
You probably guessed:
Reynard wants more money.
Of course.
What should I do?
Pay him.
We will get the money back.
If I do not end up in jail.
Oh, Russell ...
Jail is not too bad.
You know the worst thing about jail?
I do not know, Your Grace.
The violent anal sex.
And you know the best thing in jail?
Violent anal sex?
Yeah,
You are pretty quick for an American.
Jimmy used to go out with this dancer,
Jacqueline Hollis. Rumor is
he shacked up with her.
You have an address?
No, but...
I do know that she works at...
the club "Knockout".
This means that you,
unfortunately, will have to
"Work".
Don't talk to me like that.
I will kick your ass to China.
What the fuck is that?
Cocktail "Cocksucking Cowboys".
My balls still hurt.
And I didn't do you anything.
The world is unfair, man.
Call amnesty international if
you want to do something.
Salut.
I thought you guys didn't drink.
How do you mean?
Muslims.
I am a "Pyatiprotsentnik".
Ah, got it.
You know what it means?
I know what that means.
You know this other douchebag?
Am I Huggy Bear now?
Huggy Bear ...
"Starsky and Hutch" ...
My favorite TV series.
Who took these?
Some epileptic?
Yes, Helmut Newton, over here.
- Yeah, there were something wrong with the ...
-With the "thing"..
Yes, the "thing".
The "thing" can be tricky.
Hey, motherfucker!
I can bust you right now for that.
I have multiple sclerosis.
Marijuana relieves symptoms.
Dyslexia and multiple sclerosis?
Yes, my life has been hard.
You can not even spell "sclerosis".
"Scle ..."
Ohh, fuck ...
I don't know.
It's Reynard.
Clifford Reynard.
I used to steal cars with him.
I think he is a driver now.
He is a fucking prick anyways.
I claim my prize?
It's amazing.
The flexibility!
You should have seen her when she was 15.
You guys looking for me?
If you are the manager of this shit hole
then yes we are.
I'm Detective Bolano.
Detective Monroe.
You are...
Russell Bёrdvell.
What is the problem?
We are looking for the address for
one of your dancers: Jaklin Hollis
Jackie Hollis?
What ever.
She dosen't work for me anymore. She quit.
I didn't ask if she works here now.
I asked for her address.
She's into some kind of trouble?
Just give us the fucking address.
You guys are adorable...
Where are you from? What district?
We are from hell, baby.
You know that guy that discoverd
Uranus wanted to call it George.
This is the planet George.
Come on, Harris.
What?
Hello Darling.
Tell Jimmy Harry wants to see him.
- Harry who
- Harry fucking Krishna.
Get away from the door, mam.
Yeah, it is Muhammad Ali!
Leave him alone.
He is a Quaker.
You have any guns stashed anywhere?
No! I told you, he is a Quaker.
He denies violence.
What?
Fucking pig!
That's not very nice.
Jackie can you put on some coffee
for Mr. Harris here.
And you should probably have one.
You want some donuts too?
Fuckers.
Nice underwear, Jimmy.
Wide screen! Cool.
You like Glenn Campbell?
Who!
Never heard Glenn Campbell?
What's gonna happen to him?
With Glen Campbell?
With Jimmy.
Sent back to prison,
Without a nickle.
There is nothing you can do for him?
Are you trying to bribe us, mam?
No.
Damn it!
All such law-abiding ...
How much?
How much do you have?
Five ... Two!
- Two thousand
- How much do you have?
Five.
Excellent! We take it.
And he is free to walk?
If it is in his capabilities.
And I'm taking the wide screen too.
Do you need something?
No.
So tell us, Jimmy ...
Why in town?
You are not planning a caper?
You have a X-box wire?
I can't concentrate.
They were here first.
It's a Soderbergh movie!
It requires focus.
What Soderbergh?
Steven Soderbergh -
Is a Jewish American actor.
He is a Swede.
Clooney is in jail in Florida.
Jennifer Lopez is in this movie.
Takes her blouse of, but you
can't see the boobs.
Why can't you see her boobs?
Because she is a serious actress,
that's why.
She wouldn't show her boobs
for someone like you.
Caesar open.
You go open.
He told you ... mom!
Stop whining and open the door.
Why do you always pick no me?
Because you're the youngest
and most vulnerable.
That quote is Simone de Beauvoir.
If I could only find a damn thing...
50 buck coming my way!
Don't pay her, Dad.
This jackass says you wanted to see him.
Do not call Reggie a jackass. That's rude.
It is actually inaccurate.
He is more like a pathetic simpleton.
Sit down.
So you found Jimmy?
I did not find his spirit.
Sorry for Terry making fun of your religion.
I apologies on his behalf.
Jennifer Lopez is in this.
Takes her blouse of, but you
can't really see her boobs.
I know!
No, stop your lordship!
Your father...
I don't give a damn about my father!
Some cops showed up at the club tonight.
Some shit about one of my dancers.
Former dancer.
Do you think it has something to do with us?
Maybe. Maybe not.
Should I tell the Webs to cancel?
No.
Probably just a coincidence.
Get hold of the girl.
See what her story is.
Give them a warning if necessary.
So where is this grand finale you
have been promising me?
Relax, maestro.
It's on its way.
Albuquerque Racetrack and Casino.
A million dollars.
Any questions, gentlemen?
I do not know what it is:
supreme confidence  or idiocy.
What ever...
Russell ...
Do you ever think that your
God is anything else but an illusion?
No.
I love cheerleaders.
Is that part of your act?
I Majorettes, moron.
I love majorettes too.
I'm not prude.
What do you want?
Brought you a new TV.
You have a conscience after all.
You want it or not?
Weirdo.
You are the weirdo.
Who is this asshole?
It's my ex.
Looks like a douchebag.
He is a really intelligent guy.
He wrote a well regarded monograph
on André le nôtre.
And he had a nice dick.
And who is this?
My ex.
He had a nice dick too.
What's this about?
I do not know.
About loneliness?
Kind of creepy.
Like something bad gonna happen.
And there is nothing she can do about it.
Yes.
So where did Jimmy
boy say he was going?
Kenosha.
Kenosha, Wisconsin.
Yeah, right.
He has not left town.
What makes you so sure?
The Sixth Sense, honey.
Let's leave it with that
Why did you become a cop?
Your heart doesn't exactly seem to be in it.
I guess I wanted to pervert
the course of justice.
And you can shoot at people
for no reason.
And nobody can do a damn thing about it.
Any sign of Reynard?
No, he is still in there.
What's going on in the big wide world?
Two hundred people died
in an earthquake in Peru.
Who gives a fuck?
Peruvians.
That looks nasty.
Are you his wife?
Why did you stick him?
It's getting a bit trite now.
Can we play a little game?
Called "Shut the fuck up."
Mam, did you do those paintings?
He is gone.
So is he.
You know that Joseph Conrad
and Van Gogh both tried to kill themselves?
By shooting themselves in the heart?
and both missed!
It's true.
I'm not making this up!
Fuck you!
Crime scene pricks are on their way.
She says his name is Danny.
And about Reynard?
What's he up to?
I can barely get a word out of her.
She is still bawling her eyes out.
Shut up!
- What do we do with the kid?
- What can we do?
Out!
That was out.
Give me a second, Sisters.
I will play.
It's good.
What happened to
your nose sweetheart?
Chihuahua bit me.
What's up?
Clifford Reynard
died this morning.
So what?
Webb Brothers will need a new driver.
Probably soon.
If you here anything...
Yes, I know
what to do.
Fucking missed it.
You did not mean that!
Pure luck!
Come on!
No need for fucking jihad here!
Can't take him anywhere...
My mom died young.
She was an alcoholic.
And what about your dad?
I never knew him.
How about you?
He is dead.
How?
Suicide murder.
Suicide murder?
Was that some pact thing?
Like killed your mom and then himself?
No, my mother was in Tennessee.
Another woman?
No.
- Another man?
- Yes.
But he wasn't gay or anything.
I don't get it?
He worked as a security guard.
But wanted to be a SWAT guy.
- Never made it.
- Why?
- Why? I don't know.
- They are assholes?.
Well so was he.
One day he went to the bar.
He gets to drinking, get more and
more depressed and
he pour out his gun
and blew his brains out.
Unfortunately,
there is this guy sitting next to him.
The bullet goes throw my dad's head
and hit this other guy in his head
- and kills him.
- No.!
Yes.
The investigation determined that this
was a suicide
and a murder.
Although...
If my dad was dead before the bullet
hit this other guy in his head
was it actually murder?
Philosophically speaking?
It's a interesting question!
I'll ask Bob, he will know.
Let me know what he says.
Movies have become entirely without plot.
Just right to bed.
No strings, no development ...
Where is the romance?
Starts and ends with the script.
You don't have a good script -
you ain't got a shit.
Do you think you're tough, right?
Think I can help with that!
It's real. Going up.
Playboy Mansion!
Break!
Whatever it is, it's happening
down town
1pm tomorrow.
Don't ask me what.
Who is doing the driving?
The guy is formerly known as prince.
How the fuck should I know?
Something I forgot to tell you:
Surrender!
How do I look?
Suits you.
Stupid fucking cops.
You're soaked.
You ok?
Yeah, I'm ok.
Was it a bad dream?
Go back to sleep, baby.
Perfectly!
You know what they say about vertigo?
Vertigo is not the fear of falling
but the fear of wanting to fall.
Hello, hot ladies.
Something's wrong.
They are not going to rub a mosque?
They will get ISIS on their asses.
"Al-Qaeda".
Is it "al-Qaeda" or "Al Cade?"
You say, "Cade" I say
"Qaeda".
I say, "Cade," you say
What are you doing?
Preventing a terrorist attack, what else?
Fuck off.
- You fuck off.
- No, you fuck off..
You might wanna be a little careful.
Or you will end up as
a dead schizophrenic.
And that's a children's bike?
You don't think Reggie would ...?
Fuck!
It would have been better if you
went to Wisconsin, Jimmy boy.
You know him?
Yeah!
James Harris. He have been
on the run for a couple of months.
Apparently he is a Quaker.
I thought Quakers were against violence.
Was it a good shoot or a bad shoot?
That's what we call a "contentious issue".
Fuck me!
Again, really?
It's like every fucking week!
At least these guys are white.
Yeah, got to look at the bright side.
What happened to the driver?
He got away.
White, Hispanic or black?
African American.
Got away with the money
too. Almost a million.
Wait a second.
How did you know
the driver was missing?
Wild guess.
You guessed?
I never said missing. No one said missing.
- You said "what happened to the driver"!
Reynard is dead so he can't be driving.
So, Jimmy Harris asks his old friend
Reggie to be the driver.
And Reggie, dubble crossing bastard...
Decoys us and takes the money .
Whose money?
Our money.
Fuck.
Well well well...
Allah be praised.
What are you thinking?
Someone has just made
a very big mistake.
So you heard about Jimmy Harris?
I just lit a candle for him.
Lovely thought.
He's gonna need all the help he can get.
He wasn't so bad.
Always treated me ok.
He was a Quaker.
They didn't have to kill him.
He would have tried to kill them.
If he had the chance.
Quaker or not.
Tell me about Russell Berdvelle.
What is there to tell ...
He is the owner of a strip club.
He is not like Diaghilev
"Russian ballet".
He wanted to now,
why you were looking for me.
I told him that you were
looking for Jimmy.
That wasn't good enough for
Mr. Berdvellu, was it?
He's crazy.
I had a runin with him before.
What about?
He tried to get me in to do porno.
I told him to get lost.
He got nasty.
He got nasty?
Berdvell!
Nobody moves!
Snake!
Fuck!
You're a shit shot Berdvell!
Nobody cares about bystanders!
Why did you move, man?
Fuck!
Bob, are you hit?
It's just cramp. A bad one.
Go go.
I'm just gonna breath.
Come on little piggy.
Come out!
See this ring?
A gift from my mother.
It's a nice ring.
know what it's for?
For beating the shit out of
scumbags like you.
Why don't we just throw him of the roof?
I was joking.
It was a bad joke.
Wanna go grab a burrito?
I can't.
It's date night.
A million dollars?
It's a nice round number.
That is my favorite round number.
We do not need a million for pensions.
Not if you gonna get killed going after it.
I can handle myself.
Don't you worry your pretty
little head about that.
Fuck you.
Besides, fortune favors the bold.
You know where that's from?
Greek mythology.
A guy called Thurn said it just
before another guy, called Aeneas,
popped a pen in his ass.
It's like my mother said:
You are too smart for your own good.
Give me a sec...
Hey, asshole!
You shit in this?
Well there, pilgrim!
This is nice.
Yes, I do not complain.
Don't be getting any ideas, though.
I'm only here until everything
with Berdvellom is ok.
How can you afford this place?
Overtime.
Where is Reggie?
Why would I tell you?
We know that Reggie was the
driver for the racetrack heist.
Where is he now?
Forcing me to repeat.
Why the fuck wo...
Don't fucking hit me!
I'm only child!
He fled with the money.
How much?
A million bucks.
Fuck me!
A million?
How much do I get if I...
... Rat out your friend?
Yes.
50.
Two hundred.
- 175.
- 50.
Hundred.
Okay, fifty dollars!
Where is he?
You will not believe this.
Fucking Iceland.
They have something called a
"Blue Lagoon". It's a hot spa.
It's outdoors.
Probably full of sweaty Europeans
with bad teeth, fucking each other.
You will swim around in jizz.
European jizz.
It was the first film I saw.
"The European jizz?"
"The Blue Lagoon".
That or "Doc Savage:
The Man of Bronze".
Оh, fuck...
Bob?...
Yeah?
How are we going to find Reggie?
How do we track him
down without a clue?
He is black.
How many black people do
you think there are in Iceland?
We just keep our eyes open.
Not much of a plan, Bob.
- Maybe we...
- There he is.
I have a black belt in
jiu-jitsu, motherfuckers!
You are not a fighter, are you?
Even Stephen Hawking can knock you out.
I'm a lover, not a fighter.
You have no choice.
I should thank you for not killing me.
Shut up.
Iceland? What the fuck?
- I wasn't thinking straight.
- No shit!
I panicked, okay?
You would too if everyone
around you got popped.
It was murder!
The guys were surrendering!
Don't look at me:
I hate murder.
- Don't I Terry?
- He hates murder.
They really upsets me.
But more important:
where is the money?
Stashed it.
How much do you want?
All of it.
- Fuck you !
- No, fuck you, glass jaw boy!
You gonna hand over that
million bucks, or we ...
A million bucks?
Yeah, a million.
I don't have million?
Are you crazy?
Fucking idiot.
You walked away with a million dollars!
It wasn't all mine!
I gave some to the guy who planned it.
Now you are bullshiting us. Either
the Webb brothers or
Jimmy Harris planned it.
And they are all dead.
Jimmy and the Webbs were tapped out.
That's way they did it!
Everything was planned by this...
rich, British guy named, James Mangum.
Never heard of him.
Where can we find him?
I don't know.
He is this mysterious character.
He has some kind of legal business.
I'll tell you everything I know, but you need to give me something back.
How much do you have?
Two hundred.
- We take a hundread.
- It's hard but fair.
Pretty fair, man.
Okay.
How do you like Iceland?
Not the best place to blend in but...
Upside is I think I'm falling in love.
Baby! Where have you been?
You guys wanna drink?
I got some pretty good whiskey.
- I'm good.
- I'll try some of that, Kimberly..
How long have you known, Reggie?
We're old friends.
You are here on holiday?
No. Just a quick in and out.
You are together?
Yes we are.
No, we're not together. I'm
a heterosexual man.
And he also heterosexual.
Well...
Good for you, honey!
You should go to the "Blue Lagoon"!
Very refreshing.
I'm sure it is.
I go there a lot.
I'm sure you do.
Hope you choke on it.
So Reggie is gay?
If Kimberley has a dick, which I assume
she does, that makes Reggie gay.
Possible bisexual.
What if Kimberly doesn't
have...If she already ...
...closed up?
That's a good question.
That would make Kimberly a woman
and Reggie straight.
Really?
With an asterisk.
If Reggie is gay...
Do you think Reggie and Pádraic...
Is that an international symbol of sodomy?
You know exactly what this is.
I don't think that's allowed in here.
To be honest,
that's hardly allowed anywhere.
You know what you remind me of?
A bloody Cyclops.
I do not know what that means.
And you know I don't.
You never read the "Odyssey" in school?
When you stop to surprise me.
I read it in Greek,
Traveling through the
Peloponnese with my father.
I lost my fucking eye!
Calm down.
You still have one left.
I'm gonna fuck them up!
You are not going to fuck up anyone.
They are policemen after all.
I don't want to get in to some kind of...
retribution.
Your Lordship...
Specially not in my condition.
But I think you are a
little too cautious.
Do you know who the
greatest criminal in history is?
No.. I don't.
No, you don't.
Because, if you did,
he wouldn't be the greatest criminal
in the history of mankind.
Fuck, you're stoned.
But do not worry.
I'll talk to them.
Give them a little reducer
as we say in good old England.
What if it dosen't helps?
Eat your grapes, Russell.
Eat your grapes.
You shot his nuts off.
If you shoot a guy in the
nuts, he won't rise again.
Who makes these targets?
They are kind of racist.
Looks like Reggie.
Where the hell have you two been?
Following up on a tip off.
To where? Fucking Iceland?
Yeah, yeah, we were in Iceland!
Bob, that shit is not funny anymore.
Not that it was funny to begin with.
Anyway, during your
unexplained absence.
I received a very serious
allegation of assault
from this guy, Russell Berdvella.
Fuck him!
No, Terry, fuck you!
How many times do I have to tell you?
His lawyer is threatening to charge
you with attempted murder.
Attempted murder?
He shot at us!
I gave him a couple of slaps.
He is a fucking pussy!
According to him,
you failed to identify
yourself as police officers.
Which is why he fled the scene.
Those are what we call
"mitigating circumstances."
The fact that you knocked
out one of his eyes
while beating him
those are not what we call
"mitigating circumstances"!
I told you that Berdvell was part
of an ongoing investigation.
We are gonna get it cleared up in two days.
Well, you better!
Cause, this shit is not going away.
Meanwhile I had to release the prick.
Fuck me.
It is I who have to take the hard words
from the bosses above me!
So please, guys,
slowly, slowly catching monkey!
- You got it?
- Got it.
Hey, shorty!
Where do we find James Mangum?
Get out immediately!
This is private property.
Get out of here!
What are you doing?
Ohh, no, no!
Come back, bastard!
Help!
He comes only for the weekend ...
to look over his horses.
He lives in town.
Where in the town?
I do not know.
I do not know! Honestly!
Give back my fucking wig ...
Give me back my wig.
Put the wig back.
Man, I'm sorry, I did not mean to.
You ruined it!
No, it's ok!
Ruined it!
No, It's great!
You take it!
I am hungry and homeless, please help.
Hey kid, you got all the time in the
world to get a better job than this.
It's "Homeless" and not "homless".
You started with the letters to big here and
you had to scrunch them up at the end.
It is a bad presentation.
That's why you are broke.
Lazy piece of work.
Leave him alone.
Thank you.
Have you softened with age?
Need a hug?
No Glen Campbell!
Unbelievable...
Try some Elvis. They
probably got some Elvis?
You know that he died on the toilet?
He and Judy Garland.
- What did they do...
- Not at the same time.
What are you doing?
Hey, kid!
- Get off me
- Easy! I will not hurt you!
Gotcha.
Is my mom in jail?
Yes, for killing your dad.
She is not at the beach.
What?
You going to arrest me?
No. Why would we?
Are you a gangster?
You look like a beggar.
Why did she kill him?
Why did your mom kill your dad?
All right, we're good.
You can talk to us.
What are we going to do?
We got to call social services.
Might as well sell him to the Philippines.
Do you want to adopt a "homless" kid?
- No.
- Why not?
I'm not putting him back on the street.
Do you think it is
easy to look after a kid?
I have two, and it's not easy!
Of course, I love them.
But I got to feed them 24 h a day!
Guzzle as vacuum cleaners!
- It's hard work.
-Are you saying that I shouldn't have a child?
Yes!
Give me a chance.
No.
What the hell, Terry?
I'm working on a case, baby.
And Danny here is a star witness.
As in the film,
that kid who died.
In what film? What kid?
I can't remember.
You know that booze destroys memory?
Yes I know.
One of the few things in
life I can be thankful for.
Just throw your stuff in
one of the spare rooms.
Good boy.
Did you eat?
Yes, ma'am.
Then go into the shower.
I will bring a towel.
Dolores got you hooked
in her feminist crap?
Can feminists still wear sexy shorts?
Yes they can.
Don't be such a misogynist.
And don't change the subject?
How long should he stay?
I do not know.
For how long will you stay?
It's not fair.
I was in trouble.
So is he, baby.
We are just your "ordinary"
everyday family.
For members only.
What does that say?
It says you are a member.
Damn right, baby.
Sorry!
Where can I find James Mangum?
How should I know?
Where does he live?
I say it again:
How should I know?
He owns this club, right?
That doesn't mean that
I know where he lives.
How often is he here?
Every now and again.
Should you have a drink or not?
Yes, I want a drink.
"Bloody Mary".
The bloodier, the better.
Okey.
- Are you serious?
- You can't come in here looking like that.
- You can't come in.
- Do you see that guy?
He's a cop. He will kick
the shit out of you...
Okay, go.
Fuck you, Jeeves.
I see that Iceland paid off handsomely?
Here is only ten thousand.
We agreed fifty.
Reggie had to pay off some
named James Mengenu.
James Mangum ...
- You know him?
- Yes, he is often on the fights?.
He has a couple of his men.
He owns a restaurant in this hotel.
Must be crowded.
- Want to see the rest of the money?
- Here we go ...?
Hang out here and if you see
him give me a call.
Okay.
Still though ... happy days!
You are not really happy...
just a chemical reactions in the brain.
Hey, it is me, honey.
Only me.
It's just a dream.
Only a dream.
What is that?
A large Chinese plastic cat.
What does it looks like?
It is supposed to bring good luck.
Or maybe not?
That's it?
That's all you got?
You have to do a lot
better than that boys.
It can get a lot worse, fagot.
Believe me.
Worse, you say?
It can get a lot worse, haa?
What are you gonna do?
You gonna cut me?
You gonna abuse me?
You gonna rape me?
Let me tell you a little secret.
There's nothing you can do to me
that ain't already been done.
So go ahead.
Do your worst.
What do you want us to do?
I don't think the boys will be too
keen on killing a cop.
Boss!
Hello.
Sonofabitch...
You should see the other guy ...
He is totally unscathed.
Baby, come on?
I'm ok.. I'm ok.
It looks much worse than it is.
I'm ok.
Do not Cry. I'm ok.
I'm sorry I scared you.
Kiss my bloody lips.
It got to be Mangum, right?
Obviously someone we have upset.
That could be anybody.
You look like Adam Ant.
Remember him?
Fuck you, hippie.
Shouldn't you be waiting for the Brit?
I was kicked out. But he is still in there.
Enjoy a delicious lunch.
Really nice I suppose.
Any distinguishing features?
Yes. He's sitting with a bunch of Japs.
Can't miss him.
James!
There you are!
He is right there.
Hey!
How are things, man?
Oh, this is awkward ...
You are not going to
introduce us to your dad?
This is Mr. Okiyama
and Mr. Murakava we are business partners.
Ms. Ito, their interpreter.
Mr Bolano
and Mr. Monroe -
They are policemen.
Why so formal?
I'm Bob. And this is Terry.
Nice to meet you.
That was easier, right?
Can I have the lobster?
I love lobster.
What do you got there Bob?
I think it's veal. Om-Nom-nom!
Some wine, perhaps?
No, we can not drink
while we are on duty.
That would be illegal.
Is everything all right, sir?
Yes, it's fine. I would like the bill, please.
Simply fantastic!
I ever told you about that time I
puked Indian food from my nose?
Gentlemen,
Is this a social visit or do you have
a reason for embarrassing me?
We are not embarrassing you, are we Terry?
Why would we?
We just wanted to say,
that we know all about you.
and we are on to you.
You know nothing about me.
Oh, Story time!
I'm a legitimate businessman.
And if you think you can play
any dirty little tricks on me,
I think you will find
yourselves sadly mistaken.
I don't think you understand, you little shit.
You see, we don't live in your world,
You live in ours.
You know that 800 grand?
800 thousand fucking dollars,
That's ours.
That's not yours.
You have until tonight to hand
it over, and if you don't
you're gonna be fucked.
So, make sure you give us a call.
You got that?
How is that lobster, Terry?
Tasty.
Want some dessert?
No, I got to watch the waist line here.
We should do this again some time!
I look forward to it. You are
pleasant company.
Terry, that was sarcasm!
The lowest form of humor, Bob.
Sayonara!
Arigato!
Godbye!
So Mangum got his sharks involved, huh.
I must say,
I am disappointed.
I feel like you let me down.
You can't harass people like that and
think you can get away with it.
If the guy was an Arab, then yeah. But
this is a Brit we're talking about!
He is a Lord, apparently!
He has an OBI or something ...
OBI? What is that?
It's a part of the British Empire.
It don't mean a shit.
It means something to the Brits!
I'm a Prince!
It just ain't right!
It ain't right.
Not to mention having cars
blown up outside your house.
and you have been half beaten to death.
only a problem with my wife.
It wasen't even my car. I do not go by jeep.
They guzzle fuel like the devil!
- Probably Greenpeace who set fire to it.
- Evil!
Assholes!
I know!
Are you done?
- Yes
- Okay.
I gonna need your guns too.
Think I care!
I don't even like this gun.
And clear out your desks.
There is nothing in my desk.
Except that triple murder
from three years ago.
Ohh yeah! I wounder who did that?
We may never know.
Bob!
I'm telling you this as a friend:
He will destroy you.
You know that, don't you?
With all due respect,
You were never a friend of mine.
You are more of a glorified bastard.
Bernalillo County
Correctional institution
I'm staying with Terry and his girlfriend.
They got this very cool place.
That's good.
It will only be till you get out.
Terry says, you have a good
chance getting off with the trial.
Then we can live together again.
With your husbands record and
together with some other shit ...
Like history of domestic
violence or something...
That's not why I killed him.
I'm so sorry.
So, so sorry.
It's not fair!
No, it's not.
Life is unfair.
Never forget that.
I hate jellyfish.
I wonder how it got here?
Maybe it fell from a spaceship.
Is it true that they can sting you
even when they are dead?
No, I think when they are
dead... they are dead.
They are immortal, though.
What?
Jellyfish are immortal.
Bob told me.
Not everything Bob says is true.
Yes it is.
That's my greatest fear actually.
Death by a jellyfish.
Your greatest fear is death by jellyfish?
It is not funny.
Random death by jellyfish..
A friend of mine caught a jellyfish,
put it in a jar, went out.
And when he returned ...
he reached for, what he thought,
was a glass of water.
And now he is dead!
I am glad that you find it amusing.
Okay, lazy.
Lets get something to eat.
- Wait, wait.
- Come on!
I can't run in these!
Hurry!
"I am real!", said Alice and began to cry.
"You won't be more real by
crying" Tweedledum remarks.
"There is nothing to cry about"
We finish reading tomorrow.
Dad,
What happens when you die?
Nothing.
When you are dead, you are dead.
But is not mother in heaven?
No, my dear.
What did I say? It's just darkness forever.
Run along and play. I will
talk to Uncle Russell.
Growing up so quickly!
What are we going to do
with those two pricks?
They were fired today.
They are no longer police officers,
they are now civilians.
Fuck does that mean?
It is over?
No, it's not over.
Now we will kill them.
You almost broke my cock.
Can you break a cock?
It consists of tendons.
You snapped a tendon!
Well, I got to take a break,
ruminate,
Consider the options.
I'll miss the police.
I liked the structure itself.
Structure?
Maybe it's good thing that we got fired.
I was beginning to worry about you.
You know when those things
started to happen...
I'm not sure how much longer
you could have got away with it.
Especially with Terry.
Terry...
Hey, Torro!
Vámonos, Torro!
Freaking funny, huh?
Yes, it's funny.
You go, Torro!
Cool, huh?
When you got beat up last night,
did that have anything to do with me?
Of course not.
Why would it?
I know why she did it.
Who!
My mom.
I know why she stabbed my dad.
She found out what he had done...
And what had he done?
Danny,
what had he done?
He took me to this place ...
Somewhere outside the city.
There were these people there.
They did things.
You know...
They filmed it as well.
Do you know the names of these people?
Yes, I know their names.
Do you know why you're here?
Go fuck yourself.
Because I do not like snitches.
They have no honor,
No code.
Go fuck yourself.
This is the Lafayette sword.
From the revolutionary war.
Yes, there was a revolution in the
united states, hard to believe.
I stole it from Masonic Lodge in Illinois.
Have you heard of the writer,
Yukio Mishima?
Of course you haven't, you are Irish...
I forgot.
In 1970
Mishima attempted a coup
on his native Japan.
The coup failed and....
And Mishima committed seppuku.
Ritual stomach opening.
The second in command was supposed
to behead him in the end of the ritual,
but the poor fellow was so nervous,
that he missed.
Mishima's bloody head was hanging off him.
Literally.
Another guy had to step
in to finish him off.
Hope I don't miss.
Fucking Brits!
You never know when to shut up!
Poor kid.
Yes.
I have never killed anybody before.
Neither have I.
You know what they say:
Always be open to new experiences.
I'll do this on my own.
You don't have to get involved.
How come you always
look out for me, bro?
Because you're a good friend of mine.
I got your money.
You should be in bed.
Where is our Lonesome Luke?
What?
I think he's going to kill a bunch of people.
You know that in Somalia
only men have gravestones.
Walt Whitman...
was buried without his brain.
Descartes was buried
without his right hand.
You never wondered,
who created... everything?
No.
It's like:
Where does the universe begin
and where does it end?
If you can't answer that, then you
can't say that God doesn't exist.
On the other hand, Pythagoras believed
that after death
your soul go into a fucking green bean.
So what do I know.
I love this car.
It's indestructible.
Like I always say Bob:
if it ain't broke
Break it.
Detectives ...
Glad to see you again.
Do you like westerns?
I don't have your 800 thousand dollars.
I was never going to give them to you.
I just wanted to clarify that.
Not so tough now, huh?
without your fucking badges?
Listen, man,
l know we don't see eye to eye but..
Fuck you!
I must say you're taking this
turn of events rather well.
We did not come here for the money.
We don't care about the money any more.
This is about Danny Reynard.
Danny Reynard ...
I can't...
quite place the name.
You know, one day...
these students were taking a
philosophy exam and
to start the tutor grabs
a chair and puts it on a desk
and he says: "For your last test,
prove that this chair exists. "
So, everyone begin to write.
Except for one guy.
He wrote only two words.
Rises,
hands his paper to the tutor
and leaves the class.
The tutor looks at it,
and on it it says:
"What chair?"
Well...
That's certainly brave....
Fuck!
Bob?
Bob...
I love bulletproof vests.
Lets go fuck these scumbags.
I killed your snitch.
I chopped his fucking head off!
Wait ...
Don't...
I knew your last word would be shit.
Okay.
You made your point.
How much is this gonna cost me?
Your life.
Not bad.
That's a shame.
I kind of liked the guy,
in a funny sort of way.
His hair were resealing quite a bit.
His teeth was fucked up.
What are you doing?
We will give him a decent burial.
What are we? Savages?
I thought you were gonna keep
him as a souvenir or something.
That story about the philosophy
exam and the chair?
What does that actually mean?
It's not supposed to mean anything.
It's a Zen koan.
Just ponder on it.
Just ponder on it?
Yeah. I fucked it up though.
I was supposed to say:
"Prove that the chair doesn't exist".
Ahh! So it "doesn't exist"?
Man, that was some cold shit.
What's next, man?
Gonna live slow.
Die old and leave an ugly looking corpse.
What are you going to do?
I don't  know.
Something sedate.
Are you capable of being sedate?
It's like the Buddha once said ...
You're quoting fucking Buddha now?
"Do not dwell in the past
do not dream of the future.
concentrate the mind on
the present moment."
I love this song.
Great song.
Masterpiece.
Translated by Tobbeman