Business cards, invitations,
wedding invitations party menus,
receptions, catwalks, whatever
you like, there are dozens more.
I saw your confectionery department,
you sell sugared almonds...
See what I mean?
Sugared almonds mean christenings.
Christenings mean invitations.
We all need to make ourselves known
and communicate our news:
from the grocer who is moving
to the unemployed man finding a job.
When people needed
a business card, where did they go?
To the stationers or to the printers.
People ordered
a couple of thousand cards.
You'd wait a month
but how long did you keep them?
Ten years, a lifetime.
Nowadays who stays put for five years
or keeps a job two years?
What do you do
with your business cards?
They're useless.
Business cards, invitations,
party menus wedding invitations,
receptions, catwalks...
Whatever you like,
there are dozens more.
I saw your confectionery section,
you sell sugared almonds...
See what I mean?
Sugared almonds mean christenings.
And christenings mean invitations.
All right, sir?
Take a seat, drink some water.
No, I'm all right.
I'm all right, thanks.
Business cards,
invitations, party menus,
wedding and christening invitations,
receptions, catwalks...
Simon recited his spiel all day long.
At home one evening,
Simon Hirsh looked
at his hands and nails.
They were yellow
like an old dog's claws.
Simon had never imagined
he'd grow old.
Yet there it was, staring back at him.
He had not realised.
He wandered why all those years
had gone by so fast.
He tried to reflect on his life.
But what could he remember?
A dozen faces
whose names he mixed up
His daughter, long gone. The smell
of four or five houses he'd lived in.
And all those absurd things
he'd had to sell to earn a living.
How long did he have left?
Fifteen years? Twenty?
What would happen?
IT WAS AROUND THAT TIME
THAT HE MET MICKEY...
"Look," says Mickey, "relax your hips.
Go on then!"
"No I don't want to."
Go on. Look.
"How would you know? Try."
- See? Relaxed and dynamic.
- I don't care.
Look! it's great. Look.
And right, and front!
And right and front...
The knee is relaxed.
- I'm not about to dance in the street.
- The knee is relaxed. Look.
What are you waiting for?
Come on.
- Are you embarrassed?
- What's the difference? I don't want to.
- It's stupid to be embarrassed.
- I'm stupid.
- You're worried about being ridiculous?
- Just drop it.
Right now, you're being ridiculous.
We're alone.
- I don't want to.
- How d'you know without trying?
- Go on, try it. No one's looking.
- Makes no difference.
- Dancing's not the problem.
- Then what is?
I don't want to ruin my shoes!
- Shall I turn around?
- Makes no difference to my shoes.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
What are you doing this morning?
I'm talking to you, mate.
- What are you doing?
- Meeting a client in Villetaneuse.
Do me a favour? All done by midday.
I'll buy lunch at Marguery.
- Then you head to Villetaneuse.
- What's the favour?
- Surveillance.
- What?
Surveillance. For me.
- Marlon broke his arm, he can't come.
- No way.
It's dead easy:
sit in the car, look around,
read the paper,
check it's recording, turn the tape over.
- No.
- You know how to turn a tape over?
You know how to turn a tape over,
don't you?
Well, do you?
No!
What do you want?
Now's not the time for cleaning.
Get out! Close the bloody door
Listen, he's pretty wired today.
I don't think he'll make a deal
with the guy.
- Can you hear me?
- Of course.
Danata's waiting for a friend.
If she drives here,
try to get her registration number.
Loosen your hips
The hips are the key. Nice and relaxed.
Watch your feet
-Someone's at the door, Mr. Danata.
- I'll get it.
-I said I'd get it.
- Very well, sir.
Leave me for an hour.
If the phone rings, don't answer.
THE HOSPITAL HAD A SEPARATE
WING FOR DEEP COMAS
THE OTHER TWO...
LONG BEFORE ALL THAT
Don't let me got in your way, will you?
You! Don't let me get in your way.
Piss off, then!
Piss off!
- There's no room, get in the back.
- I can't!
- My leg is infected.
- It's the back or nothing.
OK, OK, I'll get in the back.
Arsehole. That piece of shit
would've run me over.
Oh, shit.
No, not Max. Marx.
Marx, like Karl Marx.
Karl Marx: ring a bell?
No? Right. What about you?
- What's what about me?
- What's your name?
- Frédéric.
- What? Frédéric?
Ha! Frédéric!
- Why? What's wrong?
- Not Frédéric.
Frédéric's a woman's name.
For fuck's sake,
take your feet off my suitcase!
Freddy...
Freddy... Freddo...
Even Freddo... Freddo's a dog's name!
You couldn't care less
what anyone says to you, eh?
How many fingers?
- Three.
- You're a fast one, aren't you?
Olympique de Marseille lost recently.
I'll have to cut your hair.
So they lost...
What do you tell your son?
Anything. I don't know...
Whatever's going through my head.
What's going on outside.
Who I've seen, what I've done.
What his cousins and friends say.
Funny stories I hear on the radio.
Sometimes I bring him newspapers
and I read to him.
Or I sing him a song.
Today I brought him pictures
of the house,
his mother, his sisters.
So when he wakes up,
he won't be completely lost.
Mickey...
It's me, Simon.
What did I expect?
What can I tell you? I don't know...
I'm supposed to talk to you...
Right, Mickey, it's me, Simon.
You went to see him?
- And how is he? Still...?
- Of course.
I wanted to go see him, but then...
- What was he thinking, going alone?
- I don't know.
- Would you like another coffee?
- Yes, please.
Two coffees, please, Miss. Thanks.
Ignore this, the lads did it for a joke.
Who was Danata?
A crook.
We'd been after him for a month:
betting, dope...
Why Mickey?
I mean, why did they shoot HIM?
Because he was there.
Just because he was there?
Sometimes that's all it takes.
Can I ask you something?
If you'd been with him,
would things have been different?
For Mickey? No.
- Have you found anything out?
- Not yet, it's too soon.
We'll do everything we can.
We'll find him one way or another.
Did he tell you what he did
outside of work? His friends?
No, not really. Why?
We haven't found anyone to notify.
No friends or girlfriend. No one.
His stuff at the station doesn't matter.
But his landlord calls us ten times a day
to get his flat back.
- What about his parents?
- Mickey doesn't have parents anymore.
The new tenants move in in a fortnight.
I went ahead and put the mattress away.
What shall I do with the rest?
Keep the furniture.
I'll take care of the rest.
The television as well?
Shall I keep the television as well?
If you want.
There's something
I don't really understand...
Are you with the police?
Police or family?
If anyone asks,
you can tell them you don't know.
Off! That's my bed. Clear off.
Can't you make less noise
when you eat? Your mouth!
Close your mouth. I see everything
in your mouth. It's revolting.
Like a concrete mixer.
Didn't you learn to eat
with your mouth shut? The belt.
The belt, there.
See those shoes?
- What d'you think they're made of?
- Leather.
Very good. What sort of leather?
Horse leather.
Nothing beats horse leather.
Did you know?
Feel them. Here, have a feel.
Feel that? Hmm? Feel the texture?
I bought them from a guy
who lost everything at the races.
- See, the initials are inside.
- The horse's?
- Course not. The guy's.
- The guy's...
He figured that nag stripped him bare,
it's his turn now. He waited five years.
Five years later, when they took
the nag to the abattoir,
he was outside, waiting.
What for?
The shoes!
We're closing.
- Marx.
- Yeah?
Can I lie next to you?
Can I sleep next to you?
Never again.
Never wake me like that again,
do you hear me?
I can't believe it.
Who do you think you are?
You poof! I'll put you right,
just you wait.
Wake me like that once more
and I'll crush your skull. Got it?
I get it, Marx.
We wanted to have lunch outside,
but it rained so we had to go inside.
Sandrine came with Jeanne.
They bought a house...
Her bloke found work again.
You know Jean-Jo the beekeeper,
the one who talks to insects.
She showed us pictures of the house.
She asked me three times how I was.
Then the rain stopped,
so the Lefèvre kids played
in the garden.
I went into my office
but the little one was sleeping so...
Simon, can you hear me?
Danata's waiting for a friend.
If she drives here,
try to get her registration number.
- I said, I'll get it.
- Very well ,sir.
Leave me for an hour.
If the phone rings, don't answer.
- What are you doing here?
- I was in the area...
You shouldn't be here.
I told them not to let anyone in!
- I needed a word.
- About?
How's it going?
The investigation? Mickey?
You think now's the time?
Nono! Tell her to shut it, will you?
Of course it's progressing.
- Have you found anything?
- Nothing conclusive yet.
We know the killer was quite young,
early twenties.
Left-handed. Wore trainers.
- We think they were pros.
- There were several of them?
That's enough, Mr Hirsch.
Let us do our job now.
Nono!
Where's that useless bastard? Call him.
- Is this linked to the investigation?
- What? The whore? No.
- You're not doing everything you can.
- What?
You said, "We'll do everything we can."
You're not.
- You're losing focus if it's not related.
- You have no idea, do you?
You think the administration
can double our numbers?
Only the murders are doubling!
The dead all matter equally.
I think you don't give a shit
about Mickey!
- You've no right.
- Admit it!
Queen of hearts,
two low black cards.
Where's the queen? The queen.
Where's the queen?
There! Two hundred francs!
Two hundred!
Red wins, black loses.
Follow the queen. Where's the queen?
There! A hundred francs. A hundred!
- Yes! Two hundred! Two hundred.
- You're a bit cagey.
The cane! The cane.
Don't just stand there for fuck's sake.
Go on, hit him! Go on! Harder!
He can't feel a thing! Go on!
Leave it! Fuck...
Shit. I could break my hand on that now.
You didn't have to hit so hard.
Shit, I think he got my ear.
Is it bleeding?
I can't see.
- It's not bleeding?
- Dunno.
The suitcase.
Coming or not? Hey!
210, 230, 250...
- 250, 270, 290, 310...
- 370.
Shut up, I'll lose count!
That's how much there is: 370.
330, 350, 370.
- How about Johnny?
- What?
Johnny's a good name, right?
- it's better than Frédéric, isn't it?
- There are gamblers in here.
There are gamblers here, I know it.
I can smell it.
Those two guys in the corner...
Don't turn around, you idiot!
Don't turn around.
Bloody shame.
What can you do with 370 francs?
Shit!
- I could've had them. Easy.
- I have some.
- What?
- Cash. I've got some if you want.
No. What if I lose it?
- It doesn't matter if you lose it.
- Doesn't matter?
- Here, if you wanna play, go.
- How much is there?
I don't know. it's dole money...
The dole! I won't touch that.
- It's my work experience. Here.
- If it's work experience... I'll count it.
- Three.
- Two.
Three plus six.
Three hundred plus six hundred.
We all need to make ourselves known
and communicate our news:
from the grocer who's moving
to the unemployed man finding a job.
When people needed
a business card where did they go?
To the stationer's or the printer's.
People ordered a couple of thousand.
You'd wait a year. But you kept them
ten years or a lifetime.
Obviously the advantage
is that they are small.
The quality is excellent.
There are logos. People feel
like they've done it themselves.
Business cards,
invitations, party menus,
wedding invitations,
receptions, catwalks...
It's out of the question. it's maintenance.
Ask Richer, it's his job.
Tonight?
I'm in his office. I'll ask.
Tonight won't work.
I tell you, tonight doesn't work.
That's your business, not mine!
I have to go. Someone's waiting for me.
No, not here again!
We've been here twice already.
What does that bloody office want now?
I'm busy. That's that.
Pain in the arse.
"We'll do everything we can.
Everything we can."
Useless bastard. He's doing nothing!
Goes all out to go for a ride though.
Sorry.
- You with them?
- No.
Thought as much.
- What about you?
- It's me they're looking for.
Just to ask me questions though.
Don't worry, they can't see us.
When they're like that, they're blind.
I've seen you somewhere?
Do we know each other?
- You friends with that cop who got shot?
- Yes.
I must've seen you with him
at that canteen...
The Marguery?
Yup, while you were having a feast,
I froze outside.
- How did you know him?
- I was his informant.
- Think they're on to something?
- No. They're making too much noise.
Anyway, they'll never find
the guy who did Danata in.
- Why not?
- Because he's a pro.
- Pros don't got found just like that.
- So they don't get found?
Sometimes. But a lot later.
Randomly. In the boot of a car.
With a hole in the head. Hands tied
with barbed wire. Same as informers.
Looks like the intermission is over.
It's not getting better in the East.
The West bows to Yeltsin's reforms.
Seventeen countries grant
an extension to the Soviet debt.
There's a picture below of women
looking at frozen chickens.
Stock exchange: down 0.4
No picture.
Let's see: weather forecast.
Not much change
over the next couple of days.
- It's late.
- Yes...
- Have you eaten?
- No.
- Are you hungry?
- Are you OK?
- No.
If you don't want to lose it, don't give it.
I didn't ask you for anything.
- Did I ask you for anything?
- No.
- See?
- It doesn't matter, Marx.
I lose his money
and he says it doesn't matter.
What is it?
What's with the puppy dog face?
Fuck it.
Where are you going?
None of your business.
- Can't I come?
- No, you can't come with me.
I need to be alone. It's business.
I don't normally have someone in tow.
I don't want to either.
I understand.
What are you going to do?
Any plans?
Better think about it.
Yesterday you said,
"I'll think about it."
- You said you would figure it out.
- it's all figured out.
If I come back,
I'll leave a note for you at the hotel.
Can't I come with you?
I'll just come to the station with you.
You can't come with me.
It's out of the question.
All right, that's OK.
Right, bye.
See you, kiddo.
Hey, sir, come quickly!
Yes, but give us until tomorrow.
- Give us until tomorrow.
- Look at that, it's disgusting.
Just look at it!
Move out of the way.
I'm thirsty, Marx.
Marx...
- I'm thirsty.
- Shut it.
Here you go. Your share.
Hey, here you go. Take it.
You gave me some cash,
I'm giving it back.
It's yours. That's business. Take it.
- What next?
- What d'you mean, what next?
What are you doing next?
I don't know what I'm doing next.
Keep things moving.
Hey! I was thinking...
What are you going to do with it?
- With what?
- Your dough.
What are you going to do with it?
Keep it stuffed in your strides?
Dunno... Why?
In that case, maybe I should keep it.
If you want. Here you go.
Here.
Don't you want
to buy yourself something?
- Like what?
- I dunno. Something you'd like.
-I'm not wearing any knickers.
- Bad habit.
There's stuff everywhere.
Hurry, I don't have all day.
Paper cups, kitchen utensils,
vacuum cleaners
made in East Germany,
frames for glasses,
three-wheel cars, typewriters...
I mean absolutely everything.
One day I decided to go solo.
So I took over a toy factory
not far from Montargy.
Unfortunately the business went bust.
I had a factory filled with toys
on my hands.
I had to empty it
so I took the stuff home.
It was everywhere.
Couldn't walk around. We crawled.
We couldn't open a cupboard
without a stuffed bear falling out.
The ducks were the worse.
15,000 ducks.
Ducks with cymbals for feet.
You wanted a glass in the kitchen...
You went for a piss...
You picked your shoes up
in the morning... Hell.
You know why I worked for Mickey?
Because he was good-looking.
And because scared me.
If a couple times I didn't get him
what he wanted, he'd beat me up.
Here, see...
That was him.
Didn't you know?
No.
- How?
- You want to know the details?
Yes.
- His method, then?
- Yes.
That was a car battery.
He made sure I was ready first.
What comes before is important.
First, he tied me to the bumper.
Then he rummaged through the boot.
He made sure it lasted a while
so I'd start sweating.
So I could think about the car jack
he'd beat me up with.
Then he came back,
like he was sorry for the wait.
It wasn't the jack, it was a plastic bag.
It was an jump lead with crocodile clips.
The price tag was still on it.
So he plugged them
into the battery and...
Music, maestro!
I thought I was finished.
What does he want?
- What?
- You know the other girl?
Do I really have to? I'm not up for it.
- Do what you want, just leave me alone!
- OK.
Leave me alone!
- Got it?
- Got it.
- I'll kill him!
- For the girl, I think I'll...
- I'm not really up for it.
- Fuck off!
You've never done it?
When I ask you if you've ever done it,
do you know what I mean?
I understand.
So have you done it?
- l don't think so.
- You haven't done it then?
You've never tried?
Not with a woman or with...?
- No. But do we have to do it?
- No one has to do anything.
- If we don't have to, I'd rather not...
- Whatever you want.
- We can still be friends though?
- What?
Even if I don't do it.
Doesn't matter. If you don't want to fuck,
don't. They're your balls, not mine.
Wedding invitations,
receptions, catwalks...
Whatever you like,
there are dozens more.
I saw your confectionery department,
you sell sugared almonds.
See what I mean?
Sugared almonds mean christenings.
Christenings mean invitations.
I have to make a call.
Simon Hirsch here.
You just called ms, who's this?
- Mickey's friend. The crocodile clips...
- Oh, and...
A guy got done in Lyon six months ago.
His name's Carver, but it's Merlin
that's important, his associate.
Merlin's behind it. The killer
came from Paris. Young guy in his twenties.
How do I find this Marlin?
- Got a pen?
- Yes, go ahead.
A nightclub in Lyon, you can't miss it:
L'enchanteur.
Talk to him when I'm not around.
All right, Colette?
Talk to him about anything you like,
the weather, read him the newspaper...
- Do you have a family?
- Two girls.
Tell him about your daughters.
You take the leg.
Ready? Let's go.
SIMON HIRSCH'S DREAM
Is that you Simon?
Come here. Closer.
Does it make you sad?
Sad?
Of course.
Why didn't you do it to me anymore?
I don't know.
You didn't want me anymore?
You weren't attracted to me anymore?
That's not it. I've always been
attracted to you. It's me.
It's just time passing.
I must've forgotten.
Is it so important?
Of course it's important.
My youth is slipping away.
- I want to be attractive, to be loved.
- Do you love that arsehole?
- What does he want?
- He finds me attractive.
What about me? Do you still love me?
I just don't know anymore, Simon.
You too felt old
and needed something else.
You found Mickey.
He's young and good-looking.
You can tell him whatever you like.
I don't mean to hurt you,
but at least
he can't betray you anymore.
Louise hadn't yet returned from work,
so Simon left her a note
on the refrigerator:
"I'm going down south,
I'll be back in two days."
In the rear-view mirror,
he saw his house, then the street,
then the town disappear.
He thought about the hospital,
Mickey's room and the silent corridor.
Then he remembered
he hadn't called work.
He nearly stopped
but continued instead.
It could wait.
There was a programme
on the telly yesterday.
It had the Iron Man
but it wasn't a series...
it was like a report and...
there was a journalist.
The journalist was interviewing
the Iron Man.
The Iron Man walked.
He was walking with his legs.
He was walking, you know, really.
- So what?
- Dunno... You don't think it's strange?
I mean, a paralysed man
who starts walking.
It was an actor doing it.
Tell an actor to sit in a wheelchair,
he sits his arse in a wheelchair.
It's his job.
It's not real, it's acting.
- It's not real if he sits in a wheelchair?
- Yeah.
We're going to Paris.
- Get in the back.
- Not me, my leg's bust.
Bloody hell!
They could get an actor
who bust his legs, like, in a bike crash.
Or just take any actor
and break his legs with a hammer.
Now you're just taking the piss.
You're joking.
Simon Hirsh calling.
Can I talk to the boss? No time.
Tell him I'm on a big deal near Lyon.
Can you sort it out
with Blondel and Mergaux?
I'll need an advance. Are you joking?
With the hotel and lunches for a week,
I'll need at least 5,000F.
Yes, 5,000 in my account.
Just search under 'H'.
'H' for Hirsch and 'B' for bank. HB.
'Human Bomb', yes, that's very funny.
- So what's your name then?
- Robert.
Listen, Robert, are you listening to me?
- Yes.
- "Yes, sir."
You call me sir, I'll call you Robert.
- Yes, sir.
- Mr Masked Avenger to you.
Yes, Mr Masked Avenger.
The worst is over.
You'll say anything I want.
- I'm listening.
- What are you doing?
Stretching my legs. It's tiring.
- Is that your family there?
- Yes.
- Your kids?
- They're cute.
- Yes.
Right.
No. Non.
No! No!
The name of the guy
you hired to kill Marlin?
- I'm Merlin!
- Merlin, Carver, whatever, I don't care.
All the same to me.
The young guy's name?
I don't know. I don't know.
- It wasn't a young guy.
- Want another go?
No! It wasn't a young guy. I swear.
It's an old guy.
His leg was bust. I swear.
I'm going shopping.
What d'you want for tonight?
What do you want for tonight?
In front of the guys you say that?
Fuck me! What have I done
to land such an idiot?
First, I don't give a shit
what I eat tonight.
Second, when I'm with people,
don't ask me what I want to eat.
And third... Take that cap off.
- What do I ask then?
- Nothing.
- Why?
- You don't understand why?
- No, I don't.
- It's embarrassing. Women ask that.
- Really?
Women, I tell you! Get it?
No?
You exhaust me.
Aren't you staying?
Come quick, it's started already
on the telly.
Careful you don't fall.
What flavour pizza is it today?
It's the Super Royale.
Mushrooms...
There's a girl going down some stairs.
She has a really long dress.
There are angels following her.
It's for perfume.
Now there's... This one is...
It's a girl.
And, um, she's... she's naked.
She's in a field
and then there are bunnies.
So that's for yoghurt.
Are you eating your pizza?
- No.
- Now there's...
- There's someone?
- No, the flat's empty.
Then he comes in...
He looks out the window
and there are children in the street...
Six children in the street.
There's the policeman
with the yellow feet.
What do you mean, what an I doing?
I'm working!
Yesterday I sold five bikes, yes, five!
How d'you think that happens,
by staying put?
I'm getting worked up? No, I'm not.
But you're starting to piss me off!
Receipts? What about them? it's hardly
my fault if the mail isn't doing its job.
I need 5,000F in my account.
5,000.
3,000, then.
Bad weather reports...
News... News...
What do killers do?
They travel, they kill, they move on.
They're always on the move.
They stay in hotels
and keep a low profile.
They stay one night, then move on.
Like travelling salesmen.
The shower room keys.
Do you have local newspapers?
- Yes, which?
- All of them.
Mr Danata wants his dough
on Monday, understood?
Monday! You piece of shit!
Why did they do this to you?
- I owe them money.
- A lot?
- Three.
- Three what?
- Three too many. Leave me be.
- Here, hold this over your nose.
Hold this. Here.
- Here you go. This enough?
- Course it's not enough.
What'll happen to you
if you don't give them the money?
- What's going to happen to you?
- What do you think?
Piss off, then. Leave me.
I've got a headache.
Piss off.
You're getting on my nerves.
Do me a favour, go.
Why did you rob the pizza place?
- You told me...
- I told you to?
I told you to go rob the pizza place?
Fuck me!
So it's my fault?
If I owe money, it's my own business.
I don't need anyone to sort it out.
Unbelievable!
You can't do a hold-up in a pizza place
every time I owe cash!
We need to lie low.
- I'm sorry.
- No.
Don't say sorry. Don't give a shit
about anyone. Fuck 'em!
If you weren't so dumb,
you wouldn't need to apologise.
- Follow me, sir.
- Yes, sir, I'm coming.
- What are they going to do to me?
- Nothing. What can they do?
Do you know if the pizza restaurant
owner pressed charges? Yes?
- Yes.
- Oh, my God.
What's pizza arsehole's name?
What about Danata's cash?
I don't know, I'll improvise.
- Or we could also kill.
- What?
- We could kill you!
- Now, that's a really great idea!
That way, your boss can definitely
say goodbye to his cash.
- Got a better idea?
- Give me work.
Your boss takes his cash
out of my salary, than were sorted.
Oh, yeah?
And what can you do, arsehole?
Pretty much the same as you, twat.
I'm gonna be the guy now. Scare me.
Look at me. Hey, look at me!
Stop eating!
Look at me and make me shit my pants.
Come on!
Go on.
What's that?
I said scare me, not be a clown.
Say stuff to me.
- What sort of stuff?
- Violent stuff.
Fucking hell.
Give me back my dough,
give it back!
Or I'll fuck you up,
I'll make confetti with your little head.
- Go on. Tell me! Say it.
- Give us back the dough.
- We'll kill you!
- Look at me.
I'll fuck you up. I want my dough.
What d'you mean never? Give it back!
- Stop.
- Can you believe that guy?
Stop it. Now hit me.
Go on, hit me! Go on, do it.
Come on, hit me. Hit! Come on!
Stop it, I'm not going to hit you.
Stop it, I'm not going to hit you, Marx.
Why would I?
Who are you?
- Know why we're here?
- What do you want?
- I did nothing wrong.
- The date?
- I don't know you.
- What's the date today? The...the...?
- The twelfth.
- The twelfth, that's right!
When were you supposed
to pay Mr Danata back?
I don't have the money.
- You don't?
- No.
You'll cough up for my friend!
- You don't wanna pay?
- But...
You'll regret this.
My friend isn't like me.
- I'm the nice guy. Wait till you see him.
- My wife is sick...
Fuck your wife!
You asked for it, I'm calling my friend!
You asked for it! Johnny!
You have to pay now, please, sir.
You have to pay!
No?
Let me handle it. Just watch.
Stop eating!
When I signal to you, you got in there
- What's the signal?
- l dunno, something like this...
A young man
and an older one with a cane.
I remember
because of the tatty suitcase.
They asked me to bin it
but I forgot.
The young guy stayed inside all day
watching television.
- Did he say anything?
- No.
- How long did they stay?
- One night.
- Could I see the suitcase?
- Sure.
- Martine, 108, please!
- I'm coming.
- Will you be wanting the room?
- Yes.
- Is the bathroom through there?
You don't have to, you know.
- Take a shower if you like.
- Whatever you like.
What do you want to do?
What do you want to do then?
Not in the mood?
Can I smoke?
- I'd like to know what it's like.
- What?
What it's like...
...between guys.
Not what you think...
I mean, what it's like in everyday life.
Feelings, all that.
You live with someone?
Yes.
What's his name?
- I don't want to tell you that.
- Stay.
If you don't want to answer, don't.
His name's Marc.
Have you known him long?
A little while. Two years.
And...
How do you live? The two of you?
See him every evening after work?
Well, yes.
Except when I'm working nights.
And when you see each other,
what do you do?
I don't know,
the same as everyone else.
We talk, have a bite to eat,
watch telly.
- Do you eat at home?
- Yes, sometimes.
- Is he the one who cooks?
- No.
No, I do. He's useless at cooking.
When you come home
in the evening...
What d'you do?
D'you open the door and... call him?
No need, he recognises me.
When he's in our room or the bathroom,
he asks. I don't answer and he knows.
- Is he jealous?
- No, he's not, really.
But I am. Loads.
I hate people looking at him,
people talking to him.
I know I shouldn't, I can't help It.
Does he know what you do?
- No, not really.
- So you lie to him?
A little bit.
Aren't you scared?
Yes, I am. All the time.
Hello, Garches Hospital, please.
Can you please put me through
to the 'deep coma' wing.
I'd like to speak to Colette,
the on-call nurse.
Hello, this is Mr Hirsch.
I'm down south.
I'm calling to see how he is.
It's stable.
Could be worse, I suppose.
Have you been talking to him?
My car!
Shit!
Shit...
- Want to press charges?
- Sorry?
Do you want to press charges, sir?
No. No, I won't press charges.
Hirsch here,
put me through to the boss.
Don't know what it's like at your end
but it's mad down here.
They're fighting for the bikes.
I'm selling ten a day. I'm snowed under.
In fact, I need another advance.
What do you mean, fired?
What are you talking about?
Wait! Wait! A grand. Just a grand.
Who else?
No, I don't know him
but I've heard of him.
Get straight back on it?
Yes, of course.
None? That's a pain.
All right, none.
There's some missing, Marx.
- Yes, OK. It is...
- There's some missing.
It's... OK.
- What?
- There's some missing.
Why the fuck are you telling me this?
What am I gonna do about it?
You handle the cash.
If you don't pay attention,
it's your problem.
- What are you doing?
- Guess.
- You're going out.
- Got a problem with that?
- No.
- So carry on, then.
- Me neither.
- So what am I gonna tell Danata?
- Dunno...
- Can't he wait a bit longer?
- So you'll lose everything again?
The kid and I keep working
and he keeps everything this time.
That was before. It won't work this time.
- What am I gonna tell him then?
- I don't know!
We could fix it
if you'll make yourself useful.
You want to make yourself useful?
Depends.
What would I have to do?
- Finish this guy off.
- What?
Finish him off. Bam!
- Who is he?
- We don't know.
We give you the address, you shoot
and your debt with Danata's erased.
Plus extra.
- All right?
- Yes.
- What are they doing here?
- We're just talking. Go to bed.
- You all right?
- I said I'm fine. I'm fine.
- So?
- No, I can't.
So you won't help Danata?
Not like that.
- You're out of options.
- Not that, not that.
- What shall I say?
- l dunno.
That's your job!
I don't give a shit!
Fuck off!
Go on. Go on, shoot!
Marx, what's going on?
What's going on?
What are you waiting for?
Let him go! Let him go!
- Right-handed or left-handed?
- He doesn't know what it's about.
- If you don't answer, I'll break both.
- Don't answer.
Please, don't!
There now, it's all over.
It's my fault.
My hand...
- Is it about the money?
- That's not all.
They want to force me
to do something.
- So why did they hurt me?
- To force me.
They know you're my mate.
- "My mate"
- So?
- You said "mate".
- What d'you want me to say?
I don't know, but...
What do they want you to do?
Imagine shooting something like that.
It's like darts.
Lift, aim and...
What are you talking about?
Do you realise what you're saying?
Darts?
What the hell? Think it's a game?
Think you'll win some bubbly at the end?
Put that down!
Ware talking about killing a guy.
Giving him one with that.
A human being. Do you understand
that? Get that into your tiny brain.
I understand that. I also know
what will happen if you don't do it.
So what?
If you don't want to do it, I can...
If you don't want to do it, I will.
I don't mind doing it.
How oleaginous,
France aligns itself with the rest.
No picture.
Yugoslavia.
it's kicking off on all fronts.
There's a picture of kids
playing ball in a bunker.
Stock market: up 0.31%.
No picture. The classifieds...
- Interested in what I'm talking about?
- Not really.
Want a fight? Eh?
We can go outside and have a fist fight.
A proper brawl.
Come on, now. Be a sport.
Can I?
Quickly though, my kid's on his own.
Daddy? Daddy, is that you?
What you doing here?
Recognise me? It's Sandrine.
That's enough now!
Look at me!
I'm tired. I'm tired...
It's going to be fine.
Come on, I'll take you home.
The lift is on the right.
Eighth floor, left out of the lift.
- So...
- What's the guy's name?
Who cares? Don't worry about that.
Anyway you can't go wrong...
there's a doormat with his initials
in front of the door.
- What are his initials?
- That doesn't matter.
So you arrive with your helmet on.
- Come out the lift...
- What helmet?
A bike helmet like all delivery boys.
He's expecting flowers,
you bring them.
- So you wear a helmet, that's the plan.
- Fine.
- You ring the doorbell.
- l ring...
He looks through the peephole.
You look normal, you...
- Look at the initialled mat.
- Whatever... Don't panic.
I won't panic.
If he asks you,
you say flower delivery.
- All right? So say it.
- What?
"Flower delivery."
Louder. He can't hear you.
- Flower delivery.
- Louder.
- What?
- Lift?
- Right.
- Floor?
- Eighth.
- Flat?
- On the left.
- What is it?
- Flower delivery!
- Louder!
- What is it?
- I'll scare him if I shout so loud.
Never you mind. Go on.
I'll wait out front.
- What?
- I forgot the gun.
What is it?
Flower delivery.
Flower delivery, sir.
So?
Well, I killed him...
Shit...
- Shit, blood...
- It's not my blood. it's not my blood.
It squirted.
- It'll fit.
- Too tight?
No, it's fine.
This one's fine too.
Jeanne?
Jeanne, where are you?
Want me to leave you alone?
- Have you called mum?
- No.
Want me to do it?
You taking all that old stuff back out?
We're going out for a walk.
Fifteen minutes.
- Watch Jeanne for us?
- Sure.
- Need anything?
- No, thanks.
Mr Marx, someone's waiting
for you downstairs.
Excuse me.
You wanted to talk to ma?
- How are you?
- Fine.
- A drink?
- No.
- What is it?
- I'm here on behalf of Mr Calvin.
He knows about what you do.
Jo the Greek in Marseilles,
Carver in Lyon, the brothers Attoun.
L'Alsaco, Francis le Begue in Grenoble.
Shall I go on?
I don't know you.
I don't know you're... Calvin, is that right?
I don't understand what you're saying
and even if I did, I only work for Danata.
It's about him, precisely.
Really?
Mr Calvin doesn't want
Mr Danata around anymore.
Looking for someone?
I'm looking for two guys
who lived here about a year ago.
- Are you still looking at the postcards?
- Yes.
Every time he left,
he sent me a postcard.
The baker read them to me.
He was always talking about Marx.
I hardly knew him.
He was always saying
Marx this, Marx that...
- There it is. It's open.
- Marx did this...
The last postcard the old lady
had received was from a city
flanked with its casino,
like a big meringue.
Simon turned it over,
and in a childlike scrawl it said:
"I am well. I hope you are too.
The weather is nice. Marx says hello.
All the best, Johnny."
it's raining, an old guy is
watching them from a window.
He rests his brow against the window.
He's thinking.
-Someone's at the door, Mr. Danata.
- I'll get it.
-I said, I'll go.
- Very well, sir.
Leave me for an hour.
If the phone rings, don't answer.
I said right. Why are you going left?
Know where your right is?
Your left hand. Know which one it is?
- It doesn't matter.
- Shit.
- I'll turn down there
- We've been here ten times already!
Are you in a bad mood?
Is it because they haven't called?
- Have they called?
- No, they haven't!
You think we'll lose the job?
You call that work?
Afraid of unemployment?
Will you bloody well overtake?
Go on, he's signalling to you.
What an arsehole!
Arsehole!
You're good.
That's extra.
Peanut?
You're not very talkative, are you?
Where are you headed?
- I have to go, things to do.
- That's OK. We'll go together.
- I can't.
- You have time, don't you? On holiday?
- No, not holidays.
- You here on business?
- No, a holiday...
- Like me.
Let's grab a bite.
- No, I can't.
- Why not?
Is it the conversation
you're worried about?
I can take care of that.
I can ask the questions
and answer them.
My friends say I'm gifted
at making conversation.
Even my wife.
That's what she misses the most.
It's just a thought, why don't we walk
a while? Eh? A walk?
Walking's not difficult.
Put one foot in front of the other
One, two. One, two.
One.
Staying here long?
Depends.
You in?
What have you been up to?
Nothing.
- Went for a little wander?
- Yeah.
- You had a good time?
- Not bad.
- You didn't meet anyone unpleasant?
- No.
Look at me when I'm talking to you.
- You didn't meet anyone?
- No.
- You didn't talk to anyone?
Look at me!
I'm looking at you.
You didn't open your big mouth?
- You want to fuck it up for us?
- No.
Don't do this. I didn't do anything.
Who was that arsehole?
- Stop! No!
- What did he tell you?
And what were you telling him
with all that crap inside your brain?
All right?
I'm sorry...
I don't know what got into me.
It drove me crazy to see you
with that guy. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
For everything.
For this. For everything.
I don't understand why you stay.
Sleep.
They should've shot me.
It would have been better for you.
For me too.
I love you, Marx.
Don't say that.
You don't know
what you're talking about.
I love you. I know.
I love you too.
Marx... can I sleep next to you?
If you want to, kid.
You all right?
I'm all right.
What about the kid?
Don't worry, he's here.
I'll take care of him.
He's mine now.
I don't want to die. I'm scared.
I know.
Right.
The shows over for you now.
Time to go.
No point in hanging about.
Time's up.
Sleep.
Stay still.
This one's better than the other one.
That one's...
crap.
You coming? it's ready.
Want some wine?
- Any Coke?
- In the fridge.
- By the way, is Johnny your real name?
- No.
- What's your real name?
- "Frédéric," said the young man.
"I hate it. I hate Freddo too.
Sounds like a dog's name." "And you
think Johnny's better?" asked Simon.
The young man just shrugged
and finished his glass.
Later, Simon felt a hand
on his shoulder.
"Are you asleep?"
It was the young man.
"Can I sleep next to you?"
"If you want, kid," said Simon,
and moved up.