The things you are saying is not a
sufficient reason for divorce
If you have another reason, tell me
- What other reason?
If he is an addict, beats you, or
doesn't pay the bills
No, he's not an addict, he's sane, and
he's a good man
So why do you want a divorce?
He doesn't want to come with me...
if he tells me he will come then I will
withdraw my request for divorce
Are you willing to come?
- No, I'm not willing to come.
Why aren't you ready?
- You know why
No, I don't know, explain it again
Tell her to give me a reason why this
is the time to go overseas
Give me a good reason to stay.
- I'll give you a thousand.
Just give me one - My father. I can't
abandon him. Do you need more?
But you can abandon your wife?
When did I abandon my wife? You
dragged me to court
You filed for divorce and dragged me
here and ruined my life
When you tell your wife and kid to go,
isn't that abandoning? Your Honor,
isn't that what he said?
Yes, and I'll say it again, when you
say you don't want to live with me
I'm not going to force you to stay
- Calm down
You wanted to live with me and now
you don't
When you prefer to go overseas
- "Prefer"? We started this together
Your Honor, after 18 months of work and
money...
... we finally received our visa ...
6 months have passed and it expires
in 40 days...
why should we lose this opportunity?
OK, you don't want to lose this
opportunity, give a suggestion
you know the situation, but you've
dragged me here
give a suggestion
This father that is being used as an
excuse has Alzheimer's
I'm not making excuses, you told me to
give you a reason
He has Alzheimer's, he doesn't even
recognize him as his son
Why are you saying this? What
difference does it make?
Does he know that you are his son?
I know that he is my father!
Your daughter's future doesn't matter
to you?
Is this argument about our daughter?
Why do you think only you care for her?
- Is it the case that all the children in
this country have no future?
I prefer my child not to be raised in
this situation and I have that right
- What situation?
- Is it better for her to have a mom and
dad here or no dad overseas?
This is why I am asking him to come
with us
I can't come, how many times do I need
to repeat myself?
So he can't come, what happens to me?
- Nothing, just return to living your life
If we could do that I wouldn't file
for divorce
- He also has to give permission for a
divorce
He's willing, he just said he is
- Are you willing?
If she prefers overseas to her family
then I have no objection, she can go
Ok, so he has given permission, so
what happens to my daughter?
- I need information, how old is your
daughter?
In two weeks she will be 11
- She can't go without her father's
permission
Her father won't give permission
- That's between you and him
- Please, sir, come and sign this
Your Honor, I have come for you to
solve my problem
- Please, ma'am, come and sign this
Where should I sign?
- Sign here
He can take everything, just give me
my daughter
I'm entitled to our daughter, she
doesn't want to come with you anyways
She doesn't understand
- Why doesn't she understand? She's 11,
why doesn't she understand?
- Please sign here and don't waste the
court's time
No one knows anything but you
- No, you're the one who knows everything
- Don't waste the court's time
What's going to happen to me? I only
have 40 days left
- Ma'am, every small issue doesn't come
to court - What do you mean small issue?
Small issue?
... my problem isn't small ...
... it's about my daughter
- He has rights to your daughter too ...
... I'm the judge and I'm telling you
that your issue is small ...
... please sign this and leave
THE SEPARATION OF
NADAR AND SIMIN
You said second floor
- This is the second floor, sir
So, what's that bottom floor?
That's the ground floor, that's the
first floor, and this is the second
The price we gave was for two floors
You're going to get your money
- Yeah, but only for two floors
I don't understand what you're
talking about
This isn't going to work, this is three
floors
Ok, I'll pay for the extra floor, move
so I can get by
Excuse me, ma'am?
Go tell your dad that they're late
Why don't you tell him?
What did I say wrong?
- What was our deal?
But I'm in the middle of studying
Dad
Hello.
- Hello.
Do you know the situation here?
we're asking you to look after my
father
but there is also some housework
but the primary responsibility is to
get him his medicine on time
keep the door closed so he doesn't
wander out, keep the window closed
I need to leave at 7:30, so you need to
be here at that time
7:30 is too early.
if I want to be on time I will have to
leave at 5:00 or 5:30
I don't know about 8:00
If you can come by 8:00 that is fine
Ring the doorbell and we'll open the
door for you
and I'll put the key here, is that ok?
- Okay
How much per month?
$300 per month
But that is so little
- This is the going price, ask around
- I live far away, I have to take several
buses
This is all I can offer, you decide
what you want to do
Give them the books
Here's your change
- Tell me by tomorrow because I have
another candidate,
so if you say no I don't lose the other
candidate  - Okay
Termeh! Your clothes
You're not coming?
Why are you taking your books?
- I want them.
- All of this for only two weeks?
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Which setting does she normally use?
- Should I go ask her?
She's not even gone yet and...
Simin, where are you going?
- I'll be back soon
- Where are you going?
- I'm going to the corner, I'll be back
I'll come back, Dad
I have an appointment.
Four.
- Why four?
I think that is it.
It's obvious that Mom uses that setting
because the color is worn out
Okay, we'll put it on four then
from today we'll put all the settings
to four
She's really going?
She'll be back.
- Termeh!
- Yes?
- Come to your grandfather
Dad
Termeh, honey, go to your room.
Dad, get up, let go of her hand
Let go of her hand, get up so I can
take you to the bathroom
Get up Dad, come on, get up
Where are you taking me?
- To the bathroom then I'll buy you a
newspaper
honey, I told you to go to your room,
go on
Where are you taking me?
- Come here
Don't put your hand there.
I'm taking this CD with me
Take whatever you want to take
- I'll just take this one
good bye
I thought that you also lived there
No, I am staying with my mother for
awhile
It's a bit difficult, it's difficult
this way
Look, I have complete faith in him,
don't worry about these things,
anyways, he's not even home
when you come in the morning he will be
at work,
and in the afternoon when he comes
back you'll go home
and your daughter will be with you
and this way my daughter is not alone,
they will play with each other
Give your answer to your sister-in-law
Where are you going?
- What is this?
Oxygen.
What is oxygen?
- Move away, you'll wake him up
- I don't hear it
what is it doing?
- Hello.
do you want to go somewhere?
- To buy a newspaper.
- What?
- To buy a newspaper
- The newspaper is in your room, come
with me
come let me take you to your room
I want to take you to your room and
give you something to eat
- Mommy ...
he peed his pants
- Sit on the bed
What is this?
Where are you going? Go back inside
go inside, close the door and wear
your slippers, everything here is wet
He would tell when he had to use the
bathroom
take him to the bathroom
I can't come now, I have a lesson
until 12:00
call my husband, did you call my husband?
Do you have his number?
okay, write it down
the pen is right next to the phone
If I bring you your pants can you put
them on yourself?
if I bring your clothes can you change
them yourself?
Simin?
- Are you able to wash yourself?
Can you?
- Simin?
I'm putting your clothes here
okay, bathe yourself and put on these
clothes
I'm putting your towel here
do you understand?
- Yes.
Bathe yourself so you're
comfortable
put your pants in that hamper
are you able to?
your pants
take your pants off and put on the
ones that I have left you,
the pants, okay?
Simin ...
- Hello, I have a question,
I've come to this house to watch over
an old man,
I wanted to ask ...
he soiled himself
if I change him is that a sin?
No one is here
he's a 70 or 80 year old man and he
isn't entirely with it
The urgency? He's been like this for
half an hour
I can?
I won't tell Dad
My sweetheart
- Stand up
get up
okay, open your legs, open your legs
a little
okay, now you take off your own pants
Card! Card!
Everybody's looking
- Who cares? Let them look
How much?
- $37.50
Did you get change?
- He didn't give me any
Did you ask for it?
- Well it's his tip
A tip... Wait a second, sir
A tip is when he pumps the gas for you,
go get the change from him
Dad!
- Quick!
Wait, sir, wait
Here you go
Keep it
Really?
Hello.
- Hello, Termeh.
Hello, ma'am
Hello, how are you?
- Fine, thank you.
Hurry, honey
- I'll go get my books
bring your test scores too
Are you good, ma'am?
- Fine, thanks, and you?
Fine, thank you.
We're sorry we're late
It's all right. How's your wife?
Thanks to God, she's well
- I'm here if you need anything
Hello, sir.
- Hello, ma'am, how are you?
How are you, Dad?
Hello, cutey pie.
- Hello.
Here's the newspaper
Do you read him the newspaper or does
he read it for you?
My son ...
Ali got married.
Who is Ali?
- Ali.
Yes, Ali is married. Termeh, hurry up
Ma'am, you didn't close the oxygen tight
enough
I did. He must have opened it
- Please close it tighter tomorrow so
that he can't open it
I'm sorry, I ...
... I don't think I can come tomorrow
But you said
- I did say I would, but it's too far,
I can't
- Ma'am, because you accepted I let go of
another candidate
It's 4pm, how will I find someone
for tomorrow? -It's too hard
It's too hard, it's too hard, I really
can't do it, it's too much to handle
Please come to the other room
- Somayeh, where's your bag?
- It's here.
- Maybe you're tired because it is your
first day
No.
You were here, you saw how it was
Somayeh, come get your book bag
Could you give me that number
They also do ultrasounds
He was moving around a lot today
- That means it's a boy
He kept kicking my mom's belly
Because he wants to born sooner
To play with me.
Can you please write it here
Tell him that I sent you
His secretary knows me
Is it a man or a woman?
- A woman
but call beforehand
You should have told me yesterday.
how am I going to leave this old man
home alone tomorrow?
Termeh, where does your mother put
the tea?  - I do not know.
You should have told me that I would
have to clean him
Clean what?
In the morning he soiled himself
It's not right for me to clean him
If you could just pay me for today and
I will go
He always used to ask to go pee
if you call an agency they will send
you a male worker
Ma'am, I can't just trust anyone
Here you go, count it
I'm sorry, it's a religious matter
It's alright.
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Good bye
- May God protect you
Yes?
I wanted to ask if I could give your
phone number to my husband?
and tell him that I got it from the
newspaper
maybe he could come and do this work
for you
Describe to him the nature of the work
and if he wants to then he can ...
I don't want to tell him that I know
you ...
I didn't tell him I was coming here
to work
Tell him to call me... just tell him to
come here tonight
It's too late for tonight
I'll come tomorrow.
just don't get a replacement
and for the money, whatever you think
is appropriate
That won't be a problem, tell him
to call me and we'll make arrangements
Thank you.
- You're welcome, bye.
And thank you.
Mr Lavasani?
Over there, please
Hi, I'm Hodjat...
I called about the job
- How are you?
Sorry I'm late
- It's okay
Where did you say you worked previously?
A shoe store
You're not going to have a problem
with cleaning him?  - What?
With cleaning him, he soiled himself
yesterday
No, that's okay, it's like my own
father
Because you're home together with no one
else there you will have to be vigilant
Your wife won't be there?
No, I'm alone for the time being
For this job isn't $300 a bit low?
How much did you have in mind?
Perhaps $400?
- $400 I definitely can't do
I'll test it out, if you're satisfied
give me a little more
Okay, I'll write down the address
I can even come this afternoon
No, someone is there today, come
tomorrow, and bring an ID.
Like what?
- A picture ID is sufficient.
Door bell?
- Mrs. Raziah - No
Her husband
- Yes.
Next, now in Farsi
That's Arabic, not Farsi
My teacher says it is
Don't ever say that to me again
What's wrong is wrong, no matter who
says or writes otherwise
For "warranty" write...
- If I write anything else she'll deduct points
It's all right, let her deduct points
Write "poshtvaneh"
"Poshtvaneh".
Hello.
- Hello
- Hello.
What happened? Your husband was
supposed to come today.
Sorry, he couldn't make it.
But what about tomorrow?
I don't know, if not then I'll come
Is he going to be reliable to come
every day?
No, the poor guy wanted to come
Yesterday some people he owed money came
with the police and took him away
Well if he has difficulties and can't
come I need to know in advance
He'll definitely come
I am going to go see those men and beg
them to let him go tonight
Please lock the door behind me.
- Okay  - God protect you
Hi.
Don't step on it, it's dirty
Go take the garbage out
Are you able to?
- Yes, I can
Now, where am I supposed to get you a clean
shirt?
Take off your top!
Take it off!
Mommy ...
... he's not in his room.
What?
- He's not in his room.
Go check the toilet
Put your hand here
Stop the ball, okay?
Hit it, hit it!
Hit it!
Somayeh, cutey pie
- Don't use your hands!
- It's okay
Fast, fast!
Good job!
Grandpa, whose side are you on?
- He's the referee
Did you see that, grandpa?
What's the score?
What happened?
- Mommy
Are you all right?
Where have you been?
This poor old man has been waiting for
half an hour
My journey is far
Hello
- Hello
and can you please take the garbage
downstairs
They'll leak onto the stairs
Yesterday I got dizzy and the bag broke
today I'll clean the stairs.
- Okay
Enter, come on.
Move your hands
Let me close the door
Ma'am?
- Is she not there?
What's her daughter's name?
- Somayeh.
Somah... Don't sit there it's wet
Somayeh!
Ms. Khalani!
Knock on the door
Somayeh! Grandpa!
Ms. Khalani!
Yes, hello
Hello, how are you?
- Fine, thank you.
Did you see the woman that works at
our house?  - Yes, cleaning the stairs.
When?
- A little while ago
- Is she not there?
- No, thanks for your help
You wait here, I'll get the house key
from the car
What happened?
Dad?
Father
Grab his feet
Dad
Dad, get up, look at Termeh.
Dad!
Breathe... Don't be scared, he's
breathing
Does your arm hurt? Help..
Move your arms...
does it hurt?
Okay walk, Dad, come on.
Walk Dad, come on we'll go buy the
newspaper, come on
Pick up your feet
Does your leg hurt? Let me
see what happened to your leg
Who did this to you?
I want to see that nothing happened
to your leg
If you permit, I want to see...
Honey, you go out
Did something happen to him?
- No, he's okay, you just go
She's gone, let me take it off...
I want to make sure nothing has
happened to your leg
Take them off
How could she?
Honey, did you take money out of the
drawer?  - No
Go to the kitchen, sweetie, go
Honey, I told you to go to the kitchen
You saw that nothing has happened, go on
Go on, sweetie, and close the door.
Hello.
Come here.
Mom, I'm thirsty
Look over him
Hello
Where were you?
Something came up, and I had to go
take care of it
- You had no right to go
He was sleeping
- So what? That means you just leave?
I was gone a short time
Short time? You're lying.
When I arrived he was dying
Usually during this time he sleeps
So this is what you do every day?
You see he is sleeping and just leave?
No, I swear today I was forced to
Why did you tie his hands?
- Go outside and wait
This was our arrangement?
I had to go, something came up,
I went to take care of it and came back
Thanks very much!
Our arrangement was for you to tie up
this old man and take care of your life?
What happened? Did something happen?
- Thank you so much
Go, sweetie, go over there...
Look after your grandpa
What were you doing in the back room?
Which room?
- What room?
The same room you took money from
Are you saying I went to your room and
took money?
I'm saying... - You say I went to your
room and took money? - You didn't?
I swear to Imam Hussain that I didn't
take your money  - Go on, leave
Sir, I'm swearing on Imam Hussain
- Go on, go...
You're saying... I took money, here's
my purse, look in my purse...
if I took money it would be in my purse,
take a look
Here, take this
Give me my purse, sir.
I'm swearing, here is my purse
- Ma'am, what are you doing?
I'm swearing, I didn't step one foot
beyond that door way
Ma'am, get out
- You're telling me that I... what did I do?
Don't you touch me!
Okay, I won't touch you, you
let yourself out
Get out  - I won't leave until you
admit that I am right
Tell me what I've done wrong
- You deserve to be kicked out
What have I done?  - It's because
she is here that I'm not doing anything
Leave! I'm being merciful by kicking you out
- Tell me how he is doing
This is my home and I'm telling you
to leave  - God is disappointed
Please leave  - God is disappointed
- Please
It's over
Father
Dad, open the door, it's me, I want to
come in
This is you looking after him?
Open the door.
Dad, what's blocking the door?
Take a look
Open the door!
Why are you yelling? He can't understand
When I tell you to watch over him it's
because of this
Maybe his leg hurts so he can't get up
Grandpa, grandpa ...
Father, open the door.
Open the door, please.
Dad, I'm going to push the door and
come in
The door will hit you, move over
Dad, I'm going to push the door and
come in... Move!
Why do you do this to yourself?
Who told you that you could come in?
What happened to him?
- Give me the keys. Get out!
I didn't steal anything from you.
- You're really pissing me off!
I did not steal, if I did I wouldn't
be here  - I don't want excuses, leave!
Get out!
Give me today's pay
You already took the money in the drawer,
didn't you?
From 5:30 in the morning, with my
daughter... Somayeh
Sir, stop!
Out!
- I swear I didn't steal.
What happened?
Sit down.
Mom, be careful
Tell them to help with your math
Goodbye, Grandpa and Dad
Daddy, Termeh said good bye
Be careful.
OK.
What happened?
- Mom says come in
Tell her Grandpa is in the car and I
can't come
She says that it is important
You haven't even divorced and you're
already hard headed
I'm busy
People divorce their wives to be less
busy
Ma'am, the reception is bad
Set it to whatever channel it picks up
Come, sit down.
- Thank you, where is Simin?
Hello.
- Hello.
Where is Termeh?
My dad is in the car and she is with
him  - Bring him in too
No, he's tired, it's time for his nap
What happened?
Did you fight with a woman today?
Did she come to you?
- Her sister-in-law called
Shameless!
What did she do?
She tied an old man to the bed
She locked the door and left to do her
own thing
If I had gotten there 10 minutes later
it would be over
Well, he's alright?
- He had fallen off the bed
and I don't know how long he was there
Where did she go?
- I don't know where she went
She said you hit her
- That I hit her?
Nonsense.
- So why did they take her to the hospital?
Why did they take her to hospital?
- You're asking me?
I just pushed her out of the house
- Well her sister-in-law told me everything
she said
What did she say? - If it dies,
the blood is on your hands
Those kind of things
She didn't say what happened?
- I hung up when she started to curse
That's what happens when you pick random
people off the street to come to your home
Don't blame me, I told you I knew her
sister-in-law but I didn't know her
Did she say what hospital?
Hello.
- Yes?
Please wait.
A woman by the name of Razieh was
brought her tonight
What's her surname?
- We don't know, but they brought in earlier
Why was she brought in?
They just told us...
- She didn't feel well, so they brought her
I'll call you. Goodbye.
I think her husband's last name is
Samadi
Razieh Asnaqi?
- She's about 30 years old, right?
They've done surgery and she is in the
recovery room
What type of surgery?
She had a miscarriage
How is her health?
- Hello? Wait. Yes, she's okay
Does she have any family here?
If she does, they'll be down there
What did you do to her?
What did I do to her?
Hello.
Hello  - Hello
- Are you well?
Thank you
Hello ma'am.
How is she?
- Who?
Your wife.
They took her to recovery
Do you know her?
I know her
Hello
- Hello.
Can we go see her?
How do you know her?
Your sister introduced her to us to
work in our home
Thanks so much for that
She was coming to your home to work?
- For a few days
You weren't able to come so she came
in your place for a few days
Sit down and eat something
Are you saying she was coming to take
care of your dad?
Only a few days...
two or three days.
Why didn't you tell me when I saw you
at the bank the other day?
I thought she already told you
Why did you come to the hospital?
To see if we could help with anything
Like what?
- To help.
We're worried
- She fell?
Please come with me and I'll explain
Please let me explain to you
I understand your situation.
You killed the child, are you here to
bring it back to life?
I'm really sorry. - Being sorry
doesn't bring back her child
Just tell me one thing.
- I said I could come..
why didn't you tell me that day?
It's my wife and child ...
... do you live in that house alone?
Let him go.
- Calm down.
Stop! This is a hospital!
Come on!
Stop!
Do you have a mental illness? Why did
you come here?
Let me see.
You're my sister
- I shouldn't have!
I shouldn't have
- Move your hand, let me see.
Come outside
Come outside, I want to talk to you
Please, I beg you
Do you want me to recline the seat?
- No.
I'll drop you off at home and go get
the others
No.
What do you mean, no?
You want to go to your parent's house
in this shape?
It's done, you're returning home tonight
I don't want to
Where are you going?
Leave it here
Have you heard his complaint?
Do you accept it?
The 13th?
I feel sad...
when I heard I got upset and went to
the hospital
Do you agree you've done this?
Is this the medical report?
Yes, after we took her to the hospital
Four and a half month old male.
You, explain...
I admit that I lost my temper
What do you mean? Did you push her?
No, I didn't push her, I tried to make
her leave my house
Explain properly, the charge is murder
It was a four and a half month old baby,
which makes it a person
I didn't go towards her
I wanted her to leave so I could close
the door
You didn't push me?
- Ma'am, one second
If I had known she was pregnant I
wouldn't have even made her leave the house
I just wanted to close the door.
Do you accept his description, ma'am?
He didn't push me, he grabbed me and
threw me down the stairs
No, I did not throw you
I just wanted her to leave the house
You throw a pregnant woman out of your
home?   - I didn't know she was pregnant
- Why are you lying?
- I found out at the hospital
Dear Judge, answer like a brother...
can't you tell when a woman is pregnant?
A woman, 4 or 5 months pregnant
- I hardly even saw you
When you would arrive I was either at
work or about to leave
and when I'd come back, she looked like
this, she had her chador on
in this garb, how can you tell?
Can you prove that he knew?
It would be against what I believe to
hire a pregnant woman for this job
Judge, I talked about my pregnancy in
front of him, his daughter, and the tutor
they all heard it
- When? I don't remember.
No, of course, you don't remember
- Sir, is this really about whether I knew?
Of course it is, if it is proven that
you knew...
... the court could imprison you from
1 to 3 years
Okay?
- What?
No, I did not know.
- Get the tutor to come in and testify
Can she come tomorrow?
I don't want to get the school
involved, it will be bad for my daughter
You asshole, you killed my son, and
you're saying this is bad for your child?
You think only your child is important?
Don't be insulting
I'm being insulting? What about him?
He hurt my wife and child...
Be quiet, respect the court
Please, he has a bit of a temper
Ma'am, did I force you to...
Temper? I should complain about her ...
... that you've gone to work without
telling me
- I wanted to help with the bills, he
hasn't worked for months
The teacher should come as a witness.
Tell her to come tomorrow.
Dear Judge, I am here today,
I came for one thing.
I've lost my child, but being called
a thief hurt more
- We're thieves?
If we're thieves, would we come and
clean your dad's ass?
- Do you have proof that she stole?
- I did not say stole...
... there was money missing from the
drawer
This is why you fought?
- He accused her of theft
Judge, my father is suffering from
Alzheimer's...
This woman, she tied him to the bed and
left...
I didn't go to work that day, I came
home early...
I saw his hands tied to the bed.
I thought he was dead.
She returned, in the state of mind I
was in...
...I was angry, I told her to leave and
she wouldn't
Where should I have gone? He accused
me of theft
If I left without asking for the money
he owed me he would think I stole it
- Sit down... your father is injured?
Yes, he is hurt
- How is he hurt?
Where is the complaint that he was
injured?
Yes, he is hurt.
Where are you going?
- To take care of my child.
Come back soon...
close the door.
What took so long?
I don't feel good, you go, I'll
come later.
He says you tied up his father and left
the house
What should I say?
What do you mean? If he makes a
complaint you could be in trouble
Where is Somayeh?
- Over there.
You go, I'll bring her
Let's go upstairs
Yes
He was asleep, I locked the door so he
couldn't leave
he himself would lock the door on his
father and leave the key for me
... I saw he did it so...
- They say you tied him to the bed
I was afraid he may wake up, get out of
bed, and hurt himself
... I swear to God... I did it...
- But, you neglected your duties
- You struck her!
- Quiet!
What right did you have to touch my
wife?
Sir, get out.
It's not important to him, but it's
important to me
Don't be aggressive.
- Please leave the room.
- I want to file a complaint against this woman.
- Write it here...
... take your father to the appointed
doctor and get an injury report.
What happened to our complaint?
- Sign this and leave
- You'll need to post bail.
For what?
You've been accused of murder, I can't
just let you leave
... $40 million
How can I afford that bail money?
I live at my father's house, and he
has Alzheimer's.
If you can't then you'll go to jail
My father can't bring it here, he
is ill... Don't write it, please...
... please don't do this, I can't go to
jail.
I've left my dad at home in his
condition... I can't go to jail
I can 't go to jail, and I don't
have the money
It's out of my hands, it's the law
Wait a minute, your honor, what will I
do about my father?
I've left my dad in his condition at
home behind a locked door...
... and now my daughter... Your Honor,
please wait, stop writing...
- You're wasting your time... Please,
go call...
I can't go to jail, I can't go..
.. I'm not going, go on and write..
- Go and fetch a policeman.
For what? Please don't, I beg you,
I beg you...
... please don't do this, my life is
ruined, please stop writing
- Don't waste time, please go call
Hello Termeh, I've run into some problems,
they're going to keep me here tonight...
... don't worry about anything, but
you'll be home alone tonight...
... keep an eye on everything, and take
Grandfather to the bathroom...
... take care of yourself.
I will call tomorrow.
Hello.
If you hadn't left, Dad wouldn't
be in jail right now
Your father's not in jail because
of me.
He struck a pregnant woman.
- It is only because you left...
... that she was here
- And how sad he was that I left
He knew that you would never leave
Did you tell him that?
- No, he knew it.
Tell me the truth, did you tell him?
Get your stuff, let's go to Mom's
What about Grandpa?
- We'll take him.
I have homework... I'm not going.
I'll leave you alone and you'll be
scared...  - OK.
If you call for me to come back then
I will have a problem
He didn't even say "don't go, don't
do it...
... I won't divorce you"...
... as though it was nothing that I
lived with him for 14 years
Father!
What are you doing here?
Why did you come?
Didn't you have an exam today?
- No, tomorrow.
Who are you here with?
Hello.
Why didn't you call and tell us you had
gotten into trouble?
I didn't want to impose
Silly man.
Sit down.
- No, we have to take him to a hearing
Where is your grandfather?
- In safe hands... don't worry
... they keep saying "my baby,
my baby"...
.. as if their 18-year-old son
was stabbed to death.
Did you talk to her?
You can't ever to talk the husband, to
her I said, sweetheart, you are young...
... next year you can have another child
What happened?
I have to get the home valued
- Okay, go.
Hello.
- Hello.
You stay here, I'll be back
- Okay, go
Thank you.
Hello, Mrs. Lavasani.
- Hi, how are you?
I'm fine, you?
- Sorry to trouble you
No, it's no trouble, I'm glad I ran
into you...
... is what they are saying true?
Unfortunately, he pushed her, she fell
and she lost her child
So, what am I supposed to say?
I don't know what they will ask you
What if they ask me something against
your husband?
I think you should tell the truth
Please do not stop there.
- Where was he?
Mr. Lavasani was in the kitchen
Did he say anything or react at all?
- If he did, I didn't notice
- How did you know she was pregnant?
- I think she told me
You asked, ma'am, why would I
have said anything?
Her daughter was drawing a picture
of a man and a woman
"This is my mother and father", she
said.
I said, "honey, your mom isn't that fat"
and she said she had a child in her belly
You didn't know she was pregnant from
her appearance?  - No.
Why do you lie? You are a woman...
.. you can't tell from someone's looks
that they are pregnant?
Okay, even if I could tell, it does
make a difference for Mr. Lavasani
This woman is his daughter's teacher.
They have colluded to tell the same story
- Why are you being rude to her?
- No one is speaking to you
When could we match our stories?
I was here last night.
One thing is clear. Right now as we
speak...
... that man could hear what we were
discussing, am I right?
Ma'am, I didn't hear you... my mind was
preoccupied with my own problems
Why would I listen to your conversation?
... should I swear by Allah?
- As if you believe in God!
No, God is just for guys like you.
Let's take a break for a moment
He is a decent man...
... I've been tutoring his daughter
for one year...
... he's truly not like that.
Why wouldn't she tell me she was
pregnant? Why did she hide it?
If I knew she was pregnant, I wouldn't
hire her
Why did you hire when you knew she
didn't have her husband's permission?
Thank you. You can go, thank you.
Thank you.
"During the age of Sasarian the people
were divided into two classes ...
...the privileged upper class and the
class of the normal people"
"Normal class."
- What did they ask?
If your father knew that she was
pregnant.
I'm sorry the trouble you had to go
through
It's okay, it's no trouble
Honey, what happened to cause your
mom to lose her baby?
Her stomach hurt
Why did her stomach hurt?
Did your dad fight with her at home?
Why would they have fought?
Maybe he was mad that she was working
in someone's home without telling him
Did he hit your mom?
- My parents don't fight at all.
So, why were your mom and dad fighting
in that picture you drew?
You showed me.
- They don't fight anymore.
They don't fight any more? Are you sure?
Yesterday he said he didn't know
that she was pregnant
... now he is saying he didn't even push
her
... and you just stand there staring at
me without saying anything
Honestly, by God, you didn't push me?
Just tell the truth
Didn't I say...
- Listen, Sir ...
... let go of this "I kicked her out of
the house, but didn't push her" line
... how far is it from the door to
the stairs? 2-3 meters?  - Yes
So in this distance, what else could
happen?
From our house to the hallway...
Look, your Honor ...
- I am talking!
You shouldn't be talking, only answering
- Be quiet!  - Did I interrupt you?
You came here to give...  - Okay, fine
- I have questions you need to answer
I have one question I want answered...
... I want to ask him ...
- Ask, ask me
If you've done nothing wrong,
what happened to her?
... why did you come to the hospital?
- As a courtesy
So you pushed her out of kindness?
During the fight was anyone else
there?
Yes, their neighbor were there.
- Okay, I'll subpoena her
Your Honor, the neighbor will collude
just like the teacher
From the beginning he has been...
Am I lying?
- I decide who is and isn't lying
... be quiet.
Sir, his wife, who wants a divorce,
brought him his bail money
My God!
Do you have a guarantor?
- What do you mean?
They will need to be a civil servant
or business owner
I have no one, my husband is unemployed
- Why does she need a guarantor?
She's been charged...
- What is she charged with?
According to his complaint ...
He had no right to make a complaint!
She admitted that she tied him up,
locked the door, and left
I explained that..
- Sir, her baby is dead!
Keep your voice down.
Are you not ashamed?
You call yourself a man?
- I said be quiet.
For God's sake listen to us.
He distorts everything, he hit my wife
and my son died... What more do you want?
... listen to us poor ones also
I told you if you didn't respect this
court I'd put you in jail for 3 days
I lost everything I have.
Do you think I'm afraid of jail?
... Be afraid of God...
Mr. Azadi, call a deputy to arrest
him
Sir, on the Koran, please don't call
Let them take me.
- Okay, leave, don't make any noise
Why should I make noise? I don't talk
and they take away my rights
Get out!
I'm going, Sir
Please, let me take my helmet.
Go out
- He'll go, he'll go himself
For 10 years I worked my ass off at
a shoe repairer
... they kicked me out like a dog, I said
the law will give you what you deserve..
... I made a complaint that lasted a
year, after that they said you lost, go home
This time I won't let that happen
Not this time, this time it's different
I have nothing to lose, my problem is...
... I can't speak like this man
I lose my temper and I can't speak
- Don't! Go outside!
Hodjat?
- I do not feel good.
Go sit down... Let's go.
What do you want with him?
- We need to take to him.
I want to talk to him
Don't go anywhere
On the Koran, your Honor
Let me talk.
Your Honor, his nerves are shot, I swear
to God it's his nerves
We've listened to him for days, but
he won't listen to us
On the Koran, every over day this month
he has been in jail
All his creditors have been after him,
and I've begged them to leave him alone
Sir, look, I beg you, your Honor, please
look
Look at this, please look
Sir, can I ask as a favor that you let
him go this one time?
Sir, I swear to God, I'm not lying
Since he's lost his job he has developed
depression, he can't help it
God is my witness
Your Honor, please forgive him
Go tell him to find you a guarantor,
quickly
God bless.
Do not leave the building.
Okay, I will wait until he returns
Will you ask her?
She'll think I'm asking her back because
she brought me bail
Let her think that
Dad ... please, for God's sake...
OK.
Do you promise?
Well, what is your promise going to be?
Dad ...
Yes?
You didn't know Razieh was pregnant?
No.
Why?
- Nothing.
So, why did you ask?
Last night mom said you knew
How would you mother know whether or
not I knew that?
She said that night at the hospital
when you learned Razieh's baby died...
... you didn't say anything
You didn't ask, "she had a child?",
you weren't surprised
In a case like that wouldn't you ask
if she was pregnant?
... but you knew...
Your mother just wants to say bad things
about me
Will you tell her?
Sweetie, I can't...
Didn't you promise?
I'm sorry.
Which step was it?
- This one
This one?
- This step
Dad, go in for a minute, I'll be
right in
Are you mad at me?
- No.
Did you go upstairs?
Yes, I went to see Mrs. Kalaniyi.
What did you want with her?
I told her they were coming to question
her tomorrow and to be careful
What does she need to be careful of?
Be careful, just to be careful, that
they would question her, that's all
Is there a problem?
As long as she tells the truth why does
she need to be careful?
Termeh ...
- Yes?
Come here
I have my homework
- Leave it, come here one minute
Okay, pretend I'm the woman
Is that right? When someone gets pushed
they go straight
They don't hit here, then here, then turn
around and hit here and fall there
Right?
If I had pushed her...
... she would have either fallen on
these stairs...
... or she would fall straight back and
hit here...
I mean she couldn't fall here...
Pretend you've been pushed, take the
path as if you had
So, how did she fall then?
- I don't know.
I'm just saying she didn't get thrown
onto these stairs
Okay, now you come and stand here
Why don't you tell them all this?
- Forget them
I want you to know. Go on...
Is this the direction he pushed you?
- No, he pushed me downwards
Look, this door doesn't permit that...
it's not even possible
You can't
- Where did you fall?
On these stairs
- Which step?  - Excuse me
I think this one
You think, or you are sure?
I'm not sure.
Ma'am, is this where you found her?
I didn't see her get pushed, but when I
arrived she was at the bottom stair
Why aren't you saying anything? Go show
them how he pushed you
I was ill, I swear to God, I didn't know
what was going on
Look, I'll stand in the place of your
wife at the doorway
... now, please stand here and with all
your strength...
... push me, I'm saying it's not
even possible
Of course you won't fall, but she's
a pregnant woman, if just one hand...
Then you come, come here and elect
whoever you want to push you
I'm saying it's not possible, excuse
me...
I'm saying if you push from here she
won't fall that way
What step? She says she fell on the
top step
Everyone here says they found her on
that step
Ma'am, did you see where she was pushed
from upstairs?
Yes, I can't see the door from up here,
but I can see the stairwell where she fell
Can you show me from where you saw it?
Perhaps she was dizzy and fell.
How many times did you go up and down
these stairs? And she was never dizzy
Excuse me, that morning when I saw you
at the top of the stairs
I asked her why the garbage had spilled
on the stairs...
she said she had gotten dizzy and
dropped the bag, isn't that right?
My daughter took it out
- But, you said that you were dizzy
Ms. Kalani, weren't the stairs cleaned
that day?
Maybe the stairs were wet and she
slipped and fell
You asshole! You pushed her!
Be respectful!
I'm not talking back because your
family is here
Eat shit, asshole!
- Don't swear! Take him out
Go on
- Don't curse
They may need him tomorrow, they won't
say anything against him
If you're saying they are lying then
make a complaint
Are you telling the truth?
Fuck me, I spent the whole morning here,
and one says she fell here and the other
says she fell there
Excuse me, please give my daughter her
backpack
There you go.
Here you go, you don't want your
drawings?
Honey, don't let this fight with your
parents upset you
Come here, let me put it in your bag
My mother did not take your money.
- I know.
That's not the reason I was fighting
with her
Well then what for?
I was upset because she abandoned my
father and left
Well, she had gone to the doctor
Go ahead.
Be careful of the stairs
As per the order, we will examine him
and write down whatever we see
Doctor, well you see, he doesn't
speak
- Didn't you say he has Alzheimer's?
Yes, he has it, but before this he
spoke, he'd say things
- This is a doctor's office, not a court,
prove it there
- He got a bruise?
- Yes, a little one
- What happened?
I'm not sure if his bruising is a result
of falling out of the bed
Don't run, slow down
Put down the window, Mom, there
is a fight
- You see this is a girl's school
Hello
- You are not allowed to stand here
I have something to say
If you have a problem, talk to the
police
I just want to talk to this woman
I have nothing to say, I don't know
you or that woman's husband
- So, why did you lie in court?
- What lies?
- She knows the lie she told.
- Ms. Safaei, call the police.
- You have a problem with someone else,
what does this woman have to do with it?
If she has nothing to do with it why
was she talking to my daughter?
What do I have to do with your
daughter?
You are a teacher of this country,
are you not ashamed?
Why did you tell her that her dad hit
her mom and she had a miscarriage?
When did I say that?
Aren't you ashamed of looking at the
picture by a 4 year old and telling ...
... her that her dad hit her mom and
caused the miscarriage?
That's not what I said
Why are you saying that I hit my wife
and kids like some kind of animal?
I swear on this Koran that I am a human
just like you
- Get up, please
Ma'am, I have nothing in my life to lose
Tell your husband not to do anything
that will make me lose my mind
Ma'am, I will
- Go on, sir
Come on, just go
I'm unemployed, I will stand at the door
to this school day and night
Either go to court and tell them you
lied or I will dig deep to uncover your
relationship with her husband
Shame on you, sir, I've kept my mouth
shut and you...
- So, why are you protecting him?
- The court asked questions and I told
the truth.
- You told the truth?
- Yes!
Put your hand on this Koran and
swear to it.
Why do you need an oath? Who do you
think you are?
I'm not afraid, what do you
want me to say?
You told the court her husband didn't
know my wife was pregnant
- Yes.
- Swear to that
I swear on the Koran that on the day I
was at their house...
... her husband did not hear our
conversation because he was in the kitchen
Is this good, or do you want me to say
something else?
He's insane
- Where are you going? Call your
husband, don't go alone
No, I don't want him to know.
Why are you standing there?
Hello?
Hello, Mrs. Qahraei.
I left you a message.
Could you please pick up the phone?
The woman who was coming to our house
for my father...
... she got the number of a gynecologist
from you?
I wanted to ask you to please give
me that number
... so I can call him to see if she went
to his office that week ...
... and if she did what the problem was.
I would appreciate it if you could call
me back.
What do you want to do?
What?
You want this fight to continue every
day?
Why? What happened?
Today he went to school and embarrassed
our child in front of everyone
What did he say?
He yelled in front of everyone that my
father killed his child
- How can she go to school any more?
Do you realize what you are doing?
What I am doing?
He is causing problems.
- He has no right.
Termeh, go to your room.
If tomorrow he goes to school and kills
you daughter, then what?
What do you want me to do?
Pack up and move abroad?
Forget abroad, I'm here trying to talk
to you about...
... Termeh and this situation you have
created for her.
I created this situation? You have some
nerve to say that to me.
Who left their spouse and child?
Who asked for a divorce?
You are the one that said to go
- Yeah, then why are you back?
I'm not back, I'm here to sort out
my daughter's situation.
It's sorted
You have two options ...
- Do not threaten me.
What threat?
You need to solve your problem with this
guy...
No, I know how to deal with him
- Didn't you hit her?
Didn't you throw her down the stairs?
Didn't her child die?
Yes! I killed her child!
Why are you being so stubborn? Put an
end to all of this
I am not paying money by force.
- How is it forced?
Put yourself in their place.
I'm not responsible for their troubles
- Their child is dead
Yeah, and my dad is handicapped, come
and see. He doesn't speak a word to me
It's not like he talked a lot before
this
He spoke few words, but those few words
made me happy
This doesn't compare to her situation
And how do you know that I hit her?
So how did the child die?
- I don't know
I don't know. For one moment consider...
... that when she left, her husband did
something to her and she blamed me.
Her daughter said they went to the
doctor that day
What was so wrong that she couldn't
wait 2 hours and go in the afternoon?
Why did she tie this old man to the bed
and leave?
The doctor said the child's death was
the result of a blow
A blow? Why does it have to be a blow
from me?
Not until it is proven to be, will I
let it go
Okay, I'll take Termeh
Shame on you. All this is going on
and you're using it to pressure me
I'm worried for Termeh
Termeh wants to live here and she needs
to learn at school
Learn what? How to fight and
antagonize?
No, learn how not to be a coward
like you.
So that any time someone yells at her
she'll back down
And he knows who to antagonize and not
to antagonize
Yes, I am coward.
You know what your problem is? Any time
you're faced with any difficulty...
... rather than deal with it, you run
away or raise your hands and surrender
Give me one reason you want to leave
this country.
You're afraid to stay.
Sorry, I wasn't here for a week and you
couldn't run the household
I couldn't, and I'm responsible.
Let me take Termeh, and you do whatever
you want to do
Termeh, honey, don't make any decision
on my account
Go wherever you are comfortable.
You still don't want to come?
It's sold for $20,000 rial
If every you use 270kg of flour...
... what is the profit each day?
How would you solve this?
Did you lie?
What?
Are you lying?
About what?
That you didn't know the woman was
pregnant?
Why?
You said when Ms. Qahraei and Razieh
were talking you didn't hear anything
Yes.
So when did you hear Ms. Qahraei gave
Razieh the gynecologist's number?
Wasn't she told it during the same
conversation?
Okay
So, if you want to calculate...
Yes, I knew.
Your mother is telling the truth.
When she was talking to you teacher in
the hall I heard it all from the kitchen
So why did you say you did not know?
Do you know what would have happened if
I said that I knew?
1 to 3 years in prison.
And I thought of what would happen
to you...
... who would you stay with?
I said I did not know.
If you knew, why did you push her?
I knew she was pregnant but at that
moment I didn't know
I had forgotten. I wasn't paying
attention.
So, tell them that.
The law doesn't get it
They'll say either you knew or you
didn't
Look at me.
If you want me to, I'll tell them
Hello.
- Hello.
Didn't I say not to come to the front
of the school?
Ms. Qahraei!
What do you want with her?
Ms. Qahraei, wait ...
If you can wait one second, I want to
explain something, that's all.
Please allow me... see... why...
Father!
Who is responsible for the safety of my
child?
I can't take action if there is no
witness
If I have no witness I just wait until
he kills my child?
- How do I know you're telling the truth?
- What reason do I have to lie?
Your Honor, I bring my wife and daughter
here to lie to you?
Your daughter is here now?
- Yes, outside, call her in, ask her.
I am afraid to take her to school.
I'm afraid to leave my father at home.
Is the plaintiff here?  - I can't leave
my dad at home.  - Are you done writing?
Almost done
You didn't know his wife was pregnant?
No, I didn't know.
When she was talking to the teacher
about the pregnancy you didn't overhear?
No, I did not hear
You didn't hear, huh?
I'm saying I didn't hear them...
The teacher came and withdrew her
statement.
- She says you knew
- She came and said that I knew?
- Yes, she came in yesterday
He went to the school and threatened her
No, answer my question, did you hear
them talking?
No I didn't.  - How did you know she
gave her the doctor's number?
My daughter told me
- What did she say?
That she got the number from the teacher
Tell your daughter to come in
Now?
You wait outside
What question?
What does he want to ask?
I do not know. Here, give it to me.
- What is your statement?
You haven't asked anything.
Did your father tell you what I would
ask while outside?
No.
- Which grade are you?
Sixth
On the day your teacher was at your
house and was talking to the care giver...
... about being pregnant, were you there?
At that time? No, I had gone to get my
books.
So, how did you know your teacher gave
the number to that woman?
She gave her the number after, when the
care giver was leaving
In front of you?
- Yes.
Why didn't you tell your father earlier?
What?
That the woman got the doctor's number
from your teacher
I didn't think it would be important to
my dad.
So did you tell your dad, or did he hear
it himself?
About the doctor's number? I told him.
You told him?
- Yes.
Okay, go
What crime have I committed?
- Nothing. You're right.
Your husband does not accept
responsibility.
I accept he is responsible, but to what
end?
To spend one year, two years in court...
... so that you get 100,000 toman a
month?
This is what saddens me, why do you
think I'm going to court for money?
When did I say that?
You think I'm a bum and my child has
died...
... and we don't understand anything.
- No, I didn't say that
- Wait, let's see what she has to say
This is not the way to go... All of this
won't bring back your child...
... and my husband won't be killed
Her husband didn't' do it intentionally.
- They are good people, they are trying
to find a solution
Take the money and put it to good use
Let's come to an agreement right now.
Leave convincing my husband to me.
He needs convincing? Leave us alone...
They're trying to make peace...
... take a look at yourself.
- Sir, please don't let him go
Wait a minute, I want to talk to you.
Hello.
- Hello.
Will you stay?
Mom...
Let us have our talk
Come, sit down, I want to talk to you.
I'm listening
Today I went to talk with her husband.
Sit down.
I talked to him and after negotiating, I
got him to agree to $15 million rather
than $40 million
Three checks of $5 million
How dare you promise him the money?
I can't constantly stress about my child's
safety.  - You don't understand what I'm
saying
Even now because you were late I was
dying of worry
I'm saying why are you butting in?
I didn't come here to fight
God, why can't she understand?
Aren't you saying I'm at fault? Aren't
you saying that I introduced you to her?
Aren't you saying none of this would
happen if I had not left?
So let me fix it
But if I tell him I'll pay, I'm
admitting responsibility
He agreed to it.
- He's not going to leave us alone.
You think he'll leave us alone if you
don't pay? - Why should I pay him?
Pretend it's my dowry.
If I need to beg for it, or borrow it,
you'll get your dowry back
But as for the money for him, I neither
have it, nor will I give it
Our child is in puberty, she's already
suffering because of that
So you understand the sensitivity of our
daughter during puberty?
If she was suffering she wouldn't stay
Why do you think she is staying
with you?
She chose you?
She stayed with you so we don't divorce
She knows I won't go anywhere without
her.
She is suffering, but she is hiding it.
You'll call him now and tell him your
husband won't pay until fault is proven.
I'll sell my car.
I don't want you to sell your car for me
- It's not for you
If your child is not valuable enough...
What bullshit are you talking? This
isn't about money.
Until the safety of my child is secured,
I can't let this go.
You no longer have a right to do
anything
Do you understand?
If I had done nothing, you'd be in jail
right now.
Make an appointment with the court and
request the bail money back.
I don't want to be out of prison because
of your bail money
Get up, Termeh.
Get up, let's go.
Get up, I tell you.
Mother, please.
I don't want to stay here any more.
- No, Mom, I won't let you.
$15 million is worth more to you, you
put your child in the middle of this
I will not let you do it.
When you don't value your child
enough to...
Mom, what are you doing?
- When you see your child's life...
You said you would stay.
I was stupid to say that.
- Mom, please!
- For the love of God, please
- I'm waiting for you in the car.
It's okay, go for a few days until the
end of exams.
Your grandma and grandpa are there too
You'll be more comfortable
- Didn't you say it wasn't serious?
It became serious
Termeh ...
Honey ...
If you cry, honey, I'll cry.
Why won't you pay him the money so that
Mom will come back?
Mom coming back has nothing to do with
this money, honey.
Yes, she was going to stay, I saw the
luggage in the car.
If you think I'm guilty, go get your
mom and tell her to come in
We'll call them and arrange to go and
give them the money
I have doubts.
Didn't he throw you?
Yes.
When you went home, did something
happen?
No, even before my child was not moving.
Before he threw you?
You mean the child died before?
I do not know. Maybe.
- Had something happened before?
I'm not sure, but I had pain the
previous night.
Have you ever had a miscarriage before?
- No.
I was hit by a car.
Your father-in-law went into the street.
I put on my chador and went after him.
He was trying to cross the street and I
ran to get him...
... so a car wouldn't hit him, but a
car hit me.
That night the pain began.
Does your husband know about this?
Why didn't you say this in court?
My husband would kill himself if he
found out I came here and told you this.
He's been crying since he pledged the
money to his creditors yesterday
What fault does my husband have? Do you
know how much this damaged our lives?
That's my fault.
Yesterday when he told me that you
promised him the money...
... I got very scared and I called a few
places and asked...
They said if you have any doubts it is a
sin to accept the money.
If we don't pay this money then we will
have to prove my husband is innocent.
You promised not to repeat what I just
told you
But your husband will not leave us
alone...
I fear for my child.
I'm afraid if sinful money comes into my
house that something will happen to her
What do you want from me?
Don't pay the money.
Don't pay.
Will your husband leave us alone,
though?
Give that to me, bring some small
plates.
Don't worry, nothing will happen.
When you withdraw your complaint from
the court we will give you the 3 checks.
God bless.
Get a pen and paper, let's write all of
this down and sign it
I have one thing to say before...
Let's just finish this
I just want his wife and my daughter to
come in, I have something to say...
Why won't she come?
Thank you.
Please, call my daughter also.
Termeh, your father is calling for you.
Hello
Termeh, come and sit here.
Excuse me
Look ...
I wrote checks and will give them to
you, no issues.
It's done
I have one favor to ask, if I may.
Ma'am, you're a religious woman
Bring a Koran and swear that I caused
your miscarriage.
Bring a Koran
Can you go grab it?
Come back soon, or they will start to
doubt...
Creditors are here for the money.
Don't ruin his reputation.
I will not swear
Didn't you say you went after his father
and were hit by a car?
Why won't you come?
- I'm afraid to swear to it.
Why?
- I have doubts
God ...
Azam, go and sit down with them.
Why are you telling me this now?
I swear I told Azam
Tell me exactly what happened
The day before the miscarriage I was
hit by a car...
... and that night I had a lot of pain.
- Let's go, it's already settled.
- No.
It is a sin. I asked.
He's agreed to pay it, let's go.
I'm scared, God will curse us.
What have you done? Look at me...
... think of my situation, show some
mercy
I'm afraid something will happen to our
child if we go through with this.
- Let's go.
- I can't.
I can't, oh God, I can't
Don't hit me, don't hit me
Ma'am, why did you come here tonight?
Didn't I tell you not to?
Didn't I say the money is sinful and we
didn't want it?
How am I supposed to live here now?
Why have you done this to me?
Come on.
Come on, let's go.
Hello.
- Hello. Come in..
Yes, so what is the decision?
Okay, your mom and dad have left it up
to you to decide where to live after
the divorce
Do you want to be with your dad or your
mom?
- Have you made your decision?
- Yes.
- Are you sure?
- Have you made up your mind, or not?
- Yes.
- So what is it, my dear?
Do I have to say it now?
- If you still haven't...
- No, I have thought about it...
- If you haven't decided
- No, I have
And?
Do you want them to wait outside if
it's too hard?
Is that okay?
Sir, wait outside for a minute.
You too, ma'am.