Auntie, you're wearing lipstick!
Nosey kid!
Scram!
Papa, Aunt Jewel has no clothes on!
What?
Where's Mama?
Hiding.
Why are you dressed like that?
I'm going out with Mama.
No way.
Just change it.
-Just this once.
-Just do it.
Where's Mama?
I haven't seen her.
-Join us.
-No, thanks.
Mama's attending a hearing today.
We'll never see the end
of that hearing.
Will you buy groceries today?
DO NOT ENTER
Alan?
It's already the afternoon.
Go buy Clorox.
No wonder it smells here.
Have you seen Mama?
Mama.
What are you doing here?
The lawyer's here.
If your Papa gets acquitted,
I'll damn your brother to hell.
Mama.
I'm the aggrieved party here,
and yet he testified in favor
of his bastard father.
And you...
You also want him acquitted,
don't you?
Mama, leave the decision
to the court.
The attorney is waiting.
He cheated on me,
and you're siding with him.
I'm not siding with anyone.
He's my father,
so I don't want him to go to jail.
Even though he left us
for his mistress,
you still don't want him
to go to jail?
Nayda, your father
is not exempt from the law.
I've talked with Judge Animas.
He is not going to acquit him.
He's fair.
He's not corrupt.
You'll be disappointed if your father
goes to jail, won't you?
-Give me some more rice.
-More rice, sure.
Attorney, do you think
Mama Flor's going to win?
I haven't lost a single court case.
If Papa Edwin lost the case,
how many years would he face?
Possibly 2 years and a half in prison.
Is that a wig?
Attorney?
You haven't had breakfast yet?
Hi. How are you?
Mama, why don't you eat?
I don't want to eat.
-Don't lose your eyeglasses.
-I won't, Mama.
I'm already full.
It's bad to leave leftovers
on your plate.
Let's go!
Nayda, El Lobo might call
about depositing the check.
Don't let the check bounce.
Do we have enough cash?
Call up the lender.
Come, Grandson,
give Grandma a kiss.
Grandma, is Grandpa going to jail?
We'll see.
Let's go.
Jewel, come on!
Are you ready?
Mama, the attorney didn't pay
for his food again.
That freeloading attorney!
To think that he charges Mama
too much for every hearing,
and he doesn't pay for his food.
What did he have?
2 sausages, 1 coffee, and 1 egg.
-Finish your milk.
-I don't want it anymore.
Finish it!
Did you know that if your father
loses the case,
he'll get 2 years in jail?
Get going.
The boy is late for school.
Come on! Let's go!
Lando!
-Here.
-Give me a kiss, Mama.
Here, put this on.
Miss Nayda.
Where's Alan?
I sent him on an errand.
Can I have a Coke?
Merly, aren't you supposed
to be at work?
I've quit.
Why?
Jobs are scarce these days.
I can always go back
to the restaurant any time.
Hello.
Here.
What are you doing here?
Why didn't you see me last night?
I was working all night.
Have you told Auntie Flor?
Not yet.
When are you going to tell her?
I'm waiting for the right time.
When is the right time?
Leave it to me.
Son of a bitch!
Hello! Good morning!
Yes, sir.
What check?
El Lobo.
Go ahead and approve it.
I will deposit before clearing.
Yes, thank you.
Thank you.
I just washed it last night
and now you're wearing it?
Don't you have 2 of those?
The other one is a different color.
-Give it to me!
-Stop it!
Stop arguing!
You asshole! It's mine!
Mr. Singh?
This is Nayda.
Can I borrow 10,000 pesos, please?
The check is going to clear soon.
Yes.
-Miss Nayda!
-Yes, sir. Thank you.
Miss Nayda,
Alan and Ronald are fighting!
Hey, stop that!
What are you fighting about?
Stop that!
Stop it!
Fuck you!
Fuck you, too!
That's my shirt!
Fuck you!
You're an asshole!
You're an asshole, too!
You've got plenty of clothes!
Why are you siding with him?
I'm not siding with anyone!
That's enough!
Why aren't you cleaning up?
It's not even dirty.
Go clean up!
Get him!
He's a thief!
Merly! Merly!
Merly!
Fuck you!
Get back here!
You lazy asshole!
Hey, come here!
Stop him!
Stop! Stop him!
Get him!
He's coming up!
Stop!
You lazy asshole!
Give that back to me!
Stop!
Fuck you!
-Stop him!
-Get him!
Hurry up!
Ronald! Alan!
Did you get him?
Hey! Hey!
Fucking thief!
Get away from me!
Stop, or I'll shoot!
Get him up.
Fuck you!
Get him!
What, you're gonna fight?
We're gonna beat you up.
Ouch!
It hurts.
Slowly.
My boil, it hurts.
Let's switch positions.
Move here.
It feels good.
Wait, I think my boil burst.
Looks like it's bleeding.
Stop, don't touch it.
Are you okay?
Are you tired?
Service?
How much?
300.
Too expensive.
I don't have that much money.
How about 200?
Do you do anal?
How about a blowjob?
I want a full service.
Service?
Sir, it's really cheap.
Blowjob?
Follow me to the hotel.
Yes, sir.
I'll text you the room number.
I'll tell the receptionist
I've got company.
Okay, sir.
Don't stand me up.
Wait.
I've got an emergency message.
I'm sorry, my grandma
just had an asthma attack.
-Next time.
-Okay.
Hey, who texted?
The Captain, he wants to see me.
Really? Ask him if he wants an orgy.
You're crazy!
He's conservative.
Walk nicely.
You are so gay!
There you go!
Here's Peter.
There, they are waiting for you.
Did you miss me?
Of course!
-How's it going?
-I'm okay.
Leaving already?
Yes, Ma'am.
So now you're crying?
What should I do?
Go home.
Why don't you want to tell
Mama Flor?
Alan.
By the way, fix the bathroom.
It's backed up.
Okay.
Ronald, you are such a slob.
How many times
do I have to tell you
not to mix your dirty clothes
with ours?
I'm getting fed up.
I'm sorry.
I heard that you fought with Alan.
Well, he took my shirt.
You're both Zenaida's relatives,
you shouldn't fight.
-You should be ashamed.
-I am.
I don't know about Alan.
Next time you should settle
your fights over drinks.
Later on tonight, let's celebrate
when Mama Flor wins.
Sure.
So what's your drama, bitch?
Let's go.
Go. I've got work to do.
Use the ladies' room.
It stinks!
Miss Nayda.
Did you and Alan fight again?
I'm pregnant.
Just as I thought.
-Hey, your change.
-2 sticks of cigarettes, please.
-2?
-Yes.
Have you told Alan?
Yes, I did. A week ago.
It's almost 3:00.
Get Lando to pick up Jonas.
What did he say?
He said he'd talk to Mama Flor,
but he hasn't talked to her yet.
Mama is attending a hearing.
Miss Nayda, please talk to Alan.
No, you two should tell Mama.
BEDMATES
FROLIC IN THE WATER
This movie theater is still open?
Let's look at what's showing.
Maybe something lewd!
Let's go!
Lewd, of course.
"Frolic in the Water."
That's crazy!
Let's go in, quick!
And what do you expect
to watch here? Disney movies?
Stupid fags.
Mother, double-time!
Our fairy godmother, quick!
You faggots! As if you're
going to run out of dicks!
Come on, faster.
Your dick is always slow.
Always expect the gays here
when they're not at the beauty parlor.
5, 5, 5, fast!
Mama, the moolah, quick!
Here, it's what you're good at.
The tickets, quick.
I expected you last week.
Well, you know,
we've been so busy.
It's up there.
Sister, the boys kept me fully booked.
Just drop the tickets in the box.
You were gone for a long time.
A boy kept asking for you.
-A boychick?
-Yes.
I've passed him on to Ed.
Miss Nayda, I'll tend the ticket box.
Okay, enjoy!
Are you the owner, Ma'am?
May I help you?
We'd like to ask a favor from you.
Can we go in?
Is there a problem?
A favor, please.
Can we go in?
We have no money for tickets.
We don't grant free entries here.
We're not going to watch the movie.
I'll just look for my son.
How old is your son?
16.
Minors are not allowed entry here.
I heard he tags along
with the homosexuals to gain entry.
That's their business, not yours.
I'm certain your son isn't here.
We don't admit minors here.
You're bothering us.
There's a customer waiting.
Okay?
How many?
Queenie, you're early today!
Bitch!
Babe, we've run out
of watermelon seeds.
Okay, I'll buy some later.
The corn nuts.
Buy the corn nuts from Mrs. Sally.
Most vendors get their supply
from her.
Why do you want corn nuts?
I crave it.
Maybe I'm the one who is pregnant.
Knock it off.
I'm just being sweet.
Papa, I did good in math.
10 x 1 = 10.
10 x 2 = 20.
10 x 3 = 30.
Repeat that to your Mom.
Did you eat your snack?
Yes, I finished it.
So what did you buy
with your money?
I bought bubble gum.
-Did you get the change?
-Yes, 2 pesos.
Uncle, Jerome texted.
Papa's acquitted.
Cousin Flor lost the case?
How fortunate for Papa.
How unfortunate for Auntie.
Lando, Papa's acquitted.
Mama, my teacher gave me this.
I got the math right.
-Really?
-Yes, Mom.
Show me how you did it.
10 x 1 = 10.
10 x 2 = 20.
10 x 3 = 30.
Very good.
Take your bath.
Jonas!
Scrub yourself well.
Why must I always take a bath?
Because you always stink.
Go now.
Are you studying, too?
No, sir.
Fool!
When I die...
...I want to be cremated.
And throw the ashes...
Wait, give me 150 pesos first.
Just wait, I'm not done yet.
Later.
Leave before somebody sees us.
Shit, you didn't even come.
You left me hanging.
Jonas, take your bath.
Later, Mama.
Do as I say! You stink!
Do as I say!
It didn't fit my mouth.
He shot a big load.
I almost choked.
It's good you didn't choke.
Was the fag here?
What fag?
Jonas saw the 2 of you.
That one?
It was nothing.
You call that nothing?
This is not a whorehouse.
It's nothing.
It's just for fun.
It's bad for the business.
Nayda, there you are!
What are you doing here?
Uncle, why did you marry a girl?
I want to be a father.
Besides, Susan loves me.
For a change,
I'm the one being loved.
You're laughing at me?
I'm laughing at myself.
I'm a nursing graduate,
what the hell am I doing here?
Why are you looking for me?
Cousin Flor is back!
Why didn't you say so?
Oh, my gosh!
Mama!
Where is she?
In the kitchen
talking to Alan and Merly.
If I didn't get pregnant,
I wouldn't have gotten married.
Mama!
Alan!
Speak up!
You jerk!
You got a woman pregnant
without thinking.
Can you afford to feed
another mouth?
Your wages can't even support
your vices!
Idiot!
You shameless fool!
What an ingrate you are!
I took you in, gave you shelter
and a job so you can have
a decent live.
Can't you wait for the proper time?
Here's another problem.
I'm neck-deep in troubles
and here you bring another.
Look at me! Look at me!
What? Are you passing
this responsibility on to me?
The movie house
is going bankrupt!
Our 2 movie houses
have closed down.
This one is all we've got now.
And you're having a kid?
Where the hell will I get the money
to feed all of you?
Tell me where...
I'll get a job after I give birth.
You're another one.
How could you let this idiot
impregnate you?
You think he's got money
because he's my relative?
All of them are dirt poor!
As poor as rats!
Mama, please don't shout.
Don't touch me!
You, do your parents know
your condition?
Not yet.
Then tell them.
Come back on Sunday, and
we'll talk about the wedding.
Thank you very much.
Yeah, right.
All right.
You can go home now.
SEEDLING
YOUNG SCREW PINE
Mama, I'll do that later.
Many of them are already dry.
Has the El Lobo check
been deposited?
Yes. There was a long line
at the bank.
Wish life were this simple.
This one's wet.
This one's dry.
This one, half-wet, half-dry.
Mama, your shoes got wet!
Oh, my!
They're still new.
It's only now
that I'm wearing them again.
Mama.
That fucking judge!
He acquitted your father.
Okay, watch me.
Swing your hips like this.
There you go.
Hey, fag.
Your boobs.
You prick, I'm gonna suck you dry.
Chest out. Like that.
-1, 2...
-Hey, stop teaching her that--
Hey, stop meddling.
Don't mind them.
Just follow me.
Come on!
Come on, fag, just follow me!
See, it's really easy!
Chin up! Chest out!
Sway your hips some more!
Oh, boy, what a dumb girl you are!
Come on, move your fucking ass!
Mama, wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
1, 2... Like this.
Do it one more time!
You're almost there!
That's it! Keep going!
See?
One more time.
Fucking faggot!
What the fuck?
Fuck off!
Assholes!
Let's go.
Tell Alan to paint this.
It's too dirty.
COCKSUCKER
Hey, Miss Nayda, let me do that!
No, I'll do it myself.
-I just wanna help.
-Thanks, I can manage.
-Sure, you're okay?
-I am.
If I were you, I'd settle for
a live-in arrangement with Merly.
Marriage is just a piece of paper.
It doesn't guarantee
that you'll stay together forever.
Look at Auntie Flor.
Her marriage broke up anyway.
See you next week.
It's only 110 pesos.
110 pesos, my ass.
It's withered.
This one?
80 pesos.
It's already withered.
No, it's not.
Are you giving it to someone?
I'm gonna give it to him, stupid.
Jonas.
I've taken my bath, Mom.
Where did that flower come from?
Uncle Ronald said you bought it.
Sure, I forgot all about it.
Mama, you smell sour already.
How much for everything?
This one and this one.
How many did you order?
3, right?
1, 2, 3.
80 pesos.
Your change.
Just a second.
Look after the stove.
Tonette, mind the canteen.
I gave the kid too much change.
Hey, kid! Just a moment!
The change I gave you,
I gave you 50. It should be 20.
No, sir, 20.
No, I gave you 50 by mistake.
Let me take a look.
Is this the one I gave you?
The other pocket.
Something must be wrong
with your eyes.
20?
Are you sure it was 20?
It could be here.
Nothing.
20... That was a 20.
What happened?
No... 50, but he was holding a 20.
How much exactly
did you hand him?
I don't know.
Let me check the cash box.
How much cash is there?
How much have we sold?
Give me one.
I won't stay long, Papa.
We'll wait for you at the restaurant.
Boy! Boy!
Looks like she's due soon.
Dressed to kill!
When are you going to be a mom --
I mean, a dad?
November.
Will you be the Godfather?
Too many sponsors already!
-Brother, where's Mama?
-Upstairs.
How's Mama?
Not good.
I'm with Papa and Carol.
They're at the restaurant.
-Where's Jonas?
-Upstairs.
Visit us on Christmas.
Stay with us.
-We'll see.
-Even if it's just for a little while!
We're very busy here.
Jewel, why the long face?
Heard you're going to college
next year.
Yes, Brother.
Okay.
BEDMATES
Sir, it's good to see you.
How much?
It's up to you.
Where do we go?
Let's just stay here.
Mama.
It's you.
I'm sorry.
I still need to take a bath.
I'll wait, then.
What do you want from me?
I need to explain.
Go on. Make it fast.
Mama, it wasn't my sole decision
to testify in favor of Papa.
I consulted with Nayda
and Danny before he died.
Just as I thought.
You all conspired against me.
Mama, please listen to me.
If the court proved that Papa
was keeping another family,
the law would recognize
his children with Carol.
If the court proved
that your father has another family,
then I could file a legal separation.
That's what I wanted.
If the court failed to prove that,
the law would not recognize
his other children.
Nayda, Jewel, and I,
we are his legal heirs.
His children with Carol
do not inherit anything.
You are after the money.
I'm not after the money, Jerome.
I want to prove
that your father cheated on me!
Because that's the truth!
I'm going to appeal the case.
Mama, aren't you tired?
You've spent a fortune
on the lawyer's fees.
I'll hire another lawyer.
Papa has been acquitted.
He was acquitted because
he and the judge lack morals.
NO LOITERING HERE!!!
No! Don't!
Please don't!
Have mercy on me!
You're mine!
No! Please don't!
Hey, she's mine!
I love you so much.
I love you, too.
Miguel, why did you do this to me?
That was fast.
Why are you looking at me
like that?
You bastard!
There's a goat!
Mr. Lando, there's a goat
inside the movie house!
There's a goat!
Come on, hurry up!
Let's catch it!
Over here, Mr. Lando!
There it is! Hurry up!
Chase it! Over there!
Right here, right here!
What happened?
There was a goat--
Go back inside.
Go, go, go!
-Have you had dinner?
-Not yet.
Go, have your dinner.
Mama, a goat
got inside the movie house.
A goat? What goat?
There's a hole in the wall.
What happened to the goat?
It's gone. Lando and the boys
chased it out.
There's a lot to fix
in this movie house.
Gotcha!
You can't catch me!
Brother, give me that!
That's mine! Give it to me!
Ouch! I can't see!
Sister Nayda,
Jonas is wearing lipstick.
Give that to me!
Wanna play?
Okay, here it is.
What is your name?
Ryan.
How old are you, Ryan?
17.
Can I have a cigarette?
Do you have any siblings?
-I have one.
-What's his name?
Jason.
What does Jason do?
He works in the market.
How much does he earn?
Depends on the sales.
Sometimes 70 or 80.
Only 70 pesos a day?
Who's better looking
between you two?
He is.
Who's got a bigger dick?
He does.
Then why isn't he in the sex trade?
He's not into it.
And you?
Do you have a small dick?