Previously on SEAL Team...
Nate was hiding a burner
phone from his wife.
The address we found in Nate's truck,
You already went, didn't you?
I mean, it's not like Nate
was the first teammate we had
to get some on the side.
This only proves that
he wasn't the exception.
What the hell were you doing, Nate?
I just need to worry about the mission,
guys to my left, guys to my right.
Do that, there's not a SEAL alive
who wouldn't want to roll with you.
JUMP MASTER: Second stick going up.
FINN (OVER RADIO):
Bandit 1, five canopies,
looking for a sixth.
Negative contact.
PILOT (OVER RADIO): Jumper in distress.
Falling to 3,000 feet.
Jumper appeared to
impact ground at speed.
(GOATS BLEATING, GOATHERD TRILLING)
(HORN HONKS)
(TRILLING)
_
S01E06
The Spinning Wheel
sync and corrected by ninh
www.addic7ed.com
ADAM: It's not often we have
to have this conversation.
Thank God. Not like this, anyway.
We'll be holding a service
soon as we're done notifying
Brian's next of kin.
Even though the death wasn't in combat,
we're still going in person.
Frogman to family. Only right.
That kid does two
tours in Trashcanistan.
Not a damn scratch.
Then he burns in a faulty 'chute.
Them the breaks.
You see Spenser?
ADAM: That doesn't make
this any less of a tragedy.
Brian's loss hits our community hard.
Apparently, he was real
tight with the Armstrong kid.
Part of his education.
- That's cold, brother, even for you.
- No, it's not.
If this kid falls apart
every time he loses a buddy,
he's in the wrong line of work.
ADAM: Damn good operator.
- He'll be missed.
- Tell you what.
Let's just wait till he
loses a buddy in combat
and see how he handles that.
Amen.
Spenser.
Yeah.
Brian's parents live in Lamont,
California.
Yeah. Yeah, he said something
about outside of Bakersfield.
We're flying out.
(SCOFF) I'm sorry, what?
You're Brian's authorized representative
to notify his next of kin.
Ah, man. Must...
Look, Brian, he-he never said anything
to me about it.
Doesn't matter.
Brian specified you on his CACO form.
Why don't you pack an overnight bag?
Civvies.
He specified that.
Wheels up at 0900.
(HELICOPTER BLADES WHIRRING)
ERIC: All right, listen up.
Captain Garcia from JSOC's
gonna read us in on the op that
he's been building. Captain.
GARCIA:
We're looking at architectural drawings
of a residential bunker
designed by the same firm in Germany
used to build 'em for Saddam.
As you can see, the plans call
for four barracks-style guardrooms
between two sets of blast doors.
Behind the second door,
there's a utility closet
and a small living area.
Now,
what do you think I'd get a mortgage for
on a place like that right now?
(CHUCKLES)
Ballpark.
This happy fella is Faraz Jelani.
He's a Yemeni fixer.
A source tell us he's the
one commissioned the plans.
Wouldn't tell the Germans
where he was planning to build.
Look, a guy works as a
fixer in that neighborhood,
of course he's gonna have a fortress,
right?
We don't think he was building
the place for himself.
And we don't believe it's in Yemen,
either.
Oh.
GARCIA: I suppose I don't
need to tell you who that is.
Hold on.
You're saying you found Abu Hassan?
We recently managed to
place a tracking device
on a vehicle belonging to
one of Hassan's couriers.
We followed that vehicle...
to this location.
MANDY: You're looking at a limestone
ridge in the Asir Mountains,
about 50 miles northeast of Abha,
in Saudi Arabia.
We believe these shapes correspond
to the guard emplacements
on the architectural plan.
And that would mean that this line
would be the ramp down to
the exterior blast doors.
Wait a second. We're gonna
make a hit inside Saudi Arabia.
Same Saudi Arabia that...
I'm sorry, that supplies
more than half of the oil that
we import from the Persian Gulf.
RAY:
Is there any chance you're gonna tell us
that the Saudis are on-on board,
th-they're gonna help
us with the snatch?
Decision's been made not to include
our Saudi allies in this operation.
Well, they're not gonna
be our allies for long.
You sure they're protecting him?
Not sure,
but we can't assume they aren't.
GARCIA: Needless to say,
the diplomatic and economic
considerations are considerable.
But Hassan was Khalid Sheik Mohammed's
senior operational commander.
And he's still directing
al-Qaeda operations in Yemen.
Makes him the biggest fish we've
gone after since bin Laden,
and now, we believe we know where he is.
But to get DOD approval,
we need to demonstrate
an assault plan that doesn't
risk a geopolitical catastrophe.
I'm sorry, we're gonna "demonstrate"?
We built a full-size replica
of the bunker inside a secure hangar.
Brass are inbound, as we speak,
to view our rehearsal,
soon as you all are up to speed.
This replica's already been built?
We spend the last few days
developing our assault plan.
SONNY: Okay, pump the brakes here.
Who the hell has been
designing our assault plan?
Keith, is Senior Chief Fuller there?
KEITH (ON INTERCOM): Yes, sir.
Standing right here.
GARCIA: Perfect. We're ready for him.
- I assume you all know Beau Fuller?
- Gentlemen.
- GARCIA: Your Charlie Team leader.
- Ladies.
Last week, while you were in Africa,
we got Charlie Team up and running.
Chief Fuller's gonna be running
you through our operation
as soon as our guests arrive.
I'm sorry.
Is that our plan or your plan?
Because if we were involved
in this whole process,
first thing we would do,
we'd get an intel brief,
then we would all put
our heads together...
- Afraid there's no time for that.
- There's no time for that.
I'm confident Chief Fuller's plan
will get us our green light.
Thank you, sir.
I'd say we've got a real shot,
assuming you fellas are able to keep up.
(CHUCKLES) Wow. Garcia has a
comedian here, ladies and gentlemen.
Gentlemen, I'm not gonna mince words.
This has the potential to be
the defining op of our lives.
This is the one you'll
tell your grandkids about.
Bottom line,
I simply cannot stress enough
the importance of
getting this one right.
Get your game faces on.
This is General Tinsdale from CENTCOM.
Ms. Burgess from State.
We want this op green-lit,
these are the people
we need to convince.
Now, as with all multi-team operations,
cooperation and communication
will be essential.
Now, as you can see,
the exterior blast doors
are only approachable via the kill zone,
right between the two guard positions.
The door, 4,000 pounds of solid,
reinforced steel.
Far as what we can expect
to find behind that door,
I'm gonna turn it over to Ms. Ellis.
Hassan's bodyguard force consists
of a dozen or so of his
most loyal fighters.
These appear to be
their living quarters,
past which,
we come to an interior blast door.
On the other side of that
should be our target,
Abu Hassan al-Qatal.
Chief Fuller will now run us through
our current thinking for the infil.
Chief.
Thank you, sir.
We're looking at a direct helo assault.
Quick and dirty land right on the "X."
25 yards from the blast door.
What we lose in surprise, we make up for
in speed and violence of action.
RAY: Look, uh, listen, seriously.
No offense, but we-we're not
talking Afghanistan here,
we're talking Saudi Air Defense.
What's the alternative?
- A low vis drive in, drive out?
- It'd be a lot quieter.
BEAU: Yeah, more risky.
Look,
we have to assume we'll be compromised
as soon as we hit the guards, anyway.
At most,
the helo gives the Saudis another, what,
90 seconds more warning?
Mandy, nearest Saudi force, how close?
Oh, here.
Eight klicks east of the target,
special police battalion in Tabab.
We estimate the minimum
response time is 14 minutes.
Chief Fuller. I trust you understand
that we cannot engage the Saudis
- under any circumstances.
- Oh, yes, ma'am.
We are aware, but we feel
comfortable with that margin.
Some of us do.
SONNY: If we engage the Saudis,
it's gonna get ugly real quick.
Again,
under no circumstances
can we cause damage
or injury to any local forces.
Bottom line, however we do this,
we got to be gone 14 minutes
after our friends in Tabab get the call.
Further demonstrate
our actions on target,
I suggest we move to the full-size mock.
I'll have some
refreshments brought down.
- If you'll please follow me.
- Showtime.
WOMAN: Mmm, refreshments.
Yeah,
so I never knew you to buck for rank.
That what I'm doing?
Oh, come on.
I know you know how many team leaders
there are for every troop chief slot.
Preacher's getting close to retirement,
you want to take his place.
Figure it's not a bad idea
to show up the competition
in front of Command, right?
Wow, you know what?
- That never crossed my mind.
- Yeah.
That's what... well,
there's a difference between me and you.
- Oh, that's just one of many.
- Yeah.
I guess so.
You want to tell me what that was about?
History, man. A lot of history.
Want to catch me up?
- On Beau and Jason?
- Yeah.
They went through Green Team together.
And Jason made team leader first.
So much for the brotherhood.
Come on, now,
who fights more than brothers?
Plus,
now, there's always,
"How many black team
leaders does it take
to screw in a light bulb?"
I'm not gonna touch that one.
- Both of them.
- Ugh.
I'm just saying,
I'm sure it hasn't been easy for him.
I can imagine.
But that does not excuse the fact
that he is a little bit of a dick.
CLAY: You done a lot of these?
ADAM: Next-of-kin notifications?
Done four.
I guess I could tell you it gets easier,
but, uh...
So what do you say?
(CAR ALARM CHIRPS) Ah,
you're overthinking.
There's no predicting what
a parent'll want to hear.
Only thing you can do is go in,
make the best of it.
"You never really know
what's behind the door
until you breach it."
ADAM: How much you, uh,
know about Brian's family?
Just what he told me.
Their dad sells insurance,
mom's a librarian.
Cul-de-sac, white picket fence,
swing in the yard.
I guess someone's got to have that life.
You know where we're going?
Uh, yeah, got an address for his mom.
Lucy Denise, 113 High Street.
There, uh, is there any chance
you want to do all the talking?
JASON: Hope they like the show.
As long as they leave some
refreshments for the rest of us.
A shame we can't afford to build
one of these ahead of every hit.
BEAU: To continue...
However we infil, this is the
first door we have to breach.
Once we're on target,
Charlie Team will engage both guards,
then be primary to the breach.
- Naturally.
- Bravo will
hang back to provide overwatch and,
if necessary,
support by fire.
Wow, keeping us really safe.
That's very thoughtful of you.
Well,
we'll try to leave something for you.
As I was saying,
after we breach and make entry,
half of Bravo Team stays outside
to maintain rear security,
rest of Bravo falls on Charlie
to clear the structure.
So, not only is Bravo Team split,
but half of it is now with Charlie Team?
BEAU: Yeah, don't worry about it.
I'll take good care of 'em.
Really?
Because, you know what, in my book,
I don't think you
should split the teams.
BEAU: So what? You worried your scouts
can't handle being away
- from their scout leader?
- (CHUCKLES): Oh. Right. Scouts.
All right.
Once we're through the blast door,
we move on to the next stage
of our presentation.
If you'll follow me, please.
JASON: This just keeps getting better.
This is the area where we're most likely
to encounter resistance,
the second blast door.
We clear this section,
get set to blow the internal blast door,
we figure we still got
eight minutes to get
in and out with Hassan.
- Another explosive breach?
- Why not?
How many noncombatants do we have
on the other side of that door?
Hassan has three wives, six children.
A couple lieutenants have families.
We have no idea
what kind of security
Hassan'll have in there.
I mean, could be half-dozen guys
in S-vests behind this door.
I want 'em on their knees,
seeing stars when we come through.
RAY: Could also be a bunch of kids.
Or there could not be. Rules of
engagement say, unless we see them,
we have no obligation to assume they're
there.
JASON: Or there could be.
I don't know about you,
but I really don't want to see
half a dozen kids dead on CNN.
TINSDALE: I believe I have a solution.
See, I was concerned
about the children myself,
thought we might find a way
to distract them, keep them busy,
out of harm's way.
So I had my staff pull stats
on the most popular
candies in Saudi Arabia.
The Galaxy bar seems to be
a consistent top seller.
Figure if we issue each
operator a dozen or so,
you can pass 'em out whenever
you come across the children.
That's good thinking, sir.
SONNY: Good-Idea Fairies drive
all the way down here from D.C.
to break our balls in person?
No matter how popular the candy is, sir,
we're not gonna be able to
have that option till we get
through that door.
Yeah, and we're not gonna be able to get
through that door unless we blow it.
No, we cut it.
We don't have time to cut it.
How much time's that gonna cost us?
Let's see, four-inch tempered steel?
Take the Broco torch two, three minutes.
Doesn't seem to leave a lot of
time to get you all back out
- before the Saudis arrive.
- Look, the torch
is too slow. We got to blow it.
JASON: Sir, I'm confident my guys
can make initial assault,
get to this door,
have plenty of time to burn it,
secure HVT,
and make exfil without
killing noncombatants
on the other side of that door.
You got two minutes.
We'll run it with the torch.
Let's do this.
ADAM: Maybe Brian got the address wrong.
His mom's name is Lucy Denise.
Maybe she owns the place.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Excuse me.
Any chance you know
somebody called Lucy Denise?
Is this some kind of joke?
Not that we know of.
How-how is it a joke, Lucy Denise?
Well, place is called Lucy's.
Been here going on 40 years.
One of the waitresses been
here almost that long.
Name's Denise.
DENISE: So, that thing where
cops are required to admit
who they are,
you ask 'em straight out...
That's just in the movies, right?
- Uh, as we said, ma'am...
- Yeah, yeah.
You're with the navy. I remember.
"Lucy Denise," huh? Well,
guess that's me.
Oh, unless she's wanted for something
or she owes you money. In that case,
I have never heard of her. (CHUCKLES)
Well, you found me.
So, you want to tell me
now why you're looking?
Brian Armstrong.
You know him?
CLAY: I swear, ma'am, we're not...
we're not trying to jam anybody up here,
okay?
Brian...
Brian is a friend.
Brian's mom used to use this
place as free babysitting.
She'd drop Brian off
whenever she was out doing...
whatever it was she was doing.
He'd sit in a corner booth
with a stack of books.
Would never drink a soda though,
no matter how many times we offered.
Strictly water or milk.
Do you, uh... do you have any idea
where we might be able to find his mom?
Oh, she passed away.
Brian couldn't have
been more than eight,
nine. Went to live with his dad.
Use some coffee?
Yeah. We both could.
Long flight.
Well, have a seat over there.
That's where Brian used to sit.
I'll go fetch you some fresh.
I don't get it.
Said his mom came to all
of his football games.
Said he talked to her every week.
ERIC: 14-minute
response time for the Saudi cops.
Clock starts as soon as
you engage the guards.
The most time-consuming portion
of this op will be breaching
the two blast doors.
If you fail to exfil with
Abu Hassan in 14 minutes,
we'll stop the drill and reset.
All right, boys, show us what you got.
I'll show you what I got.
(GRUNTS)
MAN: Three,
two, one. Execute. (MOCK GUNSHOTS)
(BEEPS, STOPWATCH TICKING) Okay.
Sentries are down.
Fire in the hole!
What in the hell was that?
A breaching charge.
You think it was big enough?
"P" for "plenty," baby.
You just turned a two-ton door
into a two-ton obstacle, numbnuts.
(ARGUING INDISTINCTLY)
Sir, will you excuse us a moment?
- Eric...
- Yeah.
All right, look, you know what,
I know that the book says
to overpower the breach
when there's no friendlies
on the other side of the wall,
but maybe we should start
thinking outside of the book.
- Oh, for a change.
- What's that supposed to mean?
The book's there to keep everyone safe.
Improvising's how people get hurt.
You know what, I'm not gonna have
to tell one of my guys' widows
that she and her kids
just had her life cored out on account
of I insisted on flying
by the seat of my pants.
Hey. Do I need to get in this?
We're good. Yeah, we got it.
It's nothing to worry about.
ERIC: Listen to me,
all right? This is not Green Team.
We shouldn't be handling
Green Team business.
Now, those people up
there are losing patience.
So whatever's between the two of you,
I suggest you let it go.
I'm not gonna tell you again.
CLAY: No swing in the yard,
no white picket fence.
Starting to feel like a pattern.
Yeah.
WOMAN: Don't you move!
Got my 20-gauge set
straight at your spines.
Pull this trigger,
both of you crap in bags
the rest of your lives.
You're making a mistake, ma'am.
We're with the Navy.
I'm Master Chief Adam Seaver.
This is Petty Officer Clay Spenser.
WOMAN: Oh, Navy, huh? Turn around.
Nice and slow.
That's not a real good idea,
bluff having a shotgun.
Not a real good idea,
go snooping around abandoned houses.
Uh,
you know the people used to live here?
Some of 'em.
For a while, seemed like
there were new people in here
every couple of months.
Look, ma'am, a, um,
friend of ours gave us this address.
We're-we're looking for a man named,
uh, Samuel Armstrong.
- Any chance that rings a bell?
- Friends of his?
His son, Brian.
Good. Sammy was a son of a bitch.
The boy was a good egg, though.
Used to wonder about him sometimes,
what happened to him.
He join the Navy?
I hope you all can keep him
from turning into his old man.
You happen to know where Samuel
went after he left here?
Sure. Son of a bitch finally got himself
sent up to the penitentiary
- in Salinas.
- Salinas.
- He still there?
- No idea.
Child Services shipped the
boy off to a state home.
Never heard from either one of
'em again.
Used to wonder about him sometimes,
what happened to the boy.
You, uh...
you happen to remember the name
of the state home?
GARCIA: All right, sir,
here we go again.
(BEEPS, STOPWATCH TICKING)
DAVIS: 14 minutes. Piece of cake.
They got to be faster out there.
(GROANS)
(MOCK GUNSHOTS)
(HORN BLOWS) ERIC: Time!
(GROANING)
(BEEPS, STOPWATCH TICKING)
(CREAKING)
It's better.
(MOCK GUNSHOTS) (THUD)
Ready to burn.
(HORN BLOWS)
Time's up, fellas.
(GROANING, CHATTER)
DAVIS: They'll get it.
They'll get it.
(BEEPS, STOPWATCH TICKING)
(GROANS)
(MOCK GUNSHOTS) (GRUNTS)
(HISSING)
Cut. Cut it! Cut it!
That's it.
(WHOOSHING, HORN HONKS)
(DOOR CREAKS OPEN)
Now that's it.
The op's off. (GROANING)
- Oh, come on.
- Sir, all due respect,
there's not gonna be any
plywood on the target.
- Or we just go explosive...
- MAN: Right.
- Not doing explosives.
- GARCIA: It doesn't matter.
Even before the fire, you were about
to miss another time target, and nobody
wanted to put their name on the op
that started a war with Saudi Arabia.
Bottom line...
Brass feels the op's too risky.
They don't want to commit.
Oh, you happy?
What the hell is that supposed to mean,
sunshine?
Playing the same plan we've
had for the last few days.
Then the Great Jason Hayes appears,
starts changing things up on the fly,
just like always.
It's not my fault that your
plan got all jacked up.
No, the only thing jacked up,
man, is your attitude.
How about your ego?
You've been trying to undermine me
this whole time. This whole time!
Why have I been
undermining you this whole time?
Because you have one tool
that you use for every job.
That charge you would have put
on the interior of that door
would have collapsed the entire bunker.
- That is your opinion!
- Yeah, it is also my opinion
that you devised a plan that
would kill innocent people.
But then again,
we all know how you feel about that.
You don't know there are
gonna be civilians on target!
You don't know that there won't be.
You know what, Jay?
You love to talk about
the Good-Idea Fairies.
Always want to talk about
the Good-Idea Fairies,
come late to an op,
screw everything up with
their lame-ass ad-libs.
But it never occurs to you that
you are the Good-Idea Fairy.
Always trying to change things up,
do something extra,
remind everyone how much better
Jason Hayes is than everybody else.
Yeah, but when somebody gets hurt,
or gets killed,
'cause you couldn't be bothered
to stick to the script?
You seriously talking about Nate right
now?
"Hey, can't blame Jason Hayes for
being aggressive." (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Break that up!
Break it up. Easy, easy.
- JASON: What do you got?!
- Come on, Santini.
Santini, come on. Hey!
Hey, relax! Hey!
You thought I was the
one with the temper.
Relax. Come on, let's go.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
JASON: You know what?
I'm not apologizing
to that jackass,
if that's what you want me to do.
Oh, what? Jason Hayes apologize?
Perish the thought.
Yeah, perish the thought.
You know,
when I was getting out of selection,
Bravo Team was deciding which candidate
from my Green Team class they
were gonna pick in the draft.
You remember any of the
conversations they had
before deciding it ought to be me?
I don't, okay? I was a 3IC back then.
Okay. All right, well,
let me ask you something.
You ever consider the color of my skin?
Come on. No, it's not about that.
It is not about that,
do you understand me?
As far as I'm concerned,
jackasses come in one color.
Yeah,
but this particular jackass is black.
- Yeah? And, so?
- Look, I get it, man.
I never could stand Beau myself.
All right?
He's an arrogant, uptight perfectionist
with no sense of humor,
and he won't think outside the box.
I get it. He drives you crazy.
Good. I'm glad that we see the same way.
Okay, well,
how do you think he's seeing you?
Better question... do I care?
He's seeing a white
guy with slept-on hair,
couple days' growth, and your shirt
flapping almost as much as your mouth.
Thanks for that, Ray.
Really appreciate it.
Look, man, the point is,
he's seeing a guy go through
life the way he wishes he could.
Look,
what do you even know about this guy?
I know enough! I know what it's
like starting BUD/S... 150 guys,
first day of Phase 1,
I'm the only black face.
Night time surf torture,
everyone laid out
side-by-side on the beach,
eyes stinging, mouths tasting like puke,
salt and sand.
Every time a wave comes in,
everybody's trying to cheat, right?
Keep their head up
so the sea water doesn't
go back in your nose.
Instructors yelling at
you to get back down.
The thing is, in the dark, Jace,
it's hard to tell one
white face from another.
So who do you think
they call out by name?
Huh?
"Perry, you get your nappy
head back down in that sand!"
We chose you because
you're a great operator.
No, you chose me because
I was the best operator.
It's what you're not understanding,
brother.
For me, for Beau,
being great's not good enough.
You go outside the box,
you're innovative, a self-starter.
If we do it, we can't follow the rules.
I'm not saying that excuses
the way Beau is at all.
I'm just saying it's something
you ought to at least take into account.
Got it, man. I got it, all right?
Look, I appreciate you talking to me,
but did you hear what
he said about Nate?
You know what? You were actually
the one who brought up Nate.
Really? Somebody gets killed
'cause I can't stick to the script?
You don't think that's what he meant?
You know what I think? (SIGHS)
I think Nate's death has been
eating at you for months now,
and I think it's time you
talked to somebody about it
'cause it's not going away.
Therapy. Therapy...
Yeah, that's never gonna happen.
Maybe not a shrink, necessarily.
But me, Alana, somebody.
- That's not what we do, Ray.
- Yeah?
Well, we also don't get into
scraps in front of the brass
and risk getting bounced out of command.
Look, how many friends have we lost?
We never talk about them.
Why is Nate so different?
You know what? Honestly,
I really don't care about the why.
All I care about is
figuring out how to fix it.
I told Naima we got scrapped.
She's making lunch.
You hungry?
No. I'm good. I'm fine.
I got something I got to do.
Somewhere I need to be, okay?
- I'm good.
- Okay.
Yeah.
Hey, Pete.
What's going on?
Thanks for coming by, man.
Well, after all we've been through,
hard to see turning
you down for a drink.
Man, it's a little thick in here,
isn't it?
Yeah, probably the AC's broken.
Well, you want to go somewhere else?
Hell, no. Drink in the heat.
- Let's pretend we're back in Kabul.
- Hey, what can I get you?
Can I get a beer and a shot of tequila?
You in?
- Yeah, make it two.
- Got it. Okay.
How long you been back in Virginia?
Oh, a couple months.
Sorry about Nate.
Yeah, I wanted to get
back for the funeral. I...
had to stay in JBad, finish a contract.
Yeah.
Um...
(INDISTINCT CHATTER,
POOL BALLS CLICKING)
Where'd you get that?
Found that in Nate's burn box.
What do you know about her?
Marjan.
You know that 'terp that you had,
the one that disappeared?
That's his wife.
Oh, yeah, I know that.
Well, after her husband disappeared,
she assumed he was
picked up by the Taliban,
thought she was next.
- Right.
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
- Enjoy.
Thanks.
So...
she comes to you, right?
And she asks you to get
her out of Afghanistan.
Nate knew I had contacts at the border.
Right.
How'd she get to Virginia?
Bad idea, Pete.
Well, what was I gonna do? Say no?
You know what I owed Nate.
(SIGHS)
Anybody else know about her?
No, just my guys.
Now what are you worried about?
You think the DOD'd go
after Molly's pension?
All it takes is one cake-eater
to make an example out of somebody, man.
Must be nice, you know? Be an officer,
seeing everything from 30,000
feet where it all makes sense.
Never having to be on the ground,
see where people live,
how messy it gets.
Right. On the ground where people live,
sweat.
Especially in the desert.
Thanks, Pete.
Thank you all for coming
back at this late hour.
On a hunch, Jason asked me
to check the thermal
imaging of the compound,
and we discovered that
because the German
design firm didn't know
where this bunker would be constructed,
there were unable to anticipate
the challenges particular
to the desert environment.
The extreme heat of the location
appears to have forced Hassan
to install a pair
of AC ducts that don't appear
on the plans we used
to design our models.
Our analysis of the
imagery suggests that
two vertical ducts were drilled
directly into the limestone cliffs,
and connect to horizontal
ducts inside the compound,
and therefore,
lack the secure countermeasures
of the rest of the bunker's vent system.
So, by dropping through the air ducts,
we bypass all sentries and blast doors,
arriving here without alerting anyone
to our presence.
Easy to beat the clock
if it never starts.
- That's right.
- GARCIA: How big are the ducts?
MANDY:
We estimate three feet by three feet.
Crawl a few hundred
feet with all that gear?
- It's gonna be tight.
- Nobody said it was gonna be easy.
TINSDALE: What about the exfil?
I hope you're not planning
to climb back up that rope
with your prisoner.
Well, once we secure the package inside,
we will communicate with Charlie Team,
they will clear inward
as we clear outward.
We'll open the interior blast
door and exfil together.
Chief Fuller,
any objections?
Well, that's damn right
it ain't gonna be easy.
But at least this way it's possible.
I say we give it a shot.
Yeah, we'll give it a shot.
EMORY: Some of the children
are only with us a few weeks.
Just long enough for their
parents to get clean,
or get their act together
enough to regain custody.
A lot of them end up coming back.
Any ever get adopted out?
EMORY: Uh, once in a while.
Mostly the younger ones.
Couples in the market for
a little bundle of joy
to jazz up the Christmas card
aren't real eager to
bring a surly teenager
into their home,
doesn't even share their DNA.
Most part,
you're here after your tenth birthday,
you're here for the duration.
CLAY: (CLEARS THROAT) What about, uh,
what about foster care?
That's a dice roll.
Department does what they can
on their budget, but never weed out
all the crazies,
entrepreneurs in it for the check.
You ask me, kids are better off with us.
At least here, they know they're safe.
Our "library."
Obviously,
no one's giving us money for books.
Barely give us enough for food.
So, the older kids leave
theirs here when they move out.
Uh, Brian's dad, we called Salinas...
place he did time...
But they had no idea where he
might've gone after he got out.
Any chance you got
some records somewhere
might help us find him?
Uh, I can check.
You want to come back to the office?
You, uh... haven't asked
what I found out about Brian's dad.
I figured nothing.
Otherwise you would've told me.
He's dead.
Took a knife in the chest
outside of a strip club
a few weeks after he got out of Salinas.
(EXHALES)
I guess that's not really a shocker.
Still.
It's a hell of a thing for
a kid to have to carry,
family like that.
Wonder how Brian managed it.
Apparently, he made up a new one.
(LAUGHS)
I guess he did, didn't he?
Shame he didn't live
long enough to realize
teams are all the family any of us need.
(CHUCKLES)
"Teams are all the family you need"?
What, did you see that on a
recruiting poster somewhere?
What about you?
You were how old when you went to live
with your grandparents? Five?
I was five when my old man split.
Then, uh...
my mom, she tried to do
the single parenting thing
for a few months, and...
I was about six
when she sent me to
live with her parents.
They were missionaries,
your dad told me.
Yeah.
Good people?
Best I ever knew.
Think you'd have been better off
if you, uh, stayed with your mom?
No, I don't think so. (CLEARS THROAT)
Way I hear it,
my mom was kind of a mess back then.
What about Ash?
You could've moved back in with him.
I wanted to get as far away
from that guy as possible.
Like I said, teams are your real family.
You don't know it yet,
but you will.
ERIC: All right.
This will be a full run-through
with live role-players.
Keep in mind, gentlemen,
this is our final shot.
We miss our time,
there's no more do-overs.
Make it count.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Look, uh, before...
What I said...
- What you actually didn't say.
- Yeah, well...
either way,
I shouldn't have got near it.
What happened with Nate, that's, uh...
that's war, man.
Appreciate that.
Doesn't mean I like you.
- But...
- Appreciate that, too.
All right, role-players are in place.
- How's it looking?
- Bravo's ready.
Charlie, same.
All right. Let's do this.
Bravo Team set.
We've reached the horizontal ducts.
Copy. Charlie set.
Standing by.
Bravo Team moving to breach.
(MOCK GUNSHOTS)
(SCREAMS) Hey. Go.
Up. Up. Come on.
Let's go!
Jackpot.
Target secure.
Roger, Bravo 1.
On my "go."
Three, two,
one... execute.
Execute.
(MOCK GUNSHOTS)
Go.
- That's a good workout.
- I told you they'd get it.
Nice job.
All right, boys, ENDEX.
What was the time?
12 minutes and change.
Two minutes to spare.
Okay, tell you what.
What do you say we run this again, huh?
This time,
why don't you give us some curveballs?
Welcome back.
Find what you're looking for?
Not really.
Oh, sorry to hear it.
Can I get you something?
Be honest, ma'am, we were hoping
you could sit with us for a sec.
A sec, I guess.
Slow morning and all.
Uh, look, ma'am...
I'm afraid it's our duty
to inform you that...
Brian Armstrong died two
days ago in rural Virginia.
At this time, we cannot disclose
the nature of his death,
but on behalf of the
Secretary of Defense...
I'm not his kin.
As far as we know, he didn't have any.
(VOICE BREAKING): Oh, that's awful.
But what he did have
was he had a lot of people
who went out of their way
to keep him safe until he
could do that for himself.
And you're one of those people.
Think you should be proud of that.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(WHISTLES QUIETLY)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
- What's up?
- Bad news, fellas.
Op's cancelled.
- Do we know why?
- Do we ever know why?
(WHISTLES SHARPLY)
ERIC: According to Mandy, turns out
Hassan wasn't even in the bunker.
Meaning he got spooked, took off?
Or he wasn't even there
in the first place.
Thank you for your hard work.
Tell your boys to get some rest.
Back at it on Monday.
Right. Look at it this way.
Next time Abu Hassan
shows up in that bunker,
we don't have to sit around
and wait for a green light.
All right? Maybe we get there in time.
Right.
- Yeah...
- Yep.
- (LOUDLY): Ca-caw! Ca-caw!
- Ca-caw.
What is that?
Cank bird.
- There's a cank bird?
- Yep.
Shows up just before an op gets canked.
Like an omen.
It's Indian. Well, Native American.
- SONNY: Anyone else hungry?
- Yeah.
GARCIA: Yeah, I'm pretty sure
one of them gentlemen clubs
up on 17 just started a
breakfast buffet.
Well, what the hell we waiting for?
Let's make it rain.
I was a friend of Nate Massey's.
I know who you are.
You worked with him.
You're not having any tea?
Not yet.
- Put it in your mouth.
- I'm sorry?
Hold the sugar between your teeth,
and drink the tea through it.
That's how I learned to drink it
when I was a little girl.
Sugar in the t...
Like this?
(CHUCKLING)
Mm-hmm.
Yeah. Okay.
That's how you drink tea in Afghanistan?
That's how my family
drinks tea in Afghanistan.
Do all Americans drink
their tea the same way?
No.
I didn't me... I'm sorry, I, uh...
You know what, I should probably...
No, I... I'm sorry.
Do you want to talk about Nate?
sync and corrected by ninh
www.addic7ed.com