Okay.
9 1 1 emergency.
I need an ambuIance.
I have you at 92 1 2 West Third Street
in Los Angeles.
Yes, room number 2.
What's the emergency?
There's been a suicide.
Who's the victim?
I am.
In seven days,
God created the world.
And in seven seconds...
...I shattered mine.
-I can have four new fillets overnight.
-Oh, no. No, thank you.
What is your name again? Ezra?
Is that right?
Yes, sir. I'II just need
your first and Iast name...
-...so I can caII up your account.
-You know what?
Here's what I'm thinking, Ezra. I think
I'm gonna maiI you the meat back...
...so you can see firsthand the type
of dog food that you're peddIing.
That won't be necessary, sir.
So how about we just start
with your Iast name?
Thomas.
And don't even get me started
on the pork.
-Have you tried the pork?
-Well, no, sir.
I'm not much of a meat eater myseIf,
but I hear reaIIy great things...
...about the pork.
-Oh, so you don't eat pork at aII?
-No, sir.
Are you Jewish?
Is that why you don't eat pork, Ezra?
WeII, can we--?
What's your first name, Mr. Thomas?
Ben.
HoId on, what was that voice?
I don't-- I don't have an order
for a Ben Thomas.
Ezra, what was that voice?
-What voice?
-Are you bIind?
-Excuse me?
-You're kidding me.
A bIind beef saIesman
who doesn't eat meat.
Now, that-- That is rich.
That is rich.
Have you ever had sex, Ezra?
Did Lawrence in Accounting
put you up to this?
Because somehow I can't imagine
the bIind, vegan...
...beef salesman having sex.
-Listen, I'm trying to heIp you, sir.
-You're trying to help me?
The bIind beef saIesman
is trying to heIp me?
I'm actuaIIy starting to feeI
pretty bad for you, Ezra.
Because I Iook at my Iife, and it is
surrounded by so much beauty...
...and you can't see shit.
Is that fair?
Does that seem fair to you, Ezra?
Do you even know
what coIor the ocean is?
Do you?
-It's bIue, sir.
-''It's blue, sir. ''
Say what you wanna say.
React.
Say what you wanna say to me.
Thank you for caIIing
Cheyenne Meats.
That's not what you wanna say,
you coward. You coward.
You bIind, vegan, beef-saIesman,
virgin coward!
-Goodbye, Mr. Thomas.
-Say what you wanna say.
Ken Anderson. NicoIe Anderson.
AIIie Anderson. Ed Rice.
Steven PhiIIips. Monica Freeman.
Sarah Jensen.
Ken Anderson! NicoIe Anderson!
AIIie Anderson! Ed Rice!
Steven PhiIIips! Monica Freeman!
And Sarah Jensen!
Hi, can I heIp you?
Yes. HeIIo, I'm Iooking for EmiIy.
-You're a friend of hers?
-Yes, ma'am.
-She's not home.
-Oh, goodness.
No, she Ieft this morning.
She had to do some more tests.
She asked me to watch Duke
untiI she got back.
Okay.
You ever try mixing banana peeI
into the soiI?
-ReaIIy?
-It works, I swear.
Oh, wouId you by chance
know where I couId find her?
Supervisor to 1 0 4.
Cardiac wing?
Take the eIevator to the fifth fIoor
then turn Ieft.
Thank you.
WeII, that's what I was just saying.
It's absoIuteIy impossibIe.
HoId the eIevator.
Thank you.
Can I heIp you?
Yes. Good evening.
I'm here to see EmiIy Posa.
I'm sorry, visiting hours
are from 8 a.m. to 4 p.m.
You know, it is reaIIy important
I speak to her for just a moment.
You'II just have to come back
during visiting hours.
Thank you very much.
So if there is one thing
that I have Iearned...
...and you aII shouId remember
about winning these contracts:
Three steps. First, teII them
what you're gonna teII them.
Step two, you teII them.
Step three,
teII them what you toId them.
We are gonna cIose
by reminding them...
...that oId girI has a 3-percent better
impuIse from sea IeveI to vacuum...
...and if they pass on that, quite
frankIy, they deserve another Sputnik.
Now, if you wiII excuse me...
...I have a very IoveIy, very hungry
woman at home waiting for me.
Sarah.
Honey.
Everyone at work kept saying
it was dayIight-savings time.
You were supposed
to be here a whiIe ago.
-I kept saying it wasn't.
-This happens aII the time. It's work.
-I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
-No, I'm angry with you.
I'm gonna be angry aII night Iong.
-I'm angry with you.
-What are you doing?
How about that?
How about I'm angry with you?
-HeIIo?
-Hey, it's me. It's your brother.
Where are you?
I'm at the beach house.
Are you okay?
Of course.
Listen, why'd you disconnect
the landline?
The phone broke.
I don't need it anymore.
Did I...? Did I do something?
No.
Not unIess you're smoking again.
No, I've put on 20 pounds.
I'm in the best shape of my Iife.
Are you eating?
Are you taking care of yourself?
-You sound terrible again and--
-Yeah, I'm fine. Look, I gotta go.
Give MeIanie and the kids
a hug and a kiss.
I'II taIk to you Iater.
You take care of yourseIf.
HoId on. I know it's been a whiIe,
but when you were staying here...
...you didn't take something of mine
by mistake, did you?
I remember giving you something.
You remember that?
Because I remember that very cIearIy.
Yeah. Yeah.
Just remember I Iove you.
Hi, my name is Ben Thomas.
I'm here to see Stewart Goodman.
Inez, Iook at me, pIease.
Inez. I'm speaking to you.
I understand you refused to take
your meds again. Is that true?
No, no, no.
Let's try using your words
this time, okay, Inez?
I mean, this siIent treatment
isn't doing anybody any good.
Inez, how can we heIp you if--?
Okay, how about I come back
tomorrow...
...and see if you've changed
your mind, okay?
ThattagirI.
I thought I was coming
to your office today.
I was in the neighborhood. I thought
I'd stop by, save you the drive.
Terrific. WeII, Iook, Iet's go taIk
in my office, yeah? Come on.
I take a no-nonsense approach.
I mean, I cut the operating costs
of this pIace...
...over 1 7 percent Iast year aIone.
-I'm sure that made them happy.
-Oh, heII, yeah.
Now, if I couId onIy get
my own finances...
...in that kind of shape,
I wouIdn't have you sitting here.
No offense.
That your new Beemer out front?
Ben, I mean, when I found out...
...that my bone-marrow transpIant
wasn't successfuI--
I'm weII aware of your
ongoing medicaI condition.
Things aren't Iooking
very promising for me.
Look...
...I have a bonus coming in January.
I just reaIIy need
this six-month extension.
ReaIIy, I mean, I am doing the very
best I can here, I promise you.
I'm gonna show myseIf out.
I'II be in touch.
WeII, thank you. I appreciate it.
I mean, this way
everybody wins, right?
HeIIo.
My name is Ben.
I totaIIy understand
if you don't wanna speak to me either.
But I wouId reaIIy Iike
to just have a moment of your time.
I'm trying to figure out
what kind of man Stewart Goodman is.
It is within my power to drasticaIIy
change his circumstances.
But I don't wanna give that man
a gift that he doesn't deserve.
I need you to teII me
whether or not he is a good person.
''The drug he gives me...
...makes me dizzy.
I want a new one.''
WeII, that sounds
very reasonabIe, Inez.
What eIse?
You can trust me.
What eIse, Inez?
He's punishing you?
How is he punishing you?
How is he punishing you, Inez?
Ben?
-Hey, Ben, where you going?
-Where's the washroom?
To the right. Is there a probIem?
-Give her a bath, right now.
-AbsoIuteIy.
Thank you. Thank you.
You have the wrong
impression here.
I'm gonna stop by
from time to time...
...make sure you're showing
these peopIe some respect.
Look, this is
a misunderstanding, okay?
You don't treat peopIe Iike that.
Let me expIain, okay, Ben?
-And I'm not giving you an extension.
-Ben!
I'm not giving you anything.
I aImost beIieved you,
you son of a bitch.
I aImost beIieved.
Okay. Grip and rip.
This time it's gonna be
a Iot different.
Hey.
-Hey, MicheIIe.
-Hey.
-Good to see you.
-You too.
-How are you?
-I'm good.
-Hey, man.
-Hey. What are you doing here?
Just coming to make sure that she
is stiII kicking your ass at everything.
And I am.
-Can we have a sec, hon?
-Yeah.
AII right.
You okay?
Yeah, I'm good. You said you were
gonna caII me on the 1 5th.
-Today is the 1 9th.
-I know.
Doctor didn't have the resuIts,
so I had no information to give you.
StiII, you shouId caII me.
-Yeah, I know. Yes, I know.
-We're stiII friends. Right?
Yeah. I'm just....
I'm doing some souI-searching,
you know?
Don't do that.
-We have a pIan.
-I know.
-Do what you promised me.
-I wiII.
You know, they rent cIubs
up at the cIubhouse.
I'm weII aware of that.
I think I'm gonna keep my ass
unkicked today.
Were you Iooking at him,
or were you Iooking at me?
ActuaIIy, I was just sitting here.
Am I doing it wrong?
I think I saw you
in the eIevator the other day.
Oh, yes.
ActuaIIy, you are being audited.
My name is Ben Thomas.
I'm with the IRS,
and you owe the government...
...$56, 2 40.1 9.
I know.
And now you get me.
WouId you have a seat, pIease,
Miss Posa?
So I've been Iooking over
the income statements...
...from the Iast three years.
-2005--
-Were--?
Were you in my room
the other night?
No, ma'am, I was not
in your room the other night.
That's not exactIy IRS protocoI.
So I've been Iooking over
'05, '06 and '0 7.
There seems to be quite a disparity
between what you cIaimed and--
Mr. Thomas?
I just got discharged.
So, you know,
unIess you're gonna, Iike...
...hauI me off
to some IRS jaiI or something...
...I'd reaIIy Iike to get home now.
-Oh, sure. No probIem.
-Okay.
I'II be in touch.
WeIcome to the TraveI Inn.
Can I heIp you?
I need a room.
How many hours?
About two weeks.
CIear it! That's it, that's it!
AII right, come on! Vamos, Manny!
AII right, aII right. That's it, that's it.
Hey!
-What you want?
-Break it up!
-You want some of this?
-Get off! Get off!
Hey, Rico, knock it off!
Somebody wanna remind Rico
where we are?
The sanctuary, coach!
-I can't hear you.
-The sanctuary, coach!
That's right, Rico, in the sanctuary.
Now give me 20 starts and stops.
Hello, this is Emily Posa.
I'm not home right now,
but please leave a message...
...and I'll call you back
as soon as possible. Thank you.
Hi, my name is Susan Nall.
I'm calling because a friend...
...told me you do letterpress
invitations, and I was wondering--
HeIIo? Hi, this is EmiIy.
Yep, I do wedding invitations.
I'm not abIe to take any requests,
though, right now.
I know someone nearby who does it.
She's not as good as I am,
but her prices are very--
HeIIo?
Duke?
Duke.
We're out here.
HeIIo, Miss Posa.
What are you doing here?
Oh, I came to see you.
Don't you peopIe ever caII ahead?
You peopIe tend to try
to hide things.
Is that meat?
No! No, no.
No. No meat. No.
-WeII, he was reaIIy enjoying it.
-He eats steamed broccoIi and tofu.
-Why?
-He's a vegetarian.
-He is a vegetarian?
-Yes.
WeII, that sucks.
Hey, can we taIk?
Do you have a moment?
No.
ActuaIIy, I have to take Duke
for a waIk.
No probIem. I'II go with you,
if you don't mind.
-So--
-Hey, hey.
Hey.
So I've been Iooking over
2005, 2006 and 200 7.
Now--
I'm Iistening.
-Can I get him for you?
-Nope. I got him.
Let me get him. Let me get him.
Let me get him.
-You aII right?
-Yes.
Whoa, sorry. Whoa, not these.
-That's okay. Watch--
-No, no. HeeI, heeI, heeI.
Yeah, maybe we shouIdn't
feed him meat.
So I've been Iooking over--
-Yeah, maybe we can do this Iater.
-Yeah.
So you cook it aII
ahead of time, I see.
No, actuaIIy. I can't remember
the Iast time I cooked.
This is my sister's way
of Iooking out for me from afar.
Do you have any sibIings?
Yes, one brother.
He's a-- He's a good egg.
Yeah, I just have the one sister too.
Are you receiving income
from any source...
...that the government
is currentIy unaware of?
WeII, IateIy I've been taking
to diving in IocaI wishing weIIs, so....
I mean, but it's just occasionaI dimes
here and there...
...or, once in a whiIe, a quarter.
No, actuaIIy...
...I had to refinance this pIace
to pay my past-due medicaI biIIs.
I've been informed that you suffer
from congenitaI heart faiIure.
Yes. Did you gather that
whiIe staIking me at the hospitaI?
No, I....
You're currentIy Status 2,
which means you're sick enough...
...to be on the nationaI UNOS
waiting Iist...
...but not sick enough to be admitted
into the hospitaI...
...and pIaced on Status 1 .
So basicaIIy, if your heart starts to faiI
quickIy and no donor can be Iocated...
...you're screwed.
Is it true that you said...
...that you do not beIieve
that you even deserve a heart...
...because your Iife is unremarkabIe
in every way?
I'm sorry.
I don't know why I said that.
Do you have to take any type
of sensitivity training...
...to join the IRS, Mr. Thomas?
-No, not reaIIy.
-Yeah.
So you don't consider yourseIf
a good person?
How wouId you answer that question
if I asked you the same?
''UnremarkabIe'' wouId be
an upgrade for me...
...I assure you.
I'm gonna freeze your accounts
as uncoIIectibIe untiI further notice.
I'm sure that'II buy you
five or six months, penaIty-free.
Here's my card.
If anyone from the IRS
tries to contact you...
...you caII me immediateIy.
Okay.
Thank you.
-Mr. Thomas?
-Yes.
Why do I get the feeIing you're
doing me a reaIIy big favor right now?
Because I get the feeIing
that you reaIIy deserve it.
AII right?
You off to...?
You off to poIIute
someone eIse's dog now?
No.
Just going home.
Where's that?
Take care, EmiIy.
You too.
-What is this thing for?
-I toId you aIready.
And why are you bringing a fish
into your room?
Because it's my room.
And I don't want anyone going
into my room, understood?
WeII, I don't think you can
keep a fish in your room.
I think I can.
WeII, I've never had anybody
who kept a fish in their room.
Now you do.
Who?
Good night.
The first time I ever saw
a box jellyfish...
...I was 1 2.
Our father took us
to the Monterey Bay Aquarium.
I never forgot when he said...
...that it was the most
deadly creature on earth.
To me it was just...
...the most beautiful thing
I'd ever seen.
I spoke to the doctor again.
He's gonna send over your fiIes
in the morning.
-Is this everything?
-Yeah.
-Any questions?
-Same one.
WeII, same answer, then.
You know, I was thinking Iast night
about when we were 1 4...
...and we made our big pact.
You remember on the beach
in front of your grandparents' house...
...we agreed that we wouId never,
never date each other's girIs?
I remembered that that night you toId
me how much you Iiked Stacy MiIIer...
...and that you were gonna
ask her out. And I said:
''Hey, man. You can't.
Her and I aIready did it.''
Which we didn't, but I wanted to...
...but she Iiked you way more
than she Iiked me, and....
So I Iied to you
because I was so jeaIous.
And I reaIized that I've been
carrying around this Iie...
...in my heart for the Iast 25--
Stop it!
Stop it.
Stay focused.
Do what you promised me.
-What, you think I'm--?
-Do what you promised me.
You think I'm gonna
Iet you down now, don't you?
I've known you my whoIe damn Iife!
Okay?
This? This? This is not something
you do every day.
Okay? This is--
This is not easy for me.
I'II make sure everything goes
as pIanned.
Don't worry.
Thank you.
Oh, my God.
HeIIo, HoIIy.
Look at you.
-What are you doing here?
-I came to see you.
-ReaIIy?
-You have a minute?
Sure. Come on in.
Here's my desk. Have a seat.
You Iook great.
-I do?
-Yes.
I feeI great.
-How are you?
-I'm reaIIy good.
I need a favor.
Whatever you need, just ask me.
I need a name.
Someone in the system.
Someone having
a reaIIy hard time...
...that needs heIp, but may be
too proud to ask for a handout.
What are you doing?
I'm heIping.
I need a name.
Okay.
Connie Tepos.
Her boyfriend almost killed her
last year when she tried to leave.
He broke three of her ribs
last month.
She's scared to death
to press charges...
...and we can't do anything.
-HeIIo.
-Hi.
-Connie Tepos?
-Yes?
My name is Ben Thomas.
I'm with the IRS.
IRS? But I aIways pay my taxes.
Yes, this is more of
a generaI inquiry.
I don't understand. What--?
May I come in?
Not now. My boyfriend is not here.
It's very important for your famiIy.
For my famiIy?
BeautifuI.
PIease, have a seat.
What's this aII about?
Your case has come to my attention.
And I wanted to get to know you.
You wanted to get to know me?
Why?
Because I'd Iike to heIp you.
I don't understand.
I'm aware of your case.
And your boyfriend.
What are you taIking about?
You know what I'm taIking about.
No, I have no idea
what you're taIking about.
Kids, go to your room.
He's coming back?
He's not coming back.
You said you were from the IRS,
but you're Iying to me.
-No.
-You're not teIIing me the truth.
Who sent you here?
PIease sit down.
I'm not going to sit down.
-PIease, caIm down.
-I'm not going to caIm down.
You come into my house.
You taIking to me
about mi caso y mi boyfriend?
-Who sent you here?
-Nobody.
Nobody?
Get out of my house immediateIy.
You can trust me.
I trust no one, Mr. Thomas.
I taIked to HoIIy.
I can get you out of here.
To a safe pIace. A beautifuI pIace.
Why did you taIk to HoIIy?
Your chiIdren are in danger here.
Don't taIk about my kids,
Mr. Thomas.
-You don't know.
-You don't have to Iive Iike this.
Get out of my house now
or I'm gonna caII the poIice.
-Okay, okay.
-Who are you?
-I want you to take my card.
-I don't need heIp.
I want you to take my card,
and caII me--
-I don't need it.
-I'm gonna Ieave it.
Okay. Thank you. Get out right now.
-You're not heIpIess.
-Can you Ieave? This is my house.
PIease, just think about it.
I don't need you.
-I can't taIk right now.
-I need to talk immediately.
-Where are you?
-I'm nowhere.
I'm gonna meet you at the house.
Look, no. I'm not at the house.
I'm traveIing. I'II taIk to you next week.
No, no, no. We need to
discuss this right now.
WouIdn't wanna get
on her bad side.
-I'II sign to that.
-Yeah.
How you doing, you two?
I'm good.
Got a big day.
Yep. No more diaIysis, George.
See you in the O.R.
Yep.
-I'II see you there as weII.
-Yes, sir.
Thank you.
So I heard you raised
enough money...
...to give a coupIe of the kids
partiaI schoIarships to coIIege.
It's no big deaI.
I just convinced a coupIe
of bigwig donors...
...that what the worId reaIIy needs
to see is more Latinos on ice.
You know, Ben,
I keep asking you this...
...but why me?
Because you are a good man.
No, reaIIy.
Even when you don't know
that peopIe are watching you.
Hello?
HeIIo?
Okay, I can't hear you,
so try back again.
Gonna hang up now.
Bye.
Mr. Thomas?
We're ready for you.
These are beautifuI.
Banana peeIs. Who knew?
EmiIy?
Can I get a refiII?
-Susan?
-Yeah.
How's Ryan?
He's good. He's at his dad's
this weekend.
WiII you teII him for me that I'm ready
whenever he is for a free Iesson?
Yeah, aII right.
Things are kind of crazy right now
with schooI...
...but maybe when schooI's out.
Oh, yeah. That's perfect.
How's the pie?
Oh, it's-- It's good.
You gonna ask her out?
The waitress.
No.
You never know.
I don't-- I don't think she sees me.
Good night, Ezra.
HeIIo?
Ben?
Hi, I'm sorry to caII so Iate.
Did--? Did someone
from the IRS contact you?
No.
I just--
I was having troubIe breathing after
I took Duke for a waIk, and I fainted.
An ambulance had to take me
to the hospital.
I'm so sorry.
I don't know why I even
caIIed you. I'm sorry.
It's just that I have your card
with me, and....
Ben?
Are you stiII there?
Yes.
Do you ever
think about dying, Ben?
Every now and again.
My face is bIuish.
It's not exactIy a good sign.
You shouId try to rest. Just--
Why don't you see
if you can get some sIeep?
I Iike taIking to you.
I like talking to you too.
WouId you teII me a story, pIease?
Okay.
AII right. Once upon a time...
...there was a little boy named--
Oh, Iucky me, you just got it
on reserve Iike that. Okay.
Let me guess. His name was Ben.
No, actuaIIy,
this IittIe boy's name is Tim.
I Iike the name Tim.
Go on.
Tim's little brother
was always pestering Tim...
...to make him paper airpIanes,
because he was reaIIy good at it.
But Tim had much bigger
dreams than that.
Okay. Then what happened?
One day, Tim went out
to the backyard...
...and he put Ieaves
and taped branches to his arms...
...and started cIimbing
the big oak tree.
His little brother said,
''Tim, you can't fly. ''
And he said,
''Yeah? You just watch. ''
He got aII the way to the top
and jumped.
How taII was this tree?
It was-- It was pretty tall.
He broke his arm.
Oh, my God--
This is a horribIe story.
Oh, no, no. It gets better.
From that experience,
Tim reaIized that he wanted to fIy.
So he dedicated his Iife
to making spaceships.
I thought you said
this was a good story.
Oh, weII....
Yeah, that is...
...untiI the dragons showed up.
Oh, okay, see,
now it's getting better.
I Iike dragons.
EspeciaIIy dragons in space.
Yes, and these were fire-breathing
space dragons...
...with really bad attitudes.
I see.
I have an idea.
Why don't you try to fall asleep...
...and when you do,
I'll just hang up.
Okay.
Ben?
Yes.
Thank you for Iistening.
And for taIking.
Try to fall asleep.
Good night, Ben.
Good night, EmiIy.
EmiIy?
I Iied to you.
I think about dying every day.
Dr. King to NICU. Dr. Wesley King,
please report to NICU.
Hey.
-Hey.
When did you get here?
Last night, after we taIked.
You sIept here?
Good morning. How's our patient?
-Morning. Better.
-Good.
-HeIIo.
-Hi, Ben. Is that right? IRS?
-Yes, how are you?
-Good, thank you.
-I'II Ieave you two aIone.
-No, no, stay, pIease. Don't go.
He can-- He can stay.
Whatever you want.
You fainted because
your heart was too weak...
...to pump enough bIood
to your brain.
It's enIarged
and it's starting to shut down.
How Iong?
It's entireIy up to your heart.
CouId be six weeks,
couId be a month.
But we've upped you to Status 1 B.
At Ieast I'm on the Iist.
Not onIy that,
but we're giving you this pager.
And when it goes off,
it means you have a donor.
The inotrope drug I started you on...
...it's gonna stabiIize your
bIood pressure within 2 4 hours.
Then what?
We wait.
-Can I do that at home?
-Once you're stabIe, you can.
Okay.
I'm gonna run to the cafeteria.
I'm gonna get you something.
If you want something eIse,
I can get you something eIse.
WouId you stay?
I mean, unIess you have
something eIse to do.
-I'd reaIIy Iike it if you stayed.
-I don't have anything.
Okay. Okay.
Hey, hey, hey.
What the heII is that thing?
It's a dog. Just for one night.
No. HoId on, hoId on.
I don't give two shits, okay?
We have a dog poIicy here.
LittIe dogs onIy.
PoodIes and Shih Tzus.
It's in the contract. It's EngIish
and Spanish for everyone to see.
And besides, that, my friend,
is not a dog.
It's a goddamn horse.
WeII, Iet me know when you add
a horse poIicy to the contract.
Yes.
Mr. Thomas, it's Connie Tepos.
Hey, Connie.
I don't know why I'm calling you...
...but I'm caIIing you.
You said you couId heIp us and--
Can you reaIIy heIp us?
This just doesn't make any sense.
-What if he finds us?
-He won't.
-What makes you so sure?
-Stop it.
-You don't know him.
Don't be weak.
-Don't be weak.
-I'm not weak.
I'm strong.
Take this. Take it.
You are gonna start this car...
...and you're gonna go.
This is reaI,
and this is gonna be your new Iife.
-Do you understand?
-Yes.
Look at those babies.
Look how beautifuI
those babies are.
I know, I know.
They deserve it.
Okay?
You're headed north up the coast.
Lorena. Lorena.
I've always believed
this place can heal the soul.
Mommy, the ocean.
Yes, the ocean.
I hope that proves true for you.
When you sign your name
on the dotted line of the contract...
...you'll own my house outright.
I only ask that you never mention
how you got the house...
...or try to contact me
for any reason.
And if you're wondering why you,
please stop.
All I ask is for you
to honor my wishes...
...and, of course,
live life abundantly.
Hey. Thanks. Got it.
Hi, Duke.
Hi, baby.
What time does the nurse come?
She shouId be there
by the time I get home.
-Ben?
-Yes.
I know I'm the girI
with the broken wing.
But who are you?
Who am I?
I am your friendIy neighborhood
tax coIIector.
Ben.
Where the heII did you come from?
I grew up in OakIand.
LiteraIIy. Okay.
Where did you go to coIIege?
As far from OakIand as possibIe.
Massachusetts Institute
of TechnoIogy.
How about you?
UCLA.
You went to MIT?
Like, the MIT?
Oh, and now you're wondering how
I wound up as a IowIy tax coIIector.
AbsoIuteIy.
-I sort of stumbIed into this job.
-That's a big stumbIe.
What from?
I aIways wanted to be an engineer.
An engineer?
What kind?
The kind that sent peopIe
to the moon.
ReaIIy?
Yes.
I don't wanna taIk
about me anymore.
That's too bad,
because you're very interesting.
Have you--?
Have you ever been in Iove?
EmiIy, pIease.
Yes, you have.
Come on, you can teII me.
Yes.
But it ended.
-What happened?
-Stop it.
-No, seriousIy, you can teII--
You need to get some rest.
I'II caII you tomorrow,
or maybe I'II stop by.
No, if I have questions tomorrow,
what then?
That's not a part of the deaI.
What the heII does that mean?
EmiIy, hoId on. HoId on.
-Just Ieave.
-EmiIy, wait.
Wait!
Thank you for everything you did.
Did you Iike the eggs?
They were okay, I guess.
I don't Iike the eggs you buy.
Okay.
You're wearing suit pants.
To weed.
Yeah, I didn't-- I didn't have
any other cIothes with me.
-You know, I was gonna get to those.
-I saw them the other day.
I figured I wouId just take the day off
and get this done for you.
Ben?
Yeah?
This is a reaIIy ridicuIous apoIogy.
Come on.
I wanna show you something.
Oh, no, I gotta finish.
You can finish tomorrow.
Come on.
This is where I used to work.
And these are the artifacts
of said work.
Wow, those are great.
How oId are they?
This one is just shy of 1 20 years.
It's how I put out my Iine of Ietterpress
cards, wedding invitations, invites.
What about this one?
That youngster...
...is the HeideIberg WindmiII, 1 956.
CaII it ''The Beast.''
WeII, that seems appropriate.
It pooped out on me
about five years ago, though.
And I can't find anybody to fix it.
It's kind of a dying art.
DefibriIIator here works, though.
LuckiIy. It kept my business afIoat.
Wanna see how?
PIease.
Okay. Now, true pressmen...
...hate that we modern girIs...
...want a deep impression.
See, for a hundred years, they tried
their damnedest just to kiss it...
...so that it didn't Ieave
an indentation.
Now it's the onIy way
to prove it's not digitaI.
I think it feeIs richer.
You okay?
Yeah.
Look, Ben....
I don't reaIIy know anything about you
or where you came from...
...but you keep showing up.
And I'm gIad.
Okay.
So Duke needs a waIk.
Are you interested?
Yes.
Come on.
Hey, hey.
Right here.
There you go.
He's Iike a different dog
with you around.
I don't think we ever
properIy bonded.
Why wouId you get such a big dog?
Did you know that Great Danes on
average onIy Iive about seven years?
They have heart issues.
I think I got him because...
...I thought he couId heIp me
with my iIIness.
It'd be something
I couId take care of...
...as opposed to being
aIways taken care of.
You know, just so you know,
I used to be reaIIy hot.
Like, unauditabIy hot.
Is that so?
Yeah.
I haven't feIt Iike this
in a reaIIy Iong time.
There's so many things
that I wanna do.
I wanna go on a pIane
for 1 3 hours...
...and not have to stress
that I can't reach my doctor.
You know, Iike, just traveI.
Go backpacking, have experiences.
See the worId.
I just wanna have the time
to figure out who it is that I am.
You know, what I Iike.
Do things, try things,
get out of my head for once.
I wouId reaIIy Iike to go running.
I think about that sometimes.
What it wouId just feeI Iike
to go running.
So...
...see you tomorrow?
Yes.
But if you need anything,
just caII and I'II come right back.
Okay.
Bye.
I had a reaIIy great time today.
Me too.
Bye.
No anesthetic. You ever
donated bone marrow before?
You're a brave guy.
How Iong have you
known NichoIas?
What the heII happened to you?
Hey, how much Ionger
are you gonna stay in my hoteI?
MoteI.
How much Ionger?
ActuaIIy, I was pIanning
on dying here.
WeII, then you need to pay
in advance.
HeIIo?
Hey, it's EmiIy.
Are you sIeeping?
Yes. No.
Is everything okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
My sister came over for a coupIe
of days Iast week with the kids...
...and it was reaIIy great.
I tried calling you a couple times.
How are you doing?
Yeah, I'm good.
Everything's fine. I've been....
I've been traveIing a Iot, so....
WeII, are you busy tonight?
What do you mean?
I don't-- Maybe you wanna
come by and say heIIo?
Around 7?
You don't have to if you don't want to.
I just, you know....
Look, I totaIIy get if you don't wanna
hang out with the dying girI, so....
I can-- I can come at 7.
Okay.
Bye.
-WeII, how you doing tonight?
-Hey.
-How you doing?
-Have fun.
-Hi.
Come in.
I am so gIad she's gone.
Are you okay if we eat outside?
Eating?
You didn't eat aIready, did you?
-No.
-Okay.
No.
WeII, it was a surprise...
...but you're on time.
I haven't cooked anybody food
for years, so you better Iike it.
Or Iie to me.
This is for you.
You don't have to say anything.
I just got it-- Change in there.
Dinner is ready and you're not.
So hurry up.
Chop-chop.
You Iook great.
Yeah. It's pink.
It's saImon.
You are so nice.
So are you.
Everything's vegetarian.
I hope you Iike eggpIant Parmesan.
I haven't treated myseIf very weII...
...in the past few years.
Start now.
AII right.
What do you think?
It's deIicious.
GIad you Iike it.
Do you wanna hear
my favorite song?
Yes. Are you gonna sing it?
No, I can't sing anymore.
Oh, and a performance.
Oh, no.
ShaII we?
You need to reIax.
This is reIaxed.
I have a surprise for you.
Surprise?
Yes.
For me?
-Keep them cIosed.
-Okay.
And open.
Okay.
You cIeaned The Beast.
ActuaIIy, I fixed it.
No, you didn't.
Oh, okay, Iet's go, then.
Wait. Are you serious?
Try it.
Okay.
Thank you.
Wait right here, okay?
I'II be right back. Wait right here.
One second.
Hey!
TeII me what's going on.
-Now!
-AII right.
Ben, you need to go home.
Do you know they keep a fuII history of
every inquiry a revenue officer makes?
-You understand?
-Keep your voice down.
-Just keep your voice down.
-No. What you are doing is a crime!
You are impersonating
a federaI officer. It's a feIony!
AII right. Listen.
You can't pIay with peopIe's Iives.
Do you understand that?
AII right.
AII right, there's a coffee shop.
There's a coffee shop
near where I'm staying.
-Tomorrow we'II sit down--
-Where are you staying, Tim?
TeII me, because I don't know
where my brother Iives!
A moteI. Five bIocks from here.
We'II sit down tomorrow morning,
I guarantee it.
Where are my credentiaIs?
Give me my credentiaIs back.
Here it is. Here. Here.
Just go home.
You have a beautifuI famiIy.
Go home and enjoy them.
Tim, Tim, Tim,
why are you even here?
TeII me, who is EmiIy Posa?
I'II expIain everything tomorrow.
Look, give me your car keys.
I'm not going anywhere.
I'm gonna be right here.
So you remember I Iove you and....
Tim, don't make me come knock
on the door, okay?
I didn't reaIize how Iate it was and....
I have a reaIIy Iong drive,
so I need to go.
I don't wanna keep Iying to you.
I don't wanna-- Wait, EmiIy.
Do you wanna pIay a game?
What game?
The ''what if'' game.
What if...
...my pager goes off...
...and it's a heart...
...and...
...it works?
And my body doesn't reject it?
And...
...what if I have time?
What if...?
What if we have chiIdren?
What if we got married?
I Iove you.
-I Iove you too.
-I Iove you.
Hi.
Is Dr. Briar on duty tonight?
She's doing her rounds.
Can you teII her it's Ben Thomas?
It's very important.
-I'II-- I'II page her.
-Thank you.
Dr. Briar to the nurses' station.
Hey.
-Is it EmiIy?
-No, no.
I'm sorry.
It's--
Is there...?
I'm sorry.
Do you have any more optimism...
...about EmiIy...
...than you did the other day?
Ben...
...when you're Iooking for a donor
with a rare bIood type...
...the odds go way down.
To what?
They go down. What's the--?
Give me a percentage.
Give me a number.
Three, 5 percent.
I know. I'm sorry.
I wish the numbers were higher.
-Thank you. Thank you.
-I do.
HeIIo?
Dan.
It's time.
I Iove you.
1:38 a.m.
HeIIo?
Ezra.
My name is Ben Thomas.
I caIIed you a few weeks ago.
You probabIy don't remember.
I do remember.
I wanna apologize for being
so cruel to you...
...but I had to be certain.
I had to be certain
that you were a decent man. Kind.
-Slow to anger.
-What do you want from me?
I wanna give you a gift.
You're gonna be contacted
by a man named Dan Morris.
You can trust him.
Was that you at the diner?
Goodbye.
9 1 1 emergency.
I need an ambuIance.
I have you at 92 1 2 West Third Street
in Los Angeles.
Yes, room number 2.
What's the emergency?
There's been a suicide.
Who's the victim?
I am.
You are gonna need to stop
Iooking at that thing so much.
Why? Is it gonna crack?
Oh, no. I paid extra
for the non-cracking kind.
I bet you did.
-Why don't you just turn that off?
-I know. No more. No more work.
I'm done. AImost done. AImost done.
Tim!
I have procedures.
I understand, but she needs
that heart or she wiII die.
-Ben?
-One, two, three.
Hey.
How you doing?
About a year after the accident,
I got sick.
I got Iung cancer,
and I needed a doubIe-Iobe transpIant.
Tim couId onIy give me one,
of course.
It must have pIanted a seed,
because he....
About six months Iater...
...he donated the right part of his
Iiver to this woman.
Her name is HoIIy.
I'm proud of you kids. Very proud.
Good job. Good job.
-Ezra.
-Yeah.
Hi.
Are you a parent?
No.
Have we met?
You okay?
You must be EmiIy.
Yes.
It's so nice to meet you.