- Hello.
Say, I was wondering...
What?
Sorry. I was wondering
if you'd like to dance.
Why not?
Kitty, who was the young man
you were dancing with last night?
Which one?
Quiet, serious-looking one.
Oh, him.
- I suppose you invited him, mother.
- I don't know who you're talking about.
I invited him.
His name is Fane and he's a doctor.
He manages a government laboratory...
...in Shanghai.
- A civil servant?
In any case.
He called around last Sunday.
We had a long chat.
I told him to come back anytime.
It's not often that you like
any of my young men.
Well, do you like him?
- Not really.
- What's wrong with him?
- Is he in love with you?
- I don't know.
I thought by now you'd know
when a young man was in love with you.
The point is whether I'm in love with him,
and I'm not.
You'd better be careful, young lady.
Time can run out, you know.
Oh, stop it, mother. Honestly.
The very idea that a woman
should marry any Tom, Dick, or Harry...
...regardless of her own feelings
is simply prehistoric.
How much longer do you expect
your father to go on supporting you?
- Hello.
- Hello. l...
I was... I was just coming...
Your father invited me.
I'm going out.
May I join you?
Right on time.
What is it exactly that you do?
I'm a bacteriologist.
That must be fascinating.
You have no idea what that is, do you?
No, I'm afraid not.
No. There's no reason you should.
I study the microorganisms
that carry disease.
Charming.
No, it's not, actually. It's the opposite.
Shall we step inside?
Do you like flowers?
Not particularly, no.
Well, I mean, yes. But we don't really
have them around the house.
Mother says, "Why purchase something
you can grow for free?"
Then, we don't really grow them either.
Does seem silly, really.
To put all that effort into...
...something that's just going to die.
I'd like to say something to you.
I came to see you
to ask you if you'll marry me.
You could knock me down
with a feather.
Could you not tell
that I'm in love with you?
You never showed it.
Oh, I...
Well, I wanted to. It's difficult. I...
But there it is.
Right.
I'm not sure that's very well put.
No, it's not. You see how clumsy I am.
I... I'm terrible at these sorts of things.
But the thing is, I've got to get
back to China very soon.
I don't have time to be cautious.
I've never thought of you in that way.
- I improve greatly upon acquaintance.
- I'm sure you do...
I'd do anything in my power
to make you happy.
Anything at all.
I think you'd like Shanghai.
It's quite exciting, it is.
Lots of dancing.
Surely you're not expecting me
to answer this second.
I don't know you at all.
Yes. Ye...
Well, we had the highest of hopes...
...but no expectation
that he'd ask her so soon.
Yes. A lovely late autumn wedding.
Oh, she's done very well for herself,
has my Doris.
At least one of them's made a success.
No, I gave up on Kitty ages ago.
Yes.
Yes. Well, I know you understand.
Well?
Is it smaller than you imagined?
I'm not sure what I imagined.
Don't you have a piano?
No. I don't play the piano.
- Who is it?
- It's I.
Come in.
Just wanted to see
if you were all settled.
So, then, you're comfortable, then?
Do you need anything?
No. I'm fine. Thank you.
Good. Good.
I am so happy you're here.
- Shall I shut the lamp?
- What for?
I must shut the lamp.
It's raining cats and dogs.
I said, it's raining cats and dogs.
Yes, I heard you.
- You might have answered.
- I'm sorry.
l... I've gotten used to not speaking
unless I have something to say.
If nobody spoke unless
they had something to say...
...the human race would
soon lose the power of speech.
Walter.
I'm sorry.
You're right. What...?
What shall we do? Shall we?
Shall we play a game?
You don't like the games I play.
They bore you.
Nonsense. Let's play cards.
Do you think you'd enjoy a night out?
We have an invitation for Saturday night.
- From whom?
- The Townsends.
Dorothy Townsend.
Do you not like her?
I've only met her once, but there's
no reason for her to put on such airs.
- Does she?
- Yes. I have no idea why.
Because she was, what,
married to a vice consul?
Honestly, they're absurd,
this Shanghai set.
Mother wouldn't dream
of asking half of them to dinner.
I'm taking that black five.
Well, it's all right.
I thought you might enjoy it...
...but we certainly don't have to go.
I don't care either way.
Go where?
- Kitty Fane?
- Hello, Dorothy.
- I'm so glad you could come.
- This is Walter.
- I'm pleased to meet you.
- This is my husband.
Charlie, stop talking
and greet our guests.
- You know Mr. Fane.
- Charlie.
- It's Dr. Fane, darling.
- Oh, dear.
- I do beg your pardon, Dr. Fane.
- Not at all.
- And this is Dr. Fane's wife, Kitty.
- Mrs. Fane.
- Mr. Townsend.
- I do apologize, Dr. Fane.
I assumed you worked with Charlie.
Oh, no. Nothing so glamorous.
I'm at the Civil Laboratory.
Oh, the government lab?
How fascinating.
Are you enjoying it?
I've never seen anything like it.
Every gesture has a meaning.
See how she covers her face
with the cloth?
She is mourning her misfortune.
What happened to her?
She was sold into slavery.
Condemned to a life
of drudgery and despair...
...in a strange land far from home.
See the chains?
They represent the heavy bondage
of her poor trapped soul...
...from which there is no escape.
And so she weeps.
She weeps for the lively,
vivacious girl she once was...
...the lonely woman she has become...
...and most of all, she weeps
for the love she'll never feel...
...for the love she'll never give.
Is that really what she's saying?
Actually, I haven't a clue
what she's on about.
I don't speak Chinese.
What was that?
Perhaps it was the amah...
They've gone.
- He heard us.
- Who?
Walter.
Walter. What if it was?
- For all he knows, you were taking a nap.
- With my doors locked?
Kitty, dear, you need a drink.
Even if it was,
my impression is he'll do nothing.
That's flattering.
He knows as well as anyone there's
nothing to be gained by making a scandal.
Has it occurred to you
that my husband is in love with me?
I have a feeling you're about
to say something awful.
It's just that women are
often under the impression...
...that men are much more
in love with them than they really are.
I wouldn't delude myself for a second
that you were in love with me.
Now there you're wrong.
Do you like your present?
It's good enough.
Charlie?
Do I make you as happy
as you make me?
Of course you do, darling.
- Hassan?
- Yes?
- Who brought this package around?
- Dr. Fane.
- When?
- While you sleeping.
It's nearly midday.
We could stop up here under the trees...
...but I'd like to press on
if it's all right with you.
Certainly my comfort's
of no concern to you.
Right. Then we'll continue.
Charlie Townsend, please.
Charles Townsend.
I need to see you.
Kitty, I can't possibly see you.
I've got a meeting in an hour at the club.
What is it?
I have to go.
What are you doing home?
I'm sorry, there's something
I need to speak with you about.
Actually, I was just about
to take my bath.
I'm afraid it's rather important, darling.
Can't wait.
Sit down.
Do you know a place called Mei-tan-fu?
No.
Well, it... It was in the papers
the other day.
It's a small town on a tributary
of the Yangtze River, in the interior.
They've had an outbreak
of cholera there.
It's the worst epidemic
anyone's seen in a long time.
The Chinese medical officer has died.
There's a convent of French nuns
trying to run the hospital.
They're doing the best they can,
but people are dropping like flies.
I have volunteered to go
and to take charge.
- Why?
- Because they need a doctor.
But you're not a doctor.
You're a bacteriologist.
I'm an M.D.
The fact that I'm foremost a scientist...
...is actually all to the good in this case.
Won't it be awfully dangerous?
I suppose it might, yes.
Now, Mei-tan-fu is a 10-day journey.
You can go by rail for the first part.
But after that it's carriage, and then
we'll have to take a sedan chair.
Who's we?
- Why, you and I, of course.
- You're not expecting me to come too.
I hoped that if I was going,
you would want to go.
Surely it's no place for a woman.
It would be madness for me to go.
- Why should I?
- To cheer and comfort me?
No. No, I won't go.
In fact, it's monstrous of you
to even ask me.
Fine. Then I shall file
my petition for divorce tomorrow.
I'm afraid that you have thought me
a bigger fool than I am.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Don't you?
I am divorcing you for adultery.
I am naming Charles Townsend
as your lover.
I'm sorry, Walter.
I realize this is very unpleasant.
But, please, let's not make this
uglier than it needs to be.
By all means. What is it that
you propose that we should do?
You could let me divorce you quietly.
You divorce me?
- On what grounds?
- That's what a gentleman would do.
Give me one reason to put myself
to an inconvenience on your account.
Please, Walter, don't be so hateful.
We didn't mean to hurt anyone.
But Charlie and I have fallen in love.
- He wants to marry me.
- Really?
I knew that you weren't
the cleverest girl...
...but I didn't know
you were actually a fool.
Yes. Well, if it makes you feel better
to hurt me, then go ahead.
But you might as well get used to it.
We love each other.
And we're sick to death of the secrecy
and compromise and the rest.
Now you curse the day
that you ever met me.
Stop mocking me.
There's no other response for
such pathetic behavior.
It's comic.
When I think about how hard
I have tried to make you happy.
Debasing myself, acting as though I was
as thrilled as you by the latest gossip.
- I don't have to listen to this.
- And as ignorant of the world as you are...
If you interrupt me again,
I'll strangle you.
Sit down.
I knew when I married you
that you were selfish and spoiled.
But I loved you.
I knew that you married me only to get
as far away from your mother as possible...
...and I hoped that one day
there'd be something more.
I was wrong.
You don't have it in you.
If a man hasn't what's necessary
to make a woman love him...
...then it's his fault, not hers.
Either way.
Tomorrow morning we are to leave
for Mei-tan-fu, or I shall file my petition.
You can't be serious about taking me
into the middle of a cholera epidemic.
Do you think that I'm not?
My God.
That's what you want, isn't it?
Do you really think
Charlie will let you do this?
I don't think Charlie has
very much to say about it.
Everything you said is true.
Everything.
I married you
even though I didn't love you.
But you knew that.
Aren't you as much to blame
for what's happened as I?
All right.
Here's what I'll do.
Gentlemen, we all have assets
to protect here.
Unfortunately, Mr. Nagata's actions
have created a rather urgent situation.
It was an unfortunate
but unavoidable incident.
- Your foreman shot a worker.
- He was an agitator.
He was a Chinese.
You may have suppressed
a very small strike...
...but in doing so, you have started
a very large demonstration.
I need to use your pen, please.
- Here you are, miss.
- Thank you.
What about support from Chiang Kai-shek?
Where does he stand?
He's a nationalist.
He will stand on the side of the Chinese.
That's why they
call themselves nationalists.
Excuse me.
Mr. Townsend.
I think you underestimated the situation.
I have three of my mills shut down
because of walkouts.
- There is talk about boycotts.
- What do you propose?
A handful of municipal soldiers is
hardly a show of force.
If you'll excuse me.
Mrs. Fane. What a pleasant surprise.
You've rescued me
from a pack of wild bores.
I wouldn't have come
if it wasn't necessary.
Are you all right?
I needed to see you. I'm sorry.
Kitty, this is not the most
opportune time for me to...
Charlie. He knows.
Right.
After you, Mrs. Fane.
- Hello, Charlie.
- Hello, George.
- Hello, Townsend.
- Pardon.
He wants a divorce.
You didn't commit yourself, did you?
- Acknowledge anything?
- No.
- Are you sure?
- Quite sure.
Well, this is a bloody scrape we're in.
He says he has proof.
We deny it. He can't prove anything.
Besides, it wouldn't do him any good
to create a scandal.
But there isn't going to be a scandal.
Walter's agreed to
let me divorce him quietly.
That's not so terrible, is it?
- Will you hold me?
- Of course I will.
Oh, God.
Charlie?
His offer comes with a condition.
- I'm not a rich man.
- He doesn't want your money.
He's agreed to let me divorce him
if Dorothy will agree to divorce you.
And if...
What?
If you'll promise to marry me.
You know, darling, whatever happens,
we must try to keep Dorothy out of it.
What do you mean?
We can't only think of ourselves.
I know Dorothy. Nothing in the world
will induce her to divorce me.
You don't want to divorce her.
- It's not a question of my marriage.
- Then what is it?
Do you have any idea of the importance
of my station here? If I were...
Why are you laughing?
I don't think Walter intended
for one minute to divorce me.
He knew you'd let me down.
- Try to understand.
- I understand, all right.
Kitty. Kitty, please.
We'll work this out, I promise.
- I'm coming with you.
- Good. I thought you might.
I suppose I needn't take more than
a few summer things? And a shroud?
I've told Hassan what you'll need.
She's packing already.
I wouldn't touch that if I was you.
They may have died in that bed.
This can be your room.
You must be the doctor's wife.
I've just met your husband
and invited myself to dinner.
I've kept the Watsons' cook for you.
She's not bad.
She'll have to do as your amah as well.
We're a little short-handed here.
Sorry, my name is Waddington.
Oh, yes, of course. Kitty Fane.
- I'm the deputy commissioner.
- Please.
I believe you're one of our neighbors.
Only neighbor, I'm afraid.
Last one standing.
And Watson was the missionary
living here?
Yes. Nice fellow. American.
Lovely family.
I'll show you their graves tomorrow,
if you like.
How kind of you.
I hope your journey wasn't too arduous.
We've been traveling for two weeks.
Two weeks?
- What did you do, swim?
- No, we didn't come upriver.
- Came overland.
- Whatever for?
Well, we wanted to take in
a bit of the countryside.
Get a bit of sun. Didn't we, darling?
Anyone for a cocktail?
Here's luck.
I was told I might get some help
from the local army officer.
Colonel Yu, is it?
Good luck with him.
He's not fond of us British.
Listen, I'll warn you,
things are pretty dicey even out here.
I'm afraid that if the cholera doesn't get us,
the nationalists might.
Tried to get those nuns to go
but they refused.
They all want to be martyrs, damn them.
Well, why have you stayed?
I was posted here. Simple as that.
I was shocked to hear you'd volunteered.
Opportunity for research.
I couldn't pass it up.
Yes. And you?
I don't suppose you've come
to Mei-tan-fu for the research.
My husband's the scientist.
Indeed.
Did you have any reaction
to the inoculation?
- You have been inoculated?
- Yes, of course.
No guarantee.
The Watsons were inoculated...
...and it didn't do them much good.
Oh, have you brought
any gramophone records?
- No, unfortunately not.
- Pity.
I'm sick of all mine.
Listen. What's all that?
Across the river.
Trying to frighten off the spirit of death.
I'm going to town in the morning,
have a look around.
I expect you'll want to rest.
I can inoculate you in the evening.
- Will you be doing yourself?
- No, I don't think so.
- You needn't bother with me, then.
- Suit yourself.
Tell me, Walter...
...is it a long, drawn-out affair,
dying of cholera?
No. All of the fluid goes out of you
in the first 36 hours.
You die of dehydration, actually.
So it's messy and very painful.
But it is relatively quick.
Good night.
It's rather unfortunate.
I thought perhaps that you
and your wife...
...you'd like to take precautions
in case you'd have to leave this place.
Do you think all this is really necessary?
You can see the picture.
I thought you'd like to put your wife's
mind at rest from this situation.
This is Colonel Yu.
He's the KMT's man.
He's posting one of his men here
at the house.
Am I a prisoner?
No. It was Mr. Waddington's idea,
actually.
- He feels we should take precautions.
- Precautions against what?
A few days ago,
British troops opened fire...
...on a group of Chinese workers
who were demonstrating in Shanghai.
Eleven were killed.
We've only just heard.
Those were plastered around the town
last night.
I shouldn't worry too much.
Even the nationalists are
afraid of cholera.
Do they take that water from the well?
Can I see where they get
their drinking water?
Well, for starters, we've got to
stop people from using this well...
...until I can test it.
Do you understand?
Yes, I understand, Dr. Fane.
I received my military training
in Moscow.
If you don't like English,
we can speak Russian.
English will be fine. Thank you.
Here. You have seen cholera before,
yes, doctor?
- At the laboratory, of course.
- No, I mean in a patient.
No. I haven't had the chance, actually.
Well, I'm not a clinician.
Did they not tell you?
I'm an infectious-disease specialist.
- Shall we?
- After you, doctor.
No, it's all right. I'm all right.
All right, let's go.
I don't need you.
Go back.
Mr. Waddington?
I'm looking for Mr. Waddington.
Wait here. All right?
Hello?
Mr. Waddington?
Mrs. Fane?
Good morning.
What can I do for you, Mrs. Fane?
I found a record for you.
Stravinsky. Very modern. Thank you.
Was there something else?
Yes. I was wondering if you could tell me
when the post comes through.
It's for Shanghai.
Unfortunately, since the cholera...
...the cowards won't venture
past the river port.
But leave it with me.
A local trader I know is making
the trip on Friday.
Townsend.
- Charlie Townsend?
- Yes.
He's an acquaintance of my husband.
- Do you know him?
- Years ago.
We were both assigned to
the consulate in Shanghai.
Charming wife.
Yes. They're very popular, aren't they?
He'd made a science of popularity.
- So you know his family?
- Well, well enough.
I like Dorothy.
Yes, I understand they're quite
the devoted couple.
Oh, he had his little flirtations.
Nothing serious.
I once heard her say
she found it most unflattering...
...that the women who fell for her husband
were so consistently second-rate.
Well, enjoy the record.
Mrs. Fane?
The letter.
Right.
Yes, it suddenly occurred to me
that Friday's much too late.
Thanks all the same.
Can you pass the salt, please?
I'm sorry, did you say something?
Could you pass the salt?
Thank you.
So this is how it's going to be.
Passing her evenings in silence.
Walter.
I wonder if you haven't gone insane.
- She's not cooking it.
- Leave it.
Leave it.
Thank you.
Are you looking to kill yourself?
Town well's contaminated.
This is dirty. It's dirty.
What?
Mr. Waddington?
Mrs. Fane? Mrs. Fane?
Mrs. Fane?
Come away. Come away.
What's the matter with Te-Ming?
You have the dead man on you.
They're very superstitious, aren't they?
She's lost three children and a husband
to the cholera.
So you can hardly blame her.
You know, this is no place for a woman.
When they telegraphed me that
you were coming out, I was astonished.
I imagined you might be
a grim-visaged old nurse...
...with thick legs and a moustache.
I came into the bungalow
and there you were...
...frail and tired and very unhappy.
It was a long journey.
But you're unhappy now.
And it occurred to me that you
and your husband might be madly in love...
...and you'd simply refused
to stay behind.
- That's a reasonable explanation.
- Yes.
But it's not the right one.
Do you know what I find strange?
That your husband should never
look at you.
He looks at the walls, the floor,
his shoes.
He has a great deal on his mind.
Yes, I'm sure of it.
Dr. Fane?
Oh, God.
All right.
What are you doing?
Martini?
Yes?
I'm the bearer of a message
from the Mother Superior.
Who?
The nun who supervises
the orphanage and the hospital.
I didn't know she was aware
of my existence.
Well, apparently,
Mr. Waddington has spoken of you.
She would very much like to meet
the loving, loyal wife...
...of the compassionate Dr. Fane.
Right. Then I must prepare myself
for the charade.
She does understand if you...
...don't want to venture into
the center of the epidemic.
If you're not afraid, why should I be?
I forgot.
Walter? Oh, my God.
You're drunk.
Don't expect anything grand.
They're miserably poor.
Hello.
It is a great pleasure to make
the acquaintance...
...of the wife of
our good and brave doctor.
Lovely to meet you too.
Mr. Waddington.
You must eat the madeleine.
Sister St. Joseph made them for you
herself this morning.
So tell me, Mrs. Fane...
...to which faith do you subscribe?
Excuse me.
We attended services.
Not religiously... Regularly.
You could say I'm a member
of the Church of England.
Which is an inoffensive way of saying...
...you don't quite believe
in anything much.
You're very pretty.
And very young.
I assure you I'm not. I feel ancient.
If Mrs. Fane would like to see over
the convent and orphanage...
...I shall be glad to show her.
Alone.
We keep the older girls busy with sewing.
It keeps them occupied.
And earns money for the convent.
That one won't allow us to baptize her.
Our music room.
Sister Maryse.
Sister Dominique was our pianist.
She died last week. Cholera.
Through there is the infirmary.
It is not a sight one would wish to see.
Shall I call Dr. Fane out to see you?
No. You needn't disturb him.
Now, with the epidemic,
we have even more to care for.
This baby was brought in this morning.
Another orphan.
She says Dr. Fane loves babies.
He spends as much time as he can
helping them out in the nursery.
Mrs. Fane?
You all right?
Yes.
It's nothing, only foolishness.
What do you want?
Sorry.
- I brought you your supper.
- All right. Just leave it there.
Is there something else?
What's that you're doing?
I am testing the nitrate levels
of a local tomato.
Why?
Can't possibly interest you.
Well, enjoy your supper.
Walter.
What do you propose we should do
if we get through the epidemic?
I have no idea.
But I don't think any good will come of
talking about a situation we should forget.
- But you don't forget.
- Please. I really must work.
Won't you listen to what I have to say?
All right. If you insist.
It's just, today...
...having been at the convent,
with those nuns.
What have they done, converted you?
No. They spoke of you.
- And it made me feel...
- What?
It made you feel what?
- I think I've been afraid of you.
- Well, you should have been.
Excuse me.
If I can't work, I'm going to bed.
I know you're angry at me.
But if we could just try and talk about...
Honestly, I don't understand you.
What is it that you want from me?
Perhaps I just want us to be
a little less unhappy.
You're mistaken in thinking I am.
I have too much to do
to think of you very much.
That's exactly what I'm trying to say.
I feel useless.
What do you propose that I do
about that?
For God sakes,
will you stop punishing me?
Do you absolutely despise me?
- No. I despise myself.
- Why?
For allowing myself to love you once.
Hello.
I'm very well. And you?
For you. And you.
I hope I haven't come
at an inconvenient time.
Sister Maryse died last night.
I've just written to inform her parents.
I'm so sorry.
But it is sinful of me to grieve...
...when I know that her good and
simple soul has flown straight to heaven.
How can I help you?
Well, I'm sure that
with the sister's death...
...you must be even more short-handed.
You see, I was wondering if I could
come to the convent...
...and do anything, just...
Just to help out.
My dear child, don't you think
you've done enough...
...coming here with your husband?
I've been here a month...
...and, believe me, I have nothing to do
from morning till night.
Perhaps I could help with the sisters
in the hospital.
That is impossible.
Cholera is a terrible thing to see.
Besides, what would happen
if you should fall ill?
I'd be happy to scrub the floors.
Anything. Just something to feel useful.
That will not be necessary.
The orphans scrub the floors.
No, no, it is our business
and our privilege to do such things.
But there is always more to do each day.
Have you spoken to your husband
of your wish?
Yes.
I don't know what you're saying.
I also found traces in the river,
downstream from the burial grounds.
- You've checked these results?
- I tested it three times.
Well, that's it, then.
I would recommend barricading
the bathing area.
Cut off all access to the river.
How far do you expect people to walk
for water?
I've no idea. Upriver, at least a half-mile
above the burial ground.
- That's too far.
- Nevertheless.
I agree with Dr. Fane. It's necessary.
Also, I thought we'd agreed
to post a directive...
...to dispose of the corpses immediately.
We've done that already.
If you don't enforce it,
then it doesn't matter.
Families are hiding bodies for days.
- They bury them too close to the river.
- I understand.
You don't have to explain it twice.
Colonel, I respectfully request...
...that you order your soldiers
to enter these people's homes...
...and remove the bodies by force
if necessary.
It's all right.
Hello.
I understand.
The spirits need access to the water.
I understand that.
I just want to move a few of these
so they don't live in the water.
He said they're under the protection
of their warlord.
If he wants to move the bodies,
he will send his own soldiers.
It isn't the best time for a Western woman
to explore a Chinese town by herself.
Oh, do be quiet.
As if you care whether I'm killed
by nationalists or boredom.
Besides, I wasn't alone.
I was with my gallant protector,
Sung Ching.
By the way,
you might be happy to know...
...that I am just as useless to the nuns
as I am to you.
I shut off the town's
only water supply today.
What will you do?
I have no idea.
Then I suppose we're both useless.
At last, something in common.
Dr. Fane. We've both been
caught out in the weather.
Not now, sorry.
I beg your pardon?
- Counting.
- Counting?
We'll camp here tonight.
What makes you think
this warlord will cooperate?
I don't think he will.
So, what do you plan to say
to persuade him?
I don't know.
These men are like animals.
They have no vision.
They only have hunger and strength.
Men like this have held the real power
in China since I was young.
But that time is coming to an end.
There's no place for them
in the new China.
I don't think you like my being here
very much either, do you?
I think China belongs
to Chinese people...
...but the rest of the world
seems to disagree.
Yes, but that's got
nothing to do with me.
I didn't come here with a gun, you know.
I came with a microscope.
I believe you.
But it would be nice
to do this work together...
...without your country's guns
pointing at our people.
Our plan is to divert
the water to the town...
...from the fields upriver,
above the burial grounds.
With your permission
and the assistance of your troops...
...the graves will be moved away
from the water...
...and Colonel Yu and his men will
enforce the prompt burial of the dead.
Maintaining the integrity
of the water sources...
...and enforcing proper sanitation
over the next weeks...
...will make a difference between
a few more deaths and possibly thousands.
He said no.
He doesn't speak any English, does he?
Tell him that's the most ridiculous suit
that I've ever seen.
I'm sorry.
Do not stop on my account
if Dr. Fane is enjoying himself.
No. No, not at all.
No, l... It's very nice.
I just... I was passing.
- No. Stay.
- I should go.
I insist.
- All right, if you like.
- Continue, Mrs. Fane.
But perhaps something
a little more soothing.
Yes, of course.
They brought in a new baby today.
The girls named her Zan Xien.
It means "brand-new."
The nuns are going to call it Katherine,
which, of course...
...none of the girls will be able to say.
Thank goodness for those nuns.
They do so much for so little in return.
I suppose you could look at it that way.
You suppose?
I think it might be
a bit more complicated than that.
They take in desperate children
and give them a chance at life.
What could be so complicated about that?
They also go to young mothers
in their homes.
They ask them to give their babies
to the convent.
They offer them money to support
their families to persuade them to do it.
They're not just here
to run an orphanage, your nuns.
They're turning those children
into little Catholics.
None of us are in China without a reason.
Still, on the whole...
...I think that what they're doing
is a pretty good deed, don't you?
I'm here to study bacteria.
I don't feel a need
to have an opinion about the rest.
Well, I do, and I admire them.
I don't think it has to be
so complicated and gloomy.
And I think what you're doing,
for instance, is incredibly noble.
You used to feel contempt for me.
Don't you still?
Walter. I can't believe that you,
with all your cleverness...
...should have
such little sense of proportion.
We humans are more complex
than your silly little microbes.
We're unpredictable.
We make mistakes and we disappoint.
- Yes, we certainly do.
- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry I'm not the perfect young woman
that you want me to be.
I'm just ordinary.
I never tried to pretend
that I was anything else.
No, you certainly didn't.
I like the theater, and dancing...
...and playing tennis. I like games.
I like men who play games.
God forgive me,
that's the way I was brought up.
I play a pretty fierce hand of bridge.
Oh, well, that's bloody exciting.
And you, you dragged me around
all those interminable galleries in Venice...
...blathering on about
the miracle of the canals...
...and the flushing of the lagoon system,
or some such nonsense.
Honestly, I'd have been much happier
playing golf at Sandwich.
I suppose you're right.
It was silly of us to look for qualities
in each other that we never had.
Yes.
Yes, it was.
Walter?
Why didn't you break down that door
when you knew I was in there with Charlie?
You might have at least
tried to thrash him.
He wasn't worth it.
Or maybe I'm just too proud to fight.
I don't know about that.
I've told Mother Superior
to keep her sisters inside the convent.
I put a guard outside the gate.
- I'd advise any Westerners to stay indoors.
- All right.
Sister, has Mrs. Fane
been at the convent today?
Oui, doctor.
But she has left a few minutes ago.
Sung Ching.
Let's go. Let's go!
Let's go!
Stop it!
Sung Ching! Where's Mrs. Fane?
Where's Mrs. Fane?
I don't know what you're saying!
Get away from her.
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
Come on.
We're out of whiskey.
Dr. Fane.
Could I trouble you for a drink?
Hello, darling.
I was stationed at Hankow
during the revolution...
...when they were massacring
all the Manchus.
I was able to help a particular family.
New documents, that sort of thing.
She was the youngest of the daughters.
I didn't pay her
too much attention at first.
Well, more than I should have, I suppose.
When I left Hankow, she followed me.
I sent her back two, three times,
but she kept coming back.
I didn't realize you had
so much affection for her.
What makes you think I do?
I can see it in your eyes.
Men are incalculable.
I thought you were
just like everybody else...
...and now I feel I don't know
the first thing about you.
I wonder what she sees in you.
Wan Xi.
She says I'm a good man.
As if a woman ever loved a man
for his virtue.
Morning.
I should think it best
to stay away from town today.
All right.
I'm going for a walk.
Come on, then.
What on earth are you doing
all the way out here?
Walking off a crippling hangover.
What are you doing?
Well, I've been attempting to purchase
a stalk of bamboo...
...off this fine gentleman here,
but his price is exorbitant.
My head is too shattered to negotiate.
- So would you like a ride home?
- On what?
The buffalo?
You see, we're diverting it
from these fields temporarily...
...sending it into the center of town,
where they can get at it easily.
It's over a half-mile.
It gave us a devil of a time in some places.
Oh, Mother.
Am I going to die?
Come, come. You mustn't be so silly.
Listen, ma chre.
Is it possible you are with child?
- No.
- Oh, yes.
- Yes.
I mean...
I suppose it's possible.
- There is no doubt about it.
- Yes. Sister St. Joseph knew at once.
She comes from a large family,
so she has experience in these matters.
I can't believe it.
Why can't you believe it?
Having a child is so natural.
Yes.
Think how happy your husband will be.
And what's happened here?
- I'm all right.
- They said you fainted.
- I'm fine.
- Let me look at you.
It's not cholera.
No. I don't think so.
Did you feel nauseous? Or just faint?
Walter, stop.
I'm pregnant.
A baby?
You're quite certain?
Yes.
Well, that's wonderful.
How long do you think
you've been like this?
Two months.
Maybe longer.
Kitty.
Am I the father?
I honestly don't know.
I'm sorry.
Well...
...it doesn't matter now...
...does it?
No.
No, it doesn't.
Dr. Fane?
Come with me.
- What is this? Where are they coming from?
- The cholera spread south along the river.
They have no doctors or facilities there.
They'll contaminate everything.
We've got to keep them outside town.
Dr. Fane.
Dr. Fane!
Stop. Stop. Stop.
Stop here. We can help you here.
Colonel, tell them not to go into town!
We'll help here!
Mrs. Fane.
Gather all the children in the music room.
Wait here.
Let's go.
That boy, bring him here. Bring him in.
I don't understand.
Why didn't he wake me?
He made an early start,
and you needed the rest.
- How far is the refugee camp?
- Just outside the town, in the foothills.
Dr. Fane told me he wanted you to leave,
but you would not.
I didn't want to leave you.
Yes, and we appreciate it, dear child.
But I think you did not want
to leave him either.
Well, it's my duty.
Duty is only washing your hands
when they are dirty.
I fell in love when I was 17, with God.
A foolish girl with romantic notions
about the life of a religious.
But my love was passionate.
Over the years my feelings have changed.
He's disappointed me. Ignored me.
We've settled into a relationship
of peaceful indifference.
The old husband and wife who sit
side by side on the sofa, but rarely speak.
He knows I will never leave him.
This is my duty.
But when love and duty are one,
then grace is within you.
Your soldier is waiting to take you back.
- I'd rather stay.
- No.
What? What is it?
What?
Mrs. Fane?
Mr. Waddington?
It's your husband.
What? What is it?
He's been taken ill.
Where is he?
Mrs. Fane.
- Walter.
- Oh, no. She can't be here. It's not safe.
- Waddington.
- I'm afraid I've got no say in the matter.
I don't want an audience.
You have to go.
- Your baby.
- Please, you must go.
Walter, tell me what I should do.
Slow that drip down.
It's running too fast.
Good, good.
Kitty? Kitty.
It's going to get much worse
before it breaks.
Are you prepared for this?
Yes.
What is it?
Can you send for more?
Kitty.
Are you awake?
Are you feeling better?
Forgive me.
Forgive you?
There's nothing to forgive.
Walter...
...l'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Mrs. Fane?
Dr. Fane would want
to be buried immediately.
Yes, of course.
What are you doing?
It's silly, really.
They'll die in a week.
It's hardly worth the cost.
- What do you think?
- I think they're quite nice.
Really?
I think you're right.
Come on.
We better hurry. Grandfather's waiting.
Kitty Fane?
As I live and breathe.
Hello, Charlie.
What are you doing in London?
I know it's been a long time.
I should have written.
Who's this fine chap? Hello, young man.
- What's your name?
- Walter.
Hello, Walter. I'm Charlie Townsend.
- How old are you?
- Five.
- Five?
- Come on, darling.
We should really press on.
Yes, of course. Well, it's...
...lovely seeing you again.
And you.
- Goodbye, Walter.
- Goodbye.
Kitty.
I'm in London for three weeks.
Perhaps we could...
Goodbye, Mr. Townsend.
Goodbye, Mrs. Fane.
Who was that, Mommy?
No one important, darling.