"Dashan Temple"
Seven Swords
Episode 38
Chu Zhaonan!
I'm here to take revenge.
You cannot beat me...
Go back!
"Liu Jingyi's Memorial Tablet"
Dad...
I am unfilial.
My martial arts are not good enough...
to take revenge for you.
Dad...
From Heaven...
give me the power...
to kill Chu Zhaonan.
Dad!
Do you hear me?
You have to help me...
to kill Chu Zhaonan.
Yufang.
Go home!
I cannot let you take revenge.
Yufang.
Yufang
You...
Yufang.
You were really going to kill Yufang?
First Brother...
- Speak!
Chu Zhaonan...
Let me ask you...
Why did you kill our jailed brothers?
You're interrogating me?
If I hadn't killed them,
I could not have entered the hall,
to try to kill Duo Geduo.
For this cause...
The old chief is dead.
Jiang Feian is dead.
How many more people will you kill?
However many it takes.
Until I kill Duo Geduo...
I will not stop.
Please explain yourself!
Chief.
Other people may not understand.
But how could you not understand?
My Dragon Sword was made to kill.
But not all of them were killed,
some were knocked unconscious.
If that was not the case,
they wouldn't have lived...
to condemn me.
And during the attack
did Duo Geduo make you kill our people?
What about Jiang Feian?
How did he die?
Jiang Feian?
Explain. Explain.
Why must I explain everything?
Once Duo Geduo is dead,
everything will have been worth it.
Tonight...
I will kill Duo Geduo in Qiantang Jiang.
If you are interested,
you can come and watch.
Chu Zhaonan...
Why did we leave Mount Heaven?
Do you still remember?
Why do we want to kill Duo Geduo?
Do you still not understand?
Master Shadow-glow once said to me...
Don't think about the past,
just concentrate on the present.
I'm saying this to you now.
Don't go to extremes.
Don't be too persistent.
This again.
Don't think about the past or the future.
I don't have any regrets in my life.
Go back now.
We can talk about this later.
Let's go!
Master...
Can a sword...
change a person's nature?
It's not the flag moving.
It's not the wind blowing.
It's your heart that is wavering.
Beware of evil inside.
Don't be too persistent.
This sword...
was given to me by my master.
He could not let go of his burden.
Since he has given this to me,
he has passed on his burden too.
If you put down your sword...
You may also put down your burden.
Listen...
You can hear the sword...
sing its lament.
Form does not differ from void,
nor void from form.
Form is identical to void,
and void identical to form.
So are inception, conception,
thought and consciousness.
That's right.
Form and void are one,
life and death are normal.
Amitabha.
Merciful Buddha.
You have seen it clearly.
You all saw that!
Chu Zhaonan
really wanted to kill Yufang.
"Dashan Temple"
Mulang...
Someone is following us.
Go and take care of him.
I will go with the others
to the warehouse.
Be careful...
We are close to the warehouse.
Don't let anybody know it's whereabouts.
It's you.
You said that if I could catch up with you,
then you would take me
to the Red Spear Society.
I'm worried that tonight will be a trap.
We cannot trust Chu Zhaonan anymore.
We lost many people last night.
Everybody...
has been waiting
for the seven swords to finish this.
I don't care if it is a trap.
We are going to fight
with Duo Geduo face to face.
We cannot and should not
escape this battle.
Let's do it!
Enough of this talk.
Xin Longzi.
- Third Brother.
You have forgotten your wine.
Step aside!
I want to see the chief.
Chief...
How long is this meeting going to last?
Don't we have things to do?
Brothers...
You needn't worry.
The seven swords
will finish this tonight.
Did you kill the person following us?
I did.
Come on.
Follow me.
The Dragon attacks well.
It will go here.
The Transience is good at defence.
It should go here.
Zhibang. Yuanyin.
You go at the sides.
Mulang can move
to wherever he is needed most.
Xin Longzi and I will be at the centre.
With this formation,
we can attack and defend very well.
I guess Duo Geduo will attack us...
with many soldiers.
As long as we stay united,
we can beat anybody.
In the past, Chu Zhaonan...
has always stayed in the middle.
Third Brother was always on the side.
If we change the formation...
Will he accept it?
I have thought about it.
Duo Geduo has always wanted
to control the Dragon Sword.
Let it stay on the side.
The soldiers will automatically
move toward it.
Then our whole formation
will become more flexible.
What do you think?
This formation is sound.
But what if Chu Zhaonan
really has surrendered to Duo Geduo?
Then Duo Geduo
will make the best of tonight.
Unless the seven of us are united
we cannot win.
This is the only choice we have.
And, Yang Yunchong still hasn't returned.
We must find him before tonight.
Where is Yang Yunchong?
If he wants his child back,
tell him to meet me at Liuhe Tower.
I know.
He must have gone to Liuhe Tower.
All right.
Let's prepare ourselves.
Then we'll go to Liuhe Tower.
Once we find Yang Yunchong
we'll go to Qiantang Jiang.
Xin Longzi...
Make sure you have enough wine.
Yufang.
Senior Fu said...
that your father was hit in the knees...
by a hidden weapon.
That's why he fell
onto First Brother's sword.
Yufang...
Yufang!
Calm down... Calm down!
Yufang...
Calm down!
Yufang.
Don't make excuses for him.
I saw it with my own eyes.
Yufang.
Take me to Qiantang Jiang.
I must take revenge for my dad.
No way...
In this mission,
everyone has their own responsibilities.
If you go,
who will take care of the children?
Believe me.
We will find out the truth.
If First Brother is responsible,
then I'll definitely...
take revenge for you.
Mulang.
My dad is gone.
He isn't with me anymore.
I have nobody now.
I have nobody left.
No. That's not so.
You have us.
Dad.
Zhibang.
Yufang...
I'm giving the belt to you now.
Tonight,
If I don't make it back,
you will have to lead
the Red Spear Society.
Zhibang.
everyone has their own responsibilities.
Your responsibility is to lead the society.
Don't worry...
I will take good care of the children.
I'll wait for your return.
Go now.
Get some rest.
There there.
Be a good girl.
Don't cry Baozhu.
You'll wake your father.
I wish you were my daughter.
Don't cry. Don't cry.
Don't cry Baozhu.
Don't cry.
Be good. Don't cry.
Don't cry. Don't cry. Don't cry.
Stop crying!
I'm sorry.
She's hungry.
She needs feeding now.
I have never thought of hurting her.
But you just don't believe me.
Fei Hongjin.
Don't say anymore.
I just want you to know...
I won't force you.
Take good care of her.
Don't let anything happen to her.
Her life is mine.
If anything happens to her,
I will hold you responsible.
They are waiting for you.
Yang Yunchong. Let's go!
The Transience Sword is not here...
You can use this for now.
Thank you.
Fei Hongjin...
I'm in your debt.
If I cannot pay you back in this life,
I will pay you back in the next.
I don't believe in reincarnation.
You'll have to pay me back in this life.
If you can't, then don't go.
Take care of Baozhu.
At midnight tonight, His Highness Duo Geduo
will await the seven swords at Qiantang Jiang.
What do you think?
Do you like tangerines?
I always dream about this tree.
But I cannot draw it very well.
You draw better than me.
You draw very well.
But because you only used black,
the picture lacked something.
Doesn't it look better now?
What's wrong?
I don't like it.
Come on. Try again.
Minghui.
Come on...
That's it.
Well done
Do you want to rest?
Your Highness.
Father.
Your Highness...
Please don't.
The soldiers are ready.
They await your command.
What has been happening?
Mr. Despicable has found the chief.
He is in the warehouse.
I have sent a team of soldiers...
to surround the warehouse.
We will eradicate the Red Spear Society.
Kill them all!
Yes.
Minghui is inside.
Would you like to speak to her?
Minghui.
No more killings...
No more killings!
Minghui!
Minghui.
He brought a sword.
He is here to kill you.
Go quickly. Go!
- Minghui.
Minghui...
Minghui!
Yang Yunchong...
You will die tonight!
Minghui.
You promised me...
that you would stop the killings.
Will you keep you promise?
I will...
after tonight, they will stop.
What will you do?
Kill Duo Geduo, or rescue Yang Yunchong?
Kill Duo Geduo.
Rescue Yang Yunchong!
Leave me alone!
I will decide my own destiny.
You have come.
Brothers,
our goal since leaving Mount Heaven,
will succeed or fail tonight.
Perhaps we should not
have left Mount Heaven at all.
Second Brother...
It's been a year already.
Do you still remember the reason
we left Mount Heaven?
To save people.
Save people.
That was just a pretence.
Think about it.
Since we left Mount Heaven,
whom have we saved?
No one.
What we have done, is kill many people.
We have killed and killed again.
The Dragon Sword is drenched with blood.
Your swords are blood stained too.
Only Senior Fu's sword remains untainted.
Tonight, we face a thousand soldiers,
Will your sword...
spill blood tonight?
Of course it will.
If Duo Geduo doesn't die,
there will never be peace in this world.
The dead will never be able to rest.
As for my own sins,
I may or may not find atonement,
that depends on Heaven's will.
Good!
Swords are made to kill people.
As swordsmen,
we shouldn't think too much.
There is only one truth we need to know.
A righteous sword,
always prevails.
You're wrong.
A sword is not good or evil.
It depends on who wields it.
I know you have suffered.
The time will come
for you to address that suffering.
But for tonight,
the seven swords
must be united in order to win.
Chu Zhaonan...
If you are still a swordsman of Mount Heaven,
then we'll go together.
Let's defeat the soldiers tonight.
And kill Duo Geduo.
Teacher...
Do you need to take a pee?
All right. No need to wake up Teacher.
Go on. Don't be scared.
The soldiers are here. Hurry!
Attack!
Quick, hurry.
Get the children out now!
Come inside quickly. Hurry!
Go on. Hurry!
First Brother.
Let's forget what has happened
this past year.
Duo Geduo is right over there now.
Come on. Let's take his head.
All right...
I'm here today...
to cut Duo Geduo's head from his body.
Good.
Let's go!