It's not the time to
start playing it safe.
Son, you have to drop.
That's playing to lose.
You got to listen to me.
I've been listening
to you my whole life.
You've got to put some pressure on.
How can a game
have such an effect on man's soul?
The way I see it,
how can it not?
You don't choose the
game. It chooses you.
And when it does,
life and golf become forever connected.
That's how it was for a young man
named Luke Chisolm.
You've got to be kidding me.
Once you make one mistake
out of the water there,
you just continue to
make the same mistake.
Are you hurt, son?
I'll get over it.
Yeah.
You the guy I saw
putting the flagstick in the field?
Yeah, and you the guy that
crashed through my fence?
Here. Let me help you.
Johnny Crawford's the name.
Yeah. Luke Chisolm.
Yeah, let me see that.
Yeah, look, put a
little pressure on there.
It'll stop the bleeding.
All right.
Yeah. Thank you.
I need to get you to my truck
to get you some medical
attention, all right?
So let's get these clubs up here.
You feel all right? You're not dizzy?
No, I'll be all right.
You're a hell of a driver.
373 people?
375.
Megan Monroe had twins last week.
Yeah. Haven't taken the sign down yet.
The evening service is just letting out.
Hey, how you doing?
I went this morning,
in case you was wondering.
Order up.
Let me guess. Same as usual.
You got it.
So are you all done there, darling?
How y'all doing here? Need more coffee?
Sure.
Oh, Sarah, I could use some more coffee.
Excuse me.
How you boys doing here?
You gonna save a dance for me tonight?
I'll think about it.
She's just playing hard to get.
Of course she is.
Mama, it's Uncle Johnny.
Hi, everybody.
This here's Luke.
He's had a small accident,
do we have that aid kit back there?
I'll get it.
Johnny, what in the world
happened to this poor boy?
Don't worry. He's gonna live.
Mercy. It looks like
you've been hit by a truck.
More like a cow.
You hit a cow?
No, I missed the cow,
but I did manage to
run through the fence.
Do you need a doctor?
No, ma'am.
I need a mechanic.
Here you go.
Sure. Thank you.
We need some strong hands
to get the car over to Brody's shop.
Jake, be a dear and help Johnny.
What about my burger?
The poor man's car just got wrecked,
and you're worrying about a burger?
Where are your manners?
Come on, Jake. Let's go. Let's go.
Jake, come on.
Have fun.
Come on, smiley. You, too.
Work some of that off.
Come on. Come on.
Let's go.
Hmm? Sarah?
Drive Luke to the inn.
I'd be much obliged. Thank you.
Sure.
There you go.
Just let me know whenever you're ready.
Mama, we'll be right back.
Thank you, ma'am.
Drive careful.
Are you right?
will this end in tears?
where you from?
Waco.
But I've been on the road
these past couple of years.
Yeah? Me, too.
Really?
Mm-hmm.
What for, school?
I'm training to be a horse whisperer.
I always thought horse whispering
was only in the movies.
But it's for real, huh?
Yep.
Well, good luck with that.
Thank you.
So where you taking me, anyway?
Oh, we're just going to the River Inn.
That's Uncle Johnny's place.
Are you two related?
No, he's just a close family friend,
but I've always known
him as Uncle Johnny.
Here we are.
Well, thanks for the ride.
Sure. You have to get
that from the outside.
Feeling it all as the wind blows
feeling it all as the time goes
do you feel my eyes
right there on you?
hello?
Don't you even think
about coming in here with those.
You must be the one
who ran off the road.
What'd you do, fall asleep at the wheel?
Well, come on.
I don't have all day to check you in.
Let's go.
And close that door behind you.
You're not bad looking.
Blind as a bat, maybe.
You married?
The neighbor girl's
looking for a husband.
No, ma'am. I'm not married.
Okay, now don't lose this key.
It opens the front door, too,
so you don't bother me
when you drag in late.
Yes, ma'am.
There's extra towels
in the cupboard there,
but it's okay to use the same one twice.
Breakfast is at 8:00.
Don't be late.
Hi, there. Thanks for teeing it up
with us here on golf central.
I'm Todd Lewis, sitting
beside Frank Nobilo,
and, Frank, we begin with
that unbelievable story
happening at the
Callaway San Antonio open.
Well, that's right, Todd.
Luke Chisolm is a name
that we've all had on our radar screens
ever since he won
the Texas state amateur championship.
Folks, if you have not
seen this highlight before,
sit back and enjoy.
It's something you will not forget.
The winner of this
tournament earns an exemption
into the Valero Texas open
just a few weeks from now.
Luke Chisolm had a one shot lead
on the final hole over Joe Buckner,
father Martin on the bag,
and look who shows up on the tee:
The number one player on the planet
and the tournament's lead sponsor, TKO.
What an intimidating presence.
Well, that's enough to
rattle anybody's cage,
and in this situation, Luke Chisolm,
he just blocks his tee shot way right.
His dad Martin wanted him...
- iron.
Whoa.
It's not the time to
start playing it safe.
Yeah, but if I make par,
he's gotta make birdie to tie me.
You're playing not to lose
instead of playing to win.
Here.
Remember who won the masters last year?
That guy over there.
Yeah, that guy over there.
Tko got his fourth green jacket.
Remember who come in second?
Nobody remembers the runner-up, Luke.
You can get on the green in two
if you hit it with the big stick.
That one hurt.
You wanna hit a few?
Your hand up to it?
Right into trouble.
Thread the needle with a 3-iron.
You bump and run it up on the green.
I think I should just
punch out right here.
You got to put some pressure on.
Hit the 3.
Hit the 3, huh?
Hey, mama, there's an easter egg hunt
at the church tomorrow.
Sounds like fun.
Can we go, dad?
You got some practicing to do tomorrow.
Martin, it's easter Sunday.
Sundays are reserved for golf.
Son, you have to drop.
That's playing to lose.
You gotta listen to me.
I've been listening to you my whole life
and this is where it's got me.
All right. Where you gonna put it?
I hope he brought a snorkel.
All right. Let's see what you got.
You gotta pull yourself
together here, son.
Am I embarrassing you?
You hooked it.
You gotta watch your right hand.
There you go.
Let it release.
Come on, now. Let's get started here.
Don't flip it. Come on, now.
Come on. One more good one.
In the hole!
Oh! Oh!
Give me another one.
You're playing not to lose
instead of playing to win.
Nobody remembers the runner-up, Luke.
God!
You gotta put some pressure on him.
Hit the 3.
He snaps his putter, flings the shaft,
and then the sad shot here,
his father Martin, walking away from son
on the final hole. Oh, my goodness.
He ends up shooting an 80 on the day.
We're going to look
at the one that started
what I believe was the meltdown
when he hit it into the hazard
and going forth from there, Frank.
What was going through his mind?
Well, I think he was still smarting,
tom, with the decision
he made off the tee,
whether to hit driver or 3-wood.
That's obviously still
in the back of his mind.
And once you've made
one mistake out of-
I had a feeling there was more going on
than meets the eye.
Wow. He chilled good.
What could I have done
differently instead.
Just hitting never
gets you out of trouble.
The problem is-
what do I got to do to
get some food around here,
kill a cow myself?
So really, this is farcical.
When you've got no chance-
wow.
That's no greenskeeper.
"Pga of America half century club. "
Hey, Luke, I was hoping you'd be here.
You can tote these.
Well, close your mouth, sugar. Let's go.
Well, where we going?
Hey, you're looking a whole lot better.
I'm feeling better.
You're in good hands with mabel.
I'll tell you what.
I'll feed you right, but
it's my brother Johnny
that you're gonna get the most from
if you're paying attention.
Now where is my dance partner?
Sarah?
Maybe you could just
introduce Luke around.
Oh, sure.
Hey, you feeling any better?
Oh, yeah. It's amazing what a shower
and some clean clothes will do.
You good with this, Duane?
Yeah, go on.
Am I ever gonna get to
see you whisper to a horse?
I don't do that just in
front of anybody, you know.
What about dancing?
You do that in front of anyone?
Hey, lookee here. It's tour boy.
Jake rustin, this is Luke Chisolm.
Yeah, we had the pleasure
earlier today at the diner.
Yeah, that was right before
I helped drag your
car out of a cow Patty.
Wasn't too happy about it at the time.
Then me and Sarah saw
you on tv, remember?
You're a regular celebrity.
Not every day I get to
help out a record holder.
Hey, Jake, be quiet.
Well, I had quite the meltdown.
Oh, yeah. I especially
liked that mud bath.
The golf channel, they
don't miss a thing.
Jake.
It's okay.
Just let him talk.
I'm sure he could
have done a lot better.
You play golf?
I can hold my own.
Yeah? On what course?
The kind with windmills, volcanoes?
Come on, guys.
All right, can we be social?
Let's play nice.
I never shot 16 on one hole before.
Yeah, well, it was a 14.
Sarah, it was a pleasure.
You wanna dance?
Leave it all behind
I didn't see where it went.
You hooked it.
You gotta watch your right hand.
Let it release.
Don't flip it.
Dad, it's getting dark.
Well, I can see just fine.
Come on, now. Let's finish
what we started here.
One more good one.
Come on, now.
There you are.
Hey.
Tough day, eh?
Yeah, I've had better.
Yeah, well, I saw you on tv.
I got to say it was painful to watch.
Try living it.
Believe it or not, I have.
I believe it.
I snooped around in your study.
Yeah? Well, I chased
the tour for a while.
Had my ups and downs.
You want an observation?
You were playing from back here, see?
Tournament golf has to
be played in front of you
where the target is.
That's a new one.
You have the mechanics.
You just don't know what it means
to play the game in front of the ball.
Well, I'm debating
on picking up a club ever again.
Well, I have a proposition for you.
Spend seven days with me in utopia,
you'll find your game.
Seven days? I don't know.
Well, it'll take you that long
to get your car fixed, you know?
So think about it, all right?
I'll be at the driving range
9:00 A.M. tomorrow morning.
Sarah.
Hey, Johnny.
I thought you could use some company.
Gonna be fireworks soon.
All right.
I also wanted to apologize for Jake.
His dad basically disowned him
after he chose the rodeo
over the family business.
He's got a warm heart, that's for sure.
I see.
You two together?
No. Everyone expects us to be, but...
I don't know, especially Jake.
So what about you?
Me.
Mom and I lost my dad
to cancer two years ago,
so I suppose I'm just...
Taking each day as they come.
I'm sorry.
"I suppose" means God
works in mysterious ways.
Johnny says he can help me with my game.
Think I should take him up on his offer?
Well, I think...
I think some time
here might do you good.
"Donations appreciated. God bless. "
Nice.
You got game, son.
You could have told me
you owned this place.
Well, you could have told me
what really happened to your putter.
What made you want to build
a golf course out here?
Well, originally I moved here
to get away from the game,
but easier said than done, I guess.
So you quit the tour?
Well, the game just wasn't a
good fit for me anymore. Yeah.
Okay, listen, let's get started.
I want to see you hit some, all right?
I want to see you swing.
These are a little better.
Yep.
Why do you grip the club that way?
Well, I don't know.
Just feels good.
Well, that's the wrong answer.
Now, let start from scratch, all right?
I need to know why you
do the things you do.
Like the foundation for your swing,
from the grip to the follow through.
Now go think about it and write it down.
The first step in finding a good game
is to find some conviction.
You got that?
Think about it.
How'd I end up here?
Unbelievable.
The toughest challenge you'll face
isn't the golf course
or even your competitor's score.
It's that casual comment
offered by someone, anyone,
about how you should be doing it.
If you don't have conviction
about where your foundation is,
that off-handed comment will
take you out of your game
and erode your confidence.
Now, you got that?
Yes, sir.
That's Ben hogan.
Yeah.
The one and only.
Place the club in my left hand
with my thumb down the shaft.
Place my right hand over my left thumb
and my lifeline.
That helps me cock my wrist
in my backswing.
That's good.
I do believe.
You're not from here, are you?
Well, not exactly.
I've lived in a lot of places.
Been around here and
there with the military.
No, I'm not from here.
How'd you end up in utopia?
You ask a lot of questions, young fella.
You really do.
I burned all my Bridges.
There was no place to turn but here.
A tour player like you,
the players you played with,
why here?
I'll tell you.
Paul Hawkins was a student of mine
way back when, that's Sarah's dad.
He was a good man
- a great man.
He let me stay with them while I...
Got my act together.
Been here ever since.
Did you get in some kind of trouble?
It's getting late.
I'm gonna see you
tomorrow down by the river.
Day break, all right?
What does the river
have to do with golf?
You'll see.
You will see.
Rhythm, balance, patience.
That's what you need
to stay in your game.
The same with fly fishing.
It takes a calm mindset
a focus on the feel,
rather than the outcome.
It takes emotional control.
Hey?
All right.
Tell me.
What was his downfall?
He took the bait.
Yeah, but why?
What made him fall into that trap?
I'm not sure.
'Cause he was hungry?
No, he was mad.
I teased him with a shadow casting,
never quite letting
the fly touch the water,
so I was able to take that fish
out of his game today.
Now, you ready to give it a try?
All right, remember.
To stay in balance in the skiff
or during your golf swing,
you have to control your emotions.
Okay?
All right.
Breathe, Luke.
Rhythm, balance, and patience.
Johnny, I got one.
Now catch it. Keep the tip up.
Keep the tip up. Take it as it comes.
All right?
Easy. Easy.
Oh!
Never fails.
Got him, Johnny.
Hey, good job, son.
Whoo!
How comes you always seem
to do things the hard way?
Good. Hey!
Come here. I want to show you something.
30 years ago, this
man named Jack nicklaus
took me out of my game.
You know how?
By staying in his game.
The calmer he was, the madder I got.
And I tried shots
I wouldn't ordinarily take.
Now, this look familiar?
A little hiccup on 18.
Well, at least you got
beat by the golden bear.
Yeah, and so would you have.
Ha ha ha.
Now tomorrow we actually
meet at the course.
Fifth fairway.
8 A.M.
I'm sorry.
It's not good to be late in life, son.
Time is too precious to waste.
I said I was sorry.
If this was a tournament,
you'd be disqualified.
Now, you wanna play like a professional,
you have to act like one, all right?
Now take a seat.
Take a seat.
Today...
We're gonna paint.
All right?
Paint?
All right.
All golf shots start
with a blank canvas.
We paint the shot with our eyes first
so our bodies can
reproduce it accurately.
Now...
What kind of shot could
you make from here?
Well, I think-
no, no, don't think.
See.
Okay.
I see a low punch eight iron.
Playing the ball back in my stance
with a slightly hooded clubface.
I can see the ball flying about 30 yards
with some hook-spin,
landing on the upslope of that hill,
bouncing up and going in the cup.
Okay.
Now go paint it.
Morning.
Just paying a visit to Paul.
Yeah.
Mama.
Hey, mama, you gonna be all right?
Just give me a minute?
Right, honey. You go have fun.
Take care.
Can't believe it's been two years.
Yeah.
I miss Paul most every day.
Whoa-ho-ho.
Hi.
Hey.
You look nice.
Well, thank you.
So your Uncle Johnny,
he's a real piece of work today.
Yeah, well, it's actually
kind of a rough day for all of us.
It's the second anniversary
of dad's passing.
It's okay.
Is there anything I can do?
Well, I was gonna ask you...
My father and I used
to go up to obra maestra
on his birthday.
I was thinking of going
out there later today,
and I could really use the company.
It'd be an honor.
Okay.
I see Uncle Johnny's
got you painting already.
Yeah, he does. I wasn't expecting that.
Looks like we're gonna
have to add another shelf.
Maybe one day there'll be
tour trophies on that shelf.
Ain't no maybes in this world, Luke.
You understand?
Yes, dad.
Good.
Now rephrase what you just said to me.
One day there will be tour
trophies on this shelf.
I'm counting on it, son.
I'm proud of you.
You ready, cowboy?
Obra maestra means
masterpiece in Spanish.
I can see why.
Sure is beautiful.
I might even go as far
as calling it utopia.
Yeah.
I suppose you might.
You ever think of living somewhere else?
Everything I need's right here.
I'm free to be myself.
Free to do the things I was born to do.
What is that?
Bring freedom to horses.
And the occasional stranger.
Come on.
Hyah! Move!
Jake.
Jake, you're coming too close.
You're gonna scare the horses.
Come on!
Whoa.
What are you doing out here with him?
I'm taking a ride.
I didn't know I needed your permission.
So tour boy, choke on anything lately?
Yeah, well, at least I
got a sport to choke on.
What do y'all play out
here, mutton busting?
You know what us tour boys say
about Hicks and sheep, don't you?
That's real funny.
I don't know who you
think you're talking to.
Boys. Hey, quit it!
Now, you're acting like
a couple of children.
Jake! Chuck, get him off!
You heard the lady.
Get off me!
How about you two hotheads
settle this over a friendly
little game of cowboy poker
after the rodeo tonight?
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the final event of the evening.
Hold on to your seats.
It's time for cowboy poker.
Introducing our players:
Duane Clint pickens
and Chuck baer, the usual suspects.
Four-time utopia rodeo
champion Jake rustin.
And our final player,
he's a first timer,
so let's give a warm utopia welcome
for professional golfer Luke Chisolm.
All right, boys, deal the cards
and let's get this party started.
Time to put up or shut up.
All right. What are we playing?
Texas hold 'em.
Yeah, but there's a catch.
You got to hold on to your chair.
Why?
You'll see.
The last man still in their seat
wins 200 bucks!
Watch out. He's got his sights set
on the usual suspects.
Chuck's all in.
Who's cannonball gonna go for next?
Watch out, slim!
Get your butt in the chair.
It's you and me.
See what you got.
Boys.
Whoa!
And the winner is the rookie.
Dang it!
Proud of you, son.
Hey, Luke, Luke, what's next for you?
Is it time to go pro?
Well, this hasn't even sunk in yet,
so I'm just gonna try to
enjoy this feeling and, uh-
he's a humble kid.
What he means to say is yes.
He will be turning pro.
Of course he'll be turning pro,
and we'll begin to look
for a sponsor's exemption immediately.
All right!
Good going, Luke. Yeah!
I'm sorry.
Yeah, I know. Laugh it up.
Hey, speaking of manure,
where'd the rhinestone cowboy go?
I was ready to gloat.
Well, Jake went off in a huff.
He's doesn't like to lose.
Well, that makes two of us.
Well, there's more to
life than winning, right?
Like what?
Family. Friendship.
Faith. Love.
Oh, yeah.
I guess those, too.
Johnny's got the horses hitched up.
It's time to go.
You know, cowboy?
Sometimes I think you
might just be hopeless.
Luke.
Get in here, smelly.
Come on in here.
I hung up your masterpiece.
You forgot to sign it.
What's this?
Oh, that?
That bottle's my greatest trophy.
No, let me explain.
It's the last liquor I ever drank.
Doesn't it tempt you?
No, just the opposite.
Makes me remember all the things I lost
because I drank too much.
That's why I put it there.
Is that why you quit the tour?
Well, more or less, yes.
More or less, yeah.
Pretty hard to drink and drive, eh?
Yeah.
Well, I'm sorry about this morning,
being late and all.
No, no, I'm not. I am not.
Learn how to paint your shot,
you learn how to be on time.
A professional golfer does both.
Now, sign your masterpiece, Picasso.
Where we headed, anyway?
Going to work on your putting.
Well, the golf course is back that way.
Uh-huh. Yeah, it is.
I thought you said we was
going to work on some putting.
That's right. That's right.
We are. Come on.
I hope you brought some of
your winnings from last night.
Well played, gentlemen. Well played.
Hear, hear. Keep practicing.
Well, look who he
dragged in here with him.
You a little stiff this morning?
Still sore I beat you last night.
You better watch it.
Enough of that, Jake, knock it off.
Hey, Jake, come on, come on.
Get the washers, all right?
Let's get the game
started here. Come on.
Same old Jake. Come on.
Okay. Now, the rules are simple.
The man who's up
pitches from behind the
marker of his choice.
Yeah, but I don't see what
this has to do with golf.
You just watch. Just watch.
Just watch. See?
Ooh! You owe me five bucks, boys.
You ready to give it a try?
Yeah, sure.
Come on. Don't make me look bad, now.
All right, it's on, boys.
There's not a chance he'll make this.
You gonna put your money
where your mouth is?
You're on.
Ho-ho!
Beginner's luck.
Here. Let's see you do that again.
All right. I will.
Everybody needs a woman's love, now
yes!
I like this game.
Crazy, cowboy.
Hey, knock it in, man.
Oh!
I'm gonna move
I got to work it on out
he's better than you!
Early in the mornin'
I play it for you more now
bend it on out
whoo!
Yeah! Yeah!
Come on.
Let's go.
We're even.
Come on, slim!
I like it like that  oh, come on!
Yeah!
I'm impressed.
Make me proud, son.
You make me proud.
Watch his form.
Right off the fingers.
I'm the rodeo king!
You know what I love
about the cowboy way?
Everything! Hey!
Whoo!
Okay, boys. Let's go. Let's go.
We're going to the links now.
We're gonna do some putting. Let's go.
Come on.
Pitching washers...
Give me an idea for a putting technique.
You're kidding, right?
No, no, sir.
I have a respect for tradition,
but I have a passion
for the truth, okay?
Now, here. Jake?
Yes, sir.
Use the face-on putter.
You use the traditional one.
5 to 1 on Jake.
Quiet in the peanut gallery here.
Come on, Jake. Help me out.
Get in the hole.
Get in the hole!
Yes!
It's gonna be a good day for me.
Good. Good.
You try.
Come on, rookie. Make me some money.
Oh! Oh!
Ooh.
Miss it. Miss it. No, no, no.
Yes!
I'm impressed.
You ready to give this one a try?
Here you go.
When in utopia, right?
Come on. Lets go.
More drinks for me tonight. Let's go.
Ain't no way.
Come on, now.
This look right?
No way. No way.
No-oh, yeah!
Let me ask you something.
Would you or could you
use this in competition?
I'd probably get laughed off the course,
but it definitely works.
Well, you keep it.
'Cause when the time comes,
you'll know when to use it.
Okay.
You have any kids?
No, sir.
That's one of my biggest regrets.
I saw your wedding photo.
Oh, you snooping around again, are you?
You snooping?
You're a super snooper.
I'm sorry.
You're a real snooper.
Well, that's a cool study room.
Pictures of all those legends.
No. Annie, my Annie,
couldn't have kids.
She used to joke that
she didn't need any
'cause she had me.
Yeah.
Well, if you don't mind me asking,
what happened?
Well, she's gone on.
Couldn't put up with
my drinking anymore.
Can't say I blame her.
Sorry to hear that.
Yeah, well...
Gone but not forgotten.
As they say...
All part of God's plan.
Yeah, I suppose.
Good night.
Night.
I'll see you in the morning.
You bet.
Let me guess.
This is where you drop me off
in the middle of nowhere.
And expect me to get back home
with the clothes on my back
and two golf tees in my pocket.
That'd be way too easy.
That's it. Wow.
Is this yours?
Yes, she is.
Um... you're not planning
on going up in this
thing though, are you?
Well, why not?
I mean, flying's a lot like golf.
Eh?
You said fly fishing
was a lot like golf.
Did I say that?
Yeah.
Maybe I did. You ready?
No way.
What?
I'm keeping my feet on the ground today.
Oh, yeah?
Whoa. I don't know about this, Johnny.
Let's turn back.
Your feet control
direction with the rudder.
The stick controls the wind and pitch.
Now, to turn, you press one foot
and you turn the wheel
in that direction.
And to go up or down, push or pull.
Got it?
Okay.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Okay. No hands, see? Like this.
You're doing good.
All right. I'm getting
it now. I'm getting it.
I think I'm getting it.
It's like riding a horse.
Keep her steady.
Uh-oh. What's...
What? Wait, wait, wait.
What just happened? What-Johnny?
Hold on. Hold on.
What happened?
We have an emergency.
Put the plane down.
Johnny, you take it. You take it.
You take control of this aircraft, son.
All right?
I don't know what to do.
Keep the nose down and level the wings.
Okay. All right?
All right.
That's good. Good.
How's that? All right.
We should try to go back, shouldn't we?
No, we can't get back.
We'll have to find a place around here.
Come on. Come on.
There's a wheat field.
All right. Good.
You're doing great, son.
Keep your wits about you, okay?
Level your wings. You
got 500 feet to go.
How about that?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You're doing great.
Steady. Steady.
Steady. Bring it in.
Bring it in. Steady.
Keep the wings level.
Okay.
Leveling my wings.
Is this good? We good?
Great. You're doing great.
Leveling. Leveling.
Bring it in. Bring it in.
Coming in. Coming in.
Wait.
Wait. What happened here?
Goodness me.
The engine turned off.
Did you turn the engine off?
The engine turned off?
Is this your idea of a sick joke?
Why are you laughing?
Confidence comes with
being prepared, my son.
As in golf or life hand in hand.
I'm about to throw up over here.
You can't play in a tournament
unless you're ready for the unexpected
on game day.
It smells delicious.
Mabel's trout's famous around here.
More famous than her pies?
Couldn't be more famous.
As famous, maybe.
But more famous?
For food in a world
where many walk in hunger,
for faith in a world
where many walk in fear,
for friends in a world
where many walk alone,
we give you thanks, o lord. Amen.
Amen. Amen.
He definitely puts the game first.
Reminds me of someone
else I used to know.
That he does.
Hopefully he finds his
way quicker than me.
Hey, there, stranger.
Hey.
So when's the last time
you caught a firefly?
Well, I don't know.
Since I was a little kid.
Well, that's too long.
Come on.
She has Paul's gift.
She always was a daddy's girl.
It's okay.
Hey, Sarah.
What?
These ones in here quit making light.
That's 'cause they know they're trapped.
It makes their lights go out.
Watch this.
Freedom's a powerful force.
Not yet.
I'm sorry.
No, I-
it doesn't mean never.
It's gonna... It's gonna rain.
Ready for today's lesson?
I can only imagine
what you got in store for me today.
Yes, sir. Today we play golf.
Good. What should I hit, a driver?
No, no, no, no.
Today we visit the history of the game
and its future.
You're gonna be playing
with hickory sticks
and a face-on putter.
Ooh.
Not bad.
Perfect.
S.F.T.
One for you.
See it. Feel it.
Trust it.
Little butter cut over that left tree.
How far?
About 310.
210.
What's the course record?
Well, you ever shot a 59?
You keep playing this
way, you just might.
Weather permitting, of course.
Yes, sir. Boom.
Not sure we can get this round in.
There ain't nothing stopping me.
I'm seeing it, feeling it,
and trusting it.
It's time to wrap it up, son.
It's not the time to
start playing it safe.
We got one more hole.
No, no, no. 59 doesn't matter, Luke.
It's matters to me.
That's not the lesson.
That was never the lesson.
You spent the whole week
teaching me how to play
the best golf of my life.
Now I'm playing it.
All right. Well, you don't have
to prove anything to me, Luke,
because I'm not your father.
You don't know anything
about my dad, so back off.
No, you can't spend your life
trying to validate
yourself with a golf score.
Well, how would you know?
It looks to me like
you quit on your dream,
living out here on this
God forsaken goat ranch.
And this is your dream today?
This? This is your dream?
You can lead a horse to water,
but you can't make him drink.
I'm sorry, Johnny.
I forgive you, son.
Whose grave you digging?
You'll soon see.
What's yours gonna say?
Mine?
Yeah, your epitaph, your headstone.
What do you want people to say about you
when you're gone, huh?
Maybe it'll say you shot a 59.
Huh?
I never thought of it like that.
Maybe we'll just leave it blank for now.
No. I mean...
I'd want it to say...
Something.
It will.
But I don't think that
your coming here...
Was an accident.
But only you can decide
what to do from here on out,
'cause, I mean,
there's nothing more
I can teach you, son.
Thank you, Johnny.
No, don't thank me.
Thank him.
'Cause God is all around us.
Inside of each of us, if you listen...
There's a still small voice of truth
leading us...
Talking to us,
and telling you
that you...
Can see God's face...
Feel his presence...
Trust his love.
Yeah.
S.F.T.
Huh?
God bless you.
Happy easter.
Luke, inside this box
is a pencil and two pieces of paper.
One is for writing down
all the truths you learned
during your time here in utopia.
The truth that life is
about faith, relationships,
character, and integrity.
That God has a purpose
and calling for you
that is much deeper
than a little white ball
falling into the cup.
These truths will become
your new heartbeat,
the foundation of your new life.
The other piece of paper
is for writing down all the lies
you've been told during your life.
Lies like your golf score
being a reflection of your true identity
and self-worth,
or that failure in golf
is failure in life.
Take the truths with you,
but bury the lies right here, right now.
Once you have buried your lies,
chisel your living epitaph.
Today I found myself
after searching all these years
and the man that I saw
he wasn't at all
who I thought he'd be
I was lost when you found me here
I was broken beyond repair
then you came along
and you sang your song
over me
it feels like I'm born again
it feels like I'm living
for the very first time
I'm living for the first time
it feels like I'm born again
it feels like I'm living
for the very first time
it feels like I'm breathing
it feels like I'm moving
for the very first time
in my life
all ready to go, are we?
Yeah, I think so.
Don't think.
See, feel, trust.
Yeah.
Now, before you leave,
I have something for you.
I have something here.
Well, you've given me
more than I can repay, sir.
Well, gifts aren't meant to be repaid.
They're meant to be passed along.
Look at this.
That was my last tournament.
You notice anything?
Huh?
Well, you're not on the leaderboard.
Yeah, that, but no.
Look again. Look again.
Look.
Oh, it's the Texas open.
Right.
That's this weekend.
Yeah. The tournament's main sponsor
is an old friend.
He says as a personal favor
he'll offer you one
of his free exemptions.
All right?
Huh?
Man.
I don't...
I don't know what to say.
Well, I think, between you and me,
it's all about the ratings.
He's probably hoping you
have another meltdown,
and I'm hoping that
you can prove him wrong.
Yeah.
Well, you can count on it.
Oh, yeah.
Now, don't go running
over any of them cows,
because I don't want you to ruin my pie.
Well, don't worry.
I can see a little better now.
Yeah, you can.
Okay. God bless you, son.
God bless you.
Aw, I'm gonna miss you.
I'm gonna miss y'all, too.
Thank you so much for everything.
You bet.
Got you a little gift.
Just keep the lid off it
and you can come visit
whenever you want.
Well...
Till next time, then.
Next time.
You need any more putting lessons,
you just let me know.
Hey, tour boy.
Well, if you need some lessons
on some cowboy poker,
well, you're just gonna have
to figure it out yourself.
Johnny.
Yeah.
Thank you for everything.
No, I wanna thank you for everything.
I really do.
Yeah.
And, son, I do believe.
Okay?
Yes, sir.
God bless you.
Thank you.
Let's get you something to eat.
Yes, mom.
Hey, bud.
I got you a little present.
Callaway's latest and greatest.
Thanks, dad.
Luke, uh...
My actions last week...
Were wrong.
I pushed you your whole
life to succeed at golf,
and I never once asked
if that's what you wanted.
I'm sorry for that.
Well, I forgive you.
I only want what's best for you.
I know.
I love you, dad.
I love you, too, son.
Well...
Ain't looked at mine in a while.
Might be overdue.
Good night, son.
Welcome home.
Hey, dad.
Yeah?
I almost forgot.
You wanna caddy for me
this week in the Texas open?
Welcome, everyone,
to the pride of the lone star state,
the Valero Texas open.
I'm Kelly Tilghman
with pga tour winner Brandel Chamblee.
A compelling story this week, Brandel,
was the sponsor invite, Luke Chisolm.
How does one go
from oblivion to center stage?
This man knows, Kelly.
In his first pga tour event,
he has a chance for redemption.
Now on the first tee,
from waco, Texas, Luke Chisolm.
Round two and three
saw heated action atop the leaderboard.
Some of golf's biggest names
pining for the lead.
Rich beem, Stewart Cink,
TKO, and Ricky Fowler.
Come on, TKO!
This pressure-filled Sunday
at the Texas open
offers an abundance of characters.
Stewart Cink, four
time masters champ TKO,
and we have a local
talent with fresh wounds.
The surprise performance
coming from Luke Chisolm,
just two weeks removed
from that complete meltdown
at the lone star event in San Antonio.
And now, he finds himself chasing,
of all people, TKO,
atop the leaderboard.
And, Kelly, you really
couldn't script it
any better than this.
No. No, you can't Brandel.
We've seen cinderella stories before,
but we've also seen
what TKO has done to
those glass slippers.
He has crushed them.
And we pick up with Luke Chisolm
now on the 10th tee.
Let's hit 3-wood.
Fairway's a little tight.
Chisolm playing it safe here
with the 3-wood on this
very reachable par 5.
That's okay, Luke.
And that shot will very likely
put some demons in his head.
It was a shot almost identical to that
that started his monumental blowup
a few weeks ago.
Luke's gonna have to
conquer those demons
if he wants to win,
and that's one of the
toughest things to do in golf.
Well, what you want to do, son?
Go back to the tee.
Head up, Luke.
Well, it's gonna be
one heck of a par, dad.
Oh, you got it.
Having taken an unplayable
lie on his first drive,
Chisolm is now back on the tee
hitting his third shot.
Looks like he's going
with the driver this time, Brandel.
And Kelly, I don't know why
he didn't use driver
the first go around.
He hasn't sniffed missing a tee shot
all week long with that
callaway octane driver.
Perfect!
Exactly as he has all week long.
See you in the clubhouse, boys.
Y'all play well.
A par after taking an unplayable
could be a turning point for Chisolm.
This Sunday has given
us a great leaderboard.
Rich beem capable of a big charge,
question marks surrounding Luke Chisolm,
and TKO as intimidating as ever.
But it looks like we're
winding down to just two.
A classic David and Goliath story
between Chisolm and TKO.
Chisolm from 12 feet...
And he sinks it!
Luke Chisolm just one back of TKO.
You know he's licking
his chops right here,
not only to make birdie,
but to put the pressure on TKO
to do the same and avoid a playoff.
Remember, TKO eagled
this hole yesterday.
And now Luke Chisolm
with his second shot
to this par 4 on the 18th hole.
Yeah!
The pressure is really on TKO now.
He has no choice but
to go for the green.
This one's looking good, Brandel.
It's on the green
with a chance at eagle.
He makes it look easy,
doesn't he, Kelly?
What an answer by the
steely veteran TKO,
who drove the green.
If he makes this eagle putt, he wins.
And how's this for excitement?
Tko and Chisolm are headed to a playoff,
both men tied at 16 under.
And TKO has the upper hand once again.
He's never been defeated in a playoff
on the pga tour,
and Luke Chisolm, his
first taste in extra holes.
They're going back to the 18th tee,
where anything can happen.
Tko and Luke Chisolm
are about to tee off
on one of the greatest risk/reward holes
in all of golf.
And earlier, Brandel had a chance
to take a closer look at this
tremendous finishing hole.
The finishing hole here is a great one.
A drivable par 4 of 355 yards
that plays downhill
and gives the players a lot of choices.
But those choices come with risks.
The green is protected
by a tree and a bunker
and a treacherous water hazard.
The green itself is
very narrow and fast,
with a lot of slope in it.
And a two-putt from above the hole
is highly unlikely.
But one of the worst places
that a player could drive the ball
would be long and to the left
in that area there,
because an up and down
would be almost impossible.
And his pitch shot
would most likely run off
the front of the green.
And there you have it, folks.
This hole provides the perfect stage
for the drama that's about to unfold.
Well, no surprise here, folks,
that TKO has taken driver out.
Obviously trying to make an eagle
and win this thing outright.
But in doing so, he brings
double bogey into play.
Tko lives for moments like this.
And TKO is one of
perhaps just 10 players
who can drive this green.
We saw him do it just
moments ago in regulation.
Oh, it sounds like he crushed that one.
Yeah, it's a good looking swing.
Always in balance.
It took off on the right line.
But there's more wind now
than there was earlier.
He's getting more help,
and with his high ball flight,
carrying that creek
should not be a problem,
but holding this green will be.
Oh, look at this.
This could be serious trouble.
That's the danger zone
Brandel was just describing.
Luke Chisolm going with
the conservative play,
iron off the tee.
No surprise there, Kelly.
He's stuck to that game plan all week,
and with only one exception
has he strayed from the fairway.
He's looking to put this ball
in a spot where he
gets the right number,
gets a wedge in his hand,
and he can put the pressure on TKO.
Luke seems relaxed.
Is this the same player
from two weeks ago?
No, it's not the same player.
He may have the same swing,
but a completely different outlook.
What do we got?
75 yards?
Just like in regulation.
Yeah.
Lob wedge.
Thank you.
This is the same shot
he had just a few moments ago,
however, the situation
is entirely different.
He knows that given TKO's lie,
he could win this tournament.
Whereas a few moments ago,
he was chasing.
See it.
Feel it.
And trust.
Not quite like his
holeout in regulation,
but under the circumstances,
a very solid shot.
If TKO was looking for a gift
from an inexperienced Luke,
he didn't get it.
Tko has a nearly impossible pitch.
He's looking at a tight flag,
the green is running away from him,
not to mention the water.
Anything short of hitting that flagstick
and he's probably going swimming.
Plain and simple here, Kelly.
He needs to play away from the hole.
It's a pretty safe bet
that's going to have
a longer birdie putt
than Luke's 8 footer.
The ultimate test for TKO,
but I wouldn't put it past him.
He's done it before.
Look at him sizing this up.
It almost looks like-
and he is, I think,
gonna go right at this hole.
This absolutely makes no sense to me.
If he doesn't hole this,
it's very likely that this ball's
gonna run off of the green.
This would really be something.
And he's got to aim
right for the flagstick.
Anything short of perfect here,
he's looking at bogie at best.
That's if he's lucky
enough to avoid the water.
The only way to pull this shot off
on that line is with a lot of speed
a lot of spin,
and he has to land it in an area
about as big as a dinner plate.
And it looks good.
It's got a chance.
Remarkable!
He's unlucky, Kelly,
that that ball didn't go in,
but lucky that it stayed on the green
and gave him about a
15-foot putt up the hill,
and maybe he can put
the pressure on Luke.
And look at him. He's not even phased.
This is a makeable putt for TKO.
Is this where experience pays off?
Generally speaking, first in
in a playoff wins.
And if he makes this, I promise you,
that hole will look
a lot smaller to Luke.
How many times has TKO
been in this exact spot
and emerged victorious?
It's that mental edge
that makes him the
great player that he is.
He thought he had that one.
Tko's tee shot
left him with a lot of stress.
His second shot left
him with a lot of work.
And now it's Luke who
has the work to do.
And TKO no longer has control
of his own fate.
That control lies with Luke Chisolm.
It was a great par
for TKO just to stay in it.
But now the door is open
for Luke Chisolm to win the Texas open.
One can only imagine what's going on
in the mind of Luke Chisolm right now.
Two weeks ago his career was over,
and now he is one putt away
from taking the Texas open
and beating the best player in golf
in the process.
Luke knew this putt was meaningless
in the big picture.
He was now answering
to a higher calling.
It was time to go to a
place beyond tradition,
to a place of buried lies
and unearthed truths.
A revolution had begun
within Luke's soul.
He had a purpose and a calling
that went beyond any scoreboard.
He saw, felt, trusted,
and stroked the putt of his life.
Utopia is defined as a
place of mythical perfection,
but I knew differently.
Utopia is indeed real.
It's a place where the
voice of truth resides
and eternal trophies line the shelves.
A place where there are no accidents.
I guess you're asking yourselves
whether or not he made the putt.
The better question is,
does it really matter?
How can a game have such an effect
on a man's soul?