Previously on Shades of Blue...
Loman!
A video game?
I heard shots. They sounded real.
You heard them too, right?
I'll protect you.
It wasn't a clean shoot.
You don't say.
There's a new bookie.
You collect, and then you
give him the rundown.
- Get on the ground.
- Lower the weapon,
- Detective Santos.
- Police.
It's you who's under arrest.
Provided your cooperation
leads to convictions,
We'll grant you full immunity.
Look, if you planned this whole thing...
Thinking I was gonna rat out my crew...
You have a daughter, don't you?
Look, the crew's gonna
be hitting the street.
I can't. Cristina's car got hit.
Her friend borrowed it and
smashed in the front end.
You never said anything
about wearing a wire.
There's a camera in the stone.
What's the matter?
Every betrayal begins with trust.
There's a rat.
There's a rat!
An FBI informant on my team.
I need to kill it.
And I need to kill it.
And you're gonna help me,
Because you're the only one I trust.
How do you know this?
Just tell me everything
that you've heard.
How many years...
Have we been working together?
Since Cristina was six.
That's ten years.
Is that how long it takes before
you really know someone...
Is ten years?
Eight?
Espada's been with me for eight years.
What about Tess?
15 years.
That's a long time.
Stood up at weddings, at funerals.
What about six?
Tufo and Saperstein... almost six years.
Six years apiece.
That's six years of roll call,
Of tough arrests, stakeouts...
Six years of seeing crime
scenes that you're never,
ever gonna unsee.
If it's too hard to believe, it's...
Probably not true.
45 years.
That's 45 years...
of friendship,
of loyalty.
Boss...
What is it really?
What is it that has you suddenly
so convinced that someone
would do this to us?
Yo, Red Simons keeps calling.
A black sedan with white fenders
has slow-rolled past his liquor store
three times in the last hour.
All right. So have dispatch send a car.
They did, but Red says
since he pays protection,
he wants one of us to
go and hold his hand.
- Now?
- 15 minutes, max.
I mean, I'd go, but I already had a few.
You know. What you want me to do?
- I'll take you.
- Harlee, no.
You and I will go.
You notice any of the team
acting different, agitated?
We're cops. Agitation
comes with the job.
Ducking shifts, private calls...
You know what I'm asking.
I can't believe this is a real question.
I have it on good authority, Harlee.
And this authority definitely
puts an informant in our crew?
Yes.
The feds deal in fear.
When people are scared,
they make mistakes.
I hand-picked this crew.
I know them. I can read them.
We pay attention,
and the decent part of this person,
the part that, deep down,
wants to be discovered...
It's gonna reveal itself.
Are you hearing this?
Come on. A liquor salesman
needs some coddling.
Can't two patrolmen coddle him?
You know, 20 years ago, a car
goes rolling by twice...
Didn't Tufo say black
import, white fenders?
Get down!
You all right?
- You're hit.
- No. I'm fine.
I'm fine. Call it in.
It's heading West on 68th street.
- Just one shooter?
- Yeah, the driver.
Single-grip shotgun.
Was he shooting at you or the store?
Does it matter?
Two officer-involved
shootings in three days?
You might want to start
wearing Kevlar in the shower.
- Too soon?
- Copy that.
Guys, guess what?
Two more liquor stores shot up
ten minutes before this one.
One's a drive-by.
Black import with replacement fenders.
This sounds like our menace.
Intentional or not,
nobody's gonna take a
shot at me, my crew,
or anybody else, all right?
Nobody goes home until we put
this son of a bitch in cuffs.
All right? I'll take the heat,
but we got to get this shooter.
Oh, speaking of shooters...
Harlee, you're gonna be with me, okay?
We'll work command at the precinct.
I heard our team numbers on the scanner.
- Where do you want me?
- When we all leave,
I want you to go over
to the doughnut shop.
All right? Just stay there.
What am I looking for?
You'll know it when you see it, okay?
Yes, sir.
- I'll be back in a minute.
- You like doughnuts?
- No, sir.
- You don't like doughnuts?
What kind of cop is he gonna be?
- Restroom?
- Employees only.
Keep it that way.
You messed up.
Can you hear me?
You have no idea what you're doing.
He knows there's a mole.
There's a leak on your end.
You're gonna get me killed.
Yo, I don't care, man.
Just keep walking.
- Come on, man.
- So you're saying
you were at your girlfriend...
What are you doing? That's
just gonna hurt you.
Listen, can Linda drive you to practice?
Because you know I hate
you dragging that cello
on the subway.
Did you get any sleep?
Not really. A little.
How about you?
I'm making breakfast.
I'm sorry, what'd you say?
- INCOMING CALL UNKNOWN
- Coward-ass police!
- Who is that yelling?
- Nobody, baby.
A concerned citizen.
- We're making juices.
- I'm sorry, baby.
I can't hear you.
Never mind.
I'll talk to you later. Be safe.
Okay.
You gonna answer that?
Somebody needs help.
Probably shot by a cop.
Santos.
One block North on Garfield. Black SUV.
But we need to debrief now.
Just tell them that you're
gonna get a cup of...
coffee.
Special Agent Stahl?
SA Molly Chen.
I've been assigned to your detail.
They're all working,
snatching collars, looking for
the liquor store shooter.
Well, there's nothing
like sleep deprivation
to make an informant crack.
You rule anyone out yet?
It can't be the rookie.
He killed a guy on his second shift.
The FBI would've pulled him.
- That's five left.
- No, four.
Tess, Espada, Tufo, Saperstein.
And Harlee.
Well, you're looking at everyone, right?
No, Donny. I forgot how to work a case.
I'm just saying you have
a blind spot for her.
A detective starts with
the most probable.
The FBI profiles potential informants
long before they pick them up.
They're looking for the most resourceful
with the most to lose and
the biggest secrets.
Who is that in your unit?
Lieutenant Wozniak, James Nava,
your new assistant district...
hang on a minute.
- Tufo!
- I'm on it, I'm on it.
Loman's at the doughnut shop.
He thinks the theater
across the street might
have some security footage.
Go help him extricate it.
- Yeah, you got it.
- And don't sleep.
Yes, sir.
Got a few calls in to you.
Look, I'm swamped, man.
Me too. Public defender just
published a tell-all about
his drug addiction.
92 of his guilty clients
immediately filed habeas corpus
petitions for new trials.
All right, so what are you
hounding me about it for?
You supervised four of the cases,
going back as far as 12 years.
Hey, so my frequent flier over
here just mentioned a kid
named Stroke flossing a
dark Sedan, custom rims.
Is Stroke the name on
his birth certificate?
You should meet his
brother, heart attack.
His real name is Clarence Morris.
He has a registered Sedan that
matches our partial plate.
There's no one at the address.
- Put Tess and Espada on it.
- Okay.
Heart attack... why would I say that?
Well, she has that effect on everyone.
Don't worry about it.
I need archive files and your notes.
Dibble, Foster, Girard, and Zepeda.
Miguel Zepeda?
Yeah, he has a decent chance
of getting out of prison.
You remember him?
He's one of the douche bags
I have a special place
for in my heart.
I'll swing by tomorrow.
Evidence techs recovered 12-gauge slugs
from all three liquor stores.
A miracle there weren't
bodies to scrape up.
Hey, what is it?
It's just some old business.
NEW YORK CITY POLICE - INFORMATION
IN THIS RECORD IS CONFIDENTIAL
Are you afraid?
Should I be?
How well do you know Miguel Zepeda?
More than I'd like to.
Why do you ask?
He claims that you
framed him for murder.
Look, I haven't seen Miguel
since he went to prison.
And when was that?
Six years ago. Grand theft auto.
You have a daughter, right?
She's six years old, right?
It's interesting math.
THIS WAS NOT THE DEAL...
DON'T TEST ME.
Were you the responding
officer last week
on a homicide at prospect park?
Yeah. A homeless girl got stabbed.
Four times.
But there was no murder
weapon found on the scene.
Yeah. Looks like.
Define epic sex.
I don't know. Over an hour?
Damn, Joe.
Good for you. Oh, no, no, no.
Joe slept through it.
Son of a bitch's phone lit up at 2 A.M.
"Amber Blue Dock Bar" wanted
to know if my husband
wanted to have some late-night
fun, so I obliged on his behalf.
No, you didn't.
Eight ways from Sunday.
Oh, that's messed up.
I mean, it's hot, but it's messed up.
- You've got to talk to him.
- Oh, and say what?
Yo, Joe, I boned your girlfriend.
Best sex I had in months.
- High five.
- I'm serious.
Serious enough to break his legs for me?
Yeah, if he actually did something.
- But you need confirmation.
- Confirmation?
You want to read the sick
stuff this bitch said?
Absolutely. But that's not the point.
Sexting is one thing,
but actual, physical,
fleshy contact... that's another thing.
Oh, no, no, no. Still cheating.
Well, technically, you're the
one that did the typing.
- Police!
- NYPD!
Police!
Stroke! Stroke, you in here?
Hands above your head, now!
Police! Get off the girl!
Off the girl! Hands up!
Wozniak received $50,000
laundered through a casino.
Have you linked that to a
specific illegal activity?
Not yet.
But his whole crew is dirty.
At some point, Wozniak's
gonna have to share
whatever his greater ambition
is with somebody he trusts.
And I'm betting it's her.
She looks angry.
Yeah. Well, so am I.
Are you completely incompetent
or just straight-up crazy?
You are my asset.
That means when I call you,
you pick up the phone.
You blew it on your end.
You have a leak. Now what?
You want me to slap a sign on my back?
There is no leak on my end.
There's only a few people
in the Bureau that even
know there's an investigation going on.
Then stop calling me.
You're not giving me a choice.
You destroyed the surveillance necklace.
- You haven't checked in.
- I wore it as long as I could.
Yeah? And what have you told him since?
- Who?
- You know who.
Harlee, if you think
there's some play here
where you tell Wozniak
that we've approached you
and you beg for his forgiveness,
that's not going to happen.
Trust me, if I knew you were
gonna blow it like this,
- I would have.
- No one has outed you.
If you're worried about the
strike team that arrested you,
I cleared them. They're solid.
Someone's talking.
Wozniak's Intel is limited at best.
Otherwise, he would have acted already.
Let me find out what he knows,
but we need to develop
some kind of protocol here
while I requisition another wire.
Requisition?
What kind of operation
are you running here?
My life is at risk because of you.
My daughter's future is
at risk because of you.
Now leave me alone.
Give me a chance to survive
your incompetence.
Agent Chen, draw your service weapon.
Excuse me?
Detective Santos feels
her life is at risk.
We're shutting down.
We're making the arrest.
Draw your weapon now,
Agent Chen.
You've got about 85 yards to decide
how you're gonna spend
the next ten years.
A bluff this size is
above your pay grade.
75 yards.
What do you want me to say?
You're really gonna blow
your whole operation?
Oh, look. Friends across the street.
Okay. Fine, fine.
You win.
I win what?
I'll follow your protocol.
And do what you're
told when you're told.
Whatever I'm told.
Two days operational,
and your informant is compromised?
Nervous, not compromised.
Wozniak doesn't know
anything definitive.
Only that we accessed his inner circle.
If I didn't think you had a strong lead
in what could be a significant
public corruption case,
I wouldn't have
authorized the operation.
But if your informant is in danger...
Detective Santos was
having second thoughts,
and that's to be expected.
We work through them.
By ordering an agent
to pull a gun on her?
I did what I had to do to
keep the operation alive.
Just give me 24 hours to find the leak
and get her in line.
In another life, I was NYPD.
I knew Harlee Santos as a rookie.
If Wozniak didn't get his hooks in her,
you could be working for her.
Well, I'll try to remember that.
24 hours.
If only I had an informant
with your enthusiasm
for backstabbing.
She was at risk. I
followed the protocol.
Four months putting this
operation together.
You almost blow it up in four hours.
Seems like it was already blown up.
Look, at Quantico, protocols
may be hard lines.
Out in the field, protocols are margins.
We push them, because
the other side will.
I understand. I've already
asked to be reassigned.
Well, that's a really bad idea.
Why?
'Cause this case is gonna make you.
I'm not talking till
somebody give me some pants.
Listen, you want pants?
Pants are what we call an
accommodation, all right?
Gangsters that shoot at cops...
you guys don't get those.
Do you want to help yourself?
I want to get out of here
and into some pants.
- That our guy?
- I didn't shoot at no one.
Listen, the only reason
you're still breathing,
Romeo, is because you didn't hit anyone.
I was with my girl all night.
I swear.
Strap me to a lie detector.
Hey, Tess, there goes an idea.
Why don't we strap your husband
to a poly, and if he passes,
then you let him keep his phone?
I wouldn't put it past the bastard
to stick a tack in his shoe.
You know, I once had this wheelman
that tried to beat the lie
detector by slathering Bengay
all over his junk.
That's an interesting strategy.
Well, pain spikes the heart
rate on the control questions.
It confuses the machine and
throws off the results.
Did it work?
I never hooked him up.
He said that he would confess
if I let him wash it off.
Creative police work.
Yeah, I've been known to improvise.
James Nava, your new ADA.
Yeah. I caught that.
Do you believe in coincidence?
Depends on the coincidence, I guess.
Well, for example, say...
Two days ago,
a police officer responds to a homicide.
An anonymous call comes in
and places the murder weapon
in the car of her ex-boyfriend.
Did you lift a knife
from the crime scene?
Absolutely not.
Did you plant the knife
in Miguel Zepeda's car
to keep him away from your daughter?
No.
Do you remember this
domestic disturbance call?
- What's up?
- Our rookie came through.
The boys upstairs pulled a still
frame from the theater camera.
Loman's still there?
Oh, yeah. Eyes still peeled
at the doughnut shop.
Didn't even ask if he could go home.
He knows we're messing with him.
- It's a battle of will now.
- Yeah.
Well, Loman's will just got us
a partial view of the shooter.
There's a woman out there
looking to post bond for you,
only she ain't your girl, Yessi,
and she's too young to be your mama.
So let her post it.
I'm not stupid enough
to shoot at the police.
Oh, but you're stupid enough to cheat.
It's not like that.
I'm loyal. Been with
the missus ten years.
Oh, ain't she lucky?
- I didn't shoot at no cop.
- Let me see your arm.
Our shooter has a tattoo on his wrist.
Well, I'll take my apology in cash...
small bills.
I'll make this brief.
This still frame tells me
that you're not our shooter,
but what it doesn't tell me is
why the shooter was in your car.
You clear that up, maybe you go home.
I... I sold the car, all right?
Off the books.
Well, why don't you give
me an off-the-books name?
Reggie.
Hothead gunslinger, holes
up on 61st and 5th.
- Cristina.
- Mom.
Someone shot at a police officer?
No one was hurt.
What are you doing here?
I thought you could use
a change of clothes.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I figured you had caffeine covered.
Hey!
Backup has arrived.
Hey.
Did motor pool fix your car already?
No, they said it's gonna
be a few days still.
You want me to lean on them?
I can manage the subway for a week.
You know what? Why don't
you meet me at my desk,
and I'll grab my things, and we'll go.
Yeah. Good lesson.
Never loan your wheels to your friends.
Oh, I don't loan it out.
- I'm not allowed.
- Well, I would hope so.
Not after they smashed it.
Who?
Your friends.
No. Someone backed into it
when it was parked on the street.
You know what? The activity log is done,
so I'm gonna take her home, okay?
Oh, I can't.
I was heading to Amy's to
work on a science project.
Speaking of which, I need supplies.
Okay. Supplies it is.
I'll grab my bag and we'll
go to the hobby store.
Mrs. Lowrey was gonna take us,
but some cash would be great.
Here.
Science is on me.
That's a 50.
It's all right. It's only money.
Thanks, uncle Woz.
So I should be home by 11:00,
but I'll text you if we go late.
- Okay.
- 10:30.
- Bye.
- Bye, gorgeous.
We need to take a drive.
I thought we found our shooter.
No, there's a new development.
Looks like Reggie should've
used some of that car money
on a decorator.
Well, we all have our priorities.
It's clear. Har?
Do you think this guy did the
shooting to make a statement?
Maybe he needs a hug.
Maybe he couldn't help himself.
Mood stabilizers... lithium.
And the shotgun.
The American way.
Is she starting to lie to you?
Cristina.
I hope she doesn't
ever feel the need to.
Wait a second. Am I going nuts?
You told me that her
friend smashed the car.
Look, I just let her story slide.
I figured it was better
than interrogating her.
You might learn things
you don't want to know.
Kids never listen anyway.
You got to model the important things.
Yeah.
Like how to get a sucker
to spot you a 50.
Like not to rat on your friends.
We should polygraph the crew. Yeah.
We can act like it's
about a missing payment,
then when they're hooked
up, straight-out ask them
about the feds.
Quickest way to know what's real.
Get down!
Police! Down!
Nice shooting, Tex.
Didn't the Marines teach you
to aim for the big circle?
If he wasn't mentally ill,
he'd be meeting the coroner.
As it is, he'll be seeing
the physical therapist.
You okay?
Go home and rest up.
I'll round up the crew and tell
them to come over for dinner.
I'm kind of exhausted, Woz.
It's your polygraph idea.
- My house at 8:30.
- Tonight?
You'll be able to sleep otherwise?
Oh, Joe's gonna be working late tonight.
Doesn't need me to wait up. What a guy.
At least that shouldn't
be too hard to verify.
Well, I shouldn't have to.
Why don't you just talk to Joe?
If I have that conversation,
I don't know where it ends.
So you just grin and bear it.
No. We make a detour.
- For what?
- Housekeeping.
- What are we doing here?
- Go take a leak, all right?
Amber?
Yeah. What are you drinking?
PBR and a tequila shot.
PBR, tequila shot.
Little rude not to text on the
day after, don't you think?
I'm sorry. Day after what?
Oh, come on. Don't play coy.
Do I know you?
Seriously?
We had sex last night.
I mean, you thought it
was my husband, Joe,
but trust me, honey, he would
never dine at the Y that long.
Did I pull your hair too
hard when I was behind you?
Look, bitch,
I don't know what you're talking about.
No? Let me jog your memory.
Do you remember now?!
Tess! Tess!
- Stop!
- Two kids!
- Two beautiful kids.
- Hey, hey!
Police business, all right?
This never happened.
It's better for both of us.
Trust me.
Let's go.
What, you and your girlfriend broke up?
Way to show some restraint.
That was restraint.
Hello, Harlee.
I told you to stay out of my apartment.
It's a very nice apartment,
especially for your pay grade.
Did anyone see you come in here?
My associate followed
Wozniak to his house.
He's probably in his barcalounger,
scratching his crotch.
Well, she missed the polygraph
equipment that he snuck in.
We're testing the whole crew.
Tonight.
You couldn't talk him out of that?
I suggested it.
Big move.
I thought he was looking at me.
I wanted to appear like
I was just as concerned
as he was... on his side.
Paranoia leads to over-thinking.
Over-thinking can get you
in this kind of trouble.
Wozniak confided in you
as soon as he knew,
and you have to own that, Harlee.
You have to own that trust.
I didn't think he'd agree to it.
I thought he'd want to be more careful.
- Is he testing you?
- No.
Just everyone else.
And they'll pass.
This actually could work in our favor...
Give him reason to doubt his Intel,
and you can nudge him
into another reality.
Suddenly, there is no informant.
Or someone has a bad day,
gets nervous, indigestion...
God knows.
If he gets a false read...
Just hope no one else in
your crooked little family
is hiding any secrets.
Hey, killer.
I almost forgot about you.
You here to relieve me?
No, I think the one
place we know is secure
is the doughnut shop, Loman.
So what is this? Penance?
Initiation. Stand down.
We booked the shooter.
Hey, doughnut boy?
An apple fritter for my friend here.
No. I'm good. I'm good. Thanks.
Hey, and an orange juice.
He logged some genuine
detective work today,
and all without shooting anybody.
There's hope for you yet, bro.
So what's the story?
Liquor store shooter.
I don't track the whys and
the what-fors, Loman.
Oh, my bad.
I thought you were a detective.
- Oh, it's like that?
- Yeah.
- Yeah?
Well, listen up. Intentions
aren't the point.
The street is an us
versus them situation.
It's best you understand that.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Where'd you grow up?
Don't even, man.
No, we... we are not
social workers, Loman.
I mean, if I'm chasing some
thug through my old hood,
the only color he sees is blue.
Shouldn't we want to change that?
- You want change?
- Yeah.
Yeah? Yeah? Become a
kindergarten teacher, Loman.
Funny.
They give us a gun and a badge
and dropkick us into calamity.
By the time I pull my cuffs
out, the die is cast,
and that's funny to you?
Look, I'm just saying,
we're meeting these
people at their worst.
No, do not put your guilt on me.
Or yourself, for that matter.
You killed a man, and he was black.
There it is.
Yeah, he also was slinging dope
and had a gun pointed at you.
We had to put the brother down.
That was his call, not yours.
- You don't know what I did.
- I know you're still breathing, Loman.
I know the politicians and the crybabies
that want to stand around the sidelines
and criticize how we do our job
never had to do our damn job.
Or had the sack to try.
Listen, man. You ain't...
you ain't hearing me.
The public don't give a damn
about your vulnerability in the street.
That's not interesting.
What it feels like to...
to bust through that door.
You think they care?
All that matters is that you get
home the same way you showed up.
- Same way I showed up?
- Yes.
The same way you showed up.
The same way I showed up.
Same way I showed up.
I don't think that's possible.
Hello?
Woz?
Have a seat. I'll be right there.
What, do you have everybody
tied up in the basement?
I changed my mind.
Even with a decent cover story,
we'd still be tipping them.
I'll just clear you tonight, Harlee.
Linda has me on green tea.
I made enough for two.
I'll get it. No rush.
I have to hit the bathroom.
The sooner we start,
the sooner we're done.
You can poly me if you want, Woz,
but I'm not gonna do
it on a full bladder.
Where is Linda, anyway?
She's talking her sister
through this week's crisis.
Can't let her know I have a polygraph.
She'll want to use it on me.
Nothing to hide, nothing to fear.
No one else has gone in?
Not since he's gotten home.
Hello?
Who's this?
I said don't answer it.
Put Cristina on the phone now.
It's not funny.
Pick up. Pick up.
Pick up, Cristina.
Mom, I'm fine.
Where are you?
We finished our work early and
went out to meet some friends.
That's all.
I'm not mad. Just tell me where you are.
Bushwick, I think.
Baby, you're not old
enough to be in some...
Hello?
Mom?
Hold on. I can't hear you.
When did you get to be 16?
I'm gonna go find somewhere quieter.
Baby, listen to me.
Don't get in a car where
someone's been drinking.
Mom... you hear me?
Can you hear me?
Make your own decisions.
Think big.
Don't... don't sell yourself short.
You're the most talented
girl in any room.
Mom are you there?
Never settle.
And never hold back.
I can't hear you. I'm gonna hang up.
Okay?
And some day, have a daughter.
She'll be the best part of your life.
Mom, I'm headed home.
Don't ever forget.
Hey, Harlee, you okay?
Yeah. I'll be... I'll be right out.
Don't take it personally, Harlee.
I need a good night's sleep.
No, I get it. Basic police work.
Start from the inside
and work your way out.
Doesn't mean I won't give
you crap for it later.
Well, I hope so.
We should call this in.
He could know it's her.
Or maybe they're having dinner.
You willing to bet her life on that?
She's a good liar.
What's your full name?
Harlee Grace Santos.
What's your badge number?
You think I framed my ex-boyfriend
for a fight we had seven years ago?
- Just one?
- No.
Miguel could run hot.
Things could get loud.
We had thin walls and nosy neighbors.
He ever get physical with you?
You see any charges?
Here.
Have you ever received
an unsanctioned gratuity
while working as a police officer?
Yes.
Who pinned your detective badge on you?
You did.
I used to like when he got jealous.
Can you believe that?
But I knew I had to get
away from him, and...
I was searching for a way out,
when I found out I was pregnant.
I almost lost the baby.
I tried to get away.
But he threatened to kill me.
And I knew he would.
And then a miracle.
Miguel got sent down
for grand theft auto,
and my whole life changed.
You know, I wasn't scared anymore.
But six years later, he got out.
I was already a cop,
so I knew I could handle him.
But he didn't come after me.
He started hanging around
Cristina's school.
Watching.
Taunting.
Just...
Like, letting me know that he
could control me at any time.
You know what I see?
I see a woman...
Pushed past her limit.
You did what you had to do
to protect your daughter,
to keep Miguel away from her.
I would do anything to protect Cristina.
Are you now or have you ever
been an informant for the FBI?
No.
I don't need you to confess.
I already got you.
You're the responding officer
to the murder that you're
framing Miguel Zepeda for.
Miguel Zepeda.
The paper trail leads right back to you.
This is a big mistake.
You can explain the theory to my lawyer.
Lawyer can't help you, Harlee.
But you could help yourself.
Erase the trail.
How would I do that?
Trust the right person.
Something I should know?
I never doubted you.
Yeah, you did.
You got to trust the right people?
Right now, that's just you.
You hungry?
Famished.
But I got to go.
Cristina ran off to some
club without telling me.
Why didn't you tell me?
Would've seemed like an excuse.
Now it's done.
See you tomorrow.
Are you now or have you ever
been an informant for the FBI?
No.
Did you plant the knife
in Miguel Zepeda's car
to keep him away from your daughter?
No.