Hey, it's me.
Pick up.
Hi.
Come in.
Drink?
No, thank you.
Perfect.
This way.
Slowly.
Hey, it's me.
Pick up.
Brandon?
Brandon, where are you?
Brandon? Brandon?
Brandon?
Ugh!
This is me calling you.
Fuck!
"I find you disgusting.
"I find you inconsolable.
I find you invasive."
This is what
the cynics used to say.
Companies would refuse
to look into the future.
They would say,
"Can we stop this virus?"
As if it was
a negative progression.
But it's growing.
More and more,
with a momentum that is unstoppable.
Now some kid snorts
the entire load of his mother's spice cupboard.
Post that on YouTube.
They would watch
as it becomes the buzz word
amongst high school
students everywhere.
Eventually, the cynicism
is turning into awe.
Do you know what's going on
with my computer?
They took it.
Yeah, I know.
Someone could have told me.
Some kind of virus.
Cool.
Thank you.
Okay, me again.
I'm dying. I have cancer.
I have one week to live.
The very worst
kind of cancer.
Of the vulva...
Hey.
You're such a dick.
What are you
doing, man?
All right, gentlemen.
If you just please make yourselves at home.
Thank you.
It falls upon me
as your beloved boss to propose a toast.
To success.
I just hope my wife
appreciates it.
Get a new tie, please.
Jesus Christ.
Oh, my goodness.
I love women in suits.
We could talk business,
I would rearrange my life.
Wow, she's beautiful.
Gray suit?
I'm gonna go talk to her.
Count me down. You should go talk to her.
Yeah, you should.
5, 4,
3, 2, 1.
Boom.
Have fun.
20 bucks says
he fucks it up.
Incoming.
Hi, excuse me. Listen,
I don't want to beat around the bush.
I think you're absolutely gorgeous.
My name's David.
Hi, David. Elizabeth.
Nice to meet you.
Elizabeth. That's
a beautiful name.
Hi, I'm David.
I don't mean to be rude. Loren.
Hi, how are you? David.
Nice to meet you.
Rachel.
Listen, can I buy you a drink?
Can I buy you all drinks?
Sure. Why not?
I would love that.
That would be my pleasure.
What are you guys drinking?
Well, we were thinking shots.
You were thinking shots?
We just did shots of tequila.
Would you guys like a shot of tequila?
Bring it on.
Love it.
Excuse me. Bartender?
Can we get 4 shots of your finest tequila?
Thank you very much.
I can see you're
very successful.
I think part of the secret to my success
is attention to detail.
Detail?
Play the game.
What game?
Okay.
Blue or green?
I like games.
I like this game.
Blue. Green.
Green, it's green.
That's brown.
Wow, wow!
I don't know how you
change the color of your eyes like that.
How do you do that so quickly?
That's amazing. That's a real talent.
Detail man.
Hey, buddy.
This guy, right here,
fucking nailed it today.
I want you to know you fucking nailed it.
You're the man.
Your pitch, amazing. Listen,
we're playing a game here.
Close your eyes again.
Blue or green?
Brown.
Fuck off.
All right. You, Loren,
close your eyes.
Blue.
You're just making that up.
See? He's good.
He's just picking
colors randomly.
You can have
his shot.
Excuse me. We need
another shot, please.
You can put
these on me.
No, I told you,
I had it.
No, I have it.
I'll get the next round.
Sure.
You're a strong, independent woman.
I like that.
Thank you. Cheers.
To nailing it...
To nailing it.
...and to success.
Yes.
Mmm!
I love that.
Oh, fuck.
Whoa!
So what do you
girls do for fun?
Fun? Karate.
You hear this song?
I love this song, I wrote this song,
I would love it
if you would dance with me
to this song
that I wrote for you.
Come on. Let's go on the dance floor.
One song.
Yeah, come on.
You're a fun girl. It'll be fun.
I'll bring her back.
Swear to God. Come on, come on, it's fun.
Toe to toe
Dancing very close
Spinning, spinning,
spinning...
Whoo!
I'm grabbing her purse
'cause she's gonna get robbed and roofied.
Dance?
No.
Are you sure? Okay.
I'm sure.
Wall to wall
People hypnotized
And they're stepping lightly
Hang each night in
Rapture
Okay, okay,
okay! Hold on.
I just gotta talk
to you one more time.
Listen, your eyes,
they're beautiful.
You know why I didn't get it
right the first time?
Because it's like a collage.
Let me see them again.
Look at those eyes.
I know the color of your eyes!
David! Come on!
Come on,
we love that game.
That's so much fun.
It's okay, 'cause
I'm going this way.
Hey, man,
he's going uptown.
Come on.
Okay.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Hey. Want a ride?
Sure.
I want your love
I want...
I'll fucking kill you!
What the fuck?
Ow! Fuck!
Jesus Christ, Sissy!
Fuck! Brandon,
don't you fucking knock?
What the fuck?
Why would I knock? I live here!
Oh, fuck!
How'd you get in?
You gave me
fucking keys.
Fuck.
You fucking scared me.
Don't I always say
call me first if you're coming into town?
Oh, my God!
I called you so many times.
You have a fucking
baseball bat?
Yeah.
Hmm.
What is this shit you put in your hair?
Honestly, it's awful.
Shampoo.
Is it for grooming dogs?
I want your love
Good to see you.
Lock the door next time.
Yeah.
Don't use all the towels.
I won't.
I want your love
But I want you.
I don't want anyone else.
There is no one else.
I love you.
I'll do anything.
Please don't say that.
I love you.
I'll do anything.
I don't have to go out!
I don't even fucking
want to go out!
I can stay with you.
I don't care. I don't care.
I don't need anybody else.
I love you.
I love you. I love you so much.
I love you, please.
I love you.
Please.
I feel sick.
I feel really sick.
Morning.
Nice earring.
Hot date?
Juice?
Mmm!
Will you use a glass?
Sorry.
You're going gray.
Do you think
I look fat?
Sit down.
Fuck you!
I'm doing
a couple gigs.
Yeah. Sure.
Can I stay?
You want toast?
Just for a few days?
I'd stay with Mark,
but he's being a fucking asshole.
Mark?
Please.
Jesus, Sissy.
What do you expect?
Pretty please?
Look, you get the sofa
and you get your ass off it
before I leave
every morning.
I will. I promise.
I will.
Okay. Okay. Okay.
We leave in 15.
Okay!
Mmm! So good!
Stop fucking around.
Leave it.
You have fluff.
I like it there.
How are you for money?
I'm good.
'Cause if you need some money...
Honestly,
I even make money
now and everything.
Yeah, sure.
Huge amounts.
What, you collect
it in that hat?
You should come
and hear me.
Yeah, I will.
"Yeah, I will"?
Like, "Yeah, I will,"
like last time?
Please come.
Where'd you get
this, anyway?
It's vintage.
Yeah,
I can see that.
Wow.
Do you like?
Yeah.
Please come.
Okay, I will.
Yay.
Sorry.
Fuck, my computer.
Well, well, well.
Morning, asshole.
Look who's decided
to grace us with his presence.
Yeah.
Don't tell me.
No cabs.
No, your wife wouldn't let me
leave this morning.
Hey. That's not cool.
You should be so lucky.
Any calls?
Yes. Like, 50.
Hey! Heads up, buddy.
Whoa!
So, how'd it
go last night?
Got home, went to bed.
Good night.
Uh-huh. Right, right.
Let's do it again tonight.
Some place classier, though.
Yeah, my sister's playing
downtown somewhere.
She's playing?
She's a musician.
Well, she's a singer.
Okay. Yeah, yeah.
You know what? That sounds like a lot of fun.
And that will
ruin your enamel.
That elevator music's
like a bad acid trip.
Good evening.
Evening.
Reservation. Sullivan?
Great. I have you on the list.
I'll have you follow me?
Thank you.
There you are.
Right this way, please.
Wow, look at that ass.
I could follow that forever.
Nice pick.
Oh!
I forget how
beautiful the city is.
Thank you.
Hi, guys. How are you both doing tonight?
What can I get you?
Your accent.
Are you... You're from...
Brazil.
Rio? Hmm?
Sao Paulo.
Oh!
That is a beautiful city.
That's...
You've been there?
Once or twice.
Can we get two
dry martinis with olives?
Mmm-hmm.
And a little bit later,
why don't you come by for a drink with us?
I'll make sure
I get those drinks.
Thank you.
Thanks.
She would be
so offended if I didn't try.
Unbelievable.
Start spreading the news
I'm leaving today
I wanna be a part of it
New York
I wanna wake up in a city
That doesn't sleep
And find
I'm king of the hill
Top of the heap
These vagabond shoes
Are longing to stray
Right through
the very heart of it
New York, New York
If I can make it there
I'll make it
Anywhere
It's up to you
New York, New York
I wanna wake up in a city
That doesn't sleep
And find
I'm king of the hill
Head of the list
Cream of the crop
At the top of the heap
These little town blues
Are melting away
I'll make
a brand new start of it
In old New York
If I can make it there
I'll make it
Anywhere
It's up to you
New York
Wow. Wow! Bravo!
She's good!
Hi.
I'm David.
Sissy.
It is a pleasure to meet you.
Nice to meet...
I think you are
absolutely fantastic
and you look great
in the dress, too.
Please, sit down.
Thank you.
What did you think?
Yeah, it was interesting.
What do you mean?
No, it was...
It was good.
It was good?
He was crying.
There were tears
coming down his face.
I saw it. You made
a grown man cry.
Really?
Mmm-hmm.
I'm gonna
get some drinks.
That's a great idea.
Why don't you get a round for the table, buddy?
Okay. I'm really
sorry about that.
He's had a rough day at work.
I think he's a little bit emotional right now.
Yeah.
So you guys
grew up in Jersey?
Yeah.
You still live there?
God, no.
That's good. That's good.
Where do you live now?
Kind of all
over the place.
Yeah?
What's the last city
you've been to?
L.A.
Los Angeles?
Mmm-hmm.
Oh, boy.
You like it there?
I mean,
I'm going back.
That must mean
you love it then, huh?
No! I can't even
fucking drive.
Wait a minute.
You can't drive? It's a nightmare.
Nope.
Why not?
I tried when I was a kid
and I was horrible.
Wait, how old were you
when you quit driving?
16.
You were 16 years old?
Mmm-hmm.
So, wait a minute.
How do you get along in Los Angeles?
I take the bus.
No. No, no, no.
Look, a girl like you
cannot be taking the bus.
What happened
to your arm here?
Oh!
When I was a kid,
I was bored.
You must have been
really bored.
I was.
All right,
we've got a problem.
Your sister cannot be
taking the bus anywhere, okay?
I know a guy who owns
a car rental company.
We're gonna get you a car,
we're gonna drive around in circles
in a parking lot and you are going to
learn how to drive.
Not stick, automatic.
It's a little easier.
I would love that.
You'd love that. That's good.
You know what? Better yet,
we're gonna get
you a golf cart
and you will drive
the golf cart around.
Wow. Now we're talking.
Everybody should drive golf carts.
A golf cart right up
Fifth Avenue, huh?
You know, they should.
They should.
It would be a lot
cleaner and greener.
It would be great for the city.
Brandon,  what do you think?
Sounds great.
Yeah?
I love your brother.
What an amazing man.
How long are you here for?
I don't know.
You don't know?
Can I see you again? Please?
Is that too forward? I find you fascinating.
I really do.
I think you're a fascinating creature.
I'd love to see you again.
Listen, why don't we...
This is a celebration,
let's get champagne.
Yes! Champagne!
Champagne for everybody.
The whole table!
Come on.
Champagne.
I've got it, I've got it.
Get out, get out, get out.
Come here,
come here, come here.
No!
Come on,
come on with me.
Get off. Get off.
How did that work?
Get off me.
Come on, come on.
Champagne on
your dress, that's...
Well,
I'm hot, I'm hot.
You are hot.
You are?
No!
You're crushing me.
I need to take this off.
I'm hot.
I need to take it off.
Nice sheets.
Aren't they nice sheets?
Bed Bath & Beyond.
Stop.
What if I kiss you
right here?
How about here?
Yeah?
Shit.
Mmm-hmm.
What?
Stop talking!
I have to be up
and out by 7:00.
It's cold.
Sissy,
get out of my room.
Get the fuck out!
Get out!
Hey, slacker.
Your computer's back.
Dave's looking for you.
Yeah. It was
really great last night.
Daddy, Daddy.
Listen, I gotta go, okay?
Thanks for calling.
Hey, buddy. Listen,
we said an hour French,
and then Isobel's
gonna pick you up
because Mommy's
picking up Nathan.
All right?
You can go after.
Yeah, I know,
but Mommy says I can't.
Okay. Well,
let's go talk to Mommy. Hmm?
She's all the way
downstairs.
Well, go downstairs
and tell her
that Daddy said
it's okay for you to go to Jason's.
Huh? Come on.
How about that? Do it.
You can do it. Get up.
Okay.
Yeah.
Mommy? Mommy?
What's up, man?
Steven said
you wanted to see me.
Yes.
Dude, 9:00 this morning,
where were you?
Dentist. Root canal.
Oh, shit.
Now, what did I tell you about that?
Who did you see?
Gary Sher, King's practice,
West 57th Street.
Good. Good. You're stinging
the company health plan, I hope, right?
Sure. That's what
it's there for, man.
All right, brother.
Listen, one more thing.
Your hard drive is filthy, all right?
We got your computer back.
I mean, it is dirty.
I'm talking like hoes,
sluts, anal, double anal,
penetration,
interracial facial, man.
Cream pie...
I don't even know what that is.
You think
it was your intern?
On my hard drive?
Yeah, someone's fucking
with your account, man.
And we're blowing
our wad in cash, you know?
It takes a really, really
sick fuck to spend all day on that shit.
Daddy, Daddy.
Yeah. Hey, buddy.
What'd she say?
She said I can go
to Jason's for a half hour,
but I have to be home
by 5:00 for dinner.
Okay. That's great. See?
Best of both worlds.
You got everything
you want. You happy?
Yup. Yup.
Yeah. You better be.
Get out of here.
Okay.
All right, see you.
Hey. You like your sugar?
I do.
Hey.
Hello.
Did you find it okay?
Yes, I'm glad
you made it.
Yeah?
I'm late. Sorry.
You look handsome.
You look amazing.
Hi.
Thank you.
How are you doing tonight?
Okay.
I have a few specials on the menu,
if you'd like to hear them?
Sure.
The soup of the day is
tomato with basil oil and parmesan crostini.
The special is
marinated swordfish,
tabouleh and
Moroccan charmoula.
It's really good.
We're also serving
a DeBragga and Spitler
New York Strip with
a side order of fries,
and the salad is snow pea and radish
with a cider vinaigrette.
Can I start you off
with a sparkling water?
Tap water's fine.
Okay.
And the wine menu is right next to...
Yup, there you go.
You want some wine?
Sure.
White? Red?
Red. Maybe...
Pinot Noir is light,
if you like it,
like, light.
Great.
Okay. I'll be back.
So...
Where do you live?
Brooklyn.
Nice.
Born and raised.
Where you from?
I was born in Ireland
and we moved here when I was a teen.
Did you get back much?
Thank you.
A couple times.
A big family?
You miss them?
Uh...
I have a sister.
I have two.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Older? Younger?
Older and younger.
I'm right
in the middle.
What?
Just wondering.
Are you nervous?
Why would I
be nervous?
You look
a little nervous.
Do I?
No.
Well, what's a date?
It's no big deal.
It took me an hour
to figure out what to wear.
You chose wisely.
Yeah.
I'm sorry, but I forgot to say
the crab comes in the shell.
Great.
Oh! Yeah. I haven't
even looked at this.
I'll have the lamb.
The lamb.
I'll have the lamb, too.
That sounds great.
Okay.
No appetizer?
I'm fine.
No.
Okay. And how would
you like the lamb?
Medium.
We recommend it
pretty pink.
Okay.
Yeah?
Okay. Pink it is.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
So you seeing anyone
at the moment?
No, I'm not.
Are you seeing anyone?
No.
No? Really?
Why is that?
I don't know.
It's just the way it is.
Yeah, I...
Actually, I'm separated.
Tragedy.
Yeah.
Kind of a recent thing.
Okay.
You were
married for long?
No.
Did we decide
on the wine?
Well, yeah. Was it the
Pinot Noir, you said?
Yeah, great.
Great choice. Okay.
I wasn't married long.
Gave it a shot. It didn't really work out.
No.
Wow.
What?
You just seem, like...
Averse to
the whole idea.
Well, yeah.
I just don't understand
why people would want to get married.
Especially nowadays,
I mean, it's... You know?
I don't see the point.
In relationships?
It doesn't
seem realistic.
Are you serious?
I mean...
Yeah. I am, really.
Well, then, you know,
why are we here,
if we don't matter
to one another?
Well...
Why are you here?
The food is supposed to be
great here.
No, no, no.
I'm not saying it like that.
I mean...
I just mean... You know?
One person for the rest of your life?
I mean, it's...
I mean, you come
to restaurants,
you see couples
sitting together,
and they don't even
speak to one another,
they don't have
anything to say.
They probably don't
have to speak because they're connected.
Or they're just bored
with one another.
Every...
Here we go.
What's your
longest relationship?
Um...
Exactly.
That's...
You can pour.
Sure.
4 months.
You have to commit.
You have to actually give it a shot.
I did.
For 4 months.
Thank you.
Look, touch that.
Your head?
No, no, no.
You're such a weirdo.
No, seriously, seriously,
seriously. Touch it.
Okay.
Oh, my God.
Do you feel that?
Yeah, what is it?
It's a remnant.
A remnant?
Yeah, from
the Neanderthals.
There's only a few of us left since the
Homo sapiens took over.
Okay.
Hmm.
That would explain
the forehead.
What's that
supposed to mean?
"What's that
supposed to mean?"
What do you mean?
Seriously, how did you get it?
What is it?
I used to play this
game with my cousin...
Mmm-hmm.
...where I'd sit on his feet
and he'd fly me through the air.
I hit my head off the ceiling
and I blacked out.
I was knocked out
for 5 or 10 minutes.
I peed my pants.
Oh!
If you had a choice
to live in the past or the future,
and you could be
anything you wanted to be,
what would you be?
What would you be?
Well, I always wanted to be a
musician in the '60s.
That's cool.
A musician?
Yeah.
'60s is tough, though.
I saw Gimme Shelter
recently, you know,
the Rolling Stones
documentary?
Yeah.
It kind of
seemed like hell.
What?
Yeah, the '60s would be,
like, the last place I would want to be.
No way!
Yes.
Ugh! Chaos!
So where and what
would you wanna be?
Um...
You know, here, now.
That's boring.
Fuck you.
Okay. Well,
this is me.
This is you?
This is me.
Thank you very much,
Brandon.
Marianne.
We should
do this again.
Right.
So is that a yes?
Maybe, yeah.
Hello? Sissy?
Oh, fuck!
Fuck!
What, are you
fucking spying on me?
Lock the fucking
door, Brandon.
Are you fucking spying?
"Are you fucking spying?"
Fuck! Brandon...
What do you want?
You wanna fight?
You want some of this?
What do you want from me?
Brandon!
What do you want?
Get off me!
Why did you
come here? Why?
Get off me!
Why? Why?
You're fucking
hurting me.
Talk to me!
Fucking bitch!
Get the fuck off,
you fucking weirdo.
Fucking slut!
Fuck you! Fuck you!
Brandon?
Brandon, I'm sorry.
Hey,
where's Brandon?
Are you Brandon's
girlfriend?
Do you wanna play?
You wanna play
with my tits?
I know Brandon
would really like it,
and I know exactly
what Brandon likes.
Come on.
Where are you
taking me?
Come on.
You'll see.
No, where
are we going?
Come on.
You want a drink?
What are you
looking at?
This view
is amazing.
Hey.
Are they vintage?
A little bit.
I love it.
Oh, yeah.
Brandon?
You know, it's cool.
It's okay.
Should I go?
Sure.
I can walk you down.
That's okay.
Can I
get you a drink?
No.
Fuck.
Need a hand?
No. The hook's odd.
There you go.
David?
Pick up.
I take it you're at your
pottery class.
Have you eaten?
No.
Are you hungry?
Can you just
give me a hug?
He's not gonna
screw you again.
You left him a message,
didn't you?
You can't help yourself.
It's disgusting.
Why are you
so fucking angry?
Why am I
That's my boss.
You sleep with him after 20 minutes.
Now you're calling him up.
What's the matter with you?
You know he's got
a family, right?
You know
he's got a family?
No.
You didn't see
the wedding ring on his finger?
No.
You're a liar.
I'm sorry.
You're always sorry.
That's all you ever fucking say.
Well, at least
I say I'm sorry.
Try doing something.
Actions count,
not words.
I'm sorry.
I fucked up.
I'm not perfect.
I make mistakes, but I'm trying.
Some people
fuck up all the time.
Look, just forget it.
This isn't working out.
Obviously.
You need to find
somewhere else to live.
I don't have
anywhere else to go.
This isn't about him.
I make you angry all the time and
I don't know why.
No. You trap me.
You force me into a corner
and you trap me.
"I've got
nowhere else to go."
I mean, what sort of
fucking shit is that?
You're my brother.
So what?
I'm responsible for you?
Yes.
No, I'm not.
Yes, you fucking are.
No, I didn't
give birth to you.
I didn't bring you
into this world.
You're my brother,
I'm your sister. We're family.
We're meant to look
after each other.
You're not
looking after me.
I'm looking
after myself.
I'm trying.
I'm trying to help you.
How are you helping me, huh?
How are you helping me?
Huh? Look at me.
You come in here
and you're a weight on me.
Do you understand me?
You're a burden.
You're just fucking
dragging me down.
How are you helping me?
You can't even
clean up after yourself.
Stop playing the victim.
I'm not playing
the fucking victim.
If I left, I would never
hear from you again.
Don't you think
that's sad?
You're my brother.
Why is it always
so dramatic with you?
Everything is always
the end of the world.
It's not fucking dramatic.
I'm trying to talk to you.
I don't wanna talk.
Try not talking.
Try just listening or thinking for a change.
Yeah, 'cause that's working great for you.
You're completely fine.
I've got my own
fucking apartment.
Oh, whoopee-fucking shit.
You have your own apartment,
that's amazing.
You have a job and an apartment.
I should be in awe of you.
Well, at least
I'm responsible for it.
At least I don't
depend on people all the time.
You're a dependency.
You're a parasite.
You don't have anybody.
You have me and your fucking pervert boss.
You slept with that fucking pervert boss.
What does that make you?
Don't talk to me about sex life, Brandon.
Not from you.
Whatever.
I'm going out.
Great. And then
you'll come back
and we'll just have
the same fucking conversation again.
No, you'll move out.
And then I'll never
hear from you again?
Hey.
You wanna
get out of here?
I could take you
somewhere.
What, are you
with someone?
Does he
go down on you?
I do.
That's what
I like to do.
I like
the way it feels.
I like the way
it's just me and it.
I wanna taste you.
I wanna slip
my tongue inside you,
just as you come.
You want me
to make you come?
I can do that.
Want me to do that?
What's up, babe?
I was just
getting some drinks.
Yeah, huh?
Whoa.
Not tonight, buddy.
I said not tonight.
I was just telling your
pretty girlfriend here,
I'd like to fuck her
in that tight pussy of hers.
I mean,
bone her real hard.
Till she's
clawing up my back.
He's kidding.
This guy's funny.
After I fuck her
hard up the ass,
I'll put my balls in her mouth
while I come in her face.
You won't let me
fuck you in the ass?
Christ.
You get to fuck her
in the ass?
You know.
Tell me more, man,
'cause I'm fucking loving this.
Smell it.
Yo!
Jesus, come on.
You motherfucker.
Hey, Romeo.
Brandon, it's Sissy.
I really need to talk to you.
Please, will you
pick up the fucking phone?
Brandon, I need you.
We're not bad people.
We just come
from a bad place.
Thanks for letting me stay.
Ladies and gentlemen,
at this time, due to
a police investigation,
we have to discharge
this train.
Please follow the conductor
to the rear of the train.
Watch your step
between cars.
Watch your step.
Follow me, please.
Follow me.
Watch your step.
This way. This way. Quickly.
This way.
Nothing to see. Move on.
Right this way, please.
This is Sissy.
Leave a message. Don't if you're an asshole.
This is Sissy. Leave a...
Shit!
Shithead.
God!