Previously on 12 Monkeys...
- James Cole.
- Where's the virus?
The plague. It is coming.
They're using Leland's daughter.
Jennifer!
I can protect you now.
I want to be a Daughter again.
- Who are you?
- The Daughters.
The paradox has destroyed your ability
to travel back to your time.
I'm not gonna let you take my son.
Jennifer, just give me the virus.
No, Jennifer!
This is your purpose.
[gunshots]
- Cassie?
- Cole.
Good-bye.
- How long were you there?
- Eight months.
This all ends when she dies.
Move out of the way!
_
♪ Come to me ♪
Railly: Where are you right now?
♪ For I'm lonely ♪
Somewhere you don't belong?
♪ Come to me ♪
Wondering who have I become.
♪ For I'm lonely ♪
♪ Darling, come to me ♪
Living a life you
never thought you'd have to.
Look out! We got scavs!
[grunting, metal clanging]
Doing things... horrible things...
you never thought you'd be capable of.
♪ Come to me ♪
♪ Forget the past ♪
No matter how hard you fought,
you'd have to live with it.
You'd adapt, transform...
Evolve.
Metamorphosis.
♪ Come to me and be my girl ♪
♪ For I love ♪
♪ Love, love you so much ♪
And sometimes you have to accept
not every
caterpillar becomes a butterfly.
[gunshots firing]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
(((( o ))))
_
[drums beating in distance]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
[celebratory din]
[gunshots from above]
This again?
Wait a minute.
- He's with me.
- With you?
He helped me find Jennifer.
He's not with them anymore.
Cole, he is them.
The first reported cases of the plague
happen here in New York.
Tomorrow... a trip around the world.
11 more cities.
The rest of the virus
is still on her plane,
and we will destroy all
of it after she's dead.
Wait.
Jennifer...
I know you don't want to do this.
But I'm supposed to.
It's my purpose.
Jennifer, Jennifer.
I need you to trust me
a little bit, okay?
Can you do that?
Please, just trust me a little.
Just a little.
Please.
Thank you.
[Jennifer laughing]
I'm gonna be in so much trouble now.
When this is done, we
are not letting her go.
Destroy the virus, we
won't have to worry about that.
There will always be more.
We may have to destroy
Markridge's lab, too,
and find their people.
Let 'em live, create an enemy.
Deacon.
What happened to you in the future?
The 12 were there... the Messengers.
But you knew that already, didn't you?
They never told me what they
were gonna do with them.
Messengers... Aaron
warned us about them.
They took over the facility,
and forced Jones to send
them back into the past.
We killed some, but a few got back.
We don't know when or where.
So you've been living in
the future this whole time?
It was August 2, 2044, when I left.
It was our first jump since
repairing the machine.
[whispering] August 2, 2044.
Why were you with him?
He saved my life.
The Monkeys want him
dead. They used him.
They've been chasing us ever since.
This is it, up here.
Security will be here soon.
All the people this would've killed.
Billions.
Let's get it out.
Don't just stand there. Help us.
You know what this
means for me if it works??
It'll erase my son.
I can't stop you.
I'm not gonna help you either.
You need to see this.
The murder of 7 billion
innocent people ends right now.
[glass popping and breaking]
Oh, no.
Times, they are a-changing!
[Ramse grunts]
[static fizzes]
It's happening.
Cole: Time changed. I felt it.
But I'm still here.
Things should be different.
I have one of Jones' injections.
It'll tether you back to 2044.
We can figure this out there.
We can't leave them here alive.
I won't let you do that.
You're letting your emotions
get in the way.
You brought me into this.
You know what needs to be done.
No.
[groans]
What are you doing?
They're gonna kill him there!
Not before he tells
us everything he knows.
Mr. Cole's tether has been activated.
He should be arriving in...
Mr. Ramse?
[groaning]
You forgot the mission, Cole.
I'm sorry.
Welcome back, asshole.
What is he doing here?
He arrived on Mr. Cole's tether.
[gasping]
We destroyed the virus,
but nothing happened.
No, Dr. Railly, something did happen.
You changed history.
You're stuck.
Nobody wants you anymore.
Why didn't stopping you change things?
It did.
It's just not the way you think.
How would you know?
You need to find a way home, Otter Eyes.
The number home is 607.
[whispering] 607.
Jones.
How do you know about Jones?
[sirens wailing]
Come on.
This is incredible.
We actually altered the future.
This is a different 2044.
Yes.
But we still remember the old one.
It's the injections that we have taken.
They render our bodies and consciousness
impervious to the changes of time.
Time shifted around us,
and altered our reality.
Look.
The plague now
started in 2018, not in 2016.
And because of you,
the CDC knew and were
better prepared for the outbreak.
Lives were saved.
Not all of them, but some.
Perhaps hundreds of thousands.
But it's strange.
With more time and more lives saved,
the potential for change is exponential.
Yet here we are, on the same course.
The people here
have no idea what we did.
No, for them nothing changed.
This is their reality.
Not ours.
We are late arrivals.
I had to investigate
our own investigation.
And as far as I can tell,
only you, Mr. Ramse, and I
are aware that anything is different.
And presumably Mr. Cole,
but we'll know once we retrieve him.
Cole has abandoned the mission.
He's emotionally compromised.
Ramse, now Jennifer.
Are you sure?
I'm sure.
We should move on without him.
So we stopped the
virus, but it still happened.
Well, it is possible that
when the Messengers used our machine
to go back in time,
that somehow they ensured
the eventual release of the plague.
We need to get
Mr. Ramse to talk.
[chair screeching]
It is so good to see you, my friend.
Jonesy and Cass, they got
a real nasty beef with you.
Worse than our little
piece of unfinished business.
They sent me in here to crack you.
They keep going on and
on about Messengers this,
12 Monkeys that.
They think you know something.
Like where they went... when they went.
What they want with our machine.
Your machine?
I know, I know.
You tell Jones...
I don't know
anything about the Messengers.
I can't help her.
Oh...
[chuckling] Oh, boy, oh, boy.
Yeah, I was hoping that
you would say that
because I gotta get
something out of you.
Cole: We need to find a place,
get off the road,
find a phone, get a message to 2044.
You know that's not how call
forwarding works, right?
Ramse had a tracker in him.
What about you, you have one?
I don't know.
I get poked and prodded a lot.
[whispers in Jennifer's head]
607.
Stop!
[brakes screeching]
The Emerson Hotel.
- Jennifer!
- This is it!
They got phones, come on!
Yes, this is good.
Yes. You've been here before.
No, I haven't.
Yes, you have. Yes, you have.
They better let me use the phone.
Yes, you have.
You have!
Do me a favor.
Stop talking.
But you have.
Need to use the phone.
Amenities for customers only.
Then I need a room.
For how long?
I don't know. Does it have a phone?
You got a credit card or ID?
No.
No ID rate is $300.
I need a name.
Morris.
- Last name?
- Morrison.
Morris Morrison.
[muttering] Mr. Morris Morrison.
Mr. Morris Morrison,
check out time is by 10:00 a.m.
No smoke or fires of any kind.
You break it, you buy it.
So if you break it, you have to buy it.
That's basically what he's saying.
Your key. Room 210.
Oh, no. No, no, no, no.
No good. No, prime. No.
He needs a prime number.
- Something like 607.
- No, really, that's fine.
Don't need a prime number.
- It's okay.
- Yes... no, we do.
Room 607 is a private residence.
- It's not available.
- We don't need 607.
- 210 is what I got.
- 210's fine.
Okay, no, well maybe
we'll speak to the manager...
- 210's fine, thank you.
- 'cause we need a prime number.
210 is fine.
Elevator's over there.
I'd double bag it with that one!
This is wrong. This isn't... what?
What room did you give them?
210.
Come on.
No.
This isn't right.
Ask for the manager.
Hello?
Jones, it's James.
James Cole?
I thought we agreed that you were not
to contact me again in this time.
We did, we did, but things have changed.
An event altering your timeline?
Yeah.
Why?
Because it got complicated.
Cole, things are changing.
Stop it. Go sit down.
Olivia: You have a purpose, Jennifer.
You have a purpose, Jennifer.
There is nothing more
important than this.
I need you to write a
note in your journal.
August 2044, come back and get me.
Send Railly with another injection.
Our agreement was made
to protect the
integrity of our timeline.
You... the future you... and Cassie,
you're gonna make a mistake.
You're gonna hurt someone.
A friend.
I cannot know these things.
It's the Emerson Hotel.
Remember to come back and get me.
Very well, you told me.
So you are still there?
Yeah.
Well, then that's either
because I'm unable to bring you back
or I'm choosing not to.
Either way, if my understanding
of causality is correct,
I have 27 years to decide. So please,
do not call me back!
Wait, wait, wait. Don't...
don't hang up.
This is your purpose, Jennifer.
Purpose. You have no purpose.
- Without me, you have nothing.
- Not anymore.
Stop the voices.
[glass shatters]
[Jennifer yelling]
Jennifer!
[yelling]
Why didn't you let her kill me?
[grunting]
You robbed me of my purpose!
If I can't have one, neither can you!
No, I'm sure of it. It
looks just like him.
James Cole.
I'm so glad
that we have this time.
Do you remember
when we would go out and
raid survivor camps?
And you would get all judge-y? Right?
And you would call
me "thief" and "tyrant"
and "killer."
And then you team up with them
to create the plague
that destroys the world.
Help me understand.
My son...
He lives here.
I didn't want to erase this world
with him in it.
Aww.
Father... of... the... year.
You know a little
something about that, right?
Fathers?
You ever hear of a place
called New Rochelle, New York?
Wilmont Road?
A little blue house,
and it had white trim.
I was parked out front
back in, uh, 2013.
Heard a man and woman fighting inside
in the house.
He chases her out,
and, uh, grabs her hair.
Starts beating her up.
Two little boys run out,
you know, chasing after her.
And the oldest was crying,
and he... he kept on crying
even when the cops came
and took his Daddy away.
Theodore William Deacon.
That was you.
I came to see you.
I wanted to see how
you became what you are.
You know, I think your daddy,
he would've gone all the way.
He would've killed your mom right there
if the cops hadn't come.
You should thank me
for calling them.
Are you mad, Deac,
that I saw you that day?
You cried.
Sad little boy.
You know what, Teddy?
All the talking...
Got me a little thirsty.
Move!
[yelling]
[gurgling]
Deacon! Deacon, stop, stop!
Stop it!
Temper, temper!
Deac... Deacon.
You need to calm down.
Hey, shh.
Calm down.
[Deacon whimpers]
Breathe.
Look at me, look at me.
I'm sorry.
He knows about my father.
Hey.
He saw.
He is just trying
to get under your skin.
[scoffs] Well, it worked.
He's not gonna talk.
We are gonna have to kill him.
No, no, no.
There's another way.
So you're saying you
changed our reality?
No.
My timeline changed into this one.
The virus occurred earlier?
Right.
And much worse than we remembered it?
Precisely.
But there were other changes as well,
at least from my perspective.
Spearhead, for example.
In my reality, we
invaded, confiscated their core,
and used it to continue our mission.
That happened.
And Dr. Lasky was killed.
Uh...
What?
I was killed?
Shot to death during the attempt
to commandeer Spearhead.
Well, then...
I prefer this reality.
So do I, Dr. Lasky.
I will need your help,
all of you, to fully understand
this timeline.
This will be all for
now. You're dismissed.
I need to have a word with you.
Is there anything you
wish to discuss, Dr. Eckland?
You really don't remember me?
I read through some part of my journal,
and it looks like your expertise
in molecular biology was quite valuable.
I apologize, Dr. Eckland,
but you were not part
of my original reality.
Well...
Well, that's going to make
it awkward tonight...
when you come to bed.
Whoa.
Déjà vu.
Happy Anniversary!
[laughing]
What are you doing?
I don't know anymore.
That's the problem!
I had a purpose.
You have a purpose, Jennifer.
Better living through mass extinction.
Kill the voices.
This plague will stop the voices.
You took it from me.
Who told you killing was your purpose?
Mothers to daughters.
Beautiful daughter.
They fill baths with water,
and they... soap and bubbles.
And they tell them that they're special.
You're special.
They say, "You have a purpose."
You have a purpose, Jennifer.
"You have a purpose."
It's not the killing.
The killing part is sad,
and it's gross, but after...
No more voices. No more variables.
Jennifer, ending the world
is not gonna stop the
voices in your head.
Stop... Stop the voices.
Oh, no, that's not what Olivia said.
Trust me, Jennifer.
Kill the world,
and then it's silence.
Olivia...
That's the woman behind the 12 Monkeys.
She said I was primary.
You are primary.
- I'm important.
- You're special.
You can see the changes
made in time, can't you?
The things I see.
- I am time.
- You are time.
Primary.
I see everything.
The others like me.
The numbers. 607.
You, her.
Cassie?
You want her to love you,
but she doesn't.
Being single is not
the end of the world.
You two together is, though.
If the Monkeys get what they want,
- when the forest is red...
- When the forest is red...
You and me, we could have time together.
You'll have all the time you want.
All of it, even.
You know, like a kiss.
You just have to close your eyes
and let the world die.
You can be with him.
No.
[knocking on door]
Sir, we need to speak with you.
He found you.
Mr. Cole?
Sir?
[knocking continues]
James Cole!
My apologies, Mr. Cole,
but we have you in the wrong room.
Sorry for the confusion, Mr. Cole.
My concierge hasn't
memorized our residents list.
But I made some calls.
Cleared the whole thing up.
607.
[key jangles, lock turns]
My family has run this
hotel for over 100 years.
This particular suite
was purchased in perpetuity
in 1944 by a Mr. James Cole.
Every year when I was a kid,
my father would send me in here to dust.
Always a day after Easter.
Spring cleaning, he called it.
Yeah, we... we decided
to keep everything as-is, you know,
like a museum.
I still like to
look at the old pictures.
You know?
Was he your grandfather, sir?
Because you look just like him.
Well, I'll leave you to it, Mr. Cole.
Jennifer, how did you see all this?
How did you know?
Is it always numbers?
What's wrong?
What is that?
You can be with him. Yes, you do.
Jennifer, no!
Hey, hey!
Sit down, sit down.
Sit down, it's okay. It's not too deep.
Everything's changing.
Green to red.
It starts here.
This place... I've seen it.
Primaries.
It's all in my head.
Pieces, pictures, places.
You... and her.
Why do I always have to do bad things
to get your attention?
Why did you do that?
I have nothing left.
Of course you do.
Listen, you need to
forget about your mother,
and your father, whatever
the hell the 12 Monkeys told you.
You're not supposed to kill billions.
Look, I-I don't know
what your purpose is, okay?
I-I don't even know what mine is.
But there is
something that you have to do.
Leave.
Just go.
Get out of this.
Go and find your purpose.
You do have one.
One that's right.
Just go.
Leave all this behind.
Okay.
[door opens]
You're here to shoot me again?
No.
I don't know anything about them.
I never did.
I helped them find the virus.
That was it.
So you could torture me or whatever.
What about your son, Ramse?
2044 made you that hard, Cass?
Sam?
Is that you, buddy?
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
Hey, Whit. Whit!
The Messengers.
I don't know anything.
Where did they go?
Don't hurt him.
Kill me.
[alarm blaring]
Cass? Cass!
Don't hurt him!
Mr. Deacon, we had a deal.
I thought your people
had this place secured.
Unh!
Do you know who we are?
You call yourselves The Daughters.
Where is James Cole?
Gone.
And why has he not been returned?
Mr. Cole is no
longer part of the mission.
There is no reason to return him.
We will not leave here until
James Cole is returned.
You have until dawn.
The Emerson Hotel, Suite 607.
The day he called you and
you refused to help.
Why do The Daughters care about
the fate of James Cole?
James Cole understands something
you all have forgotten.
Our fates are intertwined.
Here and in the past.
Our Mother knows this.
Many cycles ago, James
Cole made a choice.
An act of mercy.
For that, a debt was issued
and now that debt has been repaid.
Get up.
[scanner whirring]
[power humming, glass clinking]
What changed your mind?
[grunting and groaning]
Welcome back, Mr. Cole.
Just like old times.
Sam is here.
Cassie threatened to hurt him.
She wouldn't do that.
You don't know her anymore.
Everything's changed now.
Everything.
[door opens]
Let's go for a walk.
When this mission began,
you and I were both at a crossroads,
neither sure if the
other could be trusted.
And you've always known more than me,
and you've always held back.
You knew I'd get stuck in 2015.
So much for trust.
At any moment, what you did in the past
could've changed everything.
Nothing was certain.
And this shift in our
timeline is the proof.
Stopping Jennifer Goines
and destroying the
virus changed history.
We pushed back the plague.
We delayed it.
And it hurt them, Mr. Cole.
Maybe. A little.
Cassie still sends the
message. She still dies,
only now, a few years later,
along with billions of other people.
I wouldn't call that a victory.
♪ Come to me ♪
What is that?
Music, James.
And more to the point, it's a broadcast.
Shortwave.
From somewhere out there.
What you and Dr. Railly
did in 2016 changed things.
Here.
Our records show
that some of the quarantine zones
didn't fall as quickly as before.
So there were more survivors.
Human lives spared
because we dared to challenge fate.
Do you know what that is?
It's hope, Mr. Cole.
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
This machine,
this power,
no matter what we achieve,
we must always
operate under the assumption
that we're dealing with an enemy
whose capabilities are equal to our own.
Messengers.
We don't know where they went,
or when, or even a year.
I had hoped Mr. Ramse could tell us.
He doesn't know.
[scoffs]
Katarina...
we made mistakes.
All of us.
James,
I need to know.
Are you still with me?
[sighs]
I'm still with you.
♪ ♪
1944.
That's where I
think the Messengers went.
♪ ♪
Don't worry, Kat. I'm going.
I'm just gathering up my things.
You know, the most fun I ever had
was breaking down all the
walls you built around yourself.
And now I get to do it all over again.
Good night.
[ominous music]
♪ ♪
[clears throat]
Hey.
So much is different.
Yeah, I can see that.
I noticed, uh,
everybody's real cozy with Deacon now.
I'm really not sure
how all this is gonna work
now that you're
here, and not back in 2016.
♪ ♪
We have a mission to finish.
We do.
The only way that's happening
is if you're willing to
do what needs to be done.
Like before.
Look, I know your
being this way is my fault,
but this isn't who you are.
What I am is because of me.
Nobody else.
Everyone and everything changes, Cole.
I know that.
I was sent back in time to kill a man.
That was supposed to fix everything.
It didn't.
So I killed more people.
Nothing changed.
And then I saved someone.
Someone who should've died.
And that...
that is what changed things.
♪ ♪
It's the only thing
that's ever made any difference.
As for the mission...
I'm ready when you are.
[breathes deeply, exhales sharply]
Cont..