[This is a fictional drama
based on historical facts.]
[Events depicted might
differ from actual events.]
Wook.
You fools!
Kill them all!
What?
How absurd!
You came in here like mice.
Subtitles Ripped By www.vikisubtitle.com
What did you steal?
Hand it over immediately!
Immediately!
Follow him!
What?
Darn it!
How could this be?
Did you lose him?
Did you lose all of them?
I'm sorry.
Did they steal
the bronze mirror pieces?
Did you already know
about the bronze mirror pieces?
Please tell me all about them.
Aren't I on your side already?
Yes.
Yes, I'll tell you everything.
The bronze mirror pieces
is a pact between me
and five other noblemen.
Our pact is, 'sal jae su ho guk,'
meaning, “the noblemen
will kill the King and rule the nation.”
These five words are engraved on there,
along with our names.
We put our lives on the line
for the pact.
Five years ago on that night,
were you in Father's room, too?
Can I tolerate all of this
and rise to the throne?
Nonetheless,
I'll still go with you.
What can you give me?
What do you want?
Become completely
loyal to me.
How could you become
Wang Sik Ryeom's sword,
the man who killed my father?
How could you?
[Shine or Go Crazy]
[Episode 18]
I heard the virtuous men
infiltrated here last night!
What's happening?
What did they steal?
Could it be?
They stole our bronze mirror pieces.
Then
doesn't this mean
they have all 5 pieces?
What do we do now?
The bronze mirror pieces have
our pact engraved on it.
As I've told you before,
they won't be able to
figure it out that easily.
What if they do?
Right now, there's
an order to arrest them.
They won't be able to reveal
the bronze mirror pieces that easily.
They'll have to admit
that they're thieves
who killed Kim Jong Sik and Hong Gui Ui,
and broke into my house
before doing that.
I'll find ways to counterattack them.
Trust me.
I'll contribute
to the war with Wang Sik Ryeom.
Thank you for your sincerity.
I'm planning on releasing Cheong Ok
and her younger sister.
Cheong Ok will be our
emergency messenger.
And we must find out
the noblemen's plans,
so it's better for Cheong Ok
to stay at Wolhyanglu.
Okay.
Have you seen the bronze mirrors?
You'll have to see them with me.
These people are
Goryeo's rotten roots.
But their names alone
aren't enough as evidence.
There's a pact to kill the First King
on this bronze mirror.
That's why Wang Sik Ryeom
was obsessed with it.
After we find it,
the problem is the antidote.
The next great meeting
must be held by the King.
Will it be possible
to make the antidote?
No middlemen will give
us advance payments.
Pungwoo Trading Company is too powerful.
Yool.
Has anyone agreed to
a credit transaction?
Us neither.
Nothing is working out.
Right.
Did you hear the news, Miss?
Last night, the virtuous men infiltrated
Wang Sik Ryeom's house.
What are you talking about?
They mobilized the palatial soldiers
and they pursued them.
So were they captured or hurt?
No.
They said they ran away safely.
Is anyone here?
Why is that guy here?
And who's that person beside him?
- What brings you here?
- Yes, Shin Yool.
Mr. Yang is here too, I see.
Say hello.
He runs everything at
Pungwoo Trading Co.
Never mind.
What brings you here?
- You're done with us.
- What do you mean?
All of your wealth was given
to Pungwoo Trading Co.
but why are you still here?
You want us to hand over our homes?
You need to move out,
so that we can move in.
That's ridiculous!
Give us some time.
Then we'll pay for our land here.
You have 15 days.
If you don't pay within 15 days,
you'll have to leave.
Look here!
- How could we do that in 15 days?
- If we pay,
then this land
and the house is ours.
You've promised.
How can we get the money in 15 days?
Now we're really going down!
Miss.
Is there a way for our
company to survive?
It's not impossible.
What is it?
We need to get the spices
that are being delivered on the ship.
The spices do yield a lot of money.
The prices of spices have skyrocketed
in the central districts.
It's probably risen more than 10 fold.
With that money, we
can pay for our house,
and we'll have seed money as well.
But you said we need
30,000 ginseng roots.
There is one person in the capital
who has 30,000 ginseng roots.
Who is it?
It's Princess Yeo Won.
Miss.
So you're going to meet her right now?
She's Prince Wang So's wife!
Do you think she'll help us?
We'll be lucky if she
doesn't treat us badly!
I'm against it, too.
It won't work anyway.
I hate all of the Hwang family!
Gaebong!
Don't worry, you fool!
Everything will be returned.
The world's most interesting goods
will be stocked in
the magical storage room,
and at this inn,
Goryeo's, I mean,
all the world's men
will come here and make a ruckus.
Chunghae Trading Co.
is no ordinary company.
Don't worry.
What are you doing?
- Are you okay?
- What are you talking about?
Didn't you get hurt
when the soldiers chased after you?
My shoulder, my back!
Even my legs!
Does it hurt a lot?
Of course it does!
- Not there, but a little lower.
- Here?
Or…
Or here?
You keep touching where
it hurts, go left.
Go right!
Yeah, a little lower.
Go a little lower.
Why did you hit me?
I don't think you got hurt.
What do you mean?
I wasn't hurt at all.
- *Hyungnim!
- Why are you so gullible?
[Hyungnim: formal version
of older brother or male.]
I'm only gullible with you.
Is that so?
Gaebong.
What are you thinking about?
What are you imagining about?
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
Gaebong.
Everything is almost done.
Just hold on a little longer.
I'll return everything
to where it once was.
Don't you trust me?
I do.
- It just feels weird.
- What does?
It's the first time
someone's said to me,
“Don't worry,” “Trust me.”
and “I'll take care of it.”
I always used to say that.
Weren't the weight of those words
quite heavy?
They were heavy at times,
But thinking that
I could protect my people
on my own,
I was happy.
So whenever there was a problem,
I found a solution.
But this time,
I just can't find a way.
No.
I know there is a way,
but I can't decide
if I should keep going or give up.
That's why you can't
scratch your own back.
What?
Didn't you say that to me before?
When you have a lot on your mind,
it's best to simply make calculations.
Make calculations?
What do you mean?
Compare the pros and the cons,
and choose the pros.
You already know the answer,
you don't need to complicate things.
Seeing your expression,
it seems you've found the solution.
Now that I'm thinking about the pros,
I think I can see a way.
But what if I can't
compare the pros and cons?
Aren't you a trader, Gaebong?
Then there should be
a standard for traders.
You just need to follow that.
Do you really think so?
Of course, I think so.
Thank you for understanding.
You brat.
Then you may leave now.
You want me to leave?
I can't walk you out.
I have work to do.
Wait.
Hey, Gaebong!
Gaebong!
That brat.
Thank you
for always being by my side.
Thank you.
Oh man, we were alone in this room.
- Father!
- My son!
Okay, okay.
Welcome back.
- Have you been well?
- Yes.
I've been well, Father.
Tomorrow, I'll give
a requisition order at the meeting.
We must admit all men
to compulsory service,
so that we won't run into a problem
with the move to the west.
Yes.
I know very well what I must do, Father.
I'm so proud of you.
Yes.
You must be tired from
your long journey here, General Gwak.
Here, here.
Sit down.
How long has it been?
It's the first time
we've seen one another
since we defeated the Khitans.
I'm still alive because
you fought with us.
You don't need to thank me.
Goryeo needed to defeat the Khitans too.
But
you speak the language of Goryeo.
Thanks to one Goryeo man,
I became furious and
learned the language.
That man must have some guts
to make the great General Gwak furious.
Should we catch and put
him to death for you?
So, what is your request?
Father.
General Gwak is going to
attack his surroundings
so he can establish a nation
in the central districts.
He's planning a blitz attack,
so he needs you to provide the soldiers.
So please let me meet the King.
I will persuade him.
Well
you don't need to meet the King.
He's not in stable
mental health right now.
He can't make any judgments.
The one you must meet isn't the King,
but it's Prince Wang Wook.
He's the next in line,
and the noblemen and I support him.
Is that so?
He'll be the new King
of the central districts.
Make him one of your men.
Do you know Chunghae Trading Co.?
You're asking for Chunghae
Trading Co. again?
Father.
It was a trading company in Gaebong,
but 5 years ago, the assistant
head of the company
and General Gwak were arranged to wed.
But the assistant head
married a Goryeo man,
and she went to Goryeo with him.
Your Highness.
She's already married.
And 5 years ago, too.
Isn't she absurd?
How could brothers
fight over one woman?
That assistant head was
a magnificent woman.
I heard she established
a company in Goryeo.
Have you heard of it?
Of course I have.
Prince Wang Wook knows about it well.
You can ask him about the details.
Is the assistant head still doing well
with that Goryeo man?
We shall talk about this again later.
Could I disturb you for one moment?
After what Wang Sik Ryeom said,
you must be close with
the assistant head?
Have you seen her Goryeo husband?
He was ragged looking,
but the look in his eyes and his spirit
was like that of a tiger.
I was disappointed to have lost her,
but I understand why she chose that man.
Wang Sik Ryeom mentioned
that brothers fought over one woman.
What does that mean?
Sit down.
Chunghae Trading Co. is not involved
in the move to the west anymore.
What brings you here?
I have something to ask you.
Sit down.
Please go ahead.
Have you
ever been married?
What are you talking about?
Why do you talk of
a marriage, all of a sudden?
If she was married,
she wouldn't not talk about it.
There has to be a reason
she can't talk about her marriage.
It's because the identity
of that Goryeo man
can't be revealed.
Could it be?
I understand.
We've talked about marriage before.
I've asked an unnecessary question.
I'll be leaving.
It was a difference in temperature.
A difference in temperature.
I've found evidence.
I'll reveal it at the great meeting
and let the world know!
Wang Sik Ryeom is leading the meeting.
Subtitles Ripped By www.vikisubtitle.com
Will it be okay?
No, we must make
the King lead the meeting.
That way the bronze mirror
will be recognized
as evidence.
If Wang Sik Ryeom leads the meeting,
he might try to find
faults in the evidence.
Thus the most important thing is
to find the antidote.
The antidote that Wang Wook has.
Five years ago,
was that the man
who wed the assistant head?
Yes, that's right.
But considering his appearance,
he must be of the royal family.
Brothers, I see.
I have a favor to ask of you.
Please don't reveal to anyone
about this marriage.
That means erasing all memories
related to the assistant head.
Then
when I become King,
I'll repay you.
I'm very greedy.
I'll give you
anything you want.
It's you.
Here.
Soon the great meeting will take place.
So?
I have all of the evidence
to punish Wang Sik Ryeom.
I'll reveal it during
the great meeting,
and then the whole world know.
Then I'll remove him from his position
and punish him.
In order to do that,
the King must lead the great meeting.
Wook, try to change the fate of Goryeo
with me, your own brother.
Please give me the antidote.
If the marriage is found out,
Shin Yool will die.
How will you protect her?
How will you save her?
Wook.
It's the last chance.
It's the last chance to stop the war
between the royal family,
so that everyone can live humanely!
It's the last chance.
Please take my hand.
The antidote is the last opportunity
to save Shin Yool.
The hand I should take isn't yours.
You must show your respect
to Prince Wang Wook
when you're in front of other people.
He's the one who'll be King.
Don't trust Wook that much.
The way I see it,
I don't think he'll
stay loyal to you.
Poong.
Loyalty, you see,
depends on what I have
against the opponent.
Wook has no choice
to be loyal to me
until the assistant head is dead.
Wook has been bewitched by that woman?
What kind of woman is she?
She's an impudent woman.
Don't keep her close to you.
That makes her more interesting.
Don't you dare!
The problem right now isn't Wook,
but So.
He meddles in everything I do,
and now he's trying to take my life?
So why did you stand idle?
You must kill him.
The best defense is to attack.
That attack needs a deadly weapon
that will destroy the enemy instantly
in order to gain victory.
I'm looking for it.
I'm looking for a deadly weapon
to destroy Wang So!
Why are you alone?
I had to go somewhere.
- Was it Chunghae Trading Co.?
- Yes.
Yes.
Did you meet that woman?
What did she say when she saw you?
Now.
Let's talk about our
offers to one another.
Sure.
Leave us now.
What can you offer me?
Before that,
I have something to ask you.
Before,
you said that two brothers
fought over one woman.
Is one of those brothers
Prince Wang Wook
and the other…?
It's So.
It's a man named Wang So.
Wang So.
It a letter saying that
the King hasn't improved.
The great meeting is
right around the corner.
Is there really no other way?
Princess Yeo Won.
She's given me her sincerity.
I've given her my sincerity as well.
If we still can't save him,
then I must take action myself.
You can't.
The evidence we've
gathered for 5 years
could all go to waste.
Don't worry, Eun Chun.
I will win, no matter what.
This won't do.
I can't provide soldiers for you
with that offer.
Come on.
Wait.
If I tell you an interesting story,
will you fulfill my request?
Don't forget
the promise you made with me.
I don't forget promises,
Your Highness.
This man, this man!
I heard you were looking for me.
Yes.
You're just as I've heard.
Brothers would fight over you.
Yes.
Try to seduce me with your skills.
What are you doing?
What do you mean?
I just want to play with you.
What are you?
Ouch!
Let me go.
Hey, let me go.
Do you know who I am?
I'm Wang Sik Ryeom's son, let me go!
Gyeong!
Come here!
Did you just hit me, Prince Wang So?
Next time, that'll be in your body.
Poong, leave now.
You could've just used your words.
You have to treat people
like him like that,
so that they won't
come back again.
You must be in control of your temper.
You said that I have fire above my head.
It's not like I have a fire for a hat.
Is the King doing well?
I feel so tired, all of a sudden.
Oh, boy.
Oh, boy, I feel so
tired, all of a sudden.
Don't worry.
I'm trying.
Do you need anything?
You.
You just need to be by my side.
You're my greatest source of energy.
Gaebong.
Is Baek Myo gone?
Did she leave?
Thank you.
It's not an antidote, per se.
I obtained a medicinal
herb that's most similar
and I've made the antidote.
But you should only expect
a temporary neutralization
of the poison.
Thank you so much.
It's already been 15 days
since he last left his room.
He must attend
the great meeting tomorrow.
I'm worried.
I'll be with him until the meeting,
and I'll escort him there.
I've obtained the antidote.
- Is that true?
- Your Highness!
Please keep this a secret for now.
Please prepare for the great meeting.
Wang Sik Ryeom and those in favor
of the move the west
will object strongly.
We must be prepared.
I understand, Your Highness.
- Ji Mong.
- Yes, Your Highness.
The antidote is temporary.
Now, we must try to change
Goryeo with the King.
Your Majesty!
So is here, Your Majesty.
I'm here.
It's you, So.
So is here.
You must take your medicine, Hyungnim.
Here's the medicine.
Here.
- Medicine?
- Yes.
It will clear your head, Hyungnim.
Here, slowly.
Chew it well.
Yes, chew it well.
Drink some water, too.
Here.
There we go.
I'm sleepy.
How am I always so sleepy?
If you're sleepy,
then you should sleep.
You should sleep comfortably.
I'll wake you up,
so you can lean on me and sleep.
What are you doing with this?
Let's put this aside, here.
Go to sleep, lean on me.
Here's your blanket.
There you go.
Now that I'm doing this,
I remember when we were young.
Well
I lost my way in the palace
and I was so scared,
but you held my hand so tight
and told me,
“It's okay, you little boy.”
“It's okay, So.”
“If we follow that
road, we'll be okay.”
“If we follow that road to
the end, we'll be okay.”
Then you took my hand and kept going.
Do you remember that?
Did I do that?
Yes, you did.
Yes.
I guess I did.
Hyungnim.
This time, you can hold
my hand and follow me.
I'll lead you to where you need to go.
I was scared then, too.
What if you're scared too, So?
What do you mean?
That's ridiculous!
I'm not scared at all!
So please wake up.
You need to wake up soon,
so you can walk down that path.
I'll walk with you by your side.
It's okay, Hyungnim.
Yes.
It's okay.
The sun is up.
When will you get out of my bed?
As the supervisor of the move to west,
I'll report to you the progress.
Yes, what was the result?
I have a lot to tell you, Your Majesty.
I've been asleep for too long.
I must have a lot to do.
You must take care of everything.
Have you found a way
to capture Wang Sik Ryeom?
He killed the First King?
Wang Sik Ryeom did?
The noblemen did?
This is the evidence.
Sal jae su ho guk.
They'll kill the King
and rule the nation.
You'll lead the great meeting this time,
and you must punish them for treason.
Even if it's Wang Sik Ryeom,
no one will take the side
of a treasonous man.
Soon the requisition
order will commence,
and if the move to the
west is accomplished,
the people will suffer greatly.
We must catch them before that happens.
I will.
I will punish those men no matter what.
Ji Mong.
Go to the Great Hall and get ready.
Yes, Your Majesty!
Here are the documents
you've asked me to prepare.
I've prepared how much money
the spices will yield.
Thank you.
Don't tell my brother or Baek Myo
that I'm going to
meet Princess Yeo Won.
Okay, but I'll accompany you today.
You must win, Your Highness.
And hold on, Your Majesty.
You must hold on.
The King must've confined
himself in his room again today.
They say he can't leave his room
because he's afraid of the sun.
It's a big problem.
What do you mean?
Wang Sik Ryeom takes care of everything.
For a while,
there's been some disorder,
so I couldn't give
the requisition order
for the move to the west.
Thus, today
I will proclaim the requisition order
for wartime mobilization!
Before that, the ruler
of the central districts,
General Gwak will come here
and introduce himself to you all.
Now, come in.
What are you doing, Wang Sik Ryeom?
How dare you bring a foreigner
to a great meeting of Goryeo?
What's the matter, Your Highness?
Leave immediately, General Gwak!
It's that man.
The man who was trying to marry Gaebong
five years ago.
Here comes the King!
Your Majesty!
This is General Gwak,
who rules the central districts.
General Gwak is my old friend.
I invited him here
for he has something to share with us.
He'll cover up his crimes
with Gaebong's marriage.
I won't let that happen.
I will take Wang Sik Ryeom down today.
- Testify?
- Your Majesty.
Even if he's an old
friend of Wang Sik Ryeom,
I think it's wrong that
he's attending this meeting!
Please make him leave!
I invited him because he has
something to share with us!
Please wait a moment.
Since you're here, please
enjoy your time here.
I haven't been able
to attend the meetings,
but my health has improved,
and starting today, I'll
attend all meetings.
Please prepare the fire,
and call my royal bodyguards.
Your Majesty.
Why do you need a fire all of a sudden,
and why do you need
the royal bodyguards?
Subtitles Ripped By www.vikisubtitle.com
Why do you need them at this meeting?
Pull yourself together, Your Majesty!
There's rumor that
you've gone insane.
Look, Wang Sik Ryeom.
How dare you make such
ludicrous remarks?
The King is well and healthy.
How dare you say he's insane?
Your Highness.
Aren't you meeting General Gwak again
after a long time?
It's been about 5 years, hasn't it?
Five years ago,
the secret of the First King's death,
do you know anything about that?
What?