My name is Karl Glocken, and
this is a ship of fools.
l'm a fool. And you'll meet
more fools as we go along.
This tub is packed with them.
Emancipated ladies. Ball players.
Lovers. Dog lovers.
Ladies of joy. Tolerant Jews.
Dwarfs. All kinds.
And who knows, if you
look closely enough..
..you may even find
yourself on board.
Good morning, doctor.
Good morning.
l'm glad to get out of Veracruz.
The whole damn country
is ready to explode.
Well, did you get a look at them?
Anything interesting?
Anything interesting at all?
There's a dwarf, that high.
A couple of young American painters.
And a Jewish salesman with an
infectious sense of humor.
Women, Willie. Women.
Well, a rather attractive
middle-aged American woman.
But l'm afraid she's too far
from the cradle for you.
Those are the kind that can sometime
appreciate what they are getting.
There's a Spanish dancing troupe,
interesting, but maybe professional.
They've had those Spanish dance
troupes on board before.
And the usual assortment
of our countrywomen.
Professors' wives? Saleswomen
putting on airs?
- l'm afraid so. - Governesses?
- Maybe you shouldn't.
- That's all right.
You're really getting off
at Bremerhaven, huh?
lt wasn't a very long career.
Three voyages.
Long enough.
l don't know what the hell l'm
going to do without you.
You'll manage.
You want to know the sentimental,
disgusting truth?
l've become fonder of you than
of most people in my life.
We just got used to each
other, that's all.
Who am l to play chess with?
Who am l to talk to?
You've seen the kind of characters
we get on this ship.
l get a cold shudder every time l
have to go to the captain's table.
l must be in my dotage.
After my..
l was looking for something.
l thought l could learn something
new by being a ship's doctor.
But l've seen all this before. l've
seen all these people before.
Never on a ship, that's all.
Come in.
- Lunch is served, captain.
- Thank you.
Please?
- What should l tell them this
time? - Tell them anything you like.
Tell them l had to fix the toilets.
1933 will be a good year.
l am optimistic.
At any rate, it is starting
out most auspiciously.
Ah it is good to be on a German
boat with German people, going home.
Say what you will, there is a feeling
when German people get together.
l cannot explain it. 'Gemutliche
Kameraderie..'
..which exists among
no other people.
At least l have found
it nowhere else.
You know what they say in Mexico?
Mexicans loathe the Americans,
hate the Spaniards..
..distrust the English, admire
the French and love the Germans.
That is all very nice. l am glad
that they say those things.
But as far as l am concerned,
after a few weeks in Mexico..
..you can keep the Mexicans too.
How long has it been since you
have been home, Herr Freytag?
- Four months. - You must be
glad to be going home too.
Yes, my wife is there.
Why is it that every charming
man l meet is married?
Fraulein Spockenkieker, you
have wounded to me the quick.
Excepting you, Herr Rieber.
l'm sorry.
That little dog is so sweet.
He has shared so much of the
professor's life and mine..
..l feel sometimes
he is like our son.
Do you think it's correct to
bring a dog to the table?
Bebe goes with us everywhere.
We have taken him to some
of the best restaurants.
Nobody seems to mind.
You know, it's gonna be
a wonderful trip, David.
l still feel funny about
you picking up the tab.
Look, we weren't gonna
talk about that.
Did l ever tell you these have been
the best three months of my life?
Did l ever tell you that l care for
you so much it's very upsetting?
What? What's the matter?
Twenty-six days in separate beds.
lt's probably a very good thing.
We'll get to know each other.
We'll find out whether we have
anything going for us besides sex.
l give you one more time
to hang yourself.
l know you got more
money from the Swede.
- l gave you what l got. - The
barman told me different.
He is a liar.
lf you're holding out on me, l
swear l'll rip your lying tongue out.
Rip my guts out. l don't
have any more money.
l asked for a table alone.
l'm sorry, madame, there is
no room for a table alone.
Please don't bother getting up.
You're an American?
- And my name's Bill Tenny.
- Mary Treadwell.
Yes, madam?
l'll have the pate and the
Rheinischer Sauerbraten.
- You, sir? - You got a steak?
- Yes, sir. - Thick?
We will do our best.
l'd better stick to
the simple stuff.
You know l was in Veracruz trying..
..to teach them greasers
how to play the ball.
Man, they tried to poison me.
You know, l had the
runs for three weeks.
How interesting.
l'd like to hear more about it.
Herr Rieber, l hear that you
publish a national magazine..
..with certain intellectual
features.
A garment trade magazine,
but modern. Modern.
Good afternoon. l'm Willie
Schumann, the ship's doctor.
The captain sends his regrets.
He's unable to come to lunch,
because of ship's business.
Doctor, l am Siegfried Rieber.
This is Professor Hutten,
Frau Hutten.
- Please. - No, no allow me.
And their dog, Bebe.
This charming young lady is
Fraulein Spockenkieker.
Herr Freytag, Frau Schmitt, Herr
Graf and his nephew Johann.
Please don't let me interrupt
your conversations.
We were just discussing
Herr Rieber's magazine.
Yes l have invited talented writers
from all over the nation..
..to contribute on one topic:
How we can expunge foreign
influences..
..and restore Germany to
its national greatness.
What foreign influences?
lf you need any attendance,
l'll be at your disposal.
Thank you.
On my part, doctor, you need
have no concern for me.
l do not believe in
'materia medica.'
Really?
Have you found something
better to replace it?
- Faith. - Faith. l see. Very well.
A toast. A toast to the German
woman, the most beautiful in the world.
- Delicious. - Herr Rieber.
- Good afternoon. - Good afternoon.
- Karl Glocken. - Julius Lowenthal.
The herring is very good.
l'll have that and a couple
of hard-boiled eggs.
l beg your pardon.
You aren't Jewish, are you?
No. l have my own minority group.
They usually give a Jew a table
of his own on a boat like this.
Why do you think they
put us together?
lt's their way of being friendly.
Perhaps they thought
we might hit it off.
You are sure you are not Jewish?
Reasonably sure.
You resemble a brother-in-law
of mine in Stuttgart.
That's the way it is.
People are always mistaking
me for someone else.
- Spot of wine? - Just a touch.
My God. Where are we
going to put them?
We'll have to manage.
Professor, what is it?
What's happening? Who
are all those people?
There's nothing to be concerned
about Frau Schmitt.
- l have spoken to one of the
officials. - But what is it?
lt has to do with the price
of sugar on the world market.
- Sugar? - Yeah. You see..
..the sugar planters have been
unable to get their price..
..so they burned their crops..
..in the fields rather than
let the prices go down.
Something had to be done about
the Spanish laborers..
..so the Cuban government hit upon
a humanitarian plan of action.
They're sending them home.
- How do you feel? - 'Bien.'
Good.
l come to see you later, yes?
Please put her there in the corner.
- Where can they wash?
-There are two spigots.
- What?! - lt is not my fault.
Stop talking to me in this way.
You just don't put 600 people..
..on a deck like this with
only two outlets to wash!
You don't know them.
They wouldn't wash if they could.
You don't know what pigs they are.
The deck has to be cleaned.
Bring the hoses out.
- The hoses? - Bring the
hoses out, l said!
l cannot turn hoses on them.
lt's better to turn
the hoses on them..
..than for them to
live this way, no?
- Break out the hoses.
- Turn on those hoses.
l take it you are not
exactly pleased..
..that we are cabin
mates on this voyage.
l have already requested a change
in the accommodations.
You may take it from me..
..that l'm not exactly overwhelmed
with the prospect either.
However, pending changes..
..since we are captives of each
other's company for 26 days..
..l think it is best if we
reach an understanding.
Our cosmetics, for instance..
..l will keep mine on
this side of the sink.
And you keep yours on that
side. That's right?
Which bunk do you prefer?
The lower or the upper?
l was assured the lower.
lt is yours.
What are your habits?
l, myself, rise very
early in the morning.
l take it that if this evening is
an example, you are a late bird.
lf you sleep late, l will see
that l do not disturb you.
And l hope you, in turn, will try
your best not to disturb me.
One other thing.
My wife has informed me in the most
sarcastic terms possible..
..l snore.
Good night.
- You a painter, huh? - Yeah.
- What was you doing in Mexico?
- l was a timekeeper in a mine.
l thought you said
you was a painter.
l am a painter, but l was
a timekeeper in a mine.
- Why? - To support
myself as a painter.
- What's the matter? Don't you
make any money painting? - No.
Oh now, wait a minute.
Come on. Wait a minute.
You mean to tell me you work at
something you can't make a living off..
..so you gotta take a job
to make enough money..
..to go on working at
work you can't live on?
But that is the heroic life.
That is the way men who trust
themselves can afford to live.
- A strange neck of the woods.
- What do you mean?
Strange neck of the woods.
Look, l run into all kinds
of people, you know, but..
Did l tell you what happened
to a guy in Veracruz..
..when l was coming
through immigration?
Well l'm standing in line see.
So l see this clerk..
..and l holler, Hey, Pancho,
get over here.
Just being friendly-like..
..like back home you call
a taxi driver Mac
..or a Pullman porter George.
Well this little Negro..
You know these coast..
..Mexicans got mostly Negro
blood in them, l'm told.
Well, he just looks
up and stares at me.
The next thing l know, everybody's
going ahead of me in this line.
Then l realize that this
little Negro resented it.
- l think l'll turn in. - Me too.
Come in.
- Good evening. - Good evening.
l'm the doctor. You
wanted to see me?
Yes. l need something
to help me sleep.
- Are you ill? - No, no.
l just want something
to help me sleep.
- Do you often have trouble
sleeping? - Yes. Always.
- Does your doctor help you to
sleep? - Yes. Occasionally.
Take off your robe.
- You're sure you're the ship's
doctor? - Oh l am the ship's doctor.
Lean forward, please.
- What is it? - Your hands are cold.
l'm sorry.
Breathe deeply.
When was your period?
- Look, is it necessary to..?
- Yes, it is necessary.
All right. Last week.
l'm sure you'd never have
any trouble sleeping.
No, never.
Tell me your secret.
A clear conscience, of course.
That's a neat trick, having
a clear conscience..
..when you work as
a doctor on a ship..
..which has 600 people
living on an open deck.
You know, you just can't take pills
every time you can't sleep..
..or anytime you want to be stimulated
or sedated. lt has its effect.
What are you laughing at?
My house has been burned. They've
taken everything l had.
Now l'm being taken to prison, to
an island l know nothing about.
And you're giving me a
Sunday school sermon.
- You can put your robe
back on now. - Thank you.
You've got a gentle touch.
Maybe you're not as stuffy
as you pretend to be.
No. l hope not.
You gonna help me?
Your doctor may have
helped you too often.
l'm very helpless at this moment.
You can leave me without any help.
That's your prerogative.
This is for tonight only.
- How old are you? - l'm old
enough, as you can see.
Much too old.
- Forty-five? - Not that old.
- How old are you? - Forty-two.
- How old are you? - Forty-one.
- You're joking. - Thank you.
Lie back, please.
You will feel it in a moment.
- Yes. - Talk.
- l beg your pardon? - Talk
until the drug takes effect.
This boat smells of cabbage.
Why does every German
boat smell of cabbage?
Keep talking.
What do you want me to talk about?
Anything you like. Just talk.
What's your name?
- Schumann. - No. Your first name.
Wilhelm.
lt's perfect.
Perfect.
Stop that now!
- Have you made this trip before?
-Oh l make it at least twice a year.
- Are you in some sort of business?
- l'm in the jewelry business.
A special part. l sell
religious trinkets.
Any religion. You name it, l got it.
l sell neck chains, bracelets,
anklets.
lt sounds like good business.
lt's a very good business.
People feel better when
they wear these things.
l feel good too.
With all this stuff on me, l feel
like an African l met in Paris.
He bought from me a crucifix,
Buddha and mezuzah. All on one chain.
Do you know what he said?
He said, lt may not help,
but it can't hurt.
You seem to get along
very well with people.
Oh l like people.
lf you look for it, you can find
something good in anybody.
lt must be difficult sometimes.
For instance, doesn't it bother you
that you and that little man..
..are the only two Germans who
aren't at the captain's table?
Do you think that bothers me?
Besides, l like that little man.
What kind of a salesman do
you think l would be..
..if l couldn't deal with
a situation like that?
A salesman is supposed
to deal with..
..a difficult situation
and overcome it.
Listen. lt's not a new story.
White men hate black men.
Moslems hate Buddhists.
That's the way it goes. There's
prejudice everywhere.
lt does no good to give it back.
You have got to use your noggin.
There now, you must not mind
not winning against me.
After all, l was Ping-Pong champion
of the Sportsverein in Frankfurt..
..three times over.
- Morning.
- Morning. - Morning.
Herr Freytag picks some
bizarre company.
Ja, l suspect they are
birds of a feather.
Well, shall we play again?
Or perhaps l might suggest
another game.
- What game? - Any game.
One which you might win.
- What game do you mean?
- You have no idea?
l will not let you talk
that way to me.
- l'm sorry. - How dare you!
l could not resist.
l couldn't resist either.
What do your parents feel
about you going to Europe?
My mother's thrilled. lt's
something she's always wanted to do.
l think my father gave me up
for lost a long time ago.
- What do your parents do?
- My father owns a store.
lt's a good store.
A furniture store.
My mother's never been
satisfied with it.
She taught me that a woman had..
..to have something of her very
own outside of her husband..
..otherwise, it was bridge games
and one day a week at the hospital.
What about that young man
you're traveling with?
David. David's an artist.
A wonderful one.
He's a bit caught up with social
consciousness right now..
..but he'll get over that.
ls it serious?
l never felt about anybody
the way l do about David.
l think that David thinks a woman..
..should follow three paces
behind with slippers.
Men usually do.
My husband certainly did. No, thank
you. l have a whiskey sour.
- What did your husband do?
-He was in the diplomatic corps.
Oh.. we put up a wonderful
front in public.
We were everybody's favorite couple.
ln private, it was something
else again.
He was jealous of me.
He was so jealous of
me that he hit me.
He hit me till l bled at the nose.
l was wondering whether
David would beat me.
We quarrel sometimes.
lt seems to come out of nothing..
.. and then it grows into such
ugliness and bitterness.
lt surprises both of us.
l guess a relationship
between a man..
..and a woman is very difficult
these days, isn't it?
Practically impossible.
Put on your beret, Carlos.
Now we can hang in The Prado.
We will hang somewhere, Carlos.
The place is uncertain.
- That's enough for today.
Thank you. - Anytime.
l just can't tell you
how much l admire you.
Why?
You create.
l'm not even sure about that.
l've never been given a
penny for any of this.
Still, l envy you. l envy
you your struggle.
l envy you your doubts
and floundering, even.
And Fraulein Brown.
l envy you that too.
She's an attractive girl, isn't she?
Are you two going to be married?
l am sorry. l don't mean to pry.
You know, the distasteful curiosity
of the non participant.
That's all right. l don't honestly
know whether we'll get married.
l told you how uncertain my life is.
Look l need all the help l can get.
l need someone who can believe in a
man who hasn't proved himself yet.
Someone to be there. Be for me.
Couldn't Fraulein Brown be that?
Fraulein Brown is a modern woman.
Their needs are a lot more
complicated than our mothers' were.
l'm crazy about Jenny. l really am.
l.. l've never felt this way about
anybody, the way l feel about her.
l guess l'm afraid to find out
how apart we really might be.
l see.
l see, l suppose one of the saddest
things in the world must be..
..to see two people who feel
so much for each other..
..and who feel that they
belong together..
..and yet they really don't
belong together at all.
- Hello. - Hello.
What are you doing?
l'm making one of these.
- How many of these
do you have? - Many.
Here is a bull.
A dog.
Do you think anyone in first class
would be interested to buy them?
l would.
Good morning.
- How long have you been here?
- About a half an hour.
No, no, don't get up. Lie back.
Did you put this over me?
Of course.
l'm glad to see you are on deck.
lt was a wonderful drug you
gave me, whatever it was.
What was it, incidentally?
You don't expect me
to tell you, do you?
Oh you can actually laugh.
Did l startle you very much?
lt's good to hear you laugh too.
Did you ever have all
the worst possible..
..things that can happen
to you happen?
Well, it gives you the most
irresponsible feeling.
Nothing more can happen.
Hey!
Are you all right?
lt takes a great deal of courage
to tangle with those two.
l have a certain security with them.
They are the only characters on
the boat smaller than l am.
Such a charming lady makes a
charming morning even more charming.
Thank you.
He's wonderful.
He certainly is.
The one thing about
these children..
..they seem to have a better
time than anyone on the boat.
lf you expect me to speak
a word in defense..
..of those two little monsters,
you're much mistaken.
My prescription for them is to throw
them overboard in a leaky lifeboat.
You didn't have a childhood at all?
Nothing like theirs.
At least, l hope not.
Well.. when l was 4, l persuaded my
little brother to drink lye water.
- Lye water? - Yeah, l
told him it was milk.
So he went to screaming about the
house. His mouth was scrubbed out.
l was beaten black-and-blue.
l meant him no harm.
l was only curious to know
whether it would kill him.
And what about your childhood?
Did nothing gay ever
happen to you at all?
No.
l was the perfect dupe.
l believed anything
anybody ever told me.
l was full of the highest hopes and
the most unbelievable innocence.
However it's true, at the age of 12
..l did have an experience
with the housekeeper..
..that left an indelible
impression on me..
..shocked my mother no end and
cost the poor girl her job.
Well, there is hope
for you after all.
Oh.. the toreros are having
a fiesta tonight.
- l know. - Are you coming?
l wasn't planning to.
l thought we might have
a dance if you did.
Of course, you probably don't dance.
- Exactly how dull do you
think l am? - You are dull.
You're dull..
..stolid..
..unimaginative..
..helpless..
..and charming.
Yes, charming.
Oh you're blushing.
That's the most charming thing l've
ever seen in my whole life.
l've never seen a man blush before.
l'm not blushing. l must
have a temperature.
Well anyway, l'll wear my..
my only dress..
..and l'll give you the choice
of any dance you like.
And l have a feeling it's
gonna be a slow waltz.
l happen to excel in the flamenco.
l was an intellectual.
l was a philosopher and
teacher of philosophy.
Until three years ago, l learned
l was going to die.
Then my wisdom dropped from
me like soiled rags.
l was naked as the day l was born.
l heard a voice.
The most loving voice l've ever
heard. The voice of God!
And God said to me..
God speaks to him. He speaks
to him personally.
Be quiet, Gregorio! You have
to spit on everything.
l asked myself, why was l afraid?
What are my personal sufferings..
..but a divine grace that can
be made useful to others?
- The miracle is.. - Miracle?
What miracle? Can you
make us a miracle?
Can you get us out
of this slop and..
..into the upper decks, where
we a man can breathe?
- That is a miracle.
-You blasphemous pig!
You are the pig. We are all pigs.
Look at the way we live!
Listen! Listen to me!
- God's mercy is in.. - God?
There is no God down here!
Do you know what l would
do if God were here?
l would curse him to his face.
- Yeah!
l would spit in his face!
l would send him down into
his own hell! - Yeah!
- Get him out of here! - Yeah!
Wait! Wait! You can't!
The hoses. And give them more
than a bath this time.
Yes, sir. The hoses!
- A toast to 'el capitan.'
- A toast to 'el capitan'!
'El Capitan', with the hope that
this beautiful occasion..
..may serve to bring those
two great countries..
..Spain and Germany,
closer together.
The Spanish heritage, the German
empire in all its glory.
- 'El Capitan', - 'El Capitan',
Good God.
Looking for someone?
What do you mean?
Dr. Schumann is a very
charming man, isn't he?
He's in steerage.
People say there are
only three reasons..
..why a man would
be a ship's doctor:
He wants to travel. Or
his health is not good.
Or he's escaping from the law.
Which is it with Dr. Schumann?
Dr. Schumann has a quite serious
case of heart trouble.
Will you excuse me?
- What is your name?
- My name is Johann.
Why were you staring at me, Johann?
- How is your father?
- He's my uncle.
He's sleeping in the cabin.
The doctor gave him something
to quiet him down.
- Dance with me. - l don't dance.
l will show you.
Do you feel that?
Only Spanish women move like that.
lt is called the 'meneo.'
Feel?
l am not a gypsy, you know.
l am real Spanish, and
this is the sign.
- You're doing it on purpose.
- Oh, no.
l was born this way.
Do you hear what they say?
My hip bones.
They say, 'Meneo..'
.. 'meneo'..
..all by themselves.
- Will you buy me a bottle
of champagne? - l can't.
Just a small bottle.
l don't have anything.
Not a pfennig.
Excuse me.
- Shall we sit down?
- Oh, yes. Of course.
Here we are.
- You're doing your job
very well. - My job?
lsn't it the duty of the
ship's personnel..
..to see that unescorted women
don't get too unhappy?
- l am here because l want to be.
-Now you really are doing very well.
Don't you believe me?
Does it matter whether l do or not?
Well perhaps you would
prefer to remain alone.
Oh, no. No. Please stay
and have a drink with me.
lt's my birthday.
ls it really your birthday?
Forty-six. Me, 46. l
can't believe it, 46.
Well we Europeans are not as
conscious of age as you are.
Besides, when one looks as you
do and arouses in people..
..the feeling you do,
does it really matter?
You're very kind.
There's a time when hearts
grow cold and hard.
Women lose their grace
and become shrill.
They run to fat or
turn to beanpoles.
Take to secret drinking.
They marry men too young for them
and get just what they deserve.
lt's enough to scare anyone..
..waiting for fear and loneliness
to do their work.
Mrs. Treadwell, you are a very
exciting woman, and you know it.
Tell me.
Wouldn't it unnerve you to
have an affair with me?
Good evening. Are you enjoying
yourselves? You're not dancing.
Captain, do you have a second?
- Yes.
There's a man in steerage. One of
your men took his carving knife away.
He needs his knife for his work.
This is the kind of thing he does.
Very nice. Very nice indeed.
The man's an artist. He's not
gonna do anybody any harm.
- You are absolutely certain
of that? - l'm certain.
Unfortunately, l have to be answerable
not only for your safety..
..but for the safety of the ship.
Captain, the man is an artist. He
needs his knife for his work.
l'm sorry.
Enjoy the party.
l feel sorry for him.
You feel sorry for him?
He's a nice man. He doesn't
like doing this.
But he's doing it. That's
the point, isn't it?
David, you're gonna
hate me for this..
..but l'm glad those people in
steerage don't have knives.
What's the matter? Afraid they'll come
up over the sides and murder us..
..in our nice, clean, white beds?
Maybe they should.
You're so unattractive
when you get like this.
So violent and myopic.
lt's exactly the kind of thing
that infects your work.
What about my work?
l told you no one would
dance with me.
Elsa, dance with your father.
- Mama, please. - Dance
with your father.
Elsa.
When you go to a dance, you
first dance with your escort.
Now, l am your escort, so you
will first dance with me.
Then, when you're seen dancing,
someone else will invite you.
Besides, you haven't danced with
your papa since your last birthday.
Papa, please. l don't want to dance.
l'm sorry. l didn't
know anyone was here.
Don't be ashamed. What's the matter?
Come here. Sit down.
Sit down. Come here. Come here.
Tears are good. You know
what they say in Turkey?
They say tears wash the eyes
and one can see better.
At least l think they
say it in Turkey.
Turkey.
Now tell us, what is the reason for
this great emotional outburst?
Why isn't a charming young
lady like you inside..
..enjoying the music and dancing?
Because no one wants to dance
with me. And l'm not charming.
You are telling me you
are not charming?
An expert who has been to lstanbul,
Hamburg and Paris?
You are telling me?
And l am telling you that anybody
with eyes in his head..
..can see that you are charming.
Ask anybody with any intelligence.
Ask Glocken.
ls this young lady charming
or isn't she?
- Charming. - There.
l told you.
And how old are you?
Sixteen.
Adolescence.
What is adolescence?
Adolescence is a time when people
worry about things..
..there's no need to worry about.
Sixteen.
l promise you, at 1 7, you will be
even more charming than you are now.
At 21 , you will be gorgeous.
And at 25, devastating.
And l won't stand any arguments.
'Tales from the Vienna Woods.'
David, 'Tales from
the Vienna Woods.'
Dance with me.
You never like to dance.
l think l've been happiest
when l was dancing.
Sometimes l wish..
..that l'd tied a tape measure to
my ankle when l danced all my life.
Then l could tell you how many miles
l've traveled when l was happiest.
David, dance with me.
Well..
l'm gonna enjoy this party
in spite of you, David..
..so if you'll excuse me..
..l'm gonna dance with the
first man who asks me.
And here he comes.
- May l have this dance?
- Delighted.
Good evening.
Good evening. You seem
in good spirits.
- l am. l delivered a baby tonight.
- How wonderful.
- What was it, a boy
or a girl? - Boy.
- What about our celebration?
- What do you mean?
- Our dance. - You intimidated
me. l really don't dance.
l thought so. Well, this is a waltz,
and even you can manage a waltz.
- l doubt it. - l don't.
Just follow me and then
follow the music.
How do you feel?
l can't seem to get over this cold.
But l guess l'll be better if l
can get another night's sleep.
- You have to help me again.
- lt's not helping you.
Oh, Willie. Don't lecture me.
You'll lose count.
l'm trying to tell you
how serious it is.
Why are you trying to tell me?
Are you trying to tell
me l'm an addict?
As a publisher, my aim is to direct
the minds of the readers..
..to the vital issues
of our society.
l have lately got a doctor to begin
a series of articles advocating..
..the extermination of
all the unfit at birth.
That's the way it's with Herr
Rieber. He's thinking all the time.
All this will be accomplished
painlessly, of course. Painlessly.
Not only defective or useless
children, but the old too.
Old persons over 60 or 65, perhaps.
The same measures will be taken
with Jews, of course..
..and any illegitimate
mixtures of race.
White with colored of any kind,
Chinese, Negroes..
..and for any white man convicted
of a serious crime..
..well, as for him..
There is only one problem with
all this. Who will be left?
That is the difficulty. No one is
ever willing to accept a new idea.
Shall we dance?
l like to listen to Herr Rieber.
Every time l listen to him,
l feel reassured.
l know no one could ever take
him or his party seriously.
Pardon me.
May l?
How do you feel?
Try a little longer.
l promise to help you
when the time comes.
l want to sit down.
lt's a nice party. Are
you enjoying it?
Can l have a cigarette, please?
May l get you something?
Thank you.
Excuse me, please.
l feel like l'm gonna die.
l know.
- What the hell's the matter with
you? - You are selfish, boorish..
l don't know why l can't
get you out of my system.
You're not even really pretty.
- Thank you.
Your head is filled with such garbage!
l wish l could just empty it out.
Take your hands off me! David, stop
it. l'll call for the purser.
- Leave me alone. - Jenny, Jenny..
What? What do you
want from me? What?
l wish l knew.
Oh, Jenny. Jenny, what's the matter?
l'm crying. That's what's
the matter, l'm crying.
The sweetest face. The sweetest
face in the world.
David. David, what's
gonna happen to us?
You never were any good at that.
lt has a zipper, remember?
What a wonderful sky.
l'm sure you and your wife
watch clouds together.
l wish there was someone
to watch clouds with me.
You're an extremely romantic woman,
Mrs. Treadwell, aren't you?
lt's been the handicap of my life.
l can't settle for things. Bernard
Shaw said it, didn't he?
lf you can't get what you want..
..you better damn well settle
for what you can get.
What did you want, Mrs. Treadwell?
A useful life.
Someone to love me. Forever.
Ridiculous of me, wasn't it?
And what happened?
l chose the wrong man.
How many times have you heard
that said, l wonder.
He was the most promising.
The most handsome.
He had the most glorious facade.
The facade was all there was.
He made me the best-known wife of
the best-known skirt-chaser..
..in the community.
l made life hell for him.
lt ended in the divorce courts.
We met one day in the corridor
outside the courtroom.
He struck me.
l took every penny he had.
So you must forgive me if l'm not
exactly receptive to the idea..
..of other people's happiness
in marriage. l'm envious.
You and your wife probably
have the closest thing..
..to a perfect life as one can get.
Nothing is perfect, Mrs. Treadwell.
l just wanted to tell you that l
would have bought the champagne.
l would have bought it
if l had the money.
Come in.
- How old are you? - Nineteen.
You're one year older than l am.
Can you give me something?
l'm not asking for much, but
l must have something.
Pepe would beat me within
an inch of my life..
..if l don't give him something.
But aren't you a dancer?
You better go.
Good. More dollars.
Let's see, there was the
student and the sailor..
- What about him? - He
did not have anything.
- What was he doing here?
- He wanted to see me.
Did it ever occur to you that
someone might just want to see me?
Did it ever occur to you that..
..l might want to be with
someone my own age?
l am a human being too Pepe,
whether you think so or not.
Who told you? Who told you
you were a human being?
lf it were up to you, l would spend
the whole voyage on my back.
l'll tell you what you are.
What you are is something
l picked up on the street..
..when you were 14 with
dirty underpants.
Trying to stop men for
a few 'centavitos'
..for you and your dirty family.
Lowenthal! You're snoring!
That's what my wife says.
Why are they doing this to you?
l lived with a man who controlled
the lives of 5000 people.
l mean controlled.
l didn't want to, but l became
entangled with those people's lives.
l came to know that every
piece of food l ate..
..every piece of clothing l had..
..was coming out of their lives.
One day, l entered one
of their houses.
l'll never forget it.
The woman who lived there saw..
..the shock in my eyes
at the way they lived.
And she said, Pardon me.
l said, Pardon you for what?
So she said, Pardon me for my house,
pardon me for the way it looks..
..pardon me for everything.
And then she said, But, of course,
you must understand that..
..most of this place
is a garbage dump..
..and l'm just a piece of garbage.
l began by hiding agitators
in the chapel of the house..
..and l ended by helping
them get arms.
You don't say anything.
l don't know what to say.
l haven't met many
people in my life..
..who have committed themselves
to anything.
You never talk about yourself.
There's not very much to tell.
l came from a Hamburg worker's family,
l worked hard to become a doctor.
- l tried to be a man, l got
this. - lt is formidable.
lt's idiotic. Marked
for life like cattle.
Are you married?
Children?
Two sons.
Are you happy?
Who is happy?
Why isn't she here with you now?
There was no reason in dragging her
halfway across the world with me.
What about you? Are you married?
- Three times. - What happened?
Never found the right one.
Maybe l was waiting for
someone like you..
..someone l could teach the waltz.
l'm sure.
Just think. lsn't it wonderful?
Two strangers on a ship.
We will never meet again.
And we can talk.
We can talk like friends.
Or even lovers.
We can talk like two people who
meet on the other side of the grave.
Keep talking.
Do you have any feeling for me?
No, of course not.
Of course not.
lt's funny.
You know what l thought
you might be?
l thought you might be the
innocent, romantic love..
..l should have had in my girlhood.
Of course, nobody ever
loved me innocently.
And how l would have laughed
at him if he had.
l never could hit a curve
ball on the outside corner.
l beg your pardon?
l never could hit a curve
ball on the outside corner.
That's very interesting.
What does it mean?
You wouldn't know if l told you.
All right, l'll tell you.
You're at bat, see? At bat.
Bat! Bat!
Okay, now you're at bat. The
pitcher, he's out there.
Now he's winding up, and
he turns her loose and..
Just as it gets to you,
it dips down and away.
And that is a curve ball
on the outside corner.
l could never hit that
pitch with a paddle.
- l see. - No, you don't see.
You don't see at all.
You don't know what it's
like to be out there..
..crowd's yelling
for you to deliver.
And they start talking.
The pitchers, they talk.
He can't hit a curve ball
on the outside corner.
And from then on out,
that's all you see..
..is curve balls on
the outside corner.
So you've had your big chance.
And you have muffed it.
l can still hear my old man yelling
at me from the stands..
..even though he wasn't there.
Big Will. You are a bum!
You are a bum, just like me.
l think you're being a bit harsh
on yourself, Herr Tenny.
A bum.
You know, l travel a lot.
My folks give me some money.
Not much, but some.
They are more comfortable
when l'm not around.
You know what l find? l find the
most amusing things about people..
..are their guilt's that they
drum up for themselves.
For instance, l estimate that
there must be at least..
..873 million people in the
world who don't even know..
..what a curve ball on
the outside corner is.
So l think it a bit excessive for
you to think that you have..
..muffed your whole life just..
..because you couldn't hit it,
paddle or no paddle.
Do you understand what
l mean, Herr Tenny?
No.
You know what l think?
- No. - l think..
..that you are a sawed-off
intellectual.
Bottoms up, shorty.
The purser, from whom l learn what
little l know about this ship..
..has informed me that you were
seen leaving La Condesa's cabin..
..at a highly unrespectable hour.
No comment, Willie? l think that's
one of the reasons l like you.
You don't have my vulgarity.
l wonder if it's really true that
life is as stupid and meaningless..
..as it seems to be on this ship.
The Lutzes and their daughter, the
Huttens and their blessed dog.
And that gross little Rieber..
..who thinks of himself as
the wave of the future.
l suppose a great case could be
made for my own foolishness.
Will your wife be there to
meet you at Bremerhaven?
She's a wonderful woman.
We've been polite to each other
for a good many years.
Well, your sons will
be glad to see you.
We hardly know each other anymore.
What will you do, go back
to your practice?
l'm the kind of doctor l hate.
The hack general practitioner.
What would you have
liked to have been?
- A good doctor. - Don't
you think you are?
Fair to middling.
What do you think happens to
a woman like La Condesa..
..when she's deported under
such circumstances?
How long are you going to
keep me a penniless beggar?
Do l have to ask you for change
to go to the barber?
- Remember the agreement, Johann?
- The agreement.
You are to receive everything
after my death.
Your mother was so pleased for you.
She was so pleased for
your opportunity.
My mother was pleased for a
chance for money for herself.
How can you keep me a penniless
beggar? How can you do that?
Don't you have a heart at all?
l have a heart. That's
why l can do it.
What would you do with
the money, Johann?
l have seen you watch that
gypsy dancer's buttocks..
..as she walks on the deck.
l will not nourish your lust.
- Good morning. - Good morning.
- Good morning.
l have been trying to persuade Mrs.
Treadwell to have some breakfast.
There's nothing like it, you know.
Especially the morning after.
At home, we always used
to have it English-style:
Kidneys, sausages, kippers,
things like that.
How elegant.
Well, l think l'll look in
on the bar before dinner.
What a hard-trying race they are.
English-style for breakfast,
French-style for dinner.
And every now and again, a
comfortable lapse back..
..to sauerbraten, sauerkraut
and beer.
He seems very attentive;
l'll say that for him.
Did you ever see such
a collection of bores?
The attentive Lt. Huebner, the
happily-married man Herr Freytag.
And here comes the ape.
Morning.
'Espece de type'!
How's the painting?
l haven't been able to
do much onboard, but..
..here's something l've
been doodling with.
You can see l'm in love.
Of course. Everybody on
this ship is in love.
Love me whether or not l love you.
Love me whether l am fit to love.
Love me whether l am able to love.
Even if there is no
such thing as love.
Love me.
- Where've you been? - l've been
talking to that Mrs. Treadwell.
You know, she's so bitter.
She frightens me sometimes.
Well, what do you think?
lt's interesting.
l think it's good.
Well, of course it's good.
You couldn't do anything
that wouldn't be good.
- lt's wonderful. - But?
Does it have to be the same
thing all the time?
Just what do you mean?
You know; the exploitation
of the masses.
Well, it's true, isn't it?
Well, it's just that.. No matter
how well these things are done..
..they always turn out to be
posters after all, don't they?
You hate my work, don't you, Jenny?
l think it's good.
- Here he comes. Now, watch.
- What is it?
l told the steward. Just watch.
- lf you will come this way, sir.
- l'm going to have lunch.
Yes. Another table has
been arranged for you.
- Arranged? Who arranged it?
- Right over here, sir.
Now he will see how we feel.
Dr. Schumann, they have placed
Herr Freytag at another table.
Herr Rieber, you are a real
anti-Semite. l don't know any Jews.
l don't know anything
about them at all.
l'm not an anti-Semite.
How can you say that?
l'm very fond of the Arabs.
l lived among them for a while and
found them to be very good people.
You have not said a word, Dr.
Schumann.
What do you think about..?
- Excuse me.
Doctor has heart trouble.
Do you suppose we should send
to inquire after him?
Schumann.
Schumann. ls that not a Jewish name?
My wife is Jewish.
l told that American woman.
- She must have told them.
- Now come, have some wine.
lt's Niersteiner Domtal.
Why be upset? The company is
much better at this table..
..l can assure you.
When Glocken isn't smoking one
of his foul-smelling cigars.
You know l don't mind not being
seated at the captain's table.
Perhaps because l was never
invited in the first place.
Those pious hypocrites.
- Why do you take it? - l have
been taking it for a long time.
Oh, yes, he has. He has 2000 years
of suffering behind him.
Well, l'm not going to take it.
A little patience. A
little understanding.
The world's getting
better all the time.
As my Aunt Rebecca used to say..
l don't give a damn what your
Aunt Rebecca used to say.
Do you think any of you are
any better Germans than l am?
Do you?
Yes. Yes, l have a Jewish wife.
She's Jewish. Let me
tell you about her.
She'd never hurt anyone in her life.
Anyone.
You.. You good, middling people.
You aren't fit to be in
the same world as her.
l saw some of you in the chapel this
morning. You kneel there and pray.
You pretend that you
are good people.
Good people?
You can't even exist without
your prejudices.
And the worst thing about you is..
..that you don't even
recognize what you are.
You..
Sometimes l think, in spite
of how much you understand..
..it's enough already.
What's going on?
They moved Herr Freytag from
the captain's table..
..because his wife is Jewish.
And it's my fault.
l had to tell that dreadful Brunhilda
to stop her from chattering on so.
So stupid of me. He's
such a nice man.
l'd no idea this was
going to happen.
- You're not gonna cry,
are you? - Of course not.
l never cry.
What do they got against the Jews?
Back home, we don't have anything
against the Jews.
Hell, l never even saw
a Jew till l was 15.
Maybe you were too busy lynching
Negroes to take time out for the Jews.
Why don't you ring for the steward?
He might give you something.
l have been ringing! Ringing!
Ringing! Ringing!
A fellow gave these pills
to me in Tangiers.
He had a theory that seasickness has
something to do with the eardrums.
You know, Lowenthal?
Yes?
You are really not
such a bad fellow.
You think so?
These statements that l make, you
mustn't take them personally.
No, of course not.
lt is the march of history. History
is beyond us, Lowenthal.
Feel better?
- A little. - Good.
You know, the thing l can't understand
is why you want to go back to Germany.
l would not want to be
where l was not wanted.
Why don't you go back
to your own country?
Germany is my country. My
father was born in Germany.
And my grandfather was
born in Germany.
As a matter of fact, where are you
from? l can't place your accent.
You speak German like no
one l have ever heard.
The last 20 years of my life
were spent in Germany.
Austria?
Near the border.
That's what l thought.
Lowenthal, you know it is
a historical fact that..
..the Jews are the basis
of our misfortunes.
- Of course. - You agree?
Of course. The Jews and
the bicycle riders.
Bicycle riders? Why
the bicycle riders?
Why the Jews?
- Hey, what's going on?
- Man overboard!
Man overboard!
Hey, man overboard!
- Get her out of here! - Take
her to our cabin, please.
Turn him over.
Can you understand it?
A man jumps from a moving ship at
night, in the middle of the ocean.
And is drowned to save
the life of a dog.
Yes, l can understand.
Who was he?
He was a woodcarver. He carved
little animals with his pocketknife.
Come in, please.
Doctor, what can we do?
Well, you're doing all
that can be done.
- How did it happen? - Yeah.
How did it happen?
- He was thrown overboard.
-Who would do such a thing?
But look at him. He knows that
someone tried to drown him!
- His heart is broken. - Doctor!
You are not leaving?
Perhaps we could get him some
broth. Some hot broth.
Yes. You can give him some broth.
lt won't do any harm.
ls that all?
Yes, that's all.
The man who saved him is dead.
Did he say a man is dead?
l know how you feel.
No. You don't. You're
like the others.
You thought the captain was
justified in taking his knife away.
That's what you thought, wasn't it?
You were the one who felt
sorry for the captain.
That was you, wasn't it?
Why can't we be honest
with each other?
l don't know.
- Maybe we're afraid to be.
- Well, let's try.
Maybe we'd better try.
You say l hate your painting.
Well, l do.
Oh, God help me, but l do.
l don't know why.
You've said it. Maybe it's because
l'm not very good at it myself.
Or maybe.. just maybe it's because
it means so much to you..
..more than anything,
more than even me.
That's being honest, isn't it?
Yes, that's honest.
Well, l'll tell you something
that's even more sad.
l can't be what you want me to be.
And l know what you need. You need
someone just to be there..
..to deny herself for you.
David, l wish l could be
like that, but l can't.
- l just can't. - Jenny,
l know you can.
Well, it means leaving
me with nothing.
You know? Nothing.
Jenny, do you know what l need?
l need something very simple.
l need a woman. But that's so
difficult for you, isn't it?
You're so full of competition.
Do you know how empty it is,
how frustrating it is..
..to reach out for something and
then you find it isn't there?
To feel that someone is with you.
David, don't you think that l am?
Don't you think that l
am in spite of myself?
- Haven't l tried everything? - Yes,
you have tried. You've split a gut.
lt's so hard for you. l know.
lt's so hard for both of us.
All right, you say my work is..
..the most important thing
in my life. lt is.
But that's the way l am.
l can't help it.
And whoever shares my life is just
going to have to put up with that.
She's going to have to
live a life for me.
Jenny, l know this sounds
selfish, but it's true.
We're not gonna go on
together, are we?
Are we?
David?
Come in.
l would have come to you.
Well, they said you
weren't feeling well.
l'm just tired, that's all.
- Were you sleeping? - No.
Don't you know it's very unhealthy
to sleep with your clothes on?
- Where are they? - What?
- Where are they? - What are you
looking for? - Where are..
Stop rifling through my things.
Here they are. Put them on.
Come on. Put them on.
And l'll read to you
until you sleep.
Some pretty risqu? literature
you've got here.
'Natural Resistance' and
'Clinical Medicine.'
'Researches on Rheumatism.'
'Diseases.. '
l don't know why l'm so tired.
Why, yes, of course. Well, that's
the way it is sometimes.
The woodcarver died.
Yes, l know.
l have been unable to
accept death. Never.
No matter how many
times l've seen it.
l always feel as though
l'm responsible.
Now..
..let's see what we've got here.
The dissolute Lady Chatterley sat
waiting for the gardener to enter.
He entered, stopping for a moment,
sensing someone in the room.
His muscles sinewy in the moonlight.
She spoke his name softly. The
gardener went over to her.
He kissed Lady Chatterley..
..with a kiss such as she had
never been given before.
Her arms were waiting for him,
both resisting and demanding.
'Jonathan, ' she said, 'Jonathan,
darling, you are violating me.'
Where did you get that?
You're so strange.
Sometimes you're so bitter. Then
you're soft and warm, like a child.
l'm just a woman.
Lie back.
There's three days to Tenerife.
l know.
What will your treatment be like
for you there? Do you know?
Will you be imprisoned?
lt will be some kind of an
imprisonment, l imagine.
But you mustn't think of me
sleeping on a stone floor..
..and living on bread and water.
This is not my style.
Now..
Now l'm going to read to you..
..from this book exactly
the way it's written.
lf this doesn't put you to sleep,
nothing ever will.
The liver is a large,
glandular organ..
..irregularly shaped and
of reddish-brown color.
Come on.
- Please come with me to the table.
- No. l've done enough.
You just have to take it
from here on by yourself.
- Are you sure l look all right?
- You look lovely.
Now, go on.
Good evening.
Hello.
Waiter.
l would like one bottle
of champagne, please.
Would you like to join me?
Why not? What are we celebrating?
Quarrel?
lt's over.
l'm sorry.
Will you excuse me? l have
to go to the bridge.
Do you want to dance?
No.
No, not this time.
Thank you.
l think l'm going to
go to my cabin..
..because for me, a little
German music goes a long way.
Don't be embarrassed.
Nobody is watching.
Will l see you later?
Later.
Herr Freytag?
Herr Freytag!
l want to tell you how sorry l am.
l wanted to tell you that
with all my heart.
Heart?
You have no hearts. Any of you.
l'm sorry. l've no right
to be rude to you.
l have no right to
be rude to anybody.
You must be very much in love..
..with your wife to stand
up for her that way.
My wife and l are separated.
Yes.
Yes!
l..
l thought l could face what we had
to go through after we were married.
l couldn't.
l wasn't ready to give
up my position..
..because of my employer's
prejudices.
My family talked to me about it.
My friends.
My dear friends.
So l panicked.
Panicked!
l asked my firm to transfer
me to Mexico.
And you'll never believe what l did.
l wrote a letter.
Dear Marianne:
We can't go on together.
l've imagined her face a thousand
times when she got the letter.
That face has followed
me everywhere.
Now l'm going back.
l don't even know where she is.
But l've got to find her.
Plead with her to understand.
To forgive me.
lf she cares for you,
she'll understand.
Don't you see?
Even if she does, l know
l'll never forget.
l wrote that letter.
Listen to that music, Glocken.
Now try to tell me you don't
react to that music.
Schmaltz.
Tell me, Glocken, now honestly.
When you hear that music
wherever you are..
..don't you have a special
feeling about being a German?
l'll tell you now
Lowenthal honestly.
When l hear that music
wherever l am..
..l have a special feeling
about being a dwarf.
l remember being thousands of miles
from home in a theater in New York.
They put on a picture of the
funeral of the Kaiserin Viktoria.
That good woman. How much
she meant to all of us.
You are German, aren't you?
You are the most German
person l have ever met.
l want to show you something.
l take it out every
once in a while..
..and look at it when
l want to feel good.
Why, the Order of the lron Cross!
Second class.
And a war hero, besides.
You may be the biggest fool
on this whole boat.
Why do you say that?
Where have you been
during this voyage?
Do you think this boat is a cross
section of the German people?
No!
You don't know the average
German the way l know him.
The people that produced a Goethe,
a Beethoven and a Bach..
..are not to be
sneezed at, you know?
50% of the people who produced a
Goethe, a Beethoven and a Bach..
..voted for Rieber's party last
week. - Forty-four percent.
Lowenthal, you are blind!
You're absolutely blind!
You can't see what's going on
in front of your own face.
What do you mean?
You mean this business about the
Jews? You don't understand us.
The German Jew is something special.
We are Germans first
and Jews second.
We have done so much for Germany.
Germany has done so much for us.
A little patience. A little
goodwill. lt works itself out.
Listen, there are nearly a
million Jews in Germany.
What are they going to
do? Kill all of us?
Karl, if you will excuse me. l want
to dance with a most charming lady.
Might l have the honor
of this dance?
- l want you to give me some
money or l will kill you.
Are you out of your mind?
- l will kill you. - Johann!
That's God's judgment.
l don't want to hear that anymore.
Don't you think l know
how you've treated me?
how you've cheated me?
Where is it? Where's the money?
Top drawer.
Come in.
l have money.
Come here.
Come on.
Put out my cigarette.
Tell me..
..am l your very first girl?
You are shaking. There is
nothing to be afraid of.
No.
The first time..
The first time is very important.
Stop it! Stop it! Stop it! Stop it!
l'm just teaching the
young lady flamenco.
You keep your hands
off her, you pimp.
Big hero.
l'm sorry.
l don't believe you're quite
sober, Mrs. Treadwell.
What could give you that impression?
God. He stalks them
like a mountain lion.
Did you see the makeup
on those girls?
- Do men really find that
attractive? - Some apparently do.
l would think that men
would like to know..
..what they were kissing.
l would like to know what
it is like to kiss you.
l have been looking at you,
thinking about you for a long time.
You never notice me. Why not?
Now you will not kiss me? Why not?
Do you want me to say l love you?
l never knew what people
meant by that word.
Say, don't say it. l can't
bear the sound of it.
Then why did you lead
me on during the trip?
You never considered my
feelings at all, did you?
No.
And l'm sorry for that.
Mrs. Treadwell, l'm only a third-grade
officer on a second-rate ship.
But it has given me an opportunity
to observe people.
l've seen women like you before.
Forty-six-year-old women
who are still coquettes.
They travel on boats often. Always
searching for something.
Do you know where that searching
ends Mrs. Treadwell?
lt ends by sitting in a nightclub
with a paid escort..
..who tells you the
lies you must hear.
You are a most mundane,
ordinary man.
How extraordinary that
a man like you..
..should be saying things
like this to me.
Probably true.
l think this evening's festivities
have come to an end.
- l shall be happy to see you to
your door. - lt's quite unnecessary.
l'll find my own way.
- Darling? - Yeah Leiben.
l didn't know there
was a Frau Rieber.
What do you mean, a Frau Rieber?
The purser told me you sent
a cable to Frankfurt..
..addressed to a Frau Rieber.
l did not mention it before, because
l could not bear the humiliation.
lt is the tragedy of my life.
She will not let me go.
l must go on supporting her
and the three children.
There are three children?
Well they have no understanding
of me.
And l have no understanding of them.
They hang on. They hang on. They
suck the life's blood out of me.
They will not let go.
l am a vital, passionate man.
l need love. l must have love.
Say you understand.
You must understand.
l understand.
Now, look, l bought you
a bottle of champagne, right?
A pack of them Sultana cigarettes..
..or whatever they are called
and two margaritas.
When are we gonna get together?
You have been drinking too much.
l think l will go now.
- Tonight. - Not tonight.
Tonight l am tired.
Tonight.
Very well. Just let go of my arm.
Hey. What's your cabin number?
Number 14.
l thought you weren't bothering
with that cheapskate.
l have planned something very
interesting for that cheapskate.
l gave him the cabin of that snotty
American bitch, Mrs. Treadwell.
l think you are mad.
l made some inquiries. They would
let me stay on the island.
l would be able to take care of her.
l understand your feeling about
her, her helplessness.
- But to give up everything.
- What would l be giving up?
- What would l be giving
up? - Your life!
My life. My life is obligations.
Obligation to nothing
that's real to me.
This woman.. this woman over there
in the cabin, she's real to me.
l know it sounds strange.
But she's the only real thing
that has happened to me.
Willy you have heard of shipboard
romances, haven't you?
She's sold you a bill of goods,
and you've fallen for it.
My god. l can see it if you can't.
She wants her precious needle.
- She doesn't want you.
- This may be true.
lf this is true..
When l had my heart attack,
there was a dream l had.
You can talk about death. l've
seen it many times as a doctor.
But you never know what it's like
until it almost happens to you.
l dreamed l had already died.
l dreamed l was in a box. The sweat
broke out all over my body.
l wanted to cry out, l can't
be dead, l haven't lived!
Who has?
Do you think this woman
is the answer, Willie?
A woman like this. All
she's been through.
She has seen everything. There
are no surprises left for her.
Even if it's love, Willie, l hope we
can deny the myth that love lasts.
You are not young, Mrs. Treadwell.
You have not been young for years.
Behind those old eyes, you
hide a 16-year-old heart.
Poor fool.
ls that what men really
find attractive?
Baby..
You just haven't managed to grow up.
Mrs. Treadwell of Murray
Hill, Virginia.
Now!
You can paint your toenails green.
You know how it ends, don't you?
Alone.
Sitting in a cafe..
..with a paid escort.
Let me go.
Mrs. Treadwell.
Excuse me. That greaser told
me Cabin 14. Excuse me.
Excuse me.
Get out!
You know l'm sorry, l truly am
sorry. l didn't know it l was just..
- Pig! - Hey, what the hell?
Go on. Get out. Get out. Get out!
Get out!
Get out. Get out. No! No!
- You were sleeping. - l know.
You cried out again.
Did l?
What is it?
lt's nothing.
- lt had to be something.
- lt was ridiculous.
Tell me.
Promise you won't laugh.
l won't laugh.
lt's something l saw the
time l went to Taxco.
lt was just a flash passing
by on the bus.
lt was a man and a woman. A crowd
had gathered around them.
They were staggering and swaying.
l thought they were dancing.
The man had his hand raised and
there was a long knife in it.
The woman's breast and
stomach were pierced.
The blood was so thick her skirt
was sticking to her legs.
She was beating him with a stone.
l'll never forget the
look on their faces.
lt wasn't all hatred.
lt was like there was some great
bond between them in that hatred.
And then they struck again.
l always dream about it in
some grotesque variation.
Tonight l was one of the watchers,
as if l were at a play.
Then something happened.
- What happened? - The
features changed.
Yeah?
David, the faces were
yours and mine.
Good evening, doctor.
Night, doctor.
Thank you for bringing
us home, 'capitan. '
The cuisine and the accommodations
were superb.
Yeah!
They've come for me?
For me, the voyage is over.
l have here an order..
..for something that will help
you. Any doctor will accept it.
Willie.. you try so hard.
My darling. My love.
For once, let's kiss
in broad daylight.
Bye.
l think we ought to be able to
reach Bremerhaven by Thursday morning.
Willie, you're drinking
up my best cognac.
Not that l mind, but that isn't the
thing you should be doing, is it?
You shouldn't be doing this.
l know you're still thinking about
her. She'll be all right.
By now l.. l'll guarantee she's
found someone to help her.
- Woman like that always
finds someone. - Shut up!
Willie.
That's a hell of a way to
waste good brandy, Willie.
When l think of the things
l've seen on this ship..
The stupid cruelties. The vanities.
We talk about values?
There's no values.
The dung we base our lives on.
She looked into the garbage dump.
She did something about it.
And we are the intelligent,
civilized people..
..who carry out orders we are given.
No matter what they may be.
Our biggest mission in life
is to avoid being fools.
And we wind up being the
biggest fools of all.
Why didn't l go?
Come in.
Herr doctor, Frau Lutz
wants to see you.
She say's her daughter Elsa
is not feeling well.
l'm coming.
To hell with them, Willie.
You rest here.
You don't look well. You should
see the way you look.
That is exactly what l mean.
- Good evening. - Good evening.
- Good evening.
- You called me? - Doctor,
can you give Elsa a purge?
Take two of those before you retire.
Doctor, aren't you going
to take her temperature?
l think he's been drinking.
l can just hear you saying, What
has all this to do with us?
Nothing.
Subtitles by Ayaz [ ayazonline@gmail.com ]