-=Episode 34=-
Surely... this feels like a dream.
Sitting here, looking at you like this.
I feel the same. It's just like a dream,
and it's hard to believe that
the person in front of me is my mom.
I thought that
some of your childhood looks might remain.
Seeing you now,
I might not recognize you, if we met on the street.
I too think you are very different from
what I imagined my mom to look like.
I learned from a newspaper
a few months ago, that your dad passed away.
How was the funeral done?
He was cremated.
His ashes were sprinkled in the river.
Finally handing over even a career path to you,
I feel your dad really... did wrong with you.
I don't blame my dad.
Despite all, he did the best he could to care for me.
Instead, not listening to him
and make him hurt inside is what I did.
Dad was afraid of me
and never went for a step-mom.
He spent a lifetime alone like that, and left.
You still know how to empathize with your father?
He is very pitiful.
Life is very pitiful.
Never lived an ordinary person's life.
He passed away after a lifetime as a thief.
Unexpectedly even discipline so also don't have leave.
Over there passed away.
If mother hadn't abandoned father back then,
possibly father would not have been a thief.
It's possible he might have lived as an ordinary person.
It's not like that.
You don't understand your father.
How do I not understand?
Instead, you're the one who didn't understand him.
Mother only lived with Father for four years.
But I lived with him for twenty years.
Mother isn't qualified to scold Father.
You are being a rude person.
Because live don't have mother the to live.
I unknowingly become very be rude.
Welcome. May I ask, do you have a reservation?
That. Because have came together people.
May I ask, are you perhaps Ms. Hwang's daughter?
That's right. But who are you?
We met before in front of your house.
Still according to before your family.
Live in our house under neighborhood the person.
Yes.
So, You came with your mother!
I came with Chun Ok.
- Is that so?
- That's right.
So what's your relationship with that eonni?
It's a dating type of relationship.
So that's how it is?
May I drink some tea with you?
Fine. Please sit.
You don't know all the things your father did to me.
I have heard it before from father.
He lied to you and made you very sad.
Don't care who said what?
I can't forgive your father.
So do you think that for everything you've done to me,
you'll be able to obtain forgiveness?
Chun Ok!
You know I today why came to this situation?
It is not because I miss Mother now that I came here?
I came because I miss you.
Now, then say want to think of me?
How can you say such a thing?
Whenever I needed my mother
You even one time also never by my side.
not even once did you come to find me.
Mothers of other children
Will from classroom the window send over takeaway food.
Rain the days still know come over send umbrella.
But I didn't have that sort of mother.
No matter what?
That time all never before thought blame you.
Even if it is hate you also only want to read you.
If my good pleasant to hear granny,
Mother will come see me?
Only is like that thinking of.
Do you know how much I envied other children?
With mother together hitting on umbrella?
Do you know how many tears I shed
every rainy day?
At that time, I couldn't go looking for you.
Is have difficulty.
But is not bother go where?
Have always been get your placed in the heart.
Don't care at where? All at for you to pray.
Hope you are able living well.
That's right. Thank you for praying for me.
Thanks to mother for praying for me.
That's why I'm such a success today.
Chun Ok!
I'm sorry but my name is not Chun Ok.
I long ago changed to Yu Na.
It doesn't matter how you think about it.
You're my daughter. I'm your mother.
How can I not know your conduct and deeds?
But to appear blaming I.
Pursue over and can have what use?
I beg you, forgive me.
Sorry. I can't forgive you.
It's enough that I met my mom today.
Also. Hereafter, start don't need mother.
So, does ajussi do the same work as eonni?
You're asking whether or not I'm a thief, aren't you?
You can tell me the truth.
Yes.
I'm not. Also sister although at not long before.
Because steal the matter went before several times discipline so.
But now won't steal again.
Whether she'll do it or not in the future, we wouldn't know for sure.
That is a good question.
Sister hereafter, why never will steal something?
Although sister my will also important.
But I feel that with sister the surrounding.
People atmosphere also is very important.
Surrounding have some good people?
Not just a few but a lot!
I also can very pride land say.
Oneself is a good man the one of them people.
Because of me just staying at next door.
Just like Jin Dao dog the same guarding her.
So she simply to be unable to move a single step.
Ajussi likes that eonni?
Of course. Like!
Because like. That's why let her with mother meet?
Also advise she won't steal again.
If sister one more time steal something.
Then I then, will not let her off.
I'm really envious of eonni! Because ajussi is at her side
Of course must envious.
Sister cannot without me.
Is sister called in.
It's me.
Want to eat sugar?
Why did you say you can't forgive her?
I've always wanted to say those words.
Now enough.
Can see last noodle is more than enough.
Bawl out one meal mother later.
Mentality feel that overjoyed?
"I cannot forgive."
This sentence only God can say.
Not you can casually say come out.
In fact, I hope mother can first come look for me.
Young that time one sky already imagined before several
times.
Mother come look for me the scene.
Have seen mother later what to do?
Scold one meal later later.
Still want to hold in mother the embrace loudly cry bitterly.
Now you equal to pain gave a good scolding.
But have seen mother later.
it also feels a bit like I haven't,
so I'm even more sad.
It's just like I've seen some ajumma,
that I sat beside on the subway.
Will also not know that kind of raised path given birth ajumma.
Are you hungry?
Not hungry.
Because too nervous. So all unable to feel hungry.
Just now that shop the steak is very famous.
Since have gone to.
With mother eating together one plate steak will be good.
Have what to be okay?
Just to make you happy,
I have to eat steak there?
Just forget about it. No furthermore.
Looking for restaurant. Place an order.
Understand which family best eat.
Still have ordered the best position.
Oppa.
Where are you?
I just met some people and now I'm returning home.
Now, you if no if busy.
Then come one trip to like this?
Where's that?
Yesterday, I isn't it said before?
Want to give you introduce one junior.
Is currently with him drink a cup of wine.
Sorry. Today cannot go.
Why?
I'm a little tired today.
Is that so? Then there is no other way.
Today just return home to rest.
Oh, right!
How's the guy who took a beating from me yesterday?
I was afraid I might cause trouble,
so I didn't beat him very heavily.
He's OK.
Fortunately. In future, again will contact you?
Okay. See you again oppa.
Was that the oppa from yesterday?
That's right.
But just now have said nothing happened.
Yesterday by that older brother took beating
matters.
He asked me how your injuries were.
That's why I said you're OK.
I was quite badly hurt. I'm now really in a lot of pain,
why did you casually say I'm OK?
Really unfathomable mystery.
That older brother say. Afraid cause trouble.
So specially beaten not very heavy.
That fellow talk really unfathomable mystery!
He that type of play still call very lightly?
Is it because I avoid have?
So don't have receive serious injury.
Say I'm alright. What did he say?
He said is extremely fortunate.
Extremely fortunate. That's right.
I isn't already very fortunate already!
But you just wait and see.
He provoke wrong people.
Hereafter,
Plaintive the unfortunate may leave out to he body.
Anyway, just only will boasts.
I won't boasts.
Is as far as possible low voice next energy land.
At very calm land with you to say.
Where did you both go?
With other people after meeting.
But why are you out here?
Jjanggu-mom say must come.
Is that so?
We'll go up first.
But. You two together,
seem very well matched.
Thank you very much! Elderly.
Two people together come back!
Se Yi Pyeong An land arrive granny house.
That's right.
She called to say she arrived safe and sound.
She when leaving the time I already haven't seen she one look.
No conceal you say.
She said most miss grandpa with older sister.
I'll have to call to her later.
Hit? Should be will be very happy.
I'll first go into the house. Eldest brother.
You go and rest.
Return have came very early!
That's right. Because just past holiday.
So nothing guest.
What are you doing?
This month store the sum or volume of business.
At worthwhile altogether have how much?
Jin Mi has returned?
No matter what?
Sister the person cause is still good.
See Jin Mi still remain by your side.
Have someone cause and can do what?
This month also 1,000,000 the deficit.
That point money come out from other place earn won't that be enough.
But you gone to where?
Why now then will come back?
Today, I met my mother.
Really?
That's right. Really, my mother.
What is that medicine?
Is sleeping pill.
You can't take that sort of medicine too often.
It's not good for your health.
Nothing wrong.
Is a doctor give to me open the medicine.
But you for where have ox room!
I want to sleep with you, mother.
You don't want to sleep with me?
How can I not want to?
Let's sleep together.
Today, I see sister that split second.
Tears full eye socket.
Feel that sorry older sister.
You why feel sorry!
Originally was have to with sister together share mother.
But I've always alone occupied mother.
See what you have said?
That sister compared to me even more like mother.
I unable to see! You are like that feel that?
That's right.
Don't care who see?
Also will know sister is mom mother the daughter.
Also. With Chun Ok came together that bachelor.
Also say Chun Ok with me looked alike.
Perhaps. If sister have said with you be unhappy,
Also don't be too sad.
Don't need to worry.
Don't care Chun Ok what are you saying?
Mother also will not matter.
To live within don't have mother.
Light imagine also feel is frightening.
The more think about it the more feel that sister is very pitiful.
No matter what?
Is better sister side have one position good uncle.
So look very practical.
Are you talking about Chang Man?
Yes. Return to me left business card.
Still together have drank cup of tea.
From the beginning I'm also to him have warn heart.
But feels that he doesn't look like it a bad person.
Talk with him very interesting.
Have said what?
Say will Sang Jin Dao dog the same hold on to Chun Ok sister.
Won't let she again steal something.
He is doing what work?
Said is exactly exactly drink up the manager.
Drink up is what place?
I'm also not clear. But if let me come play.
And so. You have said will go to play.
Yes. Must go to once take a look.
Jjanggu-mom haven't come yet?
That's right. Never come.
Really strange.
Have done promise just have to come!
Cannot let elderly and other people!
Will be a bit late it's all right.
I have plenty of time.
Even if time again more.
Jjanggu-mom also cannot like this towards you.
What time did you arrange with Elderly today?
You didn't have an appointment?
Then what exactly is going on?
Elderly waited for you for three hours!
That's right. So where are you now?
At your younger sister's house?
Understand. So see you tomorrow?
She said simply don't have done promise.
It seems that Elderly was mistaken.
Is he waiting for volunteer worker ajumma?
Aspiration event ajumma will not so late set out on a long journey.
He must be mistaken.
You go to tell elderly.
Jjanggu-mom will not come.
Call him go into the house to rest.
Okay. There's no need. There's no need.
I'll go say it.
Wait a while.
Really can eat. Really can eat.
Eldest brother. Da Yeong mother talk on the phone.
Jjanggu-mom now at big field.
Is that so?
Have gone to younger sister house.
That's right.
This fellow really can eat.
So eldest brother was wrong.
Wrong about what?
Didn't you say Jjanggu-mom is coming?
Jjanggu-mom will come? When.
From in the evening start until now.
You not always waiting for Jjanggu-mom?
I wasn't waiting for her!
Elderly even dinner also don't have eat.
Always waiting for she.
Who am I waiting for?
Jjanggu-mom!
Also should have said I'm not waiting for her.
Elderly a bit strange!
Brother-in-law you also don't say anymore.
Hurry go back and rest.
Have what really strange?
Nothing.
Eldest brother. You go inside to rest.
Fine.
Dumpling. Grandpa going back to house.
Please eat.
Sit?
Eldest brother. You really can't remember?
Wait Jjanggu-mom the matter?
I don't remember!
So even dinner all won't eat.
Outside do something.
That also cannot too have remembered.
You said Jjanggu-mom would come.
Already all waited for three or four hours.
I was waiting for so long?
That's right.
What do you mean?
I don't remember said those words!
Don't remember just forget about it.
Undress rest properly?
Fine.
Being that way toward your mother,
do you feel you acted correctly?
Who say me do right?
Is it because sister ask me?
That's why tell you?
You why only consider you yourself?
I feel that your mother can with you meet.
Is already very it's great.
Hey. In the world have someone the eyes and ears.
Who will acknowledge have previous criminal records Sam Beom the person is own daughter?
Still will meet.
So in future will not again meet her.
So you think it's because of your mother that you've turned out this way?
If mother hadn't abandoned me
I wouldn't have become like this.
I with you have different views.
Even if your mother didn't abandon you
and raised you properly,
you would possibly still have got at least one star(conviction).
Sister really know how to talking nonsense?
Hey. So living well is your reason.
Still have to bad then bewildering parents?
Either is family environment is relationship.
Hand over bad friends the relationship.
I hate people who look for excuses the most.
You are really amazing.
No need bewildering other people.
Is own fate.
Have blamed oneself.
Anyway.
Because like this I then unable to with sister.
Speak some profound the matter.
Where have such a thing as necessary speak have to so deep quarter!
Profound itself is no correct.
Mother apologise to you.
Then ruthless a bit. Forgive her?
You thought this matter like this is it easy?
Is it because of you self-respect too strong?
That's why like that?
Sister.
It is not easily then meet with the mother?
Abandon complain or similar feelings.
First think about how about that live in harmony?
I heard your mother has a lot of money.
Those matters again is heard from where have said!
Chang Man said she is wealthy.
That's really. Sister to my life.
A bit of help also don't have.
Only want to law the disparity.
If it were me,
I'd think of it like winning the lottery
That's really.
Sent to house inside.
That's right.
How is it?
Now is still thought Jjanggu-mom will come?
No. Is him taking wrong.
Perhaps it's a sign of Alzheimer's.
It's not Alzheimer's.
Eldest brother's memory is good.
Now also have.
I don't know that some little brothers the name.
Eldest brother is also know.
If it is Alzheimer's
that will be a big headache.
Also should have said is not.
It's not Alzheimer's.
Hello. Proprietress.
Weather really good. Look at the sky.
Now already entered into autumn.
But. Now, you wear that clothes.
That is proprietress?
That's right. What's wrong?
Yu Na has exactly the same clothes.
Is that so?
Few days ago hang on the here.
But clothes also not seeing.
So. Should be this clothes.
I'm also is here picked up.
I just for find this clothes.
Don't know have eaten how much hardship?
Thought by wind scrape leaving.
I even under house inside the courtyard also all had look for.
Early call me ask a moment will be good.
See this clothes. Really happy!
Now look. Color also is more beautiful.
Still pick up have reach trousers.
But because of too tight.
So sent to dry clean in the shop.
That is what are you saying?
I want to change finish later wear.
So sent to dry clean in the shop.
Proprietress wear. Cannot doing like that.
Why never able to!
Is other people the clothes!
Other people the clothes also can.
You just go ask around Yu Na?
Also. Hereafter, at here.
No matter who the clothes?
First wear people is owner.
Yu Na.
Please come in.
How do you do Mi Seon?
How do you do?
Yu Na. I've found you lost.
Shirt with trousers.
Where is it?
Proprietress have worn your clothes.
Omo. Proprietress why must wear my clothes!
Don't know. Say pattern also beautiful.
Like very much.
That's why pick up wear?
Really let people speechless.
Still have ask you hereafter, dry in the air clothes the time be careful.
No matter what clothing?
As long as she like will wear.
So what am I going to do!
One will have dry in the air clothes.
In other words, won't let me at rooftop dry in the air clothes?
I previously to give child care institution the Hyeon Cheol wear.
So have taken away Dong Min the clothes.
She might be unhappy.
That's why she's getting revenge on me.
Hey. Even if you are a thief.
How can move family members the items!
Don't need to worry.
With sister the clothing it's all right.
So you want to find back your clothing?
Have to find!
I can say something.
What?
Then is a thief mentality.
But you have just jump the dance what is it dance!
This? Is Saarland Bodhisattva dance.
Is Latin American dancing?
Or is Mi Seon have good taste!
Correct. Warehouse class rhythm.
Mix knight. Shake and boil.
Soul happy the is Saarland Bodhisattva dance.
Is drinking also jump Saarland Bodhisattva dance?
Talking about what!
Is drinking jump Saarland Bodhisattva dance?
Then rather pitiful.
Lady have gone to where?
Went already.
Chang Man say.
At here inside dry in the air clothes.
So proprietress will randomly wear.
Then to be limited to Yu Na the clothing.
Mi Seon why hang all it's all right?
My clothes is expensive the clothes.
Of course. At our tenant among.
Also tallest level. How can buy cheap the clothes?
I look a bit money?
It is not look have money?
Coffee shop is also you. Didn't you a bit money?
But no matter how I effort earn money?
With Yu Na compared to or is small witch see big
witch.
Yu Na compared to you have even more money?
Originally don't have money.
But she this time met with 20 years before be separated the mother.
But that position mother is a tycoon.
Chang Man also know this fact?
Is Chang Man let Yu Na see mother.
So.
Chang Man also only must catch hold of Yu Na will be enough.
Of course. Chang Man also.
Hereafter, if with Yu Na Ho result.
Then then do not eat any more hardship.
Give to me clothing?
Okay.
Over there.
Help my good good tremble.
Properly tremble one tremble.
Give you.
Just now you wear the clothes very nicely.
Why have changed again one!
Have worn other people the clothes.
In the heart felt uncomfortable.
Have to finish washing later even give her.
Have you gone crazy?
Why must even give her!
I don't want to hear other people say I'm also thief.
What are you talking about?
You in front of Yu Na wear those clothes.
Yu Na then will cheer up.
But Da Yeong say.
Yu Na the trousers very expensive.
Trousers also exceeding 100,000.
Jacket also exceeding 50,000.
But our Ga Dong Min clothes.
Up and down item added up together just was 10,000 five.
This buying and selling have done well.
Anyway. That clothes very suitable to you.
So don't care Yu Na why beg you?
No need to be even give her.
I want to accept it Dong Min the clothes money 10,000.
After that must even give her clothes.
Do that I then can mentality comfortable.
Cannot. Even if you think even give her.
I'm also not promised.
Have to pass through this time the opportunity.
Have to let her change a moment bad habit.
President. Vehicle already open have came over.
I'm leaving.
Walk carefully.
Don't even give her.
Eldest brother.
Need to go to work?
That's right. You perhaps waiting for Jjanggu-mom?
Jjanggu-mom within this time.
Why come here!
I'm only anyhow ask?
Really know how to be a busybody?
Want early in the morning start play with me this old fellow?
Vary just forget about it.
Elderly. I'm leaving.
Fine. Walk carefully.
But just now why towards elderly have said Jjanggu-mom the matter!
Feel that have bit cold and cheerless.
In fact, yesterday, I because eldest brother a bit surprised.
Why?
He said Jjanggu-mom will come.
Outside the door waited for three or more hours.
So confirmed a moment.
Jjanggu-mom simply don't have done promise.
Furthermore, eldest brother don't remember anything.
Yesterday, I emit whole body cold perspiration?
Elderly. Cannot be like that!
Cannot. Really will be trouble.
This clothes you wear get up even better.
Even can?
Is pretty good. You wear?
Mother.
Uncle say want to with you together go to work.
Let him wait a while?
Dong Min!
Sister have worn this clothes is it nice to read?
Very pretty.
Fine.
Then I today just wear Dong Min say beautiful clothes.
Let's go.
Sister.
Have a big news.
What is it news?
Second floor the Yu Na have seen.
Twenty over years before be separated the mother.
When!
Have few days.
But at where have seen? In prison?
Her mother is not that No 1 people.
Said is very wealthy family lady.
Uncle is listen to who said it!
Is Mi Seon have said.
So hereafter,
Yu Na also will to live prosperous the life?
Should be able to living well?
Mi Seon say.
Chang Man also no need to eat any more hardship.
Sister really too fortunate.
That's right.
Hereafter, also no need have stole something.
Need to go to work?
That's right.
Listen to your sister have said.
Say you recently have good thing.
Also not considered any good thing.
Da Yeong. You're wearing my clothes?
That's right.
Do they fit well?
I thought proprietress have worn.
So originally must go to get return clothes.
Very sorry.
You first let our home Dong Min the clothes.
Give take back?
So I will immediately return to you this clothes.
There's no need. I am still give you?
There's no need. Da Yeong, you can wear them.
As long as you one sentence I'm perfectly contented.
From now on, those clothes are yours.
If it is like that. I more very sorry!
No need very sorry.
If clothes well-fitting.
So just is clothes the owner.
Proprietress. I'm going up first.
It seems like she was born to make me angry.
Really hurt self-esteem!
No need hurt self-esteem.
Mother. I like this clothes.
Furthermore, feel that that person sister really very
cool.
Last night,
why did Axe hyungnim scare us like that?
I never made an appointment with hyungnim.
If doing what say those crazy!
Is elderly taking wrong.
I thought he might have Alzheimer's,
scared me to death.
Chef, you should pretend you don't know.
Of course must pretend don't know.
Even if I pretend know.
Also only will let elderly sad.
Later after I get off work. Go and look at him?
That's right.
I'll have to go and look at him.
Piece together table have come.
The Mid-autumn festival are you doing well?
I before very well.
You've just come back from the countryside?
That's right.
How is Se Hui?
At live over there pretty good.
That's right. Live very well.
Thanks to you. All very smoothly.
This box what is Zi?
Is miso with chilli. Sesame oil or similar.
Is my mother gave me.
First with president come say your greetings.
Fine.
She is a.
Matters in the past by expose later.
Become also must have bit dispirited.
More and more feel that feel very apologetic.
With former husband still have not solve the problem?
To settle that problem will take quite some time.
She said it's very complicated.
Think is with young the man have an affair then try to escape.
Also no, it's not like that.
That's right.
No can randomly say other people bad person.
Give to me one bottle of soju?
Okay. Immediately send to you.
How do you do? I am Gim Chang Man.
I am Yeong Mi.
Who is it?
Chun Ok eonni's younger sister, Yeong Mi.
Forever aesthetics be born.
Yes.
Right now I'm just in front of the colatec.
Is that so? Then, I immediately go out.
You wait a moment?
Okay.
Welcome.
Wish you have spent happily time.
Have work hard?
Yeong Mi. Come say your greetings.
Hello. First time meeting.
Who is this young lady?
She's Yu Na's younger sister.
Real younger sister.
She's her half-sister. Same mother, different father.
Say this time met with mother.
Is that position mom mother the daughter?
Yes.
But why come here!
She's studying sociology at university.
She wants to write a thesis on the colatec.
So I call her to come.
So. Enter go and look?
How much is the admission fee?
Here, my face is your admission ticket.
No need care about. You just come in.
Okay.
From where start see better?
How do you do?
We open for business at 1PM and
close in the evening at 8PM.
Admission ticket is how much money?
2000 dollar.
Can I use my phone to take a few photos?
Cannot. Give to me.
You taken the is infringe on portrait power.
But I am alright.
Why older brother able to shoot? I cannot shoot!
You are the same guest.
I'm the general manager here.
Is drinking? Manager isn't it not is really great?
Rather than said is really great.
At position is president under.
Yeong Mi. You stand a moment.
1 2 3.
Seeing later how do you feel?
Seems like understand.
I previously if don't know the new world.
But you want wrote thesis the theme what is it?
Is regarding old people leisure living subject.
So came correctly place.
I heard you're Yu Na's younger sister.
That's right.
Is a beauty!
I work here, and live next door to your sister.
Is that so?
I am not at all but send you.
Is from country side Cheongdao brought over the cucumber with chilli.
You try see.
Like this precious the vegetables.
This red pepper paste also is me brought over the country side the red pepper paste.
Thank you very much!
So. You just properly view?
Okay.
Is is drinking be in charge of piece together table the sister-in-law?
You're Yu Na's younger sister?
That's right.
This is proprietress hide inside the refrigerator.
Secretly have drank rice wine.
You try see.
Eldest brother.
You not even once give to me drink before.
This eldest brother live at our the tower room inside.
Furthermore, he's the colatec president's brother-in-law.
I am Hong Gye Pal.
I am Gim Yeong Mi.
I feel that compared to Yu Na she is more beautiful.
Thank you very much!
Yeong Mi at here very popularity!
That's right.
You why must sit here!
Hurry and go busy work?
Please walk slowly.
You taste before roast fish?
Very delicious.
Good and eat.
Here the chef have done dish very delicious.
Is me introduce she come here.
Come. Please come in.
Coffee. Please sit down.
In fact,
I saw recently the students write thesis the time.
Too dependent on internet the information.
Thesis is not that wrote.
Our Professor said the same thing.
Let our relative strength relative for.
Use foot come write.
Write the time have to bring offensive.
So write then can write out one good article.
Older brother go to college the time.
Is like that write thesis?
I not even once written before thesis.
Why?
Because never go before university.
So never written before.
I thought older brother read before university.
I am secondary school a test exam birth.
My sister?
Sister should be only read have reach secondary school.
The rest homework is at young discipline have made.
Young discipline so also not with prison the same?
Although the same. But just nice can let those.
Will not listen the children learn.
Older brother also young discipline so birth?
I not even once went before.
Young discipline so. Detention center.
Discipline so.
This kind of place.
I'm only have heard before that kind of place.
Actually have not do you know what is the situation?
If sister like before the same.
From grasp job seeking.
That is can will have opportunities go and look?
But hereafter, possibly.
A lifetime also such a thing won't happen.
I know why that won't happen.
You feel that why won't happen?
Because older brother will Sang Jin Dao dog the same.
Protect person my sister.
Of course.
Write report the time.
Have what do not understand?
Or unclear.
Then can anytime call me ask me?
Thank you. Later I will again will contact you.
You go back first.
I want busy work.
Have work hard?
Are you leaving already?
That's right. Thank you very much for letting me look around.
Write properly report.
She's a university student?
Is grade one.
With Yu Na do not seem to be!
Eyes position a bit like.
Also have seen before Yu Na the real mother?
Yes.
But why never tell me say these matters?
But eventually will be Yu Na sad the past.
She also don't want I say out.
So I'm unable to say out.
So from now on,
will Yu Na stay with her real mother?
But feels that very difficult.
I don't really like Mi Seon,
but what she said this time is right.
Everything it's all my fault.
No need bewildering parents.
When did I bear a grudge against parents!
I hate abandon children try to escape the mother.
Is living so well.
Why hate living well!
Since have ran away. Living well isn't it better?
So you feel that. Lie at a cabin inside.
Looking at leak rain the ceiling even more okay.
Then is angry.
What has happened order you get angry!
Mother living well. Then order you angry.
Only everything all order I get angry.
Lots of money the husband also order I get angry.
Go to college the daughter also order I get angry.
Really is a narrow-minded.
I every time think of mother the time.
Will feel my departed father is too pitiful.
Hey.
I compared to anyone even more esteem your father.
Furthermore, very understand him.
But. Father is father.
Mother is mother.
Sister don't understand my father.
I every time think of my father.
Then very annoying mother.
Hey.
Even if hate mother also no need show it?
Presently situation is.
Your mother take this glutinous cake.
You if want to get bit benefit.
Just have to with mother get along properly.
I from the start never before thought get what benefit?
No matter what? Your mother is big very wealthy.
Can leave it you don't bother about?
Just forget about it. Just stop those.
That's really.
Who is it?
Yun Ji.
Hey.
You starting from now identity very respected.
Cannot again randomly have stole something.
It's me.
Eonni.
When did Oppa contact you?
Last night he called me on the phone.
What did he say?
Call me with him do together.
And so.
Have said sister have done I would have made.
Sister won't do. So I will not do.
Later how say?
Call I today bring sister come over.
If I want to do, You also really will do?
That's right.
Get in the car.
But sister.
Really is separated for 25 year still have reach real mother?
Who said that?
Yesterday I went to the karaoke lounge.
Squad-leader told me.
Have seen.
Say sister will must redo people.
Do not call we'll go to hit disturb you.
That person ajussi why like this say?
Even if you looking for me.
I don't tell me will be won't do something that should be done?
That's right.
Also.
With mother meet again the people will to reform and start afresh ; to turn over a new leaf?
Correct. Mother is mother.
Steal something is steal something.
Sister. Did you get Chan Mi's phone number?
I never got it.
Should be call you.
Why?
Say sister have done. Also let our wear she.
What do you mean?
She is at other areas is pretty good.
But have bit careless.
But she very have courage and insight!
Indeed very have courage and insight.
But if do matter the time cannot just depend on courage and insight!
In future, again think about?
Deficit?
Yes. This month the deficit is 1,300,000.
But except for president.
Sister will not with anyone say these matters.
I'm also first time heard say.
Every month is deficit the matter.
If older sister know about me tell president the matter.
Then possibly will by her driven away.
Sister seems like very generous.
Even if deficit will also not say out.
Even if is like this.
Return to president buy so expensive the gift.
Your sister really you like me.
Like! In front of my face cry live well several return.
Say like president.
Also. Until now.
Is my first time see sister give other people buy a
gift.
But where's your eonni gone?
Just to in front of president seem beautifully a
bit.
So must beauty salon do head?
Sister. Welcome.
Whether or not have find my people.
At single room waiting for you.
How do you do?
Recently frequently meet!
Do you know me?
That's right.
The Mid-autumn festival are you doing well?
Yes. Before very well.
When did you come here?
About ten minutes ago.
How do you do?
First sit?
Location how would change?
I'm also not clear.
Only can be that day receive contact later immediately operation.
Who's our contact person?
It's my junior.
He's trustworthy.
I will later will alone introduce to do you know?
So what is it I have to do?
You are machine.
Let Yun Ji come attracting people.
Pull up the time have to let you do.
Oppa?
Don't care you hand over give money to me bag or is
envelope?
Then surely is cheque.
Take to later must rapid escape.
After that to recently is bank inside changed to
cash.
So.
Is the three of us with that junior together make?
Either just as a precaution.
Again add one person hand.
But. Why let sister motor equipment!
Older brother do isn't it better?
It is not pretending to?
I have already all rust.
Do machine need to spend some time.
Also. From last time initially.
Your sister compared to me even more speciality machine
area work.
So. This matter just like this say have decided.
Oppa,
honestly speaking, I don't want to do this.
That's also is what are you saying?
I don't want to, but I have to.
Want pass through this time the matter.
Want to get previously owe older brother the favor all and still attend.
You don't me any favours!
This time. I also won't need my then one portion.
And help you this time later.
Then to totally stop doing something.
Cannot. If you like this have said.
I will be unable to to do work.
No need feel sorry.
Just like this say have decided.
As long as you give my share to Yun Ji, that will fine.
Eonni. Don't say that.
You must accept it, eonni.
You must not interrupt. I will do as see fit.
Anyway. Thank you.
I cash the cocktail suits your appetite?
I feel very tasty.
This cup wine be called.
Tequila Sunrise.
At home also occasionally will think of this type of smell.
So.
Whether or not need to at keep warm cup for you cash
one cup.
Let you return home then drink bit.
Just forget about it. There have bit exaggerate.
For a while sister will reach.
You working here. Get how much wages!
I get 120.
This time receive it the Mid-autumn festival reward?
Where have such a thing as reward!
Store always at deficit.
Wait a moment. So.
Today, I give you a bit of reward?
President. There's no need.
No. I will give you bit pocket money?
Come. Accept it?
Cannot be like this!
It's all right. You just accept it?
So just pass through sister give it to me.
I cannot accept.
Why like this! Let people bewildering very sorry.
Come.
Like that I then can.
Openly with sister working together.
Jin Mi. We must leaving.
Sister want to go?
President. Next time see you again.
Fine.
Jin Mi.
You people really is not bad.
You over-praise.
Bring car?
That's right. Is Yun Ji car.
Sit I car together go back.
Just forget about it.
I just do Yun Ji car go back.
Is that so?
Then in future, again will contact you.
Older brother. Please walk slowly.
Fine. You also should go back?
Sister.
Just from shop inside came out?
You have gone where?
Have gone to beauty salon.
Sister the hairstyle very beautiful.
Even can?
That's right.
Very pretty.
Inside. President Pak around.
With Jin Mi be together.
I regarding Jin Mi really to esteem someone's
progress!
What's wrong? Have what bad matters?
No. Is a good thing feeling.
With Jin Mi happened what has happened?
Later then will tell you.
Sister. I'll take my leave first.
Fine. Walk carefully.
Okay.
Applause.
Thank you.
Take this jacket. And wait my husband and master.
Lady Pak Dae Mal the memories inside the song.
Bride eighteen years old.
Applause. Applause.
Nam Su.
Sister.
Really lacking in manners.
Who are you?
No recognize me?
Rub. Rub. Dirt-rag.
Dirt-rag.
Already have given up dirt-rag the life.
Recently have karaoke lounge.
Okay. Because Nam Su Jung mention you.
So I also have so understand.
Ask me whether or not have indirectly acquired power cut equipment with.
Mike battery charger. So I call him came.
Have done well. Have done well.
Hey. But power cut equipment what is it?
Is electric power source cut off power switch.
Our in the shop must have.
Is that so? Give him cheaper a bit.
Give him cheaper a bit.
Cheaper a bit. Cheaper a bit.
- Okay.
- Give him cheaper a bit?
So.
Selling items before.
Just for today the this the stage.
Have come one special invitation the singer.
Must give everyone introduce singer Pak Yang Sun.
Must I am here singing?
Sing?
Battery charger with power cut equipment full of anger give you Ta O chopped.
Sing? Sing?
What to do?
What can you do! Sing?
Singing. Singing. Singing.
Is my first time at second-hand goods in the shop singing.
Applause for her again.
What are you doing?
So I will start singing.
Come. Applause.
121,234.
Very well. Very well.
I'll take my leave first. Mother.
Fine. Walk carefully.
Okay.
Really know how to be a busybody?
That's right. On-the-spot interview is like that.
So. Even I also never gone before the drink up.
She already have viewed one time?
That's right.
I am really alright.
It's all right.
Should have arrived.
Yeong Mi.
Sister.
You are Yeong Mi?
That's right.