(Episode 20)
I have killed you...
over and over in my mind...
because you made my one
and only friend die.
Because I cannot forgive you.
Every time I saw you,
I could not kill you...
even after I knew you were the King.
I wanted to believe that you were not.
If you must kill me in order for it to end,
strike me.
But will it really end...
if you kill me?
How many more must you kill for it to end?
Will it end if you kill the officials?
The noblemen?
No.
As soon as someone else takes their place,
they will do the same thing.
Whom will you kill then?
I wanted to change Silla...
with you.
I wanted to prevent deaths...
caused by the Bone-rank System.
I dreamed of becoming more than Silla...
and unifying the Three Kingdoms.
But if this is where it ends,
strike me.
Now,
there is no debt between us.
Is this...
the end?
We have different paths.
I guess...
the next time we meet,
we will be enemies.
I must switch the king.
Do you mean you will
remove King Jinheung...
and make someone else king?
No.
I mean I will not make anyone king.
Not a king.
I will put forth a scarecrow...
who is a Sacred Bone.
Who?
The Hwarang who pretended
to be the King in Baekje.
He is Prince Hwi Kyung's son, Sun Woo.
Prince Hwi Kyung?
Is he not the discarded Sacred Bone?
He is Prince Hwi Kyung's son?
Even if she became ill,
the Queen will not stand for this.
Even after the previous king passed away,
the Queen protected her son all alone.
For now, she has a justification...
as Sacred Bone's guardian.
That is why we must take it away.
The money, the power,
and the position.
She did not get it for free.
The people may think it is a rebellion.
People?
(Plotting the overthrow of a monarch)
Even when things go awry,
subjects bow down in order to live.
There is nothing to be afraid of.
Let us make...
Silla ours. That is my point.
It is the only way to keep your sheds full.
Pa Oh.
Once sun rises, bring Wonhwa Ah Ro...
to Wolseong Palace.
King Jinheung...
took Master Ahn Ji's
daughter to the palace?
We were a step late.
She is the perfect bait for Master Sun Woo.
How did you lose the chance?
Things will be complicated now.
Master Young Shil, you have a visitor.
Come on in.
This is an interesting picture.
You two look alike.
It is time we talk about
the important matters.
That is why we came here today.
Have you decided...
to wield power instead of being mistreated?
You must have heard that the King...
took Master Ahn Ji's daughter.
We must change...
the owner of Silla.
What can I help you with?
There is nothing you have to do.
I shall do it with Hwarang.
Then what should I do?
You and the other officials...
will support me as a new king.
No matter how hard you try,
I will be the one who owns Silla.
Silla's owner never changed.
It will be the same this time again.
Abdicate the throne? Is that what you said?
Yes. That is the only way I can gain power.
Marry Princess Sook Myung before then.
Is it that hard for you...
to step down?
Do you still see me as a
mother coveting the throne?
You can protect the throne
only if you stay objective.
A king...
must be able to take his friend's life.
A generous king...
puts the nation into anguish.
He ends up killing all of his subjects.
However, an objective monarch...
kills fast and brutally...
when the least amount
of damage can be done.
That way, he will not have to kill more.
Are you saying...
a king must kill someone
to stay in position?
Do you think Hwarang is yours?
They believe Master Sun
Woo deserves to be king.
They saw him sacrifice his life...
in front of everyone to protect the people.
Do you...
truly believe that
Hwarangs will follow you?
I will make them mine.
How?
As you said,
I will have to find a way...
that is the fastest with
minimal casualties.
I thought you were going to be king.
Are you still working on it?
"No path started as a path."
Do you remember that?
"Someone must walk on it
for it to become a path."
"You must pound and break the hard land..."
"and pierce through it for
the water to flow out."
So...
Are you saying you will pound and break...
in order to create a path?
I do not want to be a
piece on a chess board.
Do not let the order that
someone else created...
be the order that you hold yourselves to.
You are not pieces on a chess board.
You are freer than anyone. You are Hwarang.
I will no longer remain quiet.
You will not remain quiet?
Did you decide on a rebellion?
A weak king cannot do anything.
What Silla needs...
is a powerful king who is
willing to change the nation.
I need your help, Chief Instructor.
Are you...
telling me to take a lead in a revolt?
I will leave the decision to you.
Please come back and help
Hwarangs become one.
If we split up now, I will
not be able to do it.
Why are you so sure I will help you?
Because I know we are on the same page.
Our Silla's future depends on it.
This is my intent.
Please inform the Queen.
That is good. You may go.
I saw her put something in the tea.
- Give it to me.
- It could be poison.
I said, give it to me.
I cannot let you drink it
not knowing what it is.
It is not poison you can notice instantly.
You need it to build up inside...
in order for it to work.
Did you drink it knowing what is in it?
I had my suspicions from the beginning.
Your Highness.
I shall call a physician.
Do not make a fuss.
I have seen...
the symptoms for a while.
This is the only way...
to see you by my side.
I heard you are hurt.
How is the injury?
It is fine.
However,
if I had not come here,
it would have healed faster.
I do not mind even if you heal slowly.
Either way, you will not
be able to leave here.
I brought you here as hostage.
A hostage...
so that your brother
cannot threaten my throne.
This...
is not like you, Your Majesty.
Did you forget that my
mother's blood run in me?
This might be the chance...
for you to know who I really am.
(Hwarang House)
Do you really plan on
seizing Hwarang House?
They are my Hwarangs.
I am not seizing them.
They have been mine from the beginning.
I need to take control now,
or they will go beyond my grasp.
King Jinheung is here. Open the doors.
Who is that?
Is it Ji Dwi?
Do people's personalities
change along with clothes?
He is just like the Queen.
He looks cold-hearted and cruel.
Hwarangs, show respect to the King!
I am...
the master of Hwarang, King Jinheung.
While I was in Hwarang, I saw...
how lazy...
and weak you were.
You were spoiled children
of powerful families.
However, Hwarang will now...
be reborn from head to toe...
under the management of
Silla's Royal Family...
to become strong warriors.
The King standing over there!
Are you any different?
I believe both you and Hwarang...
are weak and powerless.
Your Majesty.
Master Sun Woo.
Show your respect.
I said, show your respect.
There will be an abdication
four days from now.
As the royal guards...
that serve the King,
you will fulfil your obligations.
Hwarang...
must be free.
Only when they think and
move on their free will,
they are able to dream of
the future of a new Silla.
I am sure you have heard
of this, Your Majesty.
Are you going against me now?
I am telling you that we will decide...
for ourselves if we will
accept you as our King!
Are you not confident...
that you will be chosen?
There are two kings in Hwarang House.
What is going on?
Come here.
According to my informant,
the king might change.
- What?
What do you mean?
I thought Sun Woo was a half-breed,
but he's a Sacred Bone.
I knew he was different,
but did you see him talking to Ji Dwi?
What do you mean, Ji Dwi?
He's King Jinheung.
Instead of gaining control of us,
he is now a laughingstock. Poor Ji Dwi.
Ah Ro...
Your sister is all right.
She is currently...
I know.
Thank you about the last time.
Also,
I am sorry.
I am a bad man to you.
Of course, you should be sorry.
How can you treat a woman like me this way?
I am not a good man to you,
but you are a good woman.
Hence,
you should see a man who
feels the same as you.
Tea?
Did you just say tea?
It seems to have been for a long time.
She started coughing blood.
She told me not to say anything,
but I cannot leave her like that.
What do you think you are doing?
Is it Park Young Shil?
Who is behind you?
Pa Oh!
I shall follow your royal
command, Your Majesty.
Kill her.
Please spare me.
Have mercy, Your Majesty!
Your Highness!
Please spare me, Your Highness.
Please do not kill me.
Why did you do it?
What do you mean?
You knew it was poisoned.
Why did you drink it?
Why?
I did not know.
When I found out, it was too late.
Even if I had refused the tea,
they would have used another method.
You should have fled.
You should have renounced the throne...
and fled instead.
I tried to flee.
I wanted to avoid it.
However,
I had to live according to my fate.
If there is something you wish to protect,
become stronger.
You must be strong in order to fight.
Do not believe in frail hearts of people.
That is...
what a king must do.
Mother.
Are you reinstating me
as the chief instructor?
That is correct.
Then do you plan to disobey...
the Queen's orders?
My will is the Queen's will.
My will is Silla's will.
It is good to see you again.
How have you all been?
- Well, Master!
I am standing here today...
because I heard...
you were given a very difficult assignment.
I believe...
this choice you make...
will create a new Silla
different from the past.
Also, I am certain that you
have grown sufficiently...
that you are qualified to make that choice.
Some may call this treason.
Also,
some may call it your duty.
The choice is yours to make.
Will you be a Hwarang that
changes this nation...
from the root?
Or will you remain being
unable to do anything?
Choose.
And if you made a decision,
trust in yourself...
until the end.
You are Hwarang.
Never forget...
that you are Hwarang. Never forget.
Is something wrong?
Did you say I asked myself...
over and over...
why I must become king?
Did you say you can tell by my eyes...
that I never once gave up?
Yes, Your Majesty.
That is what I saw.
I hope everything you said was correct.
Your heart has never once changed.
But my heart is racing like this.
I heard the Queen...
is stepping down today.
That is correct.
I will become the true King today.
Are you...
worrying about me?
The throne seems very lonely.
I feel like...
you will sleep less there.
I guess I should thank you...
since I became stronger because of you.
Thanks to you,
I was able to come this far.
Is that him?
What is he doing here?
He needs to come on time.
We have gathered here today...
- to crown...
- Halt!
Do you really think...
that throne belongs to you?
We the officials think differently.
How dare you...
I, the highest official of Silla,
choose to crown...
another Scared Bone as king.
Prince Hwi Kyung's son,
Master Sun Woo.
The Hwarangs...
have chosen a king for the future of Silla.
We Hwarangs...
swear our allegiance...
to His Majesty who will empower Silla...
and who will serve the needs of the people!
Hwarang represents Silla's new conviction!
Devote yourselves to Silla...
and to the King of Silla!
Hail King Jinheung!
- Hail King Jinheung!
Traitor Park Young Shil!
You have attempted...
to kill the King and planned treason!
Receive your punishment.
- Master Park.
Furthermore!
If anyone stands with him, step forward.
The swords of Hwarang
shall not forgive you!
I wanted...
to change Silla with you.
I wanted to prevent deaths...
caused by the Bone-rank System.
I dreamed of becoming more than Silla...
and unifying the Three Kingdoms.
Can what you dream of...
come true?
It will not be easy.
But if I do not try and just breathe,
I will be living, but I will not be alive.
What if...
I eliminate those trying to kill you?
Can you change Silla?
Now, this throne is yours.
So change it as you dreamed.
Use every ounce of power you possess.
At least to avoid disappointing you,
I will take that path until the end.
I, King Jinheung of Silla,
along with Hwarang, will
put the people first...
and will lead a powerful
and prosperous Silla.
Then...
what type of king are you thinking of?
A country where people are happy...
while the king is in agony.
Where the people do not
worry about the country...
But the king worries about the people.
That is the king I am thinking of.
Those kids.
I guess...
I did catch something big.
I am sorry...
for not telling you sooner.
If that is your choice,
I respect it.
I am proud of you.
I am sure your mother would be happy...
to see you like this.
What?
You thief.
Be careful.
Get out quickly. Hurry.
Hail King Jinheung!
- Hail King Jinheung!
You really...
got here on your own.
I am glad...
it was not too late.
I shall...
bear the burden of Silla...
from now on.
Do you think...
I hated you?
I hated you, Mother?
I know...
that you...
protected Silla and me.
I shall also protect Silla and my people...
in my own way, different from yours.
I shall...
make Silla powerful.
Your Highness.
Your Highness!
How is she?
She is practically a corpse.
I have...
something to tell you.
Please stay with her.
Please.
I wish...
I could have died by your hands instead.
Why did you...
tell me not to drink the tea?
Did you...
worry about me?
I tried to let go,
but I could not.
No matter how hard I tried,
I wanted...
to go to you.
I tried to hate you.
I tried to kill you.
However,
I could not.
I...
I am sorry.
Did it go well?
It did.
His Majesty asked me to bring this to you.
Did you resent me for
locking you up in here?
It was the only choice I had...
in order to protect you from
Master Park Young Shil.
I fear I will not be able
to let you go if I see you.
I fear I will get greedy again.
Go. Do not make him wait too long.
Go to him.
Was I too late?
Now, I will never...
leave you alone.
I promise.
Let me tell you what this is.
It is volume two of the
collective information...
on all the young masters
within the capital.
So...
Briefing will cost an
additional piece of silver.
Do you want it?
Here.
I have paid my debt in full now.
You are the legendary woman
who captured the hearts...
of two Sacred Bones.
But your living situation has not changed.
How should it change?
You know.
Silk, gold, and wealthy life.
Things like that.
Is that right?
Did you wait long? Let us go have fun.
Why do you keep taking my child?
If you are bored, date.
You said you were single.
I need someone to date.
I cannot date myself!
He said he would not leave me alone.
What am I supposed to do?
My father is in his room.
Rather than hiding it like
this, should we just...
After what happened to Master Young Shil,
you are like a kite with its string cut.
Your family does not have status or wealth.
It is only natural that he opposes.
I guess.
But you have my love.
Prince Chang...
I think he plans...
to make an alliance with
Daegaya to strike us.
We see each other only if
there is a problem now.
If I remain here, people will talk about...
"the other Sacred Bone" and whatnot.
You know that.
If you were going to keep being so cool,
you should just become king.
This looks pretty nice.
Why you Dog-Bird...
It has been six months since you left.
Have you seen Ah Ro yet?
He should at least send news...
or give me some sort of assurance.
End it!
It is no loss on my part.
It is no loss.
How have you been?
I am back.
Who are you? I do not know you.
I have a bad memory.
You could not have forgotten me.
You look pretty.
Totally.
Let us get married.
I cannot handle it. I miss you too much.
I missed you.