Dad, the food is ready.
Okay, let's eat.
How does it taste?
It's good.
That's a relief.
Gosh.
Dad, can't you stop pretending everything's okay?
I really think it tastes okay.
No, it doesn't.
Oh, I might be late for work.
Are you going to continue to work there?
You started with bad intentions.
Ji Hye led me there.
Can you buy these for me?
I have a really important audition after this performance.
If I wear this necklace to the audition,
people will recognize my worth.
I finally found...
people and a place that recognize my worth.
It's all thanks to Ji Hye.
That's what I believe.
But Ji Hye didn't...
leave the necklace for you.
Still, I got an even prettier one.
Gosh, that's blinding.
Is that a tray or a mirror?
You're going to make a hole in it.
What's wrong?
You're not here to do dishes.
You came to talk, didn't you?
Well...
Go ahead.
Are you going to keep your mouth shut?
You make people feel alienated when you do that.
Really?
Are you joking?
Do you think I only want to be understood?
I want to understand you too.
Enough with seeing through other people.
Show me who you are inside.
I can't see through anything.
It's true. I thought that it was easy at times.
I could see through and read what people were thinking.
But I was wrong.
To think that you know and to think that you understand...
is a very dangerous thing.
What do you mean?
I'm talking about Ji Hye.
I think...
it happened because of me.
What? That's...
Boss.
I was worried about you. Where have you been all day?
I told you. No more locking doors.
No more secrets.
That was not too long ago. Why are you still being secretive?
Boss?
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
Why is it...
that there are so many reasons why we can't be together?
Pardon?
(Episode 15: A Reason Bigger Than 99 Other Reasons)
Mr. Eun Hwan Gi.
That's you, right?
Yes.
Who are you?
I'm just Ro Woon's neighborhood friend.
I see.
Do you think it's over?
You seem to be relieved.
But guess what?
You don't have the right to smile so happily...
beside Ro Woon.
Pardon?
There's something you don't know about.
Ji Hye was watching...
you, not Kang Woo Il.
Pardon? What are you talking about?
Of course you didn't know.
You probably never gave her a glance.
I think you have it wrong.
I don't know how she ended up getting involved with him.
It took me by surprise.
However, all of this started because of you.
She wanted to hear about you from your friend.
Should I ask Mr. Kang to do me a favor...
and give this to Mr. Eun?
I didn't get to give him the drawing in the end.
The woman he's seeing...
is a curator who only deals with professional paintings by artists.
But I'm...
My drawing is...
That's enough. You can't even drink.
I don't hate her, though.
Thanks to her,
I got to go on a fake date with him.
I was so nervous.
- Pardon? - Thank you for your help.
Hey, don't you know no one likes bad guys anymore?
He's not a bad guy.
He's sweet.
If a guy is mean to you nine times and he's nice once, you're moved.
If a guy's good to you nine times and he makes a mistake once,
you say that he changed.
Do girls have a problem counting?
One is good to you nine times while the other is good to you once.
The answer is obvious.
Are you all that dumb?
It's true. I'm dumb.
I know it will never work between us,
but I can't help looking at him.
I'm suffering the more I look at him,
but I can't stop myself.
Then just go up to him and tell him you like him.
If I do that, I won't be able to see him anymore.
I can't live without seeing him.
It's a mere crush.
Why is it such a big deal?
(Mr. Kang Woo Il)
Yes, sir.
Right now?
Yes. I'll be right there.
- Okay. - Hey.
It's after hours. Why is he calling you in?
He's abusing his power.
It's not him.
You just said, "Yes, sir".
You really are dumb.
I'm sorry. I'll take care of the tab.
Hey. Ji Hye.
Don't go.
Thank you for listening to me.
I'm lucky I have someone to talk to.
I'm sorry.
You should have given her a glance.
You should have...
listened to her at least once.
She was so desperate as she looked towards you.
How could you be so cruel and ignore her like that?
More than anyone else,
you hurt her the most.
you're responsible.
But...
how can you be beside her sister?
Reporter Woo...
tried really hard...
to reveal the truth three years ago.
But his higher-ups stopped him.
Then he got fired from the newspaper company he used to work for.
But he has never said anything like that about Ji Hye to me.
He probably wanted to...
respect her feelings.
Maybe he wanted to bury it all.
Then...
what distressed Ji Hye...
was not...
getting abandoned by Mr. Kang.
It was the thought...
that she wouldn't be able to face you again.
That she couldn't turn back.
That's probably...
what devastated her.
Please...
Please pick up.
The number you have dialed cannot be reached at the moment.
Please...
Please leave a message...
Mr. Eun.
The person who should own Ji Hye's drawing.
It wasn't Mr. Kang.
It was you.
What are you drawing?
Of what someone is always looking at.
Mr. Kang is always surrounded by a lot of people, you know.
I thought that's why she drew a building filled with people.
But I was wrong.
Mr. Eun.
What are you doing?
Nothing. I wasn't doing anything.
I was trying to see if these windowsills are dusty,
but they're not. They're clean.
I do the cleaning.
You don't need to worry about it.
My apologies.
What you see from the window you always look out of.
The flower shop and the bakery on the main floor.
The cafe on the second floor.
The hair salon on the third floor.
Right?
I think she wanted to fill...
the concrete building with people.
You're alone all the time,
so she was probably hoping you can always have warm people around you.
Here.
Take it.
The drawing has finally found its owner.
Why do you look at me like that?
It's just... You look different.
You never looked this relaxed even at home.
Are you disappointed?
I'm sorry.
This is who I really am.
I'm not disappointed. You look very comfortable.
I am.
I'm stuck at home all the time. I never have to dress up.
I don't have to force myself to speak anymore.
I don't need to put on fake smiles for other people's sakes either.
Do you stay at home all the time?
Mom and Dad told me to.
They must be ashamed of me.
That's absurd.
They must worry about you.
Anyway, I'm not supposed to be outside. I should get back soon.
Why did you want to see me?
I've been thinking about you.
I thought you had everything.
I didn't feel like there was anything I should do for you.
I took it for granted that you always put me before yourself.
Sometimes,
I even thought it was boring.
I had no idea I was hurting you so much.
It makes me sad.
Forget it.
It's not your fault.
There you go again.
You're just saying that for my sake.
You said you feel comfortable being yourself.
You look more beautiful now...
than ever.
So stop holding it back.
Say what you want to say.
You're right.
It's all your fault.
I hate you.
I like that.
But I think it's too mild.
I don't want you to be happy without me.
I hope you'll become a big failure.
Is that it?
That still sounds too moderate.
Take it a little further.
You're a jerk. You're the worst.
You're a jerk.
There you go.
That's the least you should say.
I thought I'd never see you again.
I thought you'd run away once you see who I really am.
I thought it'd be the end of everything.
Oh, my.
Are you sick again?
You should take better care of yourself to stay competitive.
I'm not sick. It's for weight loss.
Who are you trying to impress this time?
It's not like that.
I'm going to change.
I'll take better care of myself and love myself from now on.
What are you doing tonight?
- I'm... - You probably don't have any plans,
do you?
When couples go around arm in arm,
you read about them on your phone at home.
Gosh, I'm doing you a big favor.
Here.
What is this?
It's a concert Brain is promoting.
Go to the concert. I can accompany you.
Aren't I such an amazing colleague?
I appreciate your kindness, but I already have plans.
With who?
With myself.
Sorry?
I'm attending a lecture on PR this evening.
Since when do you attend those lectures?
Starting now, as I already said.
I'm going to take better care of myself and love myself.
Let's do it some other time.
Well...
Hello.
Be kinder to her.
Gyo Ri is soft-hearted. She must be attracted to kind guys.
What are you talking about?
Don't tell me you believe...
being manly means being cold on purpose.
That's just pathetic.
You're mistaken.
Enjoy the concert.
These are concert tickets. Oh, my.
Thank you. I think I'll go with my husband.
What is this?
It's weight-loss pills.
About the lecture...
Can I go with you?
Do you want to?
I'll buy you dinner in return.
Sure.
Let's go.
- Gosh. - What did I tell you?
You're so stupid.
Why are you doing this to me?
- Have some chocolate. - I don't like sweets.
Have some sweets and wake up.
- Stop it. - Wake up.
Thanks to you, I could remind myself of the role of PR.
You dozed off the whole time.
What's wrong with me?
All the other team members seem to be progressing.
I only get in trouble.
You said you have a different dream.
- You want to become a celebrity. - Still,
I feel...
a bit left out and distant from the others.
These days, you feel like a much mature person than I am.
Once you start pursuing your real dream,
you'll change.
What is this? Are you trying to send me away?
Do you feel no attachment to me?
Don't say that.
- I liked you. - So...
What did you just say?
Do you want to see where I live?
What? Now? Your parents must be there.
Well...
I knew you'd make that face.
After seeing where I live, you feel sorry for me, right?
Me? Not at all.
You live on a rooftop, the symbol of dreams.
Youths who have nothing but dreams and passion...
live either in the basement or on the rooftop.
I've always wanted to try it.
You're just saying that.
This is why...
I couldn't tell you how I felt.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know.
Don't be. I'm the one that's sorry.
When you asked me to act like we're dating,
I shouldn't have continued to grow my feelings for you.
I'll give back the clothes you bought for me.
Why?
Take them.
Now it's really over.
You're not even going to try?
Although our relationship was fake,
thank you for everything.
I finally confessed.
Now I don't have any lingering feelings.
Goodbye.
Hwan Gi stole all my dishes last time.
Now it's you?
I didn't come here to see you, so don't mind me.
I came to volunteer.
I have a heartache because of someone.
That's cold.
Sorry, were you standing there?
I'm worried about Hwan Gi.
He'll be fine.
He has someone beside him...
that keeps on knocking at his door to drag him out.
Unfortunately,
that won't be easy anymore.
We were all fools.
Not a single person...
was able to confess their feelings properly.
You're right.
Too bad for you, though.
What?
What do you mean?
Think about it.
Ji Hye was looking at someone else three years ago,
when you misunderstood her and wasted your time.
Come on.
I'm not sure if I can say this,
but you deserve it.
You're being harsh on me. I'm starting to find you scary.
Good. You shouldn't have told me everything then.
I'm sure Hwan Gi feels the same.
An open door won't be easy to close.
You fool.
Try me. Keep going.
This is Reporter Woo. He's been attacking you constantly.
He used to work for a major press.
He was best friends with that secretary from three years ago.
Also, I found this out while researching around him.
The dead secretary's little sister currently works for Brain.
What?
She must have given Reporter Woo information...
since Mr. Eun's power abuse scandal.
(New York Barbershop)
That's enough.
There's no more space.
Even if you do this, Ro Woon won't change her mind.
Come in.
I thought I should tell you in advance...
that there's no use in visiting anymore.
I'll be closing the shop soon.
Pardon?
Why all of a sudden?
The landlord changed,
and they hiked up the rent by a lot.
He doesn't have as my customers anymore.
He was here for 30 years.
How can they do that?
I don't know why Ro Woon locked herself in,
but I don't think you two were meant to be.
You should get over her.
Now I get it. You were blinded by a woman.
Did she tell you to kick Woo Il out for what he did to her sister?
She didn't tell me anything nor kick Woo Il out.
You're so high-maintenance.
Was it you...
that took over New York Barbershop?
Why did you do that?
They don't have anything left. Was it necessary?
- You saw how Yi Soo broke down. - Yes.
I finally woke up after seeing what happened to Yi Soo.
I'll have to pick out your partner myself.
Pardon?
There she is.
Yun Jung.
Hello, I'm Seo Yun Jung.
Thank you for taking time out of your busy schedule to meet with me.
I'm an impatient man.
I wanted to meet you as soon as possible.
Please have a seat.
Why are you here?
You didn't know I was coming?
Hey, you should've told me that you've been seeing her.
Why did you have to make me get involved?
You know how shy Hwan Gi is.
I should have reached out to you first.
So you two met in university?
No, we don't have that kind of relationship.
Yes. I've been wanting to be the one by his side since then.
I like him a lot.
You're so straightforward. I love it.
I'd love for you to become my daughter-in-law right away.
What do you say? Do you want to marry him?
Marry Hwan Gi?
Even just the thought of it makes me happy.
- Well, it's... - I'm sorry though.
You're not exactly my type.
What?
I like how prudent Hwan Gi is.
He can be a bit slow, but he's thoughtful and considerate.
That's...
But I see that you're a little different.
You're outgoing, impatient, and driven.
I'm like that, so people in that category don't appeal to me.
Thank you for thinking highly of me and arranging this,
but I thought you would've at least given Hwan Gi a heads up.
Judging from how pushy you are, I'm assuming you've already vetted me.
Well, that's...
Since I'm already here, I'll just be open and honest with you.
Will you be okay with us living on our own?
We'll only visit you when there are big family gatherings.
Does your family hold a memorial ceremony annually?
I can't make those pancakes.
I jumped the gun too fast.
I was too rude, wasn't I?
I just didn't think it was right.
I'm sorry for putting you in an uncomfortable position.
Your parents will disapprove of me now.
Does it mean a beginning of sad love?
(New York Barbershop)
What are those?
We have to try to revive your business.
I've had some experience in PR and marketing, you know.
It's about time we get out of this tiny barbershop.
I'm sure you've had your frustrations.
You've spent all of your life here.
We also need to protect all the memories of Mom and Ji Hye.
(30 Years of History, New York Barbershop)
Hello, please visit New York Barbershop.
Hello. Thank you.
Hello.
This is New York Barbershop.
Please visit us.
Thank you.
(30 Years of History, New York Barbershop)
- How cute! - It's so adorable.
Boss?
Why did he show up in that costume?
Just leave.
Please don't do this.
Boss, please.
What?
What are you saying? You're not Boss?
Are you Se Jong?
You're lying. I know it's you, Boss. Show me your face then.
Come on. Show me.
Who is this?
He does look like a prankster. Is it really Se Jong?
Yes, I'm Jang Se Jong today.
If I can be with her, I can let myself go and become anyone.
You're cute.
How cute!
This should be in the photo too.
This is New York Barbershop.
Please visit us!
I can let myself go,
but I cannot defy time.
Here. Drink it.
"Drink it"?
You said you're Se Jong. Can I not talk casually to you?
Stop putting on an act, Boss.
You must be exhausted. Take that off, will you?
Come on! Gosh, seriously.
Stop moving.
Reveal your face already. Goodness.
What are you doing?
Let go of me, Boss.
I'm sorry.
Can you just pretend that I'm someone else?
I just...
want to see your face once.
You're already here. Please let me see your face.
I've missed you so much.
Mom. When someone falls in love with a bear,
will a hero be born?
- What are you talking about? - Let's go, Ro Ah.
You have to leave after eating this.
You said you've missed me.
That's a separate matter.
What can't be done cannot be done.
Here. I'm on an extremely tight budget,
so this is all I can give you.
Anyway, thank you for your help.
You don't need to thank me.
Your dad's business is suffering...
because of my father.
Sorry?
How...
I'm sorry.
Now, there's another reason I can't be the one for you.
But I came.
You're saying it can't be done,
but I've decided to pursue it.
But this won't change anything.
Until now, you always ran to me.
You trust me having no idea what I had done.
After finding out, you forgave me right away.
You can...
lock yourself up now.
Just like you did,
I'll knock on the door, look into the room,
and try to drag you out.
I'll do that from now on.
I wouldn't be able to face my sister.
We shouldn't do this.
I'll do it.
I'll shamelessly insist on staying with someone I shouldn't be with.
Still, I can't do this.
Making the impossible possible is the spirit of the special forces.
Special forces.
Let me help your father's shop.
It's all my father's fault.
Okay?
Let me do it.
I don't know.
Please.
Gosh.
It's just like three years ago.
I shout my heart out, but no one listens.
One thing has changed.
What is that?
You're not alone anymore.
Gosh, that's cheesy.
Do you want one more reason why you can't be with me?
I'm not talking about myself.
My goodness.
Gosh.
I knew you'd be using elementary methods like this.
Don't tell anyone you've worked at Silent Monster.
Sun Bong.
He's right. You have a lot to learn. Who said you could leave?
Yoo Hee.
You should have told us.
We're all here to help you, Ro Woon.
Thank you so much,
everyone.
As you already know,
the market is now dominated by hair salons.
If you simply beg customers to visit a barbershop...
that has been forgotten, you'll only look pitiful.
Then what should we do?
Don't blame the world for never changing.
It's faster and more effective to change yourself.
- Excuse me. - Do you like red ginseng?
Try it.
Could you answer this questionnaire?
Hello, could you answer this questionnaire?
- Hello. - Hello.
- Try some red ginseng. - Please answer this questionnaire.
Don't feel burdened.
Try some red ginseng too.
Here's the questionnaire.
- Yoo Hee, here's one for you. - For me?
- If you're bored... - It's a bit bitter.
For an innovation, do thorough market research first.
It tastes good, right?
Please take this.
Try white.
- Pink. - It looks good.
It's nice.
It looks great.
- You look like an actor. - That's absurd.
You look amazing.
- It looks great on you. - You look great.
You look 10 years younger.
You look amazing.
Are you really my dad?
You look fantastic. You look like a different person.
Why don't you change all the towels as well?
The interior design and the signs too.
You could change the name of the shop as well.
The floor, the ceiling, and the walls will look better this way.
Oh, my.
I don't know how to pay you back for your efforts.
Still, all this feels strange and uncomfortable to me.
You need to change to be loved.
If I'm going to change everything,
what's the point of staying at the same place?
You've worked so hard. I'm so sorry.
Don't say that.
- It's okay. - We understand.
It's okay.
Dad.
Well then...
I'll get going.
Get home safely.
I can't believe him.
He never gets out of his comfort zone.
We shouldn't have urged him to change against his will.
We should find a way he can stay the way he is.
Would that be possible?
It's what someone told me before.
I'm sure there's a method of communication that suits you.
Let's find it.
Don't change.
I'll make sure to find it.
Don't worry too much. You should get going now.
- I'll get going then. - See you.
I'm reporter Han Seok Jun.
- The 38th... - Seok Jun?
Please do me a favor.
He's so popular as a host.
I can't promise you anything.
- You know that, right? - Yes. Thank you.
Please ask him to look through the material.
(New York Barbershop)
Do me a favor in return.
Pretend to be my boyfriend just once.
What?
You know that he's my first love, right?
I was an unattractive girl with braces back then.
I want to show him that I've completely changed.
But why me?
I pretended to be your girlfriend in front of your father too.
Can't you do it for me just this once?
- Still, I... - You don't want to?
I didn't say that.
Just take it.
You're doing it, okay?
I like the concept.
Can I just say hi and leave?
Yes, give me a kiss too.
Okay. What?
I have a sad history.
While keeping me on the hook,
he kissed my best friend.
Help me recover from my trauma.
Still, I can't kiss you.
It's just a little peck. Is it that hard?
I can't do that.
I can't do this either then.
Wait.
It'll be a peck on the cheek.
- On the lips. - On the cheek.
Fine, on the cheek.
Let's go.
It'll be on the cheek.
- Hi, it's been a long time. - Hi, Yun Jung.
Have you been well? Who is this?
This is Hwan Gi, the CEO of Silent Monster.
I see.
He's my boyfriend.
Hello.
Nice to meet you.
- He wanted to meet you. - I see.
Honey, you can go now.
- Should I go? - Yes.
Right now?
Thank you. Bye.
- All right, it's finished. - Thank you.
I heard other people tell me that my stylist must hate me...
because I got trendy haircuts that didn't suit me.
However, the New York Barbershop...
has kept their place for 30 years for a reason.
They have a huge presence.
Thank you so much.
You should thank Hwan Gi.
All I did was help with the contact.
Also, New York Barbershop is a good item by itself.
The producers could see that it was worth covering.
I'm leaving for the US tonight.
Pardon? The US?
It's going to be a long trip this time.
Don't be too happy.
Why all of a sudden?
So that people miss me more.
I didn't tell Hwan Gi yet.
I hope he gets upset and misses me.
You should still say goodbye.
I got to say my goodbye.
Please take good care of him.
I...
I know. Still, please take good care of him.
Take care.
Come visit me.
Please line up.
- Don't cut in line. - What's going on?
- Here you go. - Okay.
- Sure, take a picture. - You can take me.
I'm his closest friend.
You have a lot of customers.
Oh, hello.
- Please sit here to wait. - Okay.
You have to line up here.
Hey, you're here.
- Come here. - Sure, okay.
Almost done.
What is all this?
98...
Gosh, rent isn't the issue anymore.
You'll become a landlord at this rate.
It'll only be temporary.
Don't be blinded. You should always be consistent.
Gosh. All right.
2,000.
(Yoo Hee)
Yes, Yoo Hee.
Pardon?
Last year, corruption behind a huge construction was revealed.
That was also the time a famous celebrity's scandal broke out.
The one that provided the information about the scandal...
was Silent Monster.
The power abuser Eun Hwan Gi helped another power abuser...
regain his good image. Rose Airlines' Mr. Park.
Birds of a feather flock together.
There is something more beyond that.
For Congressman Eun's election within the party,
Mr. Park's in-laws have a key vote.
Congressman Eun has a great network in the press and in politics.
He's talented in dealing with issues.
Gosh.
Someone fell to her death at the company,
but he covered it up and not a single line was published.
I'm Mr. Eun Hwan Gi's secretary.
When he was talked about regarding his abuse of power,
they were able to deal with the crisis and get out of it.
They buried truths that put them at a disadvantage.
Congressman Eun would emphasize advantageous issues.
The one that executed everything...
was Brain. And also,
Silent Monster.
Reporter Woo, how can you do this without telling me?
Did you know Congressman Eun is trying to kick your father out?
I know that.
But you got one thing wrong.
Boss and Silent Monster are...
The truth is relative.
I'm sorry.
But...
Why can't you leave?
Exactly what was that about?
Ji Hye...
used to like him.
What?
That's why she suffered.
It was because she couldn't tell him how she felt.
Then...
how can I...
accept him?
I...
There is a way out for us.
We can say...
that Woo Il did it out of excessive loyalty.
- Father. - He's already gone.
We can say that we found out and fired him in advance.
Please stop it!
(My Shy Boss)
There is only one person I want to be with.
I was always stuck in one spot, but she made me run.
She also ran towards me.
How long are you going to stay here by yourself?
- I can't sleep anyway. - Porn?
Isn't that sexy?
- Go wash up. - Should I take a shower?
From head to toe?
Tell me. What are you unhappy with? Just go ahead.
Don't see me, or don't ask me.
No, just don't be curious.
I'm by myself again. Boss!
Let's grant the wish of the winner.
- I got my wish. - What was your wish?