By our ancestors,
free hunters and warriors,
By the great northern forests,
By the river Lena and Amur,
we pray to you.
Blessed Mary, Mother of God,
full of grace,
hear words of humble servant.
Forgive us honest criminals,
for the sins we
are forced to commit.
Assist us in our battle
against power-mongering polit
bureaucrats and their minions
cops and soldiers,
and every other devil in uniform.
O most gracious Mother
of the most gracious God,
bless our weapons,
temper our knives,
guide our bullets
and anoint our souls
and our grasp
may become yours.
Kolyma!
We must respect
all living creatures,
except for the police,
people who work
in government,
bankers,
usurers,
and anyone who has
the power and money
to exploit
simple people.
Stealing from this people
is allowed.
But remember:
It's crazy to want too much.
Men cannot possess more
than his heart
can love.
SIBERIAN EDUCATION
Do not move!
Stay in the car!
Learn from our brother Plank.
It is sacrilege
for an honest Siberian
to keep money
in his house.
Even the stolen money.
10 YEARS LATER
1998- CAUCASUS MOUNTAINS, RUSSIAN ARMY,
SPECIAL FORCES
Kolyma, you think I could
have his cigarettes?
Thanks!
Three minutes ago
Yes, confirmed.
A truck loaded with heroin.
I think they're the ones
we're looking for.
Yes. We will find them.
Okay, roger that.
Over and out.
They were low on gas and were
out here without a spare tank.
They were headed
some place nearby.
Look what else I found.
You something, Sergeant?
The first job I ever had
was playing dead.
1988 - RIVERBANK, SOVIET UNION
- He's dead!
- No! I know I braked in time.
Look at him! Not even a scratch!
He's got a pulse.
What the fuck do you think happened?
Maybe he's sick.
Where am I?
It's a damned miracle you're alive, boy.
You know?
Uncle Vasia!
I'm not Uncle Vasia.
And what are you doing wandering around here
all by yourself, anyway?
I'm lost.
I forgot everything.
I better go home.
- You sure you're okay?
- Yes, sir.
Gagarin?
Kolyma, we got enough
for the whole neighborhood!
Kolyma, quick!
It is the army!
They are after the truck robbers!
Run!
Easy, easy!
- You two, sit down.
- But Grandfather...
Do as I say.
Good evening, comrade Officer.
How may I help you?
Where is your husband?
In the Kasparov Cemetary.
Are you this woman's father?
No, Grandfather is
my husband's father.
I did not ask you.
Someone robbed a truck
recently.
100 pairs of boots
have disappeared.
Anna, I need you to deliver
a few words on my behalf
to this piece of trash.
Can you ask him please
why he thinks
he can come armed
in the heart of Riverbank
and enter the house
of an honest criminal?
Grandfather asks, "If by-"
- Silence! Listen, you piece of shit!
- Kolyma!
Take your hands off
my grandfather, you pig!
Comrade Commander,
The place is full of...
Jesus Christ
and all his blessed relations!
I'm sorry, grandfather Kuzya...
but thank God no one
has been hurt.
Do you realize what times we live in,
brother Plank?
Not even in our homes
can we find peace.
True, but we are always
with you, Grandpa Kuzya,
in happy times and sad.
Kolyma.
Tell me sister Lena,
brother Amur speaks too!
I crossed my land
from one part
stopping trains
singing and making my rifle,
and only the old taiga knows
I killed those cops!
And now that I'm in trouble,
Jesus Christ help me,
help me lose my gun!
Mama Siberia,
take my life!
He did it to
defend us.
Yes, but Kolyma
broke three rules.
He took a weapon without
the permission of an adult
He took it from the red corner,
and he attempted to
fire it inside the house.
These are things one
should never do!
Never!
But... it was brave.
You don't have a switchblade,
do you?
No.
Well, take this one, then.
- For me?
- Yes, Kolyma.
This switchblade has known you
since the day you were born.
It is the same blade that was
used to cut the umbilical cord
that tied you to your mother.
The switchblade is like the cross.
It stays with us our entire lives.
No, Gagarin. This is not
your switchblade.
But I...
Even if you cannot be gifted with
the blade that cut you from your mother
Here, take it!
May the good Lord also guide
your hand and...
Kolyma!
Fingers inward.
Protect your fingers
Protect yours.
Short and swift. Like this!
That way, the wound is bigger
and your opponent
dies more quickly.
Palms up,
you turn the blade and slash.
Watch Gagarin,
he's already good
Learned all by himself.
We are here.
This must be less than a kilometer away.
Eyes open
and absolute silence!
It's heroin. He's got 10 kilos.
Grandpa Kuzya, please!
I have three mouths to feed!
Three mouths?
- Yes.
- Is that so?
Then...
...Let's just start with yours.
- No! Please! No!
There's something you want to ask me?
The answer to the question
you don't want to ask me is quite simple.
There is no place for drugs
in our community.
We Siberians do not dirty
our hands with that stuff.
Come on Mel, hurry up!
I'm trying!
Not so easy, you know.
- Move over!
- Get out of there!
Get out of there, you idiot!
Three fucking Georgians!
They stole my stamps,
the ones that I had just bought!
And so you started bawling
right in front of them?
Even the painting with Stalin!
He is dressed like a pilot!
It is really rare!
But I did not cry...
Not in front of them.
Look who's coming!
Look who's come back!
The little fairy with the stamps!
You know, you're pretty cute
up close...
Even if you wear glasses!
So very cute...
Too bad you're a fairy!
- Vitalic!
- Vitalic, we are here!
We give up!
My friend Vitalic,
would like his stamps back,
Especially the one with the Red Lenin.
- Stalin! With the Stalin!
That's enough! Gagarin, that's enough!
We won!
Now listen carefully, you momma's boy
'cause I'm only going to say this once.
Nobody in this city
touchs us, Siberians.
Mama Siberia,
take my life!
Shut up!
First I'm going to release
the female.
Wait...
Now!
You see, Kolyma...
if they live only in a cage,
they die.
Because the home of every living
creature is the sky.
Go! Go!
Stop there!
Go!
No! No!
No!
Go! Go!
Go!
Go! Run!
Run! Run!
- It's from Vaisef.
- Here!
- It's from Sergei!
- He's my son.
Mel, this is it!
It's from Gagarin.
"They're keeping me seven years,
Kolyma.
"They will be sending me
far away soon.
"But I'm OK.
I am tough.
"These bastards
will never break me!
The winter seemed never ending,
and the pack was
dying of hunger.
The leader of the pack,
the oldest of all,
was out in front, comforting
the young wolves
telling them that
spring was coming.
But, at a certain point,
one young wolf
decides to stop.
He says he has had enough
of cold and hunger,
and he says he was
going to live among men.
Because the important thing
is to stay alive.
The young wolf
lets himself be caught,
and with the passing
of time,
He forgets he was ever a wolf.
One day
many years later,
as he was out hunting
with his master,
He runs sevile
to collect the prey,
but he realizes the prey
was the old leader of the pack.
He falls silent with shame
but the old wolf speaks
and says to him:
"I die happy because
I lived my life as a wolf.
"You, on the other hand, belong
neither to the world of wolves
"Nor to the world of men!"
Hunger comes and goes,
but dignity, once lost
never returns.
1989-1995
RIVERBANK, EX-SOVIET UNION
Kolyma, that girl
is looking at you.
Really?
Yeah, really.
- Do you know her?
- No.
- Do you?
- Never seen her before.
But I'd sure remember if I had.
Kolyma, we gotta go!
You sure took your time coming back!
Mel, don't tell me
you don't recognize him.
- Gagarin!
- Gagarin?
Shit!
Gagarin has gone back
to Riverbank!
My mother
I only wrote once
and that was to tell me
she had sold the house
and run off with some
truck driver from Romania.
They say that Romanians
make good lovers!
What's that?
Just a little something from
my friends inside
to make sure
I won't forget them.
So, what are you doing here in the station?
Copper, good stuff.
- And who's paying?
- The gimp.
As always.
Hey listen, you should be happy
with the price I gave you.
That is my final offer.
You think you're dealing with
a bunch of idiots, don't you, gimp?
Well you're wrong.
We're only asking for what's fair.
- And what would "fair" be?
- Three times as much.
Three times?
You Siberians
are out of your mind!
- Mel, where does he keep the money?
- In the office.
- Gagarin, don't...
- Hurry up!
- Jesus Christ, got it!
- Alright.
- Come on, let's get outta this fucking dump
- No, Gagarin.
We said what's fair.
Fair?
And what, exactly,
is fair, Kolyma?
There is no such thing as "fair".
- So how did it happen?
- Mama!
Mom!
Nobody has been here since
husband was killed.
Here kept all his fishing
gear in here.
Are you sure, you don't
have a better place to live?
There is no better
than seeing
you and Vitalic
every morning, Aunt Katya.
Move!
We're not going to arrest you.
If you do not tell me where Ageyev
and his men are,
I'll kill you. Simple as that.
Our jails are full
of people like you.
So try and act
intelligently.
Ageyev is very powerful.
He's got a lot of men.
And this is his territory.
When he finds out you have taken us,
He will kill us all!
It would be better to die...
Shit, I can't believe it!
After 7 years, I find myself
right back where I started from.
- What's with them?
- Russian army.
When the Soviet Union fell,
they left.
Then they changed their flags
and came back.
Now they're even worse
before.
Supposedly they're here to help
the peace process.
Ya, to protect us.
But all they really care about
are the weapons factories.
A lot of the clans are
making deals with them.
And those?
They shot up overnight,
like mushrooms.
So now the poor are dying of envy
as well as hunger.
That's their fucking problem.
I'm sure as hell not going to stick
around to enjoy the view.
- What are you going to do?
- To get rich.
That's a good one! Nobody in
Riverbank has ever gotten rich.
Well, I guess that means that
I'll be the first.
Bring me to see the city!
This is 'bank.
Can you really recognize it!
Completely in the hands of
Georgians now: weapons, black market...
They call this Odessa now.
The Jews control it.
Diamonds, precious stones...
This is Bridges:
prostitution, drugs...
even a few Black Seed bastards.
Why are they bastards?
What the fuck do you know about
the Black Seed?
Shit, Gagarin, just look at them.
They look like clowns!
All covered in gold and no
respect for women...
You do not know...
You're the one who doesn't know shit,Kolyma!
When I was in jail, if it were not
the Black Seed, I'd be dead.
Come on, brother, take me around!
Bring me to see the world. Come on!
Go! Go!
What time is it?
Almost five.
Your friend with the truck
isn't showing up.
- We're going to have to walk back
- But it's far!
And dangerous, too!
We're in Bridges.
Here! Put this on.
Come on, let's get a move on.
I was just asking myself...
what a bunch of Siberians
are doing in Bridges!
- Ghat, did you invite them?
- Not me!
So why the hell are they here?
There is enough shit around here already.
Can one of you Siberians tell me,
Why you are here?
Did you ask permission to
come on to our turf?
And armed!
We're on our way home.
I am Gagarin, from Riverbank. Let us pass.
Advice for a friend.
And I am Vulture,
from Bridges.
And Vulture does not take advice
from anybody!
Well, then Vulture is an asshole.
Get them!
Welcome.
I'm doctor Nikolai Sakurov,
and this is my daughter, Xenya.
It's best you don't move.
You can stay with us tonight.
We wouldn't want to trouble you, Doctor.
Trouble?
My dear woman, my daughter and I
have been welcomed like family
Ever since we came
to Riverbank.
I feel like a member of this community,
not the director of the regional hospital.
Okay, confirmed. They're the
drug traffickers we were looking for.
We'll attack as soon as
our guest tells us
where Ageyev's hideout is.
By the way, Headquarters tells me
that someone with Ageyev
we have to watch out for...
considered highly dangerous.
A certain Yuri Lebedev.
A Siberian, like you.
Goes by the name of Gagarin.
Never heard of him.
I guess we'll meet him soon enough.
You work on him,
I'll leave you alone.
I made you some tea and
Papa said you could
eat some cookies.
Was this the knife
that hurt you?
- No, this is a tattoo.
- This hurt you, right?
- You like this book?
- Yes, it's beautiful.
- Do you want it?
- But it's not yours, it's your father's.
Everything here is mine,
the house, yard...
My father is mine.
- Do you want the yard?
- No, the book is plenty.
Good.
Papa says that I'm special,
and that I play the piano well.
- And you?
- I'm no-not the piano...
Not the piano.
Special!
And you're special, too?
Once, when once I was four,
I won the record for beatings.
My father beat me for half an hour
and I didn't cry.
Not once.
- Why?
- Why what?
- Why did not you cry?
- Because men don't cry.
Oh! Poor men!
It is good to cry!
Are you happy when you cry?
That is too hard a question.
This is what I think.
I think...
that you do not cry,
but I do not read.
And that is worse than crying!
What do you mean you don't read?
Xenya does not know how to read.
Poor Xenya!
You can find someone
to read to you.
- Will you read to me?
- Of course!
Here!
"With yards of sunset yard
"Along the Nevsky of the world,
"With its glowing trail
"I linger with a Don Giovanni air. "
It's by a poet named Mayakovsky.
But do not ask me what it means,
I did not understand a word.
Xenya does not read
and Kolyma does not understand.
Kolyma!
- What is that?
- Kolyma!
The new doctor's daughter. She
arrived the same day you came back.
- She's got it all going!
- Except she's not all there in the head.
She's fine, thank you!
- Are you okay?
- Yes, I'm okay.
I guess Xenya's glad to
have found Kolyma.
That's very nice, Xenya but
you should really go home now.
People of Riverbank,
I, Yuri Lebedev
also known as Gagarin,
inform you that I have had
enough of this shit
Therefore, I have decided to kill myself.
Farewell, you shitfaces!
Do not worry, Xenya
he'll come up now.
He's probably swimming
under the boat.
No, he's not coming back up.
Gagarin, stop being such a jerk!
Come up now, asshole!
- He's not coming up.
- Mel, stop horsing around!
He's not even there, Kolyma.
Maybe he drowned.
Do not believe it, Xenya.
Gagarin, he always makes
jokes like that.
He's just making jokes.
See? I can stay under
for two whole minutes.
- What's wrong with her?
- She's crying, for you.
See, what did I tell you?
It was all a joke.
Nothing can kill Gagarin.
Don't worry, Xenya, it'll be alright.
You'll be okay.
Are you really crying for me?
Let me tell you, it is not worth it.
Nobody has ever cried for me.
People call them crazy,
insane, abnormal...
all because we don't understand
what they're thinking and saying.
But their language is the language of God.
That is why they are called
"A Gift from God."
And we must
respect them all.
Nobody is allowed
to lay a finger on them,
and it's up to us
to protect them
even if it cost us our lives.
Now, let's drink our "Chifir,"
The best tea in the whole world.
First we enjoy its warmth
and we appreciate its aroma,
and only then do we taste its flavour.
Three pleasures in one.
And think it is only just water!
Kolyma draws.
He wants to study with you.
I cannot say if he is any good
but maybe you could kindly
look and see
if our Holy Mother
guides his hand.
There is nothing for me to read.
Like an empty notebook.
Clean, white pages
waiting to be filled.
Kolyma, this is Ink
master of tattoos.
Yes, the Mother by
the grace of our Lord,
has blessed your hands.
But...
a tattoo is not simply a drawing.
A tattoo artist
is like a confessor.
He writes the story of a man
on his body.
Mans' lives can all
seem all the same.
You're born, you grow up,
you fall in love,
You have children, you work
You die.
Some enjoy life,
Some don't.
But we Siberians, Kolyma,
we fight it.
You must do your very best to learn.
For many months
you will do only one thing.
Observe.
I heard one of his men
is a real cop hunter.
Something fierce, a different
breed from the rest of you.
Comes somewhere far away.
I do not know, believe me.
I'm not that important.
Ageyev has got a lot of
good strong men.
You will never catch him.
Because Allah
is on his side.
That's funny, cause I'm pretty sure
he is on my side.
God helps one side sometimes
and sometimes he
helps the other.
What matters is being on
the right side at the right moment.
No, no, please!
I dunno a thing!
I know nothing!
No, please!
Get out of here!
You don't know shit, and another death
isn't going to do anybody any good.
And maybe because God
is on your side right now.
So go before he changes his mind.
How you say "crazy"
where you come from?
We say, "Gift from God."
Kolyma, get up!
The river is flooding.
It's already washed away
some houses from the banks.
Come on, they need all the help
they can get.
- Vitalic!
- Kolyma!
The river is washing away everything!
Gagarin and Mel are
already down at the canal.
There is all kinds of stuff you can have!
Grandfather Kuzya says we have to
help the others down at the river.
Shit, Kolyma!
There are so many helping already.
For once, we don't have to steal
or take out our knives!
Please!
- Kolyma!
- Get back inside Xenya! It's pouring here.
Papa is at the hospital.
Xenya is all alone!
Wait for me, I'm coming with you!
It is dangerous, the river
isn't normal today!
I know it is not normal! But Xenya
is not normal, neither are you!
Damnit, Xenya, I told you that
you're not coming with us!
But why?
I'm not a little girl, you know.
I'm not a little girl!
I am not going to be killed out there.
If I wanted to die,
I would do it myself!
Stop it! Go inside!
Come on, Kolyma. Let's go.
That must be worth
at least 200 rubles.
What?
That table there!
And those tires are worth
at least 20 a piece.
Here is a whole
case of vodka!
Here are more!
The liquor store must have flooded!
Hey Vitalic, your mother,
can she sell these?
Vitalic!
Look what I found!
What the fuck would
we do with the piano?
Shit, it's a good thousand!
Come on! We got to get it out
before the current grabs it.
Who is going to buy a soggy piano?
I hate piano music anyways.
Shut up, Mel!
Just pull the rope.
On my count.
One, two, three!
Vitalic?!
Shit! Vitalic, he fell under!
Fuck!
Vitalic!
How long has he been under?
I asked you!
How long has he been fucking under?!
Vitalic!
Vitalic! Vitalic!
What was the fucking piano
going to get you, anyway?
- Money.
- It's all you think about anymore.
If it were not for that piano,
Vitalic would still be here!
Oh, so it's my fault now?
Fuck you!
- Fuck you!
Xenya!
Papa! Papa!
- Papa is not here.
- Don't worry, Xenya.
We will stay with you
until he gets back.
Papa will be back soon.
Vitalic?
Is he ever coming back?
Vitalic is never coming back,
Xenya. He's dead.
Yes.
Yes, he's dead.
He's not coming back.
He's dead! He's dead!
Kolyma reads all kinds of books to Xenya.
Does Gagarin know how to read, too?
Read?
Of course I know how to read.
So now Gagarin
will read to Xenya.
No, Xenya, come on.
I don't feel like it.
So Gagarin does
not know how to read.
Yes, I do. I just don't feel like
reading right now.
Please! Please!
Pretty please!
Gagarin is nice to read to me now.
"Ask not what end the gods
have set for you,
"For me... Be wise,
Strain the wine
"And since life is brief...
"Seize the day.
"Don't think about
"Tomorrow. "
This is for fucking kids!
- Why the hell did you bring us here?
- You'll see, or should I say...
you will hear!
Yeah, what?
What is there to hear?
Real western music!
Xenya's never been on a ride.
Okay, let's go. I'm paying.
Yes!
- Where did you get that?
- You and I have to talk.
Ladies and gentlemen, I officially declare
that this blue ribbon
is happiness!
- Stay close to me. Very close.
- Okay. Very close.
- You're going to make Kolyma fly.
- Yeah, let's make him fly!
You'd say that is
fun to fly!
Terrible ride?
Papa!
Papa look
what Kolyma gave me.
Xenya is very happy!
Kolyma, please
come in for a minute.
I want to thank you.
You kids, you are
so good to my daughter.
You see, I am always
at the hospital and...
Xenya!
She is going through a very
delicate period.
Her body is now that of a woman.
But her mind...
She's feeling things that
she cannot understand
and she doesn't know how to react.
Because she is...
She is...
A gift from God.
Exactly! A gift from God.
- Careful, it is dangerous.
- Xenya wants to see.
- It's beautiful! I want one too!
- Careful.
Very high!
- Aren't they good?
- Yes!
Very, very...
And Xenya is good too!
Stupid!
Let's fly!
Make Xenya fly!
Xenya, come.
I want to show you how the good Lord
has blessed our doves' nest.
Look.
The moment has come.
It is not enough to observe any longer.
Have you decided what it will be?
Impossible love.
Then write it forever
on your body.
I cannot wait to see if the Mother
still guides your hands.
The sky and the river...
and flowers.
It's all so beautiful!
So very beautiful!
Xenya is only happy
when she is with Kolyma.
That's not good, Xenya.
I'm happy to see you too, but...
But?
I always go to Kolyma,
but he never comes to me.
Why do you not want
to see Xenya?
I want to go to
the fair with you
swim in the river with you...
I want you to read to me,
and to hold my hand, and then...
- Xenya, be careful!
- Give you a kiss.
I knew it. I knew that
Kolyma would taste good!
Xenya, sit down!
Why is Kolyma mad at me?
If Xenya comes looking for me,
I'm not here.
Even if I'm here,
I'm not here!
But why?
I know why!
- Aren't you going to eat?
- I'm not hungry.
These are really beautiful!
Who did it for you?
A colleague of yours,
a guy in Moscow.
Really, what's his name?
Plato Ivanov.
Plato Ivanov?
Wait a minute.
Plato Ivanov? I know him!
He is good!
He is very good...
but I'm Ink,
master of tattoos.
Read.
This man killed someone.
Who?
- Cops. He killed some cops, but...
- But, what?
It is not clear
why he killed them.
Where is he from?
Who is his family?
It's not clear.
Exactly. It's not clear.
He's no cop killer
He's a Black Seed.
He does business with the police.
Exactly! He is a spy!
Up to this point,
we were always inpenetrable.
When plague breaks out...
you burn sick people's belongings
You know why?
To avoid contamination.
Sooner or later...
we will not know
what we need anymore.
We won't even know who we are.
When that day comes,
Kolyma,
Not even the signs cut into
our skin will help us.
Moscow, with what money?
- Where'd that come from?
- I told you we had to talk.
Hello, Gagarin.
Grandfather Kuzya!
What is this filth
doing in our house?
Okay, what's up. I'd better be going.
You're not going anywhere!
Clean it up first.
The table!
Clean it!
Thoroughly!
Kolyma!
Gagarin!
- Gagarin, wait!
- Who the fuck does he think he is?
Those are our rules,
Gagarin.
You know we can't have
money inside the house!
Does that seem normal to you?
It's almost the year 2000
for Christ's sake!
Money is not
some dirty thing, you know.
I don't buy these
rules of yours anymore.
I do not believe in anything,
so I can do whatever I want.
- What is this place?
- Just some people I know.
People with friends
in Moscow.
- Hey Gagarin.
- I brought a friend along.
Kolyma.
Welcome.
- Hello Gagarin.
- Hey, Boris.
Gagarin!
These people are
the Black Seed!
I'll wait for you outside.
Hello, guys. How's it going?
Kolyma, wait!
Kolyma!
- You fucking junkie.
- You deal with the Black Seeds!
- You make me sick!
- Kolyma, listen to me!
Talk through your nose, asshole!
Hey fucking dickhead!
You've become a brainwashed idiot
with all the bullshit
your grandfather spouts!
He and that little retarded
whore friend of yours!
Watch out, Kolyma!
You're making the biggest
mistake of your life!
May our Lord watch over you, Gagarin.
Hey, you! Halt!
Don't you know there is a curfew
in this neighborhood?
Didn't they ever teach you how to speak?
- Let's see your ID.
- I don't have an ID.
My name's Kolyma, from Riverbank.
Want one?
Riverbank? We know all about you Siberians.
This man
worked with us.
We know that your clan killed him.
Just give me the name of who did it,
and you can walk out free.
Can you see ok?
Maybe there is something in your eye.
As you wish.
I am Shorty from Magadan.
Welcome, brother.
So you can tattoo!
This is a blessing
for our family.
Everyone wants a tattoo here.
And they will pay well for it, too.
I'm still learning.
Besides, I'm not very good yet
and I don't have any tools with me.
Everyone has a role here.
Igor is our tailor.
Kiri is our carpenter.
He fixes the bunks.
Yahoud is our cook.
Here if you don't do something,
you're nothing.
Don't worry about the tools.
Just tell us what you need.
Kolyma!
Kolyma, my son...
I have seen to it that money has arrived
in the hands of the right people,
so you will be getting out soon.
Unfortunately, this is
not good news.
I had to do this
because when you are free,
an even more difficult task
awaits you.
Grandfather Kuzya.
Welcome back, Kolyma.
I am happy to see the Mother
still guides your hands.
I had the chance to practice.
Do you know why we got you out?
Something terrible has happened to Xenya.
And the House of Lords punishment
will fall on all of us
because they did not protect her.
And now all that remains
is to show the Lord
that we are attentive to his signs
and we'll carry out
his justice.
They found her in the park.
Two women
from Riverbank.
She had been raped and beaten.
Xenya!
Xenya, it's me.
It's Kolyma.
She cannot hear you
Her mind is gone
Xenya.
The is the law:
You must find who did it.
Mel will go with you.
I loaded this
with my own hands.
That means you have
the right to use it
to kill whoever
must be killed.
This is the task
reserved for you.
Why me?
Be careful how you answer,
Grandfather Kuzya.
There is no turning back once
you kill someone.
Go! Go!
Go!
Get out!
Come on!
Grandfather!
The Mongols call Siberia,
"The Sleeping Land."
I want to go back there
and lay down.
Ok, we've got a car
guns and enough money to
loosen some tongues.
All of the clans have been notified
and they're willing
to collaborate.
So, hunting season
begins tonight, Mel.
I'd like to bring my mother a fish.
She really loves fish.
I haven't gone fishing
in so long.
Since we lost Vitalic.
Kolyma!
I heard you, Mel, but
now's not the time, okay?
I dont' feel like it and besides,
we don't have any equipment.
If that's the reason,
you will find everything you need
in the toolshed.
Nobody has set foot in here
since Gagarin has left.
You will need a flashlight.
Finally! Yes! The rod!
And the drill should be here somewhere.
Help me.
Is that where you left your switchblade?
Kolyma!
And the switchblade placed
in the door of a house...
means that a meeting of
destinies will take place there.
You sure took your time finding me!
Any longer, you and I, we'll
have to die of old age.
It wasn't easy.
I never thought I'd
see you wearing that.
It's horrible.
It is horrible...
but enlisting was
the only way to find you.
Oh, I forgot you don't drink.
The Russians are right on your tail,
Gagarin.
Lots of them.
You won't even know you're dead.
And this isn't good, right?
Because you want to be the one
to kill me.
Strange.
After all this time,
whenever I think about you,
I still picture you as a boy.
Xenya's ribbon.
I found it in Aunt Katya's toolshed.
It's stained with her blood;
so was the wall
and the mattress where you slept.
I'm listening.
You want the whole story?
It's not like those ones
your grandfather used to tell!
- There is no moral here.
- Just tell me why.
There is no why. No reason.
And no excuses either!
It just happened.
Sucks, doesn't it?
I destroy everything I touch.
Grandfather loaded it for me.
I've been waiting for you.
I kept looking towards the woods, every day,
trying to imagine when exactly you'd appear.
I missed you, you know?
We've had great company.
I was always alone, Kolyma.
I've been alone my whole life!
When I got out of jail,
I said to myself:
"You belong to no one
and no one belongs to you!
"And since the game is dirty,
No rules!
"Take everything you can without asking.
Without saying 'thank you!'
"Because no one, no one is going to
give you anything. Not for free! "
But instead, I ended
up in this shithole.
I want to go back, Kolyma.
There is only one way.
I know.
And when a criminal
dies,
his switchblade
must be broken.
One part remains
with him,
The other part, with the person whom
he loves most in this world.
Why?
Because that way
on Judgment Day,
They can find
each other
And be reunited in peace.
Dear mama,
you were right...
Some choices don't allow you
to turn back.
And now, I can never
come home again.
I think of you often.
Take care of yourself.
I've decided to follow the sun
and will go west.
I'm not sure what
my future holds,
but I can tattoo,
use a knife and shoot a gun.
Don't worry about me.
I will stop you must fight life
and I'll know how to.