SIGNS OF LIFE
- Actors -
- Sound -
Written, directed & produced
by Werner Herzog
What's the matter?
It's so hot!
Bring him over there.
He's almost dead.
Four weeks
after the parachutist Stroszek
was transferred to Crete, -
- he was wounded and had to be
withdrawn from battle.
He and another soldier
had been shot at
by partisans in the west, -
- near the town of Chania.
It occurred during a lull
in the fighting, -
- in a village held
by the Germans.
After convalescence,
Stroszek was sent to Cos
in the Dodekanes.
On that island,
there had been no fighting.
It was peaceful there.
A helpful officer
sought to find a post -
- where Stroszek could spend
the rest of the war
- without seeing
any more action.
The occupation of the island
was peaceful, -
- and only required
a garrison of 60.
Stroszek was separated
from the main garrison -
- and stationed
in the old fortress.
H is Greek wife, Nora,
and two other soldiers -
- lived together with him there.
A previous guard informed them
about their duties.
The only entrance,
which could be reached by a bridge, -
- had to be kept locked at night.
Parts of the town had been destroyed
several times by earthquakes.
As a result, old relics were
often found under the ruins.
The Venetians
began to use relics
to fill in the walls
of the fortress.
After the walls were finished, -
- this was no longer possible.
There was an am m unition depot
in the main courtyard -
- which was abandoned by the
Greeks and had to be guarded -
- even though the Germans
couldn't use it in their own weapons.
Guarding this
was their only real task.
The living-quarters were located
in a newer building
in the fortress.
There,
the still incom plete m useum
and the house of the restorer -
- had been requisitioned
by the army.
The surroundings had
a strange effect on Stroszek, -
- but he could find
no explanation for this.
However, the others adapted
themselves quickly to the place.
Stroszek had tried his hand
at various jobs without success.
At one time,
he had been a salesman.
But he had always wanted to
em igrate to Canada or Australia.
Then he thought of
going to Chile, -
- since he knew a fam ily there.
Nora nursed him in the hospital.
Stroszek had been granted
special perm ission to marry her.
What a shame that the people had
to leave all their belongings behind.
The household crockery,
their little pictures.
How touching it all is.
And now we are making ourselves
comfortable here.
Do you understand me?
If this war goes on
m uch longer, -
- we'll spend a long time here.
If the war lasts very long, -
- I m ight have a baby here.
The words are hard to read
because they run into each other.
It's beautiful.
Becker had often m issed school
because of illness.
Still, he passed his exams
with the highest marks.
When war came, stronger men
were found unfit for service.
He passed his physical, but soon
fell ill after he was drafted.
Meinhard was formerly
a bar-keeper, -
- until one of his customers
was killed in a brawl.
He then became a crane-operator.
It paid better anyway.
Everything's full of oil here.
Here everything's full of oil.
Salad in oil,
fish in oil, meat, -
- machine-gun in oil.
What a shitty country!
Empty, no ammunition.
Are we supposed
to shoot with grease?
Okay, I'll get it.
I couldn't fix
a decent meal today.
Salt and other things
are m issing.
We have wine instead.
No thanks, not for me.
It tastes like turpentine.
Dammit!
This place is full of roaches.
They're not harmful.
They are the most repulsive
things on earth.
They don't even bite.
It's not that.
They snap and pop all night
long, just like this.
Just like that all night.
Becker, listen, I've got it.
The trap has to be placed
against the wall, -
- since the roaches always keep
running along the walls.
It works like this.
Look!
The roach runs
up this board or ram p -
- until it arrives
at this trap, -
- which moves
at the slightest touch.
Then it falls into the funnel, -
- either this way or that way.
It should be baited,
but with what?
What do you think they eat,
sugar?
One could try it.
Stroszek volunteered from the beginning
for sentry duty at night.
The lights in town
were never put out at night.
He loved to sit
facing the town -
- in order to show the world
that he was still functional.
Everyplace else had been bom bed:
only this place was spared.
Stroszek thought that he could detect
a kind of anticipation in the town -
- which somehow attracted him
and seemed to offer him a challenge.
U nbelievable!
There really are roaches
in here!
There are even two of them!
I know I've got
some insecticide somewhere.
This is the right seasoning.
That's what they get -
- for being so repulsive.
Do we have turpentine
or something?
The brushes are getting sticky,
we can throw them away soon.
Maybe hot water would work.
Are you crazy?
- Gasoline.
- Gas would do the job.
I'll pick some up
when I go in town.
I can mail the letters too.
Those dam ned idiots, -
- loading me down
with a whole can.
And in this heat.
Dam m it!
That's what I say about it.
Regulations!
T o hell with them.
You took long enough.
I'm almost finished.
What do you mean, long?
You just can't reason
with those idiots from supply.
I tell them I want a little gas.
They say they haven't got any.
So I had to take a whole can.
That's regulations for you.
H urry up.
I can't take this fiddling
around m uch longer.
We've only been here
two weeks, -
- and in two days
we won't have any more work.
In 2 days
we can twiddle our thumbs.
You are always napping anyway.
Don't be angry.
All work doesn't have to go
so fast.
Here are peaches.
Not peashes, but peaches.
Please take seat.
I'll make my round on the bike.
I'm not the best guard.
There's hardly any goat's m ilk.
So we have to drink
black coffee.
- Aha.
- Aha, what?
I've always said -
- that goat's m ilk is shit;
it tastes like he-goat.
Besides, she doesn't give
any m ilk.
Maybe we should sell her.
Who would buy her?
She's as old as Methuselah.
The founders
probably brought her.
A pity.
I imagined everything
to be so nice.
A goat that gives milk,
hens that lay eggs.
I imagined
a pretty little garden.
But this place
is too dry for that.
Well, Becker, what's up?
Has the goat given any m ilk?
Found any eggs?
No, but there's a strange fellow
outside the gate.
He wants to come in.
Do we know him, or what?
No idea;
he says he's a king.
A king?
He must have a screw loose.
He's well-mannered.
Let's have a look at him.
Although the isolation of
the fortress weighed on them, -
- the appearance of a stranger -
- was felt as a violation of a domain
which had to be defended.
Excuse the disturbance.
I think I'd better leave.
I didn't realize
that soldiers were here.
I hope
that I didn't disturb you.
Would you like to have
some coffee?
No, please don't bother.
I had intended to ask this gentleman
whether I could spend the night here.
I'm a stranger in this country.
There would be room enough.
No, this is military territory.
Actually, we have no objections.
Excuse my curiosity,
but where do you come from?
I'm not sure, but I think
I was born in Portugal.
I'm a gypsy, you know,
and am probably from Portugal.
I was there as a small child.
You say that you're a king?
Does this thing work?
That's nice.
Where did you get it?
I've had it for a long time.
T ell us some more.
This is a rare occasion.
I really am a king.
I became separated
from my tribe as a child.
Since then
I've been searching for them.
I've been
practically everywhere -
in Germany for a long time, -
- in Poland, England, and Spain.
I was in Rumania too.
I'm not ashamed of my poverty;
I can live of it.
Sometimes I do card-tricks.
It is quite difficult
for us gypsies.
What a strange person.
I mean the gypsy.
Do you think he was lying?
Probably.
I didn't believe him.
He's like a paper flower
compared to this one.
Can you make anything
out of that?
It's difficult
for the words run together.
Something's m issing here.
This word is "demos. "
What does "demos" mean?
People.
- "Kyna, " the dog...
Pardon me,
I used the wrong case.
I have the feeling that life's
rather unbalanced here.
Our duty here is as sim ple
as one can imagine.
But keeping watch all night -
And one doesn't sleep
long mornings.
It's really too short.
Why do you always try
to get us to hurry?
We have plenty of time
so we can take things easy.
Look!
A super egg from a super hen.
Could you give me the chalk
for a m inute to try something?
Know how to hypnotize a hen?
You press its head to the ground
and draw a straight line from the bill.
We used to watch
my grandfather do that.
One could also draw a circle.
Then the hen would run in a circle
until it became exhausted.
Ever seen
a caterpillar procession?
There are thousands of caterpillars
creeping through the woods.
If you change the direction
of the first one so it follows the last, -
- then they run in a circle
until they are exhausted.
That would be a new method
to kill insects.
Come here my dear...
What a stupid expression
hens have.
It could hypnotize one.
Hen, who is hypnotizing
whom here?
Watch now!
Ready; set; go!
Isn't that our king?
Ah, you're still here!
This is a friendly place here.
I'd like to stay for a while.
Have you found
any of your clan yet?
You see, I've thought it over.
It could be that your clan
is also looking for you, -
- and since you
are looking for them, -
- you might be going
in circles -
- and might never meet.
I don't run in circles;
others do.
Our people
always changes directions.
That's crazy.
I have a card trick to show you.
Is that a normal pack of cards?
Y es, it's legitimate.
All nines.
There m ust be a trick to it.
You m ust have a second pack
up your sleeve.
Oh, that's a fine collection.
Here is something for you.
That's a souvenir,
a little wooden owl.
You can buy one in any shop.
Look.
The eyes and ears are moving.
Maybe hydro-pressure has something
to do with the movements.
The tail moves too.
Wait, it can be pulled out.
Something is moving inside -
a fly.
The poor things.
There's another one.
Look how it crawls.
It's half dead.
It's terrible
to do such a thing.
He's gone.
People here tell a story
about a submarine -
- that surfaced here
a few days ago.
It happened towards evening.
Some of the crew came up on deck
to get some fresh air.
It was just sunset -
- and they were so im pressed
by the setting sun -
- that they didn't notice
the enemy planes approaching.
Well, some did notice them, -
- and they were able to
escape through the hatch.
They closed the hatch
and submerged.
Three remained on deck
and were drowned.
No, I'm not uneasy.
What's bothering you then?
What are you thinking about?
T ake off your shoes.
Come here quickly, Meinhard!
Where is Stroszek?
He's in the house with Nora.
I have copies of the texts
and even translations of them.
Stroszek,
come here for a m inute.
This is Achmed.
He says he's a Turk,
and as a Turk would normally
pray 5 times a day.
But he only prays
3 times a day now -
- because the children
scoff at him.
He has a printed copy
of the inscription.
About our stone too?
About this one too;
I can read it to you,
if you like.
Don't m ind if it is
only fragmentary.
Much of it is om itted.
"... have shown reverence
to the gods, -
- have offered thanks to the gods,
also the inhabitants of Cos... "
The text begins
right in the m iddle.
It continues like this:
"... for the days are sure;
the merchants sigh no more, -
- and the ports join
in the rejoicing:
- for the seas are safe,
the pirates destroyed.
All the robbers and their chief
have been hanged, -
- even his dog has been hanged. "
I can't make m uch of that.
You've got the wrong idea.
The ancient Greeks
weren't like that.
During the Olym pic games,
they put stones between their knuckles -
- and covered them
with leather straps.
They smashed
their noses to pulp.
How beautiful it is when
the worst of the heat is gone.
Where is Becker?
He's looking
for new inscriptions.
Stop that nonsense.
There aren't any fish there.
You just don't know!
At full moon the whole sea
is full of them.
They're only an inch or so long;
but there are shoals of them.
The whole world
is full of vermin.
What a mood you're in now.
What's wrong?
Is it my fault again?
Is it because of that cock?
It wasn't my fault,
it was the children.
Do you know what kangaroos
look like on Sunday?
I can magnetize a knife.
Watch, ladies and gentlemen.
The greatest show on earth...
The magnetic current has to flow
through the arm into the knife.
It should be a straight wall,
a smooth one.
There, now fold your arms.
The one who holds out longest
is the winner.
On certain days Stroszek
became confused and apathetic.
Now and then he undertook
something with haste,
only to give it up again.
Nora acted prudently;
but he began -
- to withdraw from her
and the others.
Are you a tough one.
But only because you're light.
It's no wonder.
Now I'm only against myself.
One time Stroszek stretched a rope
and tried tight-rope walking.
Meinhard ran for Nora
to stop him.
But he was already on the rope
by the time she arrived.
But she retained her com posure,
and he didn't fall.
What on earth are you doing?
Lighting a cigarette.
Are you mad?
We'll all explode!
Oh, I see.
Give me the ones
that are finished.
I said the finished ones.
All of them.
Now fill them with some powder.
More wool.
I didn't find any sawdust,
but it should work.
What a way to cut that.
Like this you see.
That's how it should be done.
Will that help?
I'm sure that it'll work
like a rocket exploding.
No, not in any case.
I'll show you.
If I fill the rocket with powder
and then wool -
- it won't explode all at once.
It will go gradually,
understand?
Before we proceed
we ought to try one out.
How many do you have?
About 8.
Wait to set them off.
I'll get Nora.
It was Stroszek's idea
to make the fireworks -
- out of the powder taken
from the shells in the depot.
But the others
had to do the work -
- for Stroszek had again lapsed
into passivity.
Thank God that we have something
to keep us busy again.
Now we can try one out.
Give me one of those.
Where are you
going to set it off?
Over this shaft here.
I just hold it like this, light it,
and it will work just fine.
That will blow
your hand to bits.
No problem at all.
Wouldn't it be better to attach
it to a piece of wood?
You're cowards!
Out of the way there.
I won't take any responsibility
for this.
During the night, partisans
had secretly laid out a crown -
- of light stones
on the mountain.
It could be seen
from a distance.
It didn't signify
immediate danger, -
- but it did distinguish
friend and foe.
Now that I can talk,
what shall I say?
Come on in.
I won't disturb you.
Well, then -
Where are you stationed?
Here in the town.
But there is nothing to do
in this place.
I have no official duties.
I can practice all day long.
You're really lucky, aren't you?
But sometimes I have to carry
heavy objects,
and that ruins my hands.
Then I have to start all over again
until my fingers loosen up again.
I'm actually running
after my fingers.
I don't understand much about music,
but you do play well.
That was Chopin.
You may think that the music
is not fitting for this place.
It's different -
- malicious.
Chopin himself was malicious;
he was unpredictable.
The only thing
one could count on -
- was him coughing blood.
Don't you hear it in the music?
What's the matter?
Nothing, nothing at all.
Come on and tell me about it.
Is it anything special?
No, nothing special.
Then tell me what it is.
Well...
no, I do feel at home
in the fortress, -
- and we get on well enough, -
- but I feel closed in somehow,
the walls -
- Y es, I see what you mean.
You know that
we brought you here -
- especially to give you
a chance to recuperate.
Would you like to be sent
on patrol now and then?
That would be nice.
Look, I'll send you
to the southeast ridge tomorrow.
That's not dangerous.
But we have to show up there
again, anyway.
It won't be too m uch
for his knee.
I'll show you which route
to take on the map.
First to the ridge,
then the plateau.
You can be back
by the afternoon.
Wou Id you I ike to dri nk
some water?
Wife, get some water for them!
Dri nk as m uch as you I ike.
You're dri ppi ng with sweat.
Don't you want to rest?
We don't have anything to eat.
Sorry, there's no bread.
You may have
some more water, though.
The little one can hardly talk;
her mother is out
with the sheep, -
and I'm gone most of the night.
Now and then she goes into town
to visit her aunt Maria.
There she learns
to talk a little.
It's beautiful here;
there's water and fresh air.
There are no children here
for her to talk to.
She can hardly talk at all.
Won't you say your song
for them?
Go and say it.
Say it?
Say it from the beginning.
High on the mountain,
lambs are grazing, -
- grazing there in loneliness.
One of them is lost.
Run, shepherds, run!
For over the mountains
are circling...
- "vultures. "
Drink that.
It's good in the heat.
You know that I can't stand
this thin stuff.
The medical officer wants to
exam ine us today at five o'clock.
What?
Our next exam ination
wasn't scheduled for two weeks.
Don't ask me why.
They do as they please with us.
Did you know that they are
thinking of sending you home?
Why me?
Because of yesterday
on the mountain.
So, you squealed on me!
Adm it that you squealed on me,
you swine!
Sit down, Stroszek,
and go on eating.
Don't touch me.
It's better like this.
He and Nora saw the captain.
Nora, out of the way!
Get away, get out of here!
I don't see anything.
The shooting m ust be com ing
from the houses.
Stroszek has gone mad.
He shot at us.
It was just like the last time.
He had another fit.
Did you disarm him?
It was impossible;
he had a gun.
It's not partisans.
One of our men on the fortress
has gone berserk.
Stand by.
No, we don't need
any road blocks.
Alright,
send a platoon over here.
We may even have to move the H Q.
The entrance is exposed.
Who would ever
have imagined this?
Send out some sentries;
but don't alarm him.
I think his wife can lure him
out in an hour or so.
Away, go away.
Come down from here.
I promise nothing
will happen to you.
I don't follow orders anymore.
I've taken up the cause of man.
One has to keep something, -
- plants.
Their names:
wheat, barley, poppies.
Come down im mediately, Stroszek.
That's an official order.
Go away you swine!
I'm going to blow up
the whole works.
That was a m istake.
We should have taken
stricter measures.
Now he's worse and doesn't
expose himself at all.
We can't get snipers
close enough -
- because he m ight see them
and blow up the am mo.
What do you think doctor:
is there a chance
he m ight return to normal?
It's difficult to say.
What you want is a prognosis, -
- but with the information
I have,
I can't even make a diagnosis.
We don't know the extent
of his injury.
We don't have
the hospital report.
And we know nothing about his
background and circumstances -
- which led
to his present state.
Still, we can reckon that he
m ight come back to normal soon.
Just like yesterday,
after his fit.
But I wouldn't count
on a rapid rem ission.
I would suggest that we listen
to what Stroszek has to say, -
- and how he behaves and acts.
Then we m ight be able to understand
what is really the matter with him.
How should we act towards him?
With extreme caution,
in any case.
One m ust bear in m ind
that a person in his state -
- is capable
of almost anything, -
- even of executing
com plex actions.
If you provoke him, he m ight
very well blow up the depot -
- And from
the technical standpoint -
- does he have
the technical capability?
Y es.
I'm afraid he does.
If he is ready,
it could go up now.
It only takes a few grenades.
What could be
the force of the blast?
I'm not through with
my calculations.
There are 5 or 6 tons of TNT, -
- if all of
the hydro-m ines detonate.
The other am mo
is not so dangerous.
But that is enough to endanger
whole sections of the town.
The damage would be
so extensive -
- as to endanger the surrounding
houses from falling debris.
Then we have to evacuate
the other buildings.
It's what I anticipated.
Mr. Vassiliou, we have summoned you
as a civilian representative.
I hope you understand
this measure.
Do you understand me?
Y es, of course.
It's difficult to move people.
There's no place to put them.
The German's take up
too m uch space.
He asks if anything
can be done to help.
There's not m uch to eat, -
- and the boats can't be unloaded
since they can't leave the harbor.
The ships can't leave
the harbor anymore?
There's not m uch we can do now.
At least not before dusk.
If he remains quiet,
we can wait for one more night.
He'll return to normal soon,
maybe tomorrow.
He has to sleep or at least
relax his attention.
We can discuss
the evacuation separately.
The people in question will probably
have to leave their goods behind, -
- in order to facilitate it.
Stroszek repeatedly threatened
to blow the am mo -
- as soon as anyone came close.
He said he would blow up
the whole place, -
- and make the earth shake.
Then people would see what was
at the bottom of everything.
He wanted to make
this revelation.
After this, the evacuation
measures were accelerated.
Don't be sad.
If you are sad, we are too.
I haven't seen my kids
for 10 years.
I work every day,
and it is not easy.
That's I ife for you.
M uch happens
i n the course of I ife.
Come to us when you are down.
We can sit and talk.
Stroszek didn't expose himself
and held the fortress against everyone.
He was almost invulnerable.
He challenged friend and foe
to battle, -
- but no one accepted
his challenge.
He declared war on everyone
in a furious protest.
He even rebelled against
the orbit of the sun at dawn.
He screamed that one could only
encounter light with light.
Did everything go alright?
There weren't any incidents at all.
Such an action
is always unpopular.
What is Stroszek doing now?
T ake the rest of the guns
and files along too.
He's been restless.
Maybe he fears an attack.
He's still threatening
to blow the place up.
Look at this rag here.
Exactly like this here, a rag...
What is that?
He failed to set the sun on fire, -
- just as the town at which he
aimed his rockets remained unscathed.
He only managed to kill a donkey
the day before.
Now he had to be content
with a scorched chair.
Since no one accepted
his challenge,
Stroszek began to insult
the town.
A town
of im maculate virginity, -
- just waiting for someone
to bom bard it.
That's what every town
waits for.
It was her fault that things
turned out unsatisfactory.
We won't shoot at him.
The danger of him setting fire
to the am mo would be too great.
The best chance to catch him is
while he's setting off the rockets.
He said that he was going to
set off some more soon.
Y es, he still has many of the...
how do you say...?
You mean rockets?
Fireworks?
Y es, rockets.
He surely has a lot left,
because we made many of them.
If he does set off some more -
- we could certainly
overpower him, -
- for he sets off the rockets
near the battlement.
And that's far-removed
from the am mo.
He'll be so busy
with the rockets -
- that my men can scale the wall
at various points sim ultaneously, -
- particularly at dark.
T ake up your positions at 6 o'clock
when you are given the sign.
But wait to act at the moment -
- when the first rocket goes up.
There'll be
more fireworks today.
Men, the most im portant thing -
- is to scale
the wall quickly, -
- and at all three points.
You will receive equipment for it, -
- ropes, ladders, hooks,
and teargas.
Stroszek cried that they could
do nothing to him, no one could, -
- for he had now found
his calling.
At 10 years of age, he was already
catching trout with his bare hands -
- when the other boys
were still wetting their pants.
During the night when Stroszek
again started another firework display, -
- he was overpowered
by his own men.
He didn't make it to the depot,
for he was already surrounded.
In his rebellion he had
undertaken something titanic -
- for the enemy
was far superior.
Thus he had failed as miserably
as all others of his kind.