In the 16th century,
Martin Luther appeared.
He criticized the Roman Church,
savagely attacking the
Church and clergy.
The resultant break of
the protestants produced...
...a serious religious
crisis in Europe.
In 1534, in Spain, Loyola
founded the Society of Jesus.
It reflected the crisis
in Catholicism.
They fought to rebuild
the Church...
...and widened their work
beyond Europe.
In 1549, along with the gun,
Francisco Xavier landed on
the southern shores of Japan.
30 years later, more
than 200 churches,
75 priests and 300.000
believers appeared.
Japan's rulers were
worried about the new
religion's rapid spread,
since it came with the gun.
Both examples of
Western culture...
...put fear into the hearts
of the rulers.
Suppression!
The latter half of
the 16th century was...
...a bitter time for
Japan's Christians.
Countless Padres and
believers were killed.
Some disappeared.
Padre Ferreira also disappeared.
CHINMOKU
Story by Shusaku Endo
Screenplay by Shusaku Endo
and Masahiro Shinoda
Photographed by
Kazuo Miyagawa
Music by Toru Takemitsu
Starring
David Lampson
Mako Iwamatsu
Don Kenny
Tetsuro Tamba
Yoshiko Mita
Shima Iwashita
Directed by
Masahiro Shinoda
Padre...
In Macao, you promised
to pay me...
...as soon as we reached
Japan, with some extra.
Remember?
I've wanted to ask you...
Are you a Christian, Kichijiro?
Are you really Japanese?
Of course.
I am Japanese.
If the officials come,
you don't know me.
Don't forget.
We understand.
Be sure. I'm going now.
Padre! Padre!
Padre! Our hearts are
the same as yours.
You must change into
these quickly.
You must not be seen.
Please hurry!
Padre!
Shut the door!
Rest here tonight.
At dawn we'll take you
to the mountains.
You'll be safe here.
No one comes here.
Are there no priests?
No monks?
No priests or monks
have come for years.
If we were caught,
all would be killed.
We only trust our own village.
Strangers would turn us in
right away.
What about prayers?
Baptism and teaching?
We do it all.
We do the best we can,
each taking a part.
We've hid and kept on
for all these years.
The Padres and monks all
left us. They went away.
That sound?
It's rain.
The rainy season has
started and it's long.
"Let's be on our way
"To a temple in heaven.
"It is called the
Temple of Paradise.
"It is known as
the great temple.
"That temple exists
in our hearts."
Please listen to me.
Does anybody know where
Padre Ferreira has gone?
He came to Japan
twenty years ago.
And he preached here.
He went to the capital
and to Edo.
We know only he was
captured five years ago.
Since that, nothing.
Has anybody here heard
anything about him?
In Portugal, when Garrpe
and I were children,
he taught us about the lord.
We decided to come here
to teach...
Padre Ferreira's teachings.
So we want to know
what has happened:
Whether he is alive
or has died bravely...
...and gone on to Paradise.
Do you know anything?
How about you?
We warned you.
You must never go outside.
Don't be angry. We just
wanted a little sun.
Never go out of here again!
Get in here
if something happens.
Please open the door.
Don't be afraid.
We, fishermen, haven't
seen a Padre for years.
Won't you trust us?
Five days ago...
We watched you from
the other mountain.
We heard Padres were
in Tomogi Village.
From who?
From Kichijiro, a
Christian among us.
Yes, Padre.
But is he a Christian?
He surely is a Christian.
Eight years ago a man
reported his family.
They were told to
step on a medallion.
The Lord's image was
carved on it.
The fumi-e?
His brother and sister refused.
But Kichijiro was terrified.
He said he'd give up the faith.
His brother and sister
were burned alive...
...at the stake, the very next day.
And Kichijiro disappeared.
And he showed up again?
And told about us?
He's boasting he brought
Padres to Japan.
He's popular in our village.
We don't have Mass
or Confessions.
We just say our prayers.
Come to us, Padre!
Please come.
That day the wind
was very strong.
They were thrown into
the crater of a volcano.
The place was called
Hell Valley of Mt. Unzen.
Fathers Ludovico.
Johann. Antonio...
Julian, Marta, Michael...
Thomas, and Ignatius.
I remember it all very well.
The pagans cheered
as each one fell.
Uneme Takenaka was
a real demon.
And Matsukura, too.
They caught Fathers
Dominico and John.
Their hands were tied
behind them.
Straw mats were wrapped
about them and set afire.
As the fire spread, they
began to hop around.
The pagans laughed
at the mat dancers.
They enjoyed it.
And things have gotten worse.
Being a Christian is even
more difficult today.
And Magistrate Inoue
is all to blame.
He's the king of the demons.
The leader of the demons.
The islanders were very
happy to see you.
They waited a long time
for a Padre to come.
Girls even smile at me
since I brought you.
Listen to me.
I know what you want to say.
But I've reformed.
So I'm showing you around.
Why did you say you'd
give up the faith?
Just a momentary confusion.
I don't feel that way now.
Can you swear that to me?
That you'll keep the faith
under any pressure?
I swear!
So please forgive
what I've done.
But, Padre, you don't know
how they torture us.
That's why you're so angry now.
Some people are strong;
others are weak.
The strong bear up
and go to heaven.
But a weak man like me...
Padre!
The officials!
In the village?
They've found us.
Us, too?
They don't know about you.
Garrpe?
I'll take you to him.
No time for talk!
It's been reported that
there are Christians.
Now give me their names.
For 100 pieces of silver.
Take him!
We'll take him as hostage
till you talk!
We'll come back in three
days for more hostages.
Think it over.
We didn't tell them
about you Padres.
And we never will.
No matter what!
But that means you'll
all be taken hostage.
Yes, but we still won't talk.
Rather than that, we
should leave Tomogi.
We'll go to Kichijiro's island.
But since they came here,
they'll go there, too.
Go farther away.
I'd like to go along,
but it's dangerous.
Since you still say no,
we must believe you.
But we must find out
who is lying.
You all or the informer.
The hostages will then return.
Today we must take three
more to Nagasaki.
We won't harm them.
Those three are...
You... you...
And you!
The magistrate will see
you're not Christians.
Then I'll send all
of you back here.
You know Christianity
is heresy, don't you?
It was reported that
you believe that heresy.
How do you plead?
We always pay our taxes.
We have Buddhist funerals.
Then you claim you are
really not Christians?
Yes, sir.
Well, that makes the
Magistrate happy.
Do you know what this is?
A Christian carving.
Exactly.
It's Virgin Mary
whom they praise.
But it has no value to
you non-Christians.
Step on it!
You must step on this!
What's wrong?
Non-Christians should
not mind stepping on it.
So you think you've fooled us?
I saw your heavy breathing.
You're wrong.
We're not Christians.
Then spit on this!
And say Virgin Mary is a whore!
No?
How about you?
And how about you?
Spit!
We hear you!
"Let us be on our way
"To a temple in heaven.
"It is called the
Temple of Paradise."
Padre!
Been a long time!
Don't go alone.
The officials are
on this island, too.
Eat it!
We use these snakes
for medicine.
Is there a river?
You want some water?
You sure gobbled that
dried fish down.
Isn't there a river? A river...
Padre!
Why did you run off?
Don't you trust me?
Don't feel bad.
I'm just very tired.
Won't you just leave me alone?
Alone? What for?
I know a village with
Christians and Padres.
Padres?
And they're not
Japanese priests.
Padre, you don't
trust me anymore.
Mokichi was strong,
like a paddy we plant.
But a weak paddy stays weak
no matter what.
I was born weak, Padre,
like this paddy.
Kichijiro, kneel!
Our Lord was crucified.
Our Lord was crowned
with thorns.
Padre, forgive me!
Forgive me!
I'm weak, not strong
like Mokichi or Ichizo.
Here they come!
Look how big he is!
Nagasaki Magistrate sent us...
...to take custody of
Padre Rodrigues.
Thanks for your trouble.
I can speak Japanese.
Then I don't need to use
the foreign tongue.
I learned it at seminary.
I went to seminary, but
I'm not a Christian.
Why did you study then?
To succeed in life.
A samurai can take up
arms or education.
I chose education.
You knew Christianity is heresy.
Still you came. Why?
I'm ready for martyrdom.
Blind bravery like yours
is a bother to others.
Christianity is like
an unwelcome gift...
...that is forced on the receiver.
We have our own religion.
We don't need yours.
Things taught to us at
seminary are useless.
Silly bickering!
Bickering?
Change!
They're clean.
They're Buddhist priest's
sacred garments.
I don't need them.
Change quickly.
The officials are coming.
It's a Padre! I didn't know
we had a Padre here.
I've been here for
five days. Have you...
He speaks Japanese well.
It's amazing.
You mustn't talk.
Lord Chikugo is
concerned about you.
Be comfortable.
Rodrigues from Portugal.
Came from Macao.
Is that right?
We are moved by
your determination...
...in traveling the great
distance to our shores.
You must have suffered.
We are sorry to have to
give you more trouble.
Your beliefs are all right.
They are valid...
...in Spain, Portugal and
other Western countries.
But we ban Christianity
here because...
...it's of no value to Japan.
Truth should be universal.
Why else would we teach it?
If it's not truth in Japan...
...then neither is it truth
anywhere else.
AII Padres say that.
But even a tree chooses
its place to grow.
Christianity may grow
in other lands, but...
...not here in Japan.
Have you ever thought of that?
It should grow and bloom here!
It was well known
even in Europe...
...how Padres were activated
in Japan.
When permission
was given here,
the believers numbered
three hundred thousand.
If Christianity
doesn't grow here,
it is due to lack of cultivation.
Why do we talk this way?
My words won't be able
to change your minds.
Neither can yours change mine.
No matter what I say,
I will be executed.
We don't execute you
without reason.
That's not Inoue's way.
He would do so immediately.
Why do you laugh?
That is Inoue, Lord of
Chikugo, sitting there.
It's 300 mon.
What is?
You want to have me, don't you?
You're funny.
Where are you from?
Why ask that?
It doesn't matter
where one is from.
Are you crying?
No!
Whatever it is, just forget it.
Such painful things
aren't easy to forget.
You go as low as you can,
and nothing is shocking.
You aren't near as far
down as I am.
What did you do, kill somebody?
I did something worse!
You want me or not?
You have money?
Money? Sure I've got some.
Did you steal it?
I sold for it.
Fine! Nobody enjoys
taking stolen money.
Hurry up!
What's wrong?
Spit in my face!
You're really weird!
What do you mean?
If you spit on me,
I'll give you all my money.
Or I can't forgive myself.
Spit on me!
You must be bored, but
you'll see something.
You'll be interested.
Sanemon Okada and Kiku!
Your last chance!
I ask you again:
Will you not apostatize?
And you?
Hey, you! What are you
doing here?
Get away from here!
Don't loiter here!
Sanemon Okada,
do you still refuse?
They're coming for us
from Paradise.
It won't be long.
Padre, please listen!
I want to confess!
Oh, Padre! Padre!
I have deceived you.
Won't you listen?
You made fun of me.
So I hated you and the believers.
I stepped on the fumi-e. I did!
Mokichi and Ichizo were
strong, but I'm not.
Are you drunk?!
What should a weak man
like me do?
I didn't betray you
for the money.
Because they threatened me.
Get out!
Padre, listen!
I couldn't help it!
Get out!
I'm a Christian!
Throw me in jail!
Padres! Listen to my confession!
I want to repent and
start all over again.
Please, listen, Padre!
I apostatized.
But if I had been born sooner...
I'd have lived and died
a good Christian.
But I was born when
Christianity is banned.
How I regret it!
Been a long time.
I've been to Hirado.
You should visit
there sometimes.
It has a castle and
faces a peaceful bay.
I heard in Macao that
it is a beautiful town.
Not beautiful, but
most interesting.
I heard an interesting
story there.
Lord of Hirado once had
four concubines.
Concubines?
The four women always
fought each other.
The lord was troubled.
What do you think he did?
I don't know.
He threw all of them out.
Are you not interested
in a story about women?
I'm glad to know
you agree with him.
Don't you think Japan is
in the same position?
Spain, Portugal,
Holland, England...
They fight for Japan's
favor like women.
If you think the lord was wise,
you must understand why
Japan bans Christianity.
We believe a man should
have one wife.
And a married man must
get rid of other women.
Japan too should choose
his wife out of the four.
You mean it should be Portugal?
But, Padre...
Why should Japan choose
a foreigner?
A woman of his country
is best suited for him.
A woman's heart is
more important...
...than her nationality.
But if it were only
the heart that matters...
...there'd be no infidelity.
The love of an unwanted woman...
...is most troublesome to any man.
And such a marriage will
produce no offspring.
And she is barren.
If she's barren, it's not
the fault of the Church.
It is the fault of you
and your people...
...who try to separate the
believers from the Church.
It seems you don't know
Japan very well, Padre.
And it seems you don't
know Christianity well.
Thirty years ago, I too
was taught by Padres.
Still I have to forbid it.
I have my own reason.
It's not that I think
it is heresy.
Do it quickly.
Your heart is free.
It is only a formality.
It will not harm your beliefs.
Step on it, and your
troubles are over.
A samurai Christian!
Who cares about him?
Stop! Please stop!
Apostatize!
If you do, we'll stop the horse.
You mustn't, Kiku! You mustn't!
Don't look at me!
Get a hold of yourself.
Don't step on it!
Pull him out!
Kiku!
I apostatize too!
Listen to me!
Give me a fumi-e!
Take him away!
I apostatize!
Think carefully!
The sooner you step on it,
the sooner you get out.
I tell you again.
It is just a formality.
It won't hurt your beliefs.
You want the horse's hoofs, too?
I'll step on it!
Get out.
Get up!
You're leaving.
Where is everyone?
At the Magistrate's.
You're going to see a man.
He'll be here.
The Magistrate's order.
Do you know who?
Really?
Can you guess what's next?
The Magistrate says that
if Garrpe apostatizes,
the farmers will be set free.
You see, Padre.
We're not after a few
nameless people.
Many Christian farmers are
hiding all over Japan.
If you Padres apostatize,
they'll be saved, too.
You force your own dreams
on us thoughtlessly.
You never think of the
blood that must be shed.
Like those innocent farmers.
Garrpe was pure.
But you're just a coward.
Not a "Padre".
Your name?
It was Monica, but
it isn't any longer.
How will you live on?
I don't know.
What would you do,
if you were me, Padre?
You did all you could.
The Lord will forgive you.
There are no gods or Buddhas.
There is nothing at all anymore.
Did you hear? Another body
was found on the beach.
It was a Christian
woman all tied up.
How cruel!
The officials dumped her.
Even under treatment like that,
they believe in their God.
How pitiful!
They are idiots!
Duped by Padres!
They asked for it.
Are you crying?
No!
Drink! Why the tears?
Were you a Christian before?
No!
I don't care, whether
you are or not.
Where are you from?
What's it to you?
Sold, weren't you?
Yes, during the drought.
It was the only way
we could eat then.
Want to see your folks?
What for? Silly!
Any brothers?
Yes, a little one about this big.
I wonder how he's getting along.
It's a tough world!
Really tough! Too tough!
Do you know who you're to see?
The Magistrate thinks
it's time you see him.
Mr. Inoue?
Right. And the man
wants to see you too.
Don't call him Ferreira.
He has taken a Japanese
name: Chuan Sawano.
Right, Sawano?
He is working on another book.
It tells of the errors in
Christian teachings.
The title is
"Falsehoods Revealed."
I'm useful here.
I help the people of Japan.
I introduced astronomy.
I got telescopes from
a Dutch ship's captain.
I am of use here
in this country.
Sawano, we didn't bring
Rodrigues here...
...for long discussions.
Give him the old
priest's message.
They told me to urge you
to apostatize.
Look at this.
He was tied up.
He was hung by the ankles.
They cut holes behind his ears.
His blood trickled out
and kept him alive.
It was an idea of
Magistrate Inoue's.
I preached in this nation
for twenty years.
I know Japan better than you.
Our religion does not
take root here.
This country is a swamp.
You will learn that.
A swamp more terrible
than we considered.
A swamp where any
seedling planted rots.
The leaves wither
and the plant dies.
We sowed the seeds of
Christianity in it.
That is not our God.
It is not our God, but
their own gods...
...that the people of this
country believe in.
We didn't realize that
for a very long time.
Maybe you know...
The farmers worship
the Kannon as Mary.
They love that pagan
figure more...
...than the teachings of our Lord.
Probably no one will
believe what I say.
Not only you, but no one
in all Christendom...
Neither will our friends
in Macao and Rome.
The saint never noticed the fact.
He taught them about Zeus.
The Japanese changed it
into their own sun god.
They call it Dainichi,
and it became their god.
They bend and change our
God into something else...
Something quite different.
That is all.
Has anyone come to save you?
Jeers from all sides.
No one needs you!
Come on, just say you apostatize.
And you'll never go back there.
To the Magistrate's.
I don't want you to suffer.
Just apostatize!
Get out of here!
I'm a Christian.
I'll beat you!
Who's there?
A crazy one.
He says he's a Christian.
Padre, forgive me!
I came to confess.
Please forgive me!
Get out!
Well, are you frightened?
Stop being stubborn.
Take the easy way.
Sawano, he thinks
that's snoring.
You must tell him
what it really is.
That is not snoring.
It is the voices of
believers in the pit.
You were brought up
immediately, but...
...they've been there
for six hours already.
Listen to me.
Somewhere on that wall
I carved some letters.
"LAUDATE EUM."
It should be on the wall
to the right...
Near the post...
Try to touch it.
I heard the voices here
as you do now.
I did not apostatize
because I was hung.
I was hung upside down
in the pit for two days.
But I did not speak
a word against God.
I apostatized because
God had done nothing.
I prayed desperately,
but He did nothing.
He kept silent.
Pray as you like.
Those believers are
suffering terribly...
Harder than you can
ever imagine.
They hung all day yesterday.
Today, too.
Why do they have to suffer?
You can do nothing for them.
God, either.
The night I was here,
five hung in that pit.
Their voices came in
together with the wind.
The official said...
"If you apostatize,
they will be pulled out.
"They will get medical
treatment too."
Sawano, is he ready
for the fumi-e?
It's a mere formality.
Christianity is a
forbidden heresy.
Today three ships entered
Nagasaki Harbor.
They were loaded with silks,
other cloths and
two boxes of jars.
We found these in the
cargo of one of them.
Are these forbidden
Christian objects?
The Magistrate has ordered
you investigate these.
This is not a Christian object.
What do you think?
I'm of the same opinion
as Mr. Sawano's.
The Christian chalice
looks different here.
Are you sure?
Yes, sir.
Thanks for your advice.
You're dismissed.
From this day forward,
Sebastian Rodrigues...
received the name
Sanemon Okada.