Amen.
Have some cereal.
Pass the bread, Dad.
No banana today?
Pass the milk, please, Alfredo.
Well done, Anita!
You've spilled the milk again.
It doesn't matter.
Open your mouth like this...
Esther, I'm going to the garage now
to pick up the crankshaft for the tractor.
Yes, Johan. We're going out now, too.
Okay, let's all get moving.
Hand me the dishes, children.
Help me arrange the table.
Don't leave any leftovers, Dani and Anita!
Thank you, Sara.
Come on, children. We have to go.
Come, children!
Come on, Jak!
-Where's my hat?
-Right here.
Come on, children.
Sara, head along with the children.
Stay on your own for a while, Johan.
I love you, Esther.
I know, Johan.
I love you, too.
Raubart!
Raubart! Raubart!
You're a good dog...
Good dog.
Zacarias!
Hold on, he's fixing an engine block!
Hold on, Johan, damn it!
Are you in a bloody hurry, or what?
Yeah, man, a bloody hurry...
All right, Juanito, your damn crank is all ready.
-Hold it, don't let it fall.
-It's very heavy.
Watch your fingers!
Don't want them to get hurt.
One...
Two...
Three!
What did the guy on the phone want?
He wants us to fix the engine.
-What's wrong with it?
-It's completely busted.
We'll have to replace everything.
Pistons, suspension,
timing belt, crankshaft, and
redo the valves,
the head needs new spark plugs...
Did they get bent, or what?
We have to change them, anyway.
They're all elongated.
And the hoses don't work, either.
We have to do an overall cleaning of the engine.
The man on the phone wants
a plutonium exhaust. Can we do that?
Yes, right now. Get to work!
And move it!
Come on, move it!
What can't be done today
will be done tomorrow.
I thought you stopped seeing her.
Me, too.
But the days go by, and before I know it...
And the pain won't stop digging in.
A powerful thing's come over you.
You've found your natural woman.
Very few know what that means.
You'll have to carry on.
I'd hurt my wife so...
You know how I've loved her.
Just talking about it feels like lead
being poured into my guts.
If that is your destiny,
then you'll have to be brave.
A brave man makes destiny
with what he's got.
Plus, I have a woman
and I have a family, and...
My woman is called Esther, Zacarias.
It's only for you to decide,
but be careful not to betray yourself.
It's true that Marianne
is a better woman for me.
At least that's my feeling.
And that feeling may be founded
in something sacred,
even if we don't understand it.
Turn that thing up!
-The swine's on for a good lay, huh?
-Yeah!
Let me help you.
You can go in the water now.
Come, Autghe!
The water is warm.
A little cold.
Alfredo, send me one of the children for a wash!
You go, Anita.
Time for a wash!
-Right now?
-Yes, now.
Press on my toe.
I'm going to hold onto you.
Come, Anita, let's get the soap off him!
Come and help me.
Wait a moment.
You help me, too.
-Enough!
-Enough?
Yes.
Wait, there's more here.
Come, the foam is gone.
I've got water in my nose.
-Come here! Get in the water.
-No.
I want to get out.
-Hold on.
-No, I'm going!
What a wimp!
Do it softer, Mummy!
-Dad, can I go see Cornelio?
-Yes, but don't wake him up, Anita.
You've always been so good
at making the soap, Esther.
Finished, Autghe, go into the water.
Come, Esther,
let's go swim.
Be careful.
Someone has arrived.
I'll go see.
-Hello, Mother.
-Good morning, Son.
-I need to talk to Dad.
-Go in, he's milking the cows.
Thanks, see you in a while.
Good day.
Good day, Johan.
I need to talk to you.
So early?
I fell in love with another woman.
You're joking, Johan.
Well, let's go out.
Come, let's go see the snow.
Planting will be delayed this season, Johan.
Soon it will be two years.
Does Esther know about it, Johan?
I've told her everything since the beginning.
I don't want Mother...
I don't want Mother to know about this.
Don't worry.
This is only between us.
Let's go in the house, Johan.
I'll send Mother off to do something.
Yes, Dad.
What's happening to you
is the work of the enemy, Johan.
Talk to me like a father, not like a preacher.
I am both, Johan.
I think it's God's doing.
Dad, if this is the work of the Devil,
I feel sorry for myself. Truly!
But now I have to know
who's the woman I must love.
Help me if you can.
I can only tell you what I went through...
And I've never told anyone.
After your birth,
I felt an unknown attraction to another woman.
I was ready to leave my family.
But before doing that,
I forced myself to stop seeing her.
Soon enough,
I realised the excitement existed only in myself.
It was my need to feel.
You suffer, because you think the pain
of losing her will never pass...
But it will, Son.
That's true, Dad.
But when I compare the two women,
I don't ask myself what I feel for Esther now.
I think of her when I met her...
Then I realise I'd have preferred the new woman.
I simply made a mistake with Esther,
and now I have to fix it.
Esther is your wife.
She loves you as your mother loves me,
and I know how you love her, too.
You love the new woman.
It's inexplicable, but I understand.
I wouldn't like to be in your shoes, dear Johan,
but somehow, I also envy you.
I can't tell you what to do,
but I know if you don't act quickly,
you will lose them both.
Yes, Dad.
Your mother and I will support you.
-Hello.
-Hello, Sara.
-Thank you, Mum.
-You're welcome, Johan.
Goodbye, Dad.
Goodbye, Johan.
-Hi, Johan.
-Hi. What's for lunch?
-Tacos. Yes.
-Tacos! Tacos again?
Well, we sure had a good corn harvest.
There's nothing I like more.
-I'm hungry!
-Let's say grace.
Amen.
-Let me see who's there.
-Okay, Johan.
It was on Marianne's behalf.
I have to go to her business
to bring her two urgent deliveries.
Then you can take the children
to the dentist in Blumenau.
-Is that where Uncle Abraham lives?
-Yes, Alfredo.
This year only these two have been, Johan.
-Really?
-Yes. Really, Johan.
Then I'll take them, Esther.
-I brought what you asked for, Marianne.
-Fine, Johan.
Daddy, will you buy me
two of these little beads?
Shall we go to my office
and prepare the invoice?
-I want Dad to buy me some of these sweets.
-Me, too.
-Pardon me.
-Please.
I think it's a swell idea, Marianne.
-Pardon me.
-Please.
Lie down.
I can feel your heart.
This was the last time, Johan.
Peace is stronger than love.
Poor Esther.
Let me get up.
Are you ready?
I'm afraid there's more pain yet to come,
but then there will be
peace,
and afterwards, a happiness
like we've never known.
This is the saddest time of my life, Johan,
but also the best.
I don't regret anything.
We're very fortunate, my love.
Me, neither.
I smell of sex.
What's that on the floor, there?
A leaf.
-A cedar leaf?
-Yes, red cedar.
We shouldn't have left the kids with that fatso.
That fatso is a good man.
Besides, they're in the restaurant
with more people.
I'd rather go down now.
You're the best man I've ever known.
I don't know how I'll live without you.
Where are my children?
They're with Bobby in his van.
Hello, Dad, come in to watch TV with us.
Come on, make room for Daddy.
Alfredo, pass me a banana.
Sara, take good care of the children.
And you, children, obey your sister
while we're gone.
Yes, Mummy.
And don't forget your prayers.
-Right, Jak?
-Yes, Dad.
Dad...
We have to fix the leak in the barn.
We'll do that tomorrow
when Mum and I are back, Alfredo.
You'll have the whole day
to play where you want.
We're going to behave very well, Dad.
I love you, Daddy. Mummy, too.
Who can that be?
You go, Alfredo.
Dad, it's for you.
-Finished your breakfast, Cornelio?
-No.
Let's go in there. To the room.
To the room.
Who came to the house, Johan?
I don't know. A stranger.
It was on behalf of Marianne.
She needs to see me.
Damn whore!
It's very hard for her also, Esther.
What's the matter, Johan?
I've seen her again.
I've tried with all my might
but I've failed.
Poor Marianne.
Remember when we loved travelling like this?
We wouldn't stop singing.
We were always happy.
Or just remained silent,
or I would fall asleep.
However it was, just being next to you
was the pure feeling of being alive.
I was part of the world.
Now, I am separated from it.
I feel the same.
How I wished it was all just a bad dream...
To close and open my eyes
and be back in that time...
In that feeling.
That idiot's going to kill someone.
Sure, Johan.
My chest is hurting.
We're almost there, Esther.
Stop the car, Johan. I want to vomit.
Calm down, love. See how it's raining.
Stop the car.
Stop the car!
Don't follow me, Johan.
I'm cold, Johan.
Good afternoon!
-What's wrong with them?
-Let's go see.
Come with us.
Get up, get up!
-He's very stiff.
-Get up! Get up!
Tell me what happened.
What's wrong with your wife?
Did you crash? What's wrong?
My name is Juan.
She's my wife.
Her name is Esther.
Johannes Voth!
-Shall I wait in the office, Doctor?
-Yes, please.
Your wife suffered a coronary trauma.
That was the cause of her death.
And what is that?
It's a massive attack of the heart.
Why did that happen to her?
She might have been very tired,
it could be obesity,
alcoholism...
Medical science hasn't got all the answers.
Thank you, Doctor.
I will sign the paperwork
so you can take her now.
Thank you.
Saint John, verse XV, page 726.
Johan, you may seal in my daughter now.
Pull it tight.
Get in your places.
Cornelio, say goodbye to your sister.
You have to do it from this side.
Johan, come on, stand up.
Stand up.
Stand up now!
Goodbye, Esther.
Alfredo, your turn.
Goodbye, Mum.
Now leave us alone, please.
Johan, she's in peace now.
Now everything's broken, Dad.
The enemy is implacable.
It's not the Devil or anyone else. It's me.
Johan.
You are nothing in the face of this, Johan.
It was all written beforehand.
My dearest friend.
Good day, Zacarias.
Come with me outside.
Wait for me!
Can you move your ears like this?
Without the hat?
Stare at them.
And how about this?
Daddy, is being dead like sleeping,
but without waking up?
-Who told you that?
-Grandmother Ruth.
It's the truth, Anita.
Don't cry, Dad.
Follow me, Marianne.
I'd give anything to turn back time...
Go back to things as they used to be.
That's the only thing in life
that we cannot do, Johan.
I'd like to see Esther once before she's buried.
Good afternoon.
Poor Johan.
Johan will be all right now.
Thank you, Marianne.
Dad sent us to see how you're doing.
We're fine.
Come here and say hello to Mummy.
-Hello, Mummy.
Hello, Autghe.
Hello, Anita.
Dad, Mum has woken up!
Don't bother him, Anita.
Be strong, brother.
Come on, Dad, come on!
Mum wants to see you.
Come, come, come.
Come on, Dad, come on!
That's enough, Anita!
Let's go, Dad. Come on!
Come on, Dad, come on, Dad...
Go with her, Johan.
...and Grandpa helped us get dressed
this morning,
and Grandma did my hair Sunday style.
The grandparents brought us here.
They're out there, waiting for you.
And Jackob also came, and Anita.
They're all out there.
Greth didn't dress up.
Uncle Jak came, too, and Aunt Maria.
And the other Aunt Greth, and
our cousins from the north.