Remembering:
Like pure gold.
A plentiful year, Matias.
There will be others.
Plenty, like the moon,
wanes when it's not waxing.
You're tempting providence.
May be, may be...
But in serving you, Sir,
it's not my own good I'm after.
I thought it was.
Have you seen Master Paio lately?
The story goes that this year he
doubled his yield of wine and grain.
Doubled it?
That's ploughed land for you.
Sow, and up comes the wheat.
What rich fare
for an old man's eyes!
A father's eyes see no evil.
That's many winters
under the belt.
And each one frostier.
Well, my Lord, an old wolf
does better in the sheep pen.
May be, Matias, but he only
scares the she-lamb away.
What a lovely lass she is.
- Our joy, Sir.
- A joy without a doubt.
She's stretched this summer.
There's none like her in these parts.
None at all, Matias.
There's no other treasure
like her.
Lovely enough to tempt the Devil.
To cuckold him too.
It's a crying shame
not to make a fitting marriage.
The moment is ripe.
I've always heard it said
that praise without marriage
makes the maiden wilt.
It's not just any tooth
that will bite into my Sílvia.
You have to be married, my child.
Master Paio de Ayres
will be fitting for you.
He's rich, very rich,
and feeble-minded.
Perhaps settling
into this new estate
will not displease you.
But if it does,
you will always
be right and stronger
in your will and thinking.
I doubt not the honor
of your bearing,
then, more than to your husband,
you will be faithful
to these old bones.
It will be fine pig-sticking
this year.
The hog is born aloft
like a processional saint.
- And all strussed up.
- Like a sausage.
A sausage, and a well-filled one.
Look at the fat dripping out.
I'd say he's purple and puffed
out like a wineskin.
What a freak!
So many hefty fellows
to accompany a sack of farts.
He's here.
Welcome to what is your home.
Rest from the journey
that from your appearance
must have been a long one.
The partridges I gnawed on to while
away the journey did me no good.
I stopped and I had a crap.
Now I'm better.
Beautiful woods and gentle
little oak trees you have here.
Sweat of my brow, my son.
Now sup after such a heavy trip.
Not forgetting the ham
that will pick me up.
Apart from cunt there's no smell
like of smoked sausage.
Be at home, my son.
How's that for grape nectar?
It's got a kick. And the ham
is the finest, well seasoned.
It's wild boar.
Matias here killed it.
Eat and drink while I see to Sílvia.
Go on. There's no hurry.
Don't stand there glassy-eyed. Open
up the trunk and show the fineries.
Hey, Matias, drink up!
Will the girls not taste a morsel?
You there!
- Just a bite to melt in the mouth.
- I've already eaten, Sir.
She's eaten, but she didn't fatten.
That's Mistress Silvia's
half-sister.
Half of the father or whoever
cuckolded him?
Of Don Rodrigo!
He can teach a lesson
to many a lad around here.
A joke isn't an offence.
She's a nice half portion of flesh.
Is the bride the same?
Ham next to the bone is tastier.
I won't dispute that, Matias.
One must liven the spirit
while the belly settles.
Here, girl, take this kerchief.
Coy little thing!
Don't be asked twice, lass.
And there's a lot more to come yet.
For you, this is more lady-like.
Feel this for quality.
This is for maids.
I'm too old for dancing.
- Where's there's life there's hope.
- She's long in the tooth for it.
Ask your wife
who has a squeeze of her!
Peace and order in this house.
For Matias,
homespun for a doublet.
Such a weak physique
isn't worth your trouble.
Let me wrap it round you,
pull it in tight.
Look at this, Matias...
It's dazzling!
Stick out those little breasts...
Honey turns golden better in the sun.
Don't be shy, little dove.
We're at home!
A bit of color for sore eyes.
Ah, here comes the bride!
My daughter, Sílvia.
They have often sung your praises.
And I haven't been led astray.
- I entrust you with her, my son.
- She will be in good hands.
Let me finish distributing
my modest gifts
in gratitude for so honorable
a reception.
For you, whom I already esteem
as my sister,
some fine lace.
Look at the delicacy of the work.
The work of fairies
for a fairy herself.
I don't know how to thank you
for your kindness.
You will know in time,
little sister.
For you, father,
this gown from distant...
Venice.
It's too fine for a clod
from these wild parts.
But I promise you it will shine
at your wedding feast.
Finally, the gift for the bride.
I was in difficulties,
they told me the bridegroom
was the best gift for the bride.
I didn't listen.
So I've brought this ring.
Simple but precious.
On your gentle finger I place it.
I will keep it, Sir.
Won't one of you girls
help me out with this morsel?
We're not hungry yet.
Not even a little wing?
Don't you do anything
else but chew?
When I sleep I'm not gnawing.
But when I empty my bowels
I have to fill my belly again.
With chicken,
my delight is the thigh.
I roll it between my fingers,
like this,
and suck it...
Until only the bone is left.
Mistress Silvia's sister
is as slender as a willow.
But she doesn't bend.
Do you think I'm crossed-eyed?
She's got no lack of breasts.
And how well
she rolls her hips!
Don Paio!
Leave him be, Sílvia.
He's a bit silly.
A respectable girl doesn't listen.
I didn't mean any harm, girls.
I didn't get any court education,
and I've never had anything
to do with girls of your level.
- What do you say to those you know?
- Not much.
I lose my tongue
and I just manager to stutter:
"get into the right position!"
- And do they?
- Oh, yes. And why not?
- And you are going to marry...
- Your father fixed everything.
- And don't you want to?
Yes, but my fat carcass
doesn't please Mistress Sílvia.
For a toad, a frog,
goes the saying.
You're exaggerating. I shall honor
the commitments of this family.
May God hear you, Mistress...
For my part, I want to cover
this land with little Paios.
Now that Don Paio
has left us for a while
and peace has returned
to this household,
I must announce my departure
for the court.
What trials await you, father?
Nothing serious.
I want the King to honor your
wedding feast with his presence.
I shall leave at daybreak.
I leave the care of the house with
your sister who is well used to it.
I am, Sir.
If the weather doesn't upset things,
this will be a fine year for wine.
- The grapes are turning golden.
I hope to be back
for the grape harvest.
But if I'm not,
see to the workers
and the presses.
I leave with pride and trust
in you.
Go in peace, father.
Everything will go for the best.
That's as I feel.
Open the doors to no one.
The roads are full of rogues
and you are not well guarded.
Your blessing.
I bless you and the rest
of the household.
Susana, take care of your sister.
See that she doesn't get
overtired.
Go in peace, Sir.
May God go with you.
Salt in the meat,
cattle in their pens
and the bolt on the door.
Wake up, Sílvia.
- What if we went to the river?
- There are shirts to wash...
Let's go to the river.
I could die from love, I could.
Be quiet, witch.
Nobody dies from love.
- Have you washed the underclothes?
- Yes.
- And the shirts?
- I've washed them white.
Ah, I could die of love, I could.
Be quiet, broody hen.
May your mother marry you off.
And the stains of blood on the shirt?
- It's bleached out in the sun.
That's marriage for you.
I could die of love, I could...
Be quiet, witch, and wash!
Is your lad jolly?
Does he play the pipes?
You're more likely
to cry than die.
You'll wash out men's seed
and afterbirth like the rest.
He's all we needed...
He comes and goes
and no wolf grabs him.
- Change the tune.
- Is there a better one?
I saw you coming in late.
Your father'll beat you.
If he finds out!
- Your mother knows.
- She holds her tongue.
She knows who washes the
nappies and sees to the children.
Woe is me!
Be quiet, loud mouth.
You'll spread your woe.
- I'm in love.
- Who isn't?
You speak as if you were the only one.
- And I am.
Wretch! What lover wants you?
Mind the shirt or the wind will
take it, or the river will have it.
- Never mind. I'm in love.
- Wretch!
Sister,
what light is this
that seems to fear light itself?
- Never has day seemed so calm to me.
- Calm before what?
Before night.
The air is still and dark.
- Perhaps night will not come.
- What ever next!
Leave this gloomy stories
for the threshing ground.
Nothing is more eerie than silence
when there's no man in the house.
Be quiet.
Do you ear that?
No, nothing... It's the murmur
of the day passing.
Where does the day go to?
It passes into the night that gives
birth to the next day.
Your fear is making me frightened.
We are always frightened
at some time... The heart is dark.
Someone is coming.
May he come before night falls.
Father told us
not to open to anyone.
I am a pilgrim, lady, a traveler.
Blessed be the roof that shelters me.
- Bread and shelter.
- Poor man...
- He looks God fearing.
- But he has a grim look.
Let him in, sister dear.
Bread and shelter.
Come in, night is falling.
The Lord be praised,
and you blessed.
Have you come from Santiago?
From Compostela.
Have you been long
on a pilgrimage?
And what have you seen?
I have seen the anguish of men,
and the stars turning.
Have you seen any miracles
or strange things?
I have seen all that.
And Christ's blood
spilt on the highways.
Oh, suffering... God spare us
from such pain.
The Lord knows
how to protect you.
You are grave.
You must be tired and with little
patience for our questions.
Always question.
To question is to move forward.
We have seen little
of the world in these parts.
Only one world seen in the light
of a face, reflects all faces.
You may rest here tonight.
Heavenly thanks, lady.
I shall leave at dawn
for distant lands.
What route will you take?
The route of the stars.
May the Lord be with you.
First take these oranges.
In payment of your goodness.
They are from sun-drenched lands,
sweet fruit of the light.
God repay you
for such a precious gift.
My sister and I will retire.
Sweet was the orange
Sweet it was and not bitter
Where did you bring it from?
So lovely and so cherished?
I brought it from the Moors
Where it was well guarded.
I brought it at night,
In daylight I didn't dare.
I brought it as a slave
I didn't bring it as my love.
I brought it barefoot
From where it was shod.
I brought it naked
From where it was well-clad.
Susana, sister, wake up!
What sleep is this
and what happiness,
so blind and deaf
to my affliction?
Open up! Return the light to me.
What light?
- The hand that is of my kin.
- And does it burn?
It burns but it doesn't harm,
it is a blessed hand.
- Open up!
- No!
It must be the hand
of the Devil.
No, lady. Open up
if you wish to know.
I do. Put your hand through
the window and I will return it.
May you be blessed.
Jesus help us.
You're covered in blood!
Have you been injured,
dearest sister?
What hand is this lying here,
most Holy Virgin?
Did you cut it off
with the sword?
Horror of horrors!
Woe is me that I couldn't help you
because of the drugged orange.
And the one he gave to you?
I can see you didn't eat it...
Was that our Lord's will
for the salvation of us both?
Ladies, was there some
trouble here?
We heard howling and noises,
as of wolves or were-wolves.
Be calm, I heard them too.
It must have been the wind.
What else?
There are signs
of hoof prints, Mistress.
Horsemen perhaps,
sheltering from the storm.
There are traces of blood
on the steps. Beware.
Go, my friends, and many
thanks for your care.
My father will know of your zeal.
Go in peace, or you will disturb
my sister's sleep.
Come out of your shock,
Sílvia. They've gone.
What's done is done.
Tell me there was no villainy.
That it was all a dream.
My soul is steeped in blood,
Sílvia.
Don't stay dumb.
Speak to me.
Tell me nothing happened.
Nothing.
I order you to speak!
Forgive me, I no longer know
what I'm saying.
You're frozen...
Let me lie you down.
For the love of God, speak!
Open your heart to me.
Woe is me that I couldn't help
you in such an hour of need.
I knew of nothing,
as if death were on me.
What will father say if he sees you
dumb and in shock
as if you had seen Evil itself?
I saw it.
- Are you sure?
- As plain as I see myself.
Don't touch me.
Not another word on what happened.
What is over is over.
Don't touch me. I beg you.
Don't touch me.
Sílvia! Father has arrived!
Hey, do you want to scald me?
Put in more cold!
That's right. That's enough.
Take the dust of the roads
and the pomp of the court off me.
Look at my little Sílvia,
still smelling of must.
How good is it
to have you back, father.
I can see the journey
went well.
The returning
rather than the going.
An old wolf only feels well
approaching his lair.
- And what's been going on here?
- Nothing, father.
The work and the days passing. We've
brought you a taste of the new wine.
Well, bring it to me, then!
Let's see if the daughter's wine
turns her father's head.
Heavens!
With a household such as this,
a man can die in peace.
We will water your wedding
feast with this.
The union of two honorable
houses
can only mean greater prosperity
for all of us.
Seated here at this table
in harmony
we can enjoy this peace.
Let winter come,
but gently.
Let death take me,
but in Holy peace.
Yours is the fruit
of the seed I have sown.
Before my eyes see their last,
I want only the joy
of having next to me
your son.
Don't worry. We will give
you a fine nestful.
I'm sure of that.
To Don Rodrigo's health!
Long life to Don Rodrigo!
Life is for the young.
A toast to the bridal pair!
Enter and be at ease, Sir.
Forgive my intrusion,
but I have ridden far.
You arrive at a fine time.
The table is set.
It would be an offence
to decline.
When in Rome do as the Romans do.
We are simple
but clean and honest folk.
Have some of this ham.
It's divine ham, not to taste it
would invite God's anger.
- Some venison?
- It is not food that I lack, Sir.
Fill his cup, my son.
Wine made by my Sílvia.
It is strong but smooth.
And with a bouquet like no other.
It has the soul
of the one who made it.
Do you hear, Sílvia?
My little pippin is blushing.
The knight's kindness
praises the merits of a maiden
without knowing her defects,
leaving her grateful but confused.
Eppur si muove...
What a fine wedding feast!
I'm proud to be groom
to such a gentle bride.
To the bride and groom!
Wine for everybody!
Sir, it is not usual
to offend a guest
with indiscreet questions,
but we can all see
that at this merry wedding
you remain taciturn.
Is it in my power
to lighten your thoughts?
What ponderous reason is there
for your visit?
I have come for your daughter.
The conversation becomes bitter,
the air chilled.
It is too late.
My daughter is already given
and I do not go back on my word.
Under different circumstances I would
be grateful for your consideration,
but I feel you jest
with the good will at this table.
It is not my habit to jest
with a maiden's honor.
I have come for your daughter
and will do everything to take her.
- Name your conditions.
- Hand her over, father.
He'll want to fight and I feel sick
at the approaching blood.
Be quiet, no one will draw
your blood.
Please, listen.
My daughter brought up
a ferocious dragon
that is entirely devoted to her.
No human can overcome
this terrible monster.
If you are prepared to pay
for your daring with your life,
kill the dragon
and my daughter is yours.
At the first light of day
I will fight the dragon.
Father, do not encourage
this bloody battle.
Neither saint nor demon
can overcome the dragon.
A joyous wedding feast
for such beauty.