Do you understand "jet-lagged"?
OK, thanks. Be right down.
I don't know, it depends.
OK.
Give your mom my love.
Heaven has reached down to earth.
And what does this tell us?
That God has not forsaken us,
that He is always watching over us,
that He loves us.
Through this sign,
He has manifested His presence.
He is telling us,
you are not alone.
Excuse me.
Excuse me...
Could I have a light, please?
Yeah.
Thanks, you're very nice.
- OK?
- Yeah.
Yeah, thanks.
Are you taking the Metro?
Of course.
Do you...?
You both live in Paris, or not?
We actually live nearby.
I'm sorry but...
What did you say?
We live right around here...
in this neighbourhood.
Yes, OK, I understand.
Me, I stay here for a few days but...
then I leave soon for...
I'm going..-
In fact, I leave...
I'm sorry about my French.
It's awful, I know.
It's OK, don't worry.
- What's your name?
- What?
You got a problem?
What?
Don't you say excuse me?
He's not French.
I'm sorry, sir.
So he doesn't speak French?
Like a girl.
And why do you have two girls
and I have none?
OK, that's it, enough.
Hold on!
Come on, stop!
No, it's OK.
What time is it?
It's 10:05.
We don't have time?
I'm hungry-
Let's go.
- Bye.
- See you around, maybe?
- Nice meeting you.
Evening, sir.
Excuse me, good evening.
My friend...
Wanna spend the evening
with some pretty girls?
What?
A nice night with pretty girls.
Interested?
Right over there.
What do you mean exactly?
You go in, have a drink,
look around...
There are pretty girls
to keep you company.
If you want more, if you want sex,
that's possible too, OK?
But, how much?
10 Euros for a drink...
If you don't like it, you leave.
What do you think?
A great souvenir of Paris.
Trust me, I'm no crook.
There?
Good evening.
- Good evening.
Hi.
What's your name?
My name's Simon.
Will you have a drink with me?
Yeah, but how much will that be?
- 20 Euros.
- 20 Euros...
Thank you.
Where are you from?
Are you all set?
Thank you.
You're very handsome.
I'm not just saying that for work,
I really think so.
That's sweet.
Yeah, I understand.
I studied eyes in college.
Yes.
I studied the relationship
between the brain and the eye.
- You speak French very well.
- No, that's not true.
Thank you.
You OK?
- And you?
- Yeah.
What is that?
Hold on...
I have to take it off.
It's OK.
Take my number, if you like.
Really? I missed a party?
No, it was great.
I had it all to myself.
What, like I don't need dough?
Hi, girls!
- How's it going?
- Everybody's here.
Where else would we be?
Want a drag?
Why you staring, huh?
You got a problem?
On the left, at the corner.
Sit over there.
I rent it from an old lady.
She's kind of lonely.
You've got other bruises?
He was very violent.
He never let me go out.
Once, I woke up
in the middle of the night.
I was pregnant.
I had a baby boy inside me.
My belly was so big.
I woke up suddenly...
and there was blood everywhere.
And I walked into the kitchen.
And my husband was there.
He looked at me.
I was covered in blood.
It was everywhere.
And before going to the hospital...
he fucked me in the kitchen.
Are you here?
I saw a client at a hotel.
Very aggressive.
But he left me some coke.
Want a glass of wine?
You know, most of these guys...
I got the phone.
Take a look.
I love navy blue. It's got class.
Hold on! It's not right.
Sorry, excuse me.
Are you Jean?
Yes.
Did you see a girl tonight?
What?
OK.
I'm going to speak in French,
you understand?
Yes, I understand.
I'm a cop.
Understand?
Yes.
That means I could...
if I wanted to...
Do you understand?
If I fuck a whore, what's it to you?
Do you really have something,
or are you just fucking with me?
Cause if you do,
I'll hurt you.
Understand?
Stop it.
Stop.
Want to see what it feels like?
You're such a fucking pain!
Hold on, let me show you.
Turn around.
Do you like that?
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Like that?
OK, come here.
Yeah, that's good.
Are you OK?
- Yes. And you?
- Yeah.
Have I told you about the first time
I saw a woman on the Boulevard?
I walked down the Boulevard.
My mother held my hand.
We were going to Sacré Coeur.
It was a Sunday.
That day...
I noticed a woman leaning against
the side of a building.
She was big...
She was wearing a miniskirt,
without stockings.
She stared at me.
She was beautiful.
And with her finger,
she gave me a sign like this.
She was so close,
I could smell her.
At that time,
I didn't know what the smell was.
Now, I know.
It was sex.
When I was older...
I went back to find her,
just to ask her...
What did you want with me?
You see?
What did you want to do
with an 8-year-old boy?
Undress.
Rene'?
Yeah.
Wait, wait, wait...
Rene'-.
You're a kid.
It wasn't easy for me
to get this money.
I've got a wife, a kid, a home.
- Yeah, I understand.
- I have responsibilities.
Are you sure
about how you're feeling?
Look me in the eyes.
So?
Enough said. Want a drink?
Just a Coke, please.
You'll come by again...
- I hope so.
- You won't forget us?
Of course not.
You're staying in Paris, I hope?
No, no, I'm not leaving.
No, one day at a time.
Love's fleeting.
Whatever it is,
I'm much better right now.
Here's to love!
May you find love, too!
Do you... remember me?
Look.
This is your fault.
It's you who did this.
He didn't take the money.
Me... I always wanted to be a tiger.
Simon?
Yeah, it's me.
Where were you?
Why were you gone for so long?
You OK?
What are you doing?
Make love to me.
Rene.
Leave me a message after the beep.
Thank you. Goodbye.
René.
Leave me a...
Rene.
Leave me a message after the beep.
- You hungry?
- Yeah, I am.
Why didn't you come home last night?
Who are you with?
What friend?
One second.
Not now, sir!
It's fun having coffee with you!
I'm just kidding.
Where were you last night?
Why didn't you come home?
You disgust me.
Get the fuck out.
You're a piece of shit.
And you lie.
That's right, leave.
You're pathetic.
And take your money.
Take it.
Look at yourself, look...
You're a coward.
You're not a man.
You know, we get what we deserve.
I never asked you for anything, Simon.
I was just fine as I was.
I called.
You understood me.
Happy birthday to you,
Happy birthday to you...
Happy birthday, Carlo...
Thank you, thank you!
Carlo, someone's here to see you.
What are you doing here?
You OK?
Let me introduce you.
He's the son of my mother's friend.
Sort of my American cousin.
- Hi.
Excuse me.
- Have a nice evening.
- You, too.
I was putting him up for a while and...
He didn't stay long.
OK, it's fine.
You can go.
Go on.