(Bell rings)
MAN: Bow to the board.
This is the boy.
Born here in the workhouse.
Moved to the parish farm.
Nine years old today.
Time to be moved back here.
What's your name, boy?
(Faintly) Oliver Twist.
- What, what?
- The boy's a fool.
Boy, listen to me.
- You know you are an orphan, I suppose?
- What's that?
The boy is a fool. I thought he was.
You know you've got no father or mother
and that you were brought up by the parish?
- Don't you?
- Yes, sir.
What are you crying for?
I hope you say your prayers every night, hmm?
Pray for those that feed you
and take care of you.
Like a...
- Like a Christian.
- Yes, sir.
Well, you have come here to be educated
and to be taught a useful trade.
Learn from the boy next to you.
What am I to learn, sir?
Learn to pick out the oakum.
What's oakum, sir?
Stop asking so many questions.
Oakum's the fibres you unpick from the old rope.
Then it's used again
for ships of Her Majesty's Navy.
You're serving your country.
Now, get on with it.
Tom, give it a rest, will you?
We're trying to sleep.
Can't sleep. Too hungry.
We're all hungry.
Yes, but I'm frightened.
Frightened? Why?
Why?
Why? I'm so hungry, I'm frightened I might eat
the lad that sleeps next to me.
MAN: Oh, Lord God,
for the blessing
of this generous and bountiful meal
that thou hast placed before us,
we give thanks.
Amen.
ALL: Amen!
(Softly) Yeah.
(Sharp intakes of breath)
Please, sir, I want some more.
What?
Fetch the Beadle!
Mr Limbkins.
I beg your pardon, sir.
Oliver Twist has asked for more.
For more?
Compose yourself, Mr Bumble,
and answer me distinctly.
Do I understand that he asked for more
after he'd eaten supper?
He did, sir.
That boy will be hanged.
Whoa.
£5 and a boy?
Whoa!
Whoa.
When I says whoa...
I means whoa!
(Donkey brays)
(Reads) Healthy,
app...
apprentice.
£5.
Chimney sweeping is a nasty trade.
Young boys have been smothered in chimneys
before now.
That's because they damp the straw
afore they light it in the chimney
to make 'em come out again.
Damp straw makes smoke.
Smoke sends the boy to sleep.
That's what he wants.
Boys is very lazy, gentlemen.
But there's nothing like a good, hot blaze
to make 'em come out in a run.
It's humane, too.
Yes. Because even if they're stuck
in the chimney,
roasting their feet makes 'em struggle
to hextricate theirselves.
Yes.
I suppose he's fond of chimney sweeping?
He dotes on it, Your Worship.
Very well. I will sign the indentures...
..to make him Mr...
..Mr Gamfield's apprentice.
(Oliver whimpers)
My boy.
My boy, you look pale and alarmed.
What's the matter?
Please, sir... Please, sir...
What is it, my boy?
OLIVER: Don't...
- Now, then.
Don't...
Go on, my boy. Don't what?
Please don't send me away
with this dreadful man, sir.
Huh. Off all the designing orphans
that I've ever seen.
Hold your tongue, Beadle.
- Did Your Worship speak to me?
- Yes. Hold your tongue.
FIRST MAGISTRATE: Out of the question.
We refuse to sanction these indentures.
Take the boy away.
And treat him kindly.
He seems to want it.
I've just taken the measure of the two women
that died last night, Mr Bumble.
MR BUMBLE:
You'll make your fortune, Mr Sowerberry.
Think so?
The prices allowed by the board are very small.
So are the coffins.
By the by, you don't know anybody
who wants a boy, do you?
Liberal terms, Mr Sowerberry.
Liberal terms.
Now, as you are to meet your new master,
pull that cap off your eyes.
Hold your head up, sir.
Dry your eyes, sir.
(Bell rings)
Aha.
Is that you, Bumble?
No-one else, Mr Sowerberry.
I brought the orphan, Oliver Twist.
So this is the orphan, is it?
Mrs Sowerberry, will you have the goodness
to come here a moment, my dear?
Oliver Twist?
How comes an orphan to have any name at all?
- I invented it.
- You, Mr Bumble?
Aye, Mr Sowerberry.
I name all our foundlings in alphabetical order.
The last was "S".
"Swubble," I named him.
This was a "T". "Twist," I named him.
Next one as comes will be...
"Unwin". And the next "Vilkins".
I've got names ready all through the alphabet,
right up to "Z".
Why, you're quite a literary character, sir.
MR BUMBLE: Well, well.
Perhaps I may be.
Mrs Sowerberry, this is the orphan
from the workhouse.
- Dear me, he's very small.
- But he'll grow, Mrs Sowerberry. He'll grow.
Yes, I daresay he will...
on our food and drink.
Workhouse boys
always cost more to keep than they're worth.
Get downstairs, you bag of bones.
Here, Charlotte, give this boy some
of the cold bits that were put by for the dog.
MRS SOWERBERRY: You don't mind
sleeping among the coffins, I suppose.
It doesn't matter much whether you do or don't.
You can't sleep anywhere else.
(Cock crows)
(Banging)
BOY: Open the door, will ya?
Are you the new boy?
Yes, sir.
How old are you?
Ten, sir.
Then I'll whop you one when I get in,
you workhouse brat.
(Cock crows)
I beg your pardon, sir. Did you knock?
I kicked.
Did you want a coffin, sir?
- You don't know who I am, I suppose?
- No, sir.
Well, I'm Mr Noah Claypole.
And you're under me.
Now, take down the shutters!
Saved a nice little bit of bacon for you
from the master's breakfast.
In the corner with you.
And be quick about it.
They want you to mind the shop.
Do you hear?
Do you hear, Workhouse? In the corner.
CHARLOTTE: O, Lor', Noah, let the boy alone.
Let him alone?
Why, everybody's let him alone.
His mother, father,
and all his relations has let him alone.
So, he needs someone who don't.
(They laugh)
(Dog barks frantically)
Supper!
Oliver, ain't you done yet?
I've never known such an idle boy.
Get down them stairs.
Mr Sowerberry!
Supper.
I've had a thought, my dear.
"Had a thought." You want to be careful,
Mr Sowerberry. You'll get brain fever.
It's about young Twist.
What about him?
A very good-looking boy.
He will be. He eats enough.
There's an expression of melancholy
in his face, my dear.
He would make a delightful mute, my love.
l-I don't mean a regular mute
to attend grown-up funerals, my dear.
But only for children's practice.
(Church bells ring)
Look at him.
A workhouse boy and a sneak.
Mark my words, I'll see him hung.
Can't be too soon.
Workhouse...how's your mother?
OLIVER: She's dead.
Oh.
What did she die of, Workhouse?
Oh, are you gonna cry, Workhouse?
What set you off?
Not you.
Not me, eh?
No, not you.
And you'd better not
say anything about my mother.
"Better not"?
About your mother?
Well, I'm very sorry and I pity you very much,
but you must know, Workhouse,
your mother was a regular right down bad 'un.
What did you say?
A regular right down bad 'un.
It's a good thing she died when she did
or she'd be hard-labouring or transported.
Or hung, which is most likely,
isn't it, Workhouse?
Help, Mrs Charlotte!
He'll murder me! Help!
Help! Get off!
For God's sake!
Help me!
CHARLOTTE: Stop it, you beast! You animal!
NOAH: He's murdering me! Get off!
Get off me now!
I've got hold of him.
OLIVER: Let me near him!
You workhouse devil.
I'll learn you.
You brat!
Get the door, Charlotte!
In with him.
Very violent indeed, sir.
And the missus said,
"If Mr Bumble can spare the time,
then Mr Bumble's to flog him."
Cos the master's out.
In there.
- Oliver!
- Let me out of here!
Do you know this here voice, Oliver?
Yes!
Aren't you afraid of it, sir?
Ain't you trembling while I speak, sir?
No!
He must be mad.
- It's not madness, ma'am. It's meat.
- Meat?
Meat, ma'am, meat. You've overfed him.
If you'd kept this boy on gruel,
this would never have happened.
Dear, dear. This comes of being liberal.
What's all this?
Oliver Twist has turned violent, Mr Sowerberry.
Look what he's done to my eye, sir.
(Banging)
Now, then. Now, then.
You're a nice young fellow, ain't you?
He called my mother names.
And what if he did? You little ungrateful wretch.
She deserved what he said and worse.
She didn't! It's a lie!
(Gasps)
Do something, Mr Sowerberry.
(Breathlessly) He called me a liar!
Do something!
(Dog barks)
(Driver urges horses on)
(Dog yelps)
I...
Er...
I beg your pardon, miss.
But would you be so kind...
Get off my land.
I don't want no beggars here! Go on!
Get off!
Or I'll put the dog on you!
I haven't much,
but you're more than welcome to it.
Be careful. It's hot.
Seeing you gave me such a turn.
My eyes ain't what they were.
But...
I just thought for a moment...
Why are you on the road at all?
A little mite like you?
- Where are you headed?
- London, ma'am.
London.
Oh!
Dear, oh, dear, oh, dear.
Hello, my man.
What's your game?
You're not from these parts?
Where are you from, then?
I've been walking...
seven days.
Seven days?
Cor. I expect you want grub.
And you shall have it.
I'm at a low-water mark, myself,
just at the moment,
but I'll fork out and stump.
Come on, up with you. On your pins.
Oh, by the by,
my name is Jack Dawkins,
better known as the Artful Dodger.
Oliver Twist.
Why are you known as the Artful Dodger?
That's why.
Got any lodgings?
Money?
I suppose you want some place to sleep tonight,
don't you?
MAN: Rag and bone!
I expect you walking for so long
was a beak's order.
What's that mean?
Don't you know what a "beak" is?
A bird's mouth, isn't it?
Cor, you are green.
A beak's a magistrate, my son.
Where you been all your life?
WOMAN: Come back here. I want to talk to you.
(Baby cries)
(Dodger whistles)
BOY: Now, then?
DODGER: Plummy and slam.
There's two of you. Who's he?
DODGER: A new pal.
- Where'd he come from?
Greenland. Is the old 'un there?
Upstairs, sorting the wipes.
(Whispers)
This is him, Fagin.
My new friend, Oliver Twist.
Well, well...
Oliver Twist.
(Boys titter)
I hope I have the honour
of a more intimate acquaintance.
We're very glad to see you, Oliver.
Very. Dodger, take off the sausages.
And let's make a space at the table...
for Oliver.
You are staring at the pocket handkerchiefs,
hey, my dear?
There's a good many of them, ain't there?
We just looked 'em out ready for the wash.
That's all, my dear.
Blow it.
Hot.
Now, then, Oliver.
What you must have is a hot gin and water.
Warms the cockles.
Only drink it quick, cos another
of these gentlemen wants the tumbler.
- (Hiccups)
- (Boys laugh)
He's such a nice lad.
I have a feeling he'll turn out a hard worker.
Yeah, a hard worker.
Oliver.
Oliver?
(Fagin gasps)
Clever dogs.
Ah.
Fine fellows.
Ah, fine fellows.
(Lilting) Fine fellows.
Fine fellows.
What do you watch me for? Why are you
awake? What have you seen? Speak out, boy!
Quick! Quick! Or it's your life.
I wasn't able to sleep any longer, sir.
I'm very sorry if I disturbed you.
- You were not awake a moment ago?
- No, sir.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, sir.
Of course you were asleep, my dear.
I know that.
I only tried to frighten you.
You're a brave boy, Oliver.
Did you see any of those pretty things, my dear?
- Yes, sir.
- Ah!
They...
They're mine, Oliver.
My little property.
For my old age.
It's our secret.
You understand, my dear?
Yes, sir.
Can I get up now, sir?
MAN OUTSIDE: Blimey!
I hope you've been at work this morning,
my dears.
- Hard.
- As nails.
Good boys!
Good boys.
What you got, Dodger?
- Couple of pocket books.
- Lined?
Pretty well.
Oh.
Dodge...
I don't know, Dodge.
Ah.
Well.
Not as heavy as they might be.
But very neat.
And nicely made.
- Ingenious workman, ain't he, Oliver?
- Indeed, sir.
And, Charley, what have you got, my dear?
- Wipes.
- Wipes?
They're very good ones.
Oh, very...
You haven't marked them well.
The marks should be picked out with a needle.
And we'll teach Oliver how to do it.
- Shall us, Oliver?
- If you please, sir.
You'd like to make pocket handkerchiefs
as easy as Charley Bates, wouldn't you?
Very much indeed, if you'll teach me, sir.
I never met anyone so green.
(Mutters)
Now, then, boys.
The game.
We'll show Oliver
how to make pocket handkerchiefs.
You'd like to play a game, wouldn't you, Oliver?
Yes, sir.
(Fakes a groan)
BOY: Got the time, guv?
It's er...
eight o'clock.
Playing the game, were we, Fagin?
As is our custom, my dear.
He's new. Who's he?
Oh, this is Oliver.
Oliver,
these are our very good friends, Bet and Nancy.
See, Dodger, you want to learn from him.
He's got manners, he has.
Proper gentleman.
Fagin, we popped in
because we're that cold inside.
As is your custom, my dear.
Charley.
Come on, Oliver, join us.
Or don't you sit with the common folk?
Now, you want to be careful of this lot, Oliver.
He'll have you picking...
Picking out the marks. That's what we
was teaching him, ain't it, Oliver, my dear?
- Yes, sir.
- "Yes, sir"?
You know who you're talking to, do you?
What's your mother got to say
about you being here, Oliver?
I haven't got a mother. I'm an orphan.
You're in the right company, then.
Come on, Oliver, I'll teach you how to play.
It's called Spec or Speculation.
Three cards each.
And then, the one he turns up...
is trumps.
This is a pleasant life, ain't it, my dear?
When can I go out, sir?
FAGIN: Soon. Soon.
Let's...
Let's see what you've learned.
Would you like that?
Oh, yes, sir.
See if you can take this out...
..without my feeling it.
Is it gone?
You're a clever boy, my dear.
I never saw a sharper lad.
Here's a shilling for you.
Make the Dodger and Charley your models.
Especially the Dodger, my dear.
He'll be a great man himself.
Make you one, too.
If you go on this way,
you'll be the greatest man of the time.
Oh...
Thank you very much, sir.
(Traders shout)
Thief! Your handkerchief, sir.
Stop, thieves!
Thief!
Him!
Stop, thief!
(Babble of distorted voices)
Where's the gentleman?
I hope they hang him.
- He's scared to death.
- He's putting it on.
- Where's the gentleman?
- Here's the gentleman now.
Is this the boy, sir?
- Yes, I'm afraid it is.
- "Afraid it is"? That's a good 'un.
Did you hear him? "Afraid it is"?
- He's hurt himself.
- I did that, sir.
Hurt my knuckle agin his mouth.
But I stopped him.
- Get up!
- It wasn't me, sir. It wasn't me.
Course it wasn't. It never is.
- Now, get up.
- Don't hurt him.
Oh, no, sir, I won't hurt him.
This way, gentlemen.
What's next?
That is my name and address, sir.
Officer, who is this fellow?
- My name, sir, is Brownlow.
- Hold your tongue!
Officer, what's this fellow charged with?
Oh, no, no. He's not charged, Your Worship.
- He appears against the boy.
- Swear him.
Before I am sworn, I must beg to say one word.
- Hold your tongue, sir!
- I will not, sir!
Hold your tongue this instant!
You're an insolent, impertinent fellow.
- How dare you bully a magistrate?
- What?
Swear this person. I'll not hear another word.
I do solemnly swear to tell the truth, the whole
truth and nothing but the truth, so help me God.
Now, what's the charge against the boy?
- I was standing at a book store...
- Hold your tongue!
Where's the policeman? What is this?
Are there any witnesses?
None, Your Worship.
The boy is ill.
Oh, yes, I daresay.
Come along, you vagabond!
None of your tricks here.
- What's your name?
- Water.
What's your name, you hardened scoundrel?
Officer, what's his name?
What's your name, boy?
Some water. Some water.
He says his name is Sam Waters, Your Worship.
- Where does he live?
- Where do you live? Anywhere he can.
Stuff and nonsense.
Don't try to make a fool out of me.
No, no, I think he really is ill, Your Worship.
I know better or my name's not Fang.
Stand away, Officer. He's shamming.
He stands committed for three months.
Hard labour, of course. Clear the office.
Stop. Stop. Stop. Don't take him away.
What is this? Who is this? Turn this man out.
I will not be turned out!
I will speak!
I saw it all. I own the bookshop.
- I demand to be heard.
- Well, what have you got to say?
- It was not this boy.
- Not this boy? Who was it, then?
The robbery was committed by two other boys
while the gentleman was reading.
I saw it done.
I saw that this boy was perfectly amazed by it.
Why didn't you come before?
I hadn't a soul to mind the shop.
Reading, you say.
A book, I suppose.
Yes, the very one he has in his hand.
Dear me, I forgot all about it.
Well, you're a nice one.
To prefer a charge against an innocent boy.
I consider, sir,
that you've obtained that book under very
suspicious and disreputable circumstances.
Damn me!
Do you want to press charges
against this fellow?
Certainly not.
Well, you may think yourself fortunate
that the owner of the book declines to prosecute.
The boy is discharged. Clear the office.
- Damn me!
- Clear the office! Clear the office!
Next case.
Come on. Move along, sir, please.
Just move along, sir.
There's a good gentleman, sir.
Hold on, Harry. I'll give you a hand.
OFFICER: Make way for the law, sir.
Careful with him.
- Call a coach, pray.
- Right away, sir.
I'm sorry.
Oh. (Chuckles)
Poor boy.
- Mind yourself, madam.
- Thank you, sir.
- Got one, sir.
- Thank you, Officer.
Let me, sir.
- Could you drop me off, sir?
- Of course.
Right...
If you could just take his head, sir.
- Where to, sir?
- Pentonville.
Pentonville.
Answer me, where is he?
What's become of the boy? Speak out
- or I'll throttle you!
- The traps have got him! Let go of me, will ya!
Bull's-eye!
Who pitched this here at me?
Who done it?
Bull's-eye. Come here, you sneaking varmint.
What you stopping outside for?
Lay down.
(Whimpers and growls)
What you up to, Fagin?
I'll-treating the boys again?
I wonder they don't murder you.
I would if I was them.
Shh!
Don't speak so loud.
You seem out of sorts, Bill.
Give us a drink, and mind you don't poison it.
(Laughs) Charley.
Good stuff, Bill.
So, Dodger, what's it all about?
The new boy.
Come out with us before he was rightly up to it.
Got nabbed by the traps.
You see, Bill,
I'm afraid he may say something
which will get us into trouble.
You're blowed upon, Fagin.
And about time.
And I'm afraid, you see, Bill,
that if the game were up with us,
it would come out rather worse for you
than it would for me, my dear.
BILL: There's only one thing for it.
Somebody's got to find out at the office
what's being done to him.
Somebody's got to get hold of him somehow.
I ain't going near no police office.
Not for nobody, no how.
I have it, the very thing.
Bet will go, won't you, my dear?
I'm blessed if I will.
Nancy, my dear, what do you say?
It won't do. There's no use in trying it on, Fagin.
- What do you mean by that?
- What I say, Bill.
You're just the very person for it.
Nobody knows anything about you.
And as I don't want 'em to neither.
It's rather more no than yes with me, Bill.
She'll go, Fagin.
- No, she won't, Fagin.
- Yes, she will, Fagin.
(Sniffles)
Can I help you, miss?
I'm looking for my little brother.
Now, who would he be?
A lovely little boy.
Lovely manners. Gentle as falling snow.
We don't get many of those.
I think you'll be wanting Mr Fang's court.
George.
This young lady's looking for her brother.
I think he's the one that fainted
and managed to get away with it.
- Gentleman took him away.
- What gentleman?
Gracious heavens, what gentleman?
Well...
Lives in Pentonville, I believe.
Oh, my gawd.
No, no, wait, wait, wait...
His card's here somewhere.
Thank you, sir.
Mr Brownlow!
Mr Brownlow...
There's something in him
that touched my heart, Mrs Bedwin.
I can't explain it.
I feel the same, sir.
Who is he? What is he?
You know nothing of him.
He had a fever. What of that?
Bad people have fevers sometimes.
I knew a man in Jamaica who was
hanged for murdering his master.
He had a fever six times!
I know there is goodness in him.
- How do you know it?
- Goodness and innocence.
- I knew it the first moment I saw him.
- He'll deceive you.
Let you down at the first opportunity,
like all your other good and innocent causes.
If that boy is good and innocent,
I'll eat my own head, sir.
How do you feel, my dear?
Very happy, sir.
And very grateful to you indeed, sir.
Good boy.
Have we given him any nourishment, Bedwin?
Any slops?
Not slops, sir.
Broth.
A couple of glasses of port wine
would have done him a great deal more good.
Wouldn't they, Sam?
My name is Oliver, sir.
"Oliver"?
Oliver what? Oliver Waters?
No, sir. Twist. Oliver Twist.
Why did you tell the magistrate
your name was Waters?
I never told him so, sir.
You did not?
No, sir.
- You're not angry with me, are you, sir?
- No.
Queer name.
Oliver Twist.
There are a great many books,
are there not, my boy?
A great number, sir.
I never saw so many.
How would you like to grow up a clever man
and write books, hmm?
I think I'd rather read them, sir.
Oh.
Wouldn't you like to be a book writer?
I think it'd be a better thing
to be a book seller, sir.
You have said a very good thing.
Well, well. We won't make an author of you
while there's an honest trade to be learned
or brick-making to turn to.
Are you going to send me away, sir?
No, my dear child.
You need not be afraid
that I'm going to desert you.
Unless you give me cause.
- I never, never will, sir.
- I hope not.
Because I feel strongly disposed to trust you.
Thank you, sir.
I'm pleased I won't have to wear those again.
MRS BEDWIN: So are we all, my dear.
There.
(Man whistles)
MAN: Hello.
What's that?
MR BROWNLOW: This is young Oliver Twist.
- Sir, the book seller's boy brought a package.
- Stop him. There's some books to go back.
Is that the boy who had the fever?
That's the boy.
No sign of him, sir.
Oh, dear. I'm very sorry for that.
I particularly wished some books
to be returned tonight.
Send Oliver with them.
He'll be sure to deliver them safely.
Yes, do let me take them.
If you please, sir. I'll run all the way.
You shall go, my dear.
Ask Mrs Bedwin to show you the way.
And Oliver?
Yes, sir.
Give the book seller this.
The money I owe him.
I won't be long, sir.
How long do you think it'll take him?
You really expect him to come back, do you?
You don't?
With a five-pound note in his pocket?
No, I do not.
If ever that boy returns to this house,
I'll eat my own head, sir.
And yours.
Oh, my little brother!
OLIVER: No, no!
Help!
It's a miracle.
I found him. I found him.
Oh, Oliver, Oliver.
Nancy?
You're such a naughty boy to make me
suffer such distress on your account.
What's the matter, ma'am?
He ran away from his parents,
hard-working, respectable people,
and joined a set of thieves and bad characters.
Broke his mother's heart.
Young wretch.
Go home, you little brute.
I haven't got any parents. I'm an orphan.
I live in Pentonville.
Only hear him how he braves it out.
- What? Young Oliver!
OLIVER: It's true!
You come home to your poor mother!
I don't belong to them! I don't know them!
Help! Help!
"Help? Help?"
I'll give you "Help! Help!" you little wretch!
And these books!
Have you been astealing them, have you, eh?
You little villain!
That's right. You give it to him.
Only way to bring him to his senses.
I will, missus!
You come with me, you little wretch!
WOMAN: It'll do him good.
OLIVER: Who is this man?
BILL: Mind him, Bull's-eye!
OLIVER: Help! Help!
Look at him, Fagin!
Hold me, somebody.
Hold me, somebody, while I laugh it out.
Look at his togs, Fagin!
Delighted to see you looking so well, my dear.
Why didn't you write, my dear,
and say you was coming?
We'd have got something warm for supper.
Hello, Fagin. What's that? That's mine, Fagin!
No, my dear. Mine, Bill, mine.
You shall have the books.
If that ain't mine and Nancy's, I'll take
the boy back again. Come on. Hand over.
This is hardly fair, Bill, hardly fair. Is it, Nancy?
Fair or not fair, hand over, I tell ya.
Give it here, you avaricious old skeleton!
Give it here! That's for our share of the trouble.
Not half enough neither.
You may keep the books if you're
fond of reading. If you ain't, sell 'em.
They're very pretty.
Beautiful writing, isn't it, Oliver?
Send them back. They belong to Mr Brownlow.
Send them back, the books and the money.
He'll think I stole them.
- Please send them back.
- The boy's right. You're right, Oliver.
They will think you've stolen 'em.
It couldn't have happened better
if we'd chosen our time.
Help! Help! Police!
Keep back the dog, Bill.
- He'll tear the boy to pieces.
- Serve him right.
Help! Fetch the police!
Fetch the police!
Step aside or I'll split your head against the wall.
I don't care. That child shan't be torn down
by the dog unless you kill me first.
Bull's-eye! Here!
Bull's-eye!
FAGIN: Dodger!
Get after him!
Hey! (Laughs)
Hey!
So you wants to get away, my dear, did you?
Wanted to call for the police, did you?
We'll soon cure you of that.
I won't stand by and see this done, Fagin!
You've got the boy. What more do you want?
Keep quiet, Nancy,
or I'll quieten you for a good long time to come.
Let him be! Let him be!
You're a fine one for the boy to make a friend of.
NANCY:
God Almighty, help me, I am.
He's a thief, a liar, a devil,
all that's bad from this night forth.
Ain't that enough for the old wretch
without blows?
Come, come, we must have civil words.
Civil words.
Civil words?
Civil words? You old villain!
I thieved for you
when I was a child not half as old as this!
It's your living.
Yes, and you're the wretch that drove me to it.
And who will keep me at it day and night
until I die!
Dodger.
Charley. Put Oliver to bed.
Best to take them clothes off first.
They're too good to sleep in.
This suit cost more than four pence ha'penny.
I never felt such lovely stuff. Have you, Dodger?
Not me.
I'm willing to lay odds this is the same stuff
the queen wears on Sundays.
(Boys laugh)
Quick, get him.
Take it off.
Lift him up.
Up he goes.
(Barking)
Get them shoes off.
(Bells ring)
Little something for your luncheon, my dear?
Shall we have a little chat?
Oliver?
Shall us?
I expect you'd welcome...
..the sound of a human voice again,
eh, my dear?
D'you know...
..what I consider
the greatest sin in the world, my dear?
Ingratitude.
That's what you're guilty of.
We took you in, we cherished you.
If we hadn't, you might have died of hunger.
And how do you repay us? You run away.
You cry out for the police.
You cause us great anxiety and expense.
There was a lad once just like you.
I was a father to him. He ran away like you.
He indeed went to the police
and can you guess how he ended up?
They hanged him.
At the Old Bailey.
Certain evidence was made available,
not all of it precisely true, but...
..all of it necessary to provide for my own safety
and that of my friends.
Yeah. Poor boy.
Hanged.
It's a terrible thing, hanging, Oliver.
Dawn. The gallows.
The rope. The noose.
You don't always have to be guilty,
you see, Oliver.
They hang you for anything these days,
because they're so very fond of hanging.
But if you do as you're told,
we'll be very good friends yet.
You must feel free to walk about now, Oliver.
Yes, feel free.
Here, Oliver.
Yes?
I'd like you to assist me
in my toilet straight away.
Will you do that for me, my man?
All right. I'll be glad of the company.
There's a good fellow.
You may start by japanning my trotter cases.
In plain English, clean my boots.
What a pity he ain't a prig.
He don't know what's good for him.
'Spose you don't even know what a prig is.
Yes, I do. It's a...
It's a...
thief.
You're one, aren't you?
Yes, I am. And so we all are.
Down to the dog.
And he's the downiest one of the lot.
And the least given to peaching.
He wouldn't so much as bark in a witness box
for fear of committing himself.
He's an out-and-out Christian, he is.
Why don't you put yourself under Fagin, Oliver?
You'll make a fortune out of hand.
Like your old gentleman in Pentonville.
Big house that.
I had a peep at it, I did.
Nice inside, was it?
Yes.
And I slept in a proper bed in my own room.
Good stuff on the walls, eh?
Yes, indeed.
Put yourself under Fagin
and you'll be able to retire to a property
just like that.
And do the genteel.
No. He's scared he'll come to be scragged.
I don't know what that means.
If you don't take pocket handkerchiefs
and watches, nolly,
some other cove will. And you have
the same right to them as they have.
To be sure. To be sure.
It all lies in a nutshell, my dear. In a nutshell.
Take the Dodger's word for it.
He understands the catechism of his trade.
Cabbie.
I've come from Bill.
For what?
For no harm.
I don't believe it.
If I could help you, I would,
but I've not the power.
Now, I've promised him
you'll be good and silent.
If you're not, you'll only do yourself harm.
And me, too.
Did he come quiet?
Like a lamb.
Sit down.
Let me read you a lecture.
You know what this is?
Yes.
Well, then.
This is powder.
That here's a bullet.
And this is a little bit of an old hat...
..for wadding.
Now it's loaded.
Yes. I can see it is, sir.
If you speak a word when you're out of doors
with me, unless I speak to you,
this loading will go in your head without notice.
So, if you do make up your mind
to speak without leave,
says your prayers first.
NANCY:
The short and long of what you mean is,
if you're crossed by him, you'll prevent him ever
telling tales by shooting him through the head.
And you'll take your chances swinging for it.
That's it. Women always put things
in the fewest words.
Supper, Nancy.
And then a snooze afore starting.
MAN: Aha!
My pal Bill!
The door's open! Come in!
(Whispers) Don't make such a row!
Show us a glim, Toby.
Barney, a glim. Show the gentleman in.
Barney! Wake up first, if convenient!
Mr Sykes.
Come in, sir, come in.
Bill, my boy. Glad to see ya.
Who's um...
Who's this?
Only the boy.
One of Mr Fagin's lads?
Yeah. It's time.
Right.
Barkers for me, Barney.
They're loaded.
Good.
- The persuaders?
- Got 'em.
Keys. Centre bits.
Darkies.
Nothing forgotten?
Ah!
(Whispers) It's all quiet.
(Thunder)
OLIVER: I can't.
I can't.
You will.
It's Mr Brownlow's house.
Have mercy! Don't make me steal from him!
Have mercy on me!
Come here!
For God's sake, let me run away
and die in a field. I'll never come near London.
Shut it!
Get up. Or I'll strew your brains on the grass.
I'm putting you through there.
Go to the front door and unfasten it.
I can't. There's a bolt at the top.
I know it. I can't reach it.
Well, stand on a chair or something.
Just do it.
BlLL: To the door!
To the front door, damn you!
MRS BEDWIN: Who's there?
MR BROWNLOW: Mrs Bedwin?
Is that you?
Save me! Save me! Save me! For God's sake!
MRS BEDWlN: Help!
Help!
Police!
Give him here!
God damnation, how he bleeds!
- Is he hit bad?
- He's gotta be hit worse.
- Give me a pistol!
- What?
BILL: We've got to get rid of him or he'll squeal.
We've got to do him in.
Here, here!
Down here by the river!
TOBY: Bill! Bill!
- Bill!
- Help!
Help! Help!
Oh, Bill!
BILL: Help!
CHARLEY: Snap.
Snap.
Snap!
(Bull's-eye whimpers)
Well.
How are you, Fagey?
(Bull's-eye barks)
- Scarce!
Scarce!
Where's Bill?
- He's bleeding.
- What happened?
All in good time.
I can't talk business till I've ate and drank.
Nancy, I said, scarce.
Scarce!
Where's Bill?
Produce the sustenance, if you please.
Dodger.
Nancy, scarce!
- The crack failed.
- I smelt that.
For the last time of asking, where's Bill?
Dodger.
Put him to bed. Give him a nip of gin.
The boy was about to blow on us, Fagey.
He was seen.
Seen? He was seen? Who saw him?
Two old 'uns.
He shouted out.
Bill lost his head. Fired his pistol.
And hit the boy?
I dunno. There was two shots.
Only one was Bill's.
We made a run for it.
I had hold of the boy and Bill fell.
Fell? Was he hurt?
No.
Last seen he was swimming to London.
Hold up.
BILL: I told you not to bring a soul here.
Now you've brought the devil.
You said to fetch him.
His fever's that high, he don't remember nothing.
You're not well, are you, Bill?
How do you feel today?
I'm as weak as water.
Get us a drink.
What evil wind has blowed you here?
No evil wind, my dear.
(Chuckles)
You, Bill. You...you said we need to speak.
What have you done with that boy?
Where is he?
Safe and sound. The Dodger's minding him.
They're as close as Cain and Abel.
What about the boy, Bill?
We don't want anyone peaching on us, do we?
As long as that boy's alive,
we're as good as hung.
FAGIN: So what's to be done?
Nuffink.
"Nuffink."
- Not till I'm better.
- Then what?
- Then I'll do for him.
- How, Bill? Where?
Outside of London somewhere.
I'll find a river and I'll drown him.
The boy is weak.
Bill, he was wounded.
He can hardly stand, let alone walk.
When he can walk, tell me. I'll fetch him.
Now get out of here!
Yes.
Bill,
you're right.
It's for the best.
I'm burning up.
Give me my physic. Where's my physic?
You look like a corpse come back to life again.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
What do you look at me so hard for?
What are you thinking of?
Of many things, Bill. What's in that?
I'll tell you what it is.
If you haven't caught the fever, then
there's something more than usual in the wind.
And something dangerous, too!
Give me my physic, I say.
No, no, no.
There ain't a stauncher-hearted girl going.
Or I'd have cut her throat three months ago.
She's got the fever coming on.
That's it.
Here you are. It'll make you feel better.
Sit aside me.
Put on your own face
or I'll alter it so you won't know it again.
(Bill sighs)
(Snoring)
(Bill stirs)
Wait.
Yes?
Does Mr Brownlow live here?
Who are you? What do you want?
Go round the back.
I have information about Oliver Twist.
Is he all right? Is he safe?
Where is he?
I will only talk to Mr Brownlow.
He's not here.
The boy is innocent. Tell him that.
Where is he?
Safe.
But he may not be for long.
Where is he?
Give Mr Brownlow a message.
Tell him to meet me on Sunday at midnight
on London bridge.
Midnight?
And if I'm not there, tell him to come
the next night and the next.
I'll be there. Tell him.
There, my dear. You look as good as new.
How do you feel?
Tired, sir.
Well, yes, it is...
long after midnight.
Shortly you'll sleep a good sleep,
but my meaning was
how do you feel in yourself, Oliver?
Better. Thank you, sir.
But for the ache in my arm.
Come sit.
I have the very thing
for such pains as yours, my dear.
Undo the bandage.
Ah!
Oh, my God!
It's a nasty wound.
But my magic will do the trick,
you'll see, my dear.
This remedy...
is older than time.
Yes, my dear, older than time.
It was handed down from father to son.
Father to son.
And comes from...
..who can say where?
Thank you, sir.
Thank you...
for your kindness.
I'll always remember it.
Well...
Always.
Yes, always, my dear.
But who knows how long that will be?
(Bell chimes 11 times)
An hour this side of midnight.
Dark and heavy it is, too.
Good night for business, this.
Ah, what a pity, Bill, my dear,
there's none quite ready to be done.
For once you're right.
So, when will the boy be well enough
to go on his travels, then?
FAGIN: Like I say, Bill, in a day or two.
BILL: It's a pity.
For I'm in the humour too.
Does me good to hear you.
You're like yourself tonight, Bill, eh?
Quite like yourself.
Well, I don't feel like myself when you lay
that withered old claw on my shoulder,
so take it away!
Hello, Nance.
And where's the girl going to this time of night?
Not far.
What answer's that? Where are you going?
I say, not far.
- And I say where?
- I dunno where.
Then I do. Nowhere.
Sit down.
I'm not well. I want a breath of air.
Put your head out the window.
There's not enough there. I want it in the street.
(Bull's-eye growls)
Then you won't have it.
There. Now stop quietly where you are, will ya?
Do you know what you're doing?
Do I know what I'm...?
I think this girl's lost her senses.
Are you talking to me in that way?
You'll drive me on to something desperate!
Now, let me go, will ya? This minute!
- This instant!
- No!
Tell him to let me go, Fagin.
It'll be better for him.
Do you hear me?
Aye.
I hear ya.
And if I have to listen to you
for half a minute longer,
the dog will have such a grip on your throat
as he'll tear some of that screaming voice out!
What's come over you, you jade? What is it?
(Tearfully) Bill, let me go!
Let me go!
You don't know what you're doing.
Look, for only one hour.
Cut my limbs off one by one
if I don't think the girl's stark raving mad. Get up.
Get up!
No!
Argh!
(Nancy squeals and whimpers)
BILL: Now stay there!
What a precious strange girl that is.
You may say that, Bill, you may say that.
What do you think she took it
in her head to go out tonight for?
Obstinacy. Women's obstinacy, I suppose.
I thought I tamed her of that.
She's as bad as ever.
I think she's got a touch of my fever
in her blood yet and it won't come out.
Like enough.
If she's taken that way again,
I'll let her a little blood.
Without troubling the doctor!
(Door opens)
(Nancy laughs happily)
Why, now she's on the other tack.
(Nancy giggles)
Good night.
In two days, Bill, come for the boy.
(Nancy chuckles)
BILL: Light him down.
It's a pity he should fall and break his neck
without anyone seeing it.
Show him a light.
What is it, Nancy, dear, the reason for all this?
What do you mean?
That matter just now.
We'll speak of this anon.
You have a friend in me, Nance.
A staunch friend. You know me of old, Nance.
I know you well.
Good night.
Dodge.
Pull it in.
(Coughing)
Trouble.
Dodger!
WOMAN: Shall we both take him home?
Something up?
I...
I want you to do a piece of work for me
that requires great care and caution.
What is it? I ain't going near no police office.
That don't suit me, that don't.
There's not the smallest danger in it,
not the smallest.
I want someone dodged.
Who? An old 'un?
- Young 'un.
- Who is she?
- One of us.
- Who?
- (Fagin mouths)
- Nancy?
Shh!
What's she been up to?
I'm not sure she's been up to anything, my dear.
That's why I want her dodged.
She...
She may have wanted to talk to people
she shouldn't want to talk to.
I want to know where she goes, who she sees,
what she says.
Nancy?
I don't know. She's a good 'un is Nancy.
A pound, my dear.
One whole pound.
Oh!
Mr Brownlow?
Yes.
I'm afraid to speak to you here.
Come away. Follow me.
This is far enough.
Why can't we speak up there?
I told you, I'm afraid.
I may be followed.
I'm here because you told my housekeeper
that you have information
concerning the boy Oliver Twist.
- So I have.
- Tell me.
He's being held by the devil,
and he's handing him over to another what...
means to...
I must know more. Is it someone close to you?
One is.
One ain't.
These men, whoever they are,
must be delivered up by you.
Never.
Bad a life as he has led, I've led a bad life, too,
and I will not turn upon him.
The other.
Fagin.
He has the boy.
- Fagin?
- Find Fagin and you find the boy.
- Where is he?
- Spitalfields.
That's all I'll say. I've said too much.
No-one must never know who told you. Promise.
I promise.
- Tomorrow I'll put the matter before the police.
- No.
You must do it tonight.
Just say Fagin and the traps will know.
- "The traps"?
- The police.
What can I do to serve you?
Nothing.
You can do nothing.
l am past all hope indeed.
MR BROWNLOW: Take this. As a reward.
NANCY: No.
I've not done this for money.
God bless you.
Good night.
Goodbye.
Never,
never say who told you.
FAGIN: Look at him.
What a shame it is.
With his face,
he could pick old ladies' pockets in church.
His face could be a fortune to us.
Are you changing your mind?
No.
No, Bill, it has to be done.
DODGER: Fagin! Fagin!
What's got into you, Dodger?
I have to see Fagin alone.
- No, no, my dear, you can speak in front of Bill.
- No, I can't.
Yes, you can. Speak, Dodger. Tell us.
(Whispers) Nancy...
What about Nancy?
He done a bit of work for me, Bill.
I had him dodge Nancy.
What do you mean?
Tell us, Dodger. You followed her?
Yes.
To London Bridge.
And, what? What at London Bridge?
She met an old 'un. A gentleman.
And...
And? Speak, will ya!
She peached!
She told him Fagin had Oliver!
And the old man wants to go to the traps!
Now, tonight!
(Bill groans)
- Let me go! Let me out!
- Bill! Bill! A word?
Don't speak to me! It's not safe!
Hear me speak a word.
Bill, you won't be...
You won't be too violent, Bill?
Flit, boys, flit! The traps will be at the door
before you can say Spitalfields.
Flit, flit, flit!
Flit!
Come on.
Oh, it's you.
Bill?
What's the matter?
Bill, why do you look like that at me?
There's enough light for what I've got to do.
What... What have I done?
Speak to me!
You know.
You was watched tonight.
Every word you said was heard.
I never said your name, Bill.
Never.
Never...
Bill... Bill.
Bill!
Oh, God have mercy.
Nance?
(Gasps)
(Caws)
I haven't done nothing.
Be off with you.
Hello, Fagey.
Hello, lads.
What's the news, Toby, what's the news?
I have it here, Fagin.
It's all in the Chronicle.
You're in it.
Bill's in it. Oliver's in it.
The Chronicle?
Fancy that, you're famous, Fagin.
Read it.
"More information
has reached your correspondent
concerning the foul and bestial murder
that took place in Spitalfields
and which has shocked and appalled
the citizens of London.
(Toby laughs)
It is believed that the victim,
a young woman, now identified as Nancy,
was brutally beaten to death...
by one William Sykes,
a well-known dangerous villain.
The motive is as yet unclear,
but your correspondent has learned
that the murdered woman
had informed on her associate
and on an infamous fence, Fagin,
who is now wanted for the abduction
of a young boy, Oliver Twist.
(Toby chuckles gleefully)
Neither Fagin nor Sykes
are presently in custody,
but the police are engaged in searching for 'em
throughout the city and beyond.
Sykes, according to the police,
is usually accompanied by a fierce white dog."
How about that, eh?
(Bill whistles)
Come.
Come back here.
We're going back to London.
I'll have people to speak to.
I'll force shiners out of Fagin. Get to France.
Damn me, we'll risk it.
MAN: Who's he done in?
He done in a woman?
(Bill whistles)
Bull's-eye!
Don't you hear me when I whistle?
You gone deaf or something?
Come here. Come on.
I ain't gonna harm you. Come on.
Come on, Bull's-eye. Come here.
Stop it!
I'm warning you! Let go of it!
I ain't playing with you!
Let it go, you stinking varmint!
Bull's-eye!
(Bull's-eye growls)
Bull's-eye.
Get back here! Get back here!
(Bill sighs)
Damn!
Ah, it's his dog.
It's his dog!
Here, boy.
- Here.
- Don't go near him.
There is a child in danger, Inspector Blathers.
But you only seem interested in apprehending
this man William Sykes.
Your concern should be for the safety of the boy.
Allow me to say, sir,
this is our usual way of doing business.
My thinking is this.
If we get Sykes, we get Fagin.
And if we get Fagin...
Sir, we've found the dog.
Are we going to sit here all night
waiting for the traps to find us?
Shut it.
No, he's right.
We should do another flit.
(Knocking)
The traps!
What?
It's him.
DODGER: Don't let him in.
We must.
Go on.
Go on!
Ah, you...
Don't leave us in the dark.
Damn you all.
Have you nothing to say to me?
It's not safe for you to stop here, Bill.
If it's safe for you, it's safe for me.
Is it...
The body, is it buried?
(Barking)
Dodger, let him in, quick.
Dodger.
Do as I say.
DODGER: Don't come near me, you monster.
You're my witnesses. I'm not afraid of him.
And it they come here after him, I'll give him up.
I'll tell 'em you're here.
He may kill me if he likes,
but if I'm here I'll give him up.
If he was to be boiled alive, so I would!
- Why, you little...
- Yargh!
BlLL: I'll tear you limb from limb.
Help! He's here! He's here!
Break down the door!
Help!
Come on, please!
MAN: That's Bill Sykes!
Damn you all! Do your worst! I'll cheat you yet!
No! Bill, no! He's our bargaining tool.
Not yours, Fagin. Mine.
Bill!
(Crowd gasps)
Come on.
- Don't fire.
- Hold your fire, men. Hold your fire.
I'll let the boy go.
I'll let him drop.
Don't try nothing or I'll let him go!
BILL: Grab hold of that! Grab hold of it!
We must give chase, sir.
(Shouting)
Grab it!
(Bill groans)
(Crowd gasps)
(Bull's-eye barks)
(Bull's-eye howls)
MRS BEDWIN: Oliver!
Oliver.
Oliver?
Here he is, sir.
MR BROWNLOW: Come along, my boy!
Mr Grimwig has something to say to you.
Do the honours, Mrs Bedwin.
Now, then, young man,
I confess I misjudged you.
Truth to tell, I feared your benefactor
would make me eat my head.
But he's a good friend and has pardoned me.
MR BROWNLOW: And one for Oliver.
OLIVER: Thank you, sir.
- So...
- And you too, Mrs Bedwin.
- Oh, I don't know as I should, sir.
So, I'll take the liberty, if you'll allow me,
to salute you.
To Sam Waters.
Oliver Twist.
Ah, Oliver Twist.
To Oliver Twist.
Why, Oliver...
my child, what's the matter?
Why are you so sad?
(Hammering)
Are you certain, Oliver,
you wish to go through with this?
Yes, sir.
Certain.
MAN: Yes?
Is the young gentleman to come too, sir?
It's not a sight for children, sir.
It is not indeed, my friend.
But this child has seen this man
in the full career of his success and villainy,
and it is his wish, even at the cost of
some pain and fear, that he should see him now.
18.
Ho, hey!
FAGIN: Good boy.
Good boy, Charley.
Well done.
(Fagin mumbles)
Good boy, Charley, well done. Well done.
Take, take, take the boy away to bed.
Don't be frightened. Fagin.
That's me. An old man, my lord.
A very old, old man.
There's someone here who wants to see you.
Strike! Strike them all dead!
What right have they to butcher me?
Speak to him now. Quick, if you please.
For he grows worse as the time goes on.
Fagin.
You were kind to me.
Yes, yes.
I'll be kind again. I'll be kind again.
I'll be kind again.
I'm not afraid.
Oliver!
(Fagin sobs)
Let me whisper to you.
You remember the box?
Oliver?
With my pretty things for my old age, Oliver?
It's hid a little way up the chimney
in the top front room.
It's yours, Oliver.
Yours.
- But we must talk.
- Yes, yes.
But shall we say a prayer together first?
Do.
Say only one, upon your knees.
With me.
And we can talk all morning.
Outside. Outside.
You can say I've gone to sleep
and they'll believe you.
You can get me out
and the pretty things are yours, my dear. Yours!
Oh, God, forgive this wretched man.
That's right.
That's right. That will help us on.
If... If... If...
If I shake and tremble as we pass the gallows,
don't...don't...
..don't you mind, hurry on.
Now, now, now.
WARDER: Have you more to say to him, sir?
- Nothing more.
- You'd better leave him.
Press on, press on. Press on.
Press on, press on.
Softly, softly. No, no, slow.
Faster.
Faster, faster!
Faster! Faster!
Faster!
(Fagin howls)