I've been in the marketplace,
trading.
You're both terrible liars.
(Laughter)
- We are best heading north.
- We double back on ourselves,
pick up the trade winds and head
off to Shanti,
a place where everyone has a past
and nobody asks questions.
Sounds a delight.
(Thud)
Sinbad: We've been hit!
- Anwar: We must have hit coral.
- There is no coral in these waters.
Rocks then.
What are you doing?
Are you insane?
Never get off the boat,
not at sea.
We need to know
what state she's in.
What was that?
I saw something!
- Get him up. Get him up!
- Gunnar: Pull! Pull!
(Grunting)
I don't see him!
He's not there.
Sinbad!
Sync, corrected by icephoenix
www.addic7ed.com
(Gasp)
(Panting)
(Splutters)
(Coughing)
(Gasping and panting)
- You can thank me later.
- What for?
Oh, I don't know.
Saving your life?
Come on.
You weren't hard to spot.
It was the screaming
that really did it.
Make yourself comfortable.
I'm making something for your wounds.
I'm Sinbad, by the way.
Hello, Sinbad.
Okay.
(Pained hiss)
Sorry.
- Coral can really sting.
- Coral?
- That was a shark.
- A shark?
Yeah. Some kind of sea beast
or something.
- A sea beast?
- Yeah? What?
In these waters?
Well, at least your humour survived.
(Laughs)
Let's see.
I'd love to stay, really,
really I would,
but I have a ship and
a crew waiting for me.
Whoa!
Welcome to the island of
Roisin Moor.
- You?
- Mm-hm.
Doesn't that get lonely?
I entertain myself.
(Laughs)
Gunnar, we're wasting our time.
We need to be searching the water.
The current dragged us here.
Perhaps it dragged Sinbad here, too.
We're not dealing
with currents or tides.
I know what I saw down there!
A great tail, scales.
It severed the rope.
Then pray we find him first.
(Frustrated sigh)
Ah!
(Thud)
We thought we'd lost you.
Oh! You found me.
You think we'd leave you?
(Laughs)
How did you make it here?
The gods were
looking out for you.
Ah, I just have an instinct for survival.
(Gunnar laughs)
And let me just say straight off,
I don't blame any of you
for what happened.
I took the risk, I know.
It's just that sometimes,
being the hero's
a tough place to be.
Aha, I see.
Perhaps you could define hero.
(Laughs)
(Water trickling)
- So, you're here alone?
- With the odd guest.
Not alone. I'm free.
Here there's no one to tell me
what to do or when to do it.
You look tired, Sinbad.
We should get you back.
Yes, and no more swimming,
not until you've practiced.
Sinbad: I think I had it
under control.
Think you didn't.
(Laughs)
Your hospitality is kind, but we have
a long journey ahead of us.
Well, may your journey be
full of adventure and excitement
that leaves you breathless for more.
- I need to eat.
- Good.
Cook will make you something.
Here.
Roisin: Of course.
(Laughs)
May I?
I don't know what you think you're doing
in there, but it ends now, okay?
Have you forgotten
who we're running from?
Nala, she saved my life.
And we risk ours
every moment we waste.
I can't keep living like this.
I mean, we're not even living at all.
We're running.
Every day we're running,
scared of dying.
Do you think Akbari is chatting over wine,
debating the meaning of life?
He will find us.
Then go without me.
If that's how you feel, just go,
get on with your lives and
let me get on with mine.
I'm cursed, Nala. Me.
It's me who has to live with it,
not you. I'm staying.
For a desert island,
you sure have a lot of trinkets.
Yeah. You'd be amazed
what washes up here.
Nala: Gunnar?
We've gone to hell for you.
One night, one night
where I don't feel like me.
- You understand that, Gunnar, right?
- Yeah.
And I want to write poetry,
but life's a bitch and you're cursed.
Thank you.
Be on the ship by first light,
or believe me, hero,
we'll go without you.
Look, the last thing I want to do is
cause trouble with your friends.
- If you want to go, then go.
- No, no, no, really.
But I will have to leave soon.
As long as I'm back by dawn.
I mean, not that I want to
rush anything.
(Laughs)
I should hope not.
Not on your last night of freedom.
I want to know the life I saved.
Tell me everything.
Could be some kind of bone.
Pressure of the water must have
forced it through.
I've never seen any creature
that would belong to.
Save your concern, Rina.
Sinbad's alive and well.
So, I have a problem with Nala.
(Laughs)
You're not alone in that.
Anyway, I don't want to talk
about Nala.
Well, indulge me.
I am dying
for some conversation.
(Laughs)
Okay.
It was Basra, so crowded,
you couldn't move,
so hot,
you couldn't breathe.
I was with my...
Nala... was the only person who
did not weaken by the heat.
The dust.
She was like an angel.
Tell me about Gunnar.
I am starting to think that
you only want me for my mind.
He had these scratches on his chest,
four, I think.
- Other than that, he was...
- Stay away from the water tonight.
I don't like how it feels.
(Thud)
The thing that drove us here,
it's still down there.
He knows how to lift the spirits,
doesn't he?
Sinbad. Wake up.
It's nearly dawn.
Your friends are waiting.
Gunnar and Nala, remember?
(Sighs)
I've never heard those names.
We go to sleep now.
Okay.
(Clicking)
(Coughing)
Help me, please.
- What's happening?
- The curse.
The curse?
(Grunting)
I have to get off the island!
Who did this to you?
My grandmother.
She cursed me
because I betrayed her.
A curse in the moment of anger,
that's not hatred.
That's her pain.
- Your grandmother loves you.
- Hate, definitely hates me.
Think back, Sinbad,
to the time before the curse,
a time when you knew you were loved.
Think. I can help you, Sinbad.
Tell me a happy memory
and the curse will go.
(Gasping)
Every night,
she used to tell me the stories of Arabia,
of the legends.
She told me, above all those in the stories,
that I was her hero.
And then I broke her heart.
What have you done?
(Coughing)
No, good memories only!
Not bad memories.
(Coughing)
Stories of Arabia,
tell me one now,
the ones your grandmother told you.
My grandmother?
I never knew her.
(Panting)
I bring news, my lord.
Sinbad is no ordinary man.
He's surrounded by magic.
You insult the memory of my son.
Sinbad is nothing,
least of all magic.
A curse from an ancestor,
his grandmother.
It binds to him like a river weed.
We need only find the source and,
inch by inch, we will draw him in.
We've already tried.
Every guard in Basra
has been searching for her.
Your ways.
I have others.
(Clunking in distance)
- Go easy with the paprika.
- So easy with the advice.
Please don't tell me how to make gulyasleves.
I grew up with this.
For a while, anyway.
Rina, it's past sunrise.
Sinbad may not be coming back.
(Chopping)
- Nala: Rina, he's not coming.
- Then I'll bring him back.
On this ship at dawn.
He knew that.
And he knows what will happen
if Akbari finds us.
- He has a curse!
- He's made a choice.
So we just let him die?
He knows his own mind, Rina.
As you do yours.
So go, try and bring him back.
Anwar, if the curse has taken hold,
he will need you. Hurry.
Waiting puts us all in danger.
(Sighs)
Ah. I've never felt so alive!
That's good. Because we are
going on a big walk,
an adventure. I'm going to take
you to a very special place.
It's so beautiful and happy
that nothing bad on Earth
could ever touch it.
Okay, let's go.
Let's go.
Don't touch me.
Get your hands off me.
Get your hands off me!
Fish bladder, delicious.
You're bleeding again.
Ah, it's that damn...
Nala: What's wrong, Cook?
- Four scratches you said?
- What?
Would've been five if this
hadn't got stuck in the hull.
Always the way.
At least try to make some sense.
This is no bone.
This is a fingernail.
(Laughs)
Right. So we're looking for a giant
sea beast with a missing fingernail?
A place of shining treasures,
song of enchantment: Siren.
There was no song.
Can we please get back to--
No, no, Roisin was singing, in her cabin.
If you hadn't called me--
It wasn't a woman in the water.
Oh, that demon's
whatever she needs to be.
Take human form long enough
to harvest every good memory he has.
Piece by piece,
she takes his mind until he is drained.
Not a man anymore:
An empty shell on the beach.
Just the sound of wind in his head.
What's the rush?
I thought we were
masters of our own destiny.
Yeah.
We have to be there before sunset.
Just like my... someone I knew.
Stickler for timekeeping.
Someone you either loved so much,
you can't bear to speak their name,
or someone you hated and want to forget?
- Loved.
- Ah.
My brother, Jamil,
my greatest friend.
- And he was never late?
- Oh, no.
Even the cockerel went by him.
(Laughter)
And he'd always let me sleep in
as long as possible.
"Brother, when you're asleep,
you're not in any trouble,"
that's what he used to say.
Jamil! No!
He should have left me asleep.
(Coughing)
Something doesn't feel right.
(Choking cough)
I feel like I've lost something.
I can't remember.
I can't remember!
Sinbad!
Still hot.
Bed's been slept in. Still warm.
Water retains heat for at least an hour.
Body temperature's lower, would remain
constant for a shorter length of time.
He was here within last half-hour.
I think Sinbad's alive.
He survived the curse.
- What is that?
- Rina, move. Run! Run!
Pull out my teeth, put out my eyes.
I will never give him up.
Oh, you won't need to.
You cursed too well.
Sinbad is forever connected to you,
like a heartbeat.
And so you will find him.
Beware my curse, Taryn.
Yours is not the strongest magic in Basra.
I didn't understand it at first,
what I felt when I saw your grandson.
That such things could still be possible!
(Laughs)
(Sighs)
- That thing, it was a ghost?
- Not possible. They don't exist.
(Screaming)
(Thud)
What?
Come on, Sinbad,
we're nearly there now.
Wait, wait. What are you doing to me?
No, no, I don't feel like me.
Because you're tasting freedom.
(Laughs)
Come on, nobody can resist this place,
not even you.
And I'm a real stickler for timekeeping,
just like my brother.
You have a brother?
Jamil, my greatest friend.
Jamil, that name.
What about you?
Any brothers or sisters?
Uh...
I thought I had someone.
You do, my darling.
You have me.
All men.
Bone density puts them in their early 20s,
which rules out age-related tooth loss.
Remember Sinbad,
the man we came to find?
Yet they've all got teeth missing.
Doesn't make any sense.
Yes, it does.
Found them in her cabin.
We've got to get to Sinbad!
(Gasping)
- That's Lord Akbari.
- This is my nightmare, ghosts.
I don't think they're ghosts.
I mean, Akbari's not dead, is he?
And even if he was,
what would he be doing here?
Does nothing makes sense?
Has he lost his mind?
Lost his mind?
Come on,
let's get out of here.
Something is stealing his memories.
I'll explain,
but we've got to find Sinbad.
You asked for me, brother?
You think I would not hear
of Taryn's return?
Or your growing obsession now turns
to egregious assault and blood,
and now to kidnapping.
- You mistake my age for apathy.
- And you mistake my pain for obsession.
Since you find it impossible to give up your mage,
you may keep her.
I'm grateful for that, my Lord.
Though my methods may be questionable,
I assure you my motive is sound.
And you will go with her from Basra,
from Arabia.
You will settle in a part of this world
so far from here,
so far from the goodness I'm building,
you may live out your lives
in black-hearted abandon.
But you will never claim my title
or my affections in this lot.
My Lord, I beg you, not this.
You're dead to me, Akbari.
I've written it so.
You, who claim such humanity,
you can build a thousand schools of learning,
but you'll never know the workings of a heart.
Be gone by nightfall.
(Grunt)
If we've been together for so many years
then why haven't I seen this place before?
But you have, my love. Remember?
This is my sacred temple.
No.
- Give me the key.
- This can't be it.
- Not just us.
- But my darling, it is.
It's me and it's you.
That's what life is.
No, no, it's not. I have family,
friends, a mother.
- A mother? Where?
- I don't know where. I just feel it.
You have no one.
No one but me.
Give me the key.
Come on.
No! I'm not alone.
- I'm loved.
- My love.
(Smack)
(Thud)
(Sighs)
You're alone, just like me.
My lord, we must move quickly.
- This cannot look like murder.
- Let it look like what it is.
My son is dead.
I'm a murderer.
I've lost everything I ever loved.
Call the guards.
Your ways have taken me
so far from who I am,
I can never get back.
Let me give you what you need.
You as emir,
Sinbad in your grasp.
You're grieving.
Let me help you.
Let me make this all better.
Anwar: Come on.
- It's locked.
- What, you were expecting a welcome party?
(Gasps)
It's okay. Come on, you're okay.
Where...
- I need your help, my love.
- Call me by my name.
If you want your name,
remember your mother.
She's the one who named you.
We were just talking about her.
What was she like?
- You think I'll find my name with her?
- Yes.
She lost her mind when I was born.
What?
There are no stories.
There's nothing to tell.
There's nothing?
Hurry up.
If you have nothing good to
tell me...
You and I must part.
Stop! Let him live and
I will give you my memories.
- Your life for his?
- It's a beautiful story.
Don't you want to hear it?
Happy memories from my childhood.
Rina, she's stolen his memories,
she'll do the same to you.
Your parents loved you very much?
I was more precious to them than gold.
And they loved me very much.
One morning we began our great adventure.
To the house of a great man,
so rich even his servants had servants.
What he didn't have was happiness.
This man, he had no children of his own,
and he longed to hear laughter
in his enormous house.
- Let him go.
- Tell me all of your story.
- Let Sinbad go.
- Sinbad...
Tell me all of your story.
- Why are you doing this for me?
- Because we love you.
- Tell me all of your story.
- He didn't want to hear laughter.
- And he didn't need another servant.
- Roisin: No bad memories!
He wanted a living thing to own forever.
He bought me and made me his slave.
- No, you promised me happy memories!
- Keep this memory!
(Screams)
It was my family who sold me.
(Muffled scream)
And I never saw them again!
(Gasps)
(Grunt)
Rina.
(Sighs)
It's so good to see you.
Thank you.
Can we please get out of here now?
- Sinbad, they're your memories.
- My memories?
The bad ones, the ones she couldn't handle.
It's good you don't have them, come on.
- She's right.
- No, no.
It's better without them.
No more nightmares.
They're a part of me.
I want my life back.
(Gasps)
No, Sinbad, not your grandmother.
There's a curse!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for what I did.
(Gasps)
We've got to go.
We need to get you off land.
(In gruff voice)
Help me. Sinbad... Help me.
Sinbad, help me...
Help me...
Rina.
About what you said earlier.
Don't tell me you believed it too.
- Mm, these gulya...
- Sleves.
- Best I've ever had.
- Mm!
- Rina: Thank you.
- Cook, take the tiller.
I've spent so long wanting to be
anybody but me,
so I wouldn't have
the pain or the memories.
But I wouldn't
trade them for a second.
So, that's really your type?
Needy?
(Laughs)
And I have always had
a thing about long nails.
- Help me... Sinbad.
- Grandma?
- Help me!
- Dark powers. A trick!
- I have to go back home.
- Put it from your mind.
- Forget you saw it.
- Could you?
She's my family. I have to.
You heard the man.
Let's get to it.
Sync, corrected by icephoenix
www.addic7ed.com