My bleeding feet!
Hello, Mrs. Joseph.
I like your hair.
Is that strawberry blonde?
You're only jealous.
What's for the old man's
supper tonight?
He'll be lucky to get
faggots and pease pudd, he will.
Well, he can't do much
on that, can he?
All I want him for
is to keep me feet warm.
Excuse me, dearie.
Here, Gert.
I wouldn't mind having this little lot
in my stocking for Christmas.
What would you do with him?
You've been a widow too long.
You speak for yourself.
It's like riding a bicycle.
You never forget how.
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I'll send my Alfie to you.
He's not bad once he gets going.
Well, I hope he's well-sprung.
Morning.
Looking for someone, mate?
Nice day, isn't it?
Sorry.
Hackman's in the staff room.
Where he bleeding well belongs.
Good morning.
My name is Thackeray.
I'm a new teacher.
We were expecting you.
So you're the new lamb
for the slaughter.
Or should I say...
...black sheep?
No, just a teacher, Mr. Hackman.
I'm not Hackman.
Perish the thought.
He's departed,
God rest his soul.
He's probably pouring out his woes
to the divisional officer by now.
Weston.
I'm Mrs. Evans, Grace.
Deputy head.
Mrs. Evans.
Have you seen any children yet?
I looked in on Mr. Hackman's class
for a moment.
I take them for domestic science.
Like a cup of tea?
No, thank you, not just now.
You been teaching long?
This is my first appointment.
We call them jobs.
American, are you?
British, from British Guiana.
But I spent some years
in the States.
- Where?
- In California.
Weather as good as they say?
It's better.
What was your subject?
What did you major in?
Engineering.
I must be off.
Make yourself at home.
Wander around, if you like,
or stay here.
I'll introduce you at lunch.
Thank you.
This is Gillian, Mr. Thackeray.
Gillian Blanchard.
She's new here too.
Came the day before yesterday.
- Tea, Gillian?
- Thank you.
This is Mr. Mark Thackeray,
the new replacement.
Jose Dawes,
Euphemia Phillips.
They teach the little ones.
Theo Weston, you know.
I've had the pleasure.
He mistook me for Hackman.
- He's fled.
- I don't blame him.
That's enough to destroy anybody.
He got what he deserved.
I'm Clinty Clintridge.
Clinty's a marvelous artist.
Got one at the Royal Academy
a couple of years ago.
Teaching provides the bread and butter.
Well, that's all the staff
except for Mr. Bell...
...our P.T. Instructor.
I hope you're
going to stay with us.
I shouldn't if I were you, old man.
Row home while you can.
Don't discourage him, Weston.
Well, I must go.
I have to fix a bath
for a girl in Clinty's class.
Why?
Kids complained again.
Won't sit near her.
What's the matter?
Personal hygiene problems.
Fourteen and helpless.
You men are lucky.
The things we women have to do
for these kids.
Gillian, dear...
...encourage him to stay.
Why is it everyone thinks
I need encouraging?
They said the same to me.
There's something frightening but
also challenging about this school.
There's no form of corporal
punishment or any punishment.
None?
I have no real teaching experience.
I'm lost.
I don't have any experience either.
But it'll be much easier for you.
I'm a little afraid of them.
Midday dance session.
At lunch, the older kids use the hall.
I sometimes join them.
Even the old man shakes a leg.
Dancing is merely their way
of keeping fit...
...for the more exciting pastime
of teacher baiting.
Couldn't you be
a bit less discouraging?
It's the last thing I want to do.
The music's louder than usual.
They're probably celebrating
victory over Hackman.
I better go and see Mr. Florian.
I'll show you the way.
- They're good, aren't they?
- I suppose so.
The head's study is this way.
Do you two...
Do you two shake?
Well, I'll see you later,
Mr. Thackeray.
Well?
Thank you.
But I have to go
and see the principal.
You have excellent qualifications,
astonishing ones, in fact...
...as a communications engineer.
Field experience in South America...
Why do you want to be a teacher?
Reasons.
You've already tried to get
an engineering post?
I tried for 18 months, sir.
We have no blueprint in North Quay.
Most of our children are
rejects from other schools.
We must help and teach them
as best we can...
...and as much as we can.
The local authorities are not
totally on our side.
And if you accept this position,
you'll be entirely on your own.
I and the staff will do
everything we can to help you...
...but success or failure
will depend entirely upon you.
What's it to be?
I want the job, sir.
Good.
Then it's settled.
Tomorrow, you'll take over
Hackman's class.
Sapiano.
Wong.
Osgood.
Tuffen.
Pegg.
Pegg?
Joseph.
Dare.
Potter.
Denham.
Buckley.
Purcell.
Fernman.
Jackson.
Strong.
Seales.
- Palmer.
- Yes, Guvnor.
Campbell.
Present.
I don't know how much you know,
so we'll start from scratch.
First, as I call your name...
...will you read anything you like
from one of your schoolbooks?
Fernman.
Right.
"Only those who...
...arrived on...
...horseback...
...or in a public coach. "
- Thank you.
Denham.
"If 14 hens lay an egg
a day for 30 days...
...how much are the eggs a dozen,
and how many have you to sell?"
Moira Joseph.
"Pete Gilroy's weight
and the ever-tightening noose...
...about her neck...
...began slightly to impede
the wild mare's speed.
But Pete was only too fully aware
of what his fate would be...
...for he could not hope
to escape death...
...from being battered and crushed. "
Put that away, please.
Thank you.
Would anyone else like to read?
- Your name, please.
- Pamela Dare.
"And he had learned to love.
I know not why...
...for this in such as him
seemed strange of mood.
But thus it was.
And though
in solitude's small part...
...the nipped affections
have to grow.
In him this glowed...
...when all beside
had ceased to glow. "
Thank you, Miss Dare.
Next, weights and measures.
What's avoirdupois?
- Avoir de what?
- Avoirdupois.
Weights.
Heavyweight, light-heavy,
cruiserweight...
...middle, light, bantam,
fly, featherweight.
Thank you very much.
It's encouraging that
you have a sense of humour.
It seems you know so little
and are easily amused...
...I can look forward to a happy time.
Copy down the following tables.
Who does he think he is, there?
The cheeky devil.
Hello, ducks.
Thought you might need this.
How'd it go?
Let's just say, battle was joined.
I don't know what we'd do
without a cuppa.
What's your name?
I know that.
I mean, your other name.
Mark.
Couple of things, Mark.
We all know the old man's views.
Basically, we agree with them.
But he's safe in an office.
These kids come from homes where
an order is accompanied by a blow.
One rude word to their parents,
the roof will hit them.
There's nothing like that
going on here, right?
So they've got us
at a great disadvantage.
Hackman tried to be popular.
He hung himself.
Weston couldn't care less
about them, and that's no good.
I can't guide you...
...but don't take any nonsense
from these little tykes.
They're good kids, Mark,
most of them.
But if you don't solve them,
they'll break you and damn quickly.
That's been tried...
...by experts.
They're very expert.
Please can I leave the room, Guv?
Yes. And it's "Thackeray. "
Yes, Guv.
Most of you girls help your mothers
with the shopping.
So sorry, Mr. Thackeray.
Proper drafty in these parts,
isn't it?
About multiplying...
...there are a few
valuable tricks to know.
Say that you're offered roast beef
at seven shillings per pound.
Potter.
Must you do that?
I can't help it, Sir.
It's me desk.
Poor old Potts!
Sit down.
I'll speak with the caretaker
about it after school.
Isn't he nice?
I hope I didn't miss nothing.
Where was we?
About shopping or some...?
That's enough, Denham.
I was only asking, Mr. Thackeray.
I don't wanna miss nothing.
Bert, he was just about to show us
a new and valuable trick.
- When you're shopping, you see...
- I said, that's enough.
Sit down.
Do exercise four, five and six.
Very quietly.
Don't worry.
The worst is still to come.
You're still getting
the silent treatment.
What's the next phase?
Well, unless you can work up
a little black magic...
...these little bastards have
a multitude of tricks.
Why did you take up teaching?
It's good to have some kind of a job.
But I'm teaching them nothing.
I'm not even getting to first base.
Don't worry,
your lot leaves this term.
The next will be better.
They'll be just as bad.
Probably worse.
What's your answer?
What they need...
...is a bloody good hiding.
I feel rather sorry for them,
you know?
Most of them can hardly read.
You're so naive,
my dear old colleague.
They'll be earning twice as much
as us before you can shake a stick.
They'll happily be part
of the great London unwashed:
Illiterate...
...smelly...
...and quite content.
An education's a disadvantage
in this day and age.
That is ridiculous!
But still true.
So you'd better start
brushing up...
...on your voodoo if you wish
to remain sane.
Good morning.
All right, take your seats.
- All right, Sir?
- I hope you didn't hurt yourself.
You all right?
Cheap stuff they're selling nowadays.
Want me to help, Sir?
Sit down.
Take your proper places.
We can move around here,
you know, Sir.
Take your proper places.
Beg your pardon.
Something the matter?
Seales, is something wrong?
It's me mum.
She's awful sick.
I'm sorry.
Anything I can do?
Nothing.
- She's English.
- I see.
You're like my old man,
except bigger and younger.
Rotten bastard!
You shouldn't speak like that.
You know nothing.
I hate him!
Why not?
Never forgive him for
what he did to me mum. Never!
He married her, didn't he?
Didn't he?!
Today, let's take a look
at South America.
I'm sorry, Mr. Fackeray.
The bloody things just slipped.
The name is Thackeray,
and they are not "bloody things. "
They were a pile of books.
That's a good netting score.
Pam, luv, that's not a bloody pile,
but it's a pile of books.
All right, settle down.
I was only trying to help,
Mr. Thackeray, Sir.
That's right, Mr. Thackeray.
Curley was only trying to put
that little scrubber in her place.
I know what Curley was trying to do.
Now, just settle down.
We are going to study
South America.
Now turn to page 37
in your geography book.
"They were alone...
...but not alone as they who
shut in chambers think it loneliness.
The voiceless sand and the drooping
caves that lay around them...
...made them to each other press as if
there were no life beneath the sky... "
Sorry, luv.
It's the bleeding desk.
You speak such words
to your father?
You're not my bleeding father!
All I want to know is,
who does he think he is?
Mate, shut up!
Morning.
Hello, Thackeray.
How goes it?
Fine, thank you, sir.
All you boys, out!
The girls stay where they are.
What's the matter?
Out!
Out at once!
All right.
I am sick of your foul language...
...your crude behaviour
and your sluttish manner.
A decent woman keeps
some things private.
Only a filthy slut
would have done this!
Those who encouraged her
are bad too!
I don't care who's responsible!
You're all to blame!
I'm leaving for five minutes,
by which time...
...that disgusting object
had better be removed!
And open the windows
to clear the stench!
If you must play these filthy games,
do them in your homes...
...and not in my classroom!
What's the matter?
Man, oh, man!
I lost my temper. The one thing
I swore I would never do.
God, did I lose my temper!
What happened?
After all the bull
I've taken in my life...
...in a few short weeks,
those kids have got me so steamed up...
...so easy, so quickly.
I never would have thought it.
- Perhaps you're trying too hard.
- Those kids are devils incarnate.
I tried everything. Everything!
But nothing I tried...
Kids.
That's it!
Those are out.
They are useless to you.
I realized you are not children.
You will be adults in a few weeks,
with all the responsibilities.
From now on, you will be treated
as such by me and by each other...
...as adults.
Responsible adults.
Next, we'll be reasonable
with each other.
We are just going to talk,
you and I.
You will listen
without interruption.
And when I am finished,
one of you may have your say...
...without interruptions.
Next...
What a morning!
Everything's gone wrong.
The alarm didn't go off.
Then I had to wait hours for a bus.
I must've stood there
three bleeding hours...
Example:
There are two ways to enter a room.
One is like an adult,
a lady with dignity.
The other is like a brat.
Miss Dare's shown the second way.
Perhaps you'd demonstrate the first?
I'm sorry I'm late.
Next...
...we are all going to observe
certain courtesies in this classroom.
You will call me
Sir or Mr. Thackeray.
The young ladies will be
addressed as Miss...
...the boys by their surnames.
Why should we call them Miss?
We know them.
I beg your pardon?
I said, why should we
call them Miss, Sir?
We know them.
Is there a young lady you feel...
...does not deserve to be
addressed as Miss?
- No, Sir.
- Good.
Next, general deportment.
First, the young ladies.
They must prove worthy of
the courtesies we'll show them.
Soon boyfriends and marriage
will concern you.
No man likes a slut for long.
Only the worst type will marry one.
And the competition for men
on the outside is rough.
Next, men.
I've seen garbage collectors
who are cleaner.
Toughness is a quality
of the mind...
...like bravery,
honesty and ambition.
If you want to wear your hair long,
clean it...
...else you'll soon get lice and smell.
Soon your principle interest
will be girls.
You will be more attractive
with clean clothes, shoes...
...hands, face, teeth, et cetera.
Any questions?
Miss Pegg.
What about Mr. Weston, Sir?
He's never tidy, his shoes is
never brushed and his hair's a mess.
It's filthy.
Mr. Weston is not your teacher.
We won't discuss him.
I'm the one to criticize
if I fail to maintain the standards.
That's not fair.
Sir...
...or Mr. Thackeray.
Didn't you understand?
That's not fair...
...Sir.
I agree.
But it's an example of things
you'll have to put up with as an adult.
You'll just have to take it.
Next, we are going to talk
about various...
Good morning.
- I wanted to see how you were doing.
- Fine, thank you.
Good.
Thank you.
What is it?
Palmer?
What are we gonna talk about, Sir?
About life...
...survival...
...love...
...death, sex, marriage...
...rebellion, anything you want.
I never did see one like him, Pam.
Even when he blew his stack,
no swearing or nothing.
Blimey!
Ain't natural, that's what.
Does he really mean what he says?
I don't know.
It'd be a change, though, to see
those creeps acting like gents.
Here, which one do you fancy?
I like Babs.
Yeah? Watch this.
- Come on, Pam, luv.
- Get lost, Denham!
I don't like
your smelly tricks, do I?
And it's Miss Dare to you.
Get stuffed.
Come on then, luv.
You heard what Sir said,
Mr. Smarty Denham.
If you want to dance with me,
you bleeding well ask proper.
May I have the pleasure
of this dance, Miss Pegg?
Blimey!
Good old Potts.
Get you, Potter.
Shut up!
Who does he think he is,
bleeding Fred Astaire?
Come on, Miss Pegg.
Look at me.
I am a lady, I am.
Rotten tarts, all of them.
Chimney sweep was right about that.
He won't catch me
spending me nicker on them.
He said we could talk about anything.
You are so right, Tich, mate.
He did say
we could ask him anything.
Questions and answers.
Last night on the telly,
there was this travelogue picture.
You know, a lot of black women
dancing around with no tops.
Don't they ever dress proper?
What's proper varies
throughout the world...
...depending on
customs and climate.
For their climate and customs,
they were dressed properly.
Are you from South Africa?
Of course not.
South Africans is white, isn't they?
A South African is a native
of South Africa, regardless of colour.
I was born in British Guiana.
What did you mean the other day
about rebellion, Sir?
Change.
Take your hairstyles.
That's a form of rebellion, isn't it?
What, Sir?
Don't you do it
to be different from adults?
They've messed up the world,
haven't they?
- You can say that again.
- So you rebel.
Even the way you dress is
a form of rebellion, isn't it?
It's just the new fashion, Sir.
Of course, the adults look
proper stupid in our gear.
Do you think it's wrong
to be different, to rebel?
It is your duty to change
the world, if you can.
Not by violence.
Peacefully, individually,
not as a mob.
Take the Beatles.
They started a huge social revolution.
The fashions they set in dress...
...and hairstyles are worldwide now.
Every new fashion...
...is a form of rebellion.
There's an exhibit
of costumes through the ages...
...at the Victoria
and Albert Museum.
I think you should see it.
Also, you should see
the Museum of Natural History.
What, us lot go to a museum?
- Sure.
- You're joking.
You'll discover that
your hairstyles are 200 years old...
...and that your costumes
or your dress...
...is right out of 1920.
Shut up!
Look, Sir, when can we go?
There's no time after school,
and I've got to look after the kids.
I have to do the housework
and get the supper for the lodgers.
Me mum's expecting a baby any day,
and I got to babysit.
Why don't you take us?
We could go in the morning.
Who would like that?
What a drag!
Don't you want a day off?
Put your hand up.
- Put both hands up.
- Fat chance!
It wouldn't work.
It's not the sort of risk
we'd dare to take at North Quay.
I would like to try, Sir.
The best of pupils are inclined
to show off in public.
Your class?
You'd never be able
to supervise them.
When I took this job,
you said you wouldn't interfere...
...as long as I stayed
within your framework.
If you can get another
staff member to go with you...
...I'll approach the council.
I see little hope of approval.
Thank you, Sir.
Miss Blanchard, I think I can
arrange an outing with my class...
...if I can get
another teacher to go along.
I'd love to.
And it's Gillian.
When is the outing?
When we get travel warrants
and permission.
Just let me know when.
Thanks, Gillian. Bye.
Good morning.
What would you like
to talk about today?
Ladies first.
Miss Joseph.
Marriage, Sir.
You know, boyfriends and things.
How do you know he's the right one?
What to look for.
How to avoid divorce.
Don't get married.
Where's Miss Purcell?
She's to look after the home.
Her mum had the baby last night.
What hospital?
No hospital, Sir.
The doctor came to her.
She all right?
Well, she just had a kid.
Didn't she?
Now, marriage.
First, let us lay some ground rules.
I've never been married,
so what I say is as an outsider.
Now, what should a girl
look for in a man?
I think first we ought
to determine what is marriage.
Miss Joseph.
Holy wedlock.
Potter, be serious.
You'll get your turn.
Miss Pegg.
It's life, isn't it, Sir?
Everyone gets married.
I mean, sometime.
Why didn't you?
No one would have him.
I was very poor.
There was something in me
that wanted an education...
...so I put all of
my energies into that.
Well, I got started later.
Just never met the right girl.
What should a girl
look for in a man?
- Miss Clark?
- What work did you do, Sir?
I waited tables.
I cooked in a hamburger joint.
I washed dishes for a time, cars.
For a year I was a janitor
in an apartment block.
- Lots of jobs.
- You washed dishes?
I did.
But you talk posh.
- That wasn't easy.
- You didn't always talk like that?
When I was your age, I used a patois,
a kind of simple English.
I going bust your booby
if you don't get up off of this...
I didn't understand a word.
Well, I don't always understand
what you say either.
If you work hard,
you can do almost anything.
You can get any job you want.
You can even...
You can even change your speech
if you want to.
After I got my degree, I worked
in South America for an oil company.
The only women in that region...
...were jungle Indians who carried
blowpipes and poison darts.
You could have broke my hands.
We were discussing marriage.
To my mind, marriage is
no way of life for the weak...
...the selfish...
...or the insecure.
What's the matter, Weston?
These damn fool Americans!
They bog up everything
they're connected with.
What a shower!
I'll never forgive the President
for missing Churchill's funeral...
...nor sending the vice president.
Rotten manners.
- It was very naughty.
- I quite agree.
A typically stupid, appalling
and unnecessary mistake.
- What can you expect?
- Still beefing?
Give them a chance.
They've not been leading the world...
...as long as Britain has.
You continue to astonish me,
old chum.
I should've thought
if anyone took a point...
Now what?
Miss Pegg wants to know
if the netball's fixed.
Miss who?
Barbara Pegg.
Miss Pegg, Sir.
Here you are, Fernman.
Thank you, Sir.
What's going on in
this classroom of yours?
Suburban formality? It's a bit
foreign in this neck of the woods.
Some sort of experiment
in culture for the masses?
It's an elementary
experiment in courtesy.
And do we ignorant critters
have to follow suit?
- Please yourself.
- Thank goodness for that!
Do you object to being
taught manners by the boys?
I won't to be taught
by those morons.
So long as we learn,
it doesn't matter who teaches us.
Good afternoon, everybody.
Now we're talking.
Nothing like payday.
By the way, your museum visit
has been approved.
If things go wrong,
the school suffers.
Nothing will go wrong, Sir.
For a moment, I thought
I was in the wrong classroom.
Where's Jackson?
We don't know.
Tich wouldn't miss this
unless he was sick or something.
We'll give him a few minutes.
It's me, Jackson.
I have to take the wash for mum.
Can you wait?
Sure.
How long will it take?
Half a mo.
Just up the frog.
God love you.
Hang on, Tich.
I'll give you a hand.
All right.
Back on the sidewalk.
What's a frog got to do with it?
It's rhyming slang.
Old-fashioned cockney.
It's only used by old people now.
It's a drag, Sir.
Frog means road.
Frog and toad, road.
Trouble, strife, wife.
Weeping willow, pillow.
The first word.
Like the old currant bun,
that's the sun.
- Apples and pears, stairs.
- Happy kill, skill.
Ginger beer, queer.
All aboard.
I think he fancies her.
I know you do.
Pamela has a crush on you.
Women say the damnedest things.
I think he's nice.
So do I.
You've noticed.
I treat her as I do
the other girls.
I hope we can go out again,
don't you?
I hope so.
I hope we can go with him,
because he's nice.
Don't be mistaken...
...Pamela's a woman
in every sense of the word.
I mean...
...not that I blame her.
Bleeding rotten taste he's got.
Good night, Sir.
- See you tomorrow.
- Good night.
Perhaps I could tidy your desk.
- That's all right.
- It's no trouble.
You should get a flat nearby.
Brentwood's much too far away.
- There's nice ones around.
- I've thought of it.
I tell you what.
I'll keep my ears open for you.
That's kind of you,
but I'm fine.
I'll let you know.
Thank you.
Don't worry about your desk.
I'll tidy it for you every day.
Thanks, but that won't be necessary.
That's perfectly all right.
A woman's work is never done.
Good night, Sir.
Hi, fellas. How are you?
Good morning, Sir.
Mr. Florian has given us
permission for more outings.
I'd like to hear suggestions
of what we might do.
- The pictures.
- Wembley, Sir.
Cup Final Day.
Chamber of Horrors.
What about the Cavern?
You know, Liverpool.
The Beatles.
How's it going?
Fine, thank you.
He'll come with me on my day.
- You're under a supervision order too?
- That's nothing, Sir.
Most of us have broken the law.
Breaking windows, truancy,
raising hell and cussing the coppers.
You've cut yourself.
You'd better put something on that.
You'll get lockjaw.
Blimey!
Red blood.
What do you expect, pinhead?
Ink?
I didn't mean no harm.
It was a joke.
I didn't mean no crack, Sir.
It's all right.
What's with you?
Are you addressing me, Denham?
Potts was only being funny.
What you calling him pinhead for
in front of chimney sweep?
I was only joking.
Sir didn't mind.
He said, ask anything.
You call those questions?
Always on about his colour.
You're wasting our time.
Seales, you ought to know better.
What've I done?
I said nothing.
You never do,
and you're half-coloured.
You quietly sit on your ass.
If they wanna know,
why don't they ask you?
I'm not Sir, that's why.
I only wish I was.
I know what's eating you.
You fancy him, that's what.
This is a fine how-do-you-do,
isn't it, Potts?
You lay off, Denham,
you son of a bitch.
Today, I'm gonna show you
how to make salad.
You mean we've to cook and all?
Sure, why not?
My old man never cooked in his life.
He says that's women's work,
the kitchen and all.
But suppose you're on your own,
as you certainly will be shortly.
You'll have to do it for yourself
sometimes, won't you?
Not again, Sir.
This is survival training.
A normal English salad...
...not fit for human consumption,
even if you remove the slugs...
...and add a dash of the extraordinary,
a bit of mayonnaise.
Look at this.
Sorry I'm late.
Mum's at the doctor.
I didn't want to miss today.
He won't be trouble.
It's all right.
Sit down.
Make room over there for her.
Okay, come on.
Never be afraid to experiment.
And remember that you can eat well...
...even though you're broke.
See?
You ever been broke, Sir?
Real broke, skint?
Many, many times.
I don't understand you a bit, Sir.
I mean...
...you're a toff and you ain't.
What he means is...
Blimey, I can't sort of put it
into words or anything.
Well, Sir...
...you're like us, but you ain't.
I mean, you're not.
It's kind of scary but nice.
You know what I mean, don't you?
I don't know how to answer you,
except to say I teach you my truths.
It is kind of scary,
dealing with the truth.
Scary and dangerous.
Have you ever had a salad
with almonds and grapes...
...and tomatoes and lettuce
and pineapple?
She's in love with you, Mark.
You shouldn't be so surprised.
We have marvelous schools now
in the East End.
It's still difficult
to get quality teachers.
Take us,
the bottom of the pile.
Goodness knows we've had
a scruffy lot here.
Then along comes
Mr. Mark Thackeray...
...big, broad, handsome,
clean, intelligent...
...looking like
he stepped out of a bandbox.
What do you expect?
What do I do?
Nothing. Just be patient.
Thanks.
Pamela's just finding out
she's a grown woman.
You're probably the only real man
she's ever met in her life.
Don't spend too much time
alone with her.
Why didn't you ask Gillian?
I thought you'd be wiser.
Thanks.
Hello, Sir!
We can't have you queuing up.
It's Sir. He teaches
our Moira up at North Quay.
He's only got an hour for his lunch.
- What'll it be?
- Half a dozen oranges.
You'll like them.
They're lovely.
Here you are, Guv.
Penny's wedding cake.
Jeannie's older sister.
She got married,
so here's a bit of cake.
Jeannie Clark.
Yes, Miss Clark.
That was a lovely museum outing.
Will they do it again?
We're trying to arrange one a week.
That'd be lovely, won't it?
The more education, the better.
That's what I always say.
It's a proper bleeder,
what with the bomb and all.
Ain't the bombs.
It's them bleeding Yanks!
Shut your gob!
My Gert's married to a Yank.
And a proper nice gent he is and all.
Keep your opinions to yourself!
God all bloody mighty!
The entente cordiale?
Cast the mote out of your eye
before you cast the bomb out of mine!
He's a proper faggot.
Here, you'll like them.
Thank you.
Who's next?
Come on, girls.
Speak up!
I was wondering if you would also give
the girls some lessons in makeup.
I think quite a few
of them would be...
...very pretty if they knew
how to do it.
Why, certainly.
You are getting involved
with your children, aren't you?
I'm just trying to help.
That's the job, isn't it?
- You want some of this?
- No, thanks.
Is that all you're having?
You on a diet?
I'll tell you, I'm a weak man.
At the moment, a little skint.
When I eat, do I love to eat!
I love wine,
but I just can't have a glass.
I want the whole bottle.
So I avoid wine
and pastrami sandwiches...
...and baked potatoes...
...with butter and bacon...
...and strawberry shortcake
and cheesecake.
But I like to eat light for lunch.
How's the Dare girl?
No problems.
- Are you gonna stay on here?
- Until I get sorted out.
No luck with the jobs?
But I'm plugging away.
Remember a few weeks ago,
you thought you'd lost the battle?
I thought you had too.
There's a good angel
looking after me, somewhere.
Come on.
Sort yourselves out.
Come on, hurry up!
All right? Go!
Come on, Denham, hurry it up.
Land on your toes.
Do it again. Next!
Next!
Buckley!
Come on, boy.
I'm not a boy.
I'm a man.
I don't want to do it.
It's too high.
You're a fat boy.
Come on.
I'm waiting.
Get that jelly off!
Fats can't do it.
It's too high for him.
Of course, he can't do it!
When I want your opinion,
I'll ask, boy.
- I'm not a boy.
- Shut up!
Buckley, do as you're told!
Come on!
- Move out of the way, boy.
- Shut up!
Is he all right?
I don't know.
You bloody bastard!
Put that down!
You knew Fats couldn't do that.
You had it in for him.
Potter, put that down!
They're fighting in the gym!
Come on, Potts!
That was no accident!
I'll take that.
Go and help Buckley.
Go on!
Potts should have done the bastard
like he did Fats.
You all right, boy?
Yes, thank you.
Me stomach didn't half hurt.
Jackson, Ingram?
Help him up to Mrs. Evans.
All right.
What happened?
Buckley's all right.
More frightened than anything else.
Why'd you make him do that jump?
He just stood there
and refused to obey.
When he jumped, he sent the buck flying
and I couldn't catch him.
Thanks for helping me out.
That Potter went berserk.
I understand that Buckley is
a pet whipping boy of yours.
Is that right?
I'd better report it.
There'll be the devil to pay.
Potter, I can't think of anything
that excuses your behaviour.
But it was him!
He made Fats do it.
Fats said he couldn't do it.
The bully always had it in for him.
I am not concerned with
Mr. Bell's behaviour, but yours.
What if a gun or knife
had been handy?
Potter was narked.
We was all narked.
That bleeder was wrong
and you know it.
You're missing the point.
You all are.
Soon you will be out in the world.
Will you use a weapon every time
someone angers you?
You're supposed to
be learning self-discipline.
You owe Mr. Bell an apology.
Why?
Just because Bell is a teacher?
You better answer that, Potter.
Do you think you behaved
like an adult?
How about Bell
apologizing to Buckley?
My business is with you,
not Mr. Bell.
It's easy for you to talk.
No one pushes you around.
Are you a man or a hoodlum?
Do it, Potts!
Or Bell will call the law
if you don't.
You've got to have recommends
for a job in a couple weeks.
He's got to sign one.
This has nothing
to do with what I sign.
You can't trust a teacher.
We're only safe together.
Against them.
But Sir is different.
If he says Potts...
That he is, and he's wrong now.
You all know Bell's been after
old Fats for years.
Go on, Potts.
If you apologize
because you're afraid...
...then you're a child, not a man.
When I leave,
I'll have me own barrow.
So you can't touch me,
letters or no letters.
I'm sorry I'm late, Sir.
But it's me mum.
She's dead.
I've been helping me dad
with her things.
- I didn't know where to go, Sir.
- That's all right.
Ingram, take over the class.
I understand that
the passing-out class holds...
...some kind of a celebration
at the end of term.
What happens?
We dance...
...Sir.
Did you apologize because of Denham?
One should fight
for what one believes...
...provided one is absolutely sure...
...one is absolutely right.
Pass these out.
You have to fill those out...
...for national health insurance
and so on.
What are you doing, Jackson?
It's for Seales.
For flowers and a wreath.
That's wonderful of you.
May I be permitted
to contribute something?
No, thank you, Mr. Thackeray.
Here, Pam, you buy the wreath.
The name's Dare.
Miss Dare.
Well, you buy the wreath.
Send it around when the time's right.
Send it?
Aren't you going to take it?
You don't think
girls could take it, do you?
Well, why not?
It's what people would say, Sir.
What the family would say...
...if they saw us going
into a coloured person's home.
We've got nothing against you, Sir.
Honest.
But if one of us was to...
You can't imagine the things be said.
Thank you, Miss Pegg,
for making it clear.
Does that apply to the men also?
You're dead right it does.
I'll take the flowers.
Why should you do that?
Wouldn't that make you
subject to gossip?
Gossip don't worry me.
I've known Seales since kindergarten.
I'll take the flowers.
I wouldn't if I were you.
I've been looking for you.
There's a lady to see you.
Mrs. Dare.
And by the way, I've canceled
all outings for your class.
Why?
The adult approach hasn't worked.
It'd have been better
to let things be.
You'd better take your boys in for P.T.
Until I get a replacement.
I'm sorry to disturb you, Sir.
It's about Pam.
I'm Mrs. Dare.
What can I do for you?
Would you have a seat?
Would you talk to her, Sir?
I'm sure she'd listen to you.
- She's always talking about you.
- What's the problem?
She always stays out
late at night, Sir.
Often she doesn't get home
till past 11.
She never says where she's been.
She's a big girl.
I'm worried about her.
She won't listen to me.
I'm just a teacher, Mrs. Dare.
I know she'd listen to you.
It's always "Sir said this"
or "Sir said that. "
See, she won't listen to me.
She just won't.
Why doesn't her father
talk with her?
We're divorced.
He's up north somewhere.
He doesn't...
It's not wrong to...
When your marriage breaks up,
life doesn't end, does it?
Please talk to her, Sir.
I'm frightened for her.
You never know what sort
of trouble she can get into.
Please?
All right, I will.
Thank you.
Morning, Sir.
Hello, luv.
- Morning.
- How are you? How's the kids?
Hello, Guv!
Hello, Sir.
It's a lovely day, isn't it?
Your kid ain't top of the class.
My, you look as if
you've won the pools.
Better!
I got me a job.
A real one for when school ends.
Assistant engineer
in a factory in the Midlands.
They even sent me the fare!
That's marvelous.
It's not that good,
but it's a start after so long.
Do you think
she'll take the flowers?
I don't know.
Go in. Sir wants you.
Sit down.
I'd like to talk to you.
Has my mum been in?
The funeral's Saturday, 10:30.
About my mum, Sir?
She's very worried about you,
Miss Dare.
Couldn't you call me Pamela?
I think not, for the moment.
She says that
you've been staying out late.
I've just been to Gran's.
Just around the corner, not far.
Why haven't you told your mother?
She doesn't care about me.
You know that's not true.
You're not in trouble, are you?
Nowadays that's only for fools,
isn't it?
We're the luckiest kids,
the luckiest generation...
...that's ever been, aren't we?
We're the first to be really free
to enjoy life if we want...
...without fear.
What is the trouble?
If you don't want to talk,
say the word.
It doesn't bother me.
It was all right
up till about a year ago.
Of course, I miss Daddy.
He was wonderful.
But it's just one of those things.
Mum works up in a dress shop
on the West End.
And we got on fine.
Then men friends started
calling on her.
You know what neighbours are like.
That's all.
There's nothing else to tell.
She doesn't like me.
I'm in the way.
She's young and pretty, isn't she?
I'll be glad to leave school
and be on my own.
Obviously your mother loves you.
And you owe her much more
than any teacher.
I think you're wrong about her.
Did she tell you that I found her
with one of her friends?
At home? At my home?
No, I bet she didn't,
but she was!
I can't solve your problems for you.
But staying out late won't help.
It helps me.
I can't stand the sight of her!
And if you were me,
you'd feel the same.
I'm in no position to judge.
I know people make mistakes.
You're saying it's my fault?
Forgiveness is the gift of God.
People make mistakes.
It's up to you to make peace.
- Why should I? I haven't done anything.
- Grow up.
Give her another chance.
Why are you taking her side?
You're wrong not to give her a chance.
Everybody deserves that.
I thought you'd understand.
I thought I could trust you.
But you're just as Denham said.
I'm not taking the bloody flowers!
All right.
Let's line up here
in the centre.
Could we box first today, please?
Why?
It would make a change.
Just sort yourselves in pairs now.
Do you mind having a go with me?
Sapiano's hurt his wrist.
That's right. I sprained it.
I think you ought to wait and have a go
at Potter or one of the others.
He'll be done in, Sir.
I don't mind having
a punch out with you.
I think you'd better
forget that for today.
Let's go!
Let's go.
Stay where you are!
Put your head down.
Collect the gloves and put them back.
The rest of you,
line up for vaulting.
Put your head down.
You all right?
- Come over here for a minute.
- I'm all right.
I think I'll go wash up.
You all right, mate?
Are you sure?
Can I ask you something?
- How many times did you hit me?
- Once.
I'm sorry,
I didn't mean to hurt you.
I lost my temper.
I was meaning to hurt you.
You did.
You're pretty good.
Why didn't you hit me again?
Why didn't you fight?
You had me easy.
I've been after you
since you got here.
Are you afraid or something?
Hitting you wouldn't solve much,
would it?
It's the truth.
I don't understand you at all.
What's a barrow?
A barrow? With fruit on it.
A barrow!
You was wrong about Potts.
Yes, from his point of view,
at his age, I was.
- The girls was right about the gossip.
- From their point of view.
What other point is there?
You have to figure that out
for yourself.
Would you like a job teaching
the youngsters how to box?
I'll speak with Mr. Florian.
There will be some money for you.
Me? A bleeding teacher?
It's important the youngsters
know how to defend themselves.
Why are you doing this?
Good luck with your barrow.
What's the matter?
You going to a bleeding wedding?
You don't half pong, Potts!
- What's up with you, Fats?
- Nothing, Bert.
Another week and
we'll be through here.
I ain't got a job yet.
You had the bleeder yesterday.
Lucky punch.
You got eyes in the back of your head.
He could have done me
with one hand behind his back.
And none of your bleeding here.
There's ladies present.
What Sir said about the truth,
it's kind of scary, isn't it?
Good morning.
About the party,
we've got a group and all.
And the girls is fixing the grub.
You coming?
You inviting me?
Yeah, you're invited.
Thank you.
If I can, I certainly will.
What you said is right,
about a man making up his own mind.
My goodness!
You certainly look lovely.
Thank you.
Would you dance with me tonight?
Of course.
But nothing too fast.
I am getting too old for that.
We'll make it special.
Promise?
Promise.
Thank you.
Would you call me Pamela tonight?
Pamela.
Thank you.
Excuse me a minute, Bert.
It's Pam.
- You look marvelous!
- You look great!
- Where's the other earring?
- It's the thing.
- I wanna talk to the group. Come.
- Why?
Come on, I'll tell you.
Good evening.
I hear you're leaving.
It's a pity.
I'm sorry about that.
You're damn good.
You've done wonders for this show.
Thank you very much.
Anybody can be an engineer,
but teaching this mob is...
I wish I had your gift.
Why so serious, Mark?
Good God, it's Weston!
Wrap up, Clinty.
Well, I'm damned!
He wasn't giving you
a hard time, was he?
On the contrary.
Will you wave your magic wand
and make me sweet 16 again?
Nothing to do with me.
A fine lad.
Your hand's in this, all right.
If you must leave,
go to another school.
You can't waste your talent
on electronics.
Damn!
I swore I wouldn't interfere.
Would you like some more?
- Who made it?
- I did.
It's salad North Quay,
one of Sir's special recipes.
It's bloody marvelous, Barbara.
I mean, Miss Pegg.
Thank you, Mr. Weston,
I'm sure.
Actually, I don't like it.
I think it's terrible, don't you?
Blimey, I'm hot!
Thank you.
Excuse me, Sir.
I got the job I wanted.
That's wonderful.
- What is it?
- Pageboy at the Hilton.
He can't wait to get
all that Yankee money.
You're right there.
I don't want to be
a pageboy all me life.
Will you help me get
into night school?
I'd be glad to.
Ta, Sir.
You ain't half a dolly, Miss.
Ready, Pam.
Attention, everybody!
By special request,
it's a lady's choice.
Hold that, please.
Come on.
Everybody, come here.
Thank you.
Can I come and see you
sometimes, next term?
I won't be here.
Everybody's got to move on.
I'm glad I met you, though.
You've helped me a lot.
We were lucky to have you.
The whole world's waiting for you.
You're a smasher!
Thanks.
Bye.
Hold it! Listen, everybody.
I've got an announcement.
It's about Sir.
We'd like to thank you
for everything you've done.
We'd like to give you
a present to remember us by.
- Come on, Babs.
- You mean, Miss Pegg.
The time has come
For closing books
And long last looks must end
And as I leave
I know that I am leaving
My best friend
A friend who taught me
Right from wrong
And weak from strong
That's a lot to learn
What can I give you
In return
If you wanted the moon
I would try to make a start
But I would rather you let me
Give my heart
To Sir, with love
Speech! Speech!
I think I'd better go
and put it away.
Evening, Guv.
Nice, isn't it?
I'm in your bleeding class
next term.
Subtitles by
GELULA & CO., INC.