Subtitles provided by MBC
[Episode 06]
Where's the body?
The capital is crawling with troops.
If they find it first...
Easy. It's not that easy.
Good.
Have some more.
Here.
How is you're not in danger?
I made my way out
when I heard they were coming.
I see.
I felt so bad about it.
I came here to try
and rescue Commander Ki.
At least we ran into each other.
I'll go reconnoiter. Wait here.
How long do we have to wait?
Let's take him now...
What good will that do?
Finding Togon's body
is the important thing.
'Finding...'
Since when do you give orders?
Shut up and listen.
Sungnyang will show me
where the body is.
He can't suspect anything
until I've confirmed it's Togon.
Understood?
'Under...'
How dare you order me around?
Listen.
I'll be a general soon.
And after finding Togon's body,
well, you see my point.
What? How dare I?
Well.
See that Sungnyang doesn't get away.
What now?
What else? Come in.
So you were the traitor.
Traitor?
We're just on different sides.
You, the ill-fated Koryo.
Me, the Yuan empire.
Filthy Dog.
Dog?
Filthy?
Better an emperor's dog
than a village headman.
It's already been decided.
What has?
Koryo will cease to be,
it will become part of Yuan.
The court's decision was unanimous.
Because of your foul-up.
You are to abdicate.
You will come to Daidu
and submit to Yuan justice.
Togon treated Koryo with disdain.
Because of that...
I had him killed.
Sire.
What are you saying?
You admit it?
I acted alone.
My court, my people,
they have done nothing..
There is no need to abdicate.
Kill me now.
Kill me and leave my people be.
- Sire.
Open the gate.
I have Prince Togon's body!
Sungnyang, it's up to you now.
Kill me now.
I alone am guilty.
Sire.
Your life isn't enough.
Regent.
I'll take him to our capital.
You and Wang Ko deal with things here.
Father.
Regent El Temur.
I bring you the body of Togon.
Togon is in that coffin?
Yes, sir.
He should be bloated from the river.
He's in salt but still recognizable.
Check.
The stench.
Verify it's him.
Bayan, you check.
Rest in peace, Your Worship.
I can't get the stench out of my nose.
Your Worship, you're alive?
Your Worship! You left us!
Your Worship.
- Your Worship!
Sire, Togon is alive.
What are you talking about?
He isn't dead.
He's alive.
Silence! The corpse is right here!
Prince Togon.
El Temur.
You're alive.
Hail His Worship, all hail...
Togon, what is all this?
Well, um...
I'm, er...
Please, Your Worship.
Tell him they are the ones
that tried to kill you.
No. You dare not.
Go on. Did I try to kill you?
Tell him, Your Worship.
The moment you do... you're dead.
It's all right. Go on now.
Who tried to kill whom?
Well, the thing is...
Prince, Prince!
Well? Look after him.
That's enough.
Sire, they can't look after him.
It's enough that we saw him alive.
Alive or dead, it's all the same to us.
You're alive.
Thank you.
Why won't he wake up?
I'm not sure.
His internal energy is fine.
I've never seen anything like it.
Lord Zhang. Escort the doctor out.
Yes, Regent.
Who checked the corpse?
Tangqishi...
told me and I told Bayan...
You....!
Kill me, Father.
Kill us.
Yes, I should.
You made me look the fool!
Please, Regent.
The problem is what to do now.
Once he awakes,
he'll name his attackers.
Better to kill him now.
What?
Kill him now?
After the Koryo king and
his court saw that he's alive?
Should we kill them too?
That's... maybe later...
Morons.
You never learn.
I'm sorry, Father.
Bayan.
No one comes in until Togon wakes up.
Yes, Regent.
Incompetent fools.
You can open your eyes.
Everyone is gone.
The Khan is dead.
You rule now.
You are the Emperor.
Not if El Temur has his way.
There may be a way to change his mind.
Can we trust Togon?
Not to worry.
He gave me his word.
You've done it again.
Well done.
Any news of Commander Ki?
Don't take too long.
Commander.
It's Sungnyang.
It's me. Nyang.
Father.
It's me, Nyang.
It's me, Father.
Father... Father...
Yes, Father, it's Nyang.
Father.
Don't cry, sweetheart.
To see my little girl before I die
is all I could ask.
Father, be patient.
Once Togon wakes up
we'll get you out of here.
I'll get whoever did this to you.
Nyang.
Father... Father...
Father.
Never.
Never?
I gave Sungnyang my word.
What's that got to do with...!
Sir.
Sire, this is your life.
The fate of the empire.
What's a promise to some
Koryo scum compared to that?
You don't know.
Sungnyang risked his life
to protect me.
'Sungnyang, Sungnyang!'
Pull yourself together.
Sire, who do you think killed
your late father?
Only as Emperor can you
have your revenge.
Do you get it now?
Do you see what you have to do?
Father.
You!
Die! Die! Die!
You brought him here?
You spit in MY rice?
Sire, spare me, not that I deserve it.
Unhand me! Worthless..!
Sire!
Prince Togon is awake.
What?
Poor baby.
Talk down to me again...
and you're dead.
Sungnyang.
You're dead.
I'll kill you myself!
Your Worship.
It's time.
I'm so glad you're safe,
Your Worship.
Can you identify
who tried to kill you on Daechong?
I can.
Who was it?
Who tried to kill you?
Koryo... soldiers.
Your Worship.
They acted on the King's orders.
And tried to kill me.
Lies. Why are you doing this?
I saw it myself.
Ki Jaho... It was Ki Jaho.
Don't say that!
Take him away.
He did nothing.
Kill me instead.
Your life is already in my hands.
You don't die until I say so.
Escort His Worship inside.
If you please.
Sungnyang.
Father...
Father.
H-He's dying.
H-Help us.
He's dying! Help us!
Help us...
Father.
I'm sorry, Sungnyang.
My little girl.
I failed your mother...
...failed you...
Father!
No, Father. Don't die.
Father! No, Father!
No!
Father, Father!
You can't die. Father, look at me!
Stay with me, stay with me...
Father! Don't die...
Father... Father! Look at me!
You sent for me?
What is it now?
Spare me, Regent El Temur.
If you need a fool, I'll act the fool.
A coward, I'll act the coward.
Callous, I'll be callous.
A puppet...
I'll be your puppet.
Please, please don't abandon me.
Regent.
Which is the real Togon?
A simpering fool?
Or a viper waiting to strike?
Regent...
Get up.
The Emperor is dead.
Is that true?
Never blubber,
never kneel to anyone again.
You rule now.
You are His Imperial Majesty.
There is only one ruler.
And El Temur will brook no other.
Assure him who the real ruler his.
You follow?
Rule? Never.
I am not the true ruler.
That's not my place, Regent.
What a fool.
Give him everything.
You...
should take the throne.
All that is mine is yours.
You should rule us all.
Maybe he's the emperor
I've been looking for.
Right in front of me all along.
Then beg for your life.
Just don't abandon me.
Spare me.
I just want an easy life.
You are under my protection.
Regent.
On one condition.
Anything.
Name it. Anything you say.
Make my daughter Empress.
Making you my father-in-law?
Does that bother you?
Not at all.
I count myself blessed.
You have the Mandate of Heaven.
The heavens need your mandate, sir.
The Emperor of Heaven
speaks through me.
Rest easy on your throne.
Thank you, Regent.
Sungnyang, I can't die here.
I must live.
Live and exact my revenge.
I'll keep my word in some other way,
any other way.
Togon, I'll kill you.
You'll pay for my father and
Koryo somehow, some way.
Men of Koryo.
Yes, Your Worship.
Your King tried to assassinate me.
And tried to conceal that fact.
For this crime he is stripped of
his crown and will be taken to Daidu.
Those involved in the rebellion
will be enslaved.
In honor of my coronation,
Koryo will provide
200 women as concubines...
and 100 boys as eunuchs.
And 120 pounds of gold,
7500 pounds of silver...
and 100 stallions each year.
And... and...?
3,000 bolts...
Right, 3,000 bolts of silk,
100,000 sheets of parchment...
...1,000 inkstones...
And... otter... otter skins...?
10,000.
Right, 10,000...
10,000 skins?
Do they have that many otters?
Sire.
They're not easy to trap.
And even if you get that many,
skinning them alone would be...
Sire.
Koryo must obey your decree.
Even so, how can they?
You should have told me.
Memorizing it alone
has my head spinning.
No wonder he needs the parchment.
He's illiterate.
You mean he can't read?
Regent.
You didn't mention
the next king of Koryo.
The Emperor will make his decree
from Daidu.
Be ready.
Your servant awaits your decree.
Do not forget me, Sire.
Come closer.
I'll remember.
How you tried to kill me.
It's burned into my bones.
I'm not likely to forget.
What is it, Sire?
I'll be taking the concubines myself.
All the way to Yuan?
Whatever his decree,
I'll see I'm named king of Koryo.
Or all of this will have been in vain.
Every woman here.
Sir.
You can thank your king for this.
This is what you get for trying
to kill the Emperor of Yuan.
Innocents taken
as concubines and slaves.
If you must blame someone,
blame your deposed king.
He will be one of the eunuchs.
Yes, Sire.
Betray me and
you're less than a dog, a pig.
Enjoy your fate.
Your road to Yuan
will be a trip through hell.
Sire.
Sire, let us come with you.
I said no.
How can we let you go alone?
This is my final command.
I won't have you suffer because of me.
- Sire!
Serving me wasn't easy.
Thank you.
Any stragglers or loafers
will be severely punished.
Remember that.
Let Sungnyang go.
He saved your Emperor.
There's no reason for this.
Silence!
Wait. Don't forget what Father said.
Remember.
Show him every courtesy as king.
Father, he's going to die anyway...
Since when do you question me?
Your pardon.
May I ask why you're protecting him?
I've faced fierce men
on the battlefield.
But never one with such heart.
To face death with such pride.
It's a shame he has to die.
I'm not a merciful man.
Now shut up and stay in line.
Sire, I'll be fine.
The boat won't sink.
What's bothering you?
I'm ashamed of myself.
Sungnyang again?
I'm only emperor
because he kept me alive.
This is how I repay him.
You already ordered
that his life be spared.
He's probably relaxing at home
even as we speak.
Oh, Sire, I have a niece.
You'll like her.
I'm pretty picky.
Her beauty would make Buddha smile,
if I say so myself.
Oh?
Then bring her to the palace.
[The Koryo Border]
Move it along! Move it!
Time's a-wastin'! Move!
Fall behind and die. Get up!
Move!
I said move!
Shall we make camp?
The women are hurt.
At this rate, half will be dead
before we reach Daidu.
Silence.
How dare you...
Stop here.
Sir.
His High-n-Mighty wants to rest.
Make camp.
Water. Drink.
Leftovers. Share it out.
Let's go.
What is this?
You have to ask?
Whose fault is this anyway?
Don't try it if you can't do it.
Why try to kill the Emperor anyway?
He gave you his own food.
Don't be like this.
Let's go.
Come on.
Wait.
Leave it.
They're not wrong.
Sire.
Get all the women.
Sir.
What is this?
They're slowing us down.
My brother says kill them.
Well? Get them.
Sir.
Move out.
No one touches my people.
Are you so eager to die?
This is Yuan territory.
Those who disobey me die.
Have them stand down.
No more special treatment.
- Take him.
- Sir.
I will kill anyone that enters this tent.
You think you're the only killer here?
Just the sight of you makes me sick.
Last chance.
Stand down.
Sire.
Don't shoot!
You want to die with him.
Fair enough.
Move.
Never.
I hate everything about him.
Enough.
Wang Ko.
El Temur will be furious.
He's right.
He's not worth it.
Sire.
He's still breathing.
Step up the pace.
Kill anyone that slows us down.
Sir.
He hasn't fallen behind yet.
I'll help him.
You?
We won't break ranks.
Fall behind and
you'll have to kill him to survive.
Can you do that?
I need a stretcher.
Hang on, Sungnyang.
I'll save you somehow.
His Imperial Majesty.
Sire.
There you are.
Mother.
Poor boy. But you made it.
Come to the palace.
The court is waiting.
Sire, your throne.
If you please.
It is your throne now.
Pay your respects.
You have a new Emperor.
Hail the new Emperor.
Hail the new Emperor!
Hail the Emperor. Hail the Empire!
All hail! All hail!
Hail the Emperor.
Hail the Empire!
We must have a coronation.
See to it.
Empress Dowager.
Before that...
there is the wedding.
The wedding?
His Majesty has chosen
my daughter as his empress.
Sire, is this true?
Tanasiri is supposed to be quite lovely.
With El Temur as my father-in-law,
I can have my cake and eat it too.
That is Inner Court business.
You chose an empress
without consulting me?
I just...
Sire, I have never seen this Tanasiri.
Empress Dowager cannot be ignored.
Do you have something
against my daughter?
Perhaps you mean to insult me?
Is that it?
The imperial house has rules.
They'll be followed. In time.
Shall we?
Now he shows his claws.
I won't have it, not if it kills me.
El Temur holds the court
and the military in his hand.
I was the late Emperor's favorite.
I will not be bullied.
Why didn't you tell me
you're marrying El Temur's daughter?
You never asked.
I saved your life.
We should have discussed it.
Sure, later, you bet.
Now when are you bringing over
this niece of yours?
Never mind.
Never mind?
I need imperial concubines.
I won't have Tanasiri kill her, thanks.
Have you heard about Tanasiri?
Tell me about her.
A real hellcat.
Hellcat?
Haughty. And jealous.
Worse, consider who her father is,
she's an unbridled colt.
An unbridled hellcat colt.
El Temur by day. Tanasiri by night.
Lucky you.
Just my luck. No one's to blame.
Sire, pull yourself together.
You're the Emperor now.
I liked Daechong better,
with Sungnyang.
I was hoping for a place
in the imperial family.
A dog barking at
chickens on the roof, huh?
It's his early days.
Don't rush it.
Don't this, don't that,
I should have known better.
Follow me.
Bayan.
The Turks are making trouble
on our Northwestern border.
Take care of it.
The border?
Do you suspect me of something?
Half of politics is suspicion.
The other half is confirmation.
Let the heavens bear witness,
I will never betray you.
Trust me, Regent.
Root out the Turk problem.
And don't come back till you do.
Odd. Very odd.
What is?
That Sungnyang.
He smells like a girl.
Well,
maybe you've gone too long without.
Look at him.
He's prettier than most women I know.
Take a break.
Break time!
Sungnyang...
Please.
His fever is rising.
Water, please.
Thirsty?
It's for the King.
Give it to me.
Sure. Here.
Lap it up like a dog.
Yom,
I'll tear your heart out and eat it.
You can't die.
Stay. Stay with us.
Hold it.
Wait, he's Commander Ki's...
You know this dog?
What are you doing here?
What are YOU doing here?
Is Tanasiri as bad as all that?
The entire staff is worried
about her coming.
That's all the staff does is fuss.
Does he have all his teeth?
Would I do that to you?
I heard he's deformed.
Hush. Enough.
You just want me to be Empress.
You're selling me off.
Will you hush? We're here.
Beautiful or not,
I hate temperamental women.
A man should be manly.
Who wants a coward and a fool?
I wish...
I said hush.
Halt.
Your Imperial Majesty.
Welcome, Regent.
It's His Majesty. Pay your respects.
Your servant, Your Imperial Majesty.
I have heard so much about you.
You are as noble and dignified
as I heard.
People really say that?
Get up, get up.
What's your problem?
I was right.
A girl's scent. You're a girl.
Not likely.
Sungnyang is a woman.
You'll be my concubine in Daidu.
Tanasiri must be trained.
And she will fail.
If you do not learn,
you cannot be Empress.
Again, again, again.
I can't, I can't, I won't.
What will you do to Sungnyang?
As my slave, anything I want.
Were you never tempted?
Even now I can't stop my heart
from pounding.
Why is that?
Your life is in my hands.
Mine!
Don't, Sire.
Let go. I'll kill him!