Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
SISTERS OF THE GION
Master,
all the familiar furniture
being auctioned off like that...
I can hardly bear it.
Can't be helped.
Let's hope for the best.
Sadakichi,
you've been here a long time.
I'm sorry it had to end like this.
Master, I'm the one who's sorry -
for not having been able to do more.
I've made arrangements
for you to work at Kageyoshi's.
His store is doing well.
Thank you for your kindness.
Miss, will you be leaving for your native
town tomorrow with Mr Furusawa?
I plan to.
I'll help you pack, if I may.
Thank you. But I don't have much left.
Hardly more than what I'm wearing.
They're auctioning off all the things
I brought as a bride.
No one else in town
had as fine a dowry as mine.
But to return so miserably...
How will I ever be able to face my family?
Stop repeating that.
My ears ache. No one likes bankruptcy.
To think that even our child will have to
feel small among other children.
I can't... I simply can't...
Complaints, then tears.
If you have so much to say
about this shop folding,
about your things being sold,
shout it outside.
Where are you going?
Out. I can't stand to look at you any longer.
- I can't live with you any more.
- Wait!
Master!
Does anyone want flowers or tea?
I have flour, too.
Flowers or tea, anyone?
Does anyone want flowers or tea?
Flowers or tea...
- It's hot.
- Welcome.
How are things at your store?
Hopeless. I'm at the end of my tether.
Why not sell something of mine?
Would that help?
Not really.
Don't worry.
You've been so good to me.
I'd like to help if I can.
Take anything you want from here.
That's enough.
I'm sick of it all.
Good morning, Omocha.
Welcome.
I'm becoming a member of this family.
- Thank you for welcoming me.
- Is that so?
I'll do all your errands from now on.
Stop joking.
You're perspiring.
Let me wash your things.
Go to the public bath.
Wash away those unpleasant feelings.
Good idea.
So untidy-looking, sweating like that.
- Better go.
- My fortune has indeed waned.
The drop of a single leaf heralding autumn -
that's how it is.
Hurry back.
I'm opposed...
to letting him sponge off of us.
What a thing to say.
I can't be indifferent to his plight.
His business failed. So what?
Don't talk like that. We have an obligation.
We can't do much, even if he does stay.
But we can try to comfort him.
Why should we?
We're in no position to help him.
Autumn's coming
but we don't have new kimonos.
We're three to four months behind in rent.
It's not as if his coming here
will add to our expenses.
Your attitude towards men is entirely wrong.
"Obligation?" I dislike that word.
I don't know how much he's done for you.
You've already repaid it.
You grew up in the geisha quarters.
Maybe that's why.
I graduated from school. I can tell.
The men who come here use their money
to make playthings of us, that's all.
Men are all alike.
I don't need you to tell me.
I already know that.
Then act like you know it.
Since men are that way,
get all you can from them.
Never be the loser.
Don't let a poor man live off us.
What has he done for you?
Why feel so obliged to him?
He helped me become
a fully-fledged geisha.
For what?
So you'd be able to give any man pleasure?
Isn't that all?
Turning us into playthings.
Bought and sold like merchandise.
Men are our enemies.
Hateful enemies.
We should make them pay and pay.
You've been deceived by words
like "obligation" or "human empathy".
Men do just as they please.
Sister, break up with Mr Furusawa.
When he comes back, tell him.
Make him go away.
We can't get along
with an attitude like that.
In the case of men solely seeking pleasure,
what you say may be true.
It's different if there's an obligation.
Society has its rules.
Listen, Omocha.
What would people say
if I did things your way?
They would be critical.
So you'll take care of Mr Furusawa
to be praised by society?
Has that society ever treated us
like human beings?
Why must we curry its favour?
If you continue like this,
it'll be a slow death by strangulation.
Look at the other geishas
who have saved up money.
- Good morning, Omocha.
- Come to pray?
Would you like to hear
something nice, Omocha?
What is it?
Someone is very fond of you.
That's nice. Who is it?
Mr Kimura of the dry-goods shop.
He calls at your place often.
Him? Oh, bother.
Don't say that. Be kind to him.
- How silly! Goodbye.
- Goodbye.
Good morning.
Good morning,
I've been wanting to speak to you.
About what?
There's a dance performance
on the fifth of next month.
Your sister wants to be in it.
- Can you arrange it?
- Yes.
This is something I can't tell her...
so I'm telling you.
She's a skilful dancer
but does she have
a proper kimono to wear?
It's a very exclusive affair.
My reputation would be affected.
Did you hear what she said?
After making us second-raters
work like mad.
That's how she is...
Please help her take part
in the dances.
It depends on the kimono she can get.
We'll manage somehow.
It'll be a good chance for my sister
to find a wealthy patron.
Really, I worry for her.
- That's right.
- Mother...
will you listen to my story?
It makes me angry.
- You know that Mr Furusawa?
- The man who went bankrupt?
Yes. He expects us to support him.
Thanks for looking after the house.
A little mouse didn't come and nibble you?
"You're late, you're late.
It was the plaintive cry."
"The fault is mine and mine alone."
I'm so tired.
- Want some tea?
- Thank you.
I bought this.
Do you think it will suit you?
I'll look better than a kabuki actor.
It's the season for woollen clothing.
Thanks a lot.
I also bought something
that I know you like to eat.
See?
Wow.
- Good.
- Isn't it?
Lunch will be here soon. Please be patient.
Thanks.
- Here's your order.
- Thank you.
- Your money...
- Thanks.
I'm sorry. I'll pay you next time.
Next time? My boss is very strict.
Don't forget.
Hello.
- Business good?
- So-so. Not great.
Busy season is starting.
- Let's hope so.
- Mr Kimura?
How are you, Omocha?
- You bad man.
- What?
You said something to Umeryu about me.
You heard about that?
Yes, I did.
Keen on each other, are you?
- That's silly.
- Don't tempt her.
- I'll behave.
- See that you do.
- Mr Kimura...
- Yes?
I need a new kimono.
Do you have anything nice?
- Autumn wear?
- Yes.
I have some with me.
I'm on my way to Hanamikoji Street
with a very fine assortment.
Let me see them. I'll take one.
They are quite expensive.
There are cheaper ones.
It's not possible to lower the price.
Wouldn't rayon be better for you?
In which case,
you might ask at some other stores.
You're being cruel.
Was what you told Umeryu about me a lie?
- I meant it.
- I doubt that.
I'd be happy if it were true.
Listen...
I want my sister to dance
in a fine kimono.
I need a good one for her.
- Yes, but...
- Mr Kimura...
Won't you make a beautiful one for her?
Pretend that it's for me?
Instead of asking a poor man like me,
ask your patron.
I don't have anyone like that.
If I did, I'd have him buy me
lots of clothes.
Hook a rich man, then.
I hate you. You want me to do that?
So that's it.
I was a fool.
I thought you meant what you said.
All right, if that's how you feel,
I'll find many patrons,
men much kinder than you.
I was joking. Tell me what you want.
Never mind. I don't want it any more.
If you really do like me,
I can do something about one kimono.
You're really stupid.
Open your eyes.
Can't you tell whether or not
a girl likes you?
I can't, not unless you let me know.
I really can't.
Hopeless!
What a pretty design. I'll choose this.
It costs 53 yen.
The best kimono material I brought today.
Undoubtedly.
I've been watching you.
You've got younger.
I almost didn't recognise you.
You and your jokes.
I went to Mr Furusawa's place
to bid in the auction.
I was told he "wasn't at home".
Is that why you're looking so young?
I can always tell if it's the real thing
or just an affair.
You can't fool me.
- I guess you're right.
- Really?
- Ah, you're embarrassing me!
- Oh, you!
Where's the house
that Furusawa is staying at?
Be careful. It's dangerous.
- Who's there?
- It's Mr Jurakudo.
We talked about you.
He insisted on seeing you.
I haven't seen you for a long time.
Furusawa! Furusawa!
I've certainly missed you.
I've missed you.
He drank too much.
It's terrible, isn't it?
I went to the auction
at your store yesterday.
I couldn't help weeping.
All the scrolls, they were the ones I sold you.
I never thought I'd be buying
those scrolls back from you.
It's tragic. I cried in front of the others.
Can you understand how I felt?
Can you?
He's dead drunk, isn't he?
Dead drunk?
That's a mean thing to say, Furusawa.
You think I'm drunk
and just talking a lot of nonsense?
- I understand.
- Is that what you think?
Thanks for crying for me.
What an interesting man.
Who are you?
A beautiful princess.
Be careful.
- Look out.
- Who are you?
My younger sister. Please be good to her.
Your sister?
You have a beautiful sister like her?
Let's have a drink.
Pour for me, pretty princess.
Not you. If you poured,
the saké would lose its taste.
Do as you like.
Jurakudo, do me a favour.
What?
- Lend me some money.
- How much?
- 30 yen will do.
- That's too much.
- Make it 20.
- Don't be stingy.
How the world changes.
Furusawa, owner of Kyoto's
biggest cotton goods store,
asking a favour of the lowly Jurakudo
because he's in need of some pocket money.
Pitiful when one's luck changes.
What's that?
After selling me
imitation scrolls and chinaware.
I dare you to repeat that.
Making statements like that.
Are you saying I did such a thing?
That I sell phoney antiques?
Forget it.
It's pitiful.
After going only yesterday
to bid at the auction.
- I wept.
- I know that.
Those scrolls.
I understand. I was only joking.
It's only proper for you to understand.
I don't sell phoney antiques at my store.
- Understand?
- Yes.
Do you? If you do, then it's all right.
- You've had enough.
- Is this enough?
Wait a minute.
Look out! He's terribly drunk.
I'll see him home.
Where does he live?
- In Kiyomizu.
- I see.
Mr Jurakudo.
Driver, please go back to Shimokiya.
OK.
Are you awake now?
Who are you?
You were very drunk.
You made me come here.
I did?
Let me see. Who are you?
Omocha, Umekichi's sister.
She has a sister like you?
Why am I here? Is it just the two of us?
What are you saying?
I recall that I went to Umekichi's house.
Oh, yes, did I meet Furusawa there?
You did.
I certainly got drunk last night, didn't I?
Is this Shimokiya?
Have a drink?
What time is it now?
A little past 10:00 a.m..
Ten o'clock? This won't do.
Please wait.
- I want to talk to you.
- About what?
My sister wants to ask your advice
about something.
Pocket money? No!
What are your feelings towards my sister?
My feelings towards her?
Why do you ask that?
- Do you dislike her?
- What?
I see. Then it can't be helped.
Wait. No need to be hasty.
My sister has been telling me
all about you.
Is this flattery?
She says that you're very kind
and that a woman would be lucky
to have a patron like you.
- Is that true?
- Why would I lie?
- A drink?
- Thank you.
Your sister has Furusawa, doesn't she?
That's the point.
He was her patron once,
but that's all in the past.
A sense of obligation makes her help him.
But, to be honest,
my sister finds him troublesome now.
No wonder. Nothing but a parasite...
- Being down and out like that.
- That's right.
He's penniless. He'll drag her down.
Make her poor, too.
That's right.
Excuse me for making you wait.
Is there anything you'd like to order?
A lot of food.
Saké, too.
Of course, right away.
This is what my sister thinks.
If you say that you'll look after her,
Furusawa will naturally be forced to leave.
Please sympathise with her.
It's a bit awkward.
Why?
After all, I used to do business with him.
I don't think I could do it
unless she breaks up
with Furusawa first.
I'll lend a helping hand
if you'll provide money.
Money?
He doesn't even have train fare
to get home with.
How much?
Mere pocket money won't do.
- One hundred yen?
- That's perfect.
All right, for your sister's sake.
Isn't it for your sake rather than hers?
Don't say that.
- I'm home.
- Hi.
I'm so tired.
- You saw him home safely?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- He was so drunk.
- I had a hard time.
- I imagine you did.
Hungry? Care for noodles?
I've already eaten.
- This is for you.
- Thanks.
- Goes well with saké.
- I'll try some.
- Delicious.
- More saké?
More?
Empty your cup.
- Listen, Mr Furusawa.
- What?
You may not like what I'm about to say.
Don't get angry.
What is it?
You may have guessed already.
You probably know,
but you staying here makes it hard for us.
I realise that.
Expenses are mounting up.
The geisha business isn't very profitable.
I'm sorry.
We can barely make a living.
Our world is like a goldfish bowl.
Just your being here
has caused a lot of gossip.
I suppose so.
We're looking after you
out of love and loyalty.
Other people don't see it that way.
My sister doesn't say anything.
But you can imagine how it is.
I'm really sorry.
I've raised some money.
Here's 50 yen. Use it to return home.
You're kind.
I hope you'll take it the right way.
I'll leave.
You've had a hard time,
so you're very understanding.
My best regards to Umekichi.
Of course.
Goodbye, then.
Keep well.
Master! Master!
Who is it?
Sadakichi!
I haven't seen you for a long time.
- How's business?
- Where have you been?
We were all worried.
Your wife was angry,
she returned to the country. And you?
I was staying with a friend.
Got kicked out.
Then go and join your wife.
Forget it. Let's meet tonight.
Go for a walk, then go to a bar.
I'll accompany you.
Anyway, please come to my house...
Never mind about that.
I'm back.
Where is Mr Furusawa?
Not here any more.
Not here? What happened?
It was strange. He hurried out
as if he remembered something.
Went away?
I kept silent.
Didn't ask you that.
Very puzzling.
How's this?
Even an expert couldn't tell it
from the real thing.
It's extraordinary.
What's the asking price?
There's no question that it's outstanding.
Well,
shall we say 170 yen?
Excuse me.
Come and sit here.
Thank you.
My mistake. I meant 270 yen.
That's much too high.
I can't reduce the price.
You don't want it?
I'll sell it to someone else.
I'll take it.
You will?
Many thanks.
Thank you very much.
- Come here.
- Thank you.
How did it go?
Much easier than expected,
almost embarrassingly so.
Somewhat disappointing.
Naughty girl. How's Umekichi?
Happily looking forward to living with you.
Really?
But listen.
You mustn't talk about Furusawa.
Better to not complicate things.
And you should not say
that you know she loves you.
That's unwise.
I understand. I won't bungle things.
Can I meet her right away?
Do it cleverly.
Add it up yourself.
Do you think you can fool me like this?
I thought there was something strange
about you lately.
You're not good at cheating.
You'll end up in a bad way.
Why did you need so much money?
Come on, tell me.
You can't tell me?
Then...
let me tell you how I see it.
Some geisha wheedled you
into making her a kimono.
Am I right?
Don't be the kind of man
who buys a woman's love.
When I was young, girls brought me gifts.
That girl that you love can't be very good.
If she's the kind that you can marry,
I'll act as the go-between.
So, tell me who she is.
I'll go and take a look.
Omocha! Omocha!
Omocha! Something terrible has happened.
What is it?
I've been found out.
What are you talking about?
I may be fired.
Is that so?
If my employer comes, cover for me.
Don't expect me to get you out of trouble.
Help me.
My employer said that if you're willing,
he'd help us get married.
- Me, to you?
- Of course!
How silly!
Please don't mess things up.
- Excuse me.
- Hello.
- Who are you?
- I own the Marubishi.
Thank you for buying from us.
So you're the one. I see.
You're Omocha?
Yes, I am. What can I do for you?
Let's talk a bit.
All right. Why don't you come up?
Thank you.
- Please...
- Please, don't bother.
I wanted to talk to you about Kimura.
He says he made a kimono for Umekichi.
Is that true?
Oh, that? I received it some time ago.
Admitting it so glibly?
You live in geisha quarters.
Surely you ought to know
whether a mere clerk is able
to give away kimono material
that costs over 50 yen.
I wouldn't know.
I won't let you say that.
You knew and yet you...
Don't be silly.
I asked Kimura whether it was OK,
whether it would get him into trouble.
He said not to worry.
That's why I accepted the kimono.
He's been with me since he was a small boy.
I know him well.
He's honest, almost to a fault.
Is that so? Honest, is he?
A man who would try
to take advantage of a girl
by offering her a kimono?
Is that what he did?
It's partly my fault, too.
If I was a popular geisha,
I wouldn't have accepted it.
I don't have a patron.
It's hard to buy even one kimono.
That's why when he offered it...
A pretty girl and not popular?
It happens to be the truth.
I'd like to have a patron.
No one's willing to take care of me.
That's the men's fault, not yours.
You're skilled in the art of flattery.
I wish it were true.
It is.
Talking with you, I forgot to offer tea.
No, no, don't bother.
If someone would take care of a girl like me,
I'd love him with all my heart.
Please come over here. Have a drink.
It's better than tea. No one else is here.
Come over here.
All right, I will, if you don't mind.
- Please.
- Well, thanks.
Then you and your sister live here together?
Yes, the two of us work very hard.
It's no use.
All the more reason not to get involved
with a penniless clerk like him.
But I don't know anyone else.
You must know many fine men.
Find a patron for me.
I don't know a single man who'd qualify.
That can't be.
Still, the young men aren't dependable.
They don't listen
when we try to talk seriously.
Young men are no good,
they haven't suffered.
Very true.
A man like you knows
the bitter and the sweet.
I'd like to tell you about myself.
I don't mind listening.
I'm glad. I'm really glad.
If only I could have someone like you
to take care of me, I'd be delighted.
Sweet words to make an old man happy?
I really mean it.
I choose you as my patron.
You don't mind?
Well...
- Take off your haori.
- Yes, but...
No urgent business today?
Nothing special.
Then make yourself comfortable.
- This seems a bit too good to be true.
- Don't say that.
- The boss?
- Not yet.
Really?
- I'm home.
- Welcome back.
Kimura,
come.
- Welcome.
- Welcome back!
- Welcome!
- Welcome back.
She won't do.
There are plenty of geisha like her.
- Better find someone else.
- I'm sorry.
I'll let you off this time.
Behave better from now on.
I'll make the rounds of
the geisha quarters for a while,
all right?
Stay away from that girl.
I'm thinking of your future when I say this.
If I find you going near her, you'll regret it.
Don't forget.
Sorry. I'll be most careful. I'm very sorry.
You haven't been fooled by a little flattery?
Nonsense. Why do you say that?
There's no telling what you'll do.
Take a look at this, sister.
Doesn't it look nice on me?
Just do things right.
Have everything you want. Live in luxury.
Why can't you be more practical?
Working hard, growing older.
What about Mr Jurakudo?
He wants a definite answer today.
- Excuse me.
- Yes.
Well...
Mr Jurakudo.
What's the situation?
Is it OK?
She's been eagerly awaiting you.
Come on up.
- Hello.
- Welcome.
Now's the time, sister.
Let her decide.
Have some tea.
Thank you.
- Have you thought it over?
- Well...
Only one way out of this
That is to die
That would bring an end
to lamentation and grief
While knowing that
It would never be condoned
Hello, Mr Furusawa. How is everything?
Thanks. The same as usual.
Aren't you staying with Umekichi?
No, I'm staying here
at the home of my former clerk.
Is that so? I'm thinking of paying a visit.
Any message I can take?
To Umekichi?
I guess not.
No message? Excuse me, then.
- Hello.
You haven't been coming around.
No, my employer
is making the rounds now.
- I've been told to stay away.
- Oh, really?
Welcome.
Umekichi, what happened?
Was there a quarrel?
I just met Mr Furusawa.
What? Mr Furusawa?
Where?
- You didn't know?
- No!
- In Yasakashita.
- Is that so?
At the home of his former clerk.
He was reciting from a drama as usual.
- Look here.
- And then?
As I watched him, I began to feel sad.
I recalled his extravagant days.
It made me wonder if this is how life is.
Umekichi! What's wrong?
What's troubling you?
What are you doing?
Please don't stop me.
I don't understand.
What's good today?
The menu's in a foreign language.
You can order.
What is it?
I forgot my wallet.
That's very careless.
Omocha?
What are you doing here?
You fool! Didn't I warn you?
Go home!
What about you, boss? You scolded me.
What's going on here anyway?
How dare you talk that way?
All right, I'm firing you. Get out.
Leave the store.
You'd better not be there
when I get back. Stupid!
Omocha, tell me. What is he to you?
- My patron.
- What?
You can say that so brazenly
in front of me?
- You vixen!
- Vixen? Fine.
Can a geisha do business
by always telling the truth?
- Sometimes I tell a fib.
- What?
What are you doing?
So what? You're acting like my lover
after giving me one kimono.
What?
You'd better watch your step.
Try that again and you'll be arrested.
Right!
Another warning:
Don't forget about today.
- Boss.
- What?
You too, Omocha.
Stop grumbling. Get out!
I will. Remember, Omocha, I'm a man.
- Oh, I won't forget. Such a fine man.
- Get out.
How stupid can a fellow be?
Well, well.
What made you leave me and go away?
Don't you realise how I feel?
What are you saying?
Do I appear to be so heartless?
I was told you didn't want me around.
Who said that?
- Omocha did.
- Omocha?
Then I was right.
I had a feeling that's how things were.
Why did she have to do that?
Even if she did,
why did you leave without telling me?
I thought I was unwanted.
If I didn't want you, would I suffer so?
You saying that makes me happy.
But does Omocha dislike me that much?
How about moving in here with me?
If you don't mind, I will.
I don't want to stay with a sister
who acts that way.
It's comfortable here.
We'll be alone.
I'm so happy.
You say that, but won't you go away
and leave me again?
Of course not.
How could I go and leave you?
Is that true?
I'd like to borrow your phone.
- What's up?
- Your phone.
- OK.
- Please.
Who? Kimura?
What did you say? Don't tell silly lies.
I'm not lying. It happens to be true.
You've been very kind to me.
How did it happen?
- Is that really true?
- The truth.
I saw your husband at a nice place in Gion.
That's why I'm being fired.
A nice place in Gion? Where?
Omocha's house, where I made
that mistake. That's right.
Your husband is a proud patron.
I can't return to the store.
So, goodbye.
Give my regards to your husband.
Welcome back!
Has Kimura returned?
Not yet.
He hasn't?
- I'm back.
- Welcome.
I brought you something tasty from Gion.
Busy, busy. So much business to attend to.
No time to rest.
What's the matter? Not feeling well?
- Don't come near me.
- Why?
- Otake!
- Yes?
- Is the bath ready?
- Shortly.
Give this rubbish to the dog.
What's going on?
Stop this nonsense, you imbecile.
Yes, I'm an imbecile.
What are you so angry about?
Don't take me for a fool.
Where were you until now? Tell me.
With a customer.
Are you telling me the truth?
That's enough of your grumbling.
Still fooling around at your age?
Welcome home.
Jurakudo was glad, wasn't he?
I'm moving out.
For what reason?
Mr Furusawa told me everything.
You met Furusawa somewhere?
I'll send for my things later.
Sister!
Sister, wait!
What a foolish sister.
- Good evening.
Is Omocha in?
Yes. What is it?
Mr Kudo sent the car for you.
Mr Kudo did?
In that case, wait one moment.
How's business, Omocha?
Drive somewhere?
What? Don't try to act familiar with me.
Is that so?
I know about you.
Is that the kimono you got from a clerk?
Stop joking!
A beautiful face, but no wealthy patron.
Still have to hustle. I feel sorry for you.
How dare you? You're being impudent.
Where is Mr Kudo?
Mr Kudo? Forget him.
A stingy patron like him is no good.
I'll find you a rake with a lot of money.
Prefer a younger man? How about me?
I could show you a good time.
I'm not that kind of woman!
Nonsense. No use talking big.
You'll do anything for money.
Come with me. Let's make love.
Fool! How dare you say
such a thing to me?
It's been a long time.
Now here we are.
I intend to make you listen
to all my grievances tonight.
- Mr Kimura.
- I'm a bitter man.
You'll get what you deserve.
- Let me out!
- You stay here.
I said let me out!
Don't be afraid. Just come with me.
Let me out! Let me out!
It's terrible. Your sister is badly hurt.
- Omocha?
I just heard.
Umekichi, you'd better go right away.
What happened?
No use worrying about it here.
Go and see her.
Hurry.
I'll go, then.
If you need anything, let me know at once.
- Umekichi.
- Mother.
What happened?
I don't know if it was out of spite.
She was flung out of a car.
Is it bad?
I'm hoping she won't become crippled.
Oh, no...
- Where is she?
- Being treated.
Will she survive?
Let's hope so.
Omocha, what happened to you?
Are you in pain?
Now do you see?
See what happens with your attitude
of belittling men.
It led to this terrible thing.
I won't back down.
I won't be defeated by men.
He couldn't get his way with me.
So he did this cowardly thing.
I'll make him sorry for it.
Don't talk like that.
Let this be a lesson
not to trample on people's feelings.
You could have avoided this
by taking my advice.
Doing as you do?
It simply means being defeated by men.
I'll never accept that.
It's stupid! Who wants to lose to men?
Don't get so upset.
You mustn't get excited just now.
Be quiet for a while.
Do you mind?
I'll go and get my things.
Will you stay until I return?
Hurry back.
Did he go out?
Mr Furusawa?
A telegram came from his wife.
A telegram?
He and my husband left
for Mrs Furusawa's place.
Mrs Furusawa's?
Mr Furusawa is becoming the manager
of a rayon factory there.
- Is that so?
- Yes.
Did he leave me any messages?
Not in writing.
He said to tell you that he's unreliable,
that you should find a good patron.
- How could he say that?
- Strange.
I feel a bit cold, sister.
Can you put another blanket on me?
What's the matter? Why are you crying?
What's wrong?
Has something tragic happened?
Mr Furusawa left suddenly for the country
without telling me he was going.
It's exactly as I said.
They think nothing of abandoning us
when it suits them.
I don't mind. It's all right with me.
I've done all I can.
I'm sure it made Mr Furusawa happy.
I can face the world
with my head held high.
Has it helped you in a practical way?
You can face the world proudly,
but what has it done for you?
Mr Furusawa may be happy,
but what about you?
Are you better off now?
You meekly did as you were told.
And what did you gain by it? Nothing.
If we're sharp in business, we're criticised.
What are we to do?
What do they want us to do?
Why must we suffer so?
Why are there such things as geisha
in this world?
Why must they exist?
It's wrong, entirely wrong.
I wish...
I wish that they never existed.
THE END