Movie and Subtitle available at
www.phimworld.com.
Plan B
Be careful, the plan may fail.
Get someone to bring them
back soon.
Lets go up and grab them.
Good-bye Mr. Chen.
What happen?
Mr. Luo, I saw your office lights is on,
guess you are still busy.
I came back to collect something
and leaving now.
Are you new here?
Have not seen you around.
I am a temporary replacement.
How do you know my surname is Luo.
You and the actress picture appeared
in the  magazine,
concerning a foreign trip to overseas.
Dont believe in the crap published
in the magarzine.
However, your personality is different from what
it is reported.
Thats my gut feel.
The elevator is here.
Please
Are you going to the lobby
or the parking lot?
Lobby
So how careless people can be?
I have been watching the place,
have not seen anyone going into the room.
We are cooperating with
several departments,
you need full concentration,
understand?
Ye sir, I understand.
Okay, everybody listen here
These three people are major shareholder
of Fenghua International Group.
Xu Wei, Fei Kwok-Xing
and Luoyao Ming which you have met just now.
Commercial Affair Department
suspected them to be involved in
several cases of insider trading.
as well as the manipulation
of cases.
Therefore, they need to be monitored
every 24 hours
All I ask from you gentlemen and ladies are..
No matter what have they done and
whom they have met..
Including all the communication details
must be recorded.
Is it clear?
Yes sir, its clear.
Sir,
We found the target site
and dont know whether it is useful.
We depend on your team, my friend.
This task undertaken by our Intelligence Unit
is to be responsible for electronic
eavesdropping surveillance.
Ah Jun, can we start the test?
No problem.
Okay, lets begin.
Sir, there is no one at the target place,
we cant do the test now.
Channel One is working.
Channel 2 is working.
Channel 3 is working.
Channel 4 is working.
Channel 5 is working.
Channel 6 is working.
Channel 7 is working.
All channels are working perfectly.
So who will be responsible for
shutting down the system?
It has a timer system and it will
shut down automatically.
It all depends on your team now whether
we could gather evidence.
You are most welcomed.  Once the case is over,
just buy me dinner will be sufficient.
No problem at all, bring along
your wife as well.
Settled then.
I shall return to the headquarters now.
Okay.
Okay guys, listen to the schedule
for the task watch list.
Morning shift shall consist of tree,
squirrel and myself.
Confirmed.
NIght shift shall consist of Ah Jun, Yang Zhen and
Xiao Siang.
I am always stuck in the night shift roster.
If you are not happy with the arrangement,
we shall swop with each other.
Not necessary, Lao Yang and Xiao Sang
are used to work with me.
Right?
Right.
Why, are you upset?
No, how dare we be upset.
Hey, what kind of attitude is this?
If you are not happy,
bring it out then.
Come here.
No respect at all.
Thank you for what you did just now.
What are you laughing?
We have been partners for so long,
you know my character.
Commercial Crime Bureau, said
there is a very good chance to
seize the evidence this time.
They let me select the team and
thats how I make the arrangement.
You know jolly well Lao Yang's temper.
I know that he has capture
the most wanted man. Well
But the statements was
written in a mess.
The culprit got acquited and I was
given a lecture by my boss.
It almost severe our relationship
as brothers.
You must not be over
protective of him.
Show more concern for Xiao Siang.
This guy is not bad and
has a great future.
I understand and I can still
cope with the two of them.
However, on the CCB side,
They are responsible for commercial crimes
They are more on the admin task
and less practical experience on the ground.
They are not even aware of Mr Luo going up
to the office.
I shall make a report on their
carelessness.
Let it go.
We shall request for more
reinforcement next time.
We need to teach them a lesson
You are always so gentle with them.
Everything does not matter...
let bygones be bygones.
You keep laughing everytime,
What's so funny?
The more you laugh,
the more I get angry..
Why get so agitated?
Maybe I need to change
my attitude.
Ms Law has commented that
recently, I am
More and more foul temper
What happend to both of you?
Nothing.
Wan Er and myself have intention to
visit our son in England next month.
- Great.
- What are you guys doing there?
Are you sure you are allowed to
smoke at the working area?
The room is filled with smoke.
Stop smoking and stub out
the cigarettes.
Everything you also want
to have a say.
I said it once again, stub out
your cigarettes.
Sorry sir, he is in the
process of quitting.
Go and have a pee.
Going to the toilet to smoke...
Pass me a lighter.
This is not the one.
The one I need is where you got it
on the opposite side of the street.
You dare to commit and
no guts to admit?
This lighter belongs to that Mr Luo.
It has been installed with
eavesdropping devices by someone.
I'll check at the store with Mr Wang
later at the Electronic City.
To determine which channels they are using
and there may be some clue.
You can also check out the
books station.
See if we can detect who are
playing dirty tricks.
Do you know the size of
the area involved?
By the time you got the result,
the case is already closed.
Whats the matter?
Do you think I will turn
against Ah Jun?
Do you know how many years
we know each other?
Do you know what is the
relationships between us?
Do you know how many times
Ah Jun saved my life?
Sorry for nosey.
Its alright.
Have to be nosey cos you always
claimed shortage of money?
If I want to be greedy,
I will rather go for a bigger sum instead.
At least a minimum of 1 million.
Brother Yang, you are not ambitious.
1 million is already enough for you?
Thats true, I dont have the kind
of life as you do.
Let me check....
Branded watch... how much is it?
Gift from Jenny?
Nope, from father in law
as a wedding gift.
Congratulations to you, Xiao Siang
Congratulations to you.
Nothing to be happy.
In future, I need to play golf
every Mon, Wed and Fri.
Why complain as this is the life of
the riches and powerful.
You are lucky they dont
look down on you.
Dont make excuses..
Do not laugh at me
Brother Yang.
Lend me to wear it.
Dont  behave so petty,
I just wear it for two days.
Boss, its a good shot.
Good shot.
You are late again.
Good morning, Father in law.
I just drive over after work,
sorry for being late.
Good morning.
Good morning sir.
Just call my name after office hour.
Yes sir.
Your superior Director is good
in coaching newbie.
You need to learn fast.
I know that, father in law.
Let me carry it,
You are here to play golf.
Not as an attendant/
Do not get used to people
ordering you.
Your father in law loves to give orders.
Mum, younger brother is
having a nosebleed.
Dont be afraid, mum is here.
Come...come..
Mom will sing a song for you.
Its going to be alright.
Good boy.,,
Good boy.....
Its okay now, let Dad
give you a kiss,
Good boy, go to bed.
Xiao Guang looking for you
Do you mind?
No
Its over between him and me.
The divorce certificate between
Guang and me is out already.
Its just that he has not collected it.
Since it is over, why do you
still need to stay at his house?
He has left the house estate for
me and the son.
He has already moved out.
If you are willing, you can
move into the house with me.
He is my friend.
When he was with me before we separated,
both of you cant be buddies.
Now we are separated...
You said he is your buddy.
Until now, he has not mention
anything in front of others shows he
was still hopeful about the
relationship with you.
I am not interested in his intention.
Do you know how hard during our
separation period.
He failed to relocate his belongings
even after several months.
He called me every day.
And said that we must go to
England to see his son.
Whenever I want to make
it clear to him.
He says he is busy or...
he could not understand
what is happening
I know you are tired but
I've tried my best.
I am sorry.
Please do not be angry,
darling okay?
Please say no more or we end
up quarrelling again.
What are you highlighting?
These few stock prices rose
today by several cents.
If you will to buy accordingly,
how much can you earn?
Twenty cents profit for
every dollar purchased.
That is still not much.
Information indicates that there are
50 million dollars transaction done.
They are big timers, whats 10
millions to them.
It seems there are more
goodies yet to come.
I am not a fool, dont think its
so easy to make 10 millions.
We earn only more than 20,000
a month working so hard.
It will be unfair if I dont
put them in jail.
Place it over there will do.
Come and collect money from me.
Xiao Siang, what is he doing in
FengHua International?
Inspecting the system and equipment there.
What is he checking?
Generally speaking, long-range
eavesdropping devices will emit noise.
The electrical noise can be
detected by electronic signal.
However, the equipment we used
are housed on the jammer.
The other party will not
be able to detect the devices.
However, jammers itself will emit noise.
The noise will then...
affect our surveillance system.
Are our equipment behind time?
Of course not, nowadays there is no need to install eavesdropping devices with the latest technology.
Give me your cell phone
Every person has some tracking device.
By inputting the mobile phone
number into the GSM jamming set,
You can track the parties concerned.
Even if the other party does not start
As long as the battery is not
removed, the set can be traced
Your mobile phone number
92727O31
O31
Testing 123....
Isnt this very dangerous?
That may not be because the machine
may not be smarter than the human.
Look
He removed the batteries and
we cant do anything now.
You go ahead to get the time recorded.
Lend me a lighter as I need to
go out for a smoke.
I come along as well.
I got another lighter from Mr Wang
and the channel frequency is 100.
Off your mobile phone.
Why do I need to off my mobile phone?
Just do as I said.
Why didnt you pick up my
call this afternoon?
I was not free.
You went to Lau Xu place?
It does not matter to you
After work where will you be?
Come to my place if there isnt anything.
Already hinted to you that they
have something going on there.
You lose, 100 dollars please.
Mary is not with Lau Xu Jinglei instead.
You dare to lay hand on Crime Xu
Jinglei's girlfriend?
Both of you have nothing better to do?
Just for kick..
Tell me what is the kick?
Go on, speak...
Whats the matter, is there new event?
There really is something going on..
This is the new secretary called Lin Yi-ling..
Ah Zou, start recording.
We need to record the boss
flirting with the Secretary?
You never notice her designer clothers?
Just the underneath clothing
costs more than $3,000.
You look at those pieces of
shirts and skirts
And the branded watch on her wrist.
A junior secretary's salary is
about $7,000 per month.
She deserved to be on the watch list.
Why are you guys so disgusting.
Good morning,
Good morning, sir.
Good morning
Any new event takes place?
No event or issues...
Off duty then..
Okay...
Good morning
In my whole life, I have only lived in a 700 sq feet house considering the biggest..
I never realise the toilet here is
bigger than my bedroom.
I'm afraid I need time to adjust
to this environment.
Dad was here looking at the
renovation the last time.
He remiinds us to change the
bathroom water faucet to gold color.
I know you do not like the idea.
You give in to my Dad and he
will ask for more.
If you do not like the idea,
you have to bring it up. Understand?
A Hong Kong police commissioner's salary is...
181.05 thousand a month
In our group as a Security Director
His annual salary is 4.5 million.
Slightly more than commissioner except
not staying at Government House.
Hong Kong has more than 30,000 police
officers but there is only one Commissioner.
Your monthy salary is about $20,000,
When can you take the seat
of the Comissioner?
Since there is no prospect,
tender your resignation next month.
Come to my company to work
I know that you are taking care of my interest,
but I still want to
You need to understand, I am
doing it for my daughter sake.
As you will be getting married onext month,
quickly tender in your resignation as soon as possible.
I am going out for a smoke
Waiting for me here
You already know me for a long time.
You know I am not a casual person.
Dont play anymore as I cannot
afford to lose this relationship.
Just make it clear to Xu Jinglei,
I dont want to act like a thief.
Are you still a man?
What do you mean?
How many times you want me
to say it to you?
You are the first to know me
but you ran off when he appears.
When I have problems with him,
you came back looking for me again.
Now you want me to be responsible?
Well yes because I am afraid
Who doesnt  know the
character of Xu Jinglei,
Can you think about me?
Lets go
Why are you so anxious to come back?
Come back to collect something.
What is so important
Can not tell you
You do not say then I go off now.
Well
I can only tell you but do not tell others
Take out your phone batteries first.
This is a secret.
Watchout the stock price of Company tomorrow.
It should increase to $1.20 a share.
The closing price for
today is only 22 cents.
Wow, we will make a fortune then.
Do not buy too much.
Dont blame me if you cannot
let go later.
If I follow you,  I will never be able
to escape from you?
Lets go to the yacht.
Fine,
Lets get something to eat
because I am hungry.
Later I will let you eat me.
You are so bad,
Taking advantage of me.
Xiao Siang
Did you record the conversation just now?
Yes, I did.
Any problem?
I was wondering...
Whether to erase it..
My son is sick, I need money
I beg you
Why do they come back?
Please see yourself.
Dance is not over so why you hurry to come back
Get something back
What is so important
Can not tell you
You do not say I left the
Well I can only tell you but do not tell others
Before we go
to the yacht, I am hungry....
We might as well have something to eat
OK.  I will let you eat until you..
I give you so
Xiao Siang, why are you recording
this silly conversation?
If you think it is useless, then erase it.
Lets go.
Good morning.
Your account can be
effected now.
Thank you.
Lets have lunch when we are free.
Brother Yang.
How is it?
Settled.
$200,000, thats all my property.
It is what I have left.
Do you know what you are doing?
Destruction of evidence, obstruction of justice
and failure to report..
Dont tell me you guys do not know
the seriousness of the crime.
Go back and reinstate the record,
I will plead with Xiao-Guang on your case.
Boss
Insider information are everywhere
on the streets
Any normal person would do the
same thing. Since there is no harm...
This is not an excuse to do wrong thing.
Ah Jun
Ah Jun,  listen to me
A few days ago I took my son
for physical examination,
My son will be well soon
But I will have something
Liver cancer
Doctors said that I have a
year to live. I beg you
I want to leave some money for my family...
for my wife and kid
Lets go outside and talk about it.
Lets go.
Its too late
I borrow five million to purchase the stock.
$5,000,000
Are you crazy?
Trading commence
Look, the share price is moving up...
Only 7 million transacted.
I alone already purchase 5 million and
of course the price will increase
What do you mean?
Hello,  Good then,
Whats the matter?
- We are buying at an average price of 27 cents.
- Isnt it supposed to be 20 cents?
You are buying at a higher price?
Are you sure you know what you are doing?
Thats all I have left....Brother
You are killing me?
I have bought 5 million and if the
price doesnt move up
Then this stock is totally worthless
What do you mean
Now the price is moving up progressively
Sometimes there may be shortage of stocks
Hey, is it true?
8822 ah
Thank you, thank you
8822 fast recovery fast recovery
This group of people are seriously
buying the stock.
I just have my fortune read
The fortune teller told me
that I must pursue
I will also pursue...
8822 is going up ...8822 is going up...
Going up....up
Today, we must bring up
the price of FengHua stock
Otherwise how can we attract
people coming in
Thats it,
Brother Qiu
Good morning, Mr Ma
A bowl of pork chop noodles
Sandwiches and ice tea.
Alright,
Thank you.
Sources saying that Fenghua is negotiating
the acquisition by the foreigners
at a base price of $1.20
There is saying that
Fenghua bought a piece of land and
there is oil under the ground
Is it true?
Prices going up?
Have we made enough?
Sell now...sell
Sell now? Cant you see the price is
still moving up?
We have already made a profit of 10 million.
What more do you want?
You see the price is still moving up.
We wait till it reaches $1.00
then we let go? Alright?
You go ahead and wait for the price to go up,
I am selling now
Do not rush things, Brother Yang
If we sell now, we can split only a
few millions between us.
A few million is more than enough
What kind of generaton we are taking here,,
A few millions is of no use
Listen to Brother Yang, sell
the entire stake
Boss
I said to sell all stake, you hear me?
Sell..
Whats going on?
What's the matter.
What's going on
Trading of Stock 8822 suspended!!!
Listed Companies Fenghua International
has sharp fluctuations in stock price today.
in view of irregularities, the
Securities regulatory
has ordered to stop trading until the
completion of the investigation
As for the listed company
latest update
There are rumors of aqcuisition
as well as favourable news today
Spokesman of Fenghua International denied
any news or possible acquisition
The analyser in the stock market
generally felt that
In the absence of good news and
without any good background support
Once trading resumes on
the following Monday
The share price may be under
enormous pressure
Securites analyst Lu Yong-jian said
According to Fenghua net asset value
The price per share is about 15 cents
I have already said to let
go the stock
Forget it
How can we forget about the matter,
today is Friday
The following day is a public holiday,
we do not know when will trading resume
The interest already is a
big burden to us
Its net asser value is only 15 cents
I will be responsible for the 5 million loan
I shall return your two hundred
thousand as soon as possible
Why did you withdraw all the
money from our saving account?
No, I never do it.
If you lie again, I will leave
immediately.
I used the money to purchase shares
Did you make profit then?
The stock counter has been suspended
Please dont go
I have already confessed and
yet you still leave
That money is reserved for our
son medical treatment
If he needs to be hospitalized,
what will you do?
What about me..
If I am hospitalized, what will happen
What should I do?
Ah Jun, come out and talk
Do you remember about the bed?
You accompany me to buy it
Wan Er throw it away
How things between both of you?
Its all my fault
I had an affair
But I have been already
admit its my mistak
After the incident and for six
months I have been very nice to her
She has also accepted my apologies
I do not know what happened
during the last two months
She seem to have changed
to another person
I do not want to quarrel with her
Hence, I have not gone home
for the last two months
Yesterday, when I went back home
to collect something
She actually called the estate officer
to look at what I am doing
I entered the room and discovered
the bed has been changed
She should be seeing
someone special
Ah Jun
Help me to install a CCTV monitor
I would like to know who is the man
You cant solve the problem
by doing that
I will be responsible to solve
my own problem
We have been friends for so many years
and you are not willing to help me
Xiao Guang requested me to
mount CCTV monitor
He wanted to know who is the
men with you
I was thinking to tell him it is me
But I cant open my mouth
I could not even said you are my woman
This matter has nothing to do with
you had I settle properly with him
Yes I do not know
You are quite right to say
that I get to know you first
When he started to date you,
I back off
Now you are giving me a second chance
And yet, I still want to back off
Soemthing that is obviously right
has become wrong
I cannot distinguish what is
right and wrong
I do not deserve your love, I
think we forget it
It is for me to decide whether it is worth
It is not something that both of
you can decide
You need to install the CCTV monitor?
Go ahead then..
He wanted to know who is my man
I will let him see
I know the guy that I love
He will have the courage to
come looking for me
Do they have any action on the day
before yesterday night?
Is there something wrong, Officer Huang?
I want to watch the video
two nights ago
Fine
Ah Jun, prepare the stuff
Laoyang
Wait here for me
Lets go
Why are you so anxious to come
back since the show is not over yet
I need to collect something
What is so important
Can not tell you
I am leaving if you do not say
Fine...okay..
I can only tell you but do not
reveal to others, pass me your mobile
Is it because of the signal defective?
Yes, but the fault had been
repaired during that night
Lets go to the yacht now
Okay
First, lets get something to eat as
I am very hungry
Why is there no record of the activities
I find the contents boring so
I erased it
I have clearly indicate my intention
No matter whom they met or
what they said,
All must be recorded
Are you deaf?
Sorry
Fenghua International share price
was manipulated by thiis Group last night
The Top Officers have been very
dissatisfied with the event
From this very minute,
we must fully concentrate to
leep a close watch on them
Understand?
Yes sir
Alright.
This is our financial performance
report for the first half of the year
If you think that is not good enough
Here are our results for our past three
years profit and loss detailed report
The report on your company's financial year
Have not yet been given to us
Its over here
Please take a look
Ok
This is the info on the purchase
of the land
This one is our partner companies of all data
This is related to the all our
partners financial position
There are the survey report and
the assessment of the land of the company
The guys from the Securities Regulatory
Bureaus have left
Come in and talk
Officer Huang
Are we able to receive?
Its too noisy
Try to adjust and we must hear
what they say
Understand
Luo Yaoming is crazy
We have to get him to talk
about his goods
If the trading resumes and he
sold the whole cargo
How do we explain to the boss
There is nothing to discuss
with this person
Worst scenario, you and I will
take over the goods from him
to stabilise the share price
for the meantime
The boss has deposited such a large
sum of money
If there is anyting wrong, you and me
would be dead
In fact, I have already talked
with the boss
He said that Luo Yaoming has
to be eliminated
Go and ask Ah Hua to follow up
To kill him
If he is not dead then we will be doomed
I shall tell him that we overhear the
conversation from another surveillance system
to Officer Huang
How are you going to explain?
I will tell him that we hear their
conversation from another system
Later he ask when and how we
intercept and when is the cut-off time
Why we did not reported it earlier
What you want to say
Boss, things we should not hear
in the first place
We take it that we have no idea at all
Its a matter of life and death
If he doesnt die, we have to die
Do you know you are a police officer?
That guy is not a good man
You have to guts to say so
Stop it, we are brothers
Ah Jun, is the guy worth
for you to be considerate?
Being a member of the Police Force, we should
know that the truth will surface out eventually
Even we get pass this today, we will
have to face it the next time
Is there other solution?
Since we lie, we have to lie all the way
Ah Jun
Do you know we are aready stuck with it?
Its not easy to go back to normal now
Ah Jun
My family will be broken if I dont
get back my two hundred thousand
I beg you, I beg you Ah Jun
I beg you
Get up
Ah Jun, I was wrong this morning
and please do not get angry
Call me back
Boss, I really can not afford to lose
Consider helping me just for this
time, okay? Call me back
Ah Jun, for so many years
We have gone through all the hardship
Come out and talk about it
Boss, I am wrong this morning
Whatever you say, I will follow
Give me a call
Lao Wu
How long we have not
seen each other?
More than three years?
So today is a meeting with
an old friend?
Or you have valuable information
for Independent Commission Against Corruption
Nothing can escape from you
I'm not a fortune-teller
If you do not make it clear,
how will I know
We heard some thing during
one of the operation
Can you turn us in as a
prosecution witness?
I would collect evidence for you
This is a big case
Right
This is indeed a big case
But you are not qualified to
negotiate terms with me
I'll tell you from now on, all the
subsequent action
Must follow the instruction of the ICAC
You have to report to me every day and
This matter must not be
Disclosed to other department bodies
so as not to jeopardise the case
I want to catch them
all at one go
What will happen to Lao Yang
and Xiao Siang?
You have already make a big mistake
and yet still talking terms with me
I can only promise you that I will
plea to the judge on their behalf
I hope he can accept your mistake and
be lenient in his judgement
Ah Jun, thats are I can do
for this moment
You too have no other choice
He was forced taking the medicine,
try to let him spit it out
She saw my face
Is it safe here?
Only my girlfriend and myself
are holding the key
She went out a and will be
back only in one week time
Brother
I was instructed by other,
please let me go
I have two hundred thousand,
I shall give all to you
Its okay, do not panic
God bless
God bless me I dont to have to
dump the share
God bless
No need for second thought, once
trading resume, we will sell all
Of course, this junk stock is
not worth a penny
Rumours that the Company has liability of
more than 100 millions
In that case, the securities regulatory
bureaus has to perform a thorough check
Trading commence
The counter is still under suspension..
See what I mean, there is possbility
that it will stay longer than expected
Xiao Siang
Xiao Siang, counter has resumed
What is the use even it resumes
The stock price is dropping so bad
Who will want to buy at this moment
Quickly let go..
There is no connection
Nothing will happen...
Connected
- Stock 8822....
- Wait...
Whats the matter?
Fenghua International resume trading this morning
Close at $2.57 per share
Increase of more than 300 per cent
This is unusual for the
stock price volatility
Securities Regulatory Bureau has yet to
express their views on this area
The Company spokesman stressed that Fenghua
Show the public confidence and
it is completely normal
Run as your boss is
going to kill you
You betray me
Luo Yaoming ran away
Police looking for you everywhere
Contact Stuart Law and he will
advise you what to do
Move along
Son, you have to tell your mother
Dad made a lot of money buying stocks
After I am finished with my work, I shall
pick you folks back from grandma place
Ah Guang call me
He said that he had gone to the law firm
and took the divorce certificate
We are now settled once and for all
Ah Jun, where are you now?
I want to see you
I have something to take care
I shall see you later
Fine
See you later
Goodbye
20 years ago
I have to do business in California
for the first time
Imported from Germany, a number of
cheap second-hand convertible
The first guest was a gangster
He got into the car and step on
the accelerator pedal
Travel 50 miles per hour on the road and he was
very satisfied with the speed
But he was more worried about
the car convertible
If it rains, the water may leak
onto the car
At that time. how could it rain
in California
So I told him not to worry
If there is water leakage, then
I would open the door and
jump out of the car
Who knows that before I can finish...
Suddenly it began to rain heavily
It is damn unlucky
Rain water started to drop on that guy's
head bit by bit
Do you know what I did during
that moment?
We have to admit our mistake
Once we done that, we need to
change our way
For those who refuse to
admit and change
I will be able to help him
If Fenghua has gone bad tomorrow
and the situation is not good
You do not need to jump from the car,
Go jump from the building
Ah Jun
Sit
I have already taken the
divorce certificate
It is now finally settled after dragging
for a long time
It seems a lot easier
Lets go for a drink after work
Dont worry, I am okay
It is not a big issue. do not worry
Sir
Officer Li, dismiss your team
Action abolished
Ah Jun, tell them to tidy up
Understand
Please come out for a moment
Boss,  Officer Huang mobile number
Vice-Chairman of the SFC
I lnow him
Some people are just too bold
They actually turn aorund the
stock price several times
That group has been using this
tactic to make money
No respect for the law and order
According to our judegement on
this Fenghua case
It is not a problem to your
Intelligence Unit
What do you mean,  you have
suspicion on me?
Right
You have used a lot of human resources
for the past two months
and incurred a lot of expenses
out of the Government pocket
We have great expectations for you
The SFC also oversee our duty?
I did not say that
This case is handled together by us
Problems and responsibility should be
shared as a whole
For the past two months,
all Intelligence information collected will
certainly be analysed in detail
I request you to hand all the
information of the members now
However, the files in the Intelligence Unit
can only be retrieved by you alone
Please respect my authority
I am not discussing with you but rather
this is an order for you to obey
Thanks
Ah Jun
Lets go up the car and clear the stuff
Lets leave Hong Kong once and for all
What are you saying...
How do you handle your wife and kid?
The computer will be able to
recover in one night
Once they have access to the deleted records
in the hard drive, we are dead
I do not want to goto jail
Why dont we fo this...
We sneak in and destroy the hard drives
Here is the police headquarters and
you guys are really brave
The next moment, you guys can
also kill people
So what should we do now?
Is there any way?
You need to think fast
I have a plan
What is the plan
From now on, you have to listen to me
They both insisted on going to
destroy the evidence
I can not delay anymore
That stuff is very important,
you try to go along with them
To collect them back and dont
let them destroy it
How is the chicken drumstick, Mr Chen?
Delicious
I always tell my colleagues that in
the whole department
Xiao Yang is the most caring
people against me
Finished eating and then we can talk
Happen to  pass thtough the stall so
buy them back to let you taste it
If you like it, I have no problem to
buy it for you
Dont fool me.  How can people dont
collect their winning money?
You know my position
Suddenly there is a lot of money
would pose a porblem to me
Why dont you find a solution for me
Find a way to credit the money without
going through me
What are you saying
Brother, use your professional expertise
You must not talk nonsense as I
have a reputation in this industry
I will never do things against the law
No one inside theatre now
The film is ready, enter now
Half a million dollar
I said I will not be breaking the law
One Million dollars
There is audience entering the scene
3 Million dollars
I have a very good repuation
in this business
4 Million dollars
I will only do it for 10 millions
6 Million dollars
That is a discount to you
You dont even bring along the
door security card?
Sorry
Quickly disperse
Did you receive?
God bless me
that I do not need to
dump my share
God bless
God bless me not to dump...
8822 stock is dropping tremendously
It is only $1.20 now
There is information that Luo Yaoming
is letting go his cargo
He is obviously going for the money
instead of the goods
Did you locate Luo Yaoming?
Still no news
Quickly locate him
I go find Mr Chen and collect
back the transmitter
Why are there so much smoke
What's going on
Move along
Can I make a phone call?
Once the situation outside is better,
then we can use it
For decades, we have been good citizens
Just a wrong turn and we get
our clothes soaked
I found the terminal.
Do you still remember the lighter?
Luo Yaoming eavesdropping lighter can
only cover 200 meters
I trace the signal and it leads to the terminal
outside Fenghua
Do you still remember that night Luoyao Ming
suddenly returned back to the company?
Several of our colleagues failed to
see him going upstairs
He had been in the building all along
Terminal Station ia at 902, He install
the eavesdropping device on his own
He wanted to trap his boss with the device
All the secrets are in 902
We must first find it before his boss
Go up and check it out
Officer Huang said that the boss is
Ma Zhihua,, the Chairman of China Industry Group
He specializes in underground banks in
illegal betting activities
Police,  ICAC, Securities Regulatory Bureau and the
Courts cannot prosecute him
Do you know the reason?
Because all the witnesses are either suffering
from memory loss or they have disappeared
There are two accountants commiting
suicide by jumping from the building
Since you know his character, why do
you still going after him
We are daring to do wrong things but
afraid of doing the right thing
We might as well drop dead
You will die faster if you provoke him
The auntie who bought the share together with
us had jumped from the building this afternoon
If we have reported the case, she
probably would not have commit sucide
I know
But I do fear for our lives
You are a cop, why are you so afraid?
What are you afraid of?
I have divorced with Ah Guang
So congratulations
We are going off as we have some
business to take care
Lets go
Move along
Did you see it?
Are you alright?
That is not the .... of Xiao Guang?
Didnt you hear she said that
they have divorced?
Lets go
Hello
You have been followed.
Return to the police station immediately
Hello?
Xiao Siang!
Wheres your cell phone
What happed?
My phone signal have been intercepted
How is it?
Stop playing, lets go home now
Dont be mischevious, go up
the car quickly
Sit further inside
Okay, move along
You dont feel tired after a day ride
Thank you everyone. Thank you
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen
This is an era of collaboration
Many business community members
have said this before
The most important thing in a business
dealings between the partners are
To be honest and talk about credibility
Whether we agree with this argument
Personally. I think the most important
thing between partners
is communication
If we have communication problems
You will lose connectivity with
your partner
Even can be harmful to your partner
Son, quickly sit down. Its dangerous
Be obedient. Quickly sit down
This is a matter of life and death.
Very important
Sit properly and dont affect your
father while he is driving
I dont give means I will not give
Please stop quarelling
Hello?
Laoyang!
Hello? Hello?
What happen?
With good communication between the bridge
When partners are in danger then
We can lend a helping hand in time
So as to reflect the true faith
Thank you, thank you
Laoyang
Hello??
Rushing for time?
So you are the man
Pull out the gun to shoot me?
Xiao Guang, No.  Something has
happened to us
Ah Guang, its not what you think
Wan Er, you get on the train first
Didnt you say you want to
invite me for a drink
So it turned out to be a drink
for a wedding
Dont talk nonsense
Do not be afraid
Do not be afraid.
We have reached the hospital
Mr. You can not go in
I am a police officer
The police also can not enter the room
Ah Jun,  what the inside story
in this Fenghua's case,
Xiao Yang has been hit by a car
and the driver has been caught by us
The driver criminal record had been very bad
Obviously he had taken money
as a scapegoat
Half an hour ago
Please give way
Thank you, please give way
Half an hour ago we found Xiao Siang car
But up to now, we have fail
to locate him
You are still not talking even after
what had happened?
You are no match for this group of people
If you do not cooperate with me
Xiao Siang body may be thrown
from an unknown building
What have you heard
in Fenghua case?
Xiao Guang has been hit
Crime Squad is coming soon and
you cannot hide
I will definitely support you if you
tell me the truth.
Did you hear what I said?
Ah Jun
This is your last chance
what had happened during the Operation?
My action is in collaboration with the
Independent Commission Against Corruption
You must let me complete
the assignment
All the secrets are in 902
We first find it before his boss
Ladies and Gentlemen
Today, I am very pleased
Today, I am very honored
Because our Rensiao Hall Charity Fund.
Today I am very honored to inform you
Our Rensiao Hall Charity Fund has
Raise an amount of 51.86 million
in donations
On behalf of the Rensiao Church
I will like to thank this group
of philantropists here
for the support during the past year
So as to ensure the needy people
can get assistance
They can feel the community is caring
Thank you everyone
On the 25th, I have 60 million U.S. dollars
coming from foreign countries
During that time and in conjunction
with the charity event and Fenghua stocks,
Come up with a simple proposal
like a merger plan to lauder the money clean
Let go some stock to Lin Fei Fang
Brokers for this two week
To lower the stock price first
What kind of expression is that
on your face?
You do not want to work
Luen Kwong has a shareholder who claim
the company has discrepancy in the accounts
They want to find a new accountant
to re-audit the accounts
What does that mean?
You cannot handle?
Then you buy an economy class
flight on your own and fly over to
have a good talk with the drug lords
We simply find someone to kill him
Are you crazy?
You want to kill people when
there is account to be audited
Do you think I am a Lunatic Born Killers?
Can you try to talk to him first?
Afterall it is about money.
Discuss until he is satisfied
If there is no agreement, make
a call to Shang Gou and
Ask him to get some thugs to
scare the shareholder
We have already done that, Boss
He is not even afraid of Shang Gou?
Talk to him once more
If he still does not agree,
get rid of him
Dont use your own mobile during
these two weeks
Ah Hwa, give two unregistered
mobile number to them
Boss, Mr Xia is here
Mr Xia, thanks for coming
How can I dont come when you
have an official opening?
My salary is paid by the Government
just to take care of you people.
Who is this gentleman?
Let me introduce, he is commissioner Wu
of the Independent Commission Against Corruption
He is a master in golf
I have heard friends say Mr. Wu
is an expert in golf/
If you are free, you must drop in
at my country club to display your skill
No problem but today, we are
here to watch your presentation
Come, lets take a picture of the group
Mr Xia
Leave for a memory
Good, one more picture
Church Charity Foundation requested the
presence of President Rensiao
As well as UOL Group Chairman, Mr. Ma Zhihua
Thank you.
Today, my personal driver, Ah Cheng
asked me a question, he said "Boss,
I bought two lots of Chinese
business group's stock recently,
I do not know whether I can let go now"
I said to him
Our company's current market value is 15.6 billion
Last year it earned more than one billion
Dividend is 57 cents
Looking at it, the interest is even
better than bank profits
Should consider for long-term holding
Who knows Ah Cheng asked
Its been half a year
But I have not send you back
to the Company office
Do you really know what business
is in the company?
I was puzzled by his question and
dont know how to reply him
Before I have time to reply him,
he uses his mobile to make
a call to his stock broker
and sold his shares in Chinese
industry in front of my face
It seems the price is good
It tempts me to also sell some of my shares.
Hence in the future,
If you have any questions on the
China trade stock issues
Please be kind enough to call my
personal driver Ah Cheng
Thank you
Ah Cheng had been correct
I have put down all my work for
the past six months
Because I have more important
and more meaningful things to do
This year, Liren Xiao Tang Charity Foundation
has raised a total of
51,867,053 dollars of
Charitable Donations
Thank you
I want to thank all Rensiao
Hall directors and employees
During the past year's for their efforts
All the donations are from
I am sorry for this..
On the 15th there will be 60 million
U.S. dollars coming from foreign countries
During that time and in conjunction with
the charity event and the Fenghua stock
Come up with a simple proposal
like a merger plan to lauder the money clean
Let go some stock to Lin Fei Fang
Brokers for this two week
To lower the stock price first
Independent Commission Against Corruption
Hey. off the video quickly
Hey, find someone to turn off the video
Do you hear me?
What are you doing?
Turn off the video quicki
Quickly turn off the video
Then you buy an economy
class flight on your own and fly over there to
have a good talk with the drug lords
Afraid
You, what you want?
I am the one that install the monitor.
I have plenty of this kind of evidence
Son of a bitch, you did not die
Your speech is interesting. You always say
the right things for the wrong things done
Do you know how to distinguish
the difference?
I do not know what to say
Ah Hwa
Ah Hwa, where are you?
Ah Hwa has run away after receiving
money from me
Give me a life
I have 15 million which I
can give all to you
Whatever you do, you can never earned
15 million dollars in your lifetime
Kill me and you've got nothing
I'll come back in half an hour, we
will talk if you still survive
Independent Commission Against Corruption
We suspect that you are involved
With many cases relating to commercial
fraud and forgery
And also several cases of murder
and money laundering
Requires your assistance in
the investigation
The police and Independent Commission
Against Corruption has a car ready waiting for you
I have a car
Go to hell
Although you have help us gather a lot of
evidence during this past year
and now an arrest has been made
You and Yang have been relieved
of your duties
You obstruct the justice
and abuse of power for personal gain
is a crime to pay
Independent Commission Against Corruption is
making a formal arrest, do you understand?
I understand
I'm sorry for troubling you
Five to eight years
You help me to find someone as
a scapegoat for the murder
Szeto, you listen
In two hours time, trading commences
All share related to me have to be sold
You inform the brokers not to ask for
price and let go whatever I have
The important thing is when I am discharged,
there is still a  paradise for rme
Szeto, do not let me down
We will meet at the police station
All units to take note, suspect's vehicle
suddenly taking another route
All vehicles make a U-turn in front to catch up
and do not let the suspect run away
We will make a U-turn in front at that exit
Relax the bridge is not ready for
passing through, he cannot get away
Ah Cheng
Who are you?
What do you want?
Stop the car.