PAINTED SKIN
Hey... come on!.
Beauty!
are you hungry?
What would you like to eat?
Congratulations, boss ...
Say it and I'll get you whatever you want!
Really?
My heart is now yours.
Oh... so I can have it
It's on fire ...
Sneak attack! Chase them...
Shoot!
It is bad, boss!
Come on. I'll take you away.
Come on.
Hold me tight!
Sacrifice our lives!
For the sake of our parents!
Spill our blood!
For the sake of our home!
Walk a million miles!
And kill the bandits of the desert!
To save the beauty!
They're back! They're back, the
General is back!
We saved her just.
Her parents are dead.
Why has she disappeared?
Someone's knocking on the door?
Open the door!
Mistress!
Can't we just send him again?
See who's....
Bullshit!.
We're brothers.
And it's New Year.
Who?
He's back.
You're all here?
Miss Xiaowei.
It's so cold outside.
Drink some hot water.
Give it to me!
Have some flower cakes!.
Okay, thank you.
Thanks, Miss Xiaowei.
Brother Gao Xiang, drink whlie it's hot.
So attentive!
Who is this man?
He...
Right there!
General...
General, are you okay?
Why didn't you wait for us?
General...
Have you gone mad?
Hundreds of gangsters here!.
You said,
we're all brothers who'd die together.
We must all go home alive!
I'll never lead you.
Brother Young!
General... Brother Yong...
Freeze!
You won't! A soldier like you
can't go as you wish!
This is desertion and the penalty
is death!
No.
No...
Get away!
Leave me!
Everybody, take care,
General … Brother Yong …
Have you contacted him?
No!
Don't you want him to come back?
Of course I do.
Perhaps he can catch the guy who...
tore the hearts out.
I just never thought.
he'd be dejected like this.
I've never blamed him,
he must have his reasons
Be carefull
I can't live without you
Not woken up yet?
No.
Let me get you some tea.
Peirong, I haven't slept a wink for days
Peirong... I've drunk too much!
Brother Yong.
You've woken up.
Sorry.
Thanks!
I'm going!
Brother Yong.
Hey brother!
It's New Year's Eve.
At least stay with us for the...
No, thanks!.
Brother Yong, just wait a moment
I've got something to return to you .
Brother Yong, your sword...
I wish you good luck!
Waiter, any spare rooms?
Yes, sure...
Please pay a deposit a the counter first, sir
I'm leaving my horse here
and... do you think I'll run away?
Okay, fine...
Waiter, don't forget to look after my horse!
I will, I guarantee it. Rest assured!
Please pay a deposit first, sir.
I'm leaving my horse here
and...you think I'll run away?
Take care of my horse!
I will.
Take care, sir.
Happy new year!
Let's go!
Waiter, it's a big inn , nothing more than that.
Not even a slice of meat?
They have all gone home for new year,
so has the chef...
Let it be... any wine?
Sure,...I'll get it now!
A bottle of best spring liquor!
Sir, it's just sold out!
She's taken all the rest.
Sir, please choose another
Come here. Be my guest!
Please!
Waiter!
Waiter, one more bottle!
Waiter, ...
No need... Here.
I'll give this pair of jade pendants
to the one you love...
How are you doing?
Where have you been the last two years?
You're here just to ask such dull questions?.
I suspect if there's a demon in our house.
three months ago...
When Brother Sheng was back after
encountering bandits in the desert.
he rescued a young woman with
nowhere to stay.
Sister sister!
She is Xiaowei.
She claimed to be the daughter of Gao Kun.
a wealthy silk businessman.
Her parents were framed
and killed by corrupt officials.
and she was sold to the bandits...
Tell me...
So many people love Xiaowei.
Who will she go for?
How do I know what's in a woman's heart?.
Suddenly!
there appeared an assassin in the city who tore out
the hearts of so many.
The new magistrate has not yet come.
But there can't be a city without law.
Brothers, we will now take charge of the city
Until the new magistrate takes up his post.
Are you ready?
The assassin keeps killing!
Ready!
Nobody can deal with it.
Go!
The only thing he can do is step up
the patrols every night.
Then some times later,.
people start to doubt if they're
all the work of evil demons.
There is the pearl powder.
New arrival.
Do you want to try it?
Miss, what you want is this, right?
Why should I buy this?
You have to
I'll take them all!
You've got to put on makeup!
Sure, I have to put on makeup.
This way, please.
Is she really an evil demon?
I can't help you.
Let me find you a man of power.
Stay back. Back off...
The Taoist is dead, with his heart dug out ...
The killer is a big tall guy.
Xiaonou, hand me the medical kit!
Xiaowei is hurt!
Sister!
You didn't cut myself. See, I'm fine.
Impossible! I clearly saw her wound!
What are you talking about?
She is not an evil demon, is she?
She's nice and charming.
But how could she really be?.
Only you can.... understand me.
I've sent you so many letters,
I don't know if you got them.
What is up now?
Now she's become...
more friendly with everyone.
and she's getting very close to Brother Sheng!
Does anyone know you suspect she's a demon?
How dare I tell anyone else?.
No one would believe me!
Demon?
You don't believe me brother?
Of cause I do!
When did I ever disbelieve you?
What do you want me to do?
Find out the truth!
What if she's really not a demon?
Then I'll admit I'm wrong..
Please, Brother Yong!
Do you have any money?
Find me if you don't have enough.
Lend me some money.
No money? But you invited me for a drink!
You enjoyed it too, didn't you?
I've sliced them for you from six humans.
Why kill so many? How do I eat them
all at once?
That's for you to choose.
It's just a few
I don't mean to feel
bad for them.
But you've made a lot of work for
Wang Sheng..
I hardly see him these days
You're so disgusting!
You're wasting your time.
He will love me.
Why don't you just be his mistress?
What I want to be is his wife!
Listen, I shall be Mrs.Wang!
So you want to give up your training?
I have plenty of time.
But your skin won't wait.
You need more hearts to keep your human
skin from rotting.
Yes! Therefore, I've got to find a way out,
so I can stop myself eating human hearts!
Hurry up!
Be careful.
Didn't I say you should wait for me?.
Miss Xiaowei said ...
Master's irritated so we must
hurry to give out the dishes.
Let me do it!
Sister- in -law!
Mistress!
Start the meal!
Let me do it..
Where have you just been?
Everybody is waiting for you.
I've ...
Brother Wang, don't be upset with her.
Sister Peirong went to the beauty shop...
for some lavender.
to put under your pillow in a bag.
so you can sleep well.
It's New Year now.
Don't worry too much.
I know.
Sister!
Are you looking for this?
I must thank you today.
I'll give it to Brother Sheng!
I know who you've been to see.
I won't tell Brother Wang.
Something is actually not
what you think.
Anyway...
I'll tell you more
about us later.
It's good as long as you're happy.
Have a rest!
The dead bodies whose hearts
are removed are all here
Brother Sheng has run out of ideas
so our Wang's Squadron... ...
can only patrol every night
Wang's Squadron?
You're left for so long. Should we now
call it "Pang's Squadron"?
Wow.
This man is a real pro!
So accurate that he dug out the heart
in a single cut!
So I told Brother Sheng this
couldn't be done by a human.
You really believe in demons?
If I were a Yin Yang Practitioner
I surely would ...
A demon, a demon here!
Look at yourself. You believe in any crap!
What do you not believe,
Yin Yang Practitioner ?
Also, I suspect one person...
The woman Brother Sheng brought here,
Xiaowei.
Don't you love her?
I'm not sure!
You suspect her?
The killing spree began once she arrived.
I really feel the evil emanating from her...
She has a suspicious background
Enough! You can set up a booth out there
and fool the guys!
Get off! you feel good staying in a coffin?
Get off!
What he says is correct!
All done by evil demons!
I too think evil demons did this!
Don't listen to her foolish talk!
It's all nonsense!
What foolish talk? I've seen this before.
There are many demons in this world.
Some are transformed from flowers,
grass and trees...
some from tigers, wolves,
snakes and foxes......
and some from love and hatred...
Some are good, some are bad...
... No kidding!
Demons kill with a sword?
Why do assassins kill humans for their hearts?
What's your name? You seem very sure?
My name is Xia Bing.
I'm a Demon Hunter.
My name is Pang Yong.
I don't believe in demons.
This sealed part of the fox tail will direct us
to the Beautiful Fox from the Sky.
Once it senses a fox spirit in the vicinity,
it glares.
This is what brought me here.
I'm sure the demon is still in this city.
Can you sense where the demon is?
Within a ten mile radius of here.
The entire city is only some ten miles long.
I've made a box for you.
Put the hearts inside and they'll be kept fresh.
Just put it there.
Brother Sheng asked me to draw the
heart thief.. I must do it well.
Remember that old man named Xia
who cut you?
Isn't he dead?
His granddaughter is here in town!
Damn it. Their family will never let me go!
Shall I kill her for you!
Yes!
Such a big range!
This is the last place!
I've spent all my money on the case.
The Taoist priest died right here!
Also!
all the murders occured on the
east side of the city.
Look...
Not only that, they all died around the
commander's house!
Exactly!
So what do we do next?
Nothing to do with you.
Miss, this is an official matter.
I think you needn't ask.
He doesn't work for the government,
either!
Nothing to do with you as well.
Hey, where are you going?
Nothing to do with you!
Hey……
I've used up my money!
Are you okay?
You're that demon?
Don't fool around!
You wanna run?
You go over there!
Leave me alone! Get him!
Waiter! Waiter!
Stop shouting. It's new year's day. Everybody's gone.
Have you come to drink or heal me?
Don't panic. its just a small wound.
What are you doing?
Why didn't you tell me you'd blow?
I had wine in my mouth. I couldn't tell you.
Have you seen enough?
Don't move!
What?
What...you...?
Carefully…Carefully…
Be quiet.
It was done with a sword!
Demons can't use swords
Who say they can't?
Carefully, Carefully…
How do you deal with them?
Ordinary demons can be finished
with a single slash!
What if they're not ordinary?
This is the "Demon....?”.
My grandfather told me that...
its power is limitless when its
inside a capable person.
That person is surely not you!
I can't take it out.
Not me, either.
I think your grandpa
also couldn't.
Sure! How do you know?
You don't believe my words?
Yes.. yes.. I dare not disbelieve!
Don't get caught.
I would have killed the girl if
It weren't for...
So she was really helped from her old lover.
Where did you go?
I.. I just help in the reading room…
You better go to the kitchen now.
Yes!
Brother Young, I've checked it.
There is a rich man called Gao Kun
in another city.
The whole family died during a
disease epidemic 3 years ago.
He doesn't have a daughter,
She tells lies!
Peirung, where's Xiaowei?
In the beauty shop.
Brother Yong, what do you find her for?
She's not what she claimed to be!
You've brought a demon home!
Demon?
Brother Yong, do you believe
a rumour like this?
I just want to find out the truth.
Truth....Fine.
I'll take you there to see the truth.
The Gao family has no daughter!
Who are you?
Xiahou Xiang is known to be wrong all the time?
Has he misunderstood you?
That's right! Miss Xiaowei,
just go ahead,
tell us your problems!
Xiaowei, don't be scared!
Tell us everything.
I'm actually not the Gao family's daughter.
I'm only…
the maid.
But I love being with you and don't want
you to look down upon me.
That's why I made up such a stupid story.
Can anyone else verify what you said?
No.
We can!
We rescued her from the lair
of the desert bandits.
She'd have died if..
it weren't for us!
Yes… yes. Sure! We rescued her...…
Brother Wang...
I did tell lies.
But please don't banish me! Will you?
I don't want to be alone.
Get up.
With me here, nobody dare bully you.
I'll chop your hands off and see
if you're a demon!.
Brother Yong.
what are you doing? Are you crazy?
I was just teasing her....
It's the back of the blade.
I don't care what tricks you played.
Xiaowei is my family!
Your family... so what about Peirong?
Peirong is your wife!
She's been worried about you every day!
Brother Yong.
You still care that Peirong had chosen me!
Bastard!
I'm not happy.
Peirong has chosen the wrong one!
You cold-hearted thing!
They're already married.
I think you'd better give up.
Shut up!
Obsessed by that woman!
You've never seen a woman?
Pang Yong!
It's my private matter. Not yours!
I must care about the demon's case.
This is a section of tail from a fox spirit
Whenever a demon shows up, it glares.
It's always glaring. So we are all demons?
I'm the Demon Hunter... Everything I said is real!
I don't believe it... Who does?
The ghosts do!
I do!
I saw it with my own eyes!
She knows black magic.
I hurt her hand by accident!
and it healed at once.
Later I told this to the Taoist priest.
He said you're a demon with great power.
On the very next day, he died…
I've been staying with you, I know more
than anyone else.
I have an idea.
Thre's a mark on each demon
like a human's birthmark.
Dare you let us examine you?
Demon, are you scared?
Dare you?
I dare!
I do as long as you won't suspect me!
Satisfied?
Nothing to do with her. They're all my ideas
I still have one more idea.
Are you finished?
For a fox spirit to sustain the human form,
it must eat human hearts.
which is why there're so many deaths
with their hearts removed.
Are you finished?.
Sure… Are you wasting our time?
What you mean is…
if she has no heart to eat,
she'll reveal her true form?
Let's watch Miss Xiaowei for a while.
See if she'll become a demon with
no hearts to eat
I must let you know that you're wrong!
Get in!
I understand that!
You're just concerned about me.
I'm sorry!
You should apologize to Xiaowei!
I'm so sorry…
I'm so sorry for you sister!
I know why you suspect that I'm a demon.
You're worried I'll steal Brother Wang.
Yes..I really love him.
But don't misunderstand....
I'll never oppose you
Please accept me as his concubine
Please…
Xiaowei, just get up.
Sister Peirong, I beg you..…
Xiao wei.
There is only one Mrs Wang.
You should be scared today.
Xiaorou!
Yes!
Take Xiaowei back to her room.
Miss Xiaowei.
Stick with her! Even when
she's relieves herself!
Please get some rest, Miss Xiaowei.
Okay.
I have some good dim sum,
do you want some?
No, thanks.
You might try to poison me!.
Do you still suspect me?
I never suspected you.
I am sure you do!
General! General!
The Demon has done it again!
Brother Yong.
The Demon has killed some more people during
the last couple of days.
Our soldiers were placed every where, but...
..we still can't catch him.
You can't catch him... He is a demon!
Demon?
Don't you mean Xiaowei's a demon?
You've been watching her all day.
Why are there still deaths outside?
Who says there is only one demon?
Another one?
Wang Sheng, what do you think?
I think..
He should be a kung fu expert.
Only you can seize him.
I sincerely hope you stay.
Peirong, all the citizens here
will thank you!
Please!
Peirong.
Your persuasive Brother Yong.
I'm sorry.
Don't say sorry. I don't want you
to say sorry.
You've done nothing wrong.
I'm back only to see that you're happy.
You look good, dont you?
Brother Yong.
You're the best man ever.
Hope you will find a woman better than me.
Don't worry.
I've been traveling around
alone very well.
So free and nothing to be anxious about.
Lets talk later. I'll go and help
Wang Sheng now.
Stupid man!
Miss Xiao Bing. He's a good man.
Do treat him better!
Don't lump me with him.
It's not what you think.
I'm not interested in such stupid stuff...
put on our golden armour
and we are forever the strongest
Sacrifice our lives for the sake
of our parents
Spill our blood…
Xiahou Xiang!
This time, I get the plot…
Mistress…
My God! I heard that Pang Yong
killed Xiahou Xiang!
Impossible!
The Mo Zhui guys say they saw it!
Xiahou Xiang is dead.
I know.
They suspect that I killed him.
I know that as well.
I don't believe it though
Under such circumstances...
you will suffer if you follow me.
Who's following you?
Now you're following me
to catch the demon!
Catch it? Are you confident?
No, for sure!
When have I ever been confident?
But why are you still after him?
You're not scared of death?
I'm a Demon Hunter
It's my duty.
His horse is still here,
He must still be in the city.
You take a team there.
Yes, Let's go!
Go, take care general.
Get some sleep
I'll go no where tonight.
I'll stay with you
Don't worry!
I don't believe Brother Yong
killed Xiahou Xiang either.
I'll find him and ask him though.
I want to ask you.
will you love her...
if Xiaowei is not a demon?
How can Xiaowei be a demon?
Okay ... I promise.
I'll get more Taoist priests
to check her out, okay?
Okay?
You haven't answered me yet.
Will you love her?
Whether she is a demon or woman,
I won't!
Rest assured!
What's up?
Brother Wang!
I think I must go.
I've said too much....
Did you forget?
I promised to protect you.
Peirong knows this ,too.
If I die or live, that 's not important!
How could it be?
Cao Huong, Kinh Binh, Kinh An, brothers.
They all like you.
I think that nobody ever dislikes you…
in the whole world?
But I only want you to love me!
Can I not even become your mistress?
It's me who is qualified!
Don't sell yourself short!
You couldn't be my mistress.
You should find a good man..
who will take care of you and love you.
Right?
Have you ever loved me?
I don't need anyone else!
I don't have any preference
I just want to be your woman.
Even if just once…
Are you alright?
Alright.
You needn't worry if Xiaowei's a demon, okay?
What's wrong?
Why were you staying in her room?
I…
I just…
Don't need to say it
I know she really loves you.
And I understand.
It's not what you think…
It's all my fault.
As a wife , I was jealous maybe...
If you love her too,!
then make her your mistress.
I don't.
Let me finish my words.
As her elder sister, I'll decide for her.
It's you…
who still doesn't believe I can do it.
General…
Who let you out?
Don't forget you're a demon!
Don't shed a tear for a man!
Now you're more stupid than that
stupid woman!
You know I love him?
Do you know what love is,
you fly eater?
I know.
And I've told you, I love you.
But I don't love you!.
I said that long ago. You've been
shameless enough to stay!
Who will get you all those hearts
without me?.
I'll live well without you!.
Now act like a man and leave.
Get away!
Okay.
I'm sorry for what I 've done.
I'll never disturb you!.
Go!
Mistress...
Sister Peirong, you're still up?
Sister Xiaowei.
I think there is one thing
I must talk to you about.
You want me ...for some thing?
Now you know it all.
Go tell everyone.
Those who know must die, after all.
Brother Gao, Let's take a look outside.
Be careful.
Okay.
Go.
Mistress, are you all right?
I'm fine.
What do you want?
I havent decided yet
Brother Gao.
Miss Xiaowei.
Don't come in!.
Brother Gao, Sister Peirong
said she saw a demon.
Demon? Where is it?
Right here.
No!
Didn't you say you like me?,
Can you give me your heart?
Seen any demons eating a human heart?
Brother Sheng loves you. Don't hurt him!
It's useless as long as you,
Mrs Wang is here.
That's nothing.
I can let you be Mrs.Wang.
Me?
Can you guarantee that you'll
never come back?
I've seen you eat a human heart
Can I still stay alive?
Go ahead kill me!.
You think that I'm stupid?
If I kill you,
Brother Wang would miss you forever.
Drink this!
Go ahead, admit to being a demon
and killing all those people.
I'll be Mrs.Wang, and you'll be a demon!
I can.
But will you promise not to kill again?.
I'm a demon. How can I grow If I don't?.
Okay, I promise you.
When I become Mrs. Wang.
I'll stay with him, grow old and die with him.
You really love him?
Yes, I do.
Do keep your word.
If you have regrets I'll kill everyone.
You don't even know
what love is.
A demon...
Xiaorou... Xiaorou...
Help, help..
Mistress...
What's happening?
Hey,stop!
Mistress, is it you?
I'm a demon.
Go ahead kill me.
You all stop moving.
Back off.
Or I'll kill you.
Peirong, stand it! You'll be fine
Master! Mistress is really the demon!.
Xiaorou, dont talk nonsense.
Hassiter Peirong... suffered a
strange disease??
Not her? So who killed Brother Gao?
Sure.
We must avenge Brother Gao!.
She seems to have suffered from an evil poison.
It's graded by color.
The lighter the color, the more deadly it is
White is therefore the most poisonous of all.
When the whole body turns white, one will die.
Do you have any ways?
How can we save her?
You've woken up, Peirong. Feeling better?
You all leave me!
Did Xiaowei do this?
I myself.
am the demon.
Don't speak nonsense!
Don't worry. You'll be fine.
She is a demon hunter,
she must be able to help.
Don't you have your family's treasures?
Sure. My grandfather left me a lot..
Not these!
Your grandfather...
he gave me that one treasure
Sure…
Look! She really has the treasure!
It can destroy the demons.
come to think of it.
my grandfather told me..
once the demon is killed...
the dark magic cast on the human body
should vanish
Can you hear it?
Yes.
You'd have used it if it was really useful
You cannot beat her
Don't worry.
The killings should end with me
Stop speaking nonsense.
I will have the way
Peirong.
Peirong. I've taken back my sword.
You know how powerful it is?
With it...I have never lost!
You'll be safe once I kill the demon!
I'll chop her into pieces! Okay?
I'll ask you one more time.
You're sure it's Xiaowei?
I don't want any innocent deaths
You still don't believe me now?
Okay, I'm going.
You take care of Peirong.
You're really going?
I must go for sure.
You can't... You can't kill her!
Don't kid me!
Your Grandfather cut off the fox spirit's tail.
This sword's great
How could I not kill him?
My granpa cut her using his own blood!
We, the "Demon Hunters" have blood
which can especially kill demons.
If you do want to kill Xiaowei.
take me there.
Wang Sheng.
do you know what's happening?
Miss, don't go theré!
Are you really a demon?
Yes.
You killed Gao Xiang?
I killed all.
We must have revenge for Brother Gao.
You want to kill her, kill me first
Revenge for Brother Gao!.
An eye for an eye!
Revenge for Brother Gao.
Shut up!
She's a demon!
I must kill her!
But how can I give her up as a husband?
Put down the knife!
Wang Sheng.
Put down the knife first.
Peirong...
I must take all the responsibility with you!.
I'm a demon. I killed so many and deserve it.
You're my wife.
Whether you're a demon or a woman, I love you.
I love you forever.
No!
Promise me.
Live well.
Live on for me...
Evil woman!
You all see it? She is the real demon!
You all see it now? She is the real demon!
What, leave me!
You can't kill her.
What are you doing?
Go.
Give her back to me.
If you love me.
Give Peirong back to me!
If you love her so much...
why don't you die with her?
I'll die.
Get her here
Will you believe her?
If Peirong dies.
I'll die with her
If she comes back to life.
Tell her that
I haven't been a good husband.
I've failed to protect her.
I love you.
but I'm married to Peirong.
No.
Brother Sheng...
What is this?
You saved them with a thousand
year old Spirit.
You're a demon
They won't let you go, even if you save them!
How can a demon get true love in this world?
I'll get you out of here, once I kill them all
Look! He has a shadow!
Take it!
Hurry up!.
Kill him...
Do it just do it. It doesn't matter if I die
You must kill him!
Take Peirong's spirit back an save her.
Kill me! Do it quickly!
Do it!
Xiaowei...
Much hatred in the world...
..can be ceased without killing.
I now realize why.
I couldn't exert all my energy as a Demon Hunter.
It's because I've been bearing hatred.
Go ahead, save them.
General, General…
Are you okay general?
Master are you okay?
Brother Dabao are you okay?
Mistress.
General are you okay?
Brother Dabao…
Mistress, it's fine now.
Brother Yong …
Brother Yong
Brother Yong ... Brother Yong…
What's wrong with you? Brother Yong!
Wake up... Brother Yong
Brother Yong ! Wake up...
Brother Yong !…
Don't shake me anymore
I'm surely dying!
I'm so tired after a long fight.
You're sure you don't want to stay?
There's still many places I want to go.
Me too.
I'm leaving.
Take care.
Where are you going?
The world's so big, I can go wherever I want.
You seem to have a gift for
catching demons!
Hey!
Do you want to catch demons with me?
Why don't you call me master?
You're not qualified with all those mediocre skills?
I'm more experienced than you!
What are you looking at?
Take off your cap and
you look very much like a woman!
Re Edit by Ghostmann.... Enjoy!