♫ I know you ♫
♫ I walked with you once upon a dream ♫
♫ The gleam in your eyes ♫
♫ Is so familiar a gleam ♫
♫ Yet I know it's true ♫
♫ That visions are seldom all they seem ♫
♫ But if I know you ♫
♫ I know what you'll do ♫
♫ You'll love me at once ♫
♫ The way you did ♫
♫ Once upon a dream ♫
In a faraway land long ago,
lived a king and his fair queen.
Many years had they longed for a child,
and finally their wish was granted.
A daughter was born, and
they called her Aurora.
♫ Sweet Aurora ♫
Yes, they named her after the dawn,
for she filled their lives with sunshine.
Then a great holiday was
proclaimed throughout the kingdom,
so that all of high or low estate
might pay homage to the infant princess.
And our story begins on
that most joyful day.
♫ On that joyful day ♫
♫ Joyfully now to our
princess we come. ♫
♫ Bringing gifts and all good wishes
too we pledge our loyalty anew. ♫
♫ Hail to the Princess Aurora. ♫
♫ All of her subjects adore her. ♫
♫ Hail to the King,
hail to the Queen. ♫
♫ Hail to the Princess Aurora. ♫
♫ Health to the Princess
Wealth to the Princess. ♫
♫ Long live the Princess Aurora. ♫
♫ Hail, Aurora. ♫
♫ Health to the Princess
Wealth to the Princess. ♫
♫ Long live the Princess Aurora. ♫
♫ Hail to the King,
hail to the Queen. ♫
♫ Hail to the. ♫
♫ Princess Aurora. ♫
Thus, on this great and joyous day
did all the kingdom celebrate
the long-awaited royal birth.
And good King Stefan and his queen
made welcome their lifelong friend.
Their royal highness’s,
King Hubert and Prince Phillip!
Fondly had these monarchs dreamed
one day their kingdoms to unite.
Thus, today would they
announce that Phillip,
Hubert's son and heir,
to Stefanie child would be betrothed.
And so to her his gift he brought.
And looked unknowing on his future bride.
Their most honored and
exalted excellencies,
the three good fairies.
Mistress Flora!
Mistress Fauna!
And Mistress Merryweather!
- Oh.
The little darling.
= Your Majesties.
Each of us the child may
bless with a single gift,
no more, no less.
Little princess, my gift
shall be the gift of beauty.
♫ One gift. ♫
♫ Beauty rare. ♫
♫ Gold of sunshine in her hair. ♫
♫ Lips that shame the
red, red rose. ♫
♫ She'll walk with springtime. ♫
♫ Wherever she goes. ♫
Tiny princess, my gift
shall be the gift of song.
♫ One gift. ♫
♫ The gift of song. ♫
♫ Melody her whole life long. ♫
♫ The nightingale's her troubadour. ♫
♫ Bringing his sweet
serenade to her door. ♫
Sweet princess, my gift shall be...
Why, it's Maleficent.
- What does she want here?
- Shh.
Well, quite a glittering
assemblage, King Stefan.
Royalty, nobility,
the gentry and...
How quaint.
Even the rabble.
I really felt quite distressed
at not receiving an invitation.
You weren't wanted.
Not want...
Oh, dear, what an awkward situation.
I had hoped it was merely
due to some oversight.
Well, in that event, I'd best be on my way.
And, you're not offended, Your Excellency?
Why, no, Your Majesty.
And to show I bear no ill will,
I, too, shall bestow a gift on the child.
Listen well, all of you.
The princess shall indeed
grow in grace and beauty,
beloved by all who know her.
But,
before the sun sets on her 16th birthday,
she shall prick her finger
on the spindle of a spinning wheel and die!
Oh, no!
Seize that creature!
Stand back, you fools!
Don't despair, Your Majesties.
Merryweather still has her gift to give.
Then she can undo this fearful curse?
Oh, no, Sire.
Maleficent's powers are far too great.
But she can help.
But...
Just do your best, dear.
Yes, go on.
Sweet princess, if through
this wicked witch's trick
a spindle should your finger prick,
a ray of hope there still may be in this,
the gift I give to thee.
Not in death, but just in sleep.
The fateful prophecy you'll keep.
And from this slumber you shall wake,
when true love's kiss
the spell shall break.
♫ For true love. ♫
♫ Conquers all. ♫
But King Stefan,
still fearful of his daughter's life,
did then and there decree
that every spinning wheel in the kingdom
should on that very day be burned.
So it was done.
Oh, silly fiddle-faddle.
Now, come have a nice cup of tea, dear.
I'm sure it'll work out somehow.
Well, a bonfire won't stop Maleficent.
Of course not. But what will?
Well, perhaps if we reason with her.
- Reason?
- With Maleficent?
- Well, she can't be all bad.
- Oh, yes, she can.
I'd like to turn her into
a fat, old hop toad.
Now, dear, that isn't a
very nice thing to say.
Besides, we can't.
You know our magic doesn't work that way.
It can only do good, dear,
to bring joy and happiness.
Well, that would make me happy.
But there must be some way.
- There is!
- There is?
What is it, Flora?
I'm going to...
Shh-shh-shh-shh.
Even walls have ears.
Follow me.
- I'll turn her into a flower.
- Maleficent?
No, no, dear, the princess.
Oh, she'd make a lovely flower.
Don't you see? A flower
can't prick its finger.
- It hasn't any.
- That's right.
She'll be perfectly safe.
Until Maleficent sends a frost.
Yes...
Oh, dear.
She always ruins your nicest flowers.
You're right.
And she'll be expecting us
to do something like that.
Well, what won't she expect?
She knows everything.
Oh, but she doesn't, dear.
Maleficent doesn't know
anything about love,
or kindness or the joy of helping others.
You know, sometimes I don't
think she's really very happy.
That's it!
Of course. It's the only
thing she can't understand
and won't expect.
Now, now, now we'll have
to plan it carefully.
Let's see. The woodcutter's cottage,
yes, yes, the abandoned one.
Of course, the King and Queen will object.
But when we explain it's the only way...
Explain what?
About the three peasant women
raising a foundling child
deep in the forest.
Oh, that's very nice of them.
Who are they?
Turn around.
Eww!
Why, it's us!
Uh-huh.
- You mean, "we" us?
- Uh-huh.
Take care of the baby?
Why not?
Oh, I'd like that.
Well, yes, but we'd have to feed it.
And wash it and dress it and rock
it to sleep. Oh, I'd love it.
You really think we can?
If humans can do it, so can we.
And we'd have our magic to help us.
That's right.
No, no, no! No magic.
I'll take those wands right now.
Oh, better get rid of those wings, too.
You mean live like mortals?
For sixteen years?
Uh-huh.
Now, now, we don't know how.
We've never done anything without magic.
And that's why Maleficent
will never suspect.
But who'll wash?
- And cook?
- Oh, we'll all pitch in.
- I'll take care of the baby.
- Let me have it, dear.
Come along now. We must tell
Their Majesties at once.
- Flora?
So, the King and his queen
watched with heavy hearts
as their most precious possession,
their only child,
disappeared into the night.
Many sad and lonely years passed by
for King Stefan and his people.
But as the time for the princess's
16th birthday drew near,
the entire kingdom began to rejoice.
For everyone knew that as
long as Maleficent's domain,
the Forbidden Mountains,
thundered with her wrath and frustration,
her evil prophecy had
not yet been fulfilled.
It's incredible!
Sixteen years, and not a trace of her!
She couldn't have vanished into thin air!
Are you sure you searched everywhere?
Yep, yep, everywhere. We all did.
Yes, yes.
And what about the town? The forest?
The mountains?
We searched mountains, forests...
And houses and...
Let me see. And all the cradles.
Cradle?
Yep, yep.
Every cradle.
Cradle!
Did you hear that, my pet?
All these years they've
been looking for a baby.
Fools!
Idiots! Imbeciles!
Oh, they're hopeless.
A disgrace to the forces of evil.
My pet. You are my last hope.
Circle far and wide.
Search for a maid of 16,
with hair of sunshine gold
and lips red as the rose.
Go, and do not fail me.
And so, for sixteen long years,
the whereabouts of the
princess remained a mystery.
While deep in the forest,
in a woodcutter's cottage,
the good fairies carried
out their well-laid plan.
Living like mortals, they had
reared the child as their own,
and called her Briar Rose.
On this, her 16th birthday, the
good fairies had planned a party.
And something extra special for a surprise.
Well, how about this one?
This is the one I picked.
Oh, she'll look beautiful in that.
- Now, I thought a few changes here.
- Uh-huh.
Don't forget a pretty bow.
Yes, and raise the shoulder line.
- We'll make it blue.
- Oh, no, dear, pink.
- But...
- Of course, we need a few pleats.
Yes, but how are we gonna
get her out of the house?
Oh, I'll think of something.
Well, and what are you three dears up to?
- Up to?
Up to?
Uh-uh, eh... Well, well, we...
We want you to pick some berries.
- That's it! Berries!
- Berries?
- Lots of berries.
- But I picked berries yesterday.
Oh, we need more, dear.
Lots, lots more.
Yes.
- Now, don't hurry back, dear.
- But don't go too far.
And don't speak to strangers.
Goodbye, dear.
- Good bye.
- Goodbye.
Goodbye.
I wonder if she suspects.
Of course not. Come on.
Oh, will she be surprised.
- A real birthday party.
- With a real birthday cake.
Yes, and a dress a
princess can be proud of.
I'll get the wands.
Yes, you can... The wands?
Oh, no!
No magic!
But the sixteen years are almost over.
We're taking no chances.
But I've never baked a fancy cake.
Oh, you won't have to, dear.
I'm going to bake the cake.
- You?
- Now, she's always wanted to, dear.
- And this is her last chance.
- Well...
I'm going to make it 15 layers
with pink and blue forget-me-nots.
And I'm making the dress.
But you can't sew, and she's never cooked.
- It's simple.
- All you do is follow the book.
Up here, dear. You can be the dummy.
Well, I still say we ought to use magic.
"Flour, three cups."
Cups, cups, cups.
Oh.
One, two, three.
What's that for?
Well, it's got to have
a hole in the bottom.
That's for the feet to go through.
- It's pink!
- Oh, lovely shade, isn't it?
But I wanted it blue.
Now, dear,
we decided pink was her color.
You decided!
"Two eggs, fold in gently."
Fold? Oh, well.
I can't breathe!
Let me out of here.
- It looks awful.
- That's because it's on you, dear.
Now, yeast, "1 tsp."
Tsp.?
One teaspoon.
Oh, one teaspoon, of course.
Oh, gracious, how that child has grown.
Oh, it seems only yesterday
we brought her here.
Just a tiny baby.
- Why, Merryweather.
- Whatever is the matter, dear?
After today she'll be a princess,
and we won't have any Briar Rose.
- Oh, Flora.
- Now, now, now.
Well, we all knew this day had to come.
But why did it have to come so soon?
After all, we've had her for sixteen years.
Sixteen wonderful years.
Oh, gracious! We're acting
like a lot of ninnies.
Come on. She'll be back
before we get started.
You hear that, Samson?
Beautiful.
What is it?
Come on. Let's find out.
Ah, come on.
For an extra bucket of oats?
And a few carrots?
Hup, boy!
Whoa!
No carrots.
♪ I wonder. ♪
♪ I wonder why each little bird. ♪
♪ Has a someone. ♪
♪ To sing to. ♪
♪ Sweet things to. ♪
♪ A gay little love melody. ♪
♪ I wonder. ♪
♪ If my heart keeps singing. ♪
♪ Will my song go winging. ♪
♪ To someone. ♪
♪ Who'll find me. ♪
♪ And bring back a love song. ♪
♪ To me. ♪
Oh, dear.
Why do they still treat me like a child?
Who?
Aunt Flora and Fauna and Merryweather.
They never want me to meet anyone.
But you know something?
I fooled them. I have met someone.
Who?
Who? Who?
Oh... A prince.
Well, he's tall and handsome and...
And so romantic.
Oh, we walk together and talk together.
And just before we say goodbye,
he takes me in his arms,
and then...
I wake up.
Yes, it's only in my dreams.
But they say if you dream
a thing more than once,
it's sure to come true.
And I've seen him so many times.
You know, Samson,
there was something
strange about that voice.
Too beautiful to be real.
Maybe it was a mysterious
being, a wood sprite, or...
Here, stop!
Why, it's my dream prince.
Your Highness.
You know, I'm really not
supposed to speak to strangers.
But we've met before.
♪ I know you. ♪
♪ I walked with you
once upon a dream. ♪
♪ I know you. ♪
♪ The gleam in your eyes. ♪
♪ Is so familiar a gleam. ♪
♪ Yet I know it's true. ♪
♪ That visions are
seldom all they seem. ♪
♪ But if I know you. ♪
♪ I know what you'll do. ♪
♪ You'll love me at once. ♪
♪ The way you did. ♪
♪ Once upon a dream. ♪
♪ But if I know you. ♪
♪ I know what you'll do. ♪
♪ You'll love me at once. ♪
♪ - The way you... ♪
♪ - The way you did ♪
♪ Once upon a dream. ♪
Oh!
I'm awfully sorry. I didn't
mean to frighten you.
Oh, it... Wasn't that.
It's just that you're...
A stranger?
Mmm-hmm.
But don't you remember? We've met before.
- We... We have?
- Well, of course. You said so yourself.
Once upon a dream.
♪ I know you. ♪
♪ I walked with you once upon a dream. ♪
♪ The gleam in your eyes. ♪
♪ Is so familiar a gleam. ♪
♫ And I know it's true. ♫
♫ That visions are seldom all they seem. ♫
♫ But if I know you. ♫
♫ I know what you'll do. ♫
♫ You'll love me at once. ♫
♫ The way you did once. ♫
♫ Upon a dream. ♫
Who are you? What's your name?
Hmm?
Oh! My name.
Why, it's, it's...
Oh, no, no. I can't. I...
- Goodbye.
- But when will I see you again?
Oh, never, never!
Never?
- Well, maybe someday.
- When? Tomorrow?
Oh, no! This evening!
- Where?
- At the cottage in the glen.
There.
Well, what do you think of it?
Why, it's...
It's a very unusual cake, isn't it?
Yes. Of course, it'll be much
stiffer after it's baked.
Of course, dear.
What do you think of the dress?
Well, it's...
It's not exactly the way
it is in the book, is it?
Oh, I improved it. But perhaps
if I added a few more ruffles...
- What do you think?
- I think so.
What do you think, Merryweather?
I think we've had enough of this nonsense!
I think we ought to think of Rose
and what she'll think of this mess.
I still think what I thunk before.
I'm going to get those wands.
You know, I think she's right.
Here they are, good as new!
Ah-ah-ah ah!
Careful, Merryweather.
Quick, lock the doors.
Fauna, you close the windows.
Oh, block up every cranny.
We can't take any chances.
And now, you take care of the cake.
- While I...
- Clean the room, dear.
And I'll make the dress.
- Now hurry!
- Ooh!
Come on, bucket, mop, broom.
Flora says, clean up the room.
And now to make a lovely dress,
fit to grace a fair princess.
Eggs, flour...
Just do it like it says here in the book.
I'll put on the candles.
Oh, no, not pink.
Make it blue.
Merryweather!
Make it pink.
Make it blue.
Pink!
Blue.
Oh! Now look what you've done!
Shh. Listen.
- It's Rose.
- She's back.
Enough of this foolishness.
Make it pink. Now, hide, quick!
Blue.
Aunt Flora!
Good gracious! Who left the mop running?
Stop, mop.
Aunt Flora, Fauna, Merryweather.
Where is everybody?
Oh!
= Surprise! Surprise!
- Surprise!
Happy birthday!
Oh, you darlings.
This is the happiest day of my life.
Everything's so wonderful.
Just wait till you meet him.
- Him?
- Rose.
You've met some stranger?
Oh, he's not a stranger. We've met before.
- You have?
- Where?
Once upon a dream.
♪ I know you. ♪
♪ I walked with you once upon a dream. ♪
She's in love.
- Oh, no.
- This is terrible.
Why? After all, I am sixteen.
It isn't that, dear.
- You're already betrothed.
- Betrothed?
Since the day you were born.
To Prince Phillip, dear.
But that's impossible. How
could I marry a prince?
- I'd have to be...
- A princess.
And you are, dear.
Princess Aurora.
Tonight, we're taking you back
to your father, King Stefan.
But... But I can't. He's
coming here tonight.
I promised to meet him.
I'm sorry, child,
but you must never see
that young man again.
Oh, no! No!
I can't believe it!
No!
And we thought she'd be so happy.
No sign of her yet, Hubert.
Course not.
It's a good half hour till sunset.
Excellent bird.
Oh, now, come, man!
Buck up! Battle's over!
Girl's as good as here.
I'm sorry, Hubert, but after
sixteen years of worrying,
- never knowing...
- The past!
All in the past.
Tonight, we toast the future,
with something I've been
saving for sixteen years.
Here, to the future.
Right, Hubert. To the future.
Skumps, skumps.
♪ - Skumps ♪
♪ - A toast to this night. ♪
♪ - The outlook is rosy. ♪
♪ - And the future is bright. ♪
♫ Our children will marry
Our kingdoms unite. ♫
♫ Skumps, skumps. ♫
♫ Skumps. ♫
Ah, excellent vintage.
- And now, to the new home, eh?
- New home?
Children need a nest of their own, what?
Place to raise their little brood, eh?
Well, I suppose in time...
Of course! To the home!
♪ - Skumps ♪
♪ - Skumps. ♪
♪ A toast to the home. ♪
♪ One grander by far
than a palace in Rome. ♪
Now, let me fill up your
glass That last was all foam.
♫ Skumps, skumps ♫
♫ Skumps. ♫
The plans!
Well, what do you think?
Nothing elaborate, of course.
Forty bedrooms, dining hall.
Honeymoon cottage, really.
You... You mean, you're
building it already?
Built, man! Finished!
Lovebirds can move in tomorrow.
Tomorrow? But, Hubert, they're
not even married yet.
Take care of that tonight.
- To the wedding!
- Now, hold on, Hubert.
I haven't even seen my daughter yet,
and you're taking her away from me.
Getting my Phillip, aren't you?
Yes, but...
Want to see our grandchildren, don't we?
- Of course, but...
- There's no time to lose.
Getting on in years.
To the wedding!
Now, be reasonable, Hubert.
After all, Aurora knows
nothing about all this.
Well?
Well, it may come as quite a shock.
Shock?
My Phillip, a shock?
What's wrong with my Phillip?
Nothing, Hubert. I only meant...
Why doesn't your daughter like my son?
- Now, now...
- I'm not so sure
my son likes your daughter!
- Now, see here.
- I'm not so sure my grandchildren
want you for a grandfather!
Why, you, you unreasonable,
pompous, blustering, old windbag!
Unreasonable, pompous, en garde, sir!
I warn you, Hubert. This means war.
Forward! For honor! For country! For...
What's this all about anyway?
Nothing, Hubert. Absolutely nothing.
Children bound to fall
in love with each other.
Precisely. And as for grandchildren,
I'll have the royal woodcarvers
start work on the cradle tomorrow.
Splendid! King-size, of course.
Certainly. To the woodcarvers' guild.
His royal highness Prince Phillip!
Phillip?
Phillip! Phillip!
Phil, ho, Phillip!
Hurry, boy, hurry.
Change into something suitable.
Can't meet your future
bride looking like that.
But I have met her, Father.
You have? Where?
Once upon a dream.
Oh, Phillip, stop it. Stop that! Phillip!
Put me down.
Now, what's all this dream nonsense?
It wasn't a dream, Father.
I really did meet her.
Princess Aurora?
Good heavens, we must tell Stefan.
- Why, this is the most...
- I didn't say it was Aurora.
You most certainly did. You said...
I said, I met the girl
I was going to marry.
I don't know who she was.
A peasant girl, I suppose.
A peasant girl?
You're going to marry a... Why, Phillip.
You're joking.
Isn't he?
No! You can't do this to me!
Give up the throne, the
kingdom, for some, some nobody?
By Harry, I won't have it!
You're a prince, and you're
going to marry a princess!
Now, Father, you're living in the past.
This is the 14th century. Nowadays...
Nowadays, I'm still the king
and I command you to come to your senses!
- And marry the girl I love.
- Exactly!
- Goodbye, Father.
Marry the girl you... No, no!
No, no, Phillip! Stop! Come back!
Oh, Phillip!
Phillip!
Oh, ho.
Oh, how will I ever tell Stefan?
Come along now.
All right. In here, dear.
Bolt the door, Merryweather.
Fauna, pull the drapes.
And now, dear, if you'll just sit here.
This one last gift, dear child, for thee.
The symbol of thy royalty.
A crown to wear in grace and beauty
as is thy right and royal duty.
Now, dear...
Come.
Let her have a few moments alone.
It's that boy she met.
Whatever are we going to do?
Oh, I don't see why she has
to marry any old prince.
Now, that's not for us to decide, dear.
Maybe we should tell
King Stefan about the boy.
Well, why don't we?
Listen! Maleficent! Rose!
Rose!
Oh, why did we leave her alone?
- Rose!
Here.
Rose!
Rose, Rose, where are you?
- Rose!
Rose!
Rose, don't touch anything!
Touch the spindle.
Touch it, I say!
You poor, simple fools,
thinking you would defeat me!
Me! The mistress of all evil!
Well, here's your precious princess!
- Rose.
- Oh, Rose.
Oh, I'll never forgive myself.
We're all to blame.
Stefan, there's...
There's something important
I have to tell you.
Not now, Hubert.
But it's about Phillip.
Phillip? Oh, yes, of course, Phillip.
Why, where is the boy?
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
Well, send for
him immediately!
- But...
- Shh!
The sun has set!
Make ready to welcome your princess!
Poor King Stefan and the Queen.
They'll be heartbroken when they find out.
- They're not going to.
- They aren't? But...
We'll put them all to
sleep until Rose awakens.
Come.
♫ Sleeping beauty fair. ♫
♫ Gold of sunshine. ♫
♫ In your hair. ♫
♫ Lips that shame. ♫
♫ The red, red rose. ♫
♫ Dreaming of true love. ♫
♫ In slumber repose. ♫
♫ One day. ♫
♫ He will come. ♫
♫ Riding out of the dawn. ♫
♫ And you'll awaken. ♫
♫ To love's first kiss. ♫
♫ Till then, sleeping beauty. ♫
♫ Sleep on. ♫
♫ One day you'll awaken. ♫
♫ To love's first kiss. ♫
♫ Till then. ♫
♫ Sleeping beauty. ♫
♫ Sleep on. ♫
Well, just been talking to Phillip.
Seems he's fallen in love
with some peasant girl.
Peasant girl?
Yes? Yes?
The peasant girl?
Who is she? Where did he meet her?
Just some peasant girl he met...
Where? Where?
Once upon a dream.
Once upon a...
Rose! Prince Phillip!
Come on. We've got to get
back to the cottage.
Come in.
Well!
This is a pleasant surprise.
I set my trap for a peasant
and, lo, I catch a prince!
Away with him.
But gently, my pets. Gently.
I have plans for our royal guest.
≡ Maleficent!
She's got Prince Phillip.
At the Forbidden Mountain.
But we can't, we can't go there.
We can, and we must!
What a pity Prince Phillip can't be here
to enjoy the celebration.
Come.
We must go to the dungeon and cheer him up.
Oh, come now, Prince Phillip.
Why so melancholy?
A wondrous future lies before you.
You, the destined hero
of a charming fairy tale come true.
Behold, King Stefan's castle.
And in yonder topmost tower
dreaming of her true love,
the Princess Aurora.
But see the gracious whim of fate.
Why, 'tis the selfsame peasant maid
who won the heart of our
noble prince but yesterday.
She is indeed most wondrous fair.
Gold of sunshine in her hair.
Lips that shame the red, red rose.
In ageless sleep she finds repose.
The years roll by.
But 100 years to a steadfast
heart are but a day.
And now, the gates of the dungeon part
and our prince is free to go his way.
Off he rides on his noble steed,
a valiant figure, straight and tall,
to wake his love
with love's first kiss
and prove that true love conquers all!
Why, you, you...
Come, my pet.
Let us leave our noble prince
with these happy thoughts.
A most gratifying day.
For the first time in sixteen years
I shall sleep well.
Shh!
No time to explain.
Wait, Prince Phillip.
The road to true love may be
barred by still many more dangers
which you alone will have to face.
So arm thyself with this
enchanted Shield of Virtue.
And this mighty Sword of Truth.
For these weapons of righteousness
will triumph over evil.
Now, come. We must hurry.
Phillip, watch out!
Silence!
You, tell those fools to... No!
No!
Watch out, Phillip!
Hurry! Hurry, Phillip!
A forest of thorns shall be his tomb.
Borne through the skies on a fog of doom!
Now go with a curse and serve me well.
Around Stefan's castle, cast my spell!
No! It cannot be!
Now shall you deal with me, O Prince.
And all the powers of hell!
Up! Up this way!
Now, Sword of Truth, fly swift and sure.
That evil die and good endure!
Oh, uh...
Forgive me, Hubert. The wine. Now...
You were saying?
Huh?
I was? Oh, yes.
Well, after all, Stefan,
this is the 14th century.
Yes. You said that a moment ago.
Well, to come right to the point.
My son Phillip says he's going to marry...
It's Aurora! She's here!
And Phillip!
What does this mean, boy?
I don't...
But...
I don't understand.
Why, Fauna. What's the matter, dear?
Oh, I just love happy endings.
Yes, I do, too.
Blue?
Pink!
♫ I know you. ♫
♫ I walked with you. ♫
♫ Once upon a dream. ♫
Blue!
♫ I know you. ♫
♫ The gleam in your eyes. ♫
♫ Is so familiar a gleam. ♫
♫ Yet I know it's true. ♫
♫ That visions are seldom all they seem. ♫
♫ But if I know you. ♫
♫ I know what you'll do. ♫
♫ You'll love me at once. ♫
♫ The way you did once. ♫
♫ Upon A dream ♫
Corrections By:
MightyMike77020