Previously on Sleepy Hollow.
What's this about?
- Who are you?
- Katrina Crane.
This is a dream?
You're the man Abbie
told me about.
The Sin Eater.
- A family tree.
- You're a descendant of Grace Dixon.
- It's time.
- I saw Katrina giving birth.
My son.
- What did you say?
- I had a vision.
I'm sorry,
you must be mistaken.
She would've told me.
She needed to keep
it secret.
What happened to my son?
Chopping down a
Christmas tree?
An altogether
nonsensical concept.
Celebrating Yuletide with
a titular display of lumber.
Wow. Bah, humbug
to you, too, Ebenezer.
That was all gibberish.
Scrooge.
He's a Dickensian character.
A grump.
Well, you guys had Christmas,
right?
Santa Claus...
Snowmen...
Eggnog.
In my era, the term
was "egg and grog."
A draught made of rum
that led inevitably
to an aching head,
ergo, "noggin."
Abbreviated to "nog."
I get why you're upset.
Do you, now?
You find out you had a son...
and you never got to know him.
I am sorry, Crane.
If I were you, I'd be taking
an ax to something, too.
My head is swimming
with questions.
What was he like?
What did he know of me?
How did he live?
And why did Katrina not tell me
she was with child?
She put you in that cave
to protect you.
I got to assume she kept it
a secret for the same reason.
Moloch hunted them both down
centuries ago.
While I'm yet
to know the reason,
it suggests that
their fates will come to bear
in our war against him now.
That is why we must find out
what happened to my son.
And we shall start by
endeavoring to contact Katrina.
How do you plan
on doing that, exactly?
When she came to me,
it seemed like
she had to move mountains
to do it.
Those are some
pretty freaky mountains.
You expecting company?
Indeed.
The only man I know capable
of moving freaky mountains.
You called Parrish? Why?
Put yourself in my place.
How far would you go
for answers?
All the way.
Mr. Parrish,
thank you for coming.
Don't touch me, please.
Apologies, Mr. Crane.
It's not a good idea
to touch me.
Of course.
I appreciate
your hasty arrival.
Shall we venture indoors?
Well, I'm sorry
to disappoint you.
I'm a Sin Eater;
I-I-I can read, and at times,
remove sins, that's all.
No, that's not all.
You have the power
to reach across realms.
You summoned a man long dead
and brought him to me.
Summon him!
With all your heart!
Here into this room!
Now open your eyes.
You must have the ability
to reach Katrina.
Purgatory.
It isn't anything
I've ever tried before.
Please.
I beg you.
Yeah, all right.
I'll make an attempt.
That's all I can promise.
I've never used my gift
for a purpose
beyond removing sins.
Now, you listen very carefully.
A mortal soul has no place
in the realm of the dead.
Your life will be in danger.
I will have to put it in danger.
I understand the risk.
Oh, no, you don't.
Our lives are a tapestry.
Each moment
is a thread upon which
the next thread is woven.
When you reach
beyond this existence,
as you're about to,
you are tempting fate.
I cannot say what consequences
will befall you.
The consequences of inaction
weigh far greater with me, sir.
Henry.
Under the circumstances,
"Henry" will be fine.
This will frighten you.
Once I begin,
you must not stop me,
no matter how much you want to.
If you have any doubt,
now would be a good time
to make your exit.
Thanks for the warning.
We're not going anywhere.
Come.
Think of your wife.
Summon her with all your heart.
What I'm about to do
will bring you closer to her...
and closer to death.
I'm ready.
Henry!
I told you:
the closer he is to death,
the shorter distance
he is to travel.
Katrina?
No, no, no, no.
How are you here?
The Sin Eater.
Moloch is always near.
If he learns of
your presence...
Is it true we have a son?
I would have told you
when you first awoke,
but we've had fleeting moments
of precious time.
We made a covenant
when we married.
You owe me the truth.
His name.
Jeremy.
Our son's name was Jeremy.
After your grandfather.
I did not know I was with child
when I buried you in that cave.
Fortunately,
neither did my coven.
They sought to punish me
for saving your life.
It was only when I fled
to Europe in search of a spell
to unbind you from the Horseman
that I learned of my condition.
When my quest failed,
I returned home
to my coven's
relentless pursuit.
If I did not reveal
where I buried you,
they would condemn me
to a fate worse than death.
I knew then
they would not stop until
they had us both, so I fled...
- Fredericks Manor.
- Come on.
- I delivered our son under Lachlan and Grace's care.
- Hurry. Get her inside.
Push!
Mrs. Crane, it's a boy.
He was the most beautiful
creature I had ever seen.
He had your eyes.
But I couldn't keep him.
Not whilst your coven
was bent on revenge.
That would have
endangered his life as well.
I could not condemn our son
to a life as a fugitive.
To protect him,
in order to give him
a brighter future, I...
I had to let him go.
One day we'll see each other
again, little lord.
And I will hold you in my dreams
every night until then.
You are my heart and soul,
Jeremy Crane.
And always will be.
I made you a little friend.
He will watch over you
while I'm away.
He will make sure
that you are safe...
and that you are never,
ever alone.
I left him in the care
of Grace
and her husband Joseph,
a pastor at Trinity Church.
And that was the last time
I laid eyes
on our son.
This is an echo of that place,
purgatory's cruel way of
confronting me with my choice...
until I am freed.
So I come here once a day
and I light a candle
in memoriam,
and I pray for his soul.
Your own coven
banished you here?
I was put here by sisters
with great power,
known as
"The Four Who Speak As One."
I am so sorry, my love,
but I had no choice
but to give him up
in order to save him.
I will find out what happened
to our son.
I will free you from this hell.
We will defeat Moloch
and we will be together again.
I swear.
You must leave.
Release your will
to be here and you will
return to your realm.
Do it now! Go!
Crane?
Crane?!
He'll be all right.
His... his body is experiencing
a physical reaction.
You strangled me.
He means "thank you."
Your ancestor Grace...
she took custody of my child.
It seems your fates were merged
before you met.
And the fate of my son
remains a mystery.
We'll do everything
we can to find out
what happened to him, Crane.
I promise.
We don't even know if any
of your descendants
are still alive.
Well, if Jeremy married
and had three children,
the average at the time,
then we compound that number
over eight generations...
I could have as many as...
6,000 offspring.
6,000 little Ichabods.
I have an idea.
The Historical Society Library.
They have a rare records
collection dating back
to Revolutionary-era
Sleepy Hollow.
That's where we start.
Officer Mills!
My train leaves in 18 minutes.
We're five minutes away.
You'll be all right.
Well, if it's all the same,
I'd rather not presume.
Mr. Parrish...
Henry...
I beg you a further request.
Please, Mr. Crane.
The 8:05 p.m. train, seat 15B.
I do my crosswords,
they settle me.
You saved my life.
You granted me
passage to Katrina.
You have a purpose with us.
My purpose
was to separate you
from the Horseman
so that you could continue
the work for which
you have been called.
Both of you.
And that is where
my contribution ends.
Henry.
You know...
when I found your file
the first time,
I noticed...
your mother, she died
when you were young.
Cancer.
Such a perfect word for it.
Your father
has been in a nursing home
the last ten years.
Alzheimer's, I think it is.
You have no other family?
We're pretty thin
on it ourselves.
If we don't find out more
about the little
that we did have...
Crane's son
and how we're all connected...
we may not be able to do
the work that we have
been called to do.
And then all your
incredible help
will be for nothing.
There's a train
that leaves at 12:44 a.m.
Give me your word I'll be on it.
You have my word.
Frank, what brings
you back to the church?
I remember a sermon
you gave once...
about the two witnesses,
prophets of the Apocalypse.
Mm-hmm.
"Two olive trees
who stand before
the Lord of the Earth."
Symbolism, allegory...
literal?
You could ask those questions
about all the Scriptures.
Some people believe
they're absolute truths,
others see them as parables.
What happens to the witnesses?
According to the New
Testament, "witness"
means "martyr."
They're destined to die
for their testimonies.
What happens to the people
that follow them?
Apostles usually suffer
the same fate as the martyr.
You know I joined the service
because I wanted to help people?
Then my little girl
got hit by a car.
When I joined the force,
I was gone so often
my wife left me.
And now you're telling me
that the grand prize
for a life of public service
might be death.
You have to have faith
in the Lord's plan, Frank.
He always has a plan.
Oh...
If God has a plan, who's it for?
Me or him?
Frank...
what aren't you telling me?
What's happening to you, Frank?
I remember why
I stopped coming here.
From the 18th century?
No.
I don't think
we have any records
on Trinity Church.
Madam, this town has existed
since Adriaen van der Donck
dubbed it
"Sleeper's Haven" in 1655.
Surely there must
be some reference
to its many houses of worship
in the town's
Historical Society.
You speak with such
authority on the past.
Without books,
we have neither
a past nor a future.
I would've thought
a librarian above all
would comprehend that.
If we have anything
on Trinity Church,
it would be in that
section over there.
Feel free to look.
I'll be in the back.
Mistletoe.
That, you recognize.
An enduring tradition,
to the imminent peril
of all the pretty housemaids.
Let's get to work.
I found it.
Grace Martha Dixon.
Born 1751...
died 1784.
She was a young woman.
It says here, according
to eyewitness accounts,
there was a fire.
They were trapped inside.
The local townspeople
were afraid of Jeremy.
People claimed
they had seen him
start fires...
just by crying.
Katrina's powers...
He inherited them.
After the house burned down,
they found the boy
the next morning,
completely unhurt.
People came to believe
he was some kind of monster.
After that, he was
sent to a home
for orphan children of the war.
What happened to my child?
It doesn't say.
My son...
was responsible for
the death of your ancestors.
It's not your fault.
There's nothing
you could've done.
I could've been there.
That is a not a choice
you were given, my friend.
I'm so sorry.
To both of you.
I feared opening
these doors would be painful.
The home to which
my son was sent...
does it have a name?
There's nothing here.
And don't count on Miss Helpful
guiding us in
the right direction.
Oh...
she knows more
than she's telling.
Lying is a sin.
I can sense a sin a mile away.
She's gone.
Outside.
God...
What could've done this?
I won't be catching
that later train, will I?
Macey, your dad is here.
Okay, Mom. In a minute.
So how's life in the small city?
Big city was quieter.
Well, that's you in a nutshell.
Whenever you were here,
you wanted to go.
Whenever you were gone,
you wished that
you were here.
Cynthia...
I know that I made
it hard on you.
Always being gone.
I just want you to know...
I'm sorry.
You deserve better.
You know, if you would've
told me that a year ago...
you would still be living
in this house.
I do now.
Popski!
Little Bean!
Bye, Mama.
Bye-bye, honey.
You have fun, okay?
Okay.
Bye.
The librarian's personal effects
just came in from impound.
These are all of the
archivist's possessions?
Just from her office at work.
Apparently, she has
a personal safe.
You doing crosswords?
As I said,
it distracts me
from my troubles.
A good puzzle
misleads you.
It sends you in one direction,
fools you into thinking
you know what's going on.
But once you've
discovered the trick,
you see that there's often
a hidden meaning.
Just as the librarian
was trying to conceal
something from us.
You don't, perhaps,
know an unusual word for
"fidgety and restless," do you?
Gumplefik.
Gumplefik?
A perfect fit.
I'm still reconciling
today's language
and its advancements.
For example, in my era,
a "toilet" was
a vanity cabinet,
"intercourse" was simply
"social conversation,"
"awful" meant
"awe-inspiring"...
So if I went out with a guy
and we had "awful intercourse,"
we'd be going on a second date?
Disconcerting, yet accurate.
That's just weird.
What's wrong?
The box...
it's filled with pain.
This symbol...
it's the crest
of Katrina's coven,
the Sisterhood of
the Radiant Heart.
Only a member of the Sisterhood
would possess such an item.
Seriously?
The librarian from the
Historical Society was a witch?
Just as Reverend Knapp
was before her,
embedded in Sleepy Hollow
for centuries.
It explains her expression:
recognition.
She knew who you were.
Whatever is in there,
it reeks
of anger
and pain and death.
It's stronger than anything
I've felt in years.
He will make sure
that you are safe.
This drawing...
it's familiar.
I've seen this doll.
When Katrina came to me
in the dream or the vision
or whatever it was,
there was a baby carriage.
The doll was in it.
May I see it, please?
The pain,
the misery inside that box...
I think it's your son's.
The priest who governed
the orphanage...
I can feel the darkness
of his heart.
No food until penance.
The priest believed
there was only one way
of purging
the boy's affliction.
Until one day,
the child's pain
swelled in him so deeply,
he summoned the promise
of his mother's wish.
And with a single drop
of blood,
discovered the true strength
of his power.
Jeremy...
manifested his rage,
his grief,
in the absence of someone
to protect him.
He made real a champion
to keep him safe.
This violence we've seen,
I believe it's the handiwork
of this champion.
You don't know that.
I've seen this creature before
in Katrina's purgatory.
When I returned
to the cabin, I...
I could still feel
its presence.
It followed me back.
I was afraid something like this
would happen.
I warned you not to tempt fate.
Even if you're right,
why would it kill this witch?
She was a member of the coven
that banished Katrina...
that robbed the boy
of his mother.
There are more in the coven,
more who may still be alive.
This death, I fear,
may be the first
of many more to come.
It's called a "vine,"
but it has absolutely nothing
to do with shrubbery?
Yeah, it's a video,
eight seconds long.
On YouTube?
No, YouTube videos are,
like, three minutes long.
No one has time for that.
Yeah, I'm having a dad moment.
Thanks.
You know, when we looked into
that wheelchair sports camp
at the Y last year,
we never followed up.
I can give 'em a call.
Dad, you get this sound
in your voice,
it makes me feel
kind of helpless.
I'm sorry.
I mean, no matter
how scary it gets,
I'm not gonna let this thing
beat me, right?
I'm gonna keep fighting.
Remember you said that?
Yeah, that I did.
And I think it'd be
easier to fight it
if I had some hot chocolate
with lots of marshmallows.
Oh, understandable.
Oh, my God! Popski...
You can have a hot chocolate,
not a puppy.
Give me two hot chocolates
with peppermint.
She seems like a strong kid.
She is.
How strong is she?
Sorry?
I said, how strong
is your daughter?
Is she strong enough
to fight for her soul?
What did you say to me?
God may have a plan, Captain,
but we have one, too.
Who the hell are you?!
How did you know what I said?!
What the hell
are you talking about?
How did you know what I said?
I don't know! I'm sorry!
I don't know who the
hell you are, man.
Hey! What's going on here?
This guy just attacked me.
Step back, sir.
I'm New York State Police.
I'm reaching for my badge.
Sorry.
What's wrong with you?
Let's go.
We have one, too.
The contents of the
librarian's safe have arrived.
Anything of use?
All the lieutenant's found
so far are ticket stubs
from traveling carnivals over
the last hundred years.
Strange.
Mm.
You're troubled.
My father *** say to me,
"When you have a child,
he will follow your example
more than your advice."
Yet my son had
the benefit of neither.
I know that the choice
was not mine...
but it brought his rage
into the world...
then and now.
It is a father's task
to impart wisdom.
Mine taught me
not to fear my power.
I wished I could have
thanked him for this gift
while his mind was still intact.
Whatever became of your son,
you speak for him now.
I believe he was
a good man, Ichabod.
He was, after all,
molded from your clay.
Washington's Bible...
molded from clay.
Katrina buried this with me.
She said
it would provide answers
for the challenges
which lay ahead.
Psalms 139,
"And your eyes did see
my substance being
yet unformed."
A reference in both
the Bible and the Judaic Talmud
to an enchanted being
made animate from
inanimate matter.
Like the first son of God,
born of mud.
A golem.
I remember it
from Sunday school.
It's like a magical attack dog.
Forceful enough to crush
Miss Hudson's vehicle
using merely its fists.
A creature imbued with its
creator's most ardent passions.
Jeremy's doll
became the golem.
Of course, he created
a protector.
Wait a minute.
These four veiled women,
I've seen them before.
When I saw Katrina and the doll,
they were there, too.
"The Four Who Speak As One."
The librarian must have
visited them at different carnivals:
Philadelphia,
New Orleans, Chicago.
These are the women who banished
Katrina to purgatory.
If the golem has been made real
and seeks revenge against those
who hurt the boy...
then surely they'll be next.
And if they put Katrina
in purgatory...
it stands to reason
they could bring her back.
And it'd strike a powerful blow
against Moloch.
We must find them
before the golem does.
The last ticket stub,
dated two days ago,
a carnival in Dobbs Ferry,
right outside town.
That's where they are.
Wait here.
You're not going in there alone.
These women
imprisoned my wife
and left my son abandoned
without hope.
I think I'm entitled
to a private word
before we take them to safety.
It seems we've been relegated
to the part of gongoozler,
you and I.
I'm not even gonna ask.
Gongoozler means
"idle spectator."
Oh, great.
That's just great.
You go. It's cool.
Henry and I will sit back here
and gongoozle our asses off.
Now who's the Scrooge?
Be careful, Crane.
Who's there?
As you so proudly boast
of your clairvoyance,
your query suggests you're lying
or merely playing coy.
Show yourselves.
Curious.
Your aura, it's...
Displaced, fractured...
Unreadable.
Your palm,
bring it here.
Your lifeline was interrupted
long ago...
Then revived.
There is but one mortal...
With such a curious fate.
You are Ichabod Crane.
We've waited centuries
for this moment.
It was foretold...
That your arrival
would seal our fate.
Seal your fate?
I don't understand.
You will.
For tonight... we die.
If what you're
saying is true,
I can take you to safety,
but only if you release Katrina.
If our destiny is to die...
We must accept it,
whatever form it takes.
Nothing you can offer...
Will change that.
Well, then here's some
clairvoyance for you:
Death will come for you tonight
in the form of a creature
known as a golem.
Accept my offer, or your demise
will be most painful indeed.
The golem... has returned?
How?
It followed me back
from purgatory.
You found a way
between realms...
And in so doing,
repeated your wife's mistake...
By altering the ordained path.
I don't believe fate befalls us
however we act.
Only unless we act.
Then you've learned nothing.
Katrina defied fate as well.
Your death would've spared her.
And your child.
Of all the pain they endured
after you were laid to wait.
It was not
your decision to make!
A coven is meant
to be a source of good.
Yet you delivered
my wife into captivity
in the hands of the enemy.
Necessity makes
strange bedfellows.
And it was our sacred duty...
To rectify
what Katrina had undone.
Rumors of Jeremy's
fearsome companion spread.
And so they were hunted.
The creature killed
in defense of his master.
A mindless thing
that murdered anyone
who came close to the boy.
When we learned
who your son was,
what he had created...
We offered our help.
But he refused beyond control.
He chose to be alone.
With his golem.
He was afraid.
The creature was
his only means of defense.
That is why they both
had to be stopped.
What did you do to him?
The golem could not
be destroyed by our spells.
So we imprisoned
the creature in purgatory.
But your son was immune to us.
His power had grown too great.
We offered him a place
in our coven.
But he again refused.
With no other choice,
the Sisterhood
bound together...
And invoked a hex...
To stop his heart.
You murdered my son.
Death begets death.
That is the price we now pay.
Our fate is sealed,
our time run out.
How do I kill the golem?
Your son's blood gave it life.
Only his blood can end it.
Run!
- Crane!
- The Golem!
Where is he?
Where are the sisters?
They've met a just fate.
Did they tell you
how to stop it?
Only that my son's blood
gave it life,
and only his blood can end it.
I'm gonna get
these people out of here.
This way.
What hellish form
of torment is this?
Funhouse mirrors.
When did irony
become a national pastime?
You're hurt.
You said...
blood...
gave the doll life.
Your son's blood is your blood.
Your blood can destroy it.
Crane?
Stop!
I'm Jeremy's father.
You exist because I did not.
If there was any way
I could go back and change this,
believe me,
with all my heart, I would.
But fate bestowed
this task on you.
His only friend.
His guardian.
And in many ways,
a father to him.
For that, I owe you my life.
But now I'm begging you to stop.
Jeremy is gone.
There's nothing left
for you to protect.
You have to let him go.
We both have to let him go.
You've endured enough pain.
Bear it no more.
My son.
Be at peace.
Ichabod.
He's gone.
It's over.
I'm glad you're all right.
And I'm...
sorry to make a hasty exit.
But...
the next train leaves
in 18 minutes.
Mr. Parrish...
Oh, please.
It's Henry, remember?
And if I may, you were right.
- About?
- I've been called to help you
in your mission.
If I hadn't separated your
blood from the Horseman,
you would not have been able
to put the golem to rest.
Or your son.
Thank you for availing me
of your gift.
It seems no matter
how hard we both tried,
one cannot turn from fate.
No.
And yet,
for the first time, I...
I feel that fate
has delivered me a blessing.
By bringing you both
into my life.
It's our privilege, Henry.
We never bury the dead, son.
Not really.
We take them with us.
It's the price of living.
I got you something.
Oh.
♪ Ah-ha, ha. ♪
I was gonna give it to you
on Christmas Eve, but...
you look like you
need a little boost.
Oh.
You've em...
you embroidered my name
on some oversized hosiery.
How... odd.
It is a Christmas tradition.
Is it?
Merry Christmas, Crane.
Merry Christmas, Lieutenant.
I'm starving.
I'm gonna go get
some comfort food.
I'll be back in ten.
Reveal yourself!
Katrina?
Not Katrina!
Come out and face me, Moloch.
Or are you afraid?
I offer this warning.
A saint's name is a sign.
When you know my meaning,
war will take form.
And the End of Days begins.
There will be no End of Days.
You hear me?!
Your death is assured.
You and the second witness.
Face me, coward!
I touched her soul once.
Soon it will be mine forever.
And you will give it to me.
Crane?
What happened?
Moloch.
He's coming for your soul.
He says I will deliver it
to him.