Subtitles by DramaFever
[General And I]
[Episode 41]
According to the ancestral regulation
of Bai Lan State
the attempted murder of
a royal family member
can sentence you to death by torture.
Prime Minister.
I went on the battlefield voluntarily.
Besides, I'm unharmed.
How is Prince Consort
to be blamed for it?
Prince Consort brought this war upon us.
If it weren't for him
how could Your Highness possibly
have had to take such a risk?
The safety of the royal family
is the utmost priority.
It's not a matter to be overlooked.
Your Highness.
Should Your Highness spare
Prince Consort from any punishment
how could you answer to your subjects
and people who protected you?
Your Highness.
Prince Consort's crimes
are not to be condoned.
Prime Minister's fervent pleas
are absolutely right.
I concur.
Prince Consort's crimes
are not to be condoned!
I concur!
- I concur!
It seems that all my dear subjects
are much begrudged.
Everyone's anger can't
seem to be appeased.
I can't be too lenient then.
However, since the state is safe
and I'm unharmed
I ask that Prime Minister propose
a much lighter sentence.
I accept the decree.
Prince Consort, He Xia!
As the husband of the princess
and General of Fast Cavalry
he has, for his personal interests
caused disturbance to the people
and put the princess's life at risk.
He's suspected of the attempted
murder of a royal family member.
Although the princess is unharmed,
his actions are not to be condoned.
Hence, Prince Consort will be given
a lighter sentence as a warning
to appease the anger of the officials
and ease the minds of the people.
Today, Prince Consort is specially
sentenced to 30 strokes of caning.
The punishment is to be
carried right away.
- Guards!
- Present!
- Carry out the caning now!
- Yes!
Your subject...
Accepts the punishment.
Reporting to Your Highness.
Your Highness!
- Your Highness.
- Lu Yi.
How is Prince Consort?
The caning is done.
Prince Consort...
He's quite badly injured.
Your Highness!
Where are you going?
I have to take a look at Prince Consort!
Do reconsider, Your Highness.
All the officials are watching
your each and every move.
Should Your Highness
react too aggressively
and provoke Prime Minister even further
Prince Consort would have
taken 30 strokes of caning for nothing.
You're right.
I wasn't thinking.
Prince Consort is already injured.
I was just worried that
he might not be able
to withstand such
tough physical punishment.
Lu Yi.
Deliver the best medicinal herbs
in the palace to Prince Consort.
Pass on my message to him.
Tell him to recuperate well.
Once the situation isn't as tense,
I'll go and visit him.
Yes!
Young Master...
Young Master.
Bear with it.
Some prime minister he is!
What does he think he is?
How dare he treat
Young Master so brutally?
Young Master.
When have you ever had to
suffer such a grievance?
If you really don't like the princess,
we can just leave.
Let's just leave this awful place.
Dong Zhuo.
I hit you so that you'll remember
never to say anything like that again.
Young Master, I...
This is all my fault.
I forgot what I should do.
Those 30 strokes
are well deserved.
Your Highness, here's your wine.
Mo Ran.
You have been with me for years.
What do you think of me?
Your Highness is definitely a hero to me!
You're loyal and patriotic.
You care about your people.
Moreover, Your Highness
is a great husband.
You're so devoted to Princess Consort.
I'm really bad with words.
I don't know how to put it,
but all in all
you're someone who is worth
risking my life to follow.
When I was young,
my mother and I only had each other.
We were used to the fickleness
of human nature.
- People around us were hostile to us.
- Stop it!
- Everyone in the tribe wanted us dead.
- I was often bullied.
- Stop hitting him!
Whenever I couldn't tolerate it,
I'd go against them head on.
In the end, I always end up being beaten.
Whenever my mother heard that
I was being bullied
she would rush over to shield me
with her own body.
When I heard the whip slash into her body
the only thought on my mind was
that someday, I'd have them killed.
There was only hatred in me then.
It's so pretty!
But then one day, I met her.
She smiled and reached out to me.
Her eyes were brighter than
the stars that shone in the sky.
I had never seen such clear eyes.
They were so clean, sincere, and warm.
Ping Ting begged her father to help me.
For the first time in my life,
I felt kindness from a stranger.
However, her father later sacrificed
his life to save me and my mother.
That was when I first realized
there is another kind of person
in this world.
This kind of person
is compassionate and warm-hearted.
They're worthy of our respect.
They're worthy of our allegiance.
They're worthy of our protection.
I'd let go of my hatred for them.
Without her,
there would be no Chu Bei Jie.
Without her...
I could never be happy.
Your Highness.
We have to bring Princess Consort home!
Definitely.
I'll send more men to search
for Princess Consort now!
Don't bother.
I've given it some thought.
There's only one place she would go.
This is so comfortable!
Although this bed isn't as
luxurious as that in a huge manor
it is so much more comfortable.
We were so used to living in fear
that now we're at ease
I seem to find it strange.
If only we could be
so carefree every day.
Ping Ting, what are you doing?
My wife, how do I look in this outfit?
Very good.
My wife...
Sister Bai.
My wife!
- Don't run!
- Ping Ting!
We'll set out for Great Liang tomorrow.
From then on, we won't be concerned
about any worldly affairs.
It will be fine.
From then on, we'll be so carefree.
Ping Ting.
Ping Ting!
Ping Ting! Where have you been?
Ping Ting, I couldn't find you
early this morning
because you went out to
get all this done?
You really don't
take good care of yourself!
This is so heavy!
You even carried it back on your own.
Yes, it is quite heavy.
It seems that we'll just have
to eat a lot more from now on.
Subject Chu Mo Ran
returns with the army.
Greetings to Your Majesty!
Have you brought Prince
and Princess Consort of Zhenbei back?
Your Majesty, the prince has asked me
to bring you a letter.
[To my king, Your Majesty]
What does this mean?
Where are Prince
and Princess Consort of Zhenbei?
Bring it here!
How atrocious!
I am willing to take
the punishment for Prince of Zhenbei!
We're willing to take the punishment
for Prince of Zhenbei!
When did I say that
I'm going to punish him?
Chu Mo Ran, receive my command!
I receive the command!
I command you to bring your men with you
to search for Prince
and Princess Consort of Zhenbei.
Once you find him,
convey my decree immediately.
Prince of Zhenbei is to be
conferred as Regent Arch Prince
and Princess Consort as
a first rank-lady of honor.
Both of them are to return swiftly
for the sake of Great Jin.
If you can get this done,
I shall reward you handsomely.
I accept the command!
Young Master.
- Is he here?
- Yes, Young Master.
- Good.
- He's in your study.
Greetings to Prince Consort.
How is it?
Prince Consort, from what I learned
our informants in Jin State
sent news back to say that
they didn't notice Bai Ping Ting
on the routes from Bai Lan to Jin.
Moreover, Chu Bei Jie didn't return
to the imperial court with his army.
Neither of them are in Jin State?
No.
How is it with Gui Chang Qing?
Prime Minister had his men
seal off all routes around Yun-An City.
That cunning old man.
He still hasn't given up yet.
Should we send out more men
to search the nearby areas?
If Bai Ping Ting falls into
the hands of Prime Minister Gui
I'm afraid that she'd be dead by now.
Don't bother.
If Ping Ting wishes to leave
none of those morons who serve
Gui Chang Qing could hold her back.
Send out a letter to the border of
Bai Lan State and Liang State immediately
to speed up the search.
We must find Bai Ping Ting.
The border of Bai Lan and Liang?
Prince Consort means...
She won't go to Yan State and Jin State.
This is the only place she'd go.
[Liang State]
Perhaps Chu Bei Jie is also
on his way there now.
We must find them before
they leave Bai Lan State.
Yes!
Ping Ting, it's so dark out here.
We'd better light a torch.
Someone's here.
Don't drink too much.
Someone's over there.
This is the only route that leads to
the border of Bai Lan and Liang.
What is better than planting
an ambush here at the pass?
Then we'd better leave now.
Leave?
Where else could we go?
This is the only route.
What should we do?
- Come with me.
- Yes.
Don't drink too much.
Chief.
In my opinion, it's only a day's journey
from the capital to this pass.
Drink. Fill it up.
We've already been waiting
out here for three days.
We haven't even see a mosquito,
not to mention any women.
They have been tracking us.
I reckon that those two women
didn't take this route.
If so, wouldn't we have
waited here for nothing?
Enough nonsense!
Prime Minister already said that
he has had the surroundings
of Yun-An City ambushed.
As long as those two bitches
dare to leave the city
they will be throwing themselves
right into the trap.
This route that we're guarding
is the only way to the border of Liang.
As long as those bitches come our way,
we must seize them immediately.
Otherwise, we'll have to keep
waiting out here in the cold forever.
Here, here!
Quiet down.
Listen to me.
I've heard that Chu Bei Jie is
infatuated with that little bitch.
Even our Prince Consort
regards her as something precious.
- Drink!
- Here!
What if those bitches see us here
when they walk by?
Put out the fire!
They have to take this route.
Exactly!
What is that sound?
There's some movement.
Let's take a look!
Brothers, grab your weapons!
There's nothing!
- Rabbit!
- There's a rabbit!
- A rabbit!
- Catch it!
- It's a rabbit.
- Quickly!
- Go!
- Catch it!
- It's over there!
- Over there!
It's the middle of the night.
Who said it's a rabbit?
- Get back here now.
- Sit down.
How could you let it get away?
Brothers, sit down.
- Here.
- Drink.
That rabbit ran so fast.
Let's keep drinking.
- Here, drink!
- Keep drinking.
Let's play a drinking game!
Here.
We must get back at them.
Ping Ting, we can't even get past
a common fighter.
These men...
How are we to get back at them?
They are so rude.
How can we let them off?
Ping Ting, you have an idea?
Their campsite is where the campfire is.
The lookout post and the pass
must be near the campfire.
In order to prevent us from
getting through this mountain
they must have laid many traps
in this forest.
They will split into two teams to watch
this route during the day and night.
If we take this route,
we're sure to alert them.
This...
What should we do if we alerted them?
We'll just have to alert them
on purpose instead.
What?
Here, apply this to your hands.
Isn't this the cream I made
at the inn according to your formula?
What use is it?
The bamboo in this area will do.
Done!
We might have set up quite a few,
but they have to be triggered.
We can't aim at any targets
or hurt many of them.
This is our main weapon.
Ping Ting, you're going to poison them?
But where are we to use this?
Ping Ting, how do we trigger
these gadgets?
Hunting dogs.
Hunting dogs?
Drink!
Here, here. Let's continue with the game!
Five ringleaders! Six, six, six!
Eight horses!
You lose again!
Again! Again!
Five ringleaders, four lucky charms.
- Three...
- You lose, Chief!
Get back here!
Damn animal! Stupid dog!
Fill it up.
Here, fill it up.
A shoe?
This is bad!
Chief!
There's a problem, Chief!
Chief, look!
A shoe.
A woman's shoe!
- This really is...
- Lao Qi.
Well done!
Who knew that we'd catch them soon?
Where's that little bitch?
This... Lao Qi, did you set up
this thread lock?
This... I didn't set this up.
It's not me.
They aren't caught?
No.
Chief.
Perhaps those two bitches
tampered with it.
- Go after them!
- In there! Be careful!
- Be careful.
Slowly.
Yellow!
Get back here, Yellow!
Sister Bai, you're remarkable!
They fell for our interlocked traps.
They will suffer soon.
Let's go!
Put me down!
Chief! Look! They are over there!
Those two bitches!
- Go after them!
- Go!
- Quickly! Go after them!
- Put me down first!
What on earth is this?
- I'm so itchy!
We finally made it out. We're safe now.
This has been one thrilling night.
My heart is almost
leaping out of my chest.
But it now seems that such
a fright is all worthwhile.
At least, we now know that
we can't get into Liang State
from the passes of Bai Lan State anymore.
What should we do then?
Between Bai Lan and Liang
lies the Pine Mountain Range.
The route through the mountains
is very dangerous.
Although they can't station troops there
the mountain range serves as
a natural shield for Bai Lan State.
We have to get through those mountains
to enter Liang State
without being hunted by Bai Lan State.
Don't worry, you have me.
It will be all right.
Let's go.
Useless bums!
A group of men with sharp weapons
are outwitted by two
defenseless frail women?
Convey my orders!
Search for any traces
of Bai Ping Ting immediately!
Be it official routes or paths
through the mountains
all must be monitored!
Yes!
I don't believe that
you could just vanish into thin air.
Ping Ting, we've been walking
for hours now.
You are after all pregnant.
We should stop and take a rest.
Don't wear yourself out.
Here.
Ping Ting, have a snack.
I'm not hungry. You can have it.
This won't do.
You are with child.
I...
I don't like this snack.
How about this? We'll share it.
One, two, three, four, five...
Along the way, apart from spending
on food and accommodation
we spent the rest of the money
on materials to tackle those bandits.
We didn't even get ourselves any clothes.
We're almost there.
Once we get through Pine Mountain Range,
everything will get better.
You keep mentioning Pine Mountain Range,
but where is it?
We haven't even see it yet.
Wherever you are, I will find you.
Ping Ting.
Where are you?
Look.
Ahead of us is Pine Mountain Range.
Once we get through it,
we'll be in Liang State.
Thank goodness.
We've finally reached
Pine Mountain Range.
Exactly.
I hope that we can
pull through this safely.
Great.
Great!
Chu Bei Jie deployed
the army without permission
and then left his post
after attaining victory.
This seemed to have sparked quite some
discontent among my dear subjects.
Every one of you are here to impeach him.
You're going to impeach
Prince of Zhenbei?
You as well?
Right! You as well?
All of you are here to impeach him.
I'd like to ask you instead.
The throne up here...
Which one of you would like to sit on it?
- I wouldn't dare!
We definitely wouldn't dare do so!
You wouldn't dare?
I think that all of you
make a better king than I do!
We're willing to assist Your Majesty
in governing your nation.
We would go to any length to assist you!
Get lost!
Look at these reports you wrote!
Do I still need you to tell me
what is right from wrong?
Impeachment? Sentencing?
The impact of the silkworm poisoning
still affects the people greatly!
A great number of my people
are still struggling!
Why didn't any of you mention it?
Chu Bei Jie doesn't care about the world.
Every one of you here
has sinned just as much!
Ask yourselves.
Do you care about the people?
Any officials involved in the silkworm
conspiracy are to be locked up!
Your Majesty!
- You mustn't.
- We're innocent, Your Majesty!
- Grand Marshal Xie!
- We're innocent!
Do you want to end up
in the dungeon as well?
- Your Majesty!
I'm innocent!
- I'm innocent, Your Majesty!
- Your Majesty!
- I'm innocent!
A bunch of useless scum!
Get lost if you have nothing to report!
We will take our leave now.
Long live the king!
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty.
Be careful.
Who is it?
How dare you barge into
the gate of Nan-An County!
Do you think that my men are useless?
You're the garrison commander?
Exactly! I'm the guardian of the gates
here in Nan-An County!
If you want to barge in here,
you'd better ask my blade for permission!
Brothers, attack!
Kill him!
Attack!
Who are you?
Hero... Hero, do spare us!
Hero, do spare us...
Be nice.
Hero, do spare us! Let's talk nicely.
- Master!
- Let's talk nicely.
Close the door.
- Master.
- Don't come in!
Hero, do spare us! Let's talk nicely.
Be nice.
Hero, do spare my life.
We can talk nicely.
Have you seen this person?
No...
Tell the truth!
Yes... I have.
I have... No!
Hero, look.
Prince Consort sent this.
Every pass along Bai Lan State's border
received this command.
If we were to see this woman
we are to kill her
if we can't catch her alive.
Hero, spare my life!
Move it!
Step aside!
Yes.
- Master!
Master, are you all right?
Master.
He... What did he say to you?
He said that if we should dare
to harm Bai Ping Ting
we will end up like this flagpole.
This is...
Prince Consort.
This man shows up mysteriously.
He's extremely violent.
He's picked quite a few of our passes.
Yet no one could defeat him.
Apart from Chu Bei Jie,
who else is capable of that?
The garrison commander of
Xiaoyang Pass is Luo Hao?
Yes.
Judging from the passes that
Chu Bei Jie has picked
he chose only the ones farther away.
He's moving farther away
from Xiaoyang Pass.
Bai Ping Ting won't go through
the heavily guarded Xiaoyang Pass.
Unless...
Open the door!
- Open the gates!
- Quickly!
- Coming!
- Sir?
- Why are you so slow?
It's so late at night.
What is this about?
We're going to war soon.
Every household has to
submit their taxes.
If you don't wish to suffer,
you'd better pay up now!
The local authorities of Bai Lan
are collecting taxes for war.
What a bunch of assholes.
- Sir, you can't take it!
- Get lost!
They might not be
from the local authorities.
- Spare us!
- Come with me.
- Sir!
- Do you want to die?
I dare you to run!
- Don't run!
- A-Han!
Don't let them get away!
I dare you to run! How dare you rob me?
Go on! I dare you to rob me!
- I dare you to rob me!
- Sir!
Stop hitting him.
Tell me the truth.
Who exactly are you?
We're tax officials of Bai Lan State.
You should be executed for
harming an imperial official!
Release me now and I might spare you!
Why would a tax official
wear the boots of a soldier?
Exactly!
Will you tell the truth or not?
If you don't, I'll take you
to the local authorities!
- Tell the truth!
- Say it!
Tell the truth! Say it!
- Will you say it?
- Yes, yes!
Please spare us, Miss!
We're not tax officials.
We're just garrison guards around here.
- Guards?
- Impostors!
- Inconsiderate scum!
- Pose as an official?
Spare us, Miss!
I have a family to raise and feed.
We really don't wish to die for nothing,
so we... escaped from the army!
Why would soldiers of Bai Lan State
die for no reason?
Miss, you might not know,
but a few days ago, a skilled warrior
broke a few of our passes in a row.
Wherever he went,
no one could fend him off!
We have all fled from death!
The tip of his sword was
only an inch away from me.
I nearly became blind!
Tell me.
What does this man look like?
That man is as tall as a metal tower.
Everywhere he goes,
sand swirls and winds howl.
He's almost inhuman!
You're just bluffing!
I'm telling the truth!
Where did he go?
I passed out from fright,
so I didn't know where he went.
Then we heard that Prince Consort went
to deploy forces from Xiaoyang Pass.
We only became soldiers to make a living.
Who would want to die?
Besides, we weren't the only ones
who ran away.
Xiaoyang Pass?
Where has this mysterious warrior been?
I heard that he's been to
Nan-An County, Longxi County
Guandi Way, and Angu Pass.
I really don't know about the rest.
He's running off!
- Catch him!
- Stop!
- Zui Ju!
- Catch him! Don't run!
- Stop right there!
- Zui Ju!
Ping Ting!
- Miss!
- What's wrong?
- Ping Ting! Are you all right?
- Are you all right?
Subtitles by DramaFever