This...
What color do you think they are?
Purple?
No, it's plum-colored.
It means eternal love.
I love you, Soo Hyun.
I'm different from your mom.
I will never
leave your side.
Final Episode
Soo Hyun, will you go to
your office for a moment?
Soo Hyun is gruff but he is a handsome man. Soo Hyun
is a romantic man who shows me a movie when I am sad.
Soo Hyun can't write well, but he has a nice
voice. Soo Hyun is the man who made me love again.
Soo Hyun, you are the man I love.
I came to do a project.
It's called the Choi Soo
Hyun rehabilitation project.
You'll help me, won't you?
Will you do it for me, please?
Please eat a bit.
Soo Hyun, you are responsible
for repaying my kindness.
I love you, Soo Hyun.
I'll never leave your side.
You're going to stop the experiment?
Yes.
I think it will be difficult
to do at this moment.
I'm sorry.
Last time, you said something
similar, why again?
What's the problem?
I'll solve all of them for you.
It's not a problem for you to solve.
In my hypothesis,
I realized that there might be an error.
There is no such thing as
true love for a woman,
are you talking about that?
Yes.
That means it will really turn
this experiment upside down.
Then, what are we going to do now?
I already set aside the budget
to invest in your experiment,
we also decided on the direction
marketing would take.
I'll do my utmost to help you with marketing from
the point of view of a psychologist, however
for now, I will postpone this experiment.
This is really just a
small possibility, but
Soo Hyun may say he is going
to cancel the experiment.
What?
Do you know how much we
spent on this experiment?
I'm sorry, Chairman.
But if that happens, Soo Hyun has
committed a breach of contract anyway.
Let's say that the company will
compensate for the damages.
What do you think about
scolding Soo Hyun separately?
For example, like giving him a penalty.
A penalty?
Exactly what kind of plan did you come up with?
What kind of favor did you ask of the Chairman?
What do you mean?
All I was told was to give you psychological
counseling because you had a problem.
That's my seat. Since you're the client,
please sit on the opposite side.
How do you feel these days?
Just so-so.
Ah right!
An interesting thing happened to me.
I'm a psychological counselor, but
the fortune teller downstairs
said she would counsel me.
Isn't it amusing?
- Do you sleep well?- Yes.
Lie. You're not sleeping or eating well.
I do drink at least a glass of milk.
Also, a client can lie at anytime.
Catching that
and figuring out what kind of defense
mechanism and inner scars are present
to help the client is the counselor's job.
Well, that's for me to take care of.
Soo Hyun, these days, you
don't even tear up, right?
There's nothing for me to be sad about.
Your mom returned.
Isn't crying my eyeballs out at the age of thirty
six because my mom came even more abnormal?
When you were six years old,
on top of that, it's your mom
who abandoned and left you.
Because of that, you lost your
memories before the age of six
and still feel pain when
hit by water droplets.
Crying and getting angry
at appropriate times,
displaying one's emotions naturally like
that are what normal people usually do.
Isn't crying when you see
your mom a natural reaction?
The degree to which something causes one to
shed tears differs from person to person.
Also, there are defense mechanisms.
Not all defense mechanisms are bad.
I transferred the memory of
losing my mom into psychology.
That's a desirable defense mechanism.
Since I'm starting to use some professional
terms, you find it hard to understand me, right?
Ask me comfortably.
If you find something that you
don't understand, I will help you.
Maybe it's because I packed in a rush, there
are too many things that I didn't bring.
Cell phone charger, underwear, socks.
My hands are really bored because
I didn't bring my Rubik's cube.
Noona, can't we just buy all
that at the supermarket?
We have to save money,
how can we buy all that?
Also, because I bought a new camera this month,
I'm reaching my credit card's spending limit.
Out of all things, the charger. What to do?
Even though you don't pick
up Noona Hye Rim's calls,
if you get calls from work, it
wouldn't be good to miss them.
I asked for a vacation so it's alright, but
it won't do.
I'll go and bring it without her knowing.
How?
Hello.
What? She just came in the house?
Alright, I'll go right
to her and this wench...
You can't!
If you just catch her and ask her where Ji
Ho is, do you think Yoo Rim will tell you?
She'll just play dead
for a day and run away.
That's true. Then what should I do?
There is only one answer.
Storming in on the scene.
Here. Here too.
Noona, your neckline is very pretty.
You! You also said you fell for my
Unni after seeing her neckline.
No, compared to yours,
hers is just a tree trunk.
A rough and bumpy tree trunk.
Really?
This is the first time I'm hearing
that I'm prettier than my sister.
Thank you, my baby!
Aigoo, are you lovey-dovey
and playing house?
Unni, how did you come here?
Do you like it? Running away and living happily in
ignorant bliss, do you like it that much? Do you? Aiyoo!
Ji Ho,
when I was twenty one, exactly
at your age, I got married.
But,
look.
This is what your future looks like.
Do I look good? Do I look good to you?
I thought you looked good.
It was just because
Brother-in-law was a bastard.
My husband having an
affair is also my fault.
We just got married because we liked each other.
We didn't know anything about each other.
That's why starting from how we squeeze
toothpaste to the way we clean the house,
- we started fighting the day after the wedding—-
Both of us squeeze toothpaste from the bottom.
- Isn't that right, Ji Ho?- Yes.
But the cleaning...
You can't do it everyday,
once every three days. Deal?
Yes.
Look. Right now, what kind of
life will you have at this rate?
If you do things your way like
that, what if Ji Ho explodes?
I'm not a volcano. I won't explode.
I've got a firm grasp
on him, so don't worry.
Also, as you know, he's blank, white drawing
paper. I can just draw on him as I please.
Fine, let's say you two got married
after I yielded a hundred times.
How are you going to get a house?
We can rent it.
The smallest 18 pyeong (1 pyeong = 3.3 m2) room costs
700,000 to 1,000,000 Won a month. ($700-$1,000)
You, can you handle that kind of rent?
Above all that, how are the two of you
going to sleep in that tiny room?
We're going to hold onto each other tight and
sleep together, why? Try finding another fault!
Fine.
Then, let's end our relations.
What?!
Why does talk about relations
suddenly come out?
I tried so hard so you wouldn't
face a fate like mine,
but since you're coming
out like this, well.
From now on, let's live
without seeing each other.
Today, you and I are finished.
In the future, bye-bye. Okay?
I'm pregnant.
To be honest, I didn't
want to tell you this but,
I am with child.
So, I have to marry him
as soon as possible.
Noona, do you really...
You'll congratulate me, right?
Are you in your right mind, right now?
Are you?
Are you beating a pregnant woman?
What did you do? This young bastard! Ji Ho!
Noona, I'm sorry. Sorry.
He didn't do anything wrong.
Hit me instead.
Fine, you two try having a nice life!
Unni!
Noona, is it true?
Do you really have my child...
Are you crazy? It's a lie. Unni!
Unni! Unni, I'm sorry! I did wrong!
Don't run, you wench! What if
something happens to the baby?!
Unni, we will live well
so don't be against us...
For now, come to the house.
We'll talk inside.
Doctor, here are the documents.
Yes, thank you.
Doctor, my friend had a stomach ulcer.
But since he hates hospitals,
he ate and exercised well,
and I think after one year,
he went to the hospital for a check up and
it turns out he was completely cured.
So are you saying that I will
have gotten better, too?
Do you think that a stomach
ulcer and cancer are the same?
In any case, an illness is an illness.
So Doctor, even if you don't undergo
surgery, at least get examined.
You also lived happily
with a positive mind,
it's possible that the cancer may have
gotten a bit better, don't you think?
Fine, I will directly show you
what kind of condition I am in.
It's not good. It has metastasized
from the lymph nodes to the liver.
Pardon?
Now, not only does she
need radiation therapy,
she also needs chemotherapy. Surgery
is also definitely necessary.
What is the percentage
of complete recovery?
About 30%.
Doctor, still he said the percentage of
full recovery is higher than other cancers.
Undergo surgery and receive
treatment, please?
For thyroid cancer, ten years must pass before
one can know the chances of full recovery.
If it's ten years from now,
at that age, I won't be able
to finish my bucket list.
While I still have the strength,
while doing my bucket list,
I'm going to enjoy my life.
Without being able to do that and spending ten
years in a hospital receiving chemotherapy
as my life dies and rots away,
I absolutely don't want that.
Never tell the people in the
center about my present condition.
If rumors start to fly about that, I will
go back to Jeju Island because of it.
Seung Chan, the thing is...
What? Is something wrong?
It's nothing. But, why?
Can I go to your home for a moment today?
Why?
I want to act like Choi Soo Hyun.
You're sure that Soo Hyun will
be coming home late, right?
Yes, he said he'd be having dinner
together with professors from his school.
But why? What are you looking for?
Photos of Soo Hyun like the
ones you gave me last time.
Anything related to Soo Hyun's
emotional scar will do.
Are there any toys or albums
from when he was a child?
I don't know, I think he threw
them away when he moved.
No, I think my mom took the album
when she left for Switzerland.
Why? If you need it, should I tell her
to bring it with her when she comes?
Your mom is coming?
Yes, together with my father. She said they're
coming briefly for a relative's wedding.
Then, is there anything
else besides the album?
I'm not sure, if it's something that'll
help you to know Hyung's mind...
Perhaps, is it here?
Why? Are you getting any clues?
Yes, even though it's leading me in a
different direction, I discovered it.
Shamanism's Ethical
Principles and Symbolism
Between Cold-heartedness and Passion
Credit Card Receipt
Past love
- What is this?- It's a box.
It was in your closet, it's
your stuff from college right?
By any chance, did you search my room?
Answer my question. Why did you suddenly look into
things you had while you where attending Stanford?
Did you suddenly think of Claire?
That...
Also what is this? You bought a necklace from Luxury
Little Shop, and that's while I was in Daejon.
Why did you buy a necklace from a designer
shop? Who were you going to give it to?
Hye Rim.
Also these books related to past love,
Internet searches related to past love,
Why are you thinking of past love suddenly?
It's Claire, right? She is back so you are thinking of those times
while looking at these things and searching the Internet, right?
Can I talk now?
Let's hear it, although it's obvious
you'll be giving a ton of excuses.
You're right about me opening this box because
there was something I wanted to look at.
I wanted to make you the
omelettes that you like.
A recipe that my roommate, who
was a good cook, was in here.
If you can't believe me, would you like me to make
it for you according to that recipe right now?
Then, what's with the
picture taken with Claire?
Claire's picture was there?
Why didn't you throw it away?
It's useless to me.
Also this, you're right about me buying it
for a female. I already gave it to her.
Who is it? Claire?
I gave it to Hye Rim.
Are you joking?
The Pomeranian in my home, Hye Rim.
Did you not see her when you went
to my room? She was wearing it.
Also this, I read it because of a client.
Among my clients, I have one who got dumped
by her boyfriend and is having hard time.
So during her counseling sessions, she kept on quoting this
book, so I glanced at it to try to get a better understanding.
By the way, I guess you didn't see
the book about Shamanism next to it?
I was reading that book because of you.
The explanation is over, your
misunderstanding is resolved, right?
Seung Chan, please book me a plane ticket.
Ah, yes.
Aren't you going to ask me where I'm going?
Where are you going?
Alaska. I'm going to leave in three
weeks to accomplish my bucket list.
Yes.
Is there nothing else
you want to ask about?
No, there isn't.
This is the reservation confirmation.
But, the price is this expensive?
Yes, since it's double the price.
I also booked a ticket
so we can go together.
I can go with you, right?
Really?
If you come with me, it will
really mean a great deal to me.
But I searched a bit about Alaska.
I know I can do it, but I think
it'll be difficult for you.
Why?
First of all, the plane trip
will take fifteen hours.
Will it be possible? You
have cancer, Doctor.
On top of that, to see the Aurora Borealis,
you have to go to a place called Fairbanks.
During the winter, the sun barely rises.
It's all night.
Also, the temperature drops
to -54 degrees Celsius.
What do you want to say?
On top of that, the weather is unstable.
Storms, lightening, and hail.
They say it's no joke.
Oh right. You said you also wanted
to see Machu Picchu, right?
The altitude there is 2,400 meters. But you're
having difficulty with the mountain in front of us.
But you can solve all
these things in one blow.
I'm not undergoing surgery.
Doctor, the recovery percentage is 30%.
It's not only 30%, but 30% is left.
Why are you ignoring that?
I'll decide what to do with my life. I
don't want to leave it to percentages.
In three weeks, I'm definitely going
to Alaska to see the Aurora Borealis.
Whether you want to tag
along or not is up to you.
Enjoy.
Come upstairs.
Drink. It's a tea good for your
hormones when you're pregnant.
Noona, can I have a glass of water...
Go home and stuff it
down your throat there.
Also, why did you give her something
heavy to carry on your way in?
Do you know how dangerous it is to do
that at the beginning of pregnancy?
How many months along are you?
No, I don't think it reached that far.
How many weeks along are you?
What should I do? When should
I tell her I'm not pregnant?
I bought milk, anchovies, and cheese.
Now the baby's bones are being formed,
so you need to eat a lot of calcium.
You need to drink water frequently, eat lots of vegetables
and fruits. Stay away from severe exercise. Okay?
It's time, let's go.
Where?
I reserved an appointment
with the obstetrician.
What?
We need to know if the baby is doing
well and if there are any dangers.
Let's go.
I'm still in the early stages of
pregnancy, so I should be okay.
It's because it's the early stages
that it's even more dangerous!
We need to take an ultrasound and see if the baby's
heart is beating properly, and how big it is!
What are you doing just sitting there as the
baby's father? Hurry up and help her to stand.
Come here. Let's go.
Unni!
Come out quickly.
I don't want to!
Unni! I said I'm okay.
- My stomach hurts.
- What to do? Is the baby alright?
I slightly jabbed it.
Call 911!
No, you can't!
This is 911 right? There is a pregnant woman who
hurt her stomach while falling down the stairs.
I don't have it! I said I don't have it!
What don't you have?
There is no baby.
What?
I lied, I'm sorry Unni.
What's wrong with me? I keep laughing.
What should we do? Unni
seems to have lost it.
Why is your face like that?
Aren't you happy to see your
father after such a long time?
Two course A's and...
What are you going to have?
The B Course.
Is work going well?
I heard you make him do menial tasks.
You are his older brother yet you can't
take proper care of your younger brother.
Don't you have any connections
to give him a great job?
No Father, it's because
I'm still not ready yet.
If I spent all that money and sent you to study
abroad, you should at least be holding a good spot.
Instead you're giving
consultations to people.
And getting paid a meager amount of money.
Is that what you should be doing?
Can't you even answer?
You are so frustrating.
You take after your mother.
What's with that smile?
You are saying whatever you
want about me as always.
Hyung.
You know that I can't eat oysters, right?
Yet, you order oysters as you please?
Is not being able to eat oysters at
your age something to boast about?
At your age, you shouldn't be picky about
food and be able to eat everything.
That's what I'm saying. I'm old enough but
why are you still treating me like a child?
How dare you argue back?
Counseling you say? What does it matter
to you what I do? Studying abroad?
Did you ever support me financially?
If I hadn't given permission, do you
think you would have studied abroad?
I studied abroad on my own with the
money I earned. You had no part in it.
"You?"
Hyung, what's wrong with you? Saying that to our
father whom we haven't seen in a long time.
He has to be someone I can learn something from to be a father. Just
because he has money, all he knows how to do is to put on airs.
A person full of prejudice and
stubborness who does as he pleases.
Now you even want to be
treated as a father?
You punk!
Do you know why I studied abroad?
I wanted to escape from your
tyranny as soon as possible.
When I was smiling, I really wasn't smiling.
Why? Because you forced me to smile.
Eat a lot of delicious food and leave.
You have to live a long, long life
to fulfill that greed of yours.
Hyung, how dare you be rude?
Did you really want to say that
to our old and feeble father?
This is between me and father.
Someone like you who was raised with
love has no right to say that to me.
You're the one that pushed him out!
Father? Fine, I don't know about him but
at least me and mom tried our best.
We did our best to get along
with you and live well together.
But who's the one who pushed away
a mom like that and me? It's you!
The reason our family became like this
is because of you. You did wrong.
Soo Hyun, Mom did everything wrong.
What can I do to be forgiven by you?
I'm so sorry, Soo Hyun!
You're right and never come back again.
Hello.
Excuse me,
May I know which room Seo
Yeon Hee is staying at?
Excuse me, but what is your
relationship with her?
Forget it, I've found her.
Hello? Oh, Son.
Mom will be back in few days.
Are you eating well?
You can't just eat instant food.
There's the beef bone soup I made.
Eat that.
Are your preparations for
the exam going well? Oh my!
That's good! Then you just have to
receive notice from one more school?
That's good, my son. You got into two
schools that you wanted to attend.
Now all you need to do is
choose which one to attend.
What should we do about Soo Hyun?
Whether I treat him well or
console him, he gets angry.
If I try to approach him even just a
little, he slips away like a mudfish.
I don't know what more I can do for him.
It will be hard.
Professor Choi isn't an ordinary person,
because he's a psychological counselor.
Right now, what Professor Choi needs is...
a replay of emotions.
A replay of emotions?
Yes.
Professor Choi is currently looking at his
problem calmly like an audience member offstage.
"I know all the characters and the
plot." As if he were doing an analysis.
But, by doing that, he will never come
to a realization of his feelings.
Then how?
You have to put Professor Choi
on stage, as the main character.
Where are we going?
Today's counseling session
takes place outdoors.
Don't you know that counseling sessions are only
once a week? And outdoor counseling sessions...
A fortune teller's consultation
is a little different.
Whenever I feel like it, wherever I get the feel from, no matter
how many hours it takes, I'll do it. Until I wear myself out.
It seems you did quite a lot of research about me. You
even found the elementary school I used to attend.
When you were in school,
what kind of kid were you?
I was the same as other kids. I
ran around, ate, and played well.
How was it at this time?
Soo Hyun, it would be
nice if you came for me
I don't want to be here alone.
Now. One, two…
Choi Soo Hyun, why is your
expression like that for a picture?
Were you scolded by someone?! Smile.
I told you to smile more!
Alright. One, two…
A boy is so sullen when taking a picture.
You're such a loser.
Soo Hyun, why aren't you coming?
Please go ahead, I will stay
here and play for a bit.
Why play outside in this cold winter?
Just come, you punk!
I... I really will just
play a little more here.
Soo Hyun.
Do whatever you want! The kid takes after his
mother and is always doing what he wants.
Go and comfort him.
The only person who can comfort
that child now is you.
Mom.
Doctor, when you go to Alaska,
would you like this bag or
this one?
This one.
Okay, I'll order it for you.
But I don't know if she'll be
able to go with that stamina.
Doctor, in Alaska, if you do the Aurora tour, I think we'll
be able to see it easier. Should I sign us up for it?
Yes, go ahead.
But we're going quite far. Will
it be possible for her to move?
Doctor.
While we're in Alaska, it will be great to
see Igloos. Should we tour them as well?
You will say it's not
possible again, won't you?
Yes.
Why are you continuing to do this?
I want to see it with you for
a long time, that's why.
You're my mentor. Once you're my mentor,
aren't you my mentor till the end?
For twenty years, thirty years, I want
your support, what's with just six months?
Get the surgery, Doctor.
Overcome the chemotherapy and build your stamina.
Go with me to see the Aurora Borealis, Peru,
dye your hair purple, and while drinking beer
from all over the world, enjoy your life.
Spend a long, long time with me. Okay?
Fashionably Late
10. Lie down in an Alaskan igloo
and watch the Aurora Borealis.
Bucket list ♪11.
11. Get surgery.
- Are you ready?- Yes, Noona.
What are you doing? Quickly get up.
First, in about one month, we are going
to have our engagement party in the Cafe.
Afterwards, we both decided that we would each put 40%
of our wages into an installment savings account.
As for marriage, we will do it
in three years at the latest.
Three years later? Even so,
you'll be twenty four.
To me, age is not important.
For Noona Yoo Rim, while she's still pretty, I want
to have her wear a wedding dress as soon as possible.
The wedding will be the
smallest size possible.
As for the house, we'll start with a 18
pyeong (1 pyeong=3.3m2) one room on a lease.
We'll repay the debt within a year. We'll
also put money into an apartment application.
Do you think money for an apartment application
comes out of nowhere? What about living expenses?
What will you be doing then? Will you
keep working in the center as an intern?
Within three years, I will make sure to get my
LCPC. (Licensed Clinical Professional Counselor)
If I don't, Noona said she won't marry me.
As soon as we marry, Ji Ho and I will
be having four separate bank accounts.
Income, expenditure, emergency
funds, investments. Like this.
And in case we can't earn
money, we decided to
For starters, our ten year plan is like this.
The final objective is getting our house.
Also, until Noona Yoo Rim becomes a documentary
director, I'll be in her films every week.
When are you going to meet the parents?
That is the first step in marriage, do
you think it's just between you two?
Unni! Are you finally
giving your permission?
Thank you so much, Unni! We'll live well.
Get away, you wench.
How is the Doctor?
She is much better than we think.
Hyung, I'm sorry for last time.
I forgot that my father was very harsh
on you. I'm sorry for crossing the line.
Alright.
♪ Happy birthday to you,
happy birthday to you!
♪ Happy birthday, dear Soo Hyun!
♪ Happy birthday to you!
Well, say something.
Thank you for everything.
He's nervous, he's nervous,
my Hyung is nervous.
Well, thank you.
Then, don't you have to
give me presents now?
That's right, presents.
But before that, there is
something you need to do.
What is it?
If so, then me too!
Thank you, everyone.
Then, I will also...
Hey!
- Aish, seriously.- Ahh!
Come here, come here.
Don't throw it at me!
Oh my…!
Hey, come here.
-Yoo Rim, you should wash up too. -Okay.
Yes?
Hello, this is Seo Yeon Hee.
Ah, yes.
I'm leaving now.
Isn't today Soo Hyun's birthday?
Please let Soo Hyun know.
That I love him.
At that time, I think it
became imprinted onto my mind.
I've done wrong.
Because I made the ice cream drip,
my mom never came on my birthday.
Mother, you can't leave right now.
Excuse me?
Quickly... come...
Hello? Hello?
The person you are trying to reach is in
the middle of a call, after the beep—
Welcome.
I wanted to check out.
I understand.
The person you're trying to reach is in the middle
of a call, please leave a message after the beep.
It's alright. There's no
need to come out for me.
Yes, it's an 11pm flight.
I'm leaving now.
Customer! Customer!
You have a guest named Seo Yeon Hee, right?
By any chance, did she check out?
She checked out ten minutes ago.
I was unsettled by what you said
earlier, that's why I came back.
I couldn't hear it well, but it sounded
like you were talking about Soo Hyun.
Who is it?
I'm sorry, Soo Hyun.
Because I couldn't remember.
How did you know to come here?
Happy birthday, Soo Hyun.
I came way too late, right?
My birthday... did you even remember?
Yes.
What mother in this world would
forget her child's birthday?
Then, what about you saying that
you'd come back on my birthday?
Did you still remember telling me that?
That... I...
Why can't you remember that?
Do you know how hard it's
been for me because of that?
I thought you left because of me...
how much I...
I'm sorry... Mom was wrong.
Mom was...
If you've separated from father,
you should have fought to come and take me.
How could you just leave
me with such a father?
Was it so only you could live well?
I had no power.
Back then, I was kicked out,
so I didn't have anything.
Still, I tried to do whatever I could, but
your father's attorney was so powerful.
Everything was blamed on me. I
even got treatment for depression...
Still, you should have come for me!
Step-mother, younger brother and father
were living happily, except me...
Then, you got yourself a new family...
And I was the only one who was left alone.
Soo Hyun.
The fact that no one is on my
side and I'm alone in this world,
do you know how that feels?
It's... It's not like that now.
Starting from now,
I'll be by your side.
I'm sorry, Soo Hyun.
For making you wait for thirty
years, I'm really sorry.
It's your first round of chemotherapy.
You will be receiving this for a week.
Doctor, I brought over movies I've
collected. Would you like to watch them?
No, thank you.
There are dramas too. Korean,
American and British.
It's all right.
Then, how about a performance?
Choi Seung Chan's live.
Well, I guess it's not live. In
any case, it's a performance.
What kind?
♪ I was born to love you. ♪
♪ With every single beat of my heart. ♪
♪ Yes, I was born to take care of you ♪
♪ Every single day. ♪
♪ Alright! ♪
♪ I was born to love you. ♪
♪ With every single beat of my heart. ♪
♪ Yes, I was born to take care of you. ♪
♪ Every single day of my life. ♪
♪ You are the one for me ♪
Oh, Ji Ho. What is Soo Hyun doing?
Claire came so they're working together.
Clarie came again?
Yes. They said they're going to stay up all
night because they have a lot of work.
That rascal never eats with me.
She always eats with that guy.
Still, I heard you become very close.
But, why are you meeting that type of guy?
Excuse me?
I heard everything through Secretary Lee.
You're dating Choi Soo Hyun?
Ah, yes.
No wonder.
I should've known when you asked me to give him
the penalty of receiving counseling from you.
But, do you two see eye to eye?
Choi Soo Hyun is rather rude.
Is he affectionate towards you?
These days, he's become too
affectionate that it's a problem.
I fixed him through counseling sessions and he seems to
have gained confidence about being able to love now.
He's nice to every woman.
Today, this woman named Claire...
Cl... What?
Chairman, when you were dating
your wife, you had a rival, right?
How did you know that?
I saw all of your love letters...
It's a spiritual message.
But how did you get rid of your rival?
Did you hang onto him?
Love will follow the one who loves.
Don't be dispassionate.
Love will find a way.
Eat your meal.
Thank you for helping me out with my work.
It's been a lot of help.
It's nothing. I only did a
few written consultations.
Are you going back now? What about a car?
Did you take a taxi?
Yeah. I was thinking of going
straight to the airport.
There aren't any taxis you
can catch here though.
Let's go. I'll take you to the airport.
Hye Rim, I was just going to take Claire.
Claire is going back to the States, so...
Did anyone ask?
Unni, what's wrong? Did something happen?
Yoo Rim, why am I always like this?
What are you talking about?
Now I feel like I'm going
to lose Soo Hyun, too.
I'm so uneasy.
[Stage three]: A very demanding task that can
be perceived as out of the norm by society.
[Stage three task]:
You'll need this when you drive.
Welcome.
Please give me the same design as this.
Yes.
Movie Box
He's doing this crap again!
Do you think I'm going to get fooled again?
Are you crazy? I'll never go!
Oh, there's a person sitting here.
I don't think so.
Row G, seat 26. It's correct.
Audience members, during the show, ringing cell
phones and light from your cell phone's screens
can really disturb another audience member.
We who have survived broken hearts and despair,
in order to see hope through this movie,
please make sure to turn off
your cameras and cell phones.
Don't kick the seat in front of you and
please place napkins in the trashcan.
In case of a fire, please use the
emergency exit on this side.
The restroom is around
the corner on the left.
And...
to the woman in row G, seat 25.
To me, more than anyone in this world, the
woman in row G, seat 25 is precious to me.
The one who took me out of my emotional
scar was the one in row G, seat 25.
The one who also made me examine myself
was also the one in row G, seat 25.
"So that's why I have to change."
"I have to become cooler", the one who also
made me think of this is in row G, seat 25.
Awww...
I love you, Hye Rim.
What are you doing? Are you crazy?
Yes, I'm crazy.
- How was my task for stage three
of the experiment? -What?
Just now, I did the third task for stage three
of the psychological love experiment for you.
It's a task where I must endure the
inappropriate stares of people around me
to the degree that I might
appear to be crazy.
It's evidence that I've totally
fallen in love with you.
Till the very end, that damn experiment.
It's always that experiment.
I love you, Hye Rim.
♪ Even though I think about you all day ♪
♪ I just can't figure it
out, love love love ♪
♪ My sweet love♪
♪ Please don't push it away♪
♪ Don't miss it by hesitating♪
♪ How did you come here? ♪
♪ Even though you don't speak, my
eyes see it all, it's alright ♪
♪ Open your heart only to me ♪
♪ Don't act as if it isn't♪
♪ Come a little closer♪
♪ I keep laughing for no reason ♪
♪ Strangely, I keep thinking about you ♪
I'm sorry, Director.
T-That... Ah, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
Huh? You... You shouldn't do that!
♪ Even though I think about you all day ♪
♪ I just can't figure it
out, love love love ♪
Cut!♪ My sweet love♪
♪ Please don't push it away♪
Ajumma! What?
Cut! Cut!
Wait a minute.
There!
Thank you, everyone.
Then, I will also...
♪ Everything about me is lovable ♪
♪ Do you know the more you try to run away♪
Thank you everyone for loving Madame
Antoine.♪ You will fall harder for me ♪
♪ Even though I think about you all day ♪