People say I'm sending Sebastian
and Nina to New York..
so neither will take my job.
Hey, perhaps that's partly true.
Like these butterflies that
surround us this evening..
it's a time of transformation,
new beginnings.
In preparing to
open a new office..
I wanted to place my very
best people in charge of it.
And you truly are my best.
Oh.
To Sebastian and Nina. A toast.
Nina and Sebastian. Thank you.
Make us proud in New York.
And make us a lot of
money in New York.
After dinner, we went to some restaurant.
And then someone came up and said..
Hello?
Is this Nina Wei? Yes.
I'm calling from Pu Tuo
Qu Hongkang Hospital.
What's going on?
Sophia Liao is in a
coma in our hospital.
What?
What? I'm sorry.
Ms. Liao was on her bike
and was hit by a taxi.
God.
Yours was the last number
dialed on her phone.
She called me?
God.
Okay, I'm coming.
Oh, sorry.
Where is she?
Oh, my God.
I'm sorry.
How did we end up here?
You went away.
There is so much
distance between us.
What happened to the
promises we made?
What's going on here?
Nina!
Please don't bring this
music into my house.
And these buns you always bring.
Look how oily they are.
Sophia.
When your mother died, I promised
her I'd raise you properly.
When you act out, I can't fulfill
your mother's final wish.
I know I'm only your stepmother.
Are you going to be
against me forever?
Huh?
Nina, I'd like to have a word with you.
Follow me.
That liar. She never
met my mother.
This is good music.
Come.
I'll find someone else to
tutor her in Mandarin.
Do not come here again.
A smart girl like you..
with a bright future..
shouldn't have to spend
all your time with her.
Come and meet my
family for dinner.
This is so exciting.
I never get to visit
a real family.
Here's the soup.
It smells wonderful, Mrs. Wei.
Thank you, Sophia.
It's all homemade.
So your family is Korean, right?
Mom.
I already told you
they come from Korea.
I didn't come to
Shanghai till I was 14.
That's why my Chinese is so bad.
- Very good.
- Thank you.
Shanghai is a seaport.
Everyone from somewhere else.
People come and they
go, come and they go.
Enough of this silly English.
Nina. Nina.
Mrs. Liao's not at home.
Hey, it's you.
So my niece told me Cixi Tai Hou busted
you for the Faye Wong tape, huh?
All I know
Teresa, huh?
Oh, what's this?
These are so tiny.
These are not easy to come by.
This shoe was for women
with tiny bound feet.
See? Called..
3-inch golden lilies.
It's a shoe?
Do you know our family
came from Hunan?
Oh, no.
She's talking about my mother's
mother's mother's mother.
I think I got that right, huh?
Mm-hm.
And her name was Snow Flower..
and she had a
laotong named Lily.
Laotong?
Sworn sisters for life, laotong.
Like us.
Sister. Sister.
Sister. Sister. Ha, ha.
Girls, you have a lot to learn
about laotong commitment.
See, marriages used to be
made for men's reasons.
To form business alliances, to
manage households, to produce sons.
And they were obligatory.
A laotong's commitment was for
women's reasons, by choice.
For companionship,
understanding and happiness.
What you're signing today is a symbol of
your deep-hearted love for each other.
Deep-hearted love. I like that.
Here is your laotong contract.
Your vow is written in nu sh..
Sign below it.
Oh, yes. The infamous
Wong Faye CD.
Sophia's bag is at reception.
You can pick it up.
Okay, thank you.
This is the story of
Snow Flower and Lily.
Two girls born in the same
month, on the same day.
Their feet bound
on the same day.
At that moment, their
destinies tied forever.
Mama, when can I go out to play?
Lily, this is more important.
We must make your feet perfect so the
matchmaker can find you a good husband.
Madam, it is done.
Get up, walk.
Get up!
Walk.
Mama, it hurts.
Ten circles of the room.
Snow Flower! What are you doing?
Come back! Walk!
Only through pain
will you find beauty.
Only through suffering
will you find peace.
I wrap, I bind.
But you will have the reward.
Come.
Back, again.
Again.
Mama!
These are the most perfect
feet I have ever seen.
These are true golden lilies.
I will be able to find
her a good family.
But given your circumstances..
we must make another
match first.
I have found you a laotong.
Your sister in heart for life.
Her name is Snow Flower,
and she is from Tongkou.
Tongkou?
A rich girl is too
good for my daughter.
This is true. Her
family is privileged.
Her grandfather was
an imperial scholar.
But these girls have
compatible astrology signs..
so her mother does not mind
this class difference.
Can I meet her now?
Snow Flower?
Nu shu is a secret
language between women.
It is personal, between
you and your laotong.
That is why you
learn it together.
So you will know what
is in her heart.
Bright.
Moon.
Correct? Yes.
The Temple of Gupo
fair is a holy place.
We are here today in front of Gupo
to write your laotong contract.
And make your vows of
eternal commitment.
My hand opens to yours.
We of good affection..
shall never sever our bond.
We will be laotong
for all eternity.
Why can't you grow up?
Your mother's right.
You don't get these
opportunities every day.
You have to go to New York.
You shouldn't feel guilty.
Her accident had nothing
to do with you.
Enough.
Stop trying to convince me.
I've decided to stay.
I don't even know what her life
was like these past few months.
Now, with this accident, I need
to find out what happened to her.
Uh, hi, Sebastian. It's Nina.
I'm not sure when I can
meet you in New York.
I..
I just can't leave.
I need to be here for Sophia.
Sorry.
I'll be at the house.
Call me when you land.
Bye.
I am to marry a boy
I do not know.
He is from a
distinguished family.
My life will change because
of my perfect feet.
Sister, you must
come to my wedding.
Has Madame Wang found you
a match, Snow Flower?
What about bed business?
Mama has never said
anything to me.
It cannot be as hard as
embroidery or cleaning.
Why are you laughing?
Stop laughing at me.
I am not a good daughter
for leaving you.
We are women.
We are born to leave
our families.
Mama.
Go.
Lily.
Never forget we are
vowed forever.
No one will come between us.
Snow Flower.
Sun, water and
firewood are free.
But salt is a commodity.
The Taiping rebels are
creating chaos everywhere.
I am concerned about our son
trading in such a faraway place.
What do women know
about such things?
Within this household, I
make all the decisions!
Obey, obey, obey.
He will do what he wants.
My father has granted me permission
to travel to Guilin to buy salt.
I will return and sell it here.
Guilin. That is far.
Is it safe?
It is not a woman's
place to worry.
I may be gone for a long time.
Excuse me, is Claire here?
She's inside. Thanks.
Claire, you're here.
Sophia's aunt is not here.
I know. Is there another
way to reach her?
I'm in touch. She'll
be back tonight.
Are these from Sophia's family?
Yes, Sophia gave us these.
They all belong to her family.
But the most important
one is missing.
Perhaps Sophia has it.
This is a new interactive
nu shu program.
You taught me how to be a good wife.
I must fulfill all my duties.
The wife of the eldest son must
serve and honor her mother-in-law.
My daughter's birth was a disappointment.
I must bear a son.
Madam, I would like to
visit Snow Flower..
and go to the Temple
of Gupo fair.
We promised to meet
there every year.
I told you, Lily.
I do not approve of your
relationship with Snow Flower.
She is my laotong.
We are vowed forever.
Why do you forbid me to go?
You must go pray for a son.
Yong Gang will go with you.
Yong Gang.
Take this to Snow Flower.
We must rely on the wind
to carry our words.
Those winds are happy and sad.
We are forbidden to see each other.
But at every moment, I miss you.
Wait for me.
Snow Flower.
How does your husband treat you?
And yours?
Good.
However, I do not know why
Lady Lu disapproves of you.
But I am still here.
I am happy. Me too.
Lady Lu, I know what
I did was wrong.
Lady Lu!
Disobedience is a
woman's greatest sin.
Auntie.
You're here.
I flew all night and
all day to get back.
You know..
Sophia and I haven't
talked since that night.
I know.
When she first came back from Australia,
she came to see me at the gallery.
How was she?
She seemed..
very depressed.
And she was more depressed the
next few times I saw her.
She didn't even want me
to know where she lived.
Why?
Did she come back with Arthur?
No. She told me she left him.
I told her he was no good.
Nobody knows where she lives?
No.
I should have told you earlier.
But I could not bear
to tell you the truth.
My father was addicted
to the opium pipe.
He ruined our family.
Our fates have been reversed.
But our love will
always be strong.
I am happy we are blessed with sons.
We are fulfilling our fates.
But now the typhoid epidemic is upon us.
Death is all around.
Everyone is afraid and anxious.
I hope you are safe
where you are.
Dead, dead.
Madam, it is time
for your medicine.
Everyone is dead.
Madam!
Have some, madam. You
will feel better.
- Children.
- Mother.
Do not come over here. Go back.
Mother, do not leave us.
I am not avoiding you.
I may be infected.
Mother.
I am always with
you in my heart.
Good children.
- Mother! Mother!
The master is back!
The master is back.
Master and Lady Lu passed away.
They both succumbed to the plague.
On this day of the New Year..
we became Master and Lady Lu.
Mrs. Liao.
It's Nina. I used to
teach Sophia Chinese.
Do you remember me?
I remember.
I'd like to speak with
you about Sophia.
She's had a terrible accident.
Accident? What accident?
I haven't spoken
to her in years.
Sophia never saw
me as her mother.
Don't touch me.
You see how I'm forced to live?
My husband died, my
stepdaughter abuses me.
I'm a squatter in my own house.
This roof could
fall in any minute.
Understand now?
I hear you're doing well.
Good career.
You have a bright future.
I've lost everything.
Everything.
Madam. Don't call me "madam."
Madam.
- Mrs. Liao.
- I'm not Mrs. Liao anymore!
When I had money,
I was Mrs. Liao.
Now I'm just a ghost!
Today the stock market
hit a new low due to
the liquidation of
Peregrine investments.
Why did you invest everything
in the stock market?
You're losing all of our money.
Do they ever stop?
Since May '97, major indices
have been in a free fall.
We haven't paid our
bills in three months!
I'm losing patience with you!
Stop now!
I can't take this. I'm leaving!
Dad.
The market goes up and down.
Up, down, up, down.
Yes, it does.
It'll come back, you'll see.
Mrs. Liao, I'm sorry
for your loss.
Thank you for coming.
I didn't expect him to
pass away so suddenly.
And to do this in his own home?
His daughter won't speak to me.
She isn't even studying for
the college entrance exam.
If she fails, I'm sending
her back to Korea.
Nina, I feel sick. I have
to go to the bathroom.
What? There's no time. Quickly.
Hold this. Let's go.
There's no time.
I'll be right back.
Sophia.
Sophia Liao.
It's still too loud here.
You can't hear? Okay.
Over there. Let's go inside.
Here.
What did you wanna say? I still
don't understand why you did it.
I didn't know what I was doing.
I just did it.
You thought I couldn't
pass my exam?
I feel bad.
It's gonna be all right.
What about you?
Don't worry about me. Let's go.
Who's there?
I'm coming.
Does Nina Wei live here?
Yes.
Shanghai Education Board
Disciplinary Notice
Nina!
Have you nothing to say?
How could you take the
exam for someone else?
Look at me!
Do you know how hard
your father and I work..
to give you the best education?
And this is how you
show your gratitude?
Three years. You can't retake
the exam for three years.
Do you realize what you've done?
You've not only
ruined your future..
but ours too.
You have destroyed our family!
Dear Sophia:
By the time you read this
letter, you'll be in Korea.
I did what I did because I
wanted you to be happy.
Because I wanted
us to be together.
And look what happened.
We're both being punished.
I don't expect my parents
to understand what I did.
But I'm going to make
them proud of me again.
I miss you. I love you.
Nina.
May I have your order?
Yes. I would like a Caesar salad
and T-bone steak, please.
Hi. Hi.
Miss Wei? Hi. Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you. Sebastian Wu.
Hey. It's 9:00.
You should get home.
Yeah. I'm almost done.
Okay. Good night. Bye.
We have lived through years
of separation and turmoil.
I can still feel your
heart in your words.
I am happy we will
be together soon.
Lily.
Snow Flower.
Come inside. Meet my children.
You live here?
If not for your perfect
feet and good marriage..
I would not even be here.
The matchmaker did her best.
She did.
What does your husband do?
Butcher.
I would like to spend more
time with my laotong tonight.
No, I want you to
come to bed with me.
The Taiping rebels are coming!
What is happening? The
rebellion is here.
What rebellion?
There is no time to explain.
Your mother will not come out.
I will get her.
Are you leaving too?
Snow Flower, I
cannot leave here.
We have no time.
We all have to leave.
I should stay here. My
husband will find me.
It is time to go.
I will not go.
I cannot.
Put me down. I cannot go.
The cart broke! Get off!
Get the children.
You can rest soon.
It is over here.
Lay her down here.
I will go fetch the cow.
Do not worry. I
will return soon.
I am coming with you.
You take care of your mama.
Are you all right? I am fine.
How are your feet?
They are fine.
My son!
My son! My son!
Nina, it's me.
I don't have Sophia's address yet, but I
have found out Arthur is in Shanghai..
and has just opened a trendy
nightclub called Club Upside-Down.
I'll text you the details later.
Let this groove get you to move
It's all right, all
right, all right
Let this groove
light up your fuse
So stand up, all
right, all right
Gonna tell you what you can do
Excuse me.
You know, this room actually works
better when you're drinking.
Why are you here, Nina?
Is she all right?
She's here.
Do you mind if I see her alone?
There, see? See the guy?
I've never seen this before.
Something on your chest.
Aah!
So? They loved the whole idea.
They're gonna open an
office in New York.
We did it. We did it.
I'd like you to come with me.
Wow.
Thank you.
There you go. Two
Brain Hemorrhages.
Finally, your dream
is coming true.
Ha, ha. I wouldn't call it a dream.
It's just like an opportunity.
Whatever you call it.
Cheers.
So when do you leave?
I..
I haven't decided if I'm going.
What? What do you mean?
Actually, I..
I worry about you.
Don't worry about me.
I'll be okay.
I'm writing a book.
It's about laotong, the old days,
but I think it's really about us.
When I finish it, I
want you to read it.
That's nice.
But writing a book won't pay the
rent unless you get it published.
I have a new boyfriend.
He has a lot of connections
and he can help.
I know these guys of yours.
Don't go there.
Come on. This one is different.
I want you to meet him.
Ladies and gentlemen, I'd
like to dedicate a song..
to the most irritating, maddening,
stubborn woman I have ever met.
This song.. Heh-heh-heh.
Yeah, she's actually here.
She knows who she is.
I'll keep you guessing for
a little while, though.
This song is about the place I usually
find myself when we're together..
which is begging for a kiss.
Hit it.
Give me just one kiss
Just yes or no
All right, here we go.
A kiss on my cheeks
Leaving a mark of love
Give me just one kiss
Just yes or no
Excuse me there.
A kiss in my heart
Makes me miss you so
Here we go, everybody, ready?
See how she teases me?
Aww.
Yes, ladies and gentlemen.
We're up.
What a surprise.
He's a surprising guy.
What does he do, exactly?
Well, he's an Australian
businessman..
and he owns a bunch
of clubs in Shanghai.
Great. He sounds wonderful.
And he's opening his new club in Sydney,
and he wants me to go there with him.
We are leaving soon.
What?
You're leaving with him?
To Sydney? Yes.
How long have you known him?
And you've decided
to go with him?
I've known you for so long.
I've been so worried about you.
So stupid of me.
Did I ask you to worry about me?
How can you talk to
me like that, Sophia?
I just wanna tell you,
he's not right for you.
How do you know?
So it's all my fault.
Okay, fine. I won't
bother you anymore.
I'm going to New York. Good.
He will not tell me where
our son is buried.
My husband takes his sadness
and stuffs it into his fists.
So much has happened in
the years we were apart.
Fate has taught me that I
am just another woman.
I hope when I am reunited
with my husband..
I will be a better wife.
There is no purer
ambition for a woman.
I am happy you think so.
If I can change my fate..
so can you.
You think these
bruises are my fault?
I do not want you to suffer.
My relationship is different but
has something very important.
What is so important?
Lily.
Has your revered husband never
shown you that he loves you?
I seek only to help you
through this difficult time.
Our fates are so different.
I have felt your pity since
you first came into my home.
I feel pain in my heart
for you, Snow Flower.
He is my husband, Lily.
I love him.
Lily.
There are things about
men you will never know.
These are matters you
do not understand.
You are my laotong.
Everything I have is yours.
The rebels have been stopped.
Come to Tongkou.
Let me take care of
you and the children.
Come with me.
I do not understand.
If I give this
message to Lady Lu..
she will misunderstand
your meaning.
Your bond may be broken forever.
This is my intention.
My sister is at a different
station in her life.
I have become a burden to her.
She is far too stubborn
and loyal to accept this.
What you are about to do
will break her heart.
And mine, but it
will set her free.
Loving her as I do,
it is the only way.
Lady, I am Lotus. I
know who you are.
What do you want?
My sister asked me to
return this to you.
My dear laotong:
My fate has brought me many sorrows.
I cannot be what you wish.
Three sworn sisters in Jintian
have promised to love me as I am.
You need not worry
about me anymore.
Burn them.
But..
Yes.
Snow Flower is here.
Sorry my sisters and I are late.
I wish you happiness in
your marriage, Cousin Yan.
Thank you for traveling all this way
to celebrate our daughter's wedding.
I finally had to hire a private
detective to find Sophia's address.
Are you serious?
Turns out she rented
a little apartment.
She was holed up there
finishing her novel.
It's near her father's
old bathhouse.
Bathhouse?
Yeah. It's her favorite place.
Where her father would go to escape
from his wife and the stock market.
And Sophia would wait for him.
They'd have tea or a meal.
It meant the world to her.
This is the address.
She never had visitors.
And didn't go out often.
If you find my rent
money, tell me.
My dear Nina:
I'm writing a letter
I will never send.
But I must tell you the truth,
even if it's only in my heart.
How could you know how I
felt all these years..
about what you did for me?
How could I bear
another sacrifice?
Giving up your
future in New York..
and yet..
I knew your love was too strong.
There would be no asking
you to change your mind.
I had to make you hate me.
And so I lied.
I lied about wanting
to move out..
needing to be free.
The reason I moved to Sydney was
because I was pregnant with Arthur's baby.
But then I guess it
was not meant to be.
I know what you think of me.
That..
That I didn't deserve her.
You're right, I didn't.
I mean, when we were
first together..
Sophia would disappear for, I don't
know, a few hours every night.
She'd never tell me
where she'd been.
I assumed she was seeing someone
else, so one night, I followed her.
Where was she going?
To a bathhouse in Luwan.
I mean, the weird thing was..
the bathhouse was
restricted to men only.
She had to disguise
herself to get in there.
Yeah.
She wore a suit, right?
Yeah, why?
It was her father's bathhouse.
Her father's?
Nina.
There's something.. There's
something you should know.
She lost..
She lost your baby.
Excuse me.
My father left something here.
His locker number is 173.
I'm here to get it for him.
We're not open yet.
They're still cleaning.
Old Ding, leave us alone.
This lady has some
business here.
Please be quick.
Thank you.
The end of this story..
is about things of the heart
that will never change.
Madam. What is wrong, child?
My mother is very sick.
She calls for you in her sleep.
But she has other sisters.
She has no other sisters.
She misled you.
She has never had
another laotong.
For 10 years, she was
only their teacher.
She has only one
sister of the heart.
You have to see her
one last time.
I beg you.
I waited for you.
Madam, I brought you
some things from home.
I am sorry.
I knew you could not want
me to destroy the fan.
When Lily returned home after
Snow Flower's funeral..
she looked at the fan and could not
allow things to end as they had.
So she opened a new panel..
dipped her brush, and wrote
a final inscription.
The world is always changing.
Every day it's changing.
Everything in life is changing.
We have to look inside ourselves
to find what stays the same..
such as loyalty..
our shared history..
and love for each other.
In them, the truth of
the past lives on.
Now I understand Lily's last
inscription for Snow Flower..
and what it means
for Sophia and me.
My entire life, I
have longed for love.
I always thought I
understood it..
but now I see, with
shame and sorrow..
that I understand nothing
of deep-hearted love.
The love between sisters.
So many years without you.
This is my penance.
If you will come back to me..
I will never leave you.
Never again.
And we will be sisters
for 10,000 years.
SubText:
NoRMITA.326