This is your captain speaking. We will
shortly be approaching Timmins Airport.
Local time is 6:30.
It's a beautiful spring morning
and the temperature is seven degrees
with occasional light snow flurries.
I hope you've had a pleasant flight and will
enjoy your stay here in Northern Ontario.
(woman) Can I get you some more coffee?
(woman) Do you want more coffee?
Yes, thank you,
Do you mind if I sit here?
No,
(woman) Can I take your order?
Yes, please,
I'll have a Coke, please,
Diet?
Yeah, I've tried, it's just the no-eating part
that I struggle with,
I'm kidding,
I'll have a Diet Coke, yes,
Thanks,
What you reading?
Wipe The Slate, Light The Candle,
- Is that a novel?
- Well,,,
It's fiction,
Hmm,
I've been thinking of writing one of those,
You can make tons of money,
All the gullible people out there,
searching for answers,
I have the best title:
The Bleeding Child Within,
What do you think?
It's very good,
I don't know what particular area of human
pain or misery I'm gonna focus it on yet,
I just like the title,
Thanks,
I don't wanna waste it,
(slurps)
You're English, right?
Look, you seem like a really chatty
kind of person and I don't want to be rude,
but I'm not,,, chatty
so perhaps you'd be better off
sitting somewhere else,
Have you seen
some of these people?
Well, there's a few
empty tables around,
Do you wanna know
why I sat here?
Because you look like a man
who needs to talk,
You look like a guy
who hasn't talked in a really long time,
- That's why you sat here?
- That is why I sat here,
And because I need a lift,
and you were the cleanest option,
I'm sorry,
Good luck,
(alarm chirps)
Change of heart?
No, I just tried to change gear,
It's automatic,
OK, Well, good luck,
I'm driving to Winnipeg,
You'd better get out when I've had enough,
Yes, Absolutely,
No problem,
Bit of a drive, Winnipeg,
- I'm Vivienne, by the way,
- Alex,
I have to tell you,
I just got out of prison,
Oh,
Fraud?
I killed someone,
OK,
About this person you killed,,,
I don't want to talk about it, I mentioned it
because I wanted you to be aware
that ordinary-looking people
are often the ones you need to avoid,
OK, Gotcha,
Look out for the ordinary ones,
So, are you feeling uneasy now?
No,
Sure?
Well, maybe a little,
Uneasy,
I tend not to visit scared,
My mom's scared of everything and I've
made a conscious decision not to go there,
If I hadn't been starving, I wouldn't have
stopped at that diner, That's frightening,
You can't be afraid of tattoos and bad teeth,
It's part of their appeal,
- I don't really think they'd hurt anyone,
- I was talking about the food,
Oh,
Have you got kids?
- No,
- Really? At your age, no kids?
Low sperm count?
More of a low partner count,
Ah,
I know the feeling,
Guys my age just don't like me,
Mind you, you're quite an attractive-looking
guy, What's your excuse?
I don't want to talk about it,
There's a surprise,
(man on radio) A lot of weather today
- variable conditions right across the area
and I'm not sure if any of
the weather’s gonna be welcome.
The one consolation is,
down in the southwest...
(Vivienne) So, we're here,
sharing a meal,
You know, if I was a few years older,
this would be a date,
- A few? You're very generous,
- Mm-hmm,
I know how the world works, I give a little
something, you give a little something,
All right, all right, Both my parents are dead
and I have one brother,
That wasn't so hard,
He hates me,
Whoa, there!
Nothing, and then the floodgates open,
Go, Alex, Go, Alex,
We're completely different,
He's handsome and very fit,
He works at the stock exchange,
He's what you might call "a hotshot,"
(English accent) Hotshot,
Well, you know what they say,
Behind every successful man
is a truly astonished woman,
- Is that what they say?
- Yep, that's what they say,
He's gay,
That's my point exactly,
(both chuckle)
Oh! I did good,
And look at these,
Flashing balls that play music,
- Just what she's always wanted,
- You don't know my mother, Mr. Sarcastic,
She's gonna be beside herself
when she sees these,
I can't wait to see her face,
Oh, I love this song,
([music] "All Right Now" by Free)
[Music]... or hesitate
[music] Let's move before they
raise the fucking rent
[music] O www
[music] All right now,
[music] Baby, it’s all right now
[music] Baby, it’s all right now oh
(musical balls play tune)
Are you OK?
Vivienne,,,
Oh, fuck, fuck!
- Are you OK? OK, just stay,,,
- (sirens approach)
- Someone's in the car,
- Don't get upset, OK, just,,,
There is somebody still in the car,
You have to get her out of the car,
(man) Let's sit you down,
What's your name? Relax,
I'm sorry,
- (man) Let's go,
- She's locked inside the car,
You have to get her out of there!
Mr. Hughes?
I'm gonna have to ask you to hang around
for a while, A couple of days, tops,
Just till we get all the statements in,
- Procedure, You understand,
- (knock on door)
Clyde, that urgent stuff has just arrived,
Do you want me to,,,
Oh, OK, Meryl,
Uh,,, I'm sorry, Mr, Hughes,
I'm just gonna have to, uh,,,
My officer managed to retrieve
some of your things,
We can get the rest to you
once they've been released,
Anyway, just check there's nothing of Miss
Freeman's there and I'll see you out front,
I'd like to speak to her mother,
I'm sorry?
Vivienne's mother,
It's always a difficult time
for the family,
- I realize that,
- With respect, sir, I don't think you do,
If your daughter was killed in an accident,
would you speak to the driver?
I didn't kill Vivienne,
The driver of the truck killed Vivienne,
Yes, but it wouldn't be very professional
of me to go giving out personal information,
Would it?
(woman) Goodbye, Florence,
(ding dong)
(woman) Yes?
I'd like to talk to Mrs, Freeman,
Why?
Mrs, Freeman,
may I come in?
- Do I know you?
- No,
My name is Alex Hughes,
Just wanted to talk to you
for a couple of minutes,
About what?
I'm very busy and I don't do social,
(music stops)
The police have been,
haven't they?
Yes, The police were here
two hours and 20 minutes ago,
So you know what's happened,
Yes, I know Vivienne is dead,
Is that it?
Well, I just wanted to explain that,,,
I gave your daughter a lift,
It was an accident,
I'm so sorry,
OK,
(locks door)
It's just,
Vivienne bought you something,
She said you'd like them,
Sparklies,
She got me sparklies,
Um, yes,
(musical balls play tune)
Are you OK?
Take off your outdoor shoes
and put them in the row,
Don't move any of the others,
I'm to offer you something, Would you
like an herbal tea? I have 17 varieties,
- Yes, let me,,,
- No! Don't come in my kitchen,
That's off-limits,
I'm gonna give you
the licorice one,
I can't stomach the licorice one,
It tastes like cat pee,
Are you alone here?
Yes,
Do you have anybody who can
stay with you for a couple of days?
I have two parents,
They're hiking in Algonquin,
No one can get a signal,
Maybe the police could put you
in touch with someone to talk to,
- Someone qualified,
- About what?
- About what's happened,
- OK,
I just came to explain,,,
I don't handle
this sort of thing well at all,
Oh! Give me your clothes,
I'm sorry?
Take off your clothes,
Give them to me,
I'll give them back,
I,,,
I don't want the wet
contaminating my carpet,
Take off your clothes,
I'm getting you dry ones,
By the way, that's my third favorite sweater
so you can't keep it,
Don't look at me,
I'm doing my checking,
I check the kitchen every time I use it
and every time I don't use it,
That must take up a lot of time,
Yes, it does,
(dog barks)
That's Marilyn, Vivienne's dog,
I can't stand her,
So, did Vivienne live here with you
all the time?
Yes, Vivienne came on a short stay
three years ago and didn't leave,
She lived with my parents until then,
That's who she was visiting,
Why was she hitchhiking?
Vivienne wanted to be a writer,
She said she would always
try and get a ride
with the most lonely looking characters
because they had the best stories,
Mrs, Freeman,
this is all a bit difficult for me,
I came here to apologize
because your daughter died
and it was my car,
Did you do it on purpose?
- Of course not, We just stopped at the,,,
- Sit down, then,
And I'm not a missus, I'm Linda,
I haven't got a problem with you,
You must be all right - you gave Vivienne
a lift and you brought me my sparklies,
(sobs)
Is there a problem with the tea?
No, No, it's not the tea,
Are you sad
because someone you didn't know died?
This is guilt, Linda,
I feel guilty, OK?
Right, because you were driving,
- Yes, because I was driving,
- But he ran into you,
Yes, he ran into me,
- Right,
- (doorbell)
(woman) Linda,
What is she doing here again?
She's already been once today,
I'm not letting her in,
- (knock at door)
- (woman) Linda,
Go away, Florence,
Nobody wants you here, Get lost,
- Linda,,,
- Whatever it is, I don't need it, Go away,
Alex, tell her to go away,
Tell her,
Oh,
- Hello,
I think Linda
needs someone to stay with her,
- No, I don't, You're stupid,
- It's all right, Linda, I'm only here to help,
Whatever it is, I don't need it,
Leave me alone,
I really don't think
she wants to talk about it any more tonight,
And you are,,,?
- Alex Hughes,
- Goodbye, Florence,
Oh,,,
Are you staying?
- No, No, I,,,
- Yes, he's staying,
Alex Hughes is staying, and if you
come back, I'm calling the police,
OK, You have my number,
Linda, I can't stay,
- You'll have to give my sweater back then,
- I should call a taxi,
They won't pick up from this house,
not after last time,
- Well, what about a bus?
- It's too late,
- Is there a hotel?
- Yes,
- Where is it?
- It's four miles up the highway,
- I should get my clothes,
- They haven't finished their cycle,
Do you want tea?
No,
Would you like to go out and play?
I have a trampoline,
- I'll just get my things,
- I think you should stay until Tuesday,
- I'm sorry,
- They collect garbage on Tuesday,
- I don't do garbage,
- Linda, I appreciate the offer, but I,,,
It was Vivienne's job, I can't touch garbage,
so you'll have to take the bags out now,
- Do you want food?
- Linda, I'm sorry, but I can't do this,
I'll just get my clothes
and then I have to leave,
Well, you can't,,,
Don't go in my kitchen!
(screams)
I'll get your stupid clothes!
(sighs)
- Now what are you doing?
- Fuck! I didn't know this was your room,
Where are you going?
Stay still,
I saw the bunk beds
and I thought,,,
Vivienne says I'm probably the only adult
in the entire world who has a bunk bed,
I've tried other beds, I don't like them,
I've slept in this since I was three,
- I'll find somewhere else,
- No, no, Get back under here,
I need to know where you are, I don't
want you pounding around my house,
Do you snore?
I don't know,
Well, lie down and go to sleep,
I need my rest,
And if you try and touch me, I'll shoot you,
I have a gun,
Can you see the stars?
[Music] The stars at night are shining bright
[music] Deep in the heart of Wawa
Linda, I hope you don't mind,
I ate a cracker,
You what?
You went in my kitchen?
Yes,
I'm sorry,
I was a bit hungry,
I don't care,
I cleaned up afterwards,
(phone rings)
(phone continues to ring)
(answering machine beeps)
(Vivienne) Hi, this is the madhouse.
Leave us a message
and we’ll probably get back to you.
- Please speak slowly and be precise.
- (beep)
Linda,
The phone,
Linda?
Are you all right?
I'm fine, If you get your mouth
completely full of snow,
it all dissolves
and you can drink it,
Um, it's your p,,,
Aren't you cold?
I have an unusual
body-temperature control,
It feels just right,
- Have you ever had an orgasm, Alex?
- It has been known,
Vivienne once described
an orgasm to me,
It sounds like an inferior version of
what I feel when I have a mouthful of snow,
You should try it,
Hi,
I heard about Vivienne,
I'm so sorry, I really liked her,
- Is she all right?
- (gurgles)
I don't know,
- What exactly is it?
- Autism,
But she's very verbal,
I had noticed,
Are you all right?
I don't know,
I'm Maggie, And everybody's
been saying that it wasn't your fault,
- Alex,
- I know,
It's a very small town,
So has anyone
been feeding that dog?
(Alex) In a manner of speaking,
Well, if she needs anything,
I'm right here,
Not that she'll talk to me,
Bye,
(Linda) Alex,
- Alex, we have to make a snowman,
- Do we?
Vivienne came to visit me every year, We
always made a crazy-creature snowman,
We kept on doing it,
We haven't made one this year,
Linda, there's a message
from your parents,
Let's make a chipmunk,
We never made a chipmunk,
I love chipmunks,
From now on,
every time I miss Vivienne,
I'm going to make
a crazy-creature snowman,
(answering machine beeps)
(woman) Oh, hi, folks.
It's only Mom and Dad.
- Just ringing to let you know we’re fine.
- (man) Hello.
(woman) Your dad got an icicle
embedded in his privates yesterday.
- (man) Don't ask.
- But apart from that, we’re A-OK.
We hope everything's fine with you
and that Vivvy got back all right.
We'll ring you again when we get to the
next pit stop. We're miles from anywhere.
- (man) Come on. It's just a message.
- Sorry. OK, keep warm. Love you both.
Bye. Bye.
You should really try to get hold of them,
They'd want to be here,
I have to go identify
Vivienne's body today,
and tomorrow is work
and Tuesday they collect the garbage,
- Work?
- I work part-time at the valu-mart,
I stack shelves,
Will you come with me?
I don't think they'll expect you at work,
No, to see Vivienne's body,
Will you come with me?
I have to work or I won't get paid,
Well, uh,,,
If you want me to, I have to go into the
police station anyway to pick up my stuff,
- Then I should be on my way,
- I don't know why I have to go,
Everyone knows it's her,
- It's just procedure,
- I've seen it on TV,
They always let two people in the room
with them, Will you come in with me?
Yes,
If you want me to,
- Do people like you, Alex?
- Not much, no,
I'm not surprised, It's because
those glasses don't look right on your face,
You have a long face
and those glasses make you look shifty,
- Really?
- Yes,
- You need some new frames,
- I think it will take more than that,
I know how you neurotypical people
are obsessed with having friends,
I'm only trying to help you get some,
Well, I appreciate your efforts, but
in my experience, friends can be overrated,
There,
Now you look almost nice,
(man) Mrs, Freeman,
is this your daughter?
- Miss Freeman,
- Sorry,
Miss Freeman,
is this your daughter?
Linda, is this Vivienne?
She looks different,
I'm sorry, Linda,
I need verbal identification,
Is this Vivienne Freeman?
Yes, Yes, it is,
Come on,
Let's get you home,
Don't talk to me now
until I say so,
OK,
Linda!
Linda, oh, I was so sorry
to hear about Marianne,
- Vivienne,
- Vivienne?
Vivienne!
Oh, she was such a personality,
Diane,
Diane Wooton, Why I keep that name,
I'll never know, Been divorced two years,
Alex, Alex Hughes,
Oh! Now I know you're not a native,
not with that delectable accent,
No,
Linda, if there's anything I can do for you,
anything at all,,,
- Like what?
- Well, like,,,
like anything,
Oh, it must be so awful
losing a child like that,
- I didn't lose her, She's dead,
- Linda,
- What?
- It's all right, I know all about autism,
I've seen that film,
OK, well, you take care of yourself, Linda,
I'll be keeping my eye on you,
Nice meeting you, Alex,
Sure it won't be the last time,
(Alex) Have you made up your mind
about the funeral, Linda?
You have to decide what to do -
the service, the flowers, the people,
- It's not a wedding,
- No, but it takes a lot of sorting out,
It's important to get it right,
If we have the funeral on Monday,
would you stay until Tuesday?
- To put the bins out?
- The garbage cans, yes,
I don't do garbage,
OK, here's what I'll do,
I'll stay and help organize the funeral,
- And then you'll,,,
- Then I'll put the garbage out,
- On Tuesday,
- Yes,
- Perfectamundo!
- But then I have to go,
You'd better tell me about
what you think Vivienne would want,
I know what Vivienne would want,
She'd want to be alive,
What was she pestering you about?
- Who?
- This morning,
That Maggie from next door,
I think she just wanted
to pay her respects,
She's a prostitute, Alex,
I don't think she has much respect to give,
"I don't remember when
I noticed my eyebrows,
"but I know
that's when it all started,"
"What is the moment worth?"
"The past is only a memory,
"the future, a fantasy,
"It's only in the present
"that we truly live,"
OK, Vivienne,
(Maggie) See you later,
Have a good one,
(Alex) Hello, again,
(Maggie) Hello,
I just came round - it's a bit of a cliché
really - to borrow some tea, Normal tea,
- That would be to drink with the fruitcake,
- She's not mad,
No, I know,
Vivienne explained it all to me,
High functioning, can talk a glass eye
to sleep, but can't tie her shoelaces,
- Don't you like her?
- She doesn't like me, for some reason,
- So did you really come around for tea?
- Have you got any?
- Assam, Darjeeling,
- There is a god,
No, there is FedEx,
An English friend of mine
sends it over,
Don't go inventing a deity
to thank for the small miracles,
- They just happen,
- So you're a nonbeliever,
I am, which makes me
a bit of a novelty around here,
Then again, so is Linda,
It's a judgmental town, this,
The emphasis being on the "mental,"
- (Alex) I assume you're new to the area,
- Oh, no, No,
I've lived here for 12 years,
So how are you holding up?
I keep seeing her face,
She was singing,
She had all this energy,
and I walked away without a scratch,
- Are you planning on staying here a while?
- Apparently, Till after the funeral,
That's very sweet of you,
Listen, I,,,
I don't know what kind of plans
you have with my neighbor,
but I'm free tonight
and, I don't know, I could cook something,
We could have dinner, maybe?
Thank you,
([music] "Just Looking" by Stereophonics)
(sings along)
What are you listening to?
Just trying to find something for Vivienne,
Stereophonics, They're not bad,
I prefer tinnitus,
Linda, can I ask, if you don't like people,
how did you manage with Vivienne?
I don't like normal people,
I like useful people,
and people who like doing
the things I like doing,
Vivienne was very helpful to me,
We had a lot of fun,
I know how you must be feeling,
I had a son,,,
You don't know how I'm feeling
because you're not me,
- ,,, who died,
- Nobody knows how I'm feeling
because half the time,
I don't have a clue,
Well, I know how that feels, too,
When I found out about,,,
You want to go out
and play on the trampoline?
No,
- No, thank you,
- We could make a snowman,
I was gonna tell you about my son, but now
I think I'll just sit here, if it's OK with you,
Did your son like the snow?
No,
Nope, that was one of the few things
he didn't like,
Oh,
Did you know
that no two snowflakes are alike?
Wilson Bentley
photographed 2,354 snowflakes,
His best snowstorm was on his birthday,
on February 14, 1928, when he was 63,
He called it a gift
from "kind winter,"
Is it OK if I take the dog out in a bit?
Don't let her pee on my snow,
Hi,
Right on time,
I didn't know, uh,,,
I'm sure this isn't the norm, but, uh,,,
I brought you some tea bags,
Ginseng and fennel,
I find the norm usually involves chocolate
or, if I'm really lucky, perfume,
but ginseng and fennel, wow,
Come in,
And the dog comes too,
So, Mr, Snowdrifter,
what's your story?
Me? Oh,
there's nothing much to say, really,
Come on, I can tell by looking at your face
that you have some interesting baggage,
I don't have baggage,
I have haulage,
See? I told you,
You just look so,,,
- Shifty?
- Mm-mmm,
Sad,
I hope you like shrimp cocktail, It's what
I normally serve my gentlemen callers,
I'm afraid it's not very original,
but,,, I really hate to cook,
After Linda's specialized diet,
believe me, I'd eat grit,
Everything's gluten free,
She has leaky gut syndrome,
as well as a ringing in her ears,
Wow,
- So, what about you?
- What? Disease wise?
No,
You, generally,
Oh, me,
No, I like to, uh,,,
I like to keep an air of mystery about me,
At least on the,,,
first date,
- Really?
- Mm-hm,
So,
how long are you planning on staying?
You are very beautiful,
I'm leaving after the funeral,
I like you,
I really like you,
I hate having sex on a full stomach so shall
we skip the main course and go next door?
Oh, shit, I forgot about
the English-reserve thing, OK,
I'm sorry,
I've embarrassed you, Let's just eat,
No, No, it's fine,
If I'm honest,
it's what I came round for,
Well, good,
I'm glad we cleared that up,
It's been a while,
Sorry if it was a bit quick,
- I think the dog might've put me off,
- (chuckles)
It's OK,
We have all night,
So why are you going to Winnipeg?
You ask a lot of questions,
Do I?
I'm going to meet an old friend,
Hm,
A friend friend or a friend friend?
I should go,
I won't mention her again,
I promise,
Why didn't you just fly straight there
like a normal person?
Well, I thought I'd drive, take in some of
the lakes, It didn't look far on the map,
Would you even consider
driving from London to Moscow?
Well, actually,
I was looking on a globe,
The scale was a bit off,
(whispers) I think you're ready to try again,
(murmurs)
I should go,
Um,,,
I haven't done
this kind of thing before,
I'm sorry,
How much do I owe you?
What?
For last night,
What do I,,,?
You want to pay me?
Well, I thought,,,
Oh, God!
You're not, are you?
- It's just that Linda,,,
- I have a few male callers now and again,
And, yes, I like sex,
but,,,
- No, I am not a hooker,
- Oh, shit!
I feel dreadful,
Oh, it's OK, It's OK,
I have to say,
I'm more than relieved,
What? You're not a big fan
of ladies of the night?
I don't think I'd have enough money
to see you as much as I want to,
(Maggie laughs)
Oh, my God!
I booked the cars for 12 o'clock,
Is that all right?
I'm going to work,
What do you think?
OK,
(Linda wails and dog barks)
What's the matter, Linda?
What is it?
- It's on the rug, It's disgusting!
- It's OK, Linda, Just calm,,,
It's dog throw-up!
From inside the dog's stomach,
- It will make an unbelievably bad stain,
- Linda, it's OK,
It's not OK, It's not OK,
I can't do this, I can't do this!
I need Vivienne!
Well, uh,,, I'll sort it,
Please,
please don't let it leave a stain,
- If it leaves a stain, I have to move,
- Linda,
I said, I'll sort it,
Oh, please don't let it leave a stain!
And don't go in my kitchen!
(Linda sobs)
(water spills)
- Oh, Alex,
- Oh, Hello,
- Nice to see you,
What's she been eating?
- I don't know, Linda gives her bananas,
- Bananas?
She's not a monkey,
- I don't know much about dogs,
- You know about dog vomit, right?
Yeah,
Keep her off the bananas, I've heard
you can get this stuff in cans - dog food,
- Controversial, I know,
- Yeah,
Actually,
this isn't a social call today,
Really?
I just came to warn you
about Alex Hughes,
Several little birds have told me
you and he are getting social,
I don't think that's any of your business,
Clyde, Or anyone else's,
This town is getting so you can't cough
without someone alerting the authorities,
Yeah,
I looked him up on our system,
He killed someone,
- Did you know?
- No, He was driving, but it wasn't his fault,
I'm not talking about Vivienne,
He killed a guy,
He just got out,
- I didn't know that,
- I thought you should,
Now I do,
And,,,
to top it all, he hit a cop,
Just ask yourself this, Maggie,
Is that normal? Eh?
Picking up young girls,
staying with a mentally challenged lady,
killing people,
Hitting cops,
Well,
Oh, uh,,,
I have a spare ticket for a magician
up at the Legion on Wednesday,
if you're interested,
What's he gonna do, Clyde?
Make you disappear?
- (Linda) "B-a-a-n-g,"
- (Alex) You can't have two "a's" in "bang,"
(Linda) In comic-book-word Scrabble, you
can, You can have three as if you want,
With a double-letter score,
that makes 22 points,
- This game is ridiculous,
- It isn't,
It isn't, You get to say words
like "kerrang" and "boing"
- and "cowabunga" and "buttocks,"
- What comic book did that come out of?
I don't know, I just like
saying "buttocks," Buttocks,
OK, What's your word?
- I can make it up, right?
- Yes, That's the best bit,
OK, "Y-a-a,,,
"m-o-o-I,"
That's four, five, six,,,
That's 24 points,
"Yaamoo!,"
I like that, "Yaamoo!,"
OK, now you have to
give an example of it in a sentence,
Like I said, if you make up a word,
you have to give an example,
All right, Um,,,
- Spider-Man,,,
- Spider-Man?
- What's wrong with Spider-Man?
- Well, it's a bit obvious,
Oh, all right, Spider-Man,
Spider-Man,,,
is about to save the universe,,,
from an evil,,, thing,
So he hits him with a jet of web,
Yaamoo!,
And it stops him -
it - in its tracks,
- You are terrible at this game,
- I've got two more points than you,
"D-a-zed,,,
"l-i-o-u-s, Dazlious,"
- I'm assuming that's a made-up word,
- It is,
It's also 38 points for the word
and another 50
for using up all my letters,
- That makes 88 points,
- And your example?
Mister Fantastic
from the Fantastic Four,,,
He's got arms made of elastic so they
can stretch for 200, maybe 300 miles,
He's been imprisoned in a cave
for seven days
with no food
and no water and no light,
And on the eighth day,
he manages to loosen a rock
and push his way up through the top,,,
With his stretchy arms,
,,, and up into the daylight, just as the sun
is coming up over the mountains
and filling the sky
with this white-yellow light,
And there's a stillness,
and in the few minutes he's got before
his captor, the evil Doctor Doom, returns,
he stops for one second
and all he can hear
is his own breathing,
And he's totally overwhelmed
by how big the world is
and how small
and unimportant he is,
And as he turns around,
we see his face look to the sky,
And he says, very quietly,
so that no one can hear him,
he says,
"Dazlious,"
I'm gonna make some tea,
If I'm going to have any chance of winning
this game, I'm going to really need to focus,
You know where to find me,
- (Maggie) I've had a bit of a shady past,
- (Alex) Oh, really?
(Maggie) I was married for 15 years,
Arrest this woman now,
He was a very nice man,
But I had affairs,
I like the candies and the flowers -
the tea-bags bit,
I'm just not good
at the day-to-day stuff, you know?
I'm a selfish woman,
and I broke his heart,
Made a real mess of it, actually,
So, someone said
you can drink this water,
Yeah, it's supposed to have healing
properties, Why don't you take a sip?
- I don't think so,
- What? You don't want to be healed?
Set free of your demons,
- They keep me company,
- (dog barks)
- I think we should be getting Marilyn back,
- You know, Alex,,,
I think maybe your dog's been getting
a little too much exercise lately,
Perhaps you could try
walking it at home,
in the privacy
of your own bathroom,
What exactly is it
that you want to know?
Everything,
(Alex) That's Ryan, my son,
(Maggie) What?
You said you didn't have any kids,
I got a letter from Ryan,
His mum had allowed him to see his birth
certificate and I was on it, under "Father,"
And are you his real dad?
Yes,
His mum's name's Rebecca, She's the
woman that I'm going to see in Winnipeg,
We had a short fling, I suppose she
thought I was never that serious, so she,,,
It was 22 years ago,
What did he say to you?
He wrote me a list of all the things he liked
and all the things he hated,
I mean, when you saw him,
We arranged to meet in a restaurant,
I sat in the restaurant
until closing time and,,,
he never showed up,
He was in an accident
on the way to meet me,
Got hit by a drunk driver,
and he died instantly,
Oh, my God!
That is terrible,
I never even met him,
- So all I lost really was a fantasy,
- Oh, my God!
A fucking fantasy,
I spent the last four years
grieving over someone I never knew,
and now I'm doing it all over again
with Vivienne,
Come here, Come here,
(radio) Good morning. I'm Martin Scott
and I'm here every morning with you,
and we’ll be up all night, too,
with the Wawwa Rotary Club...
(boy) No, not those, dude,
Those are serial killer,
Getting warmer,
Oh, you know what, though?
Yeah, I think these
are the guys for you,
Oh, yeah,
Am I good or what?
Actually, I think I'll just stick to my old ones,
I was just browsing, really,
Eyebrowsing,
- Right?
- Uh,,,
- Thanks for your time,
- It's cool,
- I love that accent, by the way,
- Thank you,
(knocking at door)
I,,, I came to talk to Linda,
She won't open the door,
I wanted to say sorry,
So did I, and I'm still here,
Mind you, I wasn't the one
ramming a 40-ton truck into her daughter,
Look, man,
I'm not a killer,
It was an accident,
- I lost my job,,,
- My heart bleeds,
What? Haven't you ever
made a fucking mistake?
- I think you should go,
- I can't go, Not until I've,,,
Until you've what?
You lost your job? She lost her daughter,
And not just any daughter,
the one who helped her
to make some sense of all this shit,
You bought flowers,
you thick bastard?
Come on, then,
- Just get out of here,
- Look, come on, then,
Let me have it,
Let me have it! Come on! Come on!
Just don't push me,
What's the matter?
Can't finish the job? Come on!
Don't you know you can't hurt me?
Don't you know I'm fucking indestructible?
(sobs)
(Linda giggles)
What are you doing?
What does it look like I'm doing?
- I'm trampolining,
- Linda,
Could you stop bouncing
for a minute?
I want to tell you about
what happened with my son,
I went to prison,
- I went to prison because,,,
- I want you to bounce me up,
Not now, Linda,
Is it because
you had a fight with the truck driver?
Yes,
I won't see Vivienne again,
you won't see Vivienne again
and he won't see Vivienne again,
We all have to get over it,
OK, Now, bounce me up,
I'm not moving
until you play with me,
I'm gonna stay out here
all night long,
Please, Please, Alex,
Please, please, please, bounce me,
Promise to let everyone
come back tomorrow after the funeral,
Yippee! Yes!
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes, yes,
Bounce, bounce, bounce,
bounce, bounce, bounce!
(Linda laughs)
You worried about tomorrow?
No, I think it's done,
I'm worried about Linda,
Must be weird,
not wanting to be with other people,
not needing anyone to,
you know, plug into,
Don't worry on that account, She's got
quite enough going on in that head of hers,
She needs other people to do things
for her, if not necessarily with her,
Vivienne did the boring stuff,
What's she gonna do now?
You offering?
Wouldn't get past the door,
- I'm beginning to like this,
- What's that?
Being with you,
Being with Linda,
Being with myself, Again,
Hey, and I'm having sex and these muffins
are great, That sort of thing,
You be careful, Mr, Shifty,
(doorbell)
Sorry to call so early,
it's just, we had a collection,
We got a wreath for the church, but I also
wanted to bring something else I had done,
Oh, that's very kind,
- Is she in?
- Oh, yes,
Linda,
Linda!
I like your robe,
Diane's brought you something,
- What is it?
- It's a bereavement cookie,
- I can't eat that,
- Oh?
She's gluten free,
Oh!
Right,
Well, waste not, want not,
I'll take it back,
It's my nephew's
fifth birthday tomorrow so,,,
I'll scrape the icing off,
put some new numbers on,
- A nice new number five,
- I'll scrape it,
(Marilyn barking)
There,
Well,
I'll see you both in church later,
(Alex) Um,,,
- Thanks, Diane,
- Bye,
Despite both our faults, I actually think
we work quite well together, don't you?
Yes, I do,
Can you please take the dog out now?
I don't want to talk to you anymore,
- Shall I come back in about half an hour?
- I don't know, I only know how I feel now,
(woman sobs)
(muffled speech)
Hello,
You must be Alex,
I'm Dirk,
And this is Ellen,
How do you do?
I'm sorry,
I told myself I wasn't gonna cry,
Every time we go away, it's always Linda
we're worried about, isn't it, Dirk?
We never even gave Vivienne
a second thought, We ne,,, we never,,,
Ellen's a bit upset,
We've been hiking,
We came straight here, Is Linda inside?
I'm half inside, half outside,
Hi, sweetie,
Hi,
We've just been meeting Alex, Linda,
Your eyes are red,
Yes, they are,
- Mommy, cheek,
- Yeah, That's my girl, That's my,,,
- I'll let you have some time,
- Yes,
Thank you, Alex,
I thought Vivienne would appreciate
something a bit unconventional,
Perfectamundo,
Is it compulsory to cry at funerals?
No, It's not compulsory,
Good, because I don't know
if I will or not,
Wilson Bentley,
the man who photographed snowflakes,
died after walking in a snowstorm,
Is there anything you need?
Yes,
I'd like you to put your arms around me
and squeeze me really hard,
but don't touch me
with your hands,
Say when,
(Linda sighs)
(organ plays "Just Looking"
by Stereophonics)
(Ellen) Linda, Linda,
- Please sit down,
- Linda,
(door shuts)
(music stops)
For those who don't know,
I'm Vivienne's granddad,
But as our daughter Linda
was unable to look after her,
my wife Ellen and I
raised Vivienne as our own for 16 years,
Vivienne was a real one-off,
and the most gentle
and generous person I've ever met,
She had an amazing ability -
accepting people for what they are,
embracing their differences,
Most of you
are probably aware that, um,,,
Vivienne wanted to be a writer,
On her last visit to us
only a week or so ago,
she gave me a children's picture book
that she was working on,
I'd like to read it to you
because it says more about Vivienne
than anything I could put into words,
"My Little Brother,"
"My little brother James is special,
"My little brother is four
and he can't talk yet,
"He doesn't always understand
what I say to him,
"and he's not a bit interested
in my wrestling toys,
"Dad plays games with him and tries to
get him interested in rockets and football,
"but my little brother
really only likes the alphabet,
"He's very happy when we have
alphabet spaghetti for lunch,
"but then, so am I,
"Yesterday, he took my hands
and danced with me,
"Every time he does something new,
however small,
"it's a brilliant feeling,
"I wish everyone could get to know
someone like my little brother,
"He makes you look at things
in a brand-new way,
"Some people say that James won't ever
do the things I do, but it doesn't matter,
"He'll just do different things,
"I love my little brother so much and, one
day, I know he'll tell me he loves me too,
"Although he'll probably
spell it out in spaghetti first,"
Thank you, Dirk,
Please stand while we take a moment to
listen to one of Vivienne's favorite records,
by the, uh,,,
(clears throat)
Super Furry Animals,
([music] "Hello Sunshine"
by Super Furry Animals)
(people chatter)
(doorbell)
Oh, hi,
Thank you so much,
Please take your shoes off
before entering,
Excuse me,
Why is that man still here?
- Go on, Linda, hand these around,
- All these people doing social,
- It's OK, Linda,
- It's not OK, When are they gonna go?
Well, they'll have a sandwich
and then they'll go,
So what do you see in him, Maggie?
You know, Clyde,
you have a superior air about you,
Whoever told you
you were so special?
you weren't?
- It's surprisingly clean, eh?
- That's autism, They're neat freaks,
Yeah? You should take notes,
You could learn something,
- Why do you have to do that?
- What? It was a joke,
Try one of these,
They're gluten free,
You know, Alex is very fond of you,
He talks about you all the time,
Maybe when he's gone,
I could come over and,,,
Why would I want you
to come over?
They've had sandwiches,
Why are they hanging around?
Oh, thank you so much for coming,
It's very nice of you,
(gasps)
It's a funny place, this,
Never felt at home here,
But Linda always liked it, We bought it
because she wanted to be independent,
especially after Vivienne was born,
How did that happen?
Um,,,
We still don't know,
She was very close -
well, relatively close -
to a boy who went to the center,
We all assumed
it was an experiment,
She didn't seem remotely upset at first,
but she might have been forced,
We asked and we asked,
Anyhow, she was six months gone
before anyone noticed,
It's like everything with Linda,
You have to accept her totally,
And somehow, Vivienne understood that
from very early on,
Oh, she would've loved the service,
And this, too,
She loved a party,
I don't think there's ever been
more than five people in this house,
I don't know
how you persuaded her,
But, anyway,
I just wanted to say thanks,
For staying,
You didn't have to,
To be honest, the elements were
against me, I didn't have an alternative,
There's always an alternative, Alex,
This house is getting
nasty, nasty, nasty!
("Notteru Ondo" by The Drifters
plays very loudly)
It's all right, honey,
(Linda sings along to music)
Linda,
I think you should stop now,
No, it's all right, just,,,
- Can't somebody turn this off?
- Leave her alone,
- Linda, come on,
- She's OK,
(turns off music)
- She's fine,
- But this is a wake,
She's fine,
Just let her dance,
- Please!
- (music starts again)
(sings along to music)
It's like getting back on your bike,
You'll be fine,
There's no point worrying
it'll happen again, Nothing you can do,
- If it's coming, it's coming,
- Thank you, Clyde, That's very reassuring,
I can't say I'm sad to see you go,
Don't tell me,
Maggie,
Yep,
- Do you think she'll ever,,,
- No,
Drive safely, then,
- Hi,
- I'm never having that many people here,
- Where are your parents?
- I told them to go,
I had to clean the house,
They'll be back tomorrow,
Oh, right,
I would've liked
to have said goodbye,
- I'm gonna take Marilyn for a walk,
- Don't forget the,,,
Garbage,
I know, 12 o'clock,
(Maggie) Hi,
We've just come to say goodbye,
"We"?
Any chance you'd keep an eye on her?
She'll be dead in a week otherwise,
Who? Linda or the dog?
She didn't take long to settle in,
Maybe I should do the same,
I saw this house in the real-estate window
in town, It's by the lake,
Kind of tempting,
No, Stupid idea,
I told you I was selfish,
You did,
I hope you find what you're looking for
in Winnipeg,
Mm,
I wonder what that is,
Good luck to me,
Maggie, I killed a man,
The driver who ran into my son,
I found out his name,
where he lived,
I went there and I hit him,
Hard,
He fell,
He fell onto this stone floor
and he cracked his head open,
I know,
Clyde told me,
- Why didn't you,,,
- I was waiting for you to mention it,
I'm glad you did,
You know,
mostly he's upset that you hit a cop,
Thanks,
I think you're gonna find peace
when you get there,
You'll probably end up staying,
But if you're ever
passing through here again, I,,,
I've had a really nice time,
Gotta do the garbage,
Gotta do the garbage, Garbage,
Gotta do the garbage, Gotta do
the garbage, Gotta do the garbage,
They're two hours late,
Maybe they're not coming today,
What if we do what everybody in
the street - everybody in the world - does?
Put the bags out, then if they don't turn up
today, you can leave them out until they do,
No, we're not gonna do that, The bags
will split and that's when raccoons come,
Raccoons have rabies
and they mess up the snow,
I'm sorry, Linda,
I just don't know what else I can do,
- I've made arrangements,
- You are a very selfish man,
- No, I'm not, You're just unreasonable,
- I'm autistic,
Well, it's the same thing,
Apart from today, you have been very
helpful, Alex, and I want to say thank you,
You're not as interesting as Vivienne, but
you have some quite good characteristics,
Whoo-hoo,
Don't go overboard
with the praise there, Linda,
So, Linda,
I'm really going to have to go,
Very soon,
You have been very annoying,
But you've also been a friend
and I'm going to miss you,
Hm,
I didn't think
it'd be so hard to say goodbye,
It's been a real pleasure,
You are the only person
I have ever met
who I didn't have to explain
or even justify myself to,
Perfectamundo,
- Sorry about the trash,
- Mm,
- Can I send you a postcard?
- What for?
- I'll give you a ring, I've got your number,
- When will you ring me?
You know,
I think Vivienne would've liked our story,
Well, she's not here to see it, is she?
Right, then,
I'm so sorry
about your daughter,
I'm off,
I left something for you,
It's in the freezer,
(car starts)
(Linda sighs)
Snow cake,
Now, that is interesting,
(dog barks outside)
Oh, no!
(door slams)
(Linda) He stops for one second.
And he's totally overwhelmed
by how big the world is
and how small
and unimportant he is.
And as he turns around,
we see his face look to the sky.
And he says, very quietly,
so that no one can hear him:
"Dazlious."
([music] "Hello Sunshine"
by Super Furry Animals)
5@y3