Subtitle: AXIS THE SIAMESE CAT
Did you know there are more people with genius IQ’s living in China than there are people of any kind living in the
United States?
That can't possibly be true.
It is true.
What would account for that?
Well first of all, a lot of people live
in China. But here's my question:
Question?
How do you distinguish yourself in a
population of people who all got 1600 on
their SAT's?
I didn't know they take SAT‘s in China.
They dont,I wasn't talking about China anymore, I
was talking about here.
You got 1600?
Yes I can sing in a Acapella group. But I cant sing.
Does that mean that you actually got
nothing wrong?
Or you row crew or you invent a 25 dollar
PC.
Or you get into a final club.
Or you get into a final club, exactly.
You know from a womans perspective sometimes not being in an Accapella group can be a good thing.
This is serious.
Well I am admitting I do like guys who row crew.
I like guys who row crew.
Well I cant do that.
Im kidding.
Yes I
got nothing wrong on the test.
Have you ever tried?
I'm trying now.
To row crew?
To get into a final club. To row crew?
No. Are you, like-—whatever--delusional?
Sometimes,
Sometimes, you say two things at once and I'm not sure which one we're aiming at.
But you've seen guys who row crew, right?
NO.
Okay, we1l_they’re bigger than me.
They're world class athletes. And a
second ago you said you like guys who row crew
crew so I assumed you'd met one.
I guess I meant I liked the idea of it.
The way a girl likes cowboys.
Okay.
Can we get something to eat.
would you rather talk about something
else?
No, it's just that since the beginning of the conversation about finals clubs I think I may have missed a birthday.
There are more people in China with genius
IQ's than the entire population of»-
The Phoenix is the most diverse. The Fly Club, Roosevelt
punched the Pore.
Which one?
The Porcellian, the Porc, it's the best of the best.
I actually meant which Roosevelt.
Theodore.
Is it true they send a bus around to pick up girls who want to party wth the next -----
You can see why its so important to get in.
Okay, well, which is the easiest one to get into?
Why would you ask me that?
I was just asking.
None of them thats the point
Our freind Eduardo made $300,000 betting on oilfutures last sumer and
Eduardo wont come close to gettingin. the ability to makemoney doesn't impress anybody around here.
Must be nice.
He made $300,000 in a summer?
He likes meteorology.
I thought it was oil futures.
you can read the weather you can
predict the price of heating oil.
I think you asked me that because you think the final club that's easiest to get into is the one where I'll have the best chance.
I what...
You asked me which one was the easiest to get into because you think that's where I have the best chance.
The one that's easiest to get into would be the one where anybody had the best chance.
You didnt ask which one was the best one, you asked me which one was the easiest.
I was honestly just asking. Okay? I was asking just to ask.
Mark, I'm not speaking in code.
Erica~—
You're obsessed with the finals clubs. You have finals clubs OCD and you need to see someone about this who'll prescribe
some sort of medication. You don't care if side effects may include blindness,
Final clubs.
and there's a difference between being obsessed and being motivated.
Yes
there is.
Well you do-—that was cryptic—~so you do speak in code.
I didn't mean to be cryptic.
All I'm saying I need to do something substantial in order to get the attentionof the clubs.
Why?
Because they“re exclusive. ' (beat) And fun and they lead to a better life.
You think Teddy Roosevelt got elected president because he was a member of the
Phoenix Club?
He was a member of the Porcellian and yes he did.
Well why dont you concentrate on being the best you, you can be.
Did you really just say that
I was kidding
Im just stating the fact that, does'nt make it any less.
I want to be straight forward and tell you that I think you should be a lot more supportive. If I get in I'll be taking you to the EVENTS and the Gatherings and you'll be meeting people that you wouldn't normally get to meet .
You would do that for me?
Indeed
Okay I want to try and be straight forward with you and let you know that were not anymore
What is
Were not dating anymore, Im sorry
Is this a joke?
No,  it's not.
You're breaking up with me?
You're going to introduce me to people I wouldn't normally get to meet? What the
fuck is that supposed to mean?
Settle down
What was it supposed to mean?
-Erica, the reason we're able to sit here and drink is that you used to sleep with the door guy.
The door guy's name is Bobby. I haven't slept with the door guy, the door guy's a
friend of mine. He's a perfectly good class of people and what part of Long _
Island are you from——Wimbledon?
I'm going back to my dorm.
Wait is this true
Yes.
Then I apologize, okay?
I have to go...
Erica
Yes.
I'm sorry and I mean it..
I appreciate that but—I have to study
You don't have to study. Let's just talk.
I can't.
Why?
Because it's expausting. Dating you is like dating a stairmaster.
All I meant is that you go to B.U. and so you're not likely to—~currently I wasnt making acoment on your appearance——I was saying you
go to B.U. I was stating a fact thats all.
I have to go study.
You don't have to study.
Why do you keep saying I dont have to study
Because you go to B.U.!
Do you want to get some food?
I'm sorry you're not sufficiently impressed with my education.
And I'm sorry I don't have a rowboat.
So were even.
I think we should just be friends.
I don't want to be friends.
I was being polite, I had no intention ofbeing friends with you.
Im under some pressure right now  from my OS class.
If we could just order some food. I think we should
Listen. You're going to be a very succesful computer person. But you're going to go through life
thinking that girls don't like you because you're a nerd. And I want
you to know, from the bottom of my heart,that that won't be true. It'll be because you're an asshole,
Erica Albrightls a bitch. You think
that's because her family changed their name from Albrecht or do you think it's because all B.U. girls are bitches?
For the record, she may look like a 34C but she's getting all kinds of help from our friends at Victoria's Secret. She's a 34B, as in barely anything there.False advertising.
The truth is she has a nice face. I need to think of something to help me take my mind off her.
Easy enough, except I need an idea.
I'm a little intoxicated, I'm not gonna lie.
So what if it's not even 10PM and it's a Tuesday night?
The Kirkland facehook is open on my desktop and some of these people have pretty horrendous facebook pics.
Billy Olson's sitting here
and had the idea of putting some of the pictures next to pictures of farm animals and have people vote on who's hotter.
Good call Mr.Olson
Yea, it's on. I'm not gonna do the farm animals but I like the idea of comparing two people together. It gives the whole thing a very Turing feel since people's ratings of the pictures will be more implicit than, say, choosing_a number to
represent each person's hotness like they do on hotornot.com.
The first thing we're going to need is a lot of pictures.
Unfortunately, Harvard doesn't keep a public centralized facebook so I'm going to have to get all the images from the individual houses that people are in.
Let
the hacking begin.
First up is Kirkland. They keep
everything open and allow indexes in their Apache configuration, so a little WGET magic is all that's necessary to ~download the entire Kirkland facebook.
Kids’ stuff.
Next is Elliot. They're also open but
with no indexes on Apache. I can run an empty search and it returns all of the images in the database in a single page.
Then I can save the page and Mozilla will save all the images for me.
Excellent.
Moving right along.
Lowell has some security. They require a username/password combo and I'm going to go ahead and say they don't have access
to main fas user database, so they have no way of detecting an intrusion
Adams has no security but limits the number of results  to 20 a page­
All I have to is breakput the same script I used on Lowell and its done
Quincy has no online Facebook what a sham.
There is nothing I can do about that
Dunster is intense. Not only is there no public directory but there's no directory at all
You have to do searches and if your search returns more then 20 matches nothing gets returned
Once you do get results they dont link directly to the images, they link to a php that redirects or something
Weird
This maybe diffucult i,ll come back later.
Leverett is a little better. Its a lenghty search but you can do an empty search and gets links to pages with a precceding picture
Its slightly obnoxious that they let you view one picture at a time
And theres no way I am gonna go to 500 hundred pages, to download pics 1 at a time.
So its definitely necessary to break out the emacs and modify that perl script.
Done
What's going on?
Perfect timing. Eduardo's here and he's going to have the key ingredient.
Mark
What up,
You and Erica split up?
How did you know that?
It's on your blog.
Oh yeah.
Are you alright?
I need you.
I'm here for you.
No, I need the algorithm you used for the oil futures.
Are you okay?
We're ranking girls.
You mean other STUDENTS
Yeah
You think that's such a good idea?
I need the algorithm?
Give each_gir1 a base rating of 1400. At any time "Girl A" has a rating R~a and
"Girl B" has e rating R-b.
When any two girls are matched up there's an expectation of which will win based on
their current rating.
Yeah
And Those expectations are expressed this way.
Let's write it.
The one on the left.
on the right.
the right.
Who should we send it to first?
Dwyer
Neal
Who are you gonna send it to?
Just a Couple of people. The question is, who are they gonna send it to‘?
Hey guys check this out
The one on the left.
These girls
Right or Left
Left
Thats my roommate.
ALL On the left.
This isnt funny
Right
Left
All night he blogged about you
You dont want to read this.
Erica is this yours.
I stole it from a train.
Get the hell out of here.
Thats an awful lot of traffic.
You think maybe we should shut it down before we get into trouble.
Hello
Wait you say
At 4 in the morning
Well there is an unusual amount of traffic which occured.
Your saying its unusal for 4 in the morning.
No this would be unusuall for half time at the superbowl.
Alright
I gotta go in.
Whats going on.
The Harvard network is about to crash.
You dont think.
I do.
God saves us everybody.
Cant connect.
The network.
Unless this a coincidence I would think this is us.
Its not a coincidence.
O shit.
So your called in front of the add board.
Thats not what happened.
You were'nt called in front of the administartive board.
No I was back at the bar with Erica Albright
She said all that.
She said all that.That I said that stuff to her.
I was reading from the transcript of her deposition.
Why wold you even need to depose her.
Thats really for us to decide.
You think if I know she could make me look like a jerk I'll be more likely to
Mark dont.
Why dont we stretch our legs for a minute, can we do that.
Its been almost 3 hours and frankly you did spend an awful lot of time embarassing Mr.Zuckerburg with the girls testimony from the bar.
I am not embarassed, she just made alot of that up.
She was under Oath.
I guess that would be the first time someone lied under oath
They got 2200 hits within 2 hours.
Thousands
What
22 Thousand
Those guys are really fast.
Is there anyway to make this a fair fight.
Jump out and swim.
We'd have to jump out and drown.
We are genectically identical we would stay in one place.
just row the damn boat.
You hear about this?
What
Two nightss ago, a sophomore choked the network with a laptop from kirkland.
At four am
He set up a website were we vote the hotness of female undergrads
What were we doing,that none of us heard about this
I do not know, 3 hour technical row before breakfast
full course load studying.
Another 3 hours in the tank then studying.
Im not sure how we missed it.
How much activity was on this thing.
Twenty-two thousand page requests.
Twenty-two thousand
This is half of facebook, 7 houses
He developed the site in 1 night and he did it while he was drunk.
Twenty-two thousand
How do you know he was drunk
He was blogging, while doing this.
Know what it think
Way ahead of you.
This is our guy.
Cameron Worth, WINKLEVOSS, Cameron spelt the usuall way.
Taylor WINKLEVOSS, Taylor spelt the usuall way. My last nameis the same as my brother
Mr. Zuckerberg, this is an Administrative board hearing.
Your being accused of intentionally breaching security Violating copyright, Violating individual privacy
By creating the website WWW.FACEMASH.COM
You also charged with being in  violation of universty policy on distribution of digitsed images.
Before we begin with our questioning, your allowed to make a statement, Would you like to do so?
Uh ... ... I have already apologised in the Crimson,to the AVHW
To"Harvard Latino Women's Association," and to any women at harvard who might have been insulted, as I take that they were'
As for any charges stemming from the breach of security
I believe I deserve some recognition from this board.
Im sorry
I dont understand.
Which part?
You deserve recognition.
I believe I pointed out some pretty gaping holes in your system.
Scuse me may I.
Mr. Zuckerberg. Im in charge of security for all computers on the  Harvard network.
I can assure you of its sophistication
In fact it was that level of sophistication, that led us to you in less then 4 hours.
- Four hours?
Yes sir.
That would be impressive except if youd known what you are looking for you would seen it written on my dorm room window.
So six months Academic probation.
Wow,they had to make an example out of you.
They have my blog
I should have written nothing about the farm animals,that was stupid.
I was kidding for gods sake doesnt anybody have a sense of humor
- I tried to stop you
- I know
How do you do this thing were you manage to get all girls to hate us
Why do I love China:
OK Lets look at a sample problem
Suppose were given a computer a 16 bit virtual address, and a page size of 256-bytes.
The System uses a one level page table that starts at address 0x0400
Maybe you want dna on your 16-bit system who knows.
The first few pages are reserved for the hardware flag etc..
assume page table ENTRIES HAVE 8 STATUS BITS
Eight-bit status code will then be ...
Ah I see we have our first surrender
Dont worry, Mr. Zuckerberg, brighter men then you have tried and failed this class
One valid bit, One modified bit, One reference bit, 5 permission bit
That is correct
Does evrybody see how he got there
Mark?
You Mark Zuckerberg ?
Yes
I'm  Calvin Winklebaum
HI
Taylor Winklebaum
You guys related?
Good, funny never heard that before.
What can I do for you?
Did I insult your girlfriends?
No, you did'nt
I dont know
We never asked
We should
NO
We have an idea we want to talk to you about?
Got a minute.
You guys Look like you guys spent some time at the gym.
We have to
why?
We row crew.
Yeah Ive gotta minute.
GREAT.
- Have you ever beeninside the PORCILE
NO.
We can not take you past the---- cause your not a member
That hurt.
- Sandwich or something?
- Uh OK
-  Mark right?
- Yes
- Mark, this is Di Weiya • Narendra, our partner
Hi
Were really impressed with"Facemash"
We checked you out., you also built"CourseMatch"
What is "CourseMatch"
You go online and see what courses your freinds are taking.
Really harmless.
- Mark?
- Yeah?
We were talking about "CourseMatch"
Kind of a no brainer.
you --- in high school to right?
Asked for an MP3 player, that recognises your taste in music.
Any body try to buy it?
Microsoft
How much?
Didnt sell it, I uploaded for free.
- For free?
- Yeah
Why?
OK well we have something we have been working on for a while idea. We think its great It is called "the Harvard network"
You can create your own page, interests, bios, freinds
Then people can go online and see your bio.
Requests ... ...
Yeah How is that different then  "My Space" and "Freindster"
Harvard. Edu
Were going to use the most prestigious e-mail in the country.
Based on the idea that girls ...
Girls want to only go out with guys who go to Harvard.
Me and my brother dont have trouble getting ...
Basically what were talking about is MYSPACE, FREINDSTER any of those other social networking sites.
Its exclusivity.
Right.
Yeah wed love for you to work with us Mark.
We need a programmer who is creative.
And we know who can take the initiative.
This could help rehabilitate your image.
Wow you would do that for me.
WE'd like to work with you.
Our first program  graduated and went to work for Google.
Our second programer is overwhelmed with school work.
We would need you to build the site, write thwe code we will provide ...
Im in
What
Awsome
Thats what you said?
It was three or four years ago, I dont know what I said.
When did you come to Eduardo?
I dont understand that question.
You remeber answering in the affirmative.
the affirmative.
When I did you come to Eduardo with the idea for Facebook.
It was called"TheFacebook"then.
This doesnt need to be that diffucult.
Im currently in the middle of two different lawsuits
Did you answer affirmatively?
When Taylor and Cameron Winklevoss Did in November ask you to build, "Harvard Connection,"
Did you say yes?
I said I'd help.
When did you approach Mr. Savarin with the idea for the FACEBOOK
I wouldnt say I approached him.
SY?
You can answer the question
At a party at ALPHA EPSILON PI.
Whats that
JewishFraternity
It was Caribbean  night.
Why are guys like me generally attracted to Asian girls
But  Asian girls are generally attracted to guys like me
I dont know if an algorithm could find the connection to you
Its not that complicated there hot, there smart, they are not Jewish, they cant dance.
Hey Mark is here!
Mark
I think ive come up with something
I have to tell you something your not going to believe
Come on
I got pinched by the "Phoenix Club"
Are you kidding?
Its the first in a 4 step process
Send the invitation on monday
My first puch party tommorow
You got pinched by the "Phoenix
What did you want to talk to me about.
Mark you said you come up with something.
Yeah Ive think I come up with something.Come outside.
20 degrees outside
I cant stair at that thing NIAGRA FALLS, it has nothing to do with the Carribean
People came to "Facemash"-----, right?
It wasnt because hey saw pictures of hot girls
You can go anywhere on the internet and see pictures of hot girls.
Because they saw pictures of girls that they knew.
People want to go on the internet ot check out their freinds so why not build a web site that offers them freinds, pictures, profiles
whatever you can visit just browse around, maybe someone you just met at a party
Im not talking aboput a dating site.
Im talking about taking the entire social experience of college.
And putting it online.
Cant feel my legs.
I know.
Im totally psyched about this to Eduardo.
"It would be exclusive."
You would have to know the people on the site to get past your own page like.
Getting pinched.
Thats good
Its like "Final Club", but were president/
I told him I thought it sounded great,
was a great idea
There was nothing to hack people were gonna provide their own pictures,their own information.
And people would have the ability to invite or not invite their freinds to join.
In a world were social strucrure was everything.
That was the thing.
It was a big project, and he was going to have to write 10s of thousands lines of code.
So I was wondering why he was coming to me and not his roomates.
Dustin Moscovitz, Chris Hughes they were programmers.
Were gonna need a little start up cash to rent a server to get it online.
So that was why.
Did he offer terms.
Well split it 70/30.
70 for me 30 for you for putting up the 1000 dollars and for handling everything on the business end.
Youe CFO
And you said.
I said, "lets do it"
OK did he add anything else?
YES
It probably was a diversity thing
So what.
Why you think he said that?
Gretchen, excuse me for interupting, whos discovery is this.
SY, if you let me continue with my line of questioning.
They are suggesting that I was jealous of jealous of Eduardo for getting punched by the PHOENIX
And began a plan to screw him out of a company that I had'nt even invent yet.
Were you.
Gretchen!
- Jealous of Eduardo?
Stop typing were all...
I know you've done your homework and know money is not a big part of my life.
But at the moment I could buy Mount Auburn street, take the PHOENIX club and turn it into my PING-PONG room.
I'll let you know how the party ends.
We recognise thatYour A plaintiff in one suit involving Facebook
And a witness in another.
Yes, sir
At any time in the weeks prior to Mark telling you his idea
Did he mention Tyler Winklevoss,Cameron Winklevoss,
Dedre revedra or HARVARD CONNECTION
Yes,
He said they asked him to work on their site.
But that he looked at what they had and decided it wasnt worth his time.
He said even his most pathetic freinds, knew about getting people interested
in the website
then these guys.
These guys means my clients
Yes
Yes he resented, Mark resented that
they your clients that he thought that he needed to rehabilitate his image after FACEMASH
Mark didnt want to rehabilitate anything with FACEMASH
Hacked into the Harvard computers, he blew his nose at the add-board.
He got alot of notoriety
FACEMASH did exactly what he wanted to do.
Were you aware that while Mr. Zuckerberg was buliding the"TheFacebook"
He was also communictaing wth the plaintiffs
Not at the time I wasnt
It really did not have much to do with the Winklevoss dating site
How would you know, you were'nt even there.
Were you aware that while  Mr. Zuckerberg was building the "TheFacebook"
He was leading the plaintiffs to believe he was building "the Harvard Connection
Conclusion not found in evidence
We are about to find this new evidence.
From Mark Zujerburg to Tyler Winklevoss November 30, 2003, I read over all the stuff you sent me RE: HARVARD CONNECTION
and it seems like it should'nt take to long to implement
so we can talk about it after I get all the basic functionality up tommorrow night
From Mark Zujerburg to Tyler Winklevoss December 1, 2003
sorry I was unreachable tonight
I just got about  3 of your missed calls, I was working on a problem then my system collapsed.
From Mark Zujerburg to Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss December 10, 2003
this week has  been pretty busy,between HARVARD, classes and work."
So I think its probably best to postpone the meeting.
Im also really busy tommorow
OK anybody else feel like there is somethin up with this guy
Tell him OK.
But we do have to make sure we all meet up before we go off for break.
I know, I know.
Yeah watch out.
Hey Mark...
I need a dedicated LINUX box
running APACHE with------backend
Its gonna cost a little more money.
How much more.
About 200 hundred more
Do we need it.
Its gotta handle the traffic.
Do it.
I already did.
Hey guess what
I made the secound cut.
Thats good.
You should be proud of that right there, dont worry if you dont make it any further.
I'll get out of here.
From Mark Zuckerburg to Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss
and Deidre Nreanada
Dec 15 2003
I have a CS problem set that I am just getting started with and it should be about 15 hours of coding so I'll be busy tommorow night.
I wont really be free to meet until next wednesday afternoon/
I have to cancel Wednesday afternoon.
I've basically been in the lab this whole time.
And I also wont be able to do staurday as I have to meet up with my parents.
As the plaque reads "John Harvard"
Founder of HARVARD UNIVERSITY
in 1638.
Some call this the statue of 3 lies.
What are the 3 lies?
MR.Dowd
3 lies, first.
Shit
Take yor pants off.
OH No
AH Mr.Sabourin
1 - Harvard was founded in 1636.
Not 1638
2 - Hravard was not founded by John Harvard.
3 - That is not John Harvard.
Who is it.
Freind of the scupture Daniel Chester.
Keep your jacket on.
39 days after Mr.Zucermans initial meeting with my clients.
And he still has'nt completed work on HARVARD CONNECTION.
But on Jan 11 2004
Mr.Zuckerburg registered the domain name the FACEBOOK, by network soloutions.
To the best of your Knowledge had he even begun work on HARVARD CONNECTION.
Not to my knowledge.
NO
Hey Cameron Im still a little sceptical that we have enough fuctionality in the site to really draw the attention
and to gain the criticla mass neccessary to get a site like this to run.
Will speak soon.
This is the 1st time he mentioned any problems.
Yes it was.
You sent 36 e-mails
To Mr.Zuckberg
And received 16 e-mails in return
And this is the 1st time he indicated he was not happy.
Thats correct.
he had 42 days to study our system and get out ahead ...
Do you see any of your code on Facebook,
Did I use any of your code?
You stole our whole godamn idea!
Fellas
- Hows dot com site used? - Can I continue with my deposition?
You know you really dont need a forensic team to get to the bottom of this
If you guys were the inventors of Facebook,
you invented FACEBOOK
I cant wait to stand over your shoulder and watch you write us a check
Bullshit
Lets continue
February 4, 2004 -
Mark?
There is a girl in your art history class
named Stephanie • Attis, do you happen to know if she has a boyfreind
Have you evr seen her with anyone?
and if not, do you happen to know if shes going to go?
Dustin
people do not walk around with a sign on them that says im
Mark
We were suppossed to meet at nine
slept with in?
have to add a feature
What?
Should have done it its really good
Clean and simple
What are you writing?
Realtionship status
interest
This is what drives life at college
are you having sex or are'nt you
Its like people take certain classes
sit where they sit
Do what they do ... want to have some center... you know
Thats what FACEBOOK is going to be about
their going to log on after all the cake and watermelon there is a chance
- Their actually Going to get laid?
Get girl
YES
Its really good
And that was it
Its ready
Yeah
right now
That was it
You made a masthead
Yeah
"Eduardo • Savarin, Co-Founder and C F O
You have no idea what thats going to mean to my father.
Sure I do.
Lets go online?
Right now
Get your laptop out
Why Why do you need my laptop
You got emails for everybody at the "Phoenix Club"
I dont know
Im not sure if tis going to be cool that I am doing this
Spam
This is not spam
No I know its not spam
If we send to our friends, its just gonna bounce around us dorks.
I have'nt got in yet
These guys know people.
and i need their e-mails
sure
Good
Give me the mailing list
"Jabberwock12 @ Harvard E-D-U."
- These guys ... Their
Literary genius's
Their obviouis Lewis Carroll's references•
Their not so bad
I'm just saying
Yeah your right
sites  live
Lets go get a drink and celebrate.
Im buying
Mark?
are you praying?
What ever happened Cole Porter and Irving • Berlin •
Valentine's Day genius their love songs
Good point,
cause Cole Porter and Irving • Berlin • never wrote any love songs
Honey you should put your laptop away
Looking for some people scanning the same link?
ACU
Look at this,,somehow
Im really hoping its a cat that looks like Hiler
I could never get enough of that
Here?
WHAT?
Hey what is wrong
Hey
Not now
Need 20 minutes
OK, I just want to let you know that Zuckerberg stole our website
• Mark Zuckerberg he stole our web site
Its been live for more then 36 hours
Mr. Hotchkiss
lawyer, from dad
Im here with my brother Tylor and business partner----
Welcome to the "TheFacebook"
"TheFacebook"
, is an online directory to connect with different social networks
Must have an Harvard .EDU adress to register
Thats right , yes sir
I called earlier. Im looking for Mark Zuckerberg
Yes, sir he actually quoted----
read it to you
Everyone is talking alot about
Universal FACEBOOK withing HARVARD
Meaning what
I think its knd of silly that it would take the universty a couple of years to get around to it
I can do a classier job then they can
and I gave
As of yesterday evening"Zuckerberg said that over 650 students registered to use the Facebook.com,
He said that he  anticipated 900 would join by this morning
Yes,he was just reading that 650 students signed up for it on the 1st day
God If I was a drug dealer, I could not give free drugs to  650 people in a day
This guy doesnt have 3 freinds to rub together
to make a fourth
Allright yes thts what well do Mr.Hotchkiss
well put it all together and well e-mail it to you
You wont be able to go on the web site yourself
Because you dont have a ... Harvard ...
You know it would just be easier for us to email it to you
Im sure You're right, he is a good guy and hes very bright and Im sure he didnt mean to...
WOW
What he did
Well thank you very much and dad...
Id like to
This is a good guy?
We dont know that hes not a good guy
We know he stole our idea
We know lied to our faces ...
for a month and a half ...
NO..He never lied to our face
OK he never saw our faces fine. he lied through our e-mail accounts
And he gave himself a  42 day head start
Because he knows and apparently you dont
Which is that getting there first is everything
Im a competitve racer dave I dont think you need to school me on the importance of getting there first
THANK-YOU
ALL RIGHT
That was your father's lawyer?
He is our counsel
He is going to look at all this and if he thinks its appropriate, hes going to send a cease and desist letter
Whats that gonna do
What you want to hire an IP  lawyer and sue him?
No, I want to hire the SOPRANOS to beat the shit out of him with a hammer
- We dont have to do that
Thats right
We can do that ourselves
I m 6.5 220 and theres 2 of us
Well whatever Im saying lets calm down until we know what were talking about
How much more information are you waiting for
We met with Mark 3 times, we exchanged 52 e-mails
we can prove that he looked at the code
What is that on the bottom of the page
Mark Zuckerberg production
On the home page?
On every page.
They wrote Zuckerberg said he hoped the privacy option would help restore his reputation following student out rage over Facemash.com outrage committed after
Exactly what we said to him
- Hes giving us the finger in the Crimson
While we are waiting for dads lawyer to look this stuff over we can get something going in the paper
NO
People know that this is in dispute
Were not starting a knife fight in the Crimson
Were not suing
Why not
Again Why not
Hes gonna say  stupid
Me?
Say it, why not?
Because we are gentlemen of Harvard
This is Harvard, were you dont plant stories, and you dont sue people
You thought he was goona be the only one that thought that was stupid?
During the time when you say you had this idea
Did you know Tylor and Cameron, came for a family of means?
A Family of means?
Did you know their father was wealthy?
I not sure why your asking me that
Its not important that you be sure why I am asking
Not important to you
CY
Did you know that they came from money?
I had no idea weather they came from money or not
In one of your lead ups Mr. Narendra, you refernced Howard Winklevoss consulting firm
If you say so
Howard Winklevoss founded a firm whose assets are in the hundreds of millions
You also knew Tyler and Cameron were members of the Harvard finals club called THE PERCILLE
You pointed that out
Excuse us for inviting you in
To the bike room
So its safe to say that you were aware that my clients had money
YES
Let me tell you why I am asking,
Im wondering why if you knew you needed a thousand dollars
for an internet venture you didnt ask my clients for
they had demnstrated an interest inthat kind of thing.
I asked my best friend for the money because thats who I wanted to be partners with
Eduardo was the President of the Harvard Investers Association, and he was also my best friend
Your best friendis suing you for  six hundred million dollars
I didnt know that tell me more
Eduardo,what happened after the initial launch?
Im Sorry CY, would you mind adrssing him as Mr. Savarin?
Gretchen their best freinds
Not anymore
We  already went through this never mind ...
Mr. Savarin, what happened after the initial launch
It exploded
Every body on Campus Facebook me has become a common expression
And ah Mark?
And Mark was the biggest thing on campus?
That included 19 Nobel laureates and 15 Pulitzer Prize winners
Two future Olympians,and a movie star
Who is the movie star?
Doesnt matter?
Mark
Your friend, is Mark Zuckerberg ?
Yeah
He made the"Facebook"?
Cool. I am a Christy, this is Alice
Nice to meet you
maybe we can go out get a drink
Yeah Certainly,
Because, first, she said on the Facebook to find her. The second is that we can all go out for a drink
This is so great
For 2 reasons
1 cause she likes FACEBOOK and the other
They want to have drinks later
Have you ever heard so many good things packed into one regular sized sentence
Excuse me,Mark?
Yeah
I am Stewart • Singer im in your OS class
SURE
Awsome job with the Facebook
Awsome
Thanks
I'm Bob
How are you doing?
You know, I can swear he was looking at you
When he said "the next Bill Gates could be right in this room
I doubt it
I showed up late I didnt even know who the speaker was
Bill Gates
Shit that makes sense
allright thanks guys
You want to walk
What were their names?
You hear what I just said?
What
I said its time to modify the site
What does that mean?
It means, its time for the web site generate revenue
I know  the word, I am asking is how you want to do it
- Advertising
NO
Well we got 4000 members
Because Facebook is a cool
And if we start selling pop-ups for Mountain Dew
Well I wasnt thinking mountain DEW Mountain Dew, but
but at some point I am talking as the business end of the company
We dont even know what it is yet
what it is
We dont know what it can be, We dont know what it will be,
We know that its cool
that is a priceless asset Im not giving up
So when will it be finished
It wont be finished
Thats the point, the way fashion never finishes
fashion
fashion is never finished
Your talking about fashion?
Really you
I m talking about the idea and Im saying that its never finished
OK they manage to make money selling pantsl
Mark, What is this?
A what
This
Its called a Cease and Desist letter?
What were their names
Who
the Girls
When did you get this?
About ten days ago,right after we launched the site.
Hey, the girls
What were their name?
It says the Winklevoss twins are saying that you stole their ideas
I find that to be a little more then mildly annoying
They find it to be intellectual property theft
Why didnt you show this to me?
It was adressed to me
Their saying we stole the Facebook
from David Neandra and the Winklvoss twins
I know what it says
Did we
Did we what
Dont screw around with me now
Look at me
The letter said we could face legal action
No, it says I could face legal action
This from a lawyer, Mark, they must feel they have some grounds
The Lawyer is their fathers house counsel
Do they have grounds?
The grounds are our thing is cool, and popular, and"Harvard Connection" is lame
Euardo I didnt use any of their code I promiise I didnt use anything
Look a guy who builds a nice chair doesnt owe money to everyone whos ever built a a chair
Look they came to me with an idea...I had a better one.
Why dont you show me this letter?
I didnt think it was a big deal
Is there something wrong
If theres ever anything wrong
You can  tell me
Im the guy that wants to help
This is our thing
Now is there anything you need to tell me?
No
What are we doing about this?
I went to 3L Student Legal Services, and they told me to write them back
And what did you say?
When we met in January, I expressed my doubts about the site.
were it stood with grpahics, how much programming was left that I had not anticipated.
lack of hardware , we had website use and promotion and the to go on to  successfuly launch the web site.
This is your first time to you raised any of those concerns right
I raised concerns before
BULLSHIT
that's all gentlemen
Im talking about the metting in January to which this letter is refering
Yeah
Let me rephrase this
You sent  my client sent 16 emails
The first 15, you didnt raise any concerns
Is that a question?
In the 16th email you raised concerns about site functionality
Were you leading them on for six weeks
No
Then why didnt you raise any of these concerns before ...
Its raining
Im sorry
It just started Raining
Mr. Zuckerberg, do I have your full attention
No
Do you think I deserve it?
What
Do you think I deserve your full attention
I had to swear an oath before I began this deposition and I dont want to perjure myself
so I have a legal obligation to say no
OK no
You dont think I deserve your attention
I think if your clients want to sit on my shoulders
and call themselves tall, they have a right to
but there is no requirement that I enjoy sitting here, listening to people lie.
You have part of my attention you have the minimum amount.
The rest of my attention is back at the offices of FACEBOOK
Were my colleagues and I are doing thing that no one in this room including and especially your clients
are intellectually or creatively capable of doing
Does that adequately answer your condascending question?
I have 12:45, why dont we say thats lunch
Back at Two thirty
So, What' were their names
Their names were Christie and Alice
And they want to have drinks tonight
Hey man sorry, a couple of girls are freshening up in there
OK
We GOT A QUICKIE
I'll be right back
Where are you going?
Erica?
Hi
I saw you from over there, I did'nt know you came to this pub
first time
Mine too, can I talk to you alone for a secound?
I think Im good right here
I just
I love to talk to you alone
If we could talk outside
Right here is fine
I dont know if you heard about this new website I launched?
No
The Facebook?
You called me bitch on the Internet, Mark
Thats why I wanted to talk to you
On the Internet
That is why I came over
Comparing women to farm animals?
I did'nt end up doing that
Did'nt stop you from writing it.
Its as if every thought that tumbles through your head is so clever
It would be a crime for it not to be shared
The internets not written in pencil Mark
Its  written in ink
And you published "Erika • Albright" is a bitch
Right before you made an ignorant crack about my families name
And Bra size,then rated women based on their flattness
Erica is there a problem
No theres no problem
You right your snyde bullshit in a dark room
because thats what you need now a days
It was nice to see you
Dont torture me for it
If we could just go somewhere for a minute
I do not want to be rude to my friends
OK
Good luck with your video games
Yeah that was great, that was the right thing to do you apologised right
We have to expand
Tommorow
Is he mad about something
OK we are expanding to to Yale and Columbia
Dustin, I want you to share the coding work with me Chris, you are in charge of publicity and outreach
and you can start by getting us a story in the BSU newspaper
The Bridge
They hate doing stories about Harvard
Somebody at the newspaper will be a computer science major tell him
Mark Zuckerberg will do ten hours of free programming
Why do you want a story in the BU newspaper?
Because I do
Now heres the arrangement
Eduardo is CFO, owns 30% of the company
Dustin is a vice president and head of programming ,and his 5% of the company will come from my end
Chris is director of publicity, and his compenstaion will depend on the amount of work he ends up doing
Any Questions?
Who are these girls?
Sorry, they are Christie and Alice
HI
HELLO
Is there anything  we can do
No
Nothing
Yale and Columbia
- And Stanford
What?
Stanford
It is time for them to see us from PAOLO ALTO
you dont want any lunch?
No
Your welcome to some salad,
No, thank you
This must be hard
Who are you
I'm Marilyn • Delpei,I introduced myself
I mean what do you do?
I am a secoud year associate at the firm
My boss wanted me to sit in on the deposition case
What are you doing?
Checking to see how its going in Bosnia
Bosnia
Ther are enough Road but they are on Facebook?
You must really hate the Winklevoss's?
I dont hate anybody
The Winklevai are suing me for intellectual property theft
Their suing me because for the first time in their lives
Things did'nt work ou the way they were supposed to for them
He is expanding
What?
Yale, Columbia and Stanford, its gonna be in the Cromson tommorow
Really
Yeah
Well it looked like the cease and desist order really scared the shit out of him huh
- I want to hire a lawyer to file for injuctif realeasing it, the site taken down now.
Every minute the site is up HARVARD CONNECTION becomes less valuable
I want an injuction I want damages I want punitive release
I want him dead
Yeah I want those thigns to
Then why are'nt we doing anything about it
Because we are a gentleman at Harvard?
Because your not thinking about how its gonna look
hows it gonna look
Like my brother and I are in skeleton costumes chasing the karate kid around a high school gym
Cam
He has violated Maasachusets state law
He goes to Connecticut, New York and to California he will have violated federal law
By the way hes in violation of Harvard law
Theres no such thing as HARVARD law
YEAH
HThere is
Harvard student hand book
Every freshman is issued one of these
Some where in this book it says you cant steal from another student
This is what we need
You cant get a meeting with Larry Summers
My brother and I we pay tuition at this school
We carry a 3.9 GPA
We won trophys for this school
and well be rowing in the Olympics for this school
I want a meeting with the godamn president of this school
Why STANFORD
Why do you think
Im late for BIO-CHEM
OK
You dont know my name do you
Is it Stanford
I should just kick your ass
How do you go to a party
Amelia Ritter
but you prefer Amy
Your from Olinda
Your fathers in commercial real estate and your mothers never sober
Whats my major
Trombone
really
I dont know theres something about a trombone
French
Your majors French
I dint have oneMine
I dont have one
Not picking a major?
I dont go to school
Your kidding
NO
Where did you go to school?
William Taft Elementary
For a little while
Seriously
Your not like 15 years old or anything are you?
Your not like 15 are you?
no
So what do you do?
I am an entrepreneur
Your unemployed
I would'nt say that
What would you say
That Im an entrepreneur
Well then what was your entrepreneur
Well I founded an Interent company that lets folks download and share music for free
Kind of like Napster?
Exactly like Napster?
What do you mean?
I founded Napster
Sean Parker founded Napster
Nice to meet you
Your Sean Parker?
UH HUH you see the shoes on the other.
foot
table
I just slept with Sean • Parker?
You just slept on Sean • Parker?
Your a billionaire
not technically
What are you
broke
Thers not a lot of money in free music and even less if your being sued by anyone whos won a grammy
This is blowing my mind
I appreciate that
I gotta hop in the shower and get ready for class
Even though your a french major whos name is amy
Im a hard worker
Theres juice theres anything else you can find, help yourself
Mind if I check my e-mail
Yeah go ahead
AMY
Can you come out here
Just a secound
There a snake in here, Amy
What?
Where
OK there is no snake but I need to ask you something
Are you kidding me I could have been killed
How
By
Running too fast
And getting twisted in the curtain
What do you need to ask me?
I went to check my e-mail and theres a website open on your computer
Yeah after you passed out last night I went on the Facebook for abit
Whats that?
The Facebook?
STANFORD'S had it for like 2 weeks now
Its really awsome, freakishly addictive
seriously Im on the thing like 5 times a day
Mind if I send myself an e-mail
Yeah is everything  okay
Everythings great
I just need to find you Mark Zuckerberg
Ever been in this building before
This buildings a hundred years older then the country its in.
So do be careful
Were sitting in chairs
YES
Very good
You can go in now
Catherine, Ive got students now,
students
undergrads
dont know,from the looks of it they want to sell me a Brooks Brothers suit
Good morning
Good morning, sir
I'm Cameron • Winklevoss, this is my brother Tyle
Are you here because?
I'm sorry sir, I thought you were reading the letter
read the letter
well
we came up with an idea for a website called "Harvard Connection"
we've since changed the name to CONNECTU
• and Mark Zuckerberg stole that idea and
I understand
and Im asking what you want me to do about it?
Well sir
In the HARVARD student handbook which is distributed to each freshman
Under the heading standars of conduct in the HARVARD comunity
it says the college expects all the students to be honest
and forthcoming in their dealings with members in the community
stundents are required to respect public and private ownership
and instances of theft, missappropriation
- Anne?
Yes sir?
punch me in the face, go ahead
or
or unauthorised use will result in
disciplinary action
including required withdrawl from the college
you memorised that instead of doing what
what my brother came and
I came here to ask you respectfully
Sir its against university rules to steal from other students
plain and simple
have you spoken to your housemaster
yes sir
and the housemaster made a recommendation to the AD BOARD but the ADBOARD wont hear us
have you tried dealing with the other student directly
Mr Zuckerburg hasnt been responding to any of our e-mails and phone calls for the last 2 weeks
he doesnt answer when we knock on his door at KIRKLAND
and the closest Ive come to dealing with him face to face
when I saw him on the quad and chased him through HARVARD SQUARE
chased him
I I I saw him and I know he saw me, I went after him
and he disapeaared
I dont see this as a universty issue
Of course its a a universty issue
theres a code of ethics and an honor code and he violated them both
you entered into a code of ethics with the university
im sorry president summersnot with each other
im sorry president summers what you just said makes no sense to me at all
Im devestated by that
What my brother means is
Mark Zuckerburg walked into our dorm room and stole our computer
that would be a universty issue
I dont know this office doent handle petty larceny
this isnt petty larceny
this idea is potentialy worth millions of dollars
millions
yes
you might just be letting your imaginations run away with you
sir
I honestly dont think your in any position to make that call
I was the US Treasury secretary
Im in some position to make that call
"Letting our imagnations run away with us "
Is exactly what we were told to do in your Freshaman address?
well then I would suggest that you let your imaginations
run away with you on a new project
you would
everyone at HARVARD is inventing something
HARVARD undergarduates believe that inventing a job is better then finding a job is better then finding a job
So I suggest again that the 2 of you come up with a new new project
I'm sorry, sir. But thats not the poin
Please
come right at the point
you dont have to be a intellectual property expert to understand the difference between right and wrong
your saying that I dont
of course I am not saying that sir
Im saying that
really
sir
Ann
how did I get this appointment
Colleagues of their father
Let me tell you something, Mr. Winkle Voss ,Mr WinkleVoss
since your on the subject of right and wrong
This action, this meeting
The 2 of you being here, is wrong
Its not worthy of Harvard,
Its not what Harvard saw in you
You dont get special treatment
We never asked ...
Wai ...Wai..start another project
Like were amking a diorama for a science fair
If you have a problem with that Mr WinkleVoss
We never asked for special treatment
The courts allways at your disposal
Is there anything else I can do for you
TY
Thank you very much for your time
OOPPPS
I broka a 335 year old door knob
Eduardo, spring break you and Mr Zuckerburg took a trip to Newe York
Yes
What was the purpose of the trip
Well as CFO
I set up some meetings with potential advertisers
who paid for the trip
It was paid for out of the thousand dollar account I set up a few months earlier
at this point your thousand dollars was the only money that had been put into the company
YES
How did you feel the meetings went
went terribly
why
Mark was asleep
I was not asleep
can I repharse my answer
I wish he was asleep
so were at 29 schools now with over 75000 members
People who go on the Facebook tend stay on  longer  then almost any other web site now heres the most impressive statistc
91% of the people who try it once come back, Now if you'll allow me
Excuse me one secound
What sound are you making, is that like a tick
Was'nt a tick
Was
Like throttle sound
Almost a gag reflex
What is this ... ...
There was 1 more meeting scheduled for the New York
YES
It was a dinner
It was setup through my girlfreind at the time
Would you say that Mark was excited about this meeting
YES
VERY
Their not gonna card us here right
Look around
Dont be embarrsed
Tell him their not gonna card us
their not gonna card us
Mark
Are you gonna talk about adds again
Unless your the BALLET THEATRE of HARTFORD, the purpose of business is to make a profit
It is'nt a  business yet
Thats tough.
Its not tough for me , Its my job
Never mind
25 minutes late
He started Napster, when he was 19
He can be late
He is not a God
What is he?
Hes 25 minutes late
I think your just jealous
I honestly was'nt jealous
I was nervous
why
I did'nt know him at all
But I had done a search and asked around and he
He struck me as a kind of an....
WILDCARD
WHAT
He crashed out of 2 pretty big Internet companies in spectacular fashion and hes got a reputation with drugs
He also founded the companies
We dont need him
Hes here
- Im Sean • Parker
How do you do
You must be Eduardo
and Christy, and Mark
Nice to meet you
You guys dont have anything in front of you
no
TORI
HeY, baby boy
Could you bring out somethngs,
The laquered pork with that ginger confit
Tuna tartar , and the lobster claws, that'll get us started
Christie
what do you like to drink
An Appletini
great
4 of those
From that point on it was a Shauathon
The question was what did you talk about
He took through his episode with NAPSTER
I did'nt want to spend my 20's as a professinal defender
Who knew that in the begining of 2003--
They tried to sell the company to pay the 35 million they said we owed in royalties but I guess to them that was a little like
Selling a stolen car to pay for the stolen gas
So we said screw it
and declared bankruptcy
You made a name for yourself
And you are dry
TORY
and then he went on to his secound business venture
which was an online rolodex that he got thrown out of by his equity
and I wanted to do it nicely, I put on a tie and shined my shoes, but nobody wanted to take orders from a kid
So let me tell you what happened to a 20 year old the top of the DOT-COM
Im not a psychiatrist
We got that on the record
Your not a psychiatrist, but what
a psychiatrist, would say that he was paranoid
They hired private detective who followed me day and night
There were targets for high priced escorts
I cant prove it but I know they tapped my phone
So I figured Im gonna trip you up whos done all this
Private behaviour is a relic of times gone by
and somehow,someway you've managed to live your life like the DALI LAMA but
but make shit up because
they dont want you they want your idea
and they want you to say thank you while
excuse me
wipe your chin and walk away
what happened to you
and delusional
YES
WHAT
There'll be payback in case  I bought down the record companies with NAPSTER and retribution for PLEXOR to
You did'nt bring down the record companies
Name 1
In court
YEAH
You want to buy TOWER RECORD Eduardo
He told story after story about
life in SILICON VALLEY, parties at STANFORD
down in LA freinds who become Millionaires--
but mostly how Mark had to he had to come to California...
and then he cut around to FACEBOOK
So tell me about your progress
well were in 29 schools now
we got over 75000 members
tell me about the strategy your using
OK
For intance we wanted BAYLOR in Texas but BAYLOR already had a social network on campus so
instead of going right after them we made a list of every school within a hundred miles
Put the FACEBOOK on those capuses first
Pretty soon all the BAYLOR kids were seeing their freinds on our site and we were in
Its called the little bighorn, its smart Mark
Thanks that was mine
Hey you know what settle an arguement for us
I say its time to start making money through the FACEBOOK
but Mark does'nt want to advertise
whos right
well neither of you yet
The FACEBOOK is cool thats what its got going for it
you dont want to ruin it with adds, because adds are'nt cool
Exactly
Its like your throwing the greatest party on campus
and someone saying its gotta be over by 11
you dont even know what the thing is yet
How big it can get, How far it can go
This is no time to put your chips down
A million dollars isnt cool, you know whats cool
YOU
A Billion dollars
It shut everybody up
and thats were your headed
a billion dollar evaluation
unless you take bad advice in which case you might as well have come up with a cahin of very succesful Yogurt shops
when you go fishing you can catch alot of fish
or you can catch a big fish
You ever walk into a den and see a picture of him standing next to 14 trout
No hes holding a 3000 pound marlin
YEP
Thats a good analogy
OK we all know that Marlins dont really wegh 300 pounds right
Have you seen the big ones up close
No I have'nt
But looking at the guy holding a Marlin the size of a RangeRover
that would be a really big fish and a very strong guy
I think you might be getting away from the point
I dont have a dog in this fight, I just came to say HI
He owned Mark after that dinner
He picked up the check and he told Mark that they would talk together soon
and he was gone,but not before he made his biggest contribution to the company
Drop the "THE"just FACEBOOK
Thats gotta be some kind of landspeed record for talking
You want to end the party at 11
Im trying to pay for the party
there wont be a party
unless its cool
Yeah sure lets drop the"THE"
I meant catching the Marlin instead of 14 trout
does'nt that sound good
If your a trout
Im going to enter this into the record, incorporation papers for FACEBOOK and their also  registered in Florida
why Florida
Well thats were my familiy lives
and ask the respondents to stipulate that the articles of incorporation state the ownership as follows
65% for Mark Zuckberg,30% for Edurdo Severin and 5% for Dustin Markovitz
I'll stipulate
and that was April13th 2004
You can Mark it
Do you have anything here
Yes thank-you
Mr.Saverin have you ever done anything that might be considered as legitimate grounds for termination
NO
You've never did anything to embarass the company or even seriously jeapordise it
You were accused of Animal cruelty
You were'nt
This is not happenning
Well I have here an article from the Crimson
JESUS CHRIST
I cant have this Eduardo
Oh come on man, this is bullshit it another club playing a prank
I'd gotten into the PHOENIX
as as part of my initiation I had to for 1 week carry with me at all times, and take care of a chicken
They identified you as 1 of the founders of FACEBOOK Jr Eduardo Severin
Im not the expert but I think torturing animals was bad for business
I did not torture the chicken,I dont torture chickens
are you crazy
no now settle down please
I have here an article from the CRIMSON
This is scathing
I was having dinner at the KIRKLAND dining hall, with Mark and I had the chicken with me, cause I had to have the chicken with me at all times
This is College
Somebody is going to have to answer for this
The dining hall was serving chicken for dinner, so I had to feed my chicken, so wha..I took little pieces of chicken and I gave it to the chicken
Someone must have seen cause the next thing I knew, I was accused of forced cannabilism
I did'nt know
you could'nt do that
I dealt with various animal rights groups
I dealt with the associate dean at the college
this was all resolved
Someone from the Fly or the Porc must have reported it, for all I know it was the WinkleVoss's
allright lets just forget about it
This is absurd
Im being accused of animal cruelty
next i'll be accused of necrophelia
It is better to be accused of necrophelia
Im gonna have to explain this to my father ,Im goonna have to explain this to everybody
what is happenning on that
I have my final coming up for "Post War and Contemporary Art" and I havent been to class
Im supposed to write about those 4 paintings
Thats a FACEBOOK PAGE
YEAH
I put it under an ALIAS
I posted the paintings and asked people to comment.
Every once in awhile I hop and stir the pot to get a good debate going,
Was Mr Zuckberg cheating on his final exam
I.d rather not answer that question
and why not
cause Im not suing him for cheating on his final exam
Thats not what freinds do
well you just told us he was cheating
OOPPS
You told your lawyer I was torturing animals
No he did'nt tell us about it at all our litigators are capable of finding a CRIMSON article
In fact when we raised the subject he defended you
SO
993 we are so close
OH yeah that remind me....
were gonna need more money
I aggree more servers..apps
Im interviewing 2 interns to come to PAULO ALTO and we are going to have to pay them something
sorry what
I already found a house for rent on a street 2 blocks from the STANFORD campus
its perfect and its gotta pool
When did you decide to go to Califrnia for the summer
You mean when did I actually decide
Somewhere in the middle of the Sean Parker variety hout
He was right California is the place we gotta be
What your Jed Clampett
What you got the Beverly Hill Billbillies in BRAZIL
What is your problem with Sean
He doesnt bring anything to the table
doesnt have money, Dustns a better programmer
Hes got connections
got connections to VC
If we need advertisers I have connections to VC
The real players and as someone whos just really embarrased the  company in a bad way
It was the WnkleVoss's Mark
Hang-on
hit refresh
150.000
150.000 members
Eduardo
Congratulations
You dont think it was strange that he was followed by private detectives
Who came up with nothing
enough to get him out of the company the drugs the girls
We dont know if any of thats true
Read about it
and I can read about you torturing birds, since when does reading about something...
dont eat other fish, the Marlins and the Trout
Whats he talking about
Im intervieing interns at 10 tommorow night in the CS lab
Get onboard with this man you know
I dont really know what else to say
Whats going on
They have 10 minutes to get root access to a python webserver, expose its SSL encryption then intercept all traffic over its secure port
Their hacking
All behind a PIX Firewall Emulator, butn heres the beauty
You know I did'nt understand anything you just said right
I do know that
So whats the beauty
every 10th line of code written they have to take a shot,
and hacking supposed to be stealth, so anytime the server detects an intrusion, the candidate responsible has to take a shot.
I also have a program running that has a pop-up window appear simultaneously on all 5 computers.
The last candidate to hit the window has to take a shot.
Plus every 3 minutes they all have to take a shot
can I ask what part of the interns job will they need to be able to do drunk
Your right a more relavant test would be seeing if they can keep a chicken alive for a week
That was mean
HERE
WHAT IS THIS
I opened a new acount and put 1800 dollars in it
will that get you through the summer
Welcome to FACEBOOK
18000 DOLLARS
Yes
In addition to the 1000 dollars you already put up
A total of 19,000 dollars then
YES
just checking your math on that
I got the same thing
May I continue
After expressing missgivings about Mr Zuckerburg taking the company and moving it to California
for the summer why did you put 18000 dollars in the account for his use
I figured we were partners
I wanted to be a team player
I figured Mark, Dustin and the new interns
could work on the site while I was generating advertiser interest in New York
But mostly I figured
how much could possibly go wrong in 3 months
OK ready
sounds like an eight
That was like a 2
Hes better then that
Im OK
YOU SURE
Thats the doorbell
I did'nt know we had a  doorbell
Andrew get the door
No hes wired in
Thats gonna cut into the security deposit
MARK
You live here
YEAH
We live right across the street, we saw the chimney come...
Was anbody hurt
you look
We live across the street
IM SHARON
This is my...Sharon she lives right across the street
I was helping her move out, we saw the chimney
Yeah we had a little accident by the pool
You came to California
You made the right choice
Im so sorry
No problem
I didnt know you were gonna
No wait
This house and this team are great exactly what it should be
Im Sean Parker
OH Hes wired in
Thats what Im talkin about
Wheres Eduardo
He got a Internship in New York
Eduardo did'nt come out
I was crashing there for a little bit while I am taking care of somethings. But shes done for the summer so shes back at her parents palce and Im homeless
You can crash at our place at PAULO ALTO
Allright
Whats your plan for the summer
Im sorry I was looking at the architecture
I asked what your plans were
honour school till the end of the summer
your date looks so familiar to me
she looks familiar to alot of people
what do you mean
wants to buy his wife some lingerie
but hes to embarased to shop for it in a department store
comes up with an idea for a high end place that doesnt make you feel like a pervert.
He gets a 40.000 dolar bank loan borrows another 40.00 thosand from his inlaws
Opens a store and calls it VICTORIA SECRET
Makes half million dollars the first year
So the guy opens 3 more stores and after 5 years he sells the compant to leslie wester unlimited for 4 million dollars
Happy ending right
2 years later the company is worth 500 million dollars and Roy Raymond jumps off the Golden Gate bridge
Was that a parable
I date Victoria Secret models thats why shen looks familiar to you
Dont be impressed wth all this I read your Blog
You know why I started NAPSTER
The girl loved in High School was with the co-captain of the varsity lacross team
and I wanted to take her from him
So I decided to come up with the next big thing
I didnt know that
NAPSTER wasnt a failure I changed the music industry for better and for allways
It may not have been good business and it pissed alot of people off
and isnt that what your FACEMASH was about
Their sacred of me pal and their gonna be sacred of you
and their gonna say good idea kid grown-ups are gonna take it from here
but not this time this is our time
This time you goona hand over a business card that says Im CEO Bitch
Thats what I want from you
So were the hell is Eduardo
hes in New York
sucking up to Ad Execs
hes got a Internship
The companies here, a billion dollar companies here
Do you ever read FACEBOOK
I know you do
Eduardo maybe a business manager and for all I know he'll be a good one but
He shoud'nt be in New York kissing Madison Avenues ass
This is a once in a generation holy shit idea
and the water under the Golden Gate is freezing cold
look at my face and tell me I dont know what Im talking about
you ever think about that girl
what girl
the the girl from high school..the lacross thing
no
All you got is till the end of the summer
tell you what you get into honour school I'll put you on 2 continents
You dont have a place to crash Ithink you shouls definitely come live with us
lets line up some shots
excuse me
can you take this away and bring back the 1922
absoloutely Mr.Parker
TYLER
Oh and this is my brother Cameron
His Royal highness Prince Albert,
Your highness this is Taylor and Cameron WinkleVoss
of course brilliant race
Ive never seen a race that close
my grandfather Jack Kelly was one of the premiere rowers
Ive been coming to HENLEY for 30 years and Ive never seen a race that close
have you have you seen a race that close
mile and a half races are more commonly won by a boat length or two
yes thats absloutely right
brutally close
may I introduce my team...
Im sorry you haver to excuse us
we flew all the way out here to do that
would'nt of missed it brother
hows the royalty
Ah he just wanted to tell me a couple of times how close the race was
brutally, brutally excruciating
Cam the guys the prince of a country the size of NANTUCKET,relax
Mr.WinkleVoss
That was a tough beat
Im sorry dad you and Mom had to fly all this way to see this
No son dont apologise to me for loosing a race like that
I'd never  apologise to anyone for loosing a race like that
Mister Kenright
Dad this Mister Kenright part of our host family this week
Pleasuer to meet you, Pleasure to meet you
I had a chat with my daughter
she told me that she and her freinds allready talking about the race
which they've just seen  via their computers.
A new website called FACEBOOK,
do you have this in America
Im gonna find your mother
did I do something wrong
your daughter does'nt go to school in the states
No.No cambridge majoring in french literature,
though I was'nt aware there was such a thing
they have FACEBOOK at CAMBRIDGE
And apparently OXFORD and the london school of economics
for the present
good race boys live to fight another day
somebody watch my stuff
going online are we
I want to see it
What are you doing
Knock it off
I dont mind that we lost to the Dutch by less then a secound
that was a good race
and that was a fair race, that was good race
what I mind and you should mind
showing up on Monday for a race that was run on Sunday
We tried talking to him ourselves,
we tried writing a letter, we'd tried the add board, and we tried talking to the president of the uniiversity
Now I am asking you
for the last time
Lets take the considerable resources at our disposal and sew him in Federal court
Come on
I need a real drink
screw it
Lets gut the friggin nerd
but check it out, I saw him today
Manningham, Mitchel Manningham
Are you guys the WALLHACKS or Aimbots
We dont know were just shooting at each other
Use the kamikaze
like we know what that is
I saw him getting into his Turbo Carrera and he saw me to
I know he did
Dont frank I want to go on-line
Does anybody here that banging
You dont hear anything your writing code
hey somebody's at the door
Im gonnna call you back
Whats up
Mark was supposed tto pick me up at the airport an hour ago, Ive been calling his cell
He was on a 36 hour coding tear so he took a nap for a few hours
what happened here
Not happened, happening
Next big thing
Eduardo
Hey man  Back to work
Sorry about it, its the more wasted I get
I meant the more....
we understand
how old are they sean
Its not polite to ask
sean how old are they
you think you know me right
i've read enough
you know how much i've read about you
Eduardo
i waited an hour for you from the airport
what time is it
midnight, it was 3am in New York where I just came from
you got to see some of the new stuff we got
Dustin show him the wall, I'm just calling it the wall
forget about the wall, tell him about the meeting I got setup
You know Peter Thiel
NOPE
No reason you should he runs funded a 2 billion dollar hedge fund called CLARIUM CAPITAL.
Whys he setting up meetings for you
Thiel may want to make an angel investment
I dont care if hes an actual angel, why is he setting up business meetings
You've had a long flight
No I had a long wait at Tarmac at JFK, then a long wait at the passenger loading and unloading zone at SFO,
and in between there was a log flight
Im the business end of this company
and he is a house guest living here rent fre
with a very generous grant from the Eduardo Severin Foundation
I heard about your big ticket add buys "Jerry's Tuxedos"
hey man
HARVARD BARTENDING course, Your just one small step away from bagging snookies Cookies, yeah I can feel it
can I talk to you alone for a minute
sure
UH Bong hit
Im so high
Hows it going, Hows the internship, Hows Christy
Hows the internship
Mark jesus I quit the internship we talked abou this on the phone, were you even...I quit on my first day
I do rememebr you saying that
YEAH
Christy's crazy
That can be fun
NO
Psychotic, shes insanely jealous, shes irrational
and Im frightened of her
still its nice you have a girlfreind
I do not want that guy
representing himself as part of this company
You got move out here WARDO this is where it all happening
did you here what I just said
the connections the energy
MARK, MARK
Im afraid if you dont come out here your going to be left behind
I want I want I mean you
what did you just say
Its growing faster then any of us imagined it be
Its moving fast and Sean thinks that we should...
Sean's not part of this company
We have over 300 thousand memebers were in 160 schools
Im aware
including 5 in Europe
Im aware of that MARK
MARK IM THE CFO
We need more programmers and we need more money and he setup the THIEL meeting
Hes setup meetings all over town
setup other meetings
YES
Wthout me knowing anuthing about it
Your in New York
Im in in New York riding subways 14 hours a day try explaining that to me
Yeah and hows it going so far
what did you mean get left behind
I'd like to freeze this bank account and cancel all existing checks and lines of credit
May I see some ID please
YEAH SURE
Sean he'll be right wth you
You know this where they filmed TOWERING INFERNO
Hey guys come on back
Did she offer you some water
Oh yeah were cool
you must be Mark
We took a look at everything and congratulations
were gonna start you off with a 500 thousand dollar invest ment
Maurice is going to talk to you about some corporate restructurng
Well file as a corporation in DELEWARE
We've come up with a sound structure that will allow us to invest
Now let me ask you something
Whos Eduardo Severin
When did you get back
You scared me, I need you to knock
I got back this afternoon
and when were you gonna call me
JESUS it was kind of a bad trip
and I was tired
or answer 1 of my 47 texts, did you know I sent 47 texts
I did and I thought that was incredibly normal behaviour
are you mocking me
I bought you a present
Why does your status say single on your FACEBOOK page
Why does your relationship status say single on your FACEBOOK page
I was single when I set up the page
and you never bothered to change it
what
I dont know
do I look stupid to you
no calm down
Your asking me to believe that the CFO of FACEBOOK does'nt know how to change his relationship status on FACEBOOK
a little embarassing
You should take it as a sign of trust that I would tell you that
GO TO HELL
TAKE IT EASY
You did'nt change ot so you could SCREW those little SILICON VALLET SLUTS
thats not even remotely true and I can promise you that the SILICON VALLEY SLUTS dont care about anybodys relationship status on FACEBOOK
please open your present
YOUR PHONE DOES WORK
its Mark
UH open you present
Its a scarf
have you ever seenme wear a  scarf
This'll be your first
YEAH
You froze our accounts
I did
You froze the accounts
I had to get you attention Mark
Do you realise that you jeapordised the entire company do you realise that your actions could have permanetly destroyed everything I've been working on
WE'VE HAVE BEEN WORKING ON
Without money the site cant function
OK let me tell you the difference between FACEBOOK and everone else
We dont crash ever
If the servers are down for even a day our reputation is irreversibly destroyed
LOOK
Even a  few people leaving  would reverberate, through the whole user database The users are interconnected thats the whole point
College kids are line cause their freinds are online and if one domino goes the other domino goes dont you get that
I am not going back to the Carribean night of 85
HOLY SHIT
WHATS WRONG WITH YOU
did you like being nobody, Did you like being a joke, You want to go back to that
Hang on
That was the act of a child not a businessman
certainly not the act of a freind
You know how embarssed I was to cash a check today I am not going back to that life
Yeah
Maybe you were frustrated
maybe you were angry
I was
I am wiiling to let bygones be bygones cause Eduardo I've got some good news
Im sorry I was angry and maybe it was childish
But i had to get your attention
I said I've got some good news
What is it
Peter Thiel has made an ANGEL INVESTMENT OF HALF A MILLION DOLLARS
HALF A MILLION DOLLARS
and hes setting us up in an office
They want to re-incorporate the company
They want to meet you they need your signature on some documents, you got get your ass on the first flight back to San Francisco, I need my CFO
Im on my way
Eduardo
YEAH
WE DID IT
Eduardo
Your going back there already
and also Im breaking up with you
4 documents the first 2 are comon stoc agrrement purchases allowing you to buy stock in the newly re-incorporated FACEBOOK instead of the old shares which are now worthless
the third is an exchange agreement allowing you to exchange old shares for new shares
and finally the voter holing aggreement
how many shares of stock will own
1,328,334
that represents 34.4% ownership share
why the increase from the original 30%
because you may dilute to award shares to new investors
I love working with business majors dont you
You should know that Mark has already taken his 60 down to 51
Well Mark does'nt care about the money and he needs to be protected
Dustin Markowitz down to 6.81% Sean Parker 6.47%
I can live with that
and Peter Thiel 7%
like to use my pen
Eduardo
can you please repeat the question
no it was an outrageously leading question the first time and now you want hear it twice
yes will you read it back please
go ahead
COUNSEL and were you aware that when you were signing these documents that you were signing your own death certificate
it was insanely stupid of me not to have lawyers look at all this stuff
In all honesty I thought they were my Lawyers
I was your only freind
you had one freind
my father wont even look at me
OK Eduardo did Mr Zuckerburg say anything to you after you had signed the papers
there was alot of hand shaking alot of congratualtions
He already told me that he would'nt be coming back to school for at least a semester
we were saying good bye for awhile
before I left he said you gotta come back
some time around the end of November, early December
Peter wants to throw as an amazing partywhen we hit a million members, its gonna be out of control you gotts come back for it
million members
remember the algorythm
on the window at KIRKLAND
yeah i'll there
sure about this
your 20 minutes late
Yur gonna walk in there say you overslept and you did'nt have time to get dressed
Their gonna pitch you case equities theirn gonna pitch you, Their gonna beg you take their money
Your gonna nod your gonna nod
and then your gonna say which one of you is David Roth no not Roth Manningham.
which one of is Mitchel Manningham and he'll say I am
and you say
Sean Parker says FUCK YOU
In late November I got the e-mail from Mark telling me to come out to the late million member party party
what else did the e-mail say
it said that we had to have a business meeting
that Mark and Sean had played some kind of revenge stunt on CASE EQUITY
and Manningham was so impressed that he was now making an investment offer that was hard to pin down
so i went to California and I went straight to the new offices
i did'nt know weather to dress for the party or the business meeting
so i kinda dressed for both
but it did'nt matter
why not
because i was'nt called out there for either one
what were you called out there for
an ambush
Mr Severin please
at first i thought he was joking
giving more contrcts  to sign
but then I started reading
well as you know we had some new investors that...
what is this
MARK
hes wired in
how about now are you still wired in
you issued 24 million new shares of stock
you were told that if new Investors came along
how much were your shares diluted, how much were his
what were Mr.Zuckerbergs shares dilutes down to
it wasnt
what were Mr Moscovtz's shares shares dilutes down to
what were Sean Parkers shares shares dilutes down to
it wasnt
what were Peters Thiels shares shares dilutes down to
and what were your ownership  shares diluted down to
.03 percent
you signed the papers
you set me up
your gonna blame cause you were the business head of the company and you made a bad business deal with your own company
its gonna be like im not a part of FACEBOOK
wont be like your not a part of  FACEBOOK, your not a prt of FACEBOOK
my names on the MASTHEAD
you may want to check again
cause I froze the account
you think we were gonna let you parade around in your ridiculous suit and pretending you were running this company
sorry my PRADAS at the cleaners
along with my hoodie and fuck-you flip flops
you pretensious douche bag
securty's here you'll be leaving now
im not signing those papers
well get your signature
tell me this is'nt about me getting into the PHOENIX
i knew you did it,you planted that story about the chicken
i did'nt plant that story about the chicken
whats he talking about
you had me accused of animal cruelty
seriously what the hells the chicken
what you hated most was that they identified me as a co-founder of FACEBOOK
which i am
you better lawyer up ASSHOLE
cause im not coming back for 30%, im coming back for everything
hang on
i almost forgot
heres your 19 thousand dollars i would'nt cash it though I drew it on the account you froze
i like sitting next to you Sean
it makes me look so tough
thats it thats our show for tonight people
i want to see everybody here geared up for a party were going to walk into that club
like its MACYs Thanksgiving days parade, Mackie put it up on the screen,we've gotta almost be there
you allright
you were kinda rough with him
thats life in the NFL
you know you did'nt have to be that rough on him
im putting together a party
SEAN
you did'nt have to be that rough on him
he almost killed it
i'll send flowers
speaking of flowers i'm putting together a party after
CAPPA PHI BETA
Ashleys over there
Ashley
i know who she is
are you guys
Ashley and me no
i wont go to the party
why
excuse me Mark
we were just talking about you
your doing a really good job
thanks i appreciate that
these came in for you
put it on my desk
whats the package
nothing
MACKIE
YES SIR
REFRESH
you gotta hugger
i know
1 million
transformative , picture sharing application, a place where you view pictures that coincide with your social life
it is the true, the elevation of life
you go throught the party with a digital camera and your freinds re-live the party on-line
and tagging the idea
would it be easier without the bra
i spend hours watching people on while they check their freinds status update
they can see when their freinds change their profile change their photos and mostly
we lived on farms. and now we live in cities and now were going to live on the interent
i think i hear my mother
its the cops
good to see you officer what can i do for you
whats going on
was the music to loud we wre having a converstion
miss i need you to button your blouse
i can tell them to turn the music down
not mine
OK were going to need identification
keep your hands were we can see them
you got anything else in your pockets i should know about...NO NO SIR
DONT BE STUPID NOW...i dont i dont
whats this
an inhaler pump
and this...its an inhaler
how old are you
im 21
lying makes it worse
im sorry i should'nt have lied
listen something has happened
its allright were gonna be alright
i've posted bond i was'nt doing anything, i mean i got allergies
intern
it was just a party
this is gonna be news Sean, its gonna be online
i know
you know with an underage intern
its cool i have it under control
its cool i have it under contro
i will get it under control
i will call them and see what our next move is
you dont think Eduardo was involved do you
you think......NO
or Mannie one of them..somebody somebody sent the coke cause it got in there
you believe me
im sorry
go home Sean
Mark
were done for the day
yeah i was just---
what happened to Sean
he still owns 7% of the company
he still all you hd all day was that salad you want get something to eat
I cant
im not a bad guy
i know that
in emotinal testimony i assume 85% of it is exageration
and the other 15
perjury
creations the work mostly of the devil
what happens now
CY and the others are having a steak on university avenue
then they'll come back to the office and work on a settlement deal without you
their gonna settle...OH YEAH
AND YOUR GONNA HAVE TO PAY A LITTLE EXTRA
why
so these guys sign a non-disclosure aggrement, they say 1 unflatering thing and your going to jail
i invented FACEBOOK
im talking about a jury
i speialise in voire-dire jury selection
what a jury sees when they look at a defendant
clothes, hair speaking style likability
ive licenced to pratice law for all of 20 months
and i could get a jury to believe you planted the story about Euardo and the chicken
watch what else
why were'nt you at Seans sororty party that night
you think im the one who called the police on him
it does'nt matter
i asked the question and now everybody is thinking about it
you've lost your jury in the first 10 minutes
i was drunk and angry and stupid
and bloging
pay them
in the scheme of things just pay your ticket
thats a status update
you think anybody would mind if i stayed and used the computer for a minute
i dont think that would be a problem
i appreciate your help today
your not an asshole MARK
YOUR JUST TRYING SO HARD TO BE
www.moviesubtitles.org