Money is a public good.
Like water, then?
Exactly.
The white city ofAlgiers.
When Mireille abandons Pépé le Moko.
How about us?
When, yet again,
we have abandoned Africa.
Constance, you had no choice.
We know that, going south,
degrees of latitude become negative.
So we go north,
dear soul, dear friend.
You still have the watch, Godmother.
No more crimes and blood.
No more Kigali.
Hooray forvacation.
Uncle Mathias, why did you say
this watch is worth a fortune?
It doesn't even tell time.
THINGS
Henri Déricourt.
Just a second. That I know.
Right.
But Richard Christmann, I don't know.
I know they started the fire,
but never mind, it's him.
Okay, war is war,
but a crime is still a crime.
Keep checking for Alice, please.
Two M's, one N.
We're far from Byzantium, you know.
What is opening up before us
resembles an impossible story.
We're facing a sort ofzero.
I once encountered nothingness.
Well, it's a lot thinner than you think.
Jaffa, 1 948.
LIKE THIS
You're absolutely right.
I don't love any people.
Not the French,
not the North Americans,
not the Germans.
Not theJewish people,
not the black people.
With her slit eyes.
I love only my friends —
The shape ofa dollar bill.
when there are any.
CinemaScope.
Nothing else.
- Plan on staying in Haifa?
- 16:9, Uncle.
Hey, kid!
Where'd you steal that watch?
Give it to me, or I'll turn you in.
No, it's mine.
So you speak German!
You can do me a favor, my boy.
And you're educated, to boot!
What a piece of work, that Ludovic!
Who told you my name?
I know everything.
Mr. Obersturmbannführer Goldberg.
What did you do in Avenue Foch in 1 943?
Get lost, you rotten kid.
Any movement on a planar surface
not dictated by physical necessity
is a spatial form ofself-assertion,
whether it involves
empire-building or tourism.
Anybody can act as if God didn't exist,
but what has changed today
is that the bastards are sincere.
THINGS LIKE THIS
A-L-I-S-S-A.
Stop being wary ofeverything.
I'm thinking about what Ludo told us.
Okay. Like what?
The old man with the young girl.
I saw them talking to the captain.
Okay. So?
So?
The name ofthe company's
main shareholder—
Goldberg.
"Gold mountain."
Yes.
And the old man's name.
Okay.
Abandon ship,
abandon ship, abandon ship.
Quiet, Alissa. Quiet!
Meow. That's what the ancient
Egyptians called their cats.
You trouble me with each ofyour words.
Be silent, Alissa.
"Repent not ofthy confidence."
... waves of Allied bombers
crushed the Third Reich.
The Luftwaffe tried to regain the advantage
with a terrifying new tactic.
German pilots would crash
their planes into enemy bombers.
Did you know
that kamikaze inJapanese
means divine wind?
Of course.
In October 1 943, the Russian forces
pushed the Germans back.
Major Kamenskaya.
I'm a friend of your godmother,
Alexandra Irinivna.
Yes, exactly.
The former Moscow chief of judicial police.
I've read a number of books
on what she —
on what she wrote, so —
We have to talk.
Excuse me?
And you plan on staying in Haifa?
I came to take a look.
They say there's a right of return,
but for me it'sjust one way for now.
What exactly do you study at Stanford?
I lead a seminar:
Monetary creation and literary creation.
You see, even today,
what we wonder about in Moscow —
'35.
There will come a time...
- '36.
- when everybody will know why—
The Spanish Civil War.
forwhat purpose,
there is all this suffering,
- and there will be no more mysteries.
- The republicans asked the Comintern
to move the gold in the Bank of Spain
out of the country.
We must work.
The France-Navigation Company.
That's right.
- The bands are playing so gaily—
- When it reached Odessa,
- a third or a quarter of it had disappeared.
- Oh, my God!
And another third in Moscow.
...and we shall depart forever,
we shall be forgotten.
I have my theory about the first third.
For the last third,
we'll have to dig deep
into the communist archives.
...and people will remember
with kindly words...
and bless those who are living now.
Oh, dear sisters,
our life is not yet at an end.
Let us live.
Willi Münzenberg.
The music is so gay, sojoyful,
and it seems like in a little while
we shall know why we are living.
Aren't you going to tell me about Darlan?
Who was Darlan?
Do I have to answer?
Who was he?
...General Pétain,
on the German side...
...the Allied invasion of North Africa
and at that moment, Churchill,
he resisted...
At that moment, he resisted, didn't he?
Want my opinion?
AIDS is only a tool for killing
all the blacks on the continent.
I wasjust thinking.
Light exists because of what?
Because of darkness.
LIKE THIS
Ladies and gentlemen,join us
at the Berlino bar on Deck 5 at 6:45 p.m. —
Ofcourse, money was invented
so that people wouldn't have to
look one another in the eyes.
Minimum prize is 500 euros.
So we come back to zero, mister.
Luckily the Arabs invented it.
They don't even get royalties.
Ofcourse, negative numbers
came from the Indies
and stopped off a few years in Arabia,
on the way to Italy.
Fibonacci used them first.
When the British left Israel,
what exactly did you do
with the gold of the Bank of Palestine?
THINGS LIKE THIS
They always say that you can
only compare what is comparable.
In fact,
we can only compare
what is incomparable,
not comparable.
That's over and done with.
Stalin.
Hitler.
Your playacting is useless.
Stop it.
I've also learned to collaborate
with the French.
Say,
I'll teach you something
about Napoléon.
During the burning of Moscow,
he signed the decree establishing
the Comédie-Française.
I do not understand.
To understand, Herr Goldberg,
that is difficult.
I don't give a damn about the fact
that you pinched Spanish gold.
I just have to find the rest.
You no longer need to fear Moscow.
My only real job, Herr Krivitzky —
That'sjust fine, Major.
My grandmother used to say that
at the drop of a hat.
I don't want to die...
before I've seen Europe happy again...
and the words Russia and Happiness...
attached like two belt buckles.
Excuse me, friend. Excuse me.
May I askyou a question?
Still, Naples I can understand.
But Alexandria, Haifa, Odessa,
to go from Algiers to Barcelona?
Take it easy, Constance. Let's not —
Don't tell anyone.
Silence is golden.
"Islam is the West of the East."
Rudyard Kipling.
Let's go.
Once,
in 1 942,
I encountered nothingness.
Well, it's a lot thinner than you think.
Casablanca, Algiers, Cairo.
AJew.
Yes, they told me.
My parents did.
So what?
Saying it is never enough.
THINGS
... geometry as origin.
The origin being always
what we come back to,
we have been witnessing
in the past few decades,
notably in mathematics,
a return to geometry.
The idea, then, is not that geometry
must return to its origin,
but rather that we ourselves
must return to geometry as an origin
- and be part of a return —
- ...the opportunity for free time
- to do all your shopping.
- ...to geometry.
Poor things,
the only thing they own
is the name we impose on them.
There's nothing
more convenient than a text.
We only have books to put in books,
but when we must put reality in a book,
and looking below the surface,
we must put reality in reality.
I Turned Away So as Not to See
"Geometry,
which remains as topical as ever.
And even as it develops,
remaining throughout
all its new forms,
Geometry."
Husserl capitalizes Geometry.
Geometry.
"In all configurations,
Geometry."
This I cannot accept.
Not as fact.
I'll talk about it this evening.
I have to work.
Mademoiselle Alissa.
STRAIT IS THE GATE
They continued for a while to whisper...
so that the young girl
would not overhear them,
but the precaution was needless:
she was in deep conversation
with her own thoughts.
As the whole of these parts,
where the sum of these parts,
at a given moment,
denies — as each contains the whole —
the parts we are considering;
as much as this part denies them,
as the sum of the parts,
again becoming the whole,
becomes the whole of the linked parts.
I'll train those two!
Dialectical thinking is first of all,
in the same movement,
the study of a reality
inasmuch as it is part of a whole,
inasmuch as it denies this whole,
and inasmuch as this whole contains it,
conditions it and denies it,
inasmuch as, consequently,
it is at once positive and negative
in relationship to the whole,
inasmuch as its movement
must be a destructive
and conservative movement
in relation to the whole.
The photograph of a land
and its people, at last.
Doctor Hamjiri.
Welcome, welcome.
Elias.
Listen.
After Arago admitted Daguerre
into the Academy of Sciences,
a mainly British armada —
hence well before
Lord Balfour's declaration —
rushed into Palestine.
Here is one of the earliest
photographs of Haifa Bay.
Where are you now, O you beloved land?
Lord God, Lamb of God, Son of the Father,
you who take away the sins of the world —
It's all right.
You're going back to Moscow.
The devil! He turned out to be dead!
You only had to wait for us.
So then, Otto Goldberg,
Leopold Krivitzky
and even Moses Schmuke,
according to the passports.
But you pronounce Richard Christmann.
The French knew him well, since
he worked for German counterespionage
and their own.
Started in the Foreign Legion after Spain,
then in the Resistance networks
in occupied Paris for the Abwehr.
After the German defeat,
he continued to be part of the remains
of the Gehlen organization,
Major Giske, the Algerian FLN.
He ended up in Tunis as a representative
for Bayer and Rhône-Poulenc.
Several terrorist attacks.
Acquitted twice.
Like Henri Déricourt.
MARKUS, GERMAN SPY
No, that's another story.
War criminal, maybe not,
but torturer.
But you know that, Lieutenant Delmas.
Alice Simmonet.
How do you know that?
Roger Faligot's book.
The NKVD archives.
That would explain why only two-thirds
of the Spanish gold reached Odessa,
but not why Moscow
also received only a third.
The Museum of  Man network.
Germaine Tillion.
Alice.
Mr. Fontes.
"The mind borrows from matter the perceptions
from which it draws its nourishment."
"The mind" —
"The mind borrows from matter the perceptions
from which it draws its nourishment."
- "...and restores them" — Read the whole line.
- Sure!
"The mind borrows from matter the perceptions
from which it draws its nourishment
and restores them to matter
in the form of movement
on which it has stamped
its own freedom."
This poor Europe.
Not purified,
but corrupted by suffering.
Not glorified, but humiliated
by recaptured liberty.
Imagine a desert.
Imagine a concert
That hasn't been written
Imagine
Imagine a light
That later
Without you, I am —
Nothing and everything!
Did you hear?
They did away with tax havens.
So what will we do?
We'll remain in hell.
Italy has taken up too much
of our attention in the past 2,000 years.
For the French, painting is Italian,
honeymoons are in Italy,
museums are Italian,
whereas...
I find German Renaissance painting
absolutely fascinating.
Thanks for the information.
So, are you going to do anything?
You know,
all those aborted resolutions —
The United Nations have been
somewhat disunited since '48.
The crime doesn't matter,
so as for him —
Ludovic told me you know everything.
So you must also know
that they fired me.
My friends,
I've got it:
the black box.
That's why Hollywood was called
the Mecca of the Movies.
The Tomb of the Prophet.
The eyes all turned in the same direction.
The movie theater.
Yes, but...
the strange thing is that
Hollywood was invented byJews.
Adolph Zukor,
THINGS
William Fox,
David Selznick,
Samuel Goldwyn,
Marcus Loew,
LIKE THIS
Carl Laemmle,
et cetera.
Life is beautiful, you will see
How in spite of sorrow
You will have friends,
you will have love
You will have friends
WHERE ARE YOU GOING...
EUROPE?
Is there a single deed in the world of which
I can easily say today, "I've done that"?
Catherine wants to sell
my business, the garage.
Her friend wants to buy it.
They know it. I don't.
I know the bills, that I do.
France today is running
the greatest risk in its history.
You have to say "we"
to be able to say "I."
In a drama,
we fight in hopes of pulling through.
In a tragedy, not at all.
Everything remains clean.
Everything happens in private,
people ignore each other,
wars everywhere
for the past 50 years.
We look at ourselves in wars
like in a mirror.
We save time.
It takes guts to think.
Love thy neighbor? Ridiculous.
You have to love yourselfenough
not to harm your neighbor.
Today that's become impossible.
Eitheryou obey the law,
oryou betray.
We're not asking you all that, Daddy.
I wonderwhyyou don't love us.
Ideas divide us,
dreams may bring us closer.
No, nightmares.
Because there's love and pride
in your paternal blood, therefore hatred.
So, what have you come up with
today to piss us off?
First I love my brother,
and for the moment
we're talking about brotherhood.
And liberty.
Liberty is for later.
And when it comes time to talk
about equality, I'll tell you about crap.
Okay, Flo, but why don't you love us?
Excuse me, miss.
Excuse me.
We want to go to the Côte d'Azur.
Is this the right direction?
Are we on the right way
to the Cote d'Azur?
Straight? Left? Right?
Go invade some other country!
Unbelievable! French shit!
French scum!
Go on, Mother.
Go on, Mom.
Yes, to keep space and time intact,
I lied.
I neglect to experience them.
It's a little unfair.
But for myself,
I think this is what I do:
I always believe I'm elsewhere.
- I always believe I'm elsewhere.
- Drop it!
- And that each particular moment —
- Drop it.
matters none.
Anything else?
There's a character, the Mother,
who could care less ifshe has a life,
if life is considered an end in itself.
She doesn't have the slightest doubt
that she is still alive.
It never occurs to her to wonder
how and why or in what way she is.
In short, she is not aware
of being a character
because she has never,
not even for a moment,
been detached from her role.
She doesn't know she has a role.
But there you are:
maternal blood,
full of hatred,
loves and lives together.
Is this the Martin garage?
Flo, what should we say?
We don't speak to those
who use the verb "to be."
- Do you work here?
- Yes, but I don't have a contract.
We came to speak with your parents.
LOST ILLUSIONS
I quit.
I'm going back down south.
What about the comrades?
You'll come see us.
That'll be up to them.
Sure you'll come.
For tonight's news.
For the elections.
I'm filming.
Forget it, darling.
We have an appointment.
Forget it, lady.
Just for a few minutes.
For a statement.
Which one will run?
Forget it.
- But your parents made the appointment.
- What parents?
We're not making it up.
He meant, what kind of parents?
Mr. and Mrs. Martin aren't your parents?
Please don't use the verb "to be."
Now I'm totally confused.
- Well?
- No answer.
Give me that.
Not surprising, they all have cell phones
saying they aren't there.
Sorry, saying no one's home.
Get lost, Channel 3!
I don't get it. The batteries are new.
It must have a problem.
There, use the verb "to have"
and things will go much better for France.
You get that out of Balzac, Flo?
Florine.
Ifyou make fun of Balzac,
I'll kill you.
Please, sir. A few questions.
Please.
An hour and a half late.
If it had been done
as initially planned,
this project would've placed France
way ahead in book digitization,
but now it's hopelessly behind.
Should I wait foryou, sir?
No, go pick up the Prince at the airport
and stop by the office.
Well?
"Presidency" is feminine in French.
We'll see about that.
We already have.
Not at all. Our convention.
Today's August 4, right?
Flo's right. We'll have to wait a bit.
The news is at 7:00.
There's always some editing.
Give me 1 0 minutes.
I'll settle this.
Can I film while we wait?
Not at all.
You can film me.
Why don't Florine and I run for election
instead of Mom and Dad?
He's dreaming. Kids can't run for election,
even at the canton level.
Sure,
but kids are part of the people,
and the people's will exists.
Besides, we'll end up paying 30%
of France's debt because you're getting old.
The exact —
The exact profit
insurance companies make off the debt.
Can I film the pretty dress?
Sure, why not?
I'm listening.
Today, it's inconvenient.
I'd forgotten.
They were born on the same day.
Each birthday,Jean-Jacques and I
agreed to debate with them,
in theory democratically.
Do they lead it?
More or less.
We had to sign an agreement.
That's so cool!
We should film that.
We work at night.
We do what we can.
We give what we have.
How long will it take?
Unfortunately, they're allowed 24 hours.
Eitheryou wait,
or come back tomorrow.
We'll wait.
We'll wait!
I'll borrow Catherine's Mini
and be right back.
I have to settle this garage business.
Goddamn it!
Watch out, Mom.
That's right,
I could beat you all to a pulp!
I'd even attack the sun
if it ever attacked me.
Really? We're moving to America now?
No, England.
Exactly four centuries ago.
He doesn't have his heart in his mouth.
So, do you love us or not?
When I talk to myself,
I speak someone else's words
that I say to myself.
When you hearyour own voice,
where does it come from?
No, Dad, from here.
So what?
I'll inform the TV people.
No, Mom, stay!
One is part of the other.
The other is part of the one,
and there are three people.
We're four.
There is the law,
but you have duties. Say so.
Well, Mother, we're entering an age
with digital technology
where, for different reasons,
humanity will have to face problems
that won't allow themselves the luxury
of being expressed.
About the garage, for instance,
there must be redistribution of property.
It must be said, the revolution,
alas...
Fraternity...
Saint Augustine.
"I include among my friends
those who disapprove of my acts
but not my existence."
I still smile.
It's been pointless for so long.
My tongue goes back out
and into the mud.
I stay that way,
no longer thirsty,
the tongue goes back in —
The mouth closes.
It should now make a straight line.
That's it. I created the image.
Nearly everything —
grains, math, television —
there are almost as many
as prime numbers.
I don't get it, why television?
Nerve connections have become
raw material today.
So in my humble opinion
once again Africa is out of luck.
You mean, not part of history,
that's what you think.
What hasn't changed
is that there will always be bastards.
And what has changed today
is that the bastards are sincere.
They sincerely believe in Europe,
that's true.
Europe was a German musician,
a French writer,
Italian singers.
Ah,yes, The Marriage of Figaro.
But still, what we're doing is pathetic:
we distribute,
whereas we should first produce.
Yet we once knew how.
With a tom-tom.
Here and now, with these people,
I'm trying to produce something.
Don't you think?
Didn't Flo bring you sandwiches?
Yes. 5:00 p.m.
Do you think we can shoot soon?
Yes, soon, I think so.
I told you, here and now
I don't give orders.
You heard. 5:00 p.m.
It'll be all right.
Do you think —
WillJean-Jacques
give up his place to you?
I hope so.
Ask ifshe has a plan.
What do the unions say?
We'll see. First they'll say I'm right,
then do what they want.
So bye-bye Bertha.
Above all keep your mouth shut.
Show first.
Show only what's possible.
What, for instance?
Not talk about what's invisible, show it.
You want more power?
No power. A society, not a state.
Sorry, Florine, I don't get it.
The state dreams of being alone.
Individuals dream of pairing up.
Let's get a move on!
What'd she say?
Think hard about what you're fighting for,
because you just might obtain it.
- What history?
- You'll see.
Be careful, Dad!
Do you wear thongs, like Mom?
- Lucien!
- I'm curious.
Live or tell,
we don't have a choice.
I'll tell.
1 789, the night of August 4.
With the corps
all privileges were abolished,
- only common law would remain —
- Common law.
- universally applicable —
- Condemned.
to every Frenchman.
No more screen between
the individual and the law.
I scorn the dust I am made from
and which speaks to you.
You bet, pet.
Bravo.
Saint-Just. '89.
Beautiful 20-year-old bodies.
Madame,
what are these many eyes
that watch in the night?
Monsieur,
suddenly this,
suddenly that astonishes me,
there's no one here,
yet here I am speaking to you,
and you hear me since you're answering.
Monsieur,
through it all,
what are these images,
at times at liberty,
at times locked in?
This vast thought,
where figures pass.
Where colors glow.
Madame,
that was space.
And space is dying.
One word is enough.
I'm trying.
You are full of your beauty,
your strength.
And I told you too.
There's no love left between us.
You divide by the number
of elected officials
on the pretense that it is costly to democracy,
and that these officials don't work,
and that the public should be educated
about all these layers.
I'm mayor and regional councilor.
My canton's regional council
is not of my political persuasion
and we all know who does what,
and we work together intelligently.
So that argument is no good.
It must be completely revised
because it leads the population
to believe that these officials
are only there to collect their pay,
whereas the time devoted
by the state's elected officials —
and we were talking about rural officials
earlier who deserve our praise —
is given generously.
...of the Republic today guarantee
France's territorial and social cohesion.
I saw —
General councilors. It's not easy.
No election is easy.
You'll need a plan.
of course.
A plan.
Do you have one?
To be 20.
To be right.
To keep hoping.
To be right
when your government's wrong.
To learn to see before learning to read.
Isn't that cool?
You poor thing, you never listen.
Yet, without realizing it,
she had already taken the decisive step.
She was now heading
into unknown territory,
beyond the confines
of her former paradise,
alone.
Someone different than this little girl —
- The perfect union of several voices —
- fearless.
after all prevents
progress toward one another.
- Thief! Thief!
- Our reality is highly complex...
and we have a tool to understand
that deeply simplifies reality —
- Anyone seen my cap?
- and prevents us from taking it into account.
- Hey! Whitey.
- I think from that standpoint —
- Did you see anything?
- France is lagging behind.
- No, miss.
- We're a so-called developed country—
- Enough.
- that in 201 0 leaves the weakest people —
- I sawyou, you bum.
- to a dismal fate.
Hey, be careful!
What are you doing?
Welcoming a bygone landscape.
Shit, that's a Renoir!
Yes, exactly. The moron missed out
on some beautiful things.
And those two,
that's you and your mom?
Ifanyone asks, sayyou don't know.
I can't make out the brand name.
Night and day.
Thanks, I know English.
It comes from Egypt.
It was found in a pharaoh's tomb
in Tel el Amarna.
There are no hours, nothing.
Yes, but there's time,
the dawn of time.
Who decides the day?
It does.
Nothing's moving.
It's thinking.
If it goes on too long, give it a shake.
Then what?
Mystery.
What are you thinking about?
And you?
Your behind.
That really interests you?
Oh, stop! Get out!
That's enough! Beat it, damn it!
Bastards!
Assholes!
That's enough, you littlejerk!
so you went to see them again
Yes, after the first election was canceled,
the children are now awaiting
the decision of the Council of State
their father has a little place
in the south
for the first election,
the Council's decision was fair
Florine and Lucien kept their last name
Popular sovereignty was expressed
but without a pattern
this time they got 93% of the vote
with just their first names
so they're going to win
once, in the Resistance,
not far from Toulouse,
there was a small network
that was part of the "Combat" movement
"the Martin family"
whose motto was
liberate and federate
OUR HUMANITIES
In the Sudan, gold dust,
along with black slaves,
is known to be the main merchandise
in Saharan smuggling.
But we don't realize
that for centuries this gold
was one of the decisive weapons
of western Islam.
On neither the sun, nor death,
can we look fixedly.
See,
there,
two female gold diggers,
at a meeting of the Golden League.
In their image, then,
the historian doesn't seek, he finds.
To safeguard all the images of language
and make use ofthem.
Because they are in the desert
where we must go find them.
PALESTINE
STATE OF PALESTINE
It was in 1 839 that Palestine
had its first photographer.
The squaring of the circle was found
with the famous X + 3 = 1 metaphor
which Einstein sought all his life.
Clarum per obscurius.
At the end of 1 926,
inJerusalem,
Gershom Scholem wrote to
Franz Rosenzweig in Berlin.
Your cheeks are pretty amid the necklaces
The country is a volcano.
And the day will come when language
will turn itselfagainst those who speak it.
This is why the girls love you
Take me away, go on,
run me afteryou
The king had me enter his chambers
A captive lover.
And the second angel
spilled his chalice over the sea.
And it became like the blood of the dead.
During his second course
at the New School in New York,
RomanJakobson demonstrated
during the winter of'42-'43,
how it is impossible
to separate sound from meaning
and that only the notion of phoneme
- allows us to resolve this mystery.
- Writing for two voices
is only successful when dissonance
is introduced by a common note.
Tell me where the soldiers are
Where are they?
What has been done?
Isaac asked his father:
I see the fire, I see the knife,
but I don't see the lamb.
EARTH AGAINST HEAVEN
And Abraham said:
God will provide himself
a victim for a holocaust.
JEW
The Crusades and the very name
of Jerusalem explain many things.
MUSLIM
Ifthere was a desire forvengeance,
the person to avenge wasJesus Christ.
Palestine.
ODESSA
OCTOBER, ELECTROSCOPE SHUDDERED
BUT IS FALLING ASLEEP
Are there any questions?
I have a question.
You said that it was a silent movie,
so how did people understand?
Odessa.
Staircase, in the Russian language,
is a feminine word.
When construction
of the stairs was finished...
no one had any doubt that the stairs
had become an integral part of our city.
I think she's talking nonsense.
But there was something else.
Well, yes.
- Poor Vakulinchuk.
- This is the Potemkin staircase.
...thanks to
Sergei Mikhailovich Eisenstein's film,
Battleship Potemkin,
or the Year 1 905.
In the manifestation,
there wasjoy, happiness.
There you go. It's your turn.
The soldiers fired on them
because it was manifest.
And in manifest
you have mano (hand).
Not some draped sentiment,
but an ideal,
a smile that dismisses the universe.
HELLAS
Hellas.
Democracy and tragedy were wed in Athens,
under Pericles and Sophocles.
A sole child: civil war.
The Greek tragic hero:
the mortal exhibition of a speechless body,
in lieu of an impossible declaration.
PRINCIPLES OF TRAGEDY
Ismene, sister, mine own dear sister,
knowest thou what ill there is,
of all bequeathed by Oedipus?
When Ulysses, returning from the Odyssey,
reached Ithaca,
the only one who recognized him
under his disguise was a dog.
But that morning,
when he fell in line alongside Atalanta,
he realized that war
would be at the center of his life.
French Newsreels today present
the first coverage of a country in strife.
The brothers are leaving
Ourvillage
They raise a flag
And they depart
Why did I so desire the gift of prophecy?
So, Cassandra, will you be reasonable?
No.
You don't approve of the gods' plans?
But you will be silent?
No.
The dream of—
Naples.
Let's bring back duration.
More significant
than the deep structures of life...
are their breaking points,
their sudden or slow deterioration.
Their sudden or slow deterioration.
The sad thing
is that we copy the same model
dating from Mediterranean antiquity.
- Infection is an ancient event.
- It has colored with its scents,
- colors and affirmations —
- Without infection —
- all life in the western world.
- evolution would have been impossible.
The plague broke out in Naples
on October 1 , 1 943,
The same day the Allied forces
entered this unfortunate city as liberators.
Freedom is costly,
but you don't buy it
with gold or blood,
but with cowardice,
prostitution and betrayal.
Could the North Americans claim
to have liberated the peoples
and yet oblige them to feel vanquished?
Nothing and everything!
You cannot go back
Because life pushes you on
Like an endless scream
Spain is a country that at this moment
has no lack... of opportunities to die.
And even our utopias,
it being clearly understood that
the essential is not what a dictator thinks —
Mamma mia
To bloody deeds
We discoverwar only once,
but we discover life several times.
But a more loyal truth —
Viva Don Quixote!
and we might add,
within arm's reach.
Bullfight in the Plaza de Toros.
They were all there:
Hemingway, Dos Passos, Orwell.
Afterwhich,
once the bull was put to death,
toreros and spectators left for the front.
Women —
like all those building fortifications
on the outskirts of the city,
in anticipation of the Moors' offensive.
Later, Simone Weil,
after Franco's victory,
when she heard that the Germans
had entered Paris, declared:
"A great day for Indochina."
You see,
- with the verb "to be" —
- A sort of great hope after the occupation.
the loss of reality becomes flagrant.
For example, we'll soon be in Barcelona.
Better to say:
Barcelona will soon welcome us.
What time is it?
Nothing but the right time.
Alissa!
THINGS
LIKE
When the law is unfair,
justice precedes law