ALONE
See you later.
-Hello.
I'm glad you're here.
Your mother worries me
more than your father.
-She fainted again.
-Got a smoke?
There's no smoking here.
I'll smoke it later.
She seems very sad.
It must be from fatigue
and being here.
It's none of my business...
-She's too old for this.
-She wants to stay.
-lf you stayed with your father...
-No, I can't.
-You can't, or...?
-I can't.
-Only child?
-One of four.
What about the others?
They've all
gone up north.
Far away.
As far as they could.
Come, mother.
Thank you, doctor.
The operation went well,
we'll take a look
when he wakes up.
If you want, you can call
tonight to see how he is.
But listen.
You can't stay here.
-You'll get ill yourself.
-Let's go.
Goodbye.
Mother...
Let's get the bar's
phone number
so the hospital can find us.
I know the owner.
You go.
-Why not you?
-There are lots of men.
This isn't the village.
Thank God it's not.
A brandy, fat man.
I'll pay you later.
You owe me a lot.
Do me a favor...
Put the bottle down!
My father's in the hospital.
Can I give them
your number?
Of course,
what are friends for?
-How's your dad?
-Thanks.
A drink on the house.
Here, this is the number.
Don't lose it.
The bathroom's here.
-Coffee?
-My doctor says I can't have it.
-Since when?
-A long time ago.
Don't mind the apartment.
I just moved in.
I'll change
the sheets for you.
-Where will you sleep?
-On the sofa bed.
-I don't mind the sofa bed.
-I do.
Let me do it.
The doctor said
I shouldn't stay
in the hospital,
but with my family.
He didn't have to.
Feel at home here.
Stay as long
as you need to.
It's stuffy in here.
It smells like mildew.
Smells?
It stinks!
-Open the windows.
-What for?
The smell's in the walls.
Even I have that smell.
From Isabelita.
She wants you
to be the godmother.
She's not baptized?
They're waiting.
Her mother just died.
I sent a telegram
to tell you about it,
but it was
to your old address.
When?
She died February 18th,
a week after
Isabelita had the baby.
I moved in January.
She lasted long enough
to see her granddaughter.
Isabelita always
asks about you.
She'd love it
if you were the godmother.
When do you go
to the hospital?
1:30 tomorrow.
It's usually clean.
You should pick up
after you shower.
The right one's hot.
I'm going out.
I have a job interview.
I made you an omelet
and there's soup.
There's no milk or fruit.
I never eat here.
I won't be gone long.
And your food?
I'll eat later.
You're thin.
A little.
And the hospital?
I'll call later.
Do it from the bar.
Don't stay out long,
this neighborhood
is dangerous.
Do you need anything?
Where are the clothespins?
Don't open the door
to anyone.
Come on.
You know the way?
-Maybe we can see your father...
-Not me.
Remember to catch
this bus going back.
He's as strong as an ox.
He's sleeping perfectly,
stitches and all.
-How are you?
-Fine, thank you.
He asked for you.
He doesn't like you being
with your daughter.
-ls there any problem?
-No.
Things happen.
I understand.
I'll let you see him.
Maybe you can calm him down.
-Ana, she's going to go in.
-Thank you.
The doctor told me to go,
that I wasn't needed.
Maria wanted me
to go to her place
to rest...
But I can stay here
if you want.
Stupid old woman!
Shit!
I told you not to eat it.
And you go out
and do it here!
And I have
to clean up your shit!
Goddamnit!
-Excuse me.
-lt's all right.
-I can dry it off.
-You don't need to.
-I really am sorry.
-lt happens to me, too.
-Goodbye.
-Goodbye, and sorry.
Look at this mess.
Next time,
you clean it up!
The neighbors will say
we're two old pigs!
You're late.
-Any problems?
-I caught the wrong bus.
Why did you buy that?
I went by the supermarket
and you needed things.
I'll pay you.
You don't have to.
Yes, I do.
They can't say
I take money from you.
-You got the job?
-Yes.
-Doing what?
-What do you think?
Cleaning up
other people's shit.
You don't have to be ashamed.
I did that for 12 years.
What? Don't give me
your life
as an example.
It's all I have.
Keep it.
Mine is enough for me.
If he doesn't set a date for
the wedding, tell him to fuck off.
I should have
already done that.
-What about the trousseau?
-Sell it.
All the linen is monogrammed.
You're so old-fashioned.
Hello,
come in.
Everything has
to be ready by 7:00.
Call me if there's
any problems.
Start with this room.
Can we take the leftovers?
You can from the table,
but don't touch the kitchen.
You don't want any?
There isn't much left.
That's all there is.
If you don't want it,
give it to me.
You're proud
for a poor girl.
Hey! Don't touch that!
I don't want drunks here!
Let us have a drink, boss.
What a killjoy!
Let's toast.
-Your health!
-Let's toast to this spread.
-Here.
-None left.
Here, come on.
Drink, girl, drink.
-A brandy.
-Hell, 5,000 pesetas!
Brandy, coming up!
Paying your debt?
Leave me bus money.
And give me a lottery ticket.
Only your drink
and the ticket.
The rest when you're rich.
What happened?
I got a blister
at a party.
I'll put something on it.
Come on, it'll get infected.
Let's see your hand.
What kind of party was that?
Here...
I'll put on some peroxide
and you'll be fine.
How's your wife?
She can hardly move.
Having twins is hard.
Raising them will be...
Who's with her?
My mother-in-law.
That's what she needs.
Waiter!
This one's on me.
-Six tapas and 12 beers.
-Not 12 beers!
-I kept track.
-You're wrong.
-I'm wrong?
-4 beers too many.
I won't argue
over four fucking beers.
The fucker's trying
to rob us!
Let's leave.
Don't come here again!
Goddamn him!
If I wanted to steal,
I'd go to a bank,
that way I could get rich!
I wouldn't steal
some idiot's last penny!
Goddamn...
Sorry, Maria. Those bastards
piss me off.
-Okay, fat man. I have to go.
-Wait.
-I'll buy you a drink.
-Another time.
Maria...
It's awful having kids.
It puts your wife
out of service.
That's good.
Get yourself ready
for when she's better.
Ready, Don Emilio?
I like this piece,
but I'm not sure.
Let me know when you decide.
Fine, don't worry about me.
-The loin is fresher.
-For a stew?
For how many?
Just one.
Get a half pound.
1,785 pesetas.
Take out the cheese.
-I can't, it's cut to order.
-Of course.
-The roast...
-Don't take out anything.
How much?
Pay me back later, Madam.
How much, Julia?
-How much have you got?
-1,400 and...
30 more...
You need
-355 more.
-Put it on my bill.
-I'll pay you as soon as I get back.
-Whenever you want.
Thank you, Miss.
And you, too.
I'll give it right back.
That lady's not from here.
She just arrived,
she's strange...
-What have you got today?
-Let's see. The wine...
Some beef loin...
Vegetables...
Another plant?
And when you go?
I'll leave them.
Plants are good company.
I don't have time
to look after them.
-Just water them...
-I had some, they died.
Well...
I'll find a place for them.
The doctor says your dad
can go to a room tomorrow.
The doctor takes good
care of your father.
It's his job.
He has a good heart.
It's easy with money.
Many rich people
don't have one.
Neither do the poor.
No one has a good heart.
Especially here.
Everyone here just looks
out for their own pocket.
-Good and bad people are everywhere.
-Tell me another day.
Some respect for your mother!
But you say some things...
You're just
like your father.
Then leave him.
Want me to go?
-I didn't say that.
-I asked you.
I said you could stay.
I have to go now.
Don't get your hands wet
and put a bandage on them.
-Have you see Juan?
-He's over there.
Are you fucking crazy?
-I did the test.
-And?
I'm pregnant.
Fucking hell! I told you
to take the pills!
What about condoms?
I don't like condoms.
You can't get pregnant.
This is fucked,
baby.
I don't want problems.
I'll pay if you want
an abortion...
I won't have your child.
Fucking great.
Paco...
How did your girl
do her abortion?
She went to
see a social worker.
-How much was it?
-Nothing.
Free, too.
But if you need cash,
I'll help.
Are we set?
I'll be back
in a couple of days.
Want money for coffee?
You don't?
Well...
Give me a kiss.
-Hello. Your money, thank you.
-You didn't have to hurry.
It was just a few cents.
Come in.
-Are you cooking?
-Yes, my stew.
-lt's burning.
-Damnit! Goddamnit!
Goddamnit to hell!
Your money.
Did you get burned?
-A little.
-You left it on.
-What's this?
-Potato and meat stew.
For you or for the dog?
Excuse me...
No, not even Achilles
could eat it.
All day
cooking, and for nothing!
I'll make something.
No, thank you.
-Some rice?
-Don't bother.
Rice? There's some here.
-Have you got tomatoes?
-No, thank you.
In the fridge...
You're going to cook now?
This was a nice
area, but the young people
moved out and now only
us old people are left.
Some cheese?
-lt's good.
-No.
I've already eaten.
Salt?
The owners made
smaller apartments,
and they rented them out
to people from the villages,
poor people,
bums, drug addicts,
prostitutes...
The scum of the city.
Not everyone, you're daughter
isn't like that.
By the way,
what's her job?
Damn gossipy old man.
Is that any of my business?
It's a professional defect.
We retired people are bored,
so we spy on other people.
At a cleaning company.
She's smart
and wanted to study,
but her father said no.
He's old-fashioned.
I understand.
You have no family?
No, I'm not from here.
I'm from La Felguera,
in Asturias.
I've lived here for years
but since my wife died,
I have no one,
here or there.
Achilles!
Achilles,
like the Roman emperor.
I think he was Roman...
He's an old friend...
the only one I have left...
And my bodyguard.
Touch me.
Quiet!
Now I'll touch you.
Now he sees
you're my friend.
Pet him and say
something nice.
He's an old fool
that likes affection.
You're very pretty
and very grumpy.
And very clever, too.
Watch what he does.
Here, Achilles.
He likes to go out a lot.
Achilles, the door!
He's an old scoundrel.
Inés, give me a cigarette.
-Finished upstairs?
-Yes.
Stay here. I'm sick
of being alone.
-And her?
-She won't talk.
-She hasn't changed?
-Not at all.
And I can't work like that,
silent all night.
Bastards!
You're all bastards!
-Calm down, girl.
-Bastards!
Calm down...
-Fourteen.
-Nine.
-9 years with my boyfriend.
-9 more if you're not careful.
-I know.
-Twenty-one.
-Thirty-two.
-Seventeen.
-Seventeen...
-My age when I first got laid.
-And...?
It was over in two seconds.
One left.
Thirty-eight.
Thirty-eight...
-Rhymes with...
-Masturbate.
You're so vulgar!
Here...
You look like a skeleton.
-Are you going to play?
-Let her eat first.
She can give me numbers
while she eats.
What's wrong?
You're pale, Maria.
I fell asleep.
Where's that chair from?
Downstairs,
it was thrown out.
It's in good condition.
Go to bed, it's late.
Want some food?
No.
-Some warm milk?
-No.
You have to eat.
Don't be a pain.
Who's it for?
The doctor's baby.
Will he pay you?
It's a gift.
Because he's so nice.
It keeps me busy.
You're so naive.
If you say so.
I say I'm going to bed.
I've got some aloe vera.
-Rosemary or flower scent?
-Rose water.
Go to sleep.
I've got delicate
rich girl's hands.
Right...
You always said that.
I should have been rich.
You didn't want to work.
Who does?
People should
be born twice.
Once rich and once poor.
So the rich will know poverty,
and the poor can enjoy life.
What if you
had another life?
Me?
If I had another life,
I'd only change one thing.
Give me one.
Here.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
-Hello.
Look at this.
I'm bad with meat, but
I'm great at buying fish.
Looks fresh.
Looks? This bass swam
right to the fish shop.
It died in my hands.
Something this good
needs a good cook.
Well... I can cook it if I
get back early from the hospital.
What time?
It doesn't matter,
I'll wait.
I could be very late.
If it's not for lunch,
then for tea.
We'll have tea and bass.
Come on, we have a lot to do.
Don't be afraid,
we changed his room.
Come with me.
He's in good shape.
-Ana.
-Yes?
Take her to his room.
-Good morning.
You're better, right?
Come closer.
Where were you?
In your daughter's place.
I smell men.
South Zone Health Center.
To the right.
-No smoking.
-Where do I put it out?
When's your appointment?
Maria Martinez.
That's me.
Make sure you
call me Sunday.
Take care.
Maria?
Come in.
SOCIAL WORKER
That's dull.
Where's my knife?
All right! Be patient.
Let's go.
Mother?
-Check the filters.
-I did last week.
-Well, check them again.
-All right.
-Hi, Miguel.
-Hi.
Is there
any hot water left?
-The Jacuzzi's ready.
-Here.
The mechanic's
checking the filter.
-She knew we came today?
-You told her.
What's up, shorty?
-Can we talk?
-Of course.
Give me a kiss first.
You have to eat
a little more.
Come on.
-Hello.
Some soup and potatoes.
Thanks. You didn't have to.
I stayed at the hospital.
I thought so.
-Come in.
-No, thank you.
-I have things to do.
-Of course.
-Enjoy the food.
-Thank you.
Goodbye.
What are you looking at?
There's no privacy here.
Well...
What is it?
They'll do the abortion
next week.
Great! Does it cost anything?
-No.
-There you go.
Fast and free. Women
can't complain now.
My mom almost died
from an illegal abortion,
and paying for it.
I want you to come.
What for?
I'm afraid.
You?
Of what? It's
too late for that.
If I could, I would,
but we're
leaving on Monday.
Your Mom will go.
She doesn't know.
Well, tell her.
I never will.
Why not?
Because.
She didn't knock me up.
The father could be anyone...
-Bastard!
-Knock it off or you'll get it!
Will you go or not?
I told you I can't.
Besides,
I have to pay for the truck,
I need this job.
I have to work, too.
Don't worry,
I'll talk to your boss.
All right?
Come on, relax!
Everything's okay.
Come here. Come.
Come on...
Suck it like
you know how to.
Suck me the way I like.
-Be good.
-I want to have the baby.
What?
Are you crazy?
What are you saying?
-With the two of us...
-No! Okay?
I said so from the start.
-We could try...
-What? Try what?
Talk, don't stare at me.
Nothing to say?
I'll talk, then.
If you want a dick,
you can use mine.
But that's all we have.
Is that clear?
One more thing:
to be a mother,
you have to be a woman.
You're only half woman,
the other half is alcohol.
Shorty...
Between us...
things have
always been clear.
I never promised anything.
If you want a husband,
look somewhere else.
Think about it.
A child isn't a whim.
It's a mistake.
-A child isn't a mistake.
-No.
The mistake
is a mother like you.
Think about it.
Fuck you,
you son of a bitch!
-Hello.
You can
use my telephone.
I don't need to.
-Thank you. Goodnight.
-Goodnight.
The food was delicious,
we ate it all...
Achilles and I.
Hold on, your dishes.
Here.
Thank you.
Poor woman.
Doesn't she look sad?
Let's go inside.
Who is it?
I'm here with your daughter.
I told you not to knock.
-Here's the keys, see them?
-Yes, I see them.
Now what?
You woke up my mom,
what will she think of me?
-Who cares what she thinks?
-Don't shout...
I'll shout if I want to,
this is my home!
Or isn't it? Answer!
-lsn't it?
-Come to bed.
I don't want to!
Give dad orders sometime.
He's got balls.
He raises a finger
and you shit yourself.
They all have balls.
I'll cut them off!
-That's enough.
-Leave her to me.
You sure? I'm used
to dealing with drunks.
So am l, don't worry.
She has a temper,
but she's good...
-What happened?
-I told her not to drink so much.
-Something had to happen.
-Let's get her to bed.
Come closer.
Closer, damnit!
Afraid I'll smell you?
You never stop?
I like it.
Who's it for?
-The doctor...
-He's a bastard.
Don't say that.
All doctors are bastards.
They do what
they want with you.
Are we alone?
Yes.
I was thinking
of the past...
Have I been a good man?
Yes.
You hit me sometimes.
But have I acted
like a man?
We always had food.
As a man? Have I been
a good man?
What do you mean?
Forget it...
Stupid old woman,
you never understand.
It's late to ask that.
He must not have
an easy conscience. I do.
-Does it hurt?
-A little.
-Want to see the doctor?
-No.
You must be exhausted.
I'll stay today.
-You don't have to work?
-Not anymore.
A permanent vacation.
-He won't want you to.
-Ask him.
Sooner or later
it had to happen.
He knows that.
Be careful.
Let him be careful.
Woman!
Where the hell are you?
May I?
Are you here?
The bathroom...
What's wrong?
I'm all right.
I want to wash myself.
Something I ate
gave me diarrhea.
-I'll call the doctor.
-I just want to wash myself.
-Don't touch me...
-You need help.
No, I don't.
For God's sake!
I'm too old for
this foolishness.
Seeing a naked old man
won't kill me.
-I reek of shit!
-The pigs smell worse.
But I wash and
feed and care for them,
and sleep with them
if I need to!
Come on...
Some nice hot water...
Into the shower!
"The cat washes itself,
and the unwashed child
turns into a frog..."
Now you have to croak.
Come on, croak.
-Croak...
-Louder!
Croak...
Too hot!
Sorry...
I'm not hungry.
Want it?
-You're not hungry?
-No.
You eat it.
Thank you...
-Can I see the magazine?
-Of course.
You did that out of pity
for a poor old man.
What poor old man?
Why, then?
We're neighbors.
Neighbors help one other.
Of course.
So why do you ask?
We're leaving in a few days.
Why don't you go
to a nursing home?
To live with other
old people? No.
I'll stay in my own home.
I just ate
something bad earlier.
But I'm strong,
I'll show you...
No, you don't have to.
I know you're strong...
and stubborn. Come on.
You can go to bed.
I hate how old people smell.
Every age has its smell.
But old people reek
of piss.
Smell me.
What do I reek of?
Of piss?
It's late,
I have a lot to do.
Goodnight.
-Who's waiting for you?
-Nobody...
My daughter.
And you have to rest.
Goodnight.
If you need me,
bark loudly.
You're a good dog.
Goodnight, you two.
Goodnight.
Make sure to come
by tomorrow. I'll still
be a little sick.
And the bass is
in the freezer.
Well, if I can,
I'll cook it.
But I may not be able to.
If not tomorrow,
another day.
Goodbye.
Defeat is not
the enemy's triumph,
admitting the defeat is.
What do you say?
Want something?
Hello.
-What's this for?
-They're going to examine me.
-Where's your daughter?
-I sent her away.
How do you feel?
I smell man on you.
Men from the bus...
You always stink
of the same one.
Well...
Let's see
if you can go tomorrow.
This will just take
a second.
Does this hurt?
And this?
It depends if you can
get house calls.
Grandma?
I'm talking.
-Sorry.
-ls there a medical center
near your house?
Yes, there is.
Perfect.
You can leave tomorrow
if you want to.
If you think there's
no problem,
I'd like to get out of here.
-I have a lot to do.
-But you can't work.
You have to rest.
I won't work, but...
I have to look
after what's mine.
This silly dog got
nervous when he heard you.
-Are you okay?
-Just a bit tired.
-I can make you some tea.
-No, thank you.
Your blood pressure...
-I can measure it for you.
-There's no need.
I just need to rest a bit.
My husband leaves
the hospital tomorrow.
I'm glad for him...
and for you.
I'll come by to say goodbye.
Yes, please do that.
Don't go without calling.
Let's go inside.
What stitch is that?
A straight one.
To the right and back.
-With a crochet needle?
-A number 3.
Another gift?
No,
this one's for you.
A sleeveless cardigan.
I saw a girl with one
in the hospital.
Try it on.
Tomorrow you dad gets out...
and we'll return
to the village.
It looks good on you.
What do you say?
It's very pretty.
I'll put the buttons on
tomorrow.
When I see Isabelita,
she'll ask if you'll
be the godmother.
What do I say?
When is it?
In a month.
Tell her I will.
She'll be happy.
She wants to see you.
Come on, eat
the omelet.
I'm not hungry.
Eat it!
Wait a minute.
Achilles, stay.
-Hello.
My daughter.
If you need anything,
-call her.
-Thank you.
Likewise, I live here.
I'm going to the bar,
I'll wait there.
Madam,
it's been a pleasure.
In the few days
I have left,
in my many lonely hours
before me,
you will be
a pleasant memory.
Your words are touching.
Goodbye.
-I'll accompany you.
-Don't bother.
It's no bother.
On the contrary.
After seeing me naked,
my arm scares you?
Your wife was lucky,
you're good.
No, I made her suffer.
-Did you love her?
-Yes, but even so...
-You ever hit her?
-For God's sake, no!
I was right,
you're a good man.
Can I write to you?
I can't read.
-Can I call you?
-I have no phone.
-Do your neighbors?
-No.
Will you come back?
I don't know.
If you do,
will you visit me?
Yes, of course.
I wish you health.
Can I visit you?
Stop.
We're acting like kids.
Take care.
You're a very good dog.
You'll visit me?
Yes, I will,
don't worry.
I'll visit you.
Behave yourself.
Goodbye.
See you soon!
-Two coffees, right?
-Right.
And two brandies.
Right away.
-There.
-Well done.
Of course.
-Have I ever done it badly?
-Right.
How much is
a bottle of whisky?
Depends which.
3Dyc3, for example.
-Your change.
-Thanks.
For you, 1,000 pesetas.
Wholesale.
You want six?
No...
The other day...
Forget it.
If you're really sorry,
I'll forgive you.
Don't do it again.
I'll buy you a drink, okay?
For being good.
Fuck you, fat man.
What number won?
23567.
Shit! My daily disappointment.
Another 200 pesetas wasted.
It could be worse.
Let's have another drink.
A toast.
-How's your hand?
-Better.
You're tough.
-Going back to the village?
-Yes, sir.
-Have a good trip.
-Thanks.
Two, please.
Not that one,
the seven's better.
Luck comes from
where you least expect it.
Bye, Manuel.
-Here.
-You keep them.
-Not both. Take one.
-No.
You need luck more than I.
-Go in and say goodbye.
-Don't insist, mother.
He doesn't want to see me.
If he's angry,
he'll take it out on you.
We already said goodbye once,
there's no need to repeat it.
I wish I could have
spent more time with you.
With me?
Don't get me wrong,
I'm worried about you.
And the kitchen
needs to be painted.
Forget about the kitchen.
You won't go in?
I like how you smell, mother.
That's from your dad, too.
-What?
-Smelling people.
What else is from him?
Your bad temper.
Take care.
-Doctor?
-Yes.
-A lady's here to see you.
-Show her in.
Since the analysis
hasn't changed,
keep giving him
250 milligrams.
-What's up?
-I have a present for you.
No.
I can't.
-Please accept it.
-lt's against my principles.
At least look at it.
Well...
This is beautiful!
A piece of art!
My wife will love it.
Thank you.
-Sorry, what's your name?
-Rosa Jiménez Peña.
Thank you, Rosa.
-You have him ready?
-Yes.
I'll come say goodbye.
All right.
-Bye.
-I'll be right there.
-Hello.
Your mother
was going to cook it,
now I don't know
what to do with it.
I don't feel like eating it,
so I'll give to you.
It's yours.
Is that coffee?
Yes.
-lt's burning.
-Shit!
Some coffee?
The old woman's senile.
Laughing to herself!
Better laugh than grumble.
-What do you mean?
-Nothing.
My grandma said it's as easy
to smile as to grumble.
The ambulance will take you home.
You have my number,
okay?
Why do you complain so much?
Have you suffered so?
Right, you're old,
you know more.
I didn't say that.
But I am older.
If I add up all my bad luck,
I may beat you.
Maybe not.
Look, it's absurd to fight
about who's suffered more.
What I am sure about
is that I'm worse off
because my time is over,
and you, girl,
have a lot ahead.
We can agree on that,
can't we?
I buy food
every day, so as
not to buy for the week.
A plan for more than
two days is too much.
Don't be tragic, neighbor.
You're the tragic one.
Stop gabbing,
let's play cards.
But no betting just
cigarettes or matches.
100 pesetas the game.
500.
-You'll lose lots, Miss.
-I'm generous.
But don't call me 3Miss3.
All right, neighbor.
I've worked
in six houses here,
and all the housewives
say the same thing:
3lt's so hard
to find good help3.
But then they pay shit.
They want hard work
for bad pay.
-Don't exaggerate.
-I'm not.
-You get what you pay for.
-Fine, don't get excited.
I only want to explain
that I can't afford help.
Okay, fine. But you
could pay someone
to come for a couple hours.
I don't like that.
-Why not?
-I don't know.
They come for two hours,
clean the place, and go.
It's so...
Cold?
More or less.
You want them to sing
and dance for you?
No, just I don't like it.
You don't want a maid.
-You wany company.
-Perhaps.
More expensive.
Come on. I'm talking about
friendship, you can't buy that.
You can buy anything now.
-You want to count it?
-No.
My old man did
teach me cards.
You owe me 3,500.
This looks good!
My first bass.
My father gambled
what we earned
in the fields.
The bastard got the money
and went to play.
If we complained
he'd beat
the hell out of us.
My brothers left
when they could.
My sister married quickly,
a mistake...
And I stayed
a bit longer.
You didn't marry?
I was demanding.
I didn't want
to be like my mom.
And I had bad luck.
I didn't like many men,
the one I did married
my best friend.
And with all the men
in this city...?
You're a gossip.
Sorry, forgive me.
-lt's okay.
-I call it...
A professional defect.
We retired people
have nothing to do,
so we gossip.
Don't worry,
I'm having fun.
A little gossip is healthy.
In the village
I hated it,
but here
there's no one to talk to.
You hold it all in,
and it ends up burning
in your gut.
You know what?
Here's to gossip!
What did you ask?
Right...
If I'd met any men here.
A few.
I fell for the worst one.
After spending my life trying
to avoid what my mother did...
He knocked me up
and told me to fuck off.
You shouldn't smoke.
Nor drink so much.
You mother knows?
No one knows.
Now I know.
You don't matter.
-You're just a neighbor.
-Neighbors
are here to help
each other.
How?
I don't know. Listening.
And that helps?
So it won't burn
in your gut.
What will you do?
I'm going
to a clinic
for an abortion.
I'm afraid.
I'm against abortion.
You won't have one.
Still, I'm against it.
I don't give a shit.
It's my problem, I decide.
You're afraid?
Of everything.
Of it hurting,
of going alone...
of not being sure about it.
Then have the baby.
That's easy to say.
A baby is serious.
It's not a dog.
Achilles is serious.
But he isn't a baby.
Don't treat dogs like people.
People are
dying of hunger
and dogs eat well.
Some dogs are nobler
and friendlier than people.
Refering to me?
Yes.
Go to hell.
All you know about me
is that I'm pregnant.
Men knock us up, and
we have to deal with it.
Look...
I grew up in a house
of six with no bathroom,
my dad was a drunk
who beat my mom.
When he had no excuse...
Excuse? Fuck!
She never gave
that bastard an excuse...
But when he didn't
hit her, he hit us.
Why am I telling you this?
You're not like him.
What if I was?
If I just drank and gambled
and hit the baby?
I'm going to have a child
so it can grow up
the way I did?
I can't even...
give it a father.
If you would like,
I can go with you,
so you won't be alone.
There are times when
one should forget
one's principles.
I don't want you to come,
I don't want you
to say you agree.
What I want
is for you to say
my life will change.
I'm 35 years old
and I want this baby.
I have no magic wand,
but I could be
an adoptive grandfather.
I haven't much money,
but I have my pension.
I'm going to bed.
We're saying stupid things.
Are you crazy?
Or senile?
An adoptive grandfather?
-What the hell is that?
-A little respect, Miss!
You just said the stupidest
thing I ever heard.
Miss,
I swear to God,
on my word,
and on my late wife's grave,
that I have
not been joking
nor taking lightly a topic
as delicate as
the birth of a child.
I was completely serious.
I just had one son,
and he died young.
So you can understand
I never had grandchildren,
I was never a grandfather.
All I am trying
to communicate to you
is I'd love to be
a grandfather,
and I would be willing
to assume the responsibility
that would correspond to me.
That's all.
I've seen some
strange things,
but this tops all.
My dear,
I already told you.
At your age,
you haven't seen anything.
I'll think about it.
Be quick.
I don't even know you.
Are you drunk?
Do I look drunk?
If later you're sorry
or I don't like you?
Don't complicate things.
You want a baby
and I want a grandchild.
I'll be a normal grandfather.
We'll go to the park,
I'll buy him toys,
I'll play with him...
What problems could I cause?
If you don't like me,
you tell me.
Calm down,
I'll be okay.
You want some coffee?
Camomile tea, please.
I can't have coffee
this late.
Fine, grandpa.
Tonight you'll get what you want.
It's dawn.
One more day.
God's given us one more day.
Dear Mother,
wherever you are.
I named her Rosa after you.
She weighs 7 pounds
and she doesn't stop eating.
I work in the same place,
that's life.
My hands don't hurt anymore.
And I don't have
that pain inside,
nor do I have nightmares.
That's thanks to you
and to this little doll.
The adoptive grandpa
was sad when you died...
Well, we both were sad.
I know he wanted
to see you again.
But we're recovering,
thanks to your granchild,
his and yours.
He's become
a father to me, too.
But we argue a lot.
We're both stubborn,
but we always work it out.
He wants us to live
in the country,
he says it's better for her.
He'll sell his flat
and fix up our house.
The old man's crazy...
but wonderful.
It's a shame he's so old.
Speaking of men,
I'm not seeing anyone.
I like one,
but I'm in no hurry.
I don't want to make
another mistake.
I miss you, Mother.
We both miss you.
For my mother,
for all mothers.