Subtitles by OneTVAsia
"Episode 85"
My brother said he was
going to KJ Bar with Ha-na?
That's what he said.
He didn't want me
to accompany him.
They went public with
their dating.
And I've been thinking of ways
to harass Ra-hee's family.
This is it.
Should I torture them
with this?
Torture?
Are you talking about
physical torture?
No, psychological torture.
Hwang-so Soy Sauce
got its name back
got its name back?
KJ Bar?
Do-eun, it's late.
Why do you want to go there?
Do-hyeon?
He'll be there?
There he is.
They have undeniable chemistry!
It's explosive!
Don't you agree, Ra-gong?
What about you, Ra-hee?
Ra-hee.
Let go.
Ra-hee,
are you not feeling well?
Are you dizzy?
Or are you just shocked?
You're scary when you
look at me like that.
Ra-gong, I'm scared.
Stop her.
Ra-hee, don't make
yourself more pathetic.
Let's go.
Our date's ruined.
Ra-gong, you should
take Ra-hee home.
I want to go home too.
Come on.
When I first saw you here,
I wished you were a woman.
I wanted to dance with you.
I dreamed of a happy
ending with you.
A happy ending?
It wasn't a happy ending.
As I wished, you
really were a woman.
But there was a bigger
obstacle for us.
I got married and you're
at odds with my dad.
But one thing hasn't changed.
What's that?
I still love you the same.
I don't think about anything
else when I'm with you.
I don't think about you
being my dad's enemy.
I forget that I was married.
I only think about one thing.
It's that I love you.
I should go.
Thanks, Ha-na.
Thanks for the good memories.
I thank you too for helping me get
Hwang-so Soy Sauce's name back.
I heard the happy news that
Hwang-so got its name back.
I waited up to congratulate you.
Your cheeks are flushed.
You look like you're
happy and excited.
Where did you go?
Ha-na.
What?
Do-hyeon helped me get
Hwang-so Soy Sauce's name back.
I had a cocktail with him.
I'm going to go change.
Do you remember my telling you
about dopamine, norepinephrine,
neutrophin, testosterone,
oxytocin and endorphin?
The only time your body releases all
6 hormones is when you're in love.
Your behaviour today is similar
to how you behaved a year ago.
When we came back from living by
the beach, you had a frozen heart.
But today,
you seem like your old self
before we went to
live by the beach.
Did Do-hyeon melt
your frozen heart?
Do you love Do-hyeon still?
Do I still love him?
No.
I don't love him.
Do-hyeon and Ha-na have the
most chemistry I've ever seen
between two people.
I want them to make it legal.
What I mean by that is,
I'm going to get them married.
Ha-na and Do-hyeon
getting married...
Do-eun.
Yes?
You want them to get married?
Are you out of your stupid mind?
You startled me!
Why are you yelling at me?
And did you just call me stupid?
Mind your manners!
Don't forget, this is
your ex-husband's house!
How dare you yell
at me at my house!
It's only been a month since
Do-hyeon and I divorced.
This is just wrong.
Ra-hee.
How could you do this to me?
I saw you with Ha-na.
I couldn't go home after
seeing you two together.
Do you want to see me die?
How can you flaunt your
relationship with her?
I already announced that she
and I are going to get engaged.
Everyone knows she
and I are dating.
So what's wrong with
my being seen with her?
What's wrong in this picture
is you coming to my house.
It's only been a month since
I signed the divorce papers.
We just got divorced.
What does it matter how long
it's been when it's over?
It's not over for me.
That's right.
I haven't let go of you.
I only signed the divorce papers
because I thought I could work on
our reconciliation
after the divorce.
I didn't think our
marriage was really over!
All I want is you, Do-hyeon.
Can't you give me a chance?
You could give me a chance
considering the feelings we shared.
The feelings we shared?
I don't remember sharing
any feelings with you.
We were never really
husband and wife.
Were we ever man and wife even for a
day during our 6 months of marriage?
No, we weren't.
I thought I'd grow to love you
after marrying you like my dad said.
But it never happened.
You can't force yourself to
love someone and
you can't force yourself
to stop loving someone.
That's why our marriage ended.
We never had any love and
never shared any feelings.
They were never man and
wife during their marriage?
They were more like strangers
during their 6 months of marriage?
They had separate beds.
They never consummated
their marriage.
I'm saying there's nothing to stop
Do-hyeon and Ha-na.
I want them to get married.
You're getting ahead of yourself.
Yes, they're dating now.
But you can't predict the future.
I don't like that he was married.
He was someone else's husband.
Ha-na's never been married.
Ha-myung, don't be like that.
Be on my side.
They looked so good
together when they danced.
I recorded them dancing.
This was last night?
Yes, last night.
I even put it on the
company's Intranet.
You have anxiety?
Yes, Mom.
I think something will happen.
Ha-na decided to pretend to
date Do-hyeon for our safety.
But I think she's begun
to really like him.
Ha-na's cheeks were flushed
when she came home after
dancing with him last night.
Do-hyeon's sister wants him
and Ha-na to get married.
Mom, what if Ha-na
wants to marry Do-hyeon?
Should we let her or stop her?
Mr. Sul Jin-mok's a scary man.
It won't go that far.
Why?
Not everyone in love
ends up getting married.
And first love usually never lasts.
And it's no secret that our family
and Do-hyeon's are archenemies.
I want Ha-na to find out how she
really feels and find her true love.
Her true love?
Ms. Jang Ha-na?
Ms. Eun.
What is it?
It's Ms. Jang.
Why did you put it down?
You're both here.
I have a good idea.
I want to create a product called
Return of Hwang-so Soy Sauce and
let the consumers know
we got our name back.
I want to get the public's support
in getting the company stabilized.
We need more starter soy
sauce to create a new product.
And we don't have enough of it.
We have enough for the
first production,
but I'm worried about
the second production.
Yoon-chan, did something happen?
What?
Nothing.
Are you sure?
I'm listening.
Go on.
We have to make more soy sauce.
Every time we make a new soy sauce
at Hwang-so, we have a ceremony.
I should perform the ceremony
but I don't know if my grandpa
will allow me to do it.
Only men can perform Hwang-so's
ceremonies,
and only the first sons, right?
Yes.
That's why this is a problem.
Let's explain it to him and
convince him to give you permission.
What did you show up again?
I came to see my grandpa.
What?
This is not your house anymore!
You can't just keep coming here!
I'm glad you came, actually.
I let you go last time
without hurting you.
But this time, I'm
going to hurt you bad!
Chung-ran, Ra-gong!
What is it, Mom?
Hey, Jang Ha-na!
Why would you ever come here?
We have to beat her!
We have to beat her real
good so she won't come back!
Why, you little witch!
Get away from her.
Yoon-chan...
Who's this man?
He's pretty big...
Yoon-chan?
What are you doing here,
I asked you to get away from her.
What?
I don't care that you're big!
Get out of my way!
We have to get back at her
for what she's done to us!
Mom, Grandma, don't.
Let go of me, Ra-gong!
Don't stop us, Ra-gong!
Mom, Grandma, just don't do it.
You'll regret it.
He's a gangster?
Yes.
You don't want to mess with him.
He beat me a few times.
You don't want to get him angry.
That witch Ha-na's engaged
to Do-hyeon
but she's working with that man?
He's Daichong's president?
How did that idiot girl
get so lucky?
She's got SS Group's vice chairman
as a boyfriend and
Daichong's president
as a business partner?
She must've saved a nation in her
previous life to get so lucky.
So how do we teach
her a lesson now?
Can we ever teach her a
lesson in my lifetime?
I heard you got Hwang-so
Soy Sauce's name back.
You did a good job.
Thank you.
I brought my partner Yoon-chan
with me to ask you something.
What is it?
Please give me your
permission for the ceremony.
The ceremony?
What Hwang-so Soy Sauce
needs to do now is
become independent from SS Group.
If it's not financially
stable in a month,
it will again go back to SS Group.
To be financially independent,
we have to create a new soy sauce.
We don't have enough of the
starter soy sauce in stock.
Please give us your permission
for the ceremony, Grandpa.
Who's going to perform it?
I'm the president, so I will do it.
I can't allow that.
You're a woman.
For the last 400 years, only
men have performed the ceremony.
As someone who knows
the tradition well,
how can you even ask such a thing?
Grandpa, I'm all for
following tradition.
But I believe you have
to learn to be flexible.
Hwang-so Soy Sauce is
in a crisis right now.
I won't allow it.
Tradition is tradition because
it's handed down from
generation to generation.
It wouldn't have any meaning if
it's something you can easily break.
Only men can be royal chefs.
Women can't be royal chefs.
I'm home.
This is not good.
What do we do if we
can't have the ceremony?
We need a new soy sauce to
be independent of SS Group.
We have to find a way.
Let's just go forward for now.
Let's just move on with our plan.
What do you mean?
Let's keep the public's interest up
by making a new soy sauce with
the starter soy sauce we have.
Let's find a way to make
more after we do that.
Okay.
I'll get Do-hyeon's
approval tomorrow.
Why don't we use SS Group's sales
network to sell our soy sauce?
We should sell our soy
sauce at SS Foods' stores.
We can do that since we're
SS Group's subsidiary.
That's a twist.
We're using SS Group
to our advantage.
Jang Ha-na's going to launch a new
product under Hwang-so name?
She's out to humiliate you, Father.
She wants everyone to know she got
the name back and that
she's going up against SS Group.
I'll handle this.
It hurts my pride that
she's attacking us, Father.
Launch of Return of
Hwang-so Soy Sauce
Hwang-so Soy Sauce?
You want to humiliate SS Group?
You can't do that.
What are you doing?
I'm stopping you from
launching a new product.
As a board member,
I'm stopping you.
Stopping me on what grounds?
It didn't meet quality
control requirements.
Our product's top of the line.
That's to be seen.
SS Foods' research team
will review the product.
It takes at least a week.
See if you can sell it
after the review's done.
Too bad it'll be too late by then.
As a board member,
I have no choice
but to close the storage until
the review's completed.
You're being unreasonable.
That's right,
I'm being unreasonable.
You're Hwang-so Soy Sauce's
president and engaged to Do-hyeon!
Why do you get everything?
Why do I have to lose
everything to you?
I'll stop you like crazy.
I'll stop you every time
you attempt to do something.
See if you can do anything.
There's trouble.
There's an order to
close the storage.
Close the storage?
Why?
Jang Ra-hee did it to cause trouble
for Hwang-so Soy Sauce.
I think Mr. Sul Jin-mok's
supporting her.
I should go to Hwang-so Soy Sauce.
Ra-hee ordered the
storage to be closed?
I'm filing a formal complaint.
It's wrong of SS Group's board
member Jang Ra-hee to interfere in
my business for personal reasons.
I'll meet with her.
Do-hyeon.
I'll get right to the point.
You can't have Hwang-so
Soy Sauce's storage closed.
Did Ha-na tell you that?
She told on me?
This is not right.
Just cancel it.
How can you openly side
with her in front of me?
You're the one making me angrier.
The more you defend Ha-na,
the more jealous I get and
the more I want to
cause trouble for her!
Jealous?
What right do you
have to get jealous?
Who do you think you are?
I'm your ex-wife.
I was your wife until
just a month ago.
You didn't give me
time to get over you!
No one can criticize
me for my actions.
Everyone can understand my wanting
to stop your engagement and
come between you and Ha-na!
Going after someone who doesn't love
you is the kind of person you are?
Thanks for showing
me your true colours.
Now I don't even feel guilty
for having divorced you.
Do-hyeon.
If you're willing to play dirty,
I won't lose to you either.
You have my dad supporting you,
but I'm the company's vice chairman.
Let's see who wins.
SS Foods' research team
already went to the storage?
Yes.
I was about to report
it to Mr. Sul Do-hyeon.
Where's Ha-na?
She went to SS Group.
She said she'd turn her
phone off during the meeting.
Who are you?
You're not Hwang-so
Soy Sauce employees.
What are you doing?
We received an order to close the
storage from SS Foods research team.
Ms. Jang Ra-hee gave us an order
to transfer all the soy sauce to
SS Foods' research team.
Let's move everything all at once.
Let's see how much we have.
I won't let you do that.
Who are you?
Get out of our way.
I said I won't let you do that.
Just get out of my way!
Let go of her!
Are you okay, Ha-na?
We have to stop them.
We can't get the soy sauce back if
they take it to the research team.
Who are you?
Are you Mr. Sul,
the vice chairman?
I'm sorry.
I didn't know you were involved.
Just leave.
All right.
But Ms. Jang Ra-hee gave us an
order to transfer everything here
to the research team.
I said leave!
All right.
All right, Young-ho.
More men will be coming
to take the soy sauce.
They'll arrive soon.
It'll take time for us to bring
the soy sauce back
if SS Foods takes
all the soy sauce.
I know it's just temporary,
but let's lock the door.
Let's wait until Hwang-so
Soy Sauce people arrive.
It's an emergency situation because
Ra-hee ordered the storage closed.
I can't get in touch
with Ms. Jang.
I think she went to the storage.
I want to go to the storage.
All right.
I'll have the driver
bring the car around.
What's wrong?
Are you worried
about the situation?
Actually, there's something
that worries me more.
Is it about Ms. Jang?
I keep thinking the same thing.
I'm always a step behind.
And that's making me nervous.
I have this feeling that maybe Ha-na
has someone else in her heart.
Who locked the door?
It shouldn't be locked.
What's going on?
Go to headquarters and
find out what's going on.
I'm glad I can help you
protect your products.
Will you be okay?
Thanks to you I can
sell my product,
but you'll be seen as a betrayer
in your father's eyes.
A betrayer?
What you did affects
SS Group's profits.
And you sided with me
in front of employees.
I'll be in trouble with my dad.
There's another issue.
But when you become SS Group's CEO,
this could come back to haunt you.
It could.
Don't you care?
It's not important to me.
Why are you smiling?
I like that you're
worried about me.
I'm not worried about you.
You're worried about me.
I'm just stating the facts.
Fine.
It's cold.
Let's put more cardboard on here.
What happened to your hand?
Blood... What happened?
You're hurt.
Why didn't you say anything?
It's okay.
It's not okay.
Are you kidding me?
What if you get a
tetanus infection?
It stopped bleeding.
So go to a hospital
when we get out.
How did you know what to do?
I pretended to be a
man for many years.
I got into a lot of fights
but couldn't go to a hospital.
I had to treat my wounds myself.
Ha-na.
Can I kiss you on the cheek?
Did Do-hyeon melt
your frozen heart?
Do you love Do-hyeon again?