Look at me. Calm down.
Calm down.
What happened to the others?
Look at me.
Fucking dead!
The whole fucking platoon!
The Sarge totally lost it, went nuts!
Killed everyone!
Get off me! Let me go!
They're all dead!
All fucking gone!
You son of a bitch!
Let's get the fuck out of here!
No response at the village.
Luc, come on, man, come on.
Sarge?
What the hell happened here?
They wouldn't listen.
The village was cleared.
These people are innocent.
They're all fucking traitors.
You turn around and
they stab you in the back.
Hey, Sarge.
My tour is up.
I just want to go home.
Come on. Let's go home.
Let's go.
Just like the others.
You just want to leave.
Like none of this shit ever happened?
It happened!
And it doesn't just go away.
You just can't walk away.
Do you hear me?
You're a traitor too,
aren't you, farm boy?
No.
Prove it.
Kill her!
Kill that motherfucking traitor.
That's an order!
Get up. Come on!
Come on!
Come on.
Run!
No!
You've got four minutes!
Four minutes!
- OK, next.
- Four more.
- I can't find his tags.
- Excuse me, sir.
All right, here we go.
What the...?
Jesus Christ.
Nice touch. I'd hate to be the poor
schmuck who has to explain this shit
back home to Ma and Pa.
Sir, how do we write this one up?
I mean,
what do we say happened here?
Nothing.
Nothing happened here at all.
MIA. We didn't find anyone.
Do you understand me?
What,
they're gonna call this MIA?
Lincoln, this is Eagle. Come in.
I've got a code zebra.
Can you copy?
Only a few hours ago.
At least ten bodies.
Yes, sir.
- Pack 'em in ice.
- We're moving out.
Great.
Ice.
Let's move it, move it, move it!
Let's go, go, go!
All right.
How's the picture?
- Pretty ugly-
- Very funny.
Very funny.
I need a ladder.
Can you see me?
How's my hair?
Let's go.
- Somebody my size. Yeah.
- Systems check.
Next
- How's the focus?
- All right.
Good. Let's go.
OK, brother, go.
All right, so we got 'em all.
We don't have much time.
- Position seven, status.
- They're bringing the next one out.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, please.
I'll have a statement for you
later on, OK? Thank you.
- Colonel, they killed another hostage.
- Current status.
We can't even take one down.
They're linked to an intercom.
They're in the water.
Colonel, where'd you drop 'em off?
- About a mile and a half away.
- A mile and a half? We got 13 minutes.
Come on! Yo!
Hold on a minute. Hold on.
Hi. I'm with the press - CNA.
- They're waiting for me.
- Right through there.
- I'm canceling the remote.
- Charles, will you relax?
- We have to go live in one minute.
- He's absolutely gonna kill me.
Look out.
Hey, where are you going?
See? There she is.
- I know. I'm running a little late.
- A little?
- That traffic killed me.
- Veronica, we're live in 20.
Where were you?
I called your hotel for hours.
- Your mark?
- I got my mark.
- Come on.
- We're on the satellite.
- Glasses.
Mike.
Mike. OK.
- Ten, nine, eight...
- Nice shoes.
- No feet.
- Stop screwing around. Come on.
- ...three...
- Cigarette.
And live.
With nearly 30 hostages held
inside the power station
the gunmen claim
they will not release any prisoners
until their comrades are released
from federal US penitentiaries.
- Checkpoint two, all clear.
- Checkpoint three, all clear.
Keep your eyes open.
Shut up!
I said shut up!
Hey, do as you're told
and you won't get hurt.
Quiet down.
Checkpoint three, all clear.
- They're at the tower.
- We need a unit.
A mile and a half
in under four minutes?
They're eight seconds behind schedule.
This is Veronica Roberts
reporting live for CNA.
- And we're out.
- See? What'd I tell you? No problem.
No problem? This network
does not revolve around you.
Are you saying
I'm not the center of the universe?
- Don't crack wise with me.
- Come on, lighten up, Charles.
I don't play by your rules,
but I always get you the story.
You think just because you broke
a few stories that you're indispensable.
I had a chat with the network today.
Know what, Ronnie?
No, what, Chuck?
You're fired.
They're entering the drain-off tunnels.
GR13, take aim and hold fire.
- Checkpoint one, all clear.
- Checkpoint two, all clear.
GR44 is in position.
Take aim. Fire.
Fire.
Move in and secure the objective.
Clear that image up.
Clear it.
Got it.
Interceptors are
secured and powered.
- Begin playback.
- Playing back.
- Rolling.
- Checkpoint one, all clear.
Checkpoint two, all clear.
Checkpoint three, all clear.
They're buying it.
Who the hell are these guys?
- OK, OK. Here we go, here we go.
- Terminate objectives.
Checkpoint three, all clear.
Activate interceptors now.
- Homeboy's starting to like this shit.
- Don't be ridiculous.
Continue playback.
Checkpoint three, all clear.
- We're inside.
- Begin phase two.
Phase two initiated.
- Look at this guy.
- How the hell did he...?
- Hold it there, buddy!
- Hey! Hold it, pal.
Two gunmen, semiautomatic,
fully loaded,
main target to rear,
loaded pistol
and explosives detonator.
Shoot him!
You are cleared.
I repeat: You are cleared to proceed.
GR13. All clear.
No injuries. Gentlemen,
I think everybody's OK.
- Arizona team.
- GR44, status report.
GR44, do you read me?
- Problem?
- He's not responding.
Try another frequency.
GR44, status report, now.
Kill the motherfucking traitor.
That's an order!
GR44, respond!
Colonel Perry,
how many UniSols were injured?
Who are these guys?
I will address your questions
accordingly.
This marks the third successful mission
for the universal soldiers,
again without any casualties
and without any injuries.
As to the identity of the UniSols,
that remains classified.
- But, Colonel...
- These men have families,
and I will not do anything
to jeopardize their lives.
Now, excuse me. I have other matters
to attend to. Thank you.
Lieutenant, could I have
a statement, please?
There will be a complete briefing
this evening.
We can't shoot these guys.
We need pictures.
Lieutenant, please,
just one statement. Lieutenant!
Huey...
- I've got an idea.
- No, you don't.
- Yeah, I do.
- I hate when you do this.
Ronnie, what are you doing?
This is too close.
They're gonna see us.
We shouldn't be here.
All these guards.
They must still be in there.
Yeah.
- You getting this?
- They've got one hell of a mobile home.
They're turning blue.
Lowering to final stage...
at 60 sub zero.
- He just froze up. We can't tell why.
- What do you mean, "froze up"?
At the end of the mission,
he became completely unresponsive.
- Did he overheat?
- Colonel, he hardly broke a sweat.
GR44.
Why did you not respond?
What happened?
- Innocent.
- Innocent?
What do you mean by "innocent"?
The village was cleared.
The girl was innocent, Sarge.
Sarge?
Who the hell's he talking about?
That could be an old memory.
We should take him out of the program,
run some tests on him
and find out what's going on
in his head.
- GR44 stays with the program.
- But, Colonel...
He just got a little mixed-up.
Just give him the serum.
OK, guys. Memory clearance.
Take your positions.
Activate injection.
They're moving something else
onto the tarmac.
- We won't get anything from out here.
- Are you nuts?
It's a classified military operation.
You won't get
within ten yards of that truck.
I'll be right back.
You were confused.
I was confused.
You must follow orders
at all times.
I must follow my orders.
- He's fine.
- Well, if you say so.
You're in charge.
Here we go.
This looks pretty bad.
Looks pretty bad.
As soon as the flotation chamber
is filled, we'll have to put him in.
Great.
Why do I always have to do this part?
I hate this part.
Hey, Dr. Haines! Dr. Haines!
Can I get a little help on this?
Jesus.
No casualties or injuries, huh?
Power up the cooling generators
on the flotation chamber.
You got it.
- He's ready.
- Bring him in.
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
Prepare for flotation chamber entry.
Colonel, we've spotted an intruder.
Who the fuck is that?
She's taking pictures.
Huey!
Shit. What the hell
has she done this time?
Start the car!
I think now would be
a good time to leave, Huey.
- What'd you get?
- Redemption.
Let's get outta here.
Do you think we lost 'em?
How you doing?
Veronica Roberts.
CNA.
You wanna help me out?
Thank you.
Hey, easy.
Take it easy, man.
Let go of me!
- Huey...
- OK, OK.
You all right?
OK, they got 'em.
Bingo.
I want to speak to
someone in charge.
- You guys speak English?
- Awaiting instructions.
Tell them to find that film
and bring those civilians back to base.
I'm sure we can handle
this whole situation
if I could make a phone call.
- What's wrong with these guys?
- GR13, get the film and return to base.
The film.
Fellas, I don't know where...
Hey, she didn't do anything.
Christ! GR13, cease fire!
Cease fire!
Do you read me?
Cease fire! I repeat...
Hold your fire. Hold your fire.
That's an order!
No! Let go of me!
GR86, visual.
What the fuck is he doing?
Stop the girl.
Shoot if you have to.
GR44, stop the car.
That is an order.
- He stopped the car.
- Cease fire. Cease fire.
What the hell are you doing?
Come on! Get out of here!
Go! Jesus Christ,
they'll kill us!
GR44, turn the car around.
- Are you deaf?
- You are simply confused.
I'm confused.
What are you talking about, man?
Let's go. Hit it!
Do not listen to her.
What the hell is that thing?
Can you hear me?
Will you stop fucking...
Stupid piece of shit!
Shit! The bitch cut me off.
Go!
I must follow orders.
Bullshit. Hit the road!
Shit!
Woodward,
do something, will you?
Traitor.
He didn't do anything.
Well, they're not getting away
with this shit, I swear to God.
- You ready?
- Just about.
We have to take him out of the loop.
He shot a man.
Don't tell me what to do.
Right now I need every soldier I've got.
We're going after them.
Colonel Perry.
We killed an innocent man.
What do you suggest
we do, Woodward?
Let that reporter run off
with one of our UniSols?
We can't just cover this up.
We have a moral obligation
to tell the truth about this.
I thought you were more clever
than that, Woodward.
This whole goddamn program
is off the shelf.
Do you really think
those wimps at the Pentagon
would allow the regeneration
of dead soldiers?
American soldiers?
I don't think I can be
a part of this anymore.
If this is uncovered now,
we're all going to jail.
Do I make myself clear?
Why did you do that?
Why did you help me out like that?
My tour is up.
Just want to go home.
But I can't until you're safe.
What do you mean?
My God. You've been shot.
Jesus. Jesus, we gotta stop
the bleeding.
Jesus Christ,
it's gotta hurt you, man.
The bleeding has stopped.
Get in here.
Secure your positions.
All right, secure and lock!
What? Why are we stopping now?
What happened?
Out of gas.
You're out of gas.
Why not?
Shit.
God.
Oh, God.
Tracking system activated,
and we're in business.
We've picked 'em up moving due east
seven miles ahead of us.
Estimated time of interception.
- Four minutes.
- Four minutes and marking.
How you doing?
You must be pretty tired
after all that pushing and stuff.
Well, I'm gonna go...
I'll be right back, all right?
- Where are you going?
- I'm gonna go make a phone call.
D'you mind?
OK? OK.
OK.
Change.
OK. All right.
- I need some gas.
- Ran out of gas yesterday.
Refueling truck
will be here in the morning.
You wanna rent a roo.... room?
Nice outfit.
Shit.
Hey, pal,
you don't look so good.
I need to cool down.
Well, all our rooms
all have air conditioning.
Got some with waterbeds.
The pay phone's out.
Can I use your phone?
All our rooms all have telephones, too.
Only $50 a night.
No, look. I don't need a room,
I need a phone.
- What about this one?
- Sorry. That's for employees only.
Since there's the two of you,
that's called double occupancy.
That's another $10. Yeah.
Yeah, OK. Great.
And a matter of
a small $20 security deposit.
- Of course. $20. Here you are.
- Have a nice stay.
Great.
Great. Maybe there's already
something on the news.
Commence UniSol deployment.
B and C teams,
take supporting positions.
GR13, seek and destroy local
communication lines in target area.
And one prays for
the expedient, concise handling
of the terrorist situation.
In a related story, only hours
after the rescue at McKinley Dam,
news reporters become news makers.
Reporting live from the scene,
Chris Garfield.
In a surprising development,
a CNA cameraman, Huey Taylor,
was shot and killed in a motel room
in neighboring Eagle Rock City.
Witnesses allege that Veronica
Roberts, a CNA correspondent,
shot him after an apparent argument.
Cocaine and other narcotics
were found at the scene.
No way.
I don't believe this.
They won't get away with this.
This is crazy.
You must return to your room.
I mean, for crying out loud...
Mother, come here.
There has got to be a phone that works
in this godforsaken place.
- This area is not secure.
- You know, why don't you...
What are you doing?
It's not safe for you out here.
Where are your clothes?
I have to...
I have to cool down.
My God. You're burning up.
I need ice.
OK. OK.
Shame on you.
GR13, continue advance.
Target in center of structure.
What the devil's she doing
with all that ice?
Maybe I should call the police.
I've heard of cold showers before,
but this is just ridiculous.
How you doing?
I got all the ice that I could.
You OK?
How's your...?
Your wound.
It's... It's healing.
I'm... I'm gonna make
that phone call and...
I'll call a doctor or...
something.
Heat and infrared check.
Munitions and firearms identifier
powered and working.
- Don't even start with me, all right?
- Hey.
- And take this lock off. No, I will.
- Hey!
Hey, lady,
what are you doing with the phone?
- You know how much these cost?
- Shut up.
- You got a lot of nerve.
- Will you shut up?
This one doesn't work either.
Women just don't know
how to use a phone.
You killed it!
This is coming out of
your security deposit.
Goddamn it.
He's got her in sight.
GR13 has a lock on the girl.
What do you want me to do?
- Tell him to wait till they're together.
- GR13, hold fire. Maintain surveillance.
Now, back to
Nixon and the War Years, Part Seven.
We will keep America
the strongest nation in the world,
and we will couple that strength
with firm diplomacy.
No apologies, no regrets.
There was no question about that
because, as you know, when I resigned,
later, President Ford issued a pardon.
When I accepted the pardon,
in that I made it very clear
that I regretted what had happened,
and it was, in effect,
an apology for what had happened...
I want that place
completely surrounded.
GR86 and 61, take positions
at the rear of the motel.
On the war in Vietnam...
How are you feeling?
The war is over.
Maybe not.
All focus to visual.
Powering alternate scanning devices.
Motion detectors locked in.
Something weird is going on. None
of the phones in this entire hotel work.
There hasn't been a storm.
We got 'em
in the second room now.
You'd better duck and cover.
- Follow me.
- OK.
The last wall is solid concrete.
He's not going anywhere.
I think we got him trapped.
Well, go ahead. Knock it down.
What?
Get down.
Soldiers, move in.
Where in the hell is he?
- I think we lost him.
- That's impossible.
Garth, get back to your station and
get me some tracking, for Christ's sake.
You have a car?
- Give me the keys.
- Tell him to hurry.
Hurry-
You got 'em?
- Thank you.
- Good.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I am so, so sorry. I had nothing
to do with this. Really. I had no idea.
- They're leaving the motel.
- Damn it.
Come on, Woodward.
I need you out here.
Way to go, Garth.
$20 security deposit, huh?
Woodward.
He's trying to cool himself.
Are you sure
they're not following us?
No.
You're such a comfort.
Buckle up.
- I'm fine.
- It's for your safety.
How can you be so damn calm?
Your buddies just shot enough ammo
at us to destroy Eastern Europe,
and you're sitting here bitching
at me about a goddamn seat belt?
All right, all right, all right.
Here we go. All right?
I'm all buckled up.
All right, look, Mr. Top Secret.
I want some answers, OK?
I mean, first of all, you push a car
faster than my mother drives, OK?
You use ice
like other people use band-aids,
and then you run through walls.
Now, I'm sorry,
but this is not normal human behavior.
Now, just who the hell are you?
Where are you from, anyway?
France or Canada or...
I figured you gotta be French
or something because of your accent.
What accent?
All right, look.
You got a family? You got friends?
Is there a Mrs. 44
waiting for you someplace?
I mean, are you avoiding my questions,
or don't you know?
What the hell
did they do to you?
I don't know.
But I'm going to find out.
Hey, lady.
No smoking around the pumps.
I'm sorry.
Come on. Would you quit
pulling on my arm? It hurts.
- Park the car.
- Park the...?
Let's go.
Park the car?
- I need some help.
- You need some help?
- I can't help you with this.
- Get in.
Come on!
What are you doing?
Come on, man.
Not this again?
Is this necessary?
At least
leave your pants on this time.
Great. Just great.
There must be
a tracking device on me.
What do you want me
to do about it?
Look for something unusual.
Something hard.
All right.
You stay in shape, don't you?
- What are you doing in there?
- Nothing!
What do you mean, park your car?
You never heard of
valet parking?
Valet. Do I look
like a valet?
What does this look like?
Beverly Hills?
Is that supposed to be there?
Yes. Yeah, it is.
It's very normal.
Keep going.
Right.
Update informational
computer scanning system.
They've stopped up ahead
at a single-story structure.
I think I found something,
right here on the back of your leg.
- Cut it out.
- Cut it out?
Wait a minute. I can't cut it out.
I'm not gonna cut you.
Oh, God!
Shit! Shit!
You best hurry up and get out of there.
I got a business to run here.
- Take it.
- What?
- Take it?
We don't have too much time.
God, this is so gross.
Oh, God, this is so gross.
- Are you OK?
- Yeah.
Good.
I gotta lie down.
I want a complete scan
of the entire area.
Enabling infrared.
- That's his car.
- Scanning for body heat.
Got it.
Arms.
Pistol, fully loaded. Desert Eagle,
semiautomatic. That's him.
Motions and heat scan.
Follow tracking.
Flanking advance pattern.
Three teams:
north, east, south.
Converge on my command.
Team advance.
Surround target.
Teams east and south,
prepare for break and ram.
Prepare for break and ram.
Full charge.
- OK, guys, move in.
- Full charge.
No, no! He tricked us!
Hold on!
Move out!
All UniSols, retreat immediately!
Evacuate! Let's go!
Get out of there!
Take cover!
What the hell was that?
Oh, my God.
They're on fire.
Portable coolant.
Portable coolant, quick!
Put him out! Get him out!
Extinguishers! Woodward, Garth!
Garth! Get over here!
Get this guy.
- Quick! Quick! Quick!
- GR74. Get GR14.
Over here, Woodward!
Get him down.
Damn you! Put him out, I said!
Get those coolants ready!
Get that truck operating!
Woodward, get 'em over here!
Hurry UP-
Yes, Sarge.
Whoa.
Get over here! Get GR74!
Get him out!
Put that coolant on him!
We need more extinguishers!
Got it. Let's go!
Come on, hurry!
Well, here I go again.
I'm outta here.
- We're gonna lose these two, Colonel.
- $250 million apiece, we can't lose any.
- Buckle up.
- Seat belt, right. OK, go.
Jesus. He should've buckled up.
He's getting up. Go!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Shit! They're pulling the plug.
Pack it up. We're heading home.
- Everybody, back into the truck.
- Let's move it!
Woodward, what the hell
are you doing?
Yes, it's ice!
Get back in the truck!
Pack it up!
Get back into the truck, GR13.
The mission is canceled.
GR13
I said it's over.
My name is
Sergeant Andrew Scott.
He's just a mess.
Lieutenant, could you contact Colonel
Perry? We'd like him back in here.
Thank you.
You're wasting your time.
- He can't hear you.
- Jesus!
I've relieved Colonel Perry
of his command.
GR13, this mission
has been canceled.
I order you back
to the cooling chamber, now!
Orders?
I'm giving the orders
from now on.
We have a mission to complete.
Any questions?
- Something to drink?
- Yeah. I'll just have coffee.
OK. You?
Brenda?
Yes, Joe?
You want something to drink?
Yeah? OK.
He'll have a soda pop.
Great.
- He's not gonna make it.
- Shut up. He'll hear you.
Dr. Haines...
Look, if he thinks that we failed,
he's gonna kill us both.
You just keep working.
If he asks anything, just stall him.
What's he doing?
Overloading on muscle enhancers.
- He's making himself stronger.
- Great. That's just what we need.
You know, I feel like
I'm back in high school again.
I can't make heads or tails
out of any of this stuff.
But apparently,
whatever they've done to you,
it's been done on a genetic level.
"The Surgeon General has warned
that cigarettes could be hazardous
to your health."
Yeah, well,
don't believe everything you read.
- Hey. That is my last pack.
- Are you ready to order?
Yeah. Just bring us
two of your specials.
Now look, they constantly refer to
a Dr. Christopher Gregor.
Do you recognize that name?
No?
Nothing.
I think I saw a number
in here somewhere.
Do you think you can help me?
Well, it's definitely worth a shot.
- What?
- Why are you doing all this for me?
I'm not. All right?
I'm not doing all this for you.
I'm doing it for me.
You may not realize this yet,
but you are one hell of a story.
I wouldn't worry. When the truth comes
out, they'll probably make you a hero.
Here we go. "CG."
Christopher Gregor.
Look, I'm gonna go check this out. You
stay here and wait for the specials, OK?
- Do you have a phone?
- Out there.
- Thanks.
- Here's the special.
Sergeant Scott?
Could I have a word with you?
I'm all ears.
Your thermal monitor.
It's registering hot.
Nap time.
Are you nuts?
Why'd you tell him that?
Quadruple his serum.
What?
I'm going inside.
When he sits down,
I'll give you a signal.
You increase the pressure
and I'll engage the injection device
on the arm of his chair.
No, no, no.
It'll look better if I go.
- Is there a problem, medic?
- I'm just checking the injection device.
- Was it broken?
- It's making some strange noises.
- I just wanted to make an adjustment.
- Well, there's only one way to find out.
Let's see if it still works.
Dr. Haines!
- Stop it! Stop it!
- Are you ready?
- It's memory clearance time.
- Stop it! No!
- Stop it! You're gonna kill him!
- Dr. Haines!
Let him go!
Don't. Stop it.
- Stop it!
- Get off me! Get off me!
Shit. A fax.
Hey, you got enough money
to pay for all this?
You know, money? Cash?
Dollars? Dinero?
Hank!
Yeah?
We got ourselves a deadbeat
back here.
- What?
- He can't pay.
Move it, Brenda.
Hey, punk, I been slaving
all day making that slop.
- The food is good.
- Fuckin' A it is.
The question is:
How are you going to pay for it?
I don't know.
You don't know.
Ain't that cute.
I'm gonna bust your head, punk.
I don't want to hurt you.
Me? You don't want
to hurt Hank?
I just want to eat.
- Operator.
- Yeah, operator. A local number.
Prefix KL5.
Dr. Christopher Gregor.
Hey, look,
you ugly son of a bitch!
Better put that down, you son of a bitch,
'cause now I'm gonna make you bleed!
- May I help you?
- Veteran's Hospital?
- Great. Operator, where exactly is that?
- 1087 Clinton Avenue.
Clinton. Wonderful.
Thank you very much.
Shit.
How was lunch?
I'm looking for a deserter.
He's traveling
with a female POW.
Beat it, asshole.
Nice necklace. I got one just like it
made out of noses.
Now, they're in this white-and-yellow
Buick with no front or rear window.
Does that refresh your memory?
GR74
Sergeant Scott
has issued an order.
- Will you obey that order?
- Yes, sir.
He would like for you
to hold this for 30 seconds
and then drop it.
One, two, three...
I know which way they went.
- You got a pencil?
- Sure.
By the way, I like your belt.
Can I have it?
25, 26...
Hey! Where's the freezer?
Can I help you?
Yes. We would like to speak
with Dr. Gregor.
Do you have an appointment?
Yes. Yes, we do.
- Follow me.
- Thank you.
- Wait in there.
- OK. Thank you.
Oh, God.
Oh, man. I'd kill for
a cigarette right now.
You would kill someone
for a cigarette?
No. It's an expression.
You know, a figure of speech.
I mean, I wouldn't actually
kill someone for a cigarette.
I might hurt 'em real bad at this point,
but I don't think I'd kill 'em.
- Dr. Gregor, excuse me.
- Yes? What is it?
There's a young couple here to see you.
They say they have an appointment.
Appointment?
Clear!
It's all right, Luc.
It's all right.
It's over.
I... I saw it.
I remember home.
Is he all right? We need to get him into
the bathroom and cover him with ice.
I said stand to attention, private!
Get up!
Goddamn it! The whole
fucking platoon's dropping like flies!
What the hell
are you staring at?
Do you have any idea
what it's like out there?
Do you?
Well, I'm fighting this thing, man.
It's like kick ass or kiss ass.
And I'm busting heads.
It's the only way
to win this fucking war.
And these shitheads,
these yellow, traitoring
motherfuckers,
they're everywhere.
And I,
Sergeant Andrew Scott
of the US Army,
I'm gonna teach 'em all.
- Hey, freeze!
- Get down!
Drop your weapons!
See?
They're everywhere.
How could you, a doctor,
be a party to this?
I've been asking myself
that question for years.
Tell me how it worked.
By hyperaccelerating the bodies
we discovered that we could
turn dead flesh into living tissue.
But to make the process work,
the bodies ran
at dangerously high temperatures,
needed to be constantly cooled,
the brain sedated, controlled.
- Otherwise, it would eventually stroke.
- What are you saying, Doctor?
Dr. Gregor?
Excuse me.
Yes? What is it?
There's something on the TV
you should see.
Thanks.
Officials believe Colonel Perry
was shot and killed early this morning.
Authorities are still looking for
reporter Veronica Roberts,
believed to be linked to the two deaths.
They've set you up.
Closer to home, a robbery
at Hayes Supermarket turned deadly
when three armed men
entered the supermarket earlier today.
The leader of the gang
was videotaped...
Regressive traumatic recall.
What?
Trauma inflicted at the time of death.
See, in Luc's case,
he wanted to go home.
When he awoke as a UniSol,
he returned to that single emotion.
As for Scott, he thinks he's still
in Vietnam fighting the insurgents.
He doesn't realize he's alive.
He's not.
He's dead.
Just like me.
- Be sure to write.
- Now boarding, Los Angeles Express.
Now boarding.
This is insane.
You heard the doctor.
You need medical help.
I think you should turn yourself in and
get started on your treatments again.
- And then?
- Well, then we expose everything.
Dr. Gregor will help us.
I just want to go home.
You don't seem to understand.
There's a chance you won't make it.
- I'm already dead.
- No, you're not.
Goddamn it, you are not dead,
all right?
You're alive, and that is precious.
You don't just throw that away.
Now boarding,
Los Angeles direct line...
A bus ticket?
To Los Angeles.
Well...
- What is this for?
- You're safe now.
He's only coming after me.
You know,
you're making a big mistake here.
You've got your story.
That's what you wanted.
You think...
Last call, Los Angeles Express.
Now boarding.
Last call.
Passengers bound for Los Angeles.
Now boarding. Last call.
You should have left me
while you had a chance.
What, and miss all the fun?
Shit.
We're taking 'em to County right now.
Should get there just after lunch.
Oh, shit!
Get rid of 'em.
Oh, shit.
Got you now, boy.
Jesus Christ.
He's coming right for us.
Hey! Driver!
Get us out of here!
Holy shit!
Excuse me.
You should check on your driver, pal.
He don't look too hot.
- What do we do now?
- We have to stop the bus.
Gee, that's a great idea.
What a concept.
What are you doing now?
What the hell...?
Is it working?
- Oh, God.
- Do you want to play catch?
Oh, shit.
Can't find it. Here.
Oh, God.
Are we having fun yet?
Oh, my God.
You jump-
Wait a minute. What about
stopping the bus? I liked that idea.
- You jump!
- I'm not going anywhere without you.
- We'll jump together.
- OK.
Together.
OK.
Oh, shit.
Hit him!
Hit him hard!
Get the fuck up, soldier!
Get the fuck up!
Fuck!
Freeze!
Now, hold it right there!
Turn around.
Get down on your knees right now.
Put your hands over your head.
Put your hands over your head!
I had three brothers.
Come on. Let's go.
Keys.
Come on! Get up!
Money. Here. Here we go.
Thank you.
Come on, here we go.
Let's go, let's go.
Get in the car.
I'll drive, I'll drive.
Come on, get in the car.
Hurry up.
I'm gonna take you home.
Buckle up.
John, there's somebody
in the driveway, I think.
Mrs. Devreux?
Luc?
John, come here!
Luc! Mon fils.
Wait a minute. What do you mean,
Charles isn't there?
Where the hell is he?
No, look. I don't care what you've heard.
It's not true.
No...
- OK. Yeah.
- I can't believe he's alive.
I'll meet them there.
All right.
All right, thanks.
I'm gonna have to get going.
A news van from the network is gonna
meet me at the sheriff's station.
They still don't believe me, but I think
we'll be able to change their minds.
Are you OK?
So many things are missing.
So many things I remember,
but so many things I can't.
Luc, it has been 25 years.
Such a long time, 25 years.
I'll never get those years back.
Look at it this way.
You look great
for a 50-year-old.
Care for a cup, Miss Roberts?
No, no. I'd better get going, you know.
They'll be waiting for me.
Be careful.
It's turning into a downpour.
OK.
- Thank you. Thank you both.
- You're welcome.
You gonna be all right?
In time.
You know something?
I haven't smoked a cigarette
in almost two days.
Maybe I'll quit.
I'll see you.
Shit.
Where's the key?
Come on.
Shit.
Looking for something?
Ma?
Ma? Are you there?
Devreux!
Devreux, can you hear me?
Nice farm.
Exactly like you described it
back in 'Nam.
Why don't you come out here
and join our little family reunion?
I mean, what the hell are you
waiting for, farm boy? Are you deaf?
Get your ass out here!
We have some unfinished business,
you and me.
Wow! She really
has beautiful ears.
Sarge.
You want me? I'm here.
- Let the girl go.
- Don't tell me what to do, soldier.
I give the orders around here,
and you're gonna have to learn that.
She's a fucking gook traitor.
I gave you an order to kill her. Now
you have to fulfill that order, private.
Scott, the war...
it's over.
Not for me.
Not for her. Not for you.
You can't run from this war, soldier.
Not under my command.
You've grown weak.
You should've taken your...
medication.
Come on. Get up and fight.
Now I'm gonna teach you about
the chain of command, private.
When I say jump,
you say, "How high?"
Got it?
Why can't you get it
into your fucking head?
I gave you an order, soldier.
Now let me see you waste
that gook traitor.
Now, where are we gonna shoot her?
In the stomach?
Nah. In the chest?
No.
I think we should shoot her...
in the head!
Ready. Fire!
It's empty!
Luc!
Oh, God!
Oh, God, help!
Come on!
Luc!
- Run!
- No! No, Luc...
Run!
Run.
No!
Well, that's the spirit, soldier.
I mean, this is
a serious matter, private.
I can't believe you got your poor folks
involved in this too.
I got a little secret for you, boy.
You're up for a court-martial.
- You ready to go to trial?
- Give me your best shot.
Gee, I'm awful sorry about this,
but you're all sentenced to death.
Say good night, asshole.
Good night, asshole.
You're dead, soldier.
No. I'm alive.
You're discharged, Sarge.
- Son.
- You OK, Dad? Mom?
Don't worry about us.
It's over.
Here, let me help you.
Are you OK?
I have a little bit of a headache, but...
Where is he?
Around.
How do you feel?
Like a 50-year-old.