♪ Fixed & Synced by bozxphd.Enjoy The Flick ♪
Who's mad, Who's sulking.
Can you give me
my shoes, please.
Hey!
Wait. I need to do something.
Who wants this.
Everyone changes.
Live broadcast in 10,
9, 8, 7,
6, 5, 4, 3,
Good morning, Manila! Good afternoon,
London! And good evening, New York!
Wherever you are! I'm Marga Castro
and this is Mornings With Marga!
Vangie Sis!
Vangie -Sis!
Where's my cardigan?
The one I told you
to wash last week.
Never mind!
Left where, where to search now.
To start of the week, we have some very
interesting guests here in today's show
to discuss a topic that viewers
will surely relate to!
Now, the question is...
do you really need a partner
to be happy in life?
Ma'am, here it is.
Is a life alone the lifestyle
choice of today's society?
Is it true that nowadays,
people living alone are happier
than people in a relationship
- or someone living a family life?
- Who the hell is that?
This won't take long, please.
You can swallow your
cellphone if you want to!
Please, wait. This is important.
Mayor Lani!
- Hi!
- Tristan! Good morning! How are you?
Good morning. I'm good.
You look great as usual.
Thank you. Give my love
to ‘Fta Isabel, okay?
- Sure. I'll tell her that. Take care!
- Bye!
Hey, are we on for tonight?
Is there a change of plan?
I don't know about you. You
might have other plans.
I'm good. We'll ﬁnish early
at our client meeting.
- Are you going to pick me up?
- But you're the one who has a car.
Pick me up instead.
You're so cheap!
Bye! I have to go.
Sis, I already ran
out of credit load.
Oh well!
Ma, she didn't give me money!
Mama!
Why think, why stop.
- Sorry, miss!
- The hell!
Big ass stupid!
I don't know if I can go.
Sophie, it's her birthday!
You weren't there last Christmas. You
weren't there for ‘Fto Anding‘s birthday.
Okay. Okay. I'll go.
Before this becomes another
major issue. I'll go.
- You know it's gonna mean a lotto her if...
- I know.
I'm going, okay?
What else?
Be there at 8.
You can bring your
husband if you want.
Yeah. Anyway... I have to go.
- I'll see you later.
- Okay.
Good morning, ma'am.
You're done for today?
Not yet. I'll do
some cardio ﬁrst.
Your phone's ringing.
Oh, don't mind it.
- I'll go ahead.
- Alright.
Cellphone all day?
Quit that.
Madame's been giving
you a hard eye.
Are you going to
have dinner here?
I'll be staying late at the
prayer meeting tonight.
Ma! How many times a week do
you go to that prayer meeting?
You just went to
church yesterday.
Lord might soon take
you away with Him.
Miss Schulmann?
I'm Tracy, the assistant of Mr.
Pineda.
He sent me to meet you.
You're late.
What the hell is your problem?!
I'm working!
Why are you mad at me?
I'm just asking.
Then why do you keep calling?!
- Are you monitoring me?!
- What do you mean?!
Am I not allowed to call you?!
Dammit!
We're on-air!
You've been hiding in the corner
whispering to your damn cellphone!
What if I shove
it up your mouth!
It's super emergency.
I'll just call you later.
- Ls this a long distance call?
- No, I just got here half an hour ago.
So how long will you
be here in Manila for?
Around 5 days then I'll
ﬂy back to Hong Kong.
Can I see you tonight?
Why?
You're asking me why I want
to meet up with you tonight.
Well, I just have meeting
that'll finish around
8 or 9 and then I'm free.
Perfect. I have dinner.
It's my mom's birthday.
Oh tell her, I say
happy birthday.
Is the Power Point
presentation ready?
Yes, it's ready.
Will you relax?! You're
getting me tense as well!
I have to go. Just load up
endorphins there at the gym.
I'm near the ofﬁce.
Okay.
Watch it!
Thank you so much for keeping me company
on this beautiful Monday morning!
Until tomorrow, this
has been Marga Castro,
wishing everybody a
great week ahead!
Keep on smiling!
Cut!
What the?! Take this lapel off me!
Dammit! This is irritating!
What the?!
You, you and you. I want to
see you in my office now!
Ma'am, can I have your sign?
Get out of my way!
I told you! If she says take
it off, then take it off!
What's this serendipity
thing you're saying?!
Come on, Peachy. Don't you
know what serendipity means?!
Google it, girl!
And who's that one you
were eyeing earlier?
- Gay!
- Ugly!
Do you think people will watch
us early in the morning
if our guests are so ugly?
I mean, how are you supposed to
get an appetite for breakfast
if you're watching two fat and ugly
and even horribly dressed women
who are single because
nobody wants to fuck
fat ugly women!
Well?
Is there anybody wants
to say anything?
You know what, sis?
He's just so handsome!
My panty almost dropped!
His clothes suit him very well!
He's wearing a long
sleeves stripes shirt
in black pants and
leather shoes!
It's because we're actually
gunning for substance.
Oh yeah, she's right.
Substance. Yeah.
That's right.
But the topic of our show
is about single women
who choose to be single!
Those two women on
our show today,
did not choose to be single!
They had no choice to be single!
Because they're ugly! They're even fat!
They're like roasted pigs in La Lorna!
Sorry.
Do you think I'm being funny?
No.
Sure?
You're insulting me!
My God.
Yes? Who are you?
Why are you watching
my monologue?
And then, we were
together at the elevator.
Our own ﬂesh touched each other.
And then?
Peachy!
We just had our
physical contact!
That damn guy smells so good!
T-TH-S, he wears Prada.
M-W-F, Burberry.
I love it!
Chloe, you're too much!
Are you serious? You're
really sniffing him?
Why not?
Madame, she's Tita
Judy's assistant.
Yes? What can I do for you?
‘Tita Judy's asking for you.
Right now?
She said now. She's waiting
for you at her office.
Okay, thank you.
- Is this the group of Image Plus?
- Yes, sir.
- Mr. Valderama.
- Hi.
I'm Raissa Montelibano. I'm the
Managing Director of Image Plus.
- Okay.
- And this is Sabrina Madrilejos.
She's our Senior Creative Director for...
Have we met before?
Have I seen you?
I don't think so.
Are you sure we've never
bumped into each other before?
I would've remembered
if were so.
I'm mixing you up
with somebody else.
Anyways, you may proceed.
Dan, Tristan called.
It's my mom's birthday.
We'll have dinner there.
Okay.
Tell her happy birthday.
Do you trust your boyfriend
one hundred percent?
Of course.
You know what's difﬁcult about your
situation? It's your boyfriend's job.
There's so many temptations!
Muscular, macho, ﬁt!
Of course! That's his job.
Get people fit.
Surrounded by hungry
women at the gym!
They can even smell his sweat.
Wait a minute!
My boyfriend's a personal
trainer, not a gigolo!
Oh.
Valhalla Tower. Exclusivity with
accessibility and availability.
When you talk about the Valhalla Tower, you
immediately think of the fabulous life,
high-end living with
the best and ﬁnest
that is Vortex
Development Corporation.
Two icons who's
achievements and lifestyles
best represent the
kind of living
that people can expect when they become a
part of the Valhalla Towers Community.
Star athlete, top commercial model,
triathlon hero, Rainier Granada.
Beauty queen, blogger, model and
one-time tv personality, Tara Arambulo.
...for the arrival
of the guests.
Excuse me, Miss Schulmann.
It's Miss Castro
again, Miss Schulmann.
Excuse me.
This better be good. I'm in the middle
of a very important brieﬁng right now.
I'm going crazy, Val!
I'm going crazy!
Marga, you can't go crazy because
you've been crazy a long time ago!
My career is so over.
You're such a drama queen.
You also said that when you broke
up with your congressman boyfriend.
No. This is different.
There are lots of TV stations
you can transfer to, right?
With your experience, you
will surely ﬁnd a job.
You guys aren't in the business
that's why you won't understand.
They're like a maﬁa.
It's hard to transfer to another network
because they each have their own kingdom,
territory.
And I can't afford to
lose my job right now!
So what's your plan now?
I hope that monster Marga
Castro gets her karma!
I hope she gets crashed by
a piano, a steamroller,
or even the broadcast
tower of our station!
But you already announced to Facebook
that you're in a relationship.
You can even announce it on TV Patrol
or Saksi that you now have a boyfriend!
Even my mom gave me a warning.
Here's what she told me.
My child, let me be frank.
You're not that pretty.
In case you thought you're drop
dead gorgeous, well, it's not true.
Really? Your mom said that?
Too bad, Daniel
isn't here, Sophie.
He had a previous appointment.
By the way, Tristan, how's
everything with you?
I'm good, Tito.
Everything3 good.
Tristan said he's going to join
us in Europe this Christmas.
Morn, that's still tentative.
I still have to fix my schedule.
Make it happen!
It's more fun if we're all
together this Christmas.
How about you, Sophie?
My husband won't let me.
Why not?
Oh, well.
Where can we go this time?
Ma, we can go to Venice.
- Venice.
- Yes.
But Venice is like...
Everybody's there.
Oh no, we can go
to Rome instead.
Or Greece. Let's go to Greece.
In Vatican.
The show's ratings are very low.
These people would rather watch
cartoons than watch my show.
Your show is at seven
in the morning.
That's exactly my point!
People would rather watch old
episodes of Popeye and Sponge Bob
than watch me in the morning.
How do you think
that makes me feel?
Morn also said
beware of your boyfriend because good
looking ones can only cause headaches.
They attract kitties.
Girl! Your mother's
one of a kind!
I envy my friend Winston,
the writer of our show.
His boyfriend's really good looking!
And he's kind too!
Those damn queers are
happier than us, girls!
Even good looking
guys are now queers!
It's like a spreading deadly
virus without a vaccine!
It could be an evolution since
there's too many people now!
Number of queers are getting high
so that no one will give birth
and the world population
will ﬁnally be controlled.
That's the solution to the
problem of the Philippines!
Not the RH law, but spread all
gays, queers, fairies instead!
The management gave me one month
to improve the ratings of my show.
Or else, the show
will get suspended.
What?
So they're cancelling the show?
You know what, I knew that.
Eventually, all these
things will come to that.
Even the brightest, most
popular, biggest stars,
one day, will be irrelevant.
But...
I am too young and too
beautiful to be irrelevant.
Right?
Yeah.
I don't know how you do it. You work and
then you study law at the same time!
You know what it's called?
Extreme necessity.
I don't have a sponsor to
help me through school.
I have few relatives but
all of them are
below poverty line.
That's why I'm amazed
with you, best friend!
Sabs, I have news for you.
I got the scholarship.
Really?
Dammit! He rejected my call!
Hey! Who's getting into
your nerve this time?!
What took you so long?!
I've been emoting here!
Girl! My officemate loves to show off!
She ﬁnished something first. Such a VIP!
Oh well! Here are my friends.
- Peachy and Chloe.
- Hi!
- He‘s Winston.
- Winston.
He's our writer. He's the one I've told
you about who has a cute boyfriend.
- Come on! Sit here!
- Oh not too much!
Well, where is he anyway?
He's just parking the car. We just
wanted to make sure you're still here.
You guys might've left already.
- You can order now.
- Love.
She hasn't forgiven me still
for leaving you and her,
for leaving you and your dad.
Ma, can we not talk
about this, please?
I'm worried about her.
She married the wrong man.
You know, ma...
She's old enough to make her
own decisions in life, okay?
Why aren't they
having children yet?
Did she consult a doctor?
Who's got a problem?
Oh My God. Peachy!
Look who's coming!
What is he doing here?
Why? You know Yves?
Baby!
This is Yves. Okay?
- This is Amelie. I work with her. Yves.
- Hi!
And these are her friends.
Peachy and Chloe.
You look familiar.
You work at V Tower
I too, right?
So you know him already!
- He's just sweet!
- You can order now.
Go. Go. Go.
About how many years
will you be gone?
Maybe three or four years.
It depends.
That'll be quick.
You want to have coffee ﬁrst?
Let's go home. Come on.
HEY.
What's up?
So what time will you
be up tomorrow morning?
Well, I have an eight
o'clock meeting.
Eight o'clock?
Okay, let's go.
We're here. You can go now.
You can take that ride.
Why are you so quiet?
What?
You've been quiet.
What am I supposed to talk about
that I haven't told you yet?
We've been together all night.
Nines!
Congratulations for
your scholarship!
Have they exhausted
all the possibilities?
He isn't cooperating.
Huh? I thought he's the one
who want to have kids.
What happened?
I know. He's just
blaming my sister.
They've been married for ﬁve
years and still no children.
But it's not your sister's fault
that she can't have children.
Tell her husband that.
How about you?
You want to have kids?
What?
What kind of question is that?
It's a simple question.
You want to have kids?
I don't know. I guess.
I'm not thinking about it.
Why not?
You don't want to have a family?
I guess.
In the future. Maybe. Yeah.
I don't believe he's
with Amelie's friend!
I can see he doesn't really
like to be with that cheap gay!
What?! You think he goes out with
Winston just out of kindness?!
I know Yves is not gay!
You're just judgmental!
Then what?
Let's just say he's
a neat person.
He's cultured. Refined!
Educated, gentleman!
What are you talking about?!
Cleolilde, didn't you see
what they were doing?!
How did you two meet?
It's exciting. It's in Boracay!
WOW!
The boys at Station 2
were gauging up on me.
They're so cheap!
He came to my rescue!
Yes! The only thing missing is a
horse and a sunset! Right, baby?
After that, we got drunk.
They didn't do anything but grab
themselves and ﬂirt with each other!
They don't even care holding each
other's hands under the table!
They weren't holding hands!
He was just touching and
massaging his hands!
They call that acupressure!
It seemed that your prayer meeting
finished too late last night.
I was home earlier than you are.
Pastor Mike and I have been
doing a lot of things.
What's keeping you both
busy to ﬁnish that late?
Oh, we have lots of projects.
Like?
Why are you asking me
too many questions?
Why? Ls it bad to ask?!
I'd like to have a major
press conference tomorrow.
Why are you asking for
a press conference?
I can't tell you because
it's conﬁdential.
But I do have few
announcements to make.
Madame, are you retiring?!
Why would I retire? Why?
Am I irrelevant?
Oh! Those aren't my words.
- What?!
- Check Secret Manila's site!
Oh shit!
Sophie.
Yeah?
Now that that gossip about that
triﬂer beauty queen is already out,
how is that not going
to affect our pitch?!
Chill. Okay? Chill!
Apparently, 70% of Filipino males are
getting crazy over this slut beauty queen.
Ranging from the ages 11 to 111.
She's the 'it girl“
of the moment!
The object of fantasy of every
functional Filipino male
and quite possibly even
the lesbians as well.
That's why no matter what kind of
morality she has, she can sell!
This is what we need.
This is what Tristan
Valderama needs.
Somebody who can sell his
overpriced condo units!
That's why no matter what kind of scandal
she has with the rich and famous,
do you think the Valderamas will turn
their back to an opportunity to sell?
Ma'am Rai.
- Yes?
- Phone call from the Valderama Development.
Line 1 please.
See? We won the bid!
Hello. Raissa speaking.
Make sure you'll be at the
country club before 12, okay?
Hey. Did your brain stop that's
why you're staring into space?
Did you forget about it again?!
What is?
The lunch with Freddie and Isa!
Remember Freddie and Isa
with Mike and Juliet?!
Right.
Okay.
Don't be late, okay?
What?!
You'll marry him? As in you're
going to marry what's-his-face?!
Why? There's nothing
wrong with it.
- He's not your boyfriend.
- Oh, he is.
Why did I only hear
his name just now?
Well, because it's
been very private.
Private. You.
Okay. Sure.
Excuse me, Val.
I know that I'm this
popular celebrity here,
adored by millions of
fans here and abroad.
Sometimes, I really
just need my privacy.
Oh shut the fuck up, Marga.
The whole country knows even
the brand of your napkin
because you endorse it in
billboards all over EDSA.
Even your boyfriend.
Hey, girl!
Where were you?! Ma'am Karen
has been looking for you.
She's asking why didn't
you go to the taping.
Oh, My!
What happened to you?!
Did your boyfriend beat you up?!
Come here!
So how long have you
known this guy?
Along time.
About two months.
Two months and
you're marrying him?
Why? Ls there a timeline
for those kind of things?
What about you and
this Valderama guy?
How long has it been?
6... 7 years?
That's because Tristan and I
aren't in a relationship.
Oh, is that right?
So what do you guys do when you stay
overnight abroad or when you meet up?
You talk about the Republic
of the Philippines?
He harassed me!
Harassed?
H 0w?
You're getting into my nerves!
We're in public!
Are we doing something wrong?
Are you ashamed of me?!
Dammit. Will you
lower your voice?
People can hear us.
Wow! You're concern about other
people's feelings but not with mine!
You're truly amazing.
Will you stop that drama!
You're giving me a bad mood!
You're so pretentious! And
yet whenever we're alone
in a room, you're the one
who bends over first!
Oh My!
If he truly loves me,
then he'll understand.
Hey!
Try to understand the guy!
You only have an
imaginary uterus!
Wait. Ls he even out yet?
He said he isn't yet.
Who would even believe that?!
Whenever he goes out for a drink at
the karaoke bar with his friends,
those basketball players,
what does he sing?
Regine Velasquez,
Lani Misalucha!
Then he says he's not out yet? His
friends doesn't know about it?!
The hell! “You Don't Have
To Say You Love Me",
a real man he say?!
- Hi, sweetheart!
- Hi, babes!
- Hi.
- How are you?
Good. I missed you so much.
- Remember my friend?
- Hi. Hello. Hi.
Yeah. Yeah. I know you.
We've met before.
Yeah. At Republic?
Or at Acara...
- Aracama.
- Aracama. Yes.
Oh okay.
Val, this is Rainier
Granada, my ﬁancee.
You know he's a triathlete.
As a matter of fact,
he just won the recent
Iron Man in Cebu.
Oh. Wow. That's nice.
I thought you have plans of having a
vacation in the States last year?
Oh yeah. Dan and I
even talked about it.
He said you plan to spend
some days in Chicago.
And then suddenly, you
guys cancelled your plans.
What happened? Why
didn't you go?
I had a miscarriage.
I'm sorry. I didn't know.
I'm just curious, why the
sudden decision to get married?
It's Marga who asked me
if I want to marry her.
- Oh.
- Excuse me, Rainier.
I did not asked you to marry me.
I merely suggested it.
That's not the same.
Suggested.
You called me last night,
you told me to. So I
asked you to marry you.
Then you'll say yes, right?
- Babe, what?
- Don‘t misquote me.
That's not how I said it.
He just misinterpreted it.
Do you really want
to marry Marga?
Well...
it's okay.
Wow. That's so romantic.
True love.
It is.
Right? It's true love.
You know what, Val?
I want to have kids.
I think it's time for
me to be a mother.
Margs, you don't need a
husband to have a child.
What you need is a sperm donor!
- You're so... You're really so funny, Val!
- Right?
- This friend of yours is really cool.
- Yes!
- What is it? Do... Donor?
- She's so funny!
I know I'm late. Sorry, guys. I had
this meeting. It started late.
Oh by the way, Dan.
Have you seen the pictures
of your godchild?
Not yet. Let me see -Oh yeah.
Show it to him.
Can you believe
that's Sebastian?
No way! This is my godchild?!
How tall is he?
- About 5'1?
- 5'7.
And he's what? 11 years old?
- Actually, 10 and a half.
- 10 and a half!
He was just this tall!
And now, woah!
Go on.
I have more pictures.
I'm hungry-Come on!
Tastes good, right?
Of course! You know
I eat like a beast!
You make me eat anything!
You're the one who got
an amoebiasis when we
ate Isaw (GRILLED CHICKEN
INTESTINE), right?
But me, I can eat anything.
That's why I should've courted you.
You're not picky. I can save up more.
Well, sorry. You're a coward.
I was just joking.
She's going to marry this guy to get
attention from the media all over again.
Can't you see it?
Your friend wants people
to talk about her that's
how more and more people
gets interested in her.
That's how your friend
makes a lot of money.
How much does one need
in this lifetime?
I mean maybe there's
more to life than that.
Are you willing to
quit your hotel job?
No.
But...
I will get married also.
Sabs, how long have
we known each other?
Third year high school
at a party.
You were even hitting on
Karen's cousin from abroad.
But sorry, your style
didn't effect.
Because you're so old-fashioned
when it comes to girls even then.
That's not true. She just speaks in an
American accent. She's hard to understand.
Niccomedes, will
you just admit it!
You're old-fashioned.
Fine.
It's because I only
have an effect on you.
I don't think so! You're a coward
if you think of hitting on me!
Why is that? Would you agree to
be my girlfriend if I court you?
You're crazy.
Is that true?
You're so cheap!
What's going on here! Ls this
because of the oil or the vetsin?!
Who is this man you're marrying?
You don't know him.
Of course I don't know him. You've
never said anything about him.
Well, his name is Andrew.
Andrew Chow.
And?
And he's a banker. He's actually
the vice president of his bank.
His family is from Hong Kong.
Okay. I get it.
He's some big shit. Whatever, you know.
He's rich and...
So how long have you've been
known this big ass Chow dude?
Three years.
Val, three years.
And you've never told me
you're dating anybody.
You never asked.
You love him?
Do you think I'll marry
a man I don't love?
What if you go to
the States too?
What if you apply
for a job there?
If I really wanted to go to America, I
would've done that a long time ago.
I should've gone with our
batch mates who have migrated.
You know, when you leave, I will
surely miss you, Nicoomedes.
That explains why your man
treats you like a rag.
It's because you let him.
You let him!
Yeah. Yeah. Now, I know!
I just went a little
overboard with Jason.
A little? You call that little?!
His last birthday, you spent 5,500
to buy that jerk a new rubber shoes!
But it's his birthday.
Okay. Okay. Birthday.
On your mom's birthday, you spent
250 pesos for a chocolate roll.
I'm not like Winston.
What did you say about Winston?!
This friend of mine is having
an argument with his boyfriend.
Then he wants to
break up with him.
You mean the "love
team" broke up?
Yes! They had a ﬁght!
The guy hit Winston
so they split!
Amelie, just a minute.
What's the last name of
your friend's boyfriend?
I just know he's Yves.
Rivera. I remember it
because he has the same
last name as Ariel Rivera
and Marian Rivera.
Hello?
Chloe!
Yves Rivera.
Oh hello there, pretty boy.
Vangie, is Coooy there?
Yes. He's home early.
But your mom's not here yet.
She said she's going to church.
What kind of a church
is that anyway?
Do they hold services at
this time of the day?
Thank you, Mike.
Ady...
Thank you very much for
taking part at the service.
Many were tearful.
About being an ideal
mother to your children.
Oh My. Thank you
very much, pastor.
You truly are my inspiration.
I'm thankful.
Oh Jesus! That's disgusting!
You said you only go
to prayer meetings!
Why are you with a guy?!
Why?! Don't they have
guys at prayer meetings?
Ma, I saw it! You were kissing
that guy you're with!
Hey, Sabrina! You don't have the
right to talk to me like that!
Where have you been?
And who is that guy?
At a prayer meeting and
then we had coffee!
Ma, who is that guy?!
He's Mike.
- Pastor Mike.
- Pastor Mike?!
Pastor?!
Yes! Are you deaf?!
Ma! My God! You were smooching
with our congregation!
Jay, son.
- Dad?
- I bought food.
- Okay, dad.
- The bread's still hot.
This is good to match
with a potted milk.
- Eat with me.
- Okay, dad.
I don't care!
As long as there are at
least 30 photographers
and video coverage for
that press conference.
I don't care! Okay, thanks, bye!
Dammit.
Hey, will you lower you voice.
People are everywhere.
Boy, this girl has problems.
Dude, that chick...
What's her name again?
I wasn't sure it was you.
- How are you, Jaime?
- I'm good, Dan. I'm good.
How's Tristan?
He's also good.
We have to go.
Tara Arambulo?
But, Tristan, we can tell
the agency to replace her.
So we can actually take
her out of the campaign.
Why would you want me
to do that, Jaime?
That whore sells.
We need whores who sell.
That's why my brother-in-law's
crazy about her because she sells.
She does not only sell,
she's also for sale.
What about your sister?
Jaime, this is business.
Leave my sister out of it.
What?
Juliet talked to me.
She said she has a
friend who's a doctor.
Another doctor?
Sophie, stop, okay?
Let's face the fact.
Will you let me finish first?
Please!
Let's face the truth!
Whatever therapy or
medicine they offer you.
You can't have children!
Are you done?
Juliet has a friend
who's a doctor.
And this doctor can
make arrangements.
What arrangements?
Clean, legal arrangements!
In fact, they were able
to help Juliet's friend.
Wait, Sophie.
What's this?
There are women who go to this doctor.
They're
pregnant and they can't
keep their baby.
So what the doctor does, he
looks for parents for the baby.
No.
Daniel.
Please! Please, listen.
The parents will pay for
the medical expenses
of the mom while she's
still pregnant.
And when the baby is born,
when the baby is born, the biological
morn won't see the baby anymore.
And then at the hospital, at the
hospital, Daniel, -Sophie. Sophie.
The adopted parent's name will be
placed on the birth certificate.
Sophie.
I said no!
Daniel, please!
Sophie, I don't want to adopt.
Will you please
give me a chance?
I don't want to adopt! If it works to
other people, well not to me, okay?!
I see how much you love kids.
I see how you...
If I wanted to have a child,
I can.
Not you.
I won't let myself be liable
of your failure as a wife!
Now,
do you have anything
more to say?
Do you have anything
more to say?!
Ma'am, you forgot your phone at the
study room. Someone's calling.
Thank you.
Have you checked your Facebook?
Huh?
I added you.
I haven't seen it. I
didn't checked last night.
Accept my request, okay?
Okay.
Actually, we wanted
to keep it private.
But, we realize we really
owe this to our fans.
We want them to be happy
with us and for us.
Right, babe? Because we know
we wouldn't be where we are know
if it weren't for our supporters.
Do you have Twitter?
Yes, I have. Why? You're
going to follow me?
What's your name on Twitter?
@iamyves
I'll follow you, okay? Then
follow me back so we could DM.
Okay. What's your name again?
Chloe.
- C-H-L-0...
- I know how to spell Chloe.
Bye! Take care!
We'll be submitting our proposals
and our studies by early next week.
Ah, no. Too late.
We have to advance our timeline.
Marketing and Sales need
a proportional stuff
for us to move on ahead
of our schedule.
When do you really need it?
Friday.
Fri...
That's after tomorrow.
Yeah, I know.
You asked me when do I need it,
then we need it on Friday.
Okay! Friday.
Good.
You see, Val. I'm
all over the news.
And I'm not just talking
about our TV station.
I'm also featured by
our rival station.
And tomorrow I'm sure I'm all over the
entertainment page of broad sheets.
Even columns and
tabloids, I'm there.
And you know what, today?
I am number three trending
on Twitter Philippines!
I mean... everybody
is talking about me.
Same with Rainier,
he's also trending.
Do you know how the Philippine
Sports beneﬁt from my decision, Val?
Hello?
Val...
Are you still there?
Yes, still here.
Okay. AHYWBY...
I know this may surprise
you, but I really like him.
Okay.
I mean... Listen, Val.
I know you don't think
much of him but he's kind.
He's just really...
Kind.
Yeah...
Okay.
You know what?! I'm getting
pissed with your answers.
OMG!
He accepted me on Facebook,
we're already friends!
He likes me!
Did you check the number
of his Facebook friends?
1256.
And you're the 1257,
then he likes you?
You know what, Peachy?
I'll unfriend you soon!
Hi.
What are you doing here?
You're not going to let me in?
I just want to talk. That's all.
Oh, look at his body.
Would you even doubt him as gay?
Why don't you go to the gym?!
Those guys who have broad muscles wear
perfect blending of liquid foundation!
Look at that...
In his 1257 Facebook friends, 1
or 2 out of 3 or more are boys.
And they're not
just ordinary boys!
They have good looks
and hot body!
So you're saying that only because
of that, he's already a gay?!
You know what?! I know
you're just bitter!
Because you're boyfriend had a child
with his co-worker in Singapore!
And you can't accept the fact that
he's now happy with someone else.
Fine! Be part of the federation that
believes they can convert gays to real men!
Let's see if he'll give in!
There isn't any
drug or potion from Quiapo
that can change him!
Bitter! You're ugly! Damn you!
Don't fool yourself! You
think you're beautiful!
I am really beautiful!
Why are you marrying that man?
Did it ever occurred to
you that I love him?
But what about us?
What about us, Tristan?
There was never an us. There was a you,
and there was a me... but never an us.
Well, after all these years...
You will tell me that
there's never an us?
Did you even asked me?
Was that even necessary?
I think so?
Come on, Val.
You know me, Tristan.
I don't like waiting.
And the other night, I realized
I'm waiting for something
that's never going to happen.
What if you understood?
That's why I'm leaving.
Because I understand you.
Not bad, Val.
Whenever you change your mind
just tell me.
Yeah, I'll give you a call.
Just tell her.
You're being stupid. Why did you
even attempt to hit on Sab?
Whenever we go on vacation, you sleep
together in one bed and nothing happens.
So what's your plan now?
You're leaving?
You get her number.
I got your back! Just let
me eat the sisig alone.
Have you ever heard
anything from me?
Did I ever meddle
about your work?
But Jays, you know my work hours
in the studio aren't deﬁnite.
Same as mine!
My work at the gym isn't even enough!
It's a little more than the minimum wage.
That's why I have sideline!
Then tell me about
your sideline.
I accept private session!
What else do you think?
Even at night?
That is the problem with you.
You have a dirty mind!
Don't you really trust me?
Don't tell me you're
working on our project?
Mr. Valderama.
If you keep on doing that,
I guess it is better to...
Are you breaking up with me?
Are you working on
Valhalla Towers
at this hour of the night?
In this cafe?
Because I do have
a deadline, sir.
But I was the one who
gave you a deadline...
So that means I could
ask for a time-out?
Okay... I'm sorry.
Sorry for being a nagger and if
I'm asking too much. I'm sorry.
I just can't forgive you
by being always sorry.
Son of a bitch! Are you
seriously breaking up with me?
So now you're cursing
my dead mom!
That was just a ﬁgure of speech!
Asshole!
Amelie...
What else do you want me to do?!
I said I'm sorry!
Will you please stop
making a scene here?!
You're embarrassing!
Girls cry at defense, right?
Defense?
If you can't defend
yourselves, you, girls, cry.
Mr. Valderama, you should be more
careful with women who don't cry.
Yeah, I know.
I know a girl who never cries.
Or maybe she doesn't cry
in front of anybody.
There were also
boys who cry a lot.
Yeah.
Just like my best friend,
he cries easily.
We watch not-so dramatic movie at times...
and yet he cries.
You like weak men?
I just admire men who can
cry in front of others
including and especially women.
- Am I oversharing Mr. Valderama?
- Oh no! No! No! No!
It's amusing me. Go ahead!
Can you do me a favor?
We're not in the ofﬁce so please
stop calling me Mr. Valderama.
Call me Tristan.
And you're Sabrina.
You still remember my ﬁrst name?
Of course! You almost run
over me while jogging.
You know what? I
may not cry easily
but I have a very good memory.
Shut up! Let's go!
You're leaving without
settling things.
Let's talk about this next time!
You're embarrassing.
Jason! Jason!
A little after 1:00?
You drove alone about 1:00?
What's the fuss? I
do it all the time.
What time will you be out?
Let's go out after your work!
I can't, Niocs. You know
we're photoﬁnishing
our proposal for the
project launch.
It's our deadline tomorrow.
Oh, I see.
Okay, take care then!
You too.
Stop it! Not tonight, I'm busy.
Are you not even tired?
Ma! Ls there any problem?
Do I only call you if
there's a problem?
You just don't call like this.
Can I invite you for dinner?
But that's our usual rule.
I mean... you join a
beauty pageant and then
you win it and you
become a beauty queen.
And then you enter
show business.
For some but not for me.
And how can I enter
show business?
I don't know how to sing, I only dance
a little but I don't know how to act.
And I'm not even good in lying.
Of course not!
Oh, she's not a liar.
No one even believes her.
Hi Yves! What are you up to?
I'm buying coffee.
So are you going to the
French Film Festival tonight?
How did you know that...
On your Facebook! You even posted a
status that you're going alone! Right?
Or do you have
someone to go with?
Oh, no one. I used to
go with Winston but...
I'm also going there tonight!
Okay.
I'm going alone. F.Y.l.
Oh Tara! Let's talk
about your love life.
What about my love life?
Guys, I'm sure...
Look at you, having that pretty face, don't
tell me you don't a have a love life.
Let's just say that, a lot of people
love me... and I have a life.
You're funny! You answer like
you're in the show business.
No, really? I mean is there
someone special in your life?
Let's just say that I'm happy.
Happy that there's someone
special in your life?
I mean... I heard...
Oh Marga, don't be
fooled by the hearsays.
So are you denying that there is
someone special in your life?
So you're also planning to
watch Hiroshima Mon Amour?
Oh yes! I watched that
movie in DVD and...
and the actors were very gifted.
Emmanuelle Riva.
OMG! I'm such a fan!
I'm not denying anything... I'm happy!
That's all I can say.
Like you! Am I right?
Of course I am! Everybody
knows that I am so happy.
I actually know him.
I'm sure you do
because he's popular.
Speedy?
Oh! You didn't know! His mom used to
call him Speedy when he was a baby.
Oh, I know a lot of
things about Speedy.
That's why I'm sure
that you're happy.
Just shut your mouth.
Actually...
Everybody knows, like I
said, I am very happy.
And that's why...
My only wish for you Tara is that...
someday
you'll meet the perfect
guy who'll love you.
Someone that would love you
and willing to marry you.
Ouch.
Thank you!
Thank you! Thank you!
Okay! Let's watch French Film Festival
together so you won't go alone!
Huh?
I'll be out by 5:00!
Wait! What is the time
of the screening?
7:30.
Perfect! I'll see you at our office lobby
at 5:00 or 5:15! Do you have a car?
I don't have!
That's ﬁne! We can take a cab.
Then we will eat there! Okay?
So I'll see you at 5:15?
Okay!
I'll post this on Twitter!
Finally, it's happening. We
are going out on a date.
I thought you said your ratings peeked up
after you're big romantic announcement?
Yes! For one day!
Then they went back
watching SpongeBob!
Well maybe it's best since
you're getting married.
Don't you even mention that!
Val?
Do you think people would be angry
if I would cancel the wedding?
Yes?
Sabrina?
- Who's this please?
- Tristan.
- Tristan?
- Tristan Valderama.
What can I do for you, sir?
You're ready for tomorrow?
Oh, we will be there with
our campaign proposal, sir.
Good. Miss Madrilejos, impress me!
Okay?
You will be Mr. Valderama.
Good! Good.
I admit it.
I just got carried away
because...
Because what?
Because I was confused.
So how are you supposed to tell the people
that you don't to marry him anymore?
That you're cancelling the wedding after
you told everybody that you're so in love.
Do you think people
will get angry?
You seemed to be in a bad mood.
How was your guesting
with Marga Castro?
You didn't watch?
How? I can't watch it at home.
That girl asked about us!
With names mentioned?
Why? Are you afraid that
your wife would know?
You think Sophia
still doesn't know?
The world talks about us, Dan!
I want to hear it from you.
Not with somebody else, but you.
Are you alright?
Morn, what makes you
think that I'm not okay?
I know.
Okay.
I don't understand.
You perfectly know what
I am talking about.
If a person does not respect you
there's no reason for you to stay.
Not only because you signed a marriage
contract, he can't treat you like a trash.
Why are you not saying anything?
You just can't understand me.
You know Tara, Manila
is a small town
pretending to be a big city.
People always talk about each other
because everybody with somebody
knows each other.
So get used to it.
Dan, I have something
to tell you.
What?
I just hope you'd be happy because I'm sure
that people you know will talk about us.
"M Pregnant!"
What?
You've always wanted
to be a daddy, right?
Soon, you'll be a daddy!
So, did you like it?
Very much!
All a while I thought
you were already asleep
because you're eyes were
closed when I glanced at you.
Oh, no! I was just savoring
every part of the movie.
Wait.
How was that if you're not
reading the subtitles?
So you're telling me that
you can understand French?
Un p000 mas!
That's Spanish, right?
Oui!
If he is hurting you
because he meant to. Why
are you willing to suffer?
He humiliates you!
It's my fault because
I can't have a child.
Sophie.
It's my responsibility as his
wife to give him a child.
But Ma, there is
something wrong with me!
The doctor already told that it's
impossible for me to have a baby.
Because of that
you let him treat
you like trash.
You're being punished because
you can't give him a child?
You're a woman. You're his wife.
Your job isn't only to bear a child.
That's because
you're being stupid!
You should've broken up with him!
He's not respecting you anymore!
And yet you're acting
like a martyr!
It's because I love
that stupid guy!
Boys only differ in smell, shape
and size of their package.
Those are the only possible
differences of their packages.
Unless...
a horse gets ashamed of
what he's got down there!
You really have a dirty mouth!
You're talking to two women!
Wow! You hypocrite! You're the one who's
crazy over your personal trainer.
Because he carries a huge one and
has a high stamina! Get real!
You can't measure man's love in
the level of you're suffering!
If that man don't respect
you anymore, it only means
you have to go!
It's enough.
But we're not the same, Ma.
I ﬁght harder for
my relationship.
I do not give up easily.
And you think
I didn't ﬁght hard
enough for our marriage?
What else could be the reason
but you didn't love him
enough to ﬁght for him.
Are you hungry?
But the restaurants here inside
the mall are already closed.
Do you like to order some take-outs
then we could eat it at home.
We can't go to my place.
I have two room-mates in my condo.
It's small,
it's a hassle and it's
only one-bedroom.
We can go to my place. My roommates
are call center agents so
I'm usually alone at night.
That's alright Yves, I
know I can trust you.
Oh, you have a visitor.
Who?
I thought you're coming
home late from the office.
HEY
I brought you food, I
thought I won't see you.
Before you cry over
a boy, be sure that
he will cry more
when you break up.
Keep that in mind!
It seems like he has a
bigger problem than you.
It's because
our gay friend feels bitter.
You know why?
His ex-boyfriend, Yves...
is already dating someone new.
Oh, that hurts!
Of course, he can't accept that his ex is
now with a girl while he's still grieving.
Really?
Is this for real? Gossiping about
the person who is in front of you?
What are you
whispering to Pechay?
Nothing, don't mind it.
This might be one of the
things I'll miss here.
Sabs, stop being cold with me.
Why on the earth would
I be cold with you?
I knew that it was your plan.
You already told me before
that you want to study in US.
Sabs, would it make you feel bad if I
won't come home in the Philippines ever?
You thought that I believed when you
said that you'll be gone for 3-4 years?
You know what our
problems is Niccs?
We know each other so much that we can
no longer hide things from each other.
That's why you've changed when I
told you that I'll be leaving?
That's not true.
Sabs...
it's just coincidence,
I was busy and...
I thought you said that we know each other
too much that we can't lie to each other?
How can you say you
love my father?
You left him!
One day Justin and I woke
up and you were gone!
And don't tell us that we're too young
to understand because we understood!
And would you know the
reason why I did that?
What then?
You fell out of love
with my father!
He didn't love me.
How can you say that?
He gave you everything!
Because he had to.
Because I am his wife,
but he didn't love me
because I was the one
whom he wants to love.
I left him because I
want him to be happy.
I gave him freedom.
You can't say that.
Until the day he died,
Papa never re-married,
- he never even searched for another woman.
- But... but you can't say
that your father died unhappy.
If you're going to
make a decision,
please... think of yourself.
And not about what others think.
Do you think this
would be easy for me?
That I am happy?
Because ﬁnally...
- the long wait is over. But...
- But what?
If I would be in
your situation...
I'd choose to leave, Nicoo.
- Sabs.
- I want you to be happy.
That's all! That's the important
thing, that you're happy.
- Sabs.
- Don't.
Please.
You're not making it any easier
for me, you're hurting me!
Sabs.
Please.
Just don't say anything, okay?
Don't say anything that I will remember
later on and will only hurt me more.
Just don't say anything!
How many lives here?
Four, including me.
And all of them work at night,
so we're totally safe here.
Safe with what?
Whatever!
Have you had a
girlfriend before?
Yeah!
Really?!
Why are so shocked?
Well... You know because...
Because of Winston?
Were you informed that
Winston has a child?
What?!
That gay has a child?
So...
How many girlfriends
did you have?
Serious or ﬂing?
Whatever.
I had a lot of ﬂing.
For serious ones? Maybe 3 or 4.
Oh.
All your serious
girlfriends were girls?
Of course!
So you were not serious with
your relationship with Winston?
That was only a ﬂing?
Actually, I don't know.
I'm confused.
Yves... What?
Let's drink tequila!
Did you tell her the
truth about Papa?
Did you tell her
why you left him?
The reason why you left us?
No!
Not anymore.
What's the point?
Ma...
We have kept the
secret for years.
Most of people who knew
about the truth were gone.
You know before Papa died,
he told me that it
was his choice.
He was sorry for hurting you,
sorry for hurting all of us.
You're dad didn't
re-married because
right from the very start,
he wasn't looking for a woman.
Marga! What's the
meaning of this?
What's this thing online?
Why did the reporter said that
our wedding was called off?
Dear, will you do
me a favor, please?
Please just relax, okay?
What you read from the internet was true.
I changed my mind.
You what?!
You changed your mind about our
wedding and I wasn't informed first?
Because you are busy.
I can't believe this!
After you announced publicly
that we're getting married
in less than two days,
you'll cancel it!
Is this some kind
of a joke to you?
Hey, you better
watch your words!
You're insulting me!
And will you please
stop shouting at me?
Do you want me to be happy
about how you treat me?!
Marga! I'm the one living
with a peaceful life!
Then you asked for marriage!
Excuse me!
Are you saying that
I forced you?!
I beg your pardon! And I mean I
really beg your big effin‘ pardon!
You may be Rainier Granada,
but I am Marga Castro!
And Marga Castro is...
Marga Castro!
You better remember that!
Hello!
Hello, Marga!
Idiot!
Come here! Oh, My God!
I'm so stressed!
You worry me too, you know?
Ma, you don't have
to worry about me.
I can take care of
myself and you know it.
I don't want you to be alone.
I don't want you to
be all by yourself.
I want you to take risk.
What do you mean? You know
that I always take risk.
Not with this.
Come on.
Go get a life!
Okay?
Enjoy!
Good night, Ma!
Good night!
Okay!
Go on! Last shot remaining.
How am I supposed to go home now.
I feel the heal in my face.
I can't even feel my nose.
Ignore it! Don't worry
it's our last shot!
Are you getting me drunk?
No... we're just having fun!
Imagine... we watched
a French movie...
then we ate pizza, and now
we're drinking tequila!
Can I ask you something?
Why are you acting like a cat?
You're so clingy.
What do you prefer?
A girl or a boy?
- Chloe, are you okay?
- I'm okay.
Stop! Let me go home!
Go on! You can do it!
Just give it a try!
Stop Chloe, please.
I respect you!
I'm only helping you
to get a new life!
What!
I want you to be man again
by making me a woman!
Yves!
Kiss me. Just kiss me!
Good morning everybody! How's
everybody doing this Friday morning?
Are you ready?
As promised, Mr. Valderama
our campaign is ready.
Complete with the time
tables subject to the
approval of your sales
and marketing team.
Great! Let's do this, Sabrina!
When?!
When did this news come out?
Obviously, she was the one responsible
of everything that was written there.
Have you heard the
reaction of the people?
- I know!
- What are you up to?
Are the guests lined
up for tomorrow?
Madame,
were the stories true?
The ones written in...
- About me and Rainief?
- Yes, yes.
Yeah it's true, the
Wedding's cancelled.
All the tabloids are
talking about you.
Well, that's good for
the rating of the show!
Let me see that.
Certiﬁed PPP, what
do you mean by that?
Tell me! What is the
meaning of certified PPP?
Pambansang Pekpek ng Pilipinas
(NATIONAL VAGINA OF THE PHILIPPINES)
On the other hand, a whore.
Oh, my God!
Is that so?! See?! You're evil!
Once you started
dreaming on somebody,
you don't care even if you start
to act like a snake around him!
Hey! I did not!
Do I look like Galema?
Zuma's daughter?!
I didn't snatched him away and he
already broke up with that gay!
But still, you knew
his ex-boyfriend!
Shut up!
I only knew him but
we're not even friends!
He‘s Amelie's friend! He was an
acquaintance! And besides...
You're a witch!
What have you done to him?! What
happened to you last night?!
You raped him?!
Madame...
What are you doing here?
You texted Karen that you
need me here to discuss
the line up of the guests
for the next two weeks.
Okay, follow me.
So Mr. Valderama, is there
anything we can do for you?
Oh no. Everything's good.
It was a great day! Congratulations
on the presentation. Job well done!
I just like to speak with Ms.
Madrilejos for a minute.
Okay!
Sabrina...
I'm sure you're going back
to the ofﬁce after this?
Yes.
What would be the best
time to call you?
You can call me anytime for
suggestions and corrections.
No. This is not about work.
This is...
This is personal.
I like to see you.
Are you asking me out?
Yeah.
What makes you think
I will say yes?
You're planning to say no?
I don't know yet.
I know you're not gonna say no.
How are you so sure?
Because I'm cute?
I thought you're going
to present me something?
Right now?
What do you want to do? Talk
about my personal life ﬁrst?
Then you will tweet it to your followers?
Or you can post it on Facebook
I do not do that, Madame!
You think I don't know what
you do behind my back?
When you're facing
me, you're smiling.
But the moment my back is turned you
say all these terrible things about me.
And to think...
I am the one who's feeding you!
So, what?
Talk!
Our theme next week will be "survival“,
and we will start with cancer survivors."
You don't know how hard it is.
What?
They say that a career in
media always have a deadline.
People always want
someone younger,
someone more beautiful.
And the networks?
They want someone cheap...
Someone they can easily control.
You know those fans...
they have no loyalty.
One day, they scream for
you, they love you...
And then the next day? Different
insults will be thrown to you.
I don't want to be remembered as
the "Philippine National Vagina“."
Do you understand me, Winston?
I mean, do you really
understand me?
I'll try... Promise!
After this day, I won't
be talking about this.
Because I have to move on.
Getting engaged to Rainier
Ganado was a very big mistake.
Oh! He's good in bed!
But he is so stupid!
There! I said it!
He's an idiot!
I'm just attracted to his legs!
That, I understand, Madame.
You may go now.
Yes. Thank you, ma'am.
Did you have breakfast?
Yeah, I ate already.
I took a bath ﬁrst.
I'm in hurry.
What the hell are you doing?
Diorissimo.
Huh?
Sometimes Lily Dior.
And on special occasions,
like your birthday?
Chanel No. 5
I know these scents because
these are my perfumes too.
You're with your woman
all night long.
And you bring home all
of her expensive scents.
I'm not stupid, Daniel.
And don't treat
me like an idiot.
So what are you
trying to tell me?
You're leaving me?
You're leaving home?
No.
This is my house.
I live here.
And there is no space for your
woman's smell in my house.
I'm not going to stop you if you
want to be with your woman.
If it will make you happy.
I will respect that.
But don't you ever bring the scent of
your cheap woman here in my house.
If you can't leave without
her, then go with her.
I want to tell you this
before it reaches you.
She is pregnant.
Get out.
What?
I know you heard me. But I
will repeat it for emphasis.
Get out of my house!
Wear your clothes, and get lost!
What are you doing? Sophie stop!
Sophie, stop that!
Stop!
Don't you ever touch me while you
still smell like your cheap woman!
That disgusting woman
is such a primadonna!
She thinks that Gretchen Barreto
will give a damn of her beauty!
I thought you won't be angry?
I'm not angry. Do I
look like I'm angry?!
Fine! You're not mad! But I thought you
already moved on from your boyfriend?
I never knew that your friends are
that kind of people. You tramp!
So it's my fault
that you broke up?
Marga?
I went all the way here for you.
Open this freakin door right now.
Marga?
Fine. If you want,
I'm gonna leave.
I just go and I won't
even go to your funeral.
I want to die...
Okay.
So you want to die.
And so?
Do you know what people
are calling me right now?
PPP. Pambansang Pekpek ng Pilipinas.
(PHILIPPINE NATIONAL VAGINA)
Well, it's cute...
And it suits you.
It's not cute.
They are insulting me.
Marga, in all the things
you've done in your life,
you think you will be the
next Pedro Calungsod?
Does she know what you
really feel about her?
So what will Nicoo get
when he tells her that?
You will go to America and
you will never go back.
And God knows what can
happen when you're gone.
Now tell me.
Can you really take the fact
that you're leaving and she doesn't even
know about your true feelings for her?
I want to die!
I would rather die
than be a loser
I would rather die right now than
be a loser and they even insult me!
Okay. But before you die, get dressed.
Because we're going out.
No!
I don't want to go out! I
don't want people to see me.
Can't you see my
fans are mad at me?!
Stop that! What fans?
There are no fans to where
we're going. Hurry!
Huh? Really?!
No fans?!
What now?
Have you decided? Are
you going to tell her?
Pressure. Pressure. Pressure!
So, what?
You're going to
propose to Sabrina?
Are you crazy? She knows taekwondo.
Do you want her to kick my butt?
So what are you going to say?
You know, she already knows what
you really want to tell her.
You seem different.
Just answer it. You're
such a drama queen.
But why are you mad?
Because you always insult
me every time I call
or text Jason when we're
not in good terms.
- Now you're the one...
- And who told you I'm gonna answer?
My friend.
If you really don't want to answer that,
you should have cancelled that call.
Answer it.
Why did you call?
"“Hello" is the standard
opening line right?
Don't waste my time,
what do you really want?
Hello? Hello?
Are you busy?
Are you with anyone?
If I'm in a relationship, do you
think I would go out with you?
Even if you gave my company one
of our biggest project this year
I don't know... Would you?
No.
I take relationship seriously.
What about you?
What do you mean what about me?
Do you take relationship
seriously considering
that you can get
anyone you want.
You know, my situation
is not that easy.
Because...
They just... they just want
me for what I can give them.
They don't really need me...
Other than just use me.
Nicco, you want us
to take you home?
No. Just take me to the cab.
Why? Where are you going?
Did you call her? Maybe
she's not at her house.
What? I'm assuming she is.
Hi, Jason.
- Good evening.
- Let's go.
We went here to take your
mind off your problems.
Not to bring you at
the emergency room.
You know, I really don't know what to
do If I lose my job at the network.
Come on, you know that's
not gonna happen.
On TV, when you're not bringing
in cash for the network,
they won't care
about you anymore.
They won't even accompany
you to the gate.
I don't want to live this life anymore.
I'm so tired.
I'll drink to that.
What do you mean.
You're happy in your life!
You, crazy woman.
Margs. I'm the one
getting married.
What?
How could you do this to me?
Of all people in the world,
how could you do this to me?
Do what?
What food did you give Tristan
Valderama to marry you?
Don't say that you're expecting
to be that guy's girlfriend.
Well, he already told
me that he is bisexual.
My gosh, you crazy woman!
Hey, at your age, you still
believe in bisexuals?
Friend, a man nowadays is
either straight or gay!
Being bisexual is just his excuse because
he wants to learn how to use an eye liner!
You're late.
Gosh, I was with Winston at the mall. He
is so depressed because of what you did!
Valentina, the mortal enemy of Darna,
and above all, Queen of Snakes!
Look who's talking!
As if it's a big sin to...
Hey! You seduced the
boyfriend of a gay!
You're more gay than any gay!
Girl, is it my fault?
Is it my fault that I can give him
what he can't give to his boyfriend?
But you are not
effective after all.
Why?
Ask Winston where he is.
"What? The boylel had a “return
of the comeback" to sis?!
Correct! And he's even the
one who called fairy.
You know, you're such a meddler! I
don't believe in your press release!
Press release?! I'm was with
Winston when his boylel called.
What?
Hey. I'm sorry...
Now, you're begging me?
After you have insulted me?
I didn't insult you.
I just punched you.
If I take a nap, you'll suddenly
pursue anyone you want?!
You're making me crazy!
Who are you talking about?
That ﬂirty friend of Amelie you're dating
while watching Hiroshima Mon Amour!
And you even did it with her!
What are you laughing at?
It didn't drive you crazy?
You gave him a clam to eat, but
he still chosen the eggplant!
Wait, wait, wait...
Maybe the clam is not... Fresh!
Disgusting!
Stinky!
You're a maniac! Doesn't
your conscience hunt you?!
That girl, she looks
like a Rottweiler!
Wait!
Who told you that I did
it with Amelie‘s friend?!
I didn't touch her!
Babe, even though I'm jerk,
I still have fear from God.
Babe...
Oh, Hi Tristan!
Hi.
Margo Castro, this is
my good friend Sabrina.
Hi. Hello.
And this is Valeria, Sabrina.
Let's go? I think we need to go.
It's nice to see you.
Take care.
You okay?
Yeah I'm okay.
I'm always okay. Let's go.
Do I have any messages?
Yes, ma'am.
Mr. Chao called. Andrew Chao.
Andy called here?
Yes. He said he was trying to
call you but no one answered.
My phone is in mute.
Did he say anything?
Sir, we have a problem.
Room 1505 called. There's something
going on the other room.
What's going on?
They said there's a ﬁght and
they might kill each other.
Call the duty manager.
Let's go to the 15th ﬂoor.
Let's go.
You animal! I will kill you!
Let me go! I will kill that!
What's happening?
Damn you! Damn you!
Oh my gosh!
- Jason!
- Let me go!
What the hell is that?
Oh my! Did you see that?
Sabrina, can I take you home?
I can't leave my car here at
the parking lot overnight.
It's a Saturday today right? You
don't have work tomorrow right?
It's okay.
It's just that my mom might wonder
why I didn't bring the car home.
Thanks for tonight though.
HEY
I just wanna...
thank you also.
You're welcome.
May n?
Yes, you can.
Sabrina?
Nicco! What are you doing here?
Do you know him?
Yes, he's my friend.
F ﬁend?
Yes, as in...
friend.
Tristan, {his is
Niece, my best (ﬁend.
- Nicoo.
- How are you?
I called your house, they said
that you're still in office.
So I went here for you.
But there's no one around.
And then I saw your
car, and I got nervous.
It's okay.
Sabrina...
It's okay. He's my best friend.
Anyways...
call me when you get home.
Yes, sure.
Promise?
Okay.
Nice meeting you.
I got the mail from
the US Embassy.
I will have my interview
in two weeks.
Then?
That's it.
That's all you're
going to say to me?
I want you to know that...
That this is ﬁnal decision.
It seems that everything
is okay already.
Ma'am is asleep.
She told me to come
here at 12:30.
So where is she? I'll go to her.
But she might get mad.
She's the one who told me to go here!
Get out of my way!
- Oh no!
- Ma'am Marga?
It's Karen.
Madame, it's already 12:30.
Madame?
Madame! Oh, My God!
Oh, my God!
What happened to her?!
I don't know!
Call the guards downstairs.
Tell them to call an ambulance!
Hurry!
Oh God! Oh God!
You son of a bitch!
You bitch! You never
did anything right!
And I'm the one you
choose to call!
You're now dragging
me to this stupidity!
Damn you! Damn you, asshole!
Die!
I admit.
I was wrong.
I was so wrong to try
take my own life.
Because this is a
precious give from God.
And I know I have no right to take what
is only loan to me by the Lord God.
And you know...
To all of you...
Through this situation and all the
things I've been through, I realized
I don't need a man to be happy.
Because I know
that unless I can
be happy on my own,
I can never be happy in
the arms of someone else.
I left him, Ma.
It's strange.
I know that I should be sad.
But I'm actually quite happy.
I don't understand.
I know exactly what you mean.
Hello, Val.
Hello?
Hello? Are you there?
Val?
Have a safe trip!
Andy?
I'm on the way home.
See you.
What did the people
say about me?
How many columns in this newspaper
is about my suicide attempt?
Hurry! Tell me!
You're the topic of
the nation tonight!
Oh, my God, me?!
What about me? Why? Me?
Oh my God that's good!
It's about depression
and abandonment.
Well, I guess it's good.
It's a good exposure.
How about the response
of people about me?
What's the response of the people about me?
What about the network?
Are they happy with all of
this audience response?
Oh yes, ma'am!
They're very happy!
They even though
you're going to die.
They are happy about what
happened that you're okay!
Oh come on!
But you know, Karen...
I just don't get it...
where do my bruises come from?
I mean, it really hurts.
Because when you passed out, you
rolled all over and you hit you head!
I carried you!
Wasn't I in the bed?
No, you're not. I
carried her, right?
You're the relative?
Babe.
Hi, babe.
Hey, why are you late?
There's an issue with my roommates.
It's so irritating!
Who's mad, Who's sulking.
Who's to blame Hey, what is it?
Good morning sir.
Good morning Jessica, can
you fix up my papers?
- Yes. Sir.
- Thank you very much.
- Good morning.
Everyone changes Good morning.
Good morning.
Why think, why stop.
Why wait when there's nothing Ieft.
Who failed, who's mad at you.
Left where, where to search now.
Everyone changes.
Why think, why stop
Why wait when there's nothing Ieft.
Everyone changes.
Why think, why stop
Why wait when there's nothing Ieft.
Why wait when there's nothing Ieft
when there's nothing left
when there's nothing left.
Everyone changes
♪ Hope it helped -> bozxphd ♪