Action, Jake.
Cut.
Look, what's the problem here?
Remember, I want you to open the coffin
a beat after you open your eyes.
Get him out of herel
Come on! Raise the camera!
Joe, give me a hand.
Something's the matter with him.
That's all right, Jake.
Just relax.
We got you. Something's going on.
Something's weird.
- Are you okay, babe?
- Give him some air.
What's the matter? Speak to me.
Come on, talk.
What's the matter?
I don't know.
I don't know what happened.
I was in the coffin. I closed my eyes.
I thought everything would be okay.
I opened my eyes, and the camera
was right on top of me...
and I couldn't move.
It's no big thing.
I just...
For a second there,
I just couldn't move.
I don't know what happened.
I'm sorry.
Firel
Nol What happened?
Get up there!
Put some water on it!
This is great.
That's terrific.
You got it under control?
Look, Jake,
you really look exhausted, babe.
Why don't you take a shower
and go on home. We lost the sun.
Let me try it one more time.
I can do it.
I know you can,
but we don't have any sun anymore.
Can I have nuts with that
and a Manhattan?
- Yeah.
- And fries.
- Right.
- Rings.
- Anything to drink?
- Two large Cokes with ice.
Onions on everything.
- That to go?
- Yeah.
4.99.
Keep the change.
You too.
See you guys.
- Scully, how's that picture coming?
- Good. Fine.
- Great.
- I'll have a Jack Daniels, neat.
Are you serious?
You quit drinking. Remember?
Just get the drink, Doug.
What's the matter?
They cut your big scene?
Again.
Carol?
I thought you were a bartender,
not a priest.
That's right.
I'm a bartender.
Then keep the fucking glass filled.
Keep your own glass filled.
- I'm sorry.
- That's cool.
Just don't pay any attention to me.
l...
You need a place to stay?
Yeah, I guess I do.
What are you doing here?
I thought you were working.
I am. I got a week off.
I figured I'd go
to some interviews, stay busy.
- Great.
- Do you know about any sublets?
- I'II check around.
- Something available immediately.
- Not offhand.
- What... Ho!
The whole world's here.
You two know each other?
- Jake Scully, Sam Bouchard.
- Hi. Nice to meet you.
- Right here.
- I'll see you in class later.
- We got class today?
- At 3:00.
- Right.
- Good luck.
What have you been doing lately?
I just started a low-budget,
independent horror film.
'Vampire's Kiss."
I play the vampire.
Sounds interesting.
Before that I did Petruchio
in 'Taming of the Shrew."
Anything else?
You mean anything good?
You are working.
- That's good now, isn't it?
- Yeah.
- Hi. Small town.
- Jack Scully.
- Jake.
Give them hell.
Hello.
I remember that it was dark.
Really black.
I was just a little kid.
And the wall behind me was cold.
And damp.
I was hiding. I was...
Oh, yeah.
I was part of this game: Sardine.
I was it, and I was hiding.
Everybody was looking for me.
And there was humming.
I was behind the freezer
in the basement.
And I had jammed myself in
so hard behind the freezer...
that I couldn't move.
I'm afraid.
Uh-huh.
What are you afraid of?
They're not gonna find me.
But they're not supposed
to find you.
But I'm afraid
because I can't move.
Why don't you cry out?
I can't. I'm afraid.
Besides, I'm the sardine.
They're not supposed to find me.
Now particularize that.
Who can't find you?
My brothers.
They're bigger than me.
First time
they ever let me play.
If they're your brothers,
they'll want to help you, right?
No. They won't let me play again.
- They're bigger than you are.
- Yeah.
Will they hurt you?
Yes.
How?
They'll laugh at me for getting stuck
behind the freezer...
and for crying out for help.
The big baby.
That's right.
You are a baby.
I know.
Yeah, and you're afraid.
Yeah.
You must act.
I can't. I'm afraid.
- You'll never escape.
- I know.
You'll die.
Yeah.
Bullshit!
You've got to act!
Fuck the fear.
You've got to cry out for help!
Come on!
Use your body!
Cry for help!
You can do it.
I want you to cry out.
I can't. I'm a sardine.
Sardines in a can are dead.
They can't feel.
They can't be afraid.
But you're alive and afraid.
You're not a goddamn dead sardine!
- This is crap.
- Dig down deep!
Cry out!
- I can't.
- Come on.
Leave the guy alone.
Do not interrupt this exercise.
This looks like
a mind-fuck to me.
What is your name? You're not
a member of this class, are you?
That's right. I'm not.
I thought this was a class for acting,
not humiliation.
What gives you the right
to fuck around with this guy's head?
- I think you better leave.
- I think that's a good idea.
I want to act.
Come on.
Class is out.
Come on. Let's go.
I'm sorry, Will.
I can't do this today.
This is called an exit.
Shit.
What a fool I am.
You're too hard on yourself.
Some of these guys
can't get a job.
They put an ad in the trade.
They call themselves teachers.
What do they teach us?
How to be more fucked up than we are.
That's not it.
- Can we get another round?
- Coming up.
- Thanks.
- Check.
Are you married?
Separated.
Me too, as of yesterday.
We weren't married,
but it was almost the same thing.
What happened?
I'm sorry.
That's none of my business.
That's okay.
It's just...
Sounds so stupid.
These things usually do.
Caught her in bed
with another guy.
Can you believe that?
Man.
You had no idea?
None.
Christ, I keep seeing it.
Carol lying there.
Her face was glowing.
- Her face was glowing?
- Yeah.
How do you get
a girl's face to glow?
I got 16 years of good humping.
Not once did I get a glimmer,
let alone a fucking glow.
Glowing?
- I'm sorry. That's tough.
- No, you're right.
It's not that big a deal, really.
- You kicked the bitch out I hope.
- I didn't.
- Why not?
- It was her place.
You've been through the shitter.
- Where are you staying?
- I got a friend with a floor.
You ready for some good news?
Yeah.
I got this five-week gig coming up.
Seattle Rep's doing a revival
of 'Private Lives."
I've been house-sitting
for a friend.
- He gives me a good deal on the place...
- I've been looking for a sublet.
- Would this be available right away?
- Wait here.
Let me make a phone call.
Don't move.
- Do you like plants?
- Sure.
- I can't believe this.
- It's something, isn't it?
Be if ever so humble.
- This is unbelievable.
- I know if's nof much.
- Can you handle this?
- I've never seen anything like it.
- Your friend must really be loaded.
- He's filthy with the stuff.
Anyway, here they are.
Water them every day after 6:00.
- Right.
- You got it?
- That's it.
- Listen, this is really nice of you.
No thanks necessary.
One struggling actor helping another.
- That's what it's all about.
- Thank you.
- Just don't let the damn plants die.
- You got it.
- Where is he anyway?
- Alan?
- Yeah.
- He spends a lot of time in Europe.
I got a well-stocked bar.
- Rotating bed.
- "Rotating"?
Sauna and Jacuzzi in the back
just beyond the walk-in closets.
As soon as I pack up,
you can put your stuff away.
- Are you leaving now?
- Yeah, l...
The hell with it.
I got time for one more drink.
I'll still be able
to catch the last flight.
What a setup.
This is great.
Isn't it?
Thank you.
- Sam, here's to a friendship...
- Wait.
Let's do this right.
Come here.
To Hollywood.
Yeah.
What a view.
That's just part of it.
There is one very special feature
to this house.
- What are you looking at?
- Where are you?
There she is.
Show time.
I'd like you to meet
my favorite neighbor.
- See her?
- Whoa.
It gets better.
- What's she doing?
- Just keep watching. You'II see.
- You want to get a little closer?
- You bet.
- Oh, my God.
- Focused?
- She's a little out of focus. Yes!
- Yes? Hang on.
Does she do this a lot?
Like clockwork, every night.
Jesus.
What do you think?
- It's something, isn't it?
- Yeah.
Lady does the same gig every night.
Did you get a look at her face?
Too bad. She is gorgeous.
Shit.
- I gotta get going.
- Can I help you?
All right.
Don't forget your scarf.
Here's the key.
Try not to make too many
long-distance phone calls.
Thanks again.
This is good of you.
- You're doing me a favor too.
- Thank you.
- Take it easy.
- Knock 'em dead!
They're already dead in Seattle.
So long.
My, my
Uh-oh
The house is burning
buf fhere's no one home
Jesus!
Bastard.
Where fhe hell have you been?
I've been calling you all over fown.
I'm sorry, Frank. I've been having
some real problems with Carol.
I've been staying
at a friend's house.
You got a few more problems.
Rubin fired you.
- What?
- You don'f have a job anymore.
He gave me some bullshit
about artistic differences.
What the hell happened?
Nothing.
How can he do that?
They're doing it right now.
Can't we do something?
Maybe I should talk to Rubin.
You better forget it.
They've already hired another guy.
- How do you know?
- He's my client.
Now bring them up.
You're loving every minute of it,
sweetheart. It feels so good.
You're getting ready to take
a nice chunk out of the neck.
Hands down. Good.
All right, cut!
Kill the water and steam.
I thought you were gonna
give me another chance.
Look, I got a picture to make here.
I got 25 days to make it.
I got no time to fuck around
with a claustrophobic vampire...
who freezes every time
he lies down in the coffin.
- I'm not claustrophobic.
- Then what happened? Stage fright?
I don't know.
It never happened before.
It's never gonna happen again.
Good-bye. I gotta get back to work.
- You promised me another chance.
- I lied.
- Don't you yell at me!
- Big fucking deal.
- Get outta here! Beat it!
- Listen...
Joe, get him outta here! You don't come
in here yelling at me on my setl
- You don't have the right to lie to me.
- There's the door.
Go onl Get out!
Get out the door, you fruitcake.
What's wrong with you?
- He's the boss.
- It's not fair.
What's everybody standing around for?
Let's get back to work. Come on.
Just like clockwork.
There she goes.
Excuse me.
Could you move, please? Please!
I gotta go.
Thank you.
- Good morning, ma'am.
- Thank you.
I have to see you.
What time did you call?
I'm never home till after 7:00.
Yes, he hit me again.
I've got to talk to someone.
Today.
The Beach Terrace Motel?
I'II wear something special.
You'II see.
Yeah. Okay.
Bye.
- Security, please.
- This is securify.
Please come over to Bellini's.
I think we have a problem.
Excuse me.
- May I help you?
- No, thank you.
Did you see that guy?
- It's the cream Mercedes.
- Wait here, please.
- Thank you. Here you are.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Can I have my car, please?
- Yes, sir.
Thank you.
Right away. As soon as possible.
Straight toward the beach,
down the stairs.
Thank you.
Hello?
Yes.
You've got to come.
I need to talk to you.
I've got to talk to someone.
I need you.
Excuse me.
Someone's following you.
I know.
No, it's not me.
Are you all right?
He got away.
You got the purse.
You better check it.
He took something.
What's the matter?
I'm just out of breath.
Can you take me out of here?
Sure.
- Here.
- Thank you.
All right. Thank you.
I feel much better now.
I'm fine.
I saw you back there
and at the hotel.
- You've been following me.
- Yeah.
Why?
Did my husband hire you?
I'm...
What?
Yes.
I can't.
I can't do this.
Not here.
Hello, Gloria.
How are you?
Maybe you remember me.
This is Jake.
I'm the guy that almost fucked you
at the beach today.
No, that's terrible.
Hi, Gloria.
- Hello?
- How are you doing?
Sam, how's everything?
Great.
Everything okay over fhere?
Yeah. No problems.
How's our favorife neighbor?
Sfill wifh fhe midnighf shows?
- Uh-huh?
- You sound a liftle preoccupied.
I jusf called
fo see how fhings were going.
By fhe way,
any messages for me?
- Hello? Are you fhere?
- Yeah.
I'm here. I'm sorry.
There are no messages.
Goffa run.
I'll be in fouch.
My God.
If you'd like fo make a call,
please...
Hurry.
- Hello.
- Look out! He's right behind you!
- Whaf?
- My God!
Stopl You guys, stop!
What do you want?
Are you crazy?
- There's a woman being killed.
- What?
Come on!
L.A. Cify Emergency. This is 911.
Whaf are you reporfing?
This is L.A. Cify Emergency.
Hello?
I'm sorry, I can'f hear you.
Please...
Please tell me fhe nafure
of your emergency.
Don't.
No. Please, don't.
Get him off me!
He's killing her!
Stop!
God!
I'm Detective McLean.
I'm in charge
of this investigation.
I see you're an actor.
Yeah.
Ever been in anything?
'Emerald Point" and a "Hart To Hart"
that was pretty good.
Very interesting.
You make a living?
Yeah.
Good-Iooking boy.
Talented.
I got a real problem with you.
What do you mean?
I mean, you're my only witness
to this murder...
and you're a peeper.
In my book, that's a pervert
and a sex offender.
- What do you mean "a sex offender"?
- Save it.
I ask the questions.
What about this Indian? When he snatched
her pocketbook, you got it back.
- Is that right?
- That's right.
Was anything missing?
I saw him take a credit card.
Not a credit card, a card key.
He used it to get into her house.
Did Gloria know it was missing?
She didn't say anything to me.
You talked to her?
Come on,
you must have said something.
- It was just small talk, you know?
- No, I don't know.
Did you come on to her?
Were you trying to do a number
on her head?
Trying to freak her out
with all you know about her?
- You're wrong.
- Why were you following Gloria Revelle?
Because I got concerned
when I saw that guy following her.
But you kept on her tail
after this other guy disappeared.
I know, because...
- I guess I wanted to...
- You wanted to what?
Nothing.
What's this?
Some underpants.
Yours?
Where did you get them?
She dropped them in the trash.
- Who?
- Gloria.
And you just picked them up?
- Yeah.
- Why?
- I don't know.
- Tell the truth.
You fucked her and kept them
for a souvenir.
You didn't fuck her or you didn't
keep them as a souvenir?
- No to both of them.
- Are you just a harmless panty sniffer?
- You got a dirty mind.
- That's a laugh.
You peep on her, follow her, fuck her
and keep her panties as a memento.
Then you sit on the 50-yard line
and watch her being slaughteredl
That's not what happened!
I tried to save her!
Mm-hmm. Some save, Scully.
Remind me to never put my life
in your hands.
Tell me about Alexander Revelle.
- What?
- Alexander Revelle, Gloria's husband.
You knew him?
I never met him.
- You sure?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
Was he around
when Gloria got nailed?
Do you think he had something
to do with it?
Gloria Revelle was a very rich lady.
When rich wives get dead,
I usually go after the husband.
The only problem is
you saw a thief.
An Indian killed Gloria Revelle.
I won't hold you, Scully.
We have witnesses
to back up your story.
But I want you
to think real hard about this.
As far as I'm concerned...
you're the real reason Gloria Revelle
got murdered.
If you hadn't been so busy getting off
by peeping on her...
if you had called the police
about your blood brother, the Indian...
Gloria Revelle would still be alive.
Oh, yeah.
Linda, we believe fhaf you have
your own producfion company now.
Yes, Linda Shaw Enferprises.
Whaf are some of fhose enferprises?
We have a film 'Deep Ghosf'
and 'The Mafing Game. '
- 'One Nighf af a Time. '
- Yes.
I believe you have a film opening
fhis Friday af fhe Pussy Flick Theafer?
- Whaf is fhe fifle of fhaf?
- Thaf's 'Bold Obsession. '
Tell us, Linda,
whaf is your 'bold obsession'?
Sid, fhaf scripf was wriffen especially
for me, because I am an exposifionisf.
You are an 'exposifionisf'?
Do you mean an exhibifionisf?
- Yes, exhibifionisf.
- Yeah, I'm sure.
I jusf gef so excited when I know
fhey're all ouf fhere wafching me.
Of course
they're ouf fhere wafching you.
- If gefs me so hof.
- If does?
Whaf happens when you gef hof?
- If makes me wanf fo come.
- You wanf fo come.
While you're coming,
lef's wafch this clip.
Five minufes, Miss Body.
I'm ready.
We've gof five minufes.
Eddie, where fhe hell are you?
We need you on fhe sef.
- Come on. Lef's go.
- 'Holly Does Hollywood. '
The X Cinema...
L.A. 's classiesf
X- rated movie house.
This week, see fhe film fhaf everyone's
falking abouf: 'Holly Does Hollywood. '
And does if well.
Screw Magazine says...
'Holly Body keeps fhis business
where if belongs...
in fhe guffer. '
Says Eros Magazine: 'The 'Gone
Wifh The Wind' Of Adulf Films. '
'Holly Does Hollywood'
is a hedonisf's heaven.
Husfler Magazine gives if
Husfler's highesf rafing.
'Ten nominations
including Besf Picfure. '
Crifics Adulf Film Associafion.
Sfarring Holly Body.
'Holly Does Hollywood. '
Now playing at fhe X Cinema.
You home viewers...
can pick if up righf now af
Tower Records' all nighf video sale.
Excuse me.
Do you have 'Holly Does Hollywood"?
Yeah, we do. It's in our adult section.
Follow me.
- On VHS?
- Yeah, VHS. Whatever you want.
Half-inch, three-quarter, Beta.
- Is this what you're talking about?
- That's it.
- Hello. Adulf Blue Films.
- I was wondering if you could help me.
Are you the company that distributes
"Holly Does Hollywood"?
- Yes.
- I'm not some fucking stunt cock.
- I'm an actor.
- You'II have to wait.
I have been waifing,
for more than an hour.
Do you know how many picfures
I've made wifh Holly?
Baby, I am sure
you have made a lof.
I don't have to take this shit.
I got a reputation
in this business.
If you wanf fo audition,
sit down!
- I'm sorry.
- That's okay.
- Can I help you?
- How late are the auditions going today?
- Probably pasf 6:00.
- Thank you.
You're welcome. Bye.
Mr. Corso, Jake Scully.
Pleasure to meet you.
Stand over there.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
Go ahead.
I like to watch.
Makes you hot, doesn't it?
Yeah.
Makes me hot too.
Real hot.
Come over here.
I'll show you how hot.
All right.
Take off your clothes.
I want to take some pictures.
- What is it that we're watching?
- I don't know.
Are you some kind of method actor?
Give if fo me one fime now
Relax
Don'f do if
When you wanna go fo if
When you wanna come
When you wanna suck to it
Buf shoof if
in fhe righf direcfion
Make making if your infenfion
Live fhose dreams
Scheme fhose schemes
- Goffa hif me
- Hif me
Hif me wifh those laser beams
I like to watch.
Makes you hot, doesn't it?
Yeah.
Makes me hot too.
Come over here,
and I'II show you how hot.
- Where's the come shot?
- Huh? Come?
The come shot. I thought we were doing
'Body Talk" here, not 'Last Tango."
You were great out there. Really.
Come on, I'II buy you a drink.
A drink?
I don't even know you.
I'm talking business.
Come on.
You know the mirror out there?
That was my idea.
So, you're a genius.
No, but I can make a better film
than Corso, with my eyes closed.
Films cost money, you know.
I got money.
Then what are you doing in hard-core?
I wanted to meet you.
Why?
Because I think you're sensational.
I think you're the best in the business.
I'll pay you top dollar.
I'll give you points.
Whatever it takes.
- Really?
- I want you in my picture.
- You're really serious?
- Yeah, of course I am.
Okay, good.
There are some things I like
to get straight up front...
so there are no misunderstandings
later on.
- I don't blame you.
- I do not do animal acts.
I do not do S and M or any variations
of that particular bent.
No water sports either.
I will not shave my pussy,
no fist fucking...
and absolutely no coming in my face.
I get $2,000 a day,
and I do not work without a contract.
Fine.
I mean, that's no problem.
- I think we got a deal.
- Cheers.
You ever do any specialty work?
What kind of specialty work
are you looking for?
A woman alone,
getting herself off.
It's got to be really hot.
Is that all?
I have a routine that is a sure ten
on the peter-meter.
- I know. I've seen it.
- Yeah?
A few times.
Yeah, I'm known far and wide...
for that little bit of business.
I want you to know
I saw 'Holly Does Hollywood"...
and I think your acting
is top drawer.
- My acting?
- Yep.
You're fantastic.
Really. Sensational.
I'II tell you something else.
- You have got a terrific...
- Body.
Smile.
Smile"?
Look at you.
- Kimberly, how are you?
- I'm fine, just lovely.
Aren't you going to introduce me
to your friend?
- Kimberly Hess. Hello.
- Nice to know you.
So, Jake, you working?
Yeah, here and there.
We have to run.
- It's great to see you though.
- Right.
Jake and I worked together
in the past.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I thought I knew everybody
in this business.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
I don't see how someone
could know everyone.
It's a funny business.
Anyway, I wanted to ask you...
have you heard of any roles
that might be right for...
- No, I'm sorry.
- I have. I have a tip for you.
- Really?
- Yes, Simon La Farge is casting.
- You know him, right?
- No.
No? Are you from outer space?
Just tell him that you ran into me.
Here's his number.
You might want to firm up a bit
before you go and see him.
One more thing.
Do you mind working with ladies?
- Acting is acting, right?
- That's right.
I think that's really admirable.
Me, myself, I can't get into it.
But, anyway, good luck
and say hello to Simon for me.
- Good seeing you.
- Sure. Thanks.
By the way...
what's the film about?
That's good.
We need more comedians
in our business.
Good luck.
Very nice.
What can I get you?
Jack Daniels?
How about Jake Scully...
straight up?
Very funny.
Hello.
Listen, Holly...
I don't want to talk
any more business.
Yeah, well...
Listen.
Lie down.
We had one of these
in "Star Whores."
There's something I gotta tell you.
You're married.
- What then?
- I'm not a producer.
You're not a producer.
l... Hold up. I'm not...
Just a second.
I'm not interested
in making a film with you.
- What are you interested in then?
- You.
I saw you in the house
those other nights.
What house?
You know,
that show that you put on...
with the masturbation routine
and all the diamonds and everything.
I was watching you from here.
You were the girl in the window.
That wasn't Gloria. That was you.
What's it to you?
Just tell me if I'm right.
That was you in the Revelle house.
Right?
I'm not saying that it was me,
and I'm not saying that it wasn't me.
I'm saying,
why are you interested in knowing?
I think that one of my crazy friends
has played a practical joke on me.
You know how it is
with the idle rich.
Tell me, were you the girl
in the house?
- Yeah, that was me.
- I knew it.
How did this thing get set up?
Tell me just to satisfy my curiosity.
One of my crazy friends set this up,
but I don't know who.
Who hired you?
- You were the one I was playing to?
- Yeah.
- And there's no part for me.
- I'm sorry.
- This whole thing was a joke.
- Yeah.
It was a practical joke on me.
Did Sam Bouchard
set this whole thing up?
Did he hire you
to do your routine?
He didn't tell me his name.
Whoever you talked to,
what did he say?
This guy called me up and said
he had seen my self-help routine...
in 'Holly Does Hollywood"...
and he wanted to hire me
to do it in private.
He said that he had this friend
who got off on peeping.
- He didn't tell you who he was?
- No. He didn't tell me his name.
He just sent a messenger over
with money...
and with a card key...
and a wig.
Please don't leave.
Just stay here for a second.
Can you hold on?
- Hello.
- Lf's Sam.
- How are you doing? Can you hold on?
- Sure.
Hold on.
Please, listen to this guy's voice.
Tell me if he's the one
that hired you. Please.
Hello. I'm sorry. You got me
in the shower. How are you doing?
- I'm afraid I got some bad news, pal.
- What's that?
Seaffle Rep and I
had some arfisfic differences.
I'm gonna be heading back fo L.A.
So I guess you'll have fo find
anofher place fo crash.
That's him.
- You gof some company fhere?
- Actually, I do.
It's kind of a bad time to talk.
You want to call back in 15 minutes?
- Yeah...
- That was the guy who hired you?
- Yes, that was him.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure that was him.
- Listen.
- God, you're really sick.
- Listen to me very carefully.
I am not a film producer,
and I am not a rich kid.
No, you're a jerk.
Holly, please listen to me
for a second.
You were hired to do two nights' work,
to do your routine and leave.
- Is that true?
- Yes.
- Do you know why?
- You just told me why.
You just told me some guy
was playing a joke on you.
He wasn't playing a joke on you?
- Do you want to tell me what it was?
- Yes.
The truth.
The truth is a woman was murdered.
It's not funny. A woman was murdered.
You and I were set up by a murderer.
He wanted to be sure
I witnessed the murder.
That's why he hired you
to do your routine.
Meanwhile, he arranged it
so that I would be watching.
He wanted me to think that the girl
who lived there, Gloria Revelle...
was the one getting off.
Meanwhile, he thought I would watch
and keep watching.
Holly, are you listening to me?
Yes.
I don't understand what you've said.
Listen, he's a murderer!
The man who hired you is a murderer!
Come here.
Please, come here.
Do you remember
where you did your routine?
- Yes.
- You see that house down there?
- That window is where you were, right?
- Yes.
- Now do you understand?
- Yes, I understand.
I understand you're sick and you're
a liar and you need professional help.
- I do not like being yelled at!
- I'm sorry.
I should have known when you told me
I had a terrific smile.
No real producer would tell me that
in a million years.
Get out of my way.
- What?
- Just come with me to the police.
To the police? Are you crazy?
Listen to me, you weirdo...
- A woman was murdered!
- I'm leaving! Don't follow me home!
I have friends
who will break your legsl
Let go of me! God!
You weirdol
There are so many weird people.
Can I have the Hollywood
Police Department, please?
Fucking freaky actors.
That's what there is here.
Masochistic directors.
I should have known when he didn't
even know what a come shot was.
Yeah, Detective McLean, please.
Excuse me.
Stop, please.
Thank you very much, ladyl
I was set up.
Yeah, Hollywood's busiest
sex offender.
Cut it out.
Just listen to me for a minute.
I got something important
to tell you.
I know who killed Gloria Revelle.
Is this a confession?
Listen.
Just pay attention.
A few days ago I was looking
for an apartment.
Do you know any sublets
that would be available right away?
I'll check around.
I noficed fhis guy,
Sam Bouchard.
He was looking for somebody
who needed a place fo sfay.
I fhoughf if was a coincidence
fhat we kepf running info each ofher.
Hi. Again.
Anyway, now I realize
he was fhrowing out a nef.
He was sizing me up
for a parf fhaf he was casfing.
I want you to cry out for help!
I can't.
I fif fhe bill perfecfly:
lovesick sucker, ouf on his ass.
Shit.
What a fool I am.
And you know what the part was?
I'm listening.
The part of the witness.
He fold me fhere was fhis neighbor fhaf
did fhis number on herself every nighf.
- See her?
- He knew fhaf I would look.
- Nice, huh?
- Yeah.
He knew I would keep looking.
And if wasn'f Gloria.
If was Holly doing her roufine.
Thaf's why I never saw her face.
You sound like a conspiracy nut:
plots all around you.
Please, just listen to me
for a second.
Sam Bouchard is Alexander Revelle.
He hired fhe Indian
fo follow Gloria...
and snafch her purse
and sfeal fhe card key fo her house...
and fhen sneak inside.
Then when she gof home...
the Indian opened fhe blinds
so I could see him kill her.
Alexander Revelle set me up
in this house to witness the murder.
He hired a porno acfress
fo be fhe baif.
Can I have a ride, please?
Thanks a lot, you jerks!
Oh, my God.
I've been trying to build a case
against the husband all along...
but the reason
it hasn't panned out...
is because of your testimony
that Gloria was killed by an Indian.
That's just it! Don't you see?
That's what he wanted!
It looks like a burglary,
but it's a murder...
with me set up
to be the witnessl
I'm Alexander Revelle's alibi.
Listen. Stop, all right?
Just stop! Right therel
There has been an accident
up there.
- Those people are probably very hurt.
- Slow down, lady.
- Nobody's bothered to stop.
- Get in the car.
It sounds crazy to me.
I know, but it's the truth.
Maybe you better come down here.
Pull it up. That's it.
Pull your car right up there.
Stay in your car, please.
There's nothing to look at.
We'll have it cleaned up
in a couple minutes.
Get back in your car, sir.
Officer, there's a woman being killed
in that Ford Bronco right there.
He's killing her. He just hit her
in the back of the head.
We gotta do something
to help her.
- Get back in your car.
- He's killing her. He hit her.
- I don't have time to run you in.
- Please!
He's getting away.
Please call somebody on your radio.
Don't you understand?
I saw him killing her!
- You fucking idiot!
- All right, that's it, buddy.
- You're coming with me.
- Call Detective McLean.
- He knows all about this.
- All right.
Son of a...
Come here, you son of a bitch!
Are you okay?
Look what you did.
You ruined my surprise ending!
I gave you your part:
the witness.
You were perfect.
You played it to a T.
But that was it.
End of part.
Wrap Jake Scully.
You had to play the hero...
improvise all this crap
about finding a body double...
and unmasking the Indian.
But you didn't think it through.
Sometimes heroes
come to tragic ends.
What's the matter?
A little short of breath?
What a terrible way to die.
Especially when you're
so claustrophobic.
Wait a minute.
I'll give you another take.
The only problem is
you've got to act.
Come on.
Action.
And action.
Cut. Get him out of here.
Move the camera out.
Joe, give me a hand.
Jake, take it easy.
What's going on?
We're getting you out.
That's all right.
We got you. Let go.
Don't worry about it.
- Don't worry about nothing.
- It's all right. We're here.
Give him some air.
Talk to me.
Say something.
Walk it off. Just go for a walk.
Just relax. Just breathe in.
All right, that's good.
There you go.
What's the matter, babe?
Boy, you had us scared there.
What's the problem?
Wait a minute.
- Get away from me.
- Babe, just relax.
- We're just trying to help you.
- I know.
I can help myself.
Listen, Scully,
why don't you cool off?
Go on home,
and we'll shoot this another time.
All right?
Don't lie to me.
If I don't get this shot,
you'll fire me.
Don't be ridiculous.
Why would I do a thing like that?
Save the speech, Rubin. I know all about
your personal commitment to the actors.
I'm a little claustrophobic.
You'II work around it, right?
Yeah, that's right.
- I don't like your attitude.
- Yeah?
If I get this shot,
you'll like it a lot better, right?
Let's do it!
You better get it right this time.
You're one pain in the ass
I don't need.
- Okay, Joe.
- Roll sound. Quiet.
And action I
You bastard!
Don't be so melodramatic.
Kill!
What are you doing?
- What am I doing? I'm saving you.
- From who?
- From... The Indian was Sam Bouchard.
- Wait a minute.
Am I missing something?
Is there somebody here that I don't see?
Yes! The dog knocked him in.
Come look. Come here.
Look, he must have knocked him in.
He went...
I thought it belonged to Gloria, but
it must have belonged to the husband.
That's why he never barked at the Indian
when he tried to sneak in the house.
I think you're absolutely right.
We should go to the police.
- Really? You believe me?
- Yes. I believe you.
I believe you are a number one sicko
and should be put away for life!
I know all about you guys.
I've seen about you
on late-night television.
You're one of those necrophiliacs,
a corpse fucker!
- I am not.
- Yesl I turn you on, all right.
The only problem is that
I'm still movingl
Unconscious is good,
but dead is better, right?
Are you all right?
Here, take my hand.
Do not touch me.
I'm not dead yet.
I know this all seems crazy,
but I'm trying to help you.
Are you gonna stay in there
for the rest of your life?
Freeze.
Don't move your hand, Jake.
- How does that look?
- It looks great.
Good. Terrific. Hold that move.
Let's 86 the bat.
That's a wrap on the bat.
Get the bat out.
- I gotta hold the hand really still.
- Help him out.
- Turn the water off.
- Can I slip out?
Wait till we get the bar in there.
Wait till we get the stand in here.
- Okay, sweetheart.
- Between the bottom two fingers.
Good. Okay, sweetheart,
you can slide out.
Don't move the hand.
Freeze the hand.
Makeup.
Let's get a touch-up for Jake.
Don't move the hand.
Keep the hand very still.
Excuse me.
Don't move the bar!
- I'm sorry.
- Did the bar move?
That's okay.
- You're doing a great job.
- Did I flash the teeth long enough?
Best teeth flashing I've ever seen.
It looked beautiful, babe.
I'm so glad
I fired that other asshole.
This part was made for you.
I mean it. You look sensational.
- This bar is falling.
- That looks good.
- You holding up?
- Yeah.
Just a little longer.
Okay, girls, step out. Step back.
Let's bring in the body double.
- Thanks.
- The hair looks good.
Is that as hot
as that water gets?
Slide in there, sweetheart.
- Don't move the bar. It's important.
- I know.
Hi. I'm Mindy.
Pleased to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
- Listen, be very, very careful.
My breasts are very tender.
I've got my period.
We good here?
I'm gonna...
Just bring your body up like this.
My hand is right here.
I can't move my hand.
Keep your hand exactly still.
Let's shoot it.
Let's slide the bar out.
Drop the camera.
Let's get the camera down.
Wait till we're in position.
Can you bring your body
up to my hand?
Quiet, please!
I'm trying to think.
You're gonna get a lot of dates
when this comes out.
Here we go. Action.
Action with the hand.
Great action.
Is that too hard?