[Episode 12]
[TNC Manager
Rena Jeong]
I was going to leave quietly
because I'm so embarrassed and sorry.
I won't make it long.
Whatever excuses I make,
I know I'm unforgivable.
Regard it as that you were unlucky
to meet a greedy, arrogant woman.
Even if you hold it against me for long,
I'll accept it.
You told me not to say this,
butI guess it will be the last time.
I am sorry and
thank you for everything.
Do you think it's over
once you had your say?
You should hear
me out, too.
Why are you so late?
I waited for a long time.
Give me your bag.
Why are you out? You're worried
someone might kidnap this beauty?
Beauty? They kidnap pigs
regardless of looks.
Hey!
I'm glad to see
you smile again.
I was worried that you were
kicked out in with a false charge.
See? I told you my boss
was really a good person.
I'm happier that my trust in her
was proven right than being reinstated.
Then what will become of her?
Will she be fired?
No way! Strictly speaking,
she isn't to blame, either.
And since the Director and the Chairman
put full trust in her, she'll be alright.
I'm extremely tired
from this heartache.
Come on!
What?
You're tired.
Get on my back.
You can't carry me.
If you do, you'll hurt your back.
So hungry. Let's go home quickly
and have bibimbap.
Let's see who
gets there first!
Hurry up! I'm hungry!
Hey Kang Yi Sol!
Wait for me!
Why, you can't sleep?
Darn it.
I'm worried to death.
Didn't the statement of apology
conclude the case?
Not really.
That's just the start.
Usually, accidents are given banner
headlines, but apologies are not.
Sales will be down and
we'll have to deal with the aftermath.
But Min Jun is tough.
He can pull through it
so don't worry too much.
When you talk like that,
you're like a stranger.
You sure are a stepmother.
What do you mean?
Rena Jeong was
his right-hand woman.
And she left him in this situation.
How drained he must be now.
But you're saying I should
just sit back and watch.
I told you I didn't feel good
about her from the beginning.
She's a shallow person and no help
to Min Jun. It's all the better she left.
Still, I'm upset with you.
It doesn't matter
if you're upset.
You are my only husband
in the world.
If you fret your health away,
I won't forgive you.
Huh? Is that
what you meant?
Alright.
In fact, I almost fell over
with the shock a few times.
Honey.
Don't worry. I will be fine since
you care about me so much.
Like you said, I'll leave the matter
to Min Jun and take care of myself.
Let's sleep.
Being here reminds me
of my days in New York.
Have you walked along
the Hudson River?
The Hudson River?
When I was too distressed to sleep,
I used to walk there at daybreak.
It was very foggy.
Walking alone through the fog
calmed my mind as if by magic.
What caused you
sleepless nights?
I was betrayed by
someone I had trusted.
Since then, it was really
hard for me to trust people.
I thought I didn't need people
by my side for a long time.
I really thought so.
It's been quite a while since I last felt
reassured having someone by my side.
If I hold on to you,
will you stay with me?
We'll face a lot of difficulties.
But if you trust me and...
Having me by your side
won't be of any help to you.
I'm the one who caused this crisis.
Who would accept me?
What if I don't care?
I don't care.
So stand by me.
No, I don't want to.
I'm not sure I can work
in that atmosphere.
I'd rather leave now than feel guilty
and distressed working with you.
I mean it.
If you care about me,
please let me go.
I understand.
Take it.
It's yours anyway.
I was going to give it to you
at the Jinmao Tower.
Mr. Park, this is...
It's doesn't mean anything
so don't feel burdened.
You said you've never had
a good relationship in your life.
Our relationship
ends like this,
...but since that ring
brings happiness,
...I wish you
a good relationship.
Don't give it to anybody
if you don't like it.
It's more expensive
than your one-dollar ring.
Did you find a job?
No. I'll have to look
for one from now.
You can come back if you want anytime.
I'll leave your position vacant.
If you meet someone and give them
a hard time, it's not a good relationship.
I won't return to you.
I wish you health
and happiness.
Don't look back.
It's all over.
I already cast the dice.
Now it's all or nothing.
My mouth feels sandy.
Have some more.
It's your favorite yellow corvina.
Right. Eat a little more
for your loving son.
I'm going to go to temple
tomorrow morning.
Why?
I'll pray to Buddha with my mother.
We can support Min Jun with prayer.
What are you talking about?
I won't go. Never. You go alone.
It's not that you won't,
but you can't.
She's forbidden
to enter the temple.
Forbidden? How come?
Last time she went there to pray,
she ordered pork...
...and was caught by the
chief priest. Hang it.
You bigmouth!
I'm going to work.
Why?
It's Saturday, but staff are having an
emergency meeting, so I need to stop by.
Wait. Maid...
Yes, here you are.
Give this to Min Jun.
It's red ginseng brewed all night.
This is all I can do for him.
Thank you. He'll handle it well
with your concern.
Yi Sol, can you guess the
profound meaning of these shoes?
Your love will walk away from you if you
give her a pair, so I'm giving you two.
If you ever walk away from me,
come back to me.
What are these shoes for?
They're so pretty!
Hey, they're not for you.
I know.
They are for Yi Sol, right?
No.
Love is timing. If you just keep looking
at her, someone will snatch her.
Hey, be quiet!
Yi Sol might hear you.
Do you need my support?
Don't mess it up!
I'm going to confess today.
Jae Jun.
Are you going somewhere?
Yura will be here shortly.
She prepared food
for your father's health.
Can't you hear me?
You need to earn points with
your father during times like this.
How can you just watch?
What good is it to
earn points with him?
Step on Min Jun and gain a mere
hospital in Qingdao, that's all.
What?
A mere hospital?
Yes.
It's a mere hospital to me.
Let me be clear. Fixing the normal
faces for money is not what I want to do.
So forget about
the Qingdao hospital.
Forget about it?
Don't you tell me that!
Mom.
I clearly told you there
can't be two suns in the sky.
Min Jun's crisis
is your chance.
Listen to me. Get engaged
to Yura and please your father.
Then you can step over Min Jun.
Please mom!
That's why I can't even
go to comfort him...
...lest I score
a hit with Father.
Can't you stop now?
You acting like
an unselfish stepmother...
...makes me sick.
What?
This is not a family!
We sit around
the table and act caring,
...but at heart, we wish others'
failure in jealousy.
Are we a family?
Who do you think this is for?
For whom do you think I play
the hypocrite all my life?
If it's for me, stop. I'm not
interested in the Qingdao hospital.
Living as a true family caring
for each other even if it's only a day...
That's my wish. Please.
True family?
To hell with it.
You're not even blood-related.
Practice.
Can't you hear me?
One, two!
Father, how concerned
you must be.
Barley thrives after a snow,
and ground packs after a rain.
I have no doubt that TNC will
become more solid after this incident.
Please have the health food I
prepared and recover your strength.
Yeah, very good.
Every crisis is an opportunity.
Use this opportunity and get your
parents-in-law and Jae Jun on your side.
Understand?
Why should I do that?
Acting coy is not me.
Why should I deny myself
to play a prudish lady?
You really don't know?
Your true self is a super playgirl,
good for nothing.
By playing coy or whatever,
captivate Jae Jun today, okay?
I think it'll be difficult.
What?
Look. Jae Jun knows I'm going.
He's is getting away.
What's this?
He knows we're coming.
Where is he going?
What are you going to do?
I'm leaving home now. You didn't
forget we're going to the sea today, right?
Yi Sol! Come on, let's go.
Hey! We're ready.
Let's go.
Dong Gu rented a tent, a van, and
everything from his employee. Let's go.
Where are we going?
You forgot? We're going camping
today to comfort you.
We'll sleep over
in a tent tonight.
Oh, right. What should I do?
I have another engagement.
No way! This is our first family trip
since we came back to Korea.
-No, you can't pull out.
-Right.
Mom, let's just go back.
Maybe he's going on a trip alone.
Leave him alone.
Be quiet.
He's not alone.
I'm sorry.
I'm late, aren't I?
It's okay we're not late.
We have plenty of time.
Who's that tall brat?
Wait.
I'm sorry, but I can't go to
the sea again this time.
Something happened?
I forgot I had a previous engagement.
A family camping trip.
Everybody looked forward to today,
so I can't back out. Sorry.
Really? I looked
forward to today, too.
Sorry.
That's okay. They must be
waiting for you, so go ahead.
What are you going to do?
I felt heavy so I needed
some fresh air. I'll go alone.
Get going, dumpling.
Sorry. Next time we'll go
together for sure.
I'm really sorry.
Come with me.
To where?
Camping. It looks sad
to take a trip alone.
I'll relieve your stress.
Come with me.
Are you sure I can join you?
Of course.
They will welcome you.
What the heck.
He has a girlfriend?
I'm going to...!
Wait. I think I've
seen her before.
Where did I see her?
Do you know her? How?
Wait. Gosh, I think too much
alcohol killed my brain cells.
Right! Kaohsiung,
the date-for- hire!
Date-for-hire?
Oh, the masseur?
How could she be here?
She lives in Kaohsiung.
Are you sure?
Yes, I'm sure.
I have good eyesight.
Check with the
massage shop. Hurry.
It's the most famous shop
so there must be a number.
Here it is.
[Hello, I'm calling
to ask something.]
[Does the Korean masseur
still work there?]
Who the heck is that chap?
It's him. The one who made
Yi Sol cry a lot back in Kaohsiung.
What? The date partner
who broke her heart?
Is it fate? Why'd they meet again?
I don't like him.
You're not the only one
who doesn't like him.
Please stop!
What a brutal atmosphere. We're
going to shoot a film, 'Dual in the Wilds.'
You'll see. I'll act harshly
to him to shake him off.
A girl?
My Jae Jun?
Maybe you're mistaken.
No. Yura and I saw
it with our own eyes.
Can you guess who she is?
Guess? You mean
I know her?
Of course.
Remember Jae Jun lost his
heart to a lousy girl in Kaohsiung?
The masseur?
No way.
She can't be in Korea.
I checked. She moved
to Seoul two months ago.
Seems they've bee
seeing each other.
They looked so intimate.
I think they took a trip together
since they met at the train station.
No way. Jae Jun is
not that kind of a boy.
The person you have
dialed is not available...
He not
answering, huh?
He must be on the trip like Yura said.
Why would he answer your call?
Do you know anything
else about her?
No. All I know is
her name, Kang Yi Sol.
Kang Yi Sol.
Kang Yi Sol? I've heard
that name before.
I heard a rookie copied
the rainbow pizza.
Father, what's the
name of that rookie?
Kang Yi Sol something.
Right, the rookie.
That's why he asked.
Rookie?
What do you mean?
Let me promise one thing.
I'm sorry I didn't
discipline him well.
I'll make him finish with her quickly.
Please understand for today.
But they looked so intimate.
Trust me. I told you.
He's bound to come
back to my arms.
I will separate them
by all means.
Smells good.
Please sit here. I'll do it, Father.
'Father?'
Are we that familiar to each other?
I don't have a son like you.
Oh.
Mother, let me go wash these.
'Mother'? No need.
Don't get in the way
and just go sit over there.
Jae Jun, she doesn't put
a guest to work. Go get some rest.
Shall I?
Then I'll go help them
set up the tent.
Mom! What's wrong with you?
Can't you be nice
to my friend?
Have you no pride? How could
you bring that jerk here?
He's not a bad guy.
Please be nice to him.
Mr. Huh, please don't be
mean to him. I beg you.
Go away!
You're of no help!
Please go away!
No one welcomes
you here.
Exactly. We brought rice
only for six people.
If I'm short of rice,
it's your fault.
Aren't you hungry?
Let's eat.
I'm fine. You brought food
only for six people.
A man can't get sulk just
because of that? Come on.
I said I'm fine.
I'm not hungry from the
negativity I've received all day.
Are you really
not going to eat?
Alright.
It's so delicious
out here in the open air!
Come on!
Don't be mad and just eat.
I'm really full!
I am full!
Even my stomach
is so uncooperative.
Isn't it delicious?
Yes.
Have some sausages.
Where is Yi Sol?
Dong Gu, I told you
love is timing.
This is no time for you
to cook meat here.
Go give her the shoes
and confess your feelings.
Since she doesn't know your feelings
for her, she fell for him.
It's good!
By the way, why does
your family hate me?
I didn't expect a big welcome, but
I didn't know they'd be mean to me.
Actually, it's because of me.
My mom saw everything when you
gave me money at the massage shop.
That day, I was so upset
and cried a lot.
And it broke the
my family's hearts.
Weren't you resentful of me?
My pride from having money?
No, I wasn't.
I was rather distressed because
we ended like that when I was serious.
Also I was sad since I thought
I couldn't see you again.
I'm sorry. I'll never
let that happen again.
Shall we go? I will soften
the hearts of your family.
Yay!
Yay.
Is the name of the new recruit
who caused the incident Kang Yi Sol?
Yes, that's right.
Can I see her face?
Pardon?
It's because
I think I know her.
I see. Her resume should be
on the company website.
Please take a look ma'am.
This one.
How did she join TNC? She didn't get
the job through open recruit, did she?
Tell me. How did
she join the company?
In fact, it was
Director Park's order.
I knew it.
It was Min Jun as expected.
What a fresh air.
And I'm full.
-Father?
-Yes.
Now we're comfortable
without him being around.
Exactly. I've never seen
such a clumsy guy.
If I were him,
I would've left earlier.
But he has the nerves
to eat our food.
That's not all. He's jobless.
What?
How come when he has an able body?
He could do any manual labor.
He has the wrong mentality.
That's why a girl hired Yi Sol to date him
in her place back in Kaohsiung.
Yi Sol isn't clever either.
How could she see him of all guys?
I know. When there's
a nice guy like Dong Gu.
We're back, Father, Mother.
I thought you left.
No. Eat some dessert.
Jae Jun bought these.
This is your favorite icy soju.
This is your favorite beer.
Uncle, I mean brother.
Do you have my
favorite ice cream?
Of course.
Pick what you want.
I'll take this.
Oppa, I'll take this.
Give it to me.
Mr. Park Jae Jun.
We don't need this.
Please leave.
Right. I don't need
this, either.
This makes me feel flatulent.
See? No one welcomes
you here. Please go back.
Dong Gu, what's wrong with you?
I told you he's my friend.
Friend?
How can he be your friend?
He insulted you in Kaohsiung,
and how did he treat you at the club?
Did you forget he looked
down you becuase he had money?
I told you. It was a misunderstanding
and that won't happen again.
He isn't that kind
of man you think.
He's the only one who believed my
innocence and supported me. So please...
No, Yi Sol. He's right.
Forgive me. I was thoughtless
and hurt her feelings a lot.
From now on,
I'll do my best...
...to Yi Sol and
to her family that loves her.
I will never break
your hearts again. Believe me.
I think I made a mistake today
when this is your family trip.
I'll visit you often until
you forgive me.
Goodbye.
Jae Jun.
I'll leave.
See you.
Jae Jun, Jae Jun.
You're so mean!
Do you have to send him like that?
Can't you accept him for me?
Hey, we're all
worried about you!
You don't have to,
because I'm so happy.
It's the first time I've felt
like this in my 23 years of living!
When he's out of sight, I miss him,
care about him, and wish him the best.
When he's with me,
I smile and feel thrilled.
I really like him.
I like him a lot.
But if you don't like him,
I will wait.
I'll wait until you accept him.
Mr. Park Jae Jun!
Come with me.
Yi Sol is waiting for you.
Excuse me?
You mean...
Let me give you
one warning.
If you ever make
her cry again, then I...
...I will not forgive you.
Thank you, Mr. Heo Dong Gu.
I'll really be good to her.
Thank you.
What brings you here?
What's your intention?
Excuse me?
Your intention
for hiring Kang Yi Sol.
There's no intention. Jae Jun asked me
a favor and I found her talented, so...
Even so, didn't you know
you shouldn't do that?
You could tell they are
in no ordinary relationship.
He has a fiancee. As his brother, you
should have stopped him, not supported.
Stepmother.
What's your ulterior motive?
Do you want him to break off his
engagement and lose favor with Father?
You don't, right?
I believe you don't.
Then fire her.
Jae Jun is head
over heels for her.
Father will be in complete shock if
his father finds out he sees such a girl.
That's not what
you want, is it?
I can't do that.
You can't?
Why?
She's the focus of
attention due to this incident.
If she's fired in this situation,
it'll do no good to the company.
And regarding his marriage, why
don't you trust him and leave the matter...
Trust and leave the matter?
So what happened?
Did you forget what happened
in New York 10 years ago?
We left the matter to you and
what became of your wedding?
Your bride didn't show up and
brought disgrace to the family.
You didn't forget it, did you?
Both your discernment
is worth that much.
Fire her unless you want
to bring dishonor to your father.
Tada!
He prepared a lot!
Rest for a beat,
rest for two...
Rest for another,
One, two, three, four!
He's old-fashioned like us.
The person you have
dialed is not available...
That fool!
Wasn't it hard today?
My family was so demanding.
No, I enjoyed it.
Now I see why you are
cheerful and warm-hearted.
Caring for each other sincerely,
that's a true family.
We're not well off,
but we're rich at heart.
I really envy that.
I'm determined
in what I want to do.
What you want to do?
What is it?
I'll tell you at
the beach as I promised.
Let's go to the sea
next week.
Okay. I will tell my family.
Just kidding.
Let's promise this.
Whatever may happen,
let's trust each other to the end.
I'll promise.
Promise.
Look at the sky!
It's beautiful.
How's your feeling after
losing Jae Jun to someone else?
Well.
Just 'Well'? Aren't you eaten
up with fierce jealousy?
No, I like it.
I thought he was a boring ascetic,
but he has a heart capable to love.
I got interested in him.
That's good.
I don't know what
to make of men.
I knew they are foolish but how could
they fall for girls with poor backgrounds?
I know.
You see in the dramas, a rich
guy falls for a shocking poor girl...
...and the girl gets hit
or money from his parents.
'You'll marry her
over my dead body!'
What is it?
That mentality of men.
What mentality? You shouldn't
be materialistic like that.
To men, there's something
more important than money.
More important than
money? Like what?
Protective instinct.
Nope!
To men, appearance
counts the most.
Was that why
you chose me?
What are you talking about?
You know I'm unique.
I chose you for money.
I'm going to work!
Come here!
One, two, three!
He's too frank.
Mom, so he married you for
money. What about you?
Curious?
I married him for one thing.
Money?
I was ten times
more rich than him.
Then his look?
Are you going to upset me
from the morning?
Then what is it?
It's some garlic bread hot
from the oven. Eat some.
I can barely
swallow this.
I'm so nervous.
Articles on me are decreasing,
but there's no response.
I know.
You were quite an issue before,
but it's so quiet this time.
I thought the public wanted to be
impressed, but maybe I was wrong.
Why don't you go back?
There's no other place like TNC.
I can't.
I made a scene that I won't go back.
It's embarrassing before Mr. Park.
Why?
It's unlike you.
You choose substance
over your pride.
Are you interested in him?
Look, he's a married man.
I detest a married man.
So he's okay
other than that?
Please stop.
Go back to TNC.
That's the best way for now.
Take it.
It's yours anyway.
Our relationship
ends like this,
...but since that ring
brings happiness,
...I wish you
a good relationship.
You can come back if you want anytime.
I'll leave your position vacant.
Should I call him
to see how he's doing?
Right, there's no need to worry
about my pride before him?
I have no personal
feelings for him anyways.
The person you have dialed...
The person you have
dialed is not available...
We cannot live!
We want the CEO to resign now!
Resign now! Resign now!
We want Park Min Jun
to resign now!
Resign now! Resign now!
They are in a meeting.
They'll find a solution.
Stop.
Mr. Park, you shouldn't
come here.
Let's go to the conference room.
I'll explain everything.
-Let's go!
The person you have
dialed is not available.
What's going on?
I heard you calmed store owners
and sent them away.
Yes.
We have a lot of problems.
The customers' response to the
Spicy Chicken Pizza is not good.
I was reported.
It tastes different from sampling.
What's the reason?
We followed Ms. Jeong's recipe,
but it doesn't taste the same.
Then bring her right now.
That's the only way.
Father, she's
already resigned.
Doesn't matter.
Just bring her.
She has to take responsibility
for the problem she caused.
You want me to call her?
No. I'll do it.
Bring her in even if
you have to drag her.
She's the only one to get us
out of this crisis, so bring her.
[5 missed calls
Rena Jeong]
Go ahead.
Their coffee is good.
This is the restaurant
you were going to find me a job.
Our situations are reversed now.
I might have to work here.
That's why I came.
I was surprised to find you gone.
It's only right to be punished
for what you've done wrong.
Can't you come back?
It feels so empty without you.
Mr. Park alone is busy looking for
solutions and he looks exhausted.
Please come back.
Everything is messed up.
Please come back and help.
Did he send you?
No. Though no one says,
everybody feels the same way.
And I miss you so much.
Without you,
I have no one to rely on.
Do you still rely on me
after all that I've done to you?
Yes. I still like you.
You shouldn't like people easily.
Please help.
Sorry, I'm not accustomed
to physical contact.
Alright, Since I caused the
problem, I'll think about it.
Ms. Jeong!
Sorry.
Hello...
[5 missed calls
Mr. Park Min Jun]
Will I end up back there?
Yes. For now,
TNC is the best option.
This is Rena.
Yes. I was waiting
for your call.
What was your
call regarding?
Let's meet and talk.
Okay. I too have
something to tell you.
Since you're busy,
I'll visit you at your office.
I'll be waiting.
Like a brigand.
Yes, this is Rena.
Now?
One day guest?
It's for Healing Recipe,
a real hit these days.
I know. The famous
Jeong Hiyeon is the host.
The appointed guest
can't show up.
Can you make it tomorrow?
Of course. If you let me,
I can do anything.
Come to my office
tomorrow by 10.
By the way,
why did you call me again?
I'm just wondering.
You clearly said...
...no one's interested in a manager
who quit the company in disgrace...
...and I'm only a middle-aged
woman if without a title.
And I've got another tag
on top of them.
A recipe thief.
I know you're smart,
but don't try petty tricks with me.
You think I don't know that
you put on a show for this?
Since the manager job
didn't appeal to you,
and you were fired from broadcasting,
that's why you're trying to make news.
A touching story you confess
your fault to the whole nation.
Not bad.
I like that side of you.
It didn't create a great sensation,
but saved your face.
I'll put you on the air
and see the response.
If you survive this time,
you'll do well on your next.
Oh, Mr. Park.
Let me fill your glass.
I thought you wouldn't come.
Why wouldn't I?
I'm sorry I was so late.
Seems you've really hit
hard times. You became gaunt.
How have you been?
I dreamt every night that
I go to work when I can't go back.
After a such a hard time,
I've just got a job.
I appear on TV tomorrow.
I think this is
the last chance for me.
If things go well, I may be forgiven
by the public and gain my footing.
I will stake my everything
and do my best.
That's good.
I'm sure you'll do a good job.
Oh. You have something
to tell me. What is it?
Nothing.
I was just wondering
if you were doing okay.
Oh.
Didn't you say you too
have something to tell me?
Pardon?
Oh. I'm sorry I couldn't
help you in times of trouble.
I'll accept your heart.
I'll be cheering you on
from afar so do well.
Sure. I'll do a good job.
I think I should go now.
I have a lot to prepare
for the recording tomorrow.
Well, take care.
One moment, I need to buy clothes.
It's time to close.
I'll buy the
most expensive one.
I have to wear it tomorrow
so give me a little time.
Then take a look around.
Please eat some.
What the...!
Jeong Hiyeon?
Hello.
Hey, Hiyeon.
Look great.
Today you have
a new guest.
Who?
You know
Chef Rena Jeong.
-Rena Jeong?
-Yes.
I don't know her.
Oh, you don't?
How are you?
What is this?
Excuse me?
Take it off.
Take it off now!
What's wrong with you?
[Subtitles Provided by MBC
Edited by VENLOW @ Subscene.com]
Let's do it brightly,
pleasantly.
Yeah, make my day.
I'll never lose again.
Stop suffocating me
and just leave me alone!
What? Suffocating you?
I'll get rid of her
out of your sight.
I didn't know you were
this terrible person.
You're really going too far.
If you want the Qingdao hospital, you two
build it and live happily ever after!
I'll refuse it!
Get out. I'm sick to death
of incompetents.
Now it's really over.
It's all over.