I asked you will obey me!
I will be indomittable!
I will sumbit you to me, instead!
You don't have the character of Prince!
Although you have 1,000 of strength
and 10,000 swords.
That's the reason why
you can't be the one.
Sir! What have you done to him!
Doctor, doctor!
Fever is getting worse.
You'll lose your conciousness.
- What's the matter with you?
- You're not a human!
Can't you see people dying here!
This is the evidence that
Baekjae poisoned
a messengers with letter of the Emperor!
I will report this to the mainland!
We will find out the truth.
The truth!
I heard you're in difficult situation.
Bring me to castle Sabi!
I'll work things out for you!
When begging won't do any good,
you threaten me?
Bring him back.
And if things go wrong,
hide him safe.
Princess! I may not keep
the promise of being alive.
That woman?
Are you talking about Ms Jin?
Ms Jin?
This man is!
Take him to general's residence!
Jang! Aren't you Jang?
How can you...
Crown Prince!
I called him.
You?
Jang sent me a letter saying
he can work this out.
You can work it out?
Yes, he said he's notjoking.
He told me to solve this.
Yeah? What's your plan?
But you had have used me twice.
I just can't tell you for nothing.
What?
Reinstate me to Taehaksa first!
- How dare you!
- You damned man!
How dare you say it to him!
It's not worth to hear.
If you don't hear me,
you won't get what you want.
Jang!
You're begging me to kill you.
How could I not put my life here
and come this far!
You bastard!
You said you don't need to
keep weak person's promise.
My strategy is my strength.
Now I'm in control,
what will you do?
You can send me back to the Island,
But you won't hear my strategy.
You can slash me with a sword,
but you can't get out of this hell, general.
Lock him up, now!
Yes, sir!
- Take him!
- Yes, sir.
Episode 25.
Let's go.
Jang!
- Crown Prince!
- Jang! Why are you doing this?
I know your anger towards Sun.
This is a matter of Baekjae.
You shouldn't do this.
I also know what you mean.
But this is a matter with general.
Jang!
You must get your hand off this,
And entrust everything to general.
And please pretend you know
nothing about this.
I'll take care of everything
so please don't worry.
He is totally impudent.
Who does he think he's ordering to?
But if he has a strategy...
What about Dr. Mok?
How come Dr. Mok
didn't come with Jang?
Yes, why isn't he here?
He was very sick to come this far.
Something could have happened if he did.
So I had to treat him
in merchant's house in Sangdaepo.
- What?
- But soldiers are with him.
As soon as he recovers,
bring him back!
Then, you knew how he sick was,
And you trusted Jang?
There isn't any, Jang has no plan.
He's just trying to buy some time
for Dr. Mok to recover.
He must have thought of
hiding doctor somewhere.
Go and get Mok Rasoo!
Send a message now!
Yes, sir! Let's go!
He knows his life is on the line
if he has no plan.
Did he really do it for Mok Rasoo?
Jang would do it.
If he decide to save him,
he doesn't think of himself.
We'll find out if we bring Dr. Mok.
How are messengers doing?
They may be waiting orders
from mainland, no movement.
General! Use Goguryu!
Send a message to Goguryu to visit us.
They can't do anything
while Goguryu messengers are here.
But the relationship with Goguryu
is harder than Soo.
Prince is still working on it.
Surely it's that woman.
Without him
I can't smile, or be happy or sad.
Why should I do that?
Where are you going?
I need to do my business.
- Bring him back.
- Alright, come.
They guard him whole time.
What should I do?
Find a way!
Is the woman really merchant from Soo?
Yes, why do you ask?
Then, is she here as a guest?
No, she's traded with us for a few years.
This time she's settled in Baekjae.
This time?
How long ago?
Why do you ask so much?
No, she looks like someone I know.
Ok.
It looked like she went out,
is she home now?
No, she hasn't come home yet.
I have a favor to ask.
I can't walk around now,
So if she comes in,
arrange me to meet her.
Yes, no problem.
Have you been doing this
all night long?
What?
It's pity that you have to
do this for whole day.
We don't want to do this.
- But our duty is...
- You want to drink?
I have some liquor.
Liquor?
You got some left?
Tell me if you want!
It's Sogokju.
- Hansan Sogokju?
- Yes.
Brother! One shot won't hurt us.
The man inside looks he's sick.
What would happen to him?
Shall we just have a sip?
Let's do that!
Follow me.
Doctor! I'm sorry to say this.
What is it?
Boat was arrived late night,
And a lot of merchants
who trade with us, came in.
So you need to empty here.
I'll find other place,
stay there for a while.
Where are soldiers
who guard me?
Yes, I told them to move you...
Jang did this, didn't he?
I'm not going with you.
Doctor!
If I escape now,
Jang will get into trouble,
also I can't return to Taehaksa!
- But, doctor!
- I'm not going.
Boss! We must hurry.
Damn it!
Escort the doctor!
- Why are you diong this?
- I promised Jang.
Don't do this! I'm not going!
I'm not going with you.
Don't do this! I can't go!
You shouldn't do this!
Stop it!
Don't do this!
I'm sorry, doctor!
Don't do this.
Jang will get in danger.
Doctor!
Run as fast as you can.
Until you are ordered,
Don't let him move.
- Yes, sir!
- Go!
Damn it!
We're in trouble.
Tell me where you hide him!
Hide him?
I just gave him medicine,
I haven't seen him since then.
And I just got home!
Right, didn't you guys watch him?
What were you doing?
We're in deep trouble.
We shouldn't be doing this.
Let's look for him.
Yeah, let's hurry!
- What has happened?
- Boss! Boss!
Boss!
What happened?
Why are you alone without doctor?
He was caught on the street.
What?
What is it that you panic?
A friend of mine ask me
to look after a doctor from Taehaksa.
I couldn't keep his promise.
A doctor from Taehaksa?
Do you know him?
He wanted to see you
when you come back.
Why Dr. Mok want to see Ms Jin?
Did you say Dr. Mok Rasoo?
- Do you know him?
- Yes.
Then the person asked you to...
The friend from Chunwie of name is...
Jang!
Jang...
- Do you know him?
- Yes, I do.
How do you know him?
What kind of danger is he in?
I have to go to castle Sabi.
Soldiers are gathered to protect market,
I'm busy with that.
I'll go with you!
Come out!
Talk to him.
Talk about what?
Your strategy.
Do your part first!
Bring him in!
- Doctor!
- Jang!
You talk about power to test me.
It's funny.
If you have a strategy, tell me now!
Otherwise he won't be alive!
Doctor! I'm sorry.
Whatever happens to him,
I'll do this my way this time.
I didn't know you'd do this.
I've never known that
you would bring him by force.
Who is suffering from pain.
I'm truly disappointed.
Sir general!
I will change my proposal.
Reinstate of Taehaksa isn't enough now.
If you want to know my strategy,
You have to add the merit,
we achieved.
And confer me as an engineer
And confer Dr. Mok
as the master of Taehaksa!
This is my new proposal.
- Jang!
- Moreoever,
Our designation must be held first!
Otherwise I won't say a thing.
Either you kill me or not,
it's your call now, general!
You're doing this to save me
but you don't have a clue!
Jang!
Now my life and your life are on the line,
Don't I have to think anything?
How reckless are you!
Don't worry, doctor.
Trust me.
The woman you aparted in Silla.
Yeah?
How did you end up having farewell?
You couldn't win over the hierarchy?
No, she was very high class.
Finally she was caught by bodyguards.
But why do you ask now?
Have you met her again?
How can I meet her
when she is left in Silla?
If she's not here to see Jang,
why did she disguise herself
as a merchant?
So Jang told general
that he has an idea,
And he got into palace?
Yes.
He tried to burden it himself
and asked me to take care of him.
And I was so loose, gosh.
You got to find out
something now, Seochung!
Yes?
I thought Jang would listen to us
when Mok is brought here.
But he ended up rebelling.
It seems he really has the strategy.
What do you think?
I do not agree with it.
It happened anyway
and he's trying to buy some time.
- So, now is...
- General!
What do you want?
Messengers want to see you.
They do?
Message arrived from the nation!
To kill the messenger
with letter of Emperor
is insulting him
and he was very furious.
Considering the relation with Baekjae,
we won't cut off the trade
So hand over the Gubong mine to Soo!
- What?
- What did you say?
Or I was ordered to bring
general who
is responsible for this incident.
What?
We're leaving 3 days later!
Decide until morning of the day!
Whether you come with us
or hand in Gubong mine!
Gubong mine?
Is Soo confiscating the land of Baekjae?
This is total nonsense!
This must not happen
in history of Baekjae.
But, if we don't accept it,
General will be taken
with all responsibility.
We wouldn't know what will happen.
I've seen plenty of this
unfair diplomacy enough.
Then are you saying
we should hand over the gold mine?
Anyway we mustn't let general
to be taken away.
We have to stop it.
This is very intolerable.
It's not somewhere,
it's Gubong mine!
That's the biggest gold mine in Baekjae.
Right, this isn't a small issue.
It's the demand of big nation,
we can't do anything.
Are you saying we should
hand over the general?
That's why I'm discussing.
So when Prince asked to
do fabrics little slowly,
it would have never happened to us.
Why is it Sun's fault?
This is the problem
they disguised the death!
Isn't that diplomacy?
It is common that messenger
gets died on travelling far.
Every time it happens,
with bad mutual countries,
This kind of problem
always have caused.
That's why Prince always
took care of messengers first.
And negotiation comes afterward.
Plus, you could let Prince
to take care of it.
But you stole the body
and it got worse and worse.
What are you trying to say?
Are you saying general has to
be fully responsible?
It's not whose responsibility now.
To be confiscated the mine
is not only matter of loss,
It's directly related to the pride of Baekjae.
I cannot agree with that.
What? Are you saying
that we have to send the general?
All of you!
Do you think the same?
Other nations can't give up
their pride and benefit,
That's why they send a hostage.
What!
It's not too late.
You can tell them that
we'll support weapons to Goguryu.
We can go from there.
Prince Aja always have insisted it
with relation of Soo.
When we deal with the mainland,
it is much lucrative
for 3 of us to show unity.
But Baekjae and Goguryu
have been enemy for so long.
Prince Aja has been suggesting it,
And that's why most of nobles
don't support him.
That my brother can't do this.
But this isn't the ordinary situation.
Even if he does, Soo won't buy it.
We have to make them to.
Diplomacy is how much
you make them trust
and cheat each other.
Using Goguryu is the brilliant move.
Why do you hesitate?
Aren't you Baekjae person?
The relationship
between Baekjae and Goguryu
is much difficult than
Baekjae and Silla.
If he makes a wrong move,
he will be on the edge.
But if we work things out as Jang said.
General's position will never be expanded.
Rather, it extens Prince's influence.
I know enemies are all over us.
You can't get what you want
without listening to my plan.
How could I not put my life here
and come this far!
You said you don't need to
keep weak person's promise.
My strategy is my strength.
Now I'm in control,
what will you do?
You can slash me with a sword,
but you can't get out of
this hell, general.
Hand over the Gubong mine
Or the general has to be taken to Soo.
Gubong mine!
Now, general is in the corner.
Then he can go to Soo.
Do you think you'll safe after all?
Even if I'm not
I gotta win this time.
Unless you keep your promise fisn't,
I won't say a thing from my mouth.
How can't you distinguish
national and personal matter!
I will do it tomorrow!
Tomorrow, I will appoint
you and Mok's designation!
Tomorrow?
Really?
So tonight,
Open the board of doctor officially.
Do you really trust
Jang has the strategy?
Yes.
I thought he did it to save Mok
in the first place.
But I put Mok's life on the line
but he wasn't moved.
He won't put his life on risk
to just piss me off.
He has the strong will to survive.
And that's why he made it
through the steeple.
It was the same eyes
when he had at the fire steeple.
Maybe, maybe he used that?
Here you are.
Where have you been?
I sent Goosan to Silla.
Why?
I can't hide to live.
I got to bring my assets which I can.
Yes, I have an idea of myself.
Ok, by the way didn't
general's case solve yet?
Finally, he accepted Jang's proposal,
Dr. Mok will be designated
as the master tomorrow.
What?
Doesn't Dr. Wooyoung designate
as the master?
I thought it was,
but what's this designation?
Right. This is too sudden.
People are in panic
because of the messengers.
I have no idea what is happening.
I thought Jang is here,
but he's not around.
What happened?
I don't know, I saw him.
Maybe not.
That's surely I might not saw...
- How, how!
- What? What?
Who is that? Look!
It's Jang! It's Jang!
Jang!
Attention!
Neverthless, Dr. Mok Rasoo
and engineer Jang,
Were demoted regarding
their behavior in Silla,
They invented loom device
to produce pattern fabric.
They achieved high honor of Baekjae!
Therefore I absolved their sin from Silla!
Engineer trainer Jang to engineer!
Dr. Mok Rasoo is to
the master of Taehaksa,
The board of doctor has
decided yesterday!
Dr. Mok and engineer Jang
stand in front of Prince!
Come forward, Dr. Mok.
The Imperial of Baekjae
achknowledge your merit
so I designate you
as the master of Taehaksa.
Come forward, engineer Jang.
The Imperial of Baekjae
achknowledge your merit
so I designate you
as the engineer of Taehaksa.
- Jang!
What happened?
How did this happen?
I heard you were in the palace
but you weren't around.
I was so worried.
Jang!
Now I kept your promise,
let's go to general!
Time hasn't come yet.
Also, I haven't seen
my colleagues for long time,
So I have to enjoy myself.
And I need to be congratulated
for becoming an engineer.
Please wait, let's go!
- Sir, please drink a lot.
- Alright, alright.
How did this happen?
And what's that promise?
It's nothing.
How have you been?
Haneuljae people are divided
in half because of Giroo.
And general got punished
from heaven so he's in trouble.
He tried to prove the cause of death,
Giroo and Dr. Wooyoung tried their best,
They got general in deep trouble.
Let's talk this thing later.
We just need to drink it.
Of course, you don't know
how much I wanted to drink it.
I'm gonna drink until I get druken.
Yeah, that's good to hear.
Since you're back from hell,
now you're a real man.
At the east river's
sleeping bird
sun is shined
Dad, it doesn't really suit on this.
- Let's drink.
- You give it a try.
There you are.
What if a spark gets to us?
A spark?
We've done nothing wrong.
But I can't see them in their eyes.
I feel so much better.
I felt bad that
we've done it to them
But now Jang's an engineer
and doctor is the master.
So I'm relieved.
It's better to think that way.
But how in the world
could happen like this?
Does anyone know why?
I don't know well.
But Giroo said Jang can fix
this messenger incident.
That incident?
How?
It won't be easy...
So no one knows
how this end up.
Did you call us?
You two need to go
somewhere urgently.
- Just two of us?
- Yes.
Where to?
You need to go to Wolnagun.
- To Wolnagun?
- That's too far.
What do you want?
You probably have seen
the woman in Jingak temple.
The woman in Jingak temple?
The woman who was
in love with Jang?
Yes, I think I saw her in Wolnagun.
- Huh?
- She's in Baekjae?
It seems like it.
To look for Jang?
Shouldn't she be in castle Sabi, then?
That's what I thought.
If she's looking for Jang,
she must be in castle Sabi.
She's staying with
merchant in Wolnagun,
And pretending as a merchant from Soo.
A merchant from Soo?
Find out whether
she's right and if so
why she is doing that for.
- Find out in detail.
- Yes.
And this is...
Jang must not know this.
And he won't have time to.
Right, we all know who caused this.
- Let's go.
- We'd get going now.
How did this happen?
Jang said that he can
work things out with messengers.
He has a plan?
Well, I wouldn't know.
Surely, he must have something.
Would he do this without any plan?
- Yeah?
- But why?
Write that and send it
to him unanimously.
Would it help him?
If we're thinking the same thing,
it'll help.
It'll strengthen him.
Finally, general accepted
duke Seodong's proposal,
They have finished their designations.
Would he really have the plan?
If he doesn't,
he's in serious danger.
Have you stretched that thing?
Yes, yes.
It's very nicely done.
- I have a favor.
- Huh?
Whether it's Taehaksa,
palace or castle Sabi,
Do I have good connections?
Well, I'm trying to show off
But out of all people,
I have good connection.
- I know it bothers you...
- Alright.
Through your favor,
I'll show you my good connections.
I think I should create a broadband myself.
Then, find out one thing for me.
What?
- Are you engineer Jang?
- Yes, I am.
Someone wanted to deliver this.
Who sent you this?
You know, a guy...
I don't think I need to ask you a favor.
What? Are you kidding me?
What's that letter?
Have a seat.
Tell me what is your plan.
You don't have one?
Then get out of Baekjae now.
If you were trying to save my life,
You don't have to do this.
I'll take all responsibilities,
escape now.
There is! I have a plan.
The moment general designated
you as the master!
I got a plan.
So don't worry too much.
I don't know whether he'll do it
but I have a plan.
Is Jang still like that?
Yes, he's been drinking
since afternoon.
What is it? At this night!
Yes, I came to inspect your places.
Don't you have any uncomfortable things?
No, everything is fine!
By the way
you haven't decided yet?
Tomorrow at 8 o'clock
the boat departs.
We're not going with empty hands.
Whether we take general
to drown in Wang's sorrow,
or take the mine.
We have to follow Emperor's decision.
Would the mine be
more important than general?
It's 8 o'clock, decide!
Bring Jang now.
Yes!
Jang is missing.
He's not there.
What? Has he ran away?
Yes!
Find him now!
Bastard!
What is it?
How dare you!
I have to decide in between two
by tomorrow morning.
And I've born your reckless behavior
and I've done what you had asked for.
Tell me now.
What's your plan?
I said tell me now!
I already taught you my strategy!
- What?
- Definitely, I taught you.
My life was on the line
but I came back to Taehaksa
And became an engineer
and doctor became the master.
How could this happen?
Nothing is something?
The strategy which nothing can be
seen as something!
You have no plan!
Yes, but you believed
I have something,
and I acquired what I needed.
So now I can confront you like this.
The best strategy that
weak one can use to strong one.
But there is only one condition on this.
One is capacity and courage.
Like you were fooled by me,
You shouldn't be shaken
in any circumstances.
I mean, they have to trust you.
In order to do that,
you need capacity to bet your life on it!
That's why I waited for the moment
you were driven to the edge.
Because capacity that
I and Soo messengers have,
you don't have it, general.
No Emperor sends messengers
to cut off the relation.
Moreover, according to my information,
A ship was departed
but it never returned.
It means they sent a man to their country.
But he never came back here.
If you're a coward,
you can't use this strategy.
I taught you my strategy.
Now it's all up to you.
If you and I are thinking
the same thing,
it will help you.
A ship was sent to Soo but it didn't return.
They have never discussed
anything with the Emperor.
Believe in yourself.
Who could it be?
Who would send this letter?
I read his thought
and still I couldn't move general,
His will splited him and me?
You are dead meats.
- Do you want to live?
- Yes.
There is a way.
Put fire on the fire steeple.
Just kill me.
I don't want no arrows in my body.
Let's do this!
I'll do it, I'll do this!
If there's no plan,
let it drive into the corner.
Rat can bite cat.
What will you do?
Now it's time.
Tell us now!
- Listen up!
- Yes, sir!
Lock up all messengers
except Sir Gook.
And execute them tomorrow 8 o'clock.
- Proceed immediately!
- Yes.
General! What are you doing!
It happened anyhow,
I can't hand over the mine
and I'm not going either.
I'll break relation with Soo!
I needed a man to report
this situation to Soo,
so I leave you out.
Go to your country
and report this, Sir Gook!
- Take them!
- Yes, sir!
This way.
Let go, let go!
You bastards!
How did this happen?
General clarified to break the relation,
And lock up all messengers from Soo.
What?
It'll lead to a war.
I trusted your confidence,
How did you do
this reckless decision?
Please trust me, lord!
It will work outjust fine.
How can you say
that with this situation?
Prince got to wrap it up queitly now.
I told you to do this
and I'll take all responsibilities.
Let me handle it to the end.
Are you confident?
I will do it.
Lord! Lord!
I must find out one thing.
As general clarified the break of relation,
is this the decision of Baekjae Imperial?
Is this true?
Poisoning Wang wasn't enough
and you're doing this unreasonable act,
Is this the decision of Baekjae Imperial!
How dare you!
Where do you think
you're misbehaving?
Lord! I will execute Sir Gook now!
Please allow me to execute him!
I will send his neck
to the Emperor of Soo,
And show my mean.
Please allow me to execute him!
Sir Gook!
They are messengers of the mainland.
Would it be ok?
This is reckless.
Please settle it now.
After listening to Jang
who made a troble,
and doing this isn't possible.
It's not very reliable.
No, this will work.
I also haven't used that strategy,
but it will work on bigger nation.
And he's not the Emperor of Soo,
he's just a messenger.
It doesn't make sense that
we have to watch them.
Because they have stronger nation.
I believe in Jang's strategy.
What are messengers doing now?
They don't think they would be executed.
They don't think so?
I'm going to execute them
tomorrow morning, be prepared.
Are you really going to kill them?
Yes, I must.
Success of this strategy
Depends on putting every risk I have.
This is reckless.
What if it doesn't work?
What if you fail?
Your life is for sure,
doctor's life is in your hand.
The book you told me to read,
there is a story.
A man was announced
to be a death row.
On the execution day,
he requested weird proposal.
If King spares him one year,
he will teach how to fly to
King's dearest horse.
So King allowed his proposal.
His cell mate asked him
why he did such thing.
But his answer was like this.
Who would know
what would happen 1 year later?
King might die or
I might die within a year.
Or horse maybe the one.
And who knows?
Horse can really fly 1 year later!
Do you think Baekjae
will be safe after this!
I didn't want to come this far either!
But, as you said it's my fault,
or as I insist it's your obstinacy.
It happened anyway.
Handing over the mine
is humliation of Baekjae,
It cannot be accepted anyhow.
And I won't go as a hostage, either.
So we have to break
the relation with Soo.
If you do that to us,
it's a war!
Fortunately we don't share
the border with Soo.
You'd recruit forces
and request more units to Goguryu.
The sign to break the relation,
You would know it well!
I don't have any personal grudge to you.
But it happened in between
affair of our nations.
Please forgive me!
Proceed!
- Proceed.
- Yes, sir.
- Proceed!
- Yes, sir!
What are you doing?
Execute them now!
Wait! Wait a minute!
I'm sorry. It's too late.
- Soldiers!
- Yes, sir!
Wait! Demanding gold mine was
too much, I will withdraw it!
Didn't you say you already
sent a message to your country!
- Execute them!
- Wait!
I'll confess!
I lied to you!
Honestly, my Imperial doesn't know
anything about his death.
Then sending a message
to the mainland is a lie?
That's right. Break the relation,
gold mine and recall general
These are not from the mainland!
What? How can you devise it
as a messenger?
What else can we exchange your gold
if not papers or fabrics?
We're in trouble if we go back.
Well, it's too late!
You're saying this
to save your life now.
But if you go back, you will tell
General poisoned him.
What are you waiting!
Execute them now!
- Yes, sir!
- No! Please wait.
It will never, never happen!
Are you saying
you will hide the poisoning?
It's not that.
Sir Wang had a heart disease.
Emperor knows this,
so it wont' be a problem.
- What?
- And this,
I'll take care of it
and won't mention to anyone.
Please be mercy and release us!
Anyway I was ordered to maintain
The annual amount of gold.
Please I'm asking you to
maintain my decency.
And it won't be a problem.
I will swear to heaven.
Sir general!
Pleaes trust my words.
General!
We all work to benefit our countries.
Let's trust them and negotiate.
Yes! Trust me!
Alright! I want you to resume,
the disclosed Baekjae place in Gyerim.
If you do that, I will guarantee
the same amount of gold.
I'll do that.
I can talk about that!
Remove it!
Thank you, thank you.
Thank you, general.
How can you be working now?
You and doctor's life are on the line.
How can you be so calmed?
I'm nervous this time.
Either you die this time, Jang
Or my heart will explode.
Prince is coming.
Jang! You pulled it off.
You made it!
Prince is coming with smile.
Aren't you curious?
You weren't waiting for it.
Honestly, I was too nervous
and afraid to go out and wait.
That's tedious for you to say.
Well done! Your capacity
resolved a difficult issue.
Lord! I told him not to do
that next time.
Is that true?
Is it true?
Yes, I went to palace to submit permit.
I heard it myself.
Jang's strategy worked just fine.
Yes, yes...
What's your relationship with Jang?
It's more than words can express.
Why don't you meet him
and doing this behind him?
Yes, why don't you meet him now?
Yes, lady!
Send my letter again.
Yes!
What is it?
Is engineer Jang in there?
He's not here, what is it?
I'll deliver your message.
No, I'll come back.
I hired him!
You people made the incident
he was seeing Silla woman,
and insult his royalty and my insight.
He is the one who solved
a difficult issue with messengers!
So, lord! The reason
he had to run away in Silla,
I think you should conceal it for him.
I think the same.
It is the vigrous youth that
anyone could have done!
If you can't allow that much,
And misinterpret his
ability and royalty.
How can we hire intelligent man?
I'll absolve your crime,
reborn as royal servant of Baekjae!
Yes, lord!
Although things turned out fine,
if it didn't work out,
think about how much
We had to be humilated from Soo.
So general must reflect it deeply
And do not engage any affairs
except military police!
Yes, lord.
Daringly, you told me
to submit me.
He totally got me.
It's just beginning.
I should have listened to your advice.
Yes, Jang defeated you mentally.
But don't worry about it too much.
He gets things done
with reckless and capacity.
But he causes many trouble
because of it.
I used to be like him.
But I should change.
To be your enemy,
I should have learnt
your precision and moderation.
Further, your cruelty.
Yes, I hope you do.
I hope our fight won't be bored.
Prince wants to see you.
Yes.
What's the matter?
Why are you here and
doing nothing?
That's...
What's the business with Jang?
Tell me now.
That's...
- Did you come to see me?
- Yes, I have things to ask you.
Alright, follow me.
Did the same person send you again?
- Yes.
- What is it?
I have to deliver it only to you.
Ok, thanks.
It's like you as I expected.
When you shoot,
the world is shoot!