Father's Day, My son wiping the saliva
that escapes my closed lips.
We have never before fitted this made-up
holiday into our emotional calendar.
[singing]
Claude says the book's going well,
I can't believe you're writing it.
I still think you're the most surprising man I've ever known.
Have you had lots of visitors?
Laurent, Anne-Marie...
...Michel...
That's it?  She hasn't?
I thought she was supposed to be madly in love with you.
Well, that's her business.
Shall we practice that alphabet?
When I began a diet a week before my stroke
...I never dreamed of such dramatic results.
Now they know what it's like to have a
zombie for a father. Thank you.
That's not amusing.
Kids.
You want to play Hangman, dad?
I'll help you, Whisper a word.
The first letter is a C, the last an E.
The word has 7 letters.
The kangaroo jumped the wall.
The wall of the zoo.
My God, it was high.
My God, it was beautiful.
That's it.
- Say goodbye to your dad, kids. We're leaving.
Bye, dad.
Bye dad, See you next week.
It's hard to describe my grief.
I'm their father, but I can't touch them,
run my fingers through their hair...
...and hug them tight.
But I like to see them play and laugh.
That's what I call a wonderful day.
I feel sorry for myself, don't you think?
You were genuinely happy.
You think so?
Perhaps.
I don't want to miss this,
Step aside!
Enjoy. See you.
- Yeah, see you, What are you doing??
Finish the TV-Meal,
or shall I go out for dinner?
I will treat myself to a feast at Le Duc.
What a coincidence to find you here.
- Isn't that amazing?
An oyster?
It seems like it was just yesterday
when I first heard your name.
Sweet.
No compliments.
And the next chapter?
Sunday, I dread Sunday.
When they turn the TV on,
they have to make sure they're doing it right.
That is very strategic.
It can take hours until the next good samaritan comes by.
Horrible, these Sundays.
No speech therapists, no psychotherapist.
No physiotherapist, no visitors.
A skeleton staff.
Sunday is a long stretch of desert.
But today, Marie nobly suggests she takes me to mass.
I have tried to explain to her that I am not
a religious man, but without avail.
All over the world people are praying for me.
Top of the list is my daughter, Céleste.
And Marie, of course.
The most diverse deities have been enlisted to help me.
In Nepal, I'm told, they chant a mantra for me.
In Cameroon a holy man has procured
for me the goodwill of Africa's gods.
I have assigned him my right eye.
I can't deny that I have attempted to
organise this vast spiritual energy...
...to support my existence.
It may not be admirable, it may even be
a touch hypocritical, but I'll try anything.
I'm very pleased to see you here.
I came to visit you a few days ago, I brought
the Blessed Sacrament to give you Communion.
But you were asleep.
Yes, he was asleep.
- What?
Would you like me to give you Holy Communion now?
- No.
Yes.
- Would you like me to say a blessing over you?
No.
- Yes.
Heavenly Father, have mercy on Jean-Dominique,
who is cruelly afflicted.
Help his body to heal, keep his spirits buoyant,
and help him to find faith.
- My spirit is very buoyant, mister.
In the name of the father...
- You made a fool of me.
Fa?
Father?
There are...
Father, there are monks in Bordeaux who
regularly dedicate their prayers to me.
...who regularly dedicate their prayers to me.
Do they, that's good.
- But the results have been unremarkable.
We must be patient.
- Yes, the doctors say that too.
But Jean-Dominque, I want to suggest something to you
In a few weeks time, I shall be
leading a pilgrimage to Lourdes.
Lourdes?
Dear Beatrice and I thought you
might want to be part of it.
This is a trap.
- There have been some miraculous cures.
That's true.
- I've been to Lourdes.
Let's stop and return.
- I am not turning back.
It's my car, I'll drive where I like.
You said you wanted a dirty weekend.
- I never said that.
Yes you did, Lourdes is not the right place for a dirty week-end.
You've got a one-track mind.
I want to see the Madonna.
I don't believe in any of this.
- I want to see her and drink holy water.
Spare me this.
You should do that too.
It will be good for you.
Impressive, right?
I'll buy some bottles for the holy water.
That's it for me, I'm leaving.
- Stay, It could do you a lot of good.
Don't be so sure, it might be dangerous.
What if someone in perfect health happened to be here when
the Madonna appeared? One miracle, and he'd end up paralyzed.
You are terrible.
Hello.
- Good day, madam.
Look! Here's my Madonna!
Forget it.
- Yeah, then get out of my life.
Okay, I'll give it to you as a present.
Madame has a wonderful eye.
That piece is unique, it has blessed by the Cardinal.
Do we have more 318's?
- Look in the storage.
How much is that?
-1899 franc (£217).
Don't we know each other?
- I don't think so, Mister.
I don't have change.
I can't make love to you with her looking at me.
- I understand.
I wasn't stating a fact, I was making a complaint.
Let me turn her off.
No.
The only one in the whole world
Blessed by the Cardinal.
Josephine, when we get back to Paris
we're going to have to split up.
Because of her?
- No, Because of everything.
Ok, you're right.
Im going out again.
- Turn off the lights.
But not my Madonna.
La - la - la - , Come on, Jean-Do.
If you learn the L sound you'll learn to swallow.
And you'll learn to say Lourdes.
Is that okay? Is it comfortable?
'The Pressure Cooker' could be the title of the piece...
...I'm writing about my experiences here.
I could also call it 'The Eye' or 'The Diving Bell'.
Plot and location are well known.
In a hospital room, there's Mr. L,
at the climax of his life...
...trying to live with locked-in syndrome
after a serious stroke.
Ambitious and somewhat cynical,
because he didn't know failures before...
...becomes acquainted with misfortune.
We can show his transformation,
whilst listining to a commentarial voice...
...which tells the inner monologue of Mr. L.
I already have the last scene.
It's night.
Mr L, who was paralysed since
the beginning of the piece...
...suddenly jumps out of his bed
and runs over the darkly lit stage.
Then it gets dark again and we hear
Mr L's commentarial voice:
Fuck, it was a dream.
Stand up, I can stand up.
Everything is alright.
'I want to remember how all this happened
to me.'
Shall I ask someone?
No?
Hello, room 119.
- Who's that?
I'm Claude Mendibil.
I'm sitting with Jean-Do.
This is his father speaking.
- Yes, we were expecting your call.
So what do I do? Just talk?
Jean-Do can hear you.
He will answer you.
You'll hear me saying the alphabet and...
- Yes, Céline told me.
Just talk, Mister Bauby.
Can he hear me?
Jean-Dominique? This is Papinou.
I'm sitting at the open window.
How are you or is that a foolish question??
Yes, it's a foolish question.
I miss you.
I miss you, too.
God Almighty! This is an impossible way to
conduct a conversation.
Everything goes out of my mind.
No, no, I've remembered.
I'm sending you a present.
It's a surprise.
I had a thought...
...about us. We're in the same boat.
I'm stuck in this apartment.
I can't get up and down the stairs.
You try four flights of stairs
when you're ninety-two years old.
we're both locked-in cases.
You in your body and me in my apartment.
Jean-Dominique, remember...
...in the top right-hand drawer of my
writing desk there's a letter...
In it are my last wishes. It's in a file...
,,,marked 'Miscellaneous'.
I must stop now.
Don't cry.
- That's easy to say.
You're my son for Christ's sake.
Good-bye, Jean-Dominique.
I forgot, it's almost your birthday.
I'll call again.
Happy Birthday.
It can't be easy for a father to speak
to a son who he knows will never reply.
I thought an outing with a new vista would do you good.
I have another surprise for you.
Close your eyes.
Okay, now open them.
THE COUNT OF MONTE CRISTO
That was not necessary.
In two volumes.
It's not a first edition, but it's pretty old.
Would you like me to read something to you?
Which chapter?
We should use Roman digits.
We didn't think of Roman digits.
What would it be in Roman digits?
That's L, I, X.
That's faster. Next time.
50? Higher?
- Yes, higher.
Nine? 59? Ok.
Ok, there we go.
There's even an illustration.
The coincidence frightens me.
'They sat down beside him.'
'Noirtier was sitting in a wheelchair where
they put him from morning till evening...
...in front of a mirror which allowed
him to see the whole apartment...
without attempting any movement: this was something
that had become impossible for him.
Sight and hearing were the only two senses...
...which, like two sparks,
still lit up this human matter...'
'...this human matter.'
That's me, don't you think?
But no.
- But yes.
I frighten people, make them shudder.
You don't.
- I should have stayed away from Dumas.
Don't tamper with a masterpiece.
That's the lesson.
I didn't know Noirtier was the man
I was going to become.
My diving bell has dragged you down
to the bottom of the sea with me.
Jean-Do, I don't find it so bad that you
drag me down to the bottom of the sea...
...because you are also my butterfly.
That's a declaration of love.
After we finish this book...
...we'll write another one about
a long-distance runner.
You never know. Perhaps I'll become like him.
'I missed you at the bullfight.
I hope we meet again next year.
Jean-Paul.'
Le Tango, Nîmes.
'Dear Mr Bauby, the customized campmobile...
...can be delivered six to eight
weeks after your order.
Yours sincerely, Henri Raynaud.'
That's good news.
This is from Papinou.
'This is a present.'
Look, a photo of you as a kid.
Jean-Do, aged eight, Berck on sea.
From Anne-Marie.
Jean-Dominique Bauby's room.
- Who are you?
Céline Desmoulins. And you?
Inès. I want to speak with Jean-Do.
One moment.
I turned the speaker on, so he can hear you.
I can't speak with you there.
You have to, there's no one else.
Isn't the therapist there?
- No, she's not here today.
Darling?
I know I said I'd come but I got as far as
the train station and then turned back.
I just can't.
Please forgive me.
Céline?
- Yes.
Can't you just go out for a moment?
I have personal things to say.
I feel embarrassed.
- I can't leave him.
There's nobody else.
Wait, he wants to say something.
O?
One?
One minute?
I'm leaving. But not for long.
Jean-Do, are you alone now?
Darling...
I love you more than ever.
I want to see you but I haven't the courage.
I want to think of you as you were.
I hope you'll recover.
I miss you.
I miss you and I feel so alone.
I know you understand.
You're in my thoughts all the time.
I know your family is always with you.
Do you want me to come?
I'm back.
- Do you want me to come?
Do you want me to come?
- I'm back, Inès.
Every...
Every day.
Every day I'm...
Every day I'm waiting for you.
I can't understand you. Could you repeat that?
I can't understand you.
He said: I'm waiting for you every day.
If I don't get a seat on this plane.
I will miss my connection to Hong-Kong.
Take mine.
I'll take the next flight.
- Thank you.
Have a good trip.
But you're not going to Hong-Kong
you are going to Beirut.
Anything wrong? You don't feel good?
Don't worry.
Most times I forget my dreams.
People who tell you their dreams are tiresome.
But this one comes again and again.
I don't know why.
I'm afraid.
The feeling of doom wouldn't leave.
It took what I can only describe as
a miracle to lift my spirits.
It's dangerous to believe in personal miracles.
They tend to make one feel self-important.
Nevertheless, I must report that I believe
something miraculous did occur.
I began to sing.
I grunt, I sing.
My hearing isn't great and sometimes
I think I hear my heart beating.
But I tell myself it's the sound
of butterfly's wings.
Yes, I am making indomitable progress and
I may even have butterfly hearing.
I can look forward to the future.
Soon the summer will come to an end...
...and I will begin my first
autumn in this hospital.
My life is here.
An everlasting repetition.
Here.
How goes it?
He's speaking!
You're speaking.
- He can sing a song, too.
Come on, sing for Laurent.
- Please, for me.
'The kangaroo jumped the wall,
the wall of the zoo.
My God it was high,
My God it was beautiful.'
Are you ok?
Is he singing?
- No, he isn't.
I have pneumonia.
Just when I thought...
Like a sailor who watches the shore gradually disappear,
I watch my past recede.
Becoming ashes of oblivion.
What a comeback.
That's where I worked. And that couple, I know them,
but I can't remember their names.
That's my car!
My new car.
Where is the horn?
Let me hug you.
- See my car?
Lovely.
Everything ok, Théo?
Had a good week?
Are we going to the theatre?
- To the theatre? If you want to.
Can we have oysters?
- Do you like oysters now?
Don't bring him back too late.
We are leaving.
Can I get in the front?
- Sure, there's no room in the back.
Next time only you and I will go.
A little bit of wind?
Your team ok?
- Yeah, the players are ok.
You take a shower afterwards?
- We shower and wash our stuff.
Got pubic hair around your willy?
- No, not yet.
When i was young, We had one guy who didn't want to undress for the shower.
They stopped him playing football because of it.
His father wanted to fight the trainer.
He didn't do it.
His mother stopped him.
In the end, he had to leave the team.
You don't have that problem, do you?
-No, I dont have a problem with that.
Good, you dont need that.
Other news? Everything ok with mum?
- Yeah, she's ok.
You know this way?
- Yes, it's the way to Aunt Diane.
It's hot, You feel that, too?
No, I don't.
We have...
It might start to rain, I'll stop for a moment.
Dad, what's the matter?
Phone your mother!
My last thought was we'll have to cancel
going to the theatre.
We'd be late in any case.
We'll go tomorrow night.
And then I sank into a coma.
It is a book?
'THE DIVING BELL AND THE BUTTERFLY'
For Théophile, Céleste and Hortense.
I wish them lots of butterflies.
And my deepest gratitude to Claude Mendibil.
You'll understand that wihout her
this book couldn't have been written.
I was with you the whole time.
You know that.
These reviews are terrific!
You want to hear them?
The man who dictates in silence.
Without gestures or speech.
Jean-Dominque Bauby communicates
with an eyelid and writes this book.
A touching visit to the
wreckage of abandonment.
By Bernard Chapuis.
'A touching book.'
Jean-Dominique Bauby, age 43, recognized journalist,
father, free man...
...plans to write a novel about female revenge.
Jean-Dominique Bauby died on March 9th, 1997.
10 days after the publication of 'The Diving Bell and the Butterfly'
...10 days after the publication of
'The Diving Bell and the Butterfly'.