Ari, dear.
Will you please get out of bed.
We need to get going.
We can't depart like this.
Ari...
I don't want to move.
I know, but I'm going to places
that aren't for children.
I wouldn't be able to
take care of you.
You won't just be with your dad.
Your granny is there too
and she's dying to see you.
Please get up, dear.
There's no room for the bike in the car.
-I'm not going without it.
There's no room for it.
Put it in the truck.
Come here, darling.
I'm going to miss you so much,
you know that.
I'll call you later.
It will be fine, I promise.
SPARROWS
Hi buddy.
Hi.
Is that all you've got?
-Yes.
How was the flight?
It was fine.
No turbulence?
No, just a bit.
The tunnel had opened before you moved ?
-No.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm certain.
Makes the journey
a lot shorter.
Now we live here.
-I know, Mom told me.
Yes... Hello.
I'm on my way.
We eat at Mom's at 7.
But rush over to her
because she's waiting for you.
I have to get back to work.
You have the second room upstairs.
Everything alright?
-OK.
Oh, my darling boy.
My dearest, darling boy.
It's so good to see you.
-Hi Grandma.
It's been ages since
I've seen you, dear.
The last time was
the Christmas concert on TV.
You sang so beautifully.
-Yeah, thanks.
How was Spain?
Fine. We old ladies
drank quite a lot, though.
Would you like some coffee?
-No thanks, I don't drink coffee.
No, he doesn't drink coffee.
Your mom called earlier.
Did she reach you?
Yes.
That was nice.
I spoke to her husband
the other day.
What a charming man.
And they've moved to Angola.
No, Uganda.
And then they go on to Kenya, Ethiopia
and a few other places.
I don't care what your father says.
I admire your mothers energy.
Mmm... Good.
I walked by
our old house earlier on.
You did?
-Yeah.
Has the house been for sale long?
Yes, since the bank
took it. And the boat.
Please have some more to eat, boys.
Would you pass me the jam?
-Sure, there you go.
Hey, I had a word with Diddi
about you earlier.
So, he's expecting you
for work tomorrow morning.
Work?
-Yes, work.
Did you plan to stay in bed
until school starts?
No.
Could you pass me back the jam?
-Sorry.
It doesn't stay this bright
at night in Reykjavík?
No.
We are a lot farther north here.
Greetings.
-Hi.
Hi. Dagur.
-Ari.
Welcome to the West.
-Thanks.
I'm going upstairs.
-Alright mate.
Look, the rules have changed.
The boy is living with
me now. Get it?
Yes, yes.
You can't just waltz
in and out of here anymore.
No, no, no.
You have a cigarette?
-Yes, of course.
This is my new assistant.
He is as strong
as a 6-year old girl.
See you later.
Hi.
-Hello.
Wow! I can't believe it.
Great to see you.
You too.
Been here long?
-No, just got here yesterday.
Stopping long?
Well, I've actually moved back.
-OK.
I'm working at the
fish factory this summer.
Then I'll be going to
school here in the autumn.
Hi.
-Hi.
This is Einar, my boyfriend.
This is Ari, a childhood friend.
Hello.
-Hello.
Shouldn't we get going?
-Yes.
See you.
Bye.
Hi.
-Hi.
Hey, was that little Lára out there?
What? Yes.
Really? She's matured quite a bit!
-Dad, please!
Don't be so touchy.
How long has this foreigner that your
mother married been in Iceland?
About eight years.
-Eight years?
I tried calling your mother
and he answered the phone.
Doesn't he speak any Icelandic?
Yes, he does.
He just has an accent.
We always speak in Icelandic.
Well, I couldn't understand
a single word he said.
Been long since you went hunting?
-Yes, it's been a while.
Doesn't the Dane
take you out shooting?
No, he's a vegetarian.
A vegetarian, eh?
-Yes.
How about we go hunting soon.
Sure.
-Great, it's a deal then.
Greetings. How's things?
-Just ding dong.
Did you hear about Siggi?
-What has he done now?
He screwed it all up again.
-Not again?
The boat was burning oil
when he went out this morning.
But he went anyway.
The man is mentally challenged.
You missed!
-Fuck off.
Going somewhere?
-Yes, I'm just going out for a bit.
Join the game?
-No thanks.
Come on, join us. Ari?
Hello Ari.
-Hi.
Welcome home.
-Thanks.
Good to see you.
-Yes. Bye.
Hi boys.
-Hi.
Oh, fuck!
What are you doing, man?
Stop it! Stop!
Fuck! Stop!
You two, stop this bullshit!
Yes.
Right now I said!
-Yes. Sorry.
Fucking moron!
Sorry, man.
I went a bit far, maybe.
Retard!
-You alright?
Are we cool then?
Dude?
-Yes, dude.
I'm a stinking mess.
I'm off to the pool, wanna come?
Sure.
I'm going to finish here.
OK. About half an hour?
See you later.
-Yes.
Here.
You can pat him first.
Wow!
Cool, eh?
-Yes, very cool.
Hello dude.
He's so calm.
-Yes, he likes you.
Yes.
Really cute.
-Yeah.
Are you going somewhere?
-Yes.
Aren't you going to watch
the show with us?
-No, I'm going out for a while.
Don't come home too late.
-No, no.
Thanks for dinner, Grandma.
-Yes.
How's it going between
the two of you, dear?
I don't know.
I don't think he gets me
anymore than I get him.
You might have waited until
I've finished eating?
Want me to put it out?
-No, no.
What's going on?
-Midsummer Night's party in the valley.
Have you got a ride?
-Yes, with Robbi.
Do you think there is room for me?
I don't think so...
The car is full.
Yes, I have to go.
Try one of the others.
OK.
Hurry up.
No chance I can ride with you?
-There's only room for two.
Please.
You can jump on the back
if you want.
Would that be okay?
-Yeah, hurry up then. We're leaving.
Hey, fuck!
-Sorry.
What were you thinking?
-I'm sorry, I didn't know.
Hey! What's going on?
Spying on my girlfriend?
What kind of pervert are you?
Fucking creep!
Watching her pee!
Stay away from her!
Or I'll fucking kill you!
Leave him alone!
He's just a friend.
I will kill him!
Are you ok?
-Forget him!
You are drunk.
-You're fucking dead, creep!
He's just a friend!
-I'll kill you, dude.
How could he know she was peeing?
It was obvious! She handed me
her beer and walked away.
He's a fucking pervert.
Even if he was,
can't you just leave him alone?
If he leaves her alone.
-He just arrived, give him a break.
He's a fucking pervert!
-Okay, can't we all just be friends?
Are we good?
-Yeah, we're good.
Just tell him to leave her alone.
-You leave him alone, he leaves Lára alone.
He better obeys.
Hi.
What were you thinking.
I wasn't thinking, what was he thinking?
-Do you know how bad this looks for you?
I don't give a shit.
-Maybe you don't, but I do.
At least I've talked to Einar.
He's going to leave you alone.
But you have to stay away from Lára.
OK?
I'm going to kill him.
-No, Ari. Listen, leave Lára alone!
OK?
Yes.
-Then this is over.
Great.
-Great.
Very good.
Ari. Ari. Come on.
What have you done?
Come on, let's get you home.
I'll take the boy
to his grandmother's.
Get the fuck out of here, you slut!
Fuck off! Out!
When she finally got him home,
your condition was not better.
Partying all night, and Dagur
screwing Vera on the sofa!
Do you believe that hysterical bitch?
You should be ashamed of yourself!.
What kind of role model are you?
And you're still drunk.
-Stop it, Mom.
Isn't it time you stop this self-pity
that has plagued you since the divorce?
Wake up to the fact that you've
barely seen your son for years?
You should set an example for him.
You're getting a second chance.
Why can't you understand that?
Man up!
Do yourself and everyone else a favour
and go back to those AA meetings.
FOR SALE.
Hi mom, it's me.
No, I don't know the time difference.
No. This place sucks
and I don't want to be here.
Dad? Yes, Dad's fine.
I don't know anybody.
I just want to go home.
No, I am not going to school here.
Why can't I just be with you?
Oh mom, please just come home.
I don't care.
No. It won't get better.
It will not get any fucking better.
No! No!
Fuck you! Do you hear me?
Fuck you!
What's this?
A knitting club?
I'm putting this in the sink.
Mom, is there any coffee?
-No, but I can make some.
No, I'll get some at work.
Shouldn't we have dinner together?
-Yes.
Bloody noise!
You know he's very proud of you,
don't you?
Did he tell you that we watched your
Christmas concert together?
No.
Don't take all his macho nonsense
too seriously.
It's his handicap.
What have you been up to?
Haven't you been in touch with Lára
since you came?
No, not really.
Really? You were such good friends,
always together.
Yeah. I don't know.
It's a bit complicated.
She's older now.
Got herself a boyfriend and all that.
What difference does that make?
- I don't know. Maybe none.
There's your boy.
Hi.
-Hi.
I was wondering,
do you want to go hunting?
Hunting?
I like the sound of that.
Yes. Let's do it.
I'll borrow a boat, but we need the gun.
It's in the car, the back seat.
Bring the bullets from the grey bag.
-OK.
Hold it tight against your shoulder.
Otherwise it could knock you out.
See?
Understand?
-Yes.
Try it.
What did I say?
Tight against your shoulder.
Or it will hit you.
Hey, look! A seal.
Make eye contact with him
and aim directly at his head.
Otherwise he'll sink.
Now. Now! He's within range.
He's looking at you.
Now!
What's wrong with you?
He'll get away.
Tight against the shoulder.
Aim.
Thank you.
Cheers.
-Cheers.
Dad.
What's the matter?
Come and sit next to me.
-What is it?
I don't want you to go inside.
Come and sit with me.
What's going on?
What happened?
She was just lying there
when I arrived.
There's nothing we can do my boy.
Ari.
Are you alright?
Sorry to hear
about your grandmother.
Hi buddy.
I've been looking for you.
Hi.
I'm preparing the funeral.
Are you coming with me?
Yes.
I thought you were going to the pub.
Yes, I thought so too.
I have to get my act together.
I just wanted to tell you that.
This looks great on you.
A perfect flt.
I think I'll take this one.
-Yes
And take the other one for the boy.
-Yes.
And I need some shoes.
-What size?
45.
-45.
Don't I look like an idiot?
-No, you look fine.
Did you tie it yourself?.
-No, the man gave it to me like that.
Your mother used to do it for me.
You look great.
How is it?
-Good, a bit warm.
This is life.
I felt bad.
I was alone,
but then I started dancing,
and found love.
That's not dancing.
She'll make it to the next round.
Do you think so?
With a big ass like this?
Dad, it's a dance competition
not a beauty contest.
I don't care. It's TV.
Her ass fills up the whole screen.
Earth to earth.
Ashes to ashes.
Dust to dust.
We are leaving, dear.
My condolences for your loss.
Don't be afraid to talk to me
if you need anything.
OK.
-Greet your father.
My condolences.
Bye.
So that's where you're hiding.
It's all very sad.
My condolences, Ari.
But life goes on, dear.
You have to remember that.
Before you know it you'll have kids and
be married to an ugly, old woman like me
You're not ugly.
Thank you, dear.
Do you want to come inside me?
Isn't it good?
Don't you miss the city sometimes?
Yes, sometimes.
I went south with my mom last year.
We saw your concert.
You did?
-It was awesome.
Thanks.
I scored this from my uncle.
Wasted.
-No.
Completely stoned.
-I'm not.
Then you will get
the fucking munchies.
Last time we smoked,
Bassi had five hot dogs.
Five hot dogs?
That's disgusting.
It was awesome.
Believe me.
With buns and everything?
-Yes, it was awesome.
See that spider's web?
-Yuck.
Lára!
What's going on?
Where are you going?
Lára!
Lára, come here.
What is going on?
-What the hell was that?
Lára!
Einar, leave her alone.
What's he gotten himself into?
-I don't know.
That is so bloody typical for guys.
-What do you mean?
Sex, sex, sex.
All guys think about is sex.
Of course.
Lára split up with Einar because
she didn't love him.
He's upset they never had sex.
What are you saying?
Are you saying...
Einar has never fucked Lára?
-No, she never loved him.
But she could have fucked him.
Shut up, you retard.
I was just teasing her.
Jesus Christ!
What was that?
Ari. Ari!
Ari!
What?
Where were you last night?
-What do you mean?
You heard me.
Where were you last night?
I was right here.
-You're lying.
Really? Or were you so drunk
that you can't remember?
You're nothing
but a drunk and a loser.
You lost Mom, the boat, the house,
everything. You're a fucking loser!
You hardly saw me,
or spoke to me for years.
Six years.
You never remembered
my birthday.
I'm ashamed of being your son.
Do you hear me?
You're a fucking loser.
I was thinking of frying
some fish tonight.
I'm not hungry.
This should cover the beer.
-You don't have to do that.
Aren't you going to eat?
-No, I'm not hungry.
OK.
"Dear Ari. Best wishes
for all your birthdays. Dad."
Yes, that is fucking nice.
That really is funny.
Yes, it was good.
-Yeah.
My dad would never allow me to.
He goes mad when I drink.
Oh, fuck.
Hi
-Hi.
What an idiot.
-That was so lame.
You're such a pussy.
-What do you mean?
Do something about this.
-Shut up.
Dude. Why don't you screw her?
You know she digs you, go for it.
Shut up.
Seriously.
Have you never had sex?
No.
-What, really?
No
-OK.
I'll hook you up.
Trust me.
What do you mean?
-Trust me.
-Bassi. Hey Bassi. Don't.
Do you have it?
Maybe I should tell your mom...
-Dude, stop it.
How many are you?
-We're four.
Half now and half later.
Break it in two.
Okay.
-Just half now, you got that?
Look what I scored.
- What is that?
It's Ketamine.
Everybody take one.
Was I good?
I'm glad it was with you.
Would you like to meet me tonight?
Yes.
The End @