Subtitles by CJ Entertainment
Resync by Bobkaka
Park Min Ho Kidnapping Case
Part 1
Min Ho sent something.
That punk didn't even show up today.
He was here until 2 AM last night investigating.
What investigation?
I don't know.
F! That's what it was written as.
Director Yeo!
Find the real murderer of the Majang Room Salon case.
Send the result to tonight's 9 o'clock news.
If we run...
or fail to find out...
I will die.
Okay.
There was a murder last night around 1 AM in Majang.
A male and female were shot.
The video recorded on Min Ho's phone was filmed at 4:25 AM.
Min Ho left work at 2.
He didn't get home.
He got kidnapped somewhere on the way.
The handcuffs he's wearing are the ones policemen use.
Specialized handcuffs.
Only for police.
But, Min Ho's handcuffs are back at the office.
Is the kidnapper a cop?
He knows us well.
And he picked Min Ho among us.
He wasn't "picked."
If it wasn't for that F nonsense,
he would've left early.
And this wouldn't have happened.
Director Yeo.
Stop the car.
We can be easily played in a situation like this.
If we give into this bastard,
then the law becomes a joke.
Senior.
Director Yeo.
Let's focus on one thing.
This time...
We're only focusing on Min Ho.
We really need teamwork now.
At least for Min Ho.
What are you doing here?
What kind of case is it?
You guys don't need to be here.
This case is already closed.
The suspect is open.
Total of 6 bullets.
Usually 2 are empty ones.
But if the suspect put in 6 real bullets...
This wasn't an accident.
He intended to kill.
One right next to his feet.
Shot almost vertically.
The first one was a missed shot.
He was either nervous or excited.
5 random shots.
The suspect must be an amateur.
He must've shot randomly?
Both victims were fatally wounded.
One was shot in the heart.
The other was shot right next to the neck passing the artery.
That explains all this blood.
What's this?
Can you take a look at this?
This isn't a blood splash or a blood spill.
Traces of blood wiping?
Check the blood and the black stain beside it.
Director Yeo.
Let's talk for a minute.
Weren't those gunshots?
Gunshots? I didn't hear anything.
Follow him.
Yes.
Who is this?
Suspect Ji Jin Hyun.
He was filmed during our internal investigation.
Ji Jin Hyuk had an internal investigation?
Not Ji Jin Hyuk,
Lee Byung Man.
The room salon gate,
Lee Byung Man?
Ji Jin Hyuk leaked prostitute information and accepted bribery.
He had an affair with the female victim.
He must've shot them when he saw those two together.
This is going to be tough.
What other location did we miss?
Ji Jin Hyuk's house.
I'll take responsibility for this one!
What happened?
We got a report from a county sheriff.
The keys were still inside.
And the car owner was a police so we preserved the scene as is.
There isn't much traffic in this area.
And there's no cameras.
Kidnapped within 5 kilometers?
Someone stalked him.
You bastard.
He's definitely not an amateur.
There's no evidence that he was forced out.
That means he walked out on his own.
Why?
Fake accident...
The headlights are broken.
It must've been a lower car.
Where could he have gone?
Car type, year, color.
You would know, right?
You guys are pros.
Especially in hit and runs.
It's my day off.
Let me rest.
Call me as soon as you find out.
You should at least have a drink with me!
Only calls when he needs me...
What's going on?
The arrest and search happened at the same time.
Here's an escape.
Too high to jump off though.
Plus, he was barefoot.
Why is there nothing else?
Director!
Something is strange.
The investigation states that the suspect shot through the window.
But the neighbors say differently.
They heard 2 gunshots and then they heard the window shatter.
The black stain found on the cloth was a mixture of...
Wax, oil, dye, etc...
It's shoe polish.
Shoe polish?
Yes.
He must've wiped the blood stain from his shoes onto the cloth.
So it was dress shoes?
He casually wiped the blood.
Horribly aimed shots...
Something seems unnatural.
Okay.
Ji Jin Hyuk was wearing tennis shoes.
He's being framed.
Arrest is not the point for this case...
It's his tail on the line.
Lizard
Two hours between the kidnapping and filming process.
There are a total of 6 empty buildings in this 2 hour distance.
Three left, Min Ho...
Leaving your work behind is the same thing as a hit and run!
What?
Black Sonata.
There's probably hundreds of that car in Seoul.
But not that many passing from 1 AM to 4 AM last night.
Get the plate number and put it up for search.
At least tell me what happened-
Hello?
You always hang up on me!
Are you trying to cut his tail?
What kind of nonsense are you talking about?
Find the real murderer of the Majang Room Salon case.
Send the result to tonight's 9 o'clock news.
If we run...
or fail to find out...
I will die.
Okay.
What do we do now?
We have to find him.
How are we going to find him by 9 PM tonight?
I mean, the real murderer.
Real murderer?
Ji Jin Hyuk is the real murderer!
We can't release that to the press yet.
Chief.
Help us find Min Ho or stay out of it.
From now on...
I'm going to do whatever it takes.
It's certain that Ji Jin Hyuk is being falsely accused.
The crime happened at 1 AM in Majang.
And Min Ho was kidnapped roughly an hour later.
Why would that bastard move so quickly?
It's not enough to just find the real murderer.
Min Ho was put inside a trap.
We need to find out who made this trap.
Illegal phone.
We need to investigate.
Please step out.
Ah, yes.
It's the perfect place to record.
No people, no guards...
This isn't his hometown nor is it a police district.
But seeing that he came here means he knows this place well.
He's a suspicious person.
He's not stupid.
He doesn't go to places he doesn't know.
I found it!
Where?!
Are you asking me to analyze this picture?
I need accurate information as soon as possible.
Investigating an internal affair?
The result isn't that great for a crime that was prepped for a year.
1 year?
The internal investigators have been working on this for a year.
The VIP of that room salon always got away with it...
So they prepared this for a year.
In the end, that VIP's tail got chopped off.
Anyway!
Ji Jin Hyuk is a dead man.
Even if it wasn't him,
he's getting 4 terms...
He fell into the trap and now he's supposed to die. Perfect scenario ending.
This car?
Yeah!
Thank god.
Are you crazy?
We don't know where he ran off to!
They're moving together.
Thank god we have fewer options to choose from now.
But it must be hard dragging along a grown man.
He might be dead.
Do you feed a dead person water?
This bastard must've stolen another car.
Call me if someone files a missing car report.
I told you it's my day off!
Damn, I'm hungry.
I don't know what's going on but don't get involved.
This is Pandora's box.
He's on the 2nd floor.
4th floor.
I think he went to the roof.
The criminal wore your type of shoe.
Wait. Wait.
Prosecutor?
Pandora
011-6310-1630
This is Lee Byung Man's number.
Ji Jin Hyuk and Lee Byung Man have known each other.
They even had a conversation yesterday using the fake phone.
What could they have been doing together?
What bring you here?
Ryu Mi Ho?
Our business got shut down because of her.
Shut down?
I found out it was temporary.
Has it been weeks now?
She ran away all of a sudden.
Pandora.
She was going to reveal Lee Byung Man's dirty deeds.
But she disappeared all of a sudden?
It seems like Lee Byung Man made her do deliveries.
She did well at first but she wanted money and ran away.
Later, she called us.
Because she was scared.
Not the police but to a prosecutor?
She knew that Lee Byung Man was affiliated with someone in the police.
And that...
Lee Byung Man killed somebody.
Very neatly.
There are a lot of new apartments.
How do you like it here?
There are a lot of markets and it's close to Seoul.
The kidnapper needs a place to hide where no one can see.
He needs to run away eventually so he must know this place well.
A place from his childhood,
where there is no connection.
Very good.
What size are you looking for?
Are you living by yourself?
It doesn't matter if I live alone or not.
Not an apartment...
A market.
Somewhere with no cameras.
Who is it?
I'm with the police.
Excuse me but is this where Mi Ho lives?
Did you find her?
When you're a social worker,
you see lots of kids like Mi Ho.
Kids who are smart but turn bad due to lack of family support.
Isn't it crazy that they still underage girls like her?
How long has it been since she left the house?
I think it's been a week now.
After the Detective took her.
Detective?
A Detective came to get Mi Ho?
Yes.
Yes?
There was a witness for Lee Byung Man.
She's a young student.
Ryu Mi Ho.
10 days ago, Lee Byeong Man sent a picture to Ji Jin Hyuk to find her.
Then a week later, Ji Jin Hyuk took her from her house.
That's where it ends.
Pandora was trying to open the box and that's when it started.
If Ji Jin Hyuk got rid of the witness, Ryu Mi Ho...
He's not the tail, he's the body.
The next target after Lee Byung Man.
If we know what's inside Pandora's Box...
Then we can find out who purposefully closed it as well.
Ma'am! Give me some cold water!
We don't have cold water.
I had cold ones but someone just bought them all.
All?
A young man?
Yes.
That's him! He was just here!
Where did he go?
He drove off asking where Incheon was.
Incheon?
What happened?
We're still checking the cameras.
It hasn't even been 30 minutes.
Why are you looking at 40-50 minutes ago?
We checked twice but we couldn't find anything so we went back.
That can't be...
From that store to here is only 5 minutes, 10 minutes maximum.
This bastard.
What's on the opposite direction?
It's the way back to Seoul.
He's still here.
Keep looking.
Yes!
How is it?
This time it's a hotel.
I thought of you.
Can you ask room service to get me some medicine?
You haven't lost it yet.
Making jokes in this situation.
I'm serious.
I have no intention of killing you.
If your team moves quickly,
you should be able to go home tonight.
Those guys can't do it without me.
I don't know why you're doing this...
But we can help you.
The fact that I'm your target means that you trust our team.
Look at this kid talking nonsense.
Can't you see the mask on my face?
This mask from society?
Put your head down.
Chameleon
Hyung, the missing car report came in.
Old black Grandeur.
Number: 02-318
02-318.
Did you hear me?
Where is the Chief?
I'm not sure.
Is he in a meeting?
Wait! I'm not here for you!
I'm here for Mi ho!
It's all my fault.
I introduced her to that place.
You were the last person she sent a text message to.
What did she say?
This.
The annoying one?
Who is she telling you to call?
There's someone who used to always scold us.
Always told us to graduate,
not to blame our parents.
He bought us food and told us to call him when we're in trouble.
Mi Ho said that she found a way to live after stealing that money.
But, she was still scared.
I didn't call him because I didn't want him to worry.
Mi Ho knew something was coming.
Was this person someone who could've helped?
Probably...
He's a Detective.
Detective?
Yes.
What's his name?
Here.
Isn't that it?
Black 3218?
Don't point.
He could be looking somewhere else.
He's trying to fool me.
Min Ho?
Park Min Ho?
What room is that black car staying in?
Grandeur?
It's Room 302.
What's this?
What the hell do you think you're doing?
The suspect has a gun...
Since when did we start shooting?
When?!
Let's talk this over, okay?
What station are you guys from?
Internal Investigations.
He left this place clean...
He didn't clean, he just didn't come in...
This means he knew we were after him, you fools...
Well, kids who are fools become policemen.
Don't blame me.
He wants us to still chase after him.
He still has a reason to not kill Min Ho. For sure.
We have to get some time.
Ji Jin Hyuk is not the murderer.
He is affiliated with this case...
...but he is not the killer.
This is all they came up with for a year.
It's worse than your work in half a day. Stupid people.
Did you meet the prosecutors?
They were on a race with Lee Byung Man's case.
Dead or alive, we started this mess...
...so we have to clean it up.
Didn't you say to help or step aside?
I'll back off but help me out.
Find him before the prosecutors.
More investigation is needed until I can find him.
We need to get the press release as soon as possible.
Fine. What are we doing with the criminal?
We need to make one up.
Let's make one.
The moon empties everything to become full once again.
After the waning moon,
it becomes the end of the month.
I'm also going to put everything on the line this time.
Am I still in danger?
It's over now.
We got a confession that someone blamed you for everything.
There'll be a major investigation for all the corruptions.
What about me?
You won't be on the list.
Let's meet.
I'll take responsibility.
I don't trust anyone.
You guys come here and...
If something happens to me then it'll really get crazy.
Come to the place where Min Ho was kidnapped.
Show up after the 9 o'clock news.
We'll trade after the news.
If you don't come...
Then it won't get crazy...
It'll be the end.
Ma Suk Gi, 24 years of service.
International Investigation Team.
Those two know each other.
There must be a connection with the room salon and Mi Ho.
He was the one filming on the night of the crime.
And he was also the one with the gun at the motel.
Weren't those gunshots?
Gunshots? I didn't hear anything.
He was the one fooling around with the gun at the motel?
Since when did we start shooting?
When!?
Let's talk this over, okay?
We still haven't located him yet.
Okay.
Director Yeo.
First news.
The suspect for the crime that took place in a hostess bar yesterday is now arrested.
The suspect is now under arrest for the shooting yesterday.
Mr. Lee and Ms. Yang who grew a significant number of these businesses...
...has been shot for unknown reasons.
It is stated that he is currently being questioned for the purpose behind killing.
The police cannot release any information during the investigation...
...therefore they are trying their best.
There is a high chance that the arrested suspect is a former police officer.
This is Yoon Jung Hee from YCN News.
Where is Park Min Ho?
I'm sorry but I don't even trust my own mom.
So how can I trust you guys?
I put him somewhere safe, so don't worry.
Let me have some type of insurance.
If something happens to me you know he's dead, right?
Let's get in the car.
We'll send someone over to get Park Min Ho.
What is this?
What's going on?
Stand still!
What the hell?
What's up with him?
He's not talking...
Director Yeo...
I think Min Ho's in danger.
What's going to happen to him?
What happened?
Dad...
Please come out of that hell now, Dad...
I'm not going to die there like that...
I'm never going to die like that...
What?
Why is he... alone?
2 hours ago, there was a shooting incident.
They heard ammunitions...
It's the same neighborhood as the cameras.
And...
There were 2 reports of a gunshot in the Ya San area.
Subtitles by CJ Entertainment
Resync by Bobkaka
Find the real murderer of the Majang Room Salon case.
If we run...
or fail to find out...
I will die.
Director Yeo.
Let's focus on one thing.
This time...
Let's only focus on Min Ho.
Since when did we start shooting?
When!?
Let go of me and let's talk.
Help us find Min Ho or stay out of it.
From now on,
I'm going to do whatever it takes.