Download Korean Drama at DramaLoad
People say that…
…you can do anything
if you try hard enough...
...but the truth is that
there are some things...
…you can’t do no matter
how hard you try.
My poor son.
Oh God, my poor son.
What should I do?
Save him, doctor.
Please save him.
Please, doctor.
The only thing we can do
in those cases is pray.
I’m okay.
We can only pray...
...for miracles.
But they do happen.
For now...
...let me tell you
about a beautiful miracle...
...that happened to us.
[Episode 1]
[Trophology/Nutriology/Dietetics…]
["Let food be thy medicine
and medicine be thy food." -Hippocrates]
Thank you.
I'll live another day to the fullest.
[Zucchini]
[Zucchini begins shipping today]
[Hae Gil Hospital]
Mister!
This is good for slipped discs,
so ask your wife to cook it for you.
You’re always the best, Miss Lee.
Work properly.
Yes, yes.
We have our supplies for the day.
It doesn't seem like as much.
Trust me.
I'm sure there's something...
...between the meat supplier
and the deputy manager.
I don’t think so.
What do you mean?
Their meat isn’t fresh
and it's expensive...
…but we've kept the same supplier.
- Why do you think that is?
- Eh?
Ms. Yoon Jong Ja really…
We all figured it out a while ago...
…but we've just kept out mouths shut.
Huh?
Hey, hey!
Ms. Yoon, I've told you before...
...you won't get well if you don't
eat properly...
...no matter how well
the doctor treats you.
Leave me alone.
Whether I die of old age or hunger…
…I’ll be dead anyway.
I don’t care if you die of old age
or sickness, but…
…I can’t let you die of hunger…
…as long as I’m here.
Now open your mouth.
Just three bites.
No, just two bites.
- Ah!
- Take it away!
Ms. Yoon!
What?
Jesus Christ!
You just wasted food.
This is well-cooked meal
with essential nutrients.
The food's not the problem.
You just have no appetite now.
- So…
- Don’t be a snob.
How do you know how I feel?
Why do you think I don't know?
How would you?
You’re a healthy young woman.
How could you understand
a sick old lady like me?
Well.
Hey, Miss Lee.
Hey.
Hey, what are you doing?
You've been here for 67 days
as of today.
I was hospitalized here for 136 days.
I lived in a hospital room...
...with hope,
constantly afraid of death.
Do you still think
I can’t understand you?
So what?
What do you want me to do?
Is there anything you want to eat?
I’ll make it for you, okay?
You should eat and get better.
You’ll be in trouble,
if you keep not eating like this.
Tell me. I’ll make it for you.
What do you want to eat?
Ox bone soup.
[Hanu Haon: The nation’s largest
meat distributor]
You called me out at dawn...
...to make a ox bone soup for Ms. Yoon?
This place sells meat cheaply.
They sell bones and other stuff too.
- Really?
- Yes.
By the way, *Unni…
[Unni: Older sister or older female]
…I didn’t order today’s beef
for the hospital yet…
- …so I can buy that here too.
- Hey!
What will you do
if the deputy manager finds out?
Don’t worry.
If I buy better quality beef
at the same price…
…she won't be able to complain.
You're on your own.
If you tell her I was here with you…
…it'll be the end of our friendship.
Yeah, yeah.
Alright.
Let's split up so you can survive.
United we fall!
You’re really…
Hey, they're open now.
Welcome!
Welcome.
Wow!
It’s huge.
Please go to heaven.
Thank you for your sacrifice.
Just one.
Thank you.
- Two packs please.
- Two packs.
Pay at the counter beside the entrance.
Thank you.
How many do you want?
- Two packs please.
- Two packs.
That'll be $19.20.
Here you go.
Mister.
Give me fourteen packs
of beef for a soup…
Actually, fifteen packs please.
That'll be $19.20.
No, I said fifteen packs.
Fifteen packs.
Can’t you read?
Excuse me?
[Two packs per person]
[Limited sale]
Ah, no way.
This isn't enough.
Next.
I knew it.
Excuse me, mister.
Next.
How many do you want?
Give me two packs too.
Okay.
Mister, I’m sorry but…
…can you sell me just two more?
Just one more.
Pass.
God., she pushed me hard.
Aww.
What should I do?
Don’t worry.
Let’s just get in line again.
You’re so clever.
You didn’t know?
[Hae Gil Hospital]
This is Nasser Max,
a representative of Dubai Health Center.
It’s very kind of you
to come all the way.
I’m Myeong Hee Jo...
...the chairman of Hae Gil Hospital.
- Nice to meet you.
- Nice to meet you too.
Should we look around
the VIP room first?
Of course.
Come this way.
What happened to Dr. Kang?
Did you tell him about today's meeting?
I told him, but…
[Dr. Kang Dong Wook]
[The nation’s best surgeon
for coronary artery bypass surgery]
Messer.
Wait a moment.
Shall we start?
Go ahead.
We can do it now.
Do it again.
Can you get out of here?
Please?
Ah, yes.
I’m sorry.
Mr. Director.
Yes, I'm sorry.
Don't mind me.
Please continue.
Do a good job.
Yes.
Dr. Kang, it looks so real.
I'll start again.
Okay.
I’m tying it again.
Go ahead.
I'll do it again.
- Messer.
- Here.
Hello.
Huh?
Hey, hey.
The man who told you to pass
isn't there.
Look, look.
Really?
That's not him, right?
No, it's not.
God is smiling on us.
Let’s go.
Mister, give me two packs.
- Okay.
- It’s $19.20, right?
Yes.
Oh my God!
I said pass.
Wh... What?
You already bought some.
Already?
No.
What if I find it in your bag?
Mister.
Don’t be so strict.
Please understand our situation…
Please?
You bought enough for the two of you.
Why are you being so greedy?
Huh?
I’m busy.
Leave now.
Mister, it's not like that.
I’m a clinical dietitian
for Hae Gil Hospital.
I have to buy meat here today...
...to provide meals for our patients.
Also.
One of the patients won't
eat anything, so…
Do you really want me to believe this?
I tried to disguise myself with a cap
because I'm desperate...
…but I’m telling you the truth.
- I’m really from Hae Gil Hospital.
- Pass.
- Do Yoon.
- Yes.
Take a good look at these ladies...
…and don’t sell any beef
to them, alright?
- Okay.
- Mister!
Do you think that I’m lying to you?
Look me in my eyes, okay?
Hey, let’s just go.
He's not buying it.
Hey, you!
Wait a minute.
It’s you, right?
- Excuse me?
- What?
Buying our beef cheaply
and selling it at a markup...
It’s you, right?
What?
Do you think that we sell it
with no margin…
…for people like you
to take advantage of?
Mister.
- I think you've misunderstood us.
- Misunderstood?
Did you say that I misunderstood you?
Wow, what a young brat you are.
How dare you live your life for free?
Free?
My life for free?
Bom Yi.
Wait.
Mister.
I think that's a little much.
- I don’t think so.
- Let’s just go.
Wait a moment.
How dare you…
How dare you tell me
that I live my life for free?
Apologize to me right now.
Apologize?
Yes, apologize to me.
Yes, we did try to buy more beef...
...but it's because we really need it.
I don’t know what caused
such a misunderstanding, but...
...you shouldn't be that rude
without knowing me.
It's terrible manners.
Are you looking for manners
from a butcher?
I don’t know what a manners are...
...but I do know something
about a good beating.
Fine.
Just go home.
I let you go just this once.
If I see you again…
...I’ll give you a demonstration...
...a personal demonstration of how
you separate bone from flesh.
Hey, mister.
Apologize to me
for what you just said too.
Haven't you heard the saying,
"A person’s body is a gift..."
"...so not hurting them is
the start of one's filial duty"?
No, I haven't.
So what?
Who the hell are you…
...that you dare threaten my body...
...which was a gift from my parents?
Hey, mister!
Don’t run away from me.
Apologize to me right now.
If you don’t, I’ll sue you.
- Bom Yi!
- Get off me.
No, I won’t.
Apologize to me!
Right now!
Ugh!
Jesus, my beef!
Darn it.
What are you going to do
about my beef?
You’re lucky that
I’m ending this here.
If I actually see you again…
…I’ll break your legs.
Go away!
He must be really crazy.
Hey, are you hurt?
Let me see.
Oh my God.
What do you think about them,
Chairman Song?
We won't have a problem establishing
the International Medical Center…
…as long as Dr. Kang renews
his contract with us.
Dr. Kang’s contract will expire soon.
Lots of hospitals want him.
Why are you worried about it?
Dr. Kang and Bom Yi will get
married soon, won’t they?
Dr. Kang wouldn’t renew
his contract with us…
...just because they're getting married.
If he were willing to renew it,
he would have come to this meeting.
Judging by his uncooperative attitude…
...I don't think the renewal
will be easy.
Then why don’t you appoint him as
the new director of the hospital?
You have a grounds for it
since he’ll be your son-in-law.
Appoint him as director?
Then what about the current director?
He’s responsible for the hospital's
current situation.
It's been five years since then.
Why are you bringing that up again?
Yes.
It's been five years already, but...
…the hospital still hasn't
recovered yet.
Your husband is just
a figurehead anyway.
There’s no meaning in him
being director now anyway.
If you’re uncomfortable with it,
I’ll persuade him.
Maybe if we fail in renewing
Dr. Kang's contract...
…but not now.
Hey, the shooting finished
earlier than I thought.
I just did what I always do.
Wow, you've turned into a snob now.
By the way, why didn’t you participate
in the meeting today?
It’s not that I didn’t go.
It's that I couldn't.
No one asked me to come…
…even though I waited around for it.
You still should have gone.
You’re the hospital
director, after all.
Whatever.
What’s the point of going?
Even if I went,
I would just get on my wife's nerves.
Hey, why didn’t you go?
You’re a rising star.
You should be there
to brighten up the place.
I’m not interested
in the International Medical Center.
Hey, I told you not to be like this.
If you want to open the
Organ Transplant Center again…
…you shouldn’t be like this.
You should earn money
to revive the hospital…
…so we can open Organ
Transplant Center again.
Wow, is that what you're
using me for?
You’re so mean to me.
No, I’m not.
You're the one being mean.
You're marrying my daughter.
You hate me as your son-in-law?
Yes, I hate it.
I almost want to kill you.
You'll understand when you
have a daughter.
She’s my sweet little girl.
How dare you...
Don’t talk about it.
It pisses me off.
Stop talking about it.
You're laughing now?
Ha!
I remember you crying in the corner.
What do you mean?
When did I do that?
The first time we met was...
…when you had a job interview
at this hospital, right?
Yes.
It's been five years already.
That interview was five years ago.
It wasn't that day, but...
...the day of Bom Yi's surgery...
...at Se Chan Hospital on Jeju Island.
[Restricted Area]
[Operating Room]
The organ donor who provided
a heart to Bom Yi...
...was your relative, right?
Yes.
Wow, what a young brat you are.
How dare you live your life for free?
Tah-dah!
You really made this?
Of course.
In return, promise me...
...that you’ll finish all
of the rice and soup.
Okay.
How is it?
Is it delicious?
Yes!
It’s really delicious.
I’m totally cured now.
Really?
Is it that good?
It’s really tasty.
Thank you, thank you.
You’re a grown woman.
How could you pick a fight?
Write me a medical note for this.
I won't just pass through.
Why are you so mad?
*Oppa.
[Oppa: Older brother or older female]
Do you know what he said to me?
What did he say?
I can’t believe it.
He told me that I live my life for free.
He only said it
because he doesn't know you.
Of course he doesn’t know me.
How can you be so mad over something
he said without thinking?
It’s because what he said is true.
No, it isn’t.
Yes, it is.
It’s true that I'm living
my life for free.
I should have been dead
a long time ago...
…but I got someone else’s heart...
...and now I have an extra life
for free.
Hey, a heart isn’t free.
It’s something you
can’t buy with money.
It’s the most precious thing
in the world.
That’s why it’s free.
I have no way of paying for it.
Apologize to me right now.
If you don’t, I’ll sue you.
- Bom Yi!
- Get off me.
No, I won’t.
Apologize to me!
Right now!
Ugh!
- You're lucky I'm ending it here.
- Jesus, my beef!
If I actually see you again…
…I’ll break your legs.
According to what I confirmed...
…the complaint on the board is
one hundred percent true.
- What about the article?
- It’s already gone viral.
I've already found comments
calling for a boycott.
Pull the article right now
and call Lawyer Baek.
Okay.
What should I do with this man?
Dad.
Wait for us.
What are you doing over there?
Come quickly.
- Wait!
- Stop him and bring him with you now.
She promised me I could spin my top
if I got off the plane.
I only promised you could do it once.
Let him spin it just once.
Dad, what’s wrong with you?
If I made a promise with him,
I should keep it.
What are you doing in the hallway?
Stand up right now.
You behave worse and worse.
[Noona: Older sister or older female]
*Noona, dad took my top!
Kang Ba Da.
Stand up.
Darn it.
Who does this kid take after?
Who do you think he takes after?
Can’t you be patient for a moment?
I’ll let you do it at home
as much as you want.
Look, there are lots of people here.
I’ll scold you when we get home.
Please!
Stop making him cry.
He’s a grown-up now.
Why does he cry so often?
He can't do it just anywhere.
I told you not to say things
like that in front of him.
Why don’t you let me talk
with my own mouth?
I wouldn’t interrupt if you
said something right for once.
Let’s go.
Stand up.
Stand up now.
Put me down.
Put me down!
Now get in and scoot over.
I hate you, dad!
Don’t sit next to me!
- Take the bag.
- Ok.
Let’s go to Seongsan-po, mister…
…where I can take the ferry
to Udo Island.
You're from Jeju, aren't you?
Wow!
It’s the same country…
…but even the trees
are different here.
Wow.
I’m here finally.
Wow, it's so pretty.
Huh?
Mister!
Excuse me!
What are you doing?
Stop it!
Apologize to me right now.
If you don’t, I’ll sue you.
Why...are you here?
- You shouldn’t do this.
- Excuse me?
Why are you throwing trash
and leftover food...
...into the sea?
Aren’t you ashamed to ruin
the sea round beautiful Udo Island?
You're like some supervillain
destroying the ecosystem.
This one's for cans.
Bottles go...
[Udo Island Lover]
Remember, you can only have one.
If you have more,
you won't be able to eat dinner later.
- Would you like to buy ice cream?
- Yes, get me one.
Why am I crying...
...when I see these children?
What should I do?
Hey.
Would you like to buy some ice cream?
It's really tasty because it's made
from Udo peanuts.
No, that’s not what I meant, but…
By the way, is it just the two of you?
Where's your mother?
Why are you asking about mother?
Mother isn’t here.
Ba Da.
What’s the matter?
That’s…
My dad's over there.
That man… is your father?
What’s the matter?
Well...
Come here a minute.
Is your house nearby?
Yes, it's in the back.
Ah…
Let's just do this
until those people are gone.
Thank you.
By the way, ma'am...
- No, it's *Noona.
- Noona.
[Noona: Older sister or older female]
Yes?
What is it?
Why were you crying over there?
Did you see it?
I think it’s because
of the sea breeze.
So your name is Ba Da?
Yes, and my sister’s name is Poo Reum.
So together you're *Poo Reum Ba Da?
[Poo Reum Ba Da: "Blue sea" in Korea]
That's very pretty.
It isn’t pretty at all.
Grandmother told us that
we’re troublesome.
Why?
It’s because Poo Reun Ba Da
ate up my mother.
Ba Da...
What does that mean?
She went to heaven.
She died.
Okay.
I get it.
Noona.
You told me that mother always
did this to you, right?
Yeah.
Wait a moment.
Here.
If you wear it like this,
it’s good for two reasons.
It can hide your back
and it'll keep your tummy warm.
Don’t forget to mark the date
on your calendar.
Your name is Poo Reum, right?
If you have any more questions...
...call me here.
Okay.
Go in and change your clothes now.
What are you doing?
What do you mean?
Why are you here?
Don't you recognize me?
Recognize what?
What are you doing here
with my children?
What is this about?
She gave you her card?
It’s nothing.
If it’s nothing,
why did you almost hug a stranger?
If you don’t know, just be quiet.
What is she saying?
You shouldn't leave your children
so you can day drink.
What’s wrong with you, really?
What do you know about me?
Dad, don’t be mean to her.
She helped me.
How did she help you?
Tell me.
What did you do?
Why are you blaming your child?
Step aside.
It’s none of your business…
I told you to stop it.
Still…
...if you hang around my children
like this...
...someone might misunderstand.
It’s okay.
I heard that…
…they don’t have mother…
...so take good care of them, okay?
Don’t let them eat junk food…
…and give them seaweed or beans.
Make sure they sleep warm too, okay?
Bye.
Auntie.
We sold three ice creams.
I told you not to do that.
I’m sorry.
The children did it for fun.
Who the hell are you…
...that you dare threaten my body...
...which was a gift from my parents?
Hey, mister!
Don’t run away from me.
Apologize to me right now.
If you don’t, I’ll sue you.
- Bom Yi!
- Get off me.
No, I won’t.
Apologize to me!
Right now!
Ugh!
Jesus, my beef!
I've seen the video and find
no liability on our part.
By the way, does Miss Lee Bom Yi
really have today off?
Do you have any problem with that?
After filing a complaint like this...
...she should expect us to visit
her today for a settlement...
...but not she has the day off
and isn't answering her phone.
Are you considering her
a black consumer?
I'm telling you just in case.
If she asks for unreasonable amount…
…we’ll sue her too.
Miss Lee Bom Yi isn’t the kind of person
to ask for settlement money.
It's possible if she has the chance.
You’re making a big mistake now.
What do you mean?
If you go any further than this,
we’ll call a lawyer too.
Do you mean that your hospital
would deal with this?
I think there’s nothing more
to hear or say here.
Please leave now.
My daughter knows how to fight properly.
Hey, it's true she's your daughter.
Why does she cause so many problems?
She really concerns me.
What should we do?
She does it because she wants to.
God.
Really…
Do I have to tie her up at home
after she gets married?
Do it if you can.
Miss Bae.
Can you find out about Dr. Kang?
His family, his friends and...
his family issues.
I know nothing about him.
You don't need to talk so cautiously.
Miss Bae already knows
about your snobbery.
I mean, you understood her, right?
She meant that she wants you
to do a background check on Dr. Kang.
Yes.
Okay.
You.
You know where Bom Yi is now, right?
Did you write a doctor’s note
for Bom Yi?
Yes.
What a perfect couple you are.
You're suited so well for each other.
She started a war
with thousands of troops.
Excuse me?
She started a bloody war just
from posting something on the internet.
You gave her the weapon to do it.
Did you know that?
Ms. Chairman must be mad
because of Bom Yi again.
Tell me about it.
If she were here, she wouldn't
have any hair left.
I think she took the day off today
because of it.
- Her phone's off too.
- Is that right?
You didn’t know?
Didn’t she tell you
where she was going?
Well she must have another man then.
Too bad for you.
What a brat.
Our cafeteria food is good, isn’t it?
Mr. Director.
Yes?
Is there any chance that Bom Yi knows
where her heart came from?
She doesn’t know who the donor was...
...but the heart came by helicopter...
...so she would know a rough location.
I saw a heart sticker over Udo Island
on the map in her room.
What about it?
I wonder if that's where she went.
It's the anniversary of the death
of her donor.
So she finally went.
[Udo Island]
She always said she wanted to visit.
Thank you.
I’m sorry.
I should've come here earlier.
I bet you're disappointed
because it took me so long to visit.
I didn´t know what you would like…
…so I made things I do.
How…
...should I live?
Can you tell me?
You know…
There were places you wanted to go...
...things you wanted to do...
...and even people you wanted to meet...
…right?
I don’t know how…
…but if you just tell me,
I’ll do anything.
I know…
...it won’t make any difference...
...and I know it's
for my own sake, but...
…this is only thing
that I can do for you.
- What are you doing over there?
- Oh my God!
What are you doing over there?
What do you mean?
That's my business.
Why?
Your business isn’t…
…jumping in the sea, is it?
What?
You're not planning on falling
and drowning, right?
No, I’m not.
Why would I want to die?
I can't die young.
I have to live a long, healthy life...
...and live each day to the fullest.
What is she talking about?
Then don't be so careless.
Get down from there.
Jesus Christ.
Why don’t you go away, mister?
It’s slippery on those rocks
because of bog moss and seaweed.
That's none our your business.
Why is he so worried about it?
I’m not worried.
My neighbors are.
Wait.
Wait a moment.
It’s okay.
I can do it myself.
Okay, fine!
Help me!
Don’t go!
Dad!
Is she okay?
Hey!
Lady!
Soo Jeong!
Open your eyes, honey!
Hey!
Wake up!
She isn’t your wife.
Lady!
Open your eyes!
There’s someone in there.
I saw someone in the water.
Oh God.
She’s lost her mind.
Gil Dong.
Put her on my back.
Listen, just get on his back and...
Excuse me!
Here.
- Wait.
- Move!
Get me down!
Mister!
Put me down!
Doctor.
Hurry, hurry!
She’s practically out of her mind.
Here.
Be careful.
No!
You should stay calm.
Calm down.
I’m okay.
You aren’t okay.
Check on her quickly.
Hold on.
Hold on a moment.
I said I’m fine.
See?
You’re throwing up now.
Just… Just for a moment.
You were running with me on your back.
It's just motion sickness.
I’m really alright.
Ah!
Yes, she’s fine.
- She's ok.
- No, no.
- Check on her again.
- I said I’m fine!
I know you're alive
because I can hear you shouting.
You should know Dong Ha
saved your life.
You almost died.
I almost died because of him.
What?
I was in a hurry because of you.
That's why I fell in.
I’ll sue you, mister.
You talk about suing people too much.
What did you say?
Miss, do you have…
What do you call it?
Are you face blind or something?
Why don’t you recognize me?
What makes you think I can't
recognize people?
I remember you clearly.
You're the man who threw
trash in the sea...
...and drank alcohol in broad daylight.
Who do you think I am?
Okay.
Fine.
I should stop talking to you.
My bag!
Mister, have you seen my bag?
Wow, people from Seoul
are really different.
Someone saves your life and now
you're asking for your bag.
Mister!
My bag, my bag!
You’re carrying it with you!
Your foot…
Hey!
- Sit here.
- Hey!
Have a seat here.
Anyway…
…thank you.
Hey.
Yes?
Would you like to go
to my house with me…
…and take a shower?
Ha!
No thank you.
I’ll leave here
before the last ferry today.
Why not?
Why don’t you take a shower together?
Why don’t you take
your clothes off too?
Go… with me…
...and...
Are you alright?
It’s okay.
I think I saw someone in the sea.
Oh my God!
[12th Udo Health Center Workshop]
What happened to me?
Dong Wook *Oppa?
Eh?
[Oppa: Older brother or older male]
Why is Oppa in this picture?
What should I do?
The customer you’re calling is...
Does she really go to Udo Island?
Ba Da!
Dad!
Dad, are you alright?
Of course I’m alright.
- You're wet.
- Here.
What about her?
Did she leave?
I guess.
Her clothes must be all wet.
Where would she go?
She said that she’ll leave here
before the last ferry.
Let's go.
Eh?
But there are no more ferries today.
Dad.
Sing me the song.
For free?
Good enough.
The sea is in blue slumber...
Life is blooming on the land...
And the sky, and the sky...
Dreams of tomorrow...
Look, the reborn Earth...
Welcomes the
awakening morning...
Swim and break through the waves!
Run and kick up the soil!
Because I love the Earth so much...
Because the dawn is so beautiful!
- Run!
- Poo Reum!
- Future boy!
- Ba Da!
Our blue sea!
What?
Why does the ferry stop
in the middle of the day?
You’re kidding me, right?
Because of high waves,
there aren't any more ferries today.
Mister!
Mister, where does this bus go?
It goes everywhere
it’s supposed to go.
Why is he here?
It’s dangerous,
so go have a seat quickly.
By the way, mister…
…didn’t I tell you that I’d leave here
before the ferry stops?
So what?
What do you mean, "So what?"
You should tell me there were
no more ferries today.
How should I know
that the ferry would stop?
You live here,
so you’re supposed to know.
How should I know what the waves think
just because I live on Udo Island?
I’m not a descendant of Poseidon.
Where do you want to get off?
Do you have a place to go?
What if I don’t?
Would you ask me to go
to your house again?
I meant to tell you earlier, lady.
You shouldn't take others' kindness
so poorly.
It’s okay.
Just let me off wherever downtown is.
Is he kidding me?
How can this be the main street?
Huh?
Where… am I?
Excuse me!
Wait a moment!
Mister!
Stop!
Mister, I’m sorry, but…
…can you give me a ride?
Why is it you again?
Does he have a twin?
Do people just look
like each other in this town?
You told me to let you off
at the main street.
Why are you walking around here now?
There’s no lodging over there.
How can it be the main street?
It is the main street.
You’re making fun of me, right?
If you want to get it, then get in.
If you don't, that's fine too...
I'm getting in.
I am.
Mister.
I took an airplane and a boat,
and then I fell in the ocean.
I'm hungry and I'm carsick now.
Can you drive a little slower?
You told me to take you
to lodging quickly.
This is a shortcut, so just be patient.
There.
Over there.
Let me off over there.
Please?
Excuse me.
If you happen to have
a vacant room, can I...
Oh?
Why is he here again?
Are you looking for a place to stay?
That’s…
No, that’s not what I meant…
Unni!
Hey, guys!
How did you know that we live here?
I wasn't looking for you
on purpose, but...
...there aren't any more ferries today
and I couldn't find a place to stay.
By the way, why are you here?
This is our home.
Your home?
Dad!
So…
...if you'd followed me
when I asked you to come…
...it would've been a lot easier.
I rinsed them out thoroughly.
If I hang them out after spinning…
...they'll be dry by tomorrow morning.
Thank you.
By the way, is this
your mother’s dress?
Yes.
Dad threw out all her other clothes...
...so this was the only thing.
Are you sure it's okay
for me to wear it?
If you don’t want it,
would you like to wear dad’s clothes?
Thank you for the dress.
[My country house]
Did he go somewhere?
The organ donor who provided
a heart to Bom Yi...
...was your relative, right?
But then, who was it?
The one who died, I mean.
Don't you know a doctor's
code of ethics?
- That's confidential.
- Hey!
You don’t think that I came to this
hospital to follow the heart, do you?
If not, then it’s okay.
Cellular memory…
...is just a hypothesis.
There are cases where memories
are transferred...
...or transplants cause similar
behavior or habits...
…but it can’t be explained
scientifically.
Of course, I was happy and amazed
when I first found out...
...and it's true it made me care
about her more...
...but the reason I like Bom Yi
has nothing to do with her heart.
But if you marry Bom Yi...
…she’ll see your family often,
won’t she?
Probably.
Then it’s better to keep it
a secret forever...
...from your family too, right?
[Preview]
If I drink alcohol...
...I become a woman who's
too attractive.
You know, a dangerous femme fatale.
When we broke up, you told me that…
...you'd never get married
for the rest of your life.
You read my mind
even though I didn't tell you about it.
That's why I like you so much, Oppa.
Spring is coming
to our boring CEO's life.
Even her name is *Bom Yi.
[Bom means "Spring" in Korean]
I’m CEO Kang Dong Ha.
It isn’t important
whether he’s a CEO or not.
He knew all about it
and he mocked me.