- Please come in.
- Thank you.
It's magnificent.
[Music Continues]
[Chatting, Giggling]
It's got lots of rum in it.
[Latin]
Frank. Frank!
Hey. What's wrong?
You don't like steak? Hmm?
I should be eating with the crew.
Well, you're not. You're eating with us.
So, sit up, humor me and eat your steak.
- Why did you come here?
- Why am I here?
We missed you, sweetheart.
Why in the Sam Hill
do you think I'm here?
- We just wanted to check
on you. That's all.
- Stay out of this.
I don't need you spying on me.
- Spying?
- Frank!
Thanks a lot, son.
- I can take care of myself.
- Oh, really? Huh.
I can't wait for that, son.
You put me on this stupid boat
in the first place.
I didn't want to go, but I did.
Why do you have to embarrass me?
Why can't you just leave me alone?
You come outside with me.
- But, Francis...
- Stay here.
It's all right.
[Horn Honking]
Frank. Frank!
- Get your hands off me!
- Francis, stop it!
- Settle down.
- Let go of him.
- Let go of me!
- Francis, just...
Take your hands off of him!
- Listen to me, you little...
- Francis, you're hurting him!
Now, stop it!
You hear me? Don't you dare
ever talk to me like that.
Francis! My God!
My God!
Now, Frank.
Frank!
[Panting]
Oh, Christ!
What is the matter with you?
Do you want to dance?
Yeah, yeah.
I can't ever remember
feeling this way about myself,
or a place,
or someone like you.
We've come such a long way
and we've seen so many things, but...
- This is...
- [Speaking Danish]
- What?
- [Danish]
I'm not, um, I'm not so great
at expressing myself.
And maybe the only reason
I can do it right now...
is because I know you don't
understand a word I'm saying.
Right.
Roger Maris
steps up to the plate!
It's a corker down the pipe!
[Screams]
It's outta here!
- [Yelling]
- Frank, put it down! Frank!
Come on!
- It's a corker down the pipe!
- Frank, what's goin' on?
- Frank, what the hell are you doing?
- [Yelling]
- It's outta here!
- Talk to me. Tell me what happened.
I just don't cut the mustard.
Come on. Let's go.
I don't hold up under scrutiny.
Chuck!
- Gieg!
- What?
Oh, you...
Double-time it, man.
Frank's in trouble.
[Sighs]
I gotta go. I'm sorry.
I'll see you.
Come on.
- [Dancing]
- Tod, dance.
One, two, three, four.
Hey, buddy, how ya doin'? You know
you're gonna work for me someday.
Frank? Why don't we go?
Why don't we go?
Let me go. I was invited too!
Look at these guys. They're homos.
- Frank, we're gonna go.
- Get off me!
I'm fine, all right?
- Frank?
- Stop doing that.
What are you guys, homos?
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Calm down.
Shh. If you don't calm down,
I'm gonna have to hurt you.
It's okay. We got you.
Get him up.
Get him outta here.
Do you remember the last time
you and I danced?
You're gonna tell me again anyway.
It was on the deck
of the Yankee...
the night you asked me
to marry you.
I wasn't much older
than they are.
- Shall we?
- I don't wanna.
Okay.
May I?
Don't slip, Captain.
Your students are watching.
Gotta get my sea legs here.
[Sighs]
- Coming about. You ready?
- I'm ready.
[Laughs] You know, Sheldon, sometimes,
not often, you act almost half human.
I am halfway human.
Look at those two over there.
[Whispering]
"Much have I traveled
in realms of gold.
And many goodly states
and kingdoms seen.
'Round western islands
I've been,
which bards in fealty
to Apollo hold."
- Do you know what
he's talking about here?
- [Snickering]
Aw, humility.
He's saying he has traveled the seas
as Homer did, as Ulysses before him.
"That deep-browed Homer."
Brilliant, seasoned,
wise of the mind.
He commands the voyage
of the imagination...
like a god.
Piss on Homer, sir.
We're livin' it.
- [Boys Laughing]
- That's the spirit, Dean.
- Dolphins off the stern!
- Aw, dolphins. Okay. Come on.
Come on! Look!
There's one over there!
- [Boys Cheering]
- Beautiful!
- Oh, wow! This is incredible!
- Oh, she's beautiful.
[Shouting]
Lower him down.
Come on! Yes!
[Squealing]
What the hell, guys?
- What happened?
- What's going on?
Guide her alongside.
That's it.
All right, ease her away.
- Bring the nose up onto the sled.
- Okay.
- Dean, watch the spear.
- All right.
Haul away.
Easy. Easy.
Tighten it off, Tim.
That's it.
Whoa!
All right, ease away.
Easy.
Keep it coming.
What do you think?
He's punctured her lung.
Nice shot.
Finish it.
Man, I'm n-not gonna kill it.
You already have.
Go on, do it.
No way.
- What the hell's wrong with you?
- Back off, man!
- You wanna kill somethin' so bad?
- It's just a fish.
- It's just a fish!
- Come on! Let's see what you've got!
That's what I thought.
You're done here.
You're going home.
[Tracy]
The guy's gone ballistic, all right?
I'm telling you, he's gone mentally
insane. It's like cabin fever.
All right, man. Enough.
It's still not right.
They shouldn't be puttin' him
off the boat.
- The guy's outta control.
- We've all been out of control.
But we're a crew.
No, wait, wait.
That's what this whole thing
is supposed to be about.
You're the last person that should be
whining about us being a crew right now.
- Yeah? How do you figure that?
- I'd love to go into the subject...
of vertigo and everything, but I
wouldn't want you to piss your pants.
- You know what I'm sayin'?
- Oh, yeah, Tracy?
Come on!
- Get... Stop it!
- You're a real jerk. You know that?
Tell it to the dolphin, Preston.
He deserves another chance.
We'd do the same for you.
You know that.
You do whatever you want, Gil.
All right?
It's not gonna make
any difference anyway.
- The dolphin was a symptom.
- Of what?
Of a fight he can't win out here.
- But, sir, it's his father.
- It's his father, sir.
- Oh, it's his father. Mm-hmm.
- H-He, he sent him down here.
All of them.
They sent us down here because...
they want us to change or grow up
or something, and all they do
is try and keep us the same.
I mean, h-he has
all these expectations...
about who his son should be,
and he doesn't even know who Frank is.
How do you think you got here?
Do you think they owe you something?
Do you think they enjoy riding
subways and commuter trains?
The same repetition day in and day out
just to keep you in tennis shoes...
and private school?
You know, there are ground rules
in families just like on this ship.
You can understand that.
Does Frank know
how you guys feel?
I don't know.
Well, somebody should tell him.
That's it.
Well, I'm all ears.
- You may not like what you hear.
- Oh, I can take it.
Chris, they've become
what we wanted.
They're a crew.
That's why they came.
Do you remember why
we began this?
Self-reliance and discipline
through the community of sailing.
- I haven't forgotten.
- Mmm. Community.
That boy doesn't know
the meaning of the word.
So, the best thing you can do
is to keep him right here.
- He has a lot of problems.
- He better start to learn
to deal with them.
[Sighs]
Oh, Captain Compassionate speaks.
It's not about compassion.
It's not about what happens here.
- It's about what
they take away with them.
- He was coming around.
He was coming apart!
He lost control out there!
And what is so important
about being in control?
- He's just gonna have
to figure that out, isn't he?
- I'm not talking about him.
[Horn Honking]
[Chuck Narrating]
We watched in silent protest.
Aboard ship, the low morale
was matched only by the feeling...
that maybe Skipper was no different
than our own fathers back home.
We'll miss Frank.
Jesus!
Yeah, I'm... I'm sorry.
[Gil]
Frankie!
[Bell Ringing]
[Ringing Continues, Shouting]
Bye, bye!
[Bell Ringing]
Bye, Frankie!
Whoo-oo-oo!
Bye, buddy!
They never gave up on you,
you know.
[Gil]
Bye, Frankie!
I got a problem, man.
- We all have problems.
- No. A big problem.
I'm pissing fire.
Fire?
Fire.
Hmm.
Had a good time in Grenada,
did you, Tod?
Yeah. I did, actually.
Thanks for askin'.
Turn around.
Ow! Ow.
Ow.
[Groans]
Hold that.
- Next!
- [Groaning]
Robert! Drop your pants.
Way to go, Valentino.
I never even copped a feel
in Grenada.
Well, your sexual orientation
is not my problem.
[McCrea]
What do you make of it, Skipper?
"Venceremos."
Cubans.
I'll get the horn.
Jesus! She's got guns.
- [Gunfire]
- Get down! Everybody down!
Run up the colors.
We're Americans, damn it! Shay!
Run up the colors!
Jesus Christ!
Are they gonna sink us?
- Take in all sail! Do it now.
- Sails down! Get going! Go on!
- Here's the horn, Skipper.
- Who the hell do they think they are?
[Commander Speaking Spanish]
They want us
to identify ourselves.
Tell them we're the American
school ship Albatross.
Use your best
Puerto Rican accent.
[Spanish]
[Girard] They think we're
carrying Cuban refugees, Captain.
I don't think they're going to take it
lightly that I'm a Cuban national.
Nothing's going to happen.
Remind them that according
to the Geneva Convention...
firing on citizens on the high seas
is an act of war.
[Spanish]
They say they're acting
on the direct order of Fidel Castro.
[Spanish]
[Continues In Spanish]
Tell them to come aboard.
Do it! Come on!
[Spanish]
Give me your passport.
Give it to me. Come on, do it.
I don't think...
You've come a long way,
gentlemen,
but this is no time
for heroes.
I need you to be boys right now.
That's an order.
Get below.
Find your passports.
- Bring 'em on deck.
- [McCrea] All right, let's go.
- On the double!
- Let's go find those little bits.
On deck right now! Come on,
get your stuff. Go, go, go, go!
Don't worry.
Nothing's gonna happen.
Preston, got it? Let's go. Let's get
outta here. Trace! Trace, come on!
- Damn it!
- What?
I can't find my passport.
Oh, no!
Is this your stuff here?
Jesus, what a... Come on, we gotta go.
- I can't find my passport!
- Don't worry about it.
Let's go! Now, damn it!
[Spanish]
- [Spanish]
- He's Puerto Rican.
You know, Captain,
playing cat and mouse
is not very smart.
Not for the mouse. Do you know
you're violating international law...
- by boarding my ship?
- But, you invited us.
- That's bullshit, man.
- Shh.
Your cannons made
a compelling argument.
- [Spanish]
- [McCrea] It's okay. He's got one.
- I've got a passport. I swear to God.
- A stowaway?
He left his passport in Grenada.
It's being mailed to him in Panama.
- I left it last time we boarded.
- That is unfortunate.
We'll have to take him with us.
No! No!
All right, all right, all right.
If he's Cuban,
Castro wears a dress!
All right. Now we've seen
what you can do with a boy.
How would you like to go
a few rounds with a grown-up?
None of my crew
is leaving this ship.
Seventh cavalry.
What are you looking at?
You want to take a souvenir,
you take me.
[Spanish]
All right, that's it.
Let's move, gentlemen.
Now you will really have something
to teach your students, Captain.
Las estrellas...
es lo unico que un marinero
necessita para navegar.
What'd he say?
He says a real sailor only needs
the stars to navigate with.
[Chuckles]
[Chuck Narrating] And so he guided us
silently through the convoy of warships.
And we later learned they were bound
for a little known destination...
called the Bay of Pigs.
As we rode the trades,
he shared the ancient secrets...
of how to read the waves
and follow the stars.
Panama and the Americas
rose and fell away again.
With the locks of Miraflores
and a continent behind us,
we entered into a new ocean
and a new world...
- that we would stake
and claim as our own.
- [Timer Buzzing]
All right, pens down.
Time's up.
Leave your papers.
[Skipper]
Congratulations, gentlemen.
All hands may go ashore
if you please.
- [Cheering]
- You're on your own. Be careful.
[Skipper]
Buzzer's gone off, Dean.
[Chuck Narrating]
We had traveled over 6,000 miles...
and slipped past the equator
to the very edge of the earth.
Like Darwin before us,
we would see the bliss of nature...
in the absence of man.
It was as if the Albatross
had taken us to another time.
Today I finally understand Homer.
The journey's the thing.
[Shouting]
[Shouting Continues]
Should be a pencil in there.
Hold that.
"Where we go one,
we go all.
Brigantine Albatross.
Nineteen hundred and sixty-one."
That about says it all, huh?
- [Shay] Get in there, guys.
- Chuck Gieg.
Tod Johnstone.
Gil Martin.
Dean Preston.
Tracy Lapchick.
What are they doing?
Claiming their place
in the world.
Why didn't you go?
- I couldn't. It's my watch.
- Uh-uh. I could've stayed.
- Listen. You hear that?
- What?
The sound of an empty ship.
[Boys Chanting]
[Chanting Continues]
[Bell Ringing]
How you doing?
Okay. How'd you do?
730 verbal. 610 math.
Congratulations.
What about you?
- It's 1100!
- [Laughs]
- Dean, you got an 1100! That's great!
- I know.
- [Gil] You know?
- I just can't believe it, you know?
I couldn't have done it
without you guys, though.
- I really couldn't.
- You did.
This is you, Dean.
All you. Nobody else.
Thank you.
You're welcome, stupid.
I'm just testing.
When are you gonna learn,
you little wise ass?
- Here. Thanks.
- Feels different, doesn't it?
What?
Goin' back.
[Sighs]
I don't want it to end. I don't...
wanna be what I was
when I left.
What was that?
Anonymous.
[Sighing]
I've been acing tests
my whole life...
and I still haven't
figured it out.
Figured what out?
- Who I am.
- [Dean] Are you kidding?
I'll tell you who you are.
Glue. You're the glue...
that holds everyone around you
together.
Think I'm gonna choke on
the "feel good."
[Laughing]
[Thunderclaps]
[Radio]
...on the pilot. He needs help.
There goes the umbilical cord
from the Redstone rocket.
We're into countdown.
How are you, Robert?
[Radio]
We're into the two-minute point,
and at this point in the spacecraft...
all the interior cameras
are started.
Two minutes and counting.
Everything is working fine
at the moment.
The radio mikes are now on
in the space capsules.
- Shepard can talk to control.
- Here we go.
- Good luck, huh?
- [Radio] One minute
and 30 seconds to blastoff...
if no further holds
bother us at this point.
The Mercury Control count,
at the last minute you will hear...
Just a moment. I notice that the
cherry picker is being moved through,
- and we are coming up to...
- The morning watch?
- Below.
- [Radio]... countdown,
which you will hear...
in ten-second breaks.
We have just passed
the 92nd mark.
The cherry picker,
the safety device...
[Bell Ringing]
"If you can keep your head while
all about you are losing theirs
and blaming it on you;
if you can trust yourself
when all men doubt you,
but make allowance
for their doubting too."
Morning watch is on!
"Yours is the earth
and everything in it,
which is more,
you'll be a man, my son."
- [Bell Ringing]
- Okay!
- You have fun.
- [Radio] Fifty seconds and counting.
Sweet dreams, Martin.
[Radio]
...has been cut off.
It is now automatically isolated
from the rest of the atmosphere.
It has its own.
[Volume Increased]
The test conductor in the Space
Control Center has taken over.
[Shay]
Bill, Bob, Tim, Charlie, go aloft!
Get those latches closed!
[Radio Continues]
Morning, Shay.
Hey, Tracy.
- Would you trim the main, please?
- Trimming the main!
- North by west.
Get out of here, Bob.
Let the real men take over.
- Looks like we're gonna get wet.
- Yeah, we need it. I'm gonna
take a nice long bath.
- Catch some water for my laundry.
- Save some for me, buddy, huh?
Yeah. Yeah, you got it.
Goin' below!
Everybody okay?
All hands, keep out of the rigging.
Stay clear of the masts.
All right, gentlemen.
Thor's had his fun.
Let's keep a sharp eye.
[Radio]
We're coming up to countdown...
which goes in five seconds.
No, Shay! Dog her down!
- Stay out of the rigging!
- Dog her down!
[Laughing, Cheering]
[Ringing]
- [Alarm Sounding]
- Batten down all hatches!
Skipper!
White squall. Hold tight!
Hold tight!
- [Chuck] Shay!
- [Shay Groans]
- We're losin' it!
- Turn it over!
Look out!
[Screaming]
[Radio]
...agonizingly slowly.
Get outta here!
Help!
[Tracy]
Tod!
Tod! Tod!
Turn to port!
- No! Starboard! Starboard!
- Port, Tod! Port!
Port! Port, damn it!
Turn to port!
Look out!
Leave it, Tod! Get out!
Back! Back!
Come on, Tod. Grab on!
Grab on!
Come on!
Gil, come on. Let's go.
Let's get outta here.
- [Ship Creaking]
- Now, Gil! Come on!
Come on, let's go.
Everybody out!
Keep moving.
We've lost her!
- Free the staysail.
- Yes, sir!
Free the staysail!
Grab a lifeboat.
Skipper!
Right here. Come on, out.
Out this way.
Get out. Anybody in here?
Anybody in here?
Hey!
Get 'em outta there.
Shay!
Sahler!
[Screaming]
[Skipper]
Girard!
- [Rings]
- [Radio] America's
fastest traveling man...
[Skipper]
Shay!
Girard!
Oh!
[Screaming]
Alice!
Get back, guys!
Get back! She's gonna roll!
- Get in the lifeboat, now!
- Hold on.
Girard!
- Dean!
- Yeah. Yeah. Over here.
[Skipper]
Sahler! Marsh! Gil!
- Gil!
- Where's Gil?
[Screaming]
Help!
One, two, three. Wake up.
- Where's Alice?
- I think they're inside.
Come on!
No! Stay back!
She's rolling!
[Groaning]
She's down there!
Gil!
Skipper, I'll try forward.
Gil! Gil!
Gil, you gotta get outta here.
She's goin' down!
There's something down there
blocking the door!
Get me outta here, Chuck.
Get me out, please!
Come on, Chuck. I want out.
Gil, I can't move it.
You gotta push harder.
Push from your side! Gil!
- Push harder from your side!
- I don't wanna die!
Chuck! Chuck! Chuck!
We gotta go, Chuck!
Come on!
She's goin' down.
Come on, Chuck! Let's go!
Gil,
you've gotta push
from your side.
No, Gil!
- Chuck, we've gotta go!
- Help me with this door! He's drowning!
[Gagging, Coughing]
It's too late!
It's going over!
Skipper, it's too late!
- We can't stay on...
- Get off the ship! Get 'em in the boat!
- Do it!
- All right, Skipper.
[Crying]
Oh, please!
[Grunting]
[Chuck]
No, Dean!
Dean!
[Bell Rings]
[Ringing]
[Chuck Narrating]
Girard, Alice,
Dean, Gil.
Today I hate the sea.
It will never look the same again.
Look.
Shepard.
[Crying]
Skipper! Skipper!
Skipper, look! Look!
McCrea!
Captain Sheldon,
can you give us a statement?
- [Excited Chatting]
- What the hell went on out there?
[Excited Chatting]
Get away from me.
Do you have anything to say
to these parents?
Yes, and it's private.
[Siren Wailing]
- Son!
- Dad?
[Charles] Thought we'd find
a store. Get you fixed up...
and get you something to eat.
Sound good?
Hey! Your size
right on top. Here.
Why don't you take these in the back
there and see how they fit?
Ma'am, do you have boxer shorts?
- Right over there, sir.
- Okay.
[Panting]
[Crying]
[Gil's Voice]
Come on! Chuck, grab my arm!
Grab my arm!
[Gil's Voice Continues,
Sea Water Roaring]
[Charles]
Chuck, you okay in there?
Uh, I-I'm sorry.
We'll be right back
for the clothes.
- [Shay] They're gonna
try to take his license.
- [Tod] Why?
Because they need it to be simple.
They need a reason.
- Who?
- All of them.
- Everyone on that dock.
- What are we supposed to do?
Tell 'em what we know.
The truth.
- I mean, that's what he'd want.
- The truth.
We went over in a squall.
What's wrong with that?
Everybody knows
why we went over, Tod.
It wasn't from the squall.
You jibed the boat.
I was trying to get her upwind.
That's what you're supposed to do!
That's not what
the Skipper thought.
Not when you got the squares up.
He was trying to spill out
the air from the main.
It was comin' four points off the bow,
Tracy. It never would've...
Were you on the deck?
Because I was standing right there!
- All I know is that Tod
disobeyed an order twice.
- Look, it didn't...
- That's when the boat went over.
- It didn't go over
until I turned her port!
Man, you're all missing the point,
anyway. This is because of Frank.
- Frank and dear old Dad.
- What are you talking about?
I'm talking about,
they're here...
staying at
the damn Rhett House.
How do you think this thing
got put together so fast?
The old man's been out
for Skipper since day one.
The Skipper booted his kid
off the boat! What did you expect?
I told you he was a turncoat
the day we kicked him off, man.
Damn kid.
[Bell Ringing]
Frank?
- [Francis] Frank!
- Can we talk?
Yeah, I guess.
What are you doing here?
Frank, who are you talking to?
[Frank] Yeah, it's all right.
I'll be in in a minute.
What do you want?
Everyone's saying that...
that this whole tribunal is happening
because of your old man.
And because of you.
- Is that true?
- It's just typical, isn't it?
- Is it true, Frank?
- I gotta go.
Frank, he was not out
on that ship!
He doesn't know what happened.
You don't know what happened!
- I know enough!
- Frank, please!
Frank, get him to call it off.
I'm sorry.
Wait.
What is this?
You do what you've gotta do,
Frank.
[Tyler]
The United States Coast Guard...
has been asked to conduct
this maritime hearing...
to consider the revocation
of Captain Christopher Sheldon's...
U.S. Master Seaman's Certificate.
All right, Captain Sanders,
you may begin.
The Albatross.
By all accounts, a sound vessel.
An experienced captain,
an able crew.
And yet it lies out there
on the bottom...
in 2,000 fathoms
with its back broken.
There are serious questions that demand
our most serious consideration...
so that we might understand,
so that perhaps...
we may prevent such a sad event
from ever taking place again.
A freak accident?
A one in a million
meteorological anomaly?
Or was it inexperience,
misjudgment?
Negligence?
We'll see.
Please.
Thank you.
[Sanders] Captain Sheldon, Captain
Sheldon, would you consider yourself...
- a good judge of character
when it came to the boys?
- [Skipper] Yes.
- a good judge of character
when it came to the boys?
- [Skipper] Yes.
And it would be important, would it not,
in your position to have some sense...
- of their strengths and weaknesses?
- Yes, of course.
Do you recall an incident
involving Gil Martin?
What incident
would you be referring to?
Well, is it true that you forced
Gil Martin to climb the mast...
when it was clear
that he was acrophobic?
He climbed when he was ready.
Were you aware that his brother
was killed in a fall?
Yes, I was.
Sir, were you aware at any time
of the use of alcohol...
- among your crew?
- Yes, I was.
- You didn't do anything about it?
- No, I did not.
Had you ever seen a white squall
before this incident?
No.
And what makes you so sure
it was one?
I can't be sure.
You really felt that your crew
was up to the conditions?
We had come 12,000 miles together
through every kind of seas imaginable.
Except a white squall. Now, with all
due respect, Captain, they're only boys.
They're much more than that, sir.
Is it true that the reason
you expelled Frank Beaumont...
For killing a dolphin.
And that you invited him to strike you,
to fight it out...
on the deck of the ship?
Yes, that is true.
So, you allowed the use of alcohol,
among things, to go unpunished...
and yet you expelled this boy
for killing a fish.
A mammal.
It would appear to me sir,
with all due respect,
that your stewardship
as captain of the Albatross...
could be characterized
as reckless, unbalanced,
with no discipline whatsoever.
[Chuckles]
Do you find this funny?
Some kind of joke?
I don't think one second
of this is funny... sir.
The National Weather Service...
says white squalls are a meteorological
phenomenon of the imagination.
What do you say to that?
What happened to my ship
was not imagined.
It was not a dream... sir.
No, Captain Sheldon, it was not.
It was a nightmare.
[Sanders] Now, Shay,
I need you to help me out.
On the day of the accident,
do you remember where you were
when the lightning first struck?
I was on deck.
Mmm, midships.
During this squall that ensued,
why didn't you drop any sail?
[Shay] Skipper called us
out of the rigging.
[Sanders]
But your instinct was to lose sail?
Skipper's instinct was to not
get any... any of us electrocuted.
How old are you, son?
Fifteen.
[Gallery Murmuring]
And you were the first mate
of the Albatross. Is that correct?
I am the first mate of the Albatross.
That's correct.
And are you
a professional sailor, son?
No, I'm not
a professional sailor.
[Murmuring]
You say you turned hard
to starboard when the gust hit.
I thought we'd have a better chance
if I headed into the wind.
But the captain ordered you
hard to port.
- Twice.
- I'm sorry?
- Twice!
- Is that what you were trained to do?
No.
- Speak up, son. I can't hear you.
- I said, "No."
And what did you think
he was trying to do?
Put her off. To let the blow
drive the boat downwind.
By the "blow" you're referring to
the force of the storm. Is that right?
Let the blow drive the boat downwind,
and neutralize our canvas.
So when the captain gave you an order
contrary to your training,
you thought
he was making a mistake.
No.
Then why... son?
Why didn't you follow his order?
Because...
[Crying]
I panicked.
You know that's not true, Tod!
[Gallery Murmuring]
- Do you believe he panicked?
- What the hell is he doing?
- [Tyler] Quiet, please.
- [Gavel Bangs]
Maybe you can't see what's
happening here, but I can.
Tod, I appreciate
what you're trying to do here.
Maybe you could live with it,
but I couldn't.
If you think I'm gonna let a
17-year-old take responsibility,
then you underestimate me.
The Albatross was my ship.
The Ocean Academy was my school. Her
responsibility is mine and mine alone.
I can't bring your sons back.
If you want my ticket,
if that will ease your pain,
that's the least that I can do.
- This, this is easy.
- Captain Sheldon?
- Captain?
- No.
- Order, please, order.
- This proceeding is not over.
I have further questions...
- Order, please, order.
- This proceeding is not over.
I have further questions...
- No.
- for this witness.
Order!
Don't you walk out on us,
Skipper! You don't!
[Panting]
You tell me.
Was it all just a lie? Was it?
Because we listened to you,
we believed you! And we are still here.
Bad things happen sometimes, and there
is nothing that you can do about it.
It wasn't you or Tod.
It wasn't you, Tod.
It was all of us,
everyone in this room.
Because we all knew the risks
we were taking going out there.
You paid our tuition,
and you told us to go.
So why do we just have to invent
some reason now for why this happened,
just pin it on one person?
Why?
Then shame on you, Skipper.
Shame on you!
[Tyler]
Mr. Gieg.
I was in command
of the Albatross.
And I was responsible
for precious cargo.
It was my job to get you all home safely
with my knowledge and my skill.
That's the contract
that I made with your parents.
But something happened out there.
I lost control.
Maybe just for an instant,
maybe all along. I'm not sure.
But I know this.
I never saw it coming.
It was...
like I just woke up...
and a hand came down
and pushed my sails into the sea.
It got away for me,
the whole thing.
And people died.
Now... you're young and strong.
Everything's ahead of you.
You told us,
"Where we go one, we go all."
Well, we believed you.
We lived by it, sir.
And, and now you're saying
that where you go, we can't follow.
Mr. Gieg.
The Albatross...
wasn't just a ship...
or a school.
It was something
that we made.
Something
that's inside of us.
That's who you are,
Skipper.
What you gave us.
You carried us.
Now let us carry this together.
Let us carry this together.
Let it go. Just go home.
[Bell Ringing]
[Ringing]
[Chuck Narrating]
They didn't take his ticket today.
But I wonder if he'll ever
go to sea again.
I know one thing.
If he did, we'd all go with him.
To a man. No doubt.
Not even a question.
Today he joined the circle he created
by allowing us to share his burden.
The burden of sea captains
and fathers,
the burden of men.
In the end,
it just comes down to one thing.
You can't run from the wind.
You face the music,
you trim your sails, and keep going.
She's the dark star
over the sea
Go where my true love
is waiting for me
Rode the south wind
Canvas the stars
Harness the moonlight
so she can safely go
'Round the Cape Horn
to Valpariso
Red the port light
Starboard the green
How will she know
of the devils I've seen
Cross in the sky
Star of the sea
Under the moonlight
There she can safely go
'Round the Cape Horn
to Valpariso
Valpariso
Though every road I walk
will take me down to the sea
With every breath of promise
in my sack
Every love will always send
the ship of my heart
Over the rolling sea
If I should die
Water's my grave
She'll never know
if I'm damned or I'm saved
See the ghosts fly
over the sea
Under the moonlight
there she can safely go
'Round the Cape Horn
to Valpariso
Valpariso