# La-la-la-de-de-de...
# ..de-de-de-de-te-te-te-ti-ta...
# ..ta-ta-te-te-de-du-do-doo. #
- Do you have to do that?
- RING RING
Get that, Hattie.
Is it for me? I don't know.
Miss Ju-u-u-dith.
- It's yours, Judy.
- What? Oh...
Look what mother sent. What are they? Pecans.
Well, I COULD get out of my date.
- ..sure I'll get a girl.
- Where is she...
- Take 'em off.
- Are you speaking to me?
- You heard me.
- What do you mean?
- Come on, get 'em off.
- They're mine!
- They are not! I'm not starving to buy you stockings.
- You owe me a pair.
Mrs Orcutt, Linda's doing a strip-tease. Why don't you split 'em?
Go bare-legged. Places YOU go, it won't matter.
What's the trouble? What kind of place are you running?
What is going on? She's accusing me of stealing stockings...
- They're the last you get from me.
- How can I run a decent house...
- You're doing your best!
- This guttersnipe...
- I'll guttersnipe you!
I will not have this in my house!
- I'll slap her ears.
- I'd like to see you!
- Come here then.
Girls, girls. I'm moving in with Madeline.
- It won't take long. Everything you own is on your back.
- Is this brawl over?
- You're all I want to find missing!
- No, nothing ever happens here!
8 o'clock. You betcha. Goodbye.
- Do you want a date?
- Huh?
- More lumbermen?
- Must I apologise for Seattle?
- The last lot were MADE of wood.
- All right...stay and gorge yourself on lamb stew. Pat, want a date?
- Is it for dinner?
- Yes.
- Why didn't you say so? That stew's got me counting sheep!
- It's different when it's dinner.
- I feel safer when we're sitting.
- Try being less insulting this time.
- Me, insulting to a lumberman? The very idea is preposterous!
- Do we dress?
- I suppose so. We usually do.
- I'll be there, pet.
You know me, the lumberman's delight.
Mr Powell's car, for Miss Shaw. I'll tell her.
- For Linda?
- Mr Powell's car.
- I'll be the carrier pigeon.
Oh, Linda, Mr Powell's car is here.
Mr Powell isn't, just his car.
Peaceful place (!)
Anybody use a couple of tired peasants?
How was the matinee? >
More people on stage than in the audience.
It makes me sick. What's Gerda sick about?
- Five weeks rehearsal, two weeks pay.
- Show closing?
- Like a tired clam.
Aw, that's too bad. Let's all go on relief.
TAP ON DOOR
What's that? Mice.
How do you get in here?
Use the other door! Can't you read?
- ANOTHER show folding.
- We should move in with scenery.
- Yeah!
- DOORBELL
Hattie, the mice are back.
- How many doors are there?
- How many do you want?
- I asked a civil question.
- I want to see about accommodation.
- Which keeper's on duty, Hattie?
- GIRLS LAUGHING
- How amusing(!)
- Take a seat.
- I'll get Mrs Orcutt.
- Thank you, thanks.
Pardon me, I shall take the wolfhounds for a stroll.
- If you spoke louder everyone might hear.
- I forget you're old and deaf.
If you'd more respect, Mr Powell might send his car for YOU one day.
I can't wait.
- But he'd probably send YOU back.
- Oh, yeah?
- What about his chauffeur?
- Ah, he doesn't go as far as Mr Powell.
- Even a chauffeur needs an incentive.
- You should know(!)
Enjoy your lamb stew again tonight.
- I'll think of you while dining on pheasant bordelaise.
- Ooh, girls, bordelaise!
Don't eat the bones and give yourself away.
- Did you wish to see me?
- This IS a theatrical boarding house?
- One of the finest.
- I had begun to doubt it.
Are you the person I see about accommodation?
- Yes, indeed! Pardon my appearance, I've been in the kitchen.
- I would like a private bath.
- Did I say anything strange?
- Oh, don't mind the girls, we're one happy family.
I may not be able to give you just what you want.
- I CAN put you with a charming girl.
- How much is it?
- 13, if you share.
Is there a reduction by the week?
- It is 13 a week.
- Oh, my mistake.
- That doesn't include luncheon.
- Do meals go with the 13?
MRS ORCUTT: Yes, and we have a lovely kitchen.
- I have no change.
- I'll be here for a while.
What shall I do about my baggage?
- Get Miss...?
- Terry Randall.
- Miss Randall's baggage.
Pardon me, has Mr Hargraves called me yet? Why, no.
When he does, tell him I couldn't consider his play...
How do you do. This is Miss Randall. Are you in the theatre?
- Not yet.
- With proper coaching...
- Come with me, please.
- Excuse me.
- Put the trunks in Miss Maitland's room.
- What's that?
It's a feature of the club.
It's the chair Bernhardt sat in while rehearsing. I was in the company.
- Oh, you were an actress?
- Mrs Orcutt supported ME in lots of shows.
- That's Bernhardt's picture. They say she was wonderful.
- She was very good although,
- it isn't well known, we had the same coach.
- Coach? Acting's just common sense.
A good coach applies common sense. If I don't get the right play soon, I may do some coaching myself.
- What is this? Another boat docking?
- Mrs Orcutt told me to put them here.
- This is not a store-room.
- Jean, this is your new room-mate, Miss Randall.
- We've met before, after a fashion.
I'm sure you'll get on very well.
- I'm sure.
- Anything else?
- No, thanks.
- When does your baggage get here?
- The rest arrives tomorrow.
Well, we can always sleep in the hall(!)
What about the wolfhounds? You don't mind animals?
- I've roomed with them before.
- I can see that(!)
- Fresh kill?
- Yes, I trapped them myself.
- Can I ask a personal question?
- Another!
- These trunks full of bodies?
- Just those.
- We can always live in the trunks.
- Good idea. You don't mind helping? Sorry, I forgot you're not a maid.
Oh, that's all right. What a lovely dress, made by loving hands?
- Every stitch.
- Do you cook?
- Nothing fancy, just plain home cooking.
Bet you boil a great pan of water!
- You don't mind if I put this here?
- Why not, it'll scare moths away(!)
- Friend?
- It happens to be my grandfather.
- Quite a resemblance round the whiskers(!)
- That's intelligent, for you(!)
He seems pretty generous.
- He treated me well.
- Bet you wish he was younger.
In addition to your other charms, you've that insolence caused by an inferior upbringing.
Fancy clothes, fancy language and everything(!)
I also learned to speak English correctly.
We talk pig-latin here.
- And I use the right knife and fork.
- All you'll need is the knife.
- Mind if I hang these things here? I must take my bath.
- That might help(!)
Half the wardrobe is yours. Get rid of anything in your way.
I expected a rabbit to jump out of that hat(!)
Orcutt nearly fainted at the 50.
< What's she doing HERE with 50?
It must be counterfeit.
I think she's a phoney.
When she asked if 13 included meals!
- Maybe she's slumming.
- Yeah!
- Talking of slumming, when do we eat?
Wash your necks, children, the lamb is about to be sacrificed.
< I washed my neck yesterday. < So did I. < Here's Kay.
Hello. < Any luck?
No, but I saw a MANAGER! Hey, Kay saw a manager!
Was it an interview? No, I saw him as he rushed by.
Such animals DO exist! What did he look like?
Like any other animal. He had on pants, tie... Did he have hoofs?
- Did he bleat?
- I wasn't so close. You saw a mirage!
Come and get it!
Henry, mother'll get you some lovely lamb stew. Coming Kay?
- I'll be along later.
- Aren't you having dinner?
- I'm not hungry.
You've been awfully blue lately, haven't you?
After a season in Powell's office, he might say hello. It's pretty discouraging.
Oh, Miss Hamilton...
I'm afraid... I know, but could you let it go a little longer?
It's three weeks... But I don't eat here, and I've almost got a part.
I don't want to be inconsiderate...
Well, maybe I could give you a little...
Say, 10? That's something. Thanks awfully.
Ella, it's still a community tub, you know.
- Just a minute. >
- What do you think you are, a seal?
If you want to drown yourself, use the ocean. Hey, Kay!
- Why didn't you say hello?
- Hello, Jean, I didn't see you.
- You must've heard me.
- Oh, don't pay any attention to me.
- What's the matter?
Just one of those days.
- Let's have a good cry.
- All right, cry on my shoulder. I'm going to bathe anyhow.
"No casting today. Leave your name and number, we'll get in touch...
"Mr Powell isn't seeing anyone until the end of the week"...Last week...
..and the week before. Where did I get the idea I was a good actress?
- Who got all those rave notices?
- That was a year ago.
- You DO sound gloomy.
Why am I hanging on? But there's nothing else I can do. No-one to go back to.
Except someone I'll NEVER go back to.
You don't have to go back. You're the best actress here. Something good'll come your way.
I hope so. But it had better be soon.
I don't mean to butt in, but if it's a matter of a few bucks...
Oh, Jean, I've got to get that part in "Enchanted April". It's my life. It's me! No-one else can do it.
It belongs to me! Oh, Jean, I've got to get that part... I've GOT to!
That was dinner fit for a king.
I got it caught in my teeth.
Lamb stew must drive sheep herders crazy.
If your cat goes missing, I'm eating out.
Bet Orcutt's husband died of wool poisoning.
I was so interested in your discussion of "Twelfth Night."
- Thank you. I'm afraid the others don't agree.
- Barbarians!
They've had no training, my dear. When I played in "Twelfth Night"...
- Oh, did you play in "Twelfth Night"?
- Yes...I...
- ..I have some notices, if you'd care to see them...
- Please.
- Oh, they're right on top!
Just read the bits that are marked. This is from Atlantic City.
That new gal's got a crush on Shakespeare. Maybe they'll marry.
Shakespeare's dead. No!!
If he wrote "Hamlet", he is.
- Never heard of it. - Oh, you must! - I meet so many people(!)
More Shakespeare coming up.
Is it wrong to discuss the classics?
I won't take my sleeping pill tonight.
All great actresses used to know their Shakespeare.
- How about their onions? - Listen to Miss Randall, you might learn something.
- I like "Amos and Andy".
- In my day, we were actresses AND technicians. We learnt our trade with care.
That's what we should have, a trade.
- I'd like to use my hands.
- - Try your feet, they're bigger.
Trouble is, you don't take anything seriously.
After a year trying to get a job, you won't either.
Do you have to do nothing about it?
My grandfather did nothing till he was 80.
If my grandfather had sat around, there would still be Indians in Wichita.
- Who's there now?
- You're facing difficulties, what about the men who crossed the Rockies?
Did any try to see a manager?
No, but they could have. I bet I can too.
You'll get in with vanishing cream?
Time to be off. If we're not on stage by 8.30, the orchestra gets lonesome.
# Oh, we're the girls of the Edelweiss...#
ALL YODEL
Can't we ever have any peace around here?
Olga wants peace. Can't have peace without a war.
What have you done in the theatre?
Everything but burst out of a pie!
Well, if you did something for the theatre, it might do something for you.
- What theatre?
- Is there one?
I haven't looked lately.
None of you seem to take your work very seriously.
- I'm going to try. I want to know if I can act.
- Your best friends won't tell you.
Try to stretch your mind further than the next wisecrack.
I tried that once. You girls need training.
< In my day... In centuries past.
- Yes? - Just reading aloud.
Oh.
Who will we pick on now? Not me.
- Judith!
- My lumber gentlemen. No cracks!
- Sorry we're late.
- Nice to see you again.
I manage to get down here once a year. Meet Mr Millbank.
- I've known this girl since she was in pig-tails.
- Let's skip that.
Nobody ever thought that she would be an actress. >
The odds are still the same.
- Have you got a friend?
- Oh, a charming girl.
Jean, I'd like you to meet some friends.
- You said they were dressing.
- Don't start.
- They should've worn overalls.
- Cut it out!
Jean, I'd like you to meet Mr Dukenfield and Mr Millstream.
- Millbank.
- What did I say?
- Millstream.
- Do you tear down trees with your hands?
- Told you she was a kick!
- I love it!
- I can tell by the size of your shoes(!)
- < What?
- Ain't she a card?
- You come from Seattle too.
- How did you know?
- I can tell a college man.
- I got a taxi waiting.
- Let's get going.
- A taxi! I bet you drink champagne out of slippers!
- I never have...
- Let's go to Central Park and hang on the trees.
- You're killing me!
Pleasant little foursome. I predict a murder before the night's over.
DOOR OPENS
Hello.
How are your folks?
- What happened to you?
- Nearly everything.
- You're limping.
- Am I? So I am.
- Ever danced with a Seattle Romeo?
- I don't remember.
- You would!
- Why do you go out with them?
Why do I? They not only jump on you, but bore you to death.
I know how many cords of wood...
..in a pint...a pine tree is not deciduous, but has acidosis...
and Oregon will soon be bald through lack of timber.
- Why am I telling you this?
- Why not? We're sharing a room, why not our troubles?
- We started badly. Let's stay that way.
- Don't you get tired?
- Can't you take it?
- I can take it!
Mind if I ask a humble question?
- Ask it in English.
- What do you do about air in here?
In summer we do without. This time of year, we open a window.
Oh.
This thing is stuck.
Don't pull from the top.
BLAST OF LOUD TRAFFIC NOISES
- What about the sign?
- Leave it there.
- Don't those lights keep you awake?
- Yes, if you try to out-blink them. We usually use these.
- What do I do? Put it over my eyes?
- No, swallow it with water (!)
- That's ingenious. Thanks.
- Don't get sentimental.
- You sleep right away?
- Why do YOU go to bed?
I thought we might talk.
- I've had enough talk for tonight.
- Are you wondering why I'm here?
- Why not find somewhere decent?
- Isn't this a decent place?
- No!
I've always longed for an atmosphere like this.
You haven't seen atmosphere. Wait for the garbage trucks at five.
- Am I getting good?
- No, that just seemed funny.
It isn't funny to me. If I had your clothes, I'd scram, and leave you with your 'atmosphere'.
You wouldn't sell out for a wardrobe.
It's okay for you, you got yours. Linda isn't doing so bad either.
- Linda? Oh, the other girl you fight with.
- Maybe you two have the right idea.
What idea's that?
- Stop kidding.
- Oh, you mean having a grandfather.
Call him what you like.
- If I had to do it over, I wouldn't have a grandfather.
- Says YOU!
Who's in a better position to say, as my grandfather buys my clothes?
- Whadyasay?
- I said, who's in a better...
- Write it down, I'll read it in the morning.
JAZZY MUSIC ON THE PIANO
Up...one...two... three...four...
Alright, alright. That's enough for today.
- I thought he'd never stop.
- We ought to get him a whip.
- Let's run through our routine before Olga gets away.
- I need new legs.
Forget the lumberjacks, and get some sleep.
Olga, will you run through our routine? What about my concert practice?
Please. Oh, all right, and for this I studied with Kolijinsky(!)
- Tony Powell, how are you?
- Alex, how's the new school?
- Fine. You putting on a musical?
- Not unless I find an angel. Seen one?
- No, not lately.
- Hit it, Olga!
- JAZZ MUSIC ON PIANO
- Who's the blonde?
- Want to meet her?
- Never mind, I'll introduce myself.
Look who's giving us the once-over.
- Where?
- Over there.
- Who is it?
Nobody but Anthony Powell.
Oh, so that's Linda's soulmate.
- Uh-huh.
- Who's he staring at?
- I don't know, but I hope it's me.
- You can have him.
- You rehearsing for a musical?
- No, we're just getting over the DTs.
- Nice routine.
- I hear yours is okay.
- We haven't got to the best part.
- What's the matter with your friend?
- Well, I think she's kinda nervous...
- ..meeting a great man like you.
- Do I make you nervous?
- A little.
- Do you kids expect to go on stage?
- We're just waiting to be discovered.
- Well, you're discovered.
- I didn't mean it that way.
- We're looking for nightclub work. Like the Grotto.
- The Grotto?
- Well, excuse me, I AM a little nervous.
There's nothing like a cheerful letter from home. Pa got laid off,
my brother slugged a detective... lots of love, can you spare 50?
Did you like the soup? It would've made nice hot water.
Next time, I'll use it to wash out my stockings.
That meatloaf came from a museum!
I wonder what was in it.
Let's complain about the food (!)
You could've had a date with me!
- Have my share of those timber wolves.
- They mean food to me!
- Know any younger men?
- Hungry ones!
- She needs a good bawling out.
- Don't start that again!
- Start what?
- Well, Tony Powell was at rehearsal today.
- So what?
- The great Anthony Powell?
Uh-huh. He was nice and interested in us, but she ran out on him!
- He kept staring at me!
- Lucky you!
- Yeah!
- It makes you want to put a coat on!
Don't forget I'm part of this team. I'm not running AWAY from managers!
You're interfering with my art!
He's got a pretty good act himself!
- You need pumping up!
- Well, she ain't exactly a flat, just a slow leak!
- Food and men! Is that all you talk about?
- What else is there?
- Hi, Kay. New script?
- Yes.
Don't you eat here any more?
Some friends are in town, so I've been seeing them.
- Not tree chopper-downers?
- Just people.
- Pardon me, there's a dust storm blowing up.
- Howjado.
- We've met socially?
- Hope not!
- Hey, that's a good piece of skin.
- Just a trinket from my Aunt Susan.
- It's good of those animals to die for you.
- Oh, they're very smart.
They die for the RIGHT people.
YOU know rodents! I saw your Aunt Susan today - you show better taste than HE does.
- Jean.
- Think of a reply while I get this.
Don't forget Aunt Susan's car is outside. Hello. Miss Maitland here.
Yes...Mr Berger, the Club Grotto. Where? When?
I'll go right over. Kids, the depression's over.
- You gone screwy?
- String bean, wake up!
- Why?
- It's Gordon from dancing class.
- Did he propose?
- No, we're to go to the Club Grotto.
- Why?
He's got an opening in his show!
- What's the excitement?
- Who knows!
She hasn't worked in so long, this job could be her comeback!
- There's lots of action here!
- Like a circus.
- A little.
- They're great girls.
- I think so.
- They don't like ME.
- Never mind.
- Maybe there's something wrong with me?
- You're just different.
Well now, WHY? I eat the same food, and I'm doing my best to pick up their slang
though I'm not so hot. How's that? "Not so hot"!
- You both need time to understand each other.
- Yes, I suppose so.
They make a lot of noise to keep up their courage.
But they're young enough to have courage.
Young enough to have fears, too. Look how excited Jean and Ann were at just the CHANCE of a job.
It's awful, hoping some manager will interview you.
You don't have that worry. I saw you last year, you KNOW you're good.
I'm not sure. Who is an actress and who isn't?
You can't just walk up and down a room and act.
Without that job and those lines, an actress is like any girl trying not to look as scared as she feels.
Here's something to try. I've had dinner.
This is special, I'm practising cooking.
I'm glad someone is!
I'll leave it. You may get hungry.
Hattie! Coming.
- That's final?
- Yes, Dad, that's final.
I thought you might have satisfied this whim of yours and come home.
If I couldn't achieve anything without the family money
- I'd feel useless.
- Why the stage?
- There are other things.
- It appeals to me. Why did grandfather leave a nice home to become a pioneer?
He made sacrifices for a reason. For economic security.
Security from what? So I can play bridge, ride to hounds, or marry a polo player?
Is that why he endured hardships?
- What about the family name?
- Our family is from the Mid-West. No-one in New York knows our name.
They don't know me yet, but they WILL.
I'm sorry, I can't support you any longer.
Financially or morally?
- If you go on with this, you'll have to do it alone.
- I'll do it alone.
- What if you fail?
- I'll be the first to admit it.
- It may take years to find out.
- Yes, but I'm going to stick to it.
Well, are you too proud to come back home if you are a failure?
No!
- You'd come home if you failed?
- Would you have me?
Well, you're pretty stubborn,
but you're still my favourite daughter. We'll leave it there. Check, please.
JAZZ MUSIC WITH TRUMPETS
Hello Mr Powell, nice to see you again. Miss Shaw, Mr Powell.
- Won't you join us?
- Hope I'm not intruding.
- I should say not!
HOW many times have we been "introduced"?
Thirty-seven, including this evening.
- I wonder if we're fooling anyone(!)
- You're in an ugly mood.
Why can't you get me an interesting STOOGE?
I'm retained as an ESCORT. Stooge fits the bill.
- Let's go, I'm bored.
- Relax, I want to see some new numbers.
Oh, getting interested in NEW numbers?
We are SUPPOSED to be together(!)
I could get you a job with a ventriloquist(!)
Well, life is FULL of surprises(!)
- Cute kids, aren't they?
- You think so?
- Wonder who they are.
- Just RIFF-RAFF they pick up in town.
- Mr Powell, phone call for you.
- Thank you.
- Why not dance?
- If it's a WRONG number, you can get your money back.
Well, shall we dance? NO!
- Hear what she called us?
- US?
- Riff-raff! I could hit her!
- Well, you almost did!
- Powell just sat there. I should've hit him too.
- That's all we need.
- What do you mean?
I heard tonight he owns half interest in this club.
I THOUGHT it was funny we got this job all of a sudden.
- And THEN came the dawn(!)
- Think he's involved?
Atta girl! Bet you can put two and two together.
- So that's it!
- Don't be a dope! If he smiled at me tonight the way he smiled at you, I'd collapse!
- May I come in?
- Please do.
- I thought you two were very good.
- We thought so too.
- May I sit down?
It's your club.
- I have a small interest in it.
- Don't pay any attention, she's barmy!
- You don't like me?
- I like a man who takes his MOTHER out. That WAS your mother with you?
- No, that was a friend's mother.
- I can speak freely?
- Yes.
- Your 'friend' has bad taste in mothers.
I'm beginning to think so myself.
My ideal mother is young, blonde, slim and generally intriguing.
- I'll get you one. How do you like them? Tall, fat, round?
- About...YOUR size.
That's not so easy. I'm NOT stock size.
- Couldn't we talk it over at dinner?
- I'm fond of dinner. Could you send your car?
- Where to?
- I'm living at the Footlights Club, but traffic is heavy.
- I see!
- So send it here first.
Perhaps that would be better.
- Tomorrow night, after the show?
- Mama'll have a lamp in the window.
- Goodnight.
Mr Powell isn't in. Did you have an appointment?
I could wait. Wait if you like but I doubt you'll see him.
Hello? You might call later. > Mr Powell is out of town.
How'd you like that? Out of town!
I guess that was his DOUBLE peeking through the door(!)
Fancy opening an office NOT to see people.
WHISTLING A CHEERFUL TUNE
You can go in.
- Mammie singer?
- Maybe Powell forgot his shoes.
- Hello, Kay.
- Hello.
- Mr Powell's out of town.
- He may be hiding.
- We're kidding, but you need an appointment.
- I've got one.
- I'm reading that part today.
- Knock him off his chair!
- I've been studying all night.
- Do you have appointments?
- We're waiting for Randall. If she can't see Powell, we get lunch.
Starting with caviar, nice, big WHALE caviar. Miss Hamilton. >
- Good luck, kid.
- Thanks.
I'm sorry, you can't go in now.
Something came up. Mr Powell has had to cancel.
I can wait. Not today. Next week sometime.
If I could see him for five minutes.
Sorry, it'll have to be next week.
Please make it today, because...because...
Somebody catch her!
We'll take care of her.
- What's happened?
- Powell broke an appointment, and she fainted.
- Let me help.
- Give me the water.
What a guy! Breaks an appointment to get his shoes shined!
- Who does he think he is?
- < You can't go in.
- Watch me!
- Are you Anthony Powell?
- Who are you?
- Never mind.
- What...
- Why do you refuse to see people...?
- That's MY business.
- A girl fainted because of it.
- I didn't know.
- You won't, if you don't see people.
A great actress could be out there, but you'd never give her a chance!
- Are YOU a great actress?
- Never mind. Those girls need you! They need to be noticed.
I'm sorry, I couldn't stop her.
- The girl who fainted?
- Her friends are with her.
- All right.
Thank you.
- I want to talk to you.
- Go ahead.
- Okay, sonny.
- Sit down.
- I'm sitting.
I take it you hold me responsible for those girls. Is that correct?
- No, but you should see those people.
- I haven't time to see everyone who comes here.
- Huh!
Sit down, you're making me nervous.
Every year 50,000 girls decide they want to act.
Most would be better at home, washing dishes.
- The others?
- There are 50 girls for a job!
- Do you find the right one?
You never see them to say "no". That would give them SOME contact with the theatre.
- You can't complain. I've SEEN you, you're not the type.
- Very smug, Mr Powell.
- Whether you believe I'm to blame or not, run along and leave me with my conscience.
- Have you one?
I won't see ANYBODY else, I...
- Oh...Hello, Mr Carmichael, come in.
- Hello, Mr Powell.
- How are you?
- Fine.
- This has nothing to do with that other matter?
- No, nothing like that.
- Fine, sit down. Cigar? Cigarette?
- You just missed some excitement.
- So I hear. Who's the girl?
- No idea.
- A stage-struck damsel.
- An actress?
- A bad one, I can always tell.
- You're sure of that?
- I seldom miss.
These stage-struck girls would be better off at home.
- My client agrees.
- Client?
- You've got a play?
- "Enchanted April", why?
The client I spoke of is interested in the theatre.
I can't mention names, but he'd like to dabble in show-business.
Fresh money is always welcome.
- Under the circumstances, I'm not sure you'd be interested.
- What circumstances?
Here's the proposition. We can go over it. If you're still interested, we'll go on from there.
Hello. This is the Footlights Club. No, FOOT! How can it be the laundry when it's the Footlights Club?
Yes, I'm sure. I'm standing in it! Oh, go wash your OWN neck!
How's Kay? She's all right.
What did the doctor say? Malnutrition, that's not eating.
She needs good food and a rest.
She hasn't worked for a year. That's a rest.
- Come here. Shake your head.
- Why?
- Just shake it.
As I thought, I can hear it rattle.
- What did you say?
- Nothing!
Hope Powell sleeps tonight(!) What's this about Randall telling him off?
She made a lot of noise!
I'm revising my opinion of her.
Is Mr Powell's car here yet? I ain't seen it.
DOORBELL Maybe that's it.
These are for Jean Maitland. I'll see she gets them.
Thank you, I recognise the florist. They're for Jean.
Oh, so they are. Let me take them to her.
Save me a trip upstairs.
- Looks like there's a new queen bee.
- Yes, but the same king!
- How's Kay?
- Fine.
- It's so silly to go without food.
- Yes, "terribly silly"!
- I didn't mean it that way.
- How is she?
- She'll be all right.
- She should have told us.
- Sweet of you to send the doctor.
- Don't mention that.
The whole thing is so unnecessary.
- May I come in?
- The exterminators don't arrive till tomorrow.
- They missed you last time?
- I was out with a boyfriend of yours.
- These arrived for you.
- You brought them up! If I could find my purse,
- I'd give you a tip.
- I came to give YOU a tip.
I'll tell what the note says. "11 roses and the 12th is you."
You're doing well. Tell me more.
His routine's the same with all the girls. Ending with supper in his penthouse with all the trimmings.
- There's Harcourt, he's a gem.
- That isn't him you're wearing?
No, that's a star sapphire.
- Harcourt's the butler. He's very discreet, tiptoes backwards.
- I know the type.
You'll get to know him. He's deaf, so don't bother to scream for help.
I mustn't forget the lighting effect, it's very good. It goes with that tired little boy routine.
- You'll see!
- How galling for you older women to lose your meal ticket to younger riff-raff!
Meantime, I have my sable coat and star sapphire to keep me company.
- You paid too much for it.
- You're wrong. I'm not as generous as my Aunt Susan.
Goodbye! If you need a pallbearer, I'm at your service.
Ahem. I couldn't help overhearing.
- You're NOT running around with that man Powell!
- Why not?
- Just to spite Linda?
- I can take care of myself.
- You need a governess!
- I think he's charming.
- So are snakes.
- If I don't go out with him, Ann and I may lose our jobs.
- That's a lame excuse.
- You got along before.
- I'm sick of 'getting along'.
- Stick to your ideals.
- You should talk!
- NOT that grandfather thing again!
- It's none of your business.
- Sorry!
- That jacket is similar to one of mine.
- I didn't expect you so soon.
- I just wanted to see how I'd feel in one of these.
- Do you feel different?
- I'll say!
- Well, why not wear it?
- You mean it?
- Why not go OUT in ermine? You'll come BACK in rags.
- You know, you're not such a bad egg.
- As eggs go, I have my points.
Gee, thanks!
Not at all, not at all, anything for old Seattle. I'm not sure about dinner.
- Hattie, what's on tonight?
- What d'you think?
- I think I can make it.
I'll try to get another girl.
- What a well-dressed room-mate wears.
- Pardonnez-moi?
Henry, that's you, if you don't behave.
- If you're not busy, I have a couple of lumber...
- Don't mention the word 'lumber'!
I'm dining tonight on pheasant bordelaise...
- Where's Bordelaise?
- She doesn't know what PHEASANT is.
There's a difference between PHEASANT and PEASANT.
- My friend won't serve PEASANTS.
- He WILL take them out.
When he's through, he's through!
It's one thing to borrow him, another to HOLD him.
Tell the lady I won't buy anything. Goodbye! When I return I'll tell you how the other half lives.
- Let's not be late again.
- Lead the way, Higgins.
- You think she was burned up?
- Oh, have it out with knives(!)
- Hello, Bill.
- Hi, Palsy. Hello, Ann.
We're in a hurry. What's up with her?
- She's a grouch. When did you get back?
- This morning. The show was one of the quicker flops!
- I gave it up when I was seven.
- Bright girl. Busy tonight?
- Yeah.
- Well, I couldn't give you much time tonight. Tomorrow?
- Oh, I don't think I can.
- Why not?
- Since we've got this job, I haven't had time for anything.
- You've given up eating?
- It's not that. I don't think we'd better see each other for a while.
- Why?
- I just think it's better.
- Oh.
- Why do you say 'oh' like that?
- How would YOU say it?
- It sounds like it means something.
- Does it?
- What I do is my business.
- < Are you coming?
- Oh, shut up!
- Did you eat something sour?
- Sorry.
- I've got to live my own life.
- Sure.
Does it matter if I walk with you?
No, I guess not.
- That's 50,000 you owe me.
- Double or nothing.
- Okay.
Ah, we're even!
- Enjoy supper?
- Didn't dare to.
- Why?
- Because I'll go back to lamb stew.
You don't have to go back to that.
- D'you eat like this all the time?
- Practically. Why?
- Just wondered. Wish I'd been born lucky.
But you are beautiful. I'm the lucky one.
- More champagne?
- No, thanks. I won't be able to stand as it is.
BOO!
- I knew she was lying.
- Who?
- He isn't deaf.
- He hasn't been.
- You can't trust people.
- No...some coffee?
- S'wonderful view.
- Yes, it is.
- Wonderful.
- It's a beautiful city.
Like a fairyland. Full of colour, romance and glamour.
- Depends where you see it from.
- You should only see it from here.
- Those lights keep you awake?
- No.
I love New York from here. It looks all rouged and manicured and ready to go out.
- Quite a philosopher.
- It's the champagne talking.
- Mighty good talk.
- Mighty good champagne.
- Let's have more of both.
- Who are the men?
- Figures from the Orient.
- Anyone I know?
This one takes care of girls who work hard.
- This one, that they meet the right people.
- This one went to market...
- And doesn't make girls eat stew.
- Who's that?
- Mrs Powell.
We're not divorced. That's Junior. Fine-looking boy.
I don't believe in pretence. Lots of men keep quiet about their families,
- but I believe a man can have his home and lead his own life.
- Mmm.
- That is, a man of character.
- Big of you!
- It's the way I feel.
- Very big of you!
- Relax!
I want to talk to you.
You must be tired, dancing all evening.
Ooh, there you are again.
I'm glad you're not deaf, cos you wouldn't be able to hear. That would be terrible.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Terrible!
I never know where he's going!
- What?!
- Isn't that more restful?
- Something blow?
- It improves the view.
- S'beautiful.
Think what it will look like with your name flashing across the sky.
- Your name in letters that big.
- That big!
- All right, that big!
- It'll keep people awake.
- It will. I'll mould you into the greatest dancer ever.
I'll be Pygmalion, you, Galatea.
- Sounds like a fairy story.
- Isn't life a fairy story?
At work, I'm gruff Anthony Powell. That's just a pose.
With you, I'm just a boy, dreaming.
- Who are you supposed to be?
- Huh?
- Who are we?
- Pygmalion and Galatea.
- Who am I?
- You're Galatea.
- I'm Galatea!
Pygmalion carved a statue from marble and it was so beautiful, he fell in love with it.
His love brought the statue to life and they lived happily ever after.
- Did they marry?
- No! They didn't in those days.
- That's terrible!
- What's terrible?
- They didn't marry.
- She was a STATUE!
- That's what's terrible.
- It's just a story!
- Look at the trouble...
- It doesn't matter!
You're getting hysterical. Besides, he had a wife and son. Harcourt!
He should've thought of that.
You're getting excited... The coat!
- It's nothing to you, but it was something to her. He can't DO that!
- You bet he can't!
- Do something!
- I will. You run along.
Get some sleep. My lawyer will sort it out.
- Sort what out?
- Don't worry about a thing.
- You're wonderful!
- Harcourt's here.
- He'll see you to your car.
- You're wonderful!
- Yes, I'm wonderful. The whole thing is wonderful.
Whew!
# Our penthouse on Park Avenue...
# ..way in the midst of the sky...
# ..it certainly seems rather high, it certainly is rather high. #
You seem high yourself. You must've had a good time tonight.
It was wonderful. The view was wonderful, supper was wonderful, I won 50,000,
- Harcourt's wonderful.
- Who's he?
- What's his name?
- You know your own?
It'll be in letters that big! No, THAT big!
- Yours or Harcourt's?
- You said it!
He's going to marry Galatea.
Who is Galatea?
She's a statue. Shouldn't have got married... But it'll be wonderful!
Everything will be wonderful(!)
- The view is wonderful.
- You and Harcourt are wonderful.
- You're wonderful.
- Yes, yes.
- Let me help you take off your things.
- We're going to the wedding.
- You'll be there?
- I'll be there.
- Harcourt's going to marry Galatea, and we'll all live together.
- I feel terrible.
- But isn't it wonderful(?)
- Tomorrow, you'll have a hangover. That WON'T be wonderful.
- Wonderful!
How did you get into the theatre? How did any of us?
I'm always a spectator!
- What about you, Judy?
- It started years ago.
- I went to a circus and I saw a lady in pink tights. Was that you?
- I don't like pink!
- She was riding a white horse.
- Sure it wasn't a cow?
Look at me! No job, no pink tights!
- Mr Powell's car calling?
- It calls for me every night.
I wondered. I saw him today with another young lady. But you've lasted much longer than I thought.
- Is madame certain she isn't seeing things?
- Quite certain.
But you'll get a note saying he's been detained on business. He's very courteous that way!
This is where I came in! Let's go.
This'll be a great play. Actresses have begged to play Jeanette.
It's one of the best parts ever written. That more restful?
It makes ME uncomfortable.
- I'll tell you about the play.
- OK.
It opens on Long Island. It's a beautiful spring day.
Jeanette, your character, is upset. Her husband is leaving her.
We ARE here to discuss the play?
- Why do you ask?
- I'm suspicious.
- Don't you want to be a star?
- In the proper circumstances. The couch is more comfortable(!)
- Would you like your name...
- In big letters? They must be big. Jean and I are used to that.
- What?
- You love her?
- No! I was interested.
- Oh.
She's a pest now. Are you a lawyer?
- No.
- What has Jean to do with this?
- Do you want this part?
- How do you know I can act?
Because I know.
- You haven't seen me on stage.
- Oh?
- I haven't BEEN on stage.
- Er...I saw you in my office.
- I wasn't performing.
- I know an actress when I see one.
- How?
- Ever stop asking questions?
- I just like...
- I'll do the talking.
- This part needs emotion.
- But I'm not an emotional person.
- I'll mould you.
- I don't want to be moulded. I act with my brain.
- I'll mould you one...Harcourt!
- DOORBELL
Get the champagne. I'll get that.
Do you mind if I answer the door?
- How did YOU get here?
- Have you got a woman in here?
- Who wants to know?
- Who has a better right?
- Go back downstairs.
- Don't shout!
- I'M NOT.
- Where is she?
By what right do you come...
- Oh, it's YOU.
- Hello.
- What IS this?
- Exactly(!)
- We were talking about a play.
- On the floor?
- What is this, a frame-up?
- Darling, control yourself.
Don't 'darling' me. Get up!
- You go home.
- When you hear what I've got to say!
- We're signing a contract.
- With champagne?
I thought I loved you! But I see my mistake now. I only went out with you to spite Linda.
- Yes, hide your face. You double-dealing, double...
- I didn't know what I was doing.
And you preach ideals(!) You and your grandfather!
- That's enough!
- And behind my back!
Take your cape. I'll never borrow another thing, and don't try to borrow from me!
- Don't cry AGAIN!
- Hope you snakes are happy. And you, you reptile!
Never mind.
- What's funny?
- Everything!
- What she must think!
- She's thinking what I want her to think.
- Why? Why?
- I like her.
- She won't like you!
- She'll see the light.
- But your reputation! Aren't you a girl scout!
- I use my brain.
I wanted to show you I could act.
- You're a faker.
- We both are.
- I am NOT.
- You're a bigger faker than I am.
- That's libel!
Not if I can prove it. This is your son?
- I...
- If he is your son, he must be older than you. That has been used to advertise an academy for years.
- How do you know?
- My brother went there. And this lady, your 'wife',
has done a lot of face-powder ads!
- My friend, you have just broken up a VERY convenient marriage.
- I think we understand each other.
- What about the play?
- Where were we?
- Long Island.
- The scene opens there.
It's a beautiful day in spring.
- Jeanette...
- That's me.
- Right. Jeanette is broken-hearted.
She's losing her husband. Not the way I just lost MY wife...
Ssssh. She's coming!
Where is everyone? I don't know.
I was told someone wanted to see me. We'd better put the lights on.
EVERYONE SINGS # Happy birthday to you.
# Happy birthday dear Ka-ay.
# Happy birthday to you. #
I've got to sweep all this up!
Ann, it's for you, Ann.
- I feel like crying.
- Oh, no!
No speeches here!
Sit down, you're the guest of honour.
- You got the years right.
- We won't tell.
- Make a wish. >
- I'll get the lights.
- Make a wish, but don't tell.
Everyone knows what it is. It's coming true, I can feel it.
She made it!
- I hate to cut it.
- Maybe you can't!
- I resent that. Girls, I've wonderful news!
- Maybe the house is on fire(!)
- I've just talked to Terry Randall. - What's great about that?
< She's going to play the lead part in Anthony Powell's new play.
< I've only been coaching her for a short time.
That's how she got it!
Which play? His new one. "Enchanted April"?
Yes. The part of Jeanette? Yes.
You might change your opinion of Randall now.
Perhaps you'll pay more attention to your training.
Poor kid. We can't even have a party without Randall ruining it.
Randall hasn't harmed anyone.
But she looks ready to start!
Olga's right. But she stole YOUR part.
It wasn't mine. Last year I took a part from someone. This is different.
It isn't different. There's enough pain without our hating each other.
- You're crying.
- Because I'm happy. I've had my moment in the theatre. Terry deserves hers.
Saying something to her won't get me the part. There ARE other plays!
It's my birthday today. The devil with the theatre!
We'll take this scene again. Go ahead.
"Here she is now." "What shall we say to her?"
"She's probably broken-hearted. Let me talk to her."
Miss Randall, this is your cue.
- Are we rehearsing again?
- You're to come in on CUE.
Would you ask those men to stop?
We find we need those men in the theatre, Miss Randall.
If you'd listen and not contradict, you'd get better results.
- Don't be rude.
- Sorry! Do it again.
Alright, don't get excited!
Go ahead.
"She's probably broken-hearted. Let me talk to her."
- FLATLY
- "Hello mother, hello dad.
"The calla lilies are in bloom. A flower suitable for any occasion.
"I carried them for my wedding, now I place them here."
"He needs a thrashing." > "Poor child." >
"Have you come..." There's still something wrong with that line.
- Try reading it correctly.
- It was only a suggestion.
I've written some important plays. One won the Pulitzer prize. Have you written any plays?
- You don't have to be a hen to know a bad egg.
- The play is fine. I'll explain again.
- This woman's husband is leaving, she's broken-hearted.
- You told me to be light and sophisticated.
On the SURFACE. Inside, your heart is broken.
- You smile, but you're crying in your heart.
- How do I do both?
I refuse to watch my play being butchered. Mr Powell,
may I put in MY two-cents' worth? >
I have my Broadway reputation to consider.
- What has that got to do with what we're talking about?
- Miss Randall.
Pay attention to the director.
Well, what am I supposed to do?
- DO AS YOU'RE TOLD.
- Don't yell.
- I AM.
I...I...If I'm so bad, why did you hire me?
Temporary insanity. Now do as you're told!
- I...I...
- DO IT!!
- I'm doing it. The only thing is...
- How long have you coached her?
- A month.
- To get THAT bad in a month!
- I have a suggestion.
- Anything!
Could you see an older woman in the part?
- I've got to get out of this contract. Where's Carmichael?
- He should be here.
- He is, now.
REHEARSALS CONTINUE
- How's it going?
- I want out!
- That's impossible.
- Who is this client? Is he trying to ruin me?
- I don't understand.
- Listen to this.
- Isn't she turning out well?
- She's a rank amateur, as emotional as a fish, and she's a nuisance!
She questions everyone. This play can't be anything but a flop!
- Is that so?
- Are you PLEASED?
- It is my client's money.
- But I'll pay you to let me out of the contract.
- I'm sorry.
Is your client in love with this girl?
- I believe he is.
- Takes all kinds to make a world.
- Mr Powell!
- Coming, coming!
I can't understand him. He tells me to laugh AND cry... I don't know.
That's plain. Now let's get going!
SOFT ROMANTIC MELODY ON THE PIANO
Is my dress fancy enough? For Randall's opening you should wear black.
We got free tickets. To make sure SOMEBODY was there.
"The night was growing old...
..her shoes were full of feet."
- Don't you like my dress?
- Did your mother send it?
- Yes, she makes all my clothes.
- What are these? Pecans?
- Just doo-dads.
- Can I have 35 cents?
- For what?
- Terry's flowers.
- Don't make me laugh.
- Cough up! We need as much as possible.
- I'll give a dollar for her funeral.
- She loves to hate people.
- Keep the change.
- Wait a minute.
- You just love to feud!
We'll be late. We've got to get the flowers. I'm always a spectator.
Cheer up. One day you'll be a sensation.
I'll see you later. You're not coming to the opening?
No, I'll catch the CLOSING.
- D'you WANT her to flop?
- I'd like to SEE it.
- She's sore 'cos Terry took my boyfriend from her.
- Boyfriend?!
- Tired little boyfriend.
- One day, we'll sort this out!
Get me! Ain't I the one?
Will you sew me in? You look very fancy.
- I am.
- You going alone?
- No, I got a beau.
- Who?
- The butcher's helper, once I told him I had FREE passes.
DOORBELL
- That may be him.
- This is your night. I'll get the door.
- Hello.
- Hello. It's raining.
- Is that so?
- It's kinda wet.
- Rain usually is.
- Say, Butch, meet some friends.
- How did you know my name?
- Same way you knew it was raining.
Butch, I want to talk to you.
Next time Hattie visits, could you slip some chicken in with her lamb? Girls, isn't he handsome?
Some people do things like that for others. I think you should, too.
- YOU come and get the meat.
- I will.
I saw you the other day,
and you looked wonderful.
- I won't turn my back on you!
- Butch is great, he's promised us some chicken mixed with lamb.
- I didn't promise.
- Now, Butch! You promised!
I'll do something for you one day.
Butch, you got a friend? He says no!
The..er..."The calla lilies are in bloom again.
"A flower suitable for every occasion...
"I carried them on my wedding day, and now place them here." Cue. "Are you gathered to mourn?..."
- You need rest.
- I can't remember!
Of course you can't. Nobody CAN an hour before curtain time.
- When you put your foot on stage it'll come back.
- Suppose they don't?
- They always do.
- Tea?
- No, I couldn't eat anything.
- I'll leave it here.
"The calla lilies..." I don't KNOW it! "The calla lilies"
are in bloom, bloom, bloom. "Such a strange flower...
"Useful..." When are they useful?
I'll never remember. Kay!
- You should be in bed.
- No.
- It's too exciting.
- But I was coming to see you.
Keep her cheerful, Kay. She's got first-night nerves.
Kay, don't let her do any more rehearsing.
- I'll sit on her.
- It WOULD be raining as well!
If I could get through that first speech. Would you mind watching?
- "The calla lilies are in bloom again..."
- May I make a suggestion?
- I wish you would.
The way you hold the flowers.
I thought Jeanette would hold them like a child.
- They never had a child...
- I see.
- Is that what the author means?
- Yes.
- And when she says "In memory of something that has died"...
- You know this play?
- It's not a play!
It happened to someone I know.
Darling, you mustn't do that.
This is my night, too.
You must give a great performance, no matter what happens.
- Is something the matter?
- I'm just excited. Sit down, I'll get you some tea.
The condemned woman drank a hearty supper.
I felt the same. Like hiding away.
But after that opening speech, it's a thrill that only comes once.
- Is it a thrill or agony?
- It's both.
Come, we'll have to hurry.
It's opening night. Be quick.
- Wish her luck, Kay.
- Wish me luck!
- Goodbye!
- Terry!
Take this. A girl gave it to me last year. It brought me luck.
I wish you were going to be there.
I'll be there, in spirit.
- Are you coming? >
- Well!
PIANO PLAYING SOFTLY
GENTLE SINGING OF ROMANTIC MELODY
GIRLS LEAVING FOR THE SHOW
LISTENING TO IMAGINARY CURTAIN CALL
'Five minutes, Miss Hamilton, five minutes.'
'Ready, Miss Hamilton?'
'Standby, standby.'
'Curtains. Ready, Miss Hamilton? This is your night.'
HEARS TREMENDOUS APPLAUSE
SHOUTS OF 'BRAVO' APPLAUSE GETTING LOUDER
# Just give me a sailboat
# in the moonlight
# and you. # TERRIBLE SCREAM
What was that?
Kay! She jumped before I could stop her. Kay jumped?
She's lying out there.
Car 19. Go to 87 West 58th Street, ambulance call. Girl leaped out window. Possible suicide.
DRAMATIC MUSIC CYMBALS, DRUMS AND TRUMPETS
- Good evening, Mr Powell.
- Good evening.
- Full house?
- They don't know what's in store.
Looks like the boyfriend.
- This is a bad place.
- Why?
- We'll get trampled as they run out.
She isn't responsible for Kay's death.
She is. It was Kay's part, but now it's too late.
- Kay is dead.
- Please.
It's HER fault. She's made out of ice.
- You must leave.
- I'm leaving.
I'll sit out there because Kay asked me to. For every line I'll say, 'That was Kay's line.'
Every move, 'That was Kay's move.'
Kay, who's lying alone in a morgue.
I dare you to go on tonight.
I'm not going on.
- You've got to!
- Why wasn't I told?
I'd have given anything to stop this from happening.
I'm not going on, and I'll tell them why.
- Kay is dead. You had nothing to do with that.
- I killed her.
- There are 50 living people depending on you.
This show may mean as much to them as it meant to Kay. The ushers, the cleaners.
Each one demands that you go on.
- That's theatrical tradition.
- Hang tradition! I'm thinking of Kay.
Then think of Kay. Don't let HER down.
You've GOT to give the performance she wanted. You may bring her peace. KNOCK ON DOOR
< Miss Randall, three minutes to curtain.
All right. We're coming. We're ready.
OVERTURE: SLOW, DRAMATIC VIOLIN MUSIC
Pick an exit. It won't be long now.
"Here she is now." > "What shall we say to her?" > "I don't know." >
"She's probably broken-hearted. I'll talk to her."
- FAINTLY:
- "Hello mother, hello dad.
"The calla lilies are in bloom again.
"Such a strange flower.
"Suitable to any occasion.
"I carried them for my wedding, and place them here in memory of something that has died."
"He needs a good thrashing." > "You poor child." >
"Are you gathered here to mourn,
"or here to bring me comfort?"
"I've learnt something about love that I never knew before." That I never knew before.
You speak of love when it's too late.
Help should come to people when they need it.
- Why are we always so helpful to each other when it's no use?
- "My, darling."
- Those are NOT the lines.
- No, but it's the mood.
This is my home. This is where I belong. Love was in this house once...
..for me, it will always be here.
- "You're not going to see him?"
- "Yes, of course.
"He's coming today to say goodbye."
- FAINTLY:
- To say goodbye.
One should always listen closely when people say goodbye...
..because sometimes, they are really saying farewell.
Listen, I'm at the theatre. Get some photographers over here. This Randall girl's going over big.
Hear the applause...? Wait till I tell you who she is. This is HOT.
"Love comes back to its ancient dwelling."
"The old, old love that we knew of yore."
LOUD APPLAUSE
Terry Randall...Footlights Club!
- Come on!
- Hold it.
- They're calling for you.
- Who is?
- You're a success.
Say something.
VERY LOUD APPLAUSE
I SHOULD thank you on behalf of the company.
I am grateful for your applause. But I must tell you that I don't deserve it.
I'm not responsible for what happened tonight.
The person you should be applauding died a few hours ago.
A young and brilliant actress who could no longer find a spot in the theatre.
It was for HER more than anyone that I was able to go on.
And I hope that wherever she is...
..she knows and understands...
..and forgives.
APPLAUSE
CHEERFUL VIOLIN MUSIC
- Hello.
- Like the show?
- A bit heavy!
- WHAT was that speech all about?
- I don't know. But she's a sensation!
I just found out that that guy with Carmichael is her FATHER. He's Henry Simms, the wheat king.
- Wheat king. What a publicity stunt!
- I'll spread it around. There he is.
Carmichael, why so blue? We've got a hit!
- Exactly(!)
- I never doubted it. Introduce me...
- This is...
- Mr Simms, you didn't fool me.
- This hasn't worked out as I hoped.
- Cheer up! Think of your investment.
Money! I could lose my daughter!
Well, that's the price of success.
Quick, send a basket of flowers to Randall's dressing room.
- With wheat in it?
- Never mind that! Ellsworth, just the man I wanted.
- I put one over, didn't I?
- The wheat king's daughter?
- Yes.
- That's not important.
- I know.
- She has a strange quality. Like that girl you brought out last year.
- Oh, Hamilton?
- Yes, Kay Hamilton.
- Where's she now?
- Oh, she's around. Don't forget Randall is ANOTHER Anthony Powell 'discovery'.
My dear, you'll never know how good you were. You were simply wonderful.
That wasn't ME. It was someone else.
WE have to suffer to make the audience feel with us.
Does someone have to DIE? Is that what the theatre demands?
It takes heart-break as well as grease paint to make an actress.
DOOR OPENS
Don't try to say anything. We'll go to her.
- Where are you going?
- To see Kay.
But you can't. There are people to see. You're an actress now.
KNOCK ON DOOR
- You see them for me.
- But...
- <
- Hello?
Coming, coming.
Well, where's Miss Randall?
- She's gone.
- Gone? I've got an office full of people and photographers.
- Why didn't you keep her here?
- She had an important engagement.
- What about her CAREER?
- It isn't my fault.
- I build a star overnight and she runs out on me! Can you believe it?
- What about these?
- Oh, get them out of here.
Wait a minute.
Imagine! Take a woman out of a wheat-field and make her a star. Opening night! That's gratitude!
I spend time and effort... ..and they run out on you!
MELANCHOLY VIOLIN MUSIC
DRAMATIC CHANGE TO BRIGHT CHEERFUL MUSIC
# La-la-la-de-de-de-de te-te-te-la-la-la-la-de-de #
It may be a mistake. I'll never trust males again.
- What's wrong?
- Henry's in hospital.
- An accident?
- He's just had kittens.
- Well, change HIS name to HENRIETTA.
I'm completely discouraged.
It's a miracle! Mary Lou's got a part!
- Where?
- Bergen's new show. I'm so thrilled I could scream!
Read your part. Well, I'm supposed to be from the South, and I say:
- "Let's go up to Westchester."
- Go on.
- That's it.
- That's it?
Well, you should say: "Let's go UP to Westchester."
That's all wrong - "Let's go up to WESTCHESTER."
GIRLS IN UNISON
- "Let's go up to Westchester."
Hey, here comes that blushing bride! GIRLS APPLAUD
# Here comes the bride. #
Goodbye everyone. I've got to go.
Thanks for everything. If any of you hams are in Seattle, the house of Millbank welcomes you.
- I thought you lived in trees.
- Only in the summer(!)
She'll be right there!
Well, goodbye everybody. Now I'm going, I feel like crying.
Hey, it's your first job in a YEAR!
- Cheer up. We're all coming to your anniversary. Heave!
- # Here goes the bride... #
- On with you!
- Back to Seattle.
Why she hated to go is a mystery!
I know how she feels. This place is my HOME.
At least she'll have kids to keep HER company. What will WE have? Only old photographs and memories.
We're probably a different race.
Maybe. Tonight I feel like sitting with someone in the moonlight.
Good evening. Who do I see about accommodation?
Mrs Orcutt! She'll take care of you. Come in.
- Hello? Hello, Bill.
- Don't be sentimental, you're a ham at heart!
No, that was a friend of mine.
- How's your new job?
- Can I give a message to your 'late' Aunt Susan?
- Hold on. No, no message.
- I don't use BAD language (!)
- Just asking.
Fancy taking an old hag out?...
It's a feature of the Club. It's the chair Bernhardt sat in. I was in the company.
You'll like it here. We're one happy family!
Subtitles by Red Bee Media Ltd