It's raining, Lakshmi.
Keep the certificates safe.
It's midnight now.
We can't get autos aIso.
Let's spend the night somewhere
and go in the morning.
You didn't have Iunch.
I'II get you something to eat.
What wouId you get at this hour?
I may get bread & biscuit
from any tea shop.
I'II get it. Lock the door.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Come on.
- PoIice...hide or run away.
There is someone in this room too.
Open the door.
I'm not such a kind of girI.
- I hear such stories everyday.
PIease Ieave me.
- Get in to the bus.
Lakshmi...
I & my daughter came here to attend
an interview & stayed in a Iodge.
I was toId that you had
taken away my daughter.
Where is my daughter?
The girI in yeIIow dress?
-Yes.
I knew it.
Ameerpet AbbuIu got baiI for everyone
and took them with him.
She might be in the 3rd house
in the next street. Go.
I got her just now.
She is new to this.
My boss wiII teach her everything.
Take this & get her ready.
I'II take her in the morning.
Lakshmi...
Where are you my dear?
- Father...
I'm here. Don't cry, my dear.
-Who are you?
We are from Ananthapur.
She has to attend an interview
tomorrow morning.
So? A man has booked her
for Rs. 10000.
We are not such kind of peopIe.
- But we are.
I beg you. PIease Ieave her.
- Take her inside.
PIease. I beg you.
- Come here.
Take her away.
PIease Ieave us. I beg you.
Leave them.
Have you come to meet StaIin?
-Yes.
He is my son's friend.
We must go to his house tomorrow morning
and then to the interview.
Why didn't you teII me this before?
A IittIe deIay couId've taken my Iife.
Sorry. Forgive me.
Forgive me sister.
Auto...
Don't teII anything to StaIin.
Forgive me. Forgive me sister.
Leave them & coIIect money from me.
BIow...
If you drink, I wiII kiII you.
Go fast.
Thank you sir.
I paid money & booked that girI
and now you say she is gone.
Where is she?
Why haven't you eaten anything?
C'mon eat.
What's time of your interview?
2 pm.
It's her.
Eat. I wiII wait. Eat weII.
Who are you guys?
Why did you come here?
We booked herfor our boss.
Booked her?
We paid advance money too.
Here is Rs. 5000.
Who shouId I give it to?
Do you know to whose house
you've come now?
No point in taIking to you. Come.
PIease Ieave her.
- Come.
Get Iost you oId man.
- Stop.
Narayana, Ieave her.
You sit in the car.
StaIin Iives here.
Even Iightning & thunders think
twice before coming here.
If you have guts, and
if you are a reaI man, take this girI,
try crossing this road. Go.
Go & sit in their car.
I'm StaIin's motherteIIing you.
Go & sit.
StaIin is bravery...
StaIin is war of justice...
StaIin is courage...
Did you get hurt?
- No.
Ask this question to those idiots
and not my son.
Thank you very much.
- It's okay.
You don't have to worry. Be brave.
- Okay son.
Come, Iet's go inside.
-Wait. Let me ward of aII eviI eyes.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Fear has fIed...
Sing & dance...
Victory is ours...
Have courage...
Pack your punch aII the power...
Knock out the eviI in one punch...
- Come as a soIdier...
We, your army saIute you.
A soIdier is born from men Iike you.
And I'II be his servant.
Our heart and souI is forthe country...
We unite forthe nation
and saIute you...
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Lord Ram's arrow is yourthought...
Demon Ravana is the eviI in you...
Lord Hanuman is your patience...
Your reaI enemy is your anger...
Destroy eviI...
Have patience & kiII your anger...
Step forward & demoIish injustice...
We beIieve in you & waIk in yourfootsteps...
Let faith be your weapon...
HeIp yourfriends...
And you wiII be bIessed...
Donate eyes, and Iive twice...
Like our parents who give
us everything...
Donate bIood, you'II become
Iike motherto the donor...
WaIk taII with head heId high...
Break the back of eviI...
Where do you get this strength from?
From miIIions of my friends
sitting before the siIver screen...
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
I can't see any name caIIed
StaIin in this aImanac.
What?
I can see. But the pIace & pIanets
can't see him.
To heII with you and your astroIogy.
You can't be bIamed.
My son's fauIt.
He agreed to marry
when he was in the army.
He's refusing to marry after coming here.
He has gone to send her off.
When he comes home,
teII him that if he doesn't marry,
convince him that his
mother's Iife is in danger.
I can convince him in no time.
But it wouId cost you more.
I wiII give you.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
What's aII this stuff?
- It's Vasantha.
She's good match to you.
Look! -What?
Don't get angry.
If you don't marry soon,
your mother's Iife is in danger.
and your mothertoId me this...
No. AstroIogy is saying it.
Your horoscope confirms it.
How's my performance?
This astroIoger is no ordinary man.
Whatever he says wiII sureIy happen.
You be here. I wiII get yourfees.
AIong with the money,
don't forget otherthings.- I'II not.
She keeps up her word.
No one in my area has the guts
to bring marriage proposaIs for me.
How couId you do that?
I'm not from this area.
Getting smart with me?
No.-Why?
I can't breathe.
What wiII happen?
- I may die.
If you don't stop this now,
it wiII happen for sure.
No one in this worId can ever stop me.
No one can stop me...
may be you can.
I don't think you wiII give me
that opportunity.
You wiII stop yourseIf.
Where are you going?
TeII me what you're thinking about.
I'm reaIIy tensed.
Why did you mask herface?
My mother did it.
Why did she mask herface?
Remove it.
If you have the guts, remove it.
Do I need guts to remove it, ah?
Mother, he is removing the mask.
Priest!
I don't want to see herface.
- He has pasted it.
How dare you mask my face
instead of hers'?
I wiII kiII you.
I wiII hack you to death.
Enough mother. Don't get tensed.
ActuaIIy I've a weakness.
If I don't cIear my doubts immediateIy,
my head wiII break into pieces.
Die then.
My head wiII break into pieces.
TeII me who she is.
I won't teII you that
she is my daughter.
She is not my daughter.
Arrest him first.
Stop it mother.
What are you thinking?
Arrest him.
They feII in Iove & married.
It's betteryou bIess them.
Why shouId I bIess them?
Shut up.
You stupid girI!
If you marry him,
you can onIy do Bhangra dance.
Stop bIabbering.
- CooI down Jhansi.
WiII you send her out,
or shouId I handIe the situation?
What wiII you do? Beat me?
I fed you with so much Iove
that you've grown so fat.
What wiII you do?
- Listen to me.
Beat me.
- Lets go home.
She is very arrogant.
Where did he go?
What are you doing there?
Be carefuI.
I warned them. Let's go.
How dare she...! FaIIing in Iove!
You have hurt me so much that
you wiII never Iive happiIy.
Mother, pIease come.
- I must kiII them both.
Mother pIease...
Oh my God! Such a big story!
If you couId name your son as StaIin,
a foreigner's name,
can't you accept your son-in-Iaw
from a neighbouring state?
It was my husband who named
him as StaIin.
Communist Ieader.
Is yours a Communist famiIy?
I didn't know that yourfamiIy
is so powerfuI.
Now that you know,
do not enter our house again.
You got me into this matter and
made your mother scoId me.
I'm a Brahmin.
I've moIe on my tongue.
Whatever I say wiII happen.
You'II get a daughter-in-Iaw
who wiII grind you.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Hi mummy!
Why is your hair wet?
I stood first in the swimming competition.
No one can defeat you.
Forgot me? Mummy, Iook at my cup.
Idiot! In which shop did you buy this?
The shop next to the shop
where you bought this.
CooI down.
I stood first in the dance competition.
None of my achievements are
recognized in this house.
I wiII go to Jhansi sister's house.
Hi IittIe rat!
How many times to teII you that
my name is Harbajan Singh?
CaII me Harbajan Singh.
But I wiII caII you LittIe Rat.
What is that cup for?
I stood first in the swimming competition.
ReaIIy? CongratuIations.
I wanted to ask you something
for a very Iong time.
Who is the Iady in that photo?
Mind your work.
Jhansi, where are my car keys?
I kept it on the draw.
- Okay Iisten...
Who is this boy?
Him? Just touch him.
Most powerfuI.
Touch him & you wiII get eIectrocuted.
Greetings madam.
- Greetings.
Come madam.
Greetings madam.
- Greetings madam.
You can check.
- Okay madam
What is he doing in a women's coIIege?
Look who is sitting next to him.
She used to top the cIass.
But Iost both her hands
in an accident.
Since then, he is writing
her exams as she teIIs.
Look there Madam.
Not onIy her, he writes for
that bIind girI too.
What if both have exams on the same day?
It never happened Iike that tiII now.
Sirisha, give me that paper.
Give it to him after he compIetes
writing the exam.
What shouId I teII him?
TeII him that his sister gave it.
Chitra, pick up the phone.
Mummy, this is Harbajan speaking.
This phone is temporariIy not working.
Shit! She's a headache to me aIways.
What?
There is a deviI named Chitra
Iiving in our next house.
But she aIways stays in our house.
She is arrogant.
AIways teases me caIIing me LittIe Rat.
Why LittIe Rat?
- It's a big fIash back.
FIash back at this young age...?
One day, I was in the
shower & she came.
Then?
Opened the door aII of a sudden.
- Then?
And saw it.
Ever since then, she caIIs me LittIe Rat.
I don't know why she is
caIIing me Iike that.
I'm not that matured.
I've understood.
LittIe Rat is nothing but...
Leave your probIem to me.
I wiII handIe it.
What's her name?
Chitra. Teach her a Iesson.
- Keep watching.
I'm Jhansi's brother speaking.
WiII you pIease caII my sister?
Who is that?
Your brother.
TeII that I wiII caII him back in 10 minutes.
She wiII caII you back in 10 minutes.
Who are you?
I'm Chitra, your sister's friend.
HeIIo Chitra aunt.
When did you come from Dubai?
How are your chiIdren?
Just because I'm your sister's friend,
it doesn't mean I'm of her age.
Trying to know how I wiII Iook Iike?
I know, aunt.
You are bIack, short, fat...
- Shit!
EIderIy peopIe caII me
Goddess MahaIakshmi.
Young men caII me Superfigure.
What do Road Romeos caII you?
A nice chic?
Okay. Let's not fight anymore.
Since you're my sister's friend,
you're my friend too.
ShaII we pIay a game?
- Game?
Game of coIor astroIogy.
What does that mean?
I wiII teII you the coIor of your dress.
If I am right, friendship wiII
bIoom between us.
Can't teII you where it might go in future?
We must become friends first.
TeII me the coIor of my dress.
No. I'm wearing red coIor dress.
Look again.
Your dress is yeIIow.
BangIes & ear rings are aIso yeIIow.
To make it more cIear,
from top to bottom, even your
inner wear is yeIIow. Am I right?
No. Nothing matched.
She wiII never interfere in
your matter again.
What do you want?
Daddy!
-What do you want I say?
I want to go to toiIet.
If I take you there,
girIs wiII think that I'm married.
It might mar my image.
Come, I'II take you dear.
If you don't mind,
wiII you take herto the toiIet?
Aunt, same pinch.
What for?
We both are wearing the
same coIoured panty.
Thank you.
Aunt...same pinch.
What forthat?
She said it because we both are girIs.
- No.
We both are wearing the
same coIoured panty.
Thank you.
Sumathi, who are you waiting for?
Do you aIso have exam today?
-Yes sir.
Same time.
-Yes.
She has Chemistry practicaI.
How can I write your exam?
I know that.
That's why I've asked
my uncIe to come here.
Swati's practicaI exam is more important.
You must be with her.
Okay & good Iuck.
Sumathi, phone foryou.
What are you saying?
I met with an accident whiIe coming.
I can't come forthe exam.
This is my pubIic exam, uncIe.
TaIk to principaI & arrange someone
to write the exam foryou.
Okay.
Where are you going?
- I want to meet him.
Exam is going on.
You can't go inside.
It's about my Iife.
- No way.
PIease sir.
OnIy 5 more minutes
Ieft forthe exams to start.
I'm heIpIess.
CoIIege staff is not aIIowed
to write the exam.
Do one thing.
Seek externaI heIp.
I wiII permit you.
I'm doing my Inter 2nd year
in this coIIege.
Today is my pubIic exam.
Spend 3 hours & write my exam.
Do you think I don't have any work?
I'm aIready Iate to office. Go.
AtIeast you heIp me sir.
Why are you irritating?
Are we here to write your exams?
Go and find someone eIse.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Sorry Sumathi. I can't heIp you.
By Iooking at the anaIysis,
you'II get fuII marks.
Excuse me for a minute.
She is a cIever student.
She used to score 90%.
She jumped infront of my eyes.
She begged so many peopIe.
But no one came forward to heIp her.
That's why she committed suicide.
Any Iove faiIure?
It must be Iove faiIure.
She is a coIIege student, isn't she?
Does it Iook Iike a Iove affair?
RascaI!
She begged so many peopIe
to write the exam.
But no one came forward.
But now passing sarcastic comments!
How couId you say that?
Go to office at 9 am and
come home at 6 pm
and get gIued to the TV.
You're onIy concerned
about yourfamiIy.
You neverthink about others.
You won't find time to heIp others.
But you wiII find time
to watch such things.
Shame on your part!
Though she Iost her both
hands in an accident,
She never committed suicide.
Do you know why?
She beIieved that peopIe
around wiII heIp her.
But today, we broke her
trust & kiIIed her.
We aII kiIIed her.
What happened?
100 meters race for physicaIIy
chaIIenged chiIdren is about to start.
Give them a big hand and
encourage these chiIdren.
You wiII get drenched in the rain.
You be here. I wiII be back soon.
Make it fast. My baby is in the car.
- Okay madam.
Take the auto...move.
Tow this carto the poIice station.
Where is my car?
Where is my baby?
Traffic poIice towed your car away.
My baby was in the car which
you towed from the Big Bazaar.
Baby in the car?
Your car is overthere.
- Lets go.- Come.
My baby...my car.
That's my car.
My baby. Open it fast.
Take this.
My baby is missing.
Where is my baby?
Get Iost.
-What happened?
I feeI very shy.
-Why do you feeI shy?
I saw Aishwarya Rai in
my dream Iast night...
Dream...?
She garIanded me.
- Think again
Were you standing or Iying down
with a Iamp behind your head.
You aIways tease me.
He is teasing me, brother.
StiII thinking about those schooI chiIdren?
Those chiIdren wanted to heIp each other.
That's a great thing.
They have no choice.
They must heIp each other.
They are physicaIIy chaIIenged chiIdren.
They are not handicapped.
PeopIe with good heaIth & who don't heIp
others are the reaI handicapped.
The girI begged many
to write her exam.
No one came forward.
- Forget it.
PeopIe don't think of heIping others.
PeopIe do think of heIping others
but probIem they neverfoIIow it.
We must make peopIe each other.
-Yes, you're right.
Have you heIped anyone before?
ActuaIIy...
Fine. How many peopIe
can you heIp in future?
50 to 150 peopIe.
- No need.
Just heIp 3 peopIe.
We can change the worId.
Oh reaIIy! How is that possibIe?
It is possibIe.
That's me.
I wiII heIp 3 peopIe.
And I'II ask each one of them to
heIp 3 more as thanks to me.
As this chain grows,
everyone wiII try to heIp 3 peopIe.
When we heIp a stranger,
he wiII aIso be inspired
to heIp another stranger.
It isn't god who heIps us.
PeopIe must heIp each other.
God never invented current or buIb.
It was the man who invented
everything in this worId.
I beIieve in nothing is impossibIe.
Whose baby is that?
We both went to Big bazaaryesterday.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
I gave the car number in the
RTO office to know the address.
I may get a phone caII at anytime.
From RTO office.
Yes.
Address...?
Where is the address?
- KukatpaIIi.
Let us start our heIping
concept with this baby.
Don't cry baby.
Mother, we have got back our baby.
This baby was born after
7 years of marriage.
If anything had happened to her,
we wouId've aII died.
Your heIp can't be repaid
with just a thanks.
But stiII I must thank you forthe heIp.
Mere thanks aIone wiII not do.
What do you want, teII me?
There are many peopIe around us
who need heIp from others.
HeIp 3 peopIe.
And teII each one of them
to heIp 3 more.
That's aII.
A very nobIe thought.
He wiII sureIy heIp.
I wiII do it.
- Nice meeting you.
Bye.
- Bye.
They are so happy that I think
your dream wiII certainIy come true.
Look at this girI.
She is Maheshwari.
She stood 2nd in weightIifting
by Iifting 200 kgs.
We don't want her even
if she had won 1st prize.
I can't find a perfect bride
foryour son.
We must caII the Lord Brahma,
the creatorto send a perfect girI.
Find a suitabIe girI for my son.
For his styIe...
Find a girI Iike her.
Your photos are useIess.
Wait. I wiII bring you a coffee.
I don't know if you can
find a perfect bride or not.
But I'm tired of serving you coffees.
- I can drink coffee at anytime.
Look at her.
She Iooks very beautifuI.
Your son is her perfect match.
She has even put an ad
seeking groom. Take a Iook.
I want a bride Iike her.
Imagine your son with that girI...
Stop it. Back to 1955.
Imagine about them in the Iatest trend.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
He must be a sIave to me...
Your desires are outrageous...
AII your imaginations wiII go kaput...
Look at my shaking a Ieg...
Look at my styIe...
Give me a vent to reIease
my hot passions...
If you need it, I'II do it...
If youryouth wants to fight me,
I'm ready to take on you...
You wanna my Iove,
come to me...
No need to ask me,
start off instantIy...
I want you, take me into
the bIiss of darkness...
I'm waiting foryour move...
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
You're making inviting gestures
and raking up passions in me...
If you make the move,
it's tiresome to me...
You're ravishing...
you're deIicious...
I'II fuIfiII aII your desires...
Don't rush into it,
it'II dampen the spirit...
Let's enjoy Iife in high spirits...
I'II tame your wiId dreams...
If I Iose myseIf in your beauty,
I'II fight out to freedom...
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
You don't have the courage to
cross the borders of decency...
I'm ready to jump fence
if you make the first move...
Don't tempt me and
ignite my passions...
If I faII to temptation,
you're finished...
Don't throw tantrums,
I've seen many Iike you...
If you give your Iips,
I'II put my stamp of Iove on it...
If you stiII want,
I'II caress you with my Iove...
Hey you...why are you dancing?
She is the perfect match to my son.
I wiII get your commission.
- Okay madam.
Thank god! I found a girI
after a Iong time.
What is it? Back again?
-Just came to meet her.
Hey Gopi, take a Iook at
your sister-in-Iaw's photo.
Where is it? Show it to him.
Take your hand.
She is the perfect bride to my son.
She's very beautifuI.
Sister-in-Iaw! Let me aIso see her.
Is she my sister-in-Iaw?
Just a minute.
Look at this now.
She is with someone eIse.
It means she is aIready married.
How dare you chose
a married woman to my son?
I wiII...
Where did he go?
AIong with him,
he took away your money too.
Stop crying, Sirisha.
Stop crying Iike a chiId.
What happened?
Wait for me. I wiII come.
Why is she crying?
That's her personaI matter.
You go.
I said go.
Stop crying.
Did he teII his name?
- No.
Like everyday, he caIIs on
phone and speaks fiIthy.
He wrote my phone number
in the pubIic toiIet,
with a caption ''caII this number
for caII girIs''.
We Iove each other.
We convinced our parents & have
arranged the marriage too.
If my parents come to know about this,
our marriage may get canceIIed.
Why did you come here?
I toId you to stay downstairs.
Looks Iike I must settIe this matter.
TeII me.
He teIIs correctIy even the moIes on my body.
Not onIy that, he insists on
spending a night with him.
It is him.
Speak.
Don't get scared. Speak.
It's him again.
Speaking badIy.
Keep taIking.
Do not cut the phone at any cost.
Who are you?
What do you want?
Yes brother.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
What have you decided?
Who are you?
It's your brother...
Your probIem is soIved now.
He is ourfamiIy doctor.
-A doctor?
Doctor! Aren't you ashamed of yourseIf?
When your patient is unconscious,
you must check her heart beat
and the puIse rate.
Not the moIes on her body.
If I don't get your doctor's Iicense
canceIIed in 24 hours,
I wiII sIit yourthroat.
You don't have to worry anymore.
Be happy.
I was tensed of Iosing my Iove.
But you heIped me at the right time.
I don't know how to thank you.
- That's okay.
What did you say now?
- I said thanks.
I don't need yourthanks.
HeIp 3 peopIe & ask each one
of them to heIp 3 more.
That's enough.
- Sure sir.
StaIin, your sister wiII come in 10 minutes.
Come & sit in our house.
It's okay. PIease come in.
PIease sit. I wiII get you a coffee.
- Okay.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Switch to V channeI.
I said switch to V channeI.
Move.
Switch to MTV.
Increase the voIume.
Where are you going?
Why are you covering it?
What's your probIem.
Why are you so jeaIous?
Sister...
Enjoying music?
-Yeah.
Open your eyes & see.
You wiII enjoy it more.
What more wiII I enjoy?
She is mad.
Why are you Iaughing?
Give it to me.
You...in the theatre...
Yes. Theatre...the IittIe girI...same pinch.
So, it is your house, ah?
Do you know what reaIIy had happened?
Why are you asking my brotherto shut up?
Have you met before?
We met in the theatre...a IittIe girI...
-What happened?
A IittIe girI wanted to go to the toiIet...
- Is it very important?
Go inside.
So, it was you the coIor astroIogist!
Bye Chitra.
Leaving so soon.
It's time my son returns
from schooI. Bye.
Jhansi, what is your brother doing?
He was in the army.
Is he not in the army now?
- No
May be he got scared & Ieft!
How couId you say that?
- I was just joking.
What wouId they think about you?
I was just joking.
-ApoIogize to them.
I'm sorry, sister.
I didn't mean it. I was just joking.
I'm reaIIy sorry.
This was the first time
I am seeing you so angry.
What was he in the army?
Do you know who he is?
Indian Army Major.
Major StaIin.
Sir, StaIin Reporting.
-What happened?
They suddenIy attacked us.
I take charge.
Major StaIin moving, sir.
Stop this damn it.
- Listen to me.
We've to stop this.
- No sir.
We cannot go.
- Do not stop this, sir.
They are in an advantage position.
We can't Iose any more of our soIdiers.
I won't make their sacrifices go futiIe.
Their sacrifices shouIdn't go waste.
I'm very sorry, sir.
- StaIin...
What do you mean by this?
Yes, I gave this order purposefuIIy
What was my fauIt?
Why have you put me in charge
of administrative department?
What wiII I do there?
For insubordination,
I've taken this decision.
That's aII.
Sorry sir.
If StaIin hadn't taken such
a decision that day,
the situation wouId've
been different.
You're jeaIous of StaIin
and his popuIarity.
Mind your Ianguage, Captain.
- Sorry sir.
I am ready to sacrifice
my Iife forthis nation.
If I don't have that opportunity,
it's betterto quit.
Sorry sir.
As you said, my brother didn't
quit army in fear.
He resigned.
He finds happiness in others'.
Even now, he wants everyone
to heIp one another.
He started the ''HeIp 3'' movement,
and wants to change this society.
He saved two Iovers who were
about to commit suicide,
and performed their marriage.
When they thanked him,
he refused to accept it.
Instead, he asked them to heIp 3 peopIe
and in turn ask them to heIp 3 more.
Chitra, now have you understood
what my brother is.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
O Maiden! Are you the reincarnation
of ceIestiaI Gopika?
O Mr. Andhra! Are you the
Prince Charming to many Princesses?
I can't refuse your invitation...
I can't stop myseIf
from inviting you...
Touch the sky...
Got high voItage Iove eIectrocuted...
I got myseIf hijacked...
I was your madness...
I went to Vizag...
Got a remedy foryou...
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Understand the reIationship
of partnership...
AII your dreams wiII
come true easiIy...
If you ask for it on your own...
Though you deserve it,
you'II be considered cheap...
After meeting in my dream...
My youth is rebeIIing against me
after seeing your manIiness...
After seeing you...
I feII in Iove with you...
I embraced you...
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Read the signaIs emitting
from my body desiring you...
You'II go crazy after having
the taste of my Iove...
My siIk doII!
May I marry you?
May I make my eyes your home?
I desired you...
I came to you...
Ijumped the fence...
Stop. I wiII kiII you.
Move away.
-What happened?
You move away.
-What happened? TeII me.
He said he didn't have money
to buy bus ticket.
I gave him Rs. 10.
He went away without saying thanks.
WiII you hit him if
he doesn't say thanks, ah?
Hit him.
- I reaIIy don't want to hit him.
If he had thanked me,
I wouId've asked him
to heIp 3 persons.
But he didn't thank me.
If he didn't thank you, it means your
heIp wasn't thankabIe.
The other day, that girI's famiIy
thanked him so much.
He never expected it from them.
Whateveryou may say,
he is no different from them.
He took money & said nothing.
They took heIp & thanked you
and wouId've done nothing.
They wouIdn't have heIped anyone.
What do you want to say?
PeopIe are ungratefuI.
Do not taIk bad about peopIe.
The good work we started
wouId've taken deep roots.
We too want it to spread
aII overthe country.
But I don't trust these peopIe.
But I trust them.
Let's meet them right now. Come.
Take your car.
They wouId come if we
knock the door hard.-Who is it?
Greetings.
- StaIin!
Are you fine.
-Yes, thank you.
PIease come inside.
What wouId you Iike to have?
Nothing.
Your son...?
Do you want to taIk to my son?
The other day, I toId your son
to heIp 3 peopIe.
I came here to know
who he had heIped.
AII these days he was busy
getting his passport & visa.
He went to Canada just 10 days back.
I'm a software engineer.
I've 6 senior officers supervising me.
200 peopIe work under me.
24 hours work tension.
I can't do sociaI work Ieaving the job.
I don't have so much Ieisure time either.
Have you heIped anyone...?
- Stop asking such stupid questions.
I neither have a good job
nor peopIe work under me.
I'm more worried about
canceIIation of honeymoon.
And you are taIking
about heIping others?
You are right.
He doesn't even have time to eat.
How couId he find time to heIp others?
If you want any personaI heIp,
I wiII sureIy do it.
I wiII give you Rs. 5000.
You heIp someone with that money.
Bye sir.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Don't worry.
It was a good idea.
Tried to impIement it.
But faiIed.
That's their iII fate.
What if they don't heIp?
I wiII heIp.
We wiII do it foryou.
Sir, give me a rupee pIease.
- Go...
I'm very hungry.
Give me a rupee.
PIease sir.
- Stop bugging me.
Get up.
You are bIeeding.
Is it painfuI?
Get down.
-Who are you?
Get down, you rascaI.
How dare you?
-What did I do?
Drinking & driving is wrong.
But begging isn't.
HeIp if you can.
But you have no right to hurt her.
- Stop it.
HeIp someone
Why do you Iive a useIess Iife?
RascaI.
I wiII kiII you.
Leave me.
They don't heIp others.
Such peopIe must be hacked to death.
It's him.
Stop brother.
PIease Iisten to me.
Leave it.
Do you want me to keep quiet?
What eIse can we do?
You heIped 3 peopIe and
expected them to heIp 3 more.
But aII your efforts went in vain.
And now you hit a guy
Look at the consequences.
Poison spreads fasterthan medicine.
Leave it here.
Yes.
We want your good work to grow.
Let's forget everything.
Let's think that we met
with an accident.
Priya darIing, where are you?
It's getting Iate forthe show.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Hari, the guy who hit me on that
day is now in Hyderabad Centre.
Come here in 5 minutes.
I wiII wait here.
But come in 5 minutes.
Finished?
- He is getting Iate for his tuition cIass.
But we haven't got the biII.
- I wiII drop him.
PIease.
- Okay.
Bye.
- Let's go.
Where is he?
Can't you come an hour Iater?
He is gone.
If you had come immediateIy,
you couId've got him.
You said he was here with his famiIy.
There they are.
It's very hard to find him in this city.
Instead of we finding him,
I'II make him to find us.
Now a days you don't eat properIy.
- Enough.
You eat. I wiII bring it.
You forgot the phone at home.
It has been ringing since evening.
I don't know how to operate it.
HeIIo sister...
- StaIin...
Greetings MLA sir.
Ameerpet KishenIaI's son got invoIved
in a skirmish & I went to soIve it.
One man is chasing to beat me.
What shouId I do now?
Where are you now?
- Near Lakdi-ka-pooI.
Okay.
Go to my party office there.
No one wiII dare to step in.
- Okay sir.
ConstabIe, take the jeep.
Prakash...Kishore...where are you?
Rasik...where are you?
No.
Someone has cut our partyman's hand.
Don't spare him. KiII him.
How dare he?
Don't spare him. Finish him off.
Nothing happened in my party office.
Send him out.
Sir, he cut your man's hand infront of me.
I said nothing had happened, right?
ReIease him.
If anything happens in the station,
we both wiII be in troubIe.
I'm in poIitics forthe past 20 years.
I know what to do,
when & where to do.
I'm waiting outside.
Send him out.
No case has been fiIed against you.
You are free to go.
Cutting his hand is not wrong.
But you did that in the wrong pIace.
You cut my man's hand
in my party office.
Do you know my power?
You've come with 100's of
henchmen for a Ione man.
I can understand what your power is!
How dare you!
You dared put your hand on my chest.
Don't you know my power.
Eat what you want.
FuIfiII aII your desires.
See anything you want to see.
Tomorrow by 4 pm, no one in
yourfamiIy wiII be aIive.
Got it?
You have come with so many men for me.
I had kiIIed 100's of Pakistani soIdiers.
Betteryou know that.
It's foryour good I'm saying.
If you send your men at 4 pm,
you wiII feeI foryour biggest
mistake of your Iife at 4:10 pm.
If you stiII insist, go ahead.
What shaII we do now?
Come to my house with
your husband & chiId.
Your mom Iives there.
I won't come.
My mother?
You're her daughtertoo.
Don't forget that.
But I was born premature in 8 months.
Is that why she aIways says
you are premature.
If that is so, come to Ameerpet
bus stand at 3:30 tomorrow.
Where are we going?
To take an insurance poIicy on you.
Do you think that I wiII die soon?
Just because you speak Iike this,
my sister went away.
Sister...?
-Yes sister.
There she is.
Go.
Think of the deviI & the deviI is here.
-Yes.
Shit!
I wiII ring the beII.
ShaII we get down?
Why?
We got into the bus first.
Let her get down if she wants to.
- Okay.
Shit!
MaIIesh is in the bus! We wiII ask him.
-You go.
FoIIowing me!
Everyone is here.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Why is she coming after us?
ShameIess!
Yes. You are right.
Mother, get into the Iift.
You aIso get into the Iift.
There are too many in the Iift.
I'II take the steps.
He is here.
Come, Iet's pIay.
Move...
Wow!
How did you cIimb 6 fIoors in 30 seconds?
It's aII the magic of mother's miIk.
And some drink tinned miIk.
They grow physicaIIy not mentaIIy.
It's my iII fate that
I came with you in the Iift.
My iII fate too.
Come, Iet's go.
The job is over.
- So fast?
An errand is stiII pending.
I wiII deaI with it.
MaIIesh...Lakshmana..
How did he come inside?
Where are you guys?
Why are you shouting?
They won't come.
They aII are getting treatment.
It's might take a month
to get discharged.
I warned you once that
you can do nothing.
Now I've come to your house
to warn you again.
You can do nothing.
How dare you taIk Iike
that in front of me?
Ask your husband.
He wiII teII you.
It's a wife's duty to correct
her husband if he's wrong.
There is saying that
''Behind every successfuI man there's a woman''.
Likewise seeing you reminds me,
''Behind every idiot there is a woman too''.
Do you know who my father is?
Don't you know it yourseIf?
Keep your husband in controI.
Be carefuI.
PIease don't caII yourfather.
Why bIow up this smaII issue?
- This is not a smaII issue. Stop it.
What wiII you do?
When I said ''do you know my father''
he said ''Don't you know it yourseIf?''
infront of everyone.
I won't spare him.
Madam's phone.
- Madam?
Phone foryourfather?
-Who is it?
Your sister. She is very tensed.
Father...
Sister is on Iine.
What is it, dear?
Don't get tensed for a siIIy thing, dear.
I'm going to DeIhi.
I'II handIe him as soon as
I come back.
Give the phone to your husband.
You useIess!
You are unfit to be a ward member.
I got my daughter married to you.
I made you an MLA as dowry gift.
You must take good care
of my daughter, right?
But you kept quiet when some
guy shouted at her.
It's not enough if you have
gunmen around you.
You must be my daughter's gunman.
If you don't, I wiII get you kiIIed
with your own gunmen.
Give the phone to her
He insuIted me infront of everyone.
I won't Iive in this house.
Come here.
Didn't I teII you that I wiII handIe him
after coming back from DeIhi?
Why are you stiII worried?
You go home. I wiII handIe him.
UntiI you don't teII me
what you wiII do with him,
I won't move from here.
Draw a circIe around that dog.
Do it.
That dog does what we say.
After returning from DeIhi, I'II make him
stand in that circIe Iike a dog.
It's up to you then.
What do you say?
You took money from Sait.
Who wiII pay the dues?
Aren't you ashamed?
I couIdn't pay the due because
of my marriage.
I'II pay both the dues next month.
We have come to the tempIe
forthe first time.
PIease do not take the bike.
If you know to marry,
don't you know to pay the dues?
Just for one month, pIease.
- Excuse me.
Any probIem?
We took money to buy the bike.
Because of our marriage,
we couIdn't pay the dues.
We promise to pay both the dues next month,
but they don't Iisten to us.
This is the first time we have come
to the tempIe after marriage.
They want to take the bike.
He has come to tempIe with wife for
the first time. Why troubIe them?
Give us our money and
go anywhere they Iike.
Do you have Sait's visiting card?
- Take it.
These are my bike keys.
Take mine. I'II pay the dues
and wiII take my bike.
Give me those keys.
Why troubIe yourseIf for us?
- It's aIright.
I'II go in my friend's bike.
Take my bike. It's aIso new.
Anyway, we got a bike.
We don't know who you are.
But you heIped us a Iot.
Give us your address.
I'II bring back your bike.
I'II neither give my address
nor my name.
But my heIp shouIdn't end
with just yourthanks.
You heIp 3 peopIe and ask each
one of them to heIp 3 more.
Just 3 peopIe.
We wiII definiteIy do it.
The other day, when StaIin asked you
whetheryou heIped anyone,
you said you don't have time.
But today, you heIped them on your own.
That day I was very tensed
about company auditing.
Later, I feIt very bad.
If I can't heIp 3 peopIe,
my Iife has no meaning.
I heIped 2 tiII now.
Now I have heIped the 3rd one.
If he knows about this,
he wouId feeI very good.
ShaII we go?
HeIIo. I'm StaIin speaking.
HeIIo, how are you?
I'm Chitra.
Give the phone to my sister.
Sister has gone out.
Who is on the Iine?
It's for me.
Yes.
The other day you were taIking
about coIor astroIogy.
TeII me the coIor of dress I'm wearing now.
It didn't match that day.
If not the first time,
it can match the 2nd time.
Today, you are wearing
bIack coIor cIothes.
My God! You were right.
Now do you accept that
we can be friends.
I agree.
Since you have won,
I wiII give you a treat.
Come to my house.
We wiII go out together.
ActuaIIy...
What are you thinking about?
Don't you want to come out with me?
Nothing Iike that.
PIease...
I'II be there in 10 minutes.
Mother, where is younger
sister's bIack dress?
It's in the washing machine.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
You Iook very beautifuI
in this bIack dress.
My favourite movie is ''BIack''.
I bought ticket in bIack market
and saw the movie ''BIack''.
With bIack money?
No...
Wow! Surprising!
You are having bIack coffee too.
Sister!
Aren't you ashamed of yourseIf?
I wanted the bIack dress washed
fortomorrow's coIIege function,
why did you take it?
I won't go.
Sir, she hates bIack.
She wiII scoId me
even when I wear bIack cIothes.
She was wearing a white dress tiII now.
Don't what happened to her now?
she rummaged house, wore this wet
dress from washing machine.
Better return my dress back.
If you don't ...be carefuI.
Isn't this your dress?
No.
You don't have any bIack dress, ah?
You don't Iike back at aII?
Then, why did you wearthis bIack dress?
Foryou.
For me?
For what?
What?
Foryourfriendship.
Oh friendship?
If coIor matches,
ourfriendship wiII be strong.
I was just kidding.
But I was serious.
Very good.
Have your bIack coffee.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
I shed my shyness...
I fought to wear sari...
I can't stop Iove madness
taking over me...
Don't come to me...
I'II pinch your cheeks...
May I treat your madness
with my kisses...
My eyes are wide open...
Waiting to see you...
Seeing you Iike this...
Giving up myseIf to you...
Make me Iove you more forever...
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
I bIossomed into a fIower and
come to you with honey of Iove...
I'II make you mine forever...
I gave my hand foryou
to hoId it aII my Iife...
I'II hoId it aII my Iife...
Winning overyou spending
sIeepIess nights...
I'II give my heart to you...
Let's find the path
of Iove together...
My bIooming youth is
troubIing me a Iot...
It's troubIing me aIso
aIong with you...
After giving a good thought
I came to you...
You've to offeryourseIf
as the feast for ceIebrating Iove...
I Iove you with aII my heart...
I too Iove you from the
bottom of my heart...
Gift yourseIf to me...
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
You've grown up Iike a buffaIo.
Why don't you teII him
to Iove somebody?
CaIIing me buffaIo is not right.
Okay, you donkey.
That's good.
He is not after any girI.
But a girI is after him.
Who is she?
How wiII she Iook Iike?
Like her.
Infact it is her.
How is she?
Very beautifuI.
Her eyes, her nose..
she is your sister-in-Iaw.
I've decided.
Look at this face wash.
No. We don't need this girI.
No way.
My son & her? No way.
If my son becomes a poIiceman,
there wiII be no thieves in the country.
If he enters poIitics,
no part wiII oppose him.
She is nothing compared my son.
And she is a friend of that premature Iady.
I don't Iike her.
I don't want her.
Who is she?
She is my brother's mother.
Brother's mother...?
- Since she saw you with me,
you are aIso her enemy.
You do shopping,
I'II make a phone caII.
Go. Where is the booth?
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Mother...
Where is she?
- In the intensive care unit.
You can't go in.
Home Minister is behind this.
StaIin...stop.
Where are you going?
Even after knowing that
he tried to kiII my mother,
do you want me keep quiet?
Stop StaIin!
PIease Iisten to me.
Yes, pIease Iisten to her.
Don't bIow up this issue.
Don't say anything.
-Why are you saying that?
If anything happens to one's mother,
no son wiII keep quiet.
What wiII you do then?
KiII them aII?
WiII you kiII them aII?
I took a hasty decision and
broke my reIationship with mother,
If you take a hasty decision
and get framed into any case,
who wiII Iook after our mother, ah?
You saw our mother's condition, didn't you?
Look at me.
She has a fractured Ieg.
Thank God, she is stiII aIive.
If you fight with them,
another Iorry wouId crush herto death.
Forget about this matter.
If you want to see her aIive,
Iisten to me once.
I know how to soIve this matter.
Don't taIk anything against me.
Got it?
Come with me.
HaiI Muddu Krishnaiah!
Go. He won't meet you.
Just 5 minutes.
We wiII meet him & go away.
Can't you understand? Go.
Security, send them in.
Why are you standing there?
Come inside.
Greetings sir.
I'm DEO Jhansi.
I know.
He is my brother StaIin.
Come inside.
This is my house.
Look at this photo.
Giving a speech in 1962 when
I first contested eIections.
The then Chief Minister is
sitting next to me.
My moustache was very smaII then.
And this?
Inauguration of Vishaka SteeI pIant.
This was taken then.
In NeIIore, I wanted houses
to be given to goons.
I fought Iying on the track.
And this photo was taken then.
You must be wondering,
why I haven't come to the point.
Every man has 2 sides.
Dr. JekyII and Mr. Hyde.
Dr. JekyII in me the man who makes peopIe
beIieve that he's a respected Ieader.
That's him.
Mr. Hyde, the viIIain,
who is above Iaw and justice..
Meet him now, come.
Auditor's famiIy dies
in a Iorry accident.
Are they fooIs to die?
I got them crushed.
When asked to an ant,
why did you bite me?
It said, won't I bite if you
put a finger in my pit?
I'm Iike the ant.
Look, here's another news!
Unidentified men kiII the CoIIector.
Who wiII know that it was me?
He poked his nose in my matter & died.
Engineer's famiIy commits suicide.
He too poked his nose in my matters.
He died aIong with his famiIy.
None of these dead peopIe
interfered in my famiIy matters.
But your brother did.
How dare he threatens my daughter?
What?
Sir, he is a very good man.
KnowingIy or unknowingIy,
he had a fight with your men.
And a moIehiII has become a mountain.
That's why we have come to
seek yourforgiveness.
But he doesn't Iook Iike that.
No sir.
We have come forthat onIy.
ReaIIy?
Go.
Come here.
Come.
Come cIoser.
Come forward.
Stop there.
CaII my daughter.
As promised, I made stand in that circIe.
What shaII we do with him?
He insuIted me infront
my friends & my husband.
His sister must be insuIted
infront of him & aII of us.
Go & faII at my husband's feet.
Your vermiIion must touch
my husband's toe.
Go.
Ask herto do it.
Go back.
I said go back.
Sir, you are an eIderIy man.
Government is in your hands.
We are very ordinary peopIe.
But I'II ask you onIy one thing.
If you are reaIIy a Iegitimate son
to your parents,
Take on me first before daring
to touch anyone from my famiIy.
If not, none of yourfamiIy
members wiII Iive.
If you are reaIIy a Iegitimate son
to your parents...
...come.
Hey Minister.
I too have two sides.
I'm her good brother,
when I am inside the circIe.
Once I cross it,
I won't Iisten to God aIso.
He has put his hand in a ant hiII.
He is a Minister.
He has power.
As a Minister, you mean he can
do anything as he Iikes?
He has done it.
Look, you hit that man.
Minister has no Iinks with that man.
SimiIarIy, you have no Iinks
with the Minister.
But that Minister backed
the man you hit.
When I hit a bad man,
he got the support of Minister
in no time.
When I tried to spread a good thought,
with a hope to heIp 3 peopIe.
I waited for 20 days.
Nobody came forward.
What a society is this!
Excuse me sir.
Doctor is caIIing you.
In major accidents Iike this,
kidney or Iiver gets affected.
UnfortunateIy, both of your mother's
kidneys are affected.
What now?
TranspIant the kidneys?
-Yes.
If anyone of you is wiIIing
to donate your kidney...
My kidney may suit her.
Check mine.
- Sure.
Check me too.
- DefiniteIy.
You need not worry.
Your kidney transpIant was successfuI.
Okay doctor.
Have you donated your kidney
as gratitude to this mother?
I didn't donate my kidney.
Then?
Yes.
Your chiIdren's kidneys didn't suit your body.
a man who was born and brought up eIsewhere,
one whom you humiIiated in pubIic,
his kidney suited you.
Hubby...
I have run out of words.
Find out from son-in-Iaw,
how to say sorry in Punjabi Ianguage.
Come dear.
He is very cute.
He resembIes you.
Take it.
Though you know I'm retiring
from office today,
why didn't you come to my office?
We are sad since morning.
That's why we didn't come to your office.
I traveIIed in your rickshaw
to office everyday.
When Ijoined this job,
you were a bacheIor.
Now, you have aIso grown oId.
You don't need to come
from tomorrow.
Though there are many means
of transport avaiIabIe,
you went to office in my rickshaw.
I got my son admitted in a coIIege.
From tomorrow, I don't know who
wiII board my rickshaw.
Bye sir.
Stop.
- Give me the bag.
On my retirement, my company
gave me some money.
You have aIso been working
for over 30 years for me.
Retirement is common to aII.
Take this money and buy
an auto through finance. Take it.
So much money?
- It's aIright. Take it.
I don't know how to thank you.
Don't break ourfriendship
by saying thanks.
If possibIe, heIp 3 peopIe.
And ask each one of them
to heIp 3 more.
I'II sureIy do it.
Am I right?
-Yes.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
You are the oIdest fox
in the poIitics.
Why are you scared of StaIin?
You asked me to send 20 peopIe.
They got hospitaIized.
Father, party members are
waiting for a Iong time.
TeII them to drown themseIves
in Hussain Sagar.
I won't come there.
Every word StaIin said is
echoing in my ears.
Now our party man Venkatadri
has become a menace.
Teach him a Iesson.
I wiII kiII him.
Where is Venkatadri?
Where is he?
Greetings sir.
I heard that you were seen
with an Opposition MLA.
What is it about?
He is my uncIe's son who is a
member of the opposition party.
I was taIking about famiIy matters
not poIitics.
Lie during eIections.
Not after gaining power.
TeII me the truth.
You want to change the party, right?
- No sir.
I wiII kiII you.
Why are you hitting me even
afterteIIing you the truth?
TaIking against me?
StaIin too spoke against you.
What did you do?
Venkatadri...
- Stop it.
Hitting me is not a matter.
Hit him first.
Try not to threaten me.
Come.
Trying to show off.
He didn't say that.
It was StaIin who said those words.
Before it turns into an epidemic,
we must stop it.
KiII StaIin & his famiIy. KiII!
He said if you were a Iegitimate son
of your parents,
he dared you to touch him first & then his famiIy.
- No. I'm a bastard.
I'm a bastard.
Forgive me mother.
Yes, I'm a bastard.
Come here.
KiII them aII.
I am out...I am out...
I'II show you my prowess.
Don't feeI too shy.
This is onIy your engagement.
They are taking photographs.
SmiIe forthe Iast time.
Hi! LittIe Rat! I'm Chitra speaking.
Your house is Iocked.
Where have you gone?
We are in Sridharfunction haII.
Today is UncIe's engagement.
UncIe's engagement...?
Do you know what it is?
I know. It's done before marriage.
Hang the phone.
I'II continue the game.
My Iife is in a fix now.
Give the phone to your mother.
Chitra is on the Iine.
What's happening there?
Engagement
But you nevertoId me.
We decided suddenIy.
And he is aIso growing oId.
We had many proposaIs.
But this one matched perfectIy.
You saw so many girIs.
But did you ever ask me once?
You shouId have toId me this before.
But now it is too Iate.
Give him the phone.
I'II give it.
Gopi, Chitra is on Iine.
Gopi...
-What?
Chitra caIIed him.
I won't spare you.
What?
- I'II stop the engagement.
Reason?
-Acting innocence.
I'm coming there to teach you
aII a Iesson.
Okay come.
Stop here.
Take Rs. 100.
-And the baIance?
Keep the change with you.
- It is Rs. 150.
Give me your hand.
He is feeIing shy. Look dear.
Stop it.
I won't Iet this engagement go on.
Is it fair on your part?
Don't you know that I Iove you?
How did you agree to marry her?
If you are reaIIy in Iove,
you couId have toId me.
Okay, I didn't express my Iove.
Can't you atIeast understand?
You are right.
Why are you staring at!
Answer her.
Why him? You give an expIanation.
You Iove him, right?
Shit!
Excuse me.
I won't agree if you taIk bad
about my fiance.
So, you & her...
Now onIy I understood.
I aIso understood onIy now.
I wiII taIk to your peopIe
and fix your marriage.
Conduct their marriage soon.
I aIso Iike her very much.
- Okay mother.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Maiden is ravishing in herteens...
Marriage band is seen
in her eyes...
Attractive maiden!
Don't show off too much...
My heart skipped a beat...
Let our marriage band
reverberate the worId...
Hey Maiden, be ready...
to embark a new Iife journey...
Hey girI! Be carefuI...
you'II get enguIfed with Iove...
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
ShaII I Iay fIower baits foryou?
Don't try to charm me,
you can't withstand my power...
TeII me, what am I do to do now?
It's Iike fishing in troubIed waters...
You'II Iearn it when it's time...
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Keep an eye on me...
Betray me staying in my heart...
Don't worry...I'm coming...
To take you to the worId of bIiss...
My worries have become boons to me...
You needn't wait any more...
Harbajan...
What happened?
Harbajan is missing.
- Missing?
UncIe.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Harbajan!
Go fast.
- Leave me.
UncIe.
You too go down.
-Yes boss. Come on boys.
Watch how I'm going kiII him from here.
AII of you draw the Iine
on the Iine I drew.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
Greetings sir.
12 casuaIties & 19 injured.
Since aII were drunk,
We couId not provide propertreatment.
Not onIy that, aII of them are goons.
There are many cases pending
on each one of them.
Where is Home minister Muddu Krishnaiah?
- His son died on the spot.
Post mortem is going on.
He is overthere.
You wiII feeI sad if you see his postmortem.
So, pIease go out...
I wiII stay here. I want to see.
I want to see you cutting my son
into many parts.
As we grow oIder, we get high BP, diabetes.
But I'm getting better.
I'm not getting angry.
It shouId not happen.
It must aIways prick my mind.
I wiII be here.
You go ahead. I want to see that.
Muddu Krishnaiah, what is happening?
UsuaIIy, peopIe request the office
not to do post mortem.
But you're watching the
post mortem being done.
What's wrong with you?
PeopIe eIected us hoping that
we wiII do them some good.
You aIone have created so many probIems.
StaIin kiIIed my son.
Okay. But I'm against poIiticaI murders.
It might defame our party.
Compromise with him.
Okay.
Since you are my eIder,
I wiII agree forthis.
But he must come to my farm house
and seek my forgiveness.
It shouId happen in your presence.
- Okay.
But nobody shouId know about this.
I Iived with Iot of pride.
If everyone come to know about his,
I wiII feeI insuIted.
Okay.
Apart from us, no one wiII know about it.
Okay. Make other arrangements.
Why did you agree forthat?
When time is in yourfavour,
you'II get a grown up son.
But now my son is dead.
And now good time is in the offing.
In my 50 years of poIiticaI Iife,
I've faced 12 eIections.
Let them come.
Watch what's going to happen
in my farm house.
For worId peace & harmony,
Our CM wiII be here now to inaugurate
the human chain formation.
WeIcome.
- Greetings.
You're here for a good cause. Good.
Jihad! (HoIy War)
Run...
Are you okay, sir?
- I'm aIright.
Where is that girI?
Guards, find that girI.
Find that girI first.
Thousands wouId've died
if she hadn't heIp us.
If untoward had happened to this human chain
formed for worId peace & harmony,
it wouId've been a disgrace
to our country.
Where did you get this courage?
EIectric current wiII not harm me.
- How?
You saved me & aII these peopIe.
Thank you very much.
No need forthat.
HeIp 3 peopIe & ask each one
of them to heIp 3 more.
Come again.
HeIp 3 peopIe & ask each one
of them to heIp 3 more.
Who toId you this?
The one who irons my cIothes.
Yes, it was me who toId her.
But it wasn't my own thought.
I Iost my purse in the city bus.
The bus conductorfound it
and returned it to me.
When I thanked him,
he asked me to heIp 3 peopIe.
Do you know who toId him this?
-A shopkeeper in his area.
Surprising!
The Iink keeps extending further.
HeIping others is a nobIe thing.
Someone is trying to promote this.
-Yes sir.
He is trying to promote it through peopIe.
I must know who started it.
We must show to the peopIe who it is.
He must be every citizen's roIe modeI.
Investigate this chain in
the reverse order.- Okay.
I must know who it is.
StaIin is on Iine.
Who is he?- The man had a tiff with
Minister Muddu Krishnaiah.
Greetings sir.
I'm StaIin.
Don't you know Muddu Krishnaiah
is a senior poIitician?
Is this the way to behave with him?
Coming to a decision by Iistening
to his side argument is not fair.
What reaIIy happened is...
I don't want your expIanations.
Ganesh, you can go.
- If necessary, seek inteIIigence heIp.
I must know who he is in 2 days.
- Okay sir.
To soIve this probIem,
and to make Muddu Krishnaiah
not to come in your way,
Iisten to what I'm going to say.
Greetings sir.
- Greetings.
We are waiting foryou.
You said no one shouId know about this.
Who are they?
They are our men.
- Come in.
Our men...?
I don't think I've seen them before.
They beIong to our Youth Brigade cadre.
PIease take your seat.
What wouId you Iike to have?
No thanks.
It's enough if this probIem gets over.
Sir, StaIin has come.
Ask him to come in.
Greetings sir.
- PIease sit.
You seem to be highIy quaIified.
How did aII this happen?
CaIIing him quaIified?
- Let him speak.
TeII me.
TeII me sir, am I at fauIt?
Everything was yourfauIt.
Why are you getting angry?
- He is Iying.
PIease sit.
- I'm Iosing my temper.
StaIin, wait outside forfew minutes.
I was trying to settIe things, but you...?
-You are a happy man.
One of your son is a
software engineer in America.
And another one is
a doctor in AustraIia.
You're Iiving happiIy with
your grand chiIdren.
But I had onIy one son.
Died at the age of 33.
If your son had died,
wouId you accept to settIe things?
Then, don't you want to settIe things?
That's not in my bIood at aII.
When you want something,
you must Iose something.
I Iost my son.
And my heart wants it.
Is it StaIin's Iife?
Chief Ministers' post.
CM? How can you become
the CM when I'm there?
You wiII die.
StaIin wiII kiII you.
Why wouId he do that?
Why are you so ignorant?
I want both rain & thunders.
I wiII kiII you & bIame it on StaIin.
Boys, are you ready?
Don't worry.
I'II erect your statue next to
Krishnadevaraya's statue.
You can spend aII your Iife
Iooking at Buddha statue.
KiII him.
StaIin...
Stop him.
He is taking away the CM.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
The car is overthere.
KiII him.
Give it to me.
HeIIo.
- The car is here.
But don't know where they went.
I may get caught.
They must die before dawn.
Put everyone on high aIert.
Tighten the security.
He has kidnapped our Chief minister.
Shoot him at sight.
StaIin, a terrorist has kidnapped
the CM a IittIe whiIe ago.
Red aIert has been issued
in the entire state.
Government has issued
shoot at sight orders.
PoIice say that StaIin was
in the army earIier.
Sources say that StaIin has
been suspended from duties.
Is StaIin a terrorist?
You were responsibIe for aII this.
What do you mean?
-Yes sir.
You made a grave mistake
by suspending StaIin.
I had a very strong reason for doing so.
CoIoneI.
-Yes doctor.
We removed aII the buIIets expect one.
There is a buIIet cIose to his heart.
If we try to remove it,
it might damage the heart
and he may die in just 10 minutes.
No doctor.
- Not onIy that,
StaIin must not be in army anymore.
The buIIet wiII affect his heart
if he gets angry.
StaIin shouId know about this.
Okay.
StaIin Ieft the army because
I spoke that way.
I never expected such a news
about a great officer Iike him.
What now?
Something is going on there.
We must find it out.
Let's go to Andhra Pradesh
How is he?
Nothing to worry.
CarefuI.
- Okay.
Take the van away from here.
- How can we Ieave you here?
Don't worry about me.
CM must Iive. Go.
There he is.
TeamTolly ( www.TollyTorrents.com )
It's a criticaI case.
Inform the Department head.
I saw StaIin just now.
-Where?
He was admitted into Nizam hospitaI.
I'm Lt. CoI. IqbaI, I've been ordered
to protect Maj. StaIin. Orders pIease!
CM's whereabouts remains a mystery.
The onIy man who knows CM's
whereabouts is fighting for his Iife.
CM's whereabouts wiII be known
when StaIin regains consciousness.
Where is StaIin?
Don't worry.
He is being treated in the hospitaI.
You can watch that on TV.
CM's whereabouts unknown.
StaIin is tiII unconscious.
Do you have a phone?
When everyone is busy
Iooking forthe CM,
CM has caIIed our studio for
an important message to the peopIe.
A request to pubIic.
StaIin is not a terrorist.
It's a Iie.
I'm safe.
I've ordered officers to give
aII the medicaI heIp he needs.
The buIIet is very cIose to his heart.
Operating him wiII be of no use.
- Let's try.
As you see, this hospitaI
is under army's controI.
According to the doctors,
StaIin's condition is very criticaI.
Let's find out what his famiIy
members have to say.
CM has said that your brother
is not a terrorist.
What is your opinion?
My brother is a very good man.
Cutting onions wiII bring tears.
Cutting a coconut wiII
give us sweet water.
My brother is Iike a coconut.
He wanted peopIe to heIp one another.
So, he heIped 3 peopIe and asked
each one of them to heIp 3 more.
He wanted it to become a habit.
He wanted his wish to get fuIfiIIed.
But it never happened.
His heIping nature has
brought him to this condition.
I request everyone to pray
to God for his speedy recovery.
WiII the sun go on a hoIiday?
WiII the time come to a stand stiII?
Let's go.
I must see StaIin right now.
Your condition is...
Don't worry about me.
I must meet StaIin now. Let's go.
Excuse me.
Was it your brother who started this
movement of heIping 3 peopIe?
But it did not happen.
No. It has happened.
It was his thought which has
made my famiIy Iive happiIy.
The auto in which I StaIin was brought
from a man who heIped me.
ReaIIy?
-Yes.
My brother must Iive to hearthis truth.
WiII God ever go to sIeep?
WiII the sun go on a hoIiday?
Sir.
-Yes, where is he?
He escaped in an auto & is in the city.
We are Iooking for him aII overthe city.
Sit in your homes.
He wiII come to you.
Are you guys bIind?
His sister is giving an interview
for TVfrom Nizam HospitaI.
Idiots! Go there & kiII him.
Okay sir.
He is in Nizam HospitaI.
Go there. Fast.
I wiII teII you what had happened Iater.
First I must inform the
pubIic about StaIin.
He not onIy saved me but
brought a change in the peopIe.
He Ionged forthis society to change.
And now it has cost his Iife.
He is a great man.
Sir...
-What's happening there?
There are Iot of peopIe
infront of the hospitaI.
KiII everyone there.
More than 200 thousands.
He is beyond our reach
and can't be kiIIed.
Surrenderto the poIice.
You might Iive.
The sky wiII brighten up seeing you.
Greetings sir.
How is StaIin?
We stopped the operation.
-Why?
The buIIet near his heart moved
and is touching it.
We can't continue the
operation at this stage.
He wiII Iive onIy more 10 minutes.
Let's bring speciaIists from any country.
StaIin must Iive.
StaIin won't Iive no matter
where we take him.
PIease don't say that.
He wiII Iive.
PIease perform the operation.
No. Not even a percent of chance of survivaI.
How couId you say that? He wiII Iive.
You do the operation.
I refuse even if CM orders.
StaIin has no chance.
Are you god?
WiII he die if you say so?
You are aIso an ordinary man.
Becoming a doctor doesn't
mean you are God.
It's not onIy his heart.
But it beIongs to 100 miIIion peopIe.
You perform the operation.
He wiII Iive.
PIease perform the operation.
PIease give him Iife.
We have removed the buIIet.
Nothing to worry.
He wiII regain conscious in few hours.
You can see him.
Forgive me sir.
Thanks.
Thanks aIone is not enough.
HeIp 3 peopIe and ask each
one of them to heIp 3 more.
The nobIe thought you expounded
has hit Iike a cycIone...
Like a wiId raging fire,
youth is behind you...
Down with Muddu Krishnaiah!
Do you know who saved you?
Doctors...?
God?
None of these saved you.
Do you know who saved you?
These peopIe & their Iove.
You were unhappy that your
good thought nevertrickIed down.
Look how the seed you sowed has
bIoomed into a garden of fIowers.
CongratuIations StaIin.
Your post is tiII vacant
in the Indian Army.
Officers Iike you are there
to protect the country.
But we don't have men Iike him
to Iook after us.
We need him.
Let him be with us.
You aIso heIp 3 peopIe and
ask each one of them to heIp 3 more.
It gives you great happiness.
Hoping that you wouId spread
this good thought,
yours Chiranjeevi.