Uncuff him.
Back through there.
No, no, no, leave that.
Back through.
Come on. Come on.
Arms up.
Fine.
In there, get your kit off.
Come out when you're ready.
Arms up.
Kit's clear.
Feet.
Down.
Get up, son.
Get dressed.
Oi.
Single cell,
high risk.
Step through.
Upstairs.
Prisoner home!
Wait.
Through you come.
And wait.
All right. Move it.
One on, now, 111.
Through you go.
Wait.
Keep it moving, fella.
Keep it moving.
Over here.
Face the wall.
In you get.
Ah!
Feeding.
Feeding, fella.
Bruv.
Flame, double bubble, yeah?
Sorry, brother.
Ain't got one spare.
Move along.
Come on, move.
Quick as you can.
Come on, move it.
Come on.
Come on, guys,
stop wasting time.
Jog, mate.
102, Jago.
Any time.
- Yeah?
- Cell, fella.
- Fucking 111, you fucking cunt.
- Move it.
Cheers, Jago.
Safe yeah, Jago.
What's wrong with this kanga, bruv?
He's over-watching us.
I know, I can feel
his eyes in the back of my head.
Stupid fucking
junkie slut she was.
Stepped up,
done right by her.
Fair play,
offing that geezer.
Still, don't make you
nothing in here.
You conduct yourself usual
like an ordinary con.
No more performing,
no dramas.
Right? Get on yard
with the rest of them.
The yard.
Bruv, bust me a light
please, you got a lighter?
Back on.
In you go.
Brother.
That flame, yeah?
Shit.
Oh, fuck's sake.
Don't fucking die on me.
Fuck.
You must wait till I'm ready.
Miss, no, no...
Nasty bang to the head, miss.
He needs you.
Right, I'm gonna go now,
everything's sweet.
- Everything's cushy.
- Son?
Guv, it was an accident.
I swear.
- Stay there.
- Look, he walked...
I mean it, son,
don't fucking move.
Bang up!
Get in your cells now!
In your fucking cells.
Come on! Move!
It's another kick off.
- Excuse me. Excuse me.
- Ready, Mr. Haynes.
Sorry, Mr. Haynes.
- Baby oil.
- Get the sand.
Entry team. D wing.
- Here you go, lads.
- Cheers, mate.
Come on then. Yes.
Yes.
Weapons down,
stand against the back wall.
School him.
- Yes!
- Go on!
- Pin him against the wall!
- Come on then, piggy.
- Yeah, come on, you fucking pig!
- Hold his legs.
Hold his fucking legs!
Hey, calm down!
- Hold him steady!
- Too fucking greasy, the cunt!
Get hold of him!
You fucking...
You fucking come
any closer, mate,
I'll fucking skewer
this pig like a fucking hog roast.
Now, fuck off.
Drop that fucking thing
and fuck off now.
Sharpish!
That's fucking right.
You don't want
to do that, son.
- Shut up, Clive.
- Who's talking to you, cunt?
I tell you what I do want,
guv, you listening?
A helicopter,
two packs of burn and some
chocolate digestives, please.
It was a fucking
accident, guv.
I swear to you.
- All right.
- You believe me, don't you?
Yeah.
Fuck off.
In you go, lads.
Fuck you!
You fucking cunts.
Take it easy, son.
Oh, for fuck's sake.
I fucking knew it.
- Scum you lot are, fucking scum.
- Easy, son.
Fuck off,
you little cunt.
Take it easy.
Come on. Come on,
you little fucking...
- This ain't fucking gentle, boys, is it?
- Shut it!
Come on,
you little fucking...
Move!
Steady, steady, steady.
Yeah, come on,
you little cunt!
You're telling me, you catch a girl
sleeping with your friend, yeah?
Who you going to
be more vexed with?
- Your friend or your girl?
- But I expect that more from a chick.
I expect that.
You know what I mean? But the boy...
Nah, I ain't touching her.
Come on.
Easy, easy.
Right, wait.
Fuck's sake, why ain't
you lot banged up in your cells, eh?
- Easy, easy.
- Keep his head down.
Fuck.
Easy, boys, easy. We don't want
anyone to get hurt now, do we?
- Baton.
- No fucking way!
Ah!
Why don't we all
go back to our cells?
Hurry up.
Ow!
You fucking looking at?
He made a mistake, Des.
Des.
A mistake.
Out.
If I go, he's fucked.
My responsibility to you
as a non-operational member of staff,
Mr. Baumer,
is to get you away
from this incident.
And if you don't comply
this second you can surrender your keys.
No!
I'm going to
ask you to please let go of Officer...
Johnson.
No!
He hurts me, Don.
He's fucking gotta...
Oi!
We can do this.
It's okay.
Yeah?
Stay back. Stay back.
I've seen all of you,
I'm a witness.
It's fine.
You all right?
Okay, come on.
Give your name
and number in here.
Love. C-9-4-8-7-W-B.
This way. Foxtrot, Sierra,
Quebec, 14. Come in, over?
- Cuffs, please.
- Quebec 14, sir.
Request Governor Cardew
to segregation. Over.
Received, Quebec 14.
14 out.
Foxtrot Sierra
standing by.
Thank you.
Everything's under
control, Christine.
There's been an incident
involving Mr. Love
which has placed
him at extremely high degree of risk,
which is why I brought it to
your immediate attention.
I propose that
he begins treatment
for his violence as soon as possible,
in my... In my group.
He's assaulted
two of my officers
shortly after knocking
another victim unconscious.
You will not be rewarding him
with any kind of group.
- He wants to engage.
- He's a control problem.
He can be reached.
Gentlemen, I think
you'd better come with me.
So, who is he?
Eric Love.
He's starred up, ma'am.
Nineteen.
Transferred from
Durham Yo this morning.
And you were aware of this?
It came to my attention, yes.
I realize I'm new in post
but you didn't think
to tell me about a young offender
transferred two
years premature?
It was on my agenda.
You mentioned risk.
What risk?
Staff.
Sorry?
The Governor
wants to see you.
If you comply with the regime,
I'm prepared to offer you
a place back on the wing.
And a special kind of therapy
with Mr. Baumer,
with whom you co-operated upstairs.
But one more incident of any kind
that comes to my attention,
you'll be straight back down here.
Just one problem.
And you're going to
tell me what that is?
I'm just saying.
Say this therapy goes well
and it changes my life
and I rehabilitate.
And then you lay it on for the next geezer
and it works for him, and the next.
And everything's
sweet, yeah?
Crime rates start to come
down, police have got less people to nick.
Courts got less
people to convict.
Pretty soon,
you're out of a job.
Do you mind?
I said do you mind,
you fucking...
Right. Get...
Oh, what a fucking pussy.
- Oh, just take him back.
- Come on.
Fucking ungrateful cunts.
I pay your fucking
mortgages and all, you know.
Get out.
Well, it doesn't appear
Mr. Love is too ready
for therapeutic
intervention, does it?
No, no, no, no, no.
I think we should go with
your initial instinct, Christine
and give Eric Love the one chance
that Oliver thinks he needs.
But as you say,
any non-compliance
and he's off the group
and back down here.
Erm, Mr. Love.
Never talk to me again.
It's one phone call,
clean head shot outside the gate.
All right?
Fucking do one!
He went in
yesterday, bruv.
No, he didn't.
Do you think
we don't check?
And don't call me bruv.
Look, I swear to you, Nev.
Get your people now.
Yeah, but I ain't
got no tech, bruv.
- Hello.
- What's up, T?
Yeah, yeah I'm all right, babe.
But listen, where's the fucking gwap?
- I put it in.
- Don't fucking lie to me, babe,
- because I'm in a spot here...
- I put it in yest...
All right,
miss one again, hurt you.
Hey, Jinsy,
how you doing? You well?
Hello, Selfy.
You done something
to your hair? It's nice.
What you done,
you had a haircut?
Just a bit of gel,
mate, yeah.
Oh, it's nice.
It's nice.
Next.
- All right?
- Yeah. Done it.
Good.
Fucking monkey.
Your youngster,
what I've heard.
No offense to family
but the kid's
causing unnecessary
to the good order
and discipline of this jail.
And lock downs,
as you well know, cost me money.
Slap?
Stop being a psychopath
for a second, please.
No. You exercise
the gray matter, Neville.
You mentor him.
You stick him on a path
and you dedicate yourself
for a period of time.
Save me a lot
of aggravation.
Least of all,
having to murder the cunt
if sanity do not prevail.
Get Selfy take you down there.
Oi, Jim!
Fucking hell.
Yeah, see you later.
I'm gonna tell
you something, all right?
This here is not no
young offenders turn out, all right?
They will fucking dangle you,
the kangas.
They'll make it
look like suicide.
Right?
Now, me,
I can never leave.
Top someone in jail,
they do not like it.
But you, just do what
they want you to do.
Play their fucking game
and then bounce.
I ain't going
to no fucking...
Yes, you fucking are, cunt!
Don't you ever fucking
answer back to me again.
You will do what
you're fucking told.
You'll do what
the man was offering
and you will fucking behave.
Yeah.
Tomorrow you'll be
back up on the wing.
Selfy will take care of it.
Come to see you,
you know?
Start of your sentence,
the one you're doing now.
5 years old I was
sat on your knee,
listen to you and mum
slag each other off.
Eat your food.
Come on, Love. Let me get you out
of this shithole and back to your wing, eh.
Go on.
Oh.
Go up the stairs.
Flame.
Double bubble.
All of you better stop
whatever the fuck you're doing!
Who's been in my fucking cell?
Oi, answer me!
Who's been in
my fucking cell?
I will fuck you up.
Who's been in my fucking cell? Oi!
Who was in my
fucking cell?
Answer me, now!
Who the fuck was in my cell?
Ah.
Start free flow.
Thanks, guv.
All right,
it's time for class.
- Dunk him.
- Yeah.
Hard.
It don't come back to me.
No. No.
All right, tip-top.
Spoke to him, he knows
he's to mind himself.
Don't mug me off.
Listen to what the teacher
has to say, all right?
All right.
Welcome.
What's going on?
Was here when
you done your thing, man.
Burstow.
Love.
Yeah, we know that.
Eh, this guy...
He clamped down
on that fucking kanga.
Yo, where you located?
D1.
D2 above you, ain't we?
Should've gnawed 'em off.
Nah, blood.
Kid's regulating the play.
They ain't been
trained for that shit.
Hey, kangas dish
you out any damage?
Nah.
Just so you know,
it's no smoking in the group.
We'll have a break,
you can smoke by the window.
But we're all ready
to start now.
So if you just put it out,
we can begin.
As you been told
by the gentleman.
- You making a monkey out of me?
- Can you leave, please?
- Beg your pardon?
- You can't just walk in like that.
You'll get your
snout back after.
Problem is you got
to come down on him full throttle,
else it won't register. Right?
Now listen what
the gentleman has to say.
All right,
off you go then.
You stay here.
Who was that?
Neville Love.
Love. As in...
Yeah.
Jesus Christ!
He's only trying
to help, ain't he?
Nah, it's mad, blood.
Come in here, try tell a man what
to do in front of everyone.
Listen to me you,
you fucking cunty bollocks.
Forde!
Listen, you keep fucking
looking at me like I'm some sort of cunt,
Mr. Love had
his initial assessment.
- He's done extremely well.
- I'll fucking pen you.
I would be grateful
if you could escort him back to the wing.
He fucking threatened me.
Can I have my pen back,
please, Mr. Love?
- Thank you.
- Where are you, fella?
D1.
All right, come on,
let's go.
Thanks very much.
You two are on
his wing, right?
Would you do me a favor
and just keep a little eye on him?
I mean, he's only a kid.
Where were we?
D-Wing
association, unlock!
Oh, sorry, love.
10.
1, 2, 3, 4, 5,
6, 7, 8, 9, 10.
- What you stopping for?
- Yo.
Huh?
What do you reckon?
Do your thing, man.
Fucking shit!
Cunt. Fucker!
Fuck off.
You pussyhole.
- Yo, yo, come here, come here, come here.
- No, no.
- Fucking asshole.
- Listen, listen.
You can fuck
people up, yeah.
Fucking defend yourself.
But it don't make no sense
catching another fucking
case now, does it?
Now relax.
Fuck.
What?
Think you got some do-do
in your hair, bruv.
Ah.
Hey, how come you helped?
- Said to look out for you, on the wing.
- Who?
- OI.
- OI?
He's half a kanga.
What, you boys
back him do you?
Yeah,
OI's different, man. He works alone.
Don't never press the alarm.
Puts his body on the line.
And he don't get paid.
How many kangas
you know like that?
Yo, blood.
Make sure you come
back to it, yeah.
It's beneficial.
You should have
seen me before.
Yeah, I'll, er,
think about it.
Later.
Bang up, D-Wing!
You going up and down
the landing for?
Hmm? What's that about?
You need anything,
you come see me.
No, no, it weren't
like that.
What the fuck
was it like, then?
Huh?
Well, you told me to go
in the fucking group, didn't you?
Yeah, I told you to go
in the fucking group.
Fucking learn, boy.
To slow down and get out,
but not to fraternize.
What?
You know what I mean.
I think you fucking do.
Huh?
You didn't give him
a clump, did you?
No, fucking didn't.
Hmm.
You're jealous, mate.
Oh, fuck off.
He's making links,
without you, with some serious geezers,
and now you want to
go and fuck it up,
because you fucking are, mate.
Who the fuck you think
you are? Huh? Huh?
Good boy.
There you go.
Selfy's got a stomach bug.
Oh.
Like the old days.
Got to keep the show
on the road, Dennis.
Ah.
You look nice.
- Really?
- Nah.
Where you from?
Oxfordshire.
Ooh. What you doing here?
Well, I was going to ask if you would
like to walk to group with me.
No, I mean this shithole.
Well, I feel at home here.
So this is where
you open up to me and build trust, is it?
Yeah.
Look, I was, em, sent away
when I was very young to boarding school
and when I got
out the other end,
I found it really
hard to manage in the outside world.
Posh boy.
Not really.
Well, you don't get paid.
I had some family money
after my granny died.
So this is sort of like
a hobby for you, then?
No. No, I need to be here.
I got sent away when
I was young like you,
I was put into care.
Then, when I was 10,
I done a pedo in. Hmm.
Sloshed him.
Boiled water, sugar, boom.
Kiddy fiddlers,
man, strange.
They want you to reassure them that
what they're doing is normal.
Like they want you, the victim,
to let them off the hook.
They want to open up to you,
build your trust.
Now, the geezer's face,
I won't never forget.
Melted, in his hands.
I think maybe you've got the wrong
idea. Could I just come in and...
So you can start
touching me up and all?
No, you fucking wrong one.
How many fucking sugars do you take?
You fucking nonce cunt.
Why should I give
a shit about you?
'Cause I'm starred up, mate,
and very fucking violent
and you want to make
a name for yourself,
don't you, and your
fucking little group.
I don't give a shit if
you're in my group or not.
- Then why you fucking stood there, then?
- I don't fucking know.
- Have a think, then, dickhead.
- I don't want to think.
Right now, I want
to fucking hurt you.
Yeah?
Good.
Now we're getting somewhere.
Let's go.
- Morning, guv.
- Morning.
Good.
Come on, laugh.
Hi, everyone,
sorry I'm late.
Hey, why you run
last time?
Hey, he didn't run.
He chose to hold it down
instead of becoming violent
and took himself
back to the wing.
Whatever, man.
- He ran.
- No.
He made a choice.
So why you sticking
it on me for?
Because you're pressurizing him and I
don't want him to kick off.
You're defending him.
And what's wrong with that?
So why you getting involved?
Why not leave it to
his fucking dad?
Fuck you, you little
mangy cunt!
- Ryan, that was... That was wrong.
- Take it easy, man.
Take it easy.
Hey, hey, take it easy man, chill.
Chill, yeah?
You're doing the right thing.
He knows.
Fucking this
guy don't give a fuck.
You're mugging him
off by telling him.
And you're doing what
by telling me, blood?
- What you saying, blood?
- What the fuck you standing up?
I'm saying what
I'm saying, ain't I?
Des was offering support.
I don't give a fuck what
he was saying about.
And you shamed him
without meaning to.
Yeah, but he's shaming me
and you ain't got shit
to say about that,
have you, you stupid prick.
- That's enough.
- Listen. Me?
It's fucking him who's
on his fucking period, bruv.
Stepping in. Mugging man off
like I was a fucking bag head
scratching for dog-ends
on the fucking yard.
When that ain't what this
group is meant to be about now, is it for?
I'm standing up 'cause
I'm standing up. What?
I'm standing up now, what?
- The fuck you standing up for?
- Come make me sit down.
- Fall back, man.
Come. Hey, come here.
Blood, I'm standing up.
Bruv, ain't shit
going down, man.
'Cause you would have lumped Des and he
would have shanked you,
and that would have finished
the fucking group altogether, you cunt.
So relax.
Talking to me, bruv?
- Enjoy your smoke, man.
- Now we say?
Enjoy your smoke, man.
- You still talking to me, bruv?
- Why don't you enjoy your smoke.
- Fam, you still talking to me?
- Enjoy your smoke.
I ain't never had
a problem with him, you know.
You got a topic?
Hmm?
For the group discussion.
No, I'm just listening,
ain't I?
- Fair enough.
- Hmm.
It can take a session or two to get used to it.
Erm, okay,
so who's got a topic?
- Serious?
- Nah, mate.
- Take it easy, yeah?
- Cool.
Don't fucking touch me.
Look, I told you,
you get the rest when you do him.
- He's gone and done you.
- Yeah, I fucking did what you told me.
- This guy's crazy.
- Just give it to me.
- When you do him.
- All right.
And how about your
little Warren and Charmaine?
Yeah,
doing well, a big boy.
- Getting a big boy.
- Yeah.
And what about Char...
- Can I help you, young man?
- Nah, sweet.
Hey, is he about?
In a meeting.
Eric, right?
Come in.
Thanks.
It's all right.
Come to talk to you.
Man to man.
So we don't get on
each other's fucking tits no more.
Which is a good thing.
All right.
Talk.
You just order me about
and tell me to do stuff.
You don't give a fuck
about how I feel.
Well, that's it.
Fuck off, "That's it".
What else is going on?
Come on, you come here
to fucking talk to me, tell me, what is it?
Someone giving you
a fucking hard time?
Someone fucking
threatening you?
Tell me the truth.
What the fuck is going on?
Nev, I think he's just trying
to tell you something and he's...
It's fucking prison,
ain't it?
As someone whose nan who come off the
fucking boat, Barbados, yeah.
Don't like Africans.
Think they can look
at me with all their fucking tribal scars,
- mad accents and shit?
- I'm a fucking African.
Yeah?
But you ain't got
no scars and you talk South, you cunt.
- They got their fraud.
- I'll give you that.
Being honest, don't like
fucking black people.
All in. They just
prey on each other.
Don't let no one advance.
Now you see your, your Indians, your
Bangladesh, your Vietnamese,
your fucking Pakistani,
Koreans, North, South,
whatever the fuck they
want to call themselves,
now you see them, motherfuckers,
they stick together.
Slavery done it.
It was you
African nig-nogs that traded us
to the white cunts to
start though, weren't it?
Yeah, well,
I don't like yids.
- I'm a yid.
- Fuck off.
- I'm half Jewish.
- Which side?
- My father's.
- Don't count.
You're off track
with the Jews, bro.
Check it.
They arrived at the bottom,
but finished at the top.
One generation,
wherever they are.
I still ain't
having them.
Well, you're a black cunt.
If I'm a yid cunt,
you're a black cunt, he's a white cunt.
We're all a bunch of cunts
if you think about it.
Yo, slow down,
old man.
You white cunts,
you ain't all that compared to us.
- How?
- The chicks.
We got the bigger knobs.
Yeah, you lot don't go down on birds
though, do you? What fucking good's that?
I make you wrong there, bruvva.
Against the religion, acki.
No, no, no.
Listen, back door, I ain't troubling that.
Oral pleasure, permissible.
Bruv, you ain't
sucking pussy.
You ain't fucking.
That right, OI?
Yeah, if I had
a pussy to suck.
And if that pussy
was attached to a woman
with whom I had a loving
and trusting relationship,
I would consider myself
very fortunate.
Ty, you missing out, blood.
I'm telling you,
it's a part of life.
Maybe push the boat,
when I land, ain't it?
I ain't saying for definite.
I ain't saying either way.
How long you got?
13 years.
Fucking no rush then.
Plenty of time to think.
Still, you'll be getting
balls deep before me son, so...
Full report, please.
Yo.
Jab.
In the bottom.
Double jab.
Two, up two. Up two.
Hey, you don't expect me
to lift that, do you?
Nice.
Yo, fuck them, man.
I'll hold your ankles for you, let's go.
- Let's go, man.
- Nah, it's all right. Fuck it. Sweet.
Allow him, Hass,
he wants to train like a bacon.
Said you want to train like a bacon,
a fucking nonce.
It's up to you.
Big right.
4.
Left, right, uppercut,
straight right.
Double jab.
Cover that chin.
2.
4.
Hook, hook.
Drop your right
and I'll tag you.
Body, body.
Uppercut, uppercut.
What, you think
you're Ali, bruv?
Calm yourself down.
4.
Double jab.
Arms up.
Ain't gonna tell you again.
Jab hook, big right.
Ahhh!
Oi!
You fucking
seriously having that?
4.
2. 6.
6!
10!
Uppercut.
Time. Who's next?
Cunt.
Fucker.
Fucking cunt.
Who fucking sent you?
You have to stop eating.
I eat because
I'm depressed, right.
You're depressed, what about me, huh?
What do you think
it's like for me?
Mum, I'm the one
in fucking prison.
Sorry, Mum.
Mum, look I don't want
to fucking argue about it.
Mum, listen...
Look, I just want to
ask how you are...
Fuck!
Ahhh!
Fucking pussy hole.
Fucking want someone
doing, Jago, do them your fucking self.
- I ain't got that kind of clout. Please.
- Who was it then, Jago?
- Who's the fucking man?
- Please, please, please.
Was it that
fucking old cunt
at the top of the stairs
with the fucking hair, him?
I don't know what the fuck
you're talking about...
Lose your fucking
lip then, Jago cunt.
It's him, chill, chill.
That's him, yeah? Yeah?
Oh! Fucking get the...
Get the fuck down.
You...
Fuck me, you an' all?
Oi, I fucked him up,
you know.
- I cut him fucking good, mate.
- Who?
That fucking fat black bastard in the fucking
canteen, you fucking know who.
- You cut him?
- Yeah.
You fucking stuck him
on me, mate.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Drop it. Drop it!
- Huh?
Drop it!
Jags...
Jags, up here now.
Well, let go of him then.
Behave.
Get up, get up, go on.
- Yeah, there he is your fucking...
- Stay there!
You saying
I put you on him?
Is that how it is?
Using my name?
He's not some punk.
He's Eric Love, Neville's own.
Transfer or your life.
Either way, you won't
be here tomorrow.
You're getting
blood on my floor. Now fuck off.
All right.
Leave us, please.
Don't agitate me.
Dennis.
He'll be fine.
Neville.
Sit down then.
Am I right about you, Eric?
Starred up means
you're a leader.
Why you attack people
for the principle, instead of losing pride.
And no leaders,
where would we be?
Back to the fucking
Stone Age, that's where.
Scratching our recta
without no toilet paper.
Cunts.
So...
Issues, Eric.
Bring 'em here
and we can resolve any matters arising.
Know you can
take care of yourself,
but it sometimes
helps to have friends with influence.
Something you will learn.
You with me?
And no more silliness,
I want a nice quiet wing.
You can go.
You remind me of myself,
when I was your age.
All right.
What's going on?
I'm sorry?
You have to help him,
you know.
You have to teach him the answers,
the things he's supposed to say,
you know, like the
"Think Right" program.
You know,
help him get out.
like the, fucking,
"What would you do
if you were in a bar
"and a fella comes up
and starts talking to your bird?
"What you gonna do?
Oh, I'm gonna tell him politely
"that I'm with her, you know, rather than
glass the cunt." You know what I mean?
- Exactly. That bollocks.
- Okay.
That's not what
my group is about.
Your son and I
are on a journey together and we will...
No, he needs to behave.
Okay, he's suffered
enormous emotional trauma and abuse.
- Oh, I never touched him.
- Well, you weren't there.
I didn't... Okay,
that's enough, all right.
Fucking finish.
'Cause in case you haven't
fucking fully appreciated,
I am his fucking parent
and I am fucking here now.
You think you can fucking
fix him up, huh?
What, you got a fucking couple of fucking
nice little letters after your name.
Well I've got
fucking numbers.
So's he.
Do you have a family?
Have you got family?
You got someone
you go home to at night?
No?
Or would you rather
be doing fucking bang up?
Closed in with
all the rest of us?
You sick fucking
no-life, saddo cunt.
Maybe you don't feel comfortable accepting
help from other people?
Hmm?
I know I don't.
Makes me wonder what's in it for them.
Laying yourself open.
Vulnerable, ain't it?
- So why you do it then?
- What?
Lend me the fucking
shampoo, you mug.
'Cause you had some
fucking shit in your hair.
I said you had some
fucking shit in your hair
so I give you some
fucking shampoo.
Ain't put my hands on you,
ain't disrespected your mum.
And, right about now,
the more I fucking flow,
and flow, and flow,
and fucking flow,
the more I know you
ain't gonna do fuck all.
Pussy.
Stay with it.
Stay with it, that's it.
- I feel like a cunt.
- Good.
- Good?
- Yes, good.
I feel like a cunt
every day.
Stay with it,
breathe with it.
Breathe with it.
Done well.
Yeah,
it was good.
Straight.
Yeah, it was all right.
He's smiling,
look at him, he's smiling, he's smiling.
He knows he's done well, go on.
Yeah...
Anger management,
control.
Everything all right?
Fine.
Sweet.
Who's that then?
My mum.
Why?
No, I'm just saying.
Nice photo, ain't it?
- How's yours?
- Hmm?
Your mum, must be a bit
worried about you?
No, I ain't got one.
Bang up!
Thanks.
For what, blood?
For the tea, ain't it?
Come on, mate,
it's not the crown jewels.
What you do in that group?
Talk, ain't it?
- Talk?
- Yeah.
And sometimes it can go.
Sounds loops.
It is.
- Okay, so, what's the topic?
- Jail.
- Okay.
- Yeah, like what effects it has on you
and how it fucks
with your head.
- Good topic.
- You want jail, yeah, go fucking Morocco.
Ain't got peeps,
money, you're fucked.
- American jails, worse. Don't care.
- Why's that?
They shag each other
out there, ain't it?
Bruv, I'd rather
have no servery...
Welcome.
Fuck me!
What's your fucking problem?
I'm fucking here cause of you, ain't I?
- Well, sit down then.
- Don't fucking embarrass me, all right?
Don't fucking embarrass me
in front of everyone.
You want a fucking straightener?
Come on.
- Oh, my fucking God.
- Fucking have it.
- Mr. Love.
- Fucking have it then.
Don't fucking start
with me, all right?
With your poncey fucking voice
and you think you're fucking better than me.
Don't fucking start with me.
Look, just sit down
and shut up, yeah.
Fuck your class.
You fucking,
bunch of fucks!
Get me off
this fucking wing!
Off the wing, now!
Bang me the fuck up!
All right,
all right, fella.
Fucking wankers.
Get me off
this fucking wing!
Open the fucking gate!
Open the fucking gate now!
Bang me up right fucking now!
Open it!
Open the fucking gate,
get me behind my cell, now.
Think positive.
- Rise above it.
- Ryan.
I'm helping him.
It's the wrong kind of help right now.
If you just back off.
Yeah, you don't ever bite,
Ryan, do you?
Fucking everything
sorted, is it?
- Yeah, of course.
- Yeah?
- 100%.
- All times?
Like I said.
Yeah, well maybe you
ain't fucking true to yourself then,
to the fucking group
and all.
- Just watch your mouth.
- Watch me mouth?
Go fuck your mum
in her asshole, how's that sound to you?
- What the fuck did you just say?
- Yeah, there we go.
Who the fuck do you think
you're talking to, you little prick?
Take that back or I will
fuck you up right now.
What, do you think I'm one of them
little fucking pricks on the wing?
- Fucking 100%.
- Carry on smiling.
You're gonna see
what's gonna happen.
- Sit down.
- Fucking prick.
You think you can just
fucking talk how you want.
You can talk whatever the fuck
you want about my mum.
Like a fucking
dead person, I am.
I don't fucking
feel anything.
Nah, this is bullshit, man.
No one don't say nothing
about no one's mum.
You've been fucking warned.
And you too.
Hmm.
Suck your mum.
I will bury you!
I want him!
I fucking want him!
I will bury you, cunt!
Step inside the fucking ring,
you pussy!
Look, look Ty.
Lads, boys...
Listen, cause I ain't
got fuck all going on with my mum,
don't give me the right
to start slating yours, yeah.
I'm sorry.
Okay?
Ryan, don't leave me
hanging like a cunt, come on.
Yeah, look, sweet.
See, done, yeah?
Mr. Baumer, would you care to tell me
exactly what is going on in here?
I'm in the middle
of a session.
- You have a vulnerable Yo in here.
- And?
We agreed one incident
and he would have to leave.
- But he didn't do anything.
- You need to do it,
and you need to do it now.
You're going to have to go back to
the wing, just for this session, mate.
- Bullshit.
- Why?
It was agreed,
one incident and he has to come off.
Yeah, but it's all right.
Relax boys, fucking hell.
- Sweet, Ryan, yeah?
- Yeah.
- OI.
- Well done, yeah.
- Cool, thanks man.
- I'll come and see you...
I'll come and see you later.
- Okay.
- I don't think so.
- What?
- A break is a break.
He's lucky not to be
back on segregation,
which I recall formed part
of our original agreement.
Why are you so scared
of something that might actually work?
You need to calm it down.
He's building trust.
Okay, he's taking stuff on.
It is working.
I mean, seriously,
what are we doing here,
if not trying to help
prisoners like Eric fucking Love?
What is it you
don't understand? He is a young offender.
I don't give a fuck,
I want him!
You, you need to get
a hold of yourself, Mr. Baumer,
because you are
far too involved.
Sorry about Love.
Of course, we did everything we could
to accommodate him in your group.
But with someone
like that, well...
However hard we try,
sometimes there's just no hope, is there?
Warehouse him.
Protect the public
that way,
make sure he stays inside
for the rest of his life...
Fucking no better than
a fucking grass, you're not.
Fucking running your gums
in the fucking group.
Slinging your
tampon around,
until half the fucking
jail come on top. Embarrassing.
Bummer, Baumer, whatever his fucking
name is, better man than you, mate.
See that group makes you
feel part of something, like you is someone.
Fucking come here,
I thought sweet, big man's nick.
I thought nice one,
someone to look up to.
Fucking bollocks,
joking ain't you?
- Nev.
- Eh?
Fucking walking around,
fucking giving it the large'un,
intimidating people.
Yet you can't even sit
on your own fucking ass
for 5 fucking seconds.
What's that about, eh?
Fucking embarrassing,
that's what that is, fucking pathetic.
Tell you what you are mate,
a fucking prison poof.
I'm sorry, I didn't...
Here, what you doing?
What's it fucking
look like I'm doing?
No don't, mate, no, no,
what about all the work you've been doing,
all the stuff, all the changes you've
been going through in class.
Group.
It's a fucking group,
not a class.
You're a fucking man now,
aren't you?
You're a fucking man,
ain't you...
All right, we can
fucking do this.
Come on then,
let's fucking have it, let's have it.
Ain't fucking...
All right...
I fucking...
I give up.
You fucking got me.
- You let me win.
- I didn't fucking let you win.
Yes, you fucking did,
you mug, you let me fucking win.
I didn't fucking
let you win.
Yes, you did,
you mugged me right off, you cunt.
I didn't.
You've been fucking training.
Fucking hell.
Fucking fuck all,
that's what you are, mate.
That's right.
Oi, I'm talking to you, cunt.
Walking away as per usual.
Look at you.
Turn round.
Can't, can you?
Can't fucking face me,
can you?
Cause you're not
a fucking man. More like a fucking fraggle.
Come on then, round two,
let's do it proper now. Come on. No?
Don't fucking want it,
do you?
'Cause you know you'll
get fucking filled in, that's why.
I've got fucking 19 years
of this for you, cunt.
- Young man.
- Just fucking say the words
- and I'll come straight at you, cunt. Hey?
- No, no.
Remember what I told you.
In my cell, conversation we had?
Boy, boy...
Shut up, Neville!
Now there is a way through this. I
know, because you are like me.
- Like you.
- Potential is what you possess, Eric.
Fuck off you, little fuck!
Look what you
made me do now, yeah? Fucking well done.
I'm down here
for fucking years, mate.
Make sure you fucking come
and hit me fucking hard, boys.
Somebody get
his fucking inhaler.
Boy.
- Get behind your door!
- Move!
Fucking queer hands
off me, cunt.
Step aside!
Eric, easy!
Take it easy, boy!
Don't fucking kill him!
Fucking... Fucking...
Fucking milk-fed cunts.
Fucking back
to your lube now, you fucking queer.
Least I've had a shag.
Fucking virgin.
Saw a pussy, wouldn't know whether to
fuck it or slide it a saucer of milk.
Fuck off,
you fucking bender!
At least I'll be
out of here one day
fucking ironing out
one clitoris after the other, cunt.
Don't care, mate.
I like a nice tight hairy little asshole.
Give yourself 10 years, boy,
I think you'll feel the same.
You dick-sucking cunt!
I only fucking aimed
to kick off her back door
and pronged the other hole
by mistake... Ah.
Else you wouldn't even
fucking be here!
All right!
Fuck's sake.
Legs!
Oh, fuck.
Go to fucking...
Clear!
Fucking had presents
wrapped tighter than this!
Fucking civil servant cunts!
Take your fucking pips off,
let's fucking have it!
Come on you...
Fucking
have the lot of you.
Come on, take your
fucking pips off!
Let's fucking have you!
The whole
fucking gang of you!
Fucking men?
My old fucking grandma
could have fucking had any of you,
on her 60th fucking day!
Let's fucking go at it,
you cunt!
One on one!
Come on, you fucking cunts!
You fucking suck the cock of cunt,
you fucking assholes!
Go.
Oh, fucking shower, is it?
You fucking women!
Hey, what do you
fucking need?
Clean my asshole
while you're at it, you fucking nancy boy!
Boy!
If you've fucking touched him!
If you've touched him!
Come on boy, answer me.
Don't fucking leave me
hanging like this.
Just stop
all the fucking around
and answer me!
I need to hear your fucking voice.
Boy!
Don't fucking mug me off!
You touch him,
you fucking touch him!
Oh, fuck off.
What they do to you?
Fuck all.
Bottled it, didn't they.
What,
they didn't do nothing?
No, fuck all.
Pussy holes.
Junior?
I'm gonna
fucking top myself.
I...
I'm gonna fucking do it,
I swear to God.
I'm gonna smash
my fucking head
over on that fucking sink.
Get me fucking Selfy.
Get me him, he's the
only one who knows
how to fucking deal
with me when I'm like this.
I'm gonna do it, I swear.
Please, please.
Please do it.
Who else fancies a pint? I'd be up for that.
Cheers, lads.
- You have a good night, yeah.
- Yeah, home free.
All right, take it easy.
Here.
Open the door.
No, I can't Nev.
Why not?
'Cause Haynes is on Center.
Oh, fuck that.
Come on, Selfy,
open the door.
I just, I just want
to fucking get these off. I can't stand it.
It's doing
my fucking head in.
All right.
You're soaking wet.
Why do you think?
They gave me a fucking bath, didn't they?
- You all right though, yeah?
- Yeah, mate, it's fucking mad.
They fucking give me the hose.
You know, fucking wouldn't stop...
Sorry, mate.
- Where's Self?
- Don't know.
Face the wall.
Back on the wing.
Hey, you gave me
the opportunity. Fair play.
But... I'm...
I'm not wired up right
in the, um,
the father role, you know,
I can see that now.
But I do need
to know he's safe.
I need to
know that, Dennis.
Because there's one thing
I will not allow,
under any circumstances,
and that is for anyone...
To fucking top my kid.
Okay?
You know I could never
harm your flesh and blood, Neville.
The whole point
is safeguarding him.
Get you on your toes
to teach him how,
because it's not always possible
for you to be there
- to protect him from himself.
- Yeah.
You little fucking cunt.
Ah... Fuck.
I don't normally
say this, but...
You're like family to me.
I care about you, Neville.
You're like you're me own.
You fuck.
Fucking...
Haynes wanted it.
Not me. I had to go along.
Get down there quick.
You can save him.
It's all right, Dennis,
you won't feel a thing.
Argh!
Okay, go.
Hold him, hold him!
Argh!
No! Fucking...
- Cut him down, cut him down!
- All right, all right.
Sierra Foxtrot
from Kilo One, over.
Kilo One, send.
Attempted suicide
in CSU, over.
Come on then, boy.
Eric. Eric stay, please.
Oh, shit.
It's all right,
it's all right.
You're all right,
you're all right.
Daddy's here, I'm here.
I'm here, I'm here.
Okay.
Eric.
- Blood!
- Eric.
Eric.
Hey,
fucking answer me, blood.
Else it's you, bruv.
We're coming for you.
Fuck off,
you bunch of tarts.
Hey, you fuck off.
You all right, bruv?
- Yeah, sweet.
- D Wing coming in!
Hey,
hold it down, yeah, bruvva.
All right, cool.
Half hour outside.
Come on,
do you good.
Dad!
Proud to be your dad.
- Thanks, guv.
- Welcome, son.