When the editor of Playboy
told me I'd won
"Playmate of the year,"
the first thing out of my
mouth was, "are you sure?"
Did your brother
mind you being in the magazine?
I think, uh, my brother
was a little shy
because he has friends
who are 18 years old,
17 years old, who said,
you know,"hey,
your sister's in Playboy."
But his friends...
Well, I remember when I came
home to visit the family
and they came over
and they said,
"I couldn't believe it.
We saw you in Playboy,"
and they said,
"How'd you get in?"
And, "it's so wonderful."
And then he started thinking
that, you know, that...
That is pretty neat.
You know, my sister...
Playboy's motto is
"The girl next door."
They look for girls
that are wholesome and
fresh and young and naive,
they look for all of that.
So most of those girls do, uh,
have that type of background.
It took me 5 months to shoot
my Playmate-of-the-year layout.
I shot over 20,000 pictures.
It's perfection.
They don't go for just,
uh, great nude shots.
They go for art. Perfect art.
And I'm proud of that.
And, um, um,
I'm happy to share that
with somebody
who can appreciate it.
Would you like
to be just like your sister
when you grow up?
Yeah.
Why?
Because I'm proud of her.
Hi. How are you?
Hello.
Paul Snider.
Yeah, I'm Paul Snider.
How are you doing?
Snider.
Paul.
Hello.
Ha, ha, yeah.
Paul Snider.
Ah, fuck you.
Fuck you all, bastards.
He seemed a little
pissed off at something.
What, I don't know.
But not a bad guy.
He's a good tipper.
How'd he make his money?
All sorts of ways.
He did something for
me here at the club,
a cockamamie idea.
He was always promoting
some cockamamie idea.
What kind of idea was this?
A wet t-shirt contest
using all-local talent.
All right, Milly.
Oh, Milly!
There she goes.
All right, Milly!
Come on out. Really
show them what you've got!
Milly is Vancouver's
own Dolly parton.
Thank you, sweetheart.
And here comes number four.
It's lovely pat.
All right.
Just step right up
on the runway.
There she goes.
Watch her go. Whoa!
We're all getting wet.
Look at that head go.
Look at that head go!
There she is.
Whoa, baby.
All right.
Whoa!
Not much difference,
is there, guys, huh?
Good sport.
Come on, give her
a nice round of applause.
All right, here comes jeri.
All right,
let's get another one in.
Come on, there, get in there.
We've got 2, 2 just like that.
Now give me 3. Come on,
Milly, get in there.
3 for the price of one.
Paul cleared
almost $900 for himself.
Pretty good, I thought.
You should have
raised your minimum.
You should have advertised.
You blew it, man.
You blew it because
you're too cheap.
Tomorrow, Mac.
He wasn't always easy to take.
How else did he make his money?
Oh, Jesus. He'd try anything.
He pimped...
Did you say pimped?
Did I say that?
Did I say pimped?
Yeah, I guess I did.
With a couple of girls,
at least that's what I heard.
Oh, yeah,
he had something to do
with those big auto shows.
He supplied them with
hostesses, models, something.
Had the hots for cars,
cars and girls, girls and cars!
Yet one thing about
that little cocker,
he could remember
everybody's name
if he just met 'em
or met 'em 5 years ago.
He always remembered the name.
Now, I admire that.
It's a real gift.
A real gift.
They seem like really nice guys.
Al is from racine. Ford.
And Harry and Bob
are from Seattle.
Oldsmobile.
I feel funny.
It's just dinner
and some laughs.
That's it?
I'll talk to them again.
They're really nice guys.
They'll tell me straight.
If they expect more...
Some guys would...
If they expect more,
then it's off, ok?
It's off.
I am not fucking
for money, Paul.
She's not, but I am.
Ha ha ha ha!
Look, let me talk to them again
to get it straightened out.
He's a cheap hustler.
He even looks pimpish.
Why she wants to marry him?
Some kind of loyalty, I guess.
Get some of our people
to call Vancouver,
check him out,
see if there's anything.
Last name Snider, S-N-I-D-E-R.
First given, Paul,
second given, Leslie.
Yeah, I know him.
Small-timer.
Kind of a joke, really.
Always trying something.
Always in trouble.
The loan sharks, mostly.
Jeez, this isn't funny, man!
I... I... I'm getting s-sick.
Let me up. I'm getting sick.
Look at my suit.
That's a $400 suit.
That wasn't funny, man.
I mean, let's be
civilized, huh, man?
Oh, shit!
That was dangerous,
very dangerous.
And humiliating.
Please, Snider!
Do yourself a favor.
Don't say any more, please.
7 points is too much, man.
You shouldn't
humiliate me, Charlie.
Here we go again.
Charlie. Come on, Charlie.
Please, Charlie.
Charlie, you bastard!
You smart bastards,
everybody kissing your ass.
Everybody down on
their fucking knees!
Well...
Not me. I don't
kiss ass for nobody.
You're not gonna forget me.
You rotten fuckers,
you tried to kill me.
I found her, you didn't.
I found her.
I was working in this
Dairy Queen part-time
while I went to high school,
and one day this
gentleman walked in
with this gorgeous blonde.
She had a fur coat on.
They both had fur coats on.
And I had this ponytail
and this little smock on.
And I said, "can I help you?"
And he said, "well,
what's your name?"
Ha. Well, what's your name?
Dorothy. Can I help you?
You're beautiful.
Me?
May I take your order now?
I'll have something sweet,
soft, and white.
You.
Will you please
take their order?
Jesus, Paul!
She's really beautiful.
She's a baby.
Get them while
they're young, right?
I'll have a banana split...
God, I didn't go out
with boys very much.
I was very straight.
Uh, I couldn't talk
to people easily.
So, when do you
get out of school?
June, I hope.
Do you like the car?
Well, one day you'll
have a better one.
A Mercedes, maybe.
They're hot.
♪ If you want my body ♪
♪ and you think I'm sexy ♪
I'm gonna get it for you.
♪ Come on, sugar, let me know ♪
♪ If you really need me ♪
♪ Just reach out and touch me ♪
♪ Come on, honey, tell me so ♪
♪ Tell me so, babe ♪
Excuse me, sir.
The management has asked
me to speak to you.
Your fly is open,
and the whole restaurant
can see your dong.
Someone waiting on me.
That's new.
It's very nice here.
If you like Italian food,
I know a real knockout place.
I'll take you tomorrow night.
I like pizza.
Well, this is northern
Italian, 3 stars.
I know the maitre d'.
Oh.
Is there something wrong
with me? I probably
have a piece of lettuce
on my nose or something.
No, no, no, no.
It's just the light.
The way the light
catches your eyes.
Oh. You're an expert,
aren't you?
Expert at what?
Oh.
I found this in the coleslaw
at the salad bar.
It's got your name is on it.
It's not the Mercedes.
Is this a joke?
It's a real topaz,
2 carats.
It's beautiful.
Well, here's this teenager
in a town in Canada
working in a tasty freeze
or a dairy queen,
et cetera, whatever,
and this, uh...
Street-wise guy...
Yeah, I suppose initially,
he would have some flashy
appeal for her, yeah.
♪ Here comes the sun ♪
♪ La da Dee Dee ♪
I always screw that up.
♪ Sun and I say ♪
♪ It's all right ♪
Well, that's enough of that.
I don't think I'm any threat
to Paul McCartney, do you?
This is pretty.
I made it,
tried to sell them.
Must have been hard to do.
Something like this must
be really hard to do.
It's so pretty.
I'm a little high.
Your hand is shaking.
Oh, and big.
I have the biggest hands.
I never wanted to hold
hands with any boys,
'cause my hands were
always bigger than his.
I don't think I'm any good,
you know what I mean?
I have a feeling I'm no good.
I'm the first?
Well, there was
this football player.
What else?
Oh, it was plain awful.
He was so rough,
and it was all over so fast.
Wham-bam-thank-you-
ma'am, type. Ha.
I'm not really sure
it happened at all,
but I... I guess it did,
'cause he told
everybody at school
I was a lousy...
Hi.
How are you?
Hello.
That's it, yeah.
All right.
Hello.
Ha ha. Oh, my, don't we...
Ha ha... Look sharp?
Come in.
She's not ready yet.
Pour vous.
Oh, they're beautiful.
I better put them in
water right away.
She and Eileen have been
upstairs getting ready
since this morning.
You'd think it was a coronation
instead of a high school prom.
Hiya, George.
Goin' bowlin'?
Oh, lord, he looks
like a tango dancer.
He's a friend of mine.
Who?
Telly savalas. Kojak.
Bullshit.
Is this too much lipstick?
He said not to use too much.
Does it look all right?
Is this too much eye shadow?
I thought I had a vase but...
Get your feet off.
Yes, ma'am.
That was a pretty expensive
dress you bought Dorothy.
Oh, it seemed right for her.
She's almost ready.
You should see her.
Smell, mom.
Ooh.
Smell me, George.
Get out of here.
Come on.
Aw.
Smell it, Paul. Real deep.
Mmm!
That's what she smells like.
It's called toilet water.
Wait! Hold on a second.
The orchid is for Dorothy,
and the gardenia's for you.
Thank you.
He's here!
We both got a present!
They like the way you smell.
That Eileen is a knockout.
All the ladies in
this house are knockouts.
Bullshit again.
George.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
Here she comes, everybody.
She looks like a movie star!
Ahh!
Doesn't she look beautiful?
Terrific.
You look lovely.
Can we take a picture, mom?
I have a camera in the car.
I'll be right back.
Can I take the picture,
Paul? Sure.
♪ Don't go changin' ♪
♪ To try and please me ♪
♪ You never let me down before ♪
♪ Mm-mm ♪
♪ Don't imagine ♪
♪ You're too familiar ♪
♪ And I don't see you anymore ♪
♪ I would not leave you ♪
♪ In times of trouble ♪
♪ We never could have ♪
♪ come this far ♪
♪ Mm-mm ♪
♪ I took the good times ♪
♪ I'll take the bad times... ♪
Hi, Dorothy.
How are you?
Oh, hi.
That's him.
Who?
The bigmouth.
The football player.
Yeah, that's him, all right.
A jock.
How'd you know?
Just by the smart-ass
way he said your name.
Does he think I'm stupid
not to pick up on that?
Oh, now, don't start
any trouble, please?
Ha ha. It won't be any trouble.
♪ ...Although I might not ♪
♪ seem to care ♪
♪ I don't want clever ♪
♪ Conversation ♪
Jesus Christ! Who did that?
Excuse us.
Very funny. Big joke, eh?
You hurt him, Paul, didn't you?
Ha. Not enough, the prick.
♪ I want you ♪
♪ just the way you are ♪
I'm very romantic,
and I like little surprises
and, you know, little
gestures like flowers
or a call when
you don't expect it,
and, you know, things like that.
Not... not sexual things.
Well, would it surprise you
if I asked you
to take off your clothes
right now?
Would you do it?
No.
Well, why not?
That's...
That's not romantic. That's...
It took me five 5
to shoot my Playmate layout.
I shot over 20,000 pictures.
Sit up,
put your knees together
and hug 'em.
Like this?
Like that.
That's nice.
How about opening
the shirt a little?
I can't.
Oh, yes, you can.
It's fun.
Ok.
What are you doing?
Paul.
Wet your lips
and open your mouth.
What?
You know, like you
did last night.
Paul.
I can do that.
Dorothy?
Dorothy Stratten,
Playboy centerfold.
You're on Street Talk.
Hi, miss Stratten,
my name is George.
Hi, George.
Listen, we were sitting
around the garage,
and we had this question...
Uh, what's it like
to pose, uh, nude?
I mean, how's it feel?
It feels a little
chilly sometimes.
Score one for Dorothy.
We're talking with
Dorothy Stratten.
Oh, god, I look fat in that one.
Oh, jeez. I hope my mother
never sees these.
Oh, god, my mother.
What time is it?
4:30.
Hi, mom?
Yes, I know.
I'm sorry.
Give me a chance
to explain, mom.
It got so late,
I thought you'd be sleeping.
I didn't want to wake you.
I'm staying over
at Nancy's house.
No, I'm not with him.
Well, he showed
me some polaroids,
and wanted me to do
some test shots.
And we, uh, we made a deal.
If she got accepted,
I'd get $1,000.
Otherwise, nothing.
That's the usual finder's fee
that Playboy pays... A thousand.
He really believed in this girl,
or else he just
wanted to screw her.
I'm still not sure
which, maybe both.
Anyway, he convinced me.
Oh, there you go.
Ok, eyes to me.
Throw your head back.
That's it.
Sorry.
Forget it, Dorothy.
You looked better the other way.
You're holding that scarf
like it was a security blanket.
Here, come on, just relax.
Yeah.
Arch your back.
Tuck in the tummy.
I think were gonna like
that that much better.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
That's it. Good girl.
That's perfect.
Right there!
Look over here, Dorothy,
and open your mouth.
What stop are you using?
Could I talk to you
for a minute?
Listen, Dorothy, I'm gonna
wait in the dressing room.
Too many directors.
Ok.
Now maybe we can
get some work done.
That's good.
All right.
All right,
now throw your head
back a little bit
and give me a smile.
Ok, that's good.
Ok, now give me a little pout.
That a girl. That's good.
Ok, now, relax the hands again.
Now, think about an animal.
Ok.
Yeah, make it a wild animal.
It's starting to
get hot in here!
That's the way.
That's the way. All right.
Yes, all right.
Now, the little girl
is starting to learn here.
Let's go. Nice.
Oh, that's good. Now,
hold that, that's nice.
Ha ha. Yes, yes.
Little girl is growing up.
All right, here we go.
Oh, that's nice.
That's nice. Hold that.
Hold that.
Oh, yes, yes, yes!
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
She's like a big, sweet kid.
Polite, too.
No scars.
Maybe have to do
something with her hair.
Not overweight.
I like her a lot.
How old?
18, I think.
Now,
here's what
the son of a bitch did.
Now, I worked my ass off.
Then he turns around
and he goes
to another photographer,
and he uses my stuff to
convince the other guy
that the girl is good.
Then he sends
the other guy's test
into Playboy
and screws me out
of the finder's fee...
A 1,000 bucks.
Ha ha ha. I mean,
the guy is a bastard.
They'll fly her
to L.A. first-class,
take some more
test shots of her,
and then they'll decide
if they want to use her
in the magazine or not.
That's really
all there is to it.
That's all, huh?
But we do need your consent
because of her age.
And if I don't sign?
Then we both jump out a window.
No, seriously,
if you don't sign,
then it's... All off.
She wants to go.
I'm slowly beginning
to get the idea
that you want her to go.
That leaves me, her mother.
I know this could be a
real opportunity for us.
It could change our lives.
What is this "us," "our"?
I don't see any naked
pictures of you here, Paul.
I don't see any pictures of you
with your privates hanging out
for the whole world to look at.
Let's get the camera.
I'm willing.
Oh, I bet you are.
Oh, I don't know.
She wouldn't even
walk around the house
in a nightgown
before she met you.
Do you know who reads Playboy?
No, tell me.
Movie producers, directors,
agents, TV people.
The people who produce
Charlie's Angels
read Playboy.
I have this feeling
about Dorothy,
this hunch that she's
gonna be a big star
in the movies or on TV,
I don't know,
but a really big star.
But she's gonna need help.
You can't do it alone.
You need somebody.
And you're gonna be
that somebody?
I know all the tricks,
I know all the con games.
Hey, I know all
the bullshitting.
There's plenty
of that, believe me.
Together, we could be somebody.
People would know who we are.
People would know our names.
People would treat us
that special way,
the way they treat stars.
People would...
Hell, we'd walk into
a restaurant, people...
I do love her.
What did you say?
I said I love her.
Funny. I could have sworn
you said, "I love it."
You don't like me, do you?
I love Dorothy.
The answer's no.
Why?
Give me a reason.
I don't have to
give you a reason.
I'm her mother.
That's the reason.
Your attention, please.
Western Airlines flight 468
nonstop for Los Angeles...
I don't want to go.
You're dying to go.
I wish you were coming with me.
Everybody's looking
at us. Did you notice?
Yeah, a little.
Straighten up, angel.
You're slouching.
Better?
Makes you look taller.
Makes you look like a queen.
I never signed it.
Somehow it got signed, yes.
But I didn't sign it.
I can only guess how.
I never would have signed it.
Have you met him yet?
Who?
The man. The man. Hefner.
Oh, Paul, he's wonderful,
like a father or something.
Oh, excuse me. I'm sorry.
That's ok.
Where are you calling from?
Mr. Hefner's house.
You mean the mansion?
Oh, Paul, I wish
you could be here.
I wish you could
be here with me.
You should see it.
I've never seen
so many pretty girls
in my whole life.
I suddenly feel really ugly.
Is Jimmy caan there?
Who?
Sonny corleone in the godfather.
I didn't see it.
He's probably there.
He and hef are pals.
Who did you meet?
Oh, so many people.
Let me think.
I think he's a famous
athlete or something.
Name's Billy Bob,
or Willy Joe,
something like that.
Batton? Billy Joe batton?
He sort of half smiles
all the time.
Ha ha. Well, watch out
for that smile.
He's a real cocksman.
Got a bad reputation.
Is telly there?
Did you meet telly?
I don't think so. I'm not sure.
Ok, Dorothy,
when you meet people,
you should really make an effort
to try to remember their names.
It makes a good impression.
I'll try from now on.
Paul, everything
is happening so fast.
It's a little bananas.
Let's see,
they're going to
shoot some more shots
or whatever they
call them, and they say
I'm not going to be
anniversary Playmate,
but they did say
I've got a good chance,
a very good chance
of being centerfold for August.
Mr. Hefner will make
the decision next week.
Isn't it terrific?
I am so excited.
What's he like?
Mr. Hefner?
Oh, nice, like I said.
But I get the feeling
that everybody trembles a little
when they mention his name.
You know, "Mr. Hefner
wants to see you."
Was he wearing pajamas?
How'd you know?
I've been wanting to
have this talk
with you for a while,
but I guess we've been
keeping you pretty busy.
I'll say.
Coffee for
miss Stratten. Yes, sir.
Dorothy, it's going to
take a couple weeks or so
to come to a decision
on this thing, et cetera.
Oh, I understand.
Thank you.
Have a seat.
In the meantime, I imagine
you could use some money.
Yes, I could.
I thought so.
Anyway, our people thought
we could fit you in
as a bunny at our club
in century city.
Tips are pretty good.
That'll be just fine.
And I'll see if I can't
get them to find you
a little apartment
while you're waiting.
Not too expensive.
In the meantime,
you can stay here,
if you'd like,
in one of the guest rooms.
Well, I can look for
an apartment myself.
No. We'll do all that for you.
Anyway, I have a feeling
it's all very
temporary, Dorothy.
I think
there are very big
things ahead for you.
I don't know about that,
but I'll certainly try for you.
I know you will.
Well, that just leaves my, uh,
my speech.
Ready?
Yes, sir.
Playboy
is a very special
magazine, Dorothy.
There's no other
magazine like it.
All the writers,
editors, photographers,
all the girls, et cetera,
we all have a very
special relationship.
It's not like
any other magazine.
We're all like a...
Well, we're just like a family.
A family.
It's like having a family.
The whole magazine
is like having a family.
See?
I know a lot of people
say that's a lot of bull,
but that's how I think of it.
That's how we all think of it.
It's kind of a world
within a world.
It's a...
Well, it's a family.
Wasn't that neat about the job
and the apartment
and everything?
Hey, listen, it all
sounds terrific.
And, god, meeting
all those people.
They're good contacts.
It can only help.
Know what I mean?
I think so.
I'll call tomorrow.
I love you.
I love you, too. Bye.
Thanks, Johnny.
That was some phone call.
How's the kid doing?
Sounds like it's
going really right.
She was calling
from hef's place.
Johnny, be a pal and pour me
about that much scotch.
She's in the mansion?
Billy Joe batton
is making a big play for her.
the football player...
Making a move on Dorothy?
Ah, it figures.
That's the kind of town L.A. is.
Jesus Christ... I'd
be going outta my skull
if Billy Joe batton
was trying to get
in my girl's pants.
Ah... what's her name?
♪ Off ramp, it's the best ♪
♪ Take me off ramp ♪
♪ Off ramp ♪
♪ You're my best ♪
♪ Doo-doo doo-doo ♪
♪ doo-doo doo-doo ♪
♪ Off ramp! ♪
I don't like to do, like,
black dudes and white
dudes kind of stuff,
but the thing I've noticed
about black dudes
and white dudes
is that, like, black people
chastise their kids more.
And as a result,
you don't see black people
doing crazy things,
like shooting the president.
That's true,
'cause if a brother would
have shot the president,
as they were leading him
away, it'd be like,
"look, man, just don't
tell my mama, man.
My mama gonna kill me, man..."
Here she comes.
That's room 217 and 218.
219.
At the Beverly Hilton.
No, I can't, really.
Oops. That's not the way
we're supposed to do that.
That's called the bunny dip.
Playboy's motto
is "the girl next door."
They look for girls
that are wholesome and
fresh and young and naive.
They look for all of that,
so most of those girls
do, uh, have that type
of background.
You know, Snider,
I have this theory about you.
Oh, you do, do you?
I think the reason why
you're so good in bed
is because you
just plain try harder.
I mean, baby, you
put in an 8-hour day
in 15 minutes.
Ha ha ha!
Dorothy, on answering
MACHINE: Hi, it's me.
I called earlier, too,
hold it.
But I didn't leave a message.
I just wanted to let you know
that I had to work late,
but I'll call again
when I get home.
Oh, thanks for the flowers.
They're beautiful.
Ooh, flowers.
These machines
make me so nervous.
I always feel like
if I don't talk fast,
my 30 seconds will run out.
Yes, I think it would be
a terrific idea
if you take Eileen
to the carnival.
She'd love it.
Just don't let her
eat too much junk food.
I love you. Bye.
Whew, I made it.
That must be number one.
I bet you was scared as hell
she was out last night
doin' what we just did.
Look I got to get up early,
so why don't you get
the fuck outta here?
♪ Let it hang out, baby ♪
♪ Let it hang out now ♪
♪ Now, now-now-now ♪
♪ Let it hang out, baby ♪
♪ Everybody work out ♪
♪ Sookie, Sookie, Sookie, ♪
♪ Sookie ♪
♪ Sookie Sookie sooo! ♪
♪ Let it hang out, baby ♪
♪ Do the boomerang... ♪
We got the best one, sweetheart.
We got a Mercedes.
♪ Let it hang out, baby ♪
What can I get you?
Uh, 2 hot dogs,
mustard and relish,
2 orange drinks, a bag
of potato chips, fries.
And 2 caramel corn.
But no junk food. Right?
Right.
You know, that health
food'll kill you.
Don't go on the rocket again.
That's my ride, sweetheart.
Eileen, straighten up.
You're slouching again.
I know...
You want me to look
like a centerfold.
Honest? You mean it?
August.
Oh, Mr. Hefner, thank you.
Miss Stratton,
what about your mother?
How did she feel about
your photos in Playboy?
I don't think she liked
it at all at first,
but then she started
getting calls from
several of her friends
congratulating her,
and she said to me,
"I feel like a movie star."
I mean, she was so excited.
$10,000!
They're gonna give me $10,000
for having my picture taken.
Feels good, huh?
Oh, yes. Yes.
Dorothy, do you really love me?
Yes. Yes, I do.
Well, all right.
Here's how it lays out then.
I'll grab a plane by Wednesday,
Thursday at the latest,
and I'll be there.
Well, I wouldn't
have that much time
to spend with you.
It's like they've got me
running all day long.
Then when we get some time,
we'll just run over
to Vegas and do it.
We'll just do it, right?
Do it? Do what?
How about getting married?
We'll get married, Dorothy...
Make it permanent,
just like that.
We'll make it
a permanent team...
For life.
We had everything going for us,
but you fucks
wouldn't let me in.
Big fucking deal.
Well, you can take
your magazine,
your mansion, and your movies
and shove them
all up your ass now.
Liar!
I have missed you.
I have missed you so much.
Guess we should go, huh?
Somebody told Mr. Hefner
I was going to pick you up.
It's his personal car.
A little embarrassing, isn't it?
No.
♪ ...To the Gulf of Mexico ♪
♪ To lake Charles, Louisiana ♪
♪ Little bessie girl ♪
♪ that I once knew ♪
♪ She told me just to ♪
♪ come on by ♪
♪ If there's anything ♪
♪ that she could do ♪
♪ Up on cripple creek, ♪
♪ she sends me ♪
♪ If I spring a leak, ♪
♪ she mends me ♪
♪ I don't have to speak, ♪
♪ she defends me ♪
♪ A drunkard's dream ♪
♪ if I ever did see one ♪
♪ Good-luck hag, she stung me ♪
♪ To the race track I did go... ♪
Hi.
You're Dorothy.
We met the other night.
Oh, yes. This is Paul Snider.
And you are...
I'm sorry. I forgot.
That's ok. I'm...
Vince Roberts.
I'm a big fan.
Thanks.
Hey, listen, that was
my favorite TV show.
Thank you.
Canceled, huh?
Yeah.
Any chance they'll
bring it back?
I don't think so.
Ah, too bad.
Aren't many actors
around like you.
They're all lightweights.
We need heavyweights like you.
You break my heart.
Jeez, it's been a while
since that show was on.
What is it, a year now?
3.
It's been 3 years
since you were on TV?
Yeah.
Isn't that something?
Bad scripts, huh?
I guess so.
Dorothy, there you are.
Excuse me.
Yeah, you know,
good writers are really
hard to find out here.
I've got a couple
of projects in mind...
I could use a good writer,
and I can't find any.
I mean, not
a decent one, anyway,
and when you do,
they won't do what
you tell 'em to do.
Yeah. Some writers
are like that.
Would you excuse me?
I'm just gonna...
Well, I for one
hope you're back
on the tube real soon.
Thanks.
Um, are you working
on anything new now?
Just reading.
Excuse me.
See ya, Vince.
You should have talked to him.
There's hef. Straighten up.
Hi, Dorothy.
Look at her. Oh, wow...
Anytime.
Ok.
I see you got here all right.
Mr. Hefner, this is Paul Snider.
Paul, Mr. Hefner.
If a man has a right
to find god in his own way,
he has a right
to go to the devil
in his own way.
Here's another one...
Descriptions of murder
which we consider a crime
are acceptable in art
and literature,
but descriptions of sex
are prohibited.
Our society
has put hate above love,
favored killing over living.
Right?
Pretty close, but I think
I said "favored
death over life."
What? I don't understand. What?
He's quoting me.
Old ones at that.
That's great stuff.
Fine piece of work. Fine...
God, I feel hef here and I
are old friends.
You know, I think we even
have some mutual buddies.
Is, uh, telly at this bash?
Telly?
Savalas.
Telly savalas. He's an old pal.
Thought I might see him here.
Oh!
Hey, Bobo.
Ah, Bobo. Bobo, I want you
to meet Dorothy Stratten.
Hi. Hi.
Bobo Weller.
I still got your centerfold
on my wall.
Oh, wow.
Your favorite book
is The Hite Report.
You like Rod Stewart,
Linda Ronstadt,
and Boz Scaggs, right?
Oh, wow.
I'd know that bod anywhere.
What's your name? Snider.
Dorothy?
Paul.
Excuse us a second. Dorothy...
What do you do?
Uh, I'm a personal manager.
Phil, say hello
to Dorothy Stratten.
He says say hello,
you say hello.
Hello, Dorothy Stratten.
I'm Phil Wass.
Hello.
Phil produces
movies... sometimes.
Dorothy's our Miss August.
We're all very
excited about her.
Maybe if you play
your cards right,
we might just
let you present her
in her film debut.
She's a very fine actress.
Mr. Hefner...
Don't worry. He doesn't
know a damn thing
about acting anyway.
Excuse me. I'll
leave you 2 alone.
Listen, I am doing a film
called Ball Bearings.
Maybe you'd like to drop
over the office tomorrow
and meet the director.
What have I got to lose?
You don't know the director.
Excuse me
for a minute. Yeah, sure.
It's not much of a part...
She'll take it.
Hi. Paul Snider here.
Miss Stratten,
I saw your movie debut
in ball bearings.
Uh-oh. Ha ha...
Uh-oh is right.
No, I'm not the film critic,
but that wasn't much of a part.
Well, I wasn't much
of an actress, either.
Oh? Are you better now?
Oh, god, I hope so.
I'm studying.
The classics?
No. Acting. I don't know
anything about music.
Sorry. I'm so embarrassed.
Hefner didn't like it
when I quoted him.
I shoulda kept my mouth shut.
Damn.
I think it just surprised him.
Dumb move.
Maybe you were a little nervous.
Oh...
Look at these stupid clothes.
Dumb move quoting him.
You know, I was a little nervous
the first night
I was there, too...
Jesus, will you
stop sayin' that!
I mean, why the hell
should I be nervous
around Hefner and that crowd?
Bunch of smart asses...
With their stupid,
faggy hairstyles,
smug bastards.
And that Vince Roberts...
Boy, does he want to
get into your pants.
He's not going to.
He's asked you out, hasn't he?
Yes.
What'd you say?
I said I had a fella,
a steady fella.
You did?
Maybe you should.
Should what?
Go out with him.
He said he was
reading some projects.
Ho, I'm really tired.
Let's go to bed.
Do you think Hefner liked me?
Paul, come on...
I don't think he liked me.
If he just got to know me...
Look, Mr. Hefner,
are you trying to tell me
that you don't want me
to marry Paul?
You have to understand, Dorothy,
that a third party
is in kind of a funny
position, et cetera,
when you're trying to
counsel somebody
about marriage.
You never know how
it's going to end up.
It's not because
I'm going to be
a Playmate, is it?
No, no.
Of course not.
Well, some of the
other girls told me
that you didn't
like the playmates
to be married.
Frankly, we think
it's better for the image
if they're not.
You understand that, don't you?
But several have been.
Just a moment, Sam.
Who? Give me some names.
Cindy was.
Ginger, I think.
That's right. Cindy, ginger...
Look, he can't
just come right out
and say it.
He's trying to
tell you something.
I know he is,
and I think I know what
he's trying to tell me,
but I don't think
he understands.
What's wrong with him?
Well, he's...
He's got the personality
of a pimp.
That was improper.
I shouldn't have said that.
Ohh, Mr. Hefner,
that's just the way
he used to dress.
He doesn't dress
like that anymore.
Oh, god...
I am so confused.
I don't think
anybody understands.
I owe it to him.
Miss Stratten,
may I ask you
a personal question?
36-24-36.
No. I have that information
in the press release right here.
As a matter of fact,
I have it several times.
I just wanted to know
if you're married.
Yes.
I've been married
about 3 months.
I wonder why you
looked at miss Davis
when I asked you that.
No reason.
No reason? Is he
traveling with you?
No, he's not.
And why is that?
I'd like miss Stratten
to answer me...
If she would.
He's in L.A. working.
What sort of work does he do?
He's doing a show.
I'm sorry, I didn't hear that.
Could you repeat that
again a little louder?
Hal wants to someday be
the first black president
of the United States!
Git on down now!
Show 'em what you can do!
Whoo!
Give him a hand! Hal dafoe!
Whoa!
This is number 3. This is Mikey!
Mikey... whoa...
Loves to read poetry.
And Mike hopes to someday
meet Olivia Newton-John!
Oh, stop. Stop it right there.
Ladies, stop. I think
I see something.
Michael, you should be
ashamed of yourself.
No padding!
Now, that's the rules, boys!
Now, you turn around,
you bad boy.
Naughty, naughty.
Don't ever do that again!
Here we go with number 5!
This is dick!
Oh, ladies, let me tell ya,
dick speaks fluent French!
I found out last night.
Oh, dicky, show 'em
what you got, baby.
Voulez-vous coucher
avec moi, dicky?
What do you think
of dick's dong?
Hey, ladies, what do you think
of all of our beautiful,
well-hung, young men?
Ok, guys...
5, 6, 7, 8...
Whooo!
♪ ...Got to know this one thing ♪
♪ No man ♪
♪ Does it all by himself ♪
♪ I said young man ♪
♪ Put your pride on the shelf ♪
♪ And just go there ♪
♪ To the ymca... ♪
Comes to 874 bucks apiece.
Sorry, Paul.
Those are the figures.
I don't understand.
This place was packed.
Well, they weren't exactly
a bunch of big spenders.
It was no shriners convention.
Any projects in the offing,
any new films?
Well, when I go
back to Los Angeles,
I start a movie called
Wednesday's child.
What's Wednesday's child about?
Well, you're going to
spend a lot of time
watching me get
tied up and beaten.
It's not a classic. Ha ha.
Sal, will you
put the pellet
in her mouth, please?
Careful now. Don't bite it.
There's a call for you, Dorothy.
Not now, for Christ's sake.
All right, put the gun
back up to her face.
He says his line,
you shake you head no. Harder!
And then he slaps you across
the face with the gun.
What?
You bit the pellet.
Ha ha... God damn it!
What's so funny? Ha ha ha...
I'm sorry. Clean her up, please.
Oh, god.
Should I tell him to call back?
He's called 3 times.
Fucking blood pellets.
Jesus...
Look, I'm sorry to bother you,
but I found it.
It's beautiful.
Paul, listen,
I don't think this is
a very good time to talk.
I am sitting here freaking out.
It's a Paul Snider/
Dorothy Stratten car
if ever I've seen one.
But it's a little
more than I figured.
Look, I was wondering,
is there any way
that you could get
to the bank today?
I'd like to sign the papers
before somebody else grabs it.
We're gonna need another 3,000.
On your lunch hour maybe?
We've been spending
a lot of money lately.
Maybe we should wait.
There's not a better-looking set
of wheels in this
whole friggin' town.
Do you think
it might be possible
to drag miss Stratten
off the phone
for a few minutes?
He'll wait.
I'm gonna get a license plate
that spells out "STAR 80."
It's fan-fucking-tastic.
You know... S-T-A-R 8-0?
That's you.
STAR 80.
Everyone in this town
is going to know who we are.
Can you get to the bank?
Please?
Ok. Ok, I'll go to the bank.
That's my queen.
David... David...
Would you bring her in here?
What time do you think
we're gonna finish?
Late. Very late.
Late. He said very late.
If you're not gonna be home,
I thought I'd like to drop by
the mansion for a while.
Can you give him a call
and fix it for me,
let him know I'm coming?
Dorothy, is that all right?
Mm-hmm.
Damn, I wish he
wouldn't call me here.
All right.
It's a Sci-Fi.
She, uh, she plays a robot.
Get in there, you mother.
They offered us 10,000.
Well, I put a stop
to that but fast.
Startin' it
right after we finish
Wednesday's Child.
She is so beautiful.
You can just tell she's
Mr. Hefner's favorite.
She's the best.
The best.
You're pretty good-
looking yourself, Bobo.
I'm all right.
Hi, Lonni.
♪ Because you had ♪
♪ to be a big shot, didn't ya? ♪
♪ You had to open up your mouth ♪
Where's Dorothy?
Working. She called
and asked if it was ok
for him to come over.
I just couldn't say no to her.
Oh, hi, hef.
Hi, hef.
♪ You had to have ♪
♪ a white-hot spotlight ♪
♪ You had to be ♪
♪ a big shot last night... ♪
You know, that reminds me.
I got to talk to him later.
I got an idea for
a poster with Dorothy.
Damn.
Oh...
Want to get something to eat?
I'm always hungry.
Does it look like
I'm gaining weight?
Well, I, uh,
first met Mr. Snider
at the Playboy mansion.
Snider, Paul. Hi.
Martin Gebber.
We were just going
to feed our face.
Would you join us?
Sure.
Practice here, Dr. Gebber?
Uh, Geb, please.
No, Newport Beach,
but I plan to move here.
Internist?
Plastic surgery.
Cosmetic mostly.
Paul is married
to Dorothy Stratten.
He also manages her.
The chicken.
He told me he and Dorothy
were looking for
a new place to live.
And maybe since I was
moving my practice to L.A.,
we could find a place together,
share expenses.
We moved in in October,
and I took the top half,
they lived on the first floor.
It was right near the freeway,
noisy as hell.
But it suited me fine.
It had a yard for king,
a garage for my Rolls-Royce.
The Rolls
is an investment for me.
It's an investment.
I'm not into status symbols
like most people out here.
It's an investment, ok?
Dorothy had already
done the centerfold,
miss August.
She had already done parts
in Fantasy Island
and Buck Rogers.
Things were moving fast for her.
I became very fond of her.
She was handling her public
visibility very well.
She was maturing
very fast for 19,
but to me,
she was just a friend.
Understand?
A friend.
I had a gal...
Robin.
I stayed with her
most of the time,
so I didn't spend much time
at the house.
But we'd get together
once in a while...
Sunday afternoon barbecue
with a few friends.
Paul, did you
make this contraption yourself?
12 of them.
Who are you selling them to?
To anybody who wants to buy one.
She's got no real
competition, you know.
Oh, what about miss December?
Vicki something?
Next to Dorothy? You're kidding.
Where do you want me to put it?
In the garage, with all
the other "no sales."
You should buy
one of those, Nick.
If Hefner has sense at all,
it will be Dorothy.
There's nobody else
in the same class.
Has to be.
Then you can all
visit us in bel air.
Do you hear that? What?
You're moving to bel air.
Oh, yeah, sure. When?
When you become
Playmate of the year.
Get out of here.
No, I'm with him. I think
you're gonna be Playmate
of the year, too.
What the hell is this?
What is it?
I know what that is.
I saw that in a shop
on Santa Monica.
Oh, my god!
Now, don't tell us
that's for exercise, Paul.
I think I know what it's for.
So do I.
What is it?
Somebody tell me. What?
Well...
Tell her.
Ask the man who built it.
I only made it as a joke.
What did I do wrong?
I did everything you did.
Somebody tell me, huh?
What I did wrong?
You rotten fuckers!
Ooh!
Ah!
Hi, Aram.
Who's the girl in the red cap?
Ah. That's Dorothy Stratten.
Why don't you put her
in your picture, Aram?
No. Huh?
I need a real actress.
Let her read. You'll see.
Who handles her?
Peter Rose, Rose and matz.
Only deal with Peter.
Why?
I'll tell you another time.
Nice to see you, Aram.
It'll be a big picture...
5-6 million.
I hear he's got Newman.
I wish I knew
some of his pictures.
Time step? Did you
ever see time step?
No.
The last chase?
No. If it comes up,
should I lie?
No, I don't think so.
Just be yourself,
and you'll be fine.
You've got a quality,
Dorothy. Hef spotted it,
and I'm sure Aram will, too.
Oh, Peter, that's agent talk.
That's friend talk.
Well, here we are.
Gulp.
I'll wait here.
It shouldn't take long.
Ok.
Time step
and the last chase, right?
Right.
A girl can't just
sit back and say,
well, now my photos have
been seen all over the world
in Playboy,
and I'm sure many producers
and directors
have seen my pictures,
and if they like me,
they'll call me.
It just doesn't work that way.
So you still
have to go out there
and seek opportunity?
Absolutely.
Don't be nervous.
He's really very nice.
Hi.
I'm Aram.
I'm Dorothy.
Yeah, I know.
Uh...
You nervous?
Yes.
Yeah, so am I.
Well, do you know
anything about me?
Time Step was wonderful.
Uh, that's The Last Chase.
You didn't see Time Step,
did you?
No, but I'm going to.
Would you like to see
some of my pictures?
No.
Should I read for you?
Uh...
No. No.
Aram says it's
going to be a closed set
and a very tight schedule.
He says we'll be working
really long days...
14, 16 hours.
I know New York.
We wouldn't have that much time
to see each other.
I could really help you there.
Something is screwy, Dorothy.
Something else is going on here.
I can feel it.
Aram says I'm going to need
every bit of concentration.
He did, huh?
Aram says this,
and Aram says that.
Will you stop with
the fucking Aram!
Aram is a very nice man.
Oh, shit!
They're all nice to you!
"Everybody is wonderful.
Mr. Hefner is wonderful."
The whole fucking world
is wonderful to you!
Well, fuck Aram!
Or maybe you have already.
Oh, Paul...
I mean, maybe that's
what this is all about,
huh? Maybe that's
what has been going on
at those rehearsals
up at his house.
Did you fuck him?
Is that how you got the part?
That's how it's done,
out here, isn't it?
That's really unfair.
It may sound corny,
but I have to concentrate
my love on just one man.
I'm faithful.
God,
I'm such a jerk sometimes.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I do understand.
It's...
It's just that I
love you so damn much.
Paul, let's go back
to Vancouver.
I don't have to do this movie.
I'm afraid.
Of what?
I don't know.
It was nice in Vancouver.
Please, let's go back.
Angel, we can't go back.
We'd lose all the contacts
we've made here.
Please.
No.
Uh-uh.
But, I have this terrific idea.
I'm your manager, right?
Well, as your manager,
I think you should
go to New York
and become a big movie star.
I'll stay here and work
on the Dorothy Stratten poster.
It's gonna make us a fortune.
Good idea?
It came to me just like that.
Hey.
You're my queen.
I don't know. He seemed in
exceptionally good spirits
just before she left,
helping her with this and that,
being really attentive.
Gave her a going-away party.
Must have cost a fortune.
Borrowed my rolls
to drive her to the airport.
Said, "the queen
has to go in style."
And after she left,
he came back here to the house.
And then...
Then he did the damnedest thing.
I'm still not sure
why he did it,
but he built
a doghouse for king.
A beautiful doghouse.
Craziest thing.
I didn't think he even knew
I had a dog.
Yeah, move, Caroline.
Ok. Yeah, come. Give me more.
Come in a little further.
Yeah, hold that, hold that.
Yeah, Mark it. Mark it.
Take a look, Gary.
Is that ok?
That's nice.
You shouldn't chew gum.
It's got sugar in it.
Thank you.
It's him. I know it.
I can tell from the way
she says his name on the phone.
And what does she say?
Not too much. She always says
she's been working
on Aram's film all day
and doesn't feel like talking.
Why can't you accept that?
She calls it film.
Christ, she never
said "film" before.
She always said
movie or picture,
but never film.
I bet he calls it film.
That's hardly sufficient cause
to put yourself
through all this.
He's feeding her coke.
Paul, I know you're upset,
but you shouldn't even say that.
And knowing Dorothy, I doubt it.
You're wrong.
Yeah? She kept
sniffing last night...
Through the whole conversation
she kept sniffing.
Maybe she's got a cold.
Yeah, that's what she said.
Cold, my ass!
Paul, you're gonna
make yourself loony
if you keep going like this.
You got to realize,
Dorothy is every man's fantasy.
Everybody who sees her,
or even her picture
in a magazine,
for that matter,
is going to be coming after her.
And there's always
gonna be someone
who's richer than you,
more famous than you,
has a longer penis than you,
and there's nothing
you can do about it.
She's not herself, man!
Look, I know these guys, geb.
They stick a little coke
up a girl's nose,
they figure she'll do anything.
Jesus, you haven't heard
one word I've said.
Look, all you can do is
let her know you love her.
Get your own feet on the ground.
Stop complaining!
Go out and get yourself a job,
get something going,
and try to make her
proud of you!
I know it.
You're right.
I can handle this.
I can handle it.
What kind of business
are you in?
Well, I was thinking
in terms of a health spa.
You know who Dorothy Stratten
is, don't you?
I think so.
Well, that's my wife,
and I'm her personal manager...
I was thinking of calling it
"Dorothy Stratten's health spa."
All modern equipment...
Nautilus, steam, sauna.
You know, they're into
that sort of thing out here.
You just give them
white teeth, a suntan,
and some muscles,
and bang! You're a hit.
I saw a hot location
on Santa Monica.
The real estate woman
said the owner
wants 2,500 a month,
but she's pretty sure
it'll come down.
What do you think?
Something wrong, Dorothy?
No.
Well, what do you think?
It sounds ok.
You don't like it.
I can tell by the tone
of your voice
you don't like it. Shit!
Paul, do you think
we could talk tomorrow?
I'm really tired, I guess.
Yeah, sure. Uh...
Listen...
I called a couple
of times last night.
Did, uh, you get
any of my messages?
Yes, I did,
but we worked very late.
How late?
I don't remember exactly.
I was with Peggy.
Peggy Johnson.
Who's Peggy Johnson?
She's an actress.
She's in the film, too.
You'd like her.
She's really nice.
Film.
Anyway, we've become friends,
and it got so late
that I spent the night
at her apartment.
I didn't want to wake you.
I thought you'd be sleeping.
I'm staying at Nancy's house.
I guess you didn't
want to wake me.
Paul, I'm sorry,
I didn't hear you.
Nothing. It was nothing.
So, uh, how are things
going on the set?
Are you, uh,
getting along all right
with the director?
Because I think it's important
that an actress and her director
should have a good relationship.
There must be something
you can do,
for Christ's sake.
He's stealing my wife.
Can't we sue him?
Can't we make the bastard pay?
Pay for something.
Sue? For what?
For what?
You're the detective.
You're supposed to be able
to tell me for what.
Are you her manager?
Yes.
Got any contracts, any papers?
No, but...
But it was something
you both talked about, right?
It was understood, right?
Yes. It was understood.
You had a verbal contract,
then, right?
That's right, we had
a verbal contract.
We're a team.
I discovered her.
Yeah, I know. You said that.
Well, maybe...
Maybe we can try
suing him for enticement
to breach her management
contract with you.
Yeah, that's it.
Not so fast. I'm not a lawyer.
I'd have to check with one.
I know we'd have to have
documentation.
I'd like to kill
the son of a bitch.
I can't help you with that.
He called me 5 times last night.
I didn't get any sleep.
That's why I kept
missing my Mark.
We'll get it after lunch.
I don't know why
I feel this loyalty to him.
He's fooling around. I know it.
He's got other women.
He always has.
At about 3:00 in the morning,
every fucking creep on the strip
seems to wind up at our joint.
He didn't look any different
from any other schmuck
in this town,
but he talked nicer.
He said he could
get me in Playboy,
that he knew hef.
Said he could get me
in the movies.
He had a business card
and a Mercedes 450 sl,
so what the fuck?
What about the health club idea?
He couldn't get
any backing for it.
No one would give him any money.
What?
Say it.
Well, I just don't think
you should lend your name
to something like that...
A health club...
With him or anyone else.
The more he fails,
the more he seems
to hang on to me.
Yeah, this is Paul Snider.
I've been trying
to get through to hef...
Snider.
Mr. Hefner is out of town.
Can I help you?
Who is this?
Who am I talking to?
I'm Roy, Mr. Hefner's assistant.
Oh. Well, listen, Roy,
here's what it is.
I'd like to drop by
the mansion tonight
and talk to hef.
I've already
told you... yeah, right. He's out of town.
Oh, shit. I should've known
you were bullshitting me.
There is someone
I'd like him to see.
Would you maybe leave my
name at the gate, Roy?
I'm very sorry, I can't do that.
Only Mr. Hefner himself
can do that.
Aw, sure you can, Roy.
I know it's done.
It's done all the time.
Come on, give it a try.
Hey, we've met, haven't we, Roy?
I was probably with Dorothy...
Dorothy Stratten?
I know who you are,
but I can't help you.
I will leave
your message, though.
Ok, sport, leave the message.
I'll call back later.
What the fuck is this?
I bet you don't
even know Hefner.
What time
would be a good time
to call back?
I really couldn't tell you.
No. Well, I didn't
think you could.
Thanks for all your help, Roy.
You're welcome.
Are we or aren't we going?
That son of a bitch
was there the whole time.
Do you want to stay with him?
Do you want to leave him?
What do you want to do?
I think you're going to
need some legal help.
You should probably
talk to a lawyer.
Dorothy, you just can't
let him do this to you.
He's got to give you
more freedom.
You got to understand,
you're just not the same girl
you were in Vancouver.
You've grown. You've matured.
I see it happening
right before my eyes,
every day.
You're unique, Dorothy.
And you have a unique gift.
You've grown, and
he stayed the same.
Hollywood hasn't changed my values
or my personality,
but it's certainly
made me wiser.
I think I've gained 5 years
experience in 18 months.
You've outgrown him.
This is a little rough.
Are you sure
you want to hear it?
Ok.
"She's practically
moved out of the wyndham.
"She usually goes there
after shooting,
"picks up messages,
"and walks over to the Plaza.
"He's in suite 1210.
"They usually eat in the hotel.
"And in the morning,
she goes back to the wyndham
"where she waits
for the studio car
to come pick her up."
So you were right all along.
It is him.
They're hiding it pretty good.
You all right?
Yeah, sure.
I just got to take a piss.
If we just had something...
A letter, a tape,
anything where she talks
about the management thing,
I think we might have something.
On enticement, I mean.
Ah, fuck both of them.
Why don't we just say,
"look, you want her,
pal? You can have her.
But you're gonna have to pay."
I know how you feel,
but I don't think so.
Hey, maybe there's something
in alienation of affections.
I don't think so.
Yeah, it was 379.95 new.
And you can have it
for 250... Even.
It's only a year old.
Ha ha ha ha!
It was only fired on Sundays
by a little old
psychotic schoolteacher.
How do you load it?
Oh, easy. It takes one to 5.
I'll give you one.
You put it in the chamber,
you press the button,
and you cock it...
And she's ready to go.
Lefty, huh?
Feels good, doesn't it?
Well, we got a sale?
We was acting really weird.
He pasted, pinned, scotch-taped,
glued photos of her, of him,
of him and her, of her and him,
all over the downstairs
like some sort of
bizarre shrine.
Weird.
Frankly...
I thought it was a little
like a soap opera.
And I obviously misread him.
That's pretty much
the same picture.
Aw, look.
That's Eileen.
What a kid.
I was thinking
of bringing her
down here for a visit
when Dorothy comes back.
That'd be fun.
It's rough. It's really rough.
I'm not sure I can take it.
Listen, Robin, I want
to get these to king.
Did you see the prom picture?
Did I show that to you?
I bought her this white dress.
Here it is.
I've never felt this way before.
She broke my heart.
Nice, huh?
I've got a better one.
Paul, look, we really
got to move along.
It's when I'm holding her
and we were dancing.
It's really nice.
Wait just a second.
We'll be back
in an hour, all right?
Ok, man.
Ok, we'll catch you later.
Take it easy, ok?
Whoa!
Man, I thought I'd crack up
when he said, "she's
broken my heart."
I didn't think it was funny.
I can take a bragging Snider.
I can take a conniving Snider.
King!
Yeah!
I just can't stomach
a sentimental Snider.
It's about the only time
I've liked him.
Get outta here. Why?
I don't know, really.
This macho guy like that.
You don't suppose
he'd do anything crazy,
do you?
Like what?
I don't know. Like hurt himself?
Not if it means
mussing his hair.
Can't we talk now?
I'm goin' a little crazy.
I'll see you
when I come to Los Angeles.
You closed
the joint bank account.
Yes.
Why?
I'll send you some money.
You didn't answer why?
I thought it best.
For what?
Our situation, Paul.
I have to hang up now.
No, please don't hang up.
Just what the hell
is our situation?
Jesus, tell me something,
will you?
Look, if you've had an affair,
that's ok with me. I understand.
But that doesn't
mean that we should
throw the whole marriage
down the toilet.
Please, Dorothy.
Please tell me where I stand.
I have to have more freedom.
I want more freedom.
Dorothy, you can have
more freedom, honest.
That's not enough.
Things change.
I'm not the same girl
I was in Vancouver.
No, you sure ain't.
Sounds like you
got a writer now.
I don't understand
what you're saying.
I mean, I have a hunch
that you're sitting
on Aram's knee right now,
and he's moving your mouth.
He's pulling the strings!
We'll talk when I come in.
You're living with him.
I'm staying at his house
temporarily.
You're living with him.
You're sleeping with him.
You're fucking him.
Why don't you have
the guts to say it?
You're doing it.
Why can't you say it?
Take off the goddamn glasses.
I'm broke.
Paul, I'll take care
of you. You know that.
Eileen is here, isn't she?
Listen, too much
has happened already.
I'll call you in a few days.
Maybe we can talk then.
About a divorce?
Is that what you mean?
Yes.
I could change.
Jesus, give me
a chance, will you?
I'll call.
God damn it, he must be
having you followed.
Son of a bitch.
I don't want you
to see him anymore.
The whole thing can be
handled in other ways.
Promise me
you won't see him anymore.
He seemed so scared.
Hey, sis, come on in! Please?
Dorothy, I want you to promise.
Ok, I promise.
How's the water?
It's warm.
Yeah?
You'll probably
have to lead her a little.
Try and get her
to talk about Aram.
Juicy stuff if you can.
Even better you can get her
to talk about
the management thing.
She's gonna come back.
I know it.
Yeah, sure.
Just in case.
He kept changing
his fucking mind.
First he said I could have
some of her clothes,
and then he said no,
she was coming back to him.
Didn't mean a shit to me.
Marker.
Dorothy?
Sam, I'm here.
Well, I just have
a few errands to run,
then I'll be back about
2:30. I promised Eileen
that we'd buy out
rodeo drive this afternoon.
Oh, wow! It's you!
You're in the TV guide.
I'm sorry, Aram.
Eileen's going a little
bananas over something.
I didn't hear what you said.
I said I won't be home
till late.
I've got to stop at the lab.
Look, it's you!
Just a second.
Take it back a little.
There, try it there.
She said,
"I'll always take care of you."
Yeah. Now, if you can
get her to repeat that...
Ok.
Push the button down,
walk around and talk.
It's gonna be a different shirt.
So?
Well, what do you
want me to say?
Anything. Anything.
Hi, I'm Paul Snider.
Paul Snider, hi.
More, more.
Testing. 1, 2, 3, 4.
Ok.
You know, we just need
to straighten some things out.
Once we see each other,
it'll be ok.
Damn.
Damn thing doesn't work.
Hell, we don't need it anyway.
Once we spend
some time together,
everything's going
to be fine again.
I know it.
He called me in the morning
and said he was
going to see her that day.
It says Thursday at 8 P.M.
Can we watch it together?
Absolutely. We've got a date.
I'll see you 2:30, ok?
He still had some crazy idea
he could put it
all back together again.
He vacuumed the rug,
he polished the vinyl,
he cleaned the whole house.
She arrived a little after noon.
The plan was, I was
to call in an hour or so
to see how it was going.
Uh, we worked out a little code
so she wouldn't know
he was talking to me.
I tried to get through
on the phone, but, uh...
You know what happened.
I've been drinking.
I'm nervous.
I am, too.
Look at my hand.
This is a new shirt.
I must have combed my hair
a dozen times.
I guess I had some crazy idea
I could win you back.
A real schmuck, huh?
There's no chance, is there?
We have some things
we should talk about.
I know.
I love you, Dorothy.
I love you so much.
I can give you $7,000.
Please come back to me.
It's half of everything I have.
Let's make it
like it was before.
Please?
I have some of it here with me.
Remember the ring I gave you?
Yes.
Still have it?
I don't think
I want to go on
living without you.
I bought a gun.
Oh, Paul.
Things will change for you.
No!
What? You mean
maybe I'll grow up
to be a big movie director?
Or own a big magazine?
Is that what you mean?
Maybe then I could get you back!
Is that what you're saying?
Sit down!
Those fucking bastards!
I want to leave.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Please don't leave.
I want to show you something.
Please stay just a minute.
I won't do that again.
Please.
I have been working
my ass off on these.
God, I hope you like them.
They're a lot better than
the Farrah fawcett ones,
aren't they?
She sold 5 million of them
in one year.
Well, which one do you think?
We could at least still
be in business together.
Don't shake your fuckin'
head like that at me!
Is it too small-time for
the big movie star, huh?
Too tasteless, maybe?
I think...
Oh ho ho! You think.
I think that we
should break cleanly.
Oh.
I want it to be over.
Hmm. Is that what Aram
told you to say?
And what the fuck is $7,000?!
You think I'm stupid.
I may not be
a Hefner or an Aram,
but I'm not stupid.
Not just yet, you don't!
Not until you tell me
where the rest of the money is.
Who's holding it for you?
Tell me!
It's half.
Liar! Get the fuck outta here!
"I'll always
take care of you, Paul."
"I love you, Paul."
"I owe you so much, Paul."
Liar! Liar!
Liar!
I don't think you've ever known
how much I love you.
Well, maybe now you will.
You think I'm faking, don't you?
You don't think
I'd do it, do you?
You think I'm a coward.
Let's not hurt
each other anymore, please.
Oh, please.
Too small-time for you now, huh?
You slept with him last night...
Didn't you?
Answer me.
Sure you did.
You fucked the big director.
Well, now me.
I'll give you a chance to judge,
a chance to see
who the real man is!
Aah!
Stop it, Paul!
You're gonna do me
a big favor, huh?
Ok.
That's me...
A charity case.
Now, try to think of
dear Aram if you can.
They're killing me.
They're trying to kill me.
Those bastards!
Operator, can you
check on a number for me?
I think it's out of order.
What's the number, sir?
474-5051.
Hold on.
Ok.
Can you hear me?
They did this.
My queen.
Her name is Billie Joan Worth.
She's very sweet.
I was thinking she's
a maybe for November.
Where's she from?
Davenport, Iowa.
I like her.
Well, Bill, she's a technician
for a pharmaceutical company
who likes all sports,
reading, and photography.
You want sugar?
Uh, a little, please.
You won't forget Paul Snider.
Now that people recognize you,
what's it like?
Oh.
I'll go shopping in the store,
and I'll see people going,
"Hey, that's Dorothy Stratten."
Or, "Hey, can we have
a picture of you?
Can we have an autograph?"
Or even in the airport,
you know,
people rushing up to me
to get my autograph
or something.
That's really exciting for me.