Episode 90
Bermes came out with a new purse!
Oh, this is the new item.
The design is so lovely.
What do I do?
What do you mean what do you do?
You improper married woman!
Get your head straight!
But it's so pretty.
Should I buy this and stop? And think
that it's the last purse of my life.
I heard you got fired from
your dad's company.
And you have money to buy it?
Of course I don't. No money, and
no where to get money.
But you're impressive! How'd you think
of biting your brother's ear?
You think I can think straight
when I'm pissed off?
Is there really no way?
Stop drooling and give up!
You'll be comfortable
once you give up.
There's no way right?
Ah hah! There was that!
/ What's that?
I thought of it! Where I
can get money.
According to asteroid 2013 QR3,
Korea's astronomical observation
center's magnetic field will
be temporarily disturbed.
On the 18th, a section of radiowave
communication may be hindered.
What is she saying?
She's not saying anything hard.
Because of the potato star, there
can be a peak.
More than a peak, she's saying there
could be a communication disturbance.
Something like your
cell phone not working.
You rascal, you didn't know either!
That's that! A peak and
your cell phone.
That something like that can happen.
Wouldn't it be different? A peak is
electronic, and phones are radiowaves.
That's enough. Just leave it alone.
Okay. / All right!
I'll ask him. Okay, hang up!
Why is Min-hyuk so late / I'm home!
Oh, you're here?
/ You came at a good time.
Why? / You want to go on
a blind date?
She's the daughter of the president
of Min-guk company, and she's from UCLA.
I don't want to.
Why? Just meet her at least once?
Hearing about her, it's such a waste!
No, I don't want to.
/ Is there someone you're meeting?
There's no one like that.
/ Then why not?
He really...
Brother-in-law!
Sister-in-law! What brings you here?
With no call?
I just stopped by while in the
neighborhood.
Yeah? Good, come in!
There's nothing going on?
No, there's nothing. I just wanted a
date with you!
Date? I like it! Let's go eat
something delicious.
You're the best!
Sit there, wait a little. I'll finish
this quickly. / Take your time!
When is everyone coming?
Should we get some coffee? I'm tired
from coming in early.
Klimt is having an exhibition
in Korea.
What? Print?
Klimt is having an exhibition.
Gustav Klimt.
What's a klmit?
He's an artist! You dummy,
you don't even know that?
Oh, an artist?
Then we can go see it! I'll show it to
you. Where is it being held?
No thanks!
You don't even know his name.
You said it's Klimt.
I just learned his name.
No thanks, the tickets are expensive
and we don't even have time.
Brother-in-law! Why do I like
you so much?
I like you a lot, too!
The sushi earlier was good, right?
Yeah, it was so good!
I'm gonna come again next time!
Yeah, when your husband comes,
bring him. I'll buy.
Really? There's really no one
but my brother-in-law!
It's a department store!
Should we stop by?
A department store?
Do you have something to buy?
Nope! I just want to eye shop!
Are you busy? Then you can go first.
Okay! Then I'll leave. / I'm so happy
that I'm here with you.
I'm such a fool for you!
This purse is so pretty!
It's exactly my style!
I can't have these bags anymore, right?
I would've bought it if it was
before marriage.
'Cause I'm not a poor
musician anymore...
[5 years ago]
Is it okay to get this much from you?
What do I do? I feel bad.
Well, it's been a while since
you've come to Korea.
I love you! You know that I like
you the most in this world!
This break, I came to Korea
to see you!
Yeah, thanks Sister-in-law.
Kim Do-san, get your head straight!
Don't fall for that expression!
Remember the hard time you had
'cause of the card debt!
Don't ever fall for it!
Yeah Sister-in-law, you're married now.
These bags...
Oh yeah! I forgot that I had an
appointment with a client later!
I'm sorry, I'll leave first.
Look around and go!
He didn't fall for it.
What do you mean what do I do?
I'll try it again.
Drink this. Oh! I heard Soo-young
came by your office earlier!
Yeah! Did Sister-in-law tell you?
No, I called earlier and your
assistant told me.
But why didn't you tell me?
Just... I forgot.
Why did she go to your office all
of a sudden?
Is there something that brat
wants from you?
Be careful! Don't suffer like
that like before.
Honey, you think I'm stupid?
To suffer the same as before?
Mr. President!
Are you on your way to work?
Yes, I was on my way from getting
a lift lap. / Get in, I'll take you.
No, it's okay. There's a bus stop right
up... / Get in. You have luggage.
I'm on my way to work anyway, too.
Okay then...
What's that?
"Brother-in-law, have a great day!"
I'm so jealous.
Your sister-in-law is beautiful,
but her actions are pretty too!
I'm truly jealous. It's 'cause I
don't have a sister-in-law.
If I had a sister-in-law like this, I
would've given everything to her!
For sure, this is a maneuver.
If you look outwardly, it looks like
an extremely thoughtful gift.
But, it's actually really easy to
order this through the computer.
Sister-in-law is using a
maneuver on me.
"Sister-in-law"
Brother-in-law! Did you receive
what I sent you?
But Sister-in-law, why this
kind of stuff?
I'm so touched! Thanks!
Nah, it's not much!
Okay then, bye! / Brother-in-law!
Yeah? What?
I'm going to that area tomorrow,
but can you buy me dinner?
Dinner? / Yeah, are you busy?
Tomorrow, I have an appointment.
/ Aww, what?
I even sent you a gift!
Wow, I'm so sad!
The brother-in-law I liked the most in
the world is becoming 2nd place!
Ahhh, really? Then...
let's... get dinner!
Really? Wow, I'm so happy!
then I'll call you when I get
to that area. Okay!
Yeah, dinner should be okay.
But no more. Never. Don't go
against your opponent Kim Do-sang!
Are the public relations going well?
Yes. Because it's a college student
area, we're doing an event for them.
Something like finding
your fated partner.
And as a gift for applying
we're giving Kong Kong burgers.
Give the details to Team Manager Yoon.
So you're saying that it's going well?
/ Yes.
Do you believe in fate or soul mates,
too, Nah Jin-ah?
Girls believe that kind of stuff.
Yes. Two people being together
from many many people.
Honestly, I think that's a miracle that
occurs through a series of events.
There's that! That you'll meet
the person you'll meet.
That's fate's / That's what girls!
Yes?
That's a a fairy tale
that girls believe.
Excuse me? / That's not fate,
that's probability.
Person A throws a dice and if six comes
out five times in a row, that'll be cool.
Saying, how can six come out five
times in a row?
But if there are thousands of people
throwing the dice like person A,
and if there's not a single person who
gets six five times like person A,
isn't that even more weird?
It's such an obvious result
of probability.
Those who believe in fate don't go
beyond the average in total.
Yeah...
How do you know so many delicious
places? Of course, you're the best!
Nah, eat a lot!
Eating steak is making me
want a glass of wine!
Shall we get a glass of wine each?
/ Wine?
Sure! Let's drink a little.
What is this? Wine in the
middle of the day?
Let's be careful. There's some
kind of plan.
Excuse me.
Father, should we fish here?
Sit down here.
It's great weather to fish. / Right?
Sister-in-law, aren't you drinking
too much? It's still early.
Wine is okay.
Brother-in-law...
Honestly, I'm having a hard
time these days.
What is?
Married life.
I did get married, but Jang-yool
goes to America right away.
I wondered to myself "what is this"
while sitting at the single room.
The sympathy card? It's finally begun.
Should I not have gotten married?
Was I too immature?
I think like this...
I can't even sleep at night.
Even though I try to sleep, I end
up staring at the ceiling.
Sister-in-law, why are you crying?
Oh, the crying card? That's too easy!
Now she's gonna talk about
not having money.
In order to get out of this
sadness,
if there was some small
thing of happiness,
something I can feel...
In my position, it's not like I can
enjoy what I want to enjoy...
Honestly...
I can't even buy the things I like...
Exactly. The blow is coming
out slowly.
Sister-in-law, even if you're like
that, I'm not the same Kim Do-sang!
I'm the upgraded Kim Do-sang!
You shouldn't do this.
Brother-in-law, you should've gone
against our marriage even more.
You should have stopped me till the end.
If you did, then I...
Sister-in-law.
I guess she's taking the crying card
a little longer.
If I don't do anything,
she'll continue to...
Okay, I have to backfire in order
to end this thing quickly.
Sister-in-law...
I'm having a hard time too.
Excuse me? Why?
People think if you're a lawyer,
you earn money so easily.
But honestly, there's no other job
as hard as a lawyer's job.
Because the economy's hard,
just to finish one job,
I have to endure and hear
all kinds of stuff!
Why am I like this?
What is this? Is he using
a maneuver?
And I hear all this cussing and
so many bad words!
Sometimes I get treated worse
than a bug!
Brother-in-law, you've upgraded.
No, who would treat you
worse than a bug?
Be strong!
There's stuff you don't know.
I don't want to talk about this
anymore. If you're done, we should go.
What is this? This backfire?
Noh Soo-young, concentrate!
What do I do? Think of a way to
get out of this critical situation!
What're you doing? Let's go.
/ Oh, yeah...
No, grab him
Brother-in-law!
Huh? / Just throw anything!
Oh yeah! Can I tell that thing to my sister?
That thing?
Yeah, that thing.
I threw it!
You threw it? / Yeah.
Isn't your bait too big?
The bait has to be big in order
to catch a big one.
But that's too big. / It has to be at
least this big to catch a big one.
What is that thing...?
It's nothing. Never mind.
That thing? Right at the end
of the game?
No, it's a bluff. Don't fall for
it Kim Do-sang.
I ate the steak well! Let's go.
Wait, Sister-in-law! / Yes?
Why do you stop mid-sentence?
Kim Do-sang! Ignore it! It's a bluff!
What?
That thing...what is it?
Don't get sucked in!
You know the best!
Am I falling for it?
Honestly, although I'm a girl,
I understand.
That can happen to you too...
Huh? What does that...?
Should we drink just one more
glass of wine?
It bit! It bit it!
We don't know yet, we should
wait a little more.
One more glass?
Nah, I want to go home, I'm tired.
What? You should finish something
you started.
What is that thing?
Why are you being like that?
You know everything.
Darn, what do I say? A bar? Warranty?
Emergency funds? A girl?
Brother-in-law, the four things a woman
can't handle of her husband are
bars, warranties, emergency
funds, and other women.
But Brother-in-law, how can you do
that? That's just too much...
Let's not talk about it anymore.
Let's talk next time.
So what? What about those things?
I have no idea what you're
talking about!
Wow, I'm starting to get mad.
I liked you the best.
But okay. Let's talk next time.
/ Sister-in-law!
Yes?
Since we're already out, should
I buy you a purse?
Yes? A purse?
Yeah! The one we saw at
the department store.
It looked like it'll look good on you.
Why? I don't need a purse.
No, just, it's 'cause
I want to buy it for you!
Please let me buy it for you. I want
to see you holding it.
Please, it's my wish!
Your wish?
It jerked!
It jerked, right?
You got it!!
You'll meet the person
you have to meet.
Why are you saying this nonsense
all of a sudden?
Do you believe that? The fated love
that comes out in dramas and movies.
Crazy. Movies and dramas are what
plant ridiculous fantasies in women.
Do you believe that stuff too?
Never.
But there are times when I wish
that it's true.
Are you talking about her?
If it were true,
if it were fate for me to come all
the way here to meet her,
what's the meaning of that fate?
Miss Nah Jin-ah?
Is there anything you're good at?
Why didn't you say that you were sick?
Because, I wanted to win it.
Mr. President? You were here?
At this hospital?
Who are you?
It's me, Nah Jin-ah.
It'll get caught by us.
It's Miss Nah Jin-ah.
If I get better after the surgery,
will you marry me?
Mr. President.
Am I now an official employee?
Congratulations, Miss Nah Jin-ah.
Thank you!
Driver Kim, drop me off here
and go home first.
Here?
Yes, Mr. President!
What are you doing?
Are you still at the office?
Yes? Yes.
Is everyone there?
/ No, I'm here alone.
Everyone left, and Hongb- I mean Jun-
hyuk went to Myungdong for an event.
Do you have a lot of work left?
No, I just need to send one more
email and I'm done.
Then...
you know Namsan tower?
Go there by 8.
The Namsan tower? Why-
/ I'll wait for you.
Brother-in-law! You didn't have to do
this! It's so expensive.
It's okay! Expensive?
Make it over 36 months...
If unni finds out, she'll get mad.
Keep it a secret from her.
About that too...
We got a big fish, a big fish!
Isn't it impressive?
Wow, there are even fish that
get caught by you!
Yeah!
Yeah, the more you look,
the stupider it looks!
That's why it gets caught by you!
What's wrong with this?!
What do I do?
The internet's not working!
But I have to send it...
Mr. President, there's a problem, so I
have to personally turn in the papers.
I'll be about 20 minutes late.
I'm sorry.
Because of Asteroid 2013 QR3's
sudden change,
radio wave connections are disturbing
internet connections,
as well as signal lights, causing
more traffic than usual.
Mr. President, I'm on my way to
mountain Nam,
but because of the traffic, I'll be a
little more late. I'm sorry.
I didn't receive a call.
Did you call?
It's probably because of the radio
wave disturbance from the potato star.
Okay, I'm on my way.
Oh!
You didn't get a call from Sister-in-law?
No, just cause. Okay!
I at least blocked it with a purse.
Yeah, although I lost money,
at least I blocked that.
Yeah...
But...
what did I block?!
What did...
I block...?
I'm sorry, but which way is it
to the Namsan tower?
You can go this way.
Mr. President, I'll be one hour late
'cause I don't know the way there.
I'm truly sorry. If you're not there,
I'll think that you left.
Excuse me, we're sorry but...
Okay, I'm taking it.
You could've at least counted 1 2 3.
You have a new message from
Nah Jin-ah.
Driver, wait! Just drop me off here!
Excuse me, all the signal
lights are broken from here on out.
All vehicles are being stopped
so we can't go any further.
If you cross the street, there's a
bus that goes back the other way.
So please use that bus, or
the subway.
I'm sorry.
Nah Jin-ah!
What are you doing here?
/ What about you?
Me? It just happened. You?
Me too, it just happened.
What a surprise!
But you don't even know Klimt. Why
are you staring at it? You know it?
I'm a Klimt expert.
He's my favorite artist.
Meeting at a place like here. I
guess it's our ill-fated relationship!
I was hungry anyway, should
we eat fishcakes on the way home?
Hyung!
Mr. President!
I arrived so late at Namsan Tower.
I'm sorry.
I contacted you, but
I couldn't reach you.
If there's something for me to do,
I can do it-
It's okay, I had someone else do it.
I'm sorry.
But you two met and came together?
No.
We met in the streets really
surprisingly.
The bus I was riding had to stop
because of the stop lights...
I think the fact that two people meet
together is the result of
many events, so it's like a miracle.
There's that saying: The person you'll
meet, you will meet no matter what.
That's fate working.
Come eat! You were sleeping so
well, so I didn't wake you.
Someone who didn't know what
sleeping in was, slept in!
Yeah, weird things are happening!
Eat this spicy soup!
I caught this yesterday. I caught one
as big as my arm yesterday!
Mom? / Yeah? What?
The blind date you were talking
about? / Yeah.
If it's not too late, I'll do it.
It's a little uncomfortable...
/ It's not comfortable.
I saw an article about you.
I wanted to meet you in person.
Anyway, it'll end with disappointment.
/ How can you think so rationally?
Honey, you can play like this too!
How was it? / Aren't you gonna
meet again?
We're watching a concert
on the weekend.
I don 't think it's a bad idea
to have a third child.
Okay! / You don't have anything
to do tomorrow, right?
Why tomorrow? / It's best to do it when
the man is at his healthiest.
I heard you're doing well with the
person you met. Congratulations.