You Who Came From the Stars
When I was first left alone here...
I couldn't stop thinking about
when I would go back home.
Then I got a job at the
Meteorological Observatory.
Doctor Hong, you're still working?
Someone may think that you're
doing all the work here.
What book are you reading?
It's Sir Lee Soon Ji's book.
It never ceases to astonish me.
He calculated the astronomical constant and
calculated the lunar and solar eclipse dates.
It also gives us the exact calculation
of the orbits of the five planets.
Are you suggesting something
rather strange to the people?
Such as?
Like the earth we live on
is rotating.
And that it's round shaped.
It's true.
Goodness.
If the earth is rotating...
Then everyone would feel
too dizzy to stand up.
Also if it's round...
What makes you say such hearsay?
Why are you laughing?
If you look from very far away...
- You can see it.
- See what?
How beautiful our home,
the planet Earth, is.
Have you seen it from far away?
Earth is beautiful from far away.
Many from my home wanted to know
about Earth and wanted to visit.
This is how we come to Earth.
We terraformed an asteroid to camouflage
it as an ordinary asteroid.
To make sure the asteroid is invisible from
Earth, we enter at the perihelion.
In Earth years, this happens
about every 404 years.
Do I have to wait that long
if I miss this chance?
I don't know what will happen.
Gravity could offset the orbit.
More importantly,
if I cannot return this time.
It's likely that I will disappear soon.
I will likely die.
[My Love From Another Star
The Seventeenth Record]
Everything you want to do.
Let's do them ahead of time.
- Ahead of time?
- Yeah, ahead of time.
Let's do them all within a month.
Why? Why in a month?
Huh?
Why?
Why do we have to?
Huh?
I...
I am leaving.
What are you talking about?
Leave for where?
Where?
Where are you going?
Back to where I came from.
In a month...
I'm leaving to go back to
where I came from.
You're leaving?
You're going back?
Yeah.
Okay.
Go!
And then?
When are you going to be back?
Hmm? Tell me.
I'm good at waiting.
Huh?
One year?
Two years?
Ten years?
Are you not coming back?
You're not coming back?
Was that why?
That selfish thing you could do
or whatever?
Was that why, you jerk?
You're really...
You're the worst of all the jerks
I've seen.
A month?
Thank you! Thank you!
Bye.
- Good job.
- Thanks.
Are you going to Seoul?
Let me ride with you.
I'll get going then.
Thank you.
Cheon Song Yi!
Can you turn the music off?
I'm not in the mood.
Okay.
Beom! This is my car.
Sorry, she said she's not in the mood.
Do you have, 'As If I'm Shot'?
No, 'I'll Get Lost, You Go Your Way'.
No, no.
Do you have 'Never Let You Go'?
The biggest comet in the century,
ISON, has fully disintegrated.
The comet seemed to have gone through
nuclear fusion as it approached the Sun.
It could not withstand the
solar heat and gravity.
Deep South is revisiting
the Earth after 400 years.
It's approaching the Earth's orbit.
According to NASA, Deep South's
orbit overlaps with Earth's orbit.
Wait!
The biggest meteor shower
of the century is approaching.
Hey, why are you wearing
sunglasses at night?
What's wrong with her?
Did my Min Joon Hyung dump her?
Manager Do! I'll kill
him when I get him.
He's way out of Song Yi's league.
Director, her phone is off.
Is she out of her mind?
She disappeared all of the sudden.
Is this revenge for leaving
her behind last time?
- I think so.
- Hey!
Get someone else. I let her in my
movie when her career was over.
- Who?
- Cheon Song Yi's manager.
Boy, am I glad to see you.
- What do you think you are...
- Cheon Song Yi went to the hospital.
I'm sure you all remember how Cheon Song Yi
fell due to the mistake of the SFX team.
She received surgery because of organ
damage, and suffered pulmonary edema.
You made her re-do
the same scene nine times.
And then you liked the first cut the most.
And she must have gotten hurt from that.
Hence, she went to the hospital because
of her fever and abdominal pain without calling.
She is very sorry to have caused a delay.
Boy! Health comes first!
Schedules are meant to be re-scheduled.
- Reschedule it.
- Okay.
Rescheduling.
[Special Effects Lee Shin]
The number you've reached is not registered.
- You're late.
- Yeah.
I volunteered at the animal shelter today.
I see. Father told me.
You were receiving the
Young Entrepreneur Award.
I still have a far way to go,
but I got it.
Congratulations.
You are amazing.
Oh yeah.
I'm going to our eldest brother's
grave tomorrow with Mom.
You want to join us?
Oh no, I have plans tomorrow.
- I'll go alone later.
- He will be sorry to hear that.
He used to like you more than me.
- Good night.
- Okay.
Hey! Stop crying.
Let's talk!
Look at me.
You made a wish for me, Grandma.
I've learned to love.
It was a terrible thing.
It aches.
My heart is aching.
Help me.
Hey! Where are you going this early?
I feel stuffy. Jogging.
We need to talk.
I've got nothing to say to you.
You should at least answer my phone call.
Why weren't you answering?
What's the point?
You are leaving.
You're leaving in a month.
This is why I said it's not going to work.
Yeah! So I bugged off!
I said I'll let go.
Then you came out of nowhere
to be my manager.
You made me float in the air
and kissed me.
It was you!
Because you had me worried! You
signed a contract with the wrong man.
How is Jae Kyung a wrong man?
There were rumors about
you getting engaged.
- I think I'm going to get engaged.
- What?
Why do you care? You're
leaving in a month.
I'm going to get engaged with just anyone
on the date of your departure to show you.
- Do you mean that?
- Hello?
- Where are you Song Yi?
- I'm jogging.
You shouldn't over-do it.
I'm not. Where are you?
Stop right there!
Professor!
Oh my! It is you!
I didn't think I'd see you here.
Who...
Don't you remember?
It's me, Go Hye Mi.
I was in your class last year
and the year before that.
I said that you looked just like my ex, Sam Dong.
(Kim Soo Hyun's role in Dream High.)
Oh... did you?
I wanted to re-take your class so
I turned in a blank sheet for final.
You really don't remember me?
I don't know.
Hul! I'm hurt!
My parents almost kicked me
out for getting an F.
I think I can remember a bit.
Perhaps it's because I've gotten
prettier than last year.
I lost some baby fat and...
I hear that I've gotten mature.
Oh! Look what you have on your face.
You're like a baby.
One sec.
I'm okay.
Professor! Are you okay?
Are you hurt?
Yeah.
I'm okay.
Professor! You got a cell phone?
You used to only carry a pager.
- That's an improvement.
- It sort of happened.
Then can I have your number?
I'll text you later.
- That's a bit...
- Please?
Please? Please?
Tell me, hmm?
- Tell me, hmm?
- 0-1-0...
Do Min Joon! Didn't you have
something to tell me?
Huh? Yeah.
What do you want to do?
The timing is perfect for me.
You want to talk now or
not see me forever? Choose.
Bye.
Who the heck is that visor lady?
She looks like a fake Cheon Song Yi.
What happens if you don't go?
Can't you not go?
Yeah, I don't know where your home is.
Let's say that your home is somewhere.
But a person doesn't have
to live at home.
Most of the people in Seoul
are not from Seoul.
They have their homes in provinces,
but Seoul is like the second home to them.
This is on a different level.
I don't know what level that is.
I don't know!
And I don't want to know.
You said that you've lived here
for centuries!
Why now?
You lived here just fine!
Right when you've met me!
Right when I'm about to do something.
We haven't even had a good date.
Why now?
Can't you just...
Stay here with me?
If you won't then don't
get get me flustered.
Because you can just leave...
But I have to stay and live here...
Where you've left me behind.
So if you're leaving,
then leave quietly.
And leave me alone.
If that's what you want...
Then I will.
Elder brother died in an
accident exactly at my age.
You're right.
I didn't think I could
live after burying my child.
But so many years have already passed.
But I thought he couldn't drink.
That's how I remember him.
He could not.
Then why did he drink and drive that night?
The day after was my graduation.
He promised that he would come.
Your brother suffered
from depression then.
We only found out later after
the autopsy results came out.
There were drugs in his blood.
Antidepressants.
It didn't work out with the girl he liked.
I think that's why he made
such an extreme decision.
I had known him to never do such a thing.
Something must have gone wrong.
[S&C successor Lee Han Kyung
dies from drinking and driving]
Amitriptyline, chlorpheniramine...
[Autopsy showed anti-anxiety
and antidepressant medication.]
[Chlorpheniramine.]
I'm Lee Hee Kyung. I called you.
Nice to meet you. I've heard a lot
about you from Se Mi.
What's the reason you're telling me this?
He's your brother after all.
I thought that I had to stop him
because he is my brother.
In order to do that, I need to know how
much was actually done by him.
[Haneul Mental Institution]
Here. You can have all the meat.
I'm just going to eat the collagen part.
Like that's going to work.
Let's go eat grilled pork skin tomorrow.
I really don't want to age.
Then you shouldn't be drinking soju.
It's too hard without it.
You got cast in a movie.
You finally saw your dad again.
What could be so hard?
Have a drink with me.
You know that I don't drink.
Who cares? It's just you and me.
Don't keep it inside and cope
with it with a drink.
It would have been better
if it had never started.
It's too late now, because
it has already begun.
You asked me once.
How did I live alone for such a long time?
If I weren't lonely.
I did ask you that.
When I lived alone, I didn't
feel lonely at all.
Then for the first time I loved someone.
And now that I think I have to
leave her, I feel really lonely.
As if I'm the only one in the universe.
If I could turn back in time, I would.
So that I would have never met him.
That would be the best.
Then no matter how he much swayed me,
I would not be swayed.
I wouldn't like him either.
Just thinking about the days without him
makes me so sad that I want to die.
What's wrong with the lights?
Sir!
You should stop now.
It's so dark.
What should I do from now on?
Is it a blackout?
Yoon Jae!
Find a candle.
What is this?
I shouldn't have gotten him the drinks.
I thought he would make objects
float or something.
It's gotten serious.
There's not much time left.
What?
Why should I be here?
Why should I waste this
precious time with you?
I understand how you feel.
But you didn't have to say that.
Right now, every hour, every minute,
and every second, means a lot to me.
Why should I waste this precious time!
With you?
This is not where I want to be.
It's not here!
Gosh.
They say you speak from your
heart when you're drunk.
Now I know your true feelings.
30 years of friendship means
nothing when a girl is there.
Sir?
What are you doing over there?
- What are you doing?
- Move!
- What?
- I came out to see Cheon Song Yi's face.
What are you doing over there, you hypocrite!
Move! That's Cheon Song Yi's spot!
Stop.
Let's go inside.
Can't you find a better place
to use your power?
I shouldn't have made him drink.
What do I do now?
Oh my God.
When did you come in?
Who told you that you could be here?
Wake up right now!
Wake up and leave!
One, two, three!
You still don't get it?
You leave me no choice then.
I've tried.
What? He said that he never drinks.
I don't want to be with you, Mr. Jang.
What about me?
Who do you want to be with?
Cheon Song Yi.
[Widespread Blackout in Downtown Seoul Continues]
The kind of person I hate the most is the
one who loses his memory after drinking.
Sleeping somewhere other than
their home after getting drunk.
Not remembering anything
he has done the night before.
What makes a human, human?
It's free will that defines human.
But doing something against their will
due to mere alcohol consumption is...
Tsk, tsk.
What happened?
Yeah, what happened Do Min Joon?
I... I was...
You were lying down in my bed
completely drunk.
I can't remember.
Did I really do that?
No way.
I can't remember.
That's why you said that
you would never drink.
Because you teleport anywhere
and sleep anywhere.
And you can't even remember what happened.
Stay back a little.
- You're...
- I'm what?
I can't think straight.
Then what about this?
Leave! I don't want to see you ever again.
Are you kidding me?
Why did you just kiss me then?
- Does this make you mad?
- What?
That's exactly how I feel.
You confuse the heck out of me
when I'm not doing anything.
'I have to go.'
'I can't come back.'
Do you know how bad and selfish that is?
- You need to know that.
- Song Yi!
I'm coming in!
No!
- Why not?
- I don't feel like talking.
I'm not here to talk to you. I just want
to borrow some lotion. I didn't bring any.
I ran out!
Just let me rest!
You're so cheap!
What? Why aren't you leaving?
Do your teleport thing.
Go!
- It's not working.
- What the heck?
You came like that!
Why can't you leave?
Mom and Yoon Jae are outside!
Wait.
What's wrong with me?
Is it because of the hangover?
What the heck? Were you lying about
your powers and being an alien?
Don't talk to me.
Is it because of that smooch I gave you?
No!
What kind of super power
goes on and off?
You even pass out when we kiss!
There's nothing better than
someone from Earth.
She's so...
Super powers?
Oh my God!
Who were you talking to?
Talk to whom?
What are you talking about?
Were you talking to yourself then?
- That's suspicious.
- Nothing suspicious here.
Will you get out?
Yoon Jae! Did you call Dad?
I gave you his number.
I told you! He's a father to you,
but I don't remember him.
It's going to be so awkward.
Hey! He's still your father!
No matter how awkward it is,
he is always going to be your father.
You think you dropped from the sky?
Do you think you're an alien?
Hi.
But what if you get in trouble for this?
It's not even your case any more
and you got a warrant.
I'm risking my career for this.
He knows that I've been transferred
to the Criminal Trial Department.
He must have his guard down.
This is when I should strike
to get the evidence.
I didn't think he was an
aggressive type. Prosecutor!
I have a warrant for seizure and search.
Take me to Building Number Two.
Right now!
I told you.
No one by that name is here.
How will you compensate for our loss?
- Min Joon Hyung!
- Yoon Jae.
- Are you going somewhere?
- Yeah, to Mom's house.
Song Yi is acting strange.
It's hard to be with her.
Okay, I will see you later.
Min Joon!
My sister may seem tough and clueless.
But she's not.
She's really soft inside.
I don't know what happened with you two.
But she hasn't been eating or
sleeping for days now.
[Manager Do]
Do Min Joon!
What are you doing right now?
Why do I feel like we're wasting time?
One month is good and even
ten days is enough. So let's...
I really like you...
Do Min Joon.
Do Min Joon, can you hear me?
Yeah, I can hear you.
I don't know if you can hear me or not.
But I'll say it anyway.
I've been thinking...
I think I overreacted.
I was always that kid that changed
her mind every second.
I've never even liked one singer for long.
I liked the H.O.T., then Sechs Kies.
Then g.o.d., then Shinhwa.
You know I switched between about
five different fan clubs.
Anyway.
My point is that I'm not loyal.
I've been thinking and I think
I can get over you soon.
Just leave me no regrets.
Because if I send you away
without doing anything...
I'm going to have regrets.
So...
Let's do the the things that will take
others three months, a year, or two years.
Let's do them in a month like you said.
So...
After we've done everything
we wanted to do...
Maybe I could get sick of
you in less than a month.
That's how I am.
- Do Min Joon.
- What?
Do Min Joon!
What Cheon Song Yi?
Help me so that I could forget.
Help me so that I won't have regrets.
Help me so that I could be good to you.
Help me.
Okay.
But...
How could I ever...
Forget you?
Can you hear me?
Are you listening?
Let's go somewhere tomorrow.
Let's stick next to each other all day.
Then maybe I could get sick of you.
I may not like you anymore.
Are you listening?
[Manager Do]
[Let's go somewhere.]
Let's go, somewhere.
You wanted to go in the morning?
It's still before dawn.
What about you?
I...
- I didn't want to be late.
- Me neither.
- Shall we go?
- Okay.
Just... what's the point
of letting it hang free?
Let's hold hands.
Umm... why not?
Yeah, find a different institution.
By the way...
Who told the prosecutor
about the institution?
I do have someone in mind.
I will call you back.
Jae Kyung, do you have time?
Why?
What's it for?
There's someone I want you to meet.
You open it.
I need to eat right now.
I will call you back...
- What?
- Yang Min Joo went missing.
What happened?
Go in.
Your wife is waiting.
She has a lot to ask you.
- Where are you Song Yi?
- I'm jogging.
Don't overdo it.
I'm not. Where are you?
Stop right there!
Are you with Do Min Joon?
Unless I was hallucinating because
I had injured my head.
You appeared out of thin air
in front of me.
- That's right.
- On that day 12 years ago...
You disappeared in a flash and stood on
the other side of the road.
That's also true.
At first I thought you were
weird and dangerous.
Even when you were protecting
Song Yi from my brother...
I thought that you were planning something.
But I know now.
Why you said those words to me.
The accident that hurt Song Yi a while ago.
I think it was my brother.
I know.
I think my sister-in-law is locked
away in a mental hospital.
Help me so that I can get her out.
I will be able to hear more
when I find my sister-in-law.
Search the hospital for me.
They will try to smuggle her out.
She's not even on the patient list.
Okay yes sir.
Yang Min Joon went missing.
I have a lot to ask you.
Yeah okay.
Thank you anyway.
What was that? Who is it?
Was it that young girl
you saw at the park?
The one squealing for your number?
- No.
- Then?
- Is it another girl?
- No!
I need to practice reading my script.
Can you help me?
I can't act...
You don't have to act.
Just read the script.
My other managers used to do this for me.
- Scene 71?
- Yeah.
Diet? Don't!
I told you!
I don't want even one gram
of you going away.
You're perfect the way you are to me.
You're the most beautiful
girl that I know.
Young girls are loud and annoying.
I don't need...
What's wrong with this line?
It's just how it is.
Next paragraph.
Give a back hug?
What's wrong with the script?
And are you doing this
when you're shooting?
Of course! Shouldn't I?
You want to do a rehearsal then?
Do what?
Next line.
Aren't you going to do it?
Let's stop.
Why? Where are you going?
Let me go with you!
Did you get sick of me because
I was next to you all day?
My sister was never in a relationship.
So she doesn't know anything.
I'm doing this so that I could
get sick of you faster.
If we see everything, then we
won't have any more fantasies left.
Frankly, I know quite a lot being
in a relationship now.
It's all the same between men and women.
I heard that it was harder for my sister
than my mom when my father left.
She can't get over people.
She has a lot of affections.
That's her type.
She loves dogs, but she can't raise one.
Because she's afraid something
will happen to them.
I've had a lot of fun too.
So I won't be miserable and cry
about love and feelings.
I'm quite rational and clean-cut.
Do Min Joon! Do Min Joon!
Do Min Joon!
Why are you calling for me?
Where did you go?
I went to get some fresh air.
You scared me.
I thought you left.
Where would I go?
I have a feeling that
you will just go away.
What I'm saying is...
You can go.
But I was afraid that you would
leave without saying good bye.
I know I'm rational and clean-cut.
But if you leave
without saying good bye...
I won't leave.
I'm not leaving you.
I'm going to stay.
What do you mean?
I'm saying I'm not leaving.
Not in a month, or two months later.
So...
Don't be anxious.
Is it okay for you to not go?
More importantly, if I can't
go back this time.
It's likely that I will disappear.
It's likely that I will die.
It's fine.
Is it really okay?
Subtitles by DramaFever
Diet? No!
I told you!
Young girls are loud and annoying.
They are all useless.
Kisses her.
Wait no, what if he passes out again?
Gives a back hug.
(Gives a back hug and feels happy)
[I won't go anywhere and stay with
you forever after.]
Aren't you saying it?
Let's stop.
Why?
Where are you going?
Let me go with you!