(K-Pop Star 6)
(Last week)
(We watched the heated performances of six unique vocalists.)
(The competition is tight, as they are all talented.)
(The results are announced!)
(Yoo Jin, Bo Mi, Seo Jin, Da On, Myeong Seong, Yoon Ji)
(Up to Seo Jin, who was third best...)
(will go onto round 3.)
(Three contestants are eliminated, including Seo Myeong Seong.)
(Half of them passed and the other half were eliminated.)
(Their stage comes to an end with sad good-byes.)
(The second round of performances will come up next.)
The winner of K-Pop Star will be awarded 300,000 dollars,
(Which group is up next?)
(It's the Children's group, which caused a sensation.)
(The contestants are focused as they practice.)
We've had several talented children on the other seasons,
but the contestants on this season are the most talented.
It's not just potential I see.
They're already very good.
I was surprised at how good they are.
I've spotted some amazing acts.
(The young contestants were highly praised during the first round.)
It'll be a fierce competition among these children.
They're like the Avengers.
(Knowing how good the others are, there is tension in the air.)
(Lee Ga Do was praised for her great voice.)
She goes beyond your imagination. She's scarily good.
(11-year-old Kim Jong Seob showed off his dance and an original rap.)
It's unbelievable that he can rap like that at 11 years old.
I feel like I'm watching a young Zico.
(10-year-old Han Byeol mesmerized the judges with her dance moves.)
I've been a dancer for 40 years...
and the fact that I was captivated by her dance...
means she's amazingly talented.
(11-year-old Park Hyun Jin showed off his original rap full of swag.)
He's good, he has talent.
He has charisma.
(12-year-old Hong Jung Min was acknowledged for her clear voice.)
She is gifted in singing.
Her tune, beat and the emotions she shows...
surprise me.
Who do you think is the best?
Frankly, I think Ga Do is the best.
I think Ga Do is very good.
She doesn't have any trouble hitting high notes.
Her voice is perfect.
How well do you think you will do?
I'm cautious when I make assumptions,
but I'd like to be second best.
You'd like to be second best?
No.
I want to be better than Ga Do.
Do you want to be in first place?
Yes.
Dance!
I think I can beat Jong Seob in dancing.
- With your dance? - Judge Yang Hyun Suk said...
I was a better dancer.
All the contestants were so good,
so that motivated me.
Let's have the next group on stage.
(They have high expectations for the skilled children.)
(The talented young contestants walk onto the stage.)
Could you introduce yourselves?
In 1, 2, 3.
Hi, we're small but strong...
Strong...
Small...
bean...
bullets!
(Sighing)
(The judges look pleased.)
They're the small bean bullets.
They're so cute.
Ga Do looks like a small bean bullet.
(Cute)
They're so cute, but one interesting thing...
about the young contestants this season...
is that they are very talented.
- Compared to other seasons. - They are the most talented...
out of all the seasons.
The audience will be shocked as they watch these children.
They're better than those in their twenties.
I think one of them might even be the winner.
- I wouldn't be surprised. - You're right.
- It isn't about age. - Seeing how gifted they are,
there is a high possibility that might happen.
Have confidence and show us a good performance.
We'll begin with the first act...
of Small Bean Bullet.
(Who will be performing first in the fierce competition?)
Hi, I'm 12-year-old Kim Jong Seob.
(All the judges are focused.)
- How are you? - Okay.
Last time you performed,
the guest judges that are here again...
all gave you a yes.
Right.
(He not only performed an original rap, but also danced.)
I feel like he's shown us his talent and smart brain.
He's good at writing lyrics and a gifted dancer.
It's a great combination if you have both.
(The judges unanimously gave the 11-year-old a yes.)
I thought I'd mess up because I was nervous,
but I had fun, once I was on stage.
I wasn't very nervous.
I felt good.
When you told your parents you wanted to rap and dance,
were they against it?
- Didn't they tell you to study? - No, they weren't against it.
My parents are musicians, too.
My dad is a modern dancer...
and my mom is a jazz dancer.
I think I take after them.
I got my dancing skills from them.
Are you going to dance today?
Yes, I'm dancing to "Take You Down" by Chris Brown.
I've never been in love,
but I'm going to imagine that I am while I dance.
Do you think about the lyrics when you dance?
Dancing isn't just about the beat...
and moving to the rhythm, but you have to think about the lyrics.
You have to deliver emotions through your dance moves.
That's what I think.
I'd say it's more difficult than singing.
If you add emotion to each move,
the audience can see the sincerity behind it.
I believe emotions are involved in dancing.
(Wow.)
(The 11-year-old boy has a deep insight of music.)
What have you prepared for us today?
It's an original rap I wrote...
called "Destiny".
All right, let's hear it first.
Okay.
(Will he be able to put on a stage more surprising than the last time?)
("Destiny")
("Destiny" by Kim Jong Seob)
(He did well.)
(People passionately applaud him.)
Why are the kids so good?
What's shocking is that he dances well too.
- Really? - Yes.
- Let's see it. - Can you dance for us?
(They're just as excited for his dance.)
Kids are good.
I think when you dance, every move has to convey emotion.
(This 11-year-old boy has his own philosophy on dancing.)
(Jin Young screams.)
(Deeply moved, they cheer and applaud him.)
He's really good.
- He's very good. - He's unbelievable.
(Everyone can't believe how good this 11-year-old can dance.)
(He's awesome.)
This is crazy.
(They can't calm down easily.)
What do we do with him really?
Why is my heart fluttering because of the 11-year-old?
It was his last move.
This is how it feels.
I want to take him and run away from K-Pop Star.
- You want to snatch him away. - I want to disappear with him.
(Jong Seob seems dazed.)
Where should I begin?
First of all, he raps...
- There's a rap competition TV show. - Yes.
When you watch it, you can see that even professionals forget lyrics.
- There's too much to remember. - They make mistakes too.
He's so young, and he's been performing in front of many cameras,
but he's never made a mistake with the lyrics in the two rounds.
Even if we disregard everything else, that's something on its own.
And yet he's also got a great flow and delivery.
They are not done by the book though.
When he rides the rhythm, he does it on his own way.
Whether it's triplet or sixteenth note...
He doesn't know what those are, but he totally owns them.
When he sings a song, he absorbs it completely and makes it his own.
Did you see the pose?
After saying "my destiny", he took a break and did this.
(He continues to comment with much excitement.)
He's got composure,
great dance...
It's really funny. When Jin Young was complimenting Jong Seob,
Hyun Jin in the back went...
"yes".
- I was saying... - He's nodding his head.
It's like he's thinking...
"He's pretty good."
The most shocking thing about his rap and dance is that...
he takes little breaks. He's just 11 years old,
and he knows to give a little space in between his moves.
I don't understand how relaxed he is.
I think when it comes to dancing,
he doesn't measure up to me and Jin Young yet.
When it comes to rapping, he's much better than us.
Thank you.
You look like you're not approving it.
That's not it. We're not even rappers.
- It's not a compliment for him. - Right.
It's a compliment if you say he's better than Eminem.
Jin Young and I...
are not looking at Lee Jong Seob as he is now but we are...
- His name is Kim Jong Seob. - I am sorry.
We are not looking at how talented Kim Jong Seob is now...
but how he will be in two to three years. We've been seeing...
many people, and we are very surprised.
Your dance is unbelievable.
You did so well today that I can't wait for your next performance.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
There was a reason why the guest judges all passed him.
They are very precise.
More than anything...
I wrote things like this on my diary when I was 10 years old.
"I went to school today."
"I played with Jin Young."
"It was really fun."
That was the level of my writing.
But Jong Seob's rap is...
Goodness.
"It's like a nightmare virus, your talent is minus".
"I gained a lot of weight because of you but I'll go on a diet now".
It goes on and on like this.
First of all, his writing is impressive.
He didn't just write. He got all the rhymes.
Also, you have to restrain the word count for the flow.
He manages to do all that.
It means he was born to be a rapper.
If he's a high school student, I'd say he tried hard.
But it's a different story when he's a 11-year-old.
This is your natural talent.
Five years later...
After five years, he will only be a middle school student.
Who will he be in the future?
He dances so well, and he writes amazing lyrics.
You got an unbelievable talent.
(We're excited to see him grow even more.)
In the future, you will rap and dance effortlessly.
- You got an amazing talent. - He already does it effortlessly.
You got an amazing talent.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
(The first performer Jong Seob got the highest compliments.)
(The amazing first performance raises the expectation.)
(Who is the second contestant?)
Hello, I am Lee Ga Do from Changwon. I am 10 years old.
(She's cute.)
The previous contestant was praised so much...
that she must be pressured. How do you feel?
- I am a little pressured. - I see.
She's got something.
Last time, all the guest judges passed her.
(She was the first one to get a yes from all the guest judges.)
Are you more nervous than you were on the first round?
I am all right now.
I don't think she's nervous.
All right. Enjoy it then.
The real star does even better in this situation.
- Let's give it a go. - Okay.
(Everyone in the Children group chose her to rank No. 1.)
(Will she surprise us again?)
("Domino" by Jessie J)
(Everyone cheers passionately.)
Can you play the keyboard?
What was the key?
Flat.
- Do sharp. - D flat.
The note she kept hitting...
was D flat, do sharp.
Usually, girl group vocalists...
can sing as high as do.
Someone who can sing a little higher manages to sing as high as do sharp.
She didn't hit that note just sometimes. She kept hitting it.
She didn't bend the notes. She hit them precisely.
That's really hard to do.
Goodness. She doesn't have any bad habits.
Her voice, vocalization, and breathing are all very good.
Her interpretation, feeling,
and sense of rhythm are amazing as well.
She's unbelievable. Her singing is truly shocking.
Her singing is shocking.
The only problem was...
(The only problem was)
that you were a little more nervous than the first round.
(Jin Young points out that she was nervous.)
You were enjoying the performance a little less.
That was the only problem. As far as your singing ability...
is concerned, you got an unbelievable talent.
Thank you.
I thought it wasn't the best choice of a song.
The song is in repetition.
You could have showed us more what you are capable of.
(Hyun Suk wanted to see more of what she could do.)
I was so surprised by you on the last round.
She's like someone...
who can measure 10 meters.
However, today she only got to measure 10cm.
You didn't get to use all your talents.
Jin Young said that...
you hit high notes very well.
That's very important too,
but you could've chosen a song with a more interesting development...
and shown us more things.
Personally, I feel sorry.
If I were your producer,
I'd be sorry that you didn't get to show everything you got.
Okay.
(Compared to the first round,)
(she's not getting as much compliments as she did.)
I don't know if it was just me.
When Ga Do sing the first note,
she doesn't sound like a young contestant at all.
If we did a blind test...
or if we were turned back,
we would guess her...
to at least be a high school student.
Her voice has been ripened.
That's what I would think.
Other contestants in this show were born with...
dancing and entertaining talents,
and she was born with a full voice.
- She's got other talents too. - She's got other talents.
You were gifted with a rich voice.
But the song you chose...
didn't show your singing ability delicately.
It's a song designed for a performance.
It's not designed to emphasize your singing.
Next time, you should choose a song that can show your singing more.
Okay.
At first, we thought this group was a bean bomb.
But I now think they are a nuclear bomb.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
Thank you.
(The Children group are armed with a variety of talents.)
She did well.
(What would be the result for Ga Do?)
Next contestant, please.
Hello. I am Park Hyun Jin. I am from class 2 of fifth grade...
from Youngseo Elementary School.
- Hello. Have you been well? - Yes.
How have you been?
I practiced a lot,
and I practiced breathing a lot.
I think I just played when I was his age.
I played with the stones.
- We played Squid. - Right.
That's what we did when we were their age.
(The young children these days don't know those games.)
Which song will you be singing today?
I will sing Kim Gun Mo's "The Day We Broke Up".
Mr. Kim Gun Mo's "The Day We Broke Up".
What was the focus of your practice?
The key was higher than the key of the original song,
so I practiced singing high.
I couldn't sing high clearly,
so I tried to study how to sing high clearly.
(He's amazing.)
You prepared to dance too. How did you practice dancing?
I practiced dancing while thinking about...
where to make big moves and where to make small moves.
Did you study at a dancing academy?
- No. - Then?
I did it alone.
Did you do the choreography?
No, I came up with the hat performance.
I copied the original dance.
- You copied it. - Yes.
Goodness.
Like how you copy codes, we often...
copy dances too.
- When you see dancers, - Right.
- they copy other performers. - Right.
You two started like that too, didn't you?
Right.
It's just strange to hear it from such a young person.
He talks about studying and analyzing music.
He must be very smart.
(On the first round, he did his own rap.)
Does he have potential as a rapper?
He does. He has a lot of potential.
But will he be able to rap like this on the upcoming rounds?
Will his rap be as good as this?
I don't think so.
But...
I think he will sing very well.
His voice is...
(Jin Young must've found something about his voice.)
I hope you will just sing on the upcoming rounds.
(Jin Young trusted his potential and gave him a pass.)
Hyun Jin is next.
(He accepted Jin Young's advice and prepared to sing.)
What's this key?
E?
Is this B?
(Even Hyun Jin didn't know he could sing this high.)
In the far future Will you be able go this high?
What is it? Is it re?
Even girls can't sing that high. All right.
Let's do this. Just hit the highest note you can.
In the far future Like this.
In chest voice.
He rapped when he could sing like this.
- He almost got eliminated. - I know.
He's a multi-player.
I've been rapping a lot,
and I've been practicing to rap.
I haven't been singing as much as I have been rapping.
I practiced rapping hard, but I couldn't do it.
So I felt quite sad that day,
but I think this is the time when I can improve myself with feedbacks.
I started by practicing the breathing and then...
I practiced how to sing with the proper shape of my mouth.
In your group, there's a contestant...
named Jong Seob, and he will be rapping.
Would you be sad when you see him rap?
When I saw Jong Seob rap,
I envied him.
I envy him that he gets to rap.
(How will the 11-year-old Hyun Jin convey his emotions?)
I initially joined the competition as a rapper,
and I won't get to rap for a while now.
I will sing while thinking about that.
So it's a breakup with rap.
Yes.
We will listen to your singing and talk more.
Okay.
(He will sing with sad emotion of breaking up with rap.)
(The 11-year-old boy's first on-stage performance)
("The Day We Broke Up" by Kim Gun Mo)
How lovely.
(He sings with the innocence of his age.)
He's good.
That was great.
He's so pure.
(His first attempt is over.)
Jin Young's making this raspy sound...
as if he's been drinking.
He really studied the song.
He sang it so well.
(Isn't he great?)
Shall we see his dance?
I don't think we need to.
- He's slays it. - Does he really slay it?
- He is fantastic. - Does he?
He better slay it.
Put your mic down and get ready to dance.
How old are you guys?
You're talking about slaying and being slayed.
You both will turn 50 soon.
Show us what you can do.
(Wow.)
Well done. Well done.
(They watched it while holding their breath.)
This is what you call a dance.
He's a great dancer.
It's not the kind of dance where he learned...
when and how to move.
Real dancing is lip syncing the words...
to a song as you enjoy it.
Since we're judging, let me add to this.
Some people will think his singing and dancing was just so-so.
He didn't scream when he sang...
and he didn't pop any joints when he danced.
It's just...
It's so organic.
There were no additives whatsoever.
He just danced naturally with the lyrics.
He just moved however he wanted.
When I tell people to sing and dance without trying too hard,
this is what I want.
He didn't go overboard to impress us or show off...
and that alone was still enough.
Once you start teaching someone like him,
the speed at which they absorb things is incredible.
Can I ask you something? Do you not have a dance teacher?
- I don't. - This kid...
Did you teach yourself?
Yes, I copied the dancers.
Copying a dancer's choreography...
- is something you can learn. - Anyone can do that.
Most instructors teach specific moves but this boy...
ignored that and freestyled his way through.
That is why Jin Young and I are so shocked.
He slayed it, right?
Honestly, yes or no?
- He slayed it. - Right?
Let me tell you why.
I have no other option but to compare him to G-Dragon.
G-Dragon signed with me when he was 13.
When he was that age, he wasn't this good of a dancer.
He was a rapper, so he couldn't sing this well, either.
What really surprised me is that in the first round...
this kid rapped.
At the in-depth audition...
I suggested he sing a song...
and he was incredibly good.
You were there, Jin Young.
Hyun Jin, who told you to sing in the first round?
You did, Jin Young.
Don't you forget that.
Okay.
I will...
guarantee you this.
This boy will become the future of K-pop.
The future of K-pop.
He can. He really can.
I mean it.
If being a K-pop star means to lead...
the next Korean Wave,
he will become a K-pop star.
I'd love it if you'd become...
the future of K-pop and of JYP.
Who told you to sing?
You did.
I feel like I'm at a disadvantage.
You said your favorite singer is Big Bang.
Does YG still stand a chance?
I think you can become the future of YG.
That's all I have to say.
The question that I kept on asking him was...
if he has a dance instructor and he said he didn't, it was choreography.
Did you ever take singing lessons?
No. I just listen to songs and sing along.
- You just sing along? - Yes.
I asked that for a reason.
When a child shows promise in a certain field,
especially music or art,
and they even enjoy doing it,
parents send them to classes.
What's most important for kids Hyun Jin's age...
is to let them do what they like and play.
Are your parents like that?
Yes. They leave me alone and...
told me to do what I like.
That's not an easy thing for parents to do.
I think he's so natural because he had no teachers.
Because he had fun.
Why?
The artists at Antenna...
never took a music lesson in their lives.
That is why I believe Hyun Jin can become Antenna's future.
Thank you.
Hyun Jin.
Let's think about this.
You are 11 years old...
and Jong Seob is 10.
The next round is a team challenge.
Imagine one rapping, the other singing...
and both of them dancing at the same time.
That would be awesome.
That would be...
I'm just so...
(What combination will they bring?)
I really think this is your year.
He's good.
Thank you.
(Hyun Jin was lauded as the future of K-pop.)
(Will he be able to survive the intense competition?)
Hello, I'm from Incheon.
I'm 12 and my name is Hong Jung Min.
- Hello. - Her eyes are so clear.
Just look at...
Her eyes sparkle.
- Try to perform with confidence. - Okay.
(Will she give a great performance like last time?)
("Marry You" by Bruno Mars)
Thank you.
(She receives a storm of applause.)
- You sing very well. - Thank you.
Aside from everything else, you know how to sing.
I think you have a lot of potential.
As the viewers were watching her singing on TV,
they must've thought the song is easy to sing.
But in fact, this song is very difficult to sing.
It's shocking how effortlessly she can sing it.
She's unbelievable.
The inside of her body is opened like a pipe.
You can play the pipe only by blowing into it.
Her entire body is opened like a pipe.
Jin Young compared her to a pipe.
- You're wearing pink today, right? - Yes.
I think of her like a pink notebook.
She's like a notebook with a pink cover...
whose pages are all blank.
I would like to fill the notebook with her from the first page.
I have high hopes for her.
I liked your today's performance, too.
- Good job. - Thank you.
(Jung Min is in the midst of praise.)
(Who is the last participant?)
(Hui Yeol laughs.)
I'm worried about her.
(Hyun Suk exclaims.)
(Han Byeol seems more nervous than last time.)
Hello.
Hello, I'm Han Byeol from Seoul.
(She's extremely nervous.)
I said she is my favorite contestant.
I promised that I'll help her make it to the top 20.
I believe everyone will understand why when they see her performance.
Are you nervous?
Yes.
Byeol, you need to relax yourself.
- Or else, you won't do well, right? - Yes.
(It's 10 days earlier at the in-depth audition venue.)
- Hi, everyone. - Hello.
(Jin Young and Hyun Suk enter the room.)
- This room is more colorful. - Exactly.
Congratulations on passing the first round.
They look even younger in here.
(They start the in-depth audition with the youngest Ga Do.)
(Her jaw drops.)
(Byeol is intimidated by Ga Do.)
(She looks more and more worried as the audition goes on.)
(She's impressed.)
(She becomes more nervous.)
- Next up is Byeol. - Me?
(Me?)
It's Byeol's turn.
(She stands before the judges feeling daunted.)
- Is your face always that red? - No.
- Are you embarrassed now? - Yes.
(How did you feel at the in-depth audition?)
I was afraid and nervous.
Why were you afraid?
The judges were too close to me.
Did their facial expressions scare you?
- Like this. - Did Jin Young...
(They made this face.)
Like this.
Is that how they looked at you?
Yes.
(She performs feeling intimidated.)
Can you dance to another song? What's wrong?
Okay.
My stomach hurts.
I think she's too nervous today.
What's the matter with you today?
You shouldn't feel nervous in such a situation like this to be a star.
You dance much better than this.
I fell in love with you last time.
You are too nervous today.
How are you feeling today?
I'm under a lot of pressure,
but I think I can do this.
I don't know.
Shake your body like this and loosen up.
Smile and just relax.
- You need to enjoy performing. - Okay.
- Try to enjoy it. - Okay.
Don't be afraid.
Okay, let's do it.
- She's adorable. - She looks like a lead actress.
- She's so cute. - Indeed.
(Will she able to overcome her nervousness and perform well?)
("Lullaby of Birdland" by Nikki Yanofsky)
(It's hard to read the judges' faces.)
Let's watch her dance.
We'll watch you dance now.
(It's time to show her dance moves.)
- Look at her pose. - Goodness.
She already impressed me with her pose.
She looks gorgeous.
(Hyun Suk exclaims.)
(Jin Young shrieks with joy.)
(A big round of applause fills the studio.)
She's good at expressing emotions.
She's really good at it.
- What will she become? - Exactly.
I wonder that, too.
She's unbelievable.
When a young contestant comes up with a musical instrument...
and performs amazingly, I get really surprised.
While I was watching you dance, I felt...
as if you were creating...
amazing music through your dance...
except that you didn't have a musical instrument.
That's such a great talent.
Aside from everything else...
Since I'm not an expert, I don't know much about the techniques,
but your facial expressions...
and the vibe you exuded were...
were very natural. You're good at expressing emotions.
Thank you.
I can't believe my own eyes.
Good job.
Thank you.
(Hui Yeol is in the midst of praise.)
(How will Jin Young evaluate her performance?)
She is a descendant of two different lineages...
that stand out the most in the pop music industry across the world.
She's half Swedish and half Korean.
ABBA might be the only Swedish musician people think of,
but there are many other famous Swedish musicians.
They're the best when it comes to EDM.
There are many great hip hop artists, too.
- That's right. - Right.
Probably because she's a descendant of the two great lineages,
I can't criticize her techniques or strengths and weaknesses.
Thank you.
Even before...
she started dancing,
she impressed me by her pose.
(The audience members exclaim.)
She didn't even start to dance.
Seriously...
Sadly, you need a natural-born talent to become an artist.
That is absolutely true.
I think there is a strong possibility...
that she will become a great star like Beyonce.
- Thank you. - As for your song,
you chose a difficult song for you.
When the notes in the melody ascend and descend with large leaps,
it's hard to sing in tune.
The song that you just sang, there are large space...
between the notes in the melody.
It's a hard song even for professional singers to sing,
and you are only 10 years old.
Your pitch was very unstable. Other than that,
it was good that you sang the song in your own style.
You also dance in your own style.
That's the most shocking thing about you.
(He hesitates.)
Also...
(He's so touched that he's lost for words.)
What should I say? I have so many things I want to say.
Hyun Suk, please go ahead. I'll continue when I remember.
I just want to say...
I'm mesmerized and fascinated by her.
Since I didn't know this song,
I asked the other judges if they knew the song.
None of them did. You chose a very difficult song.
- You speak Korean well, right? - Yes.
You sang Mehgan Trainor's song in the first round, right?
- No, I didn't. - What song did you sing last time?
She sang Mehgan Trainor's song.
Right. You sang Mehgan Trainor's song in the first round, right?
Mehgan Trainor.
Oh, that's right.
If you join YG Entertainment, it'd be hard to communicate with him.
You see what I'm saying, right?
Would it be good or bad if it's hard to communicate with him?
It wouldn't be good, right?
Right.
You danced to Janet Jackson's song.
That's right.
It's Janet. This is how to pronounce her name.
You should pronounce it correctly.
I watched each and every dance move...
from the beginning to the end.
I really liked your dance.
- You did a great job. - Thank you.
Thank you for your performance.
How adorable.
(All the contestants' performances are over.)
That was funny.
We will discuss now.
Please wait for a short while.
(All the contestants in the children group finished their performances.)
(The judges are discussing to rank their performances.)
(All five of them were acknowledged for their talents.)
(It was a neck to neck competition. What will be the result?)
All right.
So many contestants in this group received a lot of praise.
It was hard to make a decision.
But we have to follow the rules. So we've ranked your performances.
The contestant who did the best is...
(Who could be the winner of the children group?)
Hyun Jin. Congratulations.
(11-year-old Park Hyun Jin takes the first place.)
The second best contestant is...
(Who could be the second best?)
Jong Seob.
(Kim Jong Seob takes the second place.)
(Hyun Jin and Jong Seob take the 1st and 2nd places.)
How will the two of them perform next time?
(The two 11-year-old boys receive high expectations.)
(There are three girls left.)
The third best is Byeol.
(Han Byeol takes the third place.)
The 4th place goes to Ga Do, and Jung Min takes the 5th place.
The two people at 4th and 5th places in this group...
would take the 1st or 2nd in another group.
(Will the two of them make it to the next round?)
We've never seen any young children who did as well as they did.
- This is the first time. - Exactly.
I will announce the result with joy.
All of you are qualified for the next round.
(All five contestants make it to the next round.)
- Thank you. - Thank you.
Good luck. We'll see you in the next round.
You all did a great job.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
(No one in the group got eliminated.)
(Well done.)
- This has never happened. - That's right.
Only one in the group made it to the next round, right?
Especially the young children didn't make it very far.
I had a thought.
I wondered how much money...
their performances would have been worth.
If you think of the added value after they become stars,
how much would their performance have been worth?
You're the true slave of capitalism.
(Many contestants who are older than them cried while passing here.)
(They're smiling while leaving the studio.)
(They share the joy with their families.)
(They were serious on stage,)
(but they act their ages in front of their families.)
- She is shy. - Is that so?
- Give her a hug. - Give Ga Do a hug.
- Go, Tiny Bullet! - Go, Tiny Bullet!
Did we really see this contestant in the first round?
How can you sing so effortlessly?
It's game over.
I think this contestant might win this competition.
This is a team challenge. It's "Survival Match".
This group's match will be intense.
I feel like I'm going crazy.
They are strong competitors.
This is how a girl group should be.
It's hard to make a decision.
This is a big twist.
The team to make it to the next round is...
(K-Pop Star 6)