MELINA MERCOURI in
STELLA
With
GEORGE FOUNDAS
ALEKO ALEXANDRAIGS
SOPHIA VEMBO
Screenplay
MICHAEL CACOYANNIS
Music
MANOS HADJIDAKIS
A MICHAEL CACOYANNIS FILM
PARADISE TAVERNA
LIVE BOUZOUKI MUSIC
"Anneta
and the celebrated STELLA.
All the songs about LIFE,
LOVE and DEATH...
that mirror the sou]
of the Greek people. "
PARADISE
Let's go to the Paradise Bouzouki
And when the fun dies down
Seven songs will I sing
for you to pick
The one you 'll sing
to make me say I love you
Seven songs will I sing
for you to pick
The one you'll sing
to make me say "I love you"!
- Stella, Aleko is here.
- 0k.
Mrs Maria...
My daughter isn't happy.
She always sings first,
as if Stella is the star.
That's what we agreed on
from the beginning.
But now we have offers galore.
We're nightingales proper.
Besides, my Anneta SINGS.
She doesn't croak like Stella.
Yew mrs Euterpe, but it's Stella
who packs them in.
She's trying out a new
number and she's all nerves.
Hello Aleko. What was my mom
grumping about this time'!
She resents your going out first.
- I told her to stay away.
- She's like any mother.
- Ambitious for her daughter.
- Some ambition! Singing in a taverns!
Why's it a bad thing?
I'll check if Stella's ready.
- How have you been'?
- How eke“!?
Getting plainer every day
while Stella blooms.
And why wouldn't she... As if too many
gentlemen like you ever cared for her?
Go ask Mitsos. AH she ever
befriended with were mostly scums.
- Isn't that so, Mitso?
- Keep me out of it. I'm just doing my job.
And when she's through with you,
she'll go back to her bums.
Why are you telling me this?
Something she said?
No, but I know
Stella inside out.
She doesn't care about money.
She's proud that way.
But when she falls for a guy,
it's all the way.
And after a couple of months,
she gets over it, right?
It's the fault of you men,
she says, for being so selfish.
In other words,
my time is up?
- The lights!
- Lights out!
- New tricks tonight?
- She'll dance in a spotlight.
- She saw it in the movies and liked it.
- Yeah, big thing.
Drums!
Higher!
What's that bastard doing?
- I find her disgusting.
- The men don't.
Out of my way!
That old witch!
She put the jinx on me.
I don't care if she
is Anneta's mother.
She'll never ever set another foot in here!
Where's my shirt?
- Stella!
- Here it is!
May I offer my congratulations?
Are you putting me on?
Just once I try to do
something artistic...
and I make a fool of myself.
Some joint!
- What's wrong with it?
- It doesn't even have a piano!
It has a whole orchestra.
Try doing a classy number
with bouzouki music!
I'll get myself a piano,
you wait!
Be patient and I'll get it
for you, doll!
I'm not patient.
You know me.
Sure I do. May others had a heart just
like Stella's here. Right, Aleko?
- Not even a smile for me?
- Lay off, Aleko.
- Come on, it wasn't so tragic.
- For me it was! I'm not Anneta.
- What was she going on about?
- Nothing that matters.
Think I don't know?
It's always the same.
Whenever I'm stuck on someone,
she tries to snatch him away.
And the lies she tells!
Yet deep down she loves you.
She's a good girl. Trouble is,
she's too set on getting married...
and that's not healthy,
not in our line of work.
- And you, Stella? What do you want?
- You know what I want.
To sing, dance and have all the men
at my feet.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing.
And the man
who loves you?
He'll love me
and be happy I'm his.
Do you love me, Stella?
Careful guys! My piano!
It's new dammit!
Careful! My piano!
- Congratulations.
- Thanks.
You swear you can afford it?
- You wanted a piano, right?
- Yeah but. .
- Like it?
- Adore it.
I'm coming.
Help me 11P-
Are you going
to sit up there?
Where else?
Leave my piano alone? No way man!
Slow down.
We're going past the competition!
Come on out!
- What's going on?
- I want Pepe, the pianist.
Okay.
He)', Antigone!
They want Pepe!
- Where's Pepe?
- He isn't here.
- Is he playing somewhere?
- Wherever they ask him.
I've got work for him.
I need him right away.
He's playing
at some wedding.
- Where?
- In Piraeus, the little port.
Thank you. First we'll drop the piano
at the Paradise.
To your health, Pepe!
To the happy couple!
To your health, Milto!
- Hi guys! Can anyone give a hand here?
- Gladly!
- Wow!!
- Hi there baby!
Hello guys, I missed you all.
Where have you been?
A beautiful piano,
all black and shiny!
- What make?
- The best there is.
Who's that good-looking guy?
Looks familiar.
It's Milto, the soccer player.
of Olympiakos
- The bestest!
- The greatest.
So, Pepe,
like we said... tonight.
- Leaving so soon?
- Yes.
- Why?
- Keep your hand, I've one too many here!
- What's your name?
- Your hand!
- Mine's Miltos.
- Who cares?
- Where are you going?
- Anywhere I like.
I'd like you to stay.
Something tells me
we like different things.
you're wrong.
It's getting light.
That Paradise poster
down there, is new?
Yesterday's. It was my idea.
I like to look at it.
My hair needs dyeing.
- Stella?
- What'!
- What are you thinking?
- Shall I have it dyed red?
- Stella... Know what I'm thinking?
- What my boy?
I hate having to leave every morning
like a thief.
- I'd like us to be different.
- I say we're fine.
- For how long?
- What's gotten into you lately?
I'm afraid you'll leave me,
and if you do...
Why don't you want
to marry me'!
If you're starting that talk again,
then better go.
- I can't help thinking of it.
- And I can't help resenting it.
But why Stella, why?
You can't possibly like the life
you lead... Maria, Anneta, mitsos...
What's wrong with them?
Not classy enough for you?
No Stella. You're so much better.
Why don't you want to change?
To change and be what like?
You're insulting me!
No, Stella. When you love someone,
it's only natural...
Not to me! I love people for
what they are. I ask no more.
I've told you a thousand times:
if you don;t want to kill mylove for you,
love me as I am!
But you just don't listen!
If that doesn't suit you,
go back to your world...
and leave me in peace!
Is there someone else'!
Now you're being
really insulting.
Think I'm hiding something?
You should know me better.
When there's someone else,
you'll be the first to know.
I'm sorry.
Stella...
I'm going now.
Haven't seen Aleko around lately.
Think I haven't noticed?
- Did you have a fight?
- Kind of.
I bet he took it hard.
Unlike me, you mean...
living it up!
Stop that horrid bouzouki noise!
The past three nights
he hasn't gone out.
- At all?
- No.
Thank heavens.
What are you writing,
Aleko?
Poetry.
What about?
Bourgeois boredom.
Poetry my foot.
Instead of doing some real work.
- Don't start.
- You spoiled him.
- You know how sensitive he is.
- He only knows how to spent money
At least he's rid
of that ghastly woman!
What do you say Spyrettos?
I say stop it, for God's sakes.
You're choking him.
- Are you going out?
- Yes.
- At this late hour?
Why don't you sit here with us
my child. It's so nice.
Where to?
To the horrid bouzoukis.
It's the thirteenth
of the month
My bad-luck day
I don't want to set eyes on
or greet a single soul
Every time it's the thirteenth
I don't get out of bed
I close the doors and windows
But my eyes refuse to close
All together, everyone!
Cursed day, you've done me in
You've clipped my wings
Each time I full in love
You trip me up
and lay me low
Each time I full in love
You trip me up
and lay me low
They say I'm superstitious
The truth is I was fated
On the thirteenth
to be left an orphan
to become a widow
On the thirteenth
to be left an orphan
to become a widow
- Well done Vassiliki!
- Thank you, thank you very much.
What is it?
A drunk driver wants to come in
with his car!
He'll wreck the place,
piano and all!
My piano?
We'll see about that!
Careful, we don't want
the people know.
Park that jalopy
and walk in like a man!
I want to drive in.
You're second best.
Others have driven in by train.
I do what I like,
remember?
If you have the guts,
do it.
He's dead drunk!
Don't be stupid Stella!
Come on, be a man!
I'm coming.
Stella! Get out of the way!
He'll kill you!
I took pity on you,
because you're an eyeful.
Pity that not all champions
have guts!
- So you know who I am?
- They say you have a way with the ball.
Will you park that thing?
It's blocking the entrance.
Tell me where to park.
- Wherever the hell you like.
- You show me.
Scared?
If Aleko comes,
tell him I'll be right back.
If his brakes hadn't worked,
kaput! COMING!
- So your name's Stella, eh?
- Stella!
Hey! Where are we going?
I'll take the next turn,
unless you care to go for a drive.
Like hell I do! Better turn
while you're still in one piece.
I've brought you a cognac.
It's on me.
Thanks.
- How long has it been?
- Almost 20 minutes.
She said she'd be back.
That's what she always says.
I remember last winter she
went off with this guy.
In fact, she was sitting at my
own table, but it's not it...
He said he'd show her
his motorbike...
Stop it!
And she didn't come back
till morning.
Aleco...
How could someone like you
get mixed up with her?
Look, you! We keep going
round and round!
I've lost my way.
Stop or I'll jump-
Don't try that stuff with me!
It won't work. Let me go!
- Aleko's waiting, eh?
- Yes.
- Who's Aleko?
- A gentleman.
- Who peels a pear with a knife?
- Yes.
- Then he's not for you.
- He loves me! And I melt.
- Wants to make a lady of you?
- He does.
- Poor bastard!
- Why?
- He's setting his house on fire.
- I'm the fire?
Yes. And a guy has to know
how to play or he'll get burned!
- And you do?
- So I say.
And I say you don't.
I have a match tomorrow.
If we win, I'll be coming round.
And if we lose,
I'll still be coming.
Anneta,
what's taking you so long?
Coming.
Bless you. The customers
are half asleep.
She won't be back, right'!
I told you so.
You fee] sorry for me,
don't you?
- Y o“ do...
- l...
I am pathetic indeed.
Should I pretend I don't care?
I do, I care terribly.
Why should I lie?
Why play the tough guy?
Well, I'm not.
A few days away from her
and I go to pieces.
Aleko, what's come over you?
And to think
I wanted to change her!
Me...
I know girls who'd change
their very skin for you.
You're very sweet, Anneta.
Where are you going?
I'm leaving.
It's all over.
Shall I come with you?
She's back, Anneta.
She's back.
Bravo!
Come on, Nlilto!
Hey you kicked me hard there lady!
Foul! OUT!
Kick the Referee!
Murderers!
You murderers!!!
Good night.
- Goodnight Maria
- Goodnight there.
Where's Mr. Aleko tonight?
I told him not to come.
It's been a good night.
The piano brought us luck.
I feel sorry for him,
but I hate lying.
Shame.
He was a gentleman.
The best.
Even bought you a piano.
"I'll never forget you, "
I told him.
"You and the piano
will always be in my heart. "
- What did he say?
- His eyes filled with tears.
"Good-bye, Stella, "
he said and left...
after the soccer game.
Her new number drives them crazy.
- They broke five plates.
- What do you care if they pay?
Where d'you think the
three of them broke onto?
Stella, go on home, my girl.
In a minute.
Do you expect anyone special?
I was.
He'll pay for it, you wait!
Play, Pepe, play-
Why, here I am.
0h my...
- Get rid of him.
- Kiddiwme? I have wife and kids myself!
Let me then.
- The place is closed, mister.
- Open it then. For me!
Don't argue.
Okay, for you, but only
for a little while.
- Where would you like to sit?
- Everywhere.
- But for the moment, here.
- 0k.
- Where are the musicians?
- Having supper.
- Get them.
- Right.
- Where are you going?
- Inside.
Did I give you permission?
I'm the boss tonight.
Sure.
I'm a little drunk,
but even dry I'm the same way.
- What's your name?
- Mitso.
Mine' s Mme.
Now go tell that blonde doll
to come here.
He'll skin me alive.
Tell him to go to hell!
She's a little difficult.
- Well he said...
- Get the hell out of here!
I did my best, I swear.
Please don't make trouble.
Plese I beg you go tell him yourself.
He's ready to beat me up!
She's a bit tough. Mr Mike...
Cross my heart and hope to
die I did everythingl could.
Come on now... don't make
any trouble, allright?
- What's that?
- Dynamite.
I'll throw it to her
instead of a rose.
Stella! Run!
He's going to blow us all up!
I got to hand it to you.
You're a winner!
Get up.
That's how I knee]
when I like something.
I prefer you standing.
God, my girl, what eyes!
Yours aren't so bad either.
Break it up! What's this here eh?
Get us some wine.
Music!
- I like you, Stella.
- I know.
What about you?
- You were late.
- You waited for me'!
- I was sure you'd come.
- Why?
Because I wanted it.
I'll be coming every night.
And I'll sing for you.
And I'll cover the ground
you walk on with money.
Money doesn't impress me.
I like you, Stella.
You already said that.
Do you know how it feels
like to like a woman?
Like what?
Like entering a tiger's cage.
- Beat it.
- Let me pour the beer first!
BEAT IT!
I don't spoil women.
I like them as they are.
Meaning?
Others crawl into the cage
when the tiger's asleep.
Me, I wake it
and get it all worked up.
- Understand?
- Yes.
- Stella.
- What'!
I like you.
Stella, my love!
Kiss me!
Quietly.
This way, Stella!
Hello, Thodoros!
What's up. Everything allright there?
Hi Andreas, how're you doing?
Hello, Thanassi! You sexy old devil!
That belly of yours drives me crazy!
- Hello, Vassili!
- Hello, Stella!
- Christo!Look after the lady!
- Hey you!
Take anything you fancy.
Take me!
- What will your wife say?
- Who gives a damn?
How about
a juicy watermelon?
- How's Milto?
- Fine. We're going on a picnic.
Have fun! Wow, it's heavy! Christo!
Give Stella a hand, will ya?
Thanks, Vassili! Let's go my Christo.
- Hi gorgeous!
- Hi to you Manolis!
Thank you.
Excuse me.
- You're Miss Stella?
- Yeah, that's me.
- May I have a word with you?
- Sorry, I can't right now.
Wait!
Pm Aleko's sister.
- I'm busy.
- Please.
It's important.
Come on up.
Take a seat.
I don't like discussing
my affairs with strangers.
If Aleko wants something,
he should come himself.
Aleko is ill.
- He has a fever?
- No.
What, then?
It's his nerves.
A breakdown.
He's shut himself up
and won't see anyone.
If he doesn't have a fever,
then it's nothing serious.
The doctor is very worried.
- It happened once before and...
- And?
He tried to kill himself.
Heaven forbid!
What an idea.
You realize that
my coming here wasn't easy.
I know about your liaison
with Aleko and...
Then you must know also that this
"liaison" is over, days now.
We had a family council...
and decided
to give our consent.
To what'!
His marrying you,
of course.
Come again? You lost me here.
Marrying you.
Look here, you!
I may not be high society myself,
etiquete qnd all
but I don't go into people's homes
and insult them.
Who said I wanna marry
your precious sonny?
And if I did,
who said I'd need your consent?
I broke off with him, you hear?
Because I play straight.
Or did you think
I was after his money?
All I know is that he's ill.
It's not my fault.
I was honest with him.
And don't think
I'm not sorry for him.
I do. He's a lovely man.
But don't try to pin
his illness on me.
Blame yourselves!
Think he didn't tell me about you?
Shut up! I forbid you! You're even
a worse slut than I thought.
Stella!
Coming!
Stella! Here Stella!
Get in the back with us.
My mom's up front with Miltos,
cause she gets car sick all the time.
Yeah, come on let's go now!
Isn't my wife a doll?
Hello my dove!
Go to your mama now sweety, WilPya?
Put me down, Mikes'.!
Not until you tell me
you'll always be my girl!
- I don't know 'bout always.
- Then lie.
I don't lie to those I love myself.
Then say it for real.
You men are too free
with words.
Not me! Ask me anything,
and I'll risk my life.
Today, yes. I'd do as much for you,
and more. You hear? I'd do plenty!
Do you hear that, world?
It's Stella and she's my girl!
She is Mflto's girl!
The moon is red
The river is blue
And my love in your arms
is a soft white bird
The moon is green
The river is deep
Come, my love,
dance all night long
The moon dived into the river
And my love turned yellow
like a flame
Come, my love,
dance all night long
I never felt like this.
It's scary, like being scorched
by the sun.
Go on, sun.
Go on scorching us.
I don't like being tied
this way.
Thief! Bandit!
What are we headed for?
A tourney...
Switzerland...
A good psychiatrist...
Stella... forget...
Don't open!
Who can it be?
Stella.
Stella!
- Who is it?
- Alekos.
Tell him to go away.
He'll go by himself.
- You're mine now.
- Don't.
Why?
I don't know.
I'm sorry for him.
Stella!
He's gone.
Stella.
"For Life, For Love And Death That... "
They turned me away.
Why Miltos? It wasn't my fault.
- It wasn't my fault.
- No my heart, No my love.
- They sent me away.
- Stella, Don't cry.
They think I'm heartless,
that I killed him.
Let them try say that to my face.
You're Milto's girl.
You don't need anyone. Don't cry.
Listen Stella... I've made up my mind.
We're getting married.
Yes Stella, we'll marry.
And they'll be saying "That's Milto's
wife", and they'll respect you.
What's she doing?
She sits there
without saying a word.
- It's been a terrible shock for her.
- of course...
when she dumped him she wasn't thinking.
I told him, it would end this way.
Watch your words,
or there'll be hell to pay.
Hasn't Milto shown up?
Not yet.
Stella...
Maria, do come in. I have
something to tell you.
What is it Stella?
Mike asked me to marry him.
Really, my beuty!
He's like all the others.
A posses“...
He wants to have me ties! down...
And you?
I love him.
What did you tell him?
Nothing.
I said nothing.
Maria I can take it no more.
I can't breathe.
I want to sing, to feel alive!
I'm choking, do you hear?
Chocking, chocking, chocking!
Love, you've become
A two-edged knife
Once you only gave me joy
Now you drown the joy in tears
I see no escape, no cure
She said she wouldn't sing,
but she couldn't resist it.
The very day he was buried!
She leaves them all. And you Miltos.
Just you wait. It'll be your turn next!
I'm not like the others.
We're getting married.
- What did you say?
- We're getting married.
I just saw my mother.
We've set the date.
Fires bum in his eyes
The stars tumble down
when he looks at me
Put out the lights
Put out the moon
Le! him no! see my pain
when he takes me.
When?
October 28th. The national holiday.
It's a Sunday too.
Le! him no! see my pain
when he takes me.
Why, Mike'! Why'?
- I want to know you're mine.
- You know that.
I won't share you
with other men's eyes.
- Don't you trust me?
- I don't know.
That slays me.
Trust me and go away for years...
I'll be waiting. If you don't...
Don't you understand?
Being my girl
means nothing.
I want to say "my wife".
I want you say "my husband“.
Talking about "my girlfriend" or
“my boyfriend“ are double razors.
Brings to mind the talk of the knives.
Then you shouldn't have gotten
involved with me.
I hate the very thought of marriage!
I absolutely despise it!
I laugh at all women longing to secure
themselves, with a good marriage.
1 don't wank you tube my husband
and me be your wife.
Why can't we go on as we are?
Like wild animals.
Either you're all mine
or not at all.
I'll never marry you...
Nomatter what you say. Never!
Then I'm leaving, Stella.
We either get married as I say...
or I leave
and you never see me again.
I swear it
on my mother's life.
Why are you tormenting me?
I'm waiting, Stella.
Yes or no?
Why can't I say no'!
Why don't you just let me be!
Yes or no?
Why make me say something
I may regret later?
You won't regret it. It's heads or tails
and I put my whole life in the bet.
For the last time... Yes or no?
The wedding will take place
on the 28th.
I'll go tell the others.
- It's Milto, the soccer player!
- Getting married this afternoon!
- We“ done Mike'.
- Congrats'.!
- What time's the wedding?
- At 4:00.
What's her name?
- Is she pretty?
- What else, stupid!
Ok. There are tree more weddings
but we'll manage.
0k. Take me to the bride now.
- You'll wait outside.
- Yes, Mother.
You mustn't see her
before the ceremony. So, we said...
Watch your head in that wedding there!
What now?
Maria, the wedding bonbons!
- At last.
- Come on in.
Not now, children!
Out! Everybody out! Now!
- Where do we out this?
- Put it in a handchief.
- Try it on now, go ahead.
- Now it does fit you lovely.
- A little further back.
- It'll do.
Those bells drive me crazy.
- Did he have to pick today?
- It was his mother's idea.
As for her,
don't get me started!
His mother wants this,
his mother wants that...
For her son's happiness,
why shouldn't she?
I'm Milto's mother.
Please come in.
Thank you.
You must be Maria.
- And who are you?
- Anneta, a friend of Stella's.
- May to yours then.
- Thank you.
I thought I'd come meet the bride.
What would people say if we
first meet in the chapel.
I've been urging her to call on you.
Pay her respects.
That's as it should be.
Not the other way around.
My son's not bad,
but you're a shade too pretty for him.
You don't laugh?
Do I scare you?
- No.
- I thought not.
You have my blessing.
Should I ask why you didn't visit me,
or just let it go with the wind?
- Let it go.
- Deal.
My son came home one day
and said...
“Mother, I want to get married. "
"About time, " I said.
"Who is she?"
"A fine girl, " he said. "She's poor,
an orphan but beautiful and proud.
I had a hard time
talking her into it. "
Is that how it was?
Yes.
Good. Shows you weren't out
to hook him.
Hook him up? I've never tried
to hook anyone in my life.
You're a proud one, all right.
I like that.
Thank God we won't be living together.
We would be fighting all the time.
Each housewife rules her own
house, that's what I say.
Yesterday Miltos got
your own house too.
Our own house? Where?
Not too far from mine.
He had to borrow for it.
Why didn't he ask me?
He knows I like living around here.
- Where are you going?
- For a cigarette.
And why here in the neighbourhood?
Because I like
being near my work.
Listen my child... I'm from Crete
and I don't like mincing words.
Marriage changes a woman's life.
You'll have a Husband, a home,
some kids someday.
You'll have to forget about all this.
My son may have played up
his gentle side so far.
- He did not.
- Good.
Cause if he had he'd be a liar.
He's as stubborn as a mule.
Good boy yet strongheaded -he'd kill or
get killed in order to have his way.
Get me?
I 89¢ you.
Good.
Know why I told you
all this?
Because neither of you seems
cut out for half measures.
- Am I right?
- Right.
It's not for nothing
you have those big, hungry eyes.
I'll see you in church.
Don't be late.
- So that's Stella.
- What did you think of her?
For those two,
it'll be either heaven or flaming hell.
Let's go.
- Good-bye.
- Congratulations!
- Thanks! Hope you're next.
Fat chance, with that snout!
I saw another with
butterflies - unbelievable!
I'm going home.
I've got things to do.
- What things?
- That's my business.
- We agreed you'd get dressed here.
- I've changed my mind.
- Pick me up in the car.
- What about lunch?
She's marrying the best
and she's all nerves.
I wish it were me.
Come on. Let's see to the flowers.
It's almost noon.
Miss Maria sent me.
I've brought you something to eat.
Leave it there.
- You've been crying?
- A little.
Why?
Because of all the boys like you.
I don't understand.
Never mind.
- I've got to get going...
- Wait.
- What's your name?
- Antonis.
- How old are you?
- Nearly 20.
You don't say!
Every inch a man.
Let's have a smoke.
- I have here boy.
- Oh please... Please have one of mine.
Oh excuse me.
- Is that your wedding dress?
- Yes.
You'll be stunning in white.
You mea I'm not with this one?
You always are.
I've seen you often.
Why did you never speak to me?
I didn't dare.
Has any girl told you you've
got beautiful eyes? Fiery?
No.
Pm glad I'm the first.
Me too.
Aren't you scared
saying such things on my wedding day?
Scared of what?
Of my husband.
Do you know him'!
No, but he's very lucky.
- Are you coming to the wedding?
- Unfortunately not.
Mrs Maria invited me but
I must go to the parade.
I'm standard-bearer
for my college.
Pity I can't watch you.
What is there to see really?
I'm sorry, I have to...
Oh, thank you.
You 're going?
I have to.
Good-bye, Miss Stella.
Bye, Antoni.
I wish I were in his place.
Stella!
- The weather's getting worse.
- Stella!
Aren't you dressed yet?
What are you waiting for? Quick!
- I'm not going with you.
- What did you say?
I'm not getting married.
You can't!
Stella, you can't!
Says who?
I surely can run away from their prison.
Keep my freedom.
- Then why did you accept?
- Why you said yes?
I loved him.
He forced me.
You mean you don't love him anymore?
I mean What's the point... I'll dry up
inside the moment he locks me up.
Stella, you'll go!
You can't make a fool of him!
Dump him in front of everyone!
Better now, before the wedding,
than later.
- You know him. He'll kill you!
- Then let him!
I only wanted his love,
and I gave him all I had.
Liar!
Why do they all want to change me? One's
to make a lady of me, 0110's a housewife?
- Your darn pride!
- Why'! Show me one...
Name one who hasn't tried to
change me to fit his likings!
What the hell am I then eh?
A damn record player?
Better to be killed by him
than marry him against my will!
You selfish bitch! You snake!
If you think what I'm doing
doesn't hurt...
you're wrong.
- Stella!
- Let her go.
- Let her go to hell!
- What are we gonna tell the man now?
The truth! Everything!
- Make him see what a tramp she is!
- shutup, you jealous one.
No, I'm not jealous.
It's him I'm thinking about.
It's Milto I bleed for.
We should've dragged her by force.
Stop that hysteria. I'm sorry for
him too, but I take my hat off to her.
- For spitting on her luck?
- Do the same if you can.
- I've no luck to spit on.
- And you never will.
Stella has guts! She listens to her heart.
Nothing else counts.
Are you out of your head?
You'd do the same in her shoes?
No... I Wouldn't have the guts!
That's why I bow before her now.
For me, she's like a shot in the arm,
a good dream.
Stella's never stugnunt inside. She's
always fresh, always full of life...
like a field of flowers.
Let's go.
She's late.
The bride, where's the bride?
Coming'!
I couldn't believe my eyes!
I told you
I wanted to see you.
But... the wedding?
- Glad to see me?
- And how!
- Where are you going now?
- Nowhere particular.
How would you like to be
my escort tonight?
Oh, would I!
We'll have fun!
Today everyone has fun. Right?
Come on. Let's go.
I don't give a damn,
I tell youllfls all in the head.
I rule my heart! And not all the
Stellas in the world can break it!
Why are you staring at me?
Is something the matter?
I said, is something the matter?
Go on, play!
Play Billy. You're a friend.
Tonight we'll have a ball!
Mitso, little brother, come close!
Whatever you say, Milto.
Anything for you man.
Okay, Stella.
Milto... Forget her.
She isn't worth thinking about.
You're right.
This is going to be quite a night!
She'll be here at some point - right?
We'll show her I don't give a damn!
“Oh Mikes'.!
I don't like the look of him.
Pray he leaves early,
in case Stella shows up.
- Huh Nfitso'.
- Huh Mme'.!
Miltos... The prettiest girls
are crazy about you!
Don't take it so hard!
Me? Hard? Why, can't you see
I'm laughing?
Think of all the people
laughing tonight.
They say Milto
was made a fool of...
that the bride ran out on him.
Let them laugh!
Tonight there']I be plenty of fun.
Stella?
What?
Shall I take you home?
No. To Maria's.
She's a friend.
Here we are.
- Shall I see you in?
- No.
I don't want to wake up Maria.
Go now. Quickly.
- And don't look back.
- Why?
It's bad luck.
Tomorrow?
- Tomorrow.
- Good-bye, Stella.
Good-bye, Antoni.
Stella, go away!
Go Stella, I'm going to kill you!
Didn't you hear me, Stella?
I've got a knife.
Say you're sorry. Say you'll marry me
and I'll drop the knife.
Stella,
Why don't you so?
Why?
Kiss me, Nlilto, kiss me.
Stella!
- My love!
- Kiss me!
Sss... me...
- kiss... me...
- Stella!
Stella!
Help! Murder!
Help! He]?!
- Stella!
What's going on?
What have you done, NEW?
Why'! Why'!?
Go away, all of you!
Leave her and go!
Milto!
It's all her fault!
Leave me! Leave her!
Go Mike'. “ifs not a murderer'.!
He is not a murderer'.
Go, mm'. Go'.!
It's all her fault!
Milto!
The police Milto,
they'll get you, please go...