- Hi, Stell.
- Hello.
- Hello, Stella.
Stella's got a fella!
Only he don't know it.
- Who?
- You, that's who.
My own sister, standing out here
every night making a sap of herself...
- over a guy who don't know she's here.
- You mind your own business.
Anyways, you don't know
what you're talking about.
I don't? You doll up every night
and wait to welcome me home?
- Why, of course.
- Ah, gee, thanks.
- I must give you a kiss for that.
- Stop! Take your dirty hands off me.
You're like all the rest. Fingers are
chopped at the mill when he walks by.
- But he don't look at none of them.
- Why should he? Mill hands.
Hey, wait a minute.
There's some nice girls
that are mill hands.
Where do you get off?
What's the matter with a mill hand?
I'm a mill hand.
Your father's a mill hand.
- Don't yell. The neighbors know it.
- Well, maybe he don't.
- So I'll tell him.
- Stop that!
Stop this!
What's the matter with you two?
You used to get along.
Yeah, but that was before she
started taking a business course...
to improve herself.
It's done her a lot of good,
all right.
- She ain't satisfied with none of us.
- Supper.
- What'd you say, Mom?
- Supper's ready.
So am I. Come on, Pop.
- Come on, Stell.
- I'll be in in a minute.
"The childhood sweetheart
of young Stephen Dallas.
A sweetheart until that tragic hour
when his millionaire father...
bankrupt and ill,
committed suicide.
Two days later,
Stephen Dallas disappeared...
leaving behind him a note saying
he was trying to make a life...
somewhere else.
Harvard graduate and crew man
disappeared after his father's death.
Millionaire playboy
left without a penny."
Don't be late, Charlie.
- What is it?
- Your lunch.
That's right. Get funny.
What's in it?
Just a little turkey and dressing.
That's all I had today.
Wait a minute.
Baloney again,
and apple butter.
Baloney and apple butter.
Apple butter and baloney.
That's all I get.
I ain't gonna take it no more.
- You can do without it.
- I can, huh?
- Charlie, I'll fix you something.
- Don't baby him, Mom.
Baby me? I'm old enough
to earn money, ain't I?
A man can have a home of his own
on what I'm makin'.
Charlie, wait a minute.
Oh, what do you want to
egg him on for, Stella?
That Jenkins girl's
just dyin' to get him.
Let her. If that's all the ambition
he's got, there's nothing you can do.
I don't know what
we'd do without him.
I'm gonna fix up somethin'
for him to eat.
You can leave it for him
on your way down.
He'll starve first.
Maybe you're right, Mom.
I'll take it down to him.
I'll run over to the delicatessen
and get him something nice.
Will ya?
Yeah.
Hey, the boss just phoned.
He's at Millhampton Junction.
He said to tell you the Parker contract
is right in his vest pocket.
He was chirping like a bird.
Said he'll be here in a few minutes,
but just wanted to tell you.
Hey, ain't you interested?
Yes, I'm glad Mr. Beamer
got the contract.
You oughta be.
He was chirping like a bird.
You know how he does on the telephone.
He said to put you down for a raise.
You can have that vacation now.
How's that?
I don't need a vacation now.
I have no place to go.
Huh?
Oh, nothing.
I beg your pardon.
Could you tell me where I
could find Charlie Martin?
He works on the carting machine.
Oh, yes.
The carting machines.
Why, they're closed down just now.
He'd be out in the yard, most likely.
I tell you what you do-- Go back through
the corridor the way you came in.
Instead of coming up those stairs...
there's a big gate down there.
If you go through that gate...
the path leads right down
past that first big building.
Just as you turn round the corner,
the men usually have their--
Yes?
Well, it's sort of dirty down there.
Maybe I'd better send for him.
- Won't you sit down?
- Thank you.
- McCarthy!
- Yes, sir.
- Find Charlie Martin, send him in.
- Yes, sir. Right away.
- He'll be right in.
- Thank you.
- Good morning, Dallas.
- Congratulations on that contract.
- How do you do, Mr. Beamer?
- How do you do?
- Stella Martin.
- Martin's girl?
You're all grown up.
And so pretty.
Isn't she, Dallas?
Yes.
Say, how long have you two
known each other?
- Well, we haven't really met.
- Oh, excuse me.
Mr. Dallas, this is Miss Martin.
Miss Martin, Mr. Dallas.
- How do you do?
My brother forgot his lunch,
and I didn't want him to go without.
- So I brought it to him.
- That's a nice girl.
Good to your brother.
Good to your father, too, I'll bet.
I wish I had somebody
thinking so much of me.
Eh, Dallas?
They said he went out to eat.
- Thank you.
- That's too bad.
- After all your trouble.
- I suppose it was all my fault.
- I was late.
- It wouldn't do him harm to wait.
I'll bet sometimes he's late.
Never mind. Don't you worry.
Let's see what you got. We can
make believe you brought it to us.
- Eh, Dallas?
- It isn't anything much.
Oh!
Make this yourself?
Dallas?
- Thank you.
- You too.
I hope they're not too dry.
I forgot to bring anything to drink.
- I have some milk here.
- Oh, fine.
- I'll get some glasses.
- Can I help you?
- Thank you.
- Hey, you're some cook, aren't you?
Oh, wait, please.
I hate glasses
that don't shine.
Don't you?
Shall we go?
You ready?
- Hello, Stella.
- Hello.
- Hello, Steve.
- How are you, Ned?
Don't forget, the missus will be
expecting you over for that good meal.
- You bet. Very soon.
- You go over there for dinner?
Gee, you who could be
at the River Club.
- Look.
- That's the second time this week.
I saw them in the drug store
together the other night.
You mind your own business.
- You mind our being talked about?
- Mind? I mind?
Oh, no. It's just that I can't
believe you like seeing me...
when you could be out
with all the swells.
I want to be with you.
I like being with you.
Could I take your arm?
I mean, is that all right?
Is that considered--
I wanna be like all the people
you've been around.
Educated, you know,
and speaking nice.
Don't be like anyone else.
I like you the way you are.
No, I don't want to be like me,
not like the people in this place...
but like the people
in the movie.
You know, doing everything
well-bred and refined.
And dull. Stay as you are.
Don't pretend.
Anyway, it isn't really well-bred
to act the way you aren't.
But I wanted to be different
ever since I met you.
If I was around you long enough,
I could be.
I could learn to talk like you
and act like you.
Pretty soon, l--
Well, you've done a lot for me
even in these couple of weeks.
You've done a lot for me too.
I was very lonely the day you walked in.
Oh, no, I don't smoke
and I don't drink either.
I was lonely and unhappy,
and then you--
Yes?
Oh, I shouldn't have.
You won't have
any respect for me.
Not for girls who let men kiss them
whenever they want.
I mean, I don't let--
I mean--
Well, a girl shouldn't
unless they--
Well...
unless they know a man is serious.
Ain't she got home yet?
Does the old man--
- Hello, Pop.
- What time did Stella get home?
Huh? Oh, that was about--
That was around--
Oh, I don't know,
but she woke me up.
Hey, Mom, how about the coffee?
And Pop's too.
Tell Stella I want to see her.
Gee, it was kind of late.
Let her sleep.
Tell Stella I want to see her.
Yes.
Why, she ain't here.
I wonder where she
could've gone so early?
She ain't slept there.
She spent the night with Carrie Jenkins.
It was raining hard.
She didn't go out with Carrie.
Why should she stay the night with her?
When she gets home, tell her to take
her things and be out before I get back.
Listen, you can't.
Give her a chance to explain.
You shut up!
Tell her what I said.
All right, then I guess
that goes for me too.
Finish your coffee.
I'll talk to your pa.
I don't want coffee or any part
of this dump from now on.
I'm through!
- I'll tell you later.
- Gee, where have you been?
- The old man's--
- Look, Charlie.
Married? Oh, Stell!
Gee, Mr. Dallas, that's swell.
Hey, Ma, she's here.
She's married.
Hey, Pop, it's okay now.
She's here.
We're here, Agnes.
My, oh, my, you sure is.
And there it is.
Yes, ma'am.
Who do it look like?
Let me see who you look like,
your pappy or your mammy.
Go ahead and open the door.
You'll have time for that later on.
Yes'm. Yes, ma'am.
I know who's gonna be boss
around here from now on.
Oh, gosh.
Home never looked so good to me.
Poor Stella.
I didn't mind it.
The hospital got on my nerves.
That darned doctor trying
to make me stay another week.
- He thought it would be better--
- Better for who?
It was just to get your money.
I felt as good the next day as ever.
Maybe better than I had
for a while.
Oh, Stephen,
why didn't you bring them to me?
The days wouldn't have seemed
half so long.
- I thought everybody'd forgotten me.
- I think we'll get you to bed.
Bed? I just got up.
Haven't you seen enough of me
in bed for the past three weeks?
Seems like three years to me.
You'll soon find you're not
as strong as you think you are.
You must remember I've had a great deal
of experience in these maternity cases.
Experience?
What do you think I had?
Tell me why doctors, nurses
and husbands...
always think they know more
about this maternity business.
Don't you think a mother learns anything
in that room they wheel her into?
Or is that just
a kindergarten class?
Let me tell you. I picked up
quite an experience in that room.
That wasn't out of books either.
Experience.
- Stephen.
- Yes, dear?
A dance at the River Club
tomorrow night.
I think I can wear
my blue dress.
- I'll let it out a little at the top.
- You don't want to go dancing already.
Before I went to the hospital,
I was stuck in this house...
for four solid months
without going anywheres.
We just got in to the River Club.
All my life I've died to go to the real
places and get in with the right crowd.
Just when I got a chance to get started,
I have to give it all up.
We'll go next time.
I don't want to go next time.
I want to go this time.
Stephen, I won't dance much.
I promise.
I just want to get a wave
and a manicure...
and get all dressed up again
and go hear some music...
and forget all about doctors
and hospitals and nurses.
And babies?
Ah, but Stephen, please.
Why, you're a wonderful dancer,
Mr. Munn.
If I'm any judge of horse flesh,
you don't shake a mean leg yourself.
Who's that she's dancing with?
He's pretty good too.
- I really don't know.
- His name is Munn.
He has something to do
with horse races.
The girls invite him over for golf,
and he gives them tips.
How'd you come to get hooked up
to a table like that?
They're some business friends
of my husband's.
Business friends?
What is he, an undertaker?
Get him to ditch that bunch of moss bags
and come over and join us.
Spencer Chandler's table?
We don't even know him.
Well, that won't take long.
- You know what he said after our dance?
- No. What?
He said, "Ed--"
He always calls me Ed.
"You can pick winners on a dance floor
better than you can on a racetrack."
Yeah? Ah, go on.
Don't red apple me.
No, on the level.
I'll prove it to you.
I'd have to ask Stephen first.
- Yes?
- Come here.
Excuse me. Yes?
- This is Mr. Munn.
- How are you?
Mr. Spencer Chandler wants us
to come over to his table.
- I'm sorry. We're just leaving.
- Leaving?
- It's only quarter after.
- I know, but that's late for us.
- Come just for a nightcap.
- Yes, Stephen, please.
I'm afraid we can't.
Thank you. Good night.
Good night.
I'll get the things.
He dug it out of his pocket.
The horse came in and paid 20 to 1.
What do you think of that?
- Oh, dear.
- Did you lose something?
- What was it?
- May I help you?
I remember.
I gave it to Mr.--
Pardon me.
- What do you think of that?
- What a story.
Say, Ed, did you give me back
my handkerchief?
- You never gave it to me.
- I must have lost it.
- Take mine.
- No, I didn't mean--
Wait a minute. I want you
to meet a friend of mine.
- Mr. Chandler, this is Mrs. Dallas.
- How do you do?
Spencer, I want you to prove
something to her for me.
Didn't you say I could pick 'em on
the dance floor as good as on the track?
I wouldn't feel too flattered. Munn
hasn't given me a winner in a month.
- Will you sit down?
- Thank you.
Miss Dallas, I'd like you
to meet Miss Terry.
I believe your wife lost something,
and she thought maybe Mr.--
- Mr. Munn might know.
- Thank you.
Stephen, this is Mr. Chandler.
Mr. Chandler, my husband.
Mr. Chandler asked me to dance.
You don't mind?
Sorry, my wife's just out of
the hospital and should be in bed.
We'll hurry then.
Come on.
You wouldn't like to sit down
and have a little snifter?
No, thank you very much.
Thank you.
What have I done this time?
I'll take my usual lecture. Begin.
Stella, I asked you not
to wear those earrings...
that cheap imitation necklace.
You took them off.
You agreed.
Then after we got there,
you came out of the dressing room--
I'm perfectly willing to let you
tell me how to talk and act.
But please don't give me pointers
on how to dress.
Allow me at least to know more
about one thing than you do.
After all, I've always been known
to have stacks of style.
You should have heard Ed Munn,
and he's been around a bit too.
He's traveled further,
and he--
All right, then, farther.
Whichever it is, I don't care.
Gosh, I have to think twice
every time I open my mouth.
Spencer Chandler didn't seem to
have to turn the other way either.
He only happens to be
one of the Chandlers.
Please don't say things
like that.
- Remember you're my wife now.
- And can't look at another man.
- That isn't the point at all.
- That's a laugh.
An affair between
Spencer Chandler and I.
Well, I am coming up
in the world.
Stella, can't you--
Won't you try to understand?
Please listen to me this time.
Please.
The fake jewelry is not important.
Chandler's not important.
None of these things matter
in themselves.
But what's to become of us?
That is important.
Stella,
why did you marry me?
Because I was crazy about you, silly,
and I still am, only--
- Only you just don't seem to ever--
- Once, a long time ago...
you said you were crazy
to learn everything, become someone.
Didn't you?
- Yes, Stephen.
- Please listen to me.
I'm only telling you this
because I love you.
Beamer wants to send me to New York
to handle the sales department there.
I want to go.
I want to take you with me,
but I want you to make an effort.
I want you to try to be...
what you wanted to be.
Give up a few things for me
and try to adapt yourself--
Adapt myself?
Give up a few things?
Well, what have I been doing
ever since I met you?
I'm getting
a little sick of it too.
How would it be for you to do
a little adapting for a change?
I don't see you
giving up anything.
I'll tell you one more thing.
I'm not going to New York.
I'm not gonna leave here just when I'm
beginning to get with the right people.
You go on and go to New York.
I'm gonna stay here.
Can you beat that?
Laying awake waiting for her dinner,
and not a squawk out of her.
Gosh, Carrie...
I used to think girls
at the mill were crazy...
when they got married and right
off the bat started having kids.
But honest, Stella,
would you want any more?
Sure, if I could have
another one like her.
She's been a regular pal to me.
Since Stephen's been away in New York,
I hardly know I have a husband.
He's only been here three times
this summer, and only on account of her.
He's crazy about her.
Who wouldn't be?
Oh, look at her.
Wiping it up at her age.
Can you beat that?
She's the spit of her old man.
Now, who's that? Edna?
Is this all the welcome I get?
Of all people!
- Gosh, I'm glad to see you.
- And I you.
- I haven't seen you for ages.
- Get a load of that kid.
Has she grown,
or am I crazy?
Come on.
Gee, Stell, she looks more
like you every time.
You remember Uncle Ed,
don't you, darling?
I remember you.
- Oh, let me see.
- How's that?
Oh, Ed, you shouldn't
have done this.
Don't she look like a little queen?
It's gold and turquoise.
Edna!
You want a drink, don't you?
Sure, and if you don't mind,
I'll peel this coat.
Sure, go ahead.
What'll it be?
You know me. I ain't particular,
so long as it don't jump up and bite me.
- But I've been drinking bourbon.
- What have you been drinkin'?
Nothing, but I'll take bourbon.
You oughta have been along. Maybe
you've been having too much fun here.
- I haven't been out for two months.
- Been sick?
I don't seem to get any fun
out of a good time anymore.
All the time I'm out, I'm thinkin'
of her and what she's doing...
and how soon I can get back to her.
Well, here's hoping I'll always
be around at the right time.
- What are you drinking?
- Sarsaparilla.
Stealin' the kid's drinks, huh?
Did you ever catch her
sneaking your oatmeal?
- Say, can I pick her up?
- Sure, go ahead.
Come to your Uncle Ed.
Got ya, girl.
Come on. Ain't you got a big smile
for your Uncle Ed?
Of course she has.
Come on. Smile for Uncle Ed.
- Edna!
- I'll get it.
If I could only see her
open that door just once.
- Come on.
- Come on, darlin'.
Smile for Uncle Ed.
- Oh, you remember Mr. Munn.
- How do you do?
- And Carrie Jenkins.
- Yes, how do you do?
I'll be getting along.
- Yes, darling.
- That's a fine baby you got there.
- Thank you. I think so.
- I gotta be going too, Ed.
Me too.
Just a minute.
I'll see you to the door.
Thanks for the good time.
- Bye.
- Bye-bye.
Stella, I can't have our child
living this way.
- What's wrong this time?
- It's not just this time.
Because there was a couple of drinks?
What's wrong with that?
Coming in here with that
icebergy way of yours.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to be rude.
But she's my child, too,
and I won't have this.
I hadn't wanted to take Laurel
away from you, but if you--
Take her away from me?
What are you talking about?
How dare you say such a thing?
Give her to me.
- Give her to me, I say!
- You mustn't do this.
Watch out!
You're hurting her!
Get out.
Did he frighten
Mommy's little girl?
Don't you cry.
Mommy's right here.
Mommy won't let anybody hurt you.
There, there.
You're here with Mommy, and nobody
in the world will ever take you away.
Nobody.
Thank you.
- Boy.
- That's cute.
Would you like to include
one of those too?
She's a little too grown up now,
I'm afraid. That's all.
Come on, fellas.
Mother's ready.
- Come on, boys.
- Mother, he rows it himself.
Can't we wait until he winds it again?
I want you to see how it goes.
- Thank you, Mr. Dallas.
- You'll send those right away?
- Helen.
- Oh, Stephen.
- I'm so glad to see you.
- And you.
Boys, come here, please.
- Stephen, these are my sons.
- How do you do, young gentlemen?
How do you do?
This is Mr. Dallas, whom your mother
has known for such a long time.
John.
- How do you do?
- Lee.
- And Cornelius.
- Con.
He doesn't like
to be called Cornelius.
I do too.
It was my father's name.
- Was?
- Con's the man of the family now.
He looks after us all so beautifully.
His father would be very proud.
Splendid. Nothing but the finest care
would be good enough for your mother.
But, Stephen,
tell us about you.
I gave up all thought of ever
seeing you again such a long time ago.
- What are you doing here?
- New York? I'm in business here.
If you mean this store, I'm buying
birthday presents for my daughter.
Your daughter? Oh, Stephen.
- Here she is.
- Oh, she's pretty.
- When may we meet her and her mother?
- They're not here.
Laurel goes to school near Boston,
and her mother spends her time with her.
I have so many things to hear
and to tell.
- Can you lunch with us?
- I should be back at the office now.
We'd be glad to have you, if you
don't mind carrying your own tray.
John's been saving up for a whole month
to take us to lunch. It's his treat.
That's all right. I got enough for
one more, if you don't eat too much.
How 'bout it, Mr. Dallas?
- I can't refuse an offer like that.
- Oh, good. Come along.
If you run short,
I'll lend you a couple of dollars.
Gee, thanks.
Oh, books again.
I've got a good mind to tell him
she can get books from the library.
But there's no place where you
can get a fur coat for nothing.
Boy, what I wouldn't give
to see her in one.
Oh, well. Here.
Hide them with the rest
and let me get on with this...
or it won't be ready for Christmas,
let alone her birthday.
- Gladys, where's Mother?
- Now, let me see.
She's--
- Hello, Mother.
- Hello, darling.
Miss Phillibrown, my teacher,
came home with me.
- She wants to see you.
- If I'd known, I could have fixed up.
Look at me. I'm a sight.
Look at the things all--
Oh, dear.
Mother, this is Miss Phillibrown.
- How do you do?
- Pleased to meet ya.
- Won't you sit down?
- I haven't a minute, but--
Thank you. My dear, I wonder
if I might have a glass of water.
- Of course. You too?
- No.
Maybe she'd rather have sarsaparilla.
I have some on ice.
- No, thank you.
- All right.
She's such a darling.
I didn't want to talk in front of her
in case she might be disappointed.
I spend the weekends in Boston.
May I borrow Laurel for this one?
I couldn't get her ready this time,
but if you'd ask her again--
Lollie thinks the world of you.
I know she'd have a wonderful time,
seeing some decent shows...
not just movies.
I had in mind
the galleries and museums.
- She seems so interested.
- Oh, yeah.
She's crazy about that stuff.
She gets it from her father.
Her father?
You see,
I've only heard about you.
Oh. 'Course, she don't see
as much of her father.
Mr. Dallas' business
keeps him in New York.
- Really?
- But I always spend vacation with him.
Up in Maine, in the woods.
Have you ever been there?
Oh, it's beautiful.
Your mother's given her permission
for you to spend a weekend in Boston.
- When?
- Very soon.
Oh, thank you, Miss Phillibrown.
- I really must go.
- Oh, must ya?
- Good-bye, Mrs. Dallas.
- Good-bye. Come again.
Thank you.
- Good-bye, Laurel, dear.
- Good-bye, Miss Phillibrown.
- Mother, isn't she the nicest?
- Yes, darling.
- Did you ask her to the party?
- No. You think she'd come?
Of course. Why not?
Mother! For the party?
What did you do that for?
You're always sticking your--
Mother, I'm sorry.
Come here.
I didn't mean to--
You know how I always fly off,
and l--
Well, I wanted it
to be a surprise--
Well, now that you've seen it,
you may as well slip it on...
and let me fit you
instead of this thing.
- Dummy.
- Oh, it's blue.
There.
- It's beautiful!
- Careful. Don't mash the ruffles.
Now. Oh, yeah, I forgot.
This goes here.
- Oh, no.
- Yes, it gives it a little snap.
You're just like your father. You want
everything plain as an old shoe.
Plain? With all these
beautiful, handmade ruffles.
Now, turn around.
Yes, the length's all right.
It's just the sleeves.
Take it off, let me get on with it.
- Yoo-hoo! What's going on in there?
- Come on in, Ed.
Wait till I get out.
What is this?
A Follies dressing room?
What's the matter?
He shouldn't see me like this.
Ed's known you since you were knee-high
and seen you with hardly anything on.
Even less than that. What have you
got to hide from your uncle?
- Let me see.
- Mother, make him stop.
Stop!
Lollie, don't be a little fool.
I wish you wouldn't tease her.
You know she don't like it.
I know, but I get a kick from
a young one being so finicky.
Well.
- Your car downstairs?
- No.
It's in the shop. Why?
I wanted to go to town and get
the decorations for the party.
Why not go in on the train?
Take the kid, see a show, have dinner.
No, I don't want her
to know what I'm getting.
Oh, I see.
I guess I could show you
a better time without her.
- How long will you be?
- I won't be long.
- Unless you got a drink here--
- I got sarsaparilla.
I'll meet you at the corner.
Sarsaparilla.
Honest, some of the things
I do for you.
You'll like it when you get used to it,
and it's good for you too.
- What's that?
- You can read, can't you?
Itch powder?
Things are just a little
too quiet around here.
Hey, can I see that?
What's the name of that horse?
- What's the matter?
- I got a ticket on it.
- Kokomo wins. I'm rich!
- Let me shake your hand.
Thank you.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- I'm awfully glad.
- I stand to win $30,000.
- Good.
- Have a cigar.
- What happened?
- Sir!
- You want gum. We go to all parts here.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
- Say, that was great luck.
- Did you see what happened?
He won $30,000 on a horse race.
- You're kidding.
- Kidding?
Watch 'em commence.
I can't stand it.
Another one just bit the dust.
You're killing me.
Get the old girls.
They're doing a sister act.
They must have rehearsed.
What's so funny?
Now what'd you do?
Come on, look.
They're two down there.
Gee, Ed, I don't see how you
can keep such a straight face.
What's a little kidding
among friends?
- Is that the father?
- No, it can't be.
She particularly said
her husband was in New York.
Such women don't deserve
to have children.
The one way to drink sarsaparilla
is so it don't taste like sarsaparilla.
Do you mind?
You want some?
Laurel's such a lovely child.
I don't know what to think.
Mary Anne's been asked
to her party.
Scratch that first entry of yours
and give somebody else a chance.
- Honest, I'd do anything--
- Please don't, Ed.
It's like I told you.
It's not personal.
I don't think there's a man living
that could get me goin' anymore.
I don't know. I guess Lollie just
uses up all the feelings I've got.
I don't seem to have any left
for anybody else.
You got plenty for me.
Why can't we go on as we are?
I don't know what
I would have done without you...
when Loli was with Stephen.
You're such a good sport
and such a lot of fun.
I guess you know
what you're doing.
- What's the matter?
- I got some of that stuff on me.
Wouldn't that be a hit?
I have.
It's all over here.
Gladys, are you nearly ready?
I have to let her in.
I'm ready. Miss Dallas!
Do I look all right?
None of them have ever seen me.
She's always telling them
how beautiful I am.
Honey, you sure
can live up to it.
But if I live through this day,
I'm gonna get me another corset.
Coming, dear.
How ever did you do it?
Oh, and you, Mother.
You look beautiful.
Do I?
Some favors!
Don't pull 'em. They pop
and have little hats inside.
- And little baskets.
- I put candies in with the nuts.
The place cards! They're beautiful.
Where did you get them?
I sit there,
and you sit here.
And Miss Phillibrown next to me,
and Flo Bell.
And Alice May.
Mother,
could I see the cake?
Go ahead.
Oh, look!
- One, two, three, four, five, six--
- You like it?
Here somebody is!
- Let Gladys go.
- All right.
Remember what I told you.
Yeah.
- Is this the Dallas residence?
- Yes.
Sign here, please.
- Thank you.
It's for you, Lollie.
Don't forget to say Laurel
in front of other people.
- Yes, ma'am.
- What is it?
It's from Miss Phillibrown.
She can't come.
What did she say?
"Dear, I'm sorry it's impossible
for me to come to your party...
but I'm thinking of you
this afternoon...
and I hope you will not
be disappointed.
Sincerely, your friend
Margaret Phillibrown."
That's too bad.
I do wish she could've come
just to see everything. And you.
Well, I'll fix up again
for her sometime.
Most likely the girls will have
a better time without her.
They see enough of her in school.
I know I did my teachers.
Everyone loves Miss Phillibrown.
Take these, please.
Well, anyway,
it'll make an even number.
Sure.
Come on. We'll wait
in the other room.
You sit over there.
Let Gladys go.
Remember what I told you.
- Miss Dallas' residence.
- That's right.
Miss Dallas' residence.
Okay. I'll tell her.
- Who was it?
- Miss Cheeny.
She says Alice May can't come.
Who?
Alice May Cheeny.
She sits next to me in school.
It'll make the table look better.
It won't be so crowded.
I'll fix it.
I better make some more biscuits.
The others is all dried up.
Yeah. Let's do that.
That's a very good idea.
You know, Mother.
They're not coming, or they'd be here.
Oh, Lollie, you don't think that--
We'll go in together.
I never know what to look for.
You change so much each time.
- Do I look older?
- Older? You're a young lady.
- Your wardrobe's growing up too.
- I have a costume for everything.
Fine, because we have
a wonderful invitation...
to spend our whole time together in
the most beautiful place in the world.
Better than Maine?
Where?
You'll see.
- How are you?
- Martha, this is my daughter, Laurel.
How do you do?
Oh, Daddy, how beautiful.
- This is Mrs. Morrison.
- How do you do?
- So glad to see you.
- I'm so glad to see you too.
Michael, this is Laurel
we've been waiting to meet.
Now, don't overdo it.
He's such a nice dog.
- Where are the boys?
- Still down at the stables.
Tell them their surprise is here.
You don't mind being a surprise?
Come on, Mike,
we'll go fetch 'em.
I'll show Laurel her room.
It's lovely.
How sweet.
If you let me have your keys,
I'll have Martha unpack you.
Oh, I can do it.
I'll take your coat.
Yes, thank you.
And your hat.
Oh, everything.
I like nice closets too.
We'll hang this here.
I'm so glad you brought
your riding clothes.
It was one of the things on my list,
to ride in Central Park.
We'll be using them here too.
And so many pretty dresses.
The fun your mother must have
choosing them for you.
She makes them all.
She does?
Oh, how clever.
What a lucky girl you are.
How lucky she is too.
All boys want to wear
are overalls.
I suppose you want to freshen up.
But don't change.
I'll see that your father has his tea.
He has to get right back to town.
Come down when you're ready.
Don't keep the boys waiting too long.
Thank you.
They won't acknowledge they like her.
They haven't got as far as that.
But have you noticed the hair brushing
and collar wearing going on?
I have.
Mother...
am I too little
to dance with Laurel?
- Did she say so?
- No, but Con did.
If I wanted to dance with Laurel,
I'd ask her, not Con.
I will.
Big intrigue.
Let me have it.
You'll drop it.
I will not.
- Why don't you let Con carry it?
- I wanna carry it.
- Good-bye. It's been fun.
- Oh, yes.
We'll look forward so
to next time.
I've had such a lovely time,
I don't know how to thank you.
Good-bye, Laurel.
I brought your suitcase.
- Here's a present for you.
- Thank you so much.
Good-bye!
Oh, aren't they the nicest boys?
I think so.
How did you like Mrs. Morrison?
I think she's
the loveliest lady I ever knew.
Do you really, Laurel?
Oh, I mean-- I mean--
Of course, I mean,
except my mother.
Mother, how nice!
It's a little stuffy.
I'm gonna open a window.
All right.
You happy?
I guess I'll shove off.
You two got lots to talk about.
So, what are you
gonna eat, Ed?
Me? I don't know.
I ain't very hungry.
I thought maybe
I'd stop in at--
Come back
and have dinner with us.
- You only bought two chops.
- One for you, one for Lollie.
I'm so happy,
I couldn't even look at a meal.
- What time?
- An hour.
So long, lollipops. I'll come back
and tie on the nose bag with ya.
- Want me to bring anything?
- No, thanks.
Why did you? I thought we were
gonna have a nice, quiet time alone.
So did I, Lollie, darling.
Things haven't been going
so good for poor Ed lately.
You'd never know it
to hear him talk.
You remember that big watch
and chain he used to wear?
Well, they're just
not there anymore.
I'm sorry.
She's not here anymore.
I let her go.
What did I need
with anybody around?
Oh, Mother, you shouldn't have.
Besides, I was glad to have something
to do to help pass the time away.
You know what I did?
I saved enough money out of her wages
for a deposit on a fur coat for you.
Mother, you didn't.
You're just going to
get it right back.
I don't want a fur coat now.
None of the girls at Mrs. Morrison's
are allowed to have them yet.
Oh, no?
Here.
You know what I've been thinking?
Would it cost too awfully much
for us to have a house...
with our own front door
and a little garden and flowers...
and a room for each of us?
Just in case sometimes we wanted
somebody to stay all night.
Mother, not a great big
expensive house like Mrs. Morrison's...
but just a little tiny place.
Say, tell me
about this Mrs. Morrison.
- What's she like?
- Mother, she's lovely.
She's sort of--
Well, she reminds me
of a flower...
that grows up in Maine.
All pale and delicate,
but strong too.
I don't know what you call it.
I don't care what kind
of a flower she looks like.
Is she tall or short,
dark or light, fat or thin?
- How old is she?
- She's not any special age.
She's like one of those goddesses
in my mythology book that way.
Come now. You can tell
whether she's 20 or 40.
Oh, she's not 40, no.
I guess maybe she's about 25.
And how did your father
happen to meet this goddess?
It's like a story.
Con told me all about it.
Con. Is that her husband?
Oh, no, he's dead.
Didn't I write you?
Dead, is he?
Well, that's convenient.
No, it isn't a bit convenient.
When Mr. Morrison died,
he left a whole lot of houses...
and horses and money.
Mrs. Morrison has to look out
for them all by herself.
She said she wouldn't know
what to do...
without Father to help her
and advise her.
Yeah. I can just imagine.
I just remembered.
I've got some snapshots of her.
- I just want to look at you.
- I want you to see her.
She's beautiful.
You'll be crazy about her!
The funny thing about her is that
she's not only beautiful all dressed...
but even when she wakes up
in the morning.
She spends hardly any time
on her face.
Once I saw her put soap and water
right on it.
All I can say is there are
different kinds of skin.
Besides, with her money,
she don't have to worry about her looks.
Say, are those real pearls
she's got slung around her neck?
- Look what you're doing!
- What?
You're getting cold cream
all over her picture.
- I didn't mean it.
- Give it to me.
I'll do it.
Oh, jingle bells, jingle bells
Jingle all the--
Hi, lollipops.
- Merry Christmas.
Here is the mistletoe.
Now, where's the kiss?
Run along. Go inside.
What do you mean by showing up
here in this condition? Get out.
I've got something for you.
I've been robbed.
Why, if I thought
that anybody would take--
Here you are, my dear.
A very Merry Christmas.
No, thanks. I can't take it.
I wouldn't know what to do with it.
Oh. What to do with it.
Cook it.
Run along,
give it to somebody else.
Me give my chicken to somebody else?
You think I'm gonna do that?
You come out of there.
Ed, what are you trying to do,
set the place on fire?
Cookin' a turkey.
Get that thing out of here.
- I say yes.
- Don't tell me how to cook a turkey.
I know how to cook a turkey.
- Now, come on.
- Now, listen.
I know how to cook it,
and so there.
The feet won't be very well done,
but I don't care for feet anyway.
Ed, be reasonable.
- Merry Christmas.
- Father!
I'm so glad to see you.
And am I glad to see you.
What a nice surprise.
You should see the way
I've been running to the door.
I never dreamed of anything so wonderful
as your bringing them yourself.
Ooh, what a lovely tree.
Here you are.
Oh, thank you, Daddy.
I'll put them right here
while I go call Mother.
I'll take your coat and hat.
This is a fine Christmas spirit.
You don't have anything in the house.
Strawberry. There you are.
Strawberry.
And lemon.
Peach.
What is this?
This is more sarsaparilla.
Of all the places I ever saw,
a man can't have any--
Go inside and keep him company.
I'll get dressed as fast as I can.
What are you whispering?
- You've got to go. I've got company.
- Oh, company.
- Who's the company?
- Never you mind. Just go.
I'd like to see the guy.
I tell you, Stella, no, sir.
I'm gonna sit right here
until I find out who the company is.
No, you're not.
You're gonna go.
Pushin' and a-shovin'!
I think the company
would like the turkey too.
It was the biggest turkey
I could find.
One of the finest turks
that the man had.
I never saw such a big turkey
in all of my life.
Daddy, a wristwatch.
How lovely.
- Do you like it, darling?
- Yes.
You're getting so grown up,
I don't know what to buy for you.
Mother copied it from one we saw
in the window of a shop in Boston.
- You can hardly tell the difference.
- It is pretty, isn't it?
- It was my best present till you came.
- Oh, you doll.
Well!
- Merry Christmas.
- Merry Christmas to you.
It's good to see you again.
- Well, it's good to see you.
- Sit down.
Thank you.
- The place looks awfully nice.
- You'll go to dinner with us?
Well, darling, l--
I came to ask your mother a favor.
I was wondering if you'd let me have
Laurel for the holidays this time.
I've never had a place
for her before.
This time we have an invitation
to spend it with the Morrisons.
Well.
- Would you like to go, Lollie?
- Yes.
- Oh, that is, if--
- Oh, I think it would be lovely.
- When would you want her?
- Well, my train leaves in an hour.
I was hoping I could
take her back with me.
- Today?
- No, not today. I couldn't, Father.
Mother and I
had something all planned.
Well, yes, we did, but--
Well, we could do that anytime.
Come on.
We'll have to hurry.
You have your new coat,
and you'll want these things.
I'll just get her started.
Excuse us. Hurry.
- There's your case there.
- Will this do for the train?
That's fine. Pack what you need now,
and I'll send your trunk on tonight.
All right.
She won't be very long.
This is for you, Stella.
Oh, thank you.
Stella, I'm awfully sorry...
when I see all you've done here,
and you did have plans.
- I didn't realize--
- Oh, it wasn't anything, really.
We were just going to a show
and dinner at the Bontonne.
This'll be
a real treat for her.
It's been so long
since I've seen you.
- How have you been?
- Well, thank you.
- And you?
- Oh, fine.
That's good.
Too bad your train
leaves so early.
Stella, l--
I've been thinking.
I don't know why it didn't
occur to me before...
but there's no earthly reason
why you should spend today all alone...
just because I've been
selfish and thoughtless.
There must be a later train.
Where's the telephone?
Shall we call and see?
Oh, yes, please!
Here.
Beacon Hill 3700, please.
Fooled you, didn't I?
You put me out the back door
and I went around again...
right in here.
Just where is all this company
that I'm being kicked out because of?
I'm gonna tell you this. You're not
gonna feed 'em my turkey. No, sir.
Not--
I beg your pardon.
I guess l--
Oh, I'm sorry, Stella.
I didn't mean to--
I guess I'll go now.
Mr. Dallas.
He's had a little too much
Christmas, I guess.
He was here a while ago
and brought a turkey.
I had a terrible time
getting rid of him.
- What did you find out about the train?
- I'm afraid it'll be too late.
I'm sorry.
I'm all ready.
Was I very long?
Not at all, darling.
Good-bye, Stella.
I'll take good care of her.
Bye, Stephen.
Good-bye, Mother.
- Good-bye, Stella.
- Bye.
Thank you for letting me go.
- Mrs. Dallas, Mr. Morley.
- How do you do, Mrs. Dallas?
Won't you sit down, please?
I wrote you a letter,
and in it I stated--
Don't tell me what you stated.
Just tell me what you meant.
It's only natural to suppose that you
should wish to legalize your position--
Legalize my position?
I've got a marriage license.
What are you tryin' to give me?
Your freedom.
A divorce.
Mr. Dallas feels,
and I can readily understand why...
that you might wish to remarry.
Let's get down to brass tacks. I haven't
the slightest idea of ever remarryin'.
Now, it don't happen,
by any chance, to be...
Mr. Dallas who wishes
to remarry, does it?
Well, assuming for the moment
that it does...
surely you could have
no objection.
Your allowance would be the same.
As a matter of fact, Mr. Dallas might
even be able to increase the amount--
I don't want any increases. Let him
keep it, and let me keep my daughter.
Mr. Dallas has no intention
of any change regarding your daughter.
Oh, he hasn't. Then what's he
been tryin' to win her away for?
Takin' her to fine hotels,
country places, town houses.
Makin' her dissatisfied with
the kinds of things I been givin' her.
Does he think I don't see what he's
after? He'll never get away with it.
I'm gonna give her the same things.
Everything her heart's been set on.
Fine hotels, fancy friends. I'm gonna
give 'em to her, and he'll pay for 'em.
If he's got any increases,
he can hand 'em over.
If he don't,
maybe I'll get a lawyer...
and bring in the name
of that highfalutin widow!
I won't keep ya any longer, Mr. Morley.
Thank you very much.
Just see the check is mailed to the same
place. That's all the benefits I want.
This one'll do.
Look, put some more lace on it--
I'm sorry!
Nice one.
You're wonderful, Laurel.
Dick, you threw me
that last game.
The last one came over like a bullet.
Is that any way to treat your teacher?
- That's the way to take him over.
- What's the matter? Losing your edge?
- Laurel, this is Mrs. Clews.
- I'm glad to know you.
- You're improving rapidly.
- My teacher.
We're gonna have Dad's box for
the polo game. Won't you come with us?
Oh, I'd love to.
But I should spend
the afternoon with my mother.
See ya at dinner then. Bye.
- How is your mother today?
- Oh, she's much better, thank you.
Couldn't Mrs. Clews and I visit her
this afternoon while you go to the polo?
- Oh, yes.
- That's an idea, Mother.
I've been looking forward
to meeting her.
It's unfortunate
she's been ill all the time.
- What do you say?
- I'll have to ask Mother.
- Come on.
- All right!
- I'll call you.
- All right.
Hello, darling.
- Did you have a good time?
- Oh, heavenly.
Richard's mother and a Mrs. Clews I
just met want me to go to the polo game.
And they want to spend
the afternoon with you.
And see me for the first time
in my nightgown? Huh!
I should say not. And me
with a trunk full of new clothes...
my skin is just itchin'
to get next to.
Goodness gracious. But you go along,
and say I was asleep.
No, I won't leave you
alone again.
There's no sense in the two of us
being cooped up here.
I'll be all right in a few days. I'll
get all fixed up and meet your friends.
You know what I was thinkin'?
The first night I'm able
to go down in the dining room...
we'll have this Richard
and his mother to dinner with us.
Would ya like that?
I knew you would.
Go on, now. Run along.
You mustn't keep him waiting.
Wear your blue jacket.
I love ya in that.
Boy. Oh, boy.
Listen, will you tell me
which lady is Mrs. Richard Grosvenor?
Mrs. Grosvenor's
not here, ma'am.
Oh, then please direct me
to the tennis court. Maybe she's there.
Just across the lawn
and down that path.
You mean sort of over that way
and down there?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Oh. Wait a minute.
- Here you are, young fellow.
- Oh, that's all right.
- Don't be sill'.
- Thank you.
Here goes a birdie.
- Did I say birdie?
- Well, whoo!
- Tryin' to cover it up, huh?
- No, I'll wear it everywhere.
Did you see the makeup on her?
And those shoes!
Why, I thought
she was wearing stilts.
- Hello.
- Hi, kids. How are you?
Come on.
Move down one seat.
Whatever happened to you two?
We've been back hours.
We took a shortcut.
- Say, Paul, you sure missed a show.
- What'll it be, Mr. Grosvenor?
- What show?
- That woman on the tennis court.
I'll have a chocolate ice cream soda
with chocolate ice cream...
and whipped cream on top.
- What about her?
- Make mine the same...
only with vanilla ice cream
and leave off the goo.
I didn't know they let
that kind of woman loose anymore.
- Happy?
- You should've seen the getup.
- What a woman!
- Maybe Dick knows her.
- Dick, she was looking for your mother.
- Yeah?
Pete lobbed one over the fence
and she started chasing after it.
I never saw her before.
Who is she?
I don't know, but I'd sure like
to know where she got that paint job.
- It's a Christmas tree, not a woman.
- And it walks.
- Does it talk?
- And how!
- Good?
- Delicious.
That's the one.
I heard her say to Jimmy...
"You oughta see
my little girl play tennis."
She must have some little girl.
- No, I don't like it.
- It is rather heavy.
- Let me see that one.
- This one?
- She's an ad.
- An ad for what?
We'll see in a minute.
Wait'll her hat lights up.
You're all wrong.
It's a trailer.
Do you think that one
really suits my personality?
- Yes, ma'am. Decidedly.
- You do.
I'll take that.
Send it up to Room 214.
Thank you.
"Personality."
Amy, get her.
- What's the matter?
- I must've lost my watch.
Wait a minute. You can't go
all the way back there now.
- When did you see it last?
- I want to go. Please let me go.
Don't worry about it. Let's finish
our sodas first. We'll find it.
There you are.
I've been lookin' all over for you--
Well, Lollie, what on earth--
- Mother, we're going home.
- Home?
What are you talking--
- What's the matter? What's happened?
- Nothing.
Oh, I know.
My little Lollie's had
a quarrel with her young man.
Mother, please!
Oh, don't be a little goose.
I'll tell you what you do.
I'll invite him for dinner, make
believe I don't know anything about it.
I'll pretend you're not back yet.
What's their number?
I wanna go home.
You wanna go home?
Well-- Well, what about me?
Payin' for two rooms all this time
and usin' only a bed.
Don't you think I'd like a little
of the fun you've been havin'?
I should think you'd think
of somebody else besides yourself.
You know...
I like nice people
and a little fun myself.
I'm sorry.
I don't see how your pride would let you
show him you cared that much.
If it was me, I'd stay on just to show
him that there's other fish in the sea.
It's only for you.
Well, you said yourself
this morning...
you'd never been
so happy in all your life.
And so was I too.
- Oh, dear.
- Here.
Here you are, miss.
Thank you.
Board!
- She missed it as sure as you live.
- Oh, there she is.
Nan! Did you have a blowout?
No, but just as I was leaving,
I met Ethel. Oh, I can't get my breath.
Here, sit down.
I want to tell you what Ethel told me.
You remember that funny-looking woman
parading around this afternoon?
- No, I didn't see her.
- You didn't see her?
She can't be described.
You wouldn't believe it.
I'll tell you, she was quite a number.
Her dress was up to here.
And paint an inch thick.
And bells on her shoes that tinkled--
- Oh, not bells!
- And bracelets up to here that clanked.
You never saw such a sight.
Anyway, do you know who she was?
- Who?
- Laurel Dallas's mother.
Laurel Dallas!
Oh, I can't believe it!
You mean that pretty little girl
Dick Grosvenor's been rushing?
Yes. Didn't you know her?
But are you sure?
She seemed so lovely and sweet.
Isn't it weird? To have such
a common-looking creature for a mother?
- Poor thing.
- Poor nothing.
She's wearing
Dick Grosvenor's fraternity pin.
-She won't be wearing it long.
-Not when Mrs. Grosvenor hears about it.
- Your berths are ready, ladies.
- Thank you.
-I want to tell you about--
-Ethel made it so interesting and funny.
- Lollie.
- It's lonely up there, Mother.
I want to come down here
and cuddle with you.
I'd-- I'd like
to see Mrs. Morrison.
- Was it in reference to--
- I couldn't say. It's private.
I'd have to see Mrs. Morrison.
- What was the name, please?
- Mrs. Dallas.
Mrs. Stephen Dallas.
Yes.
I will see if Mrs. Morrison is at home.
Come with me, please.
- Just wait in there, please.
- Yeah.
- Are you Mrs. Morrison?
- Yes.
I'm sorry to bother you
in your home, but l--
- Won't you sit down?
- What I have to say won't take long.
- It's just that--
- Oh, we may as well be comfortable.
It's so very warm.
Won't you take off your coat?
I know you must think it's funny,
me comin' here like this.
I'm not gonna beat
around the bush, but...
what I wanna know is
if Stephen was free...
if I got a divorce
like his lawyer wanted, would--
would you two get married?
Yes, we would.
I'm sorry if it's unpleasant, but--
- I'd rather that you knew the truth.
- Yeah.
Well, what I wanted to know is...
if you and Stephen
did get married...
well, what about Laurel?
- Would ya take her too?
- Oh, no, Mrs. Dallas.
I'm a mother.
Do you think I could ever deprive
another mother of her own little girl?
Yeah, but if the mother
didn't want her--
I mean, if she
couldn't very well have her.
- If it was inconvenient.
- Inconvenient?
Yeah. You see...
Lollie's growing up now,
and she--
well, she's quite
a responsibility.
Oh, I don't understand.
Well, you see, it's this way.
From now on, there's lots of things
Lollie ought to begin having.
I don't mean money, but...
dances and parties, you know.
Good times, and really I've never been
much at that sort of thing.
So I feel that I've done
about all I can for her.
I thought that you being
so crazy about her father...
and she takin' after him so much
that...
well, if you and Stephen
got married...
why, Lollie could come
and live with you.
And your name bein'
Mrs. Dallas, you see...
everybody would naturally
think she was...
your little girl.
Then when ya went places,
you see...
well--
You see, you're
the kind of a mother...
that any girl would be proud of.
I didn't know anyone
could be so unselfish.
And I'll say one thing. You'd never
be ashamed of Lollie either.
Everybody's just crazy about her.
Oh, she makes a wonderful impression.
She's so refined
and elegant in her ways, but--
Oh, you already know that.
Anyway, she'd--
Well, anyway, she's--
Well, she's crazy
about you already.
She don't talk as much
as she used to, but...
that's because she thinks
I'm jealous or something, and l--
Oh, I guess I was a little,
but I'm not anymore.
And you'll see.
In a little while, she'll--
Well...
in a little while,
she'll forget all about me.
And it won't be any time
before she'll--
She'll love you just--
just like you were
her real mother.
And Mrs. Morrison,
she's so wonderful. You don't know.
I do know.
And I know it hasn't come
only from her father.
I have to go.
Lollie doesn't know
I've come here, and l--
I don't want her to yet.
She's awful funny underneath.
And I thought it all out.
It'll be better...
to just let her come
for the visit like always...
and by that time,
it'll all be over.
The divorce, I mean.
And then--
Then you can
break it to her.
It'll be easier that way.
- Board!
- Good-bye, darling.
- Good-bye.
- Go on. Get inside.
- Good-bye, Mother.
- Good-bye, dear.
- You'll write to me, won't you?
- Oh, yes, I will.
Now have a nice time,
and don't think about me.
Wear your new blue dress tonight.
I wanna see ya in my mind's eye.
All right. Bye!
I love you!
Good-bye!
Good-bye, Mother!
- It's a lot of fun, isn't it?
- Yes.
- Haven't you ever played it before?
- No, I haven't.
John wouldn't go to bed
until I promised to bring these in...
so you'd still have some family
to keep you company tonight.
- How sweet.
- Oh, that John.
- And here's their breakfast.
- Gosh! You sure stand high with John.
He won't let Lee and me
see 'em, let alone feed 'em.
I suppose it's time young men removed
themselves from ladies' boudoirs.
- Okay, Dad.
- Good night, sweetheart.
- Good night, darling, and sleep well.
- I will, thank you.
Good night, Laurel.
I'll see you in the morning.
- Good night, Mother.
- I'll put these in a safe place.
Oh, I never saw Father
so happy before.
And you, dear,
are you happy?
So very, for you both.
But...
I've been worrying
and worrying about something.
Why, what could possibly
be worrying you?
Well, I don't know
what to call you.
Oh, if that's all.
I'm so glad, because I
have something to tell you...
which I hope will make you
just as happy as it has me.
From now on, you're going
to be one of us really, dear.
You're going to be a member of this
family like Con and Lee and John.
They're your brothers,
and this is going to be your home...
as much as it is theirs.
- This my home?
- Yes, dear.
You're going to live with us.
- Live here?
- Here, the town house, wherever we are.
Does it make you happy, Laurel?
Oh, yes, it makes me very happy...
to know that you want me,
and I do love you all so very much.
But I couldn't leave my mother.
Oh, you won't be leaving her.
Your mother will always
be your mother.
I could never expect or even want
to take her place in your heart.
- You'll visit her whenever you like.
- No, I couldn't.
Oh, thank you ever and ever
so much, Mrs.-- I mean--
Laurel, your mother, your father,
all of us who love you...
feel that now that
you're getting older...
there are many advantages
that we can give you.
I know.
And I do thank you.
But I'm sorry.
- Good night, Con.
- Good night, Dad.
Yes, dear?
What is it, dear?
You don't mean you thought
that I could live...
anywhere ever without Mother.
Well, you've lived without me.
Your mother and I are just
changing places for a while, that's all.
Isn't it fair for me to have a little
of what she's had all these years?
But that's different, Father.
You know it is.
I've been with Mother all these years
because I needed her.
Now she needs me,
and you need me less than ever.
Oh, Laurel, don't say that.
I'm sorry if you don't see that
what we've planned is for your good.
We thought it would make you happy.
Your mother and I have decided upon
what we think is best for you.
- My mother? Does she know?
- Certainly.
We have your interests
equally at heart, haven't we?
We both feel that this should be
your home for at least a few years.
I'm sorry, Father,
but please understand.
My home will be with my mother
as long as I live.
Oh, Stephen.
Laurel, you don't understand, dear.
This was all your mother's idea.
Her wish for you.
She planned it all herself.
Your father had
nothing to do with it.
She came to see me,
and we talked it all over.
- She came to you? When?
- Yes, dear.
Was it just after we got back
from the Mirador?
Why, I believe it was, but--
Oh, my poor mother.
My wonderful mother.
Oh, she wasn't asleep.
She heard what they said.
Oh, I must go to her.
I must go to her at once!
- Darling, tell us about it.
- Oh, please, Daddy.
Help me. I can't make my visit here.
I must go to my mother!
Sure you can see him.
That ain't meanin' that he can see you.
Hey, Munn.
Somebody to see ya.
Ed.
Ed, wake up.
It's Stella.
Ed, it's me,
Stella Dallas.
Hello, Stell.
Look, I still live
in the same old flat.
I want you to take this, get a Turkish
bath and shave and come right over.
Ed, do ya understand?
Sure. I got it.
Mommy!
Lollie! When did you--
Well, whatever brought you back?
Mother, how could you think--
As if I could ever live
anywhere else but with you.
Well, I thought you'd like it
for a while. No, really, you--
You always seem to have
such a good time with your father.
Yes, but good times aren't--
Oh, they aren't
what make you belong.
It's other kind of times.
It's when you've
cried together...
and when you've been
through things together.
That's when you seem
to love the most.
It's different when you--
Didn't they send a telegram?
They said they would.
Most likely they tried to deliver it
and I was out. I've been on the go.
- Put those in water for me, will ya?
- Oh, they're lovely.
From an old admirer.
Ed Munn blew into town.
- I've been steppin' out with him.
- Ed Munn?
Yeah. Now put 'em in water.
I want 'em all fixed nice
when he gets here.
- Mother, you don't mean that you and--
- Haven't you fixed 'em yet?
Give 'em to me.
Get some water.
There.
That'll tickle him.
Don't you remember
a long time ago we said--
- And you promised about him--
- I know what you're driving at.
Now let me tell you something. I've
spent the best years of my life on you.
A woman wants to be something else
besides a mother, you know.
Well, you will know
when you get grown up.
You can't explain
everything to a child.
Now, go on. Run along.
I've come back to stay,
if you still want me.
- Still want you?
- Laurel, my dear.
Tell me, dear.
What is it, angel? What is it?
Oh, Daddy!
What is it, sweetheart?
I thought it was for my sake...
she wanted me to come
and live with you...
and I was so glad and so proud.
But it wasn't.
It was for him.
She wanted to marry him!
- Please don't cry.
- You knew him.
- Yes, I know him.
- And she chose him!
Oh, Laurel,
come upstairs with me, dear.
All right.
So long.
Thanks a lot.
Well, hello!
You back? Gee, that's great.
Who do you think brought me home?
Dick Grosvenor.
We were just talkin' about you. I'll
get him. He's still in the driveway.
Oh, no, Con!
- I don't want to see him, not now.
- Now, now.
Oh, no--
No, not yet.
Go on upstairs, dear.
We'll take care of Dick.
Hey, Dick!
Come on back!
Laurel's here.
- When did she get back?
- She was here when I got here.
- How do you do, Mrs. Dallas?
- Hello, Dick.
- I'm glad to see you again.
- I'm glad to see you.
Con told me Laurel was here.
- All right, fella, that's one on me.
- No, she's here!
- Hey, Laurel's here, isn't she?
- Yes. Won't you stay for dinner?
Why, if I'm all right as I am.
-Of course.
-lf you don't mind, I'd like to wash up.
- Come on up to my room.
- Hurry up.
Okay, Dad.
Stephen, Laurel is here.
She's here to stay.
Who's accomplished it?
Couldn't you read between
those pitiful lines?
I told you those curtains
weren't to be drawn.
Open them, please.
Yes, madam.
Yes.
Now you must light the candles,
and we must hurry.
Yes, madam.
Come, dear.
It's nearly time for our cue.
What's this?
Oh, my darling.
I was just thinking.
I never really thought
that my mother--
I thought that she would
read about the wedding and...
even though she was too far away
to come, at least she would write to me.
Oh, my dear.
Do you think if she knew...
any distance in the world
could keep her away?
Then you think
she just doesn't know.
Sorry, but you can't stand here.
We have to keep this clear.
Move along, please.
Break up the group here.
- You too, lady.
- Please, let me see her face...
when he kisses her.
All right, folks.
You've seen enough. Come on.
Move along, please.
Come on. Clear the sidewalk.
Translation And Subtitles By
Captions, Inc. Los Angeles