Radishes are genius.
How about potatoes?
With potatoes,
it's up to the cook.
Radishes you can simmer or grill.
They're even delicious raw.
You don't grill radishes.
Sure, you do.
If you simmer and then grill it,
it loses its tartness.
Then you mix it with carrots
and sauté with sesame oil.
Sesame oil, right.
Better write it down,
you'll forget.
No need, I'll never cook it.
My husband grew up on fast food.
He'll eat anything.
Then, why'd you ask?
I thought you might
want to talk, Mom.
In that case, move your hands,
not your mouth.
It's nearly lunchtime.
Can you go buy some low fat milk
at the store?
Daddy.
Ouch.
He can at least buy milk.
He doesn't want the neighbors
to see him with a shopping bag.
What?
Even, at his, age, he wants
'to be called "Doctor"
I can't believe that.
You spoil him too much, Mom
Yokoyama Clinic.
Good morning.
Don't you wish the weather
would cool down, Doctor?
It's supposed to be another
scorcher, today.
When it's this hot, I can
hardly stand to drink water.
Cold noodles is all I can eat.
That's not good. You should
eat some eel, for your health.
I have a feeling my time
could be up any day now.
When it is, I want you
to be there for my death.
In that case,
I've got to outlive you.
See you.
Please, enjoy your walk.
ABE Hiroshi
NATSUKAWA Yui
YOU
TAKAHASHI Kazuya
TANAKA Shohei
KIKI Kirin
HARADA Yoshio
Written and Directed by
KORE EDA Hirokazu
STILL WALKING
Let's take the last train home.
If we leave at 8PM
we can make it
I told them we'd spend the night
Brought a change of clothes, too.
Can't you make up
an emergency PTA meeting?
No?
You're always blaming
someone else.
There's nothing to talk about
with them.
Dad still thinks I'm
a huge baseball fan.
You like baseball, Ryo?
I used to, long, long ago.
I want you to know,
I'm the one that's really nervous.
Though I doubt you notice.
I know, I know.
They say he even moved
near the race track.
It's a sickness, then.
As they get older, their bodies
can't keep up with women
and drink,
but not so with gambling.
It's the worst vice.
How awful.
You still have sparrows out here.
They show up because
your father feeds them rice.
We only have crows.
On garbage pick up days,
they're waiting like this.
Peel off all the skin.
Oh, there's some left.
You're such a pretty girl.
Show off your forehead.
When's Ryo coming?
On the phone he said,
by noon.
Is the "Unsmiling Prince,"
coming, too?
Yes, they're spending the night.
What a surprise.
But you know,
he didn't have to go
for a used model.
That sounds so cruel.
And besides,
it's better to marry a divorcee
than a widow.
At least a divorcee
chose to leave her husband.
You sound so scary
sometimes, Mom.
I'm just stating the obvious.
It's because you pushed him
so hard to get married.
Maybe, but he could have
had his pick
Ryo wasn't as popular
as his older brother.
That's not true.
At his graduation, all his
buttons were torn off.
He probably got beat up.
That's not true
All his lower, classmates wanted them.
He said there was
a long line of girls.
Parental pride can be blinding
Better watch out myself.
It's only been 3 years.
Since her first one died.
Isn't it 4 years ago?
In any case, it's too soon.
You think?
She's just cold
I'm not so sure
I am.
You've never worked
outside the house, Mom.
You don't know how hard
it is to be a single mom.
There you go, making fun
of me for "not working".
I'm not making fun of you.
Besides, after we put you
through college,
you only worked 3 years.
Four, it was 4 years.
Please bring it up
with your older sister.
About moving.
Shouldn't you discuss things with her?
Like about your father.
I'm sure she's got it figured out.
I'm not planning on moving back.
Although it'd be great
if they looked after them.
That's not likely.
You are, the eldest son.
I'm the second oldest son.
What's that?
Coca cola and ginger ale.
Drink them separately.
They have 'free refills
Don't, act so poor.
Say, how's school?
Average.
Average?
Yeah.
Listen.
Your mother told me yesterday,
about the rabbit.
Why did you laugh when it died?
It was funny.
What was?
Rena started saying we should
write letters to the rabbit.
What's wrong with writing letters?
Letters no one will read?
Your iced tea is
so delicious, Grandma.
They're just supermarket teabags
I used to steep my own, but.
Oh, I see.
lt must be the water, then.
It's just tap water.
You'll drink anything.
As long as you like it,
it doesn't matter.
Right?
What did you eat last night?
Sushi!
Hey!
I told you we're having
sushi for lunch.
Just the sushi that goes around
36 plates!
A new record!
Some record.
The pudding went around, too.
There's pudding
that goes around?
Melon, too!
I ordered some sushi just in case.
But if you just ate some yesterday.
It's fine, I haven't had any.
We can eat sushi everyday.
Everyday.
After the son took over at Matsu Sushi,
the fish isn't as good.
Is that so?
All done.
But they wrap their sea urchin
in cucumber, not seaweed
I like that.
Does sea urchin come with Sushi Deluxe?
That's what I ordered.
Maybe I'll call them.
Oh, don't bother.
Only one.
Don't spoil your appetite.
Oh, let them
That's what I bought them for.
You're lucky you don't get
scolded in Grandma's house
I love Grandma's house!
Too bad.
Without the "house" you
would've gotten another one.
Red bean, too.
That's for Grandma.
Oh, sorry.
You don't like red bean, do you?
Couldn't you stop
calling him Ryo?
If only for today.
To help your mother out.
But Ryo is just Ryo.
You know better.
You do it on purpose.
Tonami doesn't answer.
Publishers are probably closed
on Saturdays.
Call him back Monday.
Don't say anything
to them about my job.
Please.
If we make it through today,
we won't see them for a while.
They're your parents.
Don't be so defensive.
That's exactly why
I refuse to say I'm between jobs.
Not to him.
Oh, no.
You just get so defensive
about your father.
C'mon, carry one.
Hello.
That's "I'm home," right?
Nice to see you.
You're welcome.
lsn't it hot?
Hello.
What good manners you have.
You left this behind
I'm so sorry, he's always leaving
something behind. Thanks.
The station area's changed.
I got lost, drenched with sweat.
You're Rip van Wrinkle,
because you never visit.
That narrow bookstore's gone.
The owner got sick
and was hospitalized.
There was no one left
to look after the store.
We'll chill this
in the bathtub, and.
You said you like
cream puffs, Mother.
Thank you so much.
The first one goes to his altar.
Your flower arrangement's beautiful.
Which school, Mother?
Oh, I'm self taught.
Mom just fakes it.
When I took lessons,
it was completely different.
As long as they're pretty,
it doesn't matter.
Been a while.
Hello.
You have a nice tan
Hawaii?
No time to go anywhere.
I make do at the local park.
He walks around in his swimsuit,
can you believe it?
You've grown again, Satsuki.
Another 1.5cm over the summer.
You'll outgrow me, soon.
You eat enough
Mutsu, are you still fencing?
What?
He quit, after we bought him
all the equipment.
It's too hot and it stinks.
Oh, here's Grandpa.
It's nice to see you again.
Oh, you're here.
Hello.
He knew
I'm so sorry
He's so unfriendly.
Don't worry
My father's just like him.
When Junpei first brought
his wife here,
he ran and hid in
his examination room
I'm sorry, can you sleep OK?
I wake up sometimes.
Poor thing
I'm sorry his teeth grinding
wakes you up.
On his high school trip,
Ryota made so much noise
grinding his teeth,
they made him sleep
in a separate room.
The poor thing.
A separate room.
That wasn't me,
that was Junpei.
If you use your thumb joint,
they fall right off.
You're so good.
This always used to be my chore.
They wound up building it
as it was designed.
That's terrible.
They promised to
make it triangular
to let the sun in.
But it's square.
Exactly.
And they're still in court over it.
Oh, dear.
Don't mix it up like that.
You have to out into it.
Really?
How many years did you
watch me do this?
All done.
So pretty.
Brings back memories.
Strange, right?
Everybody does it.
No, they don't, do they?
I only know grilled
or boiled corn.
Did your grandmother teach you?
I wonder who.
Your original?
I bet, just like her flowers.
He'll be here any minute.
His eyesight's shot
but not his nose.
He couldn’t wait for supper.
He'd hear the corn popping and
eat them as fast as I cooked them.
My brother loved them.
You like corn, don't you, Atsushi?
So so.
Actually, I'm so so about corn, too.
You'll eat a lot.
They're best hot, go ahead.
With a drop of soy sauce.
So sweet!
Before we moved here,
our neighbors had a cornfield.
Sneaking in one night.
You stole corn?
Dad did.
Statue of limitation's up.
That was 30 years ago.
The next day was corn tempura.
Right as I was frying them,
there's a "Hello"
The farmer came over
to give us corn, saying
they had a bumper crop.
Just then, it started popping
in the kitchen, like before.
She tells the same story
every time she makes tempura
I sure felt awful about that.
So Junpei chimes in,
"Mother, we didn't have to"
"go buy that corn at
the green grocer’s"
He could be so smart that way.
He could.
Just like that other time.
At the bank?
He was a lifesaver.
This is going to be my room
I'll get a blue bed.
What about me?
There's no room for you
You're not moving here with us.
You can have this room, then.
Oh, good.
There's a ghost at night.
Forget it
I'm getting the piano, too
I want the piano, too.
You can't play
I'll learn.
You'll never play.
You even quit fencing.
Keep fencing, out of this.
Daddy, aren't I
moving with you?
Say, how did you feel
when your daddy died?
I don't know, I was little.
Did you cry?
I don't remember.
If it were me, I would cry
I know, what do you
call Uncle Ryota?
Like everyone,
"Daddy".
They should leave this downstairs.
Why'd they haul it up.
Are they starting to lose it?
They don't use this stuff.
They're probably lonely.
For what?
You know.
Have they said anything?
About my wife.
Not really.
It's heavy.
Do they disapprove
that it's a second marriage?
I don't think so.
She's terrific, wasted on you
watch out, you need
to watch your step.
It's too low.
It's not too low,
you're too big.
Did we eat the same food?
Ouch, ouch.
No, no, his memory's shot.
He can't remember the orders.
He served Toro sushi to the same
customer over and over again.
That sounds good.
Let's all go.
Please, spare me.
We'll have to fold.
You've always been a joker
I'm serious, I'm not joking.
How old is your father?
What? 72, I think.
Hey, same as Dad.
Really? The Doctor looks much younger.
He looks vigorous.
You call that vigorous?
Happily retired, right?
I'm jealous.
He wanted to keep working.
But his eyes.
He got cataracts.
No, the other disease.
But they also built
a big hospital nearby.
It was time for him to quit.
At least he salvaged his pride.
The sushi's here.
Here's 20,000 Yen.
Thank you.
Your change is 3,000 and
2 million Yen!
Hey, give us a discount.
Look how much we ordered.
Give me a break! I didn't tell
my wife about the sea urchin.
Here they are.
lt's heavy.
Don't eat the sea urchin.
Hey, is that you, Satsuki?
You're so tall.
I grew 1.5cm this summer
I quit fencing.
Nobody cares about your fencing club.
I almost forgot.
My wife sent this
funeral offering.
Oh, you don't need to
We don't say prayers anymore.
No, my wife was behind
Junpei in Jr High.
She gave him chocolates
for Valentine's Day.
Really? In that case,
thank you.
Why didn't you tell us
about this first?
I would never give you a hard time
about a discount.
Sorry, it just slipped my mind.
Getting yelled at for
making a funeral offering.
Why not come in
and light some incense?
I'm not dressed for it
I've got to get back.
No telling what Dad's up to.
Thanks for your business.
He's all grown up.
He used to be a bad kid.
You never know
how he might have turned out.
I'm done.
You're full? No more sushi?
Heavy.
Be careful, Satsuki.
Cheater!
Shouldn't I out it?
They want to break it.
You don't want to join them?
No, thank you.
You sure?
The handrail by the bath.
Yes, Dad fell last year
I heard.
He got such a big bruise
on his behind.
Oh, no.
Because you left
the soap on the floor
I didn't leave the soap.
Here we go again.
He's always blaming someone else.
Hey kids, if you hit it with those
there'll be nothing left.
You'll smash it.
The tiles are falling off
in the bath, too.
They just peel off
when they age
I'll fix those, later.
You don't have to,
you're a guest, Nobuo san.
You're happier
doing things, right?
I'm like a tuna.
I have to keep moving or die.
I wish it would motivate him
more at work.
That machine.
He took it upstairs for me.
The Rodeo Boy.
Happy to help.
Hurry, Daddy.
Excuse me.
Say, Ryota, now that
you have a family.
How about an RV?
I'll give you a good discount.
Living in Tokyo,
we don't need a car
I always dreamed that my sons
would take me shopping
in their cars.
Children don't necessarily grow up
the way you want them to.
They certainly don't.
Do they
I'll take you shopping in a car.
As much as you want. Which one?
Just you wait, just wait.
This white one?
You've got nerve.
You don't even have a license.
Second?
I'm full.
You can eat more.
You're still young.
But we can't have him
getting any bigger.
How old do you think I am?
Are your teeth all right?
You don't see a dentist, do you?
I'm too busy with work.
You've got bad teeth, like me.
Better watch out.
Open up wide, now.
Cut it out.
Not in front of the boy.
Is it a work call?
Yeah, well
I got a rush job from
the Setagaya Museum.
An oil painting?
Yeah, something like that
I saw an article in the newspaper
about painting restorers.
It said, "Painting Doctors"
Which paper?
I can't remember.
I'll send you a copy.
You say that, but you've
never once sent me one.
Sorry.
Well, I'm hardly as important
as a doctor.
It's not so much medical care
as it is "anti aging"
How lovely.
Can you help me?
What's that "anti" something?
I think you're past it, Mom.
You're so youthful,
you don't need it.
I'm not so sure I could help.
So I'm the only one left out?
My line of work is finally
getting the spotlight.
There's more students studying it
at my alma mater.
But when it comes time
to jobs, it's competitive.
Apparently.
You always
had such nimble fingers.
You can drink.
I take after my mother.
Yukie san could drink, too.
You could match her.
My brother's wife
I wonder where she's living.
The address on her New Year's
card hadn't changed Tokorozawa.
I see.
Wonder how she is.
If they'd had children,
we could invite her.
Now that she's remarried,
she can't really visit.
In some ways it was good
they hadn't had children yet.
A widowed single mom's harder
to marry off.
Luckily, a wonderful man
wanted me.
No, no, we're lucky
you took him.
That's not for you to say
Yukari-san, would you like to see
Ryota's childhood pictures?
Yes, please.
You'd show her
even if she didn't.
I want to get some of the pictures
of me in college.
Atsushi, you, too.
Did it break?
Did you break it?
Not yet!
Not yet.
We'll leave the two doctors
to discuss things.
What about.
What happened with repairing
the Takamatsu-zuka murals?
Restoration, not repair.
There was a long dispute about
whether to preserve
the tomb as is or to conserve
that national treasure, that mural,
Asuka Beauty,
they made into a stamp.
Ultimately, the Ministry of Culture
ruled to dismantle it,
in a rare upset for
local cultural preservation.
It'll take at least 10 years to.
That's a precious plant.
Don't do that!
Sorry.
Are you making a living?
Enough to support
a widowed single mom.
There.
Strike!
There's a crack!
Wow.
It broke.
It's hard to believe, but they
used to go to concerts together.
Classical music.
Dad's so impatient, he'd
walk fast and get way ahead.
We were always racing
to catch up with him.
Look, Mom, you're
in Hibiya Park.
You look like you're in love.
Back when I didn't
know anything.
This is just the 3 kids in this yard
This is Ryota.
Let's see.
Was he Atsushi's age?
I think about 5th or 6th grade.
The crape myrtle's still small.
We planted that right after
we moved here.
The flowers were a brighter red
than they are now.
You think?
This is when we all
went clam digging.
This is Junpei
This is Ryota.
Say, he looks like he's crying.
Whenever he heard
"Look at the camera and smile,"
he would just freeze up like.
Like this.
But he's really lightened up
since back then.
Is that true?
We owe it to you.
Not at all.
Oh, look, an essay.
From when Ryo was in grade school.
"When I grow up, I'm going
to be a doctor, like my father.
"My brother will be a surgeon, I'll be
an internist" Did you know this?
No, never
I was sure he always
wanted to be a painter.
"My father always wears
his white lab coat.
"When a patient calls, even
at night, he takes his bag"
Don't read that.
Who cares? Why are you
so embarrassed?
You don't need to
keep this stuff around.
See?
He can be exactly like Dad.
He just takes things seriously.
He can't compromise,
the way Junpei could.
If one of them had taken over
their father's clinic,
things might have been different.
Let's eat some watermelon.
Good idea.
Put these away.
Everybody line up, now.
OK, OK, picture, picture.
Come here.
Look, Mom.
What? It's so dirty.
A chocolate stain.
It'll stand out.
Wear it inside out.
No.
Please cover it up then.
lt looks so dirty.
Grandpa, please
stand to the side.
Where to, Mom?
Sorry, we're all here, now.
It's not a funeral,
it's bad luck.
It's fine Besides, we're all
here because of him
I know, but.
You're not in, Grandpa.
Grandpa, please step
in to the left.
Just a little more.
Grandpa.
Did he go to the bathroom?
We'll circle him later.
He's not dead yet.
Smile everyone.
You, too, Ryo.
And he's laughing.
We're off!
Watch for cars!
Is it hot?
Knock, knock.
Do you have to do that now?
Why?
Why don't you come
talk with us?
About what?
It doesn't matter.
Like about preserving tombs,
or whatever
Ryo was worried.
About what?
About how you feel
about his wife.
It's his life, let him do
what he wants.
You're so cold.
You weren't like that with Junpei.
Of course not
He was my heir
Ryo left the family.
What?
It was my hard work
that built this house.
Why do you call it
"Grandma's house?"
He's so petty.
Oh, there's a trick to that.
If you go like this and then
at the right spot.
Then to hold it in place,
you do this.
Says he doesn't want any.
Says tempura's all
he wants to talk about.
Just leave him be
He'll come back when he's hungry,
just like your crows.
They only come on Tuesdays
and Thursdays.
He's still a kid,
even at his age.
Oh, no.
Guess even tunas take naps.
He just finds
the tatami floor relaxing.
Yeah, our house
doesn't have any tatami.
You should get some.
That's impossible.
Our house isn't built that way.
Which is why, when we move here
we'll build a tatami room.
When are you moving?
Hopefully, before Mutsu
goes to Jr High School.
It's not definite yet.
But I showed you the blueprints.
Don't catch cold.
Like they say, when you age,
it's best to live with your daughter.
Depends on the daughter.
The ashtray.
We'll live together but
keep separate kitchens.
Of course we're happy to eat
whatever you cook.
All I'll do is look after you.
I might as well be a maid.
The body of Hagiwara Mikio,
a 53 year-old
employee from Yokohama,
was discovered today on the beach.
Oh, no.
lt's supposed to be autumn.
The night before,
he had made a rare visit alone
and stayed over.
That day, he was
shining his shoes.
Suddenly he said,
"I'm going to the beach"
By the time I said,
"Be careful".
We're home.
Where were you?
A secret.
You're sweaty.
Here.
You didn't pick it.
No.
Only his beautifully polished shoes
were left behind
I'll never forget
the sight of his shoes.
Have iced tea, not ice cream.
If only I'd said something
to him sooner.
Here we go again.
Oh, let me, at least today.
If only it were just today.
He didn't have to save him.
It wasn't even his own child.
Maybe I'll fix us a snack.
No, we've had plenty.
Well, you're all here.
After you pat it round, use
your thumb to make a bellybutton.
Here's another one.
What's that?
Poop.
Whose poop?
Daddy's.
Daddy's?
Poop? I used to make those
when I was a kid.
You should use our phone.
That Vietnamese place
was good, right?
I'm stepping outside.
Is it work?
Yes, probably.
He's so busy.
Does he come home late?
He's had a lot of overtime.
He's still in his 40s,
he'll be fine.
Whose oil painting?
A Van Gogh?
I doubt it's a Van Gogh.
How much does he get
for restoring one painting?
It's a lot of work.
How much did you say?
I'm asking her how much.
Here's your reward
for helping Grandma.
Thank you
Mutsu.
Thank you.
We love Grandma's house.
Where's Atsushi?
Not to worry,
it's not a big deal.
Listen, by the way,
do you know anyone
at Shinbido Publishers?
Yeah, I figured not.
Oh, hello.
Let's all get together
for dinner, soon.
You don't have to invite Mishima.
"Homoclomin,
"Prolmon,
"Triptanol,
"Neophagen"
Don't touch the medicine.
C'mere.
Here.
Grandma already.
This is from your Grandpa.
Have a seat.
What do you want to be
when you grow up?
What? A soccer player?
A piano tuner.
A tuner? Why?
Just spit it out, it's OK.
Because I like
my music teacher.
A woman?
The idea that a man be swayed
by some woman in his career choice.
Show me your fingers.
You seem nimble.
My father got sick
when I was a kid, too.
So I decided to become a doctor.
Did he get better?
Your father.
He died before
I became a doctor.
Being a doctor is good.
lt's a worthwhile job.
You go play.
Please don't give him
any ideas
I won't let him be a doctor.
It's not like I can afford to wait
another 20 years
I can't help that
I'm not talking to you
I know that.
Taking a little break.
Sure, you should rest.
You must be tired keeping
Dad and Mom company.
About that phone call.
Turns out they don't need me.
Oh, the Setagaya Museum?
You just made all that up
I didn't really have a choice.
So, it's a Chagall.
What is?
The oil painting you're restoring.
A Chagall?
What are you going
to do with all these?
I'm storing them
for when I need them.
When are you ever
going to need this many
paper bags?
The refrigerator's
stuffed as always
I feel safe when it's full.
Refrigerators aren't
made for safety.
They're made for refrigeration.
Hey.
Does Dad play Pachinko?
It's you?
What do you care
if I play Pachinko?
There's other things,
like haiku and yoga
I feel so relieved when I hear
that Pachinko sound.
Sure, Mom,
you've earned the right to spend
on whatever you please.
What about this house?
What about it?
Well, you know,
if you don't want us, we don't
want to force ourselves on you
I haven't said we don't want you
lt's just that.
It's just what?
I think your father won't like it.
You only bring up Dad
when it's convenient.
If we knock down
the examining room
and make separate residences
we can both be independent
I didn't know we made those sweets
from rice flour, did you?
Of course not.
It's getting cooler.
Let's go visit his grave.
What about you?
I'm fine,
I went recently.
In that case, I'll join you instead.
lt'll be a nine walk
I'd better wear a hat.
Sure, why not.
Why does she get so excited?
It's just visiting a grave
I wonder who left these flowers.
His widow?
If she came this far,
she'd visit.
Guess you're right.
Maybe it was Yoshio.
He'd never do anything
so thoughtful.
Tossing them?
Ours won't fit.
I'll light incense.
It was so hot, all day today.
The water must feel good.
There's nothing
more unbearable
than praying at
your child's grave
I never did anything to deserve this.
What do you want, Mom?
Her husband's
perfectly, nice, but...
I'm too old to live
with a stranger.
And the kids sure
make a lot of noise.
So you don't want them to.
Besides.
If they move back,
it makes it harder for you to.
Me? I can't move back
I mean, after your father dies.
After he dies. You know.
I can't take my brother's place.
Of course, I know that.
In that case.
Are you two
going to have children?
Where'd that come from?
You should think it over.
lt's harder to divorce with children.
What are you talking about?
Isn't the line normally,
"I can't wait for grandkids"
Your family isn't normal.
These days we're not abnormal.
You used to catch butterflies
in Karuizawa.
With your father.
Do you remember?
I don't.
Let's go visit your
father's grave, too.
Whatever.
Oh, it's not "whatever"
Look, a yellow butterfly.
They say butterflies that
survive the winter
come back yellow
the following year.
Really?
Sounds made up to me.
That's what I heard.
From who?
I can't remember.
After I heard that,
whenever I see yellow butterflies,
it just breaks my heart.
Climbing this hill gets
harder every year.
In a car, you'd be
up here in a flash.
It's better for you to walk.
You're right.
That was good exercise.
So, you're graduating college?
Yes, thanks to you.
Did you find work?
I wanted a job in the media but
I got turned down everywhere.
And that drama school?
Sorry, I quit that two years ago.
Oh, I see.
What a shame.
That's what you said to him
last year
I did?
I'm helping out at a small ad agency.
Maybe I'll get a job there.
That's perfectly fine, right?
When I say ads, I mean more
like supermarket flyers...
Did you take their exam?
Nothing formal like that.
Thanks
I figure I'll keep
helping out there for now.
Well, in any case, nothing's more
important than your health.
Well, my health is my only asset.
Um, seriously,
if Junpei san hadn't saved me
back then, I wouldn't be here
I just feel so sorry
and so grateful.
Thank you so much
I'll live my life
for Junpei san, too.
Excuse m e, then.
Oh, sorry.
Your legs OK?
They're numb from the tatami.
There's a step there
I'm sorry
I can walk, now.
You're still 25.
You can be anything you want.
No, I can see my life
won't go anywhere.
Come again next year.
Promise, OK?
We'll be waiting.
I will.
Excuse me, then.
Take care.
Sorry.
He got even fatter.
He must weigh over 100 kilos.
All that fat across his back.
He ate two of the desserts
he brought  for us.
And 3 cups of iced tea.
No wonder he's fat.
Look, his sweat.
Here, too, disgusting!
He even used the wrong
conjugation thanking us
for Junpei saving his life.
We should've given him
the Rodeo Boy.
You're right.
Go chase him down
at the bus stop
Ryo.
Not me.
That.
That useless piece of trash.
Why'd my son have 'to save him?
There were plenty of others.
Please don't say "useless" and
"trash" in front of the kids.
"A job in the media".
So pretentious.
He wasn't being pretentious.
The truth is he's barely
got part time work.
What's wrong with that?
He's still young.
His body just keeps growing.
There's no point
in him being alive.
You heard him apologizing.
Apologizing for being alive.
Just like that novelist,
who was it.
No, like that comedian
who keeps apologizing.
We're not talking about
novelists or comedians.
Stop comparing his life to others.
One of his socks was black.
He's doing the best that he can.
Things don't always work out
the way you want.
But how can you sit
in judgment, Dad,
saying "useless" and "trash"
Don't laugh!
What?
Wipe it with this.
You don't need to yell.
What are you so defensive about?
This has nothing to do with you!
Is being a doctor so important?
Advertising is a fine profession.
Who knows how Junpei would have
turned out if he were still alive.
We're only human
I heard "useless trash" and thought
you were talking about me.
I was scared to come out.
Thank god you were
talking about Yoshio.
If only he'd lose a little weight.
He looks like that former
sumo wrestler, who was he?
Takamiyama?
No, he's the one from Hawaii,
who's in those commercials.
I mean the one with the face
like a mid belly, like this.
What's a mid belly?
I think it's time to go.
Our driver's awake now.
Going home, so soon?
Yes we are.
Get ready!
Nobody asked him
to live Junpei's life!
Ryota, buy an RV.
We'd better put those
desserts in the refrigerator
Atsushi, can you bring
those desserts here?
Can you find a spot for
them somewhere?
There's no room.
Oh, dear, in there.
From Grandma?
3,000 Yen.
Grandma seemed to be
enjoying herself.
Of course she was The best thing
for her is to be with her family.
Did we earn some points with her?
I don't know.
She won't come out and agree to it.
She wants to preserve her son's room.
I can understand how she feels.
He's got it good.
We've got our hands full
taking care of the living.
You'd prefer she look out
for her living daughter?
Of course.
My brother's ghost isn't
going to look after their old age.
Don't worry, it's not that expensive.
lt's light.
It doesn't matter what it costs.
It's not like I'm going
to buy more than one.
Does Mother have her
own cell phone?
It's right there.
When she makes calls, she
goes and uses our home phone.
The fool doesn't trust phones
without cords.
Says to keep this here.
What?
What's so funny?
Nothing at all.
They should have stayed
for supper, too.
Oh, no
I couldn't stand to have
their whole gang
hanging around all night
Sushi for lunch and eel for dinner.
I'm impressed
I shouldn't have fried so much
tempura. What a waste.
Maybe I'll take some
tempura home.
Leftover tempura isn't any good.
lt loses its crunch
I'm glad we got the Deluxe.
Anything less and they only
give you instant soup.
Can you eat this?
Sure, you can.
You don't have to.
Grandpa will eat it for you.
Grandma will give you some eel,
instead.
You're so lucky
I can't eat all this rice, here.
Don't dump your rice
on top of my eel, Mom.
Inside your stomach,
it's all the same.
She's never had a delicate
bone in her body.
What do you mean delicate.
You're hardly one to talk
I take her to concerts and
she always falls asleep, snoring.
When was that, dear?
There are so many records
in the room next door
I used to be quite a collector,
in my youth.
Now it's just decoration.
He hardly listens to them.
They just take up space
I associate physicians
with classical music.
He was just the doctor
of a local clinic.
But in an emergency, it's good
to have a doctor in the house.
Not necessarily.
He was so busy,
he couldn’t be here when
his own son was dying
I couldn't help it I had a rash
of food poisoning patients.
Eat this.
You don't have a clue how
important work is to a man
I've never worked,
not even once.
Not that he works anymore.
What other music
do you listen to?
Well, jazz.
It's outdated, but Miles Davis
I can tolerate up
to about the Beatles.
But this recent rap crap,
you can't call it music.
You're right.
At Karaoke,
apparently he sings
Japanese ballads.
Karaoke?
I read it on Shimazu-san's
New Year's card.
"I look forward to hearing
you sing Pleiades again"
Don't read people's mail.
It was a New Year's card,
I couldn’t help it.
If you don't like it, have your
friends seal them in envelopes
Japanese ballads, huh?
Pleiades is not a ballad.
It's classier than that.
Don't you two have
a special, romantic song?
Nothing like that.
Yes, there's a record.
What is it?
It's a cherished pop song.
Want to hear it?
Last year,
she got tricked into buying " Favorite
Pop Songs" by mail order.
A 30 album set.
Who knows what it cost
I saw it in my room.
She's never listened to it.
I wasn't tricked.
How insulting, I'm not senile.
What? Who's song?
Play it on the stereo.
Now?
The needle rusted?
It plays fine.
How does this work again.
What kind of song is it?
How should I know?
It's got nothing to do with me.
But it has everything to do with you.
Mom, this song.
The city lights
are so pretty, aren't they.
Yokohama.
Blue light, Yokohama
I'm so happy
alone with you.
When is this song from?
About 1970.
Right before Expo '70.
I remember you sang it
sometimes.
We walk forever and ever,
but I only sway,
like a little boat
I sway gently
in your arms.
Only our footsteps
follow us.
Yokohama.
Blue light, Yokohama.
Your gentle kiss.
I'll leave your fresh clothes here.
With your towel.
When did you buy it?
The record?
About the time.
At ltabashi
I carried Ryota strapped to my back,
all the way to that woman's apartment.
I could hear your voice,
singing from her room.
"We walk forever and ever".
I didn't want to interrupt you
so I went straight home.
The next day, I bought it at
the Canary Record shop by the station.
Please leave your washcloth
hanging out to dry.
Remember how Mom said,
"It plays fine".
You know she plays it
when she's alone.
Kind of gives you the creeps.
That's not true.
What's strange about that?
Yeah?
Everybody has a song
they listen to on the sly.
You think?
Of course.
So you have one, too?
Which one? Tell me.
A secret.
Women are so scary.
People are scary.
Everyone is
I bet there's a baseball game on.
Want to watch?
We put a dish on the roof.
You can watch extra channels.
Not really.
There's not much to watch on TV,
these days.
There's nothing funny
but they laugh so loud.
Those laughs aren't real,
are they?
So they say.
Here.
What's that?
You treated us to a real feast today.
Why don't you treat yourself.
My, an allowance
from my own son.
How wonderful.
You're always treating us.
In that case, thank you.
What shall I buy.
What was that sumo
wrestler's name?
Still on your mind?
Solving these things
keeps your mind active.
Waka no hana?
Not him.
Kita-no-fuji?
He was really handsome.
No, he was more loveable.
Say.
Isn't it time we let Yoshio go.
Let's stop inviting him.
Why?
I feel sorry for him.
It seems painful
for him to see us.
That's why we invite him.
Can't have him forgetting
after just a dozen years.
It was his fault
Junpei died.
But Yoshio didn't.
It makes no difference.
Not for a parent.
Not having someone to hate
makes it all the worse for me.
So once a year,
I make him feel awful, too.
Will the gods punish me for that?
So I'll invite him next year
and the year after.
That's what you keep
inviting him here for?
You're cruel
I'm not cruel
I think it's normal.
Everybody keeps saying that.
When you get to be a parent,
you'll find out
I'm a parent.
A real parent.
What's that mean?
Take your bath.
Your father's, done.
Take the prince with you.
The prince?
You should.
We have a nice big bath.
Yukari-san.
We usually take separate baths.
On a day like today,
he should let his son bathe first.
He just spaces out all day.
There's no need
to bathe every day.
It's a waste of precious
hot water.
What is it, Mother?
Let Atsushi bathe first,
with Ryota.
Sure.
Usually, we don't
I'll leave your pajamas out
I brought a T shirt.
Wear them,
I bought them for you.
Where?
A discount shop, I bet.
Let's see
I'll show you.
Let's see.
You like this color.
Oh, no
Atsushi, let's take a bath.
Wait 'til I finish this part.
The bath is really narrow
I don't think we'll both fit.
Here.
What about my T shirt?
You've got your
mother's pajamas, right?
I don't need to wear those.
You should She took the trouble
to buy them for you.
Are you mad?
She's like this when I visit.
She just wants to look after me.
It's not about that.
What, then?
If she's going to buy pajamas,
she could buy a set for Atsushi, too.
All day, she treated him
like a guest, not family.
You're projecting.
She just didn't get around to it.
She had 3 toothbrushes set out.
Hand me my T-shirt.
Yukari-san.
Yukari-san, come.
Use this.
Job not going well?
It's fine Why?
Forget it, then.
Don't worry about me.
Things have changed.
Can't you.
Call your mom once in a while?
Let her hear your voice.
When I do, all she ever does
is complain.
Be patient and hear her out.
That's not my job.
Can't the two of you work things out,
without dragging me into it?
Whatever But that line about
the corn I said it, not Junpei.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
What difference does it make?
Ryo, it's too hot to get in
I'll be right there.
Not that it matters, anymore.
Damn.
Do you have a splinter?
If you can pinch a mole like this,
you'll be rich.
Grandma?
See this?
Grandma told me, so I always
tried hard to pinch it.
Not that it did much good.
Why did you want
to be a doctor, Ryo?
It was long ago.
Long, long ago.
Is it this one?
Oh, here it is
I'll give you this, too.
Oh, no, Mother.
lt's too expensive.
Oh, no, it's not expensive.
But it's a fine kimono.
My, daughter wants everything
but once she gets it, she ignores it
I gave her a beautiful kimono
but she's never worn it once
I wonder if she's
sold it on the "Inter something"
for cold hard cash
I doubt that
I wouldn't put it past her.
You get dimples
when you laugh.
It's so sweet.
What's the point of
dimples at my age.
That's not true.
A woman should be
charming at any age
I'm jealous.
Don't be.
Are you all right?
You're flushed.
Because I drank
a little tonight.
Oh, when I was young.
They said, "A woman should
never empty a glass of beer"
You young folks are lucky.
These days, I rarely drink
when I'm out.
So, you drink at home? It must be
boring, my son doesn't drink.
Well, these days
Ryota often drinks
beer at home.
Oh, really?
Just a little.
Says it helps him sleep.
Oh, I didn't know.
Better dry your hair
You'll catch cold
I weigh less than before.
What are you two
going to do about a baby?
We'll probably take some time
to think about it.
Guess you're right.
But if you're going to have one,
you shouldn't wait.
You're right.
You have to think
about Atsushi, too.
You'd hate to have things
get awkward with a new baby.
Maybe it's best that you don't.
What a shame
I wonder if this sash will match.
Maybe it's too plain.
It's normal, isn't it?
Right?
What?
It just flew in.
You followed us home
from the grave, right?
Keep it closed.
lt might be Junpei.
Hey, Mom
Junpei
Junpei.
Hurry, get it outside.
Cut it out, you're pathetic.
Calm down.
But.
See, it is Junpei.
Ridiculous
Junpei.
Gently now, gently.
It's a butterfly.
Just a butterfly.
Right.
Just a butterfly
I'm letting it go.
On my grandma's
17th memorial,
a butterfly flew in at night.
You should take
your bath, Mom.
I guess I will.
The Yokoyama family.
Oh, I see.
Please wait a minute.
The lady across the way
feels sick.
I'll take it.
Her heart again?
She's supposed to be taking
her Digitalis.
OK, call an ambulance, then
I can't.
I'd like to, but
I'm sorry I can't be
of more help.
Slowly, now.
It'll sway a little.
Slowly.
We'll stop here
and turn around.
What's her pulse?
Please get back.
Let's open up
and load her in.
You don't understand, I'm.
OK, you'll be fine.
Excuse me, get back.
Time to go to bed.
Don't walk around in
those pathetic pajamas.
He said he'd fix the tiles.
But he ate his fill,
took a nap and went home.
He's always like that
All talk and no action.
Grandma was strange, before.
It just seemed that way to her.
Even though he's gone?
Even when 'they die,
people don't really go away.
Your father's here.
Right inside you.
Half of you is made
of your father.
Half of you from me.
What about Ryo, then?
Ryo will become
a part of 'you, too.
Slowly but surely.
Slowly but surely?
What?
What's slowly but surely?
What do you say?
Do you want to let Ryo in?
Hey, let me in.
How will he get in?
From your mouth?
What from the mouth?
From your bellybutton?
Bellybutton?
My bellybutton,
slowly but surely?
I became one of
the relay runners
in the fall track meet
I saw a yellow butterfly, today.
Just like the one I caught
with Dad in Karuizawa.
When I grow up,
I want to be a piano tuner,
just like Dad.
If that's impossible,
I'd like to be a doctor.
I'm off.
Please look after him, Father.
Off you go.
Sorry there's leftover fish.
Be careful.
Don't go into the sea.
OK
The beach?
Yeah, let's go.
Don't fall
I'm fine.
And the Bay Stars baseball team?
These days,
I follow the Marinos.
You, into soccer?
I catch games at
the Yokohama stadium.
Huh, who with?
Oh, who cares.
We should go, with the kid.
We should.
One of these days.
That ship ran aground.
Go see a dentist.
One of these days.
Don't keep putting it off.
A single cavity
can ruin your teeth.
OK
It's too late if you
have to pull them.
OK, OK, OK
And take your weekends off.
You're getting older.
Yesterday, you said
I was still young.
Oh, here it is
I'm sure I still had
something left to say.
Come visit again, soon.
Please teach me
that sautéed radish recipe
I'd be happy to
I'm fine.
Shaking hands?
Oh, who cares.
Bye, Father.
See you.
Good bye.
You've got good manners.
Excuse us, then.
They'll be back
for New Years.
We can pass on New Years now.
Once a year is plenty.
Can't have them treating us too much.
Next time we won't spend the night.
I told you so.
We should've left
before dinner, yesterday.
I ate too much.
I put on 1 kilo.
Seven bus stops ahead.
I remember
the name of that sumo wrestler.
It's Kurohime-yama.
It's always like this.
I'm always a little late.
Don't do that stuff.
Don't do what?
Shaking their hands.
They'll get the wrong idea.
If a handshake gives them the wrong
idea, I'm perfectly happy to.
Oh, I remember.
What?
The name of that sumo wrestler.
Who?
Doesn't matter.
Who is it?
It doesn't matter anyway.
We never brought up
that sumo wrestler.
Three years later, Dad died
I never did get to
a soccer match with him.
Mom bickered with Dad
until the day he died,
but she died soon after him.
I never did give her
a ride in a car.
It's so hot.
The water must feel good.
Look, Mommy.
Put them in here.
Let's pray, then.
Look, ants.
Watch your step, now.
Look, a butterfly.
They say yellow butterflies like that
are white ones that survive the winter
and come back yellow the next year.
Really?
Who told you?
I wonder who.
ABE Hiroshi
NATSUKAWA Yui
YOU
TAKAHASHI Kazuya
TANAKA Shohei
KIKI Kirin
HARADA Yoshio
Executive Producers:
KAWASHIRO Kazumi / SHIGENOBU Yutaka
HISAMATSU Takeo / LEE Bong ou
Development Producer: YASUDA Masahiro
Producers:
KATO Yoshihiro / TAGUOHI Hijiri
Cinematographer: YAMAZAKI Yutaka
Production Design:
ISOMI Toshihiro / MITSUMATSU Keiko
Lighting: OSHITA Eiji
Sound:
TSURUMAKI Yutaka / OHTAKE Shuji
Music: GONTITI
Production Company:
ENGINE NETWORK, INC
Written, Directed and Edited by
KORE EDA Hirokazu
English Subtitles by Linda Hoaglund
© STILL WALKING Production Committee