That saved a wretch
Like me
I once
Was lost
But now
I'm found
Thank you, Father.
See you soon, Mr. May.
Loved the music, Mr. May.
Great choice.
- Who shall it be today, Mr. May?
- Mr. Sandberg, please.
Here's Mr. Sandberg.
Coming up to
two months now.
Just the one?
Just Mr. Sandberg,
thank you.
We'll give the others
a little more time.
You never know.
- Good morning, Mr. May.
- Good morning, Mr. White.
They're piling up
in there, Mr. May.
I'm just expecting
some news
for Mr. Radulovitz
and Mrs. Casement.
I'm very optimistic.
Mr. Radulovitz has been on
the shelf two good months.
What about the others?
Come the summer,
they'll be sharing bunks.
We do have leads.
Not every door is shut.
There may still
be someone!
She was found
two days ago.
Someone saw the cat
in the street, leaving.
"To my little Susie. "
"Happy birthday, Mum. "
I was told
there was no family.
In over 10 years I've
never seen anyone.
The postmark is last year.
"Monday, went to the shops. "
"Bought some fish.
She liked it. "
"Tuesday, the shops. "
It's all the same.
A - ha, here you are.
"Dear Mum, thank you so much
for my wonderful present. "
So she had a daughter?
"Please write again soon.
Love you with all my heart. "
Ah. "Susie. "
Susie's the cat.
Look. It's from the cat.
It's signed with a little paw.
Some people, eh?
Please call these people.
Anything they won't take
can be thrown away.
London Borough
of Kennington,
Client Services,
John May speaking.
Mr. Radulovitz.
Yes! And you are?
Mr. Radley.
And your connection with...
His son?
But your sur...
You've changed it?
Right. Great.
Thank you very much
for calling. Great.
That's just...
Just wonderful.
Unfortunately, as you know,
your father has passed away. Yes.
Died six weeks ago.
Well, you were contact...
Well, actually, in this office,
we're charged with
tracing the relatives
of those who passed
away in the borough.
And, failing that...
Yes.
Yes, your fath...
Uh, no, no, there's no obligation for
the next of kin to pay for the funeral.
No, you don't.
Indeed.
There is no obligation
to attend, but...
If I may say so...
I understand, Mr. Radu...
I mean, Mr. Radley.
Your father Mr. Radulovitz
might not have been
the best of fathers,
but, if I...
What do I...
My family?
No, I don't have a...
But surely, now that he's passed away,
his children should...
But to have found a father
after all these years...
I would...
Wouldn't you want your children,
his grandchildren, to know?
It's not too late.
Uh, no. I... I know
he's dead, but...
You're right.
I wouldn't know.
And would you be
able to think of anyone
who might have had contact?
Someone who might at least want
to be present at the funeral?
No.
And you...
You wouldn't...
No.
Very well, Mr. Radulovitz.
I'm, I'm sorry, Mr. Radley.
I understand.
Thank you.
Good-bye.
Who says it's my dog?
How do you know it's his piss?
That dog is always
out here, always.
I only have to open my door
and he rushes in my house.
Are you some sort
of dog piss expert?
Have a look up the wall.
Look how high it is.
I only got a little dog.
Yes, yes.
I would like to confirm
that a package addressed
to Miss Dawn Harvey...
What was in it?
Well, why do you
need to know?
Ashes. The ashes
of Mr. George Harvey.
What kind of ashes?
Excuse me, am I speaking
to Australia Post,
Yeperenye Shopping Center,
13 Cactus Street, Alice Springs?
Uh, what else?
Let me see.
He has a blue paw
and there's
a gray mark on...
Ah! Now, this could help.
There's a...
He has a tattoo
on his right ear of...
Well, as I said, we found
the dog next to the body.
I mean,
in the apartment of Mr. Didion.
And we thought that someone
involved with dog racing
might know the dog,
and therefore, the owner.
We are here to celebrate
the life of Jane Ford,
a woman who enjoyed life
for all it could bring.
She was born in the
summer of 1945,
as peace finally came to
the world, in Scarborough.
The only daughter of
Jack and Nora Ford.
And what a joy it must have
been for them to hold her.
The lovely, maybe unexpected fruit of
a rare reunion in those turbulent times.
She grew to enjoy what
life most readily offered,
the warmth of a sunny
day at the beach,
a simple yet
tasteful necklace,
a new stick of red lipstick.
She was passionate about dance,
flamenco in particular,
and always looked gorgeous
when stepping out
on the dance floor
in her red dress.
Later in life,
her love of animals
made her care for
her sweet cat, Susie,
with whom she shared
many happy years,
always celebrating Christmas
together in great style.
Just you again, Mr. May?
Afraid so.
Six in this one already.
This is the last one.
Got yourself a cracking
spot there, Mr. May.
By the time it's your turn,
those branches will be shading
anyone who comes to visit you.
Good to plan this
kind of thing.
Uncle Fred ended
up in Surbiton.
I'm sure he wouldn't
have liked that one bit.
London Borough of Kennington,
Client Services.
Good afternoon, Mr. Huxley.
Very well, thank you.
Found today.
No point of contact.
Yes.
I will go this afternoon.
And the address?
The neighbors complained
about the smell.
The police said it
must've been weeks.
I didn't really know him.
Bit of a loner.
You know the type.
So you live opposite, eh?
Did you know him?
No, I didn't know him.
I only get involved
if there's a problem.
Boiler.
Something like that.
You better wear these.
I can't see a record player.
No. He probably sold it
for a couple of drinks.
Oh.
Ah!
What about that, eh?
Time stops for no one.
Here he is.
Billy Stoke.
I can't say I recognize him.
They all look the same,
don't they?
Call the health department.
They need to clean and clear
this place as soon as possible.
Except for the carriage clock.
That goes to the pawn
brokers on the High Street.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Good-bye now.
No family again, Mr. May?
Maybe.
Mr. May.
Mr. Pratchett.
Could I see you
in my office, please?
As I said, your department is being
amalgamated with that of the Dulwich office,
here represented
by Miss Pilger.
And from today the coroner is
referring all cases to the new office.
- Dulwich.
- Mmm-hmm.
I guess I could
buy a bicycle.
Oh, no,
you don't understand.
You won't need to travel,
that's the point.
Uh, given the current
pressure on finances,
the council is undertaking a
new round of efficiency savings.
We're letting you go.
You're letting me go?
Mr. May, in the two months
I've been here,
I've been able to
observe you at work.
And there's no doubt
you're very thorough,
but, if I may say so,
you're also very slow,
not to say expensive,
given the number of
funerals you choose
to organize as opposed
to cremations.
But when there are
indications of religious...
John, you've been with
the council for how long?
- Twenty-two years.
Well, I think you should see
this as an opportunity
for a new beginning,
don't you?
A new life.
I'm sure the
council's references
will enable you to find
new and challenging work.
A job where people
are alive, for a change?
What about this
morning's case?
This morning? Ah, yes.
That'll be your last one.
Please close it in three days.
Should be the right size.
Sorry about this.
You know, health rules.
I understand.
I also have to wear this
stuff at work sometimes.
You're in food processing,
too, then?
Baking?
Baking? No. No, not really baking.
I'm actually a...
Well, I only have to wear
this when I see people.
People?
Yes. I mean people, uh,
who, who don't
bake anymore.
Billy.
Billy Stoke.
Worst player in the team.
Nobody would dare kick him out.
Bloody temper.
Hear that?
Managed to fight both management and
union reps about the afternoon break.
He won us five extra minutes,
then, uh, fucked off.
Just, uh,
just packed it in.
But before he does that,
what does he do?
Pisses in a vat
of pork meat.
Some of the batch
got through.
Pies never tasted so good.
Here, have one.
Thank you.
I don't smoke.
We found this in his home.
Do you know who she might be?
No idea.
Looks a bit like him.
Daughter, maybe?
Yes.
That's what I think.
It would be nice to give it
to her if she was still alive.
He must have loved her.
Funny, though.
He never mentioned a family.
We were best mates, really...
...for a time.
Like school kids,
you know, just older.
He was like me older brother.
Then, uh, Billy met the
fish-and-chips lady in Whitby,
and he left to be with her.
Whitby?
Would you know her name?
Her address, maybe?
No, sorry. Only saw her
a couple of times.
Lovely girl, though.
Billy always had a
way with the ladies.
Something about him.
Always on the edge.
I don't know.
Do you understand women?
There will be a funeral in a
few days' time in London.
Would you consider coming?
A funeral?
Don't know.
I mean, it would be good to
have a drink with him, but...
A funeral?
After so long...
You miss that train next
time and I won't be waiting.
Yeah, you will.
You love me too much.
The 12:50 service
to London, St. Pancras...
- I might have better offers.
- ... is delayed until 13:05.
Bollocks.
Hey!
You'll never find anyone who
loves you as much as I do.
Yeah? How much do
you love me then?
Well, I love you more than
you love me, that's for sure.
A black tea, please.
You should try
the hot chocolate.
Just got this new machine.
It's gorgeous.
All right.
A hot chocolate, please.
The train departing
from platform three
is the 12:50 service
to London, St. Pancras.
Hello, Mr. Pratchett?
Yes, Mr. Pratchett,
it's John May.
John May, Client Services?
Yes, I know.
I'm sorry.
I haven't been
feeling myself today.
No, still not quite right.
I don't think I will
be in tomorrow.
Yes, yes, of course.
Good-bye, Mr. Pratch...
Just put them on
top of the others.
When he was good,
he was wonderful.
And kind and loving.
When he was bad,
you got out the room.
Just half the sack
in the peeler!
And then pull the switch above
your head, the one on the left.
When they're done,
in the chipper.
And don't put your hands
in if you like your fingers.
I can only tell you about
his life here with me.
He never spoke
about his life before.
He could give you
so much just in a day,
you didn't want to be anywhere
else but with him.
Do you know what I mean?
It was me who asked
him to move in.
Worked a while on the boats.
That went, thanks to
those fools in Brussels.
So he started
helping out in here.
He was good at it.
Put extra beer in the batter.
Customers were happy.
And it was nice to have
him around all day.
Strange job you've got.
All those lives.
I couldn't do it.
I like my work.
Here, love.
You got that paper?
Oh, hell, I forgot.
Give me a minute.
Mind the child, will you?
Bit early for
another inspection.
Had the last one mid-summer.
No, no. I'm here
to find people,
well, friends maybe, for a man
who was here 20 years ago.
William Stoke?
Him?
You won't find any friends
of his around here.
What's he done now,
killed somebody?
No. Actually, he died
a few weeks ago.
Well, good riddance.
Wasn't all there,
if you ask me.
Fried a man alive, he did.
This guy were
faffin' with Mary.
Billy gets vexed,
lands him one.
So the guy
picks up a knife.
Billy grabs his arm,
shoves it in the fryer,
up to here and holds it there.
Knife and all.
Mad, I tell you.
- Says here it should be
paid in June. - Hello.
Good morning.
Uh, don't worry about that, love.
I'll sort that out.
Did you miss Mummy?
Was just tellin' him about
when Billy fried that guy.
Mad, eh?
Don't forget we promised Mum
we'd take her to the bingo.
Want some more?
Huh? No?
Don't listen to him.
Billy were cleared,
completely.
But he wasn't the
same after that.
Started drinking a lot.
Became impossible,
even with me.
And after a while,
he just upped and left.
We found this in his room.
Do you recognize her?
Did he ever speak
of a family?
No.
He never spoke
of having a family.
He did leave something behind,
but he never knew about it.
Shift ends at 4:30,
so I'll see you then.
Bye, love.
Bye.
Miss Jones, there will be
a funeral, Billy's funeral,
in a few days, in London.
You must come.
Bring his daughter and his granddaughter.
It's wonderful...
I'm sorry,
it's not possible.
But you're his family.
We're not his family.
He didn't want one.
And I can't.
It's too long ago.
It's too much to explain.
The council could help
with the transport.
I loved him.
Never loved anyone else since,
but I can't.
Please don't insist.
Do you know where he might have
moved on to when he left?
No idea.
Prison, most likely.
Good morning, Mr. White.
Mr. May. What news
from the land of the livin'?
"Friar in Robin Hood's
band," four letters?
- Tuck.
- Yeah, Tuck.
You're wasted here, Mr. May.
Mastermind, big leather chair,
that's where you belong.
I'd give it a go,
if I were you.
Mr. White, our last case,
William Stoke.
Row two, tray eight.
Forty days rotting, I believe.
Forty?
Well, he won't have
to wait any longer.
If you can get
him ready, please.
Oh, they've just taken another
three for cremation this afternoon.
I've got more checkin' out
than checkin' in these days.
I'll be out of a job soon.
Here, Mr. May,
"Flightless bird,"
four letters?
Dodo.
D - O - D - O,
"Dodo. "
I never heard of it.
You're a rare thing, Mr. May!
Another fruitful day, John,
almost there?
Mr. Pratchett.
Miss Pilger tells me
of great progress, John.
The council's very pleased.
I'm sure you'll be pleased in turn
with the references I'm preparing.
Thank you.
See, it wasn't that
difficult, after all.
Sorry?
Yeah, I've been thinking
about this, your job.
And let's face it.
The dead are dead.
Funerals are for the living.
So, if there's no one there,
there's no one to care. Right?
I mean, for the living,
could be better not to know.
You know, no funeral,
no sadness, no tears.
What do you think?
I can't say I've ever thought
of it that way, Mr. Pratchett.
Well, anyway,
the dead are dead.
They're not there.
They don't care. All right?
Mr. Pratchett!
- Yes, John?
- Mr. Pratchett...
I need a few more days.
More days? I'm afraid that
won't be possible, John.
- The council's already decided...
- My last case, William Stoke.
John, John, there's really no need
for you to. Miss Pilger can sort it.
It'll only take a few days.
Right. All right. But it'll
have to be on your own time.
Your termination notice
has already been signed
and the council can't
reissue it. Okay?
Of course.
I understand, Mr. Pratchett.
No, no, no. We have no knowledge
of an actual conviction.
But, you see, Mr. Stoke was on a,
a particular trajectory.
I think mostly short spells,
vagrancy, assaults,
that sort of thing, but,
uh, no trouble inside.
And you have no record
of any visitors?
No. We sent the old logs off
to the Metropolitan Archives.
And they can't
find them there?
Well, you could try
the Home Office, but,
you know, we're talking
about 20 years ago.
Seventeen, actually.
Mr. May, if we have to remember
what happens to every man
who's walked through here,
we wouldn't get much sleep at night.
And I like my sleep.
I'll tell you one thing.
Your Billy once hung
over the edge
of the third floor landing
from a belt with his teeth.
Three-and-a-half minutes.
He was raising money
for some charity.
And all the lads
put a few quid in.
His teeth?
Yeah, his teeth, yeah.
How about that, then?
Good-bye, Mr. May.
Yes?
Kelly Stoke?
Sorry?
You are not Kelly Stoke?
- Sorry?
- Daughter of William Stoke?
Yeah. Sorry, who are you?
I'm John May.
Kennington Borough Council.
Kennington?
I have some sad news,
I'm afraid.
Your father has died.
When?
Well, it's hard
to say exactly.
Why?
- Because...
- Um...
I don't wanna know.
Thank you.
Miss Stoke.
There is this.
I found it in his flat.
He never even wrote.
I was so angry.
Still am, I guess.
Then one day,
it was my birthday, 18.
He called.
He didn't mention
my birthday,
but he must've known.
He must have.
- Don't you think?
- Of course.
Of course he knew.
He remembered.
Well, he was
in prison, drunk,
or so it sounded,
he'd hit rock bottom and...
He wanted to square things
before he got out,
so he could start again.
Mum wasn't sure,
but we still went, though.
I almost didn't recognize him.
But he knew who I was.
And I had changed,
you know, in eight years.
But he knew as
soon as I walked in.
Yeah.
Only as soon as
he turned around,
it all came out.
I don't know where from.
I just started about Mum,
him leavin' us,
how selfish he was.
And then he started shoutin'
'cause Billy Stoke never backed down
in the face of a row, did he?
And it was horrible.
Guard had to come over.
And then he punched
the guard in the face,
turned around,
walked out the door,
and I never saw him again.
That's Dad with Jumbo.
Both Paras.
It's in the Falklands.
They were best mates.
He, uh, got in touch with
me about ten years ago.
Wanted to find Dad. I couldn't help him,
but, uh, he sent me that anyway.
No, take it.
I don't need it, I mean...
I don't know why
I kept it, really.
I'm... I'm fine.
It's just...
Really, it's just, um...
Well, it's just the shock.
I must ask.
Your mother, is she...
She's dead.
Quite peacefully.
And, um,
and someone with her.
Too early, though.
Three years ago.
I'm an orphan as of today.
Yes.
That's not nice.
- Whenever it happens.
- No.
I should go.
I'm very grateful
for your time.
Thank you.
Thank you for
coming to tell me.
Of course.
And you have
my number, if...
If you decide to involve
yourself any further.
The funeral.
And I've arranged...
Please, Mr. May,
don't say any more.
You've already
said such a lot.
Excuse me!
Your door!
John May.
Thought I heard you
comin' down the corridor.
Young footsteps.
Not many of them around here.
Come in.
I'm Jumbo.
Very pleased to
meet you, Jumbo.
Made you some dinner.
Hope it suits.
Some tea there,
just brewed.
Pour yourself a cup
and sit down. Eat.
Thank you very much.
All right?
Yes, thank you.
Perfect.
So, Billy's daughter
told you about me.
I remember her voice.
Must be a lovely girl.
Gentle.
Yes.
Didn't get that
from her father.
Knocked the bloody head off
me my first day in the army.
Wouldn't be here now,
though, if it wasn't for him.
Didn't leave me on
that bloody mountain.
The Falklands?
Right.
Fucking place.
You been in the army?
Uh, me?
No.
No, I haven't.
Best and worst of all lives,
the Paras.
Pick the meanest
bastards and then...
When I found him again,
he was on the streets, a dosser.
Mind you, he only slept
in the poshest places,
Berkeley Square, Green Park.
No Kings Cross for him.
The drink, helps you forget,
helps you to sleep
without dreamin'.
Then it gets inside you
and it won't come out.
It's awful when you think
about it. Killing a man.
And you...
You stayed on?
No.
As soon as I got out of hospital
I came down to London.
Tried settling down.
Even got married.
What a day that was.
Fell asleep in the church.
We met at a dance.
She was hiding behind the pillars,
pretending not to look.
Two left feet.
Lovely.
Them were the days.
It's all right, Officer.
Just here having a think,
that's all.
He's not from the law,
he's from St. Jude's.
St. Jude's, yeah?
Still tryin' to turn us
off drink for a soup?
What happened?
They used to send pretty
birds to convince us.
Are we not worth it now?
I'm from Kennington Borough.
I'm looking for people who might have
known a man called William Stoke.
Billy Stoke.
I'm told he used to
come here often.
Billy Stoke. You mean Big Billy?
What's with him?
Actually, he passed
away a few weeks ago.
Weeks?
We ain't seen him
for months, years even.
What is it you wanna know?
I'd like to know what he was like,
what acquaintances he had.
Yeah? Well, information like
that is worth the price of a drink.
Don't ya think?
A bottle of whiskey, please.
- Which?
- The large one.
That's what I call a drink.
Good man.
Thanks.
Well, sit down, sit down.
You'll give us a turned neck.
Big Billy.
He was the worst beggar.
Hold on a minute.
Here. Have a red one.
They're good.
No, thank you.
I haven't eaten.
His heart wasn't in it,
you see.
The punters felt it.
They never stopped.
See, it was Lesley
who got him to drink.
He'd have been sober
without her.
Lesley?
We were all mad for her.
I mean...
I weren't.
But out of the crew,
she picked Billy,
the only one who
didn't pester her.
- I didn't.
- You did!
God, do you remember that time
he nicked that chocolate for her?
It was all melted.
He's all caked in it,
all covered in this,
ugh, sticky chocolate.
Oh, yeah, he got three months for that.
Just for chocolate.
Do you know where
I can find Lesley?
Bone yard.
Good funeral, though.
Lovely lady.
Good drink after.
You know, they never
seemed to talk.
They just sat there
on a bench together.
Well, that's what
we all want, isn't it?
A woman to be quiet with.
Okay, G.
This one here, G 93485.
Ah, 93485.
Right.
Good views.
Aren't they?
Lovely.
And you would like to...
I'd like to make it available
for someone else.
A family member?
No family.
Just a friend.
London Borough of Kennington,
Client Services, John May speaking.
Yes.
Miss Stoke.
Of course.
11:00.
Not Plymouth, but two
stops before Plymouth.
Off platform two.
Yes.
Sure I'll find it.
Thank you very much,
Miss Stoke.
I mean, Kelly.
Thank you, Kelly.
See you tomorrow.
I thought this piece here.
It really has something.
I'm, I'm sure it's never
been used in a funeral before.
But you'll see... I mean,
you'll hear when you hear it.
Next Friday.
And...
Uh, uh, yes, the memorial.
They call it red granite,
but it's not red,
it's darker, more maroon.
It's like the color of
his beret in the army.
I thought your father
would have liked that.
And the place.
I really hope you like it.
It's...
Well, on a good day,
you can see for miles.
And even when the weather's
not that great,
it's so open,
you really feel you're...
You really feel you're...
I mean, he is...
He's, he's outside.
He's not inside, not under.
I was thinking next Friday
after the service,
maybe we could go somewhere
for a cup of tea or chocolate.
Just to, you know,
just to, just to chat.
If you have time,
of course. If you...
Yes.
Yes, I would like
that very much.
Just a cup of something.
And I do have time.
I have lots of time.
See you there, then, John.
And thank you.
Thank you for everything
you've done.
No need.
It was...
Just my job.
Good-bye, mate.