[Door Opens]
[Door Creaks, Closes]
[Door Buzzes]
[Clattering]
It's hard--
It's hard to envision, um--
Let's just say,
when you're locked up
for 23 hours a day,
it's hard to envision, um,
when you're not
gonna locked up
23 hours a day.
You have the tendency
to, um,
I guess,
live minute by minute.
[Footsteps Approaching]
[Door Opens, Creaks]
[Door Closes]
[Laughter Echoing In Distance]
You know what my problem was?
Is that I fucking cared
about him.
I liked him.
He was a fucking sweet kid.
I kind of put myself
first and foremost.
I-- I don't--
[Inhales]
you know--
I didn't spend too much time
thinking about,
you know, his problems
or anything like that.
[Exhales]
Shit. There's been
a hanging in 313!
It's a suicide!
Mitch killed himself!
Hurry up!
Oh, my God.
Oh, my God!
- I don't know. I didn't
really care about him.
- [Chattering]
I mean, you know, just--
You can't be friends
with everyone, right?
- [Chattering Continues]
- Is he breathing?
[Guard]
Everybody over here, on your
knees, hands in the air.
Okay, everybody over here,
on your knees,
hands on your head.
Drop the body and fall in line.
Drop him.
Let's go.
On your knees.
Hands on your head.
[Guard]
Steve, send a couple more guys
with a doctor.
Okay, Jack.
Back here on your knees, please.
Is he alive?
- Fall back in line.
Let's go. Let's go!
- Jack, hands on your head.
Yo, this guy's ice-cold.
I say yes.
I say that we all have...
just as much responsibility
for him hanging there.
If he talked to me,
I would have talked him
out of it.
This is Correction Officer Cohen
requesting an ambulance.
Cell block 313, please.
[Sighs]
So it takes
a thing like this for--
for you to see that
there is a larger problem?
It takes something like this
for you to go,
"Oh, you know what?
I think our fucking system's
fucked up!"
Well,
it was a--
a normal day.
We played some poker.
All right.
I'm in.
Are you in?
I fold.
Pair of nines.
[Humming]
All right.
Flip 'em.
Oh.
Fuck, man.
Ho!
Pair of sixes.
He had
an open-ended straight too.
Why not?
This kid never has anything.
[Chuckling]
He never has anything.
Officer--
[Door Buzzes]
Officer Robes came in
and brought us some food.
Gentlemen,
backs against the wall, please.
Um--
[Robes]
Afternoon. Got a little
card game going here?
No, we're just
jerkin' the gherkin.
And, um,
we hung around and ate.
[Laughing]
I don't know.
We talked about bullshit. We
talked about girls we'd fucked.
We told the same stories
we've heard a thousand times...
and pretended like they weren't
the same stories we've heard
a thousand times.
Yo, what are you
in here for, man?
I robbed
this convenience store.
- Really?
- Basically I just, like-- I--
I took the whole thing, man.
I went through every aisle,
dude, and I didn't even need.
Dude, I always wanted
to be in a, like,
high-speed pursuit, man.
Why?
Do you know what I mean?
She tried to
come after me with a broom.
So I just turned around
and started beating
the shit out of her.
And, like, this fucking dude
came over, man. So--
She fucking pulls
this dude over, and he, like,
gets out of his car,
and he, like, walks up to her
and just fucking
decks the bitch.
- Just fucking
knocks her out cold.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
- What were you driving?
I was driving a, uh--
a Mustang.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Was it yours?
Did you own it?
Or was it stolen?
Huh?
Was the Mustang stolen?
No, it's my car, man.
Really?
Yeah.
Come on, guys.
Let's go back to the game, huh?
I'm in.
I gotta win my cigarettes back.
Yeah, you know,
he was kind of quiet.
I don't know.
He was definitely the quietest--
He, um--
I don't know.
He didn't really show
any signs that he was gonna
do anything like that.
But he, uh--
I don't know.
He just kinda kept to himself.
Well, you know,
I think he was, um, depressed.
It doesn't really
make a difference.
It's a little more room
in the cell.
Yeah, you know,
I think it, um,
has the tendency to, uh,
take a toll
on you after a while.
[Sighs]
Let's do this.
How the fuck did you win
so many chips?
Just winning.
Just-- Just winning.
Just winning, man.
Why are you saying that?
Just luck, right?
Just luck, you guys.
Sure.
Sure?
I don't know, man.
I think something's up.
Just something smells.
- It stinks.
- [Chuckles]
Pull up those sleeves
of yours, man.
I don't know.
Seriously.
Fucking David Copperfield.
Yeah, Mitch.
Yeah.
Uh, great guy.
Great guy.
Well, we weren't best buddies,
but we were friends.
How much are these blues again?
Five.
How much?
What-- What situation?
[Inhales, Exhales]
Have you ever heard of
group psychosis?
- I'll see it,
and I'll raise it two.
- Four.
- Two to you.
- This is a bullshit game.
[Clearing Throat]
Fuckin' all in, right now.
Let's see it, homey.
I've got trip sevens.
I knew you didn't
have fuckin' shit.
Ooh!
[Chuckling]
It's mine.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
There's a hierarchy--
survival of the fittest.
You know,
eat or be eaten.
Um--
[Tapping Table]
What choice
do I really have?
Wake up, man.
Come on. Let's play again.
Come on.
Let's play again.
With what?
I don't know.
Loan me 10 cigarettes.
We'll play another game.
You guys don't have
10 cigarettes.
I need cigarettes for the
weekend. You've gotta give us
a chance to win.
How do I know you guys are gonna
give me your cigarettes?
We'll all ante up 10.
To bet with what?
Let me just borrow
a 10 from you.
Put me on fucking loan.
It's not like you don't know
where I live.
How do I know that you're gonna
give me 10 cigarettes back?
- It's not like
he's going anywhere.
- Where am I going?
Don't be a selfish prick.
Because I fucking sleep
about two feet away from you,
that's how I know.
Come on.
Look at how many fucking
cigarettes that is.
You don't want me
without cigarettes.
What, am I gonna run away?
I mean, you know where I live.
Dude, we're all
in the same cell.
Dude, I'll get you back.
I'll get you back on Monday.
Okay. Okay.
I'll give-- I'll give
you guys 10 cigarettes.
I'll give you 10 cigarettes,
and you have to give 'em
back to me on Monday.
What if we don't?
And-- And--
And you gotta fucking eat
a tube of toothpaste.
What about you if you lose?
Yeah, but if you lose--
if you lose, or you,
you've gotta fucking--
You gotta eat the toothpaste.
Fuck yeah.
You wanna do that?
Whoever goes out first eats
a tube of toothpaste? You sure?
Okay.
It's a bet, isn't it?
I'll fucking eat it.
Okay. Let's do it.
Let's do it.
Divvy out the 10 cigarettes.
First one out
has to eat a toothpaste?
Are we talking about
the entire thing?
He's gotta eat the entire thing?
You've got to eat
the whole thing.
And if you lose you've gotta
eat the whole toothpaste.
It's amazing what
a smoker will do.
[Chattering]
[Whistling]
All right. Uh, here.
I'll change you...
so that you can do
the blinds too, okay?
Whatever.
You tend to look at us as if--
as if there's some sort of--
as if the same sort of
laws and... rules...
that apply to the outside
apply in there.
They don't.
They simply fucking don't.
[Sighs]
Let's just say he was on
the bottom of the totem pole.
- Bet. Four.
- [Sighs]
You raise?
Ladies, I fold.
Triple fives.
How did he win?
You good?
He was begging for it, okay?
He was a stupid asshole.
All right?
He shouldn't have made a bet.
[Chattering]
Just bullshit.
I mean--
You know--
I feel like I'm being
kind of interrogated,
like I did something.
And it's exhausting.
You know, there's a lot
of ego in those cells.
A lot of bad stories.
A lot of--
A lot of bad things going on.
Stuff that you have
no clue about.
[Chips Clattering]
Yep.
All right.
I'm folding.
I'm out myself.
All right, homey.
It's on you.
All in.
All in?
Mm-hmm.
- Ooh!
- Wow.
Ooh!
All right.
He's bluffing.
I call.
Wanna flip 'em? Hmm?
You're about to
eat some toothpaste...
unless something
saves your life, my friend.
Yeah, he's out.
Oh!
[Chuckling]
Fucked. Fucked!
Ooh!
- All right.
- Finally the tides turn, man.
Yep!
[Chuckling]
Where you going?
What are you doing?
Come on, man.
Are you ready?
You copping out?
Come on.
I'm not gonna eat
this toothpaste, man.
What did he say?
You're not gonna eat
the toothpaste?
He's not gonna eat
the fucking toothpaste?
Not gonna eat the toothpaste?
How could you pussy out, man?
[Mockingly]
Eat a tube of toothpaste.
[Chuckles]
Just eat it, man,
and get it over with.
Come on.
Let's see it, man. We wanna
see it before we get back to
playing the rest of the game.
I'll just fu--
I'll give you guys cigarettes.
No.
I'll give you
fucking 10 cigarettes.
No.
Come on.
Then you don't
owe me anything.
You can do it.
All right.
It's either you eat the--
You gonna do it?
No.
Oh.
Well, you know--
You came up with the bet
in the first place.
So what you're gonna do...
is you're gonna eat
the fucking toothpaste.
What the fuck's
your problem, dude?
What the fuck's your problem?
Come on.
Come on, man.
Eat the toothpaste. Come on.
It was your fucking idea, dude.
Come on.
Come on. Take it.
Come on. Come on.
Come on.
[Stamps Foot]
Oh!
Come on.
Eat the toothpaste.
You know what?
He's gonna eat it. I wanna
see you eat the toothpaste.
I wanna play another game.
He's gonna fucking eat it.
You want some time
to think about it?
You ain't going nowhere.
You better eat it.
You've got time while we play
this game to eat the toothpaste.
I'll take the cigarettes.
But still,
eat the toothpaste, man.
Thank you.
All right.
We're not gonna
forget about that, brother.
It's your deal.
Go and sulk.
Do whatever you want.
It's already shuffled
and cut it, so--
Gear up, man.
Get ready for it.
It's comin'.
It's comin'
in your mouth, bitch.
[All Laughing]
Sad look in his eyes right now.
Poor guy.
Want a hug?
Um,
basically
I wasn't the leader.
Basically
it was a group thing.
Hey.
Likes to
Beat the cock
I don't know. We just--
You know, we--
Look, there's
a fucking hierarchy here.
And I kept--
I kept saying to myself,
"As long as it's not me."
Good game.
Thanks, man.
At least I got 10 cigarettes.
[Sighs]
[Urinating]
Bro,
you can have some of mine,
but you gotta eat it.
[Coughing]
Oh.
You motherfucker!
Eat the fucking toothpaste,
bitch!
[Grunting]
Hey! Get the fuck off of me!
- Are you gonna eat it?
- No! Fucking leave me alone!
All right. Well, then
you're gonna have to
suck on this, bitch.
Help!
[Laughing]
- Help!
- Are you gonna eat it now
or what?
Come on. Eat it.
Help!
[Laughing]
Did you just
fucking spit on me?
Did you spit on me?
Bitch?
Come on.
Are you gonna eat it?
No!
[Shrieking]
Okay.
I'll eat it!
That's a boy!
- That's a boy.
- Yeah. Come on.
I'll eat it.
Oh, fuck it.
Here. Here.
Pull him up.
Promise?
Okay. Okay.
I'll fucking eat it!
Say it.
I'll eat it.
I'll fucking eat it, okay?
All right. Good.
Promise?
I'll fucking eat it. Give it
to me. I'll fucking eat it.
Come on.
You like sucking on that,
don't you?
[Coughing]
Come on. Chew.
Come on!
Security.
I can't breathe.
Bro--
Bro, I promise you.
Okay.
Be a man.
Just-- Just--
Just eat the whole thing.
Here you go.
[Gasps]
All right!
[All Laughing]
Yeah, that's what
I'm talking about!
[Coughing]
Come on.
You are the man.
[Grunting]
Gotta be a man, man.
Just put it in there, man.
[Groaning]
I'm trying to eat it.
You're almost done, man.
Look at the tube.
You can do it.
You can do it, brother.
Come on. Let's go.
You can do it.
Just get it all
done at once, man.
A little bit of blood.
You can do it, man.
You can do it. See, that's all
we wanted you to do.
More. Come on.
Keep squeezing.
That's all we wanted you to do.
That's all.
Is he crying?
Don't, don't, don't--
[Chattering]
Just swallow it, dude.
Oh, come on, man.
It's okay.
[Coughing]
There we go.
That is my brother! Yeah!
[Applauding]
[Cheering]
Come on!
Come on. Here.
I'll help you up.
[Grunts]
Come on, big guy.
There you go.
Come on.
Hell, yeah.
You're good. You're good.
You're good.
You did good.
You won.
Okay.
- You won.
- Man, you looked fucked up.
Come on.
Give him a hug.
Don't do any
weird shit to him.
Now go clean yourself.
Look at you.
Go clean yourself.
See how much better
you feel about yourself, man?
Damn!
[Water Running]
Damn.
That was exciting, huh?
It kind of made my day.
Ah, geez.
He's gonna puke.
No, no, no.
He's fine.
Hey, you all right, man?
You all right?
Hey, hey.
Don't stress, man.
Don't stress. Okay?
You're all right. Okay?
- You don't feel well?
- No.
Is your stomach
out of sorts, man?
No, I'm fine.
You sure?
Yeah.
Are you mad?
No. No.
Hey, it's not
a big deal, man.
Look, dude.
It was a fucking bet,
and you lost the bet.
So we made you do it, you know
what I mean? We're just
holding you true to your word.
Would you understand
what it's like?
You have any fuckin' idea?
You have no idea
what it's like?
No?
Because you're either with 'em,
or you're against 'em.
Oh, I regret it.
I don't know if he actually
wanted to help him or not.
But I think he, uh--
he just wanted
to have some more fun.
I think he realized...
what would come
if he didn't.
How you feeling, man?
You all right?
Your stomach better?
Hey, you all right?
Yeah, I'm fine.
You sure?
Mm-hmm.
You seem
a little, um, quiet.
Your stomach
feeling all right?
Let me-- Let me, um--
I'm gonna make you a drink.
It's gonna take care of you.
You'll feel like you never ate
a whole tube of toothpaste.
I'm serious.
It's good.
It'll be good for you.
All right?
Hang in there.
I'll get you.
[Faucet Turns On]
[Fizzing]
Hey. Hey.
[Whistles]
Come on.
Drink this.
It'll help settle your stomach.
Why don't you
drink it?
Ah, come on.
Come on.
Hey.
It's all right, dude.
Now drink.
[Chuckles]
Why are you so cynical, huh?
I make you a drink,
and you assume that
I'm out to fucking get you,
that I'm out to hurt you,
that I'm out to fuck with you?
You really think that
I would drink that? Why?
I don't get it.
I don't understand.
What did I do to you?
Why are you so cynical?
Why are you
so cynical?
What did I do to you?
Why do you think
I'm trying to fuck with you?
I'm trying-- 'Cause you are.
I'm trying to help you out, man.
You're such
a fucking liar.
I'm not.
- I may live
on the streets, but--
- Hey, hey, hey.
Hey. What?
I said, I may
live on the streets,
but I'm not fucking stupid.
So don't treat me
like I'm fucking stupid.
I'm not. I'm not.
I promise.
Cheer up.
I'll make you another one.
[Faucet Turns On]
Hey, come here.
Come here. Come here.
[Gags]
I made you something.
I want you to drink it.
Come on. It's okay.
Hey. It's okay.
It's okay. It's okay.
It's okay.
Come on.
What is that, coffee?
Think you're gonna
get out of here?
Come on. Just drink it, man.
The decision has
already been made.
You've already fucking drank it.
You've already drank it.
There's no way out of this,
all right?
[Bangs]
Oh!
Come on.
It's just a little coffee,
a little salt,
a little--
a little peppers.
Come on.
Let's see you drink it.
[Sniffing]
It smells good.
[Sniffs]
Smell.
We can go there.
We can go there, man.
You wanna do it?
- You have any fucking idea?
Do you see these two?
- Hey, hey. Come on, man.
If he knows any better,
he'll drink it, dude.
Come on.
Just mellow out, man.
What are you gonna do?
Just-- Seriously.
It's not gonna kill you.
Why don't you just-- Fuck.
The fucking odds
are against you, man.
Move. Come on. Hey.
Ten, nine--
[Together]
Eight, seven, six,
five, four,
three, two, one!
[Laughing]
Aw!
Oh!
[Chattering]
[Retching]
Oh, my God!
Oh, fuck!
Oh, that is nasty,
dude.
[Retching]
Oh, ho, ho.
Oh, that stinks, man.
Oh, my God.
That stinks!
You've gotta
clean that up, man.
What--
What do you want to hear?
Yeah, it was a selfish thing.
So we wanted him--
we wanted him to clean
everything up.
Harry especially.
You know, he's very--
Yeah, you make it seem like,
you know,
it was a mutual
sort of dining experience.
You know what
you've gotta do, right?
Are you listening to me?
You're gonna clean that up.
- [Mitch]
I'll get-- I'll get the mop.
- Know what?
You're gonna clean that up
without the mop.
I think I wanna see you
clean that up with your tongue.
I mean, just put it back
where it came from, huh?
Just leave it, man.
Leave it.
I think he has gotta
eat his own barf.
It's over. It's over. Come on.
No. No.
He's had enough.
He's had enough?
He's making a mess of this place
over and over again.
- I think it's time for him
to learn a lesson.
- [Muttering]
Yeah, he's got, like,
obsessive-compulsive disorder
or some shit.
[Mockingly]
"The mess, the mess, the mess.
Clean it up."
Clean it up!
I'm not gonna live in a cell
where there's vomit
on the fucking floor!
You fucking hear me,
motherfucker?
- [Grunting]
- [Coughing]
Chill the fuck out, man!
Maybe he fucking deserves it.
[Coughing]
- Stay the fuck down!
- [Grunts]
[Coughing Continues]
[Groaning]
I'm calm.
I am calm.
Stay the fuck down!
Ow!
Eat your own fucking vomit?
You don't wanna eat your vomit?
You don't wanna eat
your own fucking barf?
Look at the mess!
You don't wanna eat it?
I'll make you eat it!
Come here! Come here!
Come here!
You will fucking eat it!
Eat it!
Let go!
Ah, that's right!
[Coughing]
[Groaning]
- Why-- Why are you doing this?
- That's enough, man.
You're making a mess
out of this place.
You're making a mess.
I'm sorry.
Clean it up.
Clean it up!
Clean it up. Hmm?
You fucking bitch!
You'll clean it up!
Do you hear me?
- Clean it up! Now!
- [Groaning, Crying]
[Coughing]
That's right.
Get on with it.
[Groans]
Put it back.
[Groaning]
Put it back
where it came from.
I'm trying.
- Put it back
where it came from!
- [Shrieking]
It's your own.
Put it back where it came from!
Put it back
where it came from!
[Shrieking]
[Crying]
- Clean it up.
- I am. I'm trying.
Clean it up!
Okay. I am.
That's good.
[Groaning]
[Coughing]
Uh, it must have been
self-inflicted...
'cause I didn't witness
anything like that.
I'm probably physically
weaker than Mitch.
How they didn't choose me...
is a fucking miracle.
I didn't do anything.
I did not beat him up.
I'm so fucking tired, man.
I'm so tired.
[Faucet Turns On]
Hey, man.
Here's a clean shirt, dude.
Are you okay?
I'm all right.
Is there anything else
I can get you?
Uh-uh.
Thanks.
What don't you understand?
If I--
If I don't--
If I don't seem like
I'm part of it,
I'll be fucking shanked
in the shower tomorrow.
You understand that?
They'll fucking kill me.
No. I think we probably still
would have fucked him up.
So what are the others saying?
Nothing. I thought
he was nothing, and he needed
to, uh, be treated like nothing.
[Chuckling]
They were all
taking part in this,
all right?
[Chuckling]
Yeah.
Why didn't I?
I don't know.
That's a good question.
I wish I did.
I knew the fucking consequences.
Help! Help!
- Help!
- Fuck!
Help!
[Guard On Intercom]
What's going on in there?
No. Nothing. Sorry, C.O.
I hit the button with my elbow.
If I have to come down there,
someone's going to the hole.
You won't have to.
I apologize.
[Muffled Screams]
[Whispering]
Shut the fuck up.
[Grunting]
You wanna fuck with me?
- [Grunting]
- Fuck!
Okay! Please, no!
[Shrieks]
You wanna fuck with me?
[Both Shouting, Indistinct]
Stop it, okay?
Okay.
Stop it. Stop it.
Stop it.
Just let go. It's okay.
[Shrieks]
Like that, motherfucker?
Hold him down.
You're dead, motherfucker.
You're dead.
You understand me?
You don't-- [Mutters]
the fuckin' alarm.
No!
You fuckin'--
[Mutters]
[Groans]
[Grunts]
Fuck you!
Fuckin' bastard!
Fucker! Fucker!
Fucker!
[Crying]
Tryin' to make us
stay here longer, huh?
Is that what you want?
No.
Is that what you want,
you motherfucker?
You piece of shit.
[Shrieks]
You damn fucking asshole!
Fuck you!
Fuck you, fucker!
[Coughs]
[Sniffs, Hawks Phlegm]
Hey, hey, hey.
Bring him over here.
[Chuckles]
Have him lick this up.
- Lick it up!
- Dinner is served.
Lick it up
like you love it!
You know you love it,
honey bunny.
Come on.
Lick it up.
Yeah.
In there.
Does it taste good?
Just pretend it's, uh,
those chicken nuggets you like.
[Laughing]
Oh.
God, he's regretting
it now, isn't he?
[Muffled]
Oh! Pretend it's chicken nuggets
in there!
Yeah.
[Laughing]
[Coughing]
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, uh, I guess
you shouldn't have pressed
that damn button.
Yeah.
Fucking ringing
the button, man.
You're gonna need a vacation.
[Chuckling]
We should, like,
piss on him.
[Laughs]
No, no, no, wait.
No, no, no.
I've got a better idea.
We can make him a cocktail.
Check it out. Looks like a
little baby turtle popping out.
[Urinating]
Like a baby
turtle head.
There we go.
Oh!
Don't get anything
on the floor, man.
Come on.
You do it.
I'm not touching it.
I'll hold him. You do it.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Oh, yeah.
[All Whooping]
Dude, it's getting on
my fucking hand, man!
Fuck! Oh!
It stinks, man.
Look at this floor.
Shit.
Oh, fuck.
Holy shit.
He looks piss-tired, man.
[Chuckling]
Yeah.
Um--
Yeah, I would've remembered
something like that.
I-- I had no choice.
They forced me.
[Crying]
I don't know.
What do you want me to say?
Hey, traitor. Huh?
Wake up.
Wake up, sleepyhead.
Traitor. Huh?
You wanna run to mama?
You know what we do with people
like you, huh,
you fucking traitor?
- I'm gonna show you
what the fuck--
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
I'm gonna fuck you
in the ass,
you fucking traitor!
Huh! People like you
that wanna fuck with me,
you fucking asshole.
Fuck you,
[Groaning]
[Mutters]
[Groaning Continues]
- [Grunts]
- [Grunting]
Take that, you fucking
asshole traitor! Huh?
[Grunting Continues]
You wanna run to mama?
[Both Grunting]
[Shouting]
[Spits]
Fucking asshole.
[Groaning]
Fix up.
I had no idea
you were such a homo.
There's gotta be
a first time, huh?
Are you all right?
Huh?
That's some fucked up shit.
Fucked up shit?
Fucking asshole
didn't get enough.
Come on, huh?
Who's next? Huh?
Admits and regrets?
[Shakily]
And then, um--
And then he--
Curiosity.
I don't, um--
Harry just...
took this broomstick.
I've thought about that
every single day.
[Crying]
I told you, man.
I'm fucking sorry.
[Inhales, Exhales]
Well--
Let's just say then
that I, uh,
shoved a stick in his ass,
and, uh,
I regret it.
[No Audio]
[No Audible Dialogue]
[Mitch Groaning]
[Sighs]
That's right.
Fuck you, man.
Now it smells like shit
on this thing, man.
What a bad day for you,
man.
You gonna press any more
red buttons, brother?
Now get your fucking ass
out of my fucking face
and get the fuck up!
He's learned his lesson, huh?
Huh? Huh?
You gonna clean that up?
What do you think, Peter? Huh?
Should we make him
clean that up?
I think it's enough, man.
Sorry, I didn't hear you.
Say again.
Huh?
I think it's enough, man.
You think it's enough?
Oh, huh.
He thinks it's enough.
- Dude, I think he's trying
to play innocent.
- I know.
We've just gotta make sure that
everyone learns their lesson
out of this, huh? You, me--
- I think it's enough, man.
- [Harry]
What? You're saying-- What?
What are you gonna do?
I'm confused...
'cause you were totally
part of this whole thing,
and now you're
fucking pussying out.
This, man--
You're being a bitch.
You think you're
not a part of this?
- You think you're
not part of this?
- You're in this shit, brother.
You wanna press
the red button?
Not that.
Fuck you. You listen.
Don't you dare play
fuckin' innocent with me,
motherfucker.
You better be careful.
I've been here.
I've seen this shit.
You've been a part of it
from the fucking beginning,
little bitch.
Mmm!
You are a stupid fuck!
Start thinking.
Start thinking, okay?
Get your hands off me.
You're a stupid fuck, man.
Get your fucking hands
off me.
He just fucking turned on us,
man. He hit the alarm.
All right, don't worry.
You're part of this.
Who made him the drink, huh?
Don't forget that.
God, man.
Don't rat on us.
He's gotta play
fucking innocent now, man.
We'll finish him off,
and then we'll
get him later, man.
[Jack]
No, we don't have to get him.
He's in this.
There's no way
he can get out of this,
and he knows it.
We're all in this together,
yeah?
So you better be careful
what you do, man.
Look at what happens.
Look at what happens!
What's going on
anyway, man?
You don't wanna fuck with us.
Hey, are you--
Is he awake?
- Dude!
- I'm sure he's fine.
He ain't pressing any buttons.
Hey, this is like,
you know, smelling salts.
- Smell this, hmm?
- Dude. Wake up, man.
- Look at that. Hmm?
Smell that? Huh?
- Ah, fuck.
- You want a taste of that?
- Wake up, man.
- I'm gonna clean up the mess.
- Wake up, dude.
You motherfucker!
Get the fuck up!
You're gonna clean up
this broom.
Get up!
[Echoing]
- Dude.
- Get your hands off of me.
Back off. Back off.
- Let go of me.
- Fucker, man.
Huh?
You better back off
OCD over here, man.
You better back off.
Leave him alone.
Honestly, back the fuck up now.
Back the fuck up now!
Back up.
Maybe he should lick that shit.
What do you think, man?
I don't know.
What do you think, Peter?
You wanna lick that shit?
Huh?
What's the fucking point, man?
You already took it to the point
you're gonna take it.
- You wanna turn on us?
- No. I'm just saying--
- Okay, good.
- You don't rat, brother.
- You better don't.
- You don't fuckin' rat.
Don't worry.
I'll be gentle, huh?
Fucking cool it, hmm?
Yeah. Hmm? That's right.
Just clean that.
Hmm? Yeah.
Mmm, nice and clean.
Stop fucking pretending, man.
What the fuck is this shit,
dude?
Wake up!
Lick it.
Suck on it, bitch.
Lick it clean.
You see this?
So that I can
clean after you.
You see this? You want this
to happen to you, motherfucker?
You fucking pig!
You filthy pig! Hmm?
All right.
We've got some movement here.
We got some movement.
You gonna stand up?
He's trying to play fucking
victim over here, man.
He's breathing, man.
He's breathing. He's fine.
You play Mr. Dramatic.
Fucking--
He just needs some time,
you know?
Fucking little actor
over here, man.
All right, I'm taking a nap.
Peter, make sure he doesn't
touch the alarm button.
Well, fuck that, man.
What am I gonna do, man?
Shut up. Shut up.
All I'm saying is that
it was too fucking much.
Shut up, dude.
All right.
I'm on your fucking side, man.
I'm just saying
it was a little much.
We'll take shifts,
all right?
Okay.
[Scoffs, Mumbles]
[Chair Clatters]
Aw, shit.
[Sobbing]
I'm--
I'm so sorry.
I wa--
I wanna lie-- I--
I-I wanna lie, because--
And--
I don't wanna be that person.
Um, so if they said what they--
what you claim they said,
um, I guess they're assholes
and they're lying.
You think of something else.
Can I have a cigarette, please?
I feel so fucking shitty,
because I'm just as bad
as the two of 'em,
because I didn't do anything,
because I didn't ring
the fucking bell, because I
didn't fucking tell the guards,
because I didn't fucking
stand up to 'em, because
I didn't do a fucking thing...
as he sat there and got raped
in the fucking ass
with a broomstick!
Because I didn't
fucking stop them,
because I was too scared.
Yeah.
Then, um--
Then they sat down
and watched TV
like nothing happened.
And Mitch, um,
spent about 30 minutes
crawling from one side
of the cell to the other.
[Harry Sighs, Exhales]
[Clattering]
I think you were right, man.
You know,
he pressed the red button.
He, uh, deserved it, right?
[Man On TV,
Indistinct]
I mean, he deserved it.
I know.
He rang the button.
I mean, if there's
one rule you don't break,
it's the red button.
We fucked up there--
in there.
We fucked up.
We went too fuckin' far.
What are we gonna do?
What are we gonna do, huh,
when they come in here
and they find him...
and they see the blood
and the fucking bruises
and the towels, huh?
We've gotta do something.
I'm fucking scared here.
[Harry]
What the fuck
do you propose to do, man?
He just had
this weird stare...
as if he could see
through the walls.
What's the reason
for all this?
[Clears Throat]
I hope this is ending soon,
because I'm being
fucking honest here.
I hope that will be enough,
but, uh--
I told you, man.
I'm fucking sorry.
I-I--
[Jack]
He wouldn't look at you,
even though
his eyes would be--
He would look
right through you.
I think he knew
what they were up to.
Because I couldn't.
Because I'm not strong enough.
Because I wouldn't survive
another fucking week in here.
I wouldn't survive another
fucking night in here.
What am I gonna do?
Look.
[Harry]
Come out and fucking say it.
I--
Look, I read a story about
these two cell mates, right?
And in the middle of the night
this one cat
fucking hangs himself.
And when his celly wakes up
in the morning he's all
fucked up in the head...
to the point that they send him
to a psych ward.
He gets out
after three months, man.
'Cause I don't wanna spend--
I don't wanna spend the rest
of my fucking life in the box.
Not for this.
It's not fuckin' worth it.
I can't, man.
I'm fucking scared, Harry.
I'm fucking scared.
Oh.
You're saying he should hang.
We've gotta do something.
Do what?
What do you wanna do?
I know what you wanna do,
so say it.
What do you wanna do?
We gotta--
We gotta get him
to fucking hang himself.
[Laughs]
Ahh!
- Hey.
- We've gotta get him
to hang himself.
There's no fucking
other option.
Hey, buddy.
Pal.
You hear what he just said?
Hey. You hear what
we're talking about?
Hmm?
We're talking about
you hanging yourself.
[Sighs]
I know that's a big thing
to... ask you to do,
but, uh--
[Sighs]
we'll be in a lot less trouble.
Think about it.
What are you gonna do?
Go home?
Tell Mommy that you, uh,
got fucked in the ass?
How are you gonna live...
the rest of your life?
I don't think it's much of
a life worth living anymore,
brother.
I think we've gone
kinda far today.
I'm sorry.
[Exhales]
We're talking about
ending it all, man.
[Exhaling Deeply]
What else are you gonna do?
[Laughing]
Huh?
What else are you gonna do?
You're fucked.
[Exhales]
We have a happier option
for you, man.
Just end it all.
End that pathetic existence
of yours, man.
We're just, like, you know--
We're just traumatized.
That's a traumatic
thing to see, man--
your celly just hangin' himself.
That's fucked up.
[Burps, Exhales]
Victims,
that's what we'll be.
[TV Continues,
Indistinct]
[Coughs]
I made it out.
There was no coming back.
There was no coming back
for us...
and for Mitch especially.
What are you trying
to imply?
What if you had been...
beaten up, pissed on,
had the shit kicked
out of you,
and then got raped
in the ass,
and then had
a fucking broomstick handle
shoved up your ass?
What would you do?
Huh?
[Jack]
So what are the others saying?
I had no idea
what they were up to.
[Jack]
You wanna hang him tonight?
[Peter] What?
You wanna hang him?
[Scoffs]
Un-fucking-believable.
Do you wanna
hang him tonight?
Is that the question?
Like what?
Like you think we've
got time to kill?
You think we're not gonna
have a fuckin' C.O. knocking
on our door in three hours?
Yeah, you know, we'll let him
come in and fucking find him
with his bloody ass.
Right? And then maybe
three days later we'll, uh--
we'll find the time to hang him.
What do you think?
Sound like a plan?
Did you listen
to a single thing
that we fucking said?
Did--
Sorry. No, I'm just
stressing out.
Don't mess around.
Don't-- I'm just
stressing out, man.
Hey. I'm just making sure
that we're all on
the same page here.
[Quavering]
I know.
Hmm?
We'll hang him.
We'll hang him, huh?
We'll hang him right there,
and the sun is gonna go up
and shine on his
beautiful dead body.
Hmm?
And you know what?
You're gonna make the sling.
[TV Off]
I don't wanna do it, man.
I don't wanna do it.
You better tie the knot.
It was your idea.
No. It's your mess.
I'm not fucking doing it.
It suits you well,
too, you know.
I'm not doing it.
It's your mess, man.
You are gonna tie the knot!
You tie the knot.
[Grunts]
We'll help you hang him.
You tie the knot.
Got it?
What was that? Hmm?
We'll do it together.
We'll lift him up together.
[Coughs]
There's no way
I'm gonna do this
without him participating.
He's gonna rat on us, man.
He was gonna.
I'm gonna rat on you?
I'm gonna fucking rat on you?
Tie the fucking knot
and prove!
I'm gonna fucking rat on you?
Shut the fuck up, man!
You're giving me
a goddamn headache!
Chill. Okay?
We are in this together,
all right? Hmm?
We are a team. Hmm?
[Sniffling]
We'll do it together.
But, you know,
you've gotta get your hands
dirty as well, man. Hmm?
Stop crying
like a little bitch.
[Slaps]
We all do it together.
I don't know about you,
Jack, but, uh,
I'm starting to like this guy
compared to that guy right now.
[Groans]
There's someone else in
the room who needs to hang.
You ready, brother?
Gonna help us out here?
Um--
Sure.
Then I "regretted" it.
[Clears Throat]
[Sobbing]
They did everything, and--
and I didn't stop 'em.
I didn't just stop them.
I didn't do anything.
I stood there,
and I didn't fucking stop 'em.
I didn't do a fucking thing.
He was lying there.
He was just lying there,
and--
and we were getting--
we were getting nervous.
Come on, man.
Quit-- Quit giving us
the silent treatment.
I know you wanna die
just as much as we
want you to, so, uh,
do something
or say something.
I know you can talk.
Hello?
I know you wanna die, man.
Come on.
Okay.
Lift him up.
What the f--
[Chuckles, Grunts]
All right, I'll let you
do us a favor.
You put the cord
around your neck.
I mean, come on.
This is supposed to be
a suicide, right?
[Jack Chuckles]
Yeah, man.
Come on.
Do it for us. Yeah.
Wow.
Do it for yourself.
Wow. You see this?
This is a man...
with some serious cojones.
Huh.
I love you, man.
[Laughs]
I fucking love you.
Give me a hug!
Yes!
Okay, ahh--
What do you think?
How should we do this?
We lift him up,
and Peter ties the knot.
Right?
-Not secure enough
in your own ideas?
-Whose fucking idea was it, huh?
You know what we do to people
like you, huh? Huh?
People like you
are people like-- like him.
You don't want to end
like him, okay?
So you better cooperate.
I mean,
it was his idea, right?
Yeah.
Come. Come.
Let's do it, huh?
Yeah.
Gonna help us?
It was my idea.
[Peter]
Come on. Yeah. Lift him up.
[Harry]
Let's do it.
[Exhales]
He didn't seem
very resistant to-- to me.
Um--
But, you know, I guess...
my, uh--
my influence
wasn't big enough.
I wish I could
fucking lie to you.
I wish I could lie to you.
But I can't,
'cause I feel so fucking bad.
Go on there.
[Groans]
Gotta shift over a little.
Here. All right.
Okay. Go again.
Lift him.
Okay. One--
[Together]
Two, three!
[Groaning]
Motherfucker.
[Groaning, Laughing]
There we go. All right.
[Labored Breathing]
Think happy thoughts,
okay?
Think happy thoughts.
You won't be here soon.
It fuckin' broke, man.
Fuck!
- Shit.
- And now what, huh?
Oh, man.
You are a sly bastard.
What should we do?
Awful.
- Oh, shit.
- Fuck!
[Jack]
He just... wouldn't die.
All right,
get his bed sheet.
Get his bed sheet, man.
Do you know how to tie a noose
with a sheet?
I was so fucking tired.
I just wanted it
to fuckin' end.
[Imitates Gunshots,
Chuckles]
Mitch was, uh--
[Harry]
Tie it up there first, man.
basically fuckin'... nothing.
[Harry]
Tie it up there, man!
No, no, don't worry. You don't
have to eat that. We're gonna
get you chicken nugget.
Okay.
But you gotta
eat it hanging.
[Coughs]
Are you ready?
All right,
let's stand him up.
I felt like there was
no fuckin' way out,
because I felt like--
because I felt like
as soon as the C.O. came in
we'd be fucked.
Let's get him up.
All right.
- Okay, all right.
- [Thudding]
[Laughs]
Okay, ready, set.
One--
[Together]
Two, three!
[Groaning]
Fucker!
Let's get him up
on the bucket.
Okay.
[Bucket Clatters]
All right. Go!
[Mutters]
[Muttering Continues]
Okay.
- Okay.
- [Groans]
Fuck.
Think happy thoughts, man.
Okay?
Think of good things.
Mitch, um,
tied the, uh,
sheet around his...
fucking piece-of-shit neck,
and, uh--
[Clicks Tongue]
I think Peter tied the, uh--
tied the knot onto the bar.
[Clears Throat]
To have it not be me.
Think happy thoughts, man.
[Peter]
Does that make any sense to you?
No?
Think happy thoughts--
[Exhales]
like, uh, flowers and shit.
I don't know.
[Chuckles]
[Mutters]
All right.
Put him on the bucket?
Yeah.
Okay.
Huh.
Ohh!
[Harry]
Damn. You're heavy, man.
Here. Here.
[Sobbing]
It was my idea.
It was my fault.
It was my idea. I--
[Harry]
See how nice I am, man?
All right.
[Match Strikes]
Okay.
There you go.
All right.
[Exhales]
Join him.
That was a lot of work.
No.
I-I-- I can't remember.
You're giving me that
really creepy look again, man.
[Laughs] I don't know!
Fuckin' guy wrapped a...
sheet around his own neck.
So, uh, technically
it's not us hanging him.
He hung himself.
Look, uh--
[Sighs]
I'm sorry.
Okay?
Things got really
fucking out of hand.
But you're really taking one
for the team now. Okay?
- [Jack] You wanna die
and save our asses?
- It means a lot to me.
Thank you.
And I will never
forget you.
Go fuck yourself.
I gave you the full truth.
He was standing on a bucket,
and, uh--
[Laughs] that son of a bitch,
man, he kicked
the fucking thing, man.
And, yeah, you kinda saw
a couple beats there where
his life was sort of--
[Inhales Deeply]
escaping him.
It was a trip.
- [Clears Throat]
- But you know what?
Maybe that makes sense.
Maybe that's what
I should've done.
I didn't stop them
from killing him.
That's what I regret.
He should've eaten
that fucking toothpaste.
[Chuckles]
I guess he's gonna
fuckin' regret that for--
Well, he's dead.
He can't regret it.
You know--
You know what my problem is?
You know what my problem was?
Is that I fucking
cared about him.
I liked him.
He was a fucking sweet kid.
Oh, God.
[Groaning]
[Exhales]
[Door Buzzes]
Hey, sleepyhead.
Hmm?
Pick it up, man.
Wake up, man.
It's showtime.
[In Southern Accent]
Showtime.
Mmm.
Well, ain't you a sight
for sore eyes, man?
This is the first freaking
dead body I've ever seen.
This shit's crazy.
Big ol' empty shell, dude.
He's cold.
That's nuts.
All right.
Should I press the alarm?
[Jack]
Just a second.
What about you, cutie patootie?
Are you ready?
Yeah.
I still don't
trust this guy.
All right, I'm ready.
All right.
Let's do it.
Okay. All right.
We're all--
We're all really shocked
and really worried. Okay?
Worried.
[Heavy Breathing]
Okay, okay, okay.
[Panting, Yelping]
There's been a hanging in 313!
It's a suicide!
Mitch killed himself!
Hurry up! Oh, my God.
Oh, my God. Shit. Oh!
[Siren Wailing]
Untie him.
Okay. I'm trying.
I'm trying.
I can't, man!
Peter, help us!
Peter! Peter!
Help out, man!
[Door Opens]
[Harry]
Dude, is he breathing?
Everybody over here
on your knees,
hands on your head!
- Let's go, guys.
- Jack, move it.
- Fall in line. Let's go.
- Jack! Join your friends,
on your knees.
- We need a couple more guys
with a doctor.
- Jack, on your feet.
- Help Mr. Cohen.
- Lift him up.
Let's go. Lift him up!
- [Jack Grunting]
- [Harry]
Is he breathing at all?
[Cohen]
Shut up!
[Guard]
Did anyone see anything?
No, man. We were sleeping, dude.
He's fucking dead. Come on.
Jack! Jack, back here
on your knees, please.
[Harry]
Is he alive?
- [Guard] Come on.
- [Harry]
Oh, fuck.
Yo, this guy's ice-cold, man.
He's been here all night.
[Peter]
What went through my mind?
Sometimes you just
have to look away.
[Scoffs]
[Taps Table]
To kill him?
I wasn't the boss of shit.
[Peter]
I thought that...
I could come here...
and I could play this cool--
[Sniffles]
and pretend like I wasn't
a fucking part of it...
and that I didn't
do anything.
But I can't.
[Sniffles]
Clean hands.
And I'm--
I'm so fuckin' sorry.
I say yes. I say that we all
have just as much responsibility
for him hanging there.
No, you've gotta
use weight.
[Men Laughing, Chattering]
[Harry]
Think, uh--
Think happy thoughts, man.
[Jack]
You wanna die
and save our asses?
Come on.
Count me in, hmm?
- [Harry]
Still gonna do it?
- [Peter] Okay.
[Jack]
Come on. Count me in, hmm?
[Peter]
That's enough, man.
[Choking]
Well, there it is.
[Chuckles]
You are one crazy motherfucker.
[Jack Gasps]
Damn, man.
[Whispers]
Oh, my God!
What is wrong with that
fucked-up brain of yours, man?
Unbelievable.
Un-fucking-believable.
[Harry]
What did that feel like?
How did that feel?
Is it what everybody says it is?
Is it all-- Make you feel
all powerful and shit?
[Sighs]
That is one ugly sight.
[Gasps]
[Harry]
That's all you, man.