DEATH IN THE NlLO
Mira.
It's her.
Seorita is the Ridgeway.
Elegant.
Some work to live.
Daisy!
A row.
Welcome to Wode Hall,
Miss Ridgeway.
We hope to live happily here.
Thanks, Barnstaple.
S that as being.
You may want to know
the staff, Miss?
AFTER.
I want to know how
to go the work.
The architect has
not reached an.
Now, Barnstaple.
Okay, seorita.
Jackie.!
Linnet!
"Jackie." Linnie.
Sorry.
The butler did not tell me.
"Do not worry.
"You look fabulous.-T
Also, as always.
Where to serve in
the t, seorita?
"In the living room.-S seorita.
Let cool.
Qu him?
Emotional problems.
He wants to marry or more nor
less than an Egyptian.
No saba no l.
I sent to investigate.
- Y? "I was married.
"Then it stopped."
What questions?
Le Negu dowry and thus
no longer wanted.
Men!
Linnet!
"It's beautiful!" I'm
glad you like it.
I want to tell you something
and ask a favor.
"Anything, you know."
It's serious.
I'm engaged.
Jackie!
It's wonderful!
"I dars work?-Job?
Here, in Wode Hall. Please.
L There must be something first.
Well, his name is Simon, Simon
Doyle and he is ...
l is all that I soad bean.
Jackie ...
"Is not it beautiful?-S,
is beautiful.
-S, right? "But est broken.
With l, and two of us.
Shoes estn killing me.
He loves the countryside.
A job here will be ideal.
Linnet, die if I marry l.
Seriously, to die.
-Ests very much in love. "I s.
Well. Qu want me to do?
You have this property.
Someone will have to help.
-Simon. "It takes experience.
Estudi Property Management in Cambridge.
It's brilliant.
If you do not like,
you can fire him.
But s you like.
Est good.
Why do not you bring
it tomorrow?
"Talking to l." Thanks.
"Jackie!" Adis.
Not to sound silly.
Do not worry, I promised Linnet.
Well, almost.
Quiz does not even like.
Nonsense. I adore!
And you're perfect for the job.
We will do all to
not disappoint.
Simon, I love you.
You make me so happy!
"The honeymoon be in Egypt."
I always talk about Egypt.
Hello.!
Linnet!
Linnie, est here.
"Come." One moment, dear.
Est here.
My Simon.
Hello.
Jackie has been a lot of you.
Not perfect? Not it lovely?
S, I think I will
make very well.
I told you.
Linnet Ridgeway''prince
marries Blue penniless.
The honeymoon be in Egypt.''God!
Tutankamn querrs not say?
Qu hell are we doing?
The Bremen sails tonight.
Barely.
Arreglarsa lawyers?
"No, silly." Then what?
lr to Egypt. She be all month.
To Andrew!
A chance encounter.
I'm traveling.
Lovers on their honeymoon.
His mind be distracted.
You understand?
Linnet is no fool, Pennington.
And neither am I!
Then you have a good trip,
evil To Andrew.
As she is Miss Bridgeway.
Qu noted as carefully?
His photography ...
or pearls?
With EDUCATION, Bowers,
or quedars you a job.
Qu I care?
This town is full of rich widows
willing to pay slavish
attention.
Next, despdame.
Well genius, Bowers!
You need a vacation.
Qu Pequeño that you look like
a trip down the Nile?
There is nothing that
would upset me more.
Two things stand: heat
and mushrikeen.
Well, then we will go.
Bowers, packs.
They must put stairs.
"Lazy!" Lazy?
It is better to travel
than arrive.
Qu view!
Feliz, Vicar?
Tonto, we are more happy
in the world.
And the more beautiful.
"And the more fortunate."
And the more alone.
Slo us and no more.
Neter-Menkewre The pyramid
is 62 meters high.
Each side of the base
measures 108 feet.
"Jackie!" Qu hell are
you doing here?
Admire the view as you.
Were on the Danielli in
Venice and Brindisi.
Qu coincidence!
Jackie, why?
We est following, deliberately.
Is that true? Is intolerable!
And ordinary.
Very ordinary.
And effective.
Very effective.
Adis.
"Bitch.
Where do we go, is shown.
"Cario ...
"Like a kangaroo on heat."
I understand it.
-S? "I guess it's my fault.
Romp commitment and
cas me with you.
He must be heartbroken.
He revels in every minute.-No.
Cario.
We are the lucky ones.
What Jackie did not ruin.
I will start.
It is the perfect honeymoon.
And no one ruin.
I love you.
I bet a race.
Colonel Race, "Poirot!
Nice to see you.
"My old friend! Qu happy!-S.
Do not you see ...
from that strange case
of clrigo beheaded.
A lucky find the knife
in the fireplace.
Luck?
Army Drops I cells; gray.
The fate I leave to the dems.
Forget your self-esteem.
Qu I can ask you here?
I am on vacation.
To navigate the Nile
in the steam.
- Y t? "I do the same.
Rather, follow sb passenger.
Slo No. I'm away, my friend.
-As-S t..
This chair est free?
In this world, buddy,
nothing is free.
"Qu said?" Olvdelo. Synthesis.
"Thanks.
Capital''Lee''"" I never travel
without this book.
Dr. Ludwig Bessner.
Bessner lnstitute in Zurich.
Jim Ferguson, a citizen
of the world.
Holiday-Est?-No.
Observe the decay of the
capitalist system.
Wow.
It has a good example here.
The young heiress kagumi.
That Parsitan!
"I do not approve?"
I'm disgusted.
In any decent society ...
S, maybe they're right.
He has too much power.
"Lord ..." Thank you.
Health.
Linnet!
"Linnet, dear." To Andrew.
Qu Surprise saba you
were not here.
Everything went very quickly.
I'm on my honeymoon.
Your honeymoon?
his is the lucky girl?
My American curator, Andrew
Pennington, love.
Simon Simon Doyle.
"Nice." The pleasure is mine.
"We're riding with?"
Slo a moment.
Do not worry. I do not intrude.
I know young people.
The target of all eyes.
Even t, Inglês your
modesty, the look.
"It's very beautiful."
And very rich.
Quin know it?
"Of course.-S.
Sorry for the intromisin,
but I have a bet with
my daughter.
You are Hercule Porridge, the
famous detective francs?
Almost.
I am Hercule Poirot, the famous
Belgian detective.
I told you, Rosalie.
Slo is a Mr.
Poirot in the world.
lnconfundible.
As I am also.
My mother is Salome Otterbourne,
the novelist.
Otter ... Salom, of course.
Encantado.
Two celebrities in one place.
Three, tell me.
I referaa genius,
not the mere money, Ser.
I present to you Colonel
Race, my old friend.
Ms. .. and her daughter ...
Encantada.
Sintense, ladies and Seorita.
Sb be writing a new book, Madam?
It takes place in Egypt, maybe?
Qu brilliant deduction, Sr.
Porridge!
I'm here to absorb
the local color
to my great opus,''Snow
on the Sphinx.''
An enigma love ice cream
becomes incandescent
when a girl English, Recinos
graduate school
plays the heartless heart
of a cruel desert sheik.
I think Mr. Poirot
is not a regular reader of
novels romnticas, mother.
Of course s. All the French are.
Not afraid of a good sex.
Unlike our major libraries.
Salome Otterbourne vetoed
by telling the truth
on men and women.
But she continues.
The truth, s.
It is so difficult
to tell the truth.
Thank you, Lord.
You may dance a tango
with me ...
seorita?
Exercise AFTER dinner.
You dance tango, Colonel?
"Soon, Mrs.
Otterbourne." Teach
him to do well.
As in Spain, when known
as the''girl''
ie with a sensual
and erotic touch.
Damn, Jackie! DJanes quiet!
Waiter.
Poirot Lord!
Linnet I saw it today.
However much you paid
to get away?
Do not accept payment
or accept it.
What dir is friendship.
Qu have to say?
I do the ridiculous? I'm crazy?
Bury the dead.
Unlike the Egyptians,
keeping body
to ensure the eternity of the soul.
No.
Properly and completely.
Give back to the past.
Slo Look forward.
Remember, time heals everything.
If you think you suffer,
est wrong.
Ms I'm enjoying it.
His pleasure is the worst
part of all this.
I do not care.
Simon was moy loved me.
Then came her ...
It's something Pequeño ...
but is lethal.
And my father taught me
to have a good tip.
Sometimes
I put this gun against his head
and AFTER slowly
pulling the trigger.
I want that noise
or every damsyms.
S what he feels.
We all feel sometimes.
But I warn you, seorita ...
D will not login to the
evil in his heart.
Ah is host.
If love can not live ah,
replace the evil it well.
Qu sad seorita.
Hello, Lord P.
-Back to the hotel? "Adnde ms?
It is a surprise to Linnet.
Feel that you like?
Depends. She smokes?
Slo A. Craven
For purposes upon ...
I spoke with Jackie?
S, a few minutes ago.
Qu good.
I hope it has entered
into reason.
For her, the reason is
the eternal vengeance.
Are you serious?
Whenever I'm serious, my friend.
Jackie is stubborn, I s,
and very possessive.
"But surely ..." Quera possess?
I suppose s.
S.
She has a genius possessed.
Want the reins.
S, and a man can not
allow it, right?
Not at all.
When he meets Linnet ...
How to explain?
It was like the moon
after sunrise.
It does not show.
AFTER to meet you,
Jackie dej exist.
S. Some women have that power.
But how to solve your
current dilemma?
I have a great plan
and guaranteed.
Driver!
At the Station Railway.
Let's Alejandra.
What msrpido you can.
Expeditiously as!
Thank you.
Mralan. Est Ah.
Welcome, welcome.
Welcome aboard the Karnak.
My name is Mr.
Chowdhury.
I'm the manager of this boat
and pleasure and cheers
are my only worry
and contentment.
Here I have ... I have here ...
S, I have a list here ...
with the names ...
and cabins.
Guessing by their faces
quin quin is, okay?
You are Mrs.
and Miss Otterbourne.
"Right?" Lncorrecto.
I'm Mrs. Van Schuyler
and want to go to my
room immediately.
Bowers will have the cabin
opposite to starboard.
The hot afternoon sun miracles
with bilious cheek and vinegary.
S. Right now, Madam.
S. You must be Dr. Bessner,
with this elegant
mustache German.
I fear that jams become
detective, Ser.
The mustache, indisputably
elegant, is Belgian.
My name is Poirot,
Hercule Poirot.
The famous Mr. Poirot?
I bow before you.
I am humbled.
Give simple names Serams
and you tell us the cabin.
More simple? S, seorita.
Undoubtedly more simple.
Definitely.
A lack of complicacin brilliant.
At one point, the lead assistant
to their cabins.
Wizard!
We left.
I suggest you take the
LAST look at the city.
Wizard!
We did it.
We got rid of it, finally.
Qu expect?
You're a genius.
It is not bad for
the Bobito Simon.
Fabulous, right?
You are Miss Ridgeway, right?
And you, Mrs. Van Schuyler.
I wondered if you break the ice.
They rarely speak to strangers.
And never with strangers
on their honeymoon.
I'm glad to break his rule.
The rules are to be broken.
At least the most,
by m.
They are beautiful.
Thank you.
And amazing,
if you know how to occur.
A tiny grain of sand
enters an oyster,
and eventually becomes
a pearl of great price
that adorns the neck of
a cute nia like you.
I never thought of as.
Shall.
The oyster was almost killed.
We go to the cabin.
It is time for your massage.
My Companions, Bowers.
Pele 15 rounds with
Jack Dempsey once.
l would never be the same.
Excuse me, Miss Ridgeway.
Madam Doyle. Madam Simon Doyle.
Will have to forgive Ms. Bowers.
Do not know the marital status.
I saw dazzled by her pearls.
Cllate.
Dara all his teeth
by owning them.
Slo because you have grudge
rather his father,
-You should not be descorts.
"Grudge?
Ridgeway Melhuish
ruined my family.
Well, you should be grateful.
Otherwise, you will not have the
pleasure of working with me.
Slo may kill her for that.
T, Madam?
Salom Otterbourne and I'm
communicating with you.
Since we communicate
by way of lawyers.
It's about that I have
come to beg ...
"Begging" "lmplorar to
appeal if you like.
The writers we are blooming
in our language.
And defamatory in
their writings.
I feel that has been interpreted
Pasin''Under the persimmon
tree''that way.
Slo The intention was to
show a girl's heart
beating to the beat
of primitive drums.
He does not understand that what
I write was really a compliment?
Frankly, Ms. Otterbourne,
I do not consider the comparacin
with a female baboon ninfmana,
a compliment
and suggest that lawyers decide
the appropriate repair
to be the target of his
vulgar stupidity.
Good afternoon.
Philistia.
We show qu is the reputation.
Sorry to interrupt.
To Andrew.
Those are the documents
you sign.
The contract of
Chrysler Building
awards from the silver mine
shipments of Baku Petrleo
Melting and Krisps
kKorn-Chew-Chew.
Sign in Pgina Tv, down, dear.
To Andrew, I have not Ledo.
No need. Everything is revised
and twice revised by m.
Always read everything
before signing.
My father taught me.
Deca who did not trust
anyone, or lawyers.
Darling Melhuish.
Qu sense of humor!
For m, Ledo in my life
a legal document
and I will not start now.
Do not say.
"It's a bit irresponsible.-S,
completely,
but dying for a Manhattan. Y t?
Est good
to be the honeymoon.
As is done.
Now the next.
I hope not to intrude.
I am a lawyer and I must say
that I admire your attitude.
His father tena reason.
Never sign a document
without reading it.
Sure agree.
Of course.
Sure, no hurry.
With permission.
I hope I have not offended.
And if he did, Mr. ...?
-Race. Colonel Race.
- And if so, Colonel?
The lawyers know how
to handle offenses.
"We're riding with the bar?" Thanks.
Very nice.
And you, Mr P.?
There is reason for concluding.
My plan to let Jackie
was a success.
S. ..
as will appear.
My congratulations.
The Colonel and I flanking ...
at a time.
Cario.
"Madam, I must sp
ak.-After, Louise.
No, now. It's important.
I wait in the bar.
"What will happen?" Received
a telegram.
My fiance returned to his
wife to his village.
Est me waiting.
I must go.
Give me the money I promised.
I've been working five years.
That's crazy.
Madam, you promised me.
Est It still married, Louise.
I implore you.
I need that money as dowry.
I have worked well.
And seguirs hacindolo
until I say so.
"Madam, I would not be denied."
Thank you, Louise.
Camel!
By God, How are alienates
everyone!
Even his own lawyer
tries to cheat?
Old fox, you notice?
Saba you were not here,
how did you say?
Slo''holiday, my friend.''
I think I can tell you.
English lawyers working
for Ms Doyle.
They suspect that Andrew
Pennington, well ...
"Embezzled money?" Something as.
Segna his father's will
She manages her money to marry
and as recently cas ...
l want you to sign a document
to save him.
Exactly.
I think this time it scared,
but then har qu?
Not only l, either.
Inside the Great
Temple of Karnak
we went through the stands
of many sheep ...
each with an image of Amenhotep the front.
S.
S, are sheep.
Rams libidinous,
FLIC, Enceladus.
Qu noble son!
With his proud flanks,
large necklaces
and shameless curved horns.
S, come, madam.
Karl Marx said
that the religion was the
opium of the people.
To his mother is sex.
Not be better to calm a bit?
May harming these animals.
My mother may be mocked by you,
but it is my mother.
I take good care little better.
Do not stop now ...
"Now that qu" "Nothing.
Sorry.
Did not mean to be impertinent,
much less offend.
Seorita, I'm not as
bad as I look.
"No?" Word of honor.
I bothered to offend her?
Linnet Ridgeway is a crab.
A Parsitan of society.
In a perfect world, was killed
as a warning to dems.
"The killed?" That said.
-Sr. ... "Jim Ferguson.
Jim, you can defame the dead?
I do not understand
the question.
It does not matter.
Is not it wonderful?
Ms all of any comprehension.
Temperament artistic, Mr.
Pennington.
Qu takes such e
traordinary ways!
I hope this does not concern me, Mr.
Poirot.
I limit myself to the world
of facts and figures.
The ancient Egyptians knew
facts and figures.
The Grand Vizier Ptahotep,
for example, was crushed under
a thousand pieces of silver
for embezzling the fortunes
of his master.
"I say." As it was.
By God!
Ests right?
Linnet, ESTs right?
Ven. Slowly.
Slowly. Levntate.
Ests right?
Qu pas?
That rock must have
fallen or pushed.
To kill me?
Jackie!
But she is not here.
By God, Madam, was
in grave danger.
Might be a horrible accident.
That rock was 4000 years ah
cay and accurate when bean people down.
No.
Not exactly 4000 years,
Mr Poirot.
The columns were built
in 1788 AC ...
Okay, but has a patient
who attend.
Qu neglect the ma!
"Now ..." I'm fine. Really.
It is better to return to the
ship and rest a while.
Est good.
But only a couple
of hours, Doctor.
I visit the Temple of
Abu Simbel tonight.
It's extraordinary.
The figure of the eastern end
is the famous statue vocal.
- Really?-S.
We arrive on time.
Thank you, Doctor.
At dusk beeps sad and mournful.
-L scares me. "It's harmless.
By God! Fantstico Son!
I find frightening.
They are not.
Think that song for me?
Why not? You are divine.
Welcome to the Temple
of Abu Simbel.
The facade is 25 m longiud.
Each of the statues of Ramss ll
is 20 m high.
Aljate m!
Go!
Carlo!
She can not ruin everything.
He could not bury their dead.
You can not get away.
No, I can not get away.
Not believe that Simon
tricks cheating me.
I'm sorry to see it
here, seorita.
Disclpeme to say,
but embarks on a dangerous
journey in rough seas
to deal with unfortunately
current unknown.
"Why do you say?" Because
it's the truth.
ECENT Cut the ties that
bind it to safety.
An can repent, if
you really want.
We must continue our
star where we carry.
Even the disaster?
Even in hell itself.
"I forgot my purse.
Be right back. "Well.
Well ...
We are alone, friend of mine.
Bean had no opportunity to
speak with you privately.
From what we have to talk?
From my repute, Madam Doyle.
-Directs the institute in Zurich.
"As is.
And you've said many nasty
things about me
influential people and POSITION.
"I say that is a fake.-Mrs.
Doyle!
"A dangerous fake." Esccheme.
My friend Myra Seligman
heard him too well.
Le dej apply those
horrible shots.
We developed a urine
treatment armadillo.
S. Bean used before
with great success.
In the case of Myra, went mad.
Thank you.
Do not allow this.
Your comments about my treatment
can not continue.
Demndeme, if you dare.
He knows that is impossible.
One of my clinically escndalo
mean ruin.
Then be his funeral.
Well, hopefully not yours.
Want a chocolate cream
or coercion, maybe?
The above service is very slow.
No, thanks.
Qu time?
Ah there is a clock.
Use your eyes.
Your mother taught you
that the servants
difference is the eccentricity
of the impolite?
"My mother was a lady." Quality
that did not inherit.
Bedtime.
Good. Where to est my stole?
I have not seen.
"Sure the tena?" Of course s.
Use your eyes.
Mr. Poirot.
I hope that one day
can tell some of their cases,
the more juicy.
"The more juicy?"
The more bloody.
When you wish, Madam.
"Good evening, Ser."
Good evening.
"Excuse me." Do not worry.
It looks very sooliento
tonight, Mr Porridge.
S, I have a lot ...
The dream overwhelms me.
S why would not I can hardly
keep your eyes open.
Fool. Neither do I.
May accompany up to my cabin?
For here, as you know.
I suppose this little rough and
trying to seduce you arrive.
Do not leave without at least
give a semblance of fight.
The persecution is
very important.
Mother!
No, here is better.
There is a dangerous escaln.
Always stumble.
No. it is the ro.
The old est Nile
restless tonight.
That's right.
There are disturbing trends.
Here we are.
No, no. Adentro.
"Good evening." Good
evening, Madam.
Hello.
"You were on the ground?-S.
The moon is beautiful.
A night of honeymoon.
If the daughter of slo
clrigo drink water,
finished safely in Geneva.
A diamond.
"Simon, we're waiting."
Excuse me.
It's your turn.
"Double." Qu?
He was her man
but he Háqqah wrong.
I accompanied?
No, thanks.
You can repeat your bet?
Excuse me.
If the main season of the vicar
has not touched liquor
expect to find the champagne.
White Background.
Sorry, Carian, was not thinking.
They swore to be faithful
to each other ...
I fear that we won.
I go to sleep.
It's bedtime.
I second the idea.
Good night.
That bed bugs do not bite!
- Vienna, Simon? "No slow.
Pick up a little.
"Good evening." Good evening.
"It's late.
I lie. "No, come on, syntactic.
Cuntame you.
I have not much to tell, really.
I am the daughter of
Otterbourne Salom.
If the wife of a God who
has never touched wine,
can bet to finish in whiskey.
More. Were ...
saying something about
someone's daughter.
In Salom Otterbourne,
the novelist.
Salom?
It did him behead a man?
Must happen to someone I know.
"Enough." Enough qu?
"Liquor." Liquor.
Perhaps your business?
"I guess not." Right.
Qu going, Simon? Ests scared?
"Afraid of qu?-Scared ...
that this lady tell the
story of my life.
S Now I must go.
No, wait.
It is a very sad story.
As a three-hanky, if
you're sentimental.
For the love of God, Jackie.
Qu?
Go to sleep and stop doing
the ridiculous.
''Simon says''I'm doing
Simon says ... I go to sleep.
Sleep.
T're disgusting!
Go to sleep!
As I can try!
Listen, Jackie!
Kill you first!
Jackie!
Quickly. Aydelo.
"By God." Heavens!
Bring to Dr. Bessner.
Llvela to his cabin.
Tranquilcela.
Qu did?
The seorita Bowers
is a nurse, right?
PDAL to look after her.
Come.
Simon ...
That it is not alone.
Then look at health
surveillance.
Quickly.
Acustese.
Bring to Ms. Bowers.
"Simon!" Relax.
Rosalie was by Ms.
Bowers.
She is a nurse. She's caring.
Take too long.
Ms. Bowers is bean bed. Coming.
"Between ms sooner the
better." How est?
How you can stay after
shooting his ex-lover?
How can he be so heartless?
Quiet. Here comes Ms. Bowers.
Estars well.
This is Doyle.
There was an accident ...
S. Ms. Otterbourne inform me.
I believe that an injection
of morphine calm.
It is effective if Mrs.
Van Schuyler gets nervous.
Ferguson, call Alemán health
surveillance in next door.
-PDAL that meets
Doyle.-S, right.
This looks bad.
Get another napkin.
Quiet.
The bones are broken.
There are many losses of blood.
Est good.
Aydemir take him to my cabin.
I'm afraid of blood
as a woman?
Mr. Ferguson, Aydemir a lift.
I stay with her tonight.
We do not know how to react.
-Ms. Bowers, est bien? "As is.
I applied morphine.
Do not be left alone.
Good.
Young girl, come with me.
Be more useful than this fool
who is afraid of blood.
Open my door.
As, slowly. Care. Very good.
We're fine.'re Almost there.
Very good.
Get a towel for the head fra, s?
S, Doctor.
Search the revlver.
There should be at ah, right?
-S.-S.
Jackie.
It should not be alone.
It is not alone. Do not worry.
For God's sake, everything
has been blamed ma.
The treated badly.
Saba not what Háqqah.
She was drunk.
That hurt.
Not be better tell your wife?
S.
S, please.
No, Djel sleep.
Do not worry until tomorrow.
The best I can do is sew.
There is no exit wound.
The bullet embedded est.
There will have to wait
to get to Wadi Halfa.
Sbale sleeve.
Lmpielo with this.
Ask splints
and then splinting
when he is asleep.
Thank you, Doctor.
Now, do not worry.
Everything will be fine.
It is not.
Qu?
The weapon, he is not.
Quin can have it?
Esclqueme.
I hope it is not important.
Sometimes''
I put this on his head revlver
AFTER and slowly pull
the trigger.''
Qu?
Nothing.
Speak to the manager.
I am in charge of the case.
We will be responsible
until reaching port.
"I am at your disposal." Thanks.
What can I say about this?
He was shot with a
bullet very minor,
22 gauge, I think.
The revlver was near the head.
Here we can see the whole
versengen''.''
Curse, unable to speak Inglês?
"It means scorching.-S,
singeing.
Excuse ...
Well, well ...
-Qu conclude, then? "Qu?
I think it's CFLI.
Ms. Doyle was dying.
Quera for us to identify
the murderer.
Unt finger with his own blood
and''J''wrote on the wall.
Jacqueline.
What he says is stupid.
She died instantneamente.
"Really?-S. No time to write.
No.
It was a joke?
Very small and not very
good taste, I fear.
But the''J''est on the wall.
We have to explain qu.
Cândido melodramtico
is a gesture.
Cul is the hour of death?
Been dead at least six hours
and no more than eight.
That is, between 12
and as two o'clock.
"Which is extraordinary." Why?
Because it means that Ms.
Jacqueline
could not.
T told me yourself, Colonel,
that Ms.
Doyle went out of the living
room shortly before 11:45
to go to bed.
Since then,
Jackie was in sight of Ms.
Murray and Mr. Doyle
or Mr. Ferguson and Ms. Bowers,
he was injected with morphine
and accompanied in his
cabin all night.
Simon Doyle is ruled out because
of his broken leg.
I guess not pruning
walking wounded?
Not one step, I assure you.
Great!
DISPOSAL eyelet process
as follow.
I am afraid not, Colonel.
Almost everyone in this boat
Why saban hated Miss
Ms Jackie Doyle.
It was precisely the person
for confabulacin''.''
At least, Mr, you can
not suspect m.
Why not?
Tena a motive to kill her, according
to I discovered last night.
Then s listening.
But it was not a cause.
Habra could sue.
And risk the ruin?
Murder is more expensive.
And safest, if not discovered.
"But as something can
be done." I disagree.
At the time of the shooting to Mr.
Doyle,
you might be on deck
quiz suffering from insomnia.
Voices could have odo,
look out the living room window
and see what happens.
Go to sleep!
As I can try!
Listen, Jackie!
Kill you first!
Jackie!
He could remember the position
of the revlver.
Then, when he was called
from his cabin
could collect revlver
Heed while Mr. Doyle.
Ms later, when all was quiet
could leave the cabin without
his patient's knowledge,
go to the cabin of Mrs. Doyle
and kill her.
No, Doctor, I can not dismiss.
What it suggests is
ubermssig''.''
lnjurioso, s.
I'm not here to be insulted.
Find anything in glaze?
Not catch flies with vinegar.
"Qu said?" An old proverb francs
too long to explain.
Preparmonos for investigation
Customer justifying it.
How long pas, according
to their clculos,
between the time you
and the Doctor
removed Mr. Doyle's living room
and when he came back
to find the revlver?
"About three or four minutes."
Three or four minutes.
You were next to the living
room when the shot oy.
It could be entirely
possible that you
notice the position
of the revlver.
Agreed. Totally possible.
Also entirely possible that you
wait until the salon
was emptiness,
it removed the revlver
and AFTER you say no bean found.
Yluego, before reporting to Dr.
Bessner of prdida,
use it to kill Ms. Doyle.
I could have done all
that, but I did not.
And you, seorita,
revlver could pick up
before leaving here
while Mr.
Ferguson attend to Mr. Doyle.
-Lr by Ms. Bowers. "Well.
When he went to find Ms. Bowers,
could pass through the cabin of Mrs.
Doyle
and murder.
A minute or two ms of delay.
Miss Bowers, wake up.
Seorita Bowers.
What will happen?
Come, please.
There was an accident.
Why we had to take it?
Tenamos no reason to kill.
But it was''a crab,
a Parsitan in the
skin of society''
it deserves to be killed.
-S, but ...-S, she was killed
as an example for the dems.
Nasty Spanish francs.
Belga, Belgian space,
please lord.
And you, seorita,
was anxious to avoid major
damage to his mother.
I may not have done that.
He consulted two days ago.
Was the reply.
You're right, seorita,
you can not defame the dead.
You are horrible.
Pretend to be nice and respectful
yslo intended deceive.
I find what he is
hiding, seorita.
The truth.
AFTER giving her the morphine
to Miss Jackie,
"She did not move
at all?" Exactly.
Reaccin nervosa, alcohol
and morphine together.
Have sunk the Titanic.
Undoubtedly it could
not be the killer?
No, no way.
But you may s.
I?
S, you seorita.
Suppose I was on deck
when they fired.
Saw what was happening
and learned in the revlver
Where to qued.
Young girl, come with me.
Be more useful than this fool
who is afraid of blood.
While Mr.
Ferguson and Ms. Rosalie
helped Dr. Bessner,
he could leave his patient
and go up the gun.
Had enough time
before Mr.
Ferguson returned to find him.
Port could go down to the cabin of Mrs.
Doyle
and murder.
It's absurd.
Why kill Mrs. Doyle?
Because his father was
Melhuish Ridgeway,
unscrupulous dealings which
ruined his father
and condemned to a
life of servant.
Nonsense.
Quin said that?
You yourself, seorita
makes three days.
How dare listen to a private
conversation?
Some voices are heard from afar.
Is that true?
S.
Ve?
Why would kill her for something
that happened years ago?
It still suffers because
its effects deeply.
No, seorita unfortunately
I am not convinced
their protests.
Tena means, motive, opportunity,
and what is more,
the disposal to kill.
I finished, Mr. Poirot?
For the moment,
but ms preprese to answer
questions if necessary.
I will start.
Poirot Lord ...
It is true about Linnet?
Absolutely true.
I do not mat.
S we all believe, but I did not.
Quiet, seorita.
We know that it was ace.
We have evidence.
-Tests. "Thank God.
But Simon, est bien?
The Doctor seems satisfied
with her condition.
It was crazy last night.
I could have killed him.
Thinking I forgive?
It is very probable.
S that men are less Enticed
to women who treat them well.
Miss Bowers, acompela
to his cabin.
Ms afternoon take a visit.
Thank you.
I think we should visit first.
He must be awake.
Good idea.
What more ...
confuses me is the revlver case.
"The gun?" Disappeared Why?
I do not understand the importance.
In many cases this happens.
Even when attempting confabulacin?
No.
Why taking the trouble
J''''writing on the
wall with blood
and then hid the
revlver of''J''?
I understand what you say.
They found something.
One thing is certain:
Mrs Doyle mat not a fish.
Est good?-S, thanks.
Deb lost consciousness.
Eat something. We give strength.
Thanks. Do not want to see food.
Do not want to see?
-I? "Please. Go ahead.
I can not believe it.
Linnet est dead.
It is a hard blow.
I guess that Jackie
is quite dicult,
but it s not as commit a murder.
Rest assured, Ser.
We know that it was Miss Jackie.
Thank God.
Any idea of who might be?
Well, almost anyone.
Yesterday, she said
all in this boat were
his enemies.
We have reason to believe
that he was right.
Lord ...
Sorry.
I came to see if it
was easier for you.
So ease in as I can.
Thanks, Louise.
You find the body.
Quiz can give us some light.
Sorry ...
Est accusing me?
At a respectable young man?
"I swear by my dead mother
..." Hush, Louise.
No stories.
You have to tell the truth.
Syntactic.
Lord detective, Cramer.
A poor Mrs.
Doyle all loved her. It was ...
He was young, beautiful.
No one will want to kill her.
Louise, that's not true.
Lncluyndote ...
They may talk about something
that we all understand?
He says that everyone loved to Ms.
Doyle.
At least it is something new.
Cundo Mrs. Doyle was alive?
Last night, Mr.
I was in his cabin, ayudndola
to undress.
AND AFTER adnde was?
In my cabin. Adnde ms?
And there was not anything
that can help oy?
How, Lord?
My cabin is on the other
side of the boat.
Of course, if you
could not sleep,
if he had gone to the roof
Perhaps it would have
been the murderer
enter and exit the
cabin of the Lord.
But as was ...
Lord, please understand
my situation.
"I can say what else?" Nobody
accuses you of anything.
Do not worry, Louise.
I will protect.
"The lord is good." But ...
If it had not returned after
leaving the cabin,
would have had time
to witness the agresin Mr.
Doyle in the living room.
-No.-S.
Would have been able to walk
on deck, see everything
and in a timely manner,
collect revlver,
back ...
and kill Ms. Doyle.
Lord, I am accused unjustly.
Why do something so bad?
Contsteme.
Louise ...
S all of you,
Your romance
and Ms Doyle oposicin when
you wanted to go.
But I have no money
and no references.
My only option was to stay.
Precisely. The hated that.
But the mat.
One last question, Louise.
In Where are the pearls of Mrs.
Doyle?
Their pearls?
The tena made last night.
The leave in the table
next to her bed.
Ah were in the morning?
By God! Even mir.
I went to bed, I saw the Lord,
grit and salt ran
out of the cabin.
Not even looked!
But I, Hercule Poirot, I have
eyes to notice it all.
Pearls were not on the
table this morning.
Had experienced evaporated
vanished.
Disappeared.
"We must find the revlver."
And the pearls.
S. That should not
be very dicult.
It's hot.
You are right.
Lr to change my shirt.
Let us pause to refresh.
And rest to small cells; gray.
Since we last met.
I thank you for the
very timely rescue.
It was a pleasure. Or your SOS.
"You think he went to purposes
upon?" Certainly.
But a simple snake will not
stop the investigation ...
Hercule Poirot.
How is the research?
With intelligence and discrecin?
"No one to fifteen to wives?"
It still does not.
There are all dead cobra.
Hgame the favor of removing it.
Thank you.
Come Race.
A cobra? No way!
Bean never seen a snake
in a cabin first.
Jams.
Quin's next?
Pennington? Know how is it.
He's a menace.
Poirot Lord, I presume?
Disclpenos, Madam.
Quiz allow the accom.
Of course.
"Well?-Est with Mrs. Doyle?
-As is.
"Heard something strange
last night?
Of course I have a dream
lightweight s.
and I woke up something
like a pop.
A burst?
S. Like a champagne
cork as it exits.
A champagne common, clear est
not a great harvest.
're making a noise much
more discreet.
It could have been a weapon
pequeay not a cork?
Very possibly.
But must take into account
my limited knowledge
of firearms.
We found him.
We found it! Qu good!
Qu wonderful success!
The hump of the camel.
And without a misguidance.
Lord!
Lord, I am sure that we
find what they seek.
"Thanks.
Mr. Chowdhury. "Willingly.
Without doubt, the weapon
of Miss Jackie.
A new 22 Derringer.
"Four shots." Two bullets fired.
A tissue of man. It seems blood.
An ashtray mrmol to sink.
And I stole.
It's yours, madam?
Sure, it's ma.
The loss last night
at the salon.
The murderer wrapped revlver
to dampen noise.
Qu impertinence!
"The crown prince Carol
I stole this regal in Romania.
People have no respect for
property from others.
Not for the gems from others.
A qu concerns, Mr?
I refer to pearls
Potsdam, Madam,
that they belonged to Ms.
Doyle and were stolen.
Stolen?
Birla.
Stolen.
And look at me qu
with that known expresin
continental?
How pearls are related to me?
I am the ugly space
intruder, my Lord.
Or that he greatly admired
the pearls, which give
''All his teeth by
owning them.''
Bowers Damn!
My Teora is that you have an
obsessive love for jewelry,
they coveted the jewels of Mrs.
Doyle
and was determined to possess
even by theft
o. .. the murder.
Do not deny it, madam?
I imagine her walking on the
deck yesterday evening,
waiting for Ms. Doyle to sleep.
Go to sleep.!
By chance, see what
the living room.
Listen, Jackie.!
Kill you first.!
Jackie.!
By being vacuum the living room,
advantage to take the gun.
Go to the cabin of Mrs. Doyle
knowing that their
husbands will be.
He shoots
and then steals the pearls
from her bedside table.
Remove your words
or sue for libel with
the utmost vigor.
Not even the force
to which register this boat
especially his cabin, looking
for those pearls.
I wish you a great evening.
Totally obnoxious
upstart francs.
Belga, please, Madam.
You should be so rude
to the lady?
"You seem to acknowledge them
all." With reason, Colonel.
Think the elderly do not kill?
Sure it has the pearls.
The question is,
mat to get them?
Chowdhury Lord!
Suerte.
"Colonel?" We sail immediately.
I have already given the order.
At this time the Engineers
stokes the boiler.
Hurry?
Dude, I feel the presence
of evil around me.
The sooner we reach Wadi
Halfa, the better.
Keep this in safety.
Began The search for pearls.
It is the last cabin.
Perhaps the bot overboard.
You forget that we lack
the cabin Pennington.
Revismoslo now.
Hello, guys!
Our trip Cont.
Good afternoon, Madam.
I accompanied with a drink?
This wonderful young
just prepare for the
xtraordinary mixture ms
native fruit juice.
Sebek is called Golden
in honor of the God of the ancient
city of Cocodrilpolis.
For me no thanks.
I pluck the hair of the dog,
but not scale the crocodile.
Race ...
How is going with
its investigation
tragically this event, Mr.
Porridge?
Normally, as they say, Madam.
The crime of passion,
primitive instinct to kill,
as related to the
sexual instinct.
I feel compassion for the
poor alienated Jackie,
altered emotions,
Latin blood boiling
wanting revenge on who
would rob her man.
S, of course, but could
be someone else
with good reason too.
Quin?
You, Mrs. Otterbourne.
"Qu said?" Oh, your daughter
and you know
not defame the dead.
No longer have to pay the
claim for damages.
-S, but not kill for that. "No?
Another of those things golden.
Mrs Otterbourne ...
I see her looking in the living
room, among the windows
to that, as you say,
alienated poor Jackie,
disparndole Mr Doyle.
Yluego, when everyone left,
going to pick up the revlver
and AFTER going quietly to kill Ms.
Doyle.
No! My world is the love,
romance Pasinya,
not murder.
Now, Jem quiet.
If we bothered, both sorry.
Life can be so cruel!
It takes courage to face
the slander of life.
Bartender!
This croc lost its scales.
Qu woman so annoying!
Why not kill, I wonder?
Quiz algnda subscribers
libraries
together and hire a murderer.
Mrs. Van Schuyler is so stupid
he wants to play Hercule Poirot.
You know you have no evidence
that the rob her?
The pearl devolucin
not mean jams
mat not to steal them initially.
Pennington?
We tried to find the document
to sign on to Ms. Doyle.
Qu's this?
"Poirot." S?
Miss Jackie was not the unique
passenger traveling armed.
It was not that mat to Linnet.
Obviously not.
Qu mess!
T look better. Dime.
Qu hell is going on?
We check your private documents, Ser.
Is not it obvious?
They do qu?
Perhaps it Pars requisition in the affairs
of others, but we're not in Paris.
Brussels, Mr ...
I do not care if Borneo.
They have no right to be here.
We have every right.
While waiting for the Police,
the Compaa we handle
the investigation.
Do not have to do with
my documents.
They prove that, despite the marriage of Ms.
Doyle,
It still tried to control
your money.
Y qu?
There is no law that prohba.
The scam is against customers
and we do not like
to be infringed.
Yours? Quines?
The English lawyers of Ms.
Doyle.
We are not satisfied
with how do you
and his partner manage
their affairs.
"Vyasa to hell!" One moment.
"Everything is in perfect order."
I wish it were true.
But I think it came to
signing this power
and failed.
It was, then, the
Temple of Amun.
Climb to the top of
the pillar ms high.
All impuls a rock that cay
and, recently, the kills.
You can not blame that.
Get out of here!
Longer sufficient or trash.
Algnda hear more garbage from the
lips of a prosecutor public.
This is yours, I think.
Belgium.
Alistmonos for dinner.
J'ai faim''.''
"Poirot, you're a woman?
-''Femme''is a woman.
J'ai faim''.'' I have hambre.
I talk to that girl.
We meet in the dining
room, Colonel.
Ordname''''Morilles
them, please.
Morilles''I''? Morena!
How's it going, girl?
Mal, Mr Poirot.
I'm so ashamed.
His wife died y. ..
Now it's all yours again.
It's bad you want to return?
It still love him
and now I need more than ever.
Poirot Lord, may ...?
Can take you to see it?
Slo five minutes. Please!
I do not see why would not.
If he so wishes and the doctor
does not have objecin.
Ask.
Qu well!
Baj temperature.
Est well, Mr Poirot.
I have no objecin, if
the visit is short.
"Five minutes Maxim, s?"
Thank you, Doctor.
Seorita Jackie!
You can see it now.
Thanks!
"Hi, Jackie.-Simon.
Sorry about Linnet.
"Thanks." Simon, not the mat.
I swear.
No need to say.
What s.
Forgive me. Please.
Jackie.
Last night was crazy.
He could kill you.
With a gun ornament as sa?
Articles may be ...?
Volversa walk?
Do not be silly.
In Wadi Halfa sacarn me the
ball and look like new.
Remember, we only
five minutes, s?
Simon, I'm so sorry!
Quiet.
You do not have to apologize qu.
Qu's this?
Ped Morilles''dish.''
- And is that in your
qu pas?-Champion.
Sorry.
Cre we want an eel.
Slo have that.
"Order a new bottle." Why?
For the rest of the bottle
last night were fluffy.
-Mouldy?-S tenan grnulos.
It is normal sediment
Chateau Petrus wine.
"You want a drink?" No, thanks.
Stay here with your wine and I''with my whiskey.
"
Always''whiskey shots. "Wine ...
Qu strange!
Of course.
I can sit down?
Poirot, in my view it
all could do it.
All tenan a reason to do so.
It's incredible.
Absolutely.
Good night.
Good evening, Madam. Please ...
Come quickly.
Quickly.
"Bring Dr. Bessner.-S, Ser.
You know qu is it?
Money.
It looks like a piece of
thousand-franc note.
It must be blackmail.
Saba something the murderer
of Linnet Doyle.
Qu idiots we are!
The saba.
Qu said this afternoon?
''If it had not been
able to sleep,
''If he had been on deck
Quiz''had seen the murderer
entering or exiting the
cabin of Doyle Madam.''
That's what happened.
He saw the murderer.
And because of their greed,
now he is dead.
How does that help us?
An quin we do not know the mat.
No. That's not exactly true.
we were in the wrong
address, you and me.
We know almost everything
there is to know.
But what we think ...
seems incredible.
Impossible.
Assassinations.
Murder!
All the time killing.
Muri no more than an hour ago.
The beheaded.
With a thin knife.
Like this one.
Very interesting, Doctor.
Sure any of his absence?
Qu?
Then think I, Ludwig Bessner,
mat to this humble servant?
God mo!
Qu I have to do
sculpture with matters
of the lower classes?
It is well known that do not
suffer from neurosis,
slo of animal passions.
"Take the body to the
room fro.-S, Ser.
You think you know.
I confess that I
have no clarity.
Dr. Bessner told me what
happened with the maid.
I talk to you and Mr
Doyle immediately.
I do not enter.
Dr. Bessner est upset.
My good man, s.
But an angry Alemán not stop me.
Crame, s all.
Mr. Doyle, s quin mat
Louise Bourget.
Qu?
Who knows quin mat to Louise?
Quiet. Do not yell.
Mrs Otterbourne,
can not be here.
My patient rests.
It is vitally important.
It s all. Everything, Cramer!
Look, do not tolerate the elbow.
Mr. Doyle, I say that
I, Salom Otterbourne,
I have succeeded where
others have failed.
I'm even better than the great
detective Hercule Poirot.
Mrs Otterbourne, by God, clmese.
Now cuntenos the story
from the beginning.
"I refuse to speak to
l." Then do not talk.
Outside, now.
"The fever rises with
excitement." Doctor,
e are up more if
you have to say.
-Sr. Doyle. "It's about my wife!
S, est bien.
You can stay for three minutes.
Three minutes.
And you lower your voice, okay?
Qu woman!
Antiptico man.
I understand that has evidence mat quin Mrs.
Doyle?
You have understood and I have.
I guess I agree
that whoever mat Louise Bourget
Also mat to Linnet Doyle.
It is quite possible.
Well ...
I saw Louise Bourget quin mat
with my own eyes.
Please contine, Madam.
I was in the stern of the boat
talking to a crew member
I showed some fascinating
a Buffalo and a camel together
in a team, plowing the ground.
All I saw the light of the
moon, of course, Madam?
S, as it was.
I have a beautiful view.
Well, I walked away ...
And suddenly, when he went
down the corridor,
or cry.
Sali's cabin Louise Bourget.
Then I saw you open
the cabin door.
When the door opened ms
I saw it ..
The Pennington.
Or a loud bang.
Qu pas now?
Mrs Otterbourne shot.
-Sr. Pennington.-S?
Is your gun, I think.
Anyone could get it
out of the cabin.
Saban was ah.
Recently I have been told
revlver when I travel.
The killings must stop.
Unfortunately, I have
delayed a lot.
I would like to see everyone
in the living room,
where everything to be revealed
in a few ...
thirty minutes.
I can not believe it.
My mother died.
Why?
Debi discovered something.
By God! Poor thing!
He loved her, despite
everything.
And now it was.
I can not assimilate.
Suddenly qued ...
Sola.
No, it's ace.
I'll take care of.
Jim ...
Poor mother.
It will not have escaped
while alive.
Madam, seoritas, ladies ...
the game ends.
I, Hercule Poirot,
s now, without a shadow of doubt, quin mat to Ms.
Doyle,
Louise Bourget and Mrs.
Otterbourne.
Awkwardly, start the research
with the preconceived idea
Bean attended that
scene agresin,
between Miss Jackie
and Simon Doyle.
Bean that person got the gun
AFTER that all left
the salon Haban
and the bean used to kill Ms.
Doyle
and try to incriminate Ms.
Jackie.
As podrn see, no lack of
suspects among you.
May be someone who tried
to smear his mouth shut.
Or that he attributed his ruin to the father of Ms.
Doyle.
Or someone obsessed with
the idea of a robbery.
Or someone angry with the
heirs of fortunes.
Or someone with a firm Decision
to save his mother
from financial ruin.
Or even
someone eager to avoid the penalty
as curator fraudulent.
Or someone who mistook the
identity of the victim.
And then ...
record is very important.
That night we slept soundly,
not lightly, as is my custom.
Why?
Because my wine is drugged bean
someone who does not
want to be present
in the events of the night.
Quite easy.
Opened bottles left
on the tables.
T, Colonel,
return the bottle saying,
using your own words,
he was''rusty.''
This, s,
implies premeditacin by someone.
It means that yesterday
before 7:30, the crime had
already been decided.
Haba something that confused
me from the beginning.
If the intention was to
blame for Miss Jackie,
Why was not the gun in the bedroom of Mrs.
Doyle?
And then entend.
The murderer bean removed the weapon because l.
..
or she had to withdraw.
haba No other reason.
And some more beans.
Dr. Bessner,
you examined the body of Ms.
Doyle.
S.
Remember the scorched
around the wound.
The revlver was very close
to his head when shot.
That's right.
But when we recovered the
weapon of the Nile
This scarf was wrapped
in brocade.
Obviously, tan shot atravesndola
presumably to muffle the
noise of the shot.
Doctor Bessner,
if it had been fired from
among the stole,
there were charred temple of Ms.
Doyle.
That is, the shot that could
not shoot the mat
among the stole.
So maybe it was the other.
Jackie Bellefort who
shoots Simon Doyle.
Jackie!
But tenamos witness.
Sabamos as it was not.
Therefore, there was
a third shot.
In one we know nothing.
However,
slo revlver had two bullets.
The following curious
circumstance
this happened in the cabin of Mrs.
Doyle.
Ah found two bottles
of nail nails.
One bottle was marked "Rosa"
but the few drops that were ah
were not pink, but red.
And instead of the usual
smell of enamel,
vinegar.
Friends, it was red ink
tena inevitable that
a wired connection
this hanky could find
together with the revlver
wrapped in a stole.
The ink out of fabric fcilmente
leaving a pink stain PLIDA.
Then something happened
need to rinse off,
leaving no doubt.
Louise Bourget was killed
because blackmailing
the murderer.
We know this does not only by the
fragment of thousand-franc
we find between your
fingers dead
but Also curious for words said
this morning.
Naturally,
if you could not sleep ...
Of course, if you
could not sleep,
if it had been on the cover,
Perhaps it would have
been the murderer
entering or exiting the
cabin of the Lord.
Qu, exactly, that we deca?
Qu, exactly, she told us ...
with that?
S he stayed on deck
was the murderer.
S. But still you do not understand
qu I mean, Colonel.
Why do we say that to us?
As a key?
As a key, of course,
but for us qu?
Quin know the murderer.
You can do one of two things:
decrnoslo or shut up
to demand money to the
person involved.
But it does neither.
Use the conditional
tense, please.
Had I been ...''''
Slo may mean that was a key
but it was a key
to the murderer.
In other words, was present
at the time.
But, on top of you and m,
slo else was present.
Precisely. Simon Doyle.
Qu?
S.
The Doctor always accompanied him.
She tena to talk.
-Quiz tenams no option.
"Do not be so ridiculous.
I do not think that is ridiculous.
I remember his response.
Protect you''.''
''No one accuses you
of anything.''
Exactly the security that it we want y.
..
he obtained.
Lord P. ..
This time he made the
ridiculous, no doubt.
I have witnesses to prove that
I could not kill Linnet.
S that has
but it s the mat
and saw Louise Bourget.
Qu nonsense! I say, Mr. Doyle
pruning does not move
with a broken leg.
He testified before any
court in the world.
And I have to say that his testimony is ...
irrelevant.
lrrelevante?
l-Pierre-le-te-van.
I?
I have witnessed
sicolgicos where more complex
of the century.
My testimony alone had
saved Strutzrumple ...
The murderer of Dresden,
the execution.
Quiet.
Slo say it is irrelevant
because he began to meet Mr.
Doyle
five minutes AFTER he was shot.
He could not move during
those five minutes.
True, if you already triggered Haban.
But it was ace?
Note the bean is actually seen.
Ms. Jacqueline Rosalie saw fire.
Doyle saw fall to the floor.
Yluego went out to seek help,
met with Ferguson,
that habaodo shooting.
Doyle saw lslo pressing
a red hanky in his leg.
Doyle figured that
he shot Haban,
but the presumption was wrong.
The bullet is not enough to Doyle.
Was elsewhere.
Qu Yahor happens?
Jackie Doyle insists that
the bear to his cabin
and not be left alone.
Ms. Murray and Mr. Ferguson's
accompanied to the cabin.
AFTER,
Ms. Rosalie seeks
to Miss Bowers.
Andall the attention focuses
on the starboard side.
Ms. Bowers!
Doyle slo needs two minutes.
He takes off his shoes.
Collect revlver from
under the sofa,
Jackie bot where
to find him not,
runs like a hare
by the port roof
and enters the cabin
of his wife.
Then take the shawl of Mrs.
Van Schuyler
that hidden bean, wrap the gun
to dampen noise and
prevent scorching,
fires a bullet into his own leg.
Remove one of the
cartridges used,
to dispose of,
and introduces a new
indicating whether
the revlver is,
slo that two bullets were fired.
Wrap again stole the gun,
Add the stained hanky
and an ashtray mrmol for
everything collapses,
and throws the package out
the window, the Nile
You lie on the sofa
pressing the wound with
another hanky,
this time in real agony.
Extraordinary, is not as?
Impossible.
I can hardly believe it.
S. Of course, absolutely
impossible.
Why do you ask?
T odo said yourself
beans gentle steps.
Why someone will run?
The s, but do all
of that impulse?
Once and for all, Sir,
was not impulsive,
was carefully planned.
By Doyle?
Slo Doyle plays a role.
For his accomplices,
Ms. Jacqueline de Bellefort.
You must be crazy.
No, I'm not crazy.
It's true.
Quin Doyle gave an alibi?
You, by firing a shot.
And quin gave you his alibi?
Doyle,
insisting that accompanied
all night.
Not true! It is not!
S is true. To deny qu?
You and Doyle were lovers.
It still are lovers.
The plan was that Simon
killed his wife,
inherit the money, and
then at a later date
to marry his old flame.
A brilliant concept.
His persecution of Ms. Doyle,
simulated wrath of Simon,
the choice of Miss Rosalie
as a witness,
the whole development
up to the crime,
the exaggerated hysteria ...
Actually, they are merely
taking a risk:
tena Simon wound to disable it.
And disclpeme, but for m
s there was a nonsense.
The writing was nonsense
the''J''in the wall
of the cabin.
Something to melodramtico
that tena
to exonerate you.
And quin will want to
do that except ...
one accomplices?
But then ...
The plan began to unravel,
as it is?
Louise Bourget est unveiled.
Doyle sees run to the
cabin of his wife.
Hey shot
and sees him return
to the salon.
It offers the silence
in exchange for money
and in doing so, he signed
his own death.
Mr. Doyle could not kill, because
it could not move.
I swear. And to be right.
Miss Jackie the mat.
No!
S. I fear that there
is no doubt.
Just before dinner, I asked to see Mr.
Doyle.
Foolishly, s now accepts and
brings them together.
The one apparently remorseful
and upset,
and the other encouraging.
Simon, I'm so sorry.
Easy.
I am sure that when we
the tone changes.
All is well, Vicar.
It almost succeeded.
Think so. Louise knows.
I saw. Try and blackmail.
You'll have to stop it.
"We can not pay?" All my life?
Jackie, ESTs safe?
Give me money.
"To qu?" I hope so.
The distracting.
"On est Where to?" In my jacket.
In the closet.
"I love you." I s.
Are we crazy?
No s, but we can not stop.
Jackie ...
Desam luck.
Unfortunately, in their haste
Forgot leaves a fragment
of a thousand-franc note
between the fingers
of the dead woman.
But it is an unfortunate ms:
Mrs Otterbourne seen
leaving the cabin.
She does not realize
and returns to the cabin of Dr.
Bessner
to return the scalpel.
Then, ready for dinner, somewhat
flustered and agitated,
quickly reaches the dining room.
As for Mrs. Otterbourne,
when Dr.
Bessner him of the
murder of Louise,
realizes that the killer was
alejndose the crime scene.
Qu?
He says he knows quin
mat to Louise?
Quiet. Do not yell.
Mrs Otterbourne, can not be here.
What prohbo.
It seemed strange
that Mr.
Doyle was shouting at
Mrs Otterbourne.
S now that what was to
warn Jackie Háqqah
in the cabin next door.
Mrs Otterbourne, by God, clmese.
Now cuntenos the story
from the beginning.
Qu Ypor from the beginning
and the whole story?
To give time for Jackie to act
which he did immediately.
Mr. Doyle.!
It is the murderer of my wife.!
Mr. Pennington?
Boasted that his father
taught to fire bean.
And its not in vain boast.
I saw that was ...
Solt the revlver and ran
to his cabin next door.
It was very risky,
but it was her only option.
My friends ...
that's all.
Congratulations, Mr. P.,
-For a fun Teor.
"It's more than a theor.
Unfortunately,
is the truth.
Y qu pas with the first bullet?
The Jackie dispar me?
Good question, s.
They see all this table?
It has a bullet piercing
recently here.
You had time to take the bullet
and throw into the Nile
-Qu nonsense! "It is nonsense.
We have evidence that
the three bullets
are the weapon of
Miss Jacqueline.
Suppose that.
How to prove that Simon
mixed the other two?
Right.
No evidence.
Absolutely no proof.
The find, easy. No escape.
No?
Not convince a jury
without evidence.
And Where to go to get them out, Mr.
P.?
In Linnet?
No. Not Linnet.
You.
Qu mean?
Brag, Simon.
Far from boasting,
is a simple test
now accepted as evidence in
any court in the world.
It is called the
test''Moulage.''
The''test''Moulage?
S,''''Moulage.
When shooting a gun
remain in the skin plvora grains
that can be removed
with a thin layer of wax.
sa is the''test''Moulage.
Colonel, you do it?
When you say.
Guess who is willing to
submit to the test?
It does not hurt, we only
feel something ...
heat.
Jackie, qu ...?
What can we do?
Nothing.
All over.
Do not worry so much, Mr.
For m, I mean.
S cares, right? A little?
S.
Simon And do not judge too hard.
He never had money and Linnet
dazzled him with their wealth.
Simon, remember what you said?
I said if it were a story,
Linnet marry me, she moriray
I inherited everything.
It was when I knew I
conceived the idea.
I was terrified.
Saba to try something
perfectly absurd.
He even had the idea of putting
the cobra in his bed.
And you will find another use
for the snake, seorita.
I'm glad I had not killed, Ser.
Honestly.
So ...
like watching ...
tena to help him.
I've always had to help.
Jackie, I love you.
I love you, you.
Detnganse!
Poirot Lord.
Qu tragedy!
A esplndido work, Poirot,
I must say.
Could not have done the
test''Montage.''
I have no wax.
Amaze me, Colonel.
"Totally amaze me.
Adis, Mr Poirot.
I fear that the description
of their cases have to wait
until another time.
Lstima Qu, Madam!
He longed to tell you
my recent experience
on the Orient Express.
Come, Bowers. It's time to go.
This place starts to
look like a morgue.
Thank God, be in one soon.
"Old fossils." Qu
genius, Bowers!
Need a refreshing holiday.
I thought a trip to
the Gobi Desert.
Mr. Poirot, I want to
be the first to know.
We have just engaged.
Congratulations, seorita.
Lord ...
"Congratulations.
And good luck. "Thanks.
-Adis, Mr. Poirot. "Adis, Ser.
Colonel Race. "Good luck.
My little ones!
A tip ...
As they say in America:
Calmly''.''
We'll try.
In qu think?
I thought Moliro.
Eyelet were talking
sb known language.
Ambicin''The great women
is to inspire love.''