Watch and Download App at official site FastDrama.Co to support us
(Hate to Love You)
You're here.
Yes.
I'm here to meet a friend.
A friend?
Like you said,
let's become good companions.
We'll be good friends.
I'm sure of it.
That's why I'm saying this,
but there's someplace you should go with me.
Where is that?
I'd like to show you...
what kind of person I am.
If your feelings remain the same,
let's really become friends.
Taxi, taxi.
Haeng Ja? Haeng Ja...
Here you go.
She never takes taxis.
And who is that man?
Bo Geum, Bo Geum.
What is so urgent?
I just saw Haeng Ja take a taxi somewhere.
It was her, right? It wasn't someone else, was it?
You're right, it was her. She just left.
Who is the man that was with her?
Oh, that man.
Who is it?
She recently made a new friend.
That's all you have to know.
A friend?
A boyfriend?
That word makes it feel so real.
A boyfriend.
Wait.
What are we doing here?
This building belongs to me.
Even this?
Oh, this.
I see.
Why are you showing this to me?
I grew up at the market all my life.
I'm tougher, wilder and rougher...
than you probably think I am.
Do you think I wanted to be friends without knowing that?
If you approached me because you need money,
you can tell me now.
If I needed money, I would've continued being your tutor.
I thought you enjoyed...
spending time with me.
I must've been wrong.
No, you aren't.
As we get older,
it's hard to believe others.
I'm sure it's worse for you, since you've met all kinds of people.
I understand, but am disappointed.
I'm sorry.
Living alone, things like this...
has caused me problems.
I wasn't suspicious of you.
We promised to be good companions.
Yes, let's give it a try.
Let's enjoy the comfort we have as we get older.
She practically has me in the palm of her hand.
I knew she wouldn't be easy,
but I'll have to stay alert.
I wonder how much money she actually has.
More buildings are showing up every day,
although I'm not complaining.
Here you go.
Over here.
You're late.
I'm sorry. Something came up on my way here.
I'll treat you to anything you want, since I was late.
Really?
You're embarrassing me.
Stop staring at me, and eat. The food is good here.
I'll tell you about the nourishing cream after we eat.
Choong Seo.
Sitting here with you reminds me of old times.
Old times?
As time goes by, I keep thinking of when we first met.
I had forgotten about it.
Really? I remember every detail.
What do you remember the most?
Actually, it's a secret.
What is it?
I was...
interested in you when you were 20 years old.
Really?
A rich girl came to the theater every day,
saying she'd help, but only caused more trouble.
I got in so much trouble with my mom.
I barely lifted a finger at home.
I was waiting one day with a fluttering heart,
but she didn't show up.
I never saw you again after that day.
When was that?
I don't remember.
I heard rumors that you got married to a rich guy.
I think that was...
my first love,
that caused me pain before passing.
First love?
You're late.
Yes, I'm sorry.
Please don't say anything today.
What is it? Did the person you visited at the hospital die?
The hospital?
Oh, right. The hospital...
Were you really visiting someone?
You look like someone who was on a date.
I bumped into a man I used to know.
By chance?
You're saying you met the man you kept talking about by chance?
Why would you lie when you'll get caught right away?
I shouldn't tell you anything.
Did things end as soon as you met him? What's with the face?
No.
He told me I was his first love.
Really?
Why are you sighing when that's a good thing?
I feel weird.
I realized there was a time in my life like that, and I miss it,
but I don't want to go back.
Why not? Did something happen between you two?
No, it's not because of that.
It's about the difficult 30 years that followed.
I can't go through that again.
Gosh.
Who was your first love?
First love?
Wait, is it In Woo's dad?
Seriously?
You were so innocent.
I had fallen hard.
He must've been a good person back then.
Of course, he was the pride of the town.
I eloped with him in the middle of the night, so I wouldn't...
Wait a second. What am I saying?
Your life would be nothing compared to my ups and downs.
You ran away with him?
You were always a drama queen.
I wasn't normal.
Do you think you could run away like that again?
Why not, if I meet the right person?
I feel the same.
- Please enjoy. - Thank you.
You said you skipped lunch too.
Would this be enough for you?
I have to live like this for a while.
Don't look at me like that. It's not as bad as it seems.
You said you have something to tell me.
Have you ever thought about your mother's remarriage?
Is my mother getting married again?
Who is the man this time?
Well...
Bu Sik.
Sorry. I overreacted.
There's no point of hiding anything from you.
You saw how my mother caused trouble because of men as you grew up.
I asked you about that because of my dad.
It looks like he has found someone to marry.
Does that make you worry?
My father never listens to other people.
He'll get remarried if he has made up his mind.
Then what's the problem?
I don't want him to get remarried.
However, I don't want him to continue living like a nomad either.
Do you want him to get back together with your mother?
That's impossible.
In Jung would say she will leave home immediately,
and I would feel uncomfortable too.
I don't know what this feeling is.
I think both of us are selfish children.
Our parents were the ones who were selfish first.
That's true, but...
- Why? - It's just that...
I didn't expect to hear you saying such a thing.
You're right.
Our parents were selfish first.
Let's eat.
- Oh, my. Is it stuck there? - Hang on.
I thought Mi Ae's son was dating Haeng Ja's daughter.
But he's with Jung Sook's eldest daughter this time.
Did Mi Ae go somewhere?
Mi Ae has been busy lately.
Gosh. I bet she's not as busy as her son.
Bu Sik?
I'm sure he's busy as well.
He must be busy dating Haeng Ja's daughter.
Wasn't Mi Ae's son dating Haeng Ja's daughter?
I don't care. Why do you ask?
I saw Mi Ae's son eating ramyeon with your eldest daughter.
- With In Woo? - Yes.
They looked quite intimate.
They've known each other for over 10 years.
There's nothing weird about it.
My goodness. A man with a girlfriend would eat with his girlfriend.
Why would he eat with his friend?
You should be relieved that I'm the one who saw them.
Our neighbors like gossiping one another.
If a rumor starts, it would be bad for your daughter.
Bu Sik. Bu Sik.
Yes? I ate dinner.
Did you eat ramyeon with In Woo at a cart bar?
- How did you know that? - You two lived here for 10 years.
Everyone knows you guys. Are you going to keep meeting her like that?
She said she had something to discuss. It wasn't a date.
I see. So In Woo changed her strategy.
I said it wasn't like that.
Don't be so naive.
There's a rumor about you already.
They say that my son is dating two women at the same time.
That's ridiculous.
That's what people always do.
People will always spread rumors...
about someone's wrongdoings and failures.
I've been worried since you said marriage can be a good opportunity.
Those who say such things always settle with someone they love.
You should be careful too.
In Woo isn't a person like that.
They say that you can never see through a person's mind.
Isn't In Woo a person?
I'll be careful.
By the way, how close have you gotten to Eun Jo?
We're getting along well.
I think you're considering marrying her as well.
You have to be aggressive to win a woman's heart.
Speaking of which, hurry up, and get married.
If you drag it on, you may ruin the whole thing.
Marrying her?
- I'm home. - Come in for a second.
Why? I'm tired.
Oh, right. I ate dinner.
With whom?
Would you even know the person?
Tell me whatever you have to say. I'll go to sleep now.
You seem to be in a good mood.
Why would I be in a bad mood?
You cried your heart out because you were dumped just a few days ago.
Who said that I got dumped?
Pull yourself together.
Everyone knows that Bu Sik is interested in someone else.
He's only being fooled by a sly wench for now.
When he comes to his senses, he might come back to me.
My goodness. What did you say?
If you're finished, I'll leave. I'm so tired.
Why is she so stubborn?
What if Bu Sik ends up with someone else?
What would she do then?
Hey. Did you just come home?
- Yes. - Come, and sit down here.
Myung Jo.
Why? Do you have something to tell us?
Why?
Well, I have something to say to both of you.
Well... The thing is...
Gosh. I don't know where to start.
Why is it so difficult to say?
Not too long ago,
I met a lecturer at the culture center.
Since he has a vast knowledge of things,
I started taking a class with him.
As you know, I haven't had much education.
You two will find a match for you soon,
and I'll have in-laws.
Just get to the point already.
So what's your point?
Are you going to enroll in a school?
Go on.
I can't go back to school at my age.
So...
What I'm saying is that I decided to...
become good friends with the lecturer.
Friends?
I'll introduce him to you two when it's the right time.
We're friends who can talk to each other while growing old together.
That kind of friend. Just friends. Do you understand?
So that means that she has a boyfriend, right?
Did you see him?
She said she'll introduce him to us soon.
A man can be better judge of other men.
He's too old to be called a man.
You don't like this situation, do you?
Are you happy about this?
I told you before...
that I wouldn't mind her getting married if he's a good person.
She said they're just friends. Why would you talk about marriage?
You never know what could happen.
Don't get ahead of yourself.
- Eun Jo. - I want to be alone.
I understand.
She could get married?
Haeng Ja will do that?
You seem more tenacious than I thought.
What else should I do?
Come with me.
Gosh. I didn't mean that. More work?
You did a good job today.
I wish I could drink with you, but I'm busy.
Drink this before you go home.
It will help with your tiredness.
Actually...
See you tomorrow, Suk.
What was that?
Are you drinking alone?
That's good.
I've been feeling down. Let's drink together.
Excuse me. Give me a glass a pair of chopsticks, please.
No, no. This is not what it looks like.
It's okay.
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
You don't mind if I join you, right?
- Let's drink. - Okay.
One shot should be okay, right?
I hope I made the right decision.
I can quit any time if it doesn't seem right.
I've been fine all these years.
Eun Jo, Haeng Ja.
Why is he calling us?
What is going on?
Wait.
Isn't this the young man that works at the beauty center?
Hong Suk?
What happened?
- Haeng Ja, my room. - All right, come this way.
Gosh, what in the world happened?
Did he drink?
What?
I thought you were sleeping. When did you go out, drink...
and bring another person home?
I was having trouble sleeping,
so I went to a tent bar for a drink and ran into him.
My goodness.
How much did he drink?
He passed out after taking a sip.
That doesn't make sense.
I can't believe that even if you say it, Myung Jo.
- I'm sure he's right. - What?
But you shouldn't have brought him here.
Eun Jo, what kind of person is he?
He only has three numbers on his phone.
Aunt, Mr. Lee, and yours.
No one was answering,
so I had no choice but to bring him.
It's cold.
You did the right thing, since it's cold outside.
However, I can't believe he can't drink any more than a sip.
Do you know anything about him?
He shouldn't be drinking.
Maybe I should've answered the phone properly.
He said it's Hong Suk, the employee at the beauty center.
What if you answered and his identity got revealed?
How are you going to deal with that?
Still, you shouldn't have hung up without knowing the situation.
It's okay, I got a feeling.
Nothing will happen.
And remember what happened at the club. It's nothing new.
How could you be so confident?
Do you think he'd leave Suk Pyo in the streets...
after calling us?
He'd at least call the police.
It's nothing to worry about, so go to bed.
This is why I should track his location.
I don't believe this.
These two nuisances.
Suk Pyo has been acting weird nowadays.
Come on out and have breakfast.
Why are you standing there?
Have something to help with your hangover,
although I'm not sure if you have a hangover.
I'm sorry.
Why do you always apologize when you're here?
Don't be a stranger. You can make yourself at home.
I heard you did a part-time job with Eun Jo.
You can think of this as a co-worker's home.
Why aren't you sitting down?
Have a seat.
I like having more people at home.
Stop over-reacting. It's just one more person.
I don't remember the last time I had breakfast with you two.
You're always too busy,
and I barely see you.
You must've been lonely.
Is that why...
Don't you have to call your family?
They must be worried.
No one will answer, even if I called right now.
Don't worry. He's all grown up.
Eat up.
Haeng Ja is known for her food at the market.
Thank you.
You can come over whenever you want a home-cooked meal.
People need to eat well to survive.
A young man like you shouldn't rely on instant food like ramyeon.
Okay.
- Haeng Ja. - Yes?
You haven't been collecting money. What business are you starting?
Finish up, and go to school. Aren't you late?
No, I'm fine.
Are you learning the business you've been telling us about?
- I'll support... - Haeng Ja.
Who cares? I'm sure he knows who I am now.
- Right? - Of course.
Eat up.
You need to be on a full stomach to be less sad.
It's like I have another son, and it feels good.
All right. Goodbye.
Why? Is someone else in the hospital?
You know what's going on.
You said you'd give me a break for now.
I did? When did I say that?
I'm going to try to make it work this time.
It sounds like you're determined to get married.
Why not?
You want to get dragged through mud again?
If you get married again,
- it'll be your fourth, right? - Come on.
Don't say that.
I married Bu Sik's dad for money...
and the second one...
I met during my darkest time and thought it'd be better.
The third one was a total swindler.
Don't you feel bad for Bu Sik?
That's why I'm going for a better person this time.
I've known him for a long time, so there's nothing to lie about.
You haven't seen him for a while.
That's a dangerous thought.
You said you're meeting a man too.
It's just for fun.
I have no intention of getting married.
Yesterday, you said you could run away if you met the right man.
Why are you changing your words?
Did you take that seriously?
Are you being fickle?
Never mind about me.
I hope it works out if that's how you feel.
The second time is hard, but it's the same after that.
Don't be so confident.
Who knows? Maybe you'll get married before I do.
I'm leaving.
What is she talking about?
Me, get married to him?
No, that won't work out.
Wait, if she's even thinking of marrying him...
I'll have to see who this man is.
(Dia Pawnshop)
You're going to sell the building?
Yes, there is an old three-story building behind a school.
It's only caused me trouble since the day I bought it.
I'm not getting much rent out of it,
so I'm willing to sell it at a low price.
I see.
I'm considering asking you to take the job.
Would you give it a try?
It's full or units that are mortgaged.
It's very complicated.
I'll do it.
All right, thank you.
I think you'll do a good job.
Thank you.
All right, that's settled.
What are you going to do about Eun Jo?
Excuse me?
Everyone in the neighborhood knows you're seeing each other.
Well...
I'd like to marry her.
Ms. Kim.
Mother, I should've asked for your blessing first and I'm sorry.
Mother?
Could I call you that?
You already did.
Seeing that Eun Jo is dating him without a complaint,
she must be interested.
Goodbye.
- You can go in. - Okay.
Hi, what brings you here?
Hi, Ms. Kim.
This is a VIP ticket for the beauty center.
Mr. Hong sent it over.
VI... What?
This is a magic ticket you can use on anything at the center,
including hair, makeup, massages and clothes.
- Right? - That's absolutely right.
Why would he send this to me?
I'm sure it isn't free.
I heard you're starting a new business.
He told me you'd understand if I said this.
You're young, but smart.
Please visit the center whenever you can...
and come to me when you need to discuss your business.
- Have a nice day. - Bye.
Eun Jo is so lucky.
- Why? - You'll probably give this to her.
Why would I give it to her? I'm going to use it myself.
You are?
I'm a woman too, you know.
I'm going to get facials from now on...
and take care of myself.
She was a woman.
You're going to do what?
A facial.
I heard men get all kinds of treatment nowadays.
My face is getting dry from the cold weather.
I think I need to do something about it.
Then, pay for the facials.
I know, but the thing is...
Is money the problem?
Don't you get a staff discount?
Wait, no. You're a certified facial therapist.
Can't you do it for me for free?
Who brought what?
Ms. Kim Haeng Ja brought a VIP ticket for the beauty center.
Is that so?
Then you serve her yourself. Pay extra attention to her,
and provide her with the best service.
Yes, I will. Beauty, beauty.
Could she be interested in the beauty business?
Hang on.
We have to get on her good side before other companies do.
What should I do?
If we could drag her into our business...
That would be incredible.
Please lie down here.
- Lie down here? - Yes.
Please take off your robe first.
I'm not wearing anything under this.
It must be your first time getting a facial.
No one can do well at the first try.
Do men get facials here as well?
Of course.
That's embarrassing. Why would a man do that?
Do something about him.
I'm uncomfortable because it's as if I'm with a man in the same room.
Gosh. I'm trying all sorts of things thanks to Mr. Jung.
Wake up. I said, "Wake up."
Move to the next room.
She's treating her customer badly.
They said they provide the best service, but that wasn't true.
Why would she wake me up while I was having a good time?
What room should I go to?
- Please wait for a moment. - Okay.
My goodness.
What is Ms. Kim doing here?
Seriously.
Gosh. I got startled.
Mr... Mr. Jung.
Ms. Kim, you're here as well.
(Vocational Training Institute)
A penny for your thoughts, Mr. Jung.
I'm sorry.
All the customers left earlier.
- I see. - Check this out.
- Our mailbox was full of letters. - Let me see.
- We received a lot this time. - Exactly.
My gosh. What's this smell, madam?
- Oh, no. I left stew on the stove. - Not again.
She might burn the whole cafe down.
Look at this.
Do people still send handwritten letters like this?
"Dear Ms. Kim Haeng Ja, our sponsor."
"Our sponsor"?
What should I do?
- Should I pour water in here? - What's this smell?
I have to take care of this first, Ms. Kim.
Hello, Ms. Kim.
Your skin is glowing.
You look great yourself as well.
I wanted to impress you.
Oh, right. Is the foot you hurt earlier okay?
That was nothing.
- Shall I show you? - No. That's okay.
You might break your bone.
I mean, you could hurt your foot.
Please speak as you always do.
Your primitive expressions sound charming to me.
You're teasing me, right, Mr. Jung?
You're right.
Please don't do that again.
I was surprised.
Your skin looks stunning.
- Do I look okay? - You look great.