A Dariusz Jab³oñski film
Based on the book
STRAWBERRY WINE
Where's the police station?
What do you need
the station for?
He's only had a few.
I'm going to the police station.
Him you can keep.
It's like this, Lubica,
the womenfolk are complaining...
This better be the last time:
If you've got the itch to lead
your neighbor into temptation,
then do it in private.
Right then.
Get out of here and be good.
Distinctions, awards...
So what's the deal?
Honestly now:
Who sent you?
Regional command?
HQ maybe?
- Personal reasons, sergeant.
- But here?
In the middle of nowhere:?
I wanted a job as far away
from the capital as possible.
Well this is about
as far as it gets.
I applied for staff because
I'm due for retirement next year.
But from the capital???
Things are a bit different around here,
but you'll get the hang of it soon.
Now to find you
something to do...
Area's pretty big,
but sparsely populated though.
You'll see for yourself tomorrow.
You'll take the company...
bicycle.
In the morning you'll go and patrol
state property undergoing liquidation.
Right here.
We'll quarter you
at citizen Lewandowski's.
Used to live there myself.
What're you staring at?
Ain't nothing wrong with her.
How do you know?
I can see.
Want me to carve 'er up for you,
Wasylczuk?
I'll carve 'er up myself.
Don't like killing 'em is all.
I do. Main thing's for the critter
not to get scared.
Bad job spoils the meat.
Reeks of fear...
Stay away from my woman.
My woman doesn't need any help.
You were away a long time.
She said she did.
No.
You better get married,
Semen,
rather than helping out
folks all over the village.
Playing matchmaker?
I hide them if I don't know
who's coming.
That'll do.
Pass me a towel.
- Do you want some food?
- No. Have to work on the cart.
- Tomorrow. Get some rest.
- I'm heading off tomorrow.
- You just got back.
- I'm going to work.
What do you see in those woods?
God,
you live like a wolf.
What is there to see here?
Got anything special to show me?
You used to be different...
That's what you think.
I'm the way I always was:
I'm off tomorrow.
He'd better not come here.
Leave him out of this.
He's a good man.
Tell him to take his goodness
somewhere else.
Done.
This'll fix anything.
So long as it's rubber.
Inner tubes, galoshes,
padded boots.
Those were the days when
the state farms were still around.
State farm here, one over in Ni¿na,
one up in Mosczaniec...
...ten tractors in every farm,
four wheels on every tractor,
trailers, too...
Menfolk, womenfolk, kids...
...each of 'em with two legs,
galoshes on both,
not counting spares.
Now it's just farmers
and poor folk.
Patch 'em up themselves.
Sell me some cigarettes?
Not yet...
Someday.
No, thanks.
No need to thank me.
Wine's like wine.
Used to make 'em better though.
Three bottles and you were gone.
This just makes you want to piss.
"Strawberry Wine".
That's Pop.
No... that's Ma,
and that's Pop,
and that's me.
Got sent down here in '77.
Doing four years costs you no tears,
and leaves no smears.
I herded cows, fired bricks,
dug ditches, chopped trees.
- For what?
- My belief.
I believed they wouldn't nick me.
Then I got out and it
was more of the same:
Timber, animals, ditches...
Is it bad here?
Worse than anywhere else?
That's Olena.
Ruthenian girl.
We got married
in an Orthodox church.
This house...
for the two of us.
Six years ago...
That bar at 10,
Grochowska street, Warsaw
it still exist?
Now have you ever seen a police station
closed during the day?
Bless you my son:
You must be the new one.
Just like your boss.
Two weeks now and
I still haven't seen you in church.
I don't go.
I don't believe in God.
Not much at any rate.
Never mind.
Views don't have to stop
you coming to Mass.
Though your boss still has
the same views
he had under communism.
They won't let him enter a church.
He's never been...
I...
might come one of these days.
Nothing more I can do here.
Secular authority
should not be seen fraternizing
with spiritual authority.
That's the way it's always been,
and it's for the better.
- Surely not always?
- You might think not, but it has.
A man has to know whom to listen to
in different sides of life.
But the police is getting along well
with the Church now, isn't it?
Prayer doesn't improve
the clear-up rate any.
The times we had back then,
my boy:
Politics is a clash of ideas...
You wouldn't understand today.
Seventeen years waiting
for a crown.
Well?
It's sort of...
Come quick:
What are you waiting for?
Hop on:
Stop:
To the bar: : :
I'm telling you: Stop:
What are you doing?
Stop:
You will be mine: : :
Come on:
Where are you going? :
Turn it off, you f...
I'm telling you, turn it off:
Let it go:
Shit:
Doesn't count. You were supposed
to drive up to the counter.
But don't worry.
You'll make it next time, Janek.
Going to take my clothes?
Back home in Slovakia
when I was a girl
the boys would play that game.
Everybody went down
to the river to bathe
and hid everyone else's clothes.
Girls would take the boys' clothes, either.
They don't anymore?
There's no boys or girls left.
Either they've moved to the city
or they're just born old.
I'm cold.
Turn around.
Ready.
What are you doing?
Promoting you to general...
...so you won't be afraid
of anything.
I'm not even a constable.
Are you married?
No.
Not any more.
Can you still tell?
Do you miss her?
No.
Not her.
Just...
my daughter.
Where is she?
She's gone.
I don't stand a chance,
do I?
It's dry.
I like it better when it's wet.
Well it's not anymore.
Tough job with her.
She's not from around here.
I know that much.
Where is she from?
Thereabouts.
At the back of beyond.
Slovakia.
Her mother died,
she ran away
and came here
to look for her father,
a Pole who was supposed to have spent
one night at her mother's place.
She's not happy here either.
One guy tried to hang
himself because of her
and you saw what Janek did.
They'll book him for sure.
Did she find her father?
Maybe she did
and maybe she didn't.
How come you're out here?
Player doesn't work.
Head's busted.
Neat, huh?
Neat.
No sweat.
It's American.
Quick-drying.
How 'bout you, you know,
get around to him a bit
the way you do.
It's always good to know
what's going down.
You're a real pig,
you know that?
Pig or no pig...
Hurry up or we'll be late.
I have to change.
Waste of fuel, buddy.
Well?
All quiet?
There was a scuffle
but I calmed them down.
Took this away from them.
They wanted to cut up the tables.
We're smoking here,
but we're actually exhaling thataway.
Join us, won't you?
Mix it with soda
and no one'll know.
No thanks.
Some other time.
It didn't hurt him none.
Wasylczuk.
If I'd just sat down for a while
in the bar...
Then you'd have stayed there.
When he gets something in
his head there's no stopping
him no matter what.
Koœciejny sure is something.
They don't make 'em
like that anymore.
There was nothing
you could have done.
But if I hadn't stepped outside...
If you think
he'd have let a uniform stop him
you're too dumb to even be a cop.
GREAT OPENING
Hoosteller please.
I beg your pardon?
Cigarettes.
Carry on? :
Keep it up:
See.
Soon as you come here
this tragedy happens.
Screwed up our figures.
Lucky it's not just the crime
rate that went up.
The clear-up rate followed suit.
One could say you apprehended
the culprit red-handed.
That counts for something.
I didn't apprehend him.
He turned himself in.
Doesn't matter.
Main thing is you were on the scene.
Irka:
Turn them frogs off:
They are Italians, Edek.
That's what I said.
Turn it off
and play something in English.
What's the difference?
Might be all the same to you.
It isn't to me.
When I was in da hood in Noo Yawk,
we had this def gig...
The Man sent a homey down
in a chine and we cruised up
Park into the Upper West Side
where we hogged mainlines...
What's a mainline?
Cause you've always been
a great one for hogging.
A mainline...
is a mainline.
Five bucks a yard.
Don't they have excavators
over there?
Sure. But that was specialized
hazardous hogging.
So Zalatywój,
how's business?
What exactly is hogging?
Ask him.
I've never been much for English.
What is it? :
Ditches, shovels, digging:
...and pigs will fly.
Buy me a wine, will you.
It's pointless.
Don't even pay for fuel.
Delivered three pairs today,
got two to fix up...
Yo:
Zalatywój:
I asked you
how's business:
Yo:
Zalatywój...
you Gypsy mutha...
- I'll pass by Dukla.
- You do that.
- What time do you get off?
- In the evening. Then I'm out of here.
He was supposed to take you
away from all this.
He did.
Took me to Dukla.
What do you want?
I thought
you wanted more than that.
Shouldn't have missed
your chance.
- Meet me down by the river tonight.
- I'm a married woman now, Andrzej.
Winter here always like this?
Not by a long shot.
Just off to a slow start this year.
- A horse.
- I don't see no horse.
Looks like yours.
Not a chance...
- Hauling timber, too.
- What timber?
Mietek?
Does the forest ranger
know about this?
How would I know
what he knows?
Man,
if you want to freeze your ass off,
then I'll tell him to take it back,
all right?
But if you want it warm,
then get your jacket on,
we'll chop it up,
and that's that.
- But I'm a policeman.
- Get over it...
You'll freeze.
- This the only one there was, Chief?
- I kinda like it. It's old stock.
Back then even the Christmas
decorations were official issue.
Yes...
yes,
yes sir.
Well... Koœciejny's got a pass
for Christmas.
Yellow alert for us.
Well, Koœciejny?
Home for the holidays, huh?
How much leave'd they give you?
Two days, three?
For good behavior?
So what's it like inside?
Just wondering, you know.
Must be interesting I bet.
When I was in Grinpoint...
Go and see for yourself.
Don't cost nothing.
Guys like me don't go.
We got this.
Cash flow, margins, accounts.
Affairs of the heart are
out of style.
I got married, by the way.
She's too good for you.
- That's it?
- That's it.
Quiet as a lamb.
Not going home for the holidays?
I don't have a home.
Then...
Merry Christmas:
Merry Christmas...
Merry Christmas: :
Merry Christmas:
Same to you...
Got papers for that?
They say that tonight the lion
shall lie down with the lamb,
and you want papers...
Merry Christmas:
- A Merry Christmas to you, Irena:
- Same to you, Andrzej, same to you:
Have a seat officer.
Christmas...
Irka:
Get a glass over here:
Bet they'll be locking up soon.
You know, officer,
you can see a fair piece of sky
from my cell.
There's an airport nearby.
When the weather's good the planes
up there look like gold crosses.
Crosses?
Like the ones you wear on your neck,
you know...
I've never been on a plane.
What about you?
I have.
- High up?
- I guess. Above the clouds.
What's it like up there?
Beats me.
Blue.
Like heaven kind of.
Peaceful.
Were you afraid?
I was.
But it's a different sort of fear.
Like you were watching
yourself from far away
and only knew
that the other you was scared.
It's like fear but it isn't.
Like looking at yourself from far off,
you say?
Something like that.
You still sore at me?
No.
I blame myself.
That's good.
Man should blade himself
for everything.
I'm here for him to tell me
what it's like.
Who?
Him.
This is from me.
Monarchs.
They can fly up
to six thousand kilometers,
and yet they look so fragile.
Went by the river the other day.
Frozen over.
Might thaw in the spring.
I didn't know
you could make pierogi too, Mietek.
You'd be surprised
at what I can do...
So how come you
never do anything?
Don't feel like it I guess.
It's not that I'm lazy,
only a bit here and a bit there
don't make for anything permanent.
Same with everybody here.
It's the weather.
Work's like weather.
It changes.
I spent seven years
working in one place.
Every day?
Yup.
In an office.
Good job,
you don't get dirty.
Just sleepy.
I wouldn't mind working
but all I can do is drive a tractor.
Not much demand for that lately.
To each his own.
Damn it:
On Christmas Eve?
We didn't have electricity
in ¯³obiska thirty years back.
Folks saw more then, too.
Get outta here.
I don't want to swear on a holiday,
but you're talking rubbish.
They did too.
Take my granny: Saw something every day.
Like what?
All sorts of things...
Don't you believe in that?
These things are beyond our grasp
and should stay that way,
otherwise
they wouldn't be there at all.
My grandma knew all about it.
In broad daylight she saw things
others didn't even see at night.
She stopped seeing
when they hooked up the power.
Glad tidings:
Egyptian darkness
all the way down to Dukla.
Candles in windows everywhere.
And me with three pairs of boots
to deliver.
- On Christmas Eve?
- If it's urgent it's urgent.
Let me have a nip,
I'm freezing.
Should do something about the chassis
for the winter.
...you're the one,
Now you've gone
and left me crying bitter tears,
When I met you,
you were barely seventeen,
I remember seeing you
down by the lake.
And you told me
that your name was Beata,
So enchanting was
the beauty of that name.
Every day that summer
I would take you sailing
And your love it did
engulf me like a flame...
Dammit...
...just like Midnight Mass...
I'm not seeing this.
- I'm not seeing this at all.
- Of course not.
It's foggy out.
Same deal as usual,
Chestnut.
Mosey on down thataway,
and take the second right.
I'll take the roundabout way
and be back home half an hour after you.
Anybody meets you,
mum's the word.
What do you know,
froze to death.
So hot-blooded and all.
This is all that's left
of the Orthodox church.
They took it to a museum.
This was the presbytery.
And this was the nave.
And you're standing
on the threshold.
You're giving off a chill.
Froze to death,
didn't I?
But it's warm.
You should have thawed.
You only die once,
can't change anything later.
Looks like you can,
since you're sitting here.
I am and I'm not.
So why'd you come here?
Wanted to talk.
You know,
it's not so bad over there,
can't complain,
but, well...
And the silence...
Have you seen your wife?
Didn't notice me then,
wouldn't notice me now.
- Gotta be going.
- Go then.
But I have to lock up the station.
I'm a ghost, remember?
By the way: You wouldn't happen to know
whether there's a pigsticking in the area?
You get around.
Pigsticking's what I miss
the most over there.
- And the detergents?
- What about them?
- How're they moving?
- Moving, I guess.
- What kind sells best?
- Don't remember.
- So what are you doing there, then?
- What are you asking stupid questions for?
The cheapest kind sells best.
Stop that:
- What should I get for tomorrow?
- Whatever.
What is this? :
You doing me a favor here? :
I'm bored.
What with?
All this.
Look out: : :
For God's sake:
Tried to kill me:
Didn't even slow down.
- Mietek?
- Nah. Edek. On the Dukla road.
- Didn't even look back.
- Report it tomorrow.
Can't. I was driving my rig.
It's like I wasn't there.
I had no right to be.
Still got the shakes though.
- Me too.
- So, how's about we...
Nothing here.
We'll go to the bar,
sit with other people.
What do you say:?
Money plus Lubica means a good time:
I didn't know
he could play that well.
All Gypsies can.
Well, nearly all of them.
- He's a Gypsy then?
- Maybe he is. Who cares.
- I'll come by the river if you want.
- I do.
I'll be there. Tomorrow.
I'll do everything tomorrow.
Eeny meeny miny mo...
Catch a tiger by the toe.
Lubiczka,
Lubiczka...
Must be a draft somewhere.
Lubiczko, I'd wash your feet
and drink the bath-water...
Had to pay a five grand fine
for driving up those steps...
It's not you I came back for,
Janek.
Stay:
You're all the same.
No, Janek,
someone waits for me by the river.
Not enough music for you?
- What music?
- Last night's.
- What do you mean?
- You know damn well what I mean.
Everybody saw you.
In broad daylight, polka-dancing
with that... Lubica.
Chief,
it was at night,
I was off duty.
Come quickly:
I can't remember a thing...
I don't know...
I don't remember...
I don't know how...
Couldn't catch up with it.
I wanted to catch some small-fry.
She liked to come here...
No chance of buying smokes
until they open the bar, bro.
Traded them in...
Life goes on, bro...
Life goes on.
Who called them?
He doesn't remember a thing.
How could he have called
if he was in shock?
If they couldn't get
the knife out of his hand...
how could he have made
a phone call?
It's not that obvious.
Not that obvious at all.
Someone had to make that phone call.
But who?
We don't know.
Somebody.
That much we know.
He called because no one else could have.
How could he have done
a thing like that?
Killing a man is one thing,
but a woman?
Lubica?
What'd she do to him?
Where did he call from?
Did anybody see him?
How can he know where he called from
if he can't remember a thing?
There are only three phones
in this shi... in our village.
- Over here and at the priest's house:
- The village head has the third one.
It's off the hook.
What are you driving at?
Nothing's going to
bring her back to life:
We have the victim,
we have the perpetrator,
we have clear-up,
and you want to play cops...
Actually I wanted to see you
and thought
the cemetery might be a good place.
Natural, wouldn't you say?
Why do you have to appear
to me of all people?
Because you're not
from around here.
And because
you don't really believe in me.
The others would straight away.
Can't smoke either.
I went to see the priest.
He was having a pork chop.
The aroma...
He see you?
Not on your life.
Didn't see me, didn't hear me, nothing.
If a specialist
can't see you then
maybe you don't exist after all.
He's no specialist
when it comes to ghosts.
Knows a thing or two
about people is all.
That makes me the expert...
So...
- Do you...
- You want to know who did it?
Yes.
When you got here
you didn't care about anything.
I'm old and tired.
I should come back...
Lights.
The healthy kind.
From the kiosk.
You bought things from her?
It wouldn't have been right.
I sent my housekeeper.
She stocked those...
Publications
of a pornographic nature.
But it's a freedom.
That's it.
Poor soul gone astray.
Poor lambkin.
Souls will stray
when you set them free.
Quite so, quite so.
- Shall I take them inside now? :
- Let them air a while longer.
I've been a priest
for twenty eight years now.
I spent twenty six years
in the mili... police force.
It has to be done.
Either way it won't hurt,
even if it doesn't help,
and why shouldn't it help,
since it can help.
You said it.
Pass the hat.
That should do the trick...
Mietek, it's not like we're chipping
in to buy booze here. This is serious:
This is for me to do.
So, here you are.
I was having a nap.
They say you don't age in church.
Even if that's not true
you do sleep easier.
So, here you are.
Have a look.
Saint Catherine,
patron of the parish,
St. Florian,
patron saint of firemen.
And over there, if you prefer,
is the feretory with St. Joseph.
It's light enough
if four men spread the weight.
You're young and fit...
Yes but I've come
about something else.
Official business you might say.
He's waiting...
For it is written that:
"It is hard for thee
to kick against the pricks".
But you might
not be familiar with that.
If it's official business
let's go to the vicarage.
So what did he say exactly?
He said he was tired
and wants to go back there.
It's just not right:
Here one moment, there the next.
He could never stay put
when he was alive either.
Hot-blooded he was.
And he also said we had it all wrong
about the murder...
...that it wasn't Janek.
He said he'd tell me...
if I had a mass sung for him.
Put that away.
The intention's quite unusual.
You'll carry the feretory
one of these days.
- Well?
- Nice.
Sort of like
she was getting married.
Got it?
Pass it here, then.
Zalatywój wanted it that way...
It's like he's here
and yet he isn't, huh?
- You believe in all that?
- In all that what?
Well, the way things are over there,
that there is an over there, you know...
I guess I do when
I don't think about it.
When I start thinking about it
then I don't really know.
You keep hanging there
while we've got to figure
things out on our lonesome.
Relax.
No one can see me.
You go on ahead.
I'll be waiting by the church.
Look,
I don't even cast a shadow.
Got a watch?
I wouldn't want to be late.
We'll make it.
It begins at six.
You call this a mass?
Where's the people?
Where's the organist?
There's Mietek and W³adek...
I don't mean buddies,
I mean people.
Koœciejny, get real.
It's Saturday,
where am I supposed to get people from?
I want a proper mass,
or else...
Everybody up:
- Get up: I mean you:
- What for?
You know damn well what for,
don't think I forgot:
And you,
and you Radek too:
You're all under arrest:
Get a move on:
Move on:
What about the bill? :
Give me:
Come on, get moving:
Hurry up!
Move it!
Run for it!
Hurry!
Move it!
- Flat, huh?
- Flat, sure.
Fifth one this week.
It's autumn.
They're flying home.
What about the spring?
They fly to work?
You can never really tell
with geese,
but when you think about it...
Almost new:
Time does fly...
All right,
I'll take them.
Directed by
Screenplay by
Cast
Director of Photography
Music by