PRODUCED AND PROVIDED
BY GOLDENTIDE PICTURES
CO-PRODUCED BY
CJ VENTURE INVESTMENT
You are still a lamb to God.
You want to see heaven?
Don't do this please, please.
Shut up.
Please don't hurt me.
Get up! Get up.
Please, please don't hurt me.
- Get the hell up.
- Please don't kill me.
Hey, grab him!
- Okay, put him down.
- One, two...
Action.
I'm betting 6.
Call.
- Draw.
- 6 fold.
2.8
Damn, good one.
So Mister KANG.
You're saying you're fine
with your identity
laid completely bare online?
You'd better know people are
fucking sensitive about eating issues.
Once they find out you let out
carcinogenic substances
into the holy Han River
your business is fucked.
Until I build the sewage disposal
I told you I'd keep quiet.
So much trouble over
a few pennies.
Shit must be getting rough for you
but it's worse for me.
Deposit within 3 minutes
or else you'll be in trouble.
Fucking engineer trying to
cheat me.
Don't be a fussy.
Yo what's up
phony reporter?
why you hanging out here?
where's my money?
Please give me three more days.
That's too long for god's sake.
will three days get me
the principal?
Yes!
- You better bring it.
- Thank you.
If you fucking
hide out on me again
I'm going to dig out your insides.
You got it?
- Keep your words!
- I will.
what the fuck is this mess.
- Keep your words.
- I will.
- Let's head out.
- Yes sir.
- who's next?
- In Mapo.
- Let me borrow your car.
- what?
Are you going undercover?
Your outfit is...
Can you call off the
contract case from before?
Dealing with bastards
who swindle women
Means Korea is still on its toes.
Reporting things like that
is a bit iffy, no?
Reporter?
Take it easy on me, yeah?
Come on, come on!
Go right in!
This is KANG Hyeon-tae
from Sunjin Newspaper.
I'm currently in Hwanggi
Gangwon-do
Leave a message and
I'll get back to you.
WILD DOGS
KIM JEONG-HOON
CHA Jl-HUN
MYUNG KYE-NAM
LEE JAE-PO
CHO DUK-JAE
KIM SUNG-KI
KIM JEONG-SEOK
HWANG TAE-GWANG
1998, A CRIMELESS VILLAGE
OF NEW OSURI, HWANGGI
DIRECTOR HA WON-JOON
I have no insurance?
Can I still get it towed...?
Alright.
Damn HWANG and this crappy car.
You can just leave it
if it's too much to fix.
Don't scout at me
for living up here.
Oh not at all.
I'm sorry if you felt that way.
Urgh, the radiator is off.
It'll be hard for today.
Are you on a rush somewhere?
No, I'm just traveling around.
It's dangerous around here...
The dogs all ran away from lumber camp.
It seems quite quiet around here.
It's because the hill's hidden out.
we didn't even know about Korean war
until a while after it broke out.
You can get off.
I have to get permission
from the mayor.
He doesn't like strangers
coming into this town.
There he is.
Mayor, where are you headed?
- who's that?
- He's just a passerby.
why are you...
His car broke down on
the hills of Osu.
I thought he might freeze to death.
This is mister Baek's place.
He's gone to Seoul.
It'll be warm enough to sleep
with the fire lit.
Get some rest,
I'm heading back to the store.
Osuri doesn't go
around without me.
It's all in my hands...
Don't wander around at night.
Hey, you!
who are you?
- My car broke down...
- what?
Mayor let me stay
here for a night.
what? Oh... sure.
I thought you were a commie
wandering around here.
A commie?
Yes, those damn communists.
Stop hanging about here
and get back in there.
Oh it's you from overseas.
Captain CHOI, shouldn't we
run an identity check on him?
I'm sure the mayor
took care of it.
I doubt there'd be a problem.
I don't know if you've noticed
But this village is crime-free.
I'm quite good at
keeping public order
but strangers rarely
come to this village anyway.
So you, young man.
Don't make any trouble, OK?
Stop!
Stop, stop it!
I'm going to start over
with Hyeon-tae!
I'm not getting a divorce.
we'll get back together
when he comes back to Seoul.
Then what about me?
If you live with Hyeon-tae?
I'm sorry Yoo-joon.
Stop it!
Yoo-joon! Please!
You're mine! Mine!
HYEON-TAE
DELETE
DELETE SELECTED MESSAGES
CANCEL
SEND
I'm sorry. But I can't do this.
You need to divorce Hyeon-tae.
I'm going to have you even if
it means killing Hyeon-tae.
HAN Jeong-in!
DELETE FROM THIS ALBUM
HYEON-TAE
This is KANG Hyeon-tae
from Sunjin Newspaper.
I'm currently in Hwanggi
Gangwon-do
Hey.
Come out real quick.
Oh shit there's one going down.
He's here!
Alright!
He's a visitor in the town.
I should've at least gotten you
some late night snacks.
Oh no, I'm just passing by.
I don't want to be a burden...
Nah, you're no burden.
This is a connection too
if you might say.
Let's introduce each other.
I'm SO Yoo-jin from Seoul.
- Oh you're last name is SO.
- You're good looking.
Maybe because he's from Seoul.
As you know, I'm the
mayor of Osuri.
As well as the head of
Osuri elders' association.
He's an Order of
Military Merit war veteran.
Did you fight in the Vietnam war?
I went to place some order...
Probably killed around 300?
You add 50 people each time
you tell this story.
Manager PARK!
Come here say hi.
OK...
I'm PARK Nam-shik.
You've seen him before.
Say hi.
I'm Tack.
He works at our mayor's
lumber camp.
He's quite the worker.
Nah, that's all bullshit.
This fellow here
beat the hell out of all the dogs
at the camp. They all ran away!
Tack loves eating dogs but
he beats up all
the live ones to death.
Alright let's have a drink!
Shall we?
Cheers everyone.
So I put a knife to
a Vietnamese bitch's neck.
And she was shaking her ass
on top of my stomach
in front of her snuffed husband.
Woah! A Vietnamese bitch
must've been delirious.
what did I tell you I did
after I banged her?
A gunshot to her head, and bang!
Ding, dong, dang!
I can listen to this story forever.
Madam, your face gets red
in front of the chief
and your butt gets tight.
You're still beaming.
She knows men.
- Ouch!
- Don't hit me.
Stop jibbering and just drink.
Mayor.
- Hey, PARK.
- where are you going?
Hey, PARK!
He's busy.
Let's drink some more.
Hey, what do you do for living?
I'm a reporter.
I'm actually here to
talk to a friend...
about my girlfriend.
He said he's in this town.
Have you... seen him?
Nope.
Has anyone seen him?
- Nah...
- Nope.
I guess not?
Let's get up now,
we drank a lot.
Stay still!
You pretty bitch!
You're gorgeous.
I'm planning on telling everything
to Hyeon-tae when I meet him.
I'm going to tell him
how many times I had you.
what! Are you scared?
Hello? Hello?
Do you like this?
Tell me you like it.
Oh fuck this is good.
Young chicks are the best.
Fucking bitch.
who's the girl that was
cleaning up the snow?
Her name is Eun-hee.
She's a damn whore.
She says she can't
see well at night.
- what was it called...
- Night blindness?
Yeah, night blindness.
Her mom has the same eye disorder
and even some kind of cancer.
But our townspeople are generous
to give them food,
fire wood, and medicine too.
If they were in Seoul, everyone
would just try to fuck them.
This town is still warm.
Shit.
Let's go in.
This is my son,
he went to Seoul.
He's quite the brain.
He had a rough time after his mom
left him when he was 5 years old.
He's good with machines.
He takes after me.
He even made his own gun.
So I had to scold him
and take it away.
A gun?
Right. we make guns here
to go hunting for wild animals.
Hey, mister KIM.
what?
There aren't anymore parts?
Get them for me tomorrow.
what do I tell the mayor?
Can you just
leave the car and go?
Hey, Dong-gu.
I expected better of you.
what the hell are you doing?
why are you lagging so much?
You're tying him down.
I'm sorry.
I shouldn't have been
so generous in the first place.
- I should've said no from the...
- Nevermind!
Be sure to get it fixed
by tomorrow and let him leave.
Yes.
The person you called is
not available right now
please leave a message
after the beep.
Ah, bastard.
where's he hiding?
Fucker.
Eun-hee, how are you?
were you waiting for me?
Good girl.
Come with me...
Good girl!
Come here.
Listen to me before I hurt you.
Good girl.
Hey, don't do that.
Come here, come here.
Don't make this harder.
I won't hurt you like last time.
- No!
- I won't hurt you like last time.
I said come here!
You bitch!
You fucking bitch!
You fucking bit me!
You damn whore!
Come here!
Don't you dare!
You bitch come here!
Bitch! Pretty bitch!
This is for the good of both of us.
Good job.
Go wash up.
You're a bad bitch.
It's almost done
just wait up a little.
I think the mayor is
a very good person.
Of course.
He's got lots of land, too.
From this lumber camp
to the farm over there is all his.
He lives alone?
Everyone in this town
is a widower.
Oh, why is that?
what's wrong?
Hey!
what's wrong with you?
It's indigestion.
The sweet potatoes stuck.
what about the car?
Are you done fixing it?
No, not yet.
I've been busy dealing with him.
Take him inside.
Are you very ill?
You'll be better soon, you're young.
Try eating this.
I got some porridge from the
madam at the pub.
Thank you.
Do you have something to say...?
Oh yeah.
we're having
a neighborhood patrol rally
in the city next week.
I was hoping you could
write the foreword.
Captain.
what is that box on the
telephone pole?
what's in there?
I thought you'd know
as a chief patrol.
It's an electric circuit breaker
for Eun-hee's house.
Maybe you've heard already
but her eyes are kind of bad.
Night blindness?
I see you've heard.
Her house is Vietnam war hero
LEE Jong-guk's house.
He lent her that house
out of generosity.
She can't do anything
without electricity
So the electricity bill
was just too much.
He decided to turn off the lights
when she went to sleep.
And turn on the lights
when morning came.
It's strange for us to keep going
in and out of her house.
So we installed it in the streets.
Is your question answered?
Mr. LEE seems great.
Just giving out his house like that.
For sure he is!
He's a patriot for sure.
Yes, chief.
Yeah?
You left your keys?
Hold on.
I left it in my office too.
I'll take it to you right now.
what took you so long?
How can you forget the keys?
Go on ahead!
Here, I'm here.
Come here.
Hey.
Woah.
what's wrong with you?
Hurry up
if you want to leave today.
Shit.
- You gonna get your car fixed?
- Yes, chief.
Dong-gu has nimble hands.
You! when you go to Seoul
have fun getting laid.
why won't this open?
Is Osuri really a crime-free town?
It's kind of cool. I'm even
a little envious of living here.
There are only a few residents.
we know who committed what crime.
Everyone just lets everything go.
Does that mean...
There may be crime
but no crime's been revealed.
That's what it sounds like.
what are you trying to say?
You know where the
photographer is, right?
I don't know!
I just...
Hey, you.
Ah, shit.
Did you kill another dog?
Yo, you want to
take some to Seoul?
I don't eat dogs.
- Then you eat it.
- No! I don't eat dogs.
Just eat the fuck up
and shut up, mother fucker.
what, you son of a bitch!
Mother fucker?
Yeah! what!
Bring it!
I'll sew up that mouth of yours
blabbering to this fucking tagrag.
You son of a bitch!
why don't you stop now.
And you. Stop trying to
figure out this town.
Before you get
shredded to pieces.
Shithead...
That damned son of a bitch.
Hey, you.
Ah, shit. Ugh.
Eun-hee.
Hey you bitch!
Are you in for this too?
Then don't die you damned bitch.
I won't go by myself.
I'm going to take you too.
why are you here?
You want to fuck me too?
- Calm down!
- Is that so?
Calm down, please!
Hello.
Hey, honey.
Okay.
Shit.
I came here to talk to you.
About what.
Can you put this down first...
what you're going through...
I wanted to run away from it.
Then why did you come back?
I came back to take you.
Lies.
Even the priest and
the photographer.
They all said they'd help.
They didn't lie.
They probably tried to help you.
That's why I came back too.
You're lying.
- It's all a lie.
- Eun-hee...
Mom, I'll get you pain reliever.
Go, Eun-hee.
Go...
- Go...
- Mom...
I can't go anywhere without you.
I'm not leaving.
Go.
No.
Mister.
You don't have to help me.
Just leave.
I can't go without my mom.
I need money for medication too.
I know it'll be hard but
can you tell me what's going on?
So I can help you.
Can you really?
Yes.
I need evidence,
so I'm going to record this.
It first happened...
when I was fifteen years old.
The boys around the village...
Old ladies around here said
I seduced the boys.
And then
Dong-gu said
he was sorry because of
what his son had done.
He said he was real sorry.
He would give me money.
But then he also had me.
And then he bragged about it
to the other men in town.
After that...
All the men started
coming every night.
Sometimes the patrol and
the mayor would come together.
They watched
each other having me!
More men came to get me.
They did whatever they wanted.
All of them...
I want to kill them all.
I want to kill them.
Have you seen the camera
the photographer brought?
The man at the garage
gave it to the mayor.
Are you leaving?
Can you stay with me?
I'll be back with the camera.
Let's run away with your mom after.
You're really coming back, right?
I'll be back by noon.
wait for me.
I knew it.
Mother fucker.
Let's go in.
PARK has something to say?
I think he has something to say
about Eun-hee's mom.
why?
Is she almost dead?
I think so. we'll talk about
the details inside.
Alright.
Oh geez... Happy!
Did you do this?
Mayor, I'm here.
How are you all?
He's all chilling out.
It's cold, come on in.
Phew, it's cold.
Come sit over here.
Sit here.
Let's have a drink too.
Dong-gu, bring in some alcohol.
Alright.
Hurry up and bring it out.
Okay!
So, Eun-hee's mom is
almost dead?
It seems that way.
I thought she'd live a bit more.
It's not looking very good.
If her mom dies,
Eun-hee will run away.
I had a hard time last time too.
That bitch is quick.
If she runs away
everything will be ruined.
what do we do now?
Let's stop it now.
- Stop what?
- we'll get caught if it goes on.
would she go anywhere?
She likes the taste of men.
Honestly, if we...
As long as we finish off well
then we can keep on...
- He's right!
- Hold on.
I think so.
This is getting dangerous.
From what I saw last time.
She's pretty damn resentful.
If her mom dies
Eun-hee won't stay still.
Dong-gu, let's end this.
Go get rid of Eun-hee this time.
Let's end this all.
- I don't want to.
- why not?
After I got rid of
the priest and the photographer
I can't even sleep at night.
I have nightmares all the time.
If you never started
then we would've never!
This trouble wouldn't have started.
Don't say such things.
who took advantage
of her the most?
Last time you said you
would try something new
and put a condom over a gun
to push it inside her.
Are you even a human being?
what the fuck!
None of us can say that.
we're all beasts to Eun-hee.
You and me.
That's too much.
Don't say such things.
It's okay, it's okay.
You can treats whores that way.
Dong-gu has a point too though.
Dong-gu got rid of
two men last time
we can't tell him to
do that again.
I'll do it.
- You will?
- Yeah.
I don't have many days to live.
I think it's right I do this.
How?
Don't worry about it.
I'll take care of it.
This way, I'll feel better
about my grandson in Seoul.
He makes sense.
- with a gun?
- Yeah.
No way! Villagers will be shocked
at the gunshot sound.
That's not a problem.
who cares?
we've used guns much more
to kill wild dogs.
what about the corpse?
wouldn't people be suspicious?
If both of them die from gunshot.
That's an issue.
I'll do it.
I have a grinder.
Good.
This is the story.
Eun-hee's mom died
from her illness.
Eun-hee was in despair, and
jumped into a grinder.
who can rebuke?
- That's nice.
- No blood involved.
Cheers!
Let's get this over with.
- Go on.
- Do it right.
Manager PARK!
- Let me go!
- Come here.
- Just forget it.
- Yeah.
Hey, Dong-gu.
Remember the photographer?
Put him in the grinder too.
Yes, I will.
where'd you put his camera
by the way?
It's in the dog house.
Let's get rid of that too.
- Alright.
- Do it.
You are still a lamb to God.
Please, please don't hurt me.
Don't do this please.
Please don't hurt me.
- Get up! Get up.
- Please, don't do this.
Oh my...
Hyeon-tae...
Hyeon-tae, Hyeon-tae...
Hey you! Reporter!
You going for a cover?
Don't you dare do anything.
Stop!
Come out.
That bastard!
what the fuck...
why the hell is he here?
Fucking grandpa.
He's got temper.
Die you fucker.
Die!
Hey Chief Choi.
Hurry up and check it out.
Yeah call me if
there's anything wrong.
Let's go.
- You'll die if you don't go now.
- I can't!
- Hurry, leave.
- No, mom.
I'm okay honey.
Go with him.
- No, I won't.
- Do my last wish and go.
- No!
- You promised.
You can't live like a human being
unless you leave this place.
- No, no!
- Go on now.
Listen to mom.
Go on...
Hey.
Please give me some space.
I'll be right out.
Mom...
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry...
- Hey are you there?
- Yeah.
What's going on?
That reporter bastard
didn't go to Seoul yesterday.
- Did you meet Chief LEE?
- I don't even see him.
What the fuck!
I'm right after you so,
Hurry on here.
Dong-gu you dumb shit!
Hurry up and get your ass here.
Do you know what you've done?
The reporter from Seoul
ran away with Eun-hee!
If he gets out of here alive
you know we're all fucked right?
If anything goes wrong
I'll kill you first.
Get your ass here!
Now!
Fucking reporter.
You're dead.
Jang.
what.
what the hell happened.
Save me.
Take me to the hospital.
You old shit.
You're useless!
Go die!
Fucking die!
You retarded old shithead!
If Eun-hee gets out of Osuri
we're all doomed. Go after them!
They'll be heading to the stream.
That's the only way out. Let's go.
This bitch!
Fucking bitch. what the fuck
do you think you're doing!
where did he go!
Eun-hee, hurry.
Eun-hee!
Eun-hee, let's just go!
Eun-hee.
- Don't do this Eun-hee...
- Hey!
Don't do this.
what the hell?
Isn't that CHOI's gunshot?
who knows.
Let's go.
Mayor, he only knows
the way he came in.
where his car broke down.
I'll head on over there
and wait for him.
Nam-shik and mayor,
you two go this way.
Alright, sounds like a plan.
Nam-shik, let's go!
Go get him.
That little fucker.
Hey Nam-shik, come here.
Take this and chase after them.
I'll go that way.
Run.
They're getting away!
Be careful!
Shit.
we can go to your car
once we get past this hill.
Oh... fuck.
Eun-hee, I'm sorry.
It's all my fault.
I'm your mom's
high school friend.
Eun-hee, if I didn't give you
medicine for mom.
She would've died long ago.
Eun-hee.
You fucking whore!
I wouldn't have done it
if you resisted!
I thought you liked it.
You bitch!
Fuck!
This is hell...
I'll go turn on the engine.
when I honk
come to the car, okay?
It won't take long
don't worry.
If they try to attack, put this on
their body and press the button.
Fucking...
Come out you little bastard.
Come out.
- where did you take Eun-hee!
- Crazy bastard.
where's Eun-hee!
where's she, you fucking bastard!
Osuri is ruined because of you
little mother fucker.
- where did Eun-hee go!
- Fuck you, mother fucker.
where is she!
This town is ruined
because of you.
Say your last good-bye...
Are you okay?
Let's go to the car.
Dong-gu!
These little bitches...
CRIMELESS VILLAGE
GOOD-BYE
Don't blink.
Okay, done.
Do you want to get
another check-up in Seoul?
No it's okay.
It's not that serious.
Mister.
Thank you...
No, thank you.
I can finally
get my head straight.
I've learned so much...
Okay, I've beat him up
as much as you wanted.
Good job.
Hey, say "Ah".
This will get you some soju.
I think my boys hit you
a little more than I told them to.
Good work.
- Let's go.
- Yes sir.
what are you looking at.
Hey, phony!
You know what's similar among
a reporter, sperm, and a loan shark?
It's damn hard to
become a human being.
we're no human beings
So let's never run into each other.
Understand?
- Let's go.
- Yes sir.
Fucking wild dogs...