Antwerp, 1995
She's a cutie. Really.
You'll be happy. I know it.
One thing I can say about myself:
I'm a good judge of people.
For instance, I can
see that you're nervous.
The first time you came to
the bar, you were nervous too.
I said to myself:
Oops, the silent type.
An introvert.
Am I right..
or am I right?
Everything will be fine.
As long as you behave.
And produce the money.
Carnival in hell,
beware of Tinkerbell.
Her name is Bieke.
Go sit next to her.
Go sit next to her. Go on.
Can I see your drawing?
- I'd rather not.
- Bieke.
What's wrong? First time, hey?
I knew it. I'm a
good judge of people.
Bieke!
I want to talk a bit first.
Wouldn't you rather
let me spoil you?
I want to talk a bit first.
About you, about the people
who come here to visit.
My daddy doesn't allow that.
What's that?
Daddy!
Hey, dude. Hey, what's that?
Damn. He got caught!
Vincke got caught! Quick!
Quick, hurry! Hurry!
Careful!
No panic!
Follow me!
Put the gun down! Put
the gun down, damnit!
Filthy bastards! Bastard!
Take it easy.
She's coming with
me, you hear? Here!
Take it easy. Let's
not do anything stupid.
Not you.. Not us either.
We go outside together.
Nothing has happened yet.
A lot has happened.
What would you know?
Do you think I'm stupid?
Look at Bieke. She loves you.
You're her father.
She likes you.
- She needs you.
- What would you know?
I'm gonna kill you,
pal. I'm gonna kill you.
- Vincke..
- Shtt, Freddy.
Freddy!
Daddy! Daddy!
Don't move!
On your knees!
On your knees! On
your knees, now!
- Daddy!
- They're assholes, Bieke!
They're all assholes!
Daddy! Daddy!
He could have told
us a lot, Freddy.
You know me, Vincke. No risks.
We should have
busted him sooner.
- We had enough.
- I was hoping for more.
Do you think I was the first
one he asked to come up?
Look at it from
the bright side.
One less fatso, and
the girl has been saved.
Vincke? Eric?
Marseilles, five days later
- In Belgium?
- Yes.
There are potential customers,
Angelo. It would..
- ..be an important market.
- Not for me.
Fries, please.
Right away. But you
just ordered some.
What's wrong with you?
Gilles, you'd better
send somebody else.
I'm tired.
Don't start whining
about retirement again.
Angelo, people like
us don't retire.
- I hate Belgium.
- As does everybody.
But you know the
place. That's important.
Don't you have
a brother there?
- You could pay him a visit.
- If he's still alive.
Visit his grave then.
THE ALZHEIMER CASE
Film Courtesy of Gap821 OLIVAR
WELCOME TO ANTWERP
Most foreigners only
know Bruges in Belgium.
They talk about
Bruges, Bruges.
But Antwerp is much
prettier, right?
There is more to see
here than in Bruges.
Bruges is a lot smaller too.
It doesn't amount to much.
Most people don't know..
Here you go, Mr. Ledda.
You have room 633.
Is this your first
time in our hotel?
I speak Dutch.
- A bad habit.
- I've got more of those.
And? Alone?
Not anymore.
- Are you Mr..?
- Casoni.
Did you have a good trip?
I've got the files
you asked for.
It's all there.
Excuse me.
Yes, hello?
Yes, I'm working hard on it.
No, he doesn't say much.
And he looks like his head has
been under a tram for two years.
But they must know
what they're doing, no?
Yes.
My customer wants
to know when.
If everything has been
planned well, it'll go fast.
Fast is too slow.
We want to know when.
First I'm going to lay with my
head under a tram for a year or two.
Are you coming to the opening
of the exhibition with me?
No time, honey.
Building permits.
And a meeting in
Brussels. But have fun.
After all, that's what
you married me for.
- A long time ago, yes.
- What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing, Bob,
nothing. See you later.
If it gets too late, I'll have
to spend the night in Brussels.
Okay. But do me a favour.
Buy her a better perfume.
Top nomination
Bob Van Camp
Typical!
Your keys, I bet.
How often did I..
Are you smart? Are
you smart, I asked.
If you're smart,
you know who sent me.
I'm asking you
again. Are you smart?
If you're smart, you'll
also know why I'm here.
Do you know?
Where is it?
Downstairs?
You don't know
who I am, do you?
If that scum
really thinks..
If I give it to you,
will you let me go?
Please.
I swear I won't talk.
Daddy?
Daddy, I'm going
to Katrien's, okay?
Hello, who's speaking?
Yes, it's me.
No, problem
number 1 is solved.
No, you don't have to worry.
Yes, see you soon.
- Yes, Freddy?
- How do you know it's me?
Anybody in their right mind hangs
up after 20 times. What's up?
The big boss needs
us. It's rather urgent.
- You absolutely had to be there.
- I'm on holiday.
Give me ten minutes, okay?
- Never heard of mineral water?
- Mineral water? In the morning?
Definitely not with an eclair.
Shit! Fucking BMW's!
Give way to the right.
Pay some attention.
But it's true, isn't it? They
push you right off the road..
flashing their lights. Made
in Germany and who drives them?
Hair dressers and doorkeepers.
- I'll tap their rear lights.
- No, no.
I'll pee on their
door handle. Yes.
It sticks and
stinks like a hell.
The cheap models
will rust for sure..
but above all: the
insurance doesn't pay.
When you're rear light is broken..
One phone call and it's solved.
You're on the wrong track.
You're punishing the wrong one.
Yeah, yeah. The
insurance, the wrong one?
Come on. Very urgent
matter. I'm curious.
- Good morning, chief. Freddy.
- Linda.
We don't know much. Mr. Van
Camp didn't come home last night..
and didn't show up at work.
- That's for Missing People.
- The national police has been there yet..
but the lady is a good
friend of the boss.
- Is Van Parys here?
- Yes.
He wants us to investigate
the case very discretely.
Why?
Mr. Van Camp is
quite a big shot.
Director General of
the Planning Department.
Eva, chief Vincke and
inspector Verstuyft.
- Nice to meet you.
- Mrs. Van Camp.
Mrs. Van Camp is a
good friend of my wife.
- Did Linda brief you?
- Yes, well, she told me what she knows.
The car is still in the garage.
It hasn't been used yet. So..
I'm afraid something happened.
Did your husband have a reason
to leave? An argument maybe?
Is this the first time
he's gone overnight?
Verstuyft, let
Vincke do his job.
Look at that car.
Coemans knows the way.
My husband knows
his addresses.
But his work comes first.
He'd never not show up.
- Does he have any problems?
- Problems?
All big construction files
pass through his office..
I can imagine he has
friends, but also enemies.
Can we stick to the facts?
I'll try. Would you rather
do the interrogation yourself?
Or are we going to let our friends
of the national police do their job?
Van Parys, damnit.
A political buddy falls
asleep on top of his mistress..
and all Antwerp
has to act on it.
Van Parys wants to
shag her. Can't you see?
I think he killed her man.
What shall we do?
Search the whole forest?
- Drive, Freddy.
- Wait.
Don't you have
a brother there?
You could pay him a visit.
Paolo?
It's me, Angelo.
Sir? Can I help you? Are
you related to Mr. Ledda?
Distantly.
- Has he been here for a long time?
- Yes, yes. Very long.
It went fast. It started..
I know how it starts.
You're right.
Why do you need to know
French for a chief's exam?
To be able to read the menus
in the posh restaurants.
Coemans, shut up!
And stop ogling at Linda, pig!
Say, hasn't that file been
handed to Child Welfare?
- I borrowed it for a while.
- Over achiever.
Does Van Parys know about it?
Sometimes one has to
go against the rules.
Do we know anything
about Van Camp yet?
Linda and Coemans
are working on it..
but so far, no news.
I promised Mrs. Van Camp
that we'd have some news.
Freddy, you know somebody
from the national police.
Try to find out something.
Chief, we're working on
something else at the moment.
Bieke Cuypers, I guess?
The file that you requested from
Child Welfare, behind my back.
Sorry, but that case
is closed for us.
Miss Cuypers? Brigitte?
Everybody calls me Bieke.
Are you a friend of daddy?
She's 12, 13 at the most.
Sorry, I'm not doing that.
You're wrong. She looks
much younger than she is.
She's 12, 13 at the most.
Sorry, I'm not doing that.
You already said that.
You're stuck in a groove.
She's still a
child. I won't do it.
If you think you
can do this to me..
you've got another
thing coming!
One phone call! One
phone call to Marseilles!
You don't get it.
Nobody will do it.
Forget it. We'll
find somebody else.
No, you won't!
No? Give me one
reason why not.
I'll give you three.
One!
Two!
And three!
The treasure-chest of your good
friend Bob Van Camp. Understood?
Crazy!
But okay! Did you hire a
bunch of carnival singers?
My customer wants to see you.
Tomorrow. Here, same time.
Don't forget your box.
Your wallet.
Mr. Seynaeve.
Van Camp has just disappeared.
Even his mistress
doesn't know anything.
They check the passenger
lists at the airports.
He fled abroad. Is
that what they think?
Is there any concrete information
or is it occupational therapy?
Concrete information?
Occupational therapy?
Our intellectual legal friend
from the Judicial Police.
Commissioner.
If you need information,
we're very happy to oblige.
But first send us an
official piece of paper.
You're good at
that, aren't you?
Sorry, commissioner. We didn't
know you people could read.
I didn't know you
had to learn to shoot.
And since you have to learn
to shoot, Mr. Verstuyft..
why don't you have
your own shooting range?
Unfortunately, we don't have the
same budgets as the national police.
No. It's because 90% of your
budget is spent on paper.
If I used too much paper, you
can come and get some from us.
Marc.
- It'll be the night of your life.
- Yeah, yeah, I bet.
A night like you have never had
before in your entire career.
- Some other time, okay?
- Come on. Look here.
Room 105. Perfect
for a hot woman.
Excuse me, you're bothering the
lady, the other guests, and me.
And who are you?
Her pimp, maybe?
Tell me how much this hot
truffle is going to cost me.
You're looking for
something hot, right?
- A gentleman?
- No.
A customer.
Relax, relax.
You were dreaming.
Don't you know me anymore?
Stay.
Sorry. Stay.
- I can hear your blood flow.
- That's my head that's leaking.
You're a character.
Can you tell?
I know.
I fancy strange men.
Two bullets in the chest, one
in the head. Professional job.
Bastards.
Bastards! Bastards!
And the other wounds?
From the ship propeller. She
must have been mangled by it.
Freddy, make sure you'll
become chief as soon as you can.
So I don't have to do it anymore.
The child
was 12 years old, for
crying out loud!
Forensic investigation shows
that the girl is the victim..
of a brutal murder.
Her identity has
now been released.
It's 12 year old Brigitte
Cuypers, from Merksem.
She was recently involved
in child prostitution.
That case also cost
her father his life.
Have I been here
all night? Say it.
- Have I been here all night?
- Yes. Where else?
Come on, you have to go.
Get dressed.
Sorry.
- Back!
- Yes, but your pills..
Back! You have
to go back! Back!
Shit.
You were right, Gilles.
People like us don't retire.
Vincke!
We have a witness.
A hotel guest.
Mister Casoni?
- Your passport.
- Thank you.
Hello. Vincke, chief.
You can speak Flemish, chief.
I'm from everywhere
and nowhere.
This gentleman knows the
identity of the victim.
I just saw him get
in. The poor guy.
His name is Ledda.
- Angelo Ledda.
- How do you spell that?
Like in the swan,
but with two d's.
That's Greek mythology.
Basic knowledge.
- So you know Mr. Ledda?
- Yes. From here, in the bar.
A friendly person.
Retired. A real Frenchman.
This was found
under another car.
A credit card to
Angelo Ledda's name.
Guys, have a look!
I was waiting for
that. It's not your day.
Baron? It's time.
No, that's okay. Joseph
can give the injection.
You guys are good at
that, right, Joseph?
Psychiatrists don't
knock people out all the time, Gustave.
Sometimes we talk
to our patients.
Before or after the injection?
- Baron De Haeck.
- Yes, it's me.
Turn on the TV, baron.
Teletext, BRT, page 101.
Mafia crime in Antwerp
What do you think? Say what
you want about those Frenchies..
but when they make a
mistake, they fix it.
With a bulldozer,
if they have to.
You can sleep well, baron.
Don't worry. It's all over.
That is, if you
didn't forget about me.
You didn't forget about
me, did you, baron?
Great.
If I may say so..
nothing beats doing business
with an honest person.
Here's our friend Casoni.
But according to France,
this is the only Bernard Casoni.
Young guy, centre half of
Olympique Marseilles, since 5 years.
You see, in our job, it's
better to know your football..
than your Greek mythology.
So what do we
know? Angelo Ledda.
Yes, the credit cards are fakes.
In France they don't know him.
- And here?
- Here they do.
The juvenile court
has a file on him.
Unfortunately, this Ledda
has been dead for 40 years.
Let them send it anyway.
- And the woman in the trunk?
- That's Anja Laeremans.
A prostitute,
according to the barman.
No pimp, no criminal record.
Also no family or
friends, unfortunately.
- We keep searching.
- Revenge in the prostitutes scene?
And what does an
over achiever think?
Yes, yes. Why not?
Maybe the Nijvel
gang is also involved.
Chief? Things are
the way you thought.
The bullets are
from the same gun.
The woman has been shot
by the murderer of Bieke.
What's going on?
Problems?
Impossible. You're dead.
No, you're dead.
Two bullets in the chest
and one through the head.
Again.
He isn't cold
yet. Want to feel?
No way.
Stimorol.
He arrives, wants
to open his gate..
the detector has been
sabotaged. He gets out and bam.
Coemans? Did you
give them the car?
Affirmative, chief.
I am for 69.
An even sicker mind
than yours, Freddy.
Mrs. Seynaeve..
chief Vincke and
inspector Verstuyft.
We're very sorry, madam.
Life goes on.
If you were expecting
tears and a black veil..
I have to disappoint you.
But if you have
questions.. Shoot.
Where did your husband come
from at such a late hour?
He was gone for business. With
whom and where? I don't know.
We don't talk about that.
We don't talk a lot anyway.
I'm not a big talker.
Did your husband receive
any threats in the past?
Not from me.
Did he have enemies?
No.
No, only friends.
My husband had many friends.
What I'm about to
say, sounds harsh.
But we found this in
your husband's mouth.
Any idea?
No idea. But I'm glad there
still are some honest people.
- Or aren't you honest?
- Yes, I am.
I am, just a bit
suspicious by nature.
If I give it to you,
will you let me go?
I swear I won't talk.
If that scum
really thinks..
- Is he inside?
- Yes.
What are you doing?
Good morning to you too, Jean.
Didn't you hear?
Seynaeve has been shot.
Impossible.
Daddy, what on
earth are you doing?
That guy is walking around
outside here. I wish..
'I wish' is for old bags.
A man says: 'I want'.
Don't worry. He
doesn't know me.
All leads stop with Seynaeve.
- Says who? Seynaeve?
- Says I.
Bastards.
Fucking bastards.
Nothing. We have
nothing, people.
Four murders and all
we have are facts.
We need to connect the facts.
Prostitution. Revenge.
But Bieke Cuypers
is child prostitution.
And Anja is hotel
prostitution.
Two totally different scenes.
Seynaeve has got nothing
to do with prostitution.
He's in another league.
But he's been killed the
same way as Bieke Cuypers.
Not with the same weapon.
Seynaeve's bullets are
of a different calibre.
Hello?
Chief? Chief?
Bernard Casoni!
- Is that legal?
- No, it's Japanese.
Vincke.
Did you read the
papers, chief?
The woman in the trunk doesn't
have anything to do with it.
She was an angel.
And you know what happened
and want to help us?
Help you? I'm doing
your job here.
Get the scum of the streets,
because you're too slow.
I don't have much time left.
And who are the scum?
I can't tell you yet.
Then why do you call us?
If I can't finish
it, you'll have to.
Do you want the real
bastards behind all this?
Yes.
Keep searching and
you'll find them.
Unless we find you first.
Mr..
Ledda?
Well done. You
already know my name.
I do now.
Doesn't matter. I
have nothing to lose.
Just my head.
Okay, we've got
him. 0475/56.28.36.
Coemans, check with Belgacom.
No need. That's
Seynaeve's number.
Why do these thugs have
a mobile and we don't?
Ledda is our man.
And we still have nothing.
Vincke..
remember how Mrs. Seynaeve
was talking about those friends..
and how she reacted to the
money? Can I try something?
If we pressure her a
bit, she'll open up.
You'd like that, wouldn't
you? Her.. naked..
Let me give it a go.
- Sorry, Freddy, I can't allow that.
- Vincke, you said it yourself.
Sometimes one has to
go against the rules.
Mrs. Seynaeve?
- You almost look like a pro.
- The door was open.
Don't you know a
better way of coming in?
Thanks for letting me see you.
Shoot.
- Do you know Angelo Ledda?
- No.
- Bernard Casoni?
- Big? Blond?
- Dark.
- I know lots of those.
But, no, the name
doesn't ring a bell.
He called us on
your husbands mobile.
- What do you think about that?
- I should get it disconnected.
- Your act is very impressive.
- I beg your pardon.
Do you think I don't
know why you're here?
- Madam, I'm..
- What did you think?
I should put her
up against the wall?
I think you know more
than you're saying.
Oh, you're a real thinker?
I thought you were
more about action.
Come.
We can make each other happy.
Angelo Ledda?
No, never heard of him.
But that other name, Casoni..
I overheard that name
once during a phone call..
with De Haeck.
The concrete baron?
The former minister?
You asked for a name,
not a family tree.
Come on. Drink up
before it gets too warm.
Never on duty.
Fucking Belgian cop.
Vincke!
We have a name. Compliments
of Mrs. Seynaeve.
- De Haeck.
- Minister of State?
His son. Jean De Haeck.
He resigned last month..
as Director General of
the Planning Department.
Who was his successor?
Bob Van Camp.
- Fireworks?
- I think so.
Where does he live?
No, go on. They'll call back.
Blackmail. That's it.
For years, Van Camp has been
missing out on all these goodies.
They all go to big
shots, like Jean De Haeck.
Then he discovers
De Haeck's weak spot.
Children. Bieke Cuypers.
He's not answering. Again.
Van Camp blackmails De Haeck and
steals his promotion from him.
Sorry.
Hello?
Yes, hello?
I lost him. Who would
dig a tunnel here?
Verstuyft. Put him through
and record the call, okay?
Ledda.
Chief? About our agreement.
- Agreement?
- Get the scum of the streets.
Bieke Cuypers,
12. Was she scum?
That was a shame.
But not my doing.
They should keep their
filthy hands off children.
Why should I believe you?
Because I'm helping you.
I'm giving you the
bastards, for free.
Stop it and let's work
together. We can..
Too late.
About five minutes. You
people are really too slow.
- Who?
- Somebody called De Haeck.
Jean De Haeck.
Nobody will miss him.
I didn't miss him.
Nice talking to you, chief.
Till the next one.
Ledda is with De
Haeck. He killed him.
Immediate assistance.
Merodelaan 2.
Down, Freddy.
Come!
Vincke?
I feel for you, chief.
All that ugliness,
all those corpses.
And every day you take
the filth home with you.
My house is empty. That helps.
Vincke?
Damn!
Is he a good shot, Mr. Vincke?
Ledda, put your weapon
down! Weapon down!
If he's good, you only
need to do one step aside.
- But you know that.
- Come on, Vincke. One step.
One step and I blow
his head off. Vincke?
Or are you afraid, Mr. Vincke..
that the truth will go
into the grave with me?
The suspect is using a
grey Mercedes, IAM 469.
He's extremely dangerous. I
repeat: extremely dangerous.
All information has been passed to the
national police and the teams on the road.
Couldn't you do one
step to the side?
He's our only witness. Sorry.
Hey, you. Are you going
to live here?
It won't get any greener.
Sorry, I haven't been
drinking. I fell asleep.
Your lights too?
Your lights,
fallen asleep too?
That's better, isn't it? This way
you can find your papers.
Car registration, identity
card, driving license.
What's that, pal?
Damn!
Lemmens, what are
you doing here?
Okay. It's the judicial guy.
What's this? The
invasion in Normandy?
- Is the baron being threatened?
- We give no details.
- Why are you here?
- Is the baron home?
- Yes.
Lord, give all our enemies
true peace and love..
forgive them for
all their sins..
and protect us against
their ambushes. Amen.
Baron?
Chief Vincke of
the Judicial Police.
Mr. De Haeck, I have
some bad news for you.
I've already heard, gentlemen.
Many people care about me.
Joseph Vlerick, psychiatrist.
And here as a friend.
I know this is not
the best moment.
We think the murderer
knew your son.
Do you know if your son
received any threats?
Not that I know. He was
an honest civil servant.
Can I ask why the national
police are protecting you?
That's between me and them.
If you're threatened
yourself..
I can't help you,
you can't help me.
If you want to pray
with me, you're welcome.
Otherwise, please leave
the chapel. I lost a son.
For you.
Verstuyft. Yes, Coemans?
What happened?
Vincke, it's closed off here.
We think we know
who's behind it.
We've been after him for a
while. He killed Jean De Haeck..
a couple of hours ago.
- Do you have any proof?
- We're almost certain.
You want us to pass the
investigation over to you.
Forget it, Vincke.
They're my men.
I'd like to know what's
happening with the baron.
I can't say a word about it.
I'll be clear: I want
to see your files..
I advise you to do
the same with ours.
Vincke, I'll be clear too.
I don't need an intellectual
loudmouth like yourself.
Let's agree on this: you find
your murderer, we find ours.
If it's the same
one, we'll call you.
- For the group picture.
- De Keyzer..
you're a pain in the ass.
If you had let me do my
work, he would still be alive.
Excuse me.
I thought I heard
someone say 'come in'.
Mister prosecutor, what
do we owe the honour to?
The honour is ours, Vincke.
You had a run-in with the
commissioner, yesterday?
- Yes, that's correct.
- You called him a pain in the ass?
Yes, something
to that effect.
I would like you to
apologise, Vincke.
My apologies..
- ..pain in the ass.
- Vincke!
I can't continue to
ignore your arrogance.
You meddle with
their operations..
you request files, on the
basis of wild assumptions.
It's normal for him to
ask for an explanation.
Excuse me, he didn't
On the contrary, he
wanted to get rid of us.
This is the wild assumption.
The bullet that killed the
national police officer..
comes from the weapon
of our main suspect.
So it is a bit our
business, I guess.
That's new to
me. I think we..
I think it's best
to keep this quiet.
The media will call it
obstruction of the investigation..
the national police
are hiding evidence.
What do you think, prosecutor?
I expect your file
on my desk at 9 am.
Yes, and a copy on this desk.
Bieke Cuypers,
12. Was she scum?
That was a shame.
But not my doing.
They should keep their
filthy hands off children.
'Keep their filthy
hands off children'
That tells me that..
Ledda found out
about the child abuse..
and turned against his
client, Jean De Haeck.
And the baron
with his protection?
Nice talking to you,
chief. Till the next one.
He'll be next. I'm certain.
He's involved, but
how do we prove it?
- Ledda says..
- Ledda says, Ledda says..
I can sing along
with that tape by now!
You know what?
Have fun with him..
and let him go..
until all of Antwerp
is in the freezer.
Do you think I have any
sympathy for that bastard?
My sympathy is here
and nowhere else.
Without Ledda we're nowhere.
I want all the bastards.
Tell that to the
children of the policeman.
Chief? I have the file from
the juvenile court..
on Angelo Ledda who has
been dead for 40 years.
I'm afraid he's still
a little bit alive.
Here.
Five times in juvenile
court, one burglary..
four cases of violence.
Died with his father in a
house fire at the age of 17.
Juicy detail: It was suspected
that Angelo lit the fire himself.
His first murder.
Another spicy detail:
Angelo has a brother.
Paolo Ledda. I've
got the address here.
A bar in the Kerkstraat.
Right now, he
lives in St. Ursula.
Linda, Coemans,
search that bar.
- We're going to his brother.
- Bring some grapes.
I don't know.
It's only a
drawing. It could be.
The chaplain. He'll
know more about it.
He had him in his class.
Paolo, having visitors?
Chief Vincke. I'm
investigating Angelo Ledda.
Angelo? What
good does that do?
Man, stuffy! Jesus.
It's been empty for
months but have a look here.
His father's house.
Get a search
warrant for that too.
I always said that Angelo
should be three classes up.
- Highly gifted?
- Incredible memory.
And not really a bad boy.
He did everything
for everybody.
Sometimes something stupid happened,
somebody calling him 'lice head'..
or kicking his shins..
then he'd go ballistic.
I was sorry for the Ledda's.
The mother died young,
and the father..
Sometimes they fell off
the stairs, understand?
During medical checks, they
sometimes found something.
Sexual abuse?
I don't know a thing about it.
Linda, never mind
the search warrant.
Vincke! Ledda. Telephone.
Vincke.
Are you all right, chief?
I'm fine, yes.
That policeman..
Sorry, it was him or me.
- Next time it's you.
- The shooter.
I went on a family visit.
Somebody called Paolo.
Ledda?
Japanese trash!
That's our own number.
Are you all right, chief?
I saw Paolo.
We found your pills.
We know you're sick.
Shut up about me. Tell me
what you know about the scum.
We think that Van Camp..
blackmailed his
predecessor, Jean De Haeck.
It's about children. Right?
Who else is
involved? The baron?
If I give you dynamite..
will you keep it covered
up or will you let it blow?
- It will blow.
- Can I believe you?
Verstuyft. Is that
tracer connected well?
Can I believe you?
- Yes.
- No outside line?
It's an inside
line. He's in here.
Damn!
TOO SLOW
Vincke!
Ledda. Telephone.
- A drink?
- I'm here for work.
Sit down, Freddy.
I thought you preferred
being alone in a bar.
- I am alone.
- You've got me, don't you?
That can be worse
than being alone.
Any news?
They found Ledda's escape car.
- In the Helmstraat.
- That's very close to the Kerkstraat.
- His brother's house.
- We've been there.
Is that the official report?
'Dust on the pedals..
traces of animal faeces.'
- Faeces?
Shit. Dog shit,
cow shit. Shit.
Vincke, I know where he is.
Pigeon shit.
Coemans!
Sorry. I saw something move.
Sorry.
- Do you expect anybody?
- No.
Who's there?
Verheyen, Lemmens,
everything okay?
There's nobody. Nobody.
- Positions?
- Verheyen checks the north side.
- I stay near the entrance.
- Careful, people.
- Verheyen, see anything?
- Negative.
- We need more people.
- Quiet, nothing's happening.
Ask for backup!
The suspect has gone inside!
Suspect is in the
basement. I'm coming back.
Take me to the baron and
I'll let you live. Understood?
Lemmens, everything okay?
Lemmens? Lemmens!
Damn! Stay here.
Lemmens?
Come! Come, come!
Verheyen at north entrance.
I'm trying a lock-in.
Verheyen, Lemmens,
situation. Come on, answer.
Lock-in complete.
We're waiting.
Suspect sits on the S-stairs.
He has no way to go.
Put that down.
Idiot. Put that down.
Lemmens, what's
happening there? Lemmens!
The suspect has gone,
outside. Position unknown.
We stay standby.
Sergeant!
This is ridiculous.
I hired you. I paid you.
I've come to pay you back.
That attempt at your life
was an idea of your boss.
I was against it.
Shit! Sergeant!
Sergeant!
Around the other way. Come on.
How much do you want?
My son was being blackmailed. I
did it for him. Please understand.
Wouldn't you do the
same thing for your son?
- I don't have a son.
- And your father?
Wouldn't he have
done it for you?
- Shut up!
- We aren't animals, are we?
No, please!
Forgive me. Please.
I hired you. I paid you.
I did it for my son!
Weapon down! Weapon down!
Kill him! Kill him!
- Destroy him!
- Silence, baron.
Cowards! Cowards!
From Ledda.
Vincke, careful!
I need my pills.
- Who is your client?
- I need my pills.
- My pills..
- Forget about those pills.
I need my pills.
He's been here for more than 12
hours. Should we inform Judicial?
If you like them so
much, go work there.
He killed one of our men.
Judicial Police get him
when we are finished.
'When you read this, I'll
be on a beach or in a coffin.
Let it blow.'
If he'd been in a coffin,
we would have known.
The asshole is
laying on a beach.
We have time.
He'll get hungry or thirsty. Or
his shoulder will start to hurt.
Come on, boy. Talk!
Chief Vincke. Only
to chief Vincke.
Oh, no.
Daddy!
- Yes, Vincke.
- Coemans here.
I'm at the castle.
The police have left.
- Say that's not true!
- They left.
Say that's not true.
Chief, don't ask me that.
Marc, just answer
yes or no. Yes or no?
Yes. He's here with us.
He's been there for more than 15
hours. So we hear from our source.
And you assigned
the case to us.
Commissioner, how
come I don't know that?
It was because of a
protection assignment.
We didn't know..
National police couldn't
know it was Ledda.
He had no ID and
refused to talk.
I can't help it. That's
what they tell me.
Bullshit. But they're
bringing him over.
Too slow, Ledda?
He hasn't got it, chief.
- He really hasn't got it.
- Yes, Ledda.
- He just hasn't got it for you.
- And you?
It's always the same
with men like you.
Basically, you're okay..
but when you have problems, you
drag everybody down with you.
Guilty, innocent,
doesn't matter.
If you're looking for
a friend.. don't bother.
Let's not talk about
me. Waste of time.
What's the deal?
We patch you up,
we protect you..
and you fill the gaps
in our investigation.
The baron, chief.
The baron must hang.
If he's our man, absolutely.
Deal.
Tell me.
Should he be able
to follow too?
Let me start from
the beginning then.
- Mrs. Van Camp.
- Chief Vincke.
Bad news?
Mum, who is it?
It's ok, Ine. It's for Mum.
Did you find the murderer?
- A man from Marseilles.
- The murderer? The real murderer?
There's a problem, Ledda.
I have the story, but there's
no evidence against the baron.
- You have my testimony.
- Your testimony?
Shall I tell you what
a testimony is worth?
A woman and a child are
hit by a car in the street..
in broad daylight.
The woman dies instantly.
The child doesn't.
What does the driver
do? He wants to get rid of it.
Nobody around. He puts
the car in reverse..
and drives over the
child one more time.
This time the child is dead.
The driver drives away,
but it's not his lucky day.
There's a boy of
around twelve years old.
He saw everything and tries
to remember the license plate.
But he forgets one
letter. One letter.
You know what, Ledda?
One letter made the
difference in court.
The driver was
caught and acquitted.
There was no proof.
And the testimony?
Worth nothing.
Beautiful story, Mr. Vincke.
Aren't we friends then?
We have something in common.
Sadness.
Or wasn't the story about you?
Are you finished or is
there something else?
We have something
else in common. Anger.
But, yes, there
is something else.
I've got an audio
tape where..
- That first man.
- Van Camp.
Thank you.
I have a tape where he's
threatened with death..
by the baron.
I wouldn't want
it to get lost.
It's well hidden.
So if you stick
to the deal..
If I understand it
correctly, Ledda's testimony..
is the only thing we've got.
Not enough evidences to arrest the
baron, don't you think?
There's another evidence.
And why haven't
we seen that yet?
- You have to take my word for it.
- Your word?
Or Ledda's word?
Okay, I know enough.
Good. Congratulations
on this file.
We can no longer
ignore the evidence.
I can only report it, Gustave.
We can wait a week
with the arrest.
But that's it.
What should I do?
Run of to Brazil?
Baron De Haeck in the jungle.
You'd like that, wouldn't you?
No, Marcel, this
is my country.
People like me
made Belgium big.
I'm Minister of
State. I don't run.
One week. That's all I can do.
'That's all I can do.' Loser.
And your financial
games, Marcel?
Should I send copies of
invoices to the newspapers?
You're not even allowed
to be here with me..
mister prosecutor.
It's Ledda's
testimony, Gustave.
There's nothing I can do,
especially if he has real proof.
I'm sorry. There's
nothing I can do for you.
There has to be a solution.
Not while Ledda's alive.
He's stable now, but..
the problem is they waited
too long taking care of him.
We might have to
amputate his arm.
- And the Alzheimer's?
- Hard to predict.
One moment he'll be
lucid, the next he won't.
If he has to testify..
I hope this case won't
be dragged out too long.
- Is he deteriorating that fast?
- He's seriously ill.
Are you okay?
Yes. Thanks.
We have a problem, Ledda.
Tell me about it.
It's not certain that
you'll make it to the trial.
The baron will be pleased.
If you tell me
where the tape is..
I'll make sure
it won't get lost.
We have a problem.
The tape is already lost.
I forgot where I put it.
I don't even remember if I
wrote down where I put it.
If only you knew
how empty my head is.
Sorry. It might
come back to me.
Vincke? Would
you do me a favour?
Next time you come,
bring Stimorol.
And a pita.
My last wish.
- A pizza.
- No.
A pita! With a
t from 'too slow'.
I made my will, Joseph.
Don't try to break
my concentration.
With Jean gone, only you
and your wife are in it.
Your appointment as judicial
psychiatrist of Ledda..
signed by prosecutor Bracke.
You want me to declare
Ledda of unsound mind?
That man wants to
testify against me.
If they believe him, I'm lost.
And then what? One countercheck
and they blow me away.
They'll find out
that we're friends.
Psychiatrists don't just
talk to their patients, do they?
This leaves no traces,
so I've been told.
You can remove
me from your will.
It's not just about the will.
It's also about your wife.
She's so sensitive.
Would she understand it?
The parties, the young girls.
Do you really think Jean never
told me anything?
Joseph Vlerick,
judicial psychiatrist.
We know.
- It's okay.
- Sure?
Yes.
Shouldn't you
disinfect it first?
Yes, of course.
Absent-minded.
- So?
- He's out and has a hostage.
- Victims?
- He let the guards go..
but he has their guns.
- Where is De Keyzer?
- There.
There he is.
Ah, Vincke.
He must have a
reason. What happened?
All we know is that
he has a hostage.
He demands an armoured
car and two passengers.
You and Verstuyft.
- Who's the hostage?
- A doctor.
The judicial psychiatrist.
A BMW! It couldn't be worse.
Coemans!
If I don't come back,
look after her well.
He's not going to collect
the car. Mark my words.
Keep going, keep
going! Come on.
Alfa, Bravo, go!
Damn!
Vincke, feedback!
Feedback? You
shot the hostage.
Turn that off. Turn that off.
All units, block! Now!
You don't keep
your word, chief.
You're no better than
that asshole over there.
Go lay next to him,
while he's still warm.
I didn't know about
this, Ledda, really, I swear.
Do you know what the difference
is between you and me?
You believe in people.
That's very dangerous.
We can still solve
this together.
We're on the way,
the three of us.
On the way to
the light.
Ain't that true, shooter?
- Or don't you know any French?
- I do, Ledda.
The light.
Nirvana, the great light.
Well done!
You're so quiet, chief.
Are you afraid
of your friends?
- You're not a believer anymore, are you?
- We have to believe.
There are children
that count on us.
Keep searching,
Vincke, and you'll find.
Ledda! Ledda!
Did you give the order?
We judged the situation
and acted accordingly.
And that's it? Case closed?
I'm glad you're alive. I
don't care about the rest.
Are you sure of that?
Of what?
That you're glad
we're still alive.
This friend of De Haeck,
the judicial psychiatrist..
appointed by you?
I'm fed up with
your nagging, Vincke.
Better be a bit more careful.
We're on the way,
the three of us.
On the way to the light.
Keep searching,
Vincke, and you'll find.
The light. The neon. Wise guy.
Freddy, he did know
where the tape was.
The light was a hint.
The neon, of course.
Pita with a t from
'too slow'. He knew.
He did know! Torch.
- It's a pack of filthy lies.
- Lies?
It's the truth, baron.
And I can prove it all.
I'll destroy you, Van Camp.
What do you think, Vincke?
We'll see.
Will it work, or is he
going to get away with it?
We'll see, I said.
SubText:
NoRMITA.326