- English captions by emutt -
The light is somewhere here.
Shit! God...it's so dark.
So dead in here.
How about some music?
I could..
What kinda music you like?
Something mellow?
You can take your coat off...if you..want.
You're so wet.
So am I...I guess.
I'll just take it to the other room.
Ahem..is wine ok?
Wine's great.
Wait.
Here.
Cheers.
Is this music OK? If you don't like it I could...
I've never danced with another man before.
Have you ever been with a guy before?
Yeah.
Once.
When I was a teenager.
Gosh..it was...
What?
We had sex in his basement.
A friend of mine. Alexander.
My best friend really.
We were.....fifteen?
Sixteen.
He said that I was in love with him.
So I said so. Straight into his face.
"I love you"
What happened?
He beat the crap out of me.
I remember..he was swinging away calling me
"petaras..petaras"
Fucking gay...fucking gay. Fucking gay.
Never saw him after that.
He moved away.
My first guy was my uncle.
Uncle Charlie.
Uncle Charlie?
He was my dad's drinkin' buddy. We called him uncle Charlie.
What happened?
Well, one night he came into my room and fucked me.
How old were you?
12.
Did your..did your dad find out?
Oh yeah.
What did he do?
He pulled a knife and then he charged him.
You mean like..stabbed him?
No..no...he charged him...20 bucks.
- No!
- Yeah.
He said if anyone was gonna fuck his
boy he may as well make money off of it.
Figured I was ruined anyay.
- Jesus!
- Um hmm.
And uncle Charlie he had a lot of friends too so...
You mean your dad pimped you out?
Pretty much.
Wow.
So...
are you relaxed now?
Yeah.
Do you like me?
Yes.
Yes I do.
So...when are we gonna fuck?
This ok?
It hurts.
You want me to stop?
No. It's good. Just..just go slow.
You like that?
Yeah.
Tell me you like it.
I like it.
Tell me to fuck you.
- Say fuck me.
- Fuck me.
Say fuck me!
Fuck me.
Oh god.
- Yeah?
- Oh yeah.
You gonna cum?
Yeah.
- You gonna cum?
- Yeah.
Good?
Yeah.
Good!
I came with..without touching myself.
I know.
It's hot.
How'd ya do it?
Magic.
I'd tell ya but I'd have tah kill ya.
You never told me your name.
Yeah I did.
Well, maybe I forgot it then.
It's Alex.
Get the fuck outta here.
That's my name.
That was my friend's name.
You mean the one that..beat you up
when you said you love him?
Yeah.
Is your name really Alex?
Is your name really John?
Nope.
It's Georgy.
In Russia I was Georgy.
But, now in America I'm John.
Was that just a story about your father?
How do ya feel?
I feel free.
Free?
Yeah.
Nice.
...all this fuckin shit. Like your fuckin' pig.
Eddie!?
Oh my god it is you.
What's up homo?
Come here...give us kisses.
You bitch. In the building..not
even gonna say hi.
That's ok. I forgive you.
Let me look at you.
Damn girl.
Oh my god. You...you..you have to come inside.
You rememeber Jacob that skinny
queer I told you all about?
I showed her your picture
she was so into you.
He's in my place right now with some friends.
We're having a little [snort]. Hmm?
Eddie! It's me!
It's Leon.
Don't you even pretend
you don't know.. I'll
never speak to you again.
You'll break my heart.
LEON! Oh my god.
I know. Right?!
What's happenin' girl how long has it been?
Oh, I don't know. Don't embarass me about time.
Come inside I've got blow.
Blow blow for the ho ho.
- I don't know.
- Come on I'll adore you and bask in your fabulousness.
I don't know. It's kinda late.
What ya got school tomorrow bitch?
Ohh..I get it. You gotta get yer
beauty sleep for teacher. Huh?
You like those nerds with big cocks dontcha you whore.
No seriously, come inside I've missed you.
Come on.
- Alright.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
Here bitch take this. I'm older
you gotta do what I say.
Come on sexy bod..movin' down the hall.Yeah.
I'm back..I'm still not talkin' to you.
Listen up girls I have a surprise for you.
I brought it with me. You ready?
Ta-dah!
It's Eddie. Remember?
I told you about Eddie. I did.
Here..take your coat off..stay awhile.
Here liquor pig drink up. You better finish
every last fucking drop cuz I'll be checking.
That's Gary. He's a little writer friend
but really just a big lush aren't ya Gary?
Now Eddie you stand right here.
Center stage.
This is the Eddie
I always talking about, remember?
Hello?
An adult speaking. You don't remember?
Fine. Whatever.
Nobody listens to me.
Yeah, you talk too much. How can we?
Oh my god! You're so funny!
Give me some coke, bitch.
If there's any left. Been gone for 4 fuckin' minutes,
it's all up your fuckin' holes.
Here Eddie have a toot.
Christ! How the fuck do you guys
do this shit?
Eddie, have a toot.
Eddie here gives the best blowjobs
fucking anywhere. In the fuckin' universe.
He's got no uvula
Had it removed from some Romanian
pimp or some shit.
Deep Throat Eddie.
That's your new name from now on.
Deep
Throat
Eddie!
Have a toot.
But that's not the best part.
Can I tell 'em?
Sure.
Ok, I'm gonna tell 'em.
You're looking at the only son of... wait for it...
Samuel Franklin Dobson, ex-mayor.
Samuel fuckin' Franklin Dobson
Isn't that right, Eddie?
And you tell them what you
said when you finally found out.
You tell them, you like the
story more than me.
Whatever, queen.
So, they come and take him
to the big scary mansion, you know?
And little Deep Throat
is still in her Go-Go outfit.
And his father's all like... blah, blah, blah!
No son of mine!
Mayor talk, mayor talk, mayor talk.
And he offers Deep Throat
here like a truck load of money and shit.
A college education, a job.
And all Deep Throat has to do is, you know...
end to this depraved life...
of godless butt-fucking. Right?
Well, Eddie here says...
Father, I am as God made me
and to follow you would be a great sin of all.
I know this story!
"My Own Private Idaho"
Keanu Reeves, River Phoenix.
Shut the fuck up!
I saw it, you saw it!
Every gay man in the universe has seen it.
I never saw it.
Yes, he's like the mayors son or the governor's son...
No, no. This is why no one talks to you.
That's why no one listens to you.
- If Eddie says that his daddy is the mayor...
- He was the mayor.
Was the mayor. Thank you Eddie.
Then Eddie's daddy was the mayor.
Yeah, right, okay. Yeah! He's the litmus test
of reality right now.
- You want to leave?
-No.
Then shut the fuck up.
- Your win... I'm listening. I'm quiet.
- OK..Shhh!
Bitch! Always have to say
something..Fuckin' .. fucking up my fucking high.
So..Anyway, little Eddie's
had this big ultimatum, right.
She has to clean up and go to college
or live the life of a hussy.
And she says: I am as God made me?
A dirty, butt-fucking, cum eating whore.
And she's cut-off without a cent.
That takes balls. Here have a toot.
Oh, that's ok.
Who are you?
Free drugs! I used to
push her out of the house.
No Eddie, there's no more drugs,
go home. God you're a machine.
Here take.
What's in the bottle?
Fine.
Sassy-pant, a
drink for our guest.
Get this man a drink.
Cuz you're a man now, aren't you Eddie?
Yeah.
Little Miss Deep Throat.
He's all Mister Clean and sober now.
Is that part of being a man?
I guess you'll never know.
Check you with the attitude,
Mr. Big Cock.
Not big enough
for that wide ol' hole of yours.
Ohhh...Oh, the lip, I love it!
Show off your cock. Come on..
just the head, just the one eye...come on.
How much?
Excuse me?
I'm strictly cash now.
You gotta pay to play.
Oh, no!
My little Eddie's all grown up.
I think I'm gonna cry.
It's hard to see them go.
No sir!
Not a dancing slut no more. Not a..
Not a drugged out devil but real
bonafide whore.
Cash only! Please!
I am an agent of desire.
A what? I like that.
"Do not ask me who I am, and
do not ask me to remain the same."
Hey, "Dingle-dick"! What movie is that from?
That's not a movie. It is Foucault.
Who?
Never mind.
I met him.. he's dancing at the Cirlcle-Jerk
and I just had to have her.
Wrap her up I'll take her.
Owww, such a whore. You're a born whore.
Yeah..I bring wonder boy home and
the rest is history.
That was good times, huh?
The best.
- I used to cook you dinner...
-Yeah.
We took care of each other, didn't we?
Yeah. We did.
I was so in love with this kid
I could never tell him tho.
He'd run for the hills, wouldn't ya?
Oh yeah.
Oow..We'd party!
We had fun. We had our
day in the sun as they say.
Those were good, good, good times, weren't they?
Yeah.
Good times! Good fuckin' times!
Hey, hey!
What?
Dance..dance for us.
Come on. I wanna see you dance.
Dance for us, River Phoenix.
Shut the fuck up!
Oh my god, there's my coke in my hands.
-Nope.. no, no it's yours!
No, god.
You wanna chop it up and snort it?
Oh, my God!
Hey..hey..dance for us!
No, I do not know.
Come on. Dance for us.
Shows 'em what you got.
Ohhh, wow. Lookie.. lookie Eddie.
Five whole dollars! Huh?
Come on, dance for us.
- Ok!
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
-  Really?
Yeah! Why not? Fuck it.
- For old-times sake.
Fucking Technicolor!
- Move queen!
- I'm trying, queen!
Ohhh.. I'll bash your fucking head in!
Wait. What are you doing?
Wait for the music.
God, so impatient.
Ah ha!
Yeah. Remember that? Yeah? Do you?
Wait, wait! Hold the show!
There, ladies and ladies.
Deep Throat Eddie in the house.
Do it!
Come on bitches!
Come on! I don't believe you're feelin' it!
Fuck yeah! Take it off!
Smell it. Smell it.
Take it off!
Shake that ass, take it off!
Fucking Shit!
Yeah do it. Fuckin' slut!
Yeah! Let's see all of it!
You can!
Ready the paper now nellies.
Come on. Dance bitch.
Look at Sassy-Pants.
Fuckin' blushing like a bitch.
Oh, Butt-munch.
Oh.. Come on! Bite it! Bite it.
Oh yeah.  Dirky you dick!
Yeah Dirk. Yeah, Grind it.
Fuckin' Whore!
Eddie.
You're a whore, aren't you Eddie?
Edidie..Eeeeddie... Whore boy.
So, you really him?
Am I really who?
Eddie. The mayor's son.
Yeah, I thought so.
I wouldn't tell Leon.
He likes these things, you know.
The way they were.
Yeah, I'm not ask your name.
Doesn't matter... names.
Probably make one up anyway.
But, you're beautiful.
Thanks.
What gave me away?
Umm..You're too smart to
be one of Leon's boys.
You don't do drugs.
Nah. You're no River Phoenix.
You know who you are?
Brad Davis
"Dying in your own arms."
Have you ever seen "Querelle"?
Shame on you.
Leon... ya know...
He sees things his own way.
As if the past is perfection.
What do you see?
I see you.
Whoever you are,
reflecting back on me.
So... You really a hustler?
Yeah.
Oh yeah? You gotta website? Shit like that?
No, no I don't like it like that.
Oh yeah? How do you like it?
Random, anonymous. I like adventures.
Ahhh.. Agent of desire.
That's right.
Right. So...
So...?
How much?
What did you have in mind?
Suck my cock.
- 50.
- Cool.
Can you break a 20?
I'm kidding, I'm kidding.
I guess I'll make it an even 60.
Come over here.
Ohh.. Do not worry about them.
Just come over here.
Oh yeah..
Oh fuck.
Wow. You really suck a mean dick.
Practice.
Wow.
You really shoot.
Sorry.
No, it's hot. I like it.
I think I got some in my eye tho.
It might have blinded me a little bit.
Think I'm gonna have to check my insurance plan
on that.
Alright then, Dirk.
I can smell my cock in your mouth.
Ask me how a gay men say goodbye.
How do gay men say goodbye?
I'll call you.
- Give it!
- No!
Come on you cow.
I'll tell him.
Fuck off cock face!
Give it slut. Or I'll use it
to set your stupid ass on fire!
Stupid cow!
And where have you been young man?
Rifling through your stuff.
Find anything good?
Nothing worth stealing.
Uhh huh.
You were playing with Dingle-Dick weren't ya?
I know you were.
Do not lie to me, I can see it in your eyes.
Did you suck his cock? How big was it?
Bigger than yours.
"Bigger than yours"
What would you do without cock?
In a world without cock, you'd starve.
You'd be like the last man on the planet
trying to suck his own cock.
Cuz it was all gone and she'd starve.
What are you doing?
Getting dressed.
Why?
Because that's the only way to put my clothes on.
No. You're more beautiful when you're naked.
Oh..I gotta get going.
But you just got.
I got school tomorrow, remember?
What? Cocksucking school?
You can practice that here!
Oh, right.
Little Eddie can't be late for school.
Up early. 7AM sharp.
Buttplug 101.
Yeah, and tuition's a bitch.
Don't go.
I gotta.
- But don't.
- But I gotta.
But don't.
Fine! Go! Bye!
Hey!
Give me a hug.
Fuck off, Hippie.
- Butt-Munch.
- Eddie.
- Sassy-Pants.
- You can.. it's Gary.
Whatever, Gary!
- Gary.
- See ya.
See you soon, Dirk!
I'll call you!
All righty.
Go to bed, young man.
Do not tell me what to do.
I don't even think that was her.
Honey, I'll be right back.
Where ya going?
I ah..I forgot something in the car. I'll be right back.
Okay, hurry back.
- Something I can I do for you?
- Oh. hey... hi.
Ah..I'm sorry... I know you?
Really?
Don't I you know?
I dunno, man, do you?
I thought...
I..I could swear I...
What is your name?
Max.
Max. Right.
Wow. I..I thought you were...
Are you new to the building? I mean..
Did you just move in?
No. I was just visiting some friends.
Can't find my way out of this place.
It's like a fuckin' maze.
Yeah. Ya know, when I first
moved in here I thought it
was like that hotel in the
Shining; total labyrinth.
Oh..I'm..I'm David.
You want something?
No..no, I just...
Hey um, I'm sorry if I scared you before.
- You didn't scare me.
- It's just..
You really..I mean..I..I thought..
Yeah, yeah. I look like your friend.
I got that.
Not a friend. Just... just this guy.
It's crazy, huh?
The way that people can..
Hey. Do you need help getting out?
I mean I can show you the way. It's..it's easy.
It's no problem. I've ah..It's..it's this way.
What is this?
Laundry.
Dude, this is the basement.
Where's the way out?
Look man...
It's right there. It's..it's right there.
I just...
I just wanted to...
Just want to ask you something, okay?
Ok.
Dude ask!
Look, I'm not fag, alright?
Alright.
I mean.... I have a wife and a baby girl.
That's great.
But you... see, you...
You're not... I mean...
You're not like... like...
Like what?
Like those guys!
These fucking faggots down the
hall. I fucking hate those guys!
They make me sick.
But, you and me.
We're both men.
What?
I want to suck you off.
Oh man...
I knew this was some fag shit.
I told you, I'm not a fag!
Alright, you're not a fag.
So where'd do you want a...
Here?
I dunno, man.
We can hear if someone comes.
We can totally hear.
And I can pay you!
40 bucks. Oow..45. 45 bucks.
And you just want to suck it?
Cuz I don't get fucked or
kissed or none of that fag shit.
I know, I know, and it's cool.
It's cool.
Come here.
Slow down.
Turn around.
Dude, I told you: I don't get fucked.
I want to eat your ass.
Turn around.
You like that?
I love it.
You really do go for that ass.
Never really went for that but...
Dude...
Hey!
Hey watch it punk!
Here we are.
Welcome to attic central.
Sit over here. Huh.
Alright, let see what we have here.
Tip your head back.
Hold this up.
Just a little pressure. There ya go.
Be right back.
I guess you're a night owl, huh?
I never sleep. Sleep is for the young.
Don't you want to sleep?
Oh, I'd love it. "To sleep, perchance to dream."
Nope. Instead, it's laundry.
Laundry and books.
They make pills for that.
What? For laundry?
Sleep.
They have pills for everything.
Let's see.
Well, the bleeding stopped.
Yeah, I think so.
Did he break it?
No, no it's still there.
Good.
I'd hate to see this magnificent mug
of yours malled and maimed.
Time will do enough of that. Believe me.
Here, let me take this.
You know they say we all get the face we deserve
by the time we reach 40.
Oh is that right. It's what they say?
Well, I've stopped worrying about
that a long ago.
OK, let's see.
Ahhh, I think you'll live.
That guy really clobbered you.
No. I had him right where I wanted him.
- Is that so?
- Yeah.
If you hadn't shown up
he'd a been toast.
Well, I'm sorry I interrupted you.
Well, that's alright.
And what do we call you,
my foundling from the basement?
- Jeff.
- Jeff. Nice to meet you, Jeff.
- I am Sam.
- Nice to meet you.
There we go.
Good as new.
Ok, hold that there.
They fill up so fast.
I thought up here in the attic
I might escape the noise.
Top floor apartment.
Rent control. No noises.
But I didn't count on rain.
Water, water everywhere...not a drop to drink.
Wish I had a jungle up here.
A jungle full of plants.
Plants to soak up all this water.
You know where that goes.
Medicine time.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
No, really, thank you.
Drink your medicine.
So...
What were you boys doing down there?
It didn't look like laundry.
Ohh man... it's a..it's a long history.
Alright.
Ah..Well, let's see.
Oh. First of all, I've been trying to get
out of this building for like an hour.
Trying to get out of the building.
Yeah, I can't get free of this place.
It's an apartment building. It isn't purgatory.
I know, but...
I keep getting lost or .. or side tracked.
I mean this place is like a maze.
It's like a labyrinth?
Well, which is it? A labyrinth or a maze?
What's the difference?
Well, a maze is a trap.
A labyrinth goes somewhere.
Let me ask you something.
Is every man in this apartment building gay?
I mean, is it something in the water or what?
I do not know.
Well, I'm sure there are a few
straight guys walking around here somewhere.
But... this is the gayest building on the gayest
street in town.
Is that a problem?
No.
Are you gay?
As pink ink.
So...
So, I'm in the hallway and
this guy says he can
show me the way out.
Oh...
Then what happened?
Ah..he leads me down to the basement, and..
Yes ..
Well, first of all he goes out
of his way to tell me he's not gay.
Hmm..I see.
And then tell me he wants
suck my cock.
The guy who beat you?
He didn't beat me. He hit me.
Ahhh.
He cold-cocked me out of
the blue. The dick.
Oh really?
I tell you...
He..he had that look in his eyes like..
he really wanted to kill me.
And he probably did. Poor guy.
I'll be alright.
Not you..him.
He is the poor guy? Look at my face!
You were just lost.
He's the one who's trapped.
How is he trapped?
What? You mean?
Because he thinks he's not a man?
Cuz he craves the cock
but he's living this lie? Is that it?
Because then, who is he? Right?
I mean, no one. Who..who can know who he is?
And you, sir?
What?
Who are you one wonders.
I'm just a guy.
Just a guy.
And how do you see yourself?
You mean, as a man?
You mean, am I a gay man?
I don't know.
I guess so, I mean... I suck cock.
Well, that's a start.
Yeah, and I ain't ashamed of it either.
Well, good for you.
I like to having sex with guys.
I like turning them on.. getting fucked.
What kind of guys?
Ah, pretty much anybody.
I'm not..I'm not gay.
You know, I mean, I am but..
I don't go to parades.
And I'm not wrapped up in rainbows.
I don't want to get married.
So you are not politicized.
Yeah.
But the very act of
loving a man is in and of
itself a political
statement don't ya think?
Nah, I've never fell loved a guy.
You haven't loved a guy, yet.
Ok. I haven't loved a guy, yet.
And since I've had sex with girls.
Well, whoop-dee-do! Me too!
But you said you were gay.
You know what? Fuck gay.
Yeah, fuck gay.
Fuck it. I don't believe in it.
Well it believes in you.
You know, guys like me fought in the frontlines..
so that guys like you could enjoy
the luxury of felling so ambivalent.
Ya still get punched.
Yeah, still get punched.
So you're not gay.
Maybe you're just... queer.
Maybe.
Or maybe it's just a traveler..
a sightseer.
Maybe.
A nomad explorer.
Maybe I'm just a dude.
Maybe you're just a tourist.
Or maybe I'm just a whore.
Maybe?
Now..when you say... whore...
Oh God!
Old man, you really like to fuck.
You have no idea how...much..
How much..how much I needed that.
Oh mama!
Hey, no... no stop.
Ok, stop..
Here ya go.
Oh mama! That is one sweet ass son.
You have made this old man very happy, son.
Old guys fuck the best.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Why is that?
I don't know.
They care ya know, how it feels.
Younger guys they just...
Well, it's very nice of you to say.
But, I'm afraid I'd be just like them
if I had a few years off me.
I still like old guys best.
You ever make regular clients of the
guys you've played around with?
Nope.
Pity.
Why is that I wonder.
I like everything new.
Oh, well...new.
Nothing in the world is new kid.
I'd hate to be the one to tell you.
New to me then.
What will you do when you have
had all your dalliances..with all there is to have?
You mean when I've fucked every fag in the city?
Yes.
I'll move.
The wandering hero.
That's right. I go where my body takes me.
I like that.
I like the thought of you out there
wandering around, somewhere.
Bringing pleasure to the world.
For a price.
Oh Right. Right. We can't just give
ourselves away now can we?
Nobody's that altruistic.
More like a man's gotta eat.
Damn right.
Pay rent.
Oh yes, the rent.
And going to school, perhaps?
Umm hmm.
Perhaps.
What?
This is nice.
Beautiful boy.
- Sam?
- Yeah?
How old are you?
Old as the sun. And you?
You see those?
The flowers?
Yeah, I see them.
That's how old I am.
No. No, no son.
You're much older than those.
Your body may be young, but...
There. You see that picture?
Umm hmm.
That's how old you are.
Oh, shit!
Hi.
You're still here?
Yeah.
I think this place doesn't want me to leave.
I forget. Are you Butt-Munch
or Sassy-Pants?
Just Gary, ok?
Cool.
Anything I can do?
Wait, wait.
Sup?
Did you mean that?
Sure. Absolutely.
Have a seat.
Is wine ok?
Wine's good.
- Cheers
So...
How about some music?
- Sure.
- Yeah?
I got...I got a really good playlist.
Wow...you're really here.
When you walked into Leon's
I was like freakin' wow.
You know that..that feeling in your stomach,
You never met some but you just
feel like you've known them for a long time.
This is gonna sound really crazy.
But I swear... I dreamed about you.
- We just met like two hours ago.
- I know.
That's the crazy part...
Or creepy.
I don't mean to be creepy.
No..it's cool.
What time is it?
I do not know. I think it's too late.
I'm never gonna get any sleep.
Do you want to go?
- Are you nervous?
- My God, yes!
It's okay.
- Do I make you nervous?
- Yes.
Why?
Because your'e so.. you're so beautiful.
To me.
Thanks.
Can I ask you a question?
Sure.
Are you really hustler?
Yep.
Did you ah.. did you really sleep with Jacob?
I do not know. Who is Jacob?
Dirk. Leon..Leon calls him Dirk.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah I did.
You mind if I take this off?
Yeah, I'm sorrry. Please. I'm sorry.
Thanks.
So.. I have some money.
Great.
Do you think maybe you'd want tah...
Sure.
Ok.
So...
How much?
Depends.
What did you have in mind?
I..uh..
I really want to kiss you.
Come again.
I said I wanted to kiss you.
You're kidding, right?
No.
I'm sorry... I just..I don't kiss.
How come?
I do not know. It's too... It's so...
yuck ya know. It's too..
Intimate?
Yeah.
It's too real.
- 100 bucks to make out with me.
- Dude!
I am a great kisser.
I am, I swear I am.
I'm sure you are!
But...I mean you're a goodlooking guy.
You should find someone who'd...
But I want to kiss you.
Umm..150? 160?
Oh man are you..
What...that's gotta  be more than
you made all night.
You have no idea how much
I made tonight.
- Why?
- Why what?
Why me? Why now?
And don't say because you dreampt about me.
Because you're right, that is fucking creepy.
I mean..can't we just fuck?
No, I don't want.... I don't want to fuck.
I want to...
I want to kiss you.
I want to kiss you. I want to kiss you deep.
For like days.
Why?
Because if you kiss me, then I won't be alone.
You know? Like..Alone, alone.
Five fucking minutes.
And then you'll leave, and you'll go..and..
I can have that.
Can I have that kiss,
I can remember that kiss.
Because the kiss will be mine.
Cuz I know that you're gonna touch my soul.
That's..that's really where I
need to be touched right now. OK?
Not on my cock, not my hole...
Right here, right here. This is..this is my hole.
And I'll pay for it.
I'll gladly, happily fucking paying for it.
You got your life savings in there?
Here. 200, 200 bucks.
All you gotta do is make out with me.
And what if I don't touch your soul?
Make fun of me all you want.
I'm not making fun of you.
Dude, what if I can't?
Well..that's a chance that I'm willing to take.
Fine!
So kissing it is.
Really?
Yep, really. Give me the fucking money.
Alright. How do you want to do this?
Right here.
Right here?
Yeah.
Like that?
No.
What?
You really are a good kisser.
Come here.
What? What?
No one's ever kissed me like that before.
Is it okay?
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Just that ah...
What?
Nothing.
Feel that?
I feel that, I feel that.
Kiss me.
Holy shit!
- Holy shit!
- Right?!
I can't believe I came like that.
Me too, me too.
Are you going to sleep?
No. I'm awake.
I can hear your heart.
Umm..I'm loving this too ok, but my
leg's asleep.
Sorry.
Head rush.
Hey, wash up.
Thanks.
Hey, right here, right here.
Score.
Save that for later.
Got what you wanted?
Yeah. I did.
I feel whole again, you know?
What?
I raise up in the current of my  love.
Borne high by this shower of light.
Full of you.
And lost.
And then the light reaches my eyes.
Glances off the mirror of my soul.
And I am united once again.
Did you write that?
No, but... but I'm going to.
Who is this?
Oh..It's me!
Yeah I got that from my mom's house.
It reminds me of..me. I don't know.
You got me all...inspired here.
Hey, you know, you can crash here if you want.
No, no. Umm..I gotta get going.
I gotta keep moving.
Here.
What's this?
It is a..a griffin.
It's magic...from the sun.
It guards the treasure.
It's good luck!
OK. Thank you.
Sayonara.
Oh..How the fuck do I get out of this place?
Just turn to your right, and then stairs
to the lobby, and out the door.
Simple as that?
Simple as that.
Cool.
- See ya.
♪ capture all ♪
♪ those people ♪
♪ they seem happy ♪
♪ take them all ♪
♪ for us to measure ♪
♪ then tie them up tightly ♪
♪ catch their fathers ♪
♪ and cut them in two ♪
♪ and leave the rest to watch ♪
♪ weaker now ♪
♪ despite our efforts ♪
♪ years resisting ♪
♪ beneath us ♪
♪ we'll never lift them out ♪
♪ believe us ♪
♪ years from now ♪
♪ with all their weapons ♪
♪ they'll make it up somehow ♪
♪ and here among the crowd ♪
♪ lies another one ♪
♪ another one ♪
♪ and here among the crowd ♪
♪ lies another one ♪
♪ another one ♪
-- Captions by emutt --