English for CHINESE Audio Parts Only.
Salman SK release. "Sword of the Stranger [ENG] 720p BDRip salman sk.mkv"
Ayubowan!
ආයුබෝ වේවා!
Time: Sengoku Era (~1493 - 1598),
a time when Japan was divided
into many warring providences
each ruled by a feudal lord
Location: AKAIKE
a small and poor providence by the sea
Other: Ming Dynasty/Ming,
refers to China...
which was ruled by the Ming at the time.
Doshi, Kamou, the crates!
Keep firing!  Keep firing!
Against those numbers,
Lord Rarou (Luo-Lang) alone is enough.
Both crates are safe.
Is this the level of
swordsmen in this country?
Akaike Providence
Why don't you draw?
Is your blade a fake?
AKAGE...
Akaomi Nanashi  [Nanashi=Nameless]
It's taken many years...
To get Byakuran before us,
When the source of
immortality is in his hands,
The Emperor will be most pleased.
That was a long wait... we finally meet.
Afraid?
Pretending that you don't understand?
Or are you so afraid you can't speak?
Everyone eventually dies.
There's no one with infinite
time in this world.
Even you'll live strongly in
the time that's left for you.
If you're going to kill
me, hurry up and do it!
Don't rush to your death, I
have something I must ask you.
When you were taken from the temple,
there was a man who tried to save you.
A friend?
No idea.
Answer honestly.
I don't have any friends!
It seems like I won't
get an answer from you.
It doesn't matter... that man
was killed by my comrades.
Bastard!
That's what you deserve!
I wouldn't try.
I'm enough of an
opponent for all of you!
That guy...
Use this....
.
(In Brocken Japanese:)
U S E
D R U G
P A I N
G O    A W A Y
That's great.
That's really great.
I like you more and more.
This is the first time
I've ever been cut.
The pain of a sword,
Somehow... strange...
Strange!..
A strange feeling...
wWw.BuGGeRs.Tk
Jaya Wewa!
ජය වේවා!..