- Good morning, Patrick.
- Good morning.
- Hi, Patrick.
- Hello, David.
David, you might need these.
What time did you folks leave last night?
Don't even mention it.
Don't lose your books.
- So long, David.
- Goodbye, Daddy.
I have a theory that men are only honest
with each other over breakfast.
You know, before they put the armor on.
Tell me something, Coe.
Did my name mean anything to you
when you heard it over the phone?
No, I'm afraid not. Should it have?
I've achieved a certain degree of fame.
I'm a writer.
- Ever heard of a book called Star Reach?
- No.
Disaster?
No, but then I don't get a chance
to read much fiction.
You can't expect to enlighten everybody
with two brilliant thrusts.
If you read anything at all...
...you'd know that
Star Reach was serialized in the Post...
...was Book of the Month and MGM
bought it from its galleys for a picture.
Disaster is on the best-seller list
for 34 weeks...
...and Fox is shooting it right now.
You must be very successful.
- I'm King Midas.
- I'm delighted to hear that.
I like to experiment in my work
now and then...
...and that can run into a little money.
That whimper you just heard was my wallet.
Maybe I picked the wrong architect.
Maybe. How did you happen to pick me?
I ran across this in a magazine
in a dentist office.
And I liked it.
Yeah.
That's the only house I haven't wanted
to tear down and start all over again.
I know what you mean.
Someday I hope to get my publisher
to stop sending me galley proofs.
Every time he does that,
I try to rewrite the whole stupid book.
So, how do we go from here?
First how much do you want to spend?
Like to keep it under $100,000.
We'll certainly do something with that.
It depends on the kind of house you want,
and whether or not we can agree on it.
- At $100,000, you'd disagree?
- It's possible.
What are you,
one of these temperamental artists?
If you want to call it that.
The kind of house I design
won't advertise you, it'll advertise me.
I can't afford to have a dull house
go up with my name on it.
You ought to understand that.
Who gets the review, you or your editor?
- More coffee?
- No, thank you.
Good hips, that girl.
All right, let's say our tastes agree,
now what?
I want to see your lot, of course.
But first I'd like to read your book,
Star Reach.
My second one was better.
But aren't first ones
usually autobiographical?
Bright boy. You do read a little.
Before I go to the drawing wood,
I must know everything about you.
So far, all I know about you
is you like coffee and hips.
There are some closets I don't want opened.
I'm no stool pigeon.
Suppose you think the book's lousy?
Let's not look for trouble before we start.
- There'll be plenty of that, anyway.
- Sounds like a kidney operation.
No, it's not that bad, really, but...
You know, Altar,
designing a house for somebody...
...that's a very personal thing.
I like you, Coe.
You like me?
I'm not sure yet. I think I will.
- I'm not asking you to marry me.
- I'd have to refuse.
- Hi, there, Larry.
- Hi, Felix.
Eve called. Said you forgot the meat order.
I told Harry to have it ready.
Thanks. How'd you like the party last night?
Didn't care for it very much, Larry.
Of course, I may be old-fashioned, but
I think Bud goes a little far, don't you?
How do you mean?
You know, those jokes he tells.
I took Betty right out of the room.
I'm not a prude,
but there's no place at a party...
...for that kind of innuendos. Suggestion.
- I think Bud's harmless.
- Maybe I'm just old-fashioned.
Maybe you are. Excuse me.
Miss, I think you walked off with my cart.
No, I'm sure I...
I'm sorry, I must have been daydreaming.
Don't you think it might be easier
if we wheeled it over to your cart?
I guess it would.
You're Patrick's mother, right?
I saw you at the bus stop this morning.
- I'm David's father.
- Yes, Betty Anders was talking about you.
- How do you like the book?
- I haven't started it yet.
- I started it, but...
- But what?
His women seemed false to me.
I don't know.
It just seemed shallow somehow,
so I never finished it.
- He'll be delighted to hear that.
- Do you know him?
I'm doing a house for him.
That's right, you're the architect.
You must be a good one.
Betty said you won a prize.
A long time ago.
How do you like the neighborhood?
- I thought you'd just moved in.
- Last month. It's fine.
People are
pretty much the same everywhere.
I guess that's everything.
I'm sorry I stole your groceries.
You're not so pretty.
I have to go.
Good afternoon, Mrs. Gault.
Nice woman. Very pleasant manner.
- I caught you. You drink your milk now.
- How much?
You drink this much,
and then you can tell me a secret.
- No. That much.
- Okay, let me see you do it.
Larry, is Mr. Altar as solemn
as he is in the picture on that book?
No, not at all.
I kind of like him, Eve.
I think he's willing to take a chance
and let me do the house I really want to do.
That's the important thing, isn't it?
With enough money, so I don't have
to worry about the plumbing.
Will that be a relief.
I'm glad you made a good impression.
I was afraid you'd get there
and not understand a word he was saying.
What do you mean?
I don't know. I just thought
you'd have a head this morning.
I've got a head. Everybody's got a head.
Have you got a head, Peter?
Really, Larry. You knew
you had an important appointment.
A couple of martinis never hurt anybody.
They make me amorous.
You just think they do.
Martinis don't mix with s-e-x.
What's x-e-x?
Never mind. You just drink your milk.
Is it like Santa Claus?
In a way, son.
Is Daddy doing a house for Santa?
No, darling, he's doing a house for a writer.
I'm glad this is what you want, Larry.
I'm happy.
I think it's going to be very exciting.
- I'm glad.
- Guess what?
What, Peter?
- Guess.
- You lost a tooth?
No, but I wet the bed again last night.
You'd better be more careful, son.
This wasn't on my list.
That must be...
There was a slight mix-up at the market.
Between me and this gorgeous blonde.
- Really? Who?
- Patrick's mother.
Margaret Gault. Betty told me about her.
I hear she's very beautiful.
He drags me home from the party early.
He says he's tired.
So I get all set to watch television.
But not Felix.
He has to carry me upstairs
like a regular hero.
You know, I swear that man's got
one thing on his mind day and night.
It's getting so lately that I go out
to lunch so he won't come home for lunch.
I guess they're all alike, though.
Is Ken that way?
Yes, he's that way.
There are times
when my husband bores me stiff.
Does Ken bore you?
No, never. He's always very interesting.
Well, a girl like you.
You know, you're so beautiful,
sometimes I can't even stand you.
Old Octopus will be home for lunch soon.
I'd better get home.
- Nice to meet you, Mrs. Wagner.
- Thank you.
- Thanks for the coffee.
- Sure.
- You get a chance, come on over later.
- Okay.
Hello?
You. How did you get my number again?
No. Never.
I'll call the police
if you don't stop calling me.
Margaret, shouldn't Patrick be home
by now?
Yes, he'll be home soon, Mother.
They keep them awfully long nowadays.
When you were...
If you'd rather not wait for him,
it's perfectly all right.
I'm sure he only gets in your way.
I love to have him with me.
In fact, I wish you'd let him stay all night
with me once in a while.
It gets awfully lonely
in the valley all by myself.
All by yourself, Mother?
Who was on the phone, dear?
Just one of the women. A neighbor.
Something wrong? You seem disturbed.
No, nothing's wrong. If you don't mind,
I've got a lot of things to do.
- If I can help in any way.
- It's a little late, isn't it?
- I'm interested. I simply want to...
- You're interested in me?
Don't judge me. I'm not to be judged by you.
I'm still your mother, you know.
- Yes, I know.
- Yes, Margaret, I am.
And I know a little bit more about life
and living than you might imagine.
I imagine you know a great deal
about life and living, Mother.
You're a very cold person, Margaret.
I never could talk to you.
I used to wonder when it all happened...
...how I'd be able to explain it to you
when you were old enough to listen.
How I could make you understand what
honest-to-God love could do to a woman.
Of course, it was pure and beautiful.
I'm not a tramp, Margaret.
Please understand that.
I'm not a tramp.
What happened to me
could happen to any woman.
I don't want to hear it.
Do you know what I wish, Margaret?
I wish you'd really fall in love someday.
I am in love, Mother. With my husband.
Yes, of course.
Margaret, you married
the first nice boy that came along.
- Mom.
- Maybe it was my fault, but...
Excuse me, Mother.
See you later, Margaret.
Good morning.
I think we've got a box of corn flakes
that belongs to you.
- I read that book last night.
- How did you like it?
I saw what you meant. He doesn't see
the world very clearly, does he?
All he needs is a good house to live in.
Better give him lots of windows.
Say listen, I'm on my way now
to take a look at his property.
- Would you like to come along?
- No.
Just thought you might be interested.
- I am, but...
- It's not very far.
Not this morning. Thank you.
Maybe some other time?
Change your mind.
- Where is it?
- Bel Air.
- Is this something you do all the time?
- What do you mean?
I don't know, ask a perfect stranger to...
I just feel odd sitting here
with someone I don't even know.
I'm David's father.
You feel better now?
Suppose someone should see us?
We'll have to tell them the truth.
That we're running off to Mexico together.
Would you mind turning back, please?
Are you serious?
Yes.
Well, okay.
- I'm sorry. I just don't feel right.
- That's okay.
I saw one of your houses.
The one in Better Homes and Gardens.
I like the way the fireplace is standing
free in the middle of the room like that.
You know,
that's a caveman concept of architecture.
A roof over your head, a hole to
look out of, and a fire to huddle by.
It was a strange house.
- It was just an experiment.
- No, I liked it.
It had strength and confidence.
How'd you come across such an old issue?
Betty told me your house was in it...
...and I looked it up
in the library yesterday.
Look, this is silly.
You don't really want to go back, do you?
- This is it.
- It's beautiful.
Altar certainly picked himself a spot.
But it's so naked.
You must remember
Mexico is a very primitive country.
That's right.
Here, take this end and go out to
that point, right by that boulder there.
Okay.
- Watch out for the brush.
- All right.
- Will it go that far?
- Sure it will.
Okay.
- How are you going to do it?
- Do what?
If you put a house up here,
it'll roll right down into the street.
We'll have to anchor it to a cloud.
Stay right there and hold it tight
while I go over to the other side.
Yes, sir.
- I love the smell of earth.
- I do, too.
That about does it.
- You mean that's all?
- Just the beginning.
- What's it going to look like?
- I think I know.
- You've been very helpful. Thank you.
- Thank you.
Maybe you'd better drop me off here.
- I'll take you to your door.
- No, please. This would be fine.
Maybe you're right.
This okay?
Yes, thank you.
- I'm glad I came along.
- So am I.
Goodbye.
Who are you?
I was about to ask you the same question.
I'm Larry Coe.
- Sure. Come in.
- Thank you.
So you're the architect?
- That's who I am.
- I'm Marcia.
Hello, Marcia.
Let's hear some of your plans.
Where's Altar?
The genius? He's working.
Would you like a drink?
No, thanks. It's a little too early.
- Do you mind if I have one?
- No, please.
What's he working on?
The Fall of a Stone. Do you like that title?
Are you married or something?
Yes, I'm married or something.
Choke.
You're missing a lot, architect.
Maybe we both are.
Maybe you'd better tell Altar I'm here.
What, and have him snap off my head?
Do you think I'm crazy...
- I thought I heard you. You been here long?
- I just got here.
You still here? I thought you left long ago.
- Now, how can I leave? I'm your inspiration.
- Sure. Baby, I hate to disillusion you.
- You need all the inspiration you can get.
- Go fly a kite, will you, sweetheart?
- Had your breakfast yet?
- And lunch.
- And lunch? What time is it?
- After 3:00.
No wonder I'm so hungry.
I've been at this thing since 4:00.
- I can't get it right.
- And you won't.
Look, Marcia whatever-your-name-is...
...would it hurt your career
if you kind of cleaned up the joint?
My talent doesn't lie in that direction.
You haven't got any talent.
You don't have any talent.
I don't? You see, he gets lucky
with a couple of books...
...all of a sudden,
he's an important American writer.
I am an important American writer.
The critics said that he wrote with
facile ease, but he hasn't got a thing to say.
The critics. I eat them
like the pieces of cheese they are.
He's dying because they pan his books.
It kills him.
Yeah, I cry all the way to the bank, okay?
All right, now go someplace
and practice your fast draw.
- We're all out of Holland gin.
- And I can understand it.
Got to get rid of that miserable lush.
I'd like to go over those sketches with you.
Lot of laughs, that kid.
Sit down and have something to drink.
No, thanks. Let's get to work. I got
a few appointments with some builders.
Did you have trouble reading the sketches?
- No, I read them fine.
- Good.
It's pretty different from the house
I saw in the magazine, isn't it?
You didn't expect the same house, did you?
I don't know what I expected.
You're the architect,
you've said so often enough.
What's the matter with you all of a sudden?
Nothing.
No, there's something eating you.
What is it, Rog?
I showed your sketches
to some friends of mine.
They said I'd have to be nuts
to live in a house like that.
Who's going to live in it,
you or your friends?
That's not the point.
Nobody lives in a vacuum.
I don't want people pointing
to this oddball house:
"That's where that kooky writer lives. "
What do you want?
A house like everybody else's?
The house in the magazine
wasn't like everyone else's.
I designed that house
for a Fresno lawyer with kids.
This house is for you.
Sure. What if I have to get rid of it?
Suppose my next book flops?
And the book after that? What do I do then?
Wait for a 36-year-old writer...
...with a mustache to come along
so I can unload it?
What do you want? A guarantee
that you'll be successful always?
What difference does it make?
You design a house, up it goes,
you get 10%, good or bad.
With a book it's different.
I've got readers, I get reviews.
Shall I call your girlfriend back?
Maybe you'd like to slap her around
as I'm too busy to play scapegoat.
What do you mean?
I'm discussing your house.
Your house, Altar.
Forget it.
All right, I made a mistake.
When I met you, I told my wife:
"Here's a guy who'll be willing
to try something different. "
- Boy, was I wrong. You want to play it safe.
- That's not true.
What are you afraid of?
That some critic won't like your house?
This has nothing to do
with the lousy critics!
You know, Rog,
we both start with the same thing:
...a blank piece of paper.
But every time I try to play it safe,
I come up empty.
So now I just sit down at that drawing board
and do what I want to do.
And I hope what I like,
somebody else will like.
Maybe this isn't a great house,
I don't know.
Maybe somebody will think it's an oddball...
...but we can't try to please them all.
- You trying to say this is what I do?
- No, Rog, I don't know what you do.
I read both your books.
I like them pretty well, but...
Boy, I'd love to see what would happen
if you really broke loose.
Don't you think that's what I want to do?
Then do it. Write a book that you like,
and to hell with the critics.
You don't know.
Rog, I know one thing.
You've got to find out
what's important to you.
Sure, now this house is important to me.
And I was hoping you'd like it, but...
If you don't like it, we shake hands
and say goodbye. It's as simple as that.
You know something?
I think it's a great house.
Are you sure
I haven't talked you into anything?
Yeah, I think you did. Thanks.
There are a few improvements
I'd like to make.
- You know, this is an oddball house.
- You're an oddball character.
Look, let's take it one room at a time.
Hey, Maggie.
What did you call me?
Maggie. Why, something wrong with that?
No, nothing. How are you?
Fine. I feel just like I own
Southern California.
Altar just gave me the green light
on the house.
Of course, he doesn't know
it's going to roll down into the street.
That's wonderful. Congratulations.
I couldn't have done it without you
holding the tape. I owe you a commission.
How about an ice-cream cone
or a Coke or something?
Thanks, but I can't, really. I'm late now.
I'll owe it to you.
- It's going to be a very exciting house.
- Thanks, Maggie.
I'll see you.
- Margaret, are you home?
- Yes, I'll be out in a minute.
- Where's the mail?
- I guess I left it on the hall table.
- Hi. Did you just get home?
- No.
Why don't you get dressed?
Where's Patrick?
Betty's keeping him overnight.
I thought we could be alone.
I'm going to wash and change my shirt.
Telephone.
Margaret, telephone.
- Leave it.
- It might be important.
Don't answer it.
What's with you tonight?
Please.
Okay.
That phone's still ringing.
It's getting dark outside.
Tell me you love me.
Now, you know I love you, Margaret.
Don't you think I'm pretty?
- Of course.
- Then why don't...
Do you think of me
when you're working, Ken?
- Yes.
- What do you think?
- I don't know. I think of you.
- Do you think of making love to me?
- Now don't talk like that...
- How do you think of me, then?
Margaret, this is silly.
You know perfectly well
how I feel about you.
Tell me you want me.
Do you want me?
- You know I want you, Margaret.
- Then tell me. Talk to me, Ken.
- Honey.
- Tell me.
Don't you want to hold me? Hold me.
Margaret, we can't just...
- Why can't...
- Please, Margaret.
I'm sorry to rush things, but boy...
I've still got two hours of work tonight.
Always changes.
I tell you what.
Just give us a layout of the plan site...
...and a schematic
of one of the factory buildings...
...and after that, Martin can do the rest.
- Why don't you let him handle everything?
- Because it's right down your alley.
You won a prize
for doing almost the same thing.
- We're back to that again.
- I just wanted to illustrate a point.
That is the point. I've had it.
I don't want to keep doing
the same commercial designs.
I think the location alone
would interest you.
Look, I'm working on a house. I like it.
I can't go hopping off to Hawaii.
That wouldn't be necessary,
would it, Mr. Baxter?
Aren't there photographs
of the proposed site?
Sure there are. Some good ones, too.
I prefer to get a feel of the terrain.
You know that.
Actually, the terrain is no problem here.
We've got a good flat parcel of land.
- Good night, Mr. Baxter.
- Good night.
What do you say, Larry?
We figure the job is worth $3,000.
I think it's worth more than that.
What Larry means is
he's been getting the work...
What I mean is that I'll be working
on two jobs simultaneously...
...and trying to give them both my best.
More than $3,000.
Thank you, sir. Good night.
How much would you want?
I think the job's worth $5,000.
Isn't that a shade high
for something like this, darling?
I think we can go to $4,000.
What do you say, Larry?
- Let me think about it, Stan.
- What's there to think about?
Are two grown men
going to start bargaining like fishwives?
I like you, Eve. $4,500, Larry. Top offer.
- Have we got a deal?
- All right, it's a deal.
- Thanks a lot for dinner.
- My pleasure. I'll phone you Monday.
- Will you send the photos over?
- As soon as I can get them to you.
Why do I let myself get trapped
into doing unimportant...
Trapped? What do you mean?
What do you think happened tonight?
You knew I didn't want that job.
I knew nothing of the sort.
Why do you think I left Baxter and Baxter?
I was beginning to feel like a machine
turning out plastic practical jokes.
So again I let myself get forced
into a job that doesn't excite me.
Doesn't offer any challenge.
It's something any architect could handle.
I didn't force you into anything.
You're right, honey. I'm a big boy.
I could have said no.
Honey, have you any concept
of what I'm actually trying to do?
Apparently not. I'm just a pushy housewife.
Do you think it pleases me
that I won a prize back in 1952...
...eight years ago, and that lousy prize
has been the high point of my career?
Now you're ashamed of it?
You talk like you're ashamed of it.
No. It's just that I'm not the wonder boy
anymore. This is 1960...
Larry, for heaven's sake.
Time doesn't stand still,
you either change or you die.
Would you mind telling me
how this job is going to kill you?
I realize I'm terribly dense and stupid,
but I don't understand.
Look, for once, just try to understand.
I didn't want this job because
I want to concentrate on the Altar house.
That's something I want.
Something that excites me.
I've got things I want to state
as an architect.
And if I don't get them
out of me, I'll bust.
You know what I'm trying to say?
Do you understand?
I understand, Larry.
But what comes after the Altar house?
I think we should be grateful to Mr. Baxter.
Heaven knows we can use the extra money.
Linda. We're home.
- Hi.
- Hi, Eve.
Were the kids okay? Did they wake up?
Not a peep out of them all night.
- Who's winning?
- I don't know. Who's playing?
It's not quite 11:00, sis.
Do you want me to lift Peter before I go?
I'll do it, Linda.
- Good night, Larry.
- Good night, Hank.
Sis, there was one little fuss.
Daddy?
- What are you doing awake?
- Is it time for school yet?
No.
Mommy and I just got home.
Get back to sleep.
Daddy, tonight Peter was messing around
with my record player.
He broke the needle
and scratched up the record.
And when I tried to stop him, he got mad
and threw one of his blocks at me...
...and almost broke the window.
And when I told Lindy,
she said it was just an accident.
But it wasn't no accident, Daddy.
- We'll have to talk to him about that.
- I think you should beat him up.
We'll figure something out
in the morning, okay?
- Okay.
- Get back to sleep.
- David?
- Yes, Daddy?
I'll drive you to
the bus stop in the morning.
Okay, Daddy.
Have you got plenty of pencils
to write with?
You'd better move over here.
You wait for him, he'll be along.
There he is. Hurry up, Patrick.
Come on.
There you go.
- Thank you.
- I'm going to the lot again. Come with me?
Thank you, no.
- Come with me.
- No.
I want to see you again.
Why? You don't even know me.
I want to know you.
When can you get away?
No, I can't. I couldn't.
- When?
- Don't ask me. I don't want to.
When? Tomorrow night?
- No.
- Thursday night?
Please don't think that I...
- 8:00?
- Where?
People will see us. Please hurry.
There's a place on the beach on the way
to Malibu. It's called the Albatross.
I'll find it.
Are you sure you want to see me?
Yes. Aren't you?
No, I'm not sure at all.
8:00.
- Patrick's sound asleep.
- Good.
- What time do you think you'll be back?
- 11:00, 11:30.
I don't really know, Ken. You know
how women are when they get together.
I know.
- If you'd rather I didn't go...
- Why, no, go ahead. Don't be silly.
I don't have to go, Ken.
Maybe we could get a sitter
and we could go out somewhere together.
I have a lot of papers to go over tonight.
Now you go on and have a good time.
Suppose I were going to meet another man?
Sure.
- Would it make you jealous?
- Of course it'd make me jealous.
But you don't think it's possible?
I mean, do you? That I would.
You're my wife, Margaret.
- It happens, you know.
- Not to someone like you.
I'm no different than anyone else, Ken.
I've got the same feelings,
the same passion...
- Now stop that. Don't talk like that.
- "Passion" isn't a dirty word, Ken.
Margaret, please, you know
I don't like to hear you talk like that.
Now, come on.
You go on and have a good time, okay?
If I'm not awake when you get home,
I'll see you in the morning.
- Hi, Maggie.
- Hi.
- I thought you weren't coming.
- I said I would.
- Shall we sit down?
- Sure.
- Did you have any trouble?
- No.
Let's not talk about it, please.
- Would you like a drink?
- Please.
Good. Waiter. What do you drink?
Anything. I don't care. What do you drink?
- Martini?
- Fine.
- Waiter, two martinis, please.
- Yes, sir.
It's crowded in here.
We're pretty far from home.
I don't think we have to worry.
- The waves are wonderful, aren't they?
- They're beautiful.
I got a builder for Altar's house.
A man named Di Labbia.
I think he'll do a good job.
We start next week.
I feel very guilty. Don't you?
Yes, I do.
Do you want to leave?
No.
Good. I thought we'd go through
that whole U-turn routine again.
Thank you.
- I'm sorry, sir.
- That's all right.
He's nervous, too.
- Do you like olives?
- Don't you?
I love them.
Why do you call me Maggie?
Doesn't everyone?
Just you.
Good, I'll be the only one
in the whole wide world to call you Maggie.
Funny that you should call me that.
I guess it's because
it's such an ugly name. Maggie.
But you make it beautiful.
My father used to call me Maggie.
What's your favorite name?
I have a lot of favorite names.
Tilly, Zelda, Lizzie, Brunhilda...
You've got a silly laugh.
No, I like it. You ought to
use it more often.
I want to laugh. I really do.
It's a very sexy laugh.
Larry.
Nothing. I just want to
try saying your name.
What shall we drink to?
- Everything.
- Like what?
Living, doing, being what we want to be.
That's all that's important.
Isn't that what everyone wants?
What do you want?
I want to make love you to you.
Do you know how I feel right this minute?
That I'm...
I'm sorry, I just can't.
Don't.
Please don't.
Don't start this.
If you start this, you'll just...
Please don't. Don't kiss me.
Please don't kiss me.
If you kiss me, I'll...
Yes.
Mom.
- Can I have some more milk, please?
- All right.
- What does Altar want this time?
- He thinks the study isn't big enough.
I won't be too long, dear.
Leave his number, will you?
In case I have to reach you.
- He isn't listed, you know.
- Sure.
I'll leave it here by the telephone.
- Good night, dear.
- Good night, darling.
Hey, Mr. Coe.
What's the matter? You don't trust me?
You got to go up on the roof to check?
I don't trust anybody
who wears leather elbow patches.
I'm gonna lose my shirt on this job.
- I figure I underbid by at least $5,000.
- Don't come weeping to me.
I never weep except in church.
But just watch me
when I start cutting corners.
Don't cut corners on me.
Remember, you're a bugler.
You play the song the way I wrote it.
Without me,
your song don't get played at all.
- I'm a very important guy.
- Good.
I'll get it, Ken.
Hello?
No, I can't right now.
Maybe in a few hours.
Bye.
- Who was that, Margaret?
- Betty Anders.
Did you kill anyone?
I don't know. It's hard to tell
when everyone's shooting at once.
I know.
Ken said the same thing. He was in the...
He was in the infantry, too.
I didn't like the Army at all,
except for the people I met.
There was one man in my outfit.
He was a magician in civilian life,
and he kept all his...
How did you meet Eve?
At a dance.
He kept all his tricks in his footlocker.
One day the CO came through
with some top brass...
Is she a good dancer?
Yes, she's a good dancer.
I hate to dance.
When did you meet her?
While I was still in the service.
Home on furlough.
Did you like her right away?
Yes, I did.
Look, Maggie, you know,
people aren't born married.
They meet, date, go steady, get engaged...
...the whole natural progression
that you and Ken...
Why are we talking about this?
- You love her very much, don't you?
- Come on, Maggie.
- Is it painful for you to talk about her?
- No, but I don't see why we keep on...
- Is she very bright, Larry?
- Yes, she is.
Do you think she's pretty?
What's the next question?
"Is she better than me?"
Go ahead, ask it.
I'd never ask that.
Why not? You've asked everything else.
I guess I'm afraid of the answer.
Maggie, you never have to be afraid
of anything. Never.
Kiss me.
What are you two guys doing?
Figuring out new ways to chisel me?
- Hiya, Rog.
- Daphne, Larry Coe.
- How do you do?
- Mr. Di Labbia.
- Hello.
- Want her number?
- Honey, everybody's got my number.
- Yeah, I know.
- This sure is exciting, isn't it?
- Don't pay any attention to her.
A checker game is exciting.
Crazy legs, though.
This little group of beavers running around.
What's this costing me?
Not enough, Mr. Altar.
- It looks like a big prison.
- Excuse me, I have some work.
What difference does it make?
You're King Midas, remember?
Sure. I'm beginning to
feel like your patron.
Getting the money from the publisher
with one hand...
- And giving it to you with the other.
- How is the book coming?
- I turned it in last week.
- Good.
Rog let me read all the best parts.
It's wonderful.
It's just like poetry.
All right if I go look at your house now,
Mr. Coe?
- Certainly.
- Sure, baby, you can go look at my house.
Your house.
Listen, you know the entrance
to the dining room?
Can it wait until tomorrow?
You know, I didn't expect you today...
I'm late now. Okay?
- What is it, a blonde or brunette?
- Neither.
Bald and 50, another potential patron.
What's the matter?
Don't you like the house anymore?
Of course I do.
What kind of a crack is that?
It's just that it's hard being enthusiastic
all by myself.
I'm sorry, Rog. Can you stop by tomorrow?
We'll walk through the whole thing
step by step...
- And work over the rough spots.
- Sure.
- I got a few extras.
- No extras. No more extras.
- I'll see you tomorrow. You'll like them.
- This is expensive wood.
You see, I thought I'd put
the shutters on the outside...
...see, so they stand out from the house
like this.
Don't you hate people
who draw on tablecloths?
Yes.
- Anyhow, you'll be able to...
- How do you shave that?
How do I shave what?
- That.
- It's very simple.
You see, I have a tiny little razor
with cylindrical blades.
And I put it here like this,
and I shave it very fast.
Oh, you.
I gotta call Ken. I promised I would.
I'll be right back, okay?
- Where did you and Harry go last night?
- We went to a new place.
I don't know...
One of those coffee houses.
- Did you want anything?
- Shove off.
- Look, Margaret...
- The lady's with me. You'd better leave.
You're not her husband, mister.
Why don't you shove off?
What's the matter with you?
All right.
It's over.
All right, it's all over.
Are you all right, Maggie?
Yeah, I'm all right.
We'd better get out of here.
What did he want?
- How did he know your name?
- He didn't.
- He did. He called you Margaret. I heard...
- You must have been mistaken.
- I heard him.
- I never saw him before in my life.
How did he know your name?
- What was this "It's all over... "
- Can we stop this, please?
Maggie. What is it?
Is the truth so terrible?
You sure you want to hear it?
Yes. I want to hear it.
All right.
It was this last summer.
July.
Ken was away on a business trip,
and Patrick was staying with my mother.
I was alone.
Forget it, Maggie. I've no right to know.
But you have to know, don't you?
It was very hot that day.
I was sitting out front
when a truck went by.
The driver waved and he smiled at me.
And I smiled back.
- He was the driver?
- Yes, he was the driver.
He came back the next night.
I was ironing and he rang the doorbell
and asked for a glass of water.
He said he was thirsty.
I didn't see any harm in it,
so he came in and he stayed awhile.
I was so grateful to
have someone to talk to.
So we talked.
He said he was driving the truck
for his father.
- They had a rug-cleaning business.
- So what happened?
He kissed me.
We were standing at the door,
saying good night.
Suddenly he grabbed me.
He was trembling all over like a baby.
What are we making such a fuss about?
There's more, Larry.
I got ready for bed after he left.
I was in bed when the phone rang.
It was him.
He said he was coming over.
I told him he was crazy, that I was in bed,
that I'd call the police.
- But he said he was coming over.
- Why didn't you call the police?
I have a young son.
I locked all the doors instead.
- Then I took some sleeping pills and I...
- Sleeping pills?
When you knew he was on his way,
you took sleeping pills?
I wanted to sleep. I wanted to hide.
Go ahead.
I was almost asleep
when I heard his car pull up.
He rang the front doorbell,
but I didn't answer it.
The pills were beginning to work. I couldn't
have gotten out of bed if I wanted to.
Then I heard him trying the kitchen door.
Then I heard the door open.
You said you'd locked it.
I did, but somehow he was in the house.
He called "Margaret" from the kitchen.
I lay there half-drugged, unable to move.
Then I heard his footsteps in my room.
And I couldn't move.
I tried to fight him, Larry.
I tried. Can you understand that?
No, I can't.
Why'd you take those sleeping pills?
- I wanted to sleep. I wanted to hide.
- Why'd you leave the door open?
- I thought it was locked.
- A door is either locked or it isn't.
You wanted him inside that house.
You didn't want to hide or sleep.
You wanted him to find you.
You took those pills
to make it easy for yourself.
And you wanted what happened.
All right, Larry. I wanted him.
That's what you really
want to hear, isn't it?
I wanted him.
You...
Would you please come in and settle this?
Pete got paste all over David's model,
and now David is yelling bloody murder...
- And I can't do a thing with either.
- All right. I'll be right out.
Daddy, I'm gonna kill him.
He smeared up my whole model.
It took me three days to make it.
- Don't worry, I'll clean it off for you.
- But he's always doing things like that.
- Peter's younger than you are.
- I know, but he's got his own toys.
- He lets you use his toys, doesn't he?
- Yes.
- You should learn to share things with him.
- Okay.
- Hey, Larry, tell Eve to call.
- Sure.
Come on, kids.
- Yes?
- Hello. I'm Larry Coe.
My wife missed Mrs. Gault
at the bus stop this morning...
...and asked me if I'd... Is anything wrong?
- I'm Margaret's mother.
- Hello.
- Come in, Mr. Coe.
- Thank you.
Margaret went to bed with a fever last night.
I came from the valley to give her a hand.
I'm sorry to hear that.
- You say you're neighbors, are you?
- Yes. We live down the street.
- Patrick goes to school with my son.
- How nice.
- Is this your day off, Mr. Coe?
- No, I'm an architect.
- I work at home mostly.
- How very convenient.
- Who is it, Mother?
- It's Mr. Coe, dear.
Why don't you go on in?
I'm just fixing some coffee.
Would you like a cup?
Thank you. That'd be very nice.
Maggie, I'm sorry.
Larry, you have to know,
you have to understand that...
I don't have to know anything.
I love you.
And I love you.
And I want to kiss you.
- You'll catch my bug.
- I don't care.
- When will I see you? Will you call me?
- When will you be all right?
I'm fine now.
I didn't know what you took in your coffee,
Mr. Coe, so I brought all the fixings.
- What does he take, Margaret?
- Just...
Just cream.
So it happened to you?
Yes, Mother. It's happened to me.
You know how to read a blueprint.
That's not the way the wall was designed.
- But I got it half-finished already.
- I can't help that. Take it down...
- Anybody home?
... And do it right.
Hi, honey.
- All right, fellas, hold it.
- Anything wrong?
I just came to see my husband
and his house.
- Good. How do you like it?
- I think it's wonderful, darling.
- What is that?
- That's Altar's study.
Don't you remember I... No.
The sketches, that was on the main level.
- I think it's more interesting there.
- It's marvelous. What a view.
- How do you get up there?
- This is the stairwell.
The steps on this side go into the study
on that side...
...they go into the master bedroom.
All that is going to be colored glass.
This is the exciting part, isn't it?
When it begins to take shape.
- Are you happy with it?
- Yes. I think it's going very well.
- Let me show you the rest of it.
- No, I can't now.
I've got too many things to do.
We're having a party tonight.
A party? What's the occasion?
It's no occasion. I just thought of it
this morning after you left.
I don't know, you've been working
on this all week, and it's Friday night...
...and I just thought a little fun
wouldn't hurt us.
I thought you might like to relax.
So I'm giving a party.
- You don't mind, do you?
- No, it's good idea.
- A little sudden.
- Good.
I asked Felix to save us some good steaks,
and I've already started calling people...
...and I'm so glad you don't mind.
I've got to go and call some more people,
and I've got to pick up some things.
It's a beautiful house, darling.
- Goodbye. I'll see you later.
- Goodbye, dear.
- Don't be late tonight.
- I won't.
- Hello?
- Is this Margaret Gault?
Yes, this is Margaret Gault.
Who's this, please?
This is Eve Coe.
Hello? Margaret?
Are you there?
Yes, I'm here, Mrs. Coe.
- Are you all right? Is anything wrong?
- No, I'm fine.
Betty Anders has spoken of you so often...
...and I've been meaning to call you
for such a long time.
Now finally I've gotten around to it.
And I was wondering...
...if you and your husband
might like to come over tonight.
We're having some friends in.
I'm sure you must know some of them
and we'd so much like to have you.
That's very sweet of you.
I don't know if we could get a sitter.
I've got a whole list if you want it.
Ken's very fussy about the sitters we use.
I can understand that.
If you do get a sitter, could you come?
I'll ask him.
- He may have made other plans.
- Do try.
If you can come,
we'll look for you around 8:00.
- All right?
- Fine.
- Goodbye, Margaret.
- Goodbye.
- Good night, Mr. Baxter.
- Good night, David. Sleep tight.
- Good night, Daddy.
- Good night, David.
- Drink up, Stan. You look a little tired.
- I should be.
I've been commuting to Hawaii
for the past two months.
- Oh, yes.
- They look beautiful.
Larry, that schematic you did for us,
it was a great job.
- I'm glad you're satisfied.
- As it turns out, it was just the beginning.
- Yeah?
- Something new has come our way, Larry.
I think it was offered to us
largely on the strength of the job you did.
What is it?
- Just a city.
- What?
There'll be a city, a city in Hawaii.
We're going to substitute a city
for 4,000 acres of jungle.
That's exciting.
Housing, roads, industrial parks,
the works...
...just as Sert did in South America
on a limited scale.
- How does it sound?
- It sounds like an architect's dream.
You sending Martin out for it?
He can't handle it. We want you
to head up the entire project for us.
Me?
- Well?
- I don't know what to say.
- I'm flabbergasted.
- It's very simple. Just say you'll do it.
We figure it'll take about five years
of intensive planning.
But, Larry, this one will go down
in the architectural primers.
I can't tell you how grateful we are.
My brother said that schematic you did
had more imagination...
...than anything that Bauhaus
ever came up with.
- He just doesn't throw praise around.
- Five years. That's a long time to be away.
Away? From what?
You'll have Eve and the kids with you.
And boy, will your kids love Hawaii.
It'll be great for me having you there, too.
You know how we love Eve.
Do me a favor, will you?
Don't mention this to Eve.
- I'd rather tell her myself.
- Sure, Larry, I understand.
When are you going to put on those steaks?
- Any time now.
- No, not yet. Not until everybody gets here.
- I hope those steaks are good, Felix.
- Cut them from the cow myself.
I'll answer the door.
The way I figure it, Ramsey
should begin telling one of his jokes...
...right after his next martini,
wouldn't you say?
Darling, you already know Margaret.
- How do you do?
- Yes. Nice to see you.
- You haven't met my husband, Ken.
- Glad to know you.
Will you get them both a drink?
I'll put your coat away.
Fine. Thanks.
I think you know everybody here.
- Hi. Have we got any crme de menthe?
- I think it's somewhere down there.
- How's it going out there?
- Why don't you come and take a look?
I will. After this batch,
everybody's on their own.
Go a little easy on that, will you?
- First drink tonight.
- I want you sober.
- I'm sober. Sober as a judge.
- Stay that way.
- How come?
- Guess.
You want a lawn like a golf course,
you gotta work at it.
You know what I hate? Crab grass. I hate it.
I've found the crme de menthe. I wasn't
sure whether we had any left or not.
- What are we girls talking about?
- Girl talk. Sit down.
I like good-looking people. Men and women.
All the girls around here,
they all look alike.
They wear tweed skirts, cardigan sweaters,
and pearls. It's dreary.
That Soren character who lives next door...
I think she must wear a girdle
up to her neck.
I can't tell them apart,
like celery and carrots.
- I want to make people happy.
- Felix. What can I do for you?
- Nothing. Thank you very much.
- Surprise?
- Are you happy?
- Yes, thank you.
So the next morning,
the circus owner goes up to the horse...
...and he says "What's this I hear
about you and that zebra?"
The horse looks up, he's surprised, he says:
"Zebra? I thought those were pajamas. "
I didn't think it was funny
the first time I heard it.
Wait a minute. I got more.
How old is your son now?
- He's the same age as your son.
- That's right.
- Isn't that a nice picture, Margaret?
- Yes.
Larry did a house for the artist
about eight years ago, I think.
Excuse me, Mrs. Gault. Shall we dance?
Larry, tell me something.
What's your secret?
Your lawn, no crab grass.
I've tried six different crab-grass killers
and none of them work.
I even tried this new stuff
that's got 90% chlordane.
Who cares about crab grass?
I don't care if crab grass devours
your whole lawn or this entire community.
- That's a fact.
- I'm sorry if I...
This whole house may suddenly collapse
around our ears...
...and all you want to
talk about is crab grass.
What you need is another drink.
Give me your glass...
I'll get you a drink
and we'll toast to the weeds of the world.
Sure, Larry.
...picked that man up
and took him to the room...
...and gave him a spanking he won't forget.
My husband will not tolerate
that kind of language.
Not even from a 6-year-old.
It's hard to know what to do with them.
A man works hard all day long.
He comes home tired and angry...
- And he's supposed to be a good father.
- And a good husband.
Yeah, but that's easier.
Margaret understands a man's moods.
Children can't.
Are you a moody man, Ken?
Not excessively so.
I think I'm a good husband.
I haven't heard any kicks so far.
Hi.
The bartender told me
to give this to the lady.
With his compliments.
And this.
Thank you.
Why'd you come, Maggie?
I had to.
Are you angry?
- Would it matter if I were?
- Yes.
But I would have come anyway.
So this is where you work?
Yes, this is where I miss you most.
Larry, please.
- Maggie. I want to tell you...
- What?
- Did you ever build a city?
- No.
No, neither did I.
Ain't that a shame. I never built a city.
Have you ever been to Hawaii?
You'd better not drink any more, Larry.
Yeah, that's what Eve said.
That's remarkable, don't you think?
She's lovely, Larry. I like her.
- I want to hold you.
- Larry, don't, please.
I want to say...
Here you are, Margaret. Ken's been looking
for you. He wants to go home.
Thank you very much, Felix.
- Good night, Larry. It was a lovely party.
- Good night.
- Good night, Felix.
- Good night, Margaret.
Pretty woman.
Yes, she's a real pretty woman.
I've always envied you, you know, Larry.
Working at home, I mean.
Hi.
Hi. Who are you?
- Where's Mommy?
- She's outside.
- Would you like me to get her for you?
- No, that's all right.
You still haven't told me your name.
Peter Coe. What's yours?
- Maggie.
- You're pretty.
- See you soon, Larry.
- Yeah.
- Call. Come over.
- I will. I'll call you tomorrow.
The nicest part about being the host is...
...you don't have to drive anywhere
at the end of the night.
- It has its advantages.
- Larry.
- Good night.
- I really had a wonderful time.
- Larry, it was a great party.
- Thank you very much.
- Good night, Margaret.
- Good night.
- Glad you could have come.
- Eve, thank you.
I certainly will, dear. Goodbye.
It's the same with working at home, Larry.
The way you do.
You got a three-minute walk from your
breakfast table to your study. That's living.
And, of course, you also get a chance
to watch the procession.
- What procession is that, Felix?
- The great American marching society.
The Itchy Foot Club. Tramp, tramp, tramp.
You know who's leading
the procession, of course.
- Who?
- A woman.
You don't think much of women,
do you, Felix?
I love them. Every last one of them.
But they're all the same.
They want romance.
There's nothing romantic about the slob
they see shaving in his pajamas.
You and me, Larry,
we're furniture in our own homes.
But if we go next door...
Next door, we're heroes.
A guy like you, works at home, you got
plenty of opportunity for going next door.
Sure. I go next door all the time.
A lovely lady of 60 lives there.
Let's have some coffee, Felix.
Larry, you know what I'm talking about.
Romance. The romance seekers.
They're everywhere,
ready to fall in love at the drop of a hat.
Any place you've got a housewife,
you've got a potential mistress.
How do you know? You're the guy
that doesn't even like a dirty joke.
I'm a realist.
Society says,
"Felix, you're a one-woman man. "
I say, "Yes, of course I am. "
You want to know something, Larry?
I'm a liar. So are you. So is everybody.
- What are you getting at, Felix?
- Nothing.
I'm just an observer of the human scene.
A guy like you, the blondes
must come flocking from miles around.
Sure, I beat them off with clubs.
Never mind the clubs.
Just make sure they don't leave
any blonde bobby pins around in the car.
Eve's hair is black, remember?
And watch the ashtray.
No lipstick butts that aren't Eve's brand.
Or maybe your particular blonde
doesn't smoke?
You've got the wrong man, Felix.
I'm happily married with two kids.
Sure, we're all happily married
with two kids.
What's that got to do with your blonde?
She's happily married, too,
but maybe with only one kid, huh?
- Love them all.
- What are you doing, Felix?
Me? I'm a respectable ex-butcher,
my conscience is clear.
So is mine. Good night, Felix.
Outraged innocence
is always a good gimmick, Larry...
...but the amateur tends to overplay it.
The pro, Larry, is a guy who establishes
a definite behavior pattern at home...
...and never deviates from it, but never.
No sly secret glances
when your wife's at the same party...
...no trips to the kitchen for a quick kiss.
Kid stuff.
The pro doesn't take any real chances.
You're taking a real chance
right now, Felix.
- I'm liable to bust you right in the mouth.
- Are you? I doubt it.
Then you'd have to tell Eve that we were
discussing your blonde, wouldn't you?
And Eve's pretty close
to smelling something in the wind, anyway.
I spotted that worried-wife look on her face
when I came in.
That's why she threw
this little shindig, Larry.
To draw the straying male
back to hearth and home.
Now you take my advice and make love
to her the minute everybody leaves.
- That's enough, Felix.
- Don't worry, Larry...
...your secret's safe with me.
I'm just an ex-butcher, pal.
"See no evil, hear no evil, speak no evil. "
You and your blonde don't have to worry.
You don't know
what the hell you're talking about.
Don't I?
Good night, Larry. Nice party.
Larry?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing. What do you mean...
- Something's wrong, Larry. Now what is it?
- I said nothing.
I don't want to start an argument.
Neither do I.
My folks are going to Palm Springs
this weekend.
I think I'll go with them.
- You mean alone?
- Yes, alone.
I have some things I want to think about.
- Do you mind my going?
- No, not if you want to.
- Do what you want to do.
- Do you want me to go alone?
- I want to go down that drain.
- What?
Nothing. Sure, go ahead, honey.
- This is my little brother Peter.
- Hello, Peter.
Hi, Maggie.
- Is Eve with you?
- No, she went to Palm Springs.
- What ride you kids want to go on next?
- That one.
Okay. Come on.
Do you want to go on this, too?
You got your ticket, Pat?
You look beautiful.
Why did she go away, Larry?
Is something wrong?
No. She just wanted a few days' rest,
that's all.
Do you think she might return the courtesy?
What do you mean?
- Maybe she'd let you get away for a while.
- Maybe.
You'd like to, wouldn't you?
Hold on, Peter.
You didn't answer me, Larry. What's wrong?
The thing we should have expected
sooner or later.
Felix knows about us, Maggie.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
Then we'll have to be more careful,
won't we?
I don't think he'll cause any trouble.
Men don't gossip.
That's not the point.
But who's going to find out next?
Don't you see what can happen?
This whole thing could explode around us
and hurt a lot of people.
I don't want to hurt anyone, Larry.
Not you, not me. Not anyone.
Of course not. That's why we've got to know
where we're going.
There's got to be more for us or less.
It can't stay the way it is.
Don't talk about it, Larry.
What do you mean, "Don't talk about it"?
We've got to face up to it sometime.
- I want things to stay the way they are.
- Without going anywhere?
Like that ride our kids are on? Around
and around, no beginning and no end?
Do you want to end it?
- Maggie, I want to begin it.
- It has begun.
Larry, it's got to stay exactly like it is.
- You can't mean that.
- I do.
I feel like I'm talking to a stranger.
Maybe you are.
Maybe we should stay away
from each other for a while.
If that's what you want.
Come on, the ride's over.
First you said the 17th, I said all right.
Then you extended it to the 28th.
- Now you're telling me it'll be later.
- Be reasonable.
I've got the men working
Saturdays and Sundays.
I don't want to hear
about your construction problems.
Believe me, I'm doing...
You promised it'd be ready
by the time Altar's book is finished.
That's the middle of next month. This is...
I want a certificate of occupancy by then,
and no excuses.
- All I can do is try.
- You'd better do a lot more than try.
I'm giving you an absolute deadline.
You meet it.
- What are you so steamed up about?
- So I'm a temperamental artist.
I'm trying to get you into your house
on time.
A couple of days more or less
won't do any harm.
- What's that?
- The proof of my new book jacket.
It's attractive.
I'm beginning to sweat already.
The reviews are coming out soon.
- Did you write the book you wanted to?
- Yeah.
They'll like it.
- Rog.
- Yeah.
Look, I know my 10% doesn't buy your soul,
but you okay?
Sure, I got a few things on my mind.
It'll be okay.
- You know where I live.
- Thanks.
Rog, I'm hungry.
Yeah, you're hungry.
She's a very oral type. Always hungry.
Still, she's a nice kind of a kid.
She's clean.
Washes my socks, listens to my lousy jokes.
Maybe I ought to marry her.
My mother was clean.
Morning, Eve.
Hi, Felix.
- Nice day.
- Beautiful.
- Hiya, fellas.
- Hi.
Love them all, Brucie.
I have to wait until the neighbors call
to find out where you are.
- But you said I could go.
- Now listen to me.
I got better things to do
than to go chasing all over looking for you.
Do you understand that?
- Do you understand that, Patrick?
- Yes, Mom.
- Hello.
- Eve?
- This is Stan Baxter.
- Hello, Mr. Baxter. How are you?
Fine, thanks. Is Larry there?
No, I'm sorry, he's not.
Can he call you back?
He was supposed to call me yesterday.
Have you got a minute, Eve?
Why, yes, certainly.
I know Larry asked me not to discuss this
with you...
...but I just have to have an answer
on this Hawaiian deal.
I'm sorry, I'm afraid I...
Of course, this is something
you must decide together...
...but I honestly don't understand
his hesitation.
There you are.
- Where are the kids?
- Visiting.
- Visiting where?
- Lois Lindsey picked them up.
Stan Baxter phoned.
What did he want?
What did he want, Larry?
I'm listening.
- Why didn't you tell me about his offer?
- I wanted to think about it.
- Alone? I thought we were married.
- Don't get upset.
Why didn't you tell me?
Why did you keep it from me?
I'm not keeping it from you.
I want to think about it for a while.
For how long? He told me
you've been stalling him for five weeks.
- Please.
- He thought I was to blame.
Eve, please stop shouting.
I'll do as I please.
If you can hide something as important
as this from me, for God's sake...
- I don't know...
- It's important.
I want to get my own ideas clear
before I talked to you about it.
- When did you start doing that?
- I've always done it.
- It was my impression...
- Your impression is wrong.
...and don't you tell me I'm wrong.
This time you're wrong, dead wrong.
How could you hide something as important
as moving to Hawaii for five years?
Selling the house,
taking the kids out of school.
I can't discuss this with you if you'll
scream. I have got to go to Altar's.
- We'll talk about this later.
- Don't you leave this house.
If you do, you don't have to come back.
I'm going and I'll be back.
We'll discuss it then.
Larry, you old son of a gun.
Larry, what are you doing up here?
- Did you read the reviews?
- They came in?
Did they come in.
100% percent they came in.
Every one of them, and I broke their backs.
"Scintillating, bright, penetrating. "
"A work of art," the man said.
- That's wonderful. Congratulations.
- Yeah. I'm a genius.
I've been sitting up here saying to myself:
"Great. You did it. "
What did I do?
All my life,
I've been wanting to write a book...
...without caring what they say. I did it.
They loved it.
All those years,
this is what I've been wanting.
But it turns out this is not
what I've been wanting at all.
- Funny, huh?
- Come on, Rog. You wrote a great book.
I wrote a magnificent book.
And I sat up here alone...
...and drank to the wonderful reviews.
All alone.
What's the matter with me, Larry?
Nothing the matter with you.
You should be happy. Snap out of it.
That's the old Larry I like.
That's the one. "Snap out of it. "
Do you remember what you told me
when I was writing the book?
You said,
"You decide what's important and do it. "
- You remember that?
- That was a long time ago.
Yeah, but it's true.
- You know what's important to me, Larry?
- What?
Nothing.
And I could bust out crying
because nothing's important.
- Tell me, Larry, what's important?
- Cut it out, Rog.
Boy, I envy you.
You're married and got a family.
You know where you're going.
Sure.
Sure I do.
You know what's waiting when I get home?
A bomb about to explode
and I got no place to hide.
You want answers?
Give me some, and stop crying
because you got rave reviews.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be sorry.
Don't ask me what's important,
because I don't know.
I'm such a phony.
I got a drawer full of manufactured labels:
Architect. Husband. Father. Man.
I sew them into my clothes,
but the suits never fit.
You know,
I always believed in honor, decency.
Maybe they're just labels, too.
What is it?
I got a job I want to take, a woman I want.
People can't be hurt.
I'm hardly the one to pass out advice...
...but don't lose your head.
You didn't invent infidelity.
You ever been in love, Rog?
Really in love?
Yeah. I just want to hear her voice.
You know, the most important thing
in the world to me right now is a telephone.
There's one in the other room.
- I couldn't pick it up.
- Why not?
Because if I do, that's the beginning...
...or the end.
I've never been in love.
But I'd like to feel that way about a woman.
And if you do, don't throw it away.
It's not that easy to find.
Here are your house keys.
I feel like I just had a baby.
You know what I'm going to do?
I'm going out in that street
and fall in love with the first girl I see.
Then I'll drag her up to my new house,
and she'll cook scrambled eggs...
...and love me if I never wrote
another lousy book as long as I live.
Yeah, you do that.
I better go.
You know, it's funny.
We meet as strangers
and then half the time we part that way.
Yeah, and if we ever really get to know
another human being, it's a miracle.
I like you, Altar.
I get the feeling that I'm not going
to be seeing much of you anymore.
- Take care of yourself, will you?
- I will. You, too.
Hello?
Larry, is it you?
How are you?
How've you been?
Yes.
I've missed you, too.
All right.
I don't know.
I just don't know, Larry.
We'll have to talk about it.
I can't now. I'm late.
I'm supposed to pick up my mother.
Yes, tomorrow would be fine. Where?
Really, is it finished?
I can't wait to see it.
2:00. And then we'll talk.
I love you.
- Betty.
- Yeah?
I'm going over to Ramsey's,
see if I can have these shears sharpened.
- I'll be right back.
- All right.
Hello, Eve. It's starting to rain.
Larry's not home.
I didn't figure he was.
I wanted to talk to you, anyway.
If you'll forgive me, Felix...
I'm just not in the mood right now
for talking.
This won't take very long, Eve.
I just wanted to find out
what you did with those geraniums.
Geraniums? What do you mean?
Out front.
You handle the gardening around here,
don't you?
Yes.
They're coming along beautifully.
Betty and I wanted to plant some...
...but we wanted to know first...
Your hair looks different, Eve.
I was just about to take a shower.
I won't keep you very long.
Why don't you let your hair fall free
around your face, Eve?
You have such a lovely face.
Thank you.
Felix, all we did with those flowers was
follow the nursery instructions, that's all.
When did you start to plant them?
I don't know. This spring, I think.
I don't know.
Why don't you ask Larry when he gets back?
Larry may not get back
for quite some time, Eve.
Why don't you take off the ribbon, Eve?
Listen, Felix, I don't have time
for this kind of foolishness.
Take it off, Eve.
There.
Isn't that better?
I think I'd better turn on some lights.
What for?
It's getting dark outside.
It's really coming down.
Do you like to watch a storm, Eve?
I love storms.
Listen, Felix,
I've got a lot of things to do.
Was it very painful, Eve?
Taking off the ribbon?
No.
- Was it?
- No.
Now, why don't you...
Come on, Eve, you want to and I know it.
Get out!
Eve, what is it?
Felix.
Tell me, architect.
How am I any different from you?
Did you find him?
Yeah.
I've been sitting here wondering...
...what gave Felix the peculiar notion
that I'd be an easy mark.
Do you know why, Larry?
It seems so simple.
It explains so many things. So simple.
Don't touch me.
- Eve, please.
- What, Larry?
I know.
I guess I've known all along.
There is another woman.
I knew it.
I want you to leave the house, Larry.
I don't want you near the children.
I don't want to see you.
I want to forget that I ever loved you
or knew you.
I just want you to go.
Go wherever you want to go.
Do whatever you want to. Go with her.
Go to hell. Just get out of my sight.
Can't you be happy here?
Is it me?
Because if it is me, Larry,
I want you to tell me where I was wrong.
I can change.
It's just that I don't... It's just
that I don't know what I should do.
- Please don't cry, Eve.
- I can't help it.
Larry, I want us to be
the way we used to be.
I don't understand what's happened.
I don't know us anymore. Where are we?
I don't know, Eve.
Larry, please help me.
You see, I don't think
I could live without you.
Please, Larry.
Don't leave me.
I've been peeking in windows.
It's beautiful.
It's been so long.
Do you know how long it's been?
Yes.
I'm going away.
Where?
To Hawaii.
I'm going to build a city.
You're all going?
Of course...
...it has to be that way.
There's so much to say...
...and yet there's nothing.
Don't you have a key to this house?
Yes, I guess there's one here someplace.
I left a key here for Di Labbia.
Where is it?
It is an exciting house.
There are some things I'd like to change.
Poor Mr. Altar.
He doesn't know this is really our house.
You know what I'd do if we lived here?
No. What would you do?
I'd build a moat around this place.
Keep the whole world out.
No friends? No visitors?
No one. Just you and me.
I do love you, Maggie.
I know that.
And I love you.
Mr. Coe, is that you?
Hi, Frank.
I figured I'd stop up
and have another look around.
Maggie, this is Mr. Di Labbia.
- How do you do?
- Hello.
You know, I really got a kick
out of this house.
I never built one like it before.
I've got to check up on a few items.
Excuse me.
You've got quite a husband, Mrs. Coe.
Goodbye, Larry.
Bye, Maggie.