Are you crazy?
You'll wake up
the whole neighborhood.
- Hi, Mom.
- Don't "Hi, Mom" me.
What are you still doing up?
It's past 1:00.
- I thought I'd wait for you.
- Well, I'm home.
Now you can get to sleep.
Come on.
Andale.
I'm really not tired.
Kristen, don't start with me.
You know what your shrink said.
He's full of it.
I'm not going to let you
get me into an argument.
Now get to sleep.
Mom, I'm still having
those awful dreams.
Elaine,
where do you keep the bourbon?
I'll be right down.
I've got a guest.
And you don't want
to keep him waiting?
That's right. I don't.
Good night.
One, two,
Freddy's coming for you
Three, four,
better lock your door
Five, six, grab a crucifix
Seven, eight, gonna stay up late
Nine, ten, never sleep again
One, two,
Freddy's coming for you
Three, four,
better lock your door
Five, six, grab a crucifix
Seven, eight, gonna stay up late
Nine, ten...
Hi. What's your name?
Kristen. What's yours?
What is this place?
I got to go now.
Wait, little girl.
Don't go in there!
Little girl?
This is where he takes us.
Come on. We're going.
Freddy's home.
Put me down. You're hurting me.
And in local news, two more
teenage deaths have occurred...
both suicides.
County health officials
are at a loss to explain...
this alarming trend.
Nothing like a little
cheery news to start the day.
Doc, I got a new theory
about all these suicides.
Don't hold back on us, Max.
We need all the help we can get.
It's fucked-up chromosomes.
Think about it.
All their parents dropped acid
during the sixties.
It beats Simms' theory.
She thinks it's sex,
drugs, and rock 'n' roll.
Shit.
That's what keeps people alive.
Hi, Taryn.
You don't look so hot, kid.
Are you getting some sleep?
I didn't think so.
Good morning, Dr. Gordon.
Good morning, Jennifer.
How are the burns?
Regular, menthol, ultra-light.
They're healing up nicely.
I've been good. When do I get
my cigarette privileges back?
Don't hold your breath.
- Phillip.
- Hey, Doc.
How is he?
He's cooling down.
If he continues having
these outbursts...
I'll have to have him
isolated permanently.
Don't worry.
It won't come to that.
I read the report
on the new staff member.
What did you think?
I don't understand why
some grad school superstar...
is being treated
like a seasoned pro.
She's doing ground-breaking
research on pattern nightmares.
We don't need any outside help.
I know these kids.
I don't want some hotshot
taking chances with them...
just so she can get published.
Dr. Gordon, Dr. Simms,
to examination, stat.
This is ridiculous.
I know my daughter.
She's just trying
to get some attention.
I won't play one of her
little games with her.
Suicide attempt.
Just down from Country General.
- What's her name?
- Kristen Parker.
She was fine
until we tried sedating her.
She tore her stitches out.
Kristen, we want to help you!
Hold her.
I'm Dr. Gordon.
I want to help you.
Be careful, Max!
Back off, Max.
Kristen, put the scalpel down.
Nobody's going to hurt you.
Five, six, grab your crucifix
Seven, eight,
better stay up late
Nine, ten, never, never...
Never sleep again.
Where did you learn that rhyme?
Tell me about the kids.
Well, they're survivors
in a way.
They're all severely
sleep disordered...
insomnia, narcolepsy,
bed-wetting.
But the nightmares
are their common thread?
Right.
They share a group delusion...
a boogieman,
for lack of a better word.
They're so traumatized...
they'll do almost anything
not to sleep.
Anything?
We lost a kid a month ago
to Fairview.
I don't know where
he got the razors...
but he cut off his own eyelids
to stay awake.
Oh, God.
Shook the kids up pretty badly.
By the way, that was great work
with the new patient.
Pretty smooth for an intern.
I have had some experience
with pattern nightmares.
I've got to get going.
Let me help you.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome.
Now, be sure
that you check in with Max.
He'll give you
the whole twenty-five-cent tour.
I'll see you later.
Oh, Miss Thompson...
You can call me Nancy.
You call me Neil.
What was that nursery rhyme
all about?
It was just something
that the kids say...
to keep the... boogieman away.
Anyway, that's group therapy.
This whole wing
is devoted to the program.
I guess... yeah.
You can use this office
for the time being.
This will be fine.
I'll have you set up
in your own space...
by the end of the week.
The patients' rooms
are down this way.
This is Phillip.
We call him "The Walker."
- Why is that?
- Because I sleepwalk.
A perfectly normal event
that our illustrious staff...
loves to theorize about
endlessly.
Phillip, this is Nancy.
Hi. Welcome to the snake pit.
Thanks.
Nice work.
They really ought to be carved
out of wood...
but they won't let me have
a knife.
I might, you know...
This lump over here is Kincaid.
Take a good look.
He gets himself thrown in
the quiet room so often...
you probably won't see
a lot of him.
I do it so I don't have to look
at your ugly face all the time.
I love you, too.
Nice meeting you.
They're really good kids,
but don't let them fool you.
They're dangerous...
to themselves and to each other.
Hi, Joey.
Why, thank you.
- Hey, Marcie. How you doing?
- Great.
These going to "C" Ward?
I'll walk you down.
See you later, Joey.
Mrs. Parker, was Kristen
acting any different?
Did you notice anything strange
before she made the attempt?
Kristen specializes
in strangeness.
I've spent thousands
on psychiatrists.
Did she always have nightmares?
No. They've gotten worse since
I took away her credit cards.
I'm serious.
I don't know
what you want from me.
Just some answers.
Other kids are involved,
not just Kristen.
All good kids, smart kids.
I'm sorry to hear that.
You're the experts, not me.
If I had any insight
into any of this...
I would share them with you,
believe me.
I'm sure you would.
Excuse me.
I have to get downtown.
I'll need to get her things.
I had them packed
in a suitcase. Teresa.
I'll get them.
Please, I don't mind.
It's the first door
at the top of the stairs.
You.
Oh, my God. Run!
Get us back out, Kristen!
Do it now!
I used to live in this house.
That's just a house
I dream about.
Have you ever done that
before...
pulled someone into your dream?
When I was a little girl,
like four or five...
if I had a nightmare,
I'd always bring my dad in.
The dreams
would always get better.
He used to tell me about it
the next day.
He used to think
they were his dreams.
When did that stop?
When I was still a kid.
My folks got divorced,
and after a while...
I just thought
I imagined the whole thing.
I guess I didn't.
It's an amazing gift.
The man in my dreams,
he's real, isn't he?
He's real.
OK. Group's in session.
Straight talk only in this room.
Today I'd like to start
getting us acquainted...
with our new staff member
Nancy Thompson.
Let's make her welcome.
You've already met
Phillip and Kincaid...
and, of course, Kristen.
How about the rest of you tell
Nancy about yourselves?
Will, how about you first?
Hi, I'm Will Stanton.
I've had a little accident,
as you can see...
ended up in this chair.
Accident, my ass.
You said this was straight talk.
So he took a jump. He wasn't
sticking needles in his arms.
Save it, Kincaid. Jennifer?
I'm Jennifer Callfield...
and as soon as
I get out of here...
I'm going to Los Angeles
to be an actress.
I'm going to be on TV.
Yeah. "Lifestyle
of the Rich and Psychotic."
Screw you.
This is Joey. He used to be
a debater in school.
Now he doesn't talk much.
I'm Taryn White.
The only reason I'm in here...
is because
it's better than juvie hall.
Also because I'm going through
some very strange shit.
Your dreams?
Everybody has bad dreams.
Can I interject something
just to save time?
Sure, Phillip, go ahead.
According to our kind hosts...
our dreams
are a group psychosis...
sort of a mellow mass hysteria.
The fact that
we all dreamt about this guy...
before we ever met
doesn't impress anybody.
So we go in circles...
making minimal progress
with maximum effort.
You won't make any progress...
until you recognize your dreams
for what they are.
And what are they?
The by-products of guilt.
Psychological scars
stemming from moral conflicts...
and overt sexuality.
Oh, great.
It's my dick that's killing me.
Tell me what's supposed
to be happening again.
You're being attacked
by the bog demon.
Fourteen.
Doesn't count.
You got to say the words.
- This is stupid.
- Come on.
In the name of Lowrek,
Prince of Elves, demon begone.
Good.
You conquered the demon...
but your horse
is sinking in the bog.
What do you do?
I go to bed, and get a new horse
in the morning.
How do I score that...
enchanted slumber or death?
All right, fellas. Lights out.
Aw, Max.
"Aw, Max." You know the rules.
Come on, Joey. You, too.
Every time
we get a good game going...
it's always, "Lights out."
- Good night, fellas.
- Night, Max.
OK, you get first shift.
Oh, come on.
I had it last night.
Good. Just remember,
keep your eyes open...
and one whimper,
and you wake me up, OK?
- This is nice.
- You never been here before?
No. I think it opened
when I was at school.
Best Thai food in Springwood.
Of course, it's the only
Thai food in Springwood.
Do your parents
still live around here?
My mother passed away.
She died in her sleep.
I'm sorry.
My father and I...
Things just seemed
to fall apart after that.
Sounds like a rough time.
It was.
What if I told you that...
your patients
are in real physical danger...
from their dreams?
The nightmares are nothing but
a symptom of the real problems.
Then let's just eliminate
the symptom for the time being.
With Hypnocil?
That's right.
You want me to prescribe...
an experimental
psychoactive drug...
to a bunch
of suicidal teenagers?
Just until we get things
under control.
Dream deprivation is
nothing to fool with.
You have no business
taking it yourself.
I used to be like them.
I know what
they're going through.
So do I.
You told me they were survivors,
and they are.
But how much longer
they survive is up to us.
I'm sorry, Nancy.
The answer's no.
Phillip, wake up.
Have a nice stroll, asshole.
What? What are you doing?
Hey! Come on, man!
What are you, crazy?
Oh, shit! What's he doing?
Get help! Get help!
What's the matter?
Don't do it, Phillip!
God! Stop!
I want us to talk
about last night.
I want us to get our feelings
out in the open.
He wasn't strong enough,
so he got wasted. That's all.
That's all?
Is that what you think?
He couldn't hack it,
so he got nailed. Period.
Yeah. Big, tough badass.
How long will you last?
Longer than any of you.
Go ahead and fight.
That's what he wants.
Who?
Who do you think?
What does he want?
To turn us against each other
so we'll be weak.
- Horseshit.
- No, she's right.
We're all
missing the point here.
Phillip's death
was a sleepwalking accident.
Nothing more.
No. I could see him
up there... his face.
He was wide awake...
all the way down.
Then it was suicide.
Phillip quit. He gave up.
Joey says it wasn't suicide.
Listen to me, Joey.
Phillip killed himself.
That's a cowardly thing.
That's an empty thing.
He let himself down.
He let all of us down.
It was murder!
Can't you understand that?
That bastard murdered him!
I'm not listening to this.
How much longer will you go on
blaming your dreams...
for your own weaknesses?
How much longer will you keep
blowing smoke up our ass?
There will be
no repeat occurrences...
of last night's events.
Your doors will be locked
during sleeping hours.
We'll start a policy
of evening sedation.
Anybody tries drugs on me
will get his ass kicked!
You just bought yourself
a night in the quiet room!
- Sit down!
- Fuck you! You sit down!
Easy, Kincaid.
Nobody's putting me to sleep!
Get away! Let me alone!
Ain't nobody
putting me to sleep!
I don't want to go to sleep!
I ain't going to sleep!
Stay in your seats.
We'll begin sedation tonight,
starting with him.
You can't.
They'll be defenseless.
That's precisely
what they need...
some uninterrupted REM sleep
to release that negative energy.
I'm prescribing Hypnocil.
It's a dream suppressant.
I know what it is.
I just can't believe it.
What has she talked you into?
Nothing. It's my decision.
I want these dreams stopped
till we get some answers.
I can't allow that.
Then I'll go to Carver
if I have to.
He'll either back me up
or accept my resignation.
All right.
But if something goes wrong...
I'll make sure
that you're held responsible.
I mean that.
Fully responsible.
I can't believe
I just said that.
Can we get
the Hypnocil by tomorrow?
We're going to try.
I hope you know
what you're getting us into.
Ain't gonna dream no more,
no more
Ain't gonna dream no more
All night long, I sing this song
Girl, what are you doing?
- Watching TV.
- I can see that.
Why don't you read a book?
You watch too much damn TV.
Research.
Right.
You're going to be a TV star.
Wait and see.
If Simms catches you here
after lights out...
she's gonna chew my ass.
I gotta stay up, Max.
Just tonight, please?
I can't handle the nightmare.
Not after Phillip. Not tonight.
I never saw you.
Thanks, Max.
Hi, sweet stuff. Good news.
Can't be good news,
coming from you.
- Pulled night duty.
- So?
So, got the keys to heaven,
baby.
- What?
- The dispensary.
I am talking
clean pharmaceutical high...
a night at Club Meth.
I don't do that shit.
Yeah?
What are those, beauty marks?
- Those are ancient history.
- Oh, yeah?
If you're ever in the mood
for a history lesson...
I'm your teacher, understand?
Stay out of my face,
or I'll go straight to Max.
Who's going to take the word
of a crazy junkie chick?
Fuck off!
It's silly to ask, but how many
of what did they kill?
Don't say that. I love animals.
I bought it red,
so I didn't know what it was.
Probably an artificial bird.
Ever go to acting school?
Not in the beginning.
I started on a talk show.
So you don't always say
you have to study?
I think you should
study, work...
then maybe you can make it.
- Can I ask you something?
- Certainly.
Who gives a fuck what you think?
One, two,
Freddy's coming for you
Three, four,
better lock the door
This is it, Jennifer...
your big break in TV.
Welcome to prime time, bitch!
Don't be ashamed, young man.
This is a place for sorrow.
What faith do you follow?
Science, I suppose.
Sad choice.
There are times when it doesn't
offer much comfort.
I've seen you before, Sister...
Mary Helena.
You do volunteer work
at the hospital.
From time to time,
when I'm needed.
I should have been able
to save them.
Only one thing
can save the children.
The unquiet spirit
must be laid to rest.
It is an abomination
to God and to man.
Excuse me, sister.
What are you doing up here?
I was talking to...
To who?
Doesn't matter.
Are you ready to go now?
Sure.
Are you finished?
Yeah. I'm sorry.
I guess I'm not hungry.
That's OK.
That's pretty. What is that?
This is my Malaysian dream doll.
It's supposed to bring
good dreams.
I could use some of that
right about now.
You know, I used to think...
I could do something
for the kids...
make some kind of difference...
but they're slipping through
my fingers, every one.
You're doing the best
you can for them, Neil.
Am I?
I'm running out of answers.
A patient sleepwalks
out of a high-security ward.
A girl alone in a room dies.
I can't believe
this is happening.
Nothing makes any sense.
Then maybe you're ready.
For what?
The truth.
Try me.
Only if you're willing
to put aside...
everything you've learned
and trust me.
Can you do that?
I can do that.
Straight talk only in this room.
- Is this group?
- Yeah, unofficially.
Soon there won't be enough
of us left to call it group.
Listen up, you guys.
Nancy has something to say.
I know who's trying to kill you.
Don't humor us.
We're not in the mood.
He wears a dirty brown hat.
He's horribly burned.
He has razors on his right hand.
Who is he?
His name is Freddy Krueger.
He was a child murderer
before he died.
And after he died...
he became something worse.
Six years ago,
he killed my friends.
He almost killed me.
Why is he after us?
Yeah. What did we do?
It's not you.
Your parents, my parents...
they burned him alive.
And now we're paying
for their sins.
You are the last
of the Elm Street children.
Mom and Dad...
I mean, that's crazy.
They never mentioned anything...
Sure. Parents tell
their kids that sort of thing...
"Good night. Say your prayers.
"By the way, we torched
some maniac last night."
So what do we do
about this creep?
Kristen is the key.
She has a very special talent.
A gift.
I haven't been able to do that
since I was little.
- You did it the other night.
- That was different.
You never lose a gift like that.
You just forget how to use it.
How about it? Will you try?
All of you have
this inner strength...
some special power
that you've had...
in your most wonderful dreams.
Together, we can learn
to use that power if we try.
You sound like Peter Pan.
Remember, open mind?
Taryn,
would you pull the shades down?
We're going to try
a little group hypnosis.
I want you all to follow
this pendulum with your eyes.
Tune out everything else.
Nothing else exists
but the pendulum.
Take us there, Kristen.
Breathe deeply and relax.
Starting with your toes,
relax everything...
till there's no tension
left in your bodies.
Keep following the pendulum.
You find yourselves
getting tired.
Nothing would feel better
right now...
than a nice, long, deep sleep.
I'm going to count backwards
from five.
When I finish...
you will all be asleep.
Five...
four...
three...
two...
one.
Sorry.
That's OK. We'll try again.
Everybody take five.
I was willing
to go through with this...
for the kids' peace of mind,
but you'll have to face reality.
Joey, I just wanted to get you
alone for a second.
I mean, look, I really like you.
Do you like me?
I know this sounds crazy...
but I make up excuses to come
into the ward every day...
just to see you.
You're so cute.
Let's just try one more time.
If it doesn't work,
I promise I'll...
We're here.
- Where here?
- We're in the dream.
No, we're not.
We're still here in the group.
In my dreams, I can walk.
My legs are strong.
In my dreams,
I am the Wizard Master.
Try something, Kristen.
What can you do in your dream?
A perfect score.
The crowd goes wild.
Dig this.
Kincaid, please.
That's very unnerving.
Hey, check out Taryn.
In my dreams, I'm beautiful...
and bad.
I could get into
a lot of trouble for this.
But I know you won't
say anything, will you?
Unzip me.
Do you like my body, Joey?
What's wrong, Joey?
Feeling tongue-tied?
What's happening?
- He's close.
- Who, Freddy?
He's heavy in the halls.
- Where's Joey?
- Freddy's got him.
Quiet, everyone! Listen.
The room's changing.
What the heck's going on here?
What's happening?
Get away from the wall.
Help!
Don't panic! Quiet down!
This isn't real!
Get us out!
Quiet! The door!
What's going on in here?
What's wrong with Joey?
Code blue.
Oh, my God.
He's in a deep coma.
There's nothing we can do.
This is inexcusable.
The session was unauthorized.
It was purposely conducted
without my knowledge.
Unusual steps were called for.
Is that what I should
tell his parents?
I understand you prescribed
a highly experimental drug.
He's not in a coma...
Your opinion
is of no interest to me.
Furthermore, you've created
panic among the patients.
That's not true.
In four days,
we've had two suicides.
Now he's in a coma.
It's safe to say your approach
has failed, entirely.
You're both relieved of duty.
I want you out today.
I'm sorry, Neil.
I'm afraid
you brought it on yourself.
For God's sake, Elizabeth...
will you please just try
to help the kids?
Will you listen to them?
Of course I will.
What are we going to do?
There's nothing that we can do.
It's out of our hands.
Sister!
This is where it began.
This wing's been closed
for years.
What was this place?
Purgatory... fashioned
by the hands of men.
Twisted, lonely souls.
The worst
of the criminally insane...
were locked up in here
like animals.
This whole facility
was shut down in the forties.
Some sort of scandal?
A young girl on the staff...
was accidentally locked in here
over the holidays.
The inmates
kept her hidden for days.
She was raped...
hundreds of times.
When they found her,
she was barely alive...
and with child.
That girl was Amanda Krueger.
Her child...
The bastard son
of a hundred maniacs.
Some say he was murdered...
though no body was ever found.
You said something before
about laying him to rest.
You must find the remains...
and bury him in hallowed ground.
Hallowed ground?
Sister?
If your only faith is science,
Doctor...
it may be you
that's laid to rest.
Wait!
Sister!
Let go of him, you bastard.
Oh, my God.
I've got to go in.
We have no choice.
Getting yourself killed
won't help the kids at all.
Besides, we do have a choice.
Assuming your mysterious nun
is right.
I've heard weirder things
this week.
All right. Whoever she is...
she seems to know
more about Krueger than I do.
The question is,
what happened to his body?
They burned him to death
in his boiler room...
and they hid the remains.
Who would know
where they're hidden?
Only one man knows...
and it's time for him to talk.
You can't take Nancy
away from us!
She's all we have!
You're a sick girl, Kristen.
If you want to get better,
you must trust me now.
Take her to the quiet room
and sedate her.
You stupid bitch!
You're killing us!
All right, everybody.
Back to bed.
Hi, Daddy.
Well, if it isn't
my little girl.
My baby come to see her daddy?
It's been a long time.
But you're here. Sit down.
What did I do to get so lucky?
I thought that you were
trying to forget me.
That's not true.
You're the one trying to forget.
I need your help, Dad.
Krueger's back.
Fred Krueger is dead.
You always had a little trouble
trying to understand that.
You know what he did.
He's doing it again.
She's telling you the truth.
I don't believe we've met...
and this isn't
any of your goddamn business.
We can stop him this time...
stop him for good...
but we need to know
where his bones were hidden.
I've lost too much
over this already.
I'm through with it.
People are still dying
after all this time.
Stop running away from it.
You owe me.
It was nice seeing you again,
princess.
Next time, don't...
don't stay away so long.
I'll be OK.
Just give me a minute.
It's the hospital.
- Dr. Gordon?
- Taryn.
You've got to come right away.
Kristen had a total shit attack.
Simms doped her up
and put her in the quiet room.
Simms put Kristen
in the quiet room for the night.
- They sedated her.
- Oh, no.
She can't stay awake for long.
She's all alone.
Freddy's going to get her.
Just stay cool.
Help is on the way.
Just hurry!
I got to get there.
- You go. I'll get the remains.
- It's no use.
I'll talk to him.
Make Simms understand.
She'll never understand.
I got to get to Kristen.
Be careful.
My name is Neil Gordon.
Pleased to meet you.
There, now we've met!
Now listen to me!
Maybe you don't care whether
Nancy lives or dies, but I do!
You and I are going
on a little scavenger hunt.
Please, God...
don't make me sleep.
What the hell are we doing here?
I won't be long.
What do you think you're doing?
Look, I'm sorry.
I really need this. I got...
I'll reimburse you.
You keep my driver's license.
I'll be back.
Max, I need to see Kristen.
- You don't understand.
- Save your breath.
Dr. Simms
gave me specific instructions.
No one sees Kristen,
especially you.
But, Max, she needs me.
She's in danger.
You got to believe me!
I really think you mean well,
but my kids been dying off...
and even without Simms' orders,
I wouldn't let you near her.
OK, Max. I understand.
Can I say good-bye
to the others?
I don't know.
It'll be my last chance.
Five minutes.
They're in the TV room.
Where have you been?
There's no time. Come on.
- Where?
- Our last group.
In there.
We knew nobody would ever
find it in that place.
I'm not sure
I can find it myself anymore.
It's deep in the heart
of the place.
Take it slow.
Straight talk only in here.
What about Kristen?
We can't get to her. I tried.
I was hoping we'd have more time
to learn to use the dreams...
but Joey's in there.
Kristen's going in, too.
They need us.
We're trying to go in,
to link up?
It's now or never.
I'm not going to kid you.
This is dangerous.
If you die in this dream,
it's for real.
Nobody has to go in
that doesn't want to.
I'm in.
Me, too.
Let's go kick the motherfucker's
ass all over dreamland.
Remember, you have to stay
together whatever happens.
That's the only way
we can beat him.
All right.
Clear your mind of everything.
Picture yourself
in the quiet room...
the soft, white walls...
the total silence...
only the sound
of your heart beating.
Picture yourself there
with Kristen.
I'm going to count backwards
from five...
and when I'm done,
we'll all be asleep.
We'll all be in the quiet room.
Five...
four...
three...
two...
one.
I knew you'd come.
We wouldn't let you go in alone.
No way. We're a team!
Listen, everybody.
Joey needs us. I can feel him.
Where is he?
How do we find him?
Stay in the middle of the room!
Whatever happens, stay together!
You'll wake up
the whole neighborhood.
Why are you still up?
It's past 1:00.
I just thought I'd wait for you.
Well, I'm home.
You can get to sleep now.
Come on.
Andale.
What's that for?
I'm just glad you're home.
Mom, I had the most awful dream.
Elaine,
where do you keep the bourbon?
I'll be right down.
Kris, I've got a guest.
I just don't want to be alone.
I said
where's the fucking bourbon?
You should listen
to your mother!
God damn it, Kristen,
you ruin everything!
Every time I bring a man home,
you spoil it!
You know what your shrink says?
You just want attention!
Is that you?
Welcome home, Taryn.
Look familiar?
OK, asshole, let's dance!
Why should we fight?
We're old friends, you and I.
Remember?
Let's get high.
What a rush.
You guys? Where are you?
Is somebody there?
You look tired.
Have a seat.
No, thanks.
I'm fine just the way I am.
For now, maybe.
But when you wake up...
it's back...
in the saddle...
again.
My leg!
It's the chair for you, kid!
I am the Wizard Master.
I am the Wizard Master!
In the name of Lowrek,
Prince of Elves, demon begone!
Sorry, kid.
I don't believe in fairy tales.
Somebody?
What is that?
I don't know.
Yo. I thought I heard voices.
Kincaid, I could kiss you.
What's stopping you?
Cool. So where's Joey?
I don't know.
This place is a maze.
It's time to stop guessin'
and start messin'.
Yo, Freddy, where you hiding,
you burnt-face pussy!
We should find the others first.
You think you're hot shit,
don't you?
Come get a piece of me!
Krueger, pussy!
I knew he was a little chicken.
Shit.
- It's a door.
- But it doesn't go anywhere.
Yes, it does.
This is it.
Are you ready?
Let's snuff the sucker.
That's it.
The Caddy.
Going somewhere?
I said I'd show you where
the goddamn thing was.
I never said I'd stick around.
- We've got work to do.
- What are you talking about?
You're about to attend
a funeral...
one that's long overdue.
Joey, look.
All the little piggies
come home.
Let him go, Krueger!
Your wish is my command.
He's never been this strong.
The souls of children...
give me strength.
Always room for more.
- What's that?
- What?
Listen.
Somebody else is out here.
We're alone.
Bury the fucking thing!
It's really you.
I killed you once before,
you son of a bitch.
Let's try this way.
Kristen, can you pull us out?
They sedated me.
We're stuck here.
It's a dead end.
What the hell?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Perhaps if there was more of me
to spread around.
Wow.
Did I say that?
You found your dream power.
You saved us, Joey.
- You blew him away!
- Put me down.
Are you OK?
I think so.
He's gone.
It's over.
Daddy?
I've crossed over, princess.
Crossed over?
I couldn't go without
telling you how sorry I am...
for all the things I've done.
I love you so much.
I'll always love you.
Die.
You're mine now, little piggy.
Please, God, for the children.
For Nancy.
Ashes to ashes.
Dust to dust.
Lay this spirit to rest.
I won't let you die.
I won't let you.
I'm going to dream you
into a beautiful dream...
forever and ever.
"Trust in Him at all times.
"Pour out your hearts to Him...
"for God is our refuge.
"Hear my cry, O God.
"Listen to my prayer.
"From the ends of the earth,
I call to you.
"I call as my heart grows faint.
"Lead me to the rock
that is higher than I.
"For You have been my refuge...
"a strong tower against the foe.
"I long to dwell
in the tent forever...
"and take refuge in the shelter
of Your wings."
Even though we entrust Nancy
to the earth...
her courage and spirit
shall remain with us...
for the Lord God
has comforted us...
saying, "That whoever
finds his life will lose it...
"and whoever loses his life
for my sake, will find it.
"They shall live forever
in the glory of His kingdom.
"May the Lord bless you
and keep you.
"The Lord make his face
to shine down upon you...
"and be gracious to you.
"The Lord turn His face
toward you and give you peace."
Oh, my God.
You were his mother.