May I borrow your blue sweater?
Everybody has gone crazy
around here...
since they put the soldiers
on the other side of the compound.
Poor boys. They have been
prisoners for years.
Now that they are back home,
they want to have a little fun.
[ German ]
What did she say?
She said, “What about those
who are here, because they don't know...
what happened to their families
and have no homes to go back to?”
[ German ]
My soldier is still trying
to find out...
where his father
and mother are.
They lived in Cassino,
and the police say...
they did not come back
after it was evacuated.
He went to Rome twice...
hoping to find them.
[ French 1
JV' [ Man Singing]
Karin,
there is your troubadour.
JV' [ Continues ]
See you later.
Good luck.
Ru try.
JV' [ Continues ]
- Hello.
- Good evening.
Beh?
What do you say?
- It's cool tonight.
- What?
It's cool! Cold! Brr!
[Sicilian ]
Cold, cold.
I don't understand you.
I can't say in English.
[ Italian ]
N' [Singing In Sicilian ]
I like you very, very.
You decided?
Say me: O prendere 0 lasc/are.
I don't know - I don't know what -
I - I don't understand it.
Or take me or leave me.
[Sicilian ] Why do you laugh?
You're so crazy.
You don't know anything about me.
We've spoken
to each other a few times...
over the barbed wires,
and now you want to marry me?
Sure.
- I can't make you out.
- I like you very, very.
[Sicilian ]
Later, if you find out
I'm different from what you think?
I know women,
and if you are different -
[Sicilian ]
Now, what does that mean?
I have learned this one and that.
I know this one and that.
This means here.
Oh, you'll spank me.
[Sicilian ]
You must decide -
If you really mean it,
I will let you know...
- tomorrow night.
- [ Kissing Sound ]
He's simple and nice.
He comes from an island
in the Mediterranean Sea.
- Do you like him?
- He says it's beautiful.
His English doesn't make sense.
He's amusing enough.
He's just a boy.
- What will you do?
- I don't know.
What can I do?
He wants to marry me.
He's crazy.
We'll see tomorrow. It all depends
if I get the visa for Argentina.
Otherwise, I know what I'll do.
Buenos dias.
- [ Italian ]
- [Spanish ]
[ Italian ]
[Spanish ]
- Buon g/omo.
- Buenos d/Zas.
[Spanish ]
- Your name, please?
- Karin Bjornsen.
- Place of birth?
- Kovno, Lithuania.
- And the date of birth?
- May 8, 1920.
- Father's name?
- Karl Bjornsen.
Your mother's maiden name?
Maria Pasvalys.
- And your occupation?
- None.
[Spanish ]
And now tell the consul
something about yourself and how...
you happen to be interned here.
Lived in Czechoslovakia
before the war.
Married to an architect who died
after the German invasion.
Emigrated to Yugoslavia.
Following the German occupation,
moved to Italy...
because wanted
by the German police.
Entered Italy secretly.
Took up residence here...
with false
identification papers.
After September 8...
managed to remain unmolested...
duﬂng the German occupation.
Then -
Then I was interned...
by the Italian authorities.
[Spanish ]
Do you have a recall affidavit
to emigrate to Argentina?
[Spanish ]
The consul says the letter
you submitted is not enough...
to authorize
your transfer to Argentina.
- I see.
- Buenos d/Zas.
- [Women Murmuring ]
- Graz/e.
Grazie.
[ Latin ]
[ Italian ]
[ Indistinct Good-byes ]
[Sicilian ]
[Ship's Horn Sounds]
I'm cold.
It's better down there.
Let's go.
[ Italian ]
Give me my coat.
I'll put it on.
I was a prisoner too,
in Australia.
[ Man ] I was in South Africa.
- Going to Stromboli?
- Yes.
I work at the lighthouse.
II vulcano.
Come.
Guarda.
- Is it always active?
- Yes.
Look, look.
The stones
are falling in the sea.
Wait.
- My suitcases.
- Yes. Sit down.
[Sicilian ]
Vincenzo!
I'll see you when I come back
from the lighthouse.
[Sicilian ]
[ Italian ]
How do you do, Father?
How do you do?
So you received the papers I sent you
and were married properly?
Fine, fine.
[ Italian ]
I understand English.
It makes me happy
when someone comes back...
and brings his wife here
to raise his family.
You see, so many of our people
have left already...
or are waiting to leave
for Argentina...
Australia, America,
France, England...
wherever they have relatives
who send them money to go.
[ Italian ]
The earth...
life is very hard.
[ Italian ]
St. Bartolo, our patron saint,
will bless you.
It was St. Bartolo
who stopped...
the lava and the fire up there.
With his hands...
he saved our homes.
You will be happy here,
won't you?
This is your home now.
Grazie, padre.
Good-bye, Father.
[ Baby Crying]
E un bambino.
Why did you kiss
the hand of the priest?
It's the custom.
This is a ghost island.
Nobody lives here.
If there was nobody here,
there would be no bamb/no, no?
Zia Rosaria.
[ Italian ]
Karin, this is my Aunt Rosaria.
- How do you do?
- Pleased to meet you.
- Oh, you speak English.
- I've been in America many years ago.
Lots of people here
have been in America.
- In America, and you came back here?
- This is my home.
Let's go.
Ls my boat still good?
[ Italian ]
How is the fishing this year?
[ English, indistinct]
[ Italian ]
Yes, but he left for Australia.
You have nobody
to send you money.
His sister sent him the money.
Guarda.
He died in the war.
His family go to the continent.
[ Man ] Everybody left.
This is our home.
[Sicilian ]
[ Sicilian ] Come.
- Soon everything like before.
- Before what?
[ Sicilian]
Guarda. Look.
Come.
This is bedroom.
Look, Karin, how beautiful.
[Sicilian ]
Karin.
Karin, come!
[Sicilian ]
See?
I understand.
“From the mountain.”
Houses...
fields - destroyed.
The strong people no go away.
Understand?
All must build again.
Terra.
[ Italian ]
New terra.
See?
We plant again -
barley, vines.
Leave me alone!
I don't care
about your barley...
or your vines...
or your new terra.
I want to leave this island
and go away, far away.
Like all the others who lived here
and were born here...
and went away, far away!
[ Italian ]
Listen.
This is my home.
You're my wife.
You stay here because I want to.
19,377 lire.
- That's all you have?
- Yes.
- What do you think you can do with that?
- Plenty.
I am your wife...
and this is your home,
but I'm not like you.
You slept very well
last night, huh?
But I didn't sleep.
I'm different.
I'm very different from you.
I belong to another class.
I can't live like this
in this filth!
This is no life
for civilized people.
Keep on counting
your 19,000 liras.
You need much more
for a woman like me.
Parla slow, slow.
I don 'z' understand.
That! You understand that?
Money, money, money.
You'd need much more money
for a woman like me.
I'm a civilized human being...
and I'm used to other things,
better things.
What do you think
you can do with that money?
Here everything,
everything must be changed.
- Yes, everything change.
- Yes, but when?
You must do it right away.
I am your wife, and this is your home.
But I have to live in it too,
and I'm not an animal.
- [ Groans]
- Yes, sure. I understand. You will see.
Yes, I will see.
[Sobbing 1
[ Baby Crying]
[ Crying Continues]
I want to get out.
What's the matter?
Che... che c'é?
Huh?
You cry?
- No.
- No?
Well, it's not you.
Bamb/no... /'/ name?
Si si.
Say something.
Say something more.
No.
Oh, talk to me.
Talk. Talk.
[ Baby Crying]
[ Crying Continues]
[ Men Speaking Sicilian]
[ Italian ]
Who are you?
Those people work in America.
America
is a big country, beautiful.
Your husband sent us
to work in this house.
Lots of people was in New York.
I had a son in America...
and I was working -
[ Broken English ]
And I make good money too.
On Sunday
I even go fish in automobile.
I even go in automobile...
to get my relief check.
Everybody in America
drive automobile.
We come all to Stromboli.
You see that hole?
Volcano is very dangerous.
Sometime blow up...
and lots stones go up
and come down...
break the floor
and make big hole...
and burn everything,
like in 1944.
Why did you leave America?
I leave America -
America is good for young fellows.
I am old man,
and I come back to Stromboli.
This fellow too old...
and stupid in the head.
I don't want to die here.
I want to go back over
to my son in Brooklyn...
and he saves money for my trip.
I am going back in Brooklyn
in about 10 years.
- How old are you?
- Seventy-three.
[ Chi/d Shouting]
Signora! Signora!
[Shouting In Italian ]
Good morning.
How are you today?
Good morning, Father.
I was wondering
how you're getting along.
You can see for yourself.
I stay out here.
My house is filled with little old men
who speak about America all the time.
- Sit down.
- Thank you.
Well, with a little time and patience,
everything will be all right.
Everything? You mean this island
and the volcano too?
No. I mean
your home and you.
Maybe I can help you.
I told your husband it was all right
to take the tiles from the Moletta house.
The Molettas left this island
26 years ago.
I don't think they'll mind.
You see...
I'm sort of a trustee
for the properties...
of those who have gone abroad.
I think the tiles will make
your room a little brighter...
and nobody will mind
a little robbery.
Those who have gone away
help those who are left behind.
And I, well,
I act as the middleman.
Then try to help us, Father.
I can't take life like this.
Antonio is still a boy.
Yes, I love him...
but he doesn't understand
how a woman like me feels.
I think he does.
I know how hard
he try to get work.
The fishing season
has started...
and the boats have
full crews already.
You see, there are only
four boats from Stromboli.
The rest come
from other islands.
Yet Antonio has managed
to find a place.
He sacrificed his pride.
He owned a boat of his own
once, you know.
He has done it all for you.
I know it because I talked with him.
Yes, I suppose he's doing his best,
but can't he realize that -
that I can't live here
and that he should take me away?
You need money to emigrate,
and a place to go.
Those who were born here -
all they wanted was to leave.
You can imagine how I feel,
Father, a stranger.
These black rocks,
this desolation...
that - that terror.
This island drives me mad, Father.
Won't you help us, please?
You are both young.
Make Antonio save his money
instead of spending it.
Help him, and perhaps you will
be able to leave too someday.
But while you have
to stay here...
make a good home
for yourself and for him.
It will make it easier
for both of you to wait.
If you do this,
merciful God will help you.
With me, God has
never been merciful.
Karin!
Guarda. Look.
[ Sicilian ]
I caught many, many fish.
[Sicilian ] We are rich!
I'm going to Messina
to sell all the fish.
What fish?
What are you talking about?
Like this, you see?
Many, many. Fantastic.
[Sicilian ]
We sell the fish.
Ciao.
[ Footsteps Retreating]
" [ Man ] Signora!
Yes'?"
All finished.
You want to see?
Yes, I'm coming.
- How do you like?
- O bra v/I/ Be/I/s/mo/
- [ Laughs]
- How do you like it?
It's wonderful.
Just wonderful.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Did you finish
painting that bench?
I want it in here right away.
I cut the chair.
Is it all right?
No, you haven't.
I want you to cut the legs off.
I did cut them.
But you want them shorter?
Yes, but I want them
like the other chairs.
- I want all the chairs real low, you see?
- Yes. All right.
Thank you.
N' [ Humming ]
Good morning.
Would you like to come in
and see the house?
Il/lo/to gentile of you
to come and see me.
I'd like you to come in
and see the house.
En-Enter.
Entrate.
Please, translate for them.
Tell them I would like them to come in.
[Sicilian ]
- Did you tell them?
- Yes.
- What did they say?
- You heard: just nothing.
Good morning, Rosaria. Would you
like to come in and see the house?
- No.
- But what is the matter?
Why are you all against me? I haven't hurt anyone.
Why does everyone act like this?
Why you do things like this?
You are not modest.
But I haven't done
anything wrong.
It's not my fault
if I'm different.
I look different,
I act different, and I feel different.
I've tried to make the house
better for me and my husband.
What in the world
can you have against that?
You have no modesty.
The weather's clearing up, huh?
Too much wind
on the other side of the island.
You don't think my husband
will come home tonight?
No, don't think so.
Then do me a favor and take me to the
woman who has the sewing machine.
The one who fixed
the curtains for me.
I'd like her to help me
with my new dress.
It will be easier to wait
if I have something to do.
That woman is not so good.
Her reputation is cosi cosi.
I don't care if her reputation
is cosi cosi.
I'm old enough to take care of myself.
How far is she?
- On the other side of the church.
- Wait.
I'll get the material,
and then you can take me there.
Why did she do that to me?
Maybe not on purpose.
This is the house.
This is the -
Does she speak English?
- No.
- Will you come in and help me?
- Why not?
Because my wife
is very jealous.
Oh. [Laughing]
All right. Good night. Thank you.
Bye.
[ Sheep Bleating]
[ Knocking ]
- Buona sera.
Could you cue/re for me
on the macch/ha?
Si.
Cosi.
There.
[ Treadle Whirring]
Oh, it's you.
- What's the matter? Are you sick?
- No, just malaria.
Oh, malaria.
What's going to happen
to your lighthouse when you're gone?
[Man ] My mate is there.
Poor fellow. He has to stay on that rock
all alone until you get well?
Si si.
' S/Qﬂora?
'Hmm?
Grazie.
[Sicilian ]
Fine, thank you.
I can try it on.
Oh, it's already dark.
JV' [ Men Singing In Sicilian ]
♪! [ Guitar]
[Sicilian ]
[ Men Chuckling]
JV' [ Resumes]
[Sicilian ]
N' [ Resumes ]
- Karin!
- You came back.
- Let's get out of here.
- Let me change.
- You don't want to make me look ridiculous
- - We're going now!
JV' [ Resumes]
Come on.
Cammina.
[ Sicilian ] I break your face!
What's the matter?
I haven't done anything wrong.
I went there to use
her sewing machine.
You went to the house
of a bad woman.
- I'll show you.
- Yes, yes, you'll show me. But you don't scare me!
Cammina.
JV' [ Continues ]
The money went to your head.
I suppose you came back rich...
and that's why
you're acting this way.
Well, how much did you get
selling your fish?
Here. This.
How much is it?
30,000 lire. About $40.
30,000 lire.
- My partners got more money than me.
- Why?
They took advantage of me
because you are different.
They know I have
to take care of you.
They know
I cannot wait for better job.
They give me a smaller share...
that I will work more for you.
I will work more for you.
Don't worry about it.
- Give me a match.
- Yes.
So-
- You change everything.
- Mm-hmm.
Pictures.
Yes, the pictures of your family,
I put them away.
- Madonna?
- The Madonna too.
- My mama put the Madonna there.
- All right.
I didn't throw it away.
I just moved it.
Look here.
A tree... in the house.
Yes. You don't like it?
Yes.
Maybe.
I did as you suggested.
I changed the house
to make it better for him, for me.
To make the waiting easier.
But when he saw it...
it bothered him.
He didn't have the courage
to say anything, but I -
I knew he was hurt...
and this morning
he went through...
all the old things
that I'd put away -
the awful furniture,
pictures, holy images -
and when he held them in his hand,
I could feel his great nostalgia...
and his resentment towards me.
I understand him.
Antonio is a good, simple boy.
In all his life, his only experience
has been his military service.
Yes, I understand him too,
Father...
but who understands me?
You are the only man here...
who can understand, perhaps.
Please advise me and help me.
I - I'm going mad.
I'm so unhappy, Father.
I suffer, believe me.
You must have courage.
I told you:
You're both young.
Must I waste my youth here?
It's inhuman. I can't go on.
What is it you want to do?
I - I don't know.
You must try to find a way,
Father, to help me.
Help me.
Antonio - you know
how poor his English is.
If I don't speak to him
like a child...
he doesn't understand.
One word is enough
to upset him.
Will you explain
to him, Father?
He doesn't need explanation.
The boy is just as unhappy
as you are.
Maybe even more.
Then there is no way out?
No hope?
Be patient and calm.
Perhaps I can write to some
of our people in America or Australia...
and see if there is a way
they can bring you there.
Please, please do.
Do you think it is possible?
I think so. The people
who were born on this island...
are very good people-
Take, for instance, Francesco Dimattina,
who went to America.
He died lately,
a widower without children...
and left $3,000,
all his fortune...
to Stromboli...
for the old
and to keep up the cemetery.
He left the money in my care.
I knew right away that you would be
the only one who could help us.
I'm only a poor churchman,
but I understand human suffering.
The dead find their peace
in desolate cemeteries...
swept by the wind and burned
by the sun, while we the living -
- I know. I know.
- Don't you think the memory of your friend would be more honored...
if you gave the money
to two young people who want to live?
- Perhaps, but I can't -
- Please listen to me. You -
You don't know about me,
and you don't know my past.
I g
I have been lost.
I have sinned.
I have chased
after illusions, adventure...
as if an evil force
were in back of me.
Now I realize
how wrong I've been...
and I want to make
something out of my life...
but this is too much.
You-You can't go
from one extreme to another.
[Sobbing ]
I've known this all along.
I sympathized with you
from the day you came to the island.
That's why I tried to give you
whatever spiritual help I could.
Oh, you're a good man.
Grazie.
This will calm you.
- Drink it.
- I'm so ashamed, Father.
I may have done wrong...
but all I want now
is a little happiness.
Where I was born,
we had a nice home.
We lost everything in the war.
Then I met a man...
an officer
in the invading army.
He seemed
more human than the rest.
He was young, always gay.
I was trapped,
like all the rest.
I - I have sinned,
but I've paid.
You - You're a sensitive...
experienced man.
I am only a poor priest.
But I can be frank with you.
I couldn't with Antonio.
But you are the one man
who can give me comfort.
I am no more than the parish priest
of a little community of fishermen.
- But your human qualities I can see -
- I am a priest!
And I can only assist you
during confession or through prayer.
You - You -
Your God won't help!
You -
Say anything you want.
All I can have for you...
is a deep feeling of pity.
May the Lord guide you.
Compose yourself.
Meditate.
Think.
- You're home already.
- Yes.
- I didn't expect you. Why are you so early?
- Where you been?
Oh, I took a walk.
I passed by the church.
Oh, what's that?
I bought it.
Un iuretto.
[Laughs] A ferret.
[ Laughing ]
How much did you pay for it?
[ Italian ]
Tomorrow begins tuna fishing.
- And these?
- Gaffe. To catch fish.
What did you buy
this little animal for?
To catch wild rabbits.
Rabbits? How?
Do you want to see?
Look.
What do you intend to do?
You're crazy!
- No, dammi.
- [ Protesting ]
[ Screeching ]
It's awful!
- Stop it! Stop it! Quick! The poor animal!
- It's fine.
Stupid! Stupid! Stop!
It's cruel and savage!
Idiot!
[ Sobbing ]
[ Screeching ]
[ Children Chattering]
[ Italian ]
[ Women Chattering
In Sicilian ]
[Man Shouting ]
[ Shouting Continues]
Oh, hello.
How are you?
- Do you feel better now?
- Si si.
[ Shouting ]
[Sicilian ]
What was it?
(Jr) pO/IPO-
Look here.
Look!
Eccolo!
[ Exclaiming ]
JV' [ Man Singing In Sicilian ]
JV' [ Man Whistling]
- [ Man] Comuw.
- [ Shutters Slam]
JV' [ Singing Resumes]
Corn uto! Corn uto!
♪ ./'[ Whistling Resumes]
N' [Singing In Sicilian ]
[ Italian ]
There's food on the table.
I don't want to eat.
What's the matter with you?
[ Shouts ]
Are you cra-
What have I done?
Stop!
Come.
[ Church Bells Tolling]
Mass begins now.
JV' [ People Singing In Latin ]
n" [ stops ]
- Let's go.
- Stop there. Don't dare muovere.
[ Karin] Antonio!
- Che fa/?
- Nothing. I just want to surprise you.
Accosta.
[Sicilian ]
[Men Talking In Sicilian ]
I hope you're not sorry
that I came.
Huh?
I had to see you.
I want to be with you.
And you change too.
Relax. Smile.
I'll go right away if you want.
- I don't want to embarrass you in front of the other men.
- That's all right.
[Sicilian ]
[ Shouts ]
[All Shouting ]
Wait. We have fish.
[Sicilian ]
[Shouting ]
[Cheering ]
N' [Singing In Sicilian ]
[Whistling ]
II [Continues]
[ Excited Chattering]
[ Man ] GesU e Mar/a.
[All ] GesU e Mar/a.
Grazie, GesU.
Grazie, Maria.
[Sicilian ]
Let's go.
- How do you feel?
- Better.
Did you like the fishing?
No, it was horrible.
What's the matter?
I don't feel well.
Why?
You think - hmm?
- Mm.
- Maybe -
Yes, it's three months now.
I believe I'm pregnant.
Karin. Mia D/o.
I am so haPPY-
- Are you?
- Yes.
Yes, I'm happy too.
[ Roaring, Crashing]
[ Panicked Shouting ]
[Thundering ]
[ Praying 1
[ Praying Continues]
JV' [ People Singing]
II [Continues]
That motorboat -
has it come to help us?
No. It is from Ginostra.
- What is Ginostra?
- Ginostra is a village...
the other side of the island.
II [Continues]
[Sicilian ]
See?
Our home is safe.
Yes.
Listen, I want to talk to you.
I don't want
to stay here any longer.
So?
So I want to go away.
- I don't want to have a child here.
- Eal/ora?
And?
And I'm leaving.
I'm going crazy here.
Rather than have
a child on this island, I'd -
- During the eruption of '30 -
-  I saw enough yesterday.
I'm not interested in 1930.
I'm going.
Nothing can keep me here.
But, Karin, listen -
Give me what money you have.
I hope you won't refuse me.
It's so little anyway.
- Yes, too little.
- I know, but I'm not afraid to face life, as long as I'm free...
as long as I can fight
and defend myself.
I know it.
You're not going
to keep me here, are you?
It's no use looking
at me that way!
It won't do you any good!
Nothing can keep me here!
Antonio!
Go down to the well and get me
some water. I want to wash.
Did you hear me?
[ Hammering ]
Antonio!
Antonio! Antonio!
What are you doing?
Open up!
Antonio!
What's the matter with you?
Open up the door!
Antonio!
[ Karin ]
Hello! Hello!
You! You!
Come. Come closer.
Can you hear me?
I need help.
I can't get out.
My husband nailed the door
from the outside. I need help.
- Why he do that?
- Get me out. I'll tell you later.
Come around.
The stairway's on the other side.
- Oh, thank you.
- What happened?
Let's not talk here.
It's dangerous. Come.
Nice, isn't it?
It's peaceful here.
Let's sit down.
My husband is jealous.
He's a brute.
He's jealous of you.
Remember the night
you had malaria...
and I came to the house
to have a dress made?
He made a terrible scene.
Afterwards, when he found out
I'd met you again -
remember when
you fished the octopus?
Mm-hmm.
He beat me like a beast.
- Mm-hmm.
- I can't stand it anymore.
I want to go away,
but I can't...
without help.
It's impossible to escape.
If I could reach the village...
on the other side
of the island, then -
But I haven't any money.
If you want to, I can help you.
You would?
He's capable of anything.
- You're not afraid?
- I am not afraid.
I can ask a leave
from the lighthouse.
I don't want to see him again.
I want to go right away.
- I take you to Ginostra in a boat.
- No, no. Not you.
They find out everything here.
I'll go alone.
No, you can't go that far.
I'll Walk.
You'll have to go
by way of the volcano.
I don't care.
I have to get there.
And then?
In Ginostra they have
larger boats, motorboats.
I'll find someone that can take me
to Lipari or maybe Messina.
You don't want me to help you?
Of course I do.
But you can't leave here.
In a few days I can,
when I have my leave.
But I can't wait.
I would like to, but I can't.
I give you the money.
[Groans, Coughs]
[Coughing 1
[ Coughing Continues]
[ Gasping 1
[Coughing 1
[ Wind Gusting]
[ Moaning ]
[Coughing 1
Oh, my God.
[Groaning ]
[Groaning, Sobbing ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Roaring ]
Enough. Enough.
Enough.
[ Coughing, Sobbing 1
I'm finished.
I haven't the courage.
The courage...
I'm afraid! I'm afraid!
I'm afraid!
[ Sobbing Continues]
Oh, God.
What mystery.
What beauty.
[ Wind Gusting]
No! I can't go back!
I can't.
They are horrible.
It was all horrible.
They don't know
what they're doing.
I'm even worse.
I'll save him.
Oh, my innocent child.
God!
My God!
He") me!
Give me the strength...
the understanding...
and the courage!
[Sobbing 1
Oh, God!
Oh, God! God!
[Sobbing ]
Oh, my God!
Merciful God!
God! God! God!
♪ J' [ Swells]