- 17,500 lei.
- Coca-Cola and two packets of LM.
- Red or blue?
- Red.
- And two half-litres of cooking oil.
- We've run out.
- What about one-litre bottles?
- We're out of those, too.
- Then some medicinal spirit.
- Sorry. No spirit either.
- Is that all?
- Yes.
47500.
- Good morning, Mrs. Caty.
- Morning, Mr. Marcel.
- Is Ovidiu up?
- Yes, Mr. Marcel, go right in!
Mitica!
Fetch more beer from the bathtub,
if it's chilled!
Morning, Mr. Marcel.
Go right in, please.
Have a seat on the couch.
I'll be right back. Please go in.
Heavy...
- This is the last cold one.
- So, it's the last.
- How's it going, Mr. Marcel?
- Tough, Mr. Mitica!
I don't need to teach you
about doing business.
- I'd like a word with Ovidiu.
- I think he's still sleeping.
At this hour? It's 9 o'clock.
I told him I'd be here at 9.
He's not asleep. Go right in.
So he's awake.
Go right in, Mr. Marcel.
Mitica, move this, will vou!
It's my way.
My, oh, my!
- Morning, lad!
- Morning, sir!
What dou you think you're doing?
STUFF AND DOUGH
The packages have to get there
by 2 at the latest! It's 9 now.
By the time you get up, get dressed,
have a bite, it'll be 9:30.
By the time you start the car, your
mum gives you a kiss, it'll be 9:45.
If you leave by 10,
you'll be in Bucharest in 4 hours.
Listen up: You don't stop,
you don't buy soda...
- And you don't pick up hitchhikers.
- Yes.
You drive straight to your destination.
- Fill up at Competrol.
- I filled up last night.
Fill up so you don't run on empty.
- Alright?
- Yes.
- So where do you have to go?
- 16, Agricultori St.
- Bucharest, 16, Agricultori St.
- Yes, Bucharest.
- By what time?
- Two.
- How many packages?
- All of them.
Six!
- Six packages!
- Six packages.
- Better jot it down!
- I'll remember it.
Take a sheet of paper
and write down what I told you!
Hello? Hang on!
Haven't you got a proper sheet oî paper?
What do you use for bookkeepimg? Scraps?
Take a nice blank sheet
of A4, a ballpoint
pen, and write down what I said!
Come on, Ovidiu,
please, what the hell.
Mother!
Turk, my man, have you got
everthing you need?
Yes, they're here in the car park.
I'll call you when the lad leaves.
When do you take a shit? Morning
or evening? Are you regular?
It's a serious question.
Take me: I shit
in the morning, at 9,
9:30 at the latest.
I can only shit at home.
Anywhere else, I hold it in.
You just sit on something hard
and force the shit back up.
You wriggle, you clench...
When do you take a shit?
In the evening, mostly.
Too bad! You can't rely on
a bloke who shits in the evening.
They all pull fast ones.
In your case it's good, because
you won't waste any more time now.
Hurry up! If you need
to go en route, you
don't stop! Better
you shit yourself!
I'm joking, lad. But I'm very serious!
Jot it down:
"Thîngs to do". Underline it...
(Transport: 1) 6 packages...
(2) of medical substances...
What kind of medical substances?
Pharmaceuticals - it's
written on the box!
That's all you need to know!
(3) Where?
Bucharest, 16, Agricultori St.
I've told you how to get there.
After lancului, turn left, then right...
- And straight ahead to number 16.
- Yes!
- (3) You ask for Mr. Doncea.
- 4) I ask for Mr. Doncea.
(4) You ask for Mr. Doncea.
(5) You unload the packages.
(6) You return double quick
to Constanta.
Here"s 1,000 greenbacks. YOU get
another grand on your return.
2,000 for a trip to Bucharest?
When you do a good job for me,
you'll be satisfied with the payoff.
That means, three more deliveries
and I can buy my own stall!
We'll see about that. If there'll be
more deliveries. I'll let you know.
Let's see the list!
Here are the packages.
Two Phenylbutazone,
three Preg... dnisone.
In brackets: % Extract. Sol. Phials.
And two Phenylbutazone.
Two more?
Here.
What about a delivery docket
in case I get stopped?
How about I send it by post
and you kiss the money goodbye?
Alright.
I"m off.
- Do I have to call you from Bucharest?
- Never mind that! You just drive.
What are you doing?
Get out of that bed!
I told you we're in a hurry!
Do I make myself clear or not?
- Just a sec...
- Get up and get on with it!
What does the list say?
Departure at 10.
And another thing:
Only we two know about this!
- Alright?
- Alright.
Want me to stay with you
till you get dressed?
No.
What"s up?
We're off to Bucharest.
Yes, we're taking the van.
We have to deliver some medicine.
I don't know, medicine... You coming?
I don't know what time it is.
So, you're coming?
I can only wait until 10.
No! Who is she?
You're not bringing anybody.
Mother!
- Have I got any ironed T-shirts?
- Look in your cupboard!
- Where in the cupboard?
- The top shelf.
Didn't I iron them yesterday?
They're all laid out.
Don't leave before having a bite!
At least have some coffee.
I haven't got time.
What, leaving on an empty stomach?
- Is Vali going too?
- Yes.
Then who'll bring me my stuff
from the wholesaler's? I'm out of beer.
- When will you be back?
- I don't know...
- Tonight.
- I'll be out of stock until tomorrow.
Couldn't Ivanov have
given you more notice?
That's the way to do things,
in an organised way.
- Using your head, dear!
- That's right!
- Tell him you'll go tomorrow.
- I have to be in Bucharest by 2.
So what you go tomorrow?
- What have you got there?
- Medicine.
- I don't like that Ivanov.
- You're being unfair.
Two years ego, during the sugar shotage,
who helped you out?
I've known Ivanov since we worked at
the plant together. He's a good bloke.
He makes good money
and he's got a good life.
Right. You've got customers waiting.
- Don't get cheeky!
- They're kicking up a fuss outside...
- What's the big rush?
- I'll have a cuppa, Mum, but quick.
I can't right now. Let me feed grandma.
- 0r maybe you could feed her.
- Alright.
- When'll Vali be here?
- He's on his way.
Don't want any more?
Granny's had enough.
Take her to her room.
Let her sit down
and look of the window.
If you're going, I've got a list
of stuff for the shop.
- Thanks.
- Cooking oil, medicinal alcohol...
We'll have run out of beer by tonight.
There's not much Coke left, either.
Go to the wholesaler's
and buy all this.
And lug it all the
way from Bucharest?
Big deal...
People come and ask
for a beer, a Coke...
It's summer. You have
to keep them chilled.
If you're out of stock,
they go somewhere else.
I'll buy your stuff tomorrow.
Or better send Dad.
He's not doing anything.
A cooler would do nicely.
I know, but you don't
have room for it.
Wait until I get my own shop
and then we'll buy a cooler.
- I was talking about a display case.
- We'll get a cooler and a display case.
I'm going to sell sausages, as well.
Then we'll see about your moving out?
In two weeks at the latest
and I'll be out of here.
I'm getting the shop. I already
shook hands on it with the man.
Honest!
- Hello, madam!
- Hi!
Granny, how are you? Alright?
- Is this yours?
- Yeah, have some.
This is Betty, my girlfriend...
Mrs Caty... Granny...
That's Ovarian. Lefs go!
Let me write down the list...
Give the kids some coffee!
- Your treat?
- Sit down!
- With milk?
- Yes.
Alright, but quick!
Left down the hall and then right.
I's with sugar.
My mother made it.
That's alright.
Didn't I tell you to came alone?
Where did you pick her up?
- Îîdy bit oftackle. Eh?
- Yes, really good-looking.
- What about Laura?
- I's over.
You're through with Laura? Really?
And who's she?
- She's from Medgidia.
- When did you go to Medgidia?
I didn't. She came with my cousin
to Lips's party.
So she came after I left.
Vali, buy everything on the list!
The oil, the Coke, everything...
- Tomorrow, I told you.
- Whatever... Here's the money.
- What's on the list?
- What I said!
Betty, come on, we're leaving!
Give it here.
We'll stop by the wholesaler if we can.
Give me the money.
You got wheels?
Let's take yours. Mine car's acting up.
A heavy load will wreck the dampers.
- So we're taking the van?
- Yes.
- Bye.
- Get something to eat on the way!
You're driving me crazy.
Drive safely, son!
- Drive carefully!
- Leave them alone...
Don't get into trouble on me way!
Lord, why couldn't you have gone
to Bucharest tomorrow!
Ma, I'll sit you in front of TV.
Up we go! Easy does it!
I didn't shout at her!
She wouldn't shut up.
I told her I'd go tomorrow.
- She does all the work in the shop!
- I want her off my back!
Fasten your seatbelt.
Betty!
Came on. Your seatbelt!
When I have my own shop,
I'll hire an assistant, an accountant...
Then I'll move into my own bedsit,
what the fuck!
- You'll be my driver.
- Bugger off!
And if she wants to, she can keep
the shop in that building.
I'll visit them once a week
to ask after their health.
We have to turn left, via Cernavoda.
And they'll keep the busimess?
Ovarian, you'll be a big boss...
And you'll keep giving them money?
Sure I will.
What's one got to do with the other?
I mind my own business,
my parents mind theirs.
They're going to pull down this hotel
and build a car park.
No, I's to build a fast-food place.
No. It'll be a multi-storey car park,
car wash. Petrol station. The works...
Cool. Like in the West.
Did you get a look at her?
- What's ms music?
- Quality stuff!
- Guaranteed quality.
- Music from the 'hood.
We need to stop off at Nova 2000
to fill up with petrol.
- What are you laughing at?
- Star 2000. You patsy!
That was the name of a band.
Star 2000...
What's-his-name. Petrica Geambasu...
They used to dress up like Sinatra,
with spangles, play like this...
He was in the same class
as my father at school...
You must be kidding:
See those buildings?
Ever hear of Chirvase,
the car guy with the world record?
If he got it into his head,
he could jump these fences,
and crash straight into someone's flat.
Hear about that accident in Sibiu?
A drunk driver in Audi flew off a
bridge, crashed haW-way inside a house.
He wasn't killed.
He stayed for dinner.
And what about the people
with a car in their living room...
So what they do? Listen to this!
We've got right of way.
They moved into the haft of the car
thak was embedded in the building.
The accident guy left the car there?
- No, he took it away.
- So, the man left his car or not?
- You're slow.
- I don't get it.
So the man crashed
into his own house?
No. Ha crashed into this house,
then took his half of the car away...
Why not tell us about
how you jumped over the pond.
That was different...
- When did you jump over a pond?
- A while back.
- Come on, tell us!
- Forget it, that's different.
You jummped over Lake Techirghiol
in your car?
- You're doing my head in!
- Come on, Vali.
I'll take you to
Sibiu to see that car.
Yeah, I'll look forward to it.
- Really? When?
- Soon.
Don't do that! I'll get all sweaty.
Yes. Yes, Mr. Marcel.
- Betty. I could use a backrub.
- Yes. We've left Constante.
About 5 or 10 minutes ago.
Yes, carefully, of course.
L haven't got a full tank.
I'll fill up if necessary.
Yes, I'll wait.
No, I thought you were angry with me.
If you don't mind...
Yes. Bye!
- Which Marcel? Ivanov?
- Yes, fuck him!
He got on my nerves this morning,
acting the big shot.
Don Marcelo...
I say watch your step.
What do you mean, "Watch your step"?
If he wants the to do something,
I don't. I'm no moron.
Who's this Marcel?
Roll up the window.
I's giving the a headache.
- You're sensitive to draughts?
- Who, Ovarian?
His face swells up like a balloon
from the draught.
Move it, man!
He was all uppity, said to go
straight to Bucharest,
none stop even if I was pissing myself,
to be in Bucharest by two at the latest.
Is that Ivanov's bag?
Say, dickhead,
did he cough up the dough?
Too fucking right he did!
- He's helping me buy a shop.
- Helping you, my arse!
So he gets all cocky, telling me
write it all down.
Big deal, go from Constante to Bucharest
in four hours!
I can do it in two hours and a half.
Betty, how long did
it take me on Sunday?
About four hours...
- Not the hours and a half?
- Two hours and a half.
- An hour!
- An hour.
That's my girl!
Overtake already, for fuck's sake!
You've got to have a good motor!
In a Dacia you're there in no time.
It also depends on the road. It's taking
them forever to widen this road.
Look at the state they left
that motorway in.
- But it's sfill a motorway, right?
- If you can call it that.
For 17 km you fly like the wind!
I did 170 km/h on it in a Dacia.
It hought it was going to break
in two on those slabs.
Obviously it can break in two
if you're doing 170.
If the dial goes to 170,
then that's how fast you have to go.
If not, then why did they put it
on speed dial?
Wher you speeding off to like that?
Make sure you take the first left.
Get in the right lane, Vali.
You said we'd stop off at my place.
- We will...
- You should have turned left here.
On me way back.
I haven't changed my clothes
in three days...
Shall we turn back to
let Betty get changed?
No.
Please, Vali... I just need to change
my dothes. That's all.
- I's not up to me.
- We don't have the time.
- Please...
- Hear what the man says?
You've spent 3 days wearing them.
Wear them until 6, when we come back.
- I promise...
- Yes, 7 more hours...
- Betty!
- What, can't I speak?
Give me a break!
Come on. Peasant,
you've got the horse power!
That guy in the Jeep
keeps flashing us.
Maybe he wants to overtake us.
So? He's got all the space he need!
- Maybe we've sprung a leak.
- What leak? Fuck him!
He's keeps flashin...
We're leaking oil or something...
He doesn't want to overtake.
- Better pull over.
- Come off it!
If the oil's leaking, we'd better
pull over.
Have a little patience.
Maybe he just wants to overtake.
Look, he's overtaking...
- What the hell does the fucker want?
- Let's pull over and see what's wrong.
No. Look!
- Vali, I mean it!
- No!
- I don't want to run out of oil.
- I'll pull over when I can.
- Pull over in the first lay-by!
- You're a real numbskull!
- Shit, man, pull over now!
- If you've broken my glasses...
- I didn't break anything...
- Look, there's a lay-by!
You're something else!
Happy noW?
Go and see if there's a leak!
What does this guy want?
I'll show him...
Fuckers!
There's another one!
Drive away, Vali!
- You fucking prick!
- Look out!
Fuck you, dickhead!
Fuck you, you fucker!
I've got fucking glass in my eyes!
Fuck, it hurts!
Broken glass everywhere...
Are you alright, Vali?
Yes... I'm bleeding.
The fuckers!
- Let me see, where?
- My nose... I'm alright.
- How's your leg?
- It hurts like hell!
They're coming after us!
- Who the fuck are these guys?
- How should I knoW?
They attack us with a baseball bat...
What did we do to them? Cut them up?
- Fuck all.
- What are you laughing at, you dick?
If it hasn't been for me.
We'd be dead, I'm telling you!
- They had guns!
- Like îuck did they! They had bats!
One of them had a gun.
I saw the holster.
It was his mobile phone.
How could he have a gun?
- Can't you go any faster?
- Want to crash? Let me drive!
- Want me to pull over?
- Cut it out!
- Cut it out, Vali!
- Shut up, I'm talking to Ovidiu!
Bugger off!
Get a move on!
Stupid Moldavian prick!
- What's wrong with your leg?
- It hurts!
It's nothing!
- It hurts.
- He's alright.
Forget it, Vali! Keep moving!
When we took off
we could've crashed...
They're behind us.
Let's stop and do them!
- They've got guns and clubs!
- I'll get them with the pump!
- Forget it! Keep driving!
- Don't give me orders!
We do it my way and whack them!
I don't let anybody clobber me!
- Fuck you!
- Relax! Come on, let me drive!
- What are you doing?
- Move!
Careful...
Hurry, man!
All right. Mike Heineken...
Betty, brush these shards away!
They're pricking me in the arse.
Vali turn that music down.
You're not listening to it anyway.
Hello, Mr. Marcel?
Some guys in a Jeep stopped us
and attacked us with baseball bats.
They smashed a window,
almost broke my leg...
Yes, a red one.
They're folloeing us. A red Rover.
- Nissan Patrol!
- A Nissan Patrol, I don't know, an SUV.
Vali, my partner.
Yeah, I made a mistake...
I though it was better this way.
I admit it, I'm sorry.
I made a mistake.
- Faster! They want to overtake us.
- No, it's Betty. His girlfriend.
I told you I made a mistake, Mr Marcel.
What else can I say?
They're trying to kill
us and we're talking
about whether I'm
by myself or not?
So, I didn't leave by myself!
What do you want me to do now?
Who are these guys?
How do I get rid of them?
I won't take any chances.
Not true. That wasn't the deal.
I said no! I'll turn around
and go back to Constanta
and if they stop us again, I'll
give them the bag. I'm not joking!
I'm not joking, Mr. Marcel!
What do you mean, why?
Risk my neck for 2,000 bucks?
I'm not interested!
I'm very calm. I'm turning back!
Yes.
Right. Yes.
He said to keep going and
he'll tell us what to do, later.
What did Ivanov give you to transport?
Spit it out. Ovarian.
Don't you fucking dam up on me!
Ovidiu, what's in the bag?
Give me that bag.
- Vali, stop it! Betty, stay here!
- What should I do, Vali?
- What did Ivanov give you?
- Medicine.
Don't tell me he gave
you 2,000 bucks jus
to take a bag of
aspirins to Bucharest!
- What are we carrying? Powder?
- Powder, pills, I don? Know...
He told me who to give it to
and that was all! That was the deal!
I didn't ask any questions...
For this kind of dough
you have to toil for two years.
And you didn't pu two and two together?
How did he give you the dough?
- Don't worry aboutit!
- What do you mean, don't worry?
One thousand now,
another when we get back.
- You think they're drugs?
- Definitely!
- Got the balls to open the bag?
- Sure, what the fuck!
Give me bag here.
Meclophenoxate, Prednisone...
- The cover will tear if I open them.
- Kiss my arse!
I mean it! One more Meclophenoxate.
- Yes, Mr. Marcel.
- Phenylbutazone...
- They're behind us.
- Suppositories, it says!
If I can squeeze in between
two big trucks I'll be alright.
- But how do I get rid of them noew.
- And where do you fînd two trucks?
Listen to me... I was saying that I
should go to the first police station...
Do what?
After Lehliu? They'll
have done for us by then.
There's a turn-off after Lehliu? I don't
know. You mean the Urziceni road?
No... So after Lehliu Station.
Right... I'll try...
Alright... It's dirt track?
What do you want me to do? Wreck my van?
I'll just replaced the dampers...
Alright. I'll wait for your call.
There's a country road after Lehliu
Station and they won't see us.
If we leave them behind,
we're off the hook.
- I heard.
- He said to drive in a line of cars.
I heard.
What about the delay?
He'll talk to Doncea.
- Doncea is the guy expecting the bag?
- Yes.
Betty, keep your eyes peeled.
Tell us their every move.
Overtake this guy in the Dacia!
Get your hand off the wheel!
- Stay there!
- They're behind us.
- They're tailgating us.
- Sit down!
- Let us in!
- They're way behind!
Sit down in the back!
Come on, please!
Listings! There are still
some shards of glass.
Betty, clean it up!
Please.
- Move over!
- Careful, don't cut yourself!
Look at him!
What's wrong with your indicators?
- We're all by ourselves...
- Step on it!
They're overtaking us...
They're not after us...
I told you so.
Turn on your warning lights
and let's dean up the broken glass!
We're not stopping.
You want the police to ask
about the broken window?
- I'll tell them it was a stone.
- And they'll ask you about your load.
I'll tell them I'm empty and
going to Bucharest to buy stock.
And they'll search you and find the bag.
Come on. Let's take a break. Clean
up the glass, have a piss... Please!
Alright.
Betty, help me dean up
this broken glass, please!
It's not like we get attacked
with a baseball bat every day!
You freak out, start
thinking of the movies...
imagining they're
out to get you,
carrying guns... Isn't
that right, Betty?
They had guns. I'm telling you!
I saw one on his belt...
They didn't have guns.
You watch too much TV.
- Tell her!
- Why, is it so impossible?
Everybody's got guns.
You can buy one if you want to.
Air guns, Betty of Medgidia!
You said you could buy one in the port!
- Ovarian, did they have guns?
- I didn't see any.
As a matter of fact, I didn't have
time to look.
Like you said. It's
enough to freak out,
you startthinking
they're out to get you.
You freak out and imagine they're
running you off the road.
That's only in America.
Yes, Mother.
We'll get everything on the list.
Right, wafers and lollipops too.
Ma, what the hell! Right, bye!
Not even in America. Know what Adi said
when he got back from the States?
Which Adi?
- Laura, his girlfriend's brother.
- Ex-girlfriend.
Which Laura?
That blonde from Lips's party?
- The one wearing Turkish jeans?
- Don't tell me you're better dressed.
- You and she were an item?
- Yes. So, Adi's her brother.
- You were saying, Vali?
- I cam remember...
Yes... In the two years
he spent in the States,
he didn't hear a single gunshot
in the big city.
- He was in New York, then?
- No, Las Vegas, LA, somewhere.
Anyway, it's not like that.
Give me 6,000.
Thanks.
- I can't believe they let us go...
- You think they're still after us?
How could they be, if they overtook us?
I keep thinking they'll
pull out in front of us.
The hell they will.
They weren't after us.
Ivanov...
Yes... I don't know.
They overtook us on the main road.
Haven't seen them since.
About 16 km to the Urziceni tum-off.
We'll watch our backs. Alright.
He said lo be careful - they'll be
waiting for us further down the road.
I don't think so.
That's what I'd do -
come out of the blue with my gun.
They don't know where we're heading.
Bingo, Betty! You won a T-shirt!
Do we keep going, or lie low
so you can stick it to them...
- Tell me, man!
- Keep going.
When we get to Lehliu
we'll take the turn-off.
- What do we do?
- We keep going.
Look at him!
The Faclia road was gravelled.
Didn't you see it was gravelled?
- Yeah, cobblestones.
- That's what I said.
And the gravel gets
flattened by the cars.
What flattened by the cars?
The gravel gets flattened
after it's laid.
No, bulldozers are for laying asphalt.
That road wasn't surfaced.
What, didn't you hear
the gravel flying around?
Yes, and then they spread the gravel.
Yes, and then they roll it in
with the compactor.
What compactor?
The cars press it in.
What cars, nitwit? The compactor
does it, because it's heavy.
What about the chips?
They just lay them and then
coat them with asphalt.
It's not them. It's a Suzuki.
Look, these are uncoated chippings.
- And it gets pressed in by cars!
- By the compactor!
- Because if the asphalt hardens...
- As if you went to university!
- I did. What the fuck!
- For two years.
Fuck you! You only did ten grades.
Careful, the
turn-off is coming up.
They're nowhere near.
We'll keep going.
Take the turn-off.
They're sure to be waiting further on.
To steal your bag
with Meclophenoxate...
You're sure it's
Meclophenoxate?
If they wanted the bag
why didn't they take it the first time?
Or afterwards. On the highway...
Stop revving the motor, you'll flood it.
Like they wanted to steal your bag
and your windscreen wipers...
Vali!
Ovidiu, isn't that them behind us?
- Where the fuck did they come from?
- Keep going! Faster!
- Faster!
- This is the best she can do.
- Stop!
- What does he want?
Don't mind him, keep going!
- Don't look, keep going!
- Tell me where to turn left.
They're overtaking us again.
Stop looking!
Keep going!
Where could I hide
with those guys behind me?
- Step on it!
- Want to take my place?
- Let me drive then.
- I can't see any turn-off...
Really! Get out of the way, woman!
- Now they've nabbed us for speeding.
- Where?
That white Dacia.
Easy.
I can't be bothered
to wrangle with them.
I know what to say to them.
We've got money. We'll
pay and that's that!
Yes, alright. They've
stopped our guys too.
- Documents and registration, please.
- Registration.
- And your driving license?
- I left it at home.
Have another look...
No. I'm sure I left
it in my jeans pocket.
- So, you don't have a license?
- Yes. I do! You can check.
- Your ID.
- Betty, look in my jacket.
- Perhaps the little girl has it...
- No. I'm positive it's at home.
But you can check over the radio.
- Blood type?
- It's not there.
That will make the fine bigger.
So you were travelling at 60 km/h
in a built-up area.
- We can send you the photo as proof.
- No need, I believe you.
- Where are you headed?
- Bucharest.
- Is this your vehicle?
- No, it's a company vehicle.
- Where is the license registered?
- In Constanta.
Check this license, please.
Valentin Patranescu, Constanta.
ID number: BG 080326. I repeat...
- What's the rush?
- So we can get back home early.
Stuff is cheaper in Bucharest.
Do you know the fine
for not having your license on you?
20000.
The law imposes a
fine of 600.000 to
900,000. 300.000 if you
pay within 48 hours.
I think you should keep looking...
You'll have 50,000
more to pay within 48
hours' for speeding in
a residential area.
- I don't have it on me.
- Keep looking. I'll wait.
I told you not to argue.
If I give him the license,
he'll confiscate it.
- Do you have it on you?
- Yes, but I'm not showing it!
Better to give him 100000
than have him suspend it.
Go grease his palm
and let's get out of here.
Give me 100.000..
No. 50,000. That'll do.
I'll go.
Let me drive.
- What are you doing?
- We're taking Ivanov's route.
Why this way?
Mind we don't get stuck...
- Don't you worry!
- How do we get back?
The road is back this way.
- You bribed him?
- Yes.
- How much?
- 250,000.
What the fuck! You patsy!
Make Ivanov refund it.
Turn left...
Past that cart.
Yes, you think?
That's it, good.
There's the water tower.
At first there's asphalt'
then it's a dirt track.
Goodbye, asphalt! That's it!
Go too fast down here at night
and you're a goner!
This road is only fit for an SUV.
An SUV is good on any road.
Good speed on asphalt.
4-wheel drive for the potholes...
This is a road for an
all-terrain vehicle.
Not to mention the suspension...
The suspension is shitty... I mean
it's rigid, shakes you to jelly.
There are all kinds of SUVs.
Town SUVs, off-road SUVs...
The best are those with good suspension.
A Rover's the car. Baby!
We were lucky the police pulled us over.
Otherwise those guys would have got us.
All in all, we were lucky.
What's this, another cop?
Look, another one.
He's feeling hot...
He's taken the wife out for a picnic...
- No way, it's a hooker.
- Don't bother them, then.
These potholes!
I told Ivanov I'd wreck my axle...
- That asphalt looks like heaven...
- Wait, there's a truck coming.
Geez!
At last!
- We're back in business!
- Welcome back to civilization!
I can't believe it's ten past two.
What with the coppers,
what with crawling along that lane...
Anyway, Doncea knows we'll be late.
How are you enjoying the trip, Betty?
Ever coming with us to Bucharest again?
- Aren't you thirsty?
- Let's get a Coke.
I'm kind of hungry.
While I fill up, you go buy some grub.
There's a shop not far from Dorally.
Dollary...
Yes, we'll stop at the petrol station.
They've only got oil...
They've got to have something...
Just motor oil, can't you see?
- Are you buying anything?
- What, oil?
- Maybe they've got other stuff...
- They haven't got anything.
- 300,000 lei's worth of petrol.
- Betty, want a Coke?
- Want anything?
- Me? Nothing.
- I'll get you litre of oil.
- Nothing, thanks!
Betty, Coke or Fanta?
Ovidiu, the SUV!
It's the same make...
- Don't wash it!
- Leave the little fucker alone!
Go away!
Get lost!
- The cigarette!
- Sorry!
This is a petrol station!
You can't smoke here!
What the fuck do you want?
- Watch your language!
- I'm watching my language.
What the fuck do you want?
Tell me!
- Vali!
- Get in the car.
Come and get your money!
Don't mind him, he's upset!
- You didn't need have a go at him.
- Fuck them!
That little urchin pissed me off, too.
- Why did the other one butt in?
- He told me to put out my cigarette.
I don't want to have
anything more to do with Ivanov.
We unload the stuff and off we go.
You were shitting yourself
when you saw that SUV.
Easy...
Man, these Bucharest drivers!
- No signal. Nothing...
- Did you see that one?
What about this one!
Keep looking in the wing mirror'
I almost sideswiped that car...
They're too small,
those Tico cars...
Look in the wing
mirror for me, will you.
The light's red!
Is it much farther?
I think it's on the right.
- First right?
- Yes.
Let me ask someone...
- What street?
- Agricultori.
Excuse me! Agricultori?
Thanks a lot.
I think it's on the left.
- Look, this is it!
- Yes, Agricultori.
This side or the other?
I think it's the same. Try left.
Yes, man. Agricultori!
Let's see if we can get past
all these cars...
You've got room.
16 you said? This is 65.
- 16?
- Yes.
16?
80! I think it's the other way!
Past the intersection...
Look!
This is it.
Turn the engine off.
Nobody's home.
He knew we were coming.
- I don't think the bell is working.
- We'll knock on the gate.
There's nobody here...
He knew we were coming.
He must have popped out.
- What's the time?
- Ten to three.
He'll be back at half past three max.
He knew we'd be late
and he went out to get some stuff.
- What do we do?
- We wait, what else?
Stop knocking!
We're waiting here like a couple
of idiots! Let's do the shopping.
- No!
- Come on, please!
We could be waiting for ages...
We deliver the goods
and then we do the shopping.
My arse has gone numb.
Take a walk!
How about I take the van
and go with Betty to do the shopping.
- And you wait here for Doncea.
- What about the bag?
You hang on to it.
No. We'll wait a bit longer.
He won't be much longer.
It was just an idea.
- What's the time?
- Five past three.
Let's go! Fuck Doncea!
- One of us has to stay in the van.
- Why?
- I don't want it to get broken into.
- Who would break into this jalopy?
I don't want to have
to worry about it!
I'll stay behind.
Let her stay behind.
- I wanted to see those sandals...
- Not now.
- Go, I'll slay.
- I can't carry all the stuff with her!
Alright, I'll stay... Big shots...
- Betty, listen here.
- Get me a croissant! I'm hungry.
Look after the bag.
Don't get out of the van!
What did your mother say? Oil?
- Coke, beer, alcohol, mineral water.
- It's stupid to buy beer here.
Let's not buy beer then. Get the rest...
- Got any oil in glass bottles?
- Plastic bottles.
- How many in a case?
- 12.
- How much is a bottle?
- 12,000.
- 12 times 12... 320...
- Bollocks! 240 something...
We'll take four of these.
- Got any beer in cans?
- Yes.
- Alcohol free?
- With alcohol...
We're not getting beer.
Puffed wheat!
I haven't eaten that stuff for ages!
- We have to buy Cola and pretzels.
- And something to eat.
- Bananas - full of protein.
- You eat bananas, if you like!
- They've got croissants here...
- Buy one for Betty and for yourself.
- How much is the Coke here?
- 13,900.
- We have to buy 10 cases.
- It's cheaper at the fat bloke's.
Why is it so expensive here?
It's 1,000 cheaper down there.
Wait, I don't get it.
Why is it so expensive here?
I wonder if Doncea is back?
I'll call...
Ten cases of Cola.
I left my mobile phone in the car.
Damn it!
- Oil... Do we get any spirit?
- Yes.
- How many cases of oil?
- 4.
Hurry up, will you!
Fuck Doncea! Let him wait!
- How many cases?
- 16...
It'll take too long by the time
you get the invoice and pay!
- I'm going back to the van.
- Wait, I'm coming with you.
I have to call that guy.
What's the time?
It's late, fuck it, I'm going.
Give him the oil now.
I'll stay behind and pay.
- Four cases?
- No, two.
It's OK.
- Here's the list.
- You want a trolley?
- Yes.
- Take the money.
- Anything else?
- I told you...
Coke, alcohol, cooking oil water...
That's all. And the trolley.
- The trolley...
- And the invoice.
Didn't I tell you not to leave the van?
- What have you got shit for brains?
- And so do you!
- You went to get a fucking ice cream!
- Big deal!
That's right! In two minutes flat
they'd have cleaned out the van.
Fuck!
What's the matter?
What are you het up about?
The clever girl left the van unlocked
and went to buy ice cream.
- Did they take the bag?
- No.
You left the van unlocked?
- Yes, but nothing happened.
- So what?
You were supposed to keep an eye
on the van, not buy ice cream!
I ask her why she left it.
And she says nobody broke in.
Leave her be, man!
You knew why I left you behind.
Didn't you?
Answer me!
Don't make eyes at him!
To look after the bag.
And you go buy
yourself an ice cream...
How could you do that! Fuck it!
What's this? Want to strangle her?
You've been rubbing me up the wrong way
all day, arsehole!
Oh yeah? You watch your mouth.
Don't you realise
they could've taken everything?
Man, I told her to stay
rooted to the spot.
Didn't I? Stop staring. You cow!
- That's enough, man, enough!
- What?
Enough!
I'll get the train
back to Constanta.
Get the fucking train
back to Constanta!
"You should be ashamed of youself.
Man, aren't we in the same shit?"
Why should I be ashamed of myself?
Tell me!
- Why?
- Leave me fucking me alone.
Ashamed of your big boss attitude.
You're full of shit.
So why are you hanging outwith me?
So now it's every man for himself?
- It's like you say...
- I say fuck!
Take your big boss bag
and shove it up your arse!
I'm looking for Mr. Doncea.
From Constanta.
He's busy. Tell me.
Tell him on behalf of Mr. Ivanov.
Come on in!
Shut the gate!
- Sit with that lad over there!
- Hello!
- Do what?
- Sit with that lad over there!
- You're Ovidiu, are you?
- Yes.
Hand it over.
The bag, give it here!
Those guys on the road
left you be, did they?
And? I've been waiting since two.
There was nobody here at three.
Give me the mobile!
I was expecting 14 packages.
There are only 6 here.
I don't know anything about that.
There're B packages missing...
Hi, Mr. Marcel!
Yes, he's here...
No, no problem.
We'd agreed on 14 packages.
Yes, right... I got a fright.
Whatever you say, yes...
Mr. Marcel, if you need anything,
you know where to find me.
One moment.
Yes, Mr. Marcel.
Tired... Yes. That was after Lehliu.
Lucky in a way that the
police stopped us.
And them too.
Yes, thank you.
It would have been good
If it'd been like that all the way.
Bye.
Gabi!
Come on.
Put this in my office!
That's all.
Bye!
- Where's my denim jacket?
- I don't know...
He put the stuff on top of it.
Does your leg still hurt?
Shall we take the same route back?
Take whatever route you like.
I'll go the same way.
When we get back
are you coming over to my place?
My motherwill make us something to eat.
We'll have a couple of beers...
- What do you say?
- I'm not hungry.
I'm not hungry.
Why the long face? We're partners'
the money's fifty-fifty.
I'll be going to bed.
I'll put some music on, eh?
- Anything special?
- Whatever!
There's been an accident.
- Shall we go and have a look?
- I'm not interested!
I think it's the SUV...
- You coming?
- Leave me alone!
- What happened?
- I don't know.
I've never seen anything like it.
They're all dead.
Make sure that yellow car
doesn't leave.
What happened there, sergeant?
Clear the perimeter, please!
Stand back! Stand well back!
Please stand back.
Fallen asleep in there?
Get moving!
You left without the cases of beer...
It's alright, I can manage.
Bring them upfront, not here.
Good evening, Mr. Ovidiu!
There've been customers
asking for beer all day
and there wasn't any to give them.
- Hello!
- Hi, son.
- Did you buy what I asked you?
- Yes, everything.
- There are some people waiting for you.
- I know.
- Mr. Marcel's here too.
- Good evening, Mr. Ovidiu!
You've got cockroaches
in the bathroom, too.
I'll send a man around
with some insecticide.
We've got things to discuss.
Mrs Caty.
Business. Invoices,
that kind of thing...
Good evening.
- There's more stuff in the van.
- Never mind the stuff. We need to talk.
Come in, get in line. Lads.
We have to talk.
Mr. Mitica!
Never mind the shop.
There are no customers at this hour.
Go into the kitchen. Have some coffee...
Relax. Feel at home.
Would you like a beer or anything?
Miss Nina, Mr. Sotir Erdogan.
My associates...
Ovidiu. The transport man...
Beatrice, Vali.
Let's start. Ovidiu,
you delivered the bag?
Yes.
Good. I said one grand before,
one grand after.
I've already given you one grand.
Erdogan!
Another grand now
and I'm done with you.
We don't count Beatrice... Vali!
You talk to your partner Ovidiu.
How you split it is your business.
Here!
Turk? Are those three really dead' or
will they turn up at my door tomorrow?
Yes, right, at your door tomorrow!
Good! Ovidiu, hows the leg?
It's fine now.
Vali, how was the trip?
The police pulled us over.
The guys in the SUV...
- But we got away. We're smart lads.
- Have you got a car?
- The white Dacia in front.
- A Dacia will do just fine...
- What's the mileage?
- Not more than 100,000 km.
Tomorrow you'll receive some packages
for Mr. Doncea.
You know the address.
You don't take Beatrice with you.
Drop them off, come back
and pick up your money!
That's about all!
Mr Ivanov, Vali and I don't want
to make any more deliveries like this.
What are you saying?
Secrets between friends?
Say it out loud for these people
to hear, too!
Come here...
Don't cross me! Or else
I'll send you your
folks and your fucking
stall to kingdom come!
What the fuck...
Come on, let's show Erdogan
where to find you in the morning.
I'll give you a lift.
Mr. Mitica, the coast is dear!
Shall I send the man
to do the bathroom tomorrow?
- I don't know... It might be expensive.
- It won't cost you anything.
I'll call you when I get home.
- Alright.
- Enough already!
Cut out the confession. Lads!
We're off!
- Have a good evening.
- Bye-bye!
- Are you hungry? Want to eat?
- Yes.
There's salad and chips.
I'll put them out for you.
The guy with the stall called.
He said to call him tomorrow
before ten.
- Bread?
- No thanks.
Alright.
If you want more, help yourself.
I'm going to bed. I'm knackered.
- How was the trip? Was it hot?
- So-so...
It was sweltering here...
That must be why I'm so tired.
- I'm going to bed. Good night!
- Good night.