STUPID BOY
- Hello.
Hi.
- Did I chat with you on line?
Yeah.
- Let's go.
Can I order what I want?
- Of course.
I'll have... I don't know.
A small De Luxe Menu.
- Aren't you hungry?
Don't you want a big one?
Well, we just met.
- A large De Luxe.
All right.
Well, no. A Cheese Royal.
Welcome to MacDonald's.
Your order, please.
Oh, no. Ice cubes!
- We said no ice cubes.
They're idiots, that's all.
You can't trust them.
Can I put this...
- Go ahead.
- What's your name?
Excuse me.
Mark. And you?
- Did you see how long
it took you to answer?
- 10 minutes!
- So tell me, what's your name?
Something was stuck.
- What's your name?
I said Mark.
- Come on. What is it?
And you?
- My real name? I'll tell you.
What is it?
- Lionel.
Lionel?
- And your's?
Loic.
- Why didn't you tell me before?
I don't know.
If I use an alias it's because
I don't want to tell you.
- On line, I understand, but here...
- What's the difference?
- Loic is nice. Unusual.
It's from Brittany.
- Are you from Brittany?
My parents met there.
- In Brittany?
They were at a demonstration
against oil spills or something.
They met there.
You want to know all about me.
- You can tell me to fuck off.
I'm just trying to protect
my character's intimacy
facing your's. I mean...
- Your character!
- I'm playing a role.
We don't know each other.
- It's great to eat.
- When was the last time?
It's been at least a day.
- A day?
- Yeah.
- Why?
I'm saving money.
- Economising on food?
I've already put some money aside.
- It's not a great idea.
I don't mind.
Food costs a lot.
- Never hungry?
I have a system.
- A system?
Aspirin with Maalox.
- You take aspirin and Maalox.
You know about that?
Photos aren't allowed.
- You finished work early?
Today, yeah.
- How are you?
- Like your picture?
- It's nice.
- You don't.
- You're working?
Yes.
"REFLECTIONS ON
HITLERIAN PHILOSOPHY"
- What's that?
Hitlerian...
- Hitler.
- You know Hitler.
Ah... Hitlerian.
I didn't understand.
Notice anything?
- Notice anything about me?
My eyebrow... The piercing.
- You see something?
Yeah. I see.
- It's a piercing.
Yes, I know.
- How do you like it?
Why did you do it?
I called right away.
Otherwise I wouldn't do it.
He disinfected it, then pinched
the skin gently and clack!
Did it hurt?
- A bit.
Good Evening.
- 2 tickets, please.
We close in 10 minutes.
- Go right in.
- Can you give me 10 minutes?
I'll take some pictures.
Do you mind?
You coming?
Be careful.
Do you want to sleep over?
I live alone.
If you want, you can stay.
It's not a problem.
Where do I put the condom?
- Leave it on the sink,
I'll take care of it.
Do you have someone? A lover?
I'm all alone.
I had someone last year
for about 2 or 3 weeks.
He was a very egocentric guy
and didn't take care of me.
I want someone to care of me
and I would care for him.
- I want to live as a normal couple
and not just sit in a corner
waiting for someone to draw near,
waiting for someone to want me.
He got up in the morning
and went right to the computer.
He went to the computer after lunch.
He was always at the computer.
- How do you get home?
- I stay with girlfriend in Lausanne.
- There aren't any
late trains to Bulle.
- You sleep at her place?
- Yes.
- Are you bi or gay?
- No, I'm gay.
- She's a friend. It's a long story.
- We care for each other.
- It's affection.
What's that devilish look?
- I was thinking about
all of your adventures.
Oh yeah?
- You're real
hot on line.
- You're direct.
- You don't go on and on.
Why waste time? Can you tell me?
- Before sex it's interesting to...
- Internet is expensive.
- What's interesting before sex
is seduction, even on line.
Seduction?
- Yes.
- Waiting a bit... Desiring the other...
Yeah. Yeah. I know.
I'm direct. With me it's:
" Come here and Bang! "
We meet and that's it.
- I don't want to piss you off but
to desire someone
you should wait awhile,
you should try, just a little.
It depends if you want to fuck or if
you're looking for something more.
You prefer feelings?
- It's about the pleasure of
being with someone
even for a moment.
- Even for a brief moment.
The pleasure of being together.
- In fact, sex itself
isn't that important.
I never...
- I don't want to disappoint you.
I never thought about it.
But I don't like to waste time.
- Understand?
I have to do this, so
go away for a moment.
- I made 300 francs last night.
How?
I was by the lake
and a car came up.
I went over because I thought
the guy was good-looking.
But not really.
He was an old man, about 75.
I told him no. I was polite, but I
said it was out of the question.
He offered 300 francs.
- For 300, you just close your eyes.
- So I got in and we
went to his place.
- I undressed.
He sucked me,
I sucked him, the usual stuff.
But then he wanted
me to eat him out!
I slide 1 finger in,
then 2, but then,
listen to this,
he pulled out a long flashlight.
I should have asked for 500 francs!
- It was as wide as this and round.
Stop!
I don't want to know.
Why not?
Why not? Not interested?
I don't want to know.
- Stop it. I don't want to know.
- You're a prude!
- Excuse me.
You know what they're up to?
They're going to fuck.
- Shut up!
" Shut up "?
I watched them the other day.
What?
- Just stop it.
They can't hear us.
People don't fuck
all the time like you.
They live normal lives.
They didn't want us to follow them.
Some people are simply
interested in life, in things...
Things!
- People don't always go to
museums with ulterior motives,
with twisted minds.
Something...
something strange
happened the other day.
How can I explain?
It's the first time.
I was on line, as usual.
I chatted with this guy.
We talked ass, then
made a rendezvous
at MacDonald's in Bulle.
You getting lurid again?
- He asked me
all kinds of questions.
- Usually you talk sex. But not him.
He really wanted to know about me.
It sort of threw me off.
Why are you so intrigued?
Why am I intrigued?
It's his honesty.
These encounters are
usually pretty cold.
But there, something happened.
He was normal
and asked normal questions.
I trusted him.
I even spoke about you.
What did you say?
You interested?
- Yes. It was about me.
- The truth.
Like what?
- I can't tell you everything.
I said that you were kind
and you help me out
letting me stay with you in Lausanne.
- That you squat at
my place and that I'm easy.
Yeah, I play the
male role in this story!
No, but that I stay
with you, you're cool
and very nice to me.
- Yeah, I'm nice.
- You're very patient.
- I'm very nice.
I said so.
Then he asked if I'm bi.
I said no, I'm gay.
- I never did that before.
Why?
It's nobody's business.
- Seeing him again?
He said yes.
Have you been in love?
- Yes.
Yes?
- For real.
With a young man?
- Yes.
A man?
- Of course. Why?
How did you meet?
- We had mutual friends.
You mean that a
friend introduced you
and it happened.
- We got along and fell in love.
What's it like to be in love?
How do you feel inside?
- When you wake up in the morning
you see the world differently,
as if you were standing on a chair.
- Normally you see a room
from a certain angle.
- Then you climb up and look
down and everything is different.
- Being in love is like that.
Fascinating!
- Climbing on chairs?
Listening to you,
knowing you're in love.
Are you still in love?
- No. It's over.
So now it's as if you fell off the
chair head first and broke your jaw.
- Exactly.
The room is as it was before.
- But from an lower point of view.
Okay.
- Slowly.
- Stop!
You're scaring me.
Don't be an idiot.
- When I drive I like...
You never drive, it's my car.
It's dangerous.
Your dad let me drive the
tractor like I wanted to.
- Don't mention that asshole.
Stop! Stop!
- Something broke!
Pull over there.
Did you look in
the rear view mirror?
God, you're ignorant!
Over there.
- You're stressing me out.
- Pull over. We're in
the middle of the road.
What a kill-joy!
- Kill-joy! Turn it off.
Idiot!
- It's not easy. You keep shouting.
The problem is that
you're being an asshole.
Now let's get going.
The hands of a watch.
I don't want to say it each time.
"Hands of a watch"
doesn't mean anything.
We just did it 10 times.
- Like the hands of a watch...
At this rate it will take
time just to start the car!
You can't talk out loud
at the driving test.
I talk out loud
to remember.
- In the meantime,
you're not starting the car.
Thank you.
Seat belt?
- With you at the wheel
I should wear a harness.
A harness!
- And a helmet.
- I need calm when I drive.
- Stop blaspheming all the time.
Blasphemy?
- Do you know what that means?
- It's pretty complicated to explain.
Yes, it's pretty complicated.
But the word "blasphemy"...
- It means you make fun of me.
It means making fun of you!
A blasphemer is someone who
speaks badly about Loic?
- Right?
Go on! Make fun of me.
Blasphemy means
speaking against God.
- So is Loic God?
- That's blasphemy?
It means to curse God.
- You're a pain in the ass
with your blaspheming!
- Yes, God.
Shit!
Please!
Calm down.
You could knock.
- I knock before coming in.
You have a problem?
- Don't you see that...
You didn't used to be so shy.
- That's finished.
" I'm a man now "!
Pass me a towel.
- I have lotion on my hands.
Lotion!
- Hand lotion.
- Give me the towel.
- Please.
- Give me that.
Fuck!
Get out!
I'm getting scorched.
Please, get out.
Give me the towel and
get out, Marie, please!
Install the exercise bar
because I have to...
Watch out!
Install it. I have a bad back.
- Get out!
- Now I know what I want to do.
Photography.
- Be a photographer.
Great!
- A photographer friend
liked my photos.
A professional?
Semi-professional. He does it
for pleasure but he's good.
He said I work well.
With the mobile?
- He thought the photos were good
and that I have some understanding.
It's a big step from pushing
buttons to becoming a photographer.
And you could do it.
You could learn in school.
There's no technique!
No technique?
Do you know about light, about...
It's an art, it's not
just snapping a...
with a telephone.
My friend knows a
little more than you do.
He said my pictures
of you were good.
This guy shows up and says:
" You can be a photographer. "
He's changed your life.
Are you in love?
I believe him. And he's not
after my body. He's a friend.
It is a chance to travel.
To go to Africa, film lions,
civilisations, villages, anything.
The things I like.
" Impressionist " things.
Impressionist photography!
He taught you that word.
- No. I...
- Why always mention him?
Do you know what it means?
It's when you take
pictures spontaneously.
You don't know what that means.
- Yes I do.
Hold on. He told you that you
were a very "Impressionistic " boy.
Wait a minute. I was only joking.
- Loic.
- Sorry.
It's...
It's a good idea.
Is that why you laughed?
No, but " Impressionism "!
So?
Don't you think I know what it is?
It was created by Impressionists,
such as Lenoir and company.
It was new at the time.
I don't see why I
can't do something new?
True.
Honestly.
I read about it.
I'm not an idiot who forgets things.
That's not it.
What will you photograph?
I told you.
Okay, but...
You always talk about leaving.
I want to go away.
- Why?
Photograph people in Bulle.
What can I photograph in Bulle?
The people.
The factory.
You should stop studying, get a job
and see what a factory is like.
Get up at 5 a.m., clean the shit,
and work on the production line.
Who would be interested?
Who'd care?
- I would.
I can't do photos just for you.
Many people will be interested.
- If I go, let me finish,
if I go away, I can return with
things that people have never seen.
It would be better
to take pictures of
the guys you sleep with.
Sleep?
I fuck them. Would that be pretty?
Okay, it's not nice.
But why just show pretty things?
Romping lion cubs,
a sunset, a palm tree?
Why not say:
" I want to film my life "?
It would be...
- Take pictures of me.
Not that I want to be photographed
but there's feeling.
You know me better than anyone.
You could photograph
me better than anyone.
Take pictures of me, not of lions.
Okay. You're already a lioness!
I'll photograph you when you roar.
Hello.
Shall I suck you?
Now?
Yes.
- Slowly. What's the hurry?
I don't like wasting time.
- It's not good while driving.
- I like to be fucked
and be sucked.
- I like to suck, too.
- Caressing? Not really.
- A real slut.
- You could say that.
- There's a lot of meat in Lausanne,
so I don't often leave.
- I'm Fribourg meat.
- I'll have to taste.
- Are you pierced?
- Can't you see?
- Over the eye.
- That's not a piercing!
- It's all I've got.
Who would have thought!
Let me see.
Suck me.
Bitch!
God! The piercings!
Fuck!
I can't believe it.
I've got to take a photo.
2 piercings!
I've never seen that.
Maxi-Banana!
I don't believe it.
You fuck yourself?
- Yeah.
That's not for me.
You walk around with this,
at work and everything?
Well, you know
salesmen get bored
and have to pass the time.
That's really passing time!
This is quite unique!
To each his own.
Have you been to Paris?
I heard that they
fist fuck up to here.
- Some guys...
All the way to here.
And you?
- More or less
up to here.
- Mid-forearm.
Mid-forearm. Do you realise
that my forearm goes to there?
I'd touch your lungs.
I can't believe you did it.
So you slide it in gently.
- It goes up to there?
- No problem.
You have to prepare yourself.
- Of course...
- What's the best position
for fucking yourself with this?
I usually sit on it.
- I want to watch.
- Take it.
That's good.
I like to try different angles.
How do you like this one?
Cool, no?
- What's that?
Don't you see?
2 piercings.
2 piercings, just under his cock.
- Under his balls.
Under his balls.
I think it's real cool.
- You like it? It's an awful photo.
It's weird and really bizarre.
Don't you like it?
- I don't know. It's a bit clinical.
- It's a genre, but rather clinical.
- It seems a bit...
Everything I do is shit!
- I didn't say that.
- Everyone thinks so.
- Did you do it
for Marie or for you?
She told me to.
I enjoy taking pictures
of things we've never seen.
You've never seen that before.
You can't please everyone.
What do you think of me?
- How do you mean? Physically?
For a start.
- What's amusing is that
you have
a very angular head.
- Don't look at me like that.
You want to freak me out?
- Your head is very... Turn you head.
- Look at the sun.
- Look straight ahead.
- Your nose practically
makes a right angle.
- Almost a 90I angle.
That's awful.
- It's good. It's good.
- But your face is very angular.
What does angular mean?
- It means many angles.
Oh, yeah, lots of angles.
- The opposite of round.
- Your face is...
a little...
Like a Stealth Bomber.
- Like a Stealth Bomber.
Lot's of... I get it.
Do you like that?
- Don't you? It's nice, it's...
I don't often look in the mirror.
- Your profile is
like a Greek statue.
Cool.
- It's nice, no? You happy?
I never thought about it.
It's strange...
I expected... I don't know.
I didn't expect anything.
- Aren't you flattered?
- Stop playing the tortured soul.
You know you're a pretty boy.
What did you say?
- You're blushing. Your blushing.
- You know you're good looking.
- Playing with those seductive eyes!
No.
- That seductive look!
I've been told I have nice eyes
but not that I look Greek.
Is that why you're
here with me now?
To discover who I am?
- I'm discovering you now.
- That's true.
- You're showing me your castle...
My Castle! Shit!
It's Gruyere Castle.
I didn't build it nor create it
nor carry the heavy stones.
- I've seen your photos.
True.
He's nice but during
exams he's not the same.
He watched me like a hawk.
I got as red as a tomato.
Here's Loic.
Loic, this is Fred.
- Hello.
I'll be leaving.
See you tomorrow?
- Yes.
Happy?
Thanks.
You said that Bulle was once
part of National League "A".
You want to get
back into League "B".
Does Bulle have a role
to play in League "B"?
Yes, I think so.
Regionally speaking
Fribourg doesn't have
a National League team.
- There should be a team to represent
the canton.
- A team which could join
National League "A"or "B".
It could only be a plus for
the young people of the region.
- Playing for thousands of fans
in Portugal, then relatively few
here, is it hard to stay motivated?
- Yes, it makes a big difference.
And there's the climate.
- It's the first year I've trained
in below freezing weather.
- It's the first time.
- But it's also cold now
in Portugal, in France...
RUI ALVES: THE MULTI-LINGUAL
BALL OF ENERGY SPEAKS HIS MIND
- Closing time.
Bye-Bye.
We're closing.
- Lionel.
Turn that off!
What's up?
- Come.
Get in here!
- What's your problem?
Suck me.
That's what you want!
You're a disgusting fake!
That's all you want!
My Greek profile! Bullshit!
Pig! It's all fake!
Bullshit!
You haven't been frank with me!
- Wait.
Queer!
- Where were you?
You crazy?
Where were you?
I took a walk.
- A walk!
Don't mock me! Liar!
I don't have to explain...
I followed you.
You were with the guy
from the museum.
He's so fat even I
wouldn't fuck him.
He ran his fingers
through your hair.
And then?
Did you fuck and suck him?
Do I ask what you do in bed?
- Shut up!
It's not the same.
He'll drop you.
How do you...
- Slut!
- You're digusting.
- Slut?
Out!
- That's it. Get out!
Do I ask you about the
sickening things you do?
Fuck off!
One doesn't follow people
in the streets.
You made me scream.
It's not good.
- Plug your ears.
It's not sordid.
It's simply someone to talk to.
But you wouldn't know.
You're only interested in yourself.
You're dirty.
You're the pig.
You go with anyone.
It's time.
- Well Loic,
I can't play mama anymore.
Nights like last night? No more!
I'm too old to babysit
and too young to play mom
to a 20 year old.
- I have goals.
Your life is a mess.
You try shocking me with your
stories. You think it works?
You think it shocks me?
It just makes me
feel sorry for you.
Do you even care?
- Do you understand?
We should stop seeing each other.
Completely.
I'm fed up watching you loaf around.
- It's depressing and unenriching.
Enough!
It's over!
LIONEL IS CALLING
5 UNANSWERED CALLS
MARIE IS CALLING
9 UNANSWERED CALLS
- Here's my Loic.
I'm not your Loic.
- Sorry.
- A strange place to meet!
Your kind of place, no?
- Let's sit down.
Okay. On the bench?
- So?
What?
Nothing!
- I'm glad to see you.
It's been awhile.
C'est la vie!
We can't see each all the time.
- The last time
we met it was a bit...
I had 5 minutes, so I called.
- 5 minutes!
- Precise!
I had to come to Lausanne.
Since we hadn't seen each other
I thought I'd call.
- What's going on in Lausanne?
It doesn't concern you.
What's this: ah, ah?
It's amazing how
many questions you ask.
- I'm interested in you.
- But why?
- I'm interested in you. I like you.
- In spite of what you think,
I don't want to sleep with you.
- You can be interested in someone
without wanting to fuck them.
You're laughing at me.
- I won't laugh.
Are you sure?
- Look. I'm not laughing.
- I won't laugh. I promise.
I've been following
a soccer player from Bulle.
- What do you mean?
I ran across an article
on him in the newspaper.
- And I went to see him play.
- He's well-known and
a really great player.
- What's his name?
- Rui Alves. You know him?
- No.
- He's great. And I don't know...
it's strange.
He interests me.
Rui interests me.
- He's a star! Everybody applauds
when he comes onto the field.
- He is the uncontested star
of the Bulle soccer team!
- I want to be famous like him.
- He's not great if he
plays for Switzerland.
- What did you say?
- Do you read the newpapers?
- You're in love.
- You say he's good-Iooking.
- I think you're in love.
- I'm not in love!
Idiot!
I'm not gay anymore.
- Not gay?
- Surprised?
- Just like that!
- Right.
Are you angry?
- I'm surprised.
I never have and never
will feel anythng for a man.
I know what I want
and that's it!
Look at Rui. He has a family.
He's healthy and intelligent.
I don't want to
spend my life fucking
nor live with some filthy man.
- All men aren't filthy.
Those I've met are.
- Did you look in
the right place?
- It's your life!
Do you want me to stay gay?
- Don't get upset.
I don't want you to stay gay.
But you said:
" Why not look for healthier men ".
" Not all men are filthy. "
- Because it seems to bother you.
You're pissed off
because you can't...
- We've discussed that.
It's clear that I'm no longer gay.
It was a bad phase.
- And things are better now?
- Calm down. I don't
want to freak you out.
- And your girlfriend?
We got in a big fight one night.
I called her every name in the book.
I spoke badly about her boyfriend.
- Boyfriend?
Yeah. Her boyfriend.
I said he was ugly.
That's not even true.
I hardly even looked at him.
Maybe he's okay.
- Why shouldn't she
have a boyfriend?
She'll stop taking care of me.
I can't stay with her as often.
- Have you spoken?
- No.
- Maybe you should.
- I don't know.
- You're suffering.
Maybe it's good, maybe it's bad.
Perhaps life decides.
Maybe life says:
" Loic and Marie are finished. "
And we must each go our own way.
- You can help life along.
It doesn't always know.
- Life makes mistakes.
- You can help it along.
I think that
given the situation,
seeing how things are going,
we shouldn't see each other.
It would be better.
I need to take distance
from certain things.
That's it.
- Shall we go?
- Come.
- Come on!
I wonder what's down there?
There's nothing. It's dark.
Come on! Come on!
- You'll get hurt!
- Come back! Marie!
- What's down there?
Nothing.
Excuse me.
- I'm Loic.
- Loic Muller.
- From Bulle.
- He's beautiful.
- His name is Noah.
- Your wife is Marisa.
- Right.
- There are many
articles on you.
- It's normal. You're the best.
- How do you know?
- I've seen you play.
- I know all about you.
- I'm a photographer.
- Photographer?
- Yes.
- How's that?
I take lots of pictures.
Impressionistic!
I'm an Impressionist.
- That's impressing!
I've taken pictures of you.
Want to see?
What?
What a goal! Incredible.
Look. With your head.
You often do that.
- You can call me Rui.
But I hardly know you.
Who's the girl?
- In that photo?
That's Marie.
My girlfriend.
- Where is she?
That's her at work
in Lausanne.
- I spend every weekend with her.
I sleep at her place.
We do things together.
- Like what?
Like normal couples.
- She likes to pose.
I hate it.
- Photographers tell lies.
I'm not a liar.
- Shall I delete?
Calm down. I'm coming.
What's happening?
- My eyes are burning. I can't see.
- Show me.
- They're not burnt, just irritated.
Shit! I can't believe it.
- We should have worn sun glasses.
- It's a little late!
- If something happens to Noah...
- Sorry.
...his mother will kill me.
- How will I get back?
I'm truly sorry. It my fault.
I made tea.
Thanks. And Noah?
Asleep in his playpen.
Your tea is here.
Are you there?
- Yes.
Good.
Should I be angry with you
about my eyes?
Or thank you for showing
me the mountains and
showing my son the snow?
- You spoke about soccer,
Bulle and being a star.
Those words frighten me because
I don't see it that way.
It's not important if
I'm not a star,
if you're not
a great photographer,
if I don't play
soccer all my life,
or stay in Bulle.
If I were a star,
as the papers say,
I wouldn't be playing
in League "B" for Bulle.
I'd be part of a
big European club.
- And if you were
a photographer you wouldn't
take pictures with a phone.
- It's not an accident we met.
- It was a chance in a million.
- I'm from Lisbon and you're
from Bulle, yet we have met.
- It's true and
it's not for nothing.
- It's not for nothing.
Thank you.
Can you hear me?
- All is well.
Marlyse is in the workshop.
A full withdrawal, please.
Shall I close?
Sign here.
Large bills or small?
- Large.
- 1,2,3,4,5.
Can I help?
I'd like a camera.
It depends on your needs.
If you're experienced,
if you want
to shoot your own films...
They all have night-shot,
auto-focus, steady-shot, etc.
Some have an in/out function,
which is fantastic.
You can stock images in your station,
if you're equiped for montage, etc.
No video recorder needed.
Of course, it costs more but
it's almost professional equipment.
And the one for 4,598?
- Let's look.
" OUR FIRST DUTY IS TO FEEL SHAME "
" BARRICADE OURSELVES "
" UNDER OUR FEET, PEACE "
" NO GOD, NO MASTER, NO PAPA "
What's it all about?
The dictionary can't define it all.
I must understand.
You're no longer here, Marie,
to explain globalisation,
Free States, G8, Tobin Tax,
underdeveloped countries, slavery...
but I will learn.
I don't know what I will be
but I know what I won't be.
I won't be anti-globalisation,
nor march with the masses,
nor cry " Kill Them ", nor be a cop,
nor sell out, nor be a hooligan,
nor neutral, nor reasonable,
nor a militant, nor a collaborator.
I won't fuck everyone, nor create a
family, sell ass, buy ass, have kids,
fear the dark, love the dark, be
a Christian, a Jew, a Buddhist,
not believe in people, be like
everyone, transparent, absent,
not look women straight in the eye,
fuck men rather than speak with them,
fuck everyone to avoid loving anyone.
I want to tell stories,
Marie, my own stories.
And no one will know if
they are real or fantasy.
I don't want to be a stupid boy.
I am not a stupid boy.