Thanks a lot.
Sure. Where are you going?
To the end of the highway.
You are not running away
from home, are you?
Did you hear me?
Mummy...
Hi, mom! Any more groceries out in the car?
No, couldn't afford any more groceries.
How come you're so late?
Stopped by for a couple of drinks
with someone from work.
Any objections?
-No, I was just wondering...
Evan!!! -What?
Don't scream like that.
I marked this label, you know.
-You did what?
I said I marked it.
And now not the hell of a lot
left in where I marked.
Well, I didn't drink it.
-You're lying to me.
I swear to god, it must have been you.
-Breathe on me.
Come on...
-Come on! Breathe on me!
God damn you!
I told you to throw out this trash this morning.
Wait, mom, I forgot,
I'm sorry.
Sorry? Don't tell me to cool it.
God damn it!
I don't wanna work all day so you could
sit on your ass and read comic books.
You make me sick when you look like that.
It's your father in you.
Makes me sick...
Well, that's not my fault.
I didn't choose him to be
my father, you did.
Yeah, and that was the biggest
mistake I ever made.
Where are you going?
I'm going away for a while.
Mom's having a hard time right now.
But I don't want you to go anywhere.
-It's ok, and it's for the best.
She'll be better when she has
one kid to take care of.
You understand.
But where are you gonna go?
-I don't know. I'll find somewhere.
Just don't worry about it.
I'll call you up some time, ok?
SUBURBIA
Now, what's this guy?
-Get a job.
Come on. Have some
fucking fun. Move up.
Come on, you've got some money there!
-I spent it all on this...
Now, remember, watch the floor.
Speedily follow down their clashes by [...]
so bouncers know where the trouble is. Okay?
Hey, get going out of there!
Hey, what about some drugs?
Black triangles, man.
They are fucking excellent, I'm telling you.
OK, if you change your mind,
I'm here.
I think I'd like to fuck your brains out.
What?
-I said I think I'd like to fuck your brains out.
Oh you would, huh?
Yeah, but it doesn't look like you have any.
Hey, cut it off! Hey, leave her alone!
Come on you homos!
Perfect example
of punk rock aggressiveness.
Gonna get this club closed down
or something before...
You, guys, have minds this big.
All right, listen up, now get off!
[...] turn that spot off, stupid!
And I'll give her goddamn clothes back!
And you guys wanna hear more music you
give her clothes back right now, suckers!
Attention, please!
Don't [...] and give her clothes back!
All right, that's, fine, show's over.
You guys are blowing your own city now.
Fuck you!
That's fucking typical.
All right, give them the muzak.
Come on, kid, on your feet.
Party's over.
You're such a fucking bitch.
You're so stupid, I swear that.
Get out.
And don't kick my car, pig!
-You call that a car?
What a total asshole!
Hey, kid, pretty fucked up, huh?
-Aha.
Get up. Need a lift home?
I can't go home.
-Can't sleep on the grass.
The snails will crawl on your face.
Come on.
What's your name?
-Jack.
Jack?
Yeah, Jack Diddley.
Looks like it's starting to rain.
No, that's just the acid rain
that comes down every night
about this time.
Oh, yeah?
Did you hear of a guy named Joe Schmo?
-Nope, never.
Well, his old man's a homo and he
can't stand living with him anymore,
so we're gonna go to pick him up
and take him out to the T.R. house, ok?
What's T.R. house?
It's one of those houses out by the 605.
County bought them up years ago
and just left then sitting there
all boarded up and rotting.
A bunch of us live in one of them.
It's pretty trashed but it's free.
Are you up for it?
It's not like I have anywhere else to go.
Keep going, fuckers.
My old man's a cop.
He's my stepdad.
My real father died in Vietnam
and mom got married again.
God, your stepdad's a cop.
-Yeah, that's not the worst of it though.
He's black.
-Black? God! What a drag!
Yeah, he came over to T.R.
one time to check it out.
Told everyone he was my father.
They laughed him right outta the door.
Parents are so lame.
What's that?
-My mom's diary. Listen to this.
May 10th, 1968. Dear diary, Mark
and I are gonna be very happy here.
The air is clear, skies are blue, and all
the houses are brand new and beautiful.
They call it "suburbia" and
that word's perfect
because it's a combination of
the words "suburb" and "utopia".
They didn't realize it would
be the slum of the future.
I'm sure with Mark's job at Lockheed
I'll never have to work again.
Huh, you wish...
Oh, and by the way, diary,
we want to have a child soon.
Suburbia is a great place for children.
And if it's a boy we're gonna name him
Evan Mark Johnson.
You know, sometimes I wish
she would have had an abortion.
Oh, yeah? They were illegal
in those days.
Hand me one of those bottles, will you?
I hate buses.
Hi, ya. Joe here?
-Hello, Jack.
Where's Joe?
-In his bedroom.
See if you can wake him up.
I gave up three hours ago.
Dad, I thought I told you
to leave that alone.
Oh, it's you...
What's going on?
Moving out again, hey, Joe?
Don't I even get a good-bye this time?
Later days.
Hey, look at those dogs over there.
Yeah, they are kind of nasty.
You gotta watch out for them.
I heard they killed a little kid
out here the other day. - No shit?
Where do they come from?
Well, I heard that when people were forced
to move from their houses,
that some of them left
their dogs behind them.
Coyotes came down from
the hills and fucked them.
After a while... wild dogs!
Jees! That's pretty amazing.
-Where did you hear that from?
There is a welcoming committee.
Close your windows.
-Shit, I'm stuck.
Oh, my god!
Fleabags. Razzle - one of the guys
of the house - captured a couple of them.
He thinks he can train them,
but we think he's a little bit tweaked.
What's up?
Shit, I forgot something.
You wanna be next?
-Huh?
A haircut.
How about a haircut?
Ah, no, thanks,
I just had a haircut.
You did? Could have fooled me!
Slim pickings.
Come on.
Hey, Jack. Who's that girl
getting a haircut?
Ah, that's Sheila.
Ha-ha-ha, that's very funny. Stay with us,
we'll be back after these messages.
Are you experiencing feelings of alienation
and depression or loneliness?
We at Southwest Woodside Hospital
know that these are cry for help.
We're only a phone call away.
Oh yeah? I know somebody checked in
in one of those places.
And you know what they cost?
What?
-800 bucks a week.
What did you say?
I said if you had 800 bucks a week,
you probably wouldn't be
depressed in the first place.
That's true. What's your name?
-Evan.
Did you get a burn, Evan?
-A burn?
Now, what's a burn?
Nobody is supposed to stay here
unless he gets a burn.
See. It's kinda nice.
Comes out like this.
Jesus, that will be there all your life.
Well, that's the idea.
See, if we didn't do that
we'd had all finds of flakes
hanging around.
Yeah, that's may be a stupid question, but
what does it stand for anyways?
Stands for "rejected".
Sounds really stupid to me.
Yeah. Well, stupid or not,
I don't have anywhere else to go.
It's like some kind of ridiculous
initiation of something.
So?
-So, I'm leaving.
Do you wanna me to drive you back?
No, I'll hitch.
Ain't you got better things to do?
Watch out for big bad wolf.
-The dogs, watch out for the dogs.
Dad? Let me in, it's me.
Came back?
-Oh, yeah.
How come?
-Well, because...
Well, I'll tell you about it some day.
If I ever get to know you better.
Are you gonna get a burn?
-I guess so.
And I thought twice about getting mine.
-Is that right? Why not?
Because I've got so many scars already.
-What kind of scars?
Hmm... This kind.
Jesus! What's that from?
I'll tell you about it some day
if I ever get to know you better.
What's going on?
Looks like they are killing the dogs.
They are not killing my dogs.
Where are you going?
Come back!
These are my dogs.
What the hell are you dressed up for?
-Yeah. - Where's the war?
Up your ass.
-Up your ass?
I'd like the long end of this rifle up your ass.
-[Wait it], Skinner, look.
What's the occasion?
We just thought we're doing
our good Americans' work for the day.
Did you hear about the little boy
that got killed by the dogs the other day?
We heard of that.
-Hey, we've got a little one over here.
[Put] that god damn gun.
Well, little ones grow up
to be big ones, you know.
Have you got papers for these guns?
Officer, we are from
"Citizens against Crime".
Most citizens are against crime, sir.
The question was do you have
papers for the guns?
Guns are all registered.
Jim Tripplett? Bob Skokes?
-That's right.
You know it's against law
to use fire arms
inside the city limits, don't you?
Yes, sir, we sure do, but this side of the street
is county property.
May be if decide to come back again
we should inform
the department or officer... Rennard.
May be you should.
-I know what you're probably thinking.
You just don't like private citizens
doing your work for you.
You're right.
By the way, officer,
is that legal inside of city limits?
What the hell?
Hey, may be we should look into there.
-No, that's our job. We'll handle.
Got a big kick out of
shooting that dog, didn't you?
Yeah, it's kinda fun.
Fu-uck.
That car looks awful to me.
Maybe we should run a make on it.
It should. This car I gave
my son Jack last year
when I bought my new one.
It sure looks like he's fucked it up.
Son of bitch, that IS your old Ford.
Come on, let's go check the place out.
No, I'm more worried
about our vigilante sharp shooters
then I am about a bunch of
teenagers in a crash pad.
There's one.
Hoodi-doo, hoodi-doo!
Mew! Bye, kitty.
Ha-ha, that was so close!
The big guy would have sat on me!
Garage sale
"When guns are outlawed
only outlaws will have guns"
It's a nice camper.
But if you're so in love with it,
why are you selling it?
Oh, we don't want to.
Got a lot of money tied up in this.
Yeah, you know, we've used it just about
every weekend for the last three years, but...
since the layoff we had to cut back
a little on recreation.
Oh, you were with GM?
12 long years.
-14 for me.
It's a helluva amount.
Makes it tough to get out and have
a good time when you can't afford the gas.
I'll tell you what.
Let me think about it.
Maybe I'll give you a call.
Have a nice day!
Have a nice day in my ass.
We can't work, can't hunt,
can't get sold the damn camper,
can't do jackshit.
Come on, let me buy you a beer.
Is there something special
you're looking for?
Yeah. Got any vibrators?
Not you again!
You know what he said?
If we had any vibrators.
Go, bastards and chickenshits!
Oh, somebody's been
on a garage raid.
French fries!!!
If you are at least 18 years old you may
designate a donation of your body or heart[...]
for medical transplanting in case of your death.
If you are looking for fine quality sofas,
look no more.
Today and tomorrow only
with name brand new low prices
you can have the sofa you've been looking for
plus the matching chair
at a price you'd expect to pay
for just a sofa.
Where are you going, kid?
-Get a drink of water.
Here, sit down. Drink this.
Water is no good.
Just here or everywhere?
-Everywhere.
Yeah, you never know
where the toxins are gonna creep in.
My aunt lived in a house that was built
on a hazardous waste dump.
Last April she had a baby and it
was born with no ears.
No ears? Fuck...
Yeah, I know these people who had a baby
that was born with two rows of teeth on top.
Jesus, this seems kind of a monster.
Yeah, just think. By the year 2000
there will be one big chemical wasteland.
Yeah, all contaminated and creepy
with gross, bubbling vines
hanging off the dead trees.
And the mutants will be roaming around
bumping into each other.
Yeah, my dad was in Vietnam and he had some
of that Asian orange crap dumped on 'im.
It had some adverse effects.
-Like what?
Hmm, his fingernails fell out,
loss of sexual appetite and...
this!
Hey, guess what?
-What?
Chicken butt!
So, I walked in the house and my father,
he threw me down on the living room floor
and held me there. And my mother
cut all my clothes off with the pair of scissors.
And then they made me stand there while
they burned them right in front of me.
You know, I was nude.
Really? All because they didn't like
the way you dress?
Yeah. And I looked just the way I do now.
I don't know what their problem was.
Hey, Jack.
What's with that Sheila girl?
Yeah, she is pretty weird. Why?
I don't know. She bugs me.
She's always staring at me.
She is? I heard she doesn't
even like guys.
What do you mean?
She likes girls?
No, no. I heard she hates sex.
How can anybody hate sex?
You're asking the wrong guy.
She looks so sad all the time.
These poor little
rich bitches always look that way.
Razzle told me she tried to
kill herself a couple of times.
Really?
-Yeah. He asked why.
You know what she said? -What?
-She said: pick a reason.
Hey, Cream, Cheese!
I know this is what you have been waiting for.
Ya, ya. Come here.
Come on. Sit!
Hey, check it out,
they did it!
What?
Chicken butt!
Oh, my god...
I wept.
Count: "1001", "1002".
This makes about two seconds.
Hey, stupid muck!
See what happens
when you get so wiped out?
You gotta stop bringing dope around here.
You're like some old 60's hippy dirt merchant.
-Yeah, groovy, man.
Thanks for helping me out, brother.
You must be a Pisces.
Jeez, this person looks like
a worse driver than me.
My mom's got a car like that.
Vehicle, driven by 35-year-old
Jina Johnson, came...
That IS her car!
Three shoppers were seriously injured
and Mrs. Johnson was booked
on felony drunk drive.
Nice going, mom.
Hey, bike!
Get me a bike!
Do I have to go to school?
No. Not for a while anyways.
-All right!
This is the cool band.
I think the lead singer a real...
Where's the house, Flea?
-Hold on, it's coming, it's coming.
Come on. We've been driving
around for hours... days, weeks.
Hey, my name is Razzle, man.
Oh, there it is!
9 out of 10 Americans would perish
in an all-out nuclear attack.
Not all would die instantly. Many fatalities
would be delayed for days or weeks
until the effects of injuries, burns
and radiation sickness took their toll.
And death from radiation is almost always
excruciatingly painful and prolonged.
Any survivors of an initial onslaught
would be four times more likely
to suffer from leukemia, sterility,
inherited disorders, birth defects
and other conditions
which wreck havoc on living cells.
If you do not live
in a possible target zone
it would seem to be little point
building a blast-proof shelter
because they need to be built
of very expensive materials
and most people
don't have that kind of money.
Tell me now.
-Tell you what?
What happened to your back.
Well... My dad used to beat me all the time.
That's what I thought you were going to say.
You'd think he was crazy.
He would get this look in his eye
and I would know, "Oh-oh... trouble".
He'd wake up in the night
and get touching me all over.
He got all turned on, you know,
and instead of actually raping me
he would stop himself by beating me up.
Does that make any sense?
Hey, where are you going?
Are you all right?
Hey, what does that "T.R." stand for?
"Totally ridiculous"?
Heh, that guy's begging for it.
Come on, fucker.
Hey, there's Skinner.
All right! That's enough of that.
Get away from my house.
Now!
Hey, what was that all about?
Just a couple of assholes
looking for a fight.
Do you think they're
gonna come inside, do you?
No, this isn't their kind of scene.
Yeah, one of those guys had a knife.
-Don't worry about it.
Wimps like that always carry knives.
Oh, shit...
Do I need a stamp to get out of here too?
-Watch it, smartass.
Hey!
You've got a rat on your shoulder.
Take your jacket off, hide the "T.R."
-What for?
We'll tell you later.
Just do it.
Ain't you got finally your turn to sleep in the bed?
-I sure am.
It's kinda like my bed was at home.
But the sheets were cleaner at home.
Ethan? Do you miss your mom?
-Yeah, I kinda do.
But I bet she doesn't miss me.
-Why do you say that?
Because she used to always call me
a pain in the ass. That's why.
Ahh... I bet she didn't mean it.
You're a real good little kid.
All that you do is play all day and
mind your own business, you're sweet.
"Have you hugged YOUR kid today"?
-So fuck off, Razzle.
All right. Where were we?
-"Hansel and Gretel".
In the morning the wicked witch got Hansel
by the hand and carried him to the shed.
She said to Gretel, "You must draw water and
cook something nice for your brother
and when he's fattened up I'll eat him".
"Dear God", Gretel cried,
"I want you to help us".
"Stop your blubbering", said the wicked red-eyed
witch, "it won't do you a bit of good".
Every morning the witch would say,
"Hold out your finger and
let's see if you're getting fat".
"But Hensel held out a chicken bone".
Oh, come on, don't stop.
-But he's asleep.
But we are not.
Read it to us, come on.
Aren't you too old for fairytales?
-Uh-uh.
Please.
Soon the witch got very impatient.
Hold there, Gretel.
Go get water and don't dawdle.
Skinny or fat, I'm gonna cook
your Hensel tomorrow.
See, you hold one hole closed,
you blow real hard
and all the snot will come
through the other hole.
That a boy! Now you won't get
your shirt sleeve so dirtied.
Could I have some change, mem?
Let God be on your side!
We don't do that anymore.
-I can't help it, I've got a jones.
Yeah, I've been using that
[...] lately.
Hey! Clear out of here.
No loitering allowed.
Oh yeah? And maybe we're doing our shopping.
Ever think of that?
Right, wise guy. Just get the hell out
before I call the police.
What a character...
-Yeah, for sure.
That guy is an asshole.
I saw him selling
PCP to some little kids once.
What a dick...
-Yeah.
What we need is some beer.
Yeah, our nerves are wrecked.
Beer? I hate beer.
-And an ice-cream for Ethan.
All right.
Hey, walk like this.
Nice day, huh?
All right, very funny.
Let's see some ID.
Look, I don't need this.
Don't come back here.
I don't need your business.
Okay. But let me have one of those slushies
over there. And make it a blue one.
All right. That's... 3.23.
-Thanks!
Happy Easter, asshole.
Hi!
-Quack-quack. -Bye!
God damn little bastards!
Came in here and fucked up my store.
Scum of the earth.
See you later.
Put the sock in it.
And I live over on Heatherton Avenue,
which is a nice neighborhood
or at least it used to be.
Now all you get are these wild teenagers
parading through
like a bunch of terrorists.
Hear, hear.
Yes. The little bastards were
fighting on my front lawn.
I had to hold them up with the shotgun
while my wife called the police.
And it took me over an hour to get through.
Yeah. And that's another thing: the police
ain't doing a god damn thing.
Excuse me, reverend Farrell.
Just so happens we have a member of
the police department with us here tonight.
We have reports of vandalism and robbery
just like any other city.
And we follow up each and every one of them.
Follow up? You came to my house
three hours later!
Well, we've got a responsibility by law
to adhere to certain procedures.
Well, while you're going through procedures
people's homes are being ruined by these monsters.
Look, I've had to repaint the side wall
of my store five times already.
Every time I turn around there is
a "T.R." spray-painted.
What the hell is "T.R." anyway?
Sandra says there was a stabbing recently
at the club where she was molested.
And that those same letters
were left near the weapon.
In blood.
Did you investigate that house
like you said you would?
No, not yet.
-Typical.
You know, Rennard, I get the feeling
you're not doing your job.
And I get the feeling you're using
innocent people as scapegoat.
Scapegoat?
We're talking about a bunch of psychos!
Mental rejects running wild on our streets!
We're talking about kids!
Kids like yours and mine.
Ha! Oh, I'm damn sure
they ain't my kids.
Gentlemen, please!
Can we be reasonable?
I know, times are tough and some of
you, people, are up against it.
Look, Rennard. If the police can't
protect the people,
then the people have to
protect themselves.
And take the law in their own hands?
If that's what it comes down to!
And use guns to solve your problems?
You're damn right!
Okay, mister! Hold it right there.
Identify yourself.
Hi! I'm Bill. Don't shoot.
Where's Jack?
Peeling potatoes.
Perfect.
What are you doing here?
I need to talk to you.
Let's go outside then, ok?
No, I need to talk to all of you.
What for?
Hi! I'm Jack's father.
Stepfather.
You're a cop!
Yes I am, but that's not the reason
why I'm here to talk to you.
I hate cops.
To the max.
Listen. You, kids, are making a pretty bad
reputation for yourselves.
Last night I was at a meeting and...
Just let me tell you...
You got people down on you.
What happened?
Well, you're gonna have to listen up
sooner or later.
I am not leaving until you do.
What do I have to do,
for Christ's sake? Pay you?
So, I think it's best for all of you
to go back to your homes
until this thing blows over.
You don't seem to understand.
Most of us don't have homes to go back to.
My parents are dopers and the state
won't even let me go home.
All they do is shove me into foster homes.
Let me tell you,
that sucks big eggs.
What do you do here all day?
Nothing.
-Watch TV.
Don't you wanna make
anything of yourselves?
What's the [...]?
Well, there's families for one thing.
Careers? College?
Families... Everyone knows
families don't work.
College? Most of us couldn't
afford lunch in high school.
What do you, kids, do for money?
Take bribes off cops.
Please, mister policeman,
don't make us leave our home.
We'll be good from now on.
We promise.
Yeah. This is the best home most of us ever had.
Besides, if we didn't have each other
we wouldn't have anything.
You gonna have to stay out of trouble.
If you don't, somebody's gonna get hurt.
Everybody's got guns these days
and they are just itching to use them.
Do you understand?
Let this be the last time I hear of T.R.
"Let this be the last time I hear of T.R."
Maybe we should get guns too.
I already have a gun.
Let's just move some place else.
-My old man's a shotgun.
Come on. Don't get so worried.
Everything will be all right.
I know I can get a forty-five,
but I have to steal it.
Let's go to Frisco!
What a pigsty!
Jesus Ch-rist!
At least they got good taste in women.
Sit down!
See that? See it?
What do you want?
We want to let you know
we are sick of your shit.
This is what you might call
a warning.
If there's any more trouble from you,
creeps, some heads are gonna roll.
You dirty whore!
You get the message?
Next time we'll do more
than tear up somebody's shirt.
Holy fuck.
You know what I was thinking?
No, what was you thinking?
Has anybody seen my shirt?
Yeah, you're wearing it.
Not this shirt, asshole.
My yellow shirt.
If somebody took that shirt
I'll knock their fucking teeth out.
Who will want that shirt.
-Don't call me an asshole.
Well, where is it then?
-What the hell is wrong with you?
Can't find my fucking shirt,
can't you hear?
And I can't find my fucking dope.
This is not where I had it.
I know you. You were probably
too twisted to remember where you put it.
I remember distinctedly.
-Distinctly.
Whatever. I had a jar of
25 black triangles in it.
Put them in my sleeping bag
down by my feet.
And now they're gone.
All I know is I go to all the trouble
putting nails up all over the place
to keep things organized and now
I can't find my god damned shirt.
My sentiment precisely.
Hey! Open this door!
Open this door right now!
Sheila?
What's going on?
You and your stupid dope!
That's what I think of your dope.
What are you doing?
Man, what did you do that for?
It's crazy!
Sheila's dead.
That's what happened to your stupid dope!
What?
-Sheila's dead.
Go ahead, read it.
To my friends.
Don't be mad at me for doing this.
But I really don't wanna
stick around any longer.
I'm sorry.
I hope all of you have fun with your lives.
The time I've lived with you was
the best part of my life. Thanks.
I love you all, especially Joe.
Gone forever, Sheila.
P.S.: I hope you don't have to move.
Huh, that's funny.
"I hope you don't have to move".
Did you hear something out there?
No, Ethan, just sit down and
be quiet for a while.
So, what are we gonna do?
I think we all should decide.
Ain't you supposed to call the police
when somebody dies?
Great. And that's just what we need.
What about the coroner?
We do that and they'll
call the police.
Right. And then they'll probably
gonna try and blame it on us.
Don't you think we should let
her parents know?
God damn it, Keef, man,
if it wasn't for you
none of this shit
would happen in the first place.
I always knew something
because of it happens.
Some friend you are.
He's just a choking fucking druggy.
Why don't you just leave him alone?
-Why don't you shut up?
Keef is our friend too,
you don't have to rag on him.
Wait a minute.
Just take her home.
Do what?
Let's just take her home.
Yeah. When Sindy Bartholomew o.d.-ed
her friends put her on the front seat
of her mother's car.
Well, that's pretty crappy.
We are not gonna do that.
I know where Sheila's parents live.
We could just bring her home.
Yes?
Are you Sheila's father?
Yes, I am.
Well. Sorry to tell you this, but...
she killed herself.
What is this? A joke?
No, it's not.
Please, take her.
We didn't know what else to do.
We'd like to go to the funeral.
If you don't mind.
Oh, god...
I'm sorry, but the mother requests
that you leave.
All of you.
Leave? How come?
Please, just do as we ask.
Mother is really very upset.
We aren't feeling that great either.
Believe me.
We understand.
Good. Then will you leave?
The mother really doesn't want you here.
Neither do I.
But we don't wanna to leave.
But you have to.
I mean, look at you.
We didn't have any nice clothes to wear.
We're sorry.
Will you please show
these young people out?
Why don't you just visit the grave
after we'd left?
Or maybe tomorrow.
Sheila was our friend. And we have
every right to be here if we want to.
We're staying right here.
-No, you are not.
We're sitting all the way in the back here.
Can't you just ignore us?
No, we can't ignore you!
We don't want you here.
We didn't like you when Sheila was alive
and we don't like you now.
If it wasn't for you
she'd probably still be alive.
No, asshole, if it wasn't for YOU,
she'd still be alive.
Don't you say that, you don't
know anything about us.
Yes, I do. Sheila told me all about you.
She told me how you couldn't
keep your hands off her.
You shut up!
You molested your own
daughter, you scumback,
and then you beat her -
she showed me the scars.
You're a fucking asshole,
you know that?
Hey you, T.R.! -Me?
-Yeah, you. Come here!
Where's Jack?
-Inside, I guess.
Go in there and find him. And tell him
to get his ass out here RIGHT NOW.
Yeah?
-Don't "yeah" at me.
And don't come up with
no fucking attitude
after what you've pulled.
We went to our friend's funeral, all right?
Big deal.
And beat the shit out of
your friend's father!
He's in the hospital,
in case you didn't know.
You can't piss off people
the way you do, Jack.
This time you've bit off more
than you can chew.
Somebody's gonna stop you.
Personally I'd like to see
all of you in jail for a while.
Yeah, "book 'em Danno".
I am not gonna arrest you.
But I DO want you out of that house.
If you don't leave
somebody's gonna get hurt.
I want you out tonight!
What?
-No way.
You can forget it.
Where are we supposed to go?
Anywhere!
Just get out of that place.
If these people can't find you,
they can't hurt you.
I want you to tell your friends
to get out of there and
pack up their things TONIGHT.
It's for your own good.
I'll be out there in a few hours
and make sure that you're gone.
Hey.
You could come home, you know.
Your mother would like that.
I like your personality.
Here.
So, do you feel anything?
-Aha, I feel kinda scared.
Oh, you shouldn't.
Hey.
Ain't nothing worth saving in here.
Yeah, but...
Don't you think we really gonna
trash this place before we leave?
Trash it?
This is so-o fucked,
I can't believe it!
So, what are you gonna do?
Go back home, I guess.
Fag city.
What about you?
-I don't know.
All right, I've got it!
Here's what we're gonna do.
Check it out.
I'm gonna go syphon
some gas out of your car.
Then when we get ready to leave -
right before we leave -
we'll set the whole place on fire.
Boom!
Will be fun to watch it burn.
What do you think?
-Whatever.
Here you are.
-Hey, buddy, what's happening?
Sit down. This is great.
I've been looking all over for you.
Your wife doesn't even know where you are.
-So?
Come here I wanna talk to you.
Over here.
Do you know what happened?
-No, what?
Hi...
-I don't wanna anything, thanks.
Give him a scotch, Marox.
They buried one of those kids today.
A 16-year-old girl.
-Really?
O.D.?
-I don't know.
Were you ready for this:
those kids busted in and
raided a funeral home.
They tore the place apart.
Are you shitting me?
Wait a minute.
What the fuck are we doing?
I don't know about you,
but there's no way anyone's
gonna make ME leave this place.
Uh-uh, wake up
and smell the coffee, man.
It's hopeless.
Your old man only wants us to leave
because he doesn't think
we can take care of ourselves.
That's bullshit.
We're smarter than those assholes.
Yeah, seems like if they
run us out of this place
the others will run us out of
the next place we'll find.
My old man's coming back later
and if we're still here
he's gonna shit Twinkies.
Can you imagine how
that girl's mother felt?
Her only daughter's up there in a box
and those son-of-a-bitches come in
wreck the place and
than brutalize the family.
Un-be-lie-vable.
I mean, I am not religious.
But if you ask me...
that's downright simple.
Well, Jack, what's it gonna be?
We've got a match?
Any match?
Save it, Razzle.
We're staying.
Staying?
Yeah, we're not leaving this place
without a fight.
Shit.
We're gonna have to go back
out there.
That's what I was thinking.
Hasta luego, shitface!