1
00:01:33,573 --> 00:01:35,165
Get your heads in the game!

2
00:01:46,186 --> 00:01:47,915
You're gonna let him kill the kid?

3
00:02:12,078 --> 00:02:13,306
Check out Sugar.

4
00:02:13,713 --> 00:02:16,910
He put on 20 pounds,
and now he's going for 20 more.

5
00:02:18,552 --> 00:02:21,953
All muscle, dude.
Rock solid.

6
00:02:23,023 --> 00:02:24,513
Right... solid bones!

7
00:02:27,461 --> 00:02:30,123
Eat slowly, kid.
lt's not going anywhere!

8
00:02:33,233 --> 00:02:36,498
lf you hustled as hard as him,
you'd be hungry too.

9
00:04:04,491 --> 00:04:07,153
Sugar, show him your curve.

10
00:04:22,309 --> 00:04:23,435
Give him the ball.

11
00:04:41,394 --> 00:04:42,418
Throw it!

12
00:05:48,228 --> 00:05:50,355
-Have a good weekend.
-You too.

13
00:07:16,116 --> 00:07:18,448
Sugar! Give me a ball!

14
00:07:18,518 --> 00:07:20,247
Hey, what's up?

15
00:07:31,731 --> 00:07:34,222
-l got one!
-l got one!

16
00:07:35,368 --> 00:07:37,427
-Hi, Sis.
-Hello.

17
00:07:38,738 --> 00:07:42,196
-Any news about the States?
-ls that all you want to hear about?

18
00:07:44,611 --> 00:07:46,636
Hi, Grandma.
Looking beautiful today.

19
00:07:46,713 --> 00:07:48,647
What's up? How's the TV?

20
00:07:48,715 --> 00:07:50,410
Erica won't let me watch baseball.

21
00:07:50,917 --> 00:07:52,646
Not during American IdoI.

22
00:07:53,119 --> 00:07:56,247
Hello, Miguel. Do you have
any good news for your mother?

23
00:07:56,322 --> 00:07:57,414
Yes...

24
00:07:57,490 --> 00:07:58,957
You're going to the States?

25
00:07:59,025 --> 00:08:00,652
Not yet, Mom.

26
00:08:00,727 --> 00:08:03,287
But l learned
how to throw a spike curve.

27
00:08:03,363 --> 00:08:04,455
A spike curve...

28
00:08:05,098 --> 00:08:06,360
What's that?

29
00:08:17,210 --> 00:08:19,371
l'm still working out the mechanics!

30
00:08:31,558 --> 00:08:33,526
When are you going to finish this?

31
00:08:34,060 --> 00:08:37,518
Soon. lt's just hard
to find the time.

32
00:08:37,597 --> 00:08:39,121
lt's pretty.

33
00:08:39,966 --> 00:08:43,561
l'm trying to match the chairs
my dad made, but l can't get it right.

34
00:08:43,736 --> 00:08:46,068
l think it's perfect.

35
00:08:47,140 --> 00:08:49,734
When l'm done,
l'll make you one just like it.

36
00:08:50,577 --> 00:08:53,137
And the rest of the house?
When will it be done?

37
00:08:54,113 --> 00:08:56,047
A month, maybe two...

38
00:08:56,382 --> 00:08:59,510
Do you know we just did it
where my mom's kitchen is gonna be?

39
00:09:00,420 --> 00:09:02,285
Don't tell me that!

40
00:09:02,422 --> 00:09:06,188
Why not? Next time we can do it
in Grandma's bedroom.

41
00:09:08,795 --> 00:09:11,559
Or we could do it on the roof?

42
00:09:14,734 --> 00:09:17,396
l hope you make it to the States.

43
00:09:17,470 --> 00:09:21,031
You hope?
Baby, there's nobody better than me.

44
00:09:21,608 --> 00:09:23,735
Okay, then...

45
00:09:23,810 --> 00:09:25,744
how about...

46
00:09:26,012 --> 00:09:27,604
l know you'll make it.

47
00:09:27,747 --> 00:09:29,442
Now we're talking.

48
00:09:30,116 --> 00:09:32,846
And the first thing
l'm going to do when l get there...

49
00:09:32,952 --> 00:09:35,216
l'm going to buy a Cadillac.

50
00:09:35,421 --> 00:09:38,413
And l'll drive it through
the ocean and bring you back with me.

51
00:09:38,491 --> 00:09:41,460
You can't drive a Cadillac on water.

52
00:09:41,594 --> 00:09:45,223
Sure you can.
ln the U.S. they build all kinds of cars.

53
00:09:45,331 --> 00:09:47,856
Ones that drive on water.

54
00:09:47,934 --> 00:09:49,424
You're crazy.

55
00:09:49,602 --> 00:09:51,229
l can take you to New York.

56
00:09:51,304 --> 00:09:53,238
There's snow there
in Yankee Stadium.

57
00:09:53,306 --> 00:09:54,933
Want to see me play
in Yankee Stadium?

58
00:09:55,041 --> 00:09:59,205
lt doesn't snow during
the baseball season, silly.

59
00:09:59,312 --> 00:10:01,803
So we'll go for Christmas.

60
00:10:03,616 --> 00:10:05,049
Promise?

61
00:10:05,218 --> 00:10:06,412
Sure. Next Christmas...

62
00:10:06,486 --> 00:10:09,387
we'll cross the sea
in my Cadillac car-boat. Done.

63
00:10:09,455 --> 00:10:11,855
You really are crazy.

64
00:10:17,864 --> 00:10:21,300
She was hot.
But l liked my hair too much.

65
00:10:21,367 --> 00:10:23,528
l liked it too, Javi.

66
00:10:26,339 --> 00:10:28,933
lf you liked your hair
so much, why did you cut it?

67
00:10:29,042 --> 00:10:31,738
l wanted a different look.

68
00:10:31,878 --> 00:10:33,573
Or a different girl.

69
00:10:35,848 --> 00:10:37,281
Hey, stop playing...

70
00:10:37,350 --> 00:10:39,477
This arm is worth a million dollars.

71
00:10:39,552 --> 00:10:41,850
He's right!
That arm's worth money.

72
00:10:41,921 --> 00:10:44,048
May God bless the golden arm!

73
00:10:44,123 --> 00:10:46,318
You call that flabby
rubber band an arm?

74
00:10:46,392 --> 00:10:47,882
Oh, Miguel!

75
00:10:48,294 --> 00:10:51,889
Dude, this arm throws a 95.
What does yours throw?

76
00:10:52,632 --> 00:10:55,157
Well, l threw 98
in Double-A in Portland.

77
00:10:55,234 --> 00:10:56,929
-98?
-That's right.

78
00:10:57,003 --> 00:10:59,198
Then why are you at the streetlights...

79
00:10:59,272 --> 00:11:01,604
selling cell phone chargers?

80
00:11:02,942 --> 00:11:05,433
And the one you sold me
doesn't even work.

81
00:12:33,866 --> 00:12:36,892
Many of you are thinking
about your famiIies.

82
00:12:38,471 --> 00:12:39,904
Your girIfriends.

83
00:12:41,541 --> 00:12:42,667
Your sibIings.

84
00:12:43,743 --> 00:12:44,732
Your grandparents.

85
00:12:46,446 --> 00:12:49,381
I know a Iot of you
are feeIing the pressure.

86
00:12:52,385 --> 00:12:55,047
But Im going to teII you
something `very important.

87
00:12:55,822 --> 00:12:57,881
Forget about it aII.

88
00:12:59,225 --> 00:13:02,752
The onIy thing you`ve got
to think about is yourseI`ves.

89
00:13:03,896 --> 00:13:06,387
Put aII your energy into your game...

90
00:13:06,666 --> 00:13:08,998
into your de`veIopment
as a baIIpIayer.

91
00:13:10,036 --> 00:13:12,334
Forget about e`verything eIse.

92
00:13:12,405 --> 00:13:14,498
And just play.

93
00:13:15,241 --> 00:13:17,436
You want to succeed?

94
00:13:18,144 --> 00:13:22,581
You've got to be like a racehorse,
focused on your final goal.

95
00:13:23,483 --> 00:13:25,280
Because everything...

96
00:13:25,351 --> 00:13:29,879
absolutely everything
depends on you.

97
00:14:15,701 --> 00:14:19,933
Berroa. When you finish,
go to Alvarez's office.

98
00:14:42,795 --> 00:14:45,161
Hey, Sugar,
they made me an offer.

99
00:14:46,098 --> 00:14:48,794
Congratulations.
What did they offer you?

100
00:14:48,868 --> 00:14:50,836
A hundred fifteen.

101
00:14:52,004 --> 00:14:55,701
But my agent takes like forty of it.

102
00:14:55,775 --> 00:14:57,470
How much did you sign for?

103
00:14:58,844 --> 00:15:00,937
Oh, you know.
About the same.

104
00:15:01,681 --> 00:15:03,273
Did you get any other offers?

105
00:15:03,349 --> 00:15:06,250
The Yankees and Seattle,
but not as much.

106
00:15:06,519 --> 00:15:11,752
Well, just don't get cocky.
Nobody likes a dickhead on the team.

107
00:15:11,824 --> 00:15:13,348
Welcome to the team.

108
00:15:23,002 --> 00:15:25,129
So, why do they call you Sugar?

109
00:15:25,638 --> 00:15:28,732
Well, l'm sweet with the ladies.

110
00:15:28,808 --> 00:15:32,073
But mostly l've got
the sweetest knuckle curve there is.

111
00:15:32,144 --> 00:15:35,443
Bullshit! You just learned
that the other day.

112
00:15:35,982 --> 00:15:38,075
They call him Sugar because
he eats so much dessert!

113
00:15:40,219 --> 00:15:41,686
He's just jealous.

114
00:15:54,867 --> 00:15:57,495
Dude, we got you
a little going away present.

115
00:16:09,415 --> 00:16:10,905
You should go to the Dodgers.

116
00:16:11,017 --> 00:16:13,042
l heard they're looking
for first basemen.

117
00:16:13,452 --> 00:16:15,784
To hell with that shit.

118
00:16:16,022 --> 00:16:18,513
The coaches are
even tougher over there.

119
00:16:19,725 --> 00:16:21,283
No more curfews.

120
00:16:21,360 --> 00:16:24,022
No more trainers telling me
what to do and how to do it.

121
00:16:24,563 --> 00:16:26,690
l feel good like this, man.

122
00:16:26,766 --> 00:16:28,597
Forget about it.

123
00:16:34,540 --> 00:16:36,906
''No hats inside the building, son!''

124
00:16:37,276 --> 00:16:40,837
''Cut your meat with the knife,
but eat it with the fork!''

125
00:16:41,080 --> 00:16:43,708
''Never put the meat
in your mouth with the knife!''

126
00:16:43,783 --> 00:16:46,274
''Or you'll chop off your tongue!''

127
00:16:46,352 --> 00:16:48,547
''Ten o'clock! Lights out!''

128
00:17:39,472 --> 00:17:40,962
Have fun last night?

129
00:17:42,141 --> 00:17:43,631
Feel better now?

130
00:17:48,080 --> 00:17:49,775
Here we go, here we go!

131
00:17:50,683 --> 00:17:52,310
Okay, Sugar, let's do this!

132
00:18:49,708 --> 00:18:52,643
Hey, wipe that smile off your face.

133
00:18:55,414 --> 00:18:58,315
Salvador, warm up.
You're pitching the next inning.

134
00:19:07,827 --> 00:19:09,260
Let's go.

135
00:19:13,499 --> 00:19:16,024
Just when l was
starting to like you.

136
00:19:16,302 --> 00:19:18,634
You go and do something stupid.

137
00:19:19,338 --> 00:19:21,670
What have you got to say
for yourselves?

138
00:19:21,740 --> 00:19:23,799
Alfonso was with us too.

139
00:19:23,876 --> 00:19:25,400
Don't give me excuses.

140
00:19:25,478 --> 00:19:27,742
Your behavior is unacceptable.

141
00:19:27,813 --> 00:19:30,805
You need to understand.
You've still got a long way to go.

142
00:19:30,883 --> 00:19:33,943
First, you've got to make it
to the minor leagues.

143
00:19:34,019 --> 00:19:36,920
Rookie ball.
Single-A, Double-A...

144
00:19:36,989 --> 00:19:38,456
Triple-A.

145
00:19:38,524 --> 00:19:43,484
All that before you
even set foot in the majors.

146
00:19:44,063 --> 00:19:47,499
So you had better watch what you do.

147
00:19:47,566 --> 00:19:51,127
Because nobody's going
to take this shit...

148
00:19:51,203 --> 00:19:53,171
from a pair of Dominican rookies...

149
00:19:53,239 --> 00:19:55,036
when you get to the U.S.

150
00:19:56,041 --> 00:19:58,009
You've been invited to spring training.

151
00:20:01,280 --> 00:20:02,542
Congratulations.

152
00:20:14,627 --> 00:20:17,824
You've got a call.
He says it's important.

153
00:20:44,123 --> 00:20:47,092
This was your father's.
l want you to take it with you.

154
00:20:47,626 --> 00:20:50,288
God has given you
a marvelous gift.

155
00:20:50,496 --> 00:20:53,226
And God willing,
you'll do great things with it.

156
00:20:57,269 --> 00:21:01,069
Miguelito! Don't ever forget
your Uncle Angel.

157
00:21:01,273 --> 00:21:02,638
Lupe! Your cousin Lupe!

158
00:21:02,708 --> 00:21:03,697
l'm Omayra.

159
00:21:03,809 --> 00:21:04,798
Your cousin. Lupe.

160
00:21:04,877 --> 00:21:06,139
Lola! Your Aunt Lola!

161
00:21:06,211 --> 00:21:08,145
Remember we went skinny-dipping
at the Malecón...

162
00:21:08,213 --> 00:21:09,202
When?

163
00:21:09,281 --> 00:21:11,772
You were like eight
and terrified of goats.

164
00:21:11,850 --> 00:21:12,976
My nephew.

165
00:21:13,052 --> 00:21:14,041
Your neighbor Ana.

166
00:21:14,119 --> 00:21:17,247
You cried and cried...
You were such a baby, man.

167
00:21:17,323 --> 00:21:18,881
What's your name again?

168
00:21:18,958 --> 00:21:20,391
l'm Omayra. Your cousin.

169
00:21:20,459 --> 00:21:21,448
Your Uncle Jefe!

170
00:21:21,527 --> 00:21:22,516
Uncle Angel.

171
00:21:22,595 --> 00:21:23,823
l grew up around here.

172
00:21:23,896 --> 00:21:26,694
Don't give me any shit. l taught you
everything you know, hear?

173
00:21:27,166 --> 00:21:28,793
Hey, Frank, what's up?

174
00:21:30,603 --> 00:21:33,936
l'm proud of you, kid.
Your father would be, too.

175
00:21:35,941 --> 00:21:38,774
Thanks. l owe it all to you.

176
00:21:38,877 --> 00:21:39,866
Not all of it.

177
00:21:40,045 --> 00:21:41,672
Just forty percent.

178
00:21:42,848 --> 00:21:46,249
l spent the best years
of my life playing in the U.S.

179
00:21:46,785 --> 00:21:50,221
Remember...
Life gives you lots of opportunities.

180
00:21:50,289 --> 00:21:52,154
Baseball only gives you one.

181
00:21:52,224 --> 00:21:55,159
When it comes, take advantage of it
as much as you can. Enjoy it.

182
00:21:56,495 --> 00:21:57,962
How's the new curve?

183
00:21:58,130 --> 00:21:59,461
lt's sweet.

184
00:21:59,531 --> 00:22:00,828
Here.

185
00:22:01,533 --> 00:22:02,830
What's this for?

186
00:22:02,901 --> 00:22:04,425
For your autograph.

187
00:22:06,005 --> 00:22:09,236
l'm kidding, you arrogant prick.

188
00:22:09,308 --> 00:22:11,538
That's so you'll write
to your family.

189
00:22:12,244 --> 00:22:14,371
And to me, too, if you feel like it.

190
00:22:45,444 --> 00:22:47,571
So where's that boyfriend of yours?

191
00:22:47,880 --> 00:22:49,040
Which one?

192
00:22:49,114 --> 00:22:51,378
That ugly kid you've got.

193
00:22:51,550 --> 00:22:52,710
Fernando!

194
00:22:53,185 --> 00:22:54,982
He's out there dancing with Sofia.

195
00:22:55,054 --> 00:22:56,521
With who?

196
00:22:56,588 --> 00:22:58,180
With Sofia.

197
00:22:59,124 --> 00:23:02,525
You know, Sis...
l'm very proud of you.

198
00:23:02,594 --> 00:23:04,687
l know you're going
to do great things, too.

199
00:23:04,963 --> 00:23:06,555
We all know it.

200
00:23:07,266 --> 00:23:08,858
l'm going to miss you.

201
00:23:09,301 --> 00:23:11,132
Come on. Let's go dance.

202
00:23:11,203 --> 00:23:14,001
No, you go. l'll come later.

203
00:23:14,073 --> 00:23:16,132
And tell Fernando
to watch it with my girl...

204
00:23:16,208 --> 00:23:18,108
unless he wants
problems with me, okay?

205
00:24:42,427 --> 00:24:43,621
Check this out.

206
00:24:44,363 --> 00:24:45,887
Did you look in the fridge?

207
00:24:49,701 --> 00:24:51,362
To the States.

208
00:24:52,137 --> 00:24:54,503
To the States. We've arrived!

209
00:25:02,648 --> 00:25:04,479
To the States!

210
00:25:09,388 --> 00:25:11,015
What's up, Jorge!

211
00:25:19,264 --> 00:25:23,826
Never, never, never
drink from the hotel minibar.

212
00:25:23,902 --> 00:25:25,529
That stuff is really expensive.

213
00:25:25,604 --> 00:25:29,597
You want beer? Buy it at the store.

214
00:25:29,875 --> 00:25:31,570
You want to see titties?

215
00:25:32,110 --> 00:25:34,169
There are magazines for that.

216
00:25:34,246 --> 00:25:36,009
Don't use the pay-per-view
in the hotel.

217
00:26:03,308 --> 00:26:04,570
Brad Johnson.

218
00:26:05,177 --> 00:26:10,444
Just out of college.
They signed him for a million dollars.

219
00:26:11,583 --> 00:26:15,280
There's a lot of guys like that.
Don't let it intimidate you.

220
00:26:15,487 --> 00:26:20,481
Everyone knows
Dominicans rule the game.

221
00:26:20,626 --> 00:26:23,186
What's this about
Dominicans ruling the game?

222
00:26:23,262 --> 00:26:26,322
l think he was talking
about the Venezuelans.

223
00:26:26,431 --> 00:26:28,160
Are these your brothers?

224
00:26:28,233 --> 00:26:31,669
Are you telling me
all Dominicans look the same?

225
00:26:31,770 --> 00:26:33,067
Exactly.

226
00:26:33,138 --> 00:26:35,663
Miguel and Marcos.
Up from Boca Chica.

227
00:26:36,441 --> 00:26:38,466
Ed and Orlando.

228
00:26:38,644 --> 00:26:41,477
l left these fools behind
when l moved up to Double-A.

229
00:26:41,546 --> 00:26:43,946
-But you couldn't hang in Wichita.
-l hurt my knee, asshole.

230
00:26:44,483 --> 00:26:46,508
But l'm healthy now.
You'll see.

231
00:26:46,585 --> 00:26:49,577
Fifty bucks you're
back in lowa next month.

232
00:26:49,655 --> 00:26:52,385
Fifty bucks that next month...

233
00:26:52,457 --> 00:26:54,618
you're still an asshole.

234
00:28:24,716 --> 00:28:26,877
Today I pitched to Gus Leonard.

235
00:28:27,085 --> 00:28:28,347
You strike him out?

236
00:28:29,087 --> 00:28:30,247
Yes...

237
00:28:30,322 --> 00:28:31,653
Liar.

238
00:28:31,723 --> 00:28:33,953
-You don't believe me?
-No.

239
00:28:34,026 --> 00:28:37,553
OK, but...
l got one strike at least.

240
00:28:38,030 --> 00:28:40,498
So, do you like it there?

241
00:28:40,565 --> 00:28:41,930
Its different.

242
00:28:42,000 --> 00:28:44,798
The food here is really sweet.

243
00:28:44,870 --> 00:28:47,737
But l thought you liked
sweet things.

244
00:28:50,609 --> 00:28:53,476
All the players are really good.

245
00:28:53,779 --> 00:28:55,178
But not Iike you.

246
00:28:55,247 --> 00:28:57,374
No, of course not.

247
00:28:57,916 --> 00:28:59,611
But they're pretty good.

248
00:29:01,753 --> 00:29:03,186
l miss you.

249
00:29:03,889 --> 00:29:05,652
l miss you, too.

250
00:30:07,919 --> 00:30:09,318
That's it right there!

251
00:30:11,456 --> 00:30:12,821
Let's go! One more!

252
00:33:08,300 --> 00:33:10,131
They're sending Antonio back.

253
00:33:12,337 --> 00:33:13,531
And you guys?

254
00:33:13,672 --> 00:33:15,037
We're staying here. Rookie ball.

255
00:33:16,141 --> 00:33:17,574
Go take a look at the list.

256
00:33:29,287 --> 00:33:30,754
We're not together?

257
00:33:30,922 --> 00:33:33,322
Straight to Single-A with Jorge.

258
00:33:33,458 --> 00:33:34,755
Congratulations.

259
00:33:41,666 --> 00:33:43,531
Where's l-A?

260
00:35:10,755 --> 00:35:12,017
''Soup.''

261
00:35:17,128 --> 00:35:18,720
The bathroom.

262
00:36:11,783 --> 00:36:15,514
E`veryone is so proud, MigueIito.
Its aII we taIk about.

263
00:36:15,887 --> 00:36:17,047
Did you get the money?

264
00:36:17,255 --> 00:36:18,244
Of course.

265
00:36:18,656 --> 00:36:21,887
And Victor, can he start construction
of the house again?

266
00:36:22,227 --> 00:36:24,092
III be sending money
e`very two weeks now.

267
00:36:24,596 --> 00:36:27,827
We just paid him.
He's coming next week.

268
00:36:28,099 --> 00:36:30,226
Did you get something
for yourself like l said?

269
00:36:30,535 --> 00:36:32,230
Me? What do I need?

270
00:36:32,570 --> 00:36:35,164
-Don't say that, Mom...
-Why?

271
00:36:35,373 --> 00:36:36,362
You didn't get anything?

272
00:36:36,641 --> 00:36:39,838
Well, maybe a pair of shoes,
but l am not telling.

273
00:36:40,245 --> 00:36:42,145
Good for you, Mom.

274
00:36:46,618 --> 00:36:49,553
l have to go, Mom.
The lady's calling me.

275
00:36:49,621 --> 00:36:50,747
Smells like dinner.

276
00:36:50,822 --> 00:36:52,983
Don't forget
who your real mother is.

277
00:36:53,191 --> 00:36:55,659
Are you going to prefer
her cooking to mine now?

278
00:36:56,227 --> 00:36:57,922
ImpossibIe, Mom.

279
00:36:58,429 --> 00:37:01,489
We love you. We miss you.
Strike one out for me, okay?

280
00:37:01,733 --> 00:37:03,428
l love you. Bye.

281
00:38:43,534 --> 00:38:44,967
C'mon, let's find you a suit.

282
00:38:45,136 --> 00:38:47,297
l can't afford a suit.

283
00:38:47,472 --> 00:38:50,669
l didn't say buy a suit.
l said find a suit.

284
00:38:50,975 --> 00:38:54,206
So when you make it to the big leagues,
you'll know what looks good.

285
00:38:55,847 --> 00:38:57,007
Like it?

286
00:38:57,415 --> 00:39:01,545
Hot damn! That's what's up, bro!

287
00:39:01,686 --> 00:39:02,710
lt's cool?

288
00:39:02,954 --> 00:39:05,582
Man, you look like an all-star.

289
00:39:23,408 --> 00:39:25,137
What about you?
You try one.

290
00:39:25,276 --> 00:39:28,768
Me? Nah...
l'm all washed up.

291
00:39:29,414 --> 00:39:31,211
C'mon, man. Don't say that.

292
00:39:39,791 --> 00:39:42,851
Dude, you have no idea.
Just wait till we go to Big Muddy's.

293
00:39:43,027 --> 00:39:44,016
Big Muddy's?

294
00:39:47,999 --> 00:39:50,126
You have to be 21 to drink there.

295
00:39:50,535 --> 00:39:53,003
This is my old license.
They won't know the difference.

296
00:39:56,774 --> 00:39:58,366
Are you crazy?

297
00:39:58,910 --> 00:40:01,344
Who's going to believe
l'm this ugly fool?

298
00:40:01,579 --> 00:40:04,571
You wish you were this good-looking.

299
00:40:05,016 --> 00:40:08,213
Believe me.
They won't know the difference.

300
00:42:55,720 --> 00:42:57,620
Relax, take it easy!

301
00:43:34,592 --> 00:43:36,082
Relax, Sugar.

302
00:43:37,128 --> 00:43:39,926
lt's the same game
we played back home.

303
00:43:40,698 --> 00:43:45,032
That's all it is. So relax.
Let's have some fun, okay?

304
00:43:45,770 --> 00:43:46,794
See? Just like home.

305
00:45:54,598 --> 00:45:55,792
Good game, Sugar.

306
00:45:56,400 --> 00:45:59,597
But that wasn't my fault.
l can go longer.

307
00:46:01,238 --> 00:46:03,763
Take it easy. lt's your first game.

308
00:46:54,492 --> 00:46:56,722
You think they know how to salsa?

309
00:46:56,861 --> 00:46:58,123
Go for it.

310
00:46:59,263 --> 00:47:00,821
But remember...

311
00:47:01,165 --> 00:47:04,134
just because they dance with you
doesn't mean they want anything else.

312
00:47:04,668 --> 00:47:06,761
Not from you, anyway.

313
00:47:06,937 --> 00:47:08,461
What's up?!

314
00:47:10,107 --> 00:47:11,369
Hey, Slim!

315
00:47:25,289 --> 00:47:27,587
C'mon, let's go for it.

316
00:47:28,926 --> 00:47:30,860
Let's do it.

317
00:49:55,005 --> 00:49:58,771
Who is your...favorite player?

318
00:52:02,499 --> 00:52:05,263
When did you realize you were
going to be a good pitcher?

319
00:52:06,236 --> 00:52:09,467
l knew since l was very young
l would be a good pitcher.

320
00:52:09,573 --> 00:52:11,837
Ten, eleven years old, around then.

321
00:52:12,042 --> 00:52:16,342
Thanks to God, l've had
the opportunity to develop my talents.

322
00:54:53,370 --> 00:54:55,031
No, it's not good.

323
00:54:56,540 --> 00:54:58,838
Because l haven't been playing well.

324
00:55:03,413 --> 00:55:05,881
Well, l'm working hard, but...

325
00:55:06,850 --> 00:55:09,011
l don't know. They might.

326
00:55:11,888 --> 00:55:14,721
Listen, let's talk about this later.

327
00:55:16,393 --> 00:55:19,692
Yeah, so... Tell me about...

328
01:02:03,600 --> 01:02:04,589
What happened?

329
01:02:06,302 --> 01:02:07,826
lt's over.

330
01:02:08,204 --> 01:02:09,296
Why?

331
01:02:09,873 --> 01:02:11,340
You know the drill.

332
01:02:11,975 --> 01:02:14,910
l'm not playing well,
so they'll bring up someone who is.

333
01:02:15,078 --> 01:02:18,946
But your knee... You're recovering.
You just need more time.

334
01:02:19,749 --> 01:02:20,807
Sugar...

335
01:02:36,199 --> 01:02:37,359
When do you leave?

336
01:02:38,001 --> 01:02:39,662
They want me to fly back tonight.

337
01:02:39,769 --> 01:02:40,963
Tonight?

338
01:02:41,604 --> 01:02:43,037
But l'm not going back.

339
01:02:44,441 --> 01:02:47,035
l've got a cousin in New York.

340
01:02:47,143 --> 01:02:48,804
You're going to New York?

341
01:02:49,846 --> 01:02:50,835
Where else?

342
01:02:51,347 --> 01:02:53,144
There's no work back home.

343
01:02:53,349 --> 01:02:55,510
And my bonus won't last forever.

344
01:02:58,254 --> 01:02:59,812
Relax, Sugar.

345
01:03:00,457 --> 01:03:02,186
l'll see you there
at Yankee Stadium some day.

346
01:03:02,325 --> 01:03:03,952
When the Knights come to town.

347
01:03:04,394 --> 01:03:06,988
l'll be in the front row,
getting drunk.

348
01:03:07,197 --> 01:03:09,222
Cheering like a maniac.

349
01:03:10,066 --> 01:03:11,192
Not for you, though.

350
01:03:12,368 --> 01:03:14,859
Yankee fans are crazy.

351
01:03:17,240 --> 01:03:19,868
You worry too much, Sugar.

352
01:03:20,844 --> 01:03:22,334
l'll be okay.

353
01:03:24,414 --> 01:03:26,541
lt's just a game, right?

354
01:03:38,061 --> 01:03:39,221
Howd you pIay today?

355
01:03:39,496 --> 01:03:40,554
Good, good.

356
01:03:40,930 --> 01:03:42,727
I bet you ha`ve Iots of groupies

357
01:03:42,899 --> 01:03:44,560
waiting for you after your games.

358
01:03:44,767 --> 01:03:45,961
I ha`ve a few.

359
01:03:46,202 --> 01:03:48,898
-A few?
-Just kidding.

360
01:03:49,205 --> 01:03:51,139
l mean, l would, but...

361
01:03:52,242 --> 01:03:54,403
None of these white girls
speak Spanish.

362
01:03:55,578 --> 01:03:59,173
Marcos plays in Arizona.
Lots of Mexicans.

363
01:03:59,549 --> 01:04:01,039
Everyone speaks Spanish.

364
01:04:01,217 --> 01:04:03,208
He has Iike fifteen girIfriends.

365
01:04:03,286 --> 01:04:06,084
-Shut up!
-He's probably lying.

366
01:04:06,523 --> 01:04:08,423
I bet hes Iying.

367
01:04:11,794 --> 01:04:13,193
Jorge went to New York.

368
01:04:13,830 --> 01:04:15,320
To the Yankees?

369
01:04:17,066 --> 01:04:19,034
No. Our team cut him loose.

370
01:04:19,435 --> 01:04:22,893
He's got a cousin there.
l don't know what he's going to do.

371
01:04:25,875 --> 01:04:27,843
He got injured pIaying for them.

372
01:04:28,578 --> 01:04:31,103
They owe him something.
Another chance.

373
01:04:31,247 --> 01:04:33,477
He's worked too hard.

374
01:04:35,285 --> 01:04:36,616
l mean...

375
01:04:36,886 --> 01:04:38,513
He's not a horse.

376
01:04:38,988 --> 01:04:41,081
But dont Iet it get to you.

377
01:04:41,624 --> 01:04:43,785
Just keep pIaying weII
and things wiII be okay.

378
01:06:00,203 --> 01:06:02,763
We waIked around the Superdome
and we started to sing...

379
01:06:02,872 --> 01:06:05,033
This LittIe Light of Mine.

380
01:06:05,541 --> 01:06:08,806
And it was powerfuI,
because it was a sad time.

381
01:06:08,878 --> 01:06:10,436
You didnt know
what was going to happen.

382
01:06:10,513 --> 01:06:12,481
But you had faith in God.

383
01:06:12,548 --> 01:06:15,915
And we marched around the Dome...

384
01:06:16,119 --> 01:06:18,110
and peopIe were coming from inside.

385
01:08:03,359 --> 01:08:05,122
Yo, Sugar!

386
01:08:05,461 --> 01:08:07,622
Holy shit!
How'd you get here?

387
01:08:07,797 --> 01:08:09,492
On an airplane, dummy.

388
01:08:18,508 --> 01:08:19,497
What did he say?

389
01:08:19,642 --> 01:08:22,577
Don't worry about it.
Man, it's good to see you.

390
01:08:22,645 --> 01:08:25,637
Good to see you, too.
But l'm a little nervous.

391
01:08:26,149 --> 01:08:28,583
lt's the same game
we played back home.

392
01:08:28,818 --> 01:08:32,049
Same rules, different place.

393
01:08:32,321 --> 01:08:34,118
Just have fun, it's only a game.

394
01:10:21,664 --> 01:10:23,256
Just do me a favor.

395
01:10:23,432 --> 01:10:26,492
Don't give it away
to the first white girl you meet.

396
01:12:46,208 --> 01:12:48,005
l don't understand.
You speak too fast.

397
01:12:48,077 --> 01:12:49,135
l don't understand you.

398
01:13:42,431 --> 01:13:44,558
Did you hear
l made player of the week?

399
01:13:44,633 --> 01:13:46,430
You told me last night.

400
01:15:51,927 --> 01:15:53,019
Slow it down.

401
01:15:53,195 --> 01:15:55,186
Just throw me strikes.

402
01:15:55,364 --> 01:15:57,423
These guys can't touch you, okay?

403
01:15:57,666 --> 01:15:59,759
Let's go. Throw strikes.

404
01:21:48,417 --> 01:21:50,044
What's up, Sugar?

405
01:21:53,288 --> 01:21:56,155
l forgot something in the clubhouse.
l'll be right back.

406
01:21:56,225 --> 01:21:58,284
Here, l'll load your bag.

407
01:22:11,139 --> 01:22:12,436
Where's he going?

408
01:22:13,141 --> 01:22:14,199
The bathroom.

409
01:26:13,582 --> 01:26:14,708
Talk to me.

410
01:26:14,916 --> 01:26:16,474
ls Jorge working today?

411
01:26:16,585 --> 01:26:17,574
Jorge?

412
01:26:17,819 --> 01:26:18,877
Jorge Ramirez.

413
01:26:18,987 --> 01:26:21,012
Jorge, the baseball player.

414
01:26:21,256 --> 01:26:24,350
Oh, the baseball player.
He left about two weeks ago.

415
01:26:24,559 --> 01:26:26,686
l think he drives a car now.

416
01:26:28,396 --> 01:26:31,729
Do you have his number?
His old number isn't working.

417
01:26:32,033 --> 01:26:33,625
No, sorry.

418
01:26:33,768 --> 01:26:37,033
But l think he was staying
with some people...

419
01:26:37,172 --> 01:26:40,141
up in Concourse Village.
Around 156th Street.

420
01:26:40,375 --> 01:26:43,071
Sometimes he still comes by to eat.

421
01:29:09,424 --> 01:29:11,016
Are you the owner here?

422
01:29:11,292 --> 01:29:13,658
Yes. How can l help you?

423
01:29:15,397 --> 01:29:17,092
l like your work.

424
01:29:17,532 --> 01:29:18,521
Thanks.

425
01:29:20,001 --> 01:29:21,559
What are you looking for?

426
01:29:22,003 --> 01:29:26,463
Oh, no. l mean... l don't know.
l was passing by...

427
01:29:27,442 --> 01:29:30,138
And l thought you might need help.

428
01:29:30,378 --> 01:29:31,777
l know how to make furniture and...

429
01:29:31,913 --> 01:29:34,905
No, l don't need anyone.
l'm not looking now.

430
01:29:38,586 --> 01:29:41,555
-Thanks for your time.
-No problem.

431
01:29:42,891 --> 01:29:44,950
Carpenter and assistant.

432
01:29:45,126 --> 01:29:47,458
3 years experience
and dri`vers Iicense necessary.

433
01:29:52,901 --> 01:29:54,232
Whats going on?

434
01:29:54,335 --> 01:29:56,132
Frank caIIed Iast night.
Where are you?

435
01:29:57,238 --> 01:29:58,637
l'm in New York.

436
01:29:58,773 --> 01:30:01,037
Oh, my God.
What are you doing in New York?

437
01:30:01,209 --> 01:30:03,200
I dont understand.
Your teams Iooking for you.

438
01:30:03,378 --> 01:30:04,902
l can't play anymore.

439
01:30:05,113 --> 01:30:08,344
Are you hurt?
What do you mean you cant pIay?

440
01:30:08,817 --> 01:30:11,411
No, l'm fine. lt's just...

441
01:30:11,586 --> 01:30:15,283
We`ve been working for this
your whoIe Iife, MigueIito.

442
01:30:15,390 --> 01:30:18,757
My God!
When youre so cIose.

443
01:30:19,294 --> 01:30:20,818
Don't worry, Mom.

444
01:30:20,895 --> 01:30:23,386
l have some money.
Everything will be all right.

445
01:30:23,565 --> 01:30:28,025
You ha`ve to go back.
Listen to me, my sweet Sugar.

446
01:30:28,103 --> 01:30:30,162
CaII Frank.
TheyII take you back.

447
01:30:30,271 --> 01:30:32,239
l can't go back.

448
01:30:32,307 --> 01:30:33,865
Did I raise you Iike this?

449
01:30:34,109 --> 01:30:36,202
Did I raise you to gi`ve up?

450
01:30:37,746 --> 01:30:39,907
l didn't give up. l...

451
01:30:40,949 --> 01:30:43,213
l'm starting something new here.

452
01:30:43,418 --> 01:30:45,613
MigueI, where are you staying?

453
01:30:47,122 --> 01:30:48,180
MigueI!

454
01:30:48,857 --> 01:30:52,588
Listen, Mom, l have to go.
The card's almost out of minutes.

455
01:30:53,128 --> 01:30:55,221
MigueI, Iisten to me, pIease.

456
01:30:55,463 --> 01:30:57,829
Don't worry.
l'm staying with a friend.

457
01:30:58,166 --> 01:31:02,227
l have a job. Everything's all right.
l'll send money tomorrow.

458
01:31:02,303 --> 01:31:05,238
Listen to me.
You ha`ve to go back.

459
01:31:05,306 --> 01:31:08,207
l love you. l'm sorry.

460
01:31:17,886 --> 01:31:19,979
l was here the other day.

461
01:31:21,055 --> 01:31:22,044
Did you find your friend?

462
01:31:22,290 --> 01:31:25,316
No... Actually,
l'm looking for a job.

463
01:31:25,393 --> 01:31:27,156
Fernando!

464
01:31:27,762 --> 01:31:30,128
Tell him you like his shirt.

465
01:31:37,372 --> 01:31:38,737
When you have them here...

466
01:31:38,807 --> 01:31:41,605
you just have to make sure
you get all the scraps off.

467
01:31:41,709 --> 01:31:43,609
Because the machine
won't wash that off.

468
01:31:44,279 --> 01:31:46,440
A little splash of water...

469
01:31:48,883 --> 01:31:50,908
You raise this up here...

470
01:31:51,553 --> 01:31:53,680
put them inside.

471
01:31:54,455 --> 01:31:55,979
And that's it.

472
01:32:01,830 --> 01:32:03,730
How long have you been
working here?

473
01:32:04,199 --> 01:32:05,291
Two years.

474
01:32:09,671 --> 01:32:11,138
Do you have family here?

475
01:32:11,773 --> 01:32:14,105
No. My wife and kids are in Mexico.

476
01:32:15,410 --> 01:32:17,776
My family is in the Dominican.

477
01:32:23,184 --> 01:32:25,482
-Remember me?
-Yes.

478
01:32:25,887 --> 01:32:29,152
But sorry,
l still don't have a job for you.

479
01:32:29,357 --> 01:32:30,984
That's okay. l already found one.

480
01:32:31,159 --> 01:32:33,457
Actually,
l'm trying to make a table...

481
01:32:33,628 --> 01:32:37,962
And l'd like to buy
some wood and supplies.

482
01:32:38,433 --> 01:32:40,663
l don't really sell raw materials.

483
01:32:43,605 --> 01:32:45,129
l just moved here...

484
01:32:45,874 --> 01:32:49,207
and l don't have a space to work.
So l was wondering if...

485
01:32:49,377 --> 01:32:51,743
lf l could use your workshop.

486
01:32:51,946 --> 01:32:55,712
l could work for you in exchange.
Help you clean up...

487
01:32:55,917 --> 01:32:57,509
Whatever you need.

488
01:32:57,585 --> 01:32:59,985
You don't have to pay me.

489
01:33:00,154 --> 01:33:01,621
Somebody paying you for the table?

490
01:33:01,789 --> 01:33:04,349
No. lt's a gift for my mom.

491
01:33:04,492 --> 01:33:05,720
Something l like to do.

492
01:33:06,427 --> 01:33:08,361
How old are you?

493
01:33:08,463 --> 01:33:09,452
Twenty.

494
01:33:09,597 --> 01:33:11,497
Who taught you to make tables?

495
01:33:11,766 --> 01:33:14,428
My dad.
He was a carpenter in San Pedro.

496
01:33:14,569 --> 01:33:18,300
l've got a few guys
from there working here.

497
01:33:18,439 --> 01:33:20,236
l'm Puerto Rican.

498
01:33:20,575 --> 01:33:23,066
What are you doing in New York?

499
01:33:23,244 --> 01:33:26,372
l came to work.
l used to play baseball.

500
01:33:26,581 --> 01:33:29,379
The whole world plays baseball.

501
01:33:29,517 --> 01:33:31,451
My son's sixteen.

502
01:33:31,686 --> 01:33:36,123
Won't touch a piece of wood
that's not a baseball bat.

503
01:33:36,624 --> 01:33:39,718
l never cared for the game, myself.
Too slow.

504
01:33:39,861 --> 01:33:41,761
Your mom still in San Pedro?

505
01:33:41,863 --> 01:33:45,060
Yeah. With my sister and brother.

506
01:33:45,199 --> 01:33:47,429
So, let's see...

507
01:33:48,036 --> 01:33:51,904
You're telling me that you want
to make a table for your mom...

508
01:33:52,040 --> 01:33:54,565
then mail it back to her
in the Dominican Republic?

509
01:33:55,610 --> 01:33:56,599
Yes.

510
01:33:58,746 --> 01:34:00,407
What's your name?

511
01:34:00,581 --> 01:34:01,673
Miguel.

512
01:34:02,817 --> 01:34:04,216
Osvaldo.

513
01:34:51,733 --> 01:34:53,360
ls Sofia there?

514
01:34:54,168 --> 01:34:56,261
Yes, it's Miguel again.

515
01:34:59,173 --> 01:35:01,038
Could you tell her...

516
01:35:02,343 --> 01:35:04,436
Just tell her l called.

517
01:35:25,366 --> 01:35:28,392
So you never liked baseball?
Not even as a kid?

518
01:35:29,303 --> 01:35:32,101
Sometimes during the play-offs
l'll watch a game or two.

519
01:35:32,273 --> 01:35:33,934
Who's your favorite player?

520
01:35:34,142 --> 01:35:37,509
l don't know enough
to have a favorite.

521
01:35:38,079 --> 01:35:39,876
C'mon, everybody has
a favorite player.

522
01:35:40,281 --> 01:35:41,339
Fine.

523
01:35:41,416 --> 01:35:42,542
José Canseco.

524
01:35:45,119 --> 01:35:46,677
That's the best you can do?

525
01:35:47,255 --> 01:35:49,553
lt's all the same to me.
What about you?

526
01:35:50,191 --> 01:35:51,522
Roberto Clemente.

527
01:35:52,760 --> 01:35:55,058
What do you know about Clemente?

528
01:35:55,396 --> 01:35:57,990
l read something where he said...

529
01:35:58,066 --> 01:35:59,556
''lf you have the opportunity...

530
01:35:59,667 --> 01:36:03,194
''to help someone, and you don't,
then you're wasting your life.''

531
01:36:03,971 --> 01:36:05,268
Besides...

532
01:36:05,339 --> 01:36:07,534
He was a carpenter, too.

533
01:36:08,376 --> 01:36:10,037
Get out of here.

534
01:36:10,111 --> 01:36:14,377
For real. He used to make furniture
during the off-season.

535
01:36:14,549 --> 01:36:16,244
Are you messing with me?

536
01:36:16,484 --> 01:36:19,385
Because you know
l can google this fool right now.

537
01:36:19,520 --> 01:36:22,353
-Google?
-Yeah, the lnternet.

538
01:36:23,091 --> 01:36:26,356
Don't worry. l'll teach you someday.

539
01:36:29,130 --> 01:36:30,995
When did you get released?

540
01:36:33,734 --> 01:36:35,531
l didn't get released.

541
01:36:37,572 --> 01:36:40,735
l left a few weeks
before the season ended.

542
01:36:41,275 --> 01:36:42,742
You left?

543
01:36:44,145 --> 01:36:45,510
When was that?

544
01:36:45,613 --> 01:36:47,740
About two weeks ago.

545
01:36:52,520 --> 01:36:53,817
Who are you staying with?

546
01:36:53,888 --> 01:36:56,152
Oh, you know, with a friend.

547
01:36:56,958 --> 01:37:01,588
But if you know somebody
who needs a roommate...

548
01:37:09,537 --> 01:37:10,697
Why'd you leave?

549
01:37:21,215 --> 01:37:22,614
Do you have any family here?

550
01:37:27,155 --> 01:37:28,486
But l'm okay.

551
01:37:28,656 --> 01:37:31,591
l have some money saved,
a couple friends.

552
01:37:31,792 --> 01:37:33,692
l'll go home to visit soon.

553
01:38:49,804 --> 01:38:51,203
Frank... it's Miguel.

554
01:38:52,139 --> 01:38:54,937
My God, MigueI.
What the heII happened?

555
01:38:55,643 --> 01:38:57,873
Sorry for calling late.

556
01:38:58,779 --> 01:39:00,041
l'm in New York.

557
01:39:00,214 --> 01:39:03,047
I heard. Youre making me Iook bad.

558
01:39:03,251 --> 01:39:05,048
What the heII are you doing there?

559
01:39:06,754 --> 01:39:11,123
l got a job, but...
l don't know if l'm going to stay.

560
01:39:11,392 --> 01:39:13,053
Where you gonna go?

561
01:39:13,261 --> 01:39:16,196
The seasons o`ver.
Your `visas expired.

562
01:39:16,430 --> 01:39:17,727
l know, but...

563
01:39:18,799 --> 01:39:20,494
l thought maybe l could...

564
01:39:22,136 --> 01:39:24,104
I can taIk to AI`varez.

565
01:39:25,139 --> 01:39:26,936
But I dont know what to teII you.

566
01:39:27,074 --> 01:39:29,702
Theyre not happy about this.

567
01:39:34,448 --> 01:39:35,437
l know.

568
01:39:35,850 --> 01:39:37,511
l'm sorry.

569
01:40:17,792 --> 01:40:19,384
Hey, look who's here.

570
01:40:20,628 --> 01:40:22,596
Well, down to work.

571
01:40:29,804 --> 01:40:31,738
l've got nowhere to go.

572
01:40:49,023 --> 01:40:50,217
So, Miguel...

573
01:40:51,158 --> 01:40:54,821
l did some research,
and now l've got a favorite player.

574
01:40:55,162 --> 01:40:56,459
Who is it, then?

575
01:40:56,630 --> 01:41:00,031
Vic Power. You know him?

576
01:41:01,001 --> 01:41:02,059
You ought to.

577
01:41:02,570 --> 01:41:05,198
One of the best first basemen ever.

578
01:41:05,606 --> 01:41:09,474
He was Puerto Rican.
But that's not why he's my favorite.

579
01:41:10,478 --> 01:41:16,644
When he first arrived in the States,
around '51, '52...

580
01:41:17,551 --> 01:41:21,749
he was playing in the minors.
Little Rock, Arkansas.

581
01:41:22,523 --> 01:41:24,923
And he stopped
into this diner for lunch.

582
01:41:25,292 --> 01:41:28,159
Now, Vic knew very little English.

583
01:41:28,529 --> 01:41:32,260
Didn't even notice the sign
hanging in the window that said...

584
01:41:32,500 --> 01:41:34,195
''Whites only.''

585
01:41:34,301 --> 01:41:37,031
And Vic was black.
l mean black like you.

586
01:41:37,638 --> 01:41:39,128
So what happens?

587
01:41:39,573 --> 01:41:42,371
He comes in
and sits down at the counter.

588
01:41:42,443 --> 01:41:45,310
And this little waitress
comes up to him and says...

589
01:41:50,751 --> 01:41:54,744
So Vic leans close
to the waitress and he says...

590
01:42:01,295 --> 01:42:02,284
Understand?

591
01:42:03,397 --> 01:42:06,389
She says, ''We don't serve blacks.''

592
01:42:06,734 --> 01:42:09,134
And he says, ''That's okay,
l don't eat black people.''

593
01:42:09,937 --> 01:42:11,268
He's my favorite!

594
01:42:25,286 --> 01:42:27,914
l called the Higgins
to give you my new number.

595
01:42:28,122 --> 01:42:29,885
But they said you split.

596
01:42:30,624 --> 01:42:32,956
l couldn't believe it, man.
l had no idea.

597
01:42:33,294 --> 01:42:35,421
Things got ugly after you left.

598
01:42:35,763 --> 01:42:38,960
We all go through slumps.
You know how it is.

599
01:42:39,333 --> 01:42:40,857
Yeah, but it wasn't just a slump.

600
01:42:41,402 --> 01:42:42,699
What was it, then?

601
01:42:45,406 --> 01:42:48,739
l don't know, but l wasn't gonna
wait for them to throw me out.

602
01:42:52,413 --> 01:42:54,540
-l'm just saying...
-Whatever, man

603
01:42:55,616 --> 01:42:59,780
You wouldn't be saying
that stuff if you made it.

604
01:43:01,956 --> 01:43:03,389
Maybe.

605
01:43:05,192 --> 01:43:07,888
Sugar!
Rafi needs you in the kitchen.

606
01:43:08,596 --> 01:43:10,325
They call you Sugar?

607
01:43:10,664 --> 01:43:13,656
What can l say? The name sticks.

608
01:43:15,970 --> 01:43:17,562
They got all kinds in this league...

609
01:43:17,638 --> 01:43:20,266
Fat cats in their 40s,
kids like you and me...

610
01:43:20,474 --> 01:43:23,466
Dominicans, Puerto Ricans,
even some white boys.

611
01:43:24,011 --> 01:43:26,479
l got this 50-year-old catcher
on my team.

612
01:43:26,580 --> 01:43:28,013
Used to play for the Dodgers.

613
01:43:28,349 --> 01:43:31,682
Can't run for shit,
but he's out there every week.

614
01:43:31,819 --> 01:43:33,684
Belly out to here.

615
01:43:34,555 --> 01:43:36,386
But he can still go deep.

616
01:43:36,790 --> 01:43:38,849
You ever hear from that kid Brad?

617
01:45:36,877 --> 01:45:40,335
l got the photo you sent,
but you have to send me more.

618
01:45:40,414 --> 01:45:41,676
Okay, Mom, but...

619
01:45:41,782 --> 01:45:43,977
it would be easier
if you got an e-mail account.

620
01:45:44,151 --> 01:45:47,678
An e-maiI account?
I can bareIy use the TV!

621
01:45:50,557 --> 01:45:52,218
l'm making you a new table.

622
01:45:52,292 --> 01:45:53,589
Its going to be reaI nice.

623
01:45:53,694 --> 01:45:55,787
l'm sure l'll love it. Thank you.

624
01:45:56,063 --> 01:45:57,257
How's Erica?

625
01:45:57,331 --> 01:46:00,357
She's good.
She got a job at the factory.

626
01:46:00,701 --> 01:46:04,831
But just part-time,
so she can keep up with schooI.

627
01:46:06,173 --> 01:46:07,640
And Luis?

628
01:46:08,008 --> 01:46:09,635
He's pitching now.
You should see him.

629
01:46:09,710 --> 01:46:12,338
He's got his brother's arm.

630
01:46:12,546 --> 01:46:15,276
Sure, but can he throw
a knuckle curve?

631
01:46:18,052 --> 01:46:21,215
I miss you, Mom.
Im working hard.

632
01:46:21,722 --> 01:46:23,155
l'll be home soon.

633
01:46:23,957 --> 01:46:25,891
Give everyone a hug for me.

634
01:46:26,694 --> 01:46:28,559
I Io`ve you, Sugar.

635
01:46:29,096 --> 01:46:30,723
l love you, too.

636
01:47:03,230 --> 01:47:04,356
Caballo!

637
01:47:06,433 --> 01:47:07,832
How you doing?

638
01:47:08,068 --> 01:47:09,296
This is Miguel, from San Pedro.

639
01:47:09,403 --> 01:47:11,394
The new guy. You ready to pitch?

640
01:47:11,538 --> 01:47:12,732
l think so.

641
01:47:12,840 --> 01:47:14,068
lt's been a while, no?

642
01:47:14,308 --> 01:47:15,741
Don't worry. He's ready.

643
01:47:15,909 --> 01:47:17,171
That's what l like!

644
01:47:17,411 --> 01:47:20,539
José, meet Miguel.
They call him Sugar.

645
01:47:20,681 --> 01:47:22,239
What's up, Sugar?

646
01:47:22,416 --> 01:47:24,884
José played
for the Padres Triple-A team.

647
01:47:25,085 --> 01:47:26,746
Hit a dinger off Pedro once.

648
01:47:26,954 --> 01:47:29,184
-Twice.
-Twice.

649
01:47:30,090 --> 01:47:31,682
l played for the Yankees.

650
01:47:32,092 --> 01:47:33,081
Milwaukee Brewers.

651
01:47:33,293 --> 01:47:34,351
Kansas City.

652
01:47:34,461 --> 01:47:37,225
Me too. l played in Bridgetown.

653
01:47:37,331 --> 01:47:40,562
Bridgetown. l was there in 2001 .
l lived on a big farm.

654
01:47:40,667 --> 01:47:42,828
-With the Higgins!
-Yeah, with the Higgins!

655
01:48:03,056 --> 01:48:05,251
This isn't soccer,
you can use your hands!

