Subtitles by DramaFever
[Love 'til the End of Summer]
[Episode 8]
Xiao Si.
You don't have to walk us out.
See you again next time.
- No need to see us out.
- Happy New Year.
Xiao Si, there's something wrong
with your parents today.
Be careful. Don't provoke them.
Bye.
Xiao Si, come here.
I have questions for you.
What were you doing yesterday?
Don't tell me you were out sketching.
You didn't even bring your sketch pad.
Tell me.
Why did you lie?
I thought I could come back in time.
You thought you could come back in time?
Whether you could and whether you lied
are two different matters.
Xiao Si.
You've never lied to me before.
Why?
He's already back. Why look into it?
- What should we eat tonight?
- Eat?
Then... if we're not having dinner,
I'll be going to the institute.
All right.
Go to the institute.
We don't have to celebrate the new year!
It's New Year.
Like father, like son.
You two are bent on
vexing me, aren't you?
You two don't have to leave today.
I'll leave, okay?
Xiao Si, you can go
wherever you want from now on.
I won't worry anymore.
I won't care anymore, okay?
And you.
You can have your books and airplanes.
You're all disappointing.
Goodbye!
You are on your own now, okay?
What's wrong? Hungry?
A little.
You eat.
No, I was going to
get it for you. You eat.
Let's each have one.
Dad, why don't we go find Mom?
You know your mom's temper.
If we go now, we'll just be
adding fuel to the fire.
That's true.
Why don't we go to the kitchen
to try our luck?
Let's go.
Dad, it's push.
There are so many things.
Is there anything you know
how to make?
It can't be harder than making a plane.
I can make mapo tofu.
There's no tofu.
We can't eat mapo tofu.
Is there something that is
simple yet filling
and can be an entree on its own?
Think about it.
Egg fried rice.
Good idea.
Eggs.
Rice.
Let's go.
Sorry, Xiao Si. I'm sorry.
Sorry.
Dad, can you really cook?
I eat at the canteen at work.
What were you flipping the pan for?
That's how the chefs do it on television.
Oh no, Dad. It's on fire!
Quick, quick! Xiao Si, hurry!
Don't get water.
Get the fire extinguisher!
Hurry, Xiao Si!
There are many things in life
you don't notice
because you're already used to them.
When life returns to its
original disorderly state
that's when you'll notice them.
It's the first day of the new year.
There probably won't be anything
more unlucky than this happening.
This is bad.
When Mom sees this,
she'll definitely kill us.
That depends on whether
your mom will come back.
Behind those forever fresh
plates of fruit
those spotless floors,
and those warm and dry clothes
are hidden a lot of thought.
You don't want to miss a second of it
because more important than air
are regards from the heart.
Dad, if you had instant noodles,
why didn't you bring them out earlier?
Then we wouldn't have been in such a fix.
I never imagined
it'd be like this either.
It should be bustling with noise
and excitement for the new year.
All right, we're fortunate to have
a bowl of hot noodles.
Xiao Si.
Do you know?
This is good.
Back then, I loved eating
your grandma's noodles with
beef and preserved vegetables.
I still remember that flavor.
Later on, I met your mom
and it turned out she likes
this flavor as well.
Dad, how did you know you liked my mom?
You two are like magnets of
the same pole, repelling each other.
Back then, your mom was
the Athena of our university.
She had a good family background
and was beautiful.
Everyone was beneath her notice.
8 out of 10 boys in
our department liked her.
Back then, I was different.
I was still a powerless young fellow.
Don't come again.
I don't even like the things you give me.
Here.
Take them!
Listen up. It's impossible between us.
You hear me?
Wait.
Please come with me to a place
before you make your decision.
Please come in.
This is amazing.
You're so amazing.
How did you do this?
It's for you.
I...
I'm willing to take the drive I have
for researching airplanes for the country
and invest it into an enthusiastic
pursuit of your affections.
You...
Will you accept me?
Wipe off your sweat first.
You're not very good at
saying endearing words.
You don't get it.
You can't use normal methods to
pursue someone like your mom.
Then how did you know Mom liked you?
I didn't know in the beginning either.
Until one day
I saw your mom talking with
another male classmate.
I realized I minded.
That's how you knew you liked her?
Of course.
Caring is the beginning of liking.
Since my mom liked you,
why would you two be like this now?
Like how?
A total mess.
Xiao Si.
Do you think we're in such a bad state?
You're often busy with work
and don't come home.
When you're back,
you lock yourself in the study.
I get the feeling
you don't really care about Mom.
No, it's because
I care too much about her.
I'm afraid of having a conflict with her
so I'd rather avoid her.
It's like that?
Your mom could never have dreamed
she would be annoyed of my profession
that she once loved.
Life is absurd sometimes.
That afternoon, I watched my father
and it seemed like I was
getting to know him again.
He's not considered old.
He's a successful middle-aged man.
His usually determined face
had a weariness I never noticed
uneasiness, and an expression
that shows experience.
It's work.
Hello?
It's me.
Right now?
No, I won't be coming in today.
I'm going to spend New Year
with my family.
Yes. Okay, bye.
It's all the way in your hair.
That was my first deep talk
with my father.
We were on equal footing.
We weren't father and son,
but more like friends.
That was the first time I realized
there are many things that
aren't as simple as they look.
Every relationship is like
river and silt.
The continuous flow
and battering of the waves
change the shape of each other's heart.
I'd like to ask you to give me an idea.
What do you think I should do now?
I mean about your mother and I.
You're asking me?
You have to win her back.
Good idea.
Thanks, son.
- Let's go.
Change your clothes first, Dad.
This way.
Dad, do you know where Mom is?
Obviously. She's my wife.
Come on.
Don't be mad anymore.
All right.
Don't be mad.
I was wrong. It's all my fault.
It was all my fault.
Our son is here. Look, he's watching you.
Okay, let's go home.
Our son is waiting to eat.
- I'm starving too.
- Then keep starving.
All right, all right.
Come on, let's go home.
Let's go.
Come on, come on.
Your bag.
Dad, you got it.
What miracle drug did you use?
A master can't divulge all his secrets.
I'll teach you when
you'll have a use for it.
What's all this?
I wasn't even gone for half a day.
Xiao Si, look at you.
How could you have forgotten to
turn off the water?
Dad, I said not to flip the pan,
but you just had to.
Honestly, you two.
Next time, you guys will leave.
Hello, Mom? How's Dad's mood?
Good, good.
I'm not bullying Zeus.
I'm treating him well.
All right.
Okay, have fun.
Happy New Year.
Okay, bye.
It's just the two of us.
Cheers.
Dad.
Xiao Si.
Thank you for today.
When we were young, we thought
our parents were invincible.
Only when we stumble upon them
when they feel helpless do we realize
it is because of love that
they were willing to act as heroes.
Every child will experience
such a moment.
They'll suddenly want to grow up faster
and shelter their parents
the way they once sheltered us.
Li Xia!
You're finally here.
Li Xia, did you do
the winter break homework?
I'm not sharing it!
I knew you finished it.
Let me copy it later.
There better not be a next time.
I promise I won't do it again.
Li Xia, you're the best!
Song Ying Ying!
If you keep slacking off,
you'll get even fatter!
Be honest with me.
Did I get fat?
I know.
I can never control myself
during New Years.
I need to diet!
I brought pastries. Do you want them?
I didn't say anything just now.
I take it back.
This is my favorite.
How come Wen Jing isn't here?
Her?
She must have come across
a hot guy on the street.
You know her.
A 10-minute trip
can turn into an hour-long trip
if she sees someone to obsess over.
Maybe she's already here
but she didn't bring her luggage in.
All right, I'll leave some for her.
It's about time. We should go to class.
Ms. Wenren said we have a class meeting.
Let's hurry and get our things.
I had so much fun during winter break.
It was awesome!
Li Xia, Li Xia!
Your Si-Ang idol group is coming!
So handsome.
Good morning.
We won't keep you from your date
with the Si-Ang idol group.
You got this.
You're so gossipy. Leave already.
Long time no see.
Did you miss us?
Sure.
I want you to give me back the photo.
What photo?
Didn't you take the photo
under the tabletop glass?
Give it to the one you were thinking of
and your wish will come true.
Doesn't my hat look nice?
Yes, you look good in anything.
Give me back my photo.
Just give it to me.
Give it back to me!
Lu Zhi Ang!
Xiao Si, save me.
Can you not be so immature?
Xiao Si, did you have
a good winter break?
It was good.
You guys can talk. I'm going inside.
What's the matter with him?
That's just how he is,
moody now and then.
He'll be fine later.
I want my photo!
No, no.
- I don't have it.
- Give it back to me!
Give it back to me! Give it back!
Hello, Miss.
Nippon Paint's face is becoming
more and more white.
Three things.
First, new semester, new start.
Turn your focus back to studying.
Starting tomorrow, everybody is to
wear the school uniform.
Second, the Arts Festival
is coming up soon.
The three contestants,
Fu Xiao Si, Li Xia, and Lu Zhi Ang
must perform well.
Especially Fu Xiao Si.
He has been chosen to be the host of
the Arts Festival evening party.
For the rest of the students
who aren't participating
don't go around making a ruckus.
Focus all your energy on studying.
We must rise above the other classes.
And one last thing.
This semester, Chen Wen Jing has
transferred to another school.
Her seat will remain empty for now.
Miss, do you know where
Chen Wen Jing transferred to?
I know where students transfer from.
I don't know where they go from here.
All right, that's all for
the class meeting. Class dismissed.
I'm really hungry. Can I eat it?
But that is for Wen Jing.
We've left food for her.
Why did she suddenly transfer?
If she were here,
the room wouldn't be so quiet.
If we know her address,
we could send letters to her.
Will we never see her transformation
from Braces Girl?
Do you think she will miss us?
She will write to us.
I hope so.
Are you participating in
the Arts Festival?
Why don't we enter as a duo?
Okay, let's go.
"Youthfulness, radiance,
talent, rise above."
Arts Festival?
"The 16th campus Arts Festival."
These are presents I'm giving you
for the new semester.
- This is for Li Xia.
- Thank you.
- Zhi Ang.
And Xiao Si.
Thank you.
Thank you for preparing gifts for us.
Were you okay that day?
Yes. I have to thank you.
What's this between you two?
It’s nothing. It's in the past.
How come yours is so big? Let's swap.
No!
I carefully selected each of your gifts.
Every person's is different.
It's okay. The ugly one fits him.
I'll switch with you.
Immature.
You can swap if you want.
- But don't--
- Wait!
These are gifts
I carefully selected for you.
You're treating it so carelessly.
Not at all. We're happy
we got gifts from you.
Why would we swap them?
All right. Maybe his is empty.
Thank you.
I'll buy something special for you.
- Let's go practice our songs.
- Let's go.
Bye.
By the way, did you guys
get home on time?
You weren't scolded, right?
We didn't catch the bus.
We stayed at Li Xia's house.
How come I didn't know?
They just stayed the night.
They left the following morning.
You guys could have called me.
You have so many questions.
Let's go practice our songs.
Next time. We'll call you next time.
Let's go.
The art studio is this way.
Where are you going?
I'm meeting someone today
so I won't be going to draw.
Xiao Si!
I'm meeting up with Yan Ran.
Li Xia is here too?
Xiao Si and I have been chosen
as hosts for the Arts Festival.
We'll be rehearsing our speeches.
Xiao Si, let's go to the auditorium.
All right.
If you don't need anything,
we'll be leaving now.
Bye.
On the banyan tree by the pond
the cicadas chirp into the summer.
So you guys really stayed overnight
at Li Xia's house?
Yes. You've asked several times already.
You're basically asking
every five minutes.
Why don't I set a timer
and remind you in five minutes?
Why didn't you guys call me?
You could have come to play at my house.
You don't even know
how boring it was for me.
Okay, we'll be sure to
tell you next time. All right?
So...
You and Fu Xiao Si slept together
in Li Xia's room?
The two of us have slept together
since we were kids. What about it?
Lu Zhi Ang, have I angered you?
Why are you so impatient
when answering my questions?
I... I'm impatient?
You're the impatient one.
Can you focus on practicing?
No! I'm not practicing anymore!
What's going on with her?
Her mood changes at the drop of a hat.
Nobody needs me.
Nobody thinks I'm important.
Nobody told me!
Why is the whole world against me?
March is the season when
sunshine reawakens.
March is the season when flowers bloom.
We'll use wisdom and passion
to sow the seeds of hope
so art can dwell in our hearts.
Xiao Si.
Do you feel unwell?
No.
It's your turn.
Where were we?
We'll use illusions and rainbows.
We'll use illusions and rainbows
to weave our youthful dreams
with no regrets
and let love flow through all corners.
Who wrote this speech? It's so gaudy.
I wrote it.
Xiao Si.
I feel our relationship isn't
the same as it was before.
I wanted you to edit my speech
but I couldn't find you.
Even if I found you, you'd be busy.
You don't have time for me anymore.
I get the feeling my best friend since
childhood is distancing himself from me.
Xiao Si, can you be nicer to me?
I consider your needs
with everything I do.
You... Can you...
Can you not treat me so indifferently?
Okay, okay.
Don't be sad. I'll edit this for you.
I'll edit your speech.
What's wrong? Are you cold?
Yes, the wind is... a bit cold.
I have an idea. Wait for me.
Li Xia, Li Xia, Li Xia!
Guess who I saw.
Who?
Fu Xiao Si and Li Yan Ran
leaving together.
That's normal. They're classmates.
Li Yan Ran was sitting on his bike seat.
A bike only has one back seat.
Otherwise, she'd be on the handlebars.
They were hugging!
It has nothing to do with me.
Nothing to do with you?
The enemy has breached
far past the front line.
Li Xia, you can't
resign yourself to fate.
Fu Xiao Si and Li Yan Ran
isn't my business
and I can't interfere.
All right.
You won't be cold this way.
The car is nice and warm
and there's a heater.
You won't have to endure the wind.
I won't have to worry now.
Thanks, Xiao Si. You're so thoughtful.
Be careful on the road.
Call me when you get home.
Where would you like to go, Miss?
Just go straight.
He's such an unromantic blockhead.
Subtitles by DramaFever