[ Siren Wailing ]
Hello, ladies and gentlemen,
boys and girls.
My name is Jimmy Breslin.
I'm a writer.
I write about New York,
the city of my birth,
where I've lived
and worked all my life--
the city that I love
and hate both equally.
Today things
are much different.
Business is booming
up, up and up.
Crime is down, down, down.
Homicides are the lowest
it's been since 1 961 .
Well, it wasn't
always like this.
This film is about a different time,
a different place--
the good old days, the hot,
blistering summer of 1 97 7.
There are 8,000,000 stories
in the naked city,
and this was one of them.
[ Dog Barking, Flies Buzzing ]
[ Man Panting ]
[ Man Shouting ]
Shut that dog up!
Shut that dog!
[ Barking Continues ]
[ Man Yelling, Panting ]
Shut that dog up!
[ Yelling ]
* There was something
in the air that night *
* The stars were bright *
*Fernando *
* They were shining there
for you and me *
- **[ Continues ]
- Wanna go to the beach tomorrow?
- Yeah, let's go toJones.
- Yeah.
-[ Dog Barking ]
-Oh, I have a hair appointment tomorrow.
- Tsk. Ah, I'll just cancel it.
- Yeah.
-*If I had to do the same again *
- Who's this?
- *I would, my friend *
- Can we help you with something?
- [ Gunshot ]
- [ Both Screaming ]
- [ Horn Honking ]
- *If I had to do the same again *
*I would, my friend--*
*Boogie nights *
- *Boogie nights *
- *Ain't no doubt *
* We are here to party *
- *Boogie nights *
- * Come on out *
* Got to get it started *
*Dance with the boogie
Get down *
* 'Cause boogie nights
are always the best in town *
* Got to keep on dancin'
Keep on dancin'*
- *Boogie nights *
- * Get that groove *
*Let it take you higher *
- *Boogie nights *
- *Make it move *
*Set this place on fire *
-*Dance with the boogie Get down *
- Hey, Vinny, how ya doin'?
- **[ Continues ]
- Hey, how ya doin'? Good to see you.
All right.
Come right in, right in.
-[ Man ] Hey, good to see you.
- Here you go.
- Dionna.
- Don't spend it all in one place.
- Thank you.
*Boogie nights--*
*...to grow up in, let's find
a place that's safe *
- *Somewhere far away *
- You look stunning.
* With no blacks
noJews and no gays *
* There but for
the Grace of God *
* There go I
Oh, I *
-* There but for the grace of God *
- * Oh, God *
- * There go I, I, I, I, I *
- Hey!
-*No blacks noJews and no gays *
-* There but for the grace of God *
- * Oh, God *
* There go I *
* Oh, I *
-* There but for the grace of God *
- * Oh, God *
* There go I, I, I, I
I, I, I, I, I *
* Carmen and the family *
*Left the dirty streets *
* To find a quiet place
overseas *
*And year after year
the kid has to hear *
* The do's and don'ts
and the dids *
*And when she's ten years old
she digs that rock 'n roll *
*But they banned
it from the home *
-* There but for the grace of God *
- *But for the grace of God *
* There go I *
* Oh, I *
- * There *
- * There but for the grace of God *
- * God *
- * There go I *
- * Oh, I *
- *It could be me It could be you *
-* There but for the grace of God *
- * Who could it be *
* There go I, I, I, I
I, I, I, I, I *
**[ Song Changes ]
[ Crowd Cheering ]
Ah, you killed me out there.
- You looked good tonight.
- You know that? You do.
- Oh, I do, do I?
- You kill me.
- [ Chattering ]
- You get me going.
Billy Martin?
Everybody wants to talk to him.
- Hey, Dionna. How've you been?
- Not too bad.
- Hey, what's up?
- [ Dionna ] Hey,Joey T.
- Hey, sweetheart.
- Hey, what's the score,Joey?
- Yankees three, A's two.
Top of the ninth.
- Nice!
- Aw, good, good.
- Come on. Let me get you a drink.
Hey, Dionna, what's with your cousin?
She's stuck up.
- Yeah, really.
- Well, what do you want?
She doesn't speak English.
Thank God. I thought I was losing
my touch for a second.
- Well, you are, you know.
- Hey, take it easy.
Mi chiamo Brian.
[ Speaking Italian ]
[ Laughing, Speaking Italian ]
- Shut up.
- Oh, si, si, si.
Vinny, it's midnight.
We got to take Chiara home.
- Hey, Dionna, I could take her home.
- Let her speak Italian.
Oh, come on.
That's all my father needs to see.
-We'll take you home.
-No, baby. You stay here. I'll take her.
- Okay? You're having a good time.
- Yeah?
- Yeah. I don't feel well.
- You wanna go back?
- I'll go get some air.
- You all right?
- Yeah. No, I just don't feel well.
- Okay, sweetheart.
- I don't mind. I don't care.
- All right.
- All right?
- [Joey ] Hey, come on, have a shot.
- No, I gotta go.
- Come on. What are you talking about?
- Come on!
- Oh, have a shot. Come on, baby.
- Peer pressure.
- To the Yankees!
[ Together]
Yankees!
- That's horrible.
- Ah, salut'.
Hey, Vinny! Vinny, pick me up
a sandwich. B.L.T. Mustard, not mayo.
- All right, baby.
- Okay. I love you.
[ Grunting, Panting ]
[ Speaking Italian ]
- Oh, Vincenzo.
- Shit.
[ Horn Honking ]
I'm fuckin' coming!
Oh, God!
Fuckin' son of a bitch.
[ Speaking Italian ]
Goddamn. Pull-Pull your panties
back up. Come on.
- [ Grumbling In Italian ]
- Goddamn it.
Shit. Fuckin' coming.
[ Continues Muttering ]
- I don't deserve this shit.
- [ Engine Starts ]
*I must have been through *
- Why do they have to come
here and do that?
- *About a million girls *
- Right in front of your house.
- *I love 'em *
- Like dogs in heat.
- *And I leave 'em alone *
- No class. No couth.
- *I didn't care *
- Hey, I had a real good time tonight.
- *How much they cried, no, sir *
- Are you busy tomorrow night?
- * The tears left me *
- I'd really like to see you again.
- * Cold as a stone *
- [ Dog Barking ]
- *But then I fooled around *
*And fell in love *
*I fooled around
and fell in love *
*Since I met you, baby *
*I fooled around and fell *
*In love *
-*I fooled around and fell in love *
- [ Gunshots, Screaming ]
*Free, on my own *
* That's the way
I used to be *
*But since I met you, baby *
*Love's got a hold on me *
-*I fooled around and fell in love *
- *It's got a hold on me now *
*I fooled around and fell--*
**[ Disco ]
*Doobie-doo
Run, run, run *
*Doobie-doo *
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
Dionna!
-* 'Cuz you been mean to me *
- *Fun, fun, fun *
-*And I've been good to you *
- *Run, run, run *
- Hey, where's my sandwich?
- Oh, shit.
- Ohhh.
- Shit. I forgot, baby.
I forgot. I'm sorry.
- Oh, baby, I got the munchies.
I'm hungry.
- Come on, let's dance.
- Forget the munchies.
- I don't want to dance.
Let's just go. Let's go.
- You wanna go?
- Let's go to the diner
and have some breakfast.
- Some eggs or something, you know?
And then we go home.
- All right.
- You don't wanna dance some more?
- I'll dance on the way out.
You follow me.
I want my breakfast.
- You look beautiful.
- Thank you, but I want my breakfast.
You danced so great
tonight, baby.
Ah, 'cause you're beautiful.
That's why.
[ Moans, Chuckles ]
Ah, don't stop.
It feels so good.
What--
What took you so long?
- I just stopped to take a leak.
- [ Sniffing ]
I drank too much tonight,
you know?
Where?
At the house?
Come on! What, are you writin'
a book or somethin'?
No, I'm just asking.
Yeah. Yeah,
you're asking. Sure.
I just asked you
what took you so long.
- I didn't accuse you of anything.
- I know, sweetie pie.
You danced beautifully
tonight too, you know?
- It was a lot of fun.
- [ Siren Wailing ]
Hey, officer, what the hell
happened over here? What's going on?
Come on.
To your right, now.
[ Police Radio, Indistinct ]
- Cruz, baby, que pasa?
- Double homicide.
- Yeah? .44-Caliber Killer?
- Looks like that.
I'm gonna see what's going on, okay?
You stay right here.
- Aw, geez, what a mess.
- Looks like somebody died
out here tonight.
- Hey, guy, what's up?
- I live over here, okay?
Oh.
These are victims six and seven.
The shit's gonna hit the fan.
[ Chattering Continues ]
Petrocelli, you're gonna like
this part. He left a note.
No shit?
He left a note?
Who is this guy?
Fuckin' William Shakespeare?
Yes, Lou,
this could be the break.
[ Petrocelli ]
Somebody bag this.
Get one of our boys
to take it down to forensics.
[ Officer ]
Eddie, let's get a shot.
[ Camera Shutter Clicking ]
[ Petrocelli ]
Hey! Hey, Vinny! You can't be there!
Come on, get outta there!
Get away from there!
Come on, get behind the line!
Come on!
- Come on, let's go.
- Get behind the yellow tape.
Come on, come on, come on.
-Let's go.
-Get him outta here. Get him outta here.
Come on.
Six and seven, Lou,
like you said.
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ Officer ]
There's nothing more to see here, folks.
- What time they find 'em?
- 1 0:20.
Who found 'em?
[ Chattering Continues ]
- [ Gagging ]
- Oh, my God!
Vincent, what's--
[ Coughing ]
Oh, my God.
Are you all right?
Baby, move over.
Move over.
I'm sorry.
You're gonna have to drive, okay?
All right. Wh-What happened?
What's wrong?
I just saw the bodies.
- The bodies?
- [ Panting ] He's back.
- Somebody got killed?
- The .44-Caliber Killer is back.
- Baby, please take me home.
Come on, I gotta get outta here.
- [ Engine Starts ]
Victims six...
[ Flies Buzzing ]
seven.
[ Man On Radio ]
All news, all the time.
This is WINS.
**[ StationJingle ]
You give us 22 minutes,:
we'll give you the world.
- WINS news time at the tone, 3:00.
- [ Time Tone ]
It happened again last night.
More terror, more bloodshed.
The.44-Caliber Killer striking
again, leaving two more dead.
The police have recovered a note left
by the killer at the murder scene,
but have not released
its contents to the press.
And so parents continue their vigil,
warning their children not to go out,:
keeping their daughters home, afraid
to have them park in Lover's Lane...
- [ Sighs ]
- for fear they'll be another
victim of the mad killer.
It's hot and hazy and humid.
People trying to out at night,
but they're afraid to.
They're afraid
to walk the streets, afraid this
mad killer will strike again,
shooting them down
in cold blood.
- [ People Chattering ]
- Good morning, Ma.
- Ritchie!
- Not a good morning for me. I'm losing.
Couldn't you put
some clothes on?
- Morning? It's 3:30 in the afternoon.
- Nice. Nice tux, Ed.
It's your mother's idea.
She got me a gig with a wedding band.
-That's what my career's boiled down to.
-Can I borrow 50 bucks, Ma?
- Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- I gotta get my car fixed.
- Sure. Take it from the kitty.
- That kitty's for our food!
This is what I'm talking
about with this kid.
Hey, Ritchie, how about
working for a living?
- Only the colored and Spanish
live off of welfare.
- Mind your own business.
What, I gotta sing for $7 5 tonight, and
he get's 50? No, no, no, no, no, no.
Twenty dollars, and you should make him
work the game.
All right, but he's not gonna
work the game. Ritchie, take $20.
- I'm out.
-[ Man ]
Do you have anything cold to drink?
[ Chattering ]
- Thanks, Ma.
- Shitty hand, as usual.
- Hey, Ritchie.
- What?
You hear about them kids
that got shot last night?
- What kids?
- Bad thing. Real bad thing.
[ Chattering In Italian ]
[ Children Squealing ]
[ Girl ]
Barracuda!
Get out of the water.
-Just a minute, Mommy.
- You've had enough.
[ Man ]
Come on, come on!
[ Men Speaking Italian ]
What the hell?
[ Continues, Indistinct ]
Hey, guys, I've been buying
the Post and the Daily News all week.
It would be nice
to get some money back.
Boy, you got some set of balls.
You should be payin' us money
just to be standin' here.
- I been spendin'a lot of money.
- Oh, come on, will ya?
[Joey ] Shut the fuck up, all right?
Just listen to this.
''Although police officials declined
to discuss the contents of the note,
our unofficial source said
it was written by a homicidal maniac,
a real sicko who lives
in a nightmare world.''
-Joey, do I look pale to you?
- You look all right, Vin.
Hey, Anthony,
do I look pale to you?
Yeah, you look like
a piece of mozzarella.
- You guys are fuckin' funny.
- Holy shit! Look at this.
They got a map of all the killings.
This is our neighborhood.
- There's Layton Avenue.
-Joe, look. We're famous.
Let me see that.
You know, I'd lay five-to-one
the killer's from right here.
You think the killer's
from around here?
Don't you think we'd notice
a sicko like that? Come on,Joey.
What do you think makes them sickos,
you idiot? You don't notice 'em.
You think this was
some random killing?
You think he just
pulled off the highway?
You don't think he knew
where he was going?
-Joey, I need another 'lude.
- You just popped it.
- Give it a couple minutes.
- It's not working for me.
Give me another one. Come on.
- Don't be fuckin' cheap.
- Hey, Vinny, man, that was
some heavy shit you saw.
- I'd be freaking out if I was you.
- Yeah, I am.
Yo, Vinny, man, I'd be freaked out too,
since the killer knows you saw him.
- What do you mean the killer saw me?
- He might think you're a witness.
- You could be number eight.
- I'm serious, man.
I saw this on a news show.
- If he caught your license plate,
he knows where you live.
- They hang around.
- You think I'm number eight?
- I'm serious.
- Yeah, 'cause the guy--
they hang around.
- They stick around.
Oh, shut the fuck up!
I only saw victims.
- They look--
- Fuck you. I didn't see nobody.
Don't start spreadin'
that shit, fuckin' asshole!
Hey, what's the matter?
Will you leave him alone?
Oh, that's real funny,
right? Ha-ha!
- What's the matter?
You can't take a joke?
- No, I can't!
- Vinny, Vinny, relax.
- Come on. We're playin' with you.
Here, here, come on.
Take a half a 'lude.
- You fuckin'asshole.
- Go home and get some sleep, all right?
- Fuckin'guy can't take a joke.
- Leave him alone.
One fuckin' 'lude ain't gonna work
on this guy. Look at his face.
Why don't you guys go
fuckin'take a walk?
We were just jokin'. Holy shit!
Look at this fuckin'creature!
Hey, guys, I got lobsters.
Live lobsters.
- What do you got there,
Woodstock? Lobsters?
- Live lobsters, two dollars each.
What, are you stealing lobster traps
now? Those guys are gonna shoot you.
- If they catch me.
- Where were you last night?
You shoot two people?
- I only shoot heroin.
- These lobsters are broke.
- And they're half dead.
What is this shit?
- They're two dollars each.
Get the fuck outta here
with your broke, half-dead lobsters!
Joey, these are good.
You can make a brisque.
- Brisque this, you junkie!
-Joey, I'm gonna go cold turkey.
- Yeah, cold turkey that!
- Aw, come on!
What do you gotta do that for?
[ Cockney Accent ] You ain't Bruce Lee.
Stop kicking Woodstock.
- Is that Ritchie?
- Yeah.
What the hell happened to you?
Look at this freak.
Nice outfit.
You get it off the dead?
[ Brian ] I thought vampires
only came out at night.
Yeah, 'cept on leap year.
What's happening, guys?
Don't give us that
''What's happening'' bullshit.
You come back to the neighborhood
lookin' like a fuckin' freak,
soundin'like a British fag,
we're supposed to be okay with that?
You're fuckin' right.
How's your wife and kid,J.T.?
I got divorced.
Moved back in with my mother.
Look,Joey.
A dollar each.
- Go home and O.D. Go fuck yourself!.
- Shut up!
I'll take five dollars
for the whole fuckin' bag.
All right, all right,
all right. Here, here.
- Here's your five dollars.
Now get the fuck outta here.
- Get outta here.
- Woodstock, I need some smoke.
- [Joey ] No, I'm handling that now.
What do you want?
I got nickels.
Yeah? All right.
I'll take two then.
[ Anthony ] Hey, Ritchie,
you heard about the killer?
Yeah, yeah, I heard. What's the matter,
Vin? Not gonna say hello?
Hello. And where the fuck
were you last night, huh?
You drove right past me
outside the club.
Will you do me a favor
and just drop this stupid accent
and talk to me for real, huh?
- Huh?
- All right.
So why didn't you come in?
We could've talked or something.
I wasn't really dressed
for disco dancing.
- [ Mocking ] Look at this jerk-off.
- Come on!
- He was dressed for Halloween,
this fuckin'goblin.
- Leave him alone.
Hey, porcupine, Vinny saw
the dead bodies last night.
- You saw the bodies?
- [ Vinny ] Yeah, I saw the bodies.
I was on my way home.
But I didn't see him, all right?
I didn't see no fuckin' killer,
you numbnuts, so don't fuckin'
spread that word around.
[ Car Approaching ]
[ Anthony ]
Hey, here comes Ruby the skank. Ruby!
Yeah, but I thought you said
your parents were in Hawaii.
First Europe,
then Hawaii.
You know, Ron, we've been dating
for three weeks now,
and all you ever do
is take me to motels.
'Kay? You wanna
see me again?
You introduce me
to your parents.
Must you continually
bring up my parents?
- What? Are you getting out of the car?
- Yeah, I gotta go.
What about our weekend
in the Catskills?
I've already
paid for the room.
Yeah? Well, then you can go there
and you can jerk off.
- 'Cause that's what you are,
a real fuckin'jerk-off.
- Fuck you, you dago wop skank!
- Whoa!
- Hey, what did you say?
- ''Dago wop skank''?
What are you? Fuckin'nuts?
- This doesn't concern you.
- Shut your fuckin' mouth!
That's my fuckin' sister!
- Stay away from the car.
- Get the fuck out of the car!
Get out of the car!
- [ Anthony Shouting ]
- [ Tires Screeching ]
- [ Indistinct Shouting ]
You fucker!
[ Continues Shouting ]
- Move your ass!
- Come on!
- [ Laughing ]
- Go back home, pretty boy!
[ All Laughing ]
He ain't showin' his face
around here again, baby.
Hey, Ruby, come over here.
I'm horny. I mean lonely.
- I need a hug.
- Then go home to your mother.
Twat you say?
I cunt hear.
I have an in-fuck-tion
in my ear.
Don't you assholes
ever grow up?
What the fuck
is your problem? I mean--
- Ruby!
- Hey, is that Ritchie?
- That freak don't want you.
- Get the fuck out of here. Ugh!
Ritchie, hey!
How are you?
- Hey, Ruby.
- How ya doin'? You look good.
- Aw, you look great.
- Good enough to eat?
Hey, I like the new look.
What, it's punk?
Yeah. You should come
to the city sometime.
- Maybe check out my band.
- [ Brian ] Yeah, they really suck.
- Yeah, they suck really good.
Just like you, Ruby.
- Come on. Relax.
Yeah, I learned
from your mother, dick.
- You gonna let your sister
talk that way to me?
- [ Brian ] She's my half-sister.
- Come on, get lost.
- [ Ruby ] Leave me the fuck alone.
- You live in Manhattan now?
- I did as of last night. I got evicted.
- Oh.
- Will you stop talking like that?
Hey, you've been
in London too?
No, but it's-- it's all in the attitude.
It's all in the attitude.
[ Cockney Accent ]
''In the attitude.''
Well, I-I gotta go. My father's
gonna kill me. I'll see you.
- It was great seeing you.
- Yeah, you too. You look good.
- [ Chattering ]
- You take care of yourself, Ruby.
- Yeah.
- Be careful. Ritchie, come here.
I wanna talk to you.
- Yo, see you later.
- Take it easy on the rebound.
[ Man Shouting, Indistinct ]
- Whoa, whoa.
- Oh. You tryin' to knock me down?
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Slow down.
Relax. It's okay.
[ Vinny ] Don't tell nobody.
It's between you and me.
Now, it's bad enough
that I balled her, right?
But then some sick side of me had
to drive Dionna right past the spot...
where I was just sticking it
up her cousin's ass, you know?
Shit. And that's where I saw
the dead bodies, right there.
You know what? God spared me.
He spared me, man.
- [ Chuckles ]
- 'Cause it's a fuckin' omen.
No, I'm serious.
He fuckin'-- He let me go.
What the fuck could this mean?
It means something.
What do you think it means?
I don't know.
I think God's tellin' me that I'm gonna
burn in hell if I don't stop cheatin'.
[ Footsteps ]
- Didn't I tell you
you weren't ready to get married?
- Yeah.
Didn't I?
You don't fuckin' listen.
'Cause I fuckin' thought
I was gonna stop cheatin'
when I got married, you know?
I thought so. And now I'm just fuckin'
cheatin' a lot more than I ever did.
But I thought--you know, I thought
the man up there understood.
I thought He under--
would fuckin'understand.
- God has got nothing
to do with this, Vin.
- Oh, come on, Ritchie.
Yes, He does.
God is tellin' me, ''You shouldn't
be doing these things with your wife.''
- That's what He's tellin' me.
- What things?
- Don't be stupid. You know.
- What?
You know, butt-fucking,
69, doggie style.
And that's the message. God is saying,
''You gotta cut that shit out.
- Aw, come on!
- Otherwise, I'm not gonna
spare you the next time.''
That's what God's
telling me.
Now, Ritchie, I'm telling you, I swear,
I think the guy saw my license plate.
I think he's after me.
I'm telling you, I'm gonna be
number eight. My life is over.
- I'm gonna die.
- You don't gotta worry...
about anybody comin' after you
or any omen.
What the fuck
am I gonna do?
What am I gonna do?
What if I can't stop?
- What if I got some sort
of hang-up, you know?
- You don't got any hang-ups.
You know, once you're deviated,
you can't go back. You know that.
Why don't you just tell Dionna
you like these things, and,
you know, maybe she'll do it.
- Come on. You don't do
that shit with your wife.
- Why not?
- Nah, it's a fuckin' sin.
- Oh, please.
''Please, can I put it up your ass,
please? Just one time. ''
- Don't fuckin' make fun of me, man.
- Ow! Stop.
- '' Let me put it up your ass.''
- Shut up.
''Oh, Dionna--''
All right. What do you want me to
tell you? Get a fuckin' divorce then.
Divorce is fuckin' evil, Ritchie.
You got some fuckin' really bad advice.
'' Evil'' spelled backwards
is ''live.''
You're a corny fuck,
you know that?
Dionna? Dionna,
I gotta talk to you.
What are you doing here?
Vinny, what are you doing here?
- I just gotta talk to you
for a minute, okay?
- Now?
Honey, we're in trouble.
We're in the weeds. We got
Luigi here, and we're not ready.
-Just sit down here by me. Shhh.
- Vinny.
- What's wrong with you?
- I just need to talk to you
for a minute, please.
And listen to me
for once, okay?
Could you?
Could you do that for me?
- All right.
- All right?
Now, what I saw last night made me
think about a lot of things, okay?
It opened up my eyes
really wide to everything.
And those murders
made me realize...
how much I love you.
I love you, Dionna.
And I swear to God--
I swear, I promise--
I promise you and I promise God
that I'm gonna be the best husband...
that you ever had
in your entire life.
If I had eight tongues, it wouldn't be
enough to tell you how much I love you.
- Okay. You swear to God?
- I swear to God, I love you.
Okay.
[ Both Chuckling ]
I'm so sorry about everything.
I love you so dearly.
Baby, um, I'm
in the middle of work.
I got-- Dad's in trouble,
and I gotta get stuff out.
Oh, make up some excuse, and then
come with me. Let's go somewhere.
- Oh, baby, I can't.
- I'll take you out to dinner.
I'll take you anywhere.
Why don't you stay here?
I'll make you something really nice.
I'll be done here in 20 minutes.
Sit down. I'll get you a glass of wine.
- I don't want to wait 20 minutes.
- A glass of wine.
Daddy, Luigi's veal.
He's waiting.
He'll wait.
How's that husband Vinny of yours?
He's all right?
Well, he was all shook up, but
he's-- he's a lot better now.
- Thank God.
- How about you, Daddy?
You don't seem so good today?
How am I doing?
I'm concerned, okay?
I'm very worried
about your safety.
Did you see those parents
on television crying for their kids?
I don't want to be on the news talking
about the daughter I used to have.
[ Man ]
When's the food coming? Tomorrow?
[ Man #2 ] Get rid
of this thing too. It's disgusting.
- Hi. Here's your order.
- Ahh, nice. Thank you, honey.
- Beautiful, beautiful.
- Thank you for waiting.
- Tell your father he's a great man.
- That looks great. Thank you.
- Thank you, honeybunch.
- So long, sweetie.
- Give me a little pasta.
- You want some over here, Luigi?
- Yeah.
- [ Man #2 ] Okay, enough.
Luigi, look who's here.
Starsky and Hutch.
What, are we double-parked
outside or somethin'? [ Chuckles ]
You gonna invite us
to sit or what?
You both got asses.
Feel free to use 'em.
Mario? Mario!
Si, Signor Luigi?
Two setups
for New York's finest.
Ah, sure, paisan.
You're gonna invite us to a meal?
You know that's against regulations.
You sit at my table,
you eat.
Nobody's counting, huh?
Sit down.
Detective, you ever have
veal Sorrentino?
- Uh, no, I haven't.
- Well, you're gonna have it now.
- Sounds delicious.
- That's Italian for veal delight.
- Yeah? What is it?
- It's Italian food.
- Veal what?
- Italian food. Veal Sorrentino.
- Grazie.
- You need your energy to catch
the criminals of the world.
Really?
I like that.
That's good.
Sorrentino, here you go.
- Try and catch this one.
- [ Chuckles ]
Mm-hmm. Compliments
to the chef. Yeah.
Your partner ever tell you he ran
errands for me when he was a kid?
- No.
- Yeah.
When he was a pipsqueak,
too small even to piss straight.
- No, he never told me that.
- [ Luigi Chuckles ]
Never told you other things.
Luigi, my partner knows
I'm from the neighborhood.
Can we get down to business?
What business?
We need your help.
What do you want me to do?
Arrest myself?
[ All Laughing ]
You know, I wish this was a joking
matter, but it's not. It's very serious.
I want to talk to you about this
crazy son of a bitch killer.
We need your help.
You got a hundred cops
on the task force.
You need my help?
I'm only a plumber.
Luigi,you know I wouldn't be here
if I didn't have to be.
I'm asking you: This guy, how many
people did he kill?
Three, four, five?
And with no disrespect,
Detective, in Harlem last night,
your people, the coloreds,
how many of each other did they kill?
- Seven, eight?
- Eight, nine, at least.
And on Saturday,
20, if we're lucky.
- [ Laughing ]
- Okay, I'm out. I'm out.
- Take it easy. Sit, sit, sit.
- So... so!
So... why didn't you
ask me who killed them ?
Huh? Not enough, uh,
press in it for ya?
Not enough Post
or Daily News headlines?
Look, there's a homicidal maniac
runnin' around the neighborhood.
- You don't wanna do anything about it?
- Hmm.
You have been busting my balls
ever since you got promoted.
Now, why is that? Wasn't I good to you
when you were a kid?
Didn't I take you
to Yankee Stadium?
Didn't you meet
Mickey Mantle?
He signed a baseball,
''To Louie, from Mickey Mantle. ''
Motherfuck the Mick.
Willie Mays was the man.
- Get outta here. Mick was the guy.
- Oh, fuck you.
- He was the guy. Come on.
- [ Luigi ] All right, enough, enough.
And then the family--your family--
Didn't I take care of them?
I treated you like a son.
And now you have the balls to come
here and ask me to do you a favor?
Never!
When you wanted to become a cop,
did you come and ask me?
Did you ask
for my blessing? No.
And you could've been
a great plumber, as good as me.
[ Sighs ]
I'm gonna read you something,
but it can't leave this table.
Not even the newspapers
know about this.
Read it.
'' Dear sir, I am deeply hurt by the
newspaper calling me a woman hater.
I'm not. But I am a monster.
I'm a little brat.
-[ Son Of Sam ] I am the Son of Sam.
- I am the Son of Sam.
- Sam loves to drink blood.
-Sam loves to drink blood.
''Go out and kill,''
commands Father Sam.
[ Son Of Sam ]
Behind our house some rest.
Mostly young, raped and slaughtered,
their blood drained.
Just bones now.
- [ Yelling ]
- Papa Sam keeps me locked
in the attic too.
- Shut that dog up!
- I can't get out.
[ Barking ]
Shut up!
Shut up! Shut up!
When I look out the attic window
and watch the world go by,
- [ Yelling Continues ]
- I feel like an outsider.
I am on a different wavelength
than everybody else.
Programmed to kill.
Do you know where--
- No!
- [ Screams ]
However, to stop me
you must kill me.
I am the monster.
- Beelzebub. Beelzebub.
- Beelzebub. The chubby behemoth.
I love to hunt.
[ Flies Buzzing ]
Prowling the streets,
looking for fair game.
It must be the water
they drink.
[ Woman ]
Help me.
[ Son Of Sam ]
I live for the hunt. My life.
Blood for Papa.
Sir, I don't want
to kill anymore.
No, sir, no more.
But I most honor thy father.
[ Screaming ]
No!
- [ Flashbulbs Popping ]
- I want to make love to the world.
I love people.
I don't belong on Earth.
Return me to yahoos.
I want to wish you all
a happy Easter.
May God bless you
in this life and the next.
And for now,
I say good-bye and good night.
[ Women Chattering
In Italian ]
- Somebody help me!
- Police, let me haunt you
with these words.
I'll be back.
- I'll be back.
To be interpreted as
bang-bang-bang, bang-bang-bang.
Yours in murder,
Mr. Monster.''
- HolyJesus Christ.
- Holy shit.
Will you excuse me
for a minute, Atwater?
[ Whispering ]
Luigi...
sugno oggi ca perche
ho tanto respetto para Sia.
Chiesto, chiesto madman
es uno nostro.
Come on. Aiutome.
Non te preoccupare.
Ci penso io per iddu.
Grazie. Grazie.
Basket catch.
Hey, pally, that catch
in the '54 series--
[ Announcer ] There's a long drive
way back to center field.
- [ Crowd Cheering ]
- Way back! And it is caught!
- Oh, my God!
- He got lucky.
[ Man Singing With Stereo ]
*I'm gonna love you *
*Like nobody's ever loved you *
- When you sang that song,
I fell in love with you.
- Oh,yeah.
* Come rain or come shine *
- Eddie Sabatini.
- That's me, baby.
Eddie Sabatini!
- *High as a mountain *
- Come here.
* Deep as a river *
- [ Laughing ]
- * Come rain or come shine *
- Oh, baby, come here.
* Da-da-da, yeah *
- *Just when you met me *
- [ Keys Rattling ]
- * It was just one of those things *
- Oh, baby!
*But don't, don't
you ever bet me *
- Oh, my God, Ma!
- Oh, my God! Ritchie!
- I'm sorry!
- Get outta here, Ritchie!
- Oh,Jesus!
- Ritchie!
[ Eddie ] Now go inside, Helen!
Jesus! Bad timing, kid. No, no, no!
- I'm sorry.
- Get in here now!
Get in here. Get in here.
Come on, kid.
We're still newlyweds here.
Goddamn it, Ritchie!
We don't see you for a month!
- [ Quiet Chattering ]
- You come back. You're gone for a week.
- You come back again! You come, you go!
- I'm sorry.
Look, look, look. Thing is, your mother
and I have been talking.
She packed your shit up.
We want you to stay in the garage now.
I'm not stayin'
in the fuckin' garage.
- This is not the fuckin'
Sherry-Netherland.
- Use the fuckin' bedroom!
- What are you doing here?
- It's your mother and I's house.
We can do whatever the fuck
we want! You're too old
to be staying here anyway.
You should be happy that we're
lettin' you stay in a fuckin' garage.
- Ma, this guy's kickin' me out!
- Helen!
- He's makin' me live in the garage!
- Talk to this fuckin' kid.
- Ma, I can't believe this.
- Helen, talk to him!
- He's kicking me
out of my own house, Ma!
- It won't be bad in the garage.
I'll give you money
to fix it up.
You can play your guitar
loud, whatever you want!
- I want to d--
- Your mother and I,
we need our fuckin'
privacy, okay?
Now, from now on, I want you to ring
the fuckin' front doorbell.
You got that? Ring the front doorbell.
Give me your keys.
- Give me the keys right now.
Come on, give me the keys.
- I ain't givin' you--
- What are you, fuckin' 1 2?
Helen, talk to this fuckin'--
- Ma! Ma!
- Helen!
- Ma? What are you doin', Ma?
- Please don't fuckin' do this to me.
- Oh, Ritchie, stop it.
- I fuckin' hate you,
you fuckin' fat piece of shit!
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Ritchie, get back here!
- Helen, it's him or me!
- Eddie, he is my son, goddamn it!
- Now I got a case of blue balls!
- You happy? Huh?
- Eddie!
[ TVAnchorman ] The Son of Sam killer
who has been targeting...
young women
with shoulder-length hair...
has caused panic-stricken brunettes
to run to their hairdressers...
to dye their hair blonde as
protection against this madman.
But if you come in earlier,
I can't do your color.
[ Vinny ] Ruby, how come
you don't come around no more?
So you'll come in at 4:00
and we'll take care of you.
Be careful the way
your life's going, huh?
By the time you get to the altar you
might say ''I did''instead of''I do. ''
Shut up. You sound like my
fuckin' father. All right, Vinny?
- Yeah, but I'm not your
father, am I? Huh?
- No.
Hey, Vinny,
I heard you saw the killer.
- Who told you that shit?
-Just heard it around the neighborhood.
Well, I didn't see anybody,
okay? Just remember that.
Okay. Look,
thanks for the haircut.
- [ Whispers ] Use it.
- * Come on a dance with me *
- See ya, Ruby.
- [ Scoffs ]
* Gentlemen get on your feet *
* Come on and dance with me *
- Congratulations. You just
realized you were married.
- Yeah, well, I'm tryin'.
- Does Gloria need a shampoo girl?
- Hey, Gloria!
- You need a shampoo girl?
- What do you think?
Ah, there you go. See?
What about Dionna?
She need waitresses?
- Nah, she got somebody last week.
- I need a job!
I mean, I'm smart, I'm young,
I'm pretty. You know--
- Yeah, well,you got two
out of three right there.
- Shut up.
[ Cockney Accent ]
Hi. If it isn't Warren '' Beauty.''
Hey, I get more ass than
he does any day, you fuck.
- Hey, Ritchie.
- Hey, Ruby, how ya been?
You know, I copped that Who's Next
album. I was thinking about you.
- They're great, right?
- Yeah.
Fuckin', those guys are like
the godfathers of punk. You know that?
- You know that song ''Baba O'Riley''?
- Uh-huh.
That's my favorite song.
You know who wrote that?
- Englebert Humperdinck?
- Mm-mm.
What,you don't think I know?
Come on, I know. Pete Townsend.
- How'd you know that?
- I read the album credits.
I mean, the only thing
I don't get is...
why are those four guys
pissing on a big rock?
- Like in a photo shoot,
they were all drinking.
- Are you two getting married?
- Can I get to work?
- Are you jealous?
- [ Scoffs ] Please.
- I need a favor.
- What's goin' on?
- Fuckin' Eddie's got me
movin' into the garage.
- My fuckin' mother's
goin' along with it.
- What do you want me to do?
- Loan me $20.
- Ah, get outta here.
- Come on.
- Ah, you beggar, you.
- No, wait. The garage could be cool.
- Fuck that!
No, forget that.Just come and stay
with me. Dionna'll take care of you.
Seriously, no. You could fix it up.
Huh? Have privacy.
I mean, really. Fuck livin' in the
house. Hey, you know what I'll tell ya,
I'll live in the fuckin' garage,
you stay with my fuckin' crazy family.
I'll live in my fuckin' car
before I do that shit.
I'll right, here.
Shut up and take 50, all right?
- Don't ever say
I never gave you nothin'.
- Are you loaded these days?
-And use it well, all right?
- Thank you.
Fifty bucks?
Fifty fuckin'bucks?
I can turn that place
into a palace with 50 bucks.
Hey, I'm not doin'
anything later.
You know, I'll come by,
and I'll help you decorate.
- You know what that means. [ Laughing ]
- Shut up!
Might as well use this
psycho killer as an excuse.
Go ahead... blonde me.
- [ Humming ]
- You did a good job.
I could dig it, you know?
Maybe I can be
an interior decorator.
- Huh?
- You could be
whatever you want, I think.
[ Coughs, Laughs ]
Sure.
- Yeah.
- Well, you really mean that?
Of course I mean that.
Mmm. I don't know.
I figure, you're born into a slot,
you know, and that's life.
Ruby, come on. You gotta stop
with those negative vibes,you know?
You hang around with those spirit
snipers, they're gonna steal your light.
- You're too young for that.
- Uh-huh.
[ Exhales Smoke ]
What are you doing?
[ Sighs ]
Hey, come on. Come on, come on,
come on. You don't gotta do that.
- Hmm-hmm.
- Ruby, Ruby, stop, please.
You don't gotta do that.
Don't do it.
- Where are you goin'?
- I'm gonna go.
- I didn't say to go.
- Well, you didn't exactly say
you wanted me to stay.
Stay.
[ Humming ]
It's good.
[ Continues Humming ]
[ Vinny ]
Hi, baby. How ya doin'? I'm sorry. I-I--
Yeah, I'll be home.
Will you--
Yeah, I'll be an hour.
You know her. Come on.
- **[ Radio: ''Best Of My Love'']
- It's a last-minute thing.
I didn't know she was coming, okay?
Calm down.
Of course I do. Come on.
Not now, all right? Okay.
Toni-- Bye.
I gotta go, okay?
Just--
[ Kissing Sound ]
I'm telling you, Vinny, she
can't give you what you want.
Yeah, let's not talk
about her, okay?
*Feel a strange
love and affection *
- [ Chuckles ]
- Oh, my God.
*I like the way you make me
feel about you, baby *
*I want the whole
wide world to see *
- [ Both Moaning ]
- * Whoa, whoa,you've got
the best of my love *
* Whoa, whoa,you've got
- * Whoa, whoa,you've got
the best of my love *
- Gloria.
* Whoa, whoa,you've got
the best of my love *
- **[ Continues ]
- I'm feeling a little guilty now.
- Now?
- Yeah, and I'm-- I'm thinking I--
- I'm just trying to be
a good husband right now.
- Aw, Geez.
- I just don't feel like we can do it.
- You know, Vinny,
you're like a friggin' yo-yo,
back and forth, forth and back.
Let's do it, let's not do it. You know
what, Vinny? Let's just not do it.
- Okay? That's it.
- [ Mumbling ]
You think you're the only one who's got
feelings? I got a husband at home.
I know. I 1 00 percent
agree with you. Absolutely.
- What do you want me to say?
- You're a selfish bastard.
You're a selfish bastard.
- I know I'm fuckin' selfish.
- You started this. I didn't start this.
- I know it's my fault.
- Put your clothes on.
Put your fuckin' clothes on.
Clothes I put on your back.
- [ Slap ]
- **[ Continues ]
* Oh, oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh *
- Maybe we should do it
one more time, huh?
- Come on.
- How about one more time?
- Oh, Vinny, stop.
- [ Both Moaning ]
- * Oh, oh, oh, oh *
-* You've got the best of my love *
- Vinny.
- Come on, beg me for it.
- Oh, come on, Vinny.
-* Givin'you the best of my love *
- Oh, Vinny. Come on.
* You've got
the best of my love *
-* Oh, giving you the best of my love *
- [ Quiet Chattering ]
You know, with that
reward money, I'm gonna start
a college fund for my daughter.
Yeah? I'd by a yacht. Like Hugh Hefner,
I'd get Playboy bunnies walking around.
- [ Squishing Noises ]
- You can't get a yacht with ten grand.
You're gonna wind up with a row boat
with two Puerto Rican skanks.
- What are you talkin' about?
- When I get that money,
I'm gonna take my parents home to
Sicily for a whole fuckin' month.
Hey, what did I tell you about your
filthy mouth in front of my daughter?
- I apologize.
- That's your daughter?
- Yeah, she's Daddy's little sweetheart.
- Hey, there.
- Daddy!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa! Don't touch her!
- What's the matter with you?
Come here, sweetheart.
- I didn't do nothin'.
What'd you do, man?
It's all right. Daddy's here.
What, you dress like that,
you don't think it's gonna
have an effect on a baby?
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right, sweetheart.
It's okay. You okay?
Ooh, don't look
at that scary guy. Come here.
Go over-- Go play with your friends,
okay? Get away from him.
Give me more reasons
to hate your ass.
I'm back!
[ Anthony ] Give me back the 1 5
I lent you last week.
[ Brian ]
What are you talk-- I gave you the $ 1 5.
- What do you want?
- Two nicks.
- Hello, Brian.
- He-Hey! Bobby the fairy!
How's it hangin', huh?
That's Mrs. Del Fiore to you,
sweetheart. And don't wear it out.
[ Chuckles ]
Is that Ritchie?
Well, hello, stranger.
Long time no see.
Very Lower East Side.
I like it.
- I'll take two,Joey.
- Two what? Two dicks?
I'll take yours and Ritchie's.
Double the pleasure, double the fun.
Here, suck on these two nickels.
Just give me the money.
Let's go. Come on,
come on, come on. Come on.
- This money better not
be sticky, either.
- There-There you go.
Thank you.
It said in the Post
the killer's a woman hater.
That's you, Bobby.
You could be the killer.
- .44-Caliber Queer.
- Pow! Pow! Pow!
- A real ''homo-cidal'' maniac.
- He's guilty. Put him through
the penal system.
Well, only if I can have you
as my cell mate.
- How 'bout that, you motherfucker?
- Ah, shit!
You asshole!
You fucking asshole! I hate you!
Come on, don't burn him!
He's a paying customer!
- He's a fuckin' homo!
- Ridiculous, man.
Look, I gotta go drop the kid off
with her mother. I'll see you later.
- See you later at the club?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Joey, can you give me and Ruby
a lift to the subway?
Fuck no. You made her cry once already.
Come on. Sweetheart.
- Come on, princess. Princess, come on.
- Daddy!
- Hey, Ruby!
- Come on, let's go.
Daddy, Daddy,
let's go home!
- So what's goin' on with you and Ruby?
- What? She's my date.
- Your date?
She's goin' on a date with you?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Hey, Ritch, why buy the cow
when everybody else is gettin'
the milk and steaks for free?
I like the cow.
Brian, do me a favor.
Give me and Ruby a lift.
Come on, man. I'm fuckin' busy.
You can ride your cow to the subway.
Hey, cows don't fit in Corvettes.
I'm sorry, Ritch.
You're serious?
You're not gonna give me a lift?
You know, Ritch.
Nothin'for nothin',
but are you startin' to get
the feelin' that maybe you're
not that welcome around here?
I mean, do I got to
spell it out for you?
Nah, it's clear.
[ Man ] What you got this time?
'Cause I heard it before from you.
You know, and I got in trouble from you.
That's 'cause you sent me chicken.
I don't need no chicken.
I don't need no trouble from the law.
- Thank you very much. Hold on a sec.
- Hey.
Let me get back to you, okay?
I'm working.
Somebody's gotta make some money here.
- Hey, man.
- Ritchie.
- This is Ruby.
- Ruby.
- This is Midnite.
- Hello.
- Let me do a show tonight.
- Got enough performers today.
- One show.
- One show?
I got rules, Ritchie,
and you know the rules.
Five shows a day,
seven days a week.
- I know.
- You know, but if I break
the rules for you,
- I'm gonna have every little
punk comin' up here...
- I just need some moolah.
every time
they need a dime bag.
- Relax. One show.
- ''Just one show. Relax.''
- This girl's special to me.
- Oh, well, then you appeal
to my sense of romantic.
Uh-huh. Let me see
how special she is.
- What color panties you have on, honey?
- Hey.
- Let me see. What color?
I just want to see color.
- Cut it out.
- You tell me she's special.
Blue. Okay, blue.
- Stop. You're bein' rude.
- What are you doin'?
- Go ahead.
**[ Woman Vocalizing ]
**[ Woman Singing In French ]
He's got a pretty cock.
Nice size. You're a lucky girl.
Yeah, thanks.
- You in the business, baby?
- Business?
Yeah. You strip? You do fuck flicks?
What's your shtick, baby?
No, I'm-I'm not
in the business.
Girl, you're way too hot
to be giving it away.
You're so hot, you make me wish
I was a lesbian.
**[ French Continues ]
- [ Bouncer] How are you doing, guys?
- Hey.
- Go right on up.
- You wanna get this hotel room?
No. Ritchie,
wait a minute.
Look, if you're gettin'
second thoughts, I mean--
No, I'm not getting
second thoughts.
I just wanna know
if I can borrow some money...
because I wanna ditch
this whole disco look.
**[ Marvin Gaye:
''Got To Give It Up'']
Let me get your door, okay?
I wanna do this right.
*I used to go out to parties *
- Come on, baby.
- Thank you, baby.
- **[ Continues ]
- Tonight's your night. And my night.
- It's our night.
- We've been holed up
like cowards for two weeks.
Fuck the .44-Caliber Killer. We're
gonna have fun tonight. It's Saturday.
- Whoo!
- Saturday. Ulysses!
- Hey!
- How ya doing, stronzo?
- Great. Have a good time.
- [ Dionna Chuckling ]
- [ Laughs ] What an idiot.
- Ah, he doesn't have a clue.
- Oh, my God, honey. Nobody's here.
- What the fuck is going on?
- Did they all go somewhere else?
- [ Brian ] So I got to make an excuse.
I say, ''Oh, uh, I got to take care
of my grandmother, ''I say.
- Holy shit! [ Whistles ]
- Whoa.
- [ Wolf Whistle ] Dionna, what a dress!
- Easy, now.
- Look at those legs.
- They're longer than Vinny's.
- [ All Laughing ]
- A lot longer.
- That's all right, though.
I can handle it.
- Oh, man.
Hey, what's the matter here? We got
like a morgue going on. What's going on?
Everybody's afraid of this
killer,just like you, Vin.
- Ah, man.
- Not as scared as I was.
Dionna, you look very beautiful
tonight. May I have this dance?
Yeah, can I dance
with you too?
- Wishful thinking.
- Maybe youse better dance
with each other.
- Yeah, dance together.
- [ Anthony ] Now I know
why you never come out with us.
That's right. Why would I go out
with you with those Pink Panther pants?
*I like to party, oh *
* Oh, if you let me *
* Whoa, whoa *
* Come up to see me *
*And let me *
*Baby,just party *
* Come on *
**[ Continues, Indistinct ]
*Movin'up *
*And down *
*Move, shake it down *
*Ah, whoo *
**[ Indistinct ]
*If you think
you're groovy, mama *
*Let's meet face to face *
*Everybody's moving *
* This is such a groovy place *
* Oh, these things *
*Are so fine *
*Let's go party *
*A little while *
* Come on and dance, baby *
*And turn me on *
- [ Flies Buzzing ]
- [ TVAnnouncer ]
Daily News columnistJimmy Breslin...
received a letter today
from the .44-Caliber Killer.
Police said that the handwritten letter
addressed to Mr. Breslin...
contained numerous
occult symbols,
was signed
by the madman himself,
calling himself the Son of Sam.
[ Son of Sam ]
Son of Sam.
Hello from the gutters
of N. Y.C.,
which are filled
with dog manure, vomit,
stale wine, urine and blood.
- Hello, Brian.
- Hello, from the sewers of N. Y.C.,
which swallow up
these delicacies...
when they are washed away
by the sweeper trucks.
Screw Son of Sam.
I'm not cuttin' my hair.
- [ Phones Ringing ]
- Hello from the cracks in
the sidewalks of New York City,
and from the ants
that dwell in these cracks...
and feed on the dried blood that
has settled into these cracks.
- Mr. Breslin, sir,
- [ Sizzling ]
don't think that because you
haven't heard from me for a while...
that I went to sleep.
No. Rather, I am still here,
like a spirit roaming the night.
- ''Thirsty, hungry,
seldom stopping to rest,
- Thirsty, hungry,
- anxious to please Sam.''
- anxious to please Sam.
- [ Barking ]
- I love my work.
Now the void has been filled.
He won't let me stop killing
until he gets his fill of blood.
Tell me,Jim,
what will you have for me
July 29th?
Not knowing what the future
holds, I shall say farewell.
And I will see you
at my next job.
- Or, shall I say,you will see
my handiwork at the next job.
- In the name of the Father--
P.S. Please inform
all the detectives...
- [ Keys Jingling ]
- working on the case
that I wish them luck.
Keep them digging, drive on.
- Think positive.
- [ Dog Barking ]
- Here are some clues to help you along.
The Duke of Death,
the Wicked King Wicker.
- [ Woman Screaming ]
- Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
What are you doing here? Don't you know
the Son of Sam is running around?
- Go find yourself a motel, huh?
Get the hell out of here.
- [ Engine Starts ]
[ Son of Sam ]
The 22 Disciples of Hell.
John Wheaties, rapist
and suffocator of young girls.
In their blood
and from the gutter,
Sam's creation, .44-Caliber,
The Son of Sam.
Let me in!
Mick, let me in!
- Let me in!
- What? You all right?
- [ Dog Barking ]
- The Duke of Death,
the Wicked King Wicker.
Fuck you, Wicked King Wicker,
Duke of Death, Son of Sam!
Come and fucking get me!
You don't scare me!
Come and get me! I don't give a fuck!
Honey.
Honey, what are you doing?
- Honey, what's wrong?
- Baby, this is Devil worship, okay?
This is occult.
This is Manson shit.
There's somebody
outside there?
What if he thinks I saw him?
What if he fuckin' thinks
that I saw him?
- The Son of Sam?
- Yes, the fuckin' Son of Sam.
Well, why would he think
you saw him?
Did you see him?
Honey, you're scaring me.
Baby, I gotta get outta here.
I gotta get outta here.
I can't take this anymore. I'm fuckin'
gonna have a nervous breakdown.
I gotta get outta here.
Let's go away for a whole fuckin' week.
Let's just get out of here.
- When do you want to go?
- Let's go right now.
Let's pack up our shit and get
the fuck out for a while, okay?
Baby, I can't go right now.
Dad told me we might have
to fire one of the waitresses.
Oh, baby. Come on. Let's go.
Come on. We'll get a hot tub.
We'll get dirty movies.
We'll fuckin' get massages,
vibratin' beds,
the whole works.
We'll just have fun,
crazy fun, okay?
We could get
the dirty movies here.
It's not the same, baby.
It's not the same.
I can't leave Dad right now, baby,
but we can make our own vacation here.
You'll see.
We can have our own fun.
[ Sighs ]
Come on. Let's--
Come on.
Let's make love.
Baby. Baby?
Hey, baby.
Co-Could we make love
with the light on?
What?
- I wanna see us.
- You wanna make love with the light on?
Yeah, I wanna see us.
Can we try it?
Please?
All right. How 'bout instead
of making love, we fuck this time, huh?
- Yeah?
- Okay.
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Whispering ] Ow.
[ Heavy Breathing ]
Oh.
[ Heavy Breathing Continues ]
Oh, yeah.
Oh.
[ Grunting ]
[ Heavy Breathing,
Grunting Continue ]
Oh! Oh!
Yeah. Oh!
[ Moaning ]
Oh, shit.
[ Vinny Sighing ]
[ Sighing Continues ]
Good night.
Let's go to sleep.
Good night, baby.
[ Sighs ]
Good evening. This is John Jeffries,
Eyewitness News.
I'm here
with Detective Timothy Dowd,
head of the .44-Caliber Killer
Task Force.
Detective Dowd, what can you tell
our viewers about Son of Sam?
Well,John, we are putting together
a picture of the suspect,
uh, slowly, I must say.
Too slowly for our tastes,
but we have no choice.
This is a very elusive suspect.
Whenever we get there, he's gone.
We never know where
he's going to strike next.
- But I will tell you this:
- What are they talking about anyway?
The man must live somewhere, so
we have a man who we suspect--
Maybe you notice that he comes home
late, 3:00, 4:00 in the morning.
- This is all fuckin' smoke.
- It's a farce. A farce.
[ Luigi ] Smoke.
They don't know what they're doing.
[Jeffries ]
Do you have a long list of suspects?
[ Dowd ]
We have a list.
We've always had a list. We have a list
now, and we have always had a list.
-I know what we gotta do.
-John Jeffries, task force headquarters.
We gotta get this rat bastard.
We gotta do it.
'Cause they can't do it.
And maybe we offer another
$5,000 in the reward, huh?
- At least we'll get
a few more names on our list.
- Right, boss.
[ Dionna ]
It's bad.
Yeah. They're gonna catch
this bastard soon, ah?
Okay, do me a favor.
Buy me a little time.
Do the books one more time.
See if you find something.
Dad, it's math.
It's not magic.
I've been through them
four times already.
If something doesn't change soon,
I don't know what's gonna happen.
I gotta tell Connie
I gotta let her go.
Connie? Dad, she's our strongest
waitress. You can't do that.
Connie's got no children. That's only
one mouth that's got to stay empty.
- Hey, what's up.
- [ Speaks In Italian ]
- Hey, paisan.
- How ya doing?
How are you? All right?
Where were you?
Stadium. Yankees lost.
-Come on. Let's go. I'm tired.
-All right, Dad. I guess we're gonna go.
Aspett' one minute, okay?
I got something for the both of youse.
- [ Vinny ] We gotta go.
- I got something for both of youse.
Wait a minute.
- Oh,you do?
- Yeah. You like presents.
- Come here.
- What is this, Dad?
- Look at that.
- What the hell is that?
If you go out tonight, Vinny,
make her wear it for me?
Dad, I'm not gonna wear this. Come on.
We're just gonna drive straight home.
Do me a favor. For your father.
Please respect me.
This animal is killing only
young girls with long, brown
hair. Please, do it for me.
- Come on. Listen to your father.
Come on.
- Are you gonna gang up on me?
- Yeah.
- All right. I'll wear
the Barbie doll... thing.
That's right. You make me
sleep in peace, huh? Please?
- Please? Thank you.
- Come on. Let's go.
-[ Dionna ] Are they closed?
- Yeah.
- Promise?
- I swear to God.
- I hear you coming.
- * When we met *
- *It wasn't quite clear to me *
- I know you're standin' there.
- I'm here. Okay.
- * What you had in store
was there for only me *
- Wow.
*Silly,you know you took me
by surprise *
- Wow, baby. [ Wolf Whistle ]
- * Then I turned and looked *
-Jesus Christ.
- *And I saw that message in your eye *
- You like?
- You look so different.
-Jesus, I feel like
I'm cheating on you with you.
- *I fell on the floor *
- Oh. Wow. Oh, baby.
- * The way you move, girl
only made me want you more *
I wanna call you by another name.
You know what I'm gonna call you?
- I'm gonna call you Sheri.
- I like that name.
- Is it French?
- Oh, yeah.
Sheri, do you want to fuck?
Want to fuck me, Sheri?
- Do you want to fuck me?
- Yeah, I want to fuck you.
Can I call you Vincente?
[ Fake Italian Accent ] Yeah,
but first you have to suck my huge cock.
- You sure you want me
to do that, Vincente?
- [ Laughing ]
I know Sheri loves it.
Whoa, baby.
-* When you lay down next to me *
- [ Moaning ]
Wow.
*I find it hard for me
to concentrate *
*If I don't make my move
then it might be too late *
- *I've got to make sure
you don't get away *
- Oh.
- Oh, shit.
- *After all you've done, girl
to make me want to stay *
- *All my life I've been
searching for a star *
- [ Whispering, Indistinct ]
- [ Moaning ]
- *Now my search is over
and here we are *
- *Livin'in ecstasy *
- Oh, fuck!
- Oh!
- * Yeah *
-* When you lay down next to me *
- Oh, shit.
- [ Sighs ]
- * Yeah, we're in ecstasy *
- Oh, shit.
-* When you lay down next to me *
- Oh, shit. Oh, no, no, no.
Don't do that.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Did I hurt you?
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I should have never made you do this.
I'm so-- I should've never done this.
- I'm sorry, baby.
I'm really fucking sorry.
- What?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Baby, what-what happened?
- What happened?
- No, no, no.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Tell me how
you like it. I'll do it different.
- It's not that.
Baby, baby, it's not that.
- I'll do it different.
Please. It's just--
You're my wife, okay? And
I love you just the way you are.
Let's do it just like normal people,
the way we always fucking do it.
Let's just do it regular.
Come on.
But, baby, I-I-I wanna
make you happy.
- I'm gonna turn off the light, okay?
- * When you lay next to me *
All right.
Here's your slices.
Hey, what are you takin' the big one
for? What the hell's wrong with you?
- Thank you, sweetheart.
- You gotta take the big slice
all the time?
All right, listen.
We got four names on the list.
- Right.
- Read that list.
All right. Right at the top
we got Ritchie Freak.
Billy theJew,Jimmy Del Fini
and that fuckin' guy that
drives the bus to City Island.
All right. We're gonna mark
their tires with chalk.
- Chalk?
- If any of'em take a ride,
we'll know what's happening.
All right. You see that guy
over there making pies?
Don't be so obvious, Brian.
His name's Frankie Cadillac.
He just moved to the
neighborhood about a year ago...
and he lives alone
on Sampson Avenue.
My aunt tells me there's
something evil about this guy.
He's got those weirdo eyes.
- [Joey ] Yeah. We'll check him out.
- What aboutJohnny Nasso, huh?
Johnny Nasso drives a cab,
and he's a Vietnam vet.
- So what?
- So what? Vietnam vets
call themselves Sons of Sam.
- Uncle Sam and shit, huh?
- I never heard of that.
All right. Relax.
- No, no, no. That's not enough.
-Joey...
he lives alone,
his wife left him a year ago...
and he works nights.
He's a multiple category.
All right. Good work.
Put him on the list.
Write him down.
Joey, you know who I've been
thinkin' should go on the list?
- Father Cadilli.
- The priest?
Yeah. Oh, you fuckin' guys
don't remember the beatings
he used to give us?
Fuckin' nuts.
Drinks like a bastard.
- I want him on the list.
Let's put him on the list.
- No, no, no.
- Let me think about it.
- [ TVSportscaster ]
Strike one for number 44.
I know who the killer is.
- I figured it out.
- [ TVAnnouncer ]
Reggie steps back into the box.
[ Woodstock ]
ReggieJackson.
- [ Both Laugh ]
- What the fuck is wrong with you?
- What's the matter with you?
- You idiot.
I'm serious.
Son of Sam.
Uncle Sam.
Yankee Doodle Dandy.
- Bronx Bombers.
New York fuckin' Yankees.
- [ Laughing ]
What, are you mixing acid
with your dope now?
What kind of gun
did the killer use?
.44 caliber, right?
What's Reggie's number?
- 44.
- Hey, nobody said the killer
was a mulinian.
- That's why they can't find him.
- You keep talking like that, Woody,
I'm putting you at the head
of that fuckin' list.
- Give me that fuckin' pen.
- Stop, stop, stop, stop.
Enough with the list.
- Give me this fuckin' list.
- Even if he is the killer,
we need him till October!
- This is a serious list.
- We need Reggie if we're gonna
win the World Series.
- Put fuckin'Jim Rice
on the fuckin' list!
- Stop!
- Hey!
- Hey, we're running a business!
- Fuck you too.
- Oh! I told you once.
- All right. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
- Hey, you told me once.
- I'm sorry.
- Get the fuck back in there
and make me a calzone.
It's all right.
Everything's fine.
[ Barking ]
[ Yelling ]
[ Yelling Continues ]
[ Barking Continues ]
You leave this animal alone!
You leave us alone.
Samuel Carr,
I have asked you kindly...
to stop that dog from howling
all day, all night long.
- Yet he continues to do so.
- Now, Berkowitz, you listen to me!
- I have no peace, no rest.
- Harvey's a good dog.
-He usually leaves people alone.
-Now I know what kind of person you are.
- You're cruel and inconsiderate.
- The reason that this dog is
barking at you all the time...
is you tease him, you antagonize him,
you never stop fooling around with him.
- You wicked, evil man!
Child of the Devil!
- I'm gonna call the cops!
Shut that dog up!
Now you keep it up, fella, and I'm
calling the cops! I'm sick of this!
- [ Barking Continues ]
- Kill...
T-H-E...
the... dog.
[ Barking Continues ]
You won't
be barking anymore.
[ Harvey Whimpering ]
[ The Who:
'' Baba O'Riley'' ]
[ Woman Screaming ]
[ Man Screaming ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Whimpering, Crying ]
Help me!
* Out here in the fields *
- *I fought for my meals
- I fought for my meals
The .44-Caliber Killer,
who calls himself the Son of Sam,
- **[ Continues, Indistinct ]
- struck again last night,
shooting a 1 7-year-old girl...
and a 20-year-old man
as they sat in a car...
- near the Elphas disco in Queens.
- *I don't need to fight *
* To prove I'm right *
*I don't need *
* To be forgiven *
* Yeah,yeah,yeah,
yeah,yeah,yeah *
- Hi, Dan.
- How are you doing?
What can I do for you, man?
Give me a good deal.
[ Chuckles ]
- What are you looking for?
- A fuckin'new Fender.
I got just the guitar
for you, dude.
*Don't cry *
- Brand new Stratocaster.
Sunburst, rosewood neck,
- *Don't raise your eye *
with your name on it.
- *It's only *
- How much?
- * Teenage *
- 360 bucks, out the door.
- * Wasteland *
*Sally, take my hand *
*And travel south, my friend *
*Put out the fire *
*And don't look past
my shoulder *
[ Chanting ]
Reggie! Reggie! Reggie!
[ Cheering Continues ]
* Teenage wasteland *
*It's only teenage wasteland *
-* Teenage wasteland Oh,yeah *
- * Teenage wasteland *
* Teenage wasteland *
* They're all wasted *
- [ Barking ]
- Yeah. That's a good boy, Harvey. Yeah.
- Are you shot, Bobby?
- No. It was Rocco.
[ Brian ]
Let's go fuck him up!
- I'll teach you to fuck with us!
- [ Indistinct Shouting ]
- You motherfucker!
- Pussy!
Nobody messes
with Bobby Del Fiore!
No!
[ Shouting ]
[ Cheering, Whistling ]
[ Drips ]
What are you gonna have?
Keep lookin', maggot.
Keep lookin', half a fag.
- What are you doing? Stop that shit.
- [ Man ] I don't like him.
- These fuckin' guys in the pink shirts.
- Leave 'em alone, all right?
Fuckin' mind your business.
What are you gonna have?
[ Man ]
You believe this freak?
- Do you like me?
- Ritchie, be serious with me
for a minute, all right?
- Here you go.
- I don't feel like eating right here.
- Chicken's yours, right?
- Get him out of here,
or we ain't comin' back.
Doesn't bother you that
Ruby's been with so many guys?
That she's been shtupped by so many
fuckin' guys. That bother you?
What she did before she met me is
her business, don't you think?
- You really feel that?
- Yeah.
It would schieve me
a little bit, you know?
I mean, Ruby's a nice girl,
but she is a whore, you know?
- What?
- You don't love her, do you?
What's your interpretation
of love?
Commitment, responsibility,
marriage, kids, all of that.
You're not gonna marry her.
I won't let you fuckin'marry her.
What, you and Dionna
are gonna have kids?
What took you so long, Chickie?
I'm starvin'over here.
Thank you, you know? Can I get a--
I want a cheeseburger and I want fries--
Uh, I'm sorry, Vinny,
but we're out of cheeseburgers.
- Out of cheeseburgers?
- All right. Well,
can you get me a B.L.T.?
-Something like that, with a--
- Uh, sorry. Sorry. No can do.
What-- What do you got, then?
Give me whatever you got. I'm
fuckin' freakin' starvin' here.
I don't have anything.
We're closin'.
You got a 2 4-hour diner,
and you're closin'?
- I just saw you fuckin' serve
those guys over there.
- It's these fuckin' guys here.
All right. Look, guys. I don't want any
trouble.Just leave. Hit the bricks.
I just wanna eat.
You're not gonna serve me?
You're lucky I come into this
greasy spoon fuckin' diner.
- All right, Vinny.
I'll serve you, but he's gotta go.
- Who are you talking to?
- Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Wait. Hold on.
- You talking to me?
No. Hold on. Chickie, Chickie,
do you know who this is?
- Who?
- You don't know who this is, do you?
- You fuck. This is Ritchie.
- Ritchie who?
- Ritchie Trangali!
- That's Ritchie Trangali?
I know he's a little scary looking,
but that's my boy.
Look, Ritchie. I'm sorry,
but you're gonna have to leave.
- You're getting my customers nauseous.
- Come on. Fuck these guys.
Come on, Chickie. Fuck your customers.
Relax. Get some roast beef sandwiches.
- Come on. Come on.
Just,just go.Just go.
-Just like that?
Fuck this idiot. All right.
Fuck him. Fuck it. Let's go.
- You're calling me an idiot?
- Yeah, you're a fuckin' idiot.
- You fuckin' reject.
Get the hell out of here!
- Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Get him out of here.
Just take him out of my place.
- Hey, mind your fuckin'-- Fuck you!
- [ All Shouting ]
You fucking bitch!
[ Man ]
Jesus.
Tastes better
than Heinz ketchup, you fuck.
- He's fuckin' nuts.
- You like that, you fuck?
- Ritchie, easy.
- [ Spits ]
You know, Ritchie,
I don't blame them, you know?
I mean, when you're in Rome,
what are you gonna do, right?
And you come up here with that
dog collar. What do you expect--
What, you think I give a fuck?
They're all wearing dog collars.
You're wearin' a dog collar.
- I'm, I'm wearing a fuckin' dog--
- You're wearing a dog collar.
You're a fuckin' dog of society. You're
on a leash to a certain way of thinking.
- You don't see that?
- Ritchie, I don't fuckin'
understand what you're saying.
I'm not relating to this shit, okay?
Is the fuckin' heat getting to you?
No, no. Listen.
It's like everybody's
got two personalities, Vin.
Two personalities-- one you're born
with, one the fuckin' world gives you.
Are you talking about
some alter ego shit? Is this
what we're talking about now?
Ah, no. Vin, it's, like,
I got these things I like doin'.
I like doin' 'em so much,
it's like I have to do 'em.
Now, do I really like doin' 'em, or
was I preprogrammed at an early age...
to respond to liking them?
That's what I'm talking about.
You fuckin' lost me.
Yeah, fuckin'
what else is new, man?
What the fuck? Are you saying
that if I fuckin' cheat on Dionna,
it's not me that made me do it,
it's the fuckin' world?
Is that what you're saying?
Take responsibility for your
fuckin' self, man.
It's not the fuckin' world. It's your
fuckin' dick that made you do that!
Don't blame the world!
- My fuckin' dick made me do that?
- Yeah, your dick.
[ Newscaster ]
The heat wave continues throughout the
city as record-breaking temperatures...
claimed six lives yesterday.
Three fatalities
were in Brooklyn,
two in the Bronx
and one in Queens.
Crime has risen
with the temperatures.
The police are reporting an
increase in domestic violence--
All right, you two.
Out. My turn.
- Aw, gee.
- And Con Ed is asking that you
try to conserve electricity,
as several neighborhoods
in the five boroughs...
are experiencing brownouts.
[ Newscaster ] The health department
advises the elderly...
-and people with respiratory problems--
- [ Electric Appliances Whirring ]
Uh-oh.
[ Bulbs Crackling ]
[ Crackling, Whirring Continue ]
[ Whispering ]
Shit.
[ Dionna Screaming ]
Daddy! Dad!
- [ Mario ] Baby, baby.
- [ Screaming Continues ]
- [ Vinny ] Come on. Take it easy.
- It's all right.
- All right. All right.
- Oh, my God! Guys, this is not funny!
- [ Mario ]
It's us. Baby, the power's out.
- The power's out?
- [ Phones Ringing ]
- Forty-fifth precinct, Officer Hall.
Yeah, we, we do know. Yeah. It's, it's
a blackout. The whole five boroughs.
- We're doing the best we can.
Hold on, ma'am.
- [ Ringing Continues ]
Four-five precinct,
Officer Riggs. Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. We understand that
the lights are out. We have
Con Edison out in full force.
Con Ed don't know nothin',
but what I know is,
we can't expect any help
from the cops.
- [ Shouting ]
- They're gonna have their hands
full chasin'looters all night.
-[Joey ] Niggers and spics.
-[ Brian ] Spics and niggers.
[ Luigi ] Now it's ourjob to protect
our neighborhood, to defend it.
And this Son of Sam
has the blackout to hide in.
I want all our guys
on the Layton Avenue bridge.
I'm not handin'it over. It's fuckin'
my joint. Shut the fuck up.
Nobody gets in my neighborhood
without me knowin' it.
Oh, what the fuck is this?
- Oh. Oh, pull over.
- [ Chattering ]
What the fuck are you doing?
Who are you? What do you want here?
- [ Speaks In Spanish ]
- Who the fuck are you?
- Huh?
- What the fuck are you talking about?
- Get the fuck out of there!
- [ Spanish Continues ]
- [ Tires Screeching ]
- [ Shouting ]
[ Screeching Continues ]
[ Shouting Continues,
Indistinct ]
- Con Ed officials said...
- [ Shouting ]
the lights went out
at 9:34 p.m.!
I'm here at the corner
of 1 25th Street and 5th Avenue.
And black
and Puerto Rican people...
are going crazy.
As I overheard one man say,
''It's like Christmas in July.''
That's a quote.
We have reports that people are
stuck on the subways underground...
and that the city that never
sleeps has come to a standstill.
I'm gonna get out of the way
'cause I fear my safety.
Joey, get the kids
in the neighborhood.
If they need cars,
you give 'em cars.
If they need baseball bats,
you give 'em bats.
We're gonna take a bat.
We're gonna patrol the neighborhood.
We're gonna go on to different
points-- to the beach, bridge,
down to the avenue and back.
- Understand? All right.
- [ All ] Yeah.
[ Shouting, Indistinct ]
Here we go. Come on. Let's go.
[ Shouting Continues ]
[Joey ] Louisville Slugger.
Here you go Come on. Take it. Come on.
- [ Shouting Continues ]
- Come on. Let's go!
[ Chanting ] We'll get you, Son of Sam!
We'll get you, Son of Sam!
- Come on!
- We'll get you, Son of Sam!
We'll get you, Son of Sam!
- We'll find you!
And then you call Frankie.
Tell him to bring the feast lights...
and the generators 'cause Luigi
is gonna give a big block party,
with the cannoli and the baba rum and
the sausage and peppers and the spetini.
That psycho is gonna have
no place to hide.
Freddie! Oh! Hey!
What'd you bring?
Hey, look at this. Who the hell--
Hey, hey, hey, that's my man!
- I love you, I love you, I love you!
- [ Chuckling ]
Bang! Bang! Bang!
Bang! Bang!
I got you!
[ Kids Shouting ]
Bang! Bang!
I got you, Son of Sam!
- We got a fuckin' gig.
You know, singin'?
- Serious?
- We're going to be
at fuckin' C.B.G.B.'s.
- At C.B.G.B.'s.
- Vinny, this is our first gig, man.
This is a big deal.
- That's great. In the city.
- No, congratula-- No,
I'm serious. We're excited.
- It really is beautiful.
- Congratulations. A toast.
- Yeah.
- I'm singing.
- They're gonna pay you
and everything. That's great.
- I don't know about that.
- Maybe I'll come down.
What's it called?
How do you spell that C.B.G.B.?
C.B.G.B. You never heard of it?
It's on the Bowery in the city.
Oh, C.B.G.B.
You and Ritchie
seem really happy together.
Yep, we are.Just try and enjoy it
while it lasts. You know what I mean?
I guess that's a good philosophy
as long as you're not married.
Listen, um, I know that
you've been with Vinny before.
I mean, it's not a secret
or anything.
That was a long time ago,
a long time ago--
before you two got together, let
alone got married, all right?
No, no, no, no.
I know that. I know that.
I'm not, I'm not accusing you
of anything. Um--
- Then what do you want?
- A-All I... wanted to say was that...
since you've been with him,
maybe you could tell me what he likes.
- You're serious?
- Yeah.
[ Laughs ]
If I knew, I wouldn't be asking.
I mean-- Look.
You think this is easy for me?
Talking to you about Vinny,
and, you know, my husband's
sexual likes and dislikes.
It's--
And so you ask me,
'cause I should know.
No, I-- You guys looked happy
when you were goin' out.
And you're so sexy and confident
and everything.
Listen. I mean,
sometimes I-I think that, um, that,
you know, he's, he's cheating on me.
Anyway, you know,
I wa-- I wanna please him,
but I, I don't think that I do.
You have any advice?
Anything?
Look, Dionna.
You are, uh, very pretty, okay?
You're sexy.
I happen to know that Vinny
loves you very much.
I know he loves me,
but, um,
I think I disappoint him.
So what do you want me
to do?
Do you want me to tell you
how to fuck your husband?
Yeah, fine. I'll tell ya.
[ Snickers ]
First, you can't be his wife.
[ Chuckles ]
- That's number one. Too late for that.
- Yeah.
[ Chattering ]
Hey, Chuckie.
Chuckie, come here!
Come here.
Get the hell over here!
- Is this it? This where we're going?
- It looks like it.
The sign's C.B.G.B., right? And this is
Bleecker. Corner of Bleecker and Bowery.
This is the Bowery. This is where
my father told me all the bums were.
- But who are these people here?
- You scared? Buy us some beer.
- What is this?
- I can't believe Ritchie
made us come over here.
What the hell is the matter with him?
I won't even park my car here.
What the fuck is this?
Oh, my God. Look at those girls
looking at me like that.
Look at them looking at me
like I'm the freak.
Come on.Just don't
pay attention to them.
Look at that thing on her tongue.
I, I don't like this place.
I think maybe we should go.
You think so? You think
that's right, though, huh?
Maybe we should go in
and say hello to Ritchie.
And just maybe go for one drink,
and then we'll get the hell out, huh?
- Your call.
- No.
I, I, I wanna go.
I schieve this place.
- You sure?
- Yeah, I'm sorry. Let's just go.
Okay. All right.
Where the hell do you want to go?
- Um--
- Anywhere. I don't care.
- 54?
- Studio 54?
- Is that where you wanna go?
- We're dressed for it, baby.
We're dressed for it.
Okay. It's your car. It's your night.
We'll go wherever you want.
* Hello from the gutters
of New York City *
-[ Crowd Cheering ]
-* Filled with urine vomit, stale wine *
* And blood *
* Hello from the sewers
of N.Y.C. *
[ Cheering Continues ]
* Which swallow up
these delicacies *
* I said hello, hello *
* From the gutters of the city *
* Where we're washed away
by the sweeper trucks *
* Hello, hello, hello, hello *
* Hello *
* Oh, hell, oh, hell, oh, hell
oh, hello *
- * Hello *
- [ Ruby ] *Hello *
- * Good-bye *
* This summer you die *
* Hello from the cracks
in the sidewalks *
* Of New York City *
* From the ants
that dwell here *
* In these cracks *
* These cracks *
* Hello from the ants
that feed on dried blood *
* Of the dead that's fallen
into these cracks *
- **[ Disco ]
- [ Chattering, Shouting ]
*I'm sick and tired
of bad dates *
- Buddy, I know Steve!
- *Don't flaunt no shit
No time to wait *
- Please.
- *I just want to gravitate *
* Out of sight, out of sight *
- * Oh, let's go *
- Come on. Come on.
* Out of sight, out of sight *
* Oh, let's go *
- This is crazy.
- Oh, my God.
Oh, look at the line.
Jesus Christ.
Honey, I can't wait to hear
what music they're gonna play in here.
- **[ Singing Continues ]
- You get so excited
by this stuff, don't ya?
Honey, we're gonna dance.
The people we're gonna see. My God.
Wow. Look at the limos and everything.
Look at the people.
I don't want to wait on line.
Excuse me, you waiting on line to get--
- Yes, I am. I'm waitin' to get in.
- Oh, my God.
Those are, those are men.
[ Laughing ]
Shh!
- He sure is ugly, though.
- Shh!
Oh, over here.
Over here.
- How are we gonna get in, baby?
- Oh, please!
- Why don't we walk up
and pretend, you know?
-Just push right through.
Go ahead.
Act like you belong.
- How ya doing?
- Whoa, whoa. Are you on the list?
- What list?
- Did somebody put you on the list?
- Yeah.
- How do you know about the list?
- If you're not on the list,
you got to get behind the line.
- The line? Wait a minute.
Hey, wait a minute, son.
You're confusing me.
What do you mean about the line?
Come on. I don't have time
for this. Let's go. Come on.
Behind the ropes, guy.
- We came all the way from the Bronx.
- Vinny, give him some money.
Look how beautiful she is.
Let her in. Come on.
Hey, it's the first goddamn star
I've seen tonight.
Give me the camera. Come on.
Just stand there for one second.
What's your name?
- My name's Vinny.
- Vinny, smile, smile!
- That's it. Oh, God, you're beautiful!
- Hey, we're trying to get in.
- Hey, who's your lady?
Why don't you come with us?
- She's my wife.
- All right. Everybody out.
- [ Man ] Ooh! Ooh!
- Here we are, Vinny!
- Ooh! Ooh!
Simon says hold this.
Simon says hold this. [ Chuckles ]
- Come on. Let's go! Vinny!
- Come on. Let's go.
- This is your palace.
- Oh, Simon, it's a beautiful palace.
[ Vinny ]
Whoo!
[ Camera Shutters Clicking ]
- There you go, baby.
- Goddamn.
- Here.
- Oh, shit. I never knew
places like this existed.
- [ Laughing ]
- Oh, honey, I'm really stoned.
- There, let me see.
- Maybe we should go.
Oh, come on. You want to go?
I don't really want to go.
I want, I want to stay.
But if you wanna go, I'll go.
I don't care. Whatever you want.
You want to go
or you want to stay?
If you want to stay,
I'll stay.
- You sure? If you want to go, I'll go.
- [ Sniffing ]
- No. I'll stay.
- Okay, let's stay. We're stayin'. Good.
**[ Disco ]
Honey, people can see us.
Oh, come on, baby. Trust me.
Just close your eyes like this.
Come on. Trust me.
Please trust me.
*Everybody dance *
*Doo-ooh, clap your hands
Clap your hands *
[ Woman Moaning ]
*Everybody dance *
*Doo-ooh, clap your hands
clap your hands *
- *Music never lets you down *
- [ Moaning, Chattering ]
*Puts a smile on your face
anytime, anyplace *
*Dancing helps
relieve the pain *
*Soothes your mind *
*Makes you happy again *
*Listen
to those dancing feet *
* Close your eyes and let go *
*But it don't mean a thing
if it ain't got that swing *
Take it up your fuckin'--
That's it. I'm fuckin'--
- Come on.
- *Everybody dance *
- I'm coming.
- *Doo-ooh, clap your hands
clap your hands *
*Everybody dance *
*Doo-ooh, clap your hands
Clap your hands *
- [ Dionna Moaning ]
- *Everybody dance *
*Doo-ooh, clap your hands
Clap--*
**[ ABBA On Radio:
''Dancing Queen'']
Is this another one
of your shortcuts?
* You can dance *
- So what, you're not gonna talk?
- * You can jive *
- The whole way home?
- *Having the time of your life *
- * Ooh, see that girl *
- Come on, Vinny. Tell me something.
- What do you think?
- * Watch that scene
Digging the dancing queen *
Did that guy fuck you
better than me?
What are you talkin' about?
I'm embarrassed.
I don't wanna talk about that.
Fuckin' embarrassed about?
Did he fuck you better than me?
*Friday night
and the lights are low *
- I did it for you.
- You did it for me.
Oh, that's really nice. You did it
for me. Did you like it for me?
- **[ Singing Continues ]
- Did you fuckin'come for me, huh?
- Was that for me?
- That was the pills. That was the coke.
Don't blame the pills,
you fuckin' lesbian fuckin' whore.
Don't fuckin'
do that shit.
You were there too.
You're a fuckin' whore.
I can't be a whore,
'cause I'm a man, okay?
You're the fuckin' whore,
you stupid lesbian fuckin' whore!
And you're a faggot
fuckin' hairdresser.
- Get the fuck out of the car.
- You get the fuck out.
- I said get out!
- There's a psycho out there!
- There's a killer out there
killing people!
- I don't give a shit!
I hope he fuckin' kills you.
Get the fuck out of my car!
It is my car! I will not get out!
You get the fuck out!
I don't give a fuckin' shit!
Get the fuck out of the car!
- I will not get out of the car.
- Get out!
You get out of my car!
Get out of it right now!
- Fuckin' piece of shit.
- *Dancing queen *
-Fuckin' make me sick, you fuckin' slut.
-*Feel the beat *
* Of the tambourine
Oh,yeah *
- **[ Continues ]
- I am a slut? You're calling me a slut?
You lowlife piece of shit!
You fucked my cousin!
You didn't think
I knew about that.
I smelled her pussy juice
all over your fuckin' face!
You fuckin' sick bastard!
How dare you?
And all this time I'm thinking
there's something wrong with me.
You perverted sick fuck!
Come on, Dionna, please. I'm sorry.
Just get in the fuckin' car.
- No.
- * You're a teaser You turn them on *
Come on. Get in the car.
Come on. Let's go.
- *Leave them burning
and then you're gone
- Fuck you.
Come on. Get in the car.
Please, baby.
Baby? Don't you dare ''baby''
me! I'm gonna wait here.
I'm gonna wait here until somebody
comes along. You know what?
I gonna wait until some soul brother
comes along in his big black Cadillac.
And you know and I know that
he's got a big black dick too.
Don't talk like that.
Just get inside the car.
- Oh, fuck you.
- Please, please, don't
make me have to beg you.
- Come on. Don't make me
have to hurt you.
- Hurt me?
Don't you even
fuckin' lay a pinky on me!
I'll get him to kick your ass,
and then I'll fuck him!
You wanna watch, Vinny?
Will that turn you on, Vinny?
You linguini dick motherfucker!
You wanna watch?
You wanna watch while I suck
a big black dick in the back
of a big black Cadillac?
- Shut the fuck up!
- You shut the fuck up.
Get the fuck inside
the car now!
Hello!
Anybody out there?
- Shut the fuck up and get
inside the car now.
- Any black dick out there?
It better be big, 'cause
there's some free pussy here!
You know why I don't get hard anymore?
Because you don't turn me on anymore.
- You're a fuckin' pervert.
- Get inside the car. I'm sick of this.
I'm gonna take you to your
father's house, and then I don't
want to see you from then on.
All right. You wanna drive?
Drive me over there, you fuckin' dyke!
- *Dancing queen *
- Faggot fuckin' hairdresser!
I hope he kills you!
I hope you die here!
- Dionna! Dionna, come back here!
- *Digging the dancing queen *
Dionna, come back! Come on!
Don't fuckin' leave me here!
I hope he fuckin' kills you,
you fuckin' faggot pansy!
-You motherfuckin'cunt! Come back here!
-Fuck you!
- Dionna, come on! Come back!
- Stick it up your fuckin'ass!
Dionna, don't fuckin'
leave me here! Dionna!
- [ Buzzing ]
- [ Newscaster ]
Today is July 29th, 1 97 7--
- [ Panting ] Help me. Somebody help me.
- Death Day.
It was one year ago today that
Son of Sam shot and killed...
Donna Lauria
on Burke Avenue in the Bronx.
In his latest letter
toJimmy Breslin,
the killer taunted police
by saying he would be back
tonight to mark his anniversary.
-[ Phones Ringing ]
-Hundreds of off-duty police officers...
have volunteered to work
from sunset to sunrise.
Police are urging New York City
residents to stay indoors tonight...
as the full moon
almost guarantees...
the.44-Caliber Killer
will strike again.
- Honey, get away from the window.
- Please, be safe.
[ Dog Barking ]
Holy shit.
No fuckin' way!
I don't fuckin' believe
this shit!
Johnny boy,
you ain't goin' nowhere tonight.
- Happy anniversary.
- What the fuck did I do?
It's what you're not
gonna do.
What the fuck did I do?
Hey, man, I fought
for this fuckin' country!
Is this the thanks
you give me?
[Joey ]
Oh, Father Cadilli.
You mind telling us
where you're goin'?
- Do, do I know you boys?
- Oh, you sure do, Father.
It's been a long time. We're gonna
have to search you and your car.
It's for the good
of the neighborhood, Father.
You know, boys, you really
don't, don't want to do this.
Oh, I do.
- Father, give us a blessing, will you?
- What?
Just give us a blessing, huh?
Forgive them, Father,
for they know not what they do.
Come on, Father. Something original.
Come on. I've heard that before.
'' Let your heart keep
My commandments.
Do not let kindness
and truth leave you.''
All right.
Thank you, Father.
[ Horn Honking ]
Vincent, it's the middle
of the night.
What's the matter with you? Vinny, don't
make everybody know your business, okay?
Come on.
Tomorrow's another day.
- Come on. I--
- She'll be all right with me.
Just tell her
to come home with me.
Tomorrow's another day.
Listen to me.
- [ Flies Buzzing ]
- [ Son of Sam ]July 29th, 1 97 7.
This is a warning to all police
agencies in the Tri-State area.
For your information,
a Satanic cult has been instructed
by their high command, Satan,
to systematically kill
and slaughter...
young girls of good health
and clean blood.
- Executioners of the cult--
- [ Son of Sam ] Hi.
My name...
is Mr. Williams...
[ Panting ]
and...
I live...
in this hole.
I have several children
who I'm turning into killers.
- [ Dog Barking ]
- Wait till they grow up.
- [ Barking Continues ]
- No! Shut that dog up!
[ Grunting ]
[ Panting ]
How can this be?
- I thought I killed you, Mr. Black Dog.
- [ Barking ]
How did you get in here?
Leave me alone!
What do you want?
I want you to go out
and kill.
- Kill! Kill!
- [ Whimpering ]
- Kill!
- [ Weakly ] Okay, Mr. Black Dog.
I will kill. I will.
I'll do anything you say.
I'll do anything you say!
Yes, master. I will kill.
I will kill!
Yeah, if I can. If I can.
Listen, I got to go.
- All right.
- Gentlemen, good morning.
- [ Chattering ]
- [ Claps Hands ] Gentlemen!
Congratulations. Death Day came
and went without an incident.
Now I need you to stay sharp.
I want you to pay attention
to every detail. I don't care
how big or how small.
We're close.
He knows we're close.
This sick bastard,
he knows we're onto him.
- [Joey ] All right. We're close.
- Take the fuckin' thing.
- He knows we're out there.
- Everybody's checking out.
- Chickie, give me a fork.
- Hey, Vinny.
- Yeah?
- You're 86'd,
you and your freaky friend.
- Chickie, relax, man.
- What are you talking about?
What happened?
- Chickie, it's all right.
- You didn't tell them what happened?
That freaky bastard.
He scared my customers.
- They thought they were having
dinner with the Son of Sam.
- Who? Who?
Fuckin' Ritchie. I never seen nothin'
like it-- not even in 'Nam.
- He's fuckin' exaggeratin'.
- The kid was there lookin'
like Night of the Living Dead.
My customers, they get nervous
just from lookin' at him.
- So I go over to the table,
and I ask him very nice--
- Oh, come on!
It didn't happen like that at all.
What are you fuckin' makin' it up for?
- It didn't happen like that?
- No it didn't fuckin' happen like that.
He didn't jump up
from the table like madman?
He didn't break a glass over his head
and start licking the blood...
like fuckin' Bela Lugosi?
Didn't happen like that?
I never seen nothin' like it.
That kid scared the shit out
of everybody in the fuckin' place.
Didn't happen like--
You know what?
I'll serve you guys,
but not you, Vince.
- And not that fuckin' ghoul.
He's 86'd for life.
- Like I fuckin' care.
- Yeah, 86 me too.
- You're 86'd 'cause
it didn't happen like that.
You're so fuckin'crazy,
you know that? You're fucked up.
Hey, hey, Vinny.
What's the matter with you?
Ritchie does somethin' like that
and you don't tell us?
- Come on. What, are you shitting me?
- What do you mean?
You're not gonna take
that shit for serious, are you?
What does Chickie gotta lie for?
What's the matter with you?
- Is there anything else we should know?
- You hiding something?
-What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
-You didn't tell us about this.
- Anything we should know?
- What are you protecting Ritchie for?
- What else ain't you telling us?
-Joey, don't fuckin' touch me
like that, all right?
- What's the matter with you?
- I'm gonna leave you now
before something happens.
- What's wrong with you?
- Vinny, come on. Will you just--
- What's the matter with you?
- Vin!
- Hey, Vinny!
- He's protectin' him.
- This guy's out of line.
- He's protectin' Ritchie.
- That fuckin' Ritchie, man.
- He's prote-- He's got him brainwashed.
- I'm telling you.
He must have something on him.
- [ Knocking ]
Vinny, come back in here!
Vinny, come on in here!
What's up with this attitude
on this kid? What's up with him?
Hey, leave him alone.
It ain't him.
[ Clapping, Cheering ]
*Let's all chant *
- **[ Continues ]
- So where do you know Ritchie from?
Don't worry.
You don't have to be jealous.
I knew him
long before I ever met you.
[ Chuckles ]
I just didn't know he did porno.
- Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
- [ Knock At Door ]
You gonna play my Dead Boys? Don't make
me fuckin' dance to this disco shit.
Hello, Ritchie, Mr. Macho Man, tough
Bronx boy. What are you doing here?
Shut the fuck up!
You fuckin' say anything to
anyone, I'll fuckin' kill you!
- Midnite!
- Don't you touch Bobby!
Get your hands off him!
- I'll tell your fuckin' mother
know what you do, you bitch!
- Get your hands off him!
I'll fire your ass!
- I've done you every favor.
- [ Son of Sam ] M-U--
R-D...
E-R.
Murder.
[ Radio Announcer ]
Well, hi, everybody.
Welcome to another big ball game
with the Yankees and the Orioles
here at Yankee Stadium.
I know everybody's been
complaining about the heat,
and it has been terrible.
The heat wave has been brutal.
So we've got the perfect setting
for a ball game,
and it's gonna be a very exciting game--
as it usually is, as we've told you--
and especially with
Scotty McGregor and Ron Guidry.
Now, Guidry has more stuff than
McGregor, but Scotty McGregor...
gives the Yankees
a hard time when he's pitching,
and he's doing that again today.
And coming to the plate, ReggieJackson,
who's really been struggling as of late.
Reggie steps
into the batter's box,
taps the plate,
and he does look determined.
So Scotty McGregor steps off
the mound, gets back on.
Here's the pitch.
Strike one for number 44.
Now if you remember, Reggie
has had a lot of problems...
with Billy Martin
just about all year.
He's in Martin's doghouse
and Martin yells at him,
but Reggie doesn't even
bother to look at him.
They've had their problems,
but they get over it.
- [ Dog Barking ]
- So Reggie steps back into the box.
- Here's the pitch.
- [ Woman Screaming ]
A swing and a miss. Reggie swung
right on top of that slider.
- [ Screaming Continues ]
- Reggie looks for the sign from
third base coach Dick Howser...
then steps back into the box,
and number 44 is ready.
- Help! Help!
- McGregor into the windup.
Here's the pitch.
Reggie swings, hits a foul ball
back into the seats.
And as I look down,
looks like he split that bat...
and he's gotta walk back
and get himself another bat.
By the way, while he's doing
that,you know what's happening
in New York lately.
And Abe Beame, who used to be
my accounting teacher
in Richmond Hill High School,
the mayor of New York,
is really having his problems
with the-- trouble with the--
the Son of Sam's murders that are
happening-- up in the Bronx, by the way.
So I want all you people to be
a little careful when you go out
for a little spooning at night.
All right,
back to the ball game now.
And the Yankees have really been
in a slump lately.
Reggie needs one of those long balls to
get them out of it if he possibly can.
Reggie steps back into the box.
Got the new bat, don't forget.
And McGregor checks the sign
from home plate.
Here's the pitch.
Into the swing.
A long fly ball!
Holy cow! That is gone!
- [ Crowd Cheering ]
- Deep into the right field bleachers...
to tie the Orioles two apiece
in the bottom of the fifth inning.
ReggieJackson, who gets those
clutch home runs when you need 'em,
sure came through that time.
Holy cow! Unbelievable!
Let's go now to Eyewitness News
reporterJohn Jeffries,
who has been covering
this story throughout.
Son of Sam struck last night
in Brooklyn for the first time.
I'm here,John Jeffries, in the
predominantly black neighborhood
of Bedford-Stuyvesant...
in Brooklyn, New York,
to get a darker perspective.
- Ma'am.
- Yes?
I'm just hoping that
they get him quick. I don't care.
- Thank you.
It's terrible.
Bad for Brooklyn,
bad for New York, bad for America
and bad for the world.
- Thank you, sir.
- You're welcome.
- Your view.
- Let me tell you.
Son of Sam knows better
than to come into Bed-Stuy,
do or die, with that crap.
- 'Cause we don't care.
- [ Man ] 'Cause we don't play that.
He's not that crazy. I would love
to beat him down right now.
He would wish he was dead. I'd just love
to catch him right here in Bed-Stuy.
- Thank you.
- Exactly.
Hello. My name
is Cassandra Buchanan.
I live there
at 85 Crown Street,
and I am going to give you
your darker perspective.
The darker perspective is:
I thank God, I thank God,
I thank God...
that it is a white man
that kills all of those white people.
Because if it were
a black man...
who kills all of those
white people,
there would be
the biggest race riot...
right here
in New York City.
And I'd like
to say one thing.
I am surprised that you are
in the black community.
- I didn't think you liked black people.
- [ Residents Chuckling ]
- Uh-oh!
-John Jeffries here...
- [ Chattering ]
- in the Bedford-Stuyvesant
section of Brooklyn, New York.
- Thank you,John.
- [ Chattering ]
He's crazy.
He had this look in his eyes.
He said he was gonna kill me.
- You have to help me,Joey.
- All right. Don't worry, Bobby.
Nobody's gonna hurt you.
It's a good thing you came to me.
- Don't worry.
- Okay.
- Hey, Vinny, you seen Ritchie?
- Nah, not me.
He's the only guy on the list
we can't account for last night.
Where's this club,
C.B.G.B.'s?
Are you still
with that shit? Huh?
I don't know how you guys
follow this clown. It's like
the blind leading the blind.
Hey, who's blind?
They think for themselves, right?
- I got my own mind, Vinny.
- I got my head screwed on straight.
Yeah, ex-exactly.
Let me tell you something.
I know Ritchie like
if he was my brother, okay?
Even though you saw him outside
the disco on the night of the killing?
- Especially.
- We don't know where he was
during any of the killings.
Even though he fits the police profile?
He's got those weird religious beliefs.
That shit he pulled at the
diner, that don't mean nothin'?
You know him that well?
- Yeah, I know him that well.
- Tell him, Bobby.
Tell him about the fag strip joint.
Tell him who the star attraction was.
What the fuck are you talkin' about?
Fag joint? Come on.
Ritchie's a dancer
at Male World.
A friend of mine works there.
He also does porno flicks.
Did you know that
about your friend?
What else don't you know
about this pervert?
Doesn't make him the Son of Sam
just 'cause of that. Come on.
Killer, fag, pimp,
punk rocker.
Queer, pervert,
homo, degenerate.
Whatever the fuck it is.
I mean, come on.
Who wants something like that
around here anyway?
He's your friend, huh? Don't you
wanna know what's goin'on with him?
I do, and as soon as he calls me, I'm
gonna have a fuckin' talk with that guy.
You're gonna fuckin' talk to him? Vinny,
you ain't thinkin' straight.
There are people gettin' killed
in our neighborhood.
Now, are you
with us or not?
Hey, Vin,
it's not your fault.
You didn't know; nobody did. That
Ritchie's a crazy fuck, but he's smart.
He's eluded the police
and the FBI all this time.
- Listen to him, Vin.
- Okay, Vin, forget about us.
But what happens if Dionna's next?
How are you gonna live with that?
Knowing that you could've saved her life
if you acted like you had some balls.
Come on, Vin.
Okay, all-- okay.
Okay, all right.
I'll help you guys, okay?
It's not just you, Vinny.
He fooled the whole world.
Yeah, okay-- I said all right.Just
leave me alone, okay? Shut the fuck up.
Okay, okay. You're doin'the right
thing, Vin, okay?
Oh, yeah, sure I am. Yeah, I'm a great
friend. I'm a great fuckin' friend.
**[ Punk Rock ]
[ Indistinct Singing ]
[ Chattering ]
Wait a minute.
Is that Vin?
- Where?
- Right there.
That's why he didn't
make the gig.
The fuckin' idiot
got the dates mixed up.
Give me your shades.
Watch me fuck with him.
- What you gonna do?
- Watch this. Watch.
- [ Car Door Opens ]
- Hey, man.
- Hey, what the fuck?
- You're the guy! You've
seen our handiwork.
- Get the fuck away from me.
- The cult's gonna get you, brother!
- What the hell's the matter?
Get the fuck out of here!
- Hey, man!
Oh, shit, Ritchie.
You fuckin' asshole!
- [ Laughing ]
- You almost made me fuckin'
piss on myself, you fuck.
Jesus! What the fuck did you do
to your hair? That shit looks stupid.
What the fuck are you doin' here
anyway, man? The gig was last week.
[ Chattering Continues ]
Ritchie, I gotta talk to you, okay?
I gotta-- I gotta be serious with you.
We gotta be straight
to each other, okay?
Man to man,
square business, okay?
I'm serious. Fuckin' look at me
when I'm talkin' to you.
Are you in a cult?
Come-- Ritchie, answer me. Are you
in a fuckin' cult? Please tell me.
What kind of cult?
What do you-- What kind of answer
is that? I'm asking-- You know--
Let me tell you something,
funny boy.Joey T's in there.
He's got them all riled up,
and they're lookin' for you, okay?
They got this list that they've
been makin', and spyin' on people.
You're on the top of the fuckin'
list, okay? Now laugh at that shit.
Wait a minute.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. What list?
You can tell me, please.
Friend to friend.
I'm not gonna call the cops.
Are you the Son of Sam?
They think I'm the Son of Sam?
Really? You think I'm the Son of Sam?
It doesn't matter
what I think anymore.
It doesn't matter what I think, 'cause
they're in there lookin' for you.
Doesn't matter what you think?
Must've thought something, huh?
Brought 'em down here on me.
Nah, nah, I didn't do that.
I just ca--
I just wanted things to be cleared out
and straightened out.
- All right. So?
- I just told 'em to talk
to you, that's it.
Why don't you talk to me
like a man,
one on one, man to man,
like we always have?
- Aw, fuck.
- I wanted to.
But you've been acting
so fuckin' strange that I don't
even know what to do anymore.
- Me?
- Ritchie, look at yourself.
Look in the fuckin' mirror.
- Huh? Look at that hair.
What the fuck is that, huh?
- What, are you kidding me?
Since when does your hairstyle determine
whether or not you're a fuckin' killer?
- I'm not talkin' about
your fuckin' hairstyle.
- What are you talkin' about?
Normal people don't dress the way
you do. Normal people don't--
Normal people?
You think I'm the Son of Sam
and you bring a lynch mob
down here to string me up.
- Ritchie, I'm your--
I'm just tryin' to straighten--
- I thought you were my friend.
I'm tryin' to understand you, okay?
I am your fuckin' friend.
- You're not my friend.
- I made a fuckin' mistake.
What do you want me to say?
What am I supposed to do?
Bobby the Fairy tells me you're
a nude dancer at a fag club.
- What am I supposed
to do with that, huh?
- What?
Bobby the Fairy says
you're a fuckin' fag dancer.
Listen, Bobby the Fag
don't know shit, okay?
'Cause he's a homo,
now I'm one?
I don't know.
You tell me.
You tell me. Are you suckin' dick?
Is that what you're doin' there?
Hey, first you think I'm the fuckin'
Son of Sam. Now I'm a fuckin' homo.
I can't believe this.
[ Chuckles ]
You lost all faith in me?
I don't know you, Ritchie.
I don't know
who you fuckin' are.
I don't know you, man.
I don't know you, you fuck. Fuck you!
- [ Ruby ] Let's go, Ritchie!
- You're gonna need me, Ritchie.
- Don't do me any favors, asshole.
- Oh, you're gonna need me.
- Ruby, come here!
- He's a fuckin' prick.
- What happened?
-Ruby! Hey, Ruby, could you talk to him?
-What the fuck did you do?
- Let me talk to you for a minute.
- Ruby.
Go fuckin' home, Vinny!
You're always startin' fuckin' trouble.
- Motherfucker.
- I'll tell you somethin'.
Those are the freakiest fuckin' people
I've ever seen in my fuckin' life.
- Fuckin' filthy.
- I could take fuckin' ten showers,
I'd still feel
fuckin' dirty.
We didn't fuckin'
see him, though,Joe.
- Get outta the way. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- [ Grunts ]
You fuckin' watch where you're goin',
you fuckin' freak.
Fuck you, Guido!
- What'd you say?
- Fuck you, Guido!
- Guido.
- All right, man,
you're drunk, all right?
So we're gonna give you one more chance.
Who's your favorite baseball team?
Boston Red Sox.
- [ Grunts ]
- Motherfucker.
Here he comes,Joe!
- Yeah! Yeah!
- [ Grunting ]
- Come here, you son of a bitch!
- [ Grunts ]
- Come here!
- [ Groaning ]
Boston Red Sox!
Go back to Fenway,
you Beantown cocksucker!
- Come on, let's go home.
- I ruined my fuckin' pants!
[ Luigi ]
Who does this look like?
- It looks like a young Dean Martin.
- Dean Martin.
This looks like that guy
on the Grand Concourse, Matty.
- Come on. You're not serious.
- Yeah, I'm serious.
- Reno!
- Yo.
That Matty
on the Grand Concourse.
- Bring him here. I wanna talk to him.
- I'm on my way.
[ Neighbors Chattering ]
Nah, it doesn't look like him.
It doesn't really look like him at all.
What do you mean, it doesn't
really look like him?
Hey, Vin, if you can't see
what's happening, then you're
as brainwashed as Ruby is.
- What do you mean, I'm brainwashed?
- Look what he's doin' to her.
- [ Moaning ]
- He's fuckin'Ruby...
while people are standin'
around and fuckin'filming it.
I mean, would you
do that to Dionna?
Huh? Would you fuck
your wife in a porn film?
- Your wife, not mine.
- I mean, Ruby's goin' along with it,
but you don't think he's got
some kind of spell over her?
He's turnin' her
into a fuckin' porn star.
Come here.
Now you tell me...
if that doesn't
look like Ritchie.
- Holy shit! Let me see that.
- Son of Sam.
- Wake up, Vinny.
- Oh, shit!
[ Chattering ]
Hey, Vinny,
where the hell you been?
- Traffic was crazy. I'm sorry, baby.
- You don't call.
You're three hours late.
What, now you show up?
- I don't know what happened.
Traffic was terrible.
- Hey, Vinny.
- Come on, sexy. Let's go.
- No, Dee, stay right where you are.
- No, come on, let her go.
I gotta cut her hair.
- Yeah, you'll cut her hair.
- Vinny?
- Dee, come over here.
I gotta cut your hair.
- Stay where you are.
He'll be with you in a minute.
- I'm sorry I'm late.
-Just crazy things goin' on.
Move, Gloria.
- I'm lookin' like a person--
- What are you shovin' me for?
What the hell's the matter?
- Who's next?
- Vinny, pull yourself together.
-Johnny, you see the Yankees
play last night, huh?
- What about ReggieJackson?
He's a god, huh?
- Vinny, get in the bathroom.
- Nah, Thurman Munson's the one.
- Shave and take some Listerine.
- I always loved this fat fuck.
- I want you to pull yourself together.
You take some Listerine. You pull
yourself together for these customers.
- This is a business here.
You respect it.
- [ Panting ]
- I'm going through
a real tough time right now.
- Yes, all right.
- I was just hoping that you
would help me out right now.
- Okay.
Now, you go pull yourself
together, and then we'll deal
with the customers, all right?
-Dee, come over here. I'm ready for you.
-Now, Vinny?
Dee, he'll be with you in a minute.
Did you hear a word I just said?
-I don't feel like--
-I said pull yourself the fuck together.
- And then you'll come--
- You know, Gloria, if it wasn't for me,
you wouldn't have this
great place, would you?
Oh, what is that
supposed to mean?
'Cause I brought all these customers.
Where were you before?
- You came here because of me,
didn't you?
- Excuse us. I'm very sorry.
Don't fuckin' lie. If it wasn't for
fuckin' me, none of you would be here.
This place was a piece of shit
before I fuckin' came here!
Hey, watch
your fuckin' mouth!
- This is a business--
- Here, Gloria.
Here, Gloria. Take that.
Fuck you and fuck this place!
Get the fuck out of here!
Get out! Get out of my shop!
Fuckin' shit place! Fuck you and fuck
your customers, you piece of shit!
- Fuck me, Vinny? I'm gonna fuck you!
- Fuckin' keys.
- Come on.
- [ Customers Chattering ]
Forgot to lock the door,
you stupid bitch.
Just talk
to yourselves, okay?
Who took my fuckin' keys?
There they are.
My glasses.
You son of a bitches.
- [ Clattering ]
- [ Man ] He's losin'it.
[ Vinny ]
Hey, what the fuck you doin'?
What are you doin', baby?
Oh, come on.
You're not gonna fuckin'
leave me. Come on, baby.
Come on. I'm sorry
about Gloria, okay?
I'm fuckin' so sorry about that shit.
It wasn't even fuckin' worth it.
All this time
I kept my eyes closed,
and I even made myself
think that maybe it just happened once.
- And then I gotta hear it from Gloria?
- Dionna, I quit.
I quit the fuckin' shop. The whole
thing is over. This is a new Vinny.
-Do you understand what I'm tellin'you?
-*Don't leave me this way *
How many other women did you fuck
at the salon besides Gloria?
- **[ Continues ]
- Oh, baby, baby, look. I, I-- This--
I'm never gonna cheat again. I swear
to God. I'm gonna see a fuckin' priest.
I'm gonna fuckin' see a psychiatrist.
I'm gonna get the fuckin' help.
- 'Cause I know I'm sick, baby.
I know I'm fuckin' sick.
- How many!
Was one of them
named Sheri?
Oh, come on. I made that up for you,
baby. I made that up for you.
I'm not gonna-- There was no fuckin'
Sheri. Don't fuckin' leave me now.
Come on. Let's work this shit out.
You and I can make this shit happen.
- Come on. What the fuck?
- What about Plato's Retreat?
*My heart is full of love
and desire for you *
- Okay, you're right about that.
You're right about that.
- **[ Continues ]
I'm sorry what I made
you do there, okay?
Oh, you're sorry about what you
made me do. You're sorry what I did.
You're not sorry
what you did to me.
You're not sorry that I trusted you,
and you used me.
I am sorry.
But, baby, I'm not me, okay?
I'm fuckin'going through a lot
of shit right now, all right?
- He's fuckin'-- He's in a cult.
- *Don't you leave me this way *
Ritchie's in a cult, okay? And he's got
me coming or going. He's brainwashed me.
I don't even know who the fuck
I am lately, okay?
So the shit I'm doing right now is not
even me. I'm not responsible for it.
- Do you see what I'm saying?
- Oh, come on!
Come on! You're blaming Ritchie
for what you're doing?
- Come on!
- Come on, Di-- You know what?
They fuckin' think he's the fuckin'
killer, he's the Son of Sam.
- That's what I gotta fuckin'
deal with every day.
- Vinny, stop it!
What does that have to do
with you fucking other women?
Come on!
I am not stupid!
I never said you were stupid.
I'm telling you that I love you.
You can't fuckin'leave me over this
shit. We're fuckin'husband and wife.
Do you hear what I'm sayin'?
We had two fuckin' great years.
You're not gonna throw that out
for this piece of shit!
- What fuckin' big mouth Gloria
says to you!
- Wanna see?
- I'm gonna throw it all out.
I'm gonna throw it all out.
- Oh, Dionna, do--
All of it goes out the window,
just like you threw it out...
every time you stuck your
dick into some other woman!
Just throw every fuckin' thing out!
I don't give a shit!
- Fuck you!
- * 'Cause only your good lovin'*
- * Can set me free *
- Baby, look what I got for you.
- **[ Continues ]
- Look what I got. Fuckin' flowers.
That's what I came
here with, okay?
I came with fuckin' flowers, 'cause I
know I've been fuckin' up all this time.
- [ Sobbing ]
- And I've made some bad calls,
and I'm a bad fuckin' husband.
And I admit it. And I know you can't
get away with shit in life anymore.
You know, God sees everything,
plain and simple,
and I just want you
to give me another chance.
- No.
- Please, baby, give me another chance.
- I can't live without you. Please?
- You can't bring God into this.
- You can't do that anymore.
- I love you, baby.
- Baby, listen. Listen.
- I love you so fuckin' much.
- And if you leave me,
I'm fuckin' gonna die.
- You have to listen to me.
[ Sobbing ]
Okay? See...
I thought that what we had
was special together.
Oh, baby, it is special. Let me
make love to you, and I'll show you.
-Just you and me.Just you and me.
- It is just you and me.
- It wasn't. It was everybody.
- Oh, baby, it wasn't.
- It was everybody.
- I didn't care for those
fuckin' bitches.
- I love you!
- It was everybody,
and everybody else knew but me.
- And you're a liar.
- Baby, I'm so fuckin' sorry.
I fuckin' hate myself, baby.
You don't fuckin' think
I hate my fuckin' self? Come on, baby.
Don't fuckin' leave me.
Don't do this shit to me.
Look, I got nothin' in this life.
All I got is you.
And if you walk out that door,
I'm gonna fuckin'jump out
that window and kill myself.
'Cause I ain't
got nothin', baby.
You're everything in my fuckin' life,
and I ain't got shit.
I ain't got friends.
I ain't got nothin', baby.
I suck at everything I do.
You're the only fuckin' thing I have,
and I can't live without you.
Please, baby. Oh, God,
I love you so fuckin' much.
[ Sobbing ]
- Baby?
- Don't leave me. Don't leave me.
- I'm sorry, baby, but--
- I love you.
Baby, I'm sorry, but I just don't
believe you anymore.
I'm sorry.
If you fuckin' leave here now,
don't expect to come back.
- You can't fuckin'
leave me and come back.
- Vinny, let me go.
- * Oh, baby *
- I gotta go, Vinny.
-*Don't talk about leavin'me *
- Come on.
*Don't leave me this way *
*Don't leave me
this way, no *
*Don't leave me this way *
- *Don't leave me this way, baby
Don't leave me *
- Fuck this shit.
- What are you doin'?
- What am I doin'?
- Stop, stop, stop.
- No, I'm not gonna stop.
- What are you doin'?
- [ Opening Zipper]
- Ruby.
- No.
- [ Sighs ] You better stop.
- Take this off.
Stop.
- Ruby.
- Touch me.
- Want me to touch you?
- Touch me!
[ Snorting ]
[ Chattering, Yelling ]
-Joey, Ritchie's home.
-Joey!Joe!
- The sick fuck is back.
- He's back?
- This fuckin' guy!
The fuckin' balls on him,Joe!
- All right.
- Lower your voice.
- He's tryin' to disguise himself.
His hair?
He's got a fuckin' blond mohawk.
Now, him and Ruby are probably
tryin' to make a fast getaway.
-Joey, you think they're
both in cahoots?
- All right, all right.
Let's all calm the fuck down, okay?
We gotta do this right.
- We're all excited,Joey.
- All right, all right. Shhh.
We need Vinny.
[Joey ]
Yo, Vinny!
Vinny! Vinny!
- Vinny!
Vinny, vene ca!
Fuckin' shit.
Fuckin' stupid.
[ Moaning ]
- [ Pounding On Door]
- Vinny? Vinny, come on.
Vinny, open the door!
Yeah, yeah, okay.
Shhh!
- [ Pounding Continues ]
- All right!
-[ Bobby ] Open the door!
- Dionna's sleepin' right now.
- Can you come back later?
- Take the fuckin' chain
off the door. Come on.
- Come on, Dionna's sleeping.
- Take the chain off the door.
-Hey, man, I'm opening the fuckin' door.
-Hey, listen to me!
Listen to me.
Ritchie's the Son of Sam.
Well, if Ritchie's the Son of Sam, why
don't we just fuckin' call the cops?
- Fuck the cops!
- Fuck the cops? I'm calling.
- I don't give a fuckin' shit.
- What the fuck are you doin'?
- I'm callin' the cops,
you fuckin' bastard!
- Give me that fuckin'--
What the fuck is the matter with you,
huh? What the fuck is wrong with you?
Ah, you're the big tough guy
around here, aren't ya? 'Cause
you got your lackeys with ya.
- Vinny, what is the matter
with your fuckin' head?
- But if we went one on one--
-[ Grunts, Groaning ]
-[ Brian ] Everybody calm the fuck down!
[ Bobby ] Listen to him, Vinny.
Just listen toJoey T.
- Don't hurt him!
- [ Brian ] Easy, man. Come on.
Get in that fuckin' chair.
I didn't come here--
- You fuckin' hit me,Joey.
- I didn't come here to fight
with you, Vinny, okay?
- Why'd you fuckin' hit me?
- We need your help.
Ritchie's at home, okay?
We want you to help us. We want you to
go there and get him out of the house.
Oh, yeah. And then what? Then we're
gonna sit around and then play cards?
What the fuck are you talkin' about?
We take him to Luigi, okay?
- No rough stuff.
- I swear on my mother, Vin.
- On a stack of Bibles.
- I don't fuckin' believe
you guys. Yeah, right.
You know somethin'?
We're not the fuckin' black
cloud of this neighborhood!
We didn't fuck up your marriage
with Dionna! It wasn't us, it was you!
- Don't fuck with us now.
- What are you fuckin' talking about?
What am I talkin' about?
Your wife's got a big mouth.
- You fucked up with Dionna!
Don't fuck up with us!
- [ All Yelling ]
- I'm okay.
- I'm tellin' the fuckin' truth,Joey!
- [ Yelling Continues ]
- You better not talk
about my wife again!
- Don't you ever fuck with me,
you bastard!
- Come on, you fuck!
-[ Anthony ] Sit down!
- Shut up now!
- Wait! Tell him you're sorry!
-Joe, I'm just tryin'--
- Tell him you're fuckin' sorry!
- All right, all right!
Get the fuck outta here. Come here.
Now you listen to me, okay? All right?
Don't tell us that fuckin' Dionna's
in the back there sleepin', all right?
'Cause news travels fast in this fuckin'
neighborhood. You understand me? Okay?
Now, you're puttin'
that shit up your nose,
you're fuckin' taking quaaludes
like they're goin' out of style,
you're drinkin' like a fish.
You don't know what's up or down!
You understand me, Vinny?
- Yeah.
- Now, you're gonna put
your fuckin' shirt on...
and you're gonna come over
and help us, or so God,
so fuckin' help me God,
I will fuck you where you breathe!
Okay?
Let's go, Vinny.
- Let's go! Let's go!
- I'm fuckin' going.
He treats him like a fuckin'
pussy all the time.
I say one fuckin' thing,
he strangles me.
Police now have in custody
the man they believe is the
.44-Caliber Killer, Son of Sam.
He was arrested outside his home
at 35 Pine Street in Yonkers.
And New York City
can now finally rest.
- Thank God.
- I thought he would've
lived in Brooklyn.
[ TVAnnouncer ]
Let's go live now toJohnJeffries.
[ Dog Barks ]
Police! Don't move!
Get against the car!
Give me your hands.
One at a time.
- Give me your right hand.
Now! Right now!
- [ Tires Screeching ]
Give me your other hand.
One at a time. Slowly.
Inspector Dowd,
you finally got me.
And now that I've got you,
who is it that I've got?
- You know.
- No, I don't know. You tell me.
- I'm Sam.
- You're Sam. Sam who?
Sam. Dave Berkowitz.
- [ Angry Shouting ]
- A large crowd has gathered here...
awaiting the arrival
of Son of Sam suspect David Berkowitz.
The police have put up
barricades...
to protect the alleged
.44-Caliber killer...
from a potential lynch mob.
It's a great outpouring
of relief,
rage and vengeance.
Kill him! Kill him!
**[ The Who:
''Won't Get Fooled Again'']
Ladies and gentlemen,
here he comes.
-* We'll be fighting in the streets *
- Son of Sam!
-* With our children at our feet *
-*And the morals that they worship *
- Son of Sam,
- * Will be gone *
- ladies and gentlemen!
-*And the men who spurred us on *
- We don't know which car he's in.
-*Sit in judgement of all wrong *
- The crowd is going crazy.
- [ Angry Shouting ]
- It's pure pandemonium,
- [ Siren Wails ]
- hysteria, chaos.
- They're slowing down.
- *I'll tip my hat *
- Ed, do we see him?
- * To a new constitution *
- * Take a bow *
- Yes!
- *For the new revolution *
- There he is, ladies and gentlemen!
*Smile and grin
at the change all around *
- David Berkowitz!
- *Pick up my guitar and play *
- It's David Berkowitz! There he is!
- *Just like yesterday *
- The alleged.44-Caliber Killer.
- * Then I'll get on my knees and pray *
- [ Vinny Knocking ] Ritchie!
- Who is it?
- He has a crazed look on his face.
- * We don't get fooled again *
[ Shouting Continues ]
Ritchie, it's me, Vinny.
Open up. Come on, open up.
What the fuck
does he want?
* The change it had to come *
* We knew it all along *
**[ Continues ]
- What do you want?
- How ya doin'? [ Laughs ]
* The world
looks just the same *
I could never get used to that hair.
You know, it's ridiculous.
- Come on. Cut to the chase.
- Hey, Ruby.
- Uh-huh.
- How's it going?
- It's going fine.
- You mind if I borrow him
for a minute? Huh?
- Yep. Yep.
- [ Shouting Continues ]
- *I'll tip my hat
to the new constitution *
- That's him! Right there!
-* Take a bow for the new revolution *
- Get him! You get him!
- *Smile and grin
at the change all around *
- You get him!
- *Pick up my guitar and play *
- Sic him, Harvey! Kill him! Kill him!
- *Just like yesterday *
- I gotta talk to you.
- About what?
- Dionna.
-* Then I'll get on my knees and pray *
- She left me.
She's gonna divorce me.
It's all over.
- * We don't get fooled again *
- No.
- Oh, yeah.
- All right, come in, man. Come inside.
I don't want to go inside. I don't want
her to hear me. Come on. Come over here.
Come on. Let's-- Talk to me over here.
Please. Come on.
All right.
I'll be right back.
[ Shouting Continues,
Camera Shutters Clicking ]
Oh, God, Ritchie. I had this big fight
with Gloria, right?
So she calls Dionna, and she
tells her about all the women
I've been with, right?
And Dionna flips out, and she wants
to leave me. She wants to divorce me...
because I took her to Plato's Retreat,
and we had two-on-one's and everything.
I don't know what to tell you.
I mean, we're leaving tonight,
so maybe you should too.
- You should get outta here.
- That's what I'm doin'. I'm packing.
Yeah, you know something.
Me and her were like that.
- Run, Ritchie.
- What?
-I'm sorry about everything. Please run.
-What are you talkin' about?
- Come on, come on!
- Run. Get the fuck out!
- Now!
- Get that son of a bitch!
Stay right there, Ritchie!
Stay right there, cocksucker!
- Vinny.
- Luigi wants to see you.
- Come on!
- You set me up, you motherfucker!
I told you to fuckin' run.
You don't ever listen.
- Come on! What do you got?
- Stay the fuck away from me!
[ All Shouting ]
- Vinny! What the fuck are you doing?
- Come on, Ritchie!
- Get the fuck off my arm!
- Fuck you guys!
- What are they doing?
- [ Grunts, Groaning ] Fucker!
- [ Shouting Continues ]
- Get off me!
Ritchie, eat this!
- Come on! Let go of me!
- Bitch!
[ Grunts ]
[ Cheering ]
- [ Ruby ] Get off me!
- You cocksucker!
Come on, you piece of shit!
You don't look so tough now!
- Come on!
- You're gonna eat that guitar now!
- Break 'em! Come on, break 'em up!
- No! Ritchie!
- You're comin' with us.
- Get off of me!
You killin', cocksuckin', fuckin'
poison the fuckin' neighborhood.
- Come with us!
- We're gonna see Luigi right now.
Come on, listen up. You ain't gettin'
out of fuckin' this one this time.
- No, no!
- [ Ruby ] Leave him alone!
[Joey ]
All right, guys, guys. Let's go.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Shit!
You get the fuck away from him!
Get away from him!
What the fuck is goin' on here?
What the fuck is goin' on? Jesus Christ!
We caught the Son of Sam! We're takin'
him to Luigi! Don't fuck with us!
He ain't the fuckin' Son of Sam.
They caught the killer.
It's all over the news.
- They got him in Yonkers,
you stupid fuckin' idiot!
- You're fuckin' lying!
Oh, yeah? Tell me my Luger's full
of shit. Fuck with this, hero. Come on!
- My Luger says they
caught him, all right?
- All right.
One of you, go and call an ambulance!
Right now, or I start shooting.
- What happened?
- You, you, go and get a blanket.
It's on the couch.
Talk to me!
What happened?
- Oh, my God!
- Get the blanket!
[ Sobbing ]
Oh, my God, Ritchie!
Brian, talk to me!
Oh, my God! Baby.
-* There's nothing in the street *
-Just get outta here!
- Get away!
- *Looks any different to me *
-[ Ritchie ] Mommy!
- *And the slogans are replaced *
*By and by *
- [ Whimpering ]
- Ritchie! Lay still, please!
[ Eddie ]
Get out of here.Just leave him here.
You fuckin' traitor!
What the fuck are you doin'?
I'm sorry.
- Did you call that ambulance?
- Yeah, it's, it's coming.
- It's what?
- It's coming. It's coming right now.
It better be.
- [ Dog Barking ]
- Of all the things,
a parking ticket
did Son of Sam in.
On July 31 , 1 977,
he shot his last two victims.
An eyewitness noticed a parking ticket
under his windshield as he sped away.
Of the four tickets issued in that area,
one bore the name of David Berkowitz,
- [ Frank Sinatra ]
*Start spreading the news *
- a resident of Yonkers, New York.
At first, Berkowitz
claimed insanity.
- *I'm leaving today *
- saying a 2,000-year-old dog
named Harvey told him to do it.
- *I want to be *
- Eventually he pled guilty.
-*Apart of it *
- That sick fuck is serving a sentence...
- *New York, New York *
- of six consecutive terms
of 25 years to life.
- * These vagabond shoes *
- [ Announcer ]
The Yankees win their 2 1 st World Series.
- *Are longing to stray *
- [Jimmy Breslin ]
Of course the New York Yankees...
won the World Series
against the L.A. Dodgers,
- **[ Continues ]
- led by ReggieJackson's dramatic
three consecutive home runs...
in the sixth
and deciding game.
[ Announcer ]
ReggieJackson's last at bat!
Fulfillment
is written on his face.
- [ Crowd Cheering ]
- Out comes Reggie!
[Jimmy Breslin ]
Elvis Presley died.
Thirty-seven hundred were
arrested during the blackout,
with damage going
into the hundreds of millions.
To no one's surprise,
most of the destruction...
took place in Brooklyn,
Harlem and the South Bronx.
'7 7 was also one of the hottest summers
in memory in New York City.
New York, the city
that I love and hate equally.
There are 8,000,000 stories
in the Naked City,
and this was one of them.
[ Frank Sinatra ]
*If I can make it there *
*I'll make it anywhere *
*It's up to you *
*New York, New York *
*I want to wake up *
*In a city
that never sleeps *
*And find I'm ''A ''number one *
* Top of the list *
*King of the hill *
* ''A ''number one *
* These little town blues *
*Are melting away *
*I'm gonna make
a brand-new start of it *
*In old New York *
*And *
*If I can make it there *
*I'm gonna make it anywhere *
*It's up to you *
*New York *