Hello.
- Hi.
Have a seat.
Did you find us all right?
- Yes.
Everything okay?
Coffee?
- Yes, please.
Should I pour you a cup?
How about some cognac?
- No, thank you.
Makes it easier to talk.
Help yourself.
So you're applying for a job
as a window dresser? - Yes.
I was trained at Karstadt.
- I see.
What did you do at Karstadt?
- I decorated display windows.
According to the seasons:
Easter, Christmas...
In all the departments?
- Yes.
Sports and children's fashion...
How would you approach your job
today?
I'm a team-player.
- I see.
What does that mean to you?
I always got along well
with my colleagues.
Being a team player doesn't mean
everybody's nice to each other.
It means you can cope with conflicts
and find solutions...
I know how to do that.
Sorry I think...
Okay, let's stop here.
Good, Herr Kannenberg.
- Job interviews
were part of my job.
- What did you notice?
Herr Jansen?
I didn't think her body language
was quite right.
What do you mean?
- She's very nervous.
She's on the edge of her chair,
as if she wants to slide down
And just disappear.
- What do the others think?
She was quite unsure of herself.
You have to sell yourself
when you apply for a job.
When he asked, "Why are you here",
she said, "I'm a team-player".
She flunked as a team player.
She doesn't even know what it means.
SUMMER IN BERLIN
Nothing beats
a good old cup of coffee.
That's tea, Oskar!
My mother just stopped by.
She stood next to the stove.
We talked about lots of stuff.
Your mother died ages ago.
I wonder which one of us is nuts.
Me 'cause I see my mother?
Or you 'cause you don't see her?
See you tomorrow, Oskar. How could
your mother stop by anyway?
You can shut the windows
and doors tightly...
...radio gets in.
Use the whole chair.
So you're not squirming about.
Go ahead and cross your legs.
You have to when you wear
such a short skirt.
It's better.
You nicely sidestepped
the cognac trap.
To all of you: never accept any.
It's a popular trick.
After writing 40 to 80 applications
you've finally got a job interview.
It'd be a shame to spoil it.
It begins even before you enter.
You could run into anyone
in the hall or elevator.
One false move and you're done for.
It's quite a rude awakening.
Your hands...
Where should you put them?
Don't drink any coffee
if your hands are shaking.
Maintain eye contact.
Frau Engel kept looking away.
It shows how insecure you are.
Look at the interviewer.
It makes you more secure
and believable.
Okay?
- Yes.
You're a good girl.
You have good skin.
I'm Nicole Pawelski,
but they call me Nike.
Okay, then get me the accordion.
Why doesn't Ilona come any more?
- She quit.
Ilona always read to me.
You can make the bed now.
Excuse me.
Why does this cost 120 euros?
- "Climacool 3" is a top-level shoe,
with cushions in front and in back.
The sole is uniformly
soft and springy.
It deadens the impact
during running.
Climacool technology,
the best running shoe
idea in 20 years.
Out goes the bad air,
in comes the good.
That makes it expensive,
but kids love it.
So Mom's just got
to bear it, right?
Hi there. It's us again.
I've heard you like my girlfriend?
- Are you nuts?
She's quite good-looking.
Slender and...
What?
No, don't need any medicine.
Come on,
tell us your first name.
He hung up.
Know what? He'll be dreaming of you.
- Or of you. - Or of us.
I can only use a man
who gets along with Max.
I just need to find one
who gets along with me.
Max wants new sneakers,
the most expensive ones.
The problem is, we're out of cola.
We wanted to go swimming, didn't we?
It's so nice here with you, Nike.
We're so above it all.
Can you imagine
living with someone forever?
I don't believe in it.
I read that the brain produces
a sexual transmitter. It's a fact.
And after a while it's gone.
All at once.
The right ones are usually
the wrong ones. Know what I mean?
I'm actually quite normal.
It's not even getting dark tonight.
Nah - it's getting light already.
Morning.
Good morning, Mom!
Oh, Max!
Nike and I lost track of time
chatting on the balcony.
Sorry.
- It's okay.
That's sweet of you.
Bye, Mom.
Bye.
Hello, Herr Neumann. It's me.
Okay, Herr Neumann. Here we go.
Let's turn around.
Okay... great.
I have to go to school.
Oh no. Shit!
Katrin!
Shit! For Chrissake!
Great!
Hey, what's wrong with you?
You nuts or what?
You can't sleep-walk on the street
You gotta first look left, then right.
You were speeding.
It's a 30-km zone.
Hey, can you brake normal or not?!
- Who are you?
I slammed into you...
- You ran into me,
so it's your fault. - Not if you drive
like a Grand Prix driver in puberty!
I always stop for women...
- First you drive like a bat outta hell,
then slam on the brakes!
- Not in that tone.
What tone?
You just totaled my car! - Hey!
Hey! Hey!
Did you see me or not?
Sure, how could I miss you?!
How big's my rig gotta be? - You jammed
on the brakes like an idiot!
Should I back up?
- You totaled my car! - Fuck off, man!
Kiss my ass, idiot!
Can we go? - No! You've got to wait
for the cops! You're my witnesses!
I ran into him from behind.
- Hey pal, you're too loud.
Don't gimme that bullshit!
Cut the dumb nails if you can't manage.
- I'm almost done.
Tina, the check!
Oh no, look who's coming.
It wasn't his fault.
Nobody blamed him.
You think he's good-looking?
I'm just observing him.
11.80, please.
Make it 12.
- Thanks. Have a nice day. - You, too.
Shall we go?
- I'm going to the restroom.
I wanted to thank you
for braking so hard.
Nothing happened.
- No.
But something could've happened.
Something can always happen.
Weren't we leaving?
The coffee's gone!
- Nobody could've stolen it.
It can't run away by itself.
You gotta flush the toilet!
Does anyone visit this place
besides you?
During the war they shot a man
for stealing a jerry can of gasoline.
I saw it myself.
- I know.
Were you there, too?
- No, you told me about it.
Right.
How could you have been there?
It was cold, and you marched
into the dunes to shoot him.
But you didn't aim at him.
- But
the captain cried out,
"The German sword
is still sharp
in the fifth year of war!"
You have to sign here.
What am I signing?
- That I was here.
Frau Engel.
- Hello. - Hi.
Have a seat.
Would you like some coffee?
- Thanks, yes.
Could you hold this, please?
Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Cream?
- Yes. Thank you.
Would you like a piece of cheesecake?
No, thank you. - You don't mind?
- Please, enjoy. - Thanks.
So you're forty?
- Thirty-nine and a half.
You've worked in fashion before?
- Yes.
Could you work outside Berlin
for days at a time? - Basically, yes.
Why are you staring at me?
Do I scare you? - No.
I'm looking forward to working for you.
- You know what's involved, right?
Dressing the dummies,
painting their lips,
gluing on eyelashes,
putting on wigs, creating certain types,
so customers actually see themselves.
Can you picture doing all that?
- Yes.
Although at the moment
they prefer women without heads.
Fur coats - almost no face.
Expensive clothes - almost no face.
Puts a dent in sales,
but it won't last long. Normal women
want to see themselves reflected.
They want to know
if an outfit looks good on them.
I mean,
how would you like to look?
I could give you...
the job now, but I have a stack
of applications I want to look at.
I'll let you know, okay?
Hi, Charly.
Hey.
I knew you'd come this way.
I thought I'd jog with you.
I don't mind.
How far are we running?
Down this street,
then right on Sonnenburger,
across the tracks, then left
on Dänisch. At the Chinese restaurant,
we cross the bridge and take
Schwedter to Gleim and then back again.
We can talk on the way.
"Can two young people
who have truly fallen in love
ever experience a more beautiful
morning... than the one
that follows
their confession of love?"
You can't charge me
for time you spend reading.
I put two oranges in the fridge...
...and the dishes in the cupboard.
- I could listen to it over and over.
We pay lots of money
for your care, Mama.
Where's the magnifying glass
I got for you?
Now you can read by yourself.
"The girl wraps her two soft arms
around his neck,
pulling him, with an indescribable...
feeling of bliss, toward her body."
You see? It works.
Mom, that's no reason to despair.
You're together,
you can help each other.
I'm sure the neighbors
will help, too.
Yes, we're healthy.
Just a minute..., Max!
Just a second... Come here.
It's Grandma.
Hi, Grandma. I'm fine. How are you?
Yes, I will. No, I won't.
I won't forget. Okay, bye, Grandma.
Bye!
I never understand Grandma's dialect.
Why the afternoon shower?
What about those sneakers?
Do you know
how expensive they are?
How about other shoes?
- I don't want any others!
Don't tell me you can't run
in any other shoes.
This is the painter.
I just painted what I saw.
The buildings were so "East German."
To me it's just a building.
Sure, why shouldn't there be
a building in the picture?
Doesn't matter what's in the picture,
it's the painter's spirit that counts.
I painted it a long time ago.
Did you study? - I'm a window dresser.
I just paint for fun.
You can leave it here.
I'll hang it on the wall.
How much are you asking?
I asked some people...
- 120.
You'll never get that much.
You don't want the painting.
You wanna screw my girlfriend.
"You wanna screw my girlfriend!"
Is it past midnight yet?
It's my ex-husband's birthday.
Can I use your phone?
"Sorry, nobody's in, and our little cat
can't talk, so leave a message."
Is that his new chick?
Hello, here's another little cat.
I wanted to wish you a happy birthday.
Have a nice day.
I hope you catch every new disease.
All the best from me, too.
"Again she feels a man's hands
grab her arms,
and a voice close to her asks,
'Does my lover not yet know
she's truly a woman? '
Two pairs of lips carry on
a silent but intense conversation."
That's how it was with me.
Similar to that.
Read it again!
- There, the kitchen's done.
But I'm still here.
Which leg did Dad lose?
His left leg, Mama.
His right leg!
And he was a 400-meter runner.
She likes to argue,
and I'm her only daughter!
And I'm her only mother!
How do I get my inheritance
if you die before me?
I don't want
that lovely old clock to sit
in the cellar any longer!
- It was his left leg!
Are the blisters big or small?
- They look terrible.
But only on my left foot.
My sneaker's to blame. - Take it off.
Well...
You do sports?
- I run.
I have something brand new...
a special plaster for blisters.
But you should wear other shoes
for a while. Do you have sandals?
Of course. But he won't
wear them. - Yes...
that'll be 4.95.
Thanks!
- Here you are.
Is it permitted
to sit here?
Please do.
I've gotta piss.
So we meet again.
How's that?
You nearly slammed into my girlfriend.
- Oh..., her.
I think I'll have another glass.
Could I treat you to one?
Why not?
- Red wine?
Okay with me.
- I'll stick to beer.
There!
This round's on the house.
- That's real sweet of you, Tina.
You stop by so seldom.
Oh, sorry!
Listen, Tina Bambina.
- Don't call me Tina Bambina!
When I'm sitting with someone
don't haul over any free rounds.
I don't want to take him away from you.
- Then two wines and a beer.
So...
If you feel like another drink
you're welcome to join me.
And your way is straight ahead.
All I've got left is tangerine liqueur.
I don't drink it.
So, here we are.
Good morning, good morning,
good morning, sunshine.
The night is a secret to you,
but don't be blue...
Do you realize what
went down last night?
What?
I always wanted to try the anal thing.
- That wasn't it.
Is your name Roland or Ronald?
- My name's Ronald.
Easy to get mixed up.
You've always gotta flush!
I have to talk to you.
My coffee is gone.
Look what I found.
Let's take a break.
Cheers.
Is there any left?
- Yeah.
Only here for the day, too?
Thanks.
Hey, ciao.
Bye.
I thought I'd stop by again.
You know what's strange?
The good men who come here
sit where you're sitting now -
automatically.
And the jerks sit in the armchair.
Strange.
What can I say?
You don't have to say a thing, Roland.
My name is Ronald.
I've got company.
- Oh yeah?
I've got to tell you something.
Him?
Is he staying?
- We're gonna watch soccer.
Since when do you watch soccer?
- Since today.
It's gonna be a long evening.
I don't get it.
4x minus 2y equals 10.
You think Dad knows the answer?
You'll have to call him.
I don't want to understand it.
I'll never need it anyway.
Why not ask me about geography?
Ask me where Timbuktu is.
- Where's Timbuktu?
I didn't mean it that literally.
Oh, Max.
You won't go far with me.
Hi, it's me, Katrin.
Did I wake you?
Yeah, well...
Yeah, I'm sorry about the birthday call.
Yeah...
I just wanted
to get something sorted...
Hello?
I just wanted to ask...
Are you taking Max on vacation
for two weeks or not?
That's so fucked up!
I wanna know now!
Why don't you understand?
Hello?
Asshole!
Coffee or tea?
- Coffee, eggs, cheese, sausage!
I'm easy to please!
Sorry!
Come here.
The way I smell...
That's how I smell; it's my soap.
What do you transport
in your big car?
Mostly carpets.
But it doesn't fulfill me.
Neither professionally, nor personally.
Can I live here?
Sure, I do love you.
But I only have one key.
I'll get another one made.
That's not how I meant that.
- I don't get it.
The internal and external situations
don't jibe.
I really don't get it.
- Where do you live otherwise?
With my buddy, the guy you met.
- See? I gotta go.
I'm not trying to meddle.
- But you are.
He takes what he can get
without even looking.
I doubt he wasn't looking.
I looked good.
Like a bag of candy.
But my manner was lady-like.
Because he's reserved.
- What is he?
Shy. At least at first.
- That's not the sense I get.
That's your sense not mine.
What does he do?
- He hauls carpets.
He only sleeps with you. - And I only
sleep with him. - That I don't believe.
It works.
That clock survived the war.
For your girlfriend.
Thank you, Frau Timm.
If only my face were as smooth
as my ass!
I guess you haven't seen
your ass in a while.
Hi, Rico.
- Hi.
Come on, let's go.
Nice.
Real cozy.
Has Charly ever been here?
- No.
The dumb thing is:
I'm into her too.
I think that's her decision.
Hi, Charly.
- Hi.
Cigarette?
- Nope.
Do you live here for real?
- Sometimes.
I think it's romantic.
One could even sleep here.
Not if there are rats.
- There aren't any rats here.
Got a cola or something?
- I'm afraid I haven't got any.
Then let's take off. - Go on ahead.
I have to talk to Max about something.
What about?
- None of your business!
Okay, I'll wait downstairs.
What I wanted to tell you...
Don't feel like a traitor though -
because you're friends.
- No problem.
I don't want Rico to smoke.
Tell me if he does, okay?
Sure thing.
- Thanks, you're a real pal.
Frau Engel, please.
If it were up to me
I'd weed out everyone
who abbreviates street.
People who write "St." are lazy, period.
If this date is correct,
your application is three years old.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I forgot to change it.
I had it copied -
I've been applying ever since.
But none of my data has changed.
- You're forty?
39. - Our agency
prefers to place younger people.
I know it sounds silly -
you aren't old.
Can you believe I'm beat in the evening
from explaining that to people?
Yes.
Okay, I'll add you to our file.
Thank you.
But it's hopeless, isn't it?
- It's never hopeless.
You're from Freiburg,
and you moved to Berlin
after the Wall fell?
- Yes.
So, the girl from the West
married the guy from the East?
Unfortunately I had no prejudices.
I'm from the West too:
Weilheim in Upper Bavaria.
One can hear a slight accent.
Yes.
This one or this one?
- That one!
But it's very summery.
- And it's summertime.
He might move in with me.
Don't ruin the evening.
Nothing will change between us.
We wanted to go swimming.
I expected a different reaction
from my girlfriend. - What?
You're supposed to encourage me.
Why are we sitting here anyway?
- Then let's go. - No. I want to stay.
I'm not spoiled:
It's not often that I fall in love.
How can you call that love?
He nearly murdered me! Did you forget
about that? - This is ridiculous!
He isn't here tonight.
- That's not why I'm here.
A cognac with your beer?
- Not necessary.
My pleasure.
Why did you dye your hair?
I wanted to look different.
It's toilet-attendant black.
I think you're nice.
Is his name Roland or Ronald?
- Didn't he tell you?
Sure, he did.
Did you know he has a wife and kid
in Eberswalde?
Thanks. I had a nice time.
I can't, I'm not alone!
Hey! Get lost!
Man! Get lost!
Why aren't you asleep?
Nike, open up!
Something terrible happened!
Katrin? Katrin!
Is she going to die?
- No! No, Max.
Frau Engel?
Can you hear me?
Can you give me your hand?
I'm Dr. Bulling, the doctor on call.
Can you understand me?
Open your eyes, please.
Do you know where we are?
At St. Joseph's Hospital in Weissensee.
Psychiatric ward.
Open your eyes really wide.
Wide open, okay?
Open both eyes. Good.
Could you focus on my finger?
Do you see my finger? Hey!
Open your eyes, please.
Try to cooperate a bit.
Open your eyes wide
and focus on my finger.
Try to follow my finger. Exactly.
And now to the other side. Okay.
Can you see my finger at all?
- Mmh. - Yes.
Blow into this, okay?
For a few seconds.
I don't think that'll work.
- I'll try.
Watch out. Careful. Sit up higher.
Okay.
2.5 g/I.
Do you feel any pain? Does it hurt
when I press on your abdomen?
Did you fall down today?
Lift your head a bit.
I'll call Ward 9.
Just stay calm, please.
We won't find out much tonight.
I won't leave you alone.
I'll sleep here tonight.
We'll sort things out in the morning.
Good night, Max.
- Good night, Nike.
Hello.
- Hello.
I'm looking for Katrin Engel.
- Who are you?
A girlfriend.
I brought her some things.
I only drink when I feel like it.
Yesterday... I somehow lost it.
At the moment
I feel just great.
I finally have a job prospect.
Why lock me up anyway,
while all the sickos are on the loose?
You should lock up that lunatic!
Are you even looking for him?
Look at this.
It's kind of my fault too.
I left her
all alone in that joint.
To be honest,
she's just a normal drinker.
Exactly. I don't drink
any more than you do.
Your liver tells a different story.
That's why I asked you in
for a talk, Frau Engel.
Our tests show that alcohol
has caused definite damage...
I might as well go ahead
and kill myself!
I'll sell all my stuff and
pay my debts and then kill myself!
Max is old enough
to make it on his own!
I'll kill myself, nobody cares!
Or I'll go back to Freiburg!
I don't belong in here
with these alkies!
Nobody said that, Frau Engel.
This is only about you.
We're making you an offer
to stay here for a few days...
to allow us to observe you,
in case of complications
from last night.
It would also let us
counsel you a bit.
Frau Engel, it's an offer
I'd like to make.
You aren't locked up. You're free
to leave if you like, but...
From what you said,
I realize how desperate you are.
I could imagine it isn't only
because of last night.
Perhaps we should talk about it
when you've physically recovered.
Okay.
Dark blue suit and white shirt...
always look good.
My coffee is gone!
Hi, I'm from the Welfare Office.
I'd like to ask you a few questions.
Show me your ID.
It's good you asked me...
All right, Grandpa, shut up,
and no funny business, okay?
Hey!
No matter what happens,
there's gonna be blood.
Oskar?
That never used to happen
in the old days.
I'll be ready in a sec.
I have to go to school.
It's vacation time.
It's summer.
Tell me how it tastes.
I always put curry in my goulash
I'll put curry in it next time.
Want some ice cream?
- No, I don't.
Or peach compote?
I never eat compote.
Can I have a beer?
They were actually intended for me.
Cheers.
I brought a porn movie.
I don't really need that.
Can't you get a better job
than wiping old folks' asses?
Why don't you make something
out of your life!
What're you making out of your life?
I'm actually
an agricultural technician.
Never heard of it.
It's over with, anyway.
But you can't express yourself too well.
Nobody can.
At least I've tried lots of stuff.
I trained to be a seamstress.
And all you do
is haul around carpets.
I don't wanna hurt your feelings.
I just wanna rouse your ambition.
Things aren't like they used to be.
I know they aren't.
Can I ask you something else?
- Sure, go ahead.
You think because we have a sexual thing
you can act like a prick?
I don't get it.
We can go upstairs, or stay here as
long as you like. My mom isn't home.
I don't have much time.
My mother painted those pictures.
Those are three buildings.
- I can see that.
They're repainting all the buildings.
You can see how they used to look.
Does Rico still smoke?
Sometimes... Not always,
but more than he used to,
to be honest.
I wanted to go jogging with him,
but not anymore. I'm an anti-smoker.
I'm athletic, too.
You could also jog with me...
if I train harder.
Max?
This is Charly.
Hello, Charly.
- Hello.
I was just leaving. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
You wanted to join her?
- Not now.
I'm just here for the day.
Just for a few hours.
Let me tell you something.
But don't tell anybody yet.
I won't deliver carpets much longer.
- What'll you do?
Deliver electronics:
computers and stuff.
What's the difference?
Other routes, other people.
More modern altogether.
Even the ancient Romans had carpets.
We haven't agreed on the pay yet.
Then for a change you can buy yourself
some nice stuff.
I've got nice stuff.
Like this ring.
Everybody thinks it's real.
Not me.
Leave the freeway in 500 meters.
You can see where we're going.
How does it work?
- The satellite picked us up.
The satellite knows where we are
and where we're going.
But only 'cause I programmed it.
Drive 38 kilometers to the next exit
and turn around.
Why turn around?
She's a nice girl, isn't she?
- Yeah.
Is Nike looking after you?
- Yeah, but she went away today.
What - where to?
- I don't know.
Who was that man the other night?
I didn't know him.
Did he attack you?
Yes.
When are you coming back for good?
- In about 10 days.
I'm taking a kind of cure.
That's fine. Zero point zero.
Good.
Thanks.
Gotta car?
Or are you riding with someone?
Why?
- You could ride with me.
I think I'm taken.
A nice route. Along the Rhine
to Lake Constance, and then to Italy.
Wanna come along?
- Sorry, but I don't.
You want something from the lady?
- Who the hell are you?
Don't chat her up
or there'll be trouble!
Looking for adventure?
Is that soap for you?
That's never gonna be enough.
You make good sandwiches.
I'm really glad you came along.
Sometimes it gets pretty lonely.
I heard you're married
and have a kid.
Says who?
I just heard it.
Well, if it were true, I'd admit it.
You don't have to lie. There's no need.
I've got no plans for you.
Full?
- Yeah.
Got a girlfriend?
It's not that important to me.
- That's the right attitude.
Always keep a certain independence.
Maybe you aren't the one
to be giving advice. - Why not?
I wish somebody would've had
a sensible talk with me at his age.
Ice cream?
Maybe.
- What kinda ice cream you got?
Vanilla with chocolate and hazelnut.
Vanilla with chocolate.
- Vanilla with chocolate.
Bring me the check, Tina.
- The check's mine.
When the pharmacist was on night duty,
Katrin and I sometimes called him.
For fun.
I'm thinking of my son.
So you do have a kid.
You said I didn't have to lie.
Then you've got a wife, as well?
Yes.
Where is she?
In Eberswalde.
Then you can go there anytime.
That I can.
But my marriage isn't working.
But you can see your son,
can't you?
You never wanted kids?
Not by accident.
I've got two more addresses.
And two more kids.
Oh.
I had no father.
What's that got to do with it?
I shouldn't have listened to my uncle.
He always said, "Doing it standing,
from behind, makes no kids."
But that's nonsense.
What's going on?
Aren't you coming back out?
What's the big idea? Let me in!
Hey! Let me in!
Hey, open the door!
Open the door, you stupid cow!
Open up!
Okay, I've gotta climb down!
It's your fault if I fall!
Your fault!
Please, open it!
It's cold out here.
It's getting colder and colder!
Are you gonna leave me out here
all night, or what?
Good morning, good morning,
good morning, sunshine.
The night is a secret to you,
but don't be blue.
Good morning to you,
now don't be blue.
Good morning, sunshine.
Wake me up and come inside.
Oh man!
Hello!
Come here, Nike!
- What?
Come here a moment!
Frau Timm's daughter said
you were late. - Oh no. - Oh yes.
I should have known.
- What was the problem?
I was running kinda late. I don't know.
On certain days everything goes wrong.
I didn't sleep all night.
- Why do you work here?
Why do you work here?
What's this about?
You know I gotta earn a living.
I said I was sorry.
I mean, this is my job.
I got nothing against old folks.
I think about being old someday myself.
You don't look like it.
How should I look?
- Doesn't matter. Frau Timm also said...
you stay longer than you should.
You're assigned to clean her mother,
make breakfast and wash up.
That's 45 minutes at most.
If you want to stay longer,
do it on your own time.
But others are waiting for you.
Sounds like I'm up for promotion.
- Use your brain and you could be.
I think I'm impressing him,
but it's still backfiring.
Why?
- He's more or less moved in.
I'm feeding him.
He once brought me three flowers.
But then he's always taking stuff:
yesterday sausages, canned strawberries.
He also has a wife and three kids.
- Then end it!
I'm stuck on him, Katrin.
He does everything right.
He's no big-word fucker -
what he says is stupid.
But he has something very masculine.
He'd be good in advertising.
Want me to go home with you?
- No, Katie, not necessary.
Vodka and cola.
Where is he?
- On the road. - With carpets?
I guess so. Left two days ago.
I wouldn't guess if I were you.
Hi there!
Just get off work?
He said he screwed you on the balcony
while you gazed at the street -
but nobody takes him seriously.
He said you're a whore, but a good cook.
Thanks for the info.
And he has six kids
from different mothers.
And you've got six screws loose.
- I just want you to see the picture.
I'm amazed at the things
you can do.
I can do lots more, too.
I can be an all-round partner.
It all depends on you.
We can eat them this summer.
Or I'll eat them next time
I sleep on the balcony.
It's nice to have you back.
I always see your son out running.
His foot seems fine now.
Two pills three times a day.
And read the directions.
Bye.
- Bye.
Hello!
Everything comes from America:
the economy's to blame.
You mean this one?
It's for you.
Thanks, Oskar, but it isn't my style.
It was her favorite dress,
and it isn't good enough for you?
- No... it just doesn't fit me.
It's much too big.
You look pretty.
Thanks.
Hello.
I hope I didn't scare you.
I'm starting a new life this morning.
- I know.
That's what I like about you.
I still don't have a key for upstairs.
Usually I wait in the bar.
Wanna come in for a moment?
Nice sofa.
Pictures are nice, too.
Very real.
It isn't finished yet, is it?
There's no real resemblance yet.
Resemblance
is the hardest part, I think.
Too bad I never saw you...
after that day.
Me?
You're such a dainty being.
May I touch you very gently?
You can't just go and touch me.
After all, Nike is my girlfriend.
Mine, too.
Welcome home.
- Thank you.
What are you doing here?
- I don't have to wait in the bar.
I'll put the flowers in some water.
If I had a key,
I'd have gone upstairs.
I think
he's a good man for you after all.
I'm afraid we're out of cake.
Milk's out too.
Black coffee makes a person beautiful.
Go buy some cake.
- Why me?
Go on, do something for your girlfriend.
- What's this married tone of voice?
It's fine without cake.
We were almost on a first-name basis.
Do you mind?
Why should I mind?
Okay, let's use first names.
- Everybody uses first names.
People used to kiss each other.
Or would it hurt your feelings?
- I don't care.
Should I really kiss him?
- Come on, Katrin.
I got my hands behind my back.
C'mon, a real kiss!
I'm Ronald.
- I'm Katrin.
And I'm Nike.
It's good you came.
So I wasn't alone with your girlfriend.
I wouldn't stoop to that.
I'm gonna read a bit.
Since when do you read in bed?
I always did,
until you came galloping in.
You should try it yourself
now and then.
I did... but it isn't my thing.
What does it say?
Tell me what you're reading.
- A novel.
Who wrote it?
Stendhal.
Stendal is a town.
Stendhal is also a writer.
A French one at that.
Well, see...
we've learned something new.
We did? You learned something new.
When two people get along,
it isn't necessary that both read.
You're just right for me, Nike.
Have you ever thought about
why you're in this bed?
I don't get it.
Me neither.
We never had any problems.
Do you realize what problems
other people have?
Nike, it's so nice.
I mean it!
Love me! Love me!
You forgot something.
That's it.
Morning, Nike.
Come in.
Is Max home?
- No, he's out. Running.
Want some coffee?
- I borrowed this from him.
You acted so strange yesterday.
I just dumped the guy.
And I'm through with you, too.
I wouldn't have expected that from you.
You were just after him yourself!
- Are you crazy?
It isn't my fault.
I thought we were friends.
I can do without friends like you.
I'm no parasite.
Is that what I am to you?
I'm independent. I take risks.
Think about your life.
- What for?
At least I work for a living!
I'm a mother,
and I've got a kid!
- It's the same thing!
What? - Being a mother
and having a child! Anyone can do it!
You can't, Nike!
- So what!
You're self-centered!
- And you waste my time!
Then get lost!
I hope you shut the windows
when I walk by!
Another one.
All you're getting from me is coffee.
- What's the big idea!
You've gotta stop,
I've no time today.
- Not until I've played it right.
I can't leave you sitting here
with this thing.
Ouch! That hurts!
I've got so much on my mind...
- You're mean!
I don't want you to come back!
If I were a bird
and I had two wings,
I'd fly to you.
But...
since that can't be so,
but since that can't be so,
I will stay with...
Helene?
What'll it be, pretty lady?
Gimme a beer.
You look kinda worn out.
Problems?
I was hoping
to drink my beer in peace.
I'm not curious.
Sure. I've got news for you anyway.
That guy is history.
What do you mean?
- Just what I said. You can have him.
You think I want him?
I always got that impression.
I've got news for you too.
Your girlfriend went berserk.
I think she wanted to tie one on,
but she didn't get anything from me.
Katrin!
Is everything okay?
I thought something might be wrong.
Where'd you get that idea?
You know who died today?... Helene.
I'm sorry.
Well, I guess I'll be going.
Hi.
Max?
Listen, we've got money
coming from your father.
You can have the exact sneakers
you wanted.
Who's there?
- Me.
Max is lovesick.
How nice.
Am I the first?
You - always.
I think I fuck up plenty.
You - never.
We wanted to go swimming
...with Max.
Know how old I was
when I first fell in love?... Nine.
He was 14 and his name was Hansi.
Dumb name.
But he was the strongest guy
in our orphanage.
Know what he had the other guys do?
They had to write my name
on their little cocks.
They all wrote "Nike"
with a green felt-tip.
And I had a bad reputation.
At age nine already.
That's life.
I'll say!
AND SO ON...