Subbed and Timed by the Chinese Hero Zhao Zi Long Team @ Viki Please do not reuse or reupload our subtitles
A Hero's Tears - by Sun Mingyu
♫ Endless nights, not afraid it may seem like only a dream,♫
♫ Others will understand my undertaking of loyalty and gallantry.♫
♫ Moving with great ease to hoofbeats of horses, ever-victorious with swords, spears, saber and halberd.♫
♫ clouds over the imperial pagoda, an ode to good reputation across the world.♫
♫ A hero's tears, can only fall within the heart.♫
♫ Glory and emotions, remain within lifelong military metier.♫
♫ Sever the grief and joy of separation and reunion, fill the world with heroic pride.♫
♫ The mottled years, the fight for justice.♫
♫ It is the ambilight, it is a roc flying thousands of miles, it is a legend in the vast land.♫
♫ Let principled courage envelope your body. Write in a great number of ancient stories, reminiscence.♫
♫ A hero's tears, can only fall within the heart.♫
♫ Glory and emotions, remain within lifelong military metier.♫
♫ Sever the grief and joy of separation and reunion, fill the world with heroic pride.♫
♫ The mottled years, the fight for justice.♫
God of War, Zhao Yun
Episode 53
Zi Long, are you mad?
Yan Cheng. We lived in South Xu, the danger is everywhere.
All these have to do it.
I'm saying that they have civil unrest is also good.
Never mind the foreign aggression, they can deal with it themselves. Do we need to worry or trouble about it?
We don't need to bury these rotten matter. They still able to do something to us.
Now we are visitors in Jiangdong.
If they think of scheming us, they have plenty of way.
Although Your Highness have extremely protecting Wu state,
but still at all times be confronted with danger.
For the safety of Our Majesty, some of the things we have to prevent it.
Ever since the last time Jia Hua tried to assassinate His Majesty.
I am worried about His Highness' safety day and night.
This is his territory.
I cannot not guard him.
go deep into the mountains, knowing well that there are tigers (means: go on undeterred by the dangers)
That's my duties as a subordinate,
ought to be my responsibilites.
Yan Cheng, I will leave these five hundred soldiers' lives in your hands.
Zi Long!
The route on the mountain is a valley. Two sides of the mountains are steep and high.
You can send Pai Zhang to lead a thousand troops, lie in ambush on-top of the mountain slopes.
Prepare things to set on fire.
Order Gan Ling and Ling Tong, to each lead 1,000 troops, lie in ambush on both sides of the valley,
As long as after Jingzhou's army enter into the valley,
Gan Ling and Ling Tong, each block off the valley's entrance/exit.
Pai Zhang can use fire sphere and falling rocks to attack the Jingzhou's army.
At the same time have Gan Ling and Ling Tong slaughter them at both ends.
Commander's brilliant plan.
Keep in mind, Cao army have to act lifelike and appropriately leave a few survivors,
Let them spread the new that it's the Cao army who's the culprits.
Yes.
Go!
Crap! What a load of crap!
How can Gong Jin play into Zhao Zi Long's taunts?
He is a Senior Commander of troops and horses (military forces),
How could he go across to Jiang County to gather intelligence about the military situation?
What commander mean is, since we're pretending, we'll need to be more believable.
in case Zhao Zi Long die outside the Cao's camp, wouldn't that be great?
Along with Gong Jin, there's only 19 of us.
Suppose we all get discovered by Cao Army, perhaps we fall into Zhao Zi Long's cunning scheme.
Gong Jin's life will be in danger.
Your Majesty, there's no need to worry, the Commander has already thought about this.
He has a plan to counter it.
Even so, with just 19 of us
do you think, there's an opportunity to kill Zhao Zi Long?
Could it be that you don't know, during that year he once, single-handedly fought a very fierce battle at Zhang Ban Po?
Your Majesty, just relax
Back then at Zhang Ban Po, Zhao Zi Long did infact single-handedly fought a bloody battle,
but this time, there's a great difference.
This time Zhao Zi Long didn't carry his spear and he's not riding his horse.
He's alone and merely carrying a long sword.
He...
What exactly does he want to do?
Tonight the moon is bright and clear,
haven't light candle light and it's well illuminated.
being like this on the tranquil great river,
able to drink with commander, really is an aesthetic mood.
Able to drink with General Zhao under such circumstance,
also is my good fortune.
There is a saying that goes "even the slightest mistake in music cannot escape Zhou Yu's ears"
Commander, your musical talents are unparalleled
It's an honour to listen to it.
The moonlight shines like a luminous pearl, the waves are calm and soothing. It is such a wonderful moment
to play the instruments and make beautiful music.
What a pity that we're now on a reconnaissance mission.
If you wish,
I will definitely play for you in the future.
That would be wonderful. Thank you, Commander.
Come, let's drink!
Go!
As expected, it's here.
There's Cao Army!
Originally we wanted to take a walk today.
But unfortunately, it looks like we've been discovered by Cao Cao's watchmen.
Seems like we cannot finish this walk.
Since you cannot finish this walk,
Why not continue our conversation beneath the moon while drinking wine?
Good idea.
Here.
Zhao Yun.
Zhou Yu.
Looks like your old acquaintances came.
Oh, it's Brother Xia Hou!
Xia Hou Dun, since we parted ways at Bowang Slope,
it must have been a few years since we've seen each other.
Zhao Yun! You are really brave!
Coming this close to our base camp,
you are really something! Interesting!
What's interesting about that?
In those years, from Xinye to Jiangxia,
I've dealt with you guys countless times.
Here.
Brother, why would you waste time talking to him?
Let's order our soldiers to release all their arrows
and make them all porcupines!
Miao Cai, nonsense!
Do you remember that at Changban Slope,
Prime Minister wasn't willing to kill Zhao Yun.
Now, who knows if he's willing to or not.
It is even more unwise to kill Zhou Yu.
He's the Commander in Chief of the Wu Army. If we can capture him alive,
it would be considered a miraculous feat.
So that means, we musn't kill any of those two?
We can't.
If that's so, we'll surround them with our troops
and capture them for good.
Brother, do you still remember the battle at Bowang Slope?
It was Zhao Yun who pretended
to be on the retreat and lured my forces to pursue him,
making me lose a significant number of subordinates.
Nobody knows what he's plotting this time.
Since General Xia Hou seems to be so pleased looking at us drinking,
you guys should put down your weapons, take a seat
and drink with the Commander and I.
Since General Zhao already said it. You should just sit down and drink with us.
- Here, here, here. Everyone, drink! - Here. Raise your glasses!
Big Brother, who cares about what they're planning to do?
We should just send a few hundred men
and round them up. I'd like to see which is faster,
their plots or the swing of our swords.
Ready.
Commander-in-chief, they will take action now. What are we supposed to do?
Usually, it's General Zhao who trains you.
Naturally, you should ask General Zhao about how to battle with Cao Army.
When I was training the soldiers,
I have mentioned that no matter the size of the battlefield or the number of soldiers,
it is aways possible to create a powerful formation.
As long as all of you keep calm
and refrain from retreating in fear, we can fight a force of hundreds with just ten men.
Kill!
Eighteen soldiers actually defeated Cao Army with more than hundred soldiers.
Furthermore, there wasn't even one casualty.
General Zhao's recent training really has some magical effects.
You flatter me. I'm only doing my best
to fulfil the responsibility that you have entrusted me with.
Big Brother, we cannot remain in this impasse any longer.
Let's release the arrows!
Brother.
Brother!
Do what you wish!
Big Brother, don't worry about it.
If Prime Minister blames anyone, I will take full responsibilty!
Archers ready!
Seems like it's now time for plan B.
Servant! Send the signal.
Xia Hou Dun, while you're busying trying to seize the twenty odd men that you see in front of you,
you've forgotten to look behind your back.
The Wu Army misses their Commander very much.
They've sent dozens of ships to the north bank!
You rascal! To hell with your plots!
That's not my idea.
If you want to curse, curse Commander-in-Chief Zhou!
Commander-in-Chief, how do you think we should end today's issue?
We're only here at the north bank today to take a stroll
and have a few drinks. Now that we've emptied our cups,
we shall take our leave.
You want to leave? It's not that easy!
Nobody gets out of here alive!
Xia Hou Yuan, if you order the arrows to be released the same time as we do,
are you sure that you will be unharmed?
If our reinforcements continue to disembark,
Are you sure you will be able to defeat us?
Are you sure that your base camp
will not be conquered my us?
It's now late into the night. Shall we meet again during the day
so that we can engage in a proper battle
that can quench our thirst for blood?
Are you saying that you will act as what Commander Zhou has proposed and retreat?
I'm saying that we both gather our troops
and return to our camps.
Retreat!
The Polaris star has finally appeared.
It will be daybreak soon.
This really is an unforgettable night.
Perhaps, you were disappointed tonight.
Since I wasn't killed and Jingzhou's five hundred soldiers were not harmed.
I already had the premonition that it would end like this long ago.
Why would it be like this?
When Councillor Zhu Ge performed the ritual to summon the easterlie wind,
he was in possession of your military seal for a few days.
Even though he returned it to you in the end,
but he kept a mould of the seal
and I made a fake one using that.
It's Zhu Ge Liang again...
Are you telling me that your invitation to monitor enemy movements on the north bank
is also his idea?
The Councillor is far away at Jingzhou. He won't be able to anticipate every single development.
This was my idea.
What are you seeking by putting yourself in such danger?
There are a lot of things I seek.
But they need your help to be fulfilled.
Tell me about it.
The first thing is that I wish to take this opportunity of being in eminent danger of Cao Cao's army
to demonstrate clearly to you
that Cao Cao is our common enemy.
To remind you to hold back on your selfish desires
and not be driven by the need for revenge.
I don't need you to remind me of this!
- Go on.- The second thing
is that the reason why I've decided to resist Cao Cao's army using only the military formations performed
by the Wu soldiers that I have trained
without wielding my spear or mounting my steed.
I'm doing this to tell you that the soldiers in Lord Liu's army are all of this calibre.
Don't make misjudgments of this sort.
If a violent conflict breaks out between the Sun and the Liu families,
there will be no victories waiting for you.
Do you wish to intimidate me?
This is just my personal thoughts.
I already have plans regarding with whom
and how the Wu Army will fight. Go on with your speech.
Given your high musical talents,
I admire you greatly indeed.
But it's a pity that we've never gotten to know each other well.
During the battle of the Red Cliff,
I was at Jiangxia, and you were at Jiangdong.
We've never fought alongside each other.
I have always wanted an opportunity to be your comrade in battle.
This opportunity that you're talking about is a risky one indeed.
I know very well that you are careful in whatever you do.
You will not act in risky ways.
I had to do it this way if I wanted to fulfil my wish.
You keep repeating that you want to fight by my side and form a friendship with me.
I take it with a grain of salt.
All that you have done is for the sake of Liu Bei.
That's right. Ever since my Lord has arrived in Jiangdong,
you have plotted to kill him many times.
To stop you from doing so,
I really hope that we can be on friendly terms.
To be friends with me?
I'll pass.
We serve different Lords. We can never be friends.
As for sparing Liu Bei's life,
that would be even more impossible.
There's something I have to say. You have no choice must to obey it.
Liu Shen has already seized Pan Zhang in the valleys.
Pan Zhang has confessed about your plot to fake an infiltration by Cao Cao's spies
and to kill the soldiers from Jingzhou.
If you don't want Pan Zhang and all these evidence to be presented to the Queen Mother,
you must obey me on this.
The Queen Mother was already outraged by what you did earlier.
Do you want to enrage her again?
You're threatening me.
You know better than anyone that the Lord of Dongwu is a filial son.
If the Queen Mother becomes ill from the anger,
Do you, Zhou Gong Jin, think you will have it easy in Jiangdong?
I will not mention your plot to kill the Jingzhou soldiers
to my Lord and the Queen Mother.
I only hope that you can promise me
that for the remaining time that my Lord will spend in Jiangdong,
you will not try to assassinate him again.
What does it matter if I
promise or not?
After what happened yesterday night,
I know very well. As long as you are in Jiangdong,
as long as Liu Bei doesn't make a huge mistake ,
I'm not able to murder him anymore.
Commander, I believe that you are a virtuous gentleman.
But I still need to hear you say it.
Zhou Yu promised me himself that as long as the Lord lie low in Jiangdong
he will not try to plot against him anymore.
- Hopefully, he can do as he says- No matter who, a person must have limits
I believe that as the Commander the Chief,
Zhou Yu will definitely keep his words.
But remember, Jiangdong is not our homeland.
Zi Long, you still need to think of a way to persuade His Highness to return to Jingzhou quickly.
Your Highness.
Your Highness, you have to take care of your health.
Don't worry, I'm glad, I'm happy.
If you're happy, you have to drink wine.
It's alright.
My Lord, to be honest,
You've already been married to your wife for one year.
Do you intend to live here forever and not return to Jingzhou?
Zi Long, what do you mean?
Forgive my rudeness. We have yet to accomplish what we set out to do
I hope that you will not forget about it.
Zi Long, I understand how you feel.
However, the Queen Mother and the Lord of Dongwu have treated me so well
are you saying that I should give them a cold shoulder?
The Councillor is still at Jingzhou. If anything happens,
I will certainly prioritize that over everything else.
So Zi Long, you don't need to worry too much.
My friendship with the Lord of Dongwu is laying the groundwork for our fight against Cao Cao in the future.
It's a great thing!
As the saying goes, whatever situation you find yourself in, make yourself comfortable.
Zi Long, you have followed me for all these years, riding into battle,
risking your life. You have sacrificed a lot.
You should try to relax.
We've come to this paradise after all those years of turmoil,
you should enjoy yourself and not think about anything else.
Don't die without having experienced such bliss!
Thank you, My Lord. I'm afraid that this paradise that you speak of
is not for me.
Zi Long!
Look what I've brought.
How is it? I've arranged everything myself. Does it look pretty?
Yeah.
I'm really not praising myself. I just saw Sister Shang Xiang arrange flowers a few times.
So, I learned to do it myself. I've never expected I would do so well.
Tell me, I'm naturally gifted, who do I take after?
Talking about arranging flowers. Not only do you have to be clever, but you also need to have good taste.
Talking about good taste, I have to praise myself again.
If I have poor taste, how could I have fallen in love with you?
Did you hear what I said?
Yes.
Then, tell me. What did I say?
Alright, alright. I won't annoy you anymore.
No.
What are you looking at?
I'm looking... to see what you are thinking.
You couldn't be thinking of Ma Yu Rou, could you?
No. I'm only worried about His Highness' matters.
Royal Uncle Liu and Sister are doing well together. What's there to worry about?
That's exactly what I am worried about.
I've already talked to Royal Uncle Liu about returning to Jingzhou a few times.
But he has never agreed to it.
Soon, it will be one year since we came to Nanxu.
Why are you worried about this?
Think about it, the Councillor is at Jingzhou.
If anything was to happen, they would definitely inform us.
No news is good news.
You've reminded me that Councillor said
to look at the second tactic at the end of the year.
[If the Lord indulges in pleasure, it's unclear how long will it take before you can return. Fabricate an urgent piece of military intelligence, and the general shall bring the Lord home.]
Let me finish reading it!
Even his back view looks so good.
What? Cao Cao is commanding an army of three hundred thousand to Jingzhou?
My Lord, this is important news. How dare I make it up?
I have rushed here at once.
Apologies for disturbing you and Madam.
Of course, military affairs have priority. You don't need to blame yourself.
We will have to return to Jingzhou.
It's only...
My dear, don't worry.
Since I married you,
naturally, I will always follow you for my whole life.
If you go to Jingzhou, you'll be living in constant danger
I would feel guilty about it.
I am a Lord's daughter.
I know very well what kinds of difficulties I would face when I decided to marry you.
But I am not afraid.
It's just that my mother is getting older everyday.
I'm worried that I won't be able to see her ever again.
General Zhao, I have a request to make of you.
Madame Sun, please say it.
I know that the matter that troubles my mother the most
is the marriage of Sister Bao Yue.
If I could fulfill my mother's wish before leaving,
I could leave knowing that I have been a good daughter.
General Zhao, are you willing to help me?
This- Talking about marriage...
I'm afraid it's not something that can be settled in a short period of time.
Right now, the military affairs are more urgent. I'm afraid-
You don't need to trouble yourself.
I didn't mean that you and Sister Bao Yue should marry immediately.
I just want you to make a promise
to let Sister Bao Yue follow you.
And that you will take care of her.
Alright. I will promise you that I will take care of Bao Yue.
Zi Long, prepare everything tonight.
We shall leave tomorrow morning.
My Lord, in my view, we won't be able to keep this a secret for long.
It would be the best if the Empress and the Lord of Dongwu didn't know about this.
Why?
Madam Sun and the Queen Mother share a very deep bond.
The Lord of Dongwu only has this one sister. If Your Highness and Madame Sun suddenly ask to resign,
the Empress and the Lord of Dongwu probably won't be willing to let you go.
Furthermore, the Queen Mother is very particular about etiquette.
She's bound to call for a feast as a farewell for you two.
Zi Long, you're right.
But if we ride for the dock tomorrow
aren't we going to attract tons of attention?
Husband, General Zhao, I have a plan.
Tomorrow, I will inform my mother that we are going to the river bank
to perform ceremonial rituals for our ancestors.
This should not arouse any suspicions.
Moreover, Zi Long will have time to prepare
and let the soldiers reach there first.
Madam Sun, your wisdom really saved us. With this plan, we can kill two birds with one stone.
I am really unfilial.
Not only did I deceive my mother,
but I also left without saying goodbye.
Wife, it's my fault.
Many things cannot be controlled when one is in the army.
Seeing you sad like this,
I feel endlessly sorry.
Husband, you really don't need to blame yourself.
I just find it difficult to leave mother behind.
But, I am not regretting it.
You have a responsibility to all of the people in this world.
I should not be an obstacle in your path.
You don't need to worry about me.
Madam, it is such a blessing to have you as my wife.
I can die without any regrets.
- What is it? - We cannot cross the river.
The boatmen dare not sail without orders from the Lord of Dondwu
What should we do not? If we inform him now,
he's sure to prevent us from crossing the river.
My dear, perhaps we should walk for the time being.
We can think of other ideas once we cross Dongwu's border.
- Your Highness, Liu Bei and his people are starting to take action. - What happened?
Liu Bei and Madam Sun went to see the Queen Mother today
informing her that they are going to the Yangtze River to perform rituals for ancestor worship.
All of Liu Bei's men have left the Palace of Eternal Bliss.
To perform ancestral worship at the river bank? What's he plotting?
My Lord, Liu Bei might be making a run for it.
He might be trying to get back to Jingzhou. The ancestral worship is just a disguise.
Quick! Call Gong Jin. Tell him I have something important to discuss with him.
Yes.
Giddy up!
Your Highness, there are Wu soldiers behind you!
What should we do? Both the path forward
and backward are blocked by Wu forces, we have nowhere to go!
Councillor once said to do as this tactic says in case of emergency.
The love between husband and wife is deep and moving, it is a crulty to separate them.
When the phoenix shows her rage, the enemies can be subdued.
Husband, what happened?
My dear, I'm so sorry that you have to go through his.
Husband, what do you mean?
In the past, your brother connived with Zhou Yu
and planned your marriage to me.
He tried to trap me here at Nanxu and take back Jingzhou
by numbing my senses with luxury and pleasure.
Now that we have left without informing anybody,
The Lord of Dongwu must have sent people to follow and kill me.
I am at an dead end and you are implicated in this as well.
Since my brother sees me as a mere bait, I will no longer allow him to manipulate me like this.
Let me help you get out of this predicament.
My dear!
Zi Long, accompany my wife!
Yes.
Go!
- Giddy up!- Stop!
Commander-in-Chief Zhou! You've got some nerve, sending people to kill us several times!
I'm just acting by the command of the Lord. Madam, please don't blame it on me.
Commander Zhou, yes, you are here by the command by my brother.
But don't you realize that my husband and I are here by the order of the Queen Mother?
I serve the Lord only.
Madam, if you want to avoid a violent confrontation,
I suggest that you come back to Nanxu with Lord Liu.
Madame, go back first.
Leave the rest to me.
Giddy up!
If that's what you plan to do, then I shall do my job.
Capture Liu Bei, don't harm the Madame! Kill!
Kill!
Go!
Wife, are you injured?
My dear, I'm fine. Zhou Yu has brought a considerable amount of forces to pursue us.
I'm afraid we won't be able to withstand his attacks. Let's leave this place fast.
Go!
Archers! Ready!
Guan Yun Chang is here! Commander Zhou! Please draw back at once!
Commander Zhou, you have really troubled yourself to escort my Lord and Madam here.
My forces are now taking over. Commander, you can return to Jiangdong.
Zhou Yu's brilliant strategy is one of its kind,
he gave away the Princess and a his soldiers' lives.
Commander-in-Chief!
- What should we do? - That's right! What should we do?
Retreat.
Retreat! Let's go!
Brother.
Respectful madam,
please accept my salutation.
Please accept my salutation.
Second Brother, Third Brother, you don't need to be this courteous.
I have long heard that you two are generals of unparalelled prowess.
Looks like the rumours are true.
I am just a soldier.
If not for Big Brother, people would still know me as a butcher.
Madam, Third Brother is a straightforward man. Please don't mind him.
Being straightforward is a good thing.
The story of how you three became brothers in the Peach Garden
has become a well known folk tale.
I'm thankful that my husband has you two by his side
If not, he wouldn't has accomplished so much.
I should properly thank you.
Since sister-in-law is already married to Brother,
we are one family. There's no need to thank us.
Subbed and Timed by the Chinese Hero Zhao Zi LongTeam @ Viki. Please do not reuse or reupload our subtitles
♫ Passing the ashes of spring, only to sigh at summer's end.♫
♫ Unable to burn through the loneliness of fall, nor the swan song of winter.♫
♫ Light breeze flows, a cup of wine, dreams stray behind.♫
♫ Past memories like lotus flowers mirroring in the water.♫
♫ Soft rains, broken winds, much to worry about in a foggy, drunken state.♫
♫ To only sigh, but still holding on.♫
♫ Misty moon, guarding love, falling into an embrace.♫
♫ The fear of love, the thoughts of woe.♫
♫ Lalalalala...♫
♫ Once was there familiarity, tears fall, songs sang.♫
♫ The promise of espousal after incarnations never changed.♫
♫ Unwilling to disturb the past.♫
♫ Lalalalala...♫
♫ The heroes of the past oft were melancholic.♫
♫ After the rise and collapse, the success and failures, still remembering her visage.♫
♫ Remembering past dreams, a scene of painful separation.♫
♫ Lalalalala...♫
♫ Parting after a single song.♫
♫ Once was there familiarity, tears fall, songs sang.♫
♫ The promise of espousal after incarnations never changed.♫
♫ Unwilling to disturb the past.♫
♫ The heroes of the past oft were melancholic.♫
♫ After the rise and collapse, the success and failures, still remembering her visage.♫
♫ Remembering past dreams, a scene of painful separation.♫