Fuck you, marshal.
I hate you.
Watch out for this one. He's a ding.
Six counts, first degree murder,
armed robbery and assault.
Fuck you.
Okay, on your knees, Monroe.
Okay.
Say sir when you speak to me.
Okay, sir.
- You got a problem?
- I got no problems with nothing, sir.
- What's this?
- A nuclear device.
Hi, Mr. Vogel. I'm Dr. Reynolds.
How are you feeling today?
Not so good today.
The Cytoxan's making you nauseous?
I just don't feel so good.
I see.
I'd like to talk to you
about your latest CAT scans.
Would you excuse me for one moment?
That's a nice watch.
- Hello?
- Hi, it's me.
Michael, we're gonna lose the house.
This is our last chance to close.
Elaine says our bid is too low.
She thinks our bid is too low?
- How can it be too low?
- Because Elaine...
Died last Thursday. And they still
had him down for an MRI today.
Who does she think she is, Ivana Trump?
She's a goddamned real estate agent.
- Calm down.
- I am calm.
Michael, Michael, Michael.
Hey, can you eavesdrop
on somebody else's life?
- Thank you.
- Elaine says we should offer 2 million.
Two million
is more than the house is worth.
Please, honey. Please, please?
No. No, absolutely not.
Victoria, we have gone over this
and over this.
- Do you realize who built this house?
- I know it once belonged to Hal Roach.
But the pool alone...
I know it's got a great pool.
- Do you realize who swam in it?
- I know Spanky swam in it. I know.
- It's just too goddamn much money.
- If you don't want this, you don't love me.
- I have to go, okay?
- It's as simple as that.
Yeah, thank you.
Sorry, it's been a madhouse today.
We're short on staff.
I think we're gonna have to consider
trying a different drug.
Your radiation field is
here and right here.
Yeah, and what, ignore the spread
to the retroperitoneum?
It¡s a spread
to the periaortic lymph nodes.
Axial views, right?
There's your tumor mass.
There's your metastasis to the liver.
There's your lymph node.
School of Dentistry
is across the street, fellas.
Knee bone connected to the shin bone.
Neoplasm in my opinion...
Hey, Mighty Mike. Buy the house?
I don't wanna talk about it.
Victoria's dream house.
I thought you were closing.
Give it to Dr. Reynolds.
Okay, are we still on for tonight?
Dr. Reynolds, I have a new case file.
Granita, 7:00?
- Patient should be in Pediatrics.
- Pediatrics sent him up.
Can't handle him. Too dangerous.
- What the hell does that mean?
- He's a killer.
Pediatrics can just dump their overload
on us?
Tell them to cut down on tennis...
... maybe they have more time
to practice medicine.
Send him back down.
If Pediatrics determines they're dangerous,
we have to handle them up here.
- Subhuman piece of shit.
- Honestly, Dr. Byrnes.
They bus him in
twice a month from jail. Bam!
The last deputy that brought him here
had to have plastic surgery on his face.
If I were you, I'd develop a sudden pain in
the chest and leave his chart for Newman.
Because I don't think he'd hit a woman.
But then, you never know.
Page Dr. Newman.
I think I'm getting chest pain.
Dr. Newman is in Surgery.
You got to handle this. Here.
Hey, I gotta go
to the Tumor Board Conference.
Hi, I'm Dr. Reynolds.
Smoking. Very good.
You know, this wing
would never have been built...
...without the support
of cigarette smokers like yourself.
So on behalf of all of us here,
I thank you.
Funny thing, though,
it's a no-smoking facility.
Should I call Reggie White out there...
...to get him to come in here
and help you put it out?
Thank you.
You're due
for a radiation treatment today.
But before I can put my John Hancock
on this form, I have to fill it out.
Which means I have to examine you.
So I'll need you to take your top off.
Why don't you take it off?
Why don't we start over?
Hi.
I'm Dr. Reynolds.
You're looking at me like I'm an animal
or something...
...you tight-ass,
suit-wearing motherfucker...
...rolling your fresh wheels,
stacking your loot.
You do as much damage as anyone.
You just hide your shit better, right?
You think you're so down?
So bigtime cool?
No, that's lawyers. I'm a doctor.
I'm not going in that oven again.
I'm not some fucking hot dog.
Okay, that's fair enough.
I'll make you a deal.
Let me examine you...
...we'll just take a CAT scan
and finish off the chemo.
You're a motherfucking liar.
Could be.
Nice touch.
What are these from?
Bullets.
Breathe deeply.
Again.
Didn't you see them coming?
Yeah. Yeah, I seen them coming.
The bullets come out the guns
and hit me in the chest.
Wasn't there some warning?
If you're gonna shoot somebody,
why warn them?
It was a get-back thing.
Cough.
That's enough.
This has cheese.
Yeah, you ordered goat cheese.
Yeah, I ordered goat cheese.
I didn't order mozzarella.
Michael, can you...?
No, it's okay.
I'll make you a fresh one.
Michael is not talking about the house.
Apparently,
2 million is too low a bid for the Palisades.
So? Bid higher. Just bid higher.
Pretty soon
you're not gonna be worrying about money.
Tell him that.
The director of oncology
has been vacant for two months.
Why do you think
they haven't even recruited outside?
Because Bradfords got you tapped for it,
buddy boy.
He's got Newman tapped for it.
Oh, come on, Newman
is a lightweight. Ann Arbor.
There is no such thing
as a modest surgeon, is there?
Oh, Michael's not modest,
he's just superstitious.
You're Harvard Med,
you were chief resident.
You know damn well
Bradfords going to pick you.
- Has he mentioned dinner yet?
- No.
- Radicchio salad.
- Thank you.
He will. Any day now,
he's going to invite you out to Morton's.
- Morton's on Monday, that's his M.O.
- Yeah.
I don't have anything to wear.
All right, guys. To Dr. Reynolds, folks.
The youngest head of a section
in Surgery.
Finally,
a parking spot with your name on it.
Are you drinking what I'm drinking?
You will remember your friends,
won't you?
What was your name?
Because I want
the Bone Marrow Transplant Unit.
- So, what did you think of Blue?
- Blue?
A real charmer.
So long as I don't have to make
house calls.
What are you talking about?
A 16-year-old gangbanger...
...with a rare high-grade
retroperitoneal sarcoma...
...your husband had the pleasure of seeing.
- Really?
Youth Authority case.
Pediatrics sent him up.
This is delicious.
What did he do?
- Who?
- This 16-year-old boy.
I read his medical record, hon,
not his rap sheet.
Well, I read it.
He blew his stepfather's brains out.
May beauty be before me
May beauty be behind me
May beauty be above me
May beauty be below me
May beauty be all around me
Coming to bed?
I thought Sally looked
beautiful tonight.
Isn't it wonderful how she just glowed?
She didn't even have to tell us
she was pregnant.
Yes, she glowed.
Can you imagine Chip changing a diaper?
Still thinking about that boy
you saw today?
Why would I be thinking
about that boy?
What is it, Michael?
Look, Jimmy, Lou Brock.
What will you trade me for him?
Take it.
Doesn't fit me anymore.
I want you to do something for me.
I want you to turn off the machine.
- No, no.
- Don't be afraid.
No, no.
Don't be afraid.
Just do it.
For me, Mikey.
Mighty Mike.
Yeah. Here you go.
I got it.
- Yeah.
- Yes.
Hey, Michael.
Do you have a minute?
Bingo.
Morton's, 7:00.
Oh, my God. This is it.
What should I wear?
How about the new stilettos
and them black thigh-highs?
You're terrible.
Okay.
I have a zoo board meeting at 2:30.
By the time I get home...
Dr. Reynolds.
I'm just gonna have to meet
you there at 7.
Don't be late.
- What the hell is this?
- It's your worst nightmare.
- No way.
- He's been turfed over to you.
- I'm not seeing him. Page Dr. Newman.
- Now in Surgery.
- Byrnes, then.
- Pathology.
How are you?
The Youth Facility physician says
you're reporting abdominal pains.
More than usual?
Okay, more than usual.
Reports of your scans are back.
Let's take a look.
Fucked, huh?
Tumor's gotten larger.
Excuse me for a moment, please.
Metastasis to the liver and lungs.
Double whammy.
Well, there it is.
I give him one,
maybe two months at the most.
Still looking pretty.
Still looking good.
Hey, I gotta take a leak.
You know, there is the possibility
that he might be eligible...
...for the NIH Sarcoma Protocol
over at City of Hope.
What? Come on, he fits all the criteria.
Advanced stage of the disease.
Nobody this far along
could survive that degree of toxicity.
- Especially a 16-year-old kid.
- Come on, Mike.
Sixteen is an advantage.
You can do anything to a 16-year-old.
Anything but guarantee them their lives,
right, Chip?
Let's be frank, gentlemen.
Mr. Monroe is a ward of the state, right?
They pick up the tab here.
I would strongly advise against it.
Subjecting a kid...
A patient to a regimen that...
And I think
Dr. Byrnes would have to agree...
...would be a painful waste of time.
I disagree.
I think you should screen him anyways.
See if he does fit the criteria.
You take him over to City of Hope
this afternoon.
Let's get him in there
before they close their study.
Me?
He is your patient, isn't he?
They wanna give you
higher doses of chemo.
It's a fly ride, man.
Where's the fax?
They're installing it tomorrow morning.
Now what?
Jesus Christ.
Monroe?
Son of a bitch.
Drop it. Drop it.
You make a sound and you're gonna die.
I'll peel your cap right here, right now,
motherfucker.
What's the problem?
Shut up and move.
Help me!
Okay. Okay.
Keep your hands down.
Move.
Drive. I said, drive.
Drive!
Call the police! Get me out of here!
Get me out of here!
Help me!
Help! Get me out of here!
Call the police!
You need to be in a hospital.
Shit, man.
Thought I was gonna have to peel
that man's cap.
Mess with his motherfucking ride,
but this is much better.
You wouldn't peel a doctor's cap,
would you?
I'll drop you. I could care less.
- No, Dr. Reynolds hasn't called in.
- This is Mrs. Reynolds.
Okay, let me try paging him.
It's important that I reach him.
Dr. Reynolds,
please call the nurse station ASAP.
That motherfucker's dead.
They got your brother
all handcuffed and shit.
Like this is 1712.
Jesus, this looks like the 6:00 news.
It's the Hazards, man.
You don't wanna go in the Hazards at night.
Even the grandmas got tattoos out here.
Don't worry,
no one's gonna mess with you, man.
There's too many Judas around.
Don't.
Yeah, boy.
Man, fuck the police. Fuck the police.
Your 'hood?
Whole country was our 'hood
about 400 years ago.
You see, I'm a mix.
Half-breed, half-Navajo.
Don't stare at them. Don't stare.
- She's tied up, you know.
- Punk motherfuckers.
I ought to UZI
these motherfuckers up in his car.
It's just another cluckhead
robbing a store.
Hey, pull in here.
- What for?
- Just pull in.
Money.
Get out.
I got one, two months at the most.
Yeah, I heard you motherfuckers.
So, what the fuck if I bust a cap
in your ass right now, huh?
Now, get out.
You got tools?
Tools?
- Man, don't remark me.
- They're in the trunk, I guess.
I don't know, I just got it. l...
Well, then open
the motherfucking trunk, then.
Easy.
How do they live like this?
It's their 'hood, man.
You're stealing this car?
No, you are. I don't got a license.
Bing, bang.
I could care less.
I still got the touch, man.
Well, what about my...?
That is a $ 176,000 car.
You're about to trade down, man.
Now, drive.
Drive.
Listen, that's really stupid.
Easy, bust it right.
Hey, watch out, watch out.
Be careful.
Hey, bust it right. In there.
Go left. Left.
Right in there. Right in there.
- My man, Smokes.
- What's up, homey?
What's up? You're still getting fucked up
over some bitch?
Hell, yeah, you know it.
I just ain't got turned out
like your ass yet.
- Fuck you, holmes.
- Fuck you, homeboy.
Oh, you for real, man.
Yeah, but who the fuck
is this motherfucker right here?
He's all right.
That's my doctor, he's cool.
He's gonna make sure I'm all right.
I see doctor got himself
all hemmed up, huh?
You need some motherfucking walk-through
metal detectors in that damn hospital.
Because I just walk right up in that
motherfucker strapped.
You know what I'm saying?
They be checking like one out of 10.
So I figure I just stash the nine
in the ceiling of the fourth floor bathroom.
That's great.
Hey, man, you know,
I got this real bad pain in my side.
Check it out.
I don't pay attention
to that father figure.
I just handle mine,
and I'm rolling with the trigger.
Hey, doc, check it out, man.
It's a fly color, huh?
Do you have any idea
how toxic that is?
Hey, doc, the drill is talking to me.
The drill.
The drill, he's saying
he going to kill your bitch ass.
Brandon, listen to me.
You have stage four
retroperitoneal sarcoma.
What's "stage four" mean?
It means you have
an advanced inoperable tumor.
Your only hope
is high-dose chemotherapy.
Yeah, I kind of thought that.
But before I die, I want to get me
as much pussy as I can get.
Brandon, listen, I can understand
how this might make you a bit unstable.
By the way, the moniker is Blue.
Brandon Monroe is just a name on a file.
Blue.
All right, Blue, where are we going?
Is that too much to ask?
Arizona.
Shiprock. Navajo reservation.
Are you insane?
Dibe' Ni'tsaa? What the hell is this?
It's Dibe' Ni'tsaa.
- We're gonna meet someone there.
- Who?
That's enough questions, all right?
Just do what I tell you to do.
Now what the fuck are you doing?
Well, I'm just trying to make up a little time.
I have to be at Morton's at 7:00.
That sounds like a faggot.
Is he your butt buddy?
- No, he is a restaurant.
- That sounds like a faggot restaurant.
Sounds like you've had experience.
I hear this is a notorious speed trap.
We should be careful.
Hey.
You wanna tear it? Let's tear it.
I'm in control now.
- Whoo!
- Oh, no.
No.
No, no, no. Stop it.
We're gonna die.
Oh, shit!
We hit 118. Detroit iron, man. Whoo!
- Yeah.
- You're crazy.
Victoria, I wonder if he
has forgotten us.
Mrs. Reynolds, you have a phone call.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Thanks.
- Hello?
- Hi, Victoria.
Chip, where is he?
- Michael told me that...
- He disappeared.
What?
Go slow.
Well, that's a balanced meal.
Can I help you?
Thirty dollars on Number 5.
Sixty-four fifty.
Out of a hundred.
You know, miss, you really
shouldn't be smoking around that infant.
There's no ventilation here at all.
Secondary smoke definitely can do
irreparable damage...
...to a respiratory system that young.
Thirty-five fifty is your change.
- What are you, a fucking doctor?
- Well, as a matter of fact...
I don't need nobody telling me
how to take care of my kid.
You want this job, asshole?
Miss, if you knew the statistics,
I'm sure you wouldn't take that attitude.
Fuck you.
Keep frying up those mentholated lights,
and junior will end up looking just like me.
Both of you two,
get the hell out of here right now.
Or I'm calling my boyfriend.
K-BAFM at the top of the hour.
Lucky 108 FM, the tristate home
of classic rock from the '60s, '70s and '80s.
Rocking on glitter platforms
with David Bowie, with "Suffragette City"
Secondary smoke
can cause irreparable damage...
...to a respiratory system that young.
That's all right, man.
Yeah, that's all right. That's fine.
You know, my wife is probably having
a nervous breakdown right now.
I missed the most important dinner
of my life.
Yes, everything is all right.
It's just peachy.
You know, a lot of weird shit
happens in life.
What are those?
Just some A's, man.
Amphetamines.
Well, live it up, you know. Live it up.
Candy bars, alcohol, cigarettes.
The human body
is a remarkable and resilient thing...
...but you can't continue
with this kind of abuse.
- Your white blood count is extremely low.
- Oh, fuck that.
White blood count and red blood count,
you think I give a fuck about either one?
Is it any worse
than the shit you give me?
You're gonna have to crash sometime.
I promise you.
You think you know what's good for me.
You don't know shit, man.
It's all explanatory how I gets wicked
But it's mandatory that I just kick it
- Pull over.
- What?
Pull over.
Why are we pulling over? I think...
No, no, no, man. Way over.
This does not look safe.
It's not safe.
It's only beautiful.
What?
Keep rolling.
- What was that?
- Cattle guard.
- It's cool, cool.
- Huh?
It's cool.
- Just stop here, stop.
- Stop here? I'm not stopping here.
Why are we stopping here?
To sleep.
To sleep?
You know, we're gonna get shot
by some rancher out here after all this.
No, ain't no ranchers out here.
Mountain lions, maybe.
No, no, no, you know what?
There ain't no mountain lions out here.
I think there's devil worshippers, man.
They cut us up and drink our blood.
This looks like the kind of place
they'd hang.
Would you be quiet, please?
No, you...
Aliens.
There's aliens out here.
Little white motherfuckers.
- Would you please be quiet?
- The Army knows about this shit.
They've been keeping it a secret.
They've got these spaceships up there.
- They beam us up and cut us up with lasers.
- Would you please be quiet?
Good night, doctor.
Good night.
He's out there, man.
He's out there.
Good news.
There's no blood and no body.
- That's what the sheriff's office says.
- Oh, I think that's very reassuring, Victoria.
I sent Callie off with Rosa this morning.
I just couldn't bear to tell her
why Michael's mother's flying in.
Don't worry, honey.
I mean, he's only a 16-year-old boy.
Please, God, let him be gone.
Let him be gone.
I'll never cheat
another insurance company.
I'll buy Victoria the house.
Whatever it takes, I...
Just please, God, I beg you.
Just let me get out of this,
let me get out of this.
Yeah.
Good morning, doc.
Let's go.
Subhuman piece of shit.
Please leave a message at the beep.
Hello? This is Brandon Monroe.
I'm in Arizona.
I'm on my way.
Everything is cool. Let's roll.
I said, let's roll.
Look, Blue, I'm losing my mind.
I'm...
If you put that gun away
and let me out right now...
... I'll forget this everhappened,
I won't press charges, I swear to God.
Man, you as dumb as two bricks.
I'm dumb?
Right now, there is a manhunt underway
for you and me, my friend.
I'm talking FBI, state police.
Our pictures our probably plastered
all over the front page.
- Don't flatter yourself, man.
- The next time we stop for gas...
And by the way, this baby
is getting about 10 miles per gallon.
The next time we stop anywhere
for anything...
... this whole charade
is over, finished, done, finito.
Anywhere, huh?
Yeah, okay, all right.
Pull in here right now.
Right here.
Looks like nobody read
the front pages yet.
When you're checking out the menu, Mr.
Glock is gonna be looking at your dick.
So try to give any rope, any,
you will make the front page.
You know what I'm saying? So sit down.
Breakfast?
The special?
- What is the special?
- It's on the menu.
Two strips of bacon,
eggs, sunny-side up,
hash browns, some fried perch
and a side of tartar sauce.
Do you have anything that would
constitute nourishment on the menu?
We got what we got
and we don't got what we don't got.
Do you got carrot juice?
No, we got carrots.
Two specials.
And a carrot.
Nice tits, huh?
I beg your pardon?
You were checking out her tits.
I wasn't checking out anything.
Yeah, you were.
You were checking them.
Nice ass too, huh?
What would your wife say?
Why don't you grow
some pubic hair, junior.
I got pubic hair, asshole.
It's the one place I got hair left.
You're lucky.
You better eat up, man.
We won't be hanging here all day.
Hey, Fuzz.
You know, it might be wise to take
a breath between bites once in a while.
What do you care how I eat
or what I eat?
There's some relationship...
... between what you're putting
in your body and the state it's in.
You should see the shit
they give us in jail.
Horse cock and piss.
They kick it through the pie door.
Shit will kill you.
Yeah.
I knew I could make it.
Do you have any family, Blue?
My pops, my real father,
he was a down motherfucker, man,
but he's dead.
My mother died in jail too.
My brothers are all locked up and shit.
My sister, she's raising
two kids by herself.
Do you have any friends?
All the G's,
the ones I used to hang with,
they're all Glocked up or locked up
except Smokes.
I don't know nobody out there no more.
You see, I was 13 when I went to jail,
now I'm 16.
Nobody knows who I am no more.
You know what I'm saying?
I grown old.
I have a daughter. She's 3.
I have a picture. Would you like to see it?
Why the fuck not?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
That's my wife on the right
and my daughter on the left, obviously.
I worry about her growing up.
She looks nice. What's her name?
Calantha. Callie.
My mother's idea.
It's a nice name.
Yeah, I like a different name.
My homegirl's name was Leilani.
Leilani. I like that.
She was the one that got me shot up.
Bitch set me up.
You a pretty good father, man?
You'd have to ask Callie.
You could be acting the father role,
which maybe you're not, you know.
My foster father,
used to beat the shit out of me...
... and his other kids with his belt,
with the end with the buckle.
Every night
he could get his hands on us.
Sick motherfucker, man.
I should have peeled his cap a lot sooner.
It was always, "You little half-breed.
You little red nigger."
I'm the one he always tied up.
I used to go crazy
when I heard him coming.
But I knew where he kept his gat.
A 9 mm Mr. Ruger.
So one night,
he put it to my foster mom real bad.
He tied her to the radiator,
made us watch that shit.
So that was the night
I killed his ass with his own gun.
I didn't even think about it twice.
Bam, bam, bam!
You gonna eat your food?
No, you wanna kill yourself,
be my guest.
How's that carrot, man?
Listen, Blue, I'm talking to you now
human being to human being.
Oh, you mean,
like an emotional conversation?
You could call it that.
Yeah, I like to sit back
and just conversate.
Well, if you want me to drive you
to this sacred mountain...
... or wherever, or whomever,
that's fine, I don't mind driving.
I just...
I want to see my wife
and daughter again.
That's all I want.
That's all... That's all...
Don't get so pumped up.
You're getting all pumped up.
You look like you're having a nic fit.
You want a smoke?
No, thank you.
I would like to urinate, if that's okay.
Go ahead. Urinate.
Thank you.
Shoot the ball.
Excuse me.
Hey, man, check it out.
Frenchman something or other.
I didn't notice the entire name.
It's a bar, a diner, for chrissakes.
I'm in Shitsville, Arizona.
How should I know?
Just get someone here.
He's got a gun, a very large gun.
You're a motherfucking liar.
- Help, help!
- What's the matter?
He wanted to suck my dick.
I was hitching a ride to the res.
He promised to buy me breakfast.
- Son of a...
- Oh, fuck, just what I need.
Gentlemen, I am a married man
with a child.
Do I look like a homosexual to you?
Stupid motherfucker.
Goddamn it.
You fucking son of a bitch. I'll kill you.
Well, you can't suck his dick
but you can sure as hell suck mine.
Damn it, take it outside!
You know better than that.
Let's go, come on!
Come on, get him out of here.
- Take it outside!
- You fucking faggot!
- Damn it, stay out!
- Lower than whale shit, get him up.
Hold him.
Hop in, shithead.
Fucker! Son of a bitch!
Motherfucker.
Fuck, come on, man.
Get in the fucking truck.
Let's go, man.
We're gonna be running
the side roads from now.
You maniac! They were gonna kill me!
I thought you were trying
to talk straight up to me.
I should've taken you out
back there. Fuck.
Shit.
Oh, great. Now let's have a shootout.
Goddamn it.
Get behind the wheel.
If you could drive like that,
what do you need me for?
Because I'm dying, asshole.
We got a 911 call from a Dr. Reynolds.
Mrs. Reynolds.
I'm so glad you're here.
I'm so worried.
Grandma, Grandma, Grandma.
Daddy's lost.
My girl, my favorite angel.
Wonderful to see you.
- Oh, well, now she's so big.
- Give Grandma a kiss.
Hey, Earl.
Come on, let's go pay.
Come on, move it.
I said, let's go pay for gas.
Hey! You goddamn fool,
that was all your money, right?
All the fucking money.
- I'll beat the shit out of you.
- Go ahead and beat me.
Give me your watch.
Give me your watch, you fucking punk.
I should've blown up your Porsche.
You sick motherfucker.
No, I'm the doctor.
You're the sick little motherfucker.
No fucking way.
There's six rows of pumping
and a truck jamming...
... between us and the cashier.
Nobody's gonna hear nothing,
you know what I'm saying?
Give me the ring or you're gonna die.
I'll peel your cap, point-blank.
You go ahead and peel my cap,
you little bastard.
I'm afraid we're gonna have to go
30,000 rads, doc.
Make that 50,000 rads.
Strap the motherfucker in,
pull the switch.
God.
Oh, you're gonna have to die sometime.
But before you do,
I'm gonna tell you something.
Something this big OG once told me.
He was no regular person
off the reservation.
He knew where the animals go.
He knew where they were gonna come,
and where they were gonna go.
He was from Shiprock.
A full-blown medicine man.
We kicked it at night sitting at a campfire,
listening to him tell stories.
And one of them I never forgot.
You wanna hear it?
Sixty thousand rads!
Torch the motherfucker!
Oh, looks like you wanna hear it.
You see, long ago there was this family
that had two brothers.
One was small and strong,
the other was big and weak.
The weak one got sicker and sicker.
He was dying, he couldn't walk.
Take it.
So his family...
- It doesn't fit me anymore.
- They called for every medicine man.
Like from every reservation,
even the Utes and Apache.
But nobody could do shit about it.
Then, like, at sunrise one morning,
Mighty Mike.
this beetle climbed up
on the sick boy's bed.
I want you to do something for me.
Say yes.
So his family...
And they're fast runners too, man.
They chase the sun when it comes up and
run away from it when it goes down.
For me, Mikey.
Mighty Mike.
This beetle climbed up
by the sick boy's bed.
No.
They loved the sun,
these tiger beetles. They're tough.
And they're fast runners too.
They chase the sun when it comes up...
... and they run away from it
when it starts to go down.
The Sunchaser, he said a prayer
and he told the boy:
"Follow me to the lake
on the sacred mountain.
If you swim in its waters,
it will cure you of all your disease."
Shit. For four fucking days,
the Sunchaser came at sunrise.
And for four days, he said his prayer
and made his promise.
But nobody believed the boy when he
told them about the Sunchaser's promise.
Nobody, except finally his brother.
He was small but he was tough, cabron.
He was the only one
that was really down for his brother.
So at next sunrise, the younger brother...
... rode with his older brother
on his horse.
They went from sunrise,
following the Sunchaser.
They rode for fucking days
until they reached that mountain.
And when they did,
the younger brother,
he climbed up that mountain
with his sick older brother on his back.
You see it.
Do you know what I'm saying?
And he put him in the water.
And he started to swim.
And there was nothing wrong
with him no more.
Nothing at all.
I learned a lot of down shit
from that old medicine man.
May beauty be before me,
may beauty be behind me
May beauty be above me,
may beauty be below me
May beauty be all around me
I got a heart just like you do.
See, when I got sick, like...
... nobody cared about me.
You know, you think you're gonna die
and they're like...
I was in jail
hoping for someone to help me.
I wrote to that
old medicine man from jail.
He made me that prayer
to say whenever I felt bad.
And just like the Sunchaser,
he told me...
... that he would take me
to that lake on the sacred mountain...
... and drive out all of my sickness.
And if you think you're gonna stop me
from getting there, you're dead wrong.
You ain't deep enough.
Damn.
Well, what do you know?
The Black Talking God
must be with you today.
Maybe I'll kill you, maybe I won't.
Now, I'll get us some gas.
Fill it up, please, on 16.
Sixteen.
Haven't I seen you on TV?
Oh, goodness, no.
You look just like that gal
on Designing Women.
- What's her name?
- I don't watch television.
I bet you tell that to everybody.
You're right, I do.
- I don't think that's your name.
- No, that's my name.
- And I'll be right back to sign
my autograph. - Right.
Twenty dollars on pump 16.
There was also
considerable property damage.
And two motorcycles were,
shall we say, maliciously destroyed.
Perhaps I missed a beat.
Just what the hell
are you people insinuating?
My husband is the hostage here.
No one is insinuating anything.
Your husband made a judgment call.
He took it upon himself to demand...
... that a youthful offender
be transported to another facility.
A patient, a terminally ill adolescent.
Mrs. Reynolds, believe me,
no one would call them adolescents.
Mrs. Reynolds, to your knowledge,
has your husband ever been treated
for any kind of emotional problems?
I'm afraid
I don't understand the question.
Are there any areas,
any areas of your husbands past,
that he doesn't talk about?
I'm not intimidated
by police technique, Mr. Collier.
So please don't treat me
as you do everyone else.
It's information I need, Mrs. Reynolds.
My husband is a healthy,
rational, loving man.
The only emotional problem he has
is the gun that's been put to his head.
Fuck!
Motherfucker!
Beautiful.
You know, Blue,
I wish there were a sacred mountain,
I really do.
I wish there were
a magic lake on top of it...
that could take away all your pain
and make you well again.
But there is no sacred mountain.
There is no magic
that's going to cure you.
And the longer you spend searching
for it, the more you're going to suffer.
- Do you understand what I'm saying?
- Yeah, I understand.
I understand you're full of shit.
- You need medical attention.
- I need more than that.
You need me, but you don't trust me...
... because of all the stereotypes
you have about white people.
Hey, I ain't no racist, man.
I'm in the jungle, you're in the hills
looking down at me.
And you want me to think
that my life depends on you? Fuck you!
Okay, fine.
But think again,
it starts with little beads of sweat.
And then comes the coughing,
sometimes uncontrollable.
And then the chills
and the shivering.
And then when your liver
starts to shut down...
... you slip into a coma.
Why don't you let me
take you to a hospital?
Why don't you stick your head up your
ass and see what you really look like.
Okay. Fuck it!
And fuck you!
You think because you saw
some picture in some book...
... that some asshole drew
in 1850-whatever-the-hell...
... that you're just gonna pull up
in front of it like it's Disneyland?
It ain't no Disneyland, man.
It's real.
It's one of the sacred mountains.
- Ain't nothing sacred to you?
- Of course there is.
What?
Oh, look.
Look, it's the holy mountain.
And there's the medicine man waving at us.
And there's Dorothy and the Tin Man
and the Wizard of Oz and th...
Oh, I've been bitten by a rattlesnake.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
I'm gonna die right out here. Oh, God.
I'm already tachycardic.
I'm gonna have
an endocardial hemorrhage.
Oh, what am I doing?
I don't even have a watch.
What...?
Let it burn. Electricity neutralizes
the protein in the snake venom.
I can't talk proper English.
You amaze me.
Why? Because you thought I was dumb?
You think I don't use my mind?
No, I don't think you're dumb...
What the fuck do you think?
- About what?
About me, any of your patients.
You think about them?
Yes, of course.
- About the way they feel?
- Yes.
Who you shitting, motherfucker?
You ain't got the balls for it.
Indian people believe,
you bit by a snake...
... it's because of something bad
you done to someone else.
There's something crawling in you, man.
Your mind ain't in tune to your heart.
Do you know what I'm saying?
Where are you going?
I don't even understand
how you're walking.
By rights, you should be dead by now.
Can we stop for a minute?
I've just been bitten by a rattlesnake.
I'll stop when I can't see straight.
That's when I'll stop.
Where are we going?
Stop, please. Could you please stop?
Please, just stop. Stop.
Could you please just stop?
Hello? Stop.
Okay, now, if you would just
keep going when we get to...
Just keep going. Don't stop for this...
Don't stop, trust me.
Please, he's dangerous. Don't stop.
- This is rough territory.
- God.
- You in?
- Thanks.
Hang on.
Are you here for the Convergence?
The Harmonic Convergence?
Do you mind if I put my leg up?
I've been bitten by a...
There are hundreds of people here
for the Convergence.
This whole area is a power point.
I'm going into Flagstaff for supplies.
We're headed to Flagstaff. Cool.
You know, I'm really picking
up some weird energies from you two.
- Maybe you've seen us on the news.
- Shut up.
I don't listen to news.
- Well, allow me to fill you in.
- Shut up.
I'm terminally ill.
- I'm not gonna hurt you.
- I wouldn't count on it.
I said shut up, motherfucker!
Excuse me.
We're actually headed
up north of Flagstaff.
Up Shiprock way.
- Are you Navajo?
- No, he's fugitive.
My real father was Navajo.
That's what I am.
- I'm going to one of the sacred
mountains. - I love sacred mountains.
You see, there's this magic lake
on top of this mountain,
but no white man believes
that its waters are magic.
Oh, here we go.
Water is a highly concentrated element...
... with great healing power
simply awaiting release.
If you sick and you swim in its waters,
it will take away all your sickness.
Oh, how very beautiful.
Did you hear the one
about Goldilocks and the three bears?
You don't care
what anybody believes, do you?
No.
You don't have an ear for faith.
So naturally you will not allow
that throughout history...
... there have occurred innumerable
cases of instantaneous healing.
Diseased tissues rendered whole
in a flash of time.
If I could continue with my point...
The fine vibrations of the mind...
... can act on the lower vibrations
of diseased tissue.
Would you like some water?
- I'm starving. Do you have any food?
- No.
Thanks.
The Navajo are very spiritual people.
Excuse me, this spiritual master
just escaped from a California prison.
I'm his hostage.
How do you do?
I'm Michael Reynolds, Dr. Michael Reynolds.
I'm Renata Baumbauer,
Dr. Renata Baumbauer, Ph.D.
He gave me one month to live.
I had no choice, y'know what I'm saying?
Is that true? Did you tell him
he only had one month to live?
Yes.
The only thing worse
than a lawyer is a doctor.
Nine hundred to Control.
Nine hundred, go ahead.
Okay, Sector 8, there's no sign.
No sign, Sector 8.
I bet you're a Leo.
Leo people tend to be bombastic.
Are you a Leo?
I have an Uncle Leo, he's an atheist.
The man really breaks me up.
He don't cop to nothing.
I hope you've been
very successful, doctor.
Because I am now
just about convinced...
... that Western medicine will
forever regard symptoms of disease...
... as simply errors to be corrected
by drugs and surgery.
- Well, I... - You doctors will never
do us any good...
... until you wake up
and learn not to poison us.
Hey, don't look at me, man.
I didn't say nothing.
She gave you a lot of rope,
but she kicks the truth.
Yeah, well,
I've had just about enough of this bullshit.
Cancer.
Excuse me?
You are definitely a Leo, Cancer rising.
Leos look for
what they can get out of life.
At war with your home-loving other self.
Leos should wear rubies.
They bring serenity of mind.
I'm a Sagittarius, the sign of philosophy.
Higher learning and broad concepts.
I wear turquoise.
The doc's got a magic charm too.
That ring, that fly little silver one.
Yeah, he'd rather die than give it up.
You know, normally silver
relieves stress.
And enhances emotional balance.
Though perhaps in your case,
silver caused some toxic reaction.
Your state of mind is fucked up, man.
"There is nothing as important as DNA.
It carries the hereditary information
that determines the structure of proteins.
The only substance that directs cells
to grow and divide are encoded by it.
DNA. Deoxyribonucleic acid.
It is the essential constituent of life."
Watson and Crick,
The Double Helix, 1953.
"All healing comes from
the divine within.
Absolute faith makes fear
and worry an impossibility."
Edgar Cayce, 1943.
It seem the rain will never let up
I try to keep my head up
And still keep from getting wet up
It's funny when it rain, it pours
They got money for wars
But can't feed the poor
Tupac, 1994.
Come on, check it out.
- Car's clear.
- Okay.
You. You, back a bit.
You two head up the road.
Check up there.
Don and DeLane, check that way.
See if there's anybody over the ledge.
What's in the car?
He's got a battery cable.
Are you sure
this is where you wanna get off?
Not exactly my first choice.
It's been memorable.
Thank you very much.
I mean it, you know.
The meaning behind your words is cool.
Forgive yourself, Dr. Reynolds.
For what?
For whatever it was
that closed your heart.
And never go barefoot
to a snake-stomping.
Lunatic.
Can we please slow down?
I have been bitten by a rattlesnake.
Hello? This is Brandon Monroe.
I'm in Flagstaff. I'm almost there.
Everything's cool.
I don't like the way you look.
I never liked the way you look.
No, I mean it. You don't look...
You look like hell.
It's about 50 miles
before we get to Shiprock country.
No, you've got no miles left in you.
You have to let me
take you to a hospital.
And I mean now.
Fuck you.
The way you walk.
The way you talk.
The way you act.
The way you carry yourself.
You don't understand
a fucking word I say.
How can I? Half of what you say
sounds like it's in a foreign language.
I don't need you anymore, anyway.
I can get there myself.
The only place you're gonna get to
is in a fucking coma.
I've been there already.
You need to be in a hospital.
Don't yell.
That hurt.
So fuck off.
You need to be in a hospital.
What the fuck's your problem?
I got you down as gone.
So why don't you get the fuck gone?
Go.
Okay, I can go. I can go.
I'm going, I'm going.
Oh, now I can go?
Suddenly I have your permission?
After you've ruined my career.
Put a gun on me for a thousand miles.
You nearly popped me and peeled me.
Now suddenly I can go?
Without even an apology?
My apologies.
Fuck you.
You don't have to worry about your fever,
you're gonna kill yourself in this thing.
- See you around.
- Pull over.
Let me drive this thing
before you kill yourself.
Somebody's stealing
Deacon Clay's Cadillac.
Stop the goddamn car
and let me drive!
God, is that my car too?
Stop the goddamn car
and let me drive.
Are we here?
Yes, we're here.
Hey, wait a minute.
Flagstaff Medical Center.
I'm taking you into the emergency room.
Fuck. I knew you were lying to me.
You have developed pneumonia.
That is why you have a fever.
That is what I've been trying to tell you
about your lung infection.
Your white blood count is down.
If you do not get an immediate IV of
antibiotics, you'll slip into a coma...
... which you're never gonna come out of
and that's no bullshit.
No! No hospital.
If you don't get out of that car
right now...
... and I mean right now,
I'm gonna kill you myself.
Right on. Right on, then.
You know, Indians, they believe
sickness is payback for doing wrong.
Well, don't...
I've done a lot of bad shit.
If I can't square it, if I can't get
there, I'm gonna peel my cap right now.
No, don't do that.
You give me that
"your life depends on me" shit...
... I'll kill your ass with me.
Give me the gun, Blue.
I feel sorry for you.
Maybe it's like Renata said.
You don't believe in nothing
but yourself.
- Give me the gun.
- What's wrong?
You scared to watch somebody die?
Give me the gun, Blue.
Why? You wanna do it for me?
Give me the fucking gun!
I'll be right back.
With the man, right?
You're gonna dime on me.
- You don't know anything about me.
- Yeah, I do.
You never broke a law
in your whole life.
You have all the paperwork?
Yeah, I got it right here.
- Can I help you?
- Hi.
I'm Dr. Newman from Gynecology.
Here to pick up
Progesterone suppositories.
I called them down this morning.
They should be in the refrigerator.
- Dr. Newman?
- Gynecology.
I'll go check.
Thank you.
Where is it?
There it is.
Okay.
Ceftazidime. Bingo.
Hey, what are you doing?
Nothing.
I must be insane.
Hold it right there.
Let's roll.
Damn.
BLUE:
Keep your hands on the wheel and drive.
Get in.
You used the gun?
Only as a visual aid.
I would've paid to see that.
A straight white guy robbing a store.
"JCR." Who is that?
It's my big brother.
Jimmy.
He ain't around no more.
You two were really down
for each other, huh?
He was sick too.
He had a malignant tumor.
He was 11 when he was diagnosed.
My mother and I used to wheel him
to school in a wheelchair.
I put studs in the tires.
He was tough just like you.
A fighter.
I remember one time...
... we went to Mexico for Thanksgiving.
Acapulco.
And he was sunning himself on a raft,
you know, in the pool.
Fuck you.
Oh, no, that's a healthy "fuck you."
So he's out there sunning himself when
he had this sombrero over his face...
... and I don't know
what I was thinking.
I wanted to test the strength
of that sombrero.
So I got up on to the diving board
and jumped on it.
He came out of there,
he was mad as a hornet.
Chased me for an hour.
He was your age
when he went into the hospital full-time.
He hated that fucking place.
Yeah, it was cold, marble, sterile.
He said it was a place
where you went to die.
You're looking better already,
you know that?
And they gave him everything
for the pain...
... but nothing seemed to work.
Pain was unimaginable.
I want you to do something for me.
I want you to turn off the machine.
No.
- Don't be afraid.
- No.
No. No.
Don't be afraid.
You know, I...
Just do it.
At first, I couldn't do it,
and I told him so.
Mighty Mike.
But then, after a few minutes...
It's a trade, okay?
It's okay.
Okay.
And then I ran and I ran
and I ran and I ran and I ran.
You never talk personal on it before.
No.
I think we're stable.
You think this heap will make it
all the way to Shiprock?
Jam it, holmes.
This is Cynthia Allison, reporting
live from Flagstaff, Arizona,
where there has been a startling new
twist in the Dr. Reynolds kidnapping.
Michael Reynolds,
appearing live and well...
I'm so glad you're here.
Witnesses say
he was armed with a handgun.
All he said was, "Hold it right there."
And I put my hands up.
Apparently, some antibiotics,
steroids, syringes...
... and several dextrose-filled IV bags
were stolen from the pharmacy.
Reynolds' wife, Victoria, could not be...
- That's Daddy.
- ... reached for comment.
We'll be staying tight on this story.
We haven't seen anything this strange
since Patty Hearst took up with the SLA.
I never liked Reynolds.
- You never...
- Since day one.
- Hello?
- Dr. Byrnes?
I have a collect call from Dr. Reynolds.
Will you accept the charges?
Don't talk, listen.
I want you to tell Victoria
something for me.
- Chip.
- Michael, where the fuck are you?
Tell her I miss her and I love her
and I'll see her soon.
And give my love to Callie.
And...
I'm all right. I'm all right.
See you.
You want me to call the medicine man?
Tell him we're on our way?
He knows.
Well, I'm sorry
that we had to stop you this morning...
... but we're looking for fugitives.
They might be in a white Cadillac.
We're in Navajo land, holmes.
Shit.
Fuck. Son of a bitch.
More judas. We're fucked.
What are you doing?
I don't know.
Is that a car?
Just some Indian boys
driving some horses.
Livestock or people,
it's always a battle.
Hi.
Nice horses.
Just a little stomachache, holmes.
Check me out, man.
My father was Mike Her Many Horses.
I got it.
Excuse me, you on the tan horse.
Can we take car?
Go down?
- Down?
- What are you trying to say, man?
Whoo-hoo!
Hey, you drive pretty good
for a white man.
This is young Reynolds' first year
at Daytona...
... but we get the feeling
we'll be seeing more of him.
- You the man, doc.
- Whoo! Yeah.
Mighty Mike.
What was that medicine man's name?
Webster Skyhorse.
Hello?
You sure he's expecting you?
What did he say?
Nothing.
Nothing?
I don't understand.
You talked to him on the phone, right?
I didn't talk to nobody.
You didn't talk to nobody.
What do you mean, you didn't talk
to nobody? What about the medicine man?
Webster Skyhorse?
Guy who sent you the book?
Last time I saw him, I was 8 years old.
I never heard from him again.
You're joking, right?
No, man.
Everything's cool.
What about the sacred mountain?
The holy people? Wha...?
The lake?
No white man
has ever believed in its magic.
Sounds like a lot
of Indian woo-woo shit, don't it?
Right up there with rain dances
and talking coyotes.
Do you know where I got this book?
I stole it from the library in jail.
You white people donate
a lot of dumb shit at Christmas time...
You know what I'm saying?
But everything's still cool.
Everything's cool.
Everything is cool.
You warped little fuck!
I knew you were a fake.
I'm a goddamn fugitive!
For what?
A lot of shuck and jive.
That's for what.
I gave up everything.
My reputation, out the window.
Director of Oncology,
out the fucking window.
Don't get all jacked up.
So don't tell me
it's just a lot of woo-woo shit.
It can't be woo-woo shit.
We came here to find the sacred
mountain, and we're gonna find it.
I'm gonna find it.
You're nutting up on me, man.
Don't nut up on me, doc.
What are you doing here?
This is private property.
Can't be the IRS.
They drive Chryslers.
Who are you?
I'm Michael Reynolds.
Dr. Michael Reynolds.
I'm an oncologist in Los Angeles.
This is my patient.
They were talking about you
on Good Morning America.
Really?
You have television?
No. I get Good Morning America
by smoke signal.
What are you doing out here?
We came to find the sacred mountain,
Dibe' Ni'tsaa.
Just show her the book.
Show her the book.
It's just a book he's showing you.
Here's a picture of it. Check it out.
You're the one who keeps leaving messages
on my machine for my grandfather?
The medicine man, Webster Skyhorse?
That's right.
That's great.
That's who we're here to see.
He can show us
where the sacred mountain is.
My grandfather may be a medicine man,
but he's also been a lot of other things.
Now he's playing hide-and-seek
with the IRS.
I just come by to feed his dog.
Happy trails, cowboys.
Listen to me.
That boy is dying.
And he's dying the hard way.
Abdominal cancer.
The only person who's meant a damn
to him in his short miserable life...
... is your grandfather.
That may be hard to believe,
but that is why he's here.
That is all he's got left.
Who are you, his great white savior?
Federal boarding schools are full
of half-breed Indian boys just like him.
I work with them every day.
They're my people. Mine.
I've seen enough college-degree white
people like you to last me 10 lifetimes.
So why don't you just leave?
Does that look like my car?
I traded in a brand-new
Porsche 911 Turbo for this.
I've been beaten up,
bitten by a rattlesnake.
I've been humiliated
by some lunatic astrologer in a van.
I haven't shaved,
or brushed my teeth, or bathed...
... or changed my underwear
in three days.
I have dirt in every pore of my body.
You want us to leave,
you're gonna have to shoot me.
In fact, I would prefer it.
You'd be doing me a personal favor.
Go ahead. Here, shoot me.
Blue.
Blue. Blue, come on.
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Blue. Come on.
Blue.
Come on, look at me.
Look at me.
Here's some water.
Blue?
Come on. Come on. Come on, Blue.
Look at me.
Look at me. Come on.
Blue.
You scare me like that again,
I'll kill you.
Blah, blah, blah.
We're almost there, Blue.
Take this road going north.
It will become another dirt road,
and curve east.
At the point where three streams
become one...
... follow the west fork.
Lost Canyon Creek.
That is the way.
Thank you.
Dr. Reynolds?
Dr. Reynolds.
For you,
there's probably nothing up there...
... except a lot of rock,
and snow and grief.
Very deep grief.
But to the Navajo Nation,
it is a dwelling place for the spirits.
The shapes the earth takes
to tell its stories.
Don't go there
unless you're prepared to listen.
My God.
I don't believe it. It's beautiful.
Nine-oh-two to Control.
We have a forest service report
of a possible sighting...
... in the vicinity of Hesper's Peak.
Proceed there directly.
Report approaching Three Forks, over.
Ten-four.
Don't be afraid.
Just do it.
For me, Mikey.
Mighty Mike.
Come on. Come on, you can make it.
Come on. You can make it.
Come on.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, you can make it.
Remember the lake.
We're almost there at the lake.
The magic lake, Blue.
Nine-oh-two to 900.
Nine-oh-two, go ahead.
We believe that the subject vehicle
is a white Caddy...
... parked south-southeast in Grid 3.
- Say again.
- Roger.
We believe that the subject vehicle
is a white Caddy...
... parked south-southeast in Grid 3.
- Nine hundred to control.
- Nine hundred, go ahead.
Sector 11, I've got tire tracks
in sight.
Nine-oh-two to 900.
Nine-oh-two, go ahead.
Roger. I'm at your six.
About three miles back,
just coming up on Three Forks.
Nine hundred to Control.
I have the subject vehicle
in sight right now.
Come on. Come on.
I can do it myself.
Let somebody help you
for once in your life.
Come on.
Nine hundred to Control.
- Nine hundred, go ahead.
- Ten-four. I've been through Grid 8.
Thought I saw a glimmer.
I'm gonna go back and have another look.
Where is it?
Where's the goddamn lake?
It's okay, man.
It's okay.
No, it's not. It's not okay.
Oh, shit. What now?
What's he saying?
He's saying, "Thank you.
Thank you for bringing me here."
Sure.
It's no problem.
Does he believe in the lake?
Does he believe in the power
of its waters?
Now you got me talking like you.
White people...
... have never believed the power
of the Dibe' Ni'tsaa.
Yes, but what about the magic lake?
Can it really do...?
Can it really do what they say?
Can it really do that?
What do you want most?
I want it to do what I can't.
I want it to...
I want you to help Blue.
He knows.
It's my time.
He's gonna take me now.
To drive the sickness out from me.
Good.
That's real good, Blue. That's good.
That's real good.
Let's go.
Wait.
You can't come.
I mean, I don't want you to.
That's okay.
Okay, you know, I'm okay with that.
I should probably get back
before I see my face on a milk carton.
I guess this is goodbye.
Yeah.
Thank you for saving my life, Blue.
It was no big deal, man.
A man's gotta do what he's gotta do.
Yeah.
It's been real.
You know what I'm saying?
You are real, man.
Go.
Go. Get out of here.
I got you down as gone.
Blue?
Catch.
It's yours.
You practically killed me for it.
Watch out for the Judas, man.
Blue.
Blue?
Yeah?
We made it.
Nine hundred to Control,
I have the subject in sight.
Fuck!
May beauty be before me
May beauty be behind me
May beauty be above me
May beauty be below me
May beauty be all around me