FILM MAKER WITH SUPPORT FROM
NEW DANISH SCREEN
A FILM BY SØREN BALLE
Lars!
Check that it's running properly.
It's okay!
Yes!
THE SUNFISH
So Lise was down at the inn.
- Is she the wee fat one?
- She's not fat. Just a bit heavy.
So I'm talking to her at the inn
and it's going alright.
I'm thinking I'm halfway in,
but it turns out she has a boyfriend.
She could have told me that.
I sat there for an hour.
What a cockteaser.
14, 15, 20.
Two for you! 25!
- Kesse!
- Yes.
- Come to the meeting room, okay?
Listen. The technical university
wants to do some studies.
They want to send biologists out.
They'll repay with 3 tons cod.
- I'll take a handful then.
- Easy now.
- They want the Danish seines.
- That's you Kesse.
- I'm not taking anyone.
- It's 3 tons fish.
- They're just making our life hard.
- Times are changing, Kesse.
Yeah, in the old days
they'd be thrown in the water.
You're such a dinosaur, Kesse.
- See you tomorrow.
- Sorte! Fisherman's swim!
Kesse!
Phuket, Thailand. Lisbeth will book
tickets tomorrow. How about that?
- Say you want to come.
- No, thanks.
You need to get out
and go on a holiday.
I'm not going anywhere.
Oh. Suit yourself.
Okay! Everybody come over here.
Hey! Throw the balls to me.
I'm not going to say this again.
Get out of the water.
We'll continue we're we left off.
It was backstrokes.
Move your arms like mill wheels near
the ears. No talking while you swim.
The legs go like this. Okay?
Yes! Balls up here, please!
You do backstrokes on your back,
okay?
Minor detail. Push your stomach up.
That's it.
And put your head down.
And now the arms. Okay?
I've told you before. No smoking!
We have a smoking ban.
Smoke outside or stop coming here.
Kesse!
- You're very quiet today.
- Yes.
Come on. Cough it up.
- It's the finances.
- Oh.
- Could you help me out?
- How much is it?
Well
100 or 150 to shut Ole up
until I'm back on track.
- 150,000?
- Yes.
Or 100,000.
Or maybe just 80,000. I don't know.
- I don't have that much, Kesse.
- I doesn't matter.
- Focus, Lars.
- All right, all right.
No undersizes.
We need a good price.
- All right, all right.
- Drop that. Do your job properly.
All right, all right. All right.
Why are you so cranky today? Did
you get up on the wrong side of bed?
- Are there more?
- They were the last ones.
I think we have visitors, Kesse.
Inspections.
- Hi there.
- Hello.
- I'll check up here.
- Yes.
- Did you unload?
- Yes. There's nothing left.
- Can we have a look below?
- Sure.
Everything looks okay.
There's nothing down here.
- Did you think you'd find anything?
- I had hoped.
- There's always hope.
- No, everything is okay.
Goodbye.
Hello, Pia. The usual.
- Didn't you see the new menu?
- No.
- Do you like it?
- What's wrong with the old one?
- Do you want to try a new dish?
- No, just the usual for me.
All right.
Things have changed lately. Kirsten
no longer handles the accounts.
- Milk?
- No, just black coffee.
You had two incomes then. Plus
you were generous in the divorce.
I couldn't think straight back then.
We can conclude that the cod quotas
from 2005 were an over-investment.
- What's this about?
- Maybe you should sell the quotas.
- Sublease them for a while?
- No.
Sell them to one of the bigger boats.
You could still make a profit.
Many others have done it, Kesse.
Are you telling me
to wind everything up?
We can't keep investing in a failure.
If I sell the quotas
I'll have absolutely nothing left.
You haven't shown a constant profit
for a long period of time.
I need time to find a solution
and turn this around.
I can't give you that, Kesse.
Is that how you treat
a lifelong loyal customer?
I'm under pressure too.
It's not like I'm enjoying this.
At least give me six months.
- At least give me that.
- Okay. One month. That's all.
Shit!
- You put all the receipts in, right?
- I think so.
Did you sod them by date?
- Just January and February.
- I don't have time for that.
- That just makes it easier for her.
- That's easy for you to say.
- Did you sort by category?
- I didn't have time.
Oh ... she just prefers that.
- Yes.
- She just hates the mess.
Why don't you go outside
instead of just standing there?
We'll leave it
to the finance minister.
Søren!
All right.
You're a good fisherman, Kesse.
But that's not enough today.
- You need to be a businessman too.
- That's for sure.
Sell everything while you still can.
And just wipe the slate clean.
Wipe the slate clean? And do what?
This is all I know.
- Come work at the fish factory.
- No, thanks.
- You hate filleting all day.
- I'm doing just fine.
Do you expect me to believe that?
Numbers, quotas. That stuff is gone.
I could be in this garden all day.
I get holiday allowance.
Do you know what that is?
And I can go to Thailand with my wife
without a care. That's life.
That's your life.
- Cheers.
- It's fascinating, right?
- Yes.
And it can jump.
It suddenly rushes to the surface,
jumps and does a belly flop.
- Have you seen it do that?
- Not yet. But I've heard about it.
Perhaps you also heard,
that I'm the one who caught it.
- Right ...
- It's true.
Okay. How?
With something we call a net.
Sure.
It resembles our situation back then.
I'd advise you to get out.
- It's a vicious spiral.
- I'll work myself out of it.
- I just need new quotas.
- You'll need a loan for that.
- I have the house.
- Choose your battles.
- You can still wipe the slate clean.
- Drop the clean slate talk!
- It's aggravating.
- All right.
- Sorry about that.
- Don't be.
Hello there, Alf. How are things?
Just fine.
The weather could be better.
- Do you have any cod quotas to spare?
- It's too soon to say.
- How about plaice?
- No.
Well I need them myself
until I know how it looks.
- Why don't you try the inn?
- I will.
- Let me know if you hear anything.
- Yes, I'll call you. Take care.
- Hello.
Hello, Kesse! Good to see you.
- Did you miss me?
- Yes! It's your round.
I'm sure it is.
Katrine, give me five cold beers.
It's too soon to sublease.
- What about you, Poul?
- No.
- Help me out here.
- I'm holding on to mine.
- Boxer?
- It's too soon.
I can't believe this.
I shouldn't have bought beer.
- Yes, you should.
- Cheers.
Oh, it's you. What are you doing?
- I'm searching for quotas.
- Any luck?
No. It's either the wrong species
or zone. And they're expensive.
- Price is relative.
- No, it's a fact.
Kjeld!
Kjeld?
Kjeld? Is that offer
with the biologists still on?
What do you mean?
- 3 tons cod as a bonus, right?
- Kesse, I don't want any trouble.
- I'll have to clean up after you.
- I really need that bonus.
- It's 5 trips in all.
- All right.
- Fine.
- Thank you.
"Just give it up.
You're not getting any."
And I had just given her
a Tequila Sunrise.
So I took it back and drank it all
right in front of her.
It tastes like shit
but I wasn't giving it to her.
- Are you listening?
- Huh? Yes.
No, you're not. What did I say then?
- Something you didn't want to drink.
- You're not listening.
Kesse!
It's a woman. It's a god damn woman!
- Are you coming on more sails?
- Yes. The agreement is five.
- Five?
- That's what we agreed.
- He didn't tell me.
- No.
- I didn't know anything about this.
- Oh, it's you?
- Hello again.
- Do you know each other?
- Get moving, Lars.
- Aye aye, captain.
You must be Kristian.
I'm Gerd Bertelsen.
I'm doing regulation research.
I'll measure catch and mesh width ...
I don't care what you do. Just stay
out of the way. We're leaving now.
- Do you need help?
- Yes, please.
We look at the population and
try to make it more sustainable.
- So are you measuring all the fish?
- No. We don't have time for that.
So what do you need it for?
Primarily to improve the catch
according to the mesh width.
- Will we need to get new gear?
- Some of it is very outdated.
Lars! You can't be here. Go up there!
- Move away.
- Yes.
- It is rolling okay?
- Just fine!
- Do you have a minute?
- Yes.
- My work is for your sake too.
- Oh.
Our calculations are the basis
of a sustainable population.
- What do you know about fishing?
- A lot.
Sure. From university.
I've been fishing for 30 years.
- I know all about the population.
- Good. Then how does it look?
One day there's none.
The next there's plenty.
But if you saw the slow day,
you think that's how things are.
Stop it. All species are decreasing
in numbers. You know that.
- It's a livelihood for me.
- And when the fish are gone?
There are plenty of fish in the sea.
If you have a problem with me
I'll just find another boat.
- I don't.
- It seems like it.
This is a workplace. It's dangerous.
When I tell you to move, you move.
- But I have to stand somewhere.
- All right.
- All right what?
- I'll find a spot for you.
Good.
See you tomorrow.
Look at that ass.
I might invite her to a steak
restaurant or to some Italian place.
- Don't. I don't want any trouble.
- There won't be any trouble.
- A Copenhagener and a biologist.
- So? I'll just screw her.
- Do you not understand me?
- But ... Yes.
- Good. Now go finish up.
- All right, all right.
Just go! I'll be home soon!
Don't talk to me like that.
I want to talk to Kesse. Not you.
- Well, you can't.
- Hello, Inga.
- I brought you something.
- Are you done already?
- He's almost fully fledged.
- And I do feel like pushing him out.
- I got two different cakes here.
- You're too kind.
You need to gain weight.
Women like men with a bit of flesh.
- I'll see you at home, Lars.
- Don't come down here! Just go!
Kesse!
- That's a fancy new vehicle.
- We need to live a little.
- I hear you're in need of quotas.
- Oh?
- Plaice. 4.5 per kilo. 60 tons.
- I have all I need now.
Oh, that's right.
You like biologists after all.
- Did you want something else?
- No. That's it. Take care.
- How long have you had the boat?
- For a long time.
- Lars, can you fix the net?
- Yes.
- So how long is that?
- I don't have time to talk now.
Let's get moving, Lars.
- Fishermen don't like biologists.
- I know that.
- But I'm only the deck hand.
- Okay ...
- And I happen to like biologists.
- I see.
Especially when they look
as cute as you.
- And I thought ...
- Now, Lars!
- You probably find this hilarious.
- Not at all.
Drink some of this. Tiny gulps.
I found some patches.
I don't know if they can expire.
It goes behind the ear.
You might need
to pull your hair away.
There. And don't sit in here.
Go outside in the fresh air.
And keep your eye on the horizon.
You'll be fine.
Do you want to come outside?
- Thank you.
- What about that?
Just leave it. I'll be back.
- Thank you!
- You're welcome.
- Do you want some fish?
- Sure.
Lars, can you put them in a bag?
- How many do you want?
- Just a couple.
- Just use flour and butter.
- How much do you want?
- For you, 500 kroner.
- That's an illegal sale.
Someone's feeling all better.
Okay, so they're for free.
But the bag is 100 kroner.
See you.
- You're here?
- Yes.
- Hello, Kesse. The usual?
- Yes, please.
- What about the plaice?
- I'm afraid I burnt them.
Don't say that out loud.
This town will have your head.
- I just can't multitask.
- So how long are you here for?
A couple of months for now.
It might get extended.
I thought someone like you
would hurry back to Copenhagen.
- Someone like me?
- Yes.
Would you like
to show me around some day?
- Like some sod of tour guide?
- Yes.
Did you hear that, Pia?
A tour guide. What do you think?
You'll scare off
the rest of the tourists.
You don't have to do it.
I should be able to spare
the 15 minutes that'll take.
How about Sunday?
- So there you go.
- Thanks. Sure.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
Goodbye, Kesse.
Come in!
- Hi!
- Hello.
I'll be there in a second.
Come on in.
- I'll just wait here.
- No, come on in.
- Thanks for this. It's nice of you.
- Don't mention it.
I can start by showing you
one of our greatest sights.
This roundabout.
We're very proud of it.
Yes ... it's very nice.
- There's only one way in and out.
- That can't be true.
- I'll show you.
- That is so stupid. Go round again.
- One more? Okay, let's do it.
- Yes.
There's a bunker in the middle.
I don't know why.
- It's nuts.
- Crazy.
- One more time?
- No, let's go.
Did you always
want to be a fisherman?
My dad and granddad were fishermen
so it was kind of expected.
Wow! Oh my God.
This is so cool.
- It's not like Copenhagen.
- No.
- Actually I've never been there.
- Never?
I was one week in Tenerife
about 15 years ago. But that's it.
- You're a real adventurer.
- Yes.
- You have to see Copenhagen.
- Really?
Maybe you're right.
- I think I'd get lost.
- I'll show you around.
- Then maybe I should go some day.
- That's a deal.
- Oh my God.
- Yup.
Where's the open sign?
I hope they're not closed.
That's too bad.
I wanted to take you up there.
Why are they closed
when the weather is so nice?
I think we can get in here.
- Don't do that.
- Relax. I'll try and get in.
Do you want to get in trouble?
How long have you and Lars
been fishing together?
A long time.
- He's a funny character.
- Aren't we all more or less?
Yes, I guess so.
Lars is a good guy.
He's had a rough life.
His dad Gunnar and my dad were
fishing partners for many years.
One night we'd been out all night.
We were going for the last catch.
Gunnar got caught in the net.
There was nothing we could do.
Lars was just 13 or 14 years old.
For a few years
he had trouble readjusting.
Then his mum asked me
if I could take him on the boat.
He's been with me ever since.
So he's an okay guy.
- There we go.
- Thank you.
- Bye.
- Hello, Pia.
- The usual?
- No, wait. I'll try something new.
- Really?
- Which one do you want then?
- What's a Hawaii mix?
Sausages and fries with pineapple.
And with curry.
- It's good.
- Then get me one of those.
- Do you believe in clean slates?
- What do mean?
I don't know.
I'm just talking rubbish.
You don't get how serious this is.
A bonus is just a drop in the ocean.
It's a step in the right direction.
Will you take a biologist
with you every month?
You need to look
at the operations and costs.
Do you still have that deck hand on
fixed wages? No one else does that.
- I gave you a chance.
- I found the solution. More quotas.
More quotas? You need to
cut down on the costs and optimize.
Then go fish yourself, wise ass!
7 years ago I could easily get a loan.
You told me to buy the cod quotas.
I come here with a solution.
The least you can do is help me.
The house is my collateral.
- Did you find the quotas?
- I have an offer.
- At a good price?
- It's okay.
It's a temporary overdraft.
And I need to approve them.
- You have to cut down the costs.
- Wherever possible.
You know what I mean.
- Lars. We need to talk.
- Yes.
- I'm sorry but I have to fire you.
- Shut up.
- I can't afford you anymore.
- Everything is okay.
- Everything is going to hell.
- We're catching fish. It's all good.
No. Listen to me.
I wouldn't just say this.
I might be able
to take you on again at some point.
What am I supposed to do then?
There are no other jobs out there.
- I was always with you.
- I don't want this either.
- I just can't help you right now.
- You never did!
Don't do this, Lars. Lars!
I get why Kirsten left you.
You're worthless!
- Morning!
- Morning.
Can you take this? Thanks.
- Can you let go the moorings?
- Is Lars not coming? Is he ill?
Yes.
- Let go the moorings and let's go.
- Yes.
- Do you need help?
- Grab a hold here.
Grab a good hold.
I'll count to three.
One, two, three! One more time.
One, two, three! There!
I couldn't have done that alone.
Now loosen the line.
Watch out for the flood.
Come on now. Pull!
You can do this. Yes.
So that was it then. You don't have
to go out to sea for a long time now.
- It was a nice experience.
- I'm glad you think that.
I hope you got the data you need.
If not, you can come with me again.
We can arrange that.
You bastard! I need to talk to you!
Kesse!
- What the hell are you doing?
- Shut up! We need to talk!
Go home and sleep it off.
- Stop that!
- I want to talk to you!
I don't want to talk to you
when you're drunk. You know that.
- Stop that, damn it!
- We need to talk!
- What do you want to say?
- You're a bastard.
Is that all?
Damn it! Stop that! Lars.
Stop it. Come here. Don't.
Go away!
Don't!
- Go home!
- Bastard.
Go home.
Can I get a beer?
- Thanks.
- Katrine ...
- Give me 3 beers. What's up?
- What's up with what?
What's it like
taking a biologist with you?
- It's okay.
- You told us to not do it.
- Did I?
- Yes. But you did.
- Even on your spare time.
- You people talk a lot.
- Don't get things mixed up.
- Did you want anything else?
I'm just saying.
- Hello, Kesse.
- Hello, Carsten.
Do you still have those quotas?
- Wait. Can you hear that? Listen.
- What?
- It's the tune. It's changed.
- Funny. Do you want to sell or not?
- How many do you need?
- Your 60 tons of plaice.
You'll be busy on that wee boat.
- How much do you want for them?
- For you, 4.5 kroner per kilo.
You must be crazy.
- I'll pay 1.5 kroner per kilo.
- This isn't a gift shop.
- 2.5 then?
- No.
- 2.5. Come on.
3 then. That's a good offer.
- That's 180.000 in your pocket.
- Why should I lose money on you?
- Come on.
- No. I'll talk to you later.
- Now what?
- I have another suggestion.
Give me the quotas for 1.5 per kilo
and I'll bring in extras for you.
- What are you talking about?
- I know how you got that car.
- Is that biologist still with you?
- No.
Give me a couple of days.
I'll see if can work something out.
Thanks.
It's too risky.
It's not the 80's anymore.
There are more inspectors
than fishermen.
- I'll lose it all.
- It's a slippery slope.
- You'll end up in Carsten's pocket.
- I don't want to talk about it!
You just want me to shut down
and rot to death at the fish factory.
His name is Preben.
This is his number.
Call him when you bring extras in.
He'll come down and get it.
- Is he an okay guy?
- Sure. He's done this for years.
- And he's never been caught?
- No.
He'll pay you in cash.
Then we'll settle our account.
I have to say
that this surprised me.
- What?
- This. You.
You were always against
illegal fishing. You were a saint.
Was it all just hot air?
This is not something I'll brag about.
See you, Kesse.
- Hello, Inga.
- Hello, Kesse. What do you want?
- Is Lars here?
- Yes. Lars. Lars!
- All right, all right. Calm down.
- Hello, Lars.
- What do you want?
- I can take you back on.
- What happened?
- Do you want to come?
- Yes. Of course.
- See you tomorrow at 4 then.
Aye aye, captain.
- Do you want a cup of coffee?
- No, thanks.
I need to go. Take care.
- See you, Kesse!
- Yes.
- Was that all?
- Yes. 8 cod crates.
Put them over here and cover them.
- Do you have the fishing report?
- Yes. Here you go.
- See you tomorrow.
- Yes. Thanks.
- What do we do now?
- We sail back.
Preben will pick up the rest there.
Are you Preben?
Can you park over here?
- Sure. Let's have a look at it.
- Yes.
- So that was it.
- So I'll see you next week.
- We'll see.
Call me when you have something.
- So was everything okay?
- Yes. No problems.
- Let's see.
- I hope they're all there.
- Everything looks okay.
- Good.
Nothing to worry about then.
There.
- Do you want a beer?
- No, thanks.
- See you next week.
- Yes.
- Hello.
- Hi. What are you doing here?
- Will you help me with these?
- Sure.
- Did you pay for them?
- No.
- Can I come in?
- Yes, of course.
Then you cut it along the spine.
Then we remove this bone.
It's not nice to eat that.
- Are you getting it?
- Sure.
Cut the sides and then ...
Then you cut along the spine and ...
I'm in the wilderness here.
- I'll fillet them. You cook them.
- Or I could just eat them.
I don't have any dessert
I'm too full anyway.
It was really good.
Yes. You never go wrong with fish.
So ...
Now I know how to cook fish.
- Next time they might not burn.
- Right.
Yes ...
Anyway ... Yes ...
- Are you going home?
- Yes.
All right.
- Should I clear the table?
- No, I'll do it.
- I had a really good time.
- Me too.
What are you laughing at?
- It's good for my back.
- I hope I don't get seasick.
Come here.
- How long were you married?
- 19 years.
Then she met a guy from Aalborg.
I didn't know anything
for about a year.
- Ouch.
- Yes.
And then she left me for him.
- Have you ever worn a ring?
- No.
- No one ever stayed that long.
- Why?
It all ...
- It all has to fall into place.
- Yes.
I can't really explain it.
- Sounds like they were foolish.
- Very foolish.
- That's not true.
- Yes. Yes it is.
- So it's still working?
- Damn right.
Congratulations.
Have you called her?
- No.
- Why not?
- I'm not really her type.
- But is she not your type?
She's nice. Very nice actually.
- What's the problem then? Call her.
- No.
- Then text her.
- Text her? And write what?
Write: "Hello, sweetie."
Hello sweetie?
I'm not going to write that.
- That's how you do it.
- Hello, sweetie?
- I'll just write "Hey there".
- No.
- Why not?
- Hey there?
Can you not hear it?
Just write "Hey, sweetie".
- Okay. "Hey, sweetie".
- Yes.
- This is stupid.
- What?
- That's how you do it.
- That's not how I do it.
Hello, it's Kesse. Hi.
Yes, me too. I had a good time.
So I was thinking ...
Do you want to go out again?
Oh.
- So this is where you're hiding.
- Hello.
- I'm happy you called.
- Yes.
- Should we go?
- Are you in a hurry?
No. It's just ...
There are a lot of biologists here.
- Yes, you're on hostile territory.
- Yes.
Why don't we have
a look at the sunfish before we go?
- Sunny? Sure.
- Great.
Is this such a good idea?
I'm not sure I want to do this.
- Don't I need a certificate?
- I'll take good care of you.
If a fisherman is under water
it's because he's drowning.
That was incredible! Fantastic!
Wasn't it?
You deserve a kiss.
- Let's go down again.
- Sure.
Here we go.
Try Pia's new specialty.
- Hawaii mix.
- Hawaii mix?
- So what do you think?
- It's okay.
Is it good?
It's different.
- Don't you want any?
- No. It tastes like shit.
I hate you.
The fries go all soft because
of the pineapple. They're sloppy.
- What?
- Nothing.
You're not easily knocked down,
are you?
I don't plan to.
2 hours before is just a guideline.
We have plenty of time.
- You'd better take these.
- Let me.
- You should get moving then.
- Yes, we need to get in there.
- I think that was all of it.
- That's it. Thank you.
- Have a nice holiday.
- It'll be good to get away.
Okay. How does this shit world
Take care. I'll see you, when Sorte
comes home all hot and tanned.
- Let's go, Søren!
- All right, all right.
- Was that all?
- Yes. That's all we got today.
Kesse! Inspections.
- Hello there.
- Hello.
- Good catch?
- I'm not complaining.
- What did you catch?
- Plaice.
- Did you unload them all?
- Yes, were done.
That's nice.
- The weather was nice today.
- It was fine.
- That wind yesterday was worse.
- Yes.
- Hello, Kesse. Let's go.
- Have a nice day.
You too.
Jesus Christ. My pulse is racing.
Feel it.
- Shut up, damn it!
- That was damn close.
Your number was almost up.
- We're on a roll, Kesse.
- Sure.
- What's up?
- What's up.
Jesus Christ. It's my mother.
- She's so afraid you'll starve.
- That looks good.
- Tell Inga I said thanks.
- Hello, Lars.
- What the hell are you doing here?
- Well ... I ...
What's she doing here? Huh?
Lars ... Lars, damn it!
What does she think
about your illegal fishing?
Don't be stupid, Lars.
You weren't supposed to know
that we're seeing each other.
I don't care about that.
- I should have told you.
- "Stay away" you said. No trouble.
- That's because you wanted her.
- I didn't plan it.
I don't care. I don't care.
- Is she a good ride?
- Lars ...
- You must have fucked her.
- Just shut up.
This is Kesse.
Where were you, Preben?
We unloaded a long time ago.
I've been waiting for over an hour.
Call me when you get this message.
I don't want to stay much longer.
- Should we throw them in the water?
- Don't be an idiot.
Carsten, this is Kesse.
I know it's late but it's important.
Preben didn't show up. No!
I have 11 crates
that I don't know what to do with.
I tried that! He's not answering!
I am calm, it's just ...
Can you call him and tell him
to get his ass over here?
Yes. Good.
Let's go, Lars.
Put that one there.
There's no room for ...
We'll have to come back for the rest.
Put the last one back.
I'll go get the rest and more ice.
You stay here.
God damn it!
Come help me with the crates.
- Are you deaf?
- You have a visitor.
What are you doing here?
Were we supposed to meet up?
- What's this?
- I'm just keeping them here ...
I'm not stupid.
How long have you done this?
- Long enough to get by.
- You're destroying your livelihood.
- It's nothing.
- What do you want me to say?
- I don't know!
- I thought you were better than this.
Well you thought wrong.
What a shame.
That pissed her off.
Butt out, Lars.
What the hell happened to your hand?
Damn it.
This was the last time, Lars.
I can't do this.
What do you mean?
I'm sorry
but I can't take you with me anymore.
It's shit. I know that.
So ...
I'll just be getting home then.
You might as well. Take care.
Thanks.
Where the hell were you?
You could've at least called.
I had to bring the crates home.
You have the address.
Come as quick as you can.
- Good evening. Fishing inspections.
- I can see that.
We received an anonymous tip
about you keeping fish here.
Can we look in your garage?
- I can't stop you, can I?
- No.
It's all cod.
We're going to make a report now
and report a crime.
You'll get a fine
equal to the value of the catch.
You might risk having
your license withdrawn for some time.
We're taking the fish
to sort and weigh them.
You're welcome to watch.
We can press charges against you -
- but you have
the right to remain silent.
You'll receive a letter ...
Hello!
- You should get that looked at.
- Yes.
Push your thumb up.
- Good. Does this feel normal?
- Yes.
And here? You can feel that? Good.
Give me two more. Of the shots.
No! The shots.
You're ugly.
Damn ugly.
- Jesus Christ, Kesse.
- Leave!
I didn't mean to. Sorry, damn it.
Don't be like that.
I didn't do it on purpose.
Jesus.
What the hell are you looking at?
Huh?
- We're looking at you.
- You're so busy.
- So are you.
- Just say it to my face.
- Go home and sleep it off.
- You gossiping bitches.
- Calm down and drink your beer.
- Do you want to say something?
Just say it to my face.
Don't sit there and gossip.
- Kesse, listen to me. Look at me.
- You're asking for it.
- We don't want this here.
- You had this coming!
- Pretending to be such a damn saint!
- Let me ...
Get out now! This way!
Get up.
Let's go. Come on.
Get out.
That's it. Get out of here.
Kesse? What the hell happened?
- Nothing.
- You need to put ice on that.
- Huh?
- Ice! It looks horrible.
There you go. Come over here.
Come here. Is that good?
I have nothing left, Pia.
- That's not true.
- I don't.
- Not a damn thing.
- Not true.
- It's not true.
- Yes, it is.
- I have nothing.
- Come here.
Come here, Kesse.
Come here.
Come on. Come on.
Yes.
Wait.
Yes. That's it.
- No, this is no good.
- Yes, Kesse. You ...
- Come here, Kesse.
- No, it's no good, Pia.
- Yes, it is.
- I have to get home.
- No, don't. Stay here.
- No. Stop it, damn it!
You ... Kesse! Kesse!
Open the door!
I know you're in there!
Kesse, damn it!
You might want to find
a new spot for the spare key.
Oh yeah?
You've really been at it.
You look like shit.
Huh?
You're not a pretty sight yourself.
- No.
- Here. A souvenir from paradise.
- Thanks.
- Let's go. Get up, damn it.
My license is withdrawn for 3 months
and I got a huge fine.
The bank will take all of it.
The house and the car.
- Then it's really bad.
- Damn right.
She should stay
away from the docks.
I was just stupid. Stupid and naive.
I'll never fish again.
Can you ask if there are any jobs
at the fish factory?
Sure. Sure.
We have a uniform, you have to wear.
And to make sure,
that you're always clean and tidy -
- you'll get 11 work suits.
Today you'll be at the station
where they cut the heads off.
This is after that station.
The ladies here are filleting.
Your job is at the next station.
This is our new employee.
- Kristian.
- I'm Keld.
- Do you want to learn this?
- I might as well.
This chops the head off.
You push here and here.
Kesse!
What's up?
I just wanted to check in on you.
I'm not talking. Don't worry.
- Who tipped the inspectors?
- I have no idea.
I'll find out who it was.
Someone owes me a wee favor.
It doesn't matter anymore.
- We had a good business going.
- What do you want?
I'll pay that fine.
When you get your license back
we'll slowly settle the account.
You'll get your boat and quotas back.
Everything will be as before.
I think you need to go now.
- Think about it.
- I've thought about it.
Think about it.
I've thought about it.
Goodbye, Carsten.
What's up? Are you coming
to fisherman's swim tonight?
- Why? I'm not a fisherman anymore.
- Stop that. Neither am I.
Did you hear about Lars?
He got beat up.
- That wouldn't be a first.
- No, a proper beating.
Some say it was hired goons.
- What the hell did he do?
- I don't know.
I met Inga at the supermarket.
She was shook up and crying.
Hey! Where are you going? Kesse!
Did you tip the inspection? Huh?
Did you?
Do you even know what you did?!
- You had it coming!
- Did I? Did I really?
Kesse! Leave him alone.
- So ...
- Take care.
Thanks.
- Put it down for a second.
- Just step down.
- No.
- You're a wimp.
Go on.
Hello, Pia. Just the usual.
- Hello.
- Hi.
- It's been a while.
- Yes.
- Are you doing okay?
- Just fine.
I'm working at the fish factory.
I get benefits and all.
So that's all good.
- What about you?
- Fine.
- How did the project go?
- Good. It's done.
- Well, congratulations then.
- Thanks.
- I'm going back to Copenhagen.
- Oh.
- When are you leaving?
- At 4 o'clock.
- Today?
- Yes.
- Bye, Kesse.
- Bye. Do you need a ride?
- What?
- How will you get to the airport?
I can borrow Sorte's car
and take you there.
- I'm taking the train.
- Oh, okay.
Then it's ...
- Bye.
- At least we got rid of her.
- Huh?
It's not that I just think,
she was a bit too pushy.
A bit too aggressive. Right?
Maybe it's because she's from
Copenhagen. We're not like that.
Don't you think?
This is Gerd. I can't come to the
phone. Please leave a message.
- Can I buy a ticket here?
- Sure.
- Where are you going?
- I'm going to Copenhagen.
Subtitles: Christa Hejlstrup
SDI Media Denmark