(Episode 36)
Gosh, it hurts.
Hey, what are you doing?
You absolutely have to stay away
from work until you fully recover.
I'm really okay. We should
have a meeting now.
The doctor said that you shouldn't
be working now.
You got discharged on that condition.
I'm really fine. I can take
care of myself...
I will look after you. As your
co-worker, that is.
- No, Bong Hee.
- No, Mr. No.
I'll feel guilty if you don't let me take
care of you.
I'll keep beating myself up thinking that
you got stabbed instead of me.
Shall I do that?
Eat the porridge first, then take
your medication with water.
Hey, I...
I don't like porridge.
I'll... I'll help you.
No, it's okay.
No, it must be hard for you.
No, it's okay. I can do it myself.
- Does it sting?
- It's okay.
You're tickling me.
Am I?
I'm really struggling to hold myself back.
Hey.
I'll do it.
Okay.
Nothing is for certain because
it happened too long ago.
However,
there's a possibility that it was
an accidental fire, not arson.
That's the best conclusion
we can arrive at now.
How am I...
supposed to bring all this up to Bong Hee?
There's something I have to tell you.
Can you make some time for
me after work today?
Sure, I will.
The reason of the fire still
remains to be unknown.
But one thing I'm certain of...
is that your father...
was not an arsonist...
that killed...
my parents.
Actually, it was the opposite.
He saved my life...
and passed away...
while trying to rescue my parents.
Then...
why...
was my dad...
accused of killing them?
Why on earth did that happen?
It was because of me.
Sorry?
I beg your pardon?
I...
made a mistake while giving my statement.
I said that your dad is the culprit.
I gave wrong information in my statement.
Why?
Why did you do that?
Answer me.
Tell me why you did such a thing.
Whatever I say will be an excuse.
Then go ahead and give me your excuse.
Say something, please.
Do whatever you can to try
to make me understand.
Can you recognize him?
This is the man...
who killed your dad...
and mom.
Okay?
I think...
I had lost my memory temporarily...
due to the shock from the incident...
back then.
The District Attorney, Jang Moo Young,
who wrongly charged your dad...
had to conceal his mistake.
Hence,
he probably blamed him for the fire...
because he was found on the scene.
The prosecution... Back
then, the prosecution...
was even more unforgiving toward
mistakes than they are now.
No, but...
It was that man.
He's the culprit.
Whatever excuse I give, it is ultimately...
all my fault.
I must have...
gotten way ahead of myself.
He's not even calling me.
Ji Eun Hyuk, you jerk.
Hey, you're home.
Hey.
Did you cry?
Darn it. Pretend you
didn't see that at least.
Why are you about to cry too?
Hey, I'm okay.
You don't have to cry for me.
I'm not that sad.
Hey, I'm really fine.
- Hey.
- Hey, don't cry.
- Don't cry.
Eun Hyuk, you've been nice to me lately.
It's all because of meeting
you coincidentally.
Besides, who knew I had
to carry all these files?
By the way, you are going to
read these files again at home?
Don't you think you're
overworking yourself?
Eun Hyuk.
Yes?
Is it really a coincidence?
Sorry?
You always help me whenever
I'm having a tough time.
Is this really a coincidence?
Yes, it is.
I see.
I got it then.
I could have gotten the wrong idea.
We are just friends. We
are just good friends,
aren't we?
Yes, we are.
I did the right thing.
Yes, I did.
I did well.
(Sunho District Prosecutor's Office)
What brings you here?
You don't have to show it so
obviously that you hate me.
I didn't exactly come
here because I like you.
Then you should leave.
Should I go without telling
you the purpose of my visit?
I should at least tell you why.
Then go on.
I...
am going to tell you some things
that you won't like to hear...
and that will hurt your feelings.
Your son, Hee Jun.
Leave if you are going to talk nonsense.
You have it all wrong.
- Bong Hee isn't the culprit.
- Young Hee.
You know that guy who lost his memory?
His name is Jung Hyun Soo. He's your guy.
What are you saying?
You are ignorant, think
you're always right,
and never listen to others.
But you aren't stupid.
Think carefully.
If you look at all the
circumstantial evidence,
you will come to realize Jung
Hyun Soo is the culprit.
So look over the case carefully...
and stop harassing Ji Wook...
and Bong Hee.
Ji Wook is born to be a prosecutor.
Reinstate him.
(Incident Report)
(Jang Hee Jun Murder
Case at Supa Apartment)
(Water Tank Murder Case at Supa Apartment)
I was going to visit you.
Look how I ran into you.
You are here to see me?
Yes.
I was going to tell you that...
you should lead a better life.
What?
My dad was...
Eun Man Soo.
You are...
Eun Man Soo's daughter?
Yes.
He's the scapegoat who you used
to cover up your little mistake.
I'm his daughter.
- That was...
- Just listen.
My dad...
was never an arsonist.
I...
am not the murderer who killed your son.
But you think you are always right...
and that you are never wrong.
On top of that, you even fabricated
evidence and persecuted him.
Have you thought about how
the family you ruined lived?
Or how my mother lived?
Do you know how hard my life was
because of what you did to me?
You don't know, do you? You
were never interested anyway.
Let me tell you again.
My dad...
was an innocent man who did nothing wrong.
It was you...
who made a mistake.
(Attorney No Ji Wook)
No, don't. There's no need. I'm fine.
Sit down.
- Bong Hee.
- Mr. No.
Just listen to me, please.
Aren't you...
sorry?
Yes.
I don't know how to act around you.
I know that the DA's mistake
is bigger than yours.
That's that. Anyway,
it is true that you did
make the false statement...
against my dad.
You're right.
So wait for my decision.
Whether I should forgive you,
or I should just let things be.
Please sit down.
No, it's really okay.
I can do it myself. Don't worry about it.
All right, then.
Wait.
Thanks...
for coming back.
I didn't come back for good.
I'm just trying to keep
my feelings from work...
and giving myself time to
sort through my thoughts.
You're right, but...
this is more than enough for me.
Just listen to me.
They can settle right away.
Gosh, that's not how it works.
Are you sure you have
decades of experience?
Goodness, that's how things used
to be done back in the days.
Can we please get this meeting done?
Yes, please. That's what
I've wanted to say.
Ms. Lack of Evidence, shut it.
Gosh, seriously!
Let's focus on the meeting, please!
You guys are so loud.
Hey, don't record this.
You're distracting me.
Hey, you should've told us
that you were filming us.
Good. Okay.
I look pretty good.
Okay.
Can we please get this meeting done?
Yes, please. That's what
I've wanted to say.
Hey, shut it.
(Smart selection)
Gosh, seriously! Let's focus
on the meeting, please!
Hey, don't record this.
Can you...
recognize me?
Your memory must've come back.
Yes, thanks to you.
Then you must know this too.
There's no more loophole
for you to escape through.
You're charged with two
counts of attempted murders,
including what you did to me.
And I'll be sure to prove that you
killed all those people. So...
you better come clean, you scum.
The system in this country is merciful...
toward those who confess...
and repent their wrongdoings.
But personally, I don't
think scums like you...
deserve any mercy.
What was that about? Are
you not totally there yet?
Is that it? Do you not get what's going on?
No, no. That's not it.
This is just a speculation,
but someone might still be on my side.
That's what it was about.
(Sunho District Prosecutor's Office)
So you've finally decided to talk?
Mr. Jung.
First off,
I killed them all.
Whom shall I start with?
Whom shall I talk about first?
We first met through the Yang Jin Woo case,
so shall I start with Jin Woo?
No, no. I take that back.
Supa Apartment. I should
start with Supa Apartment.
You've managed to confirm the
identity of only one body...
found in the water tank there, right?
Shall I tell you who the other one is?
There's no reason for me to say no.
All right.
His name is Sung Jae Hyun.
He and Jin Woo went to
the same high school.
Go ahead and check it.
- Is that right?
- I'm not done yet.
How dare you cut me off?
There was one more.
Was his name Jang Hee Jun?
Jang Hee Jun?
I'm pretty sure it was Jang Hee Jun.
Yes, that was his name.
Well... Initially,
I had no intention of killing him.
I was working on my stuff on the rooftop,
and someone witnessed it.
That was Eun Bong Hee.
So I went there to kill her,
but I found a drunk guy instead of her.
I ended up stabbing him with a knife,
and he collapsed while crying.
"Dad."
"Dad, save me."
"Dad, help me."
"I'm terrified."
He was saying things like that.
And he kept crying.
Gosh, that guy was being such a
crybaby, and I couldn't stand it.
So I stabbed him again and killed him.
That's what happened.
Hey, Ji Hye. I'm on my
way to your office now.
Yes, okay.
I'm sorry.
I won't accept your apology.
Come with me for a second.
Why?
I'm calling from the HR department
at the Ministry of Justice.
I'd like to let you know that you have...
passed the recruitment exam
for experienced prosecutors.
(Ji Chang Wook's "101
Reasons Why I Like You"...)
(is available on music websites.)
(Epilogue)
(Love in Trouble)