[My Sweet Family]
I'm...
Episode 15
okay with her being more interested
in my money than myself.
I have no problem with her scheming
behind my back with my son.
She's a great lady.
She won't live with an old
man like me for nothing.
Do you know why I haven't
registered our marriage yet?
I was afraid she'd change her mind.
Once it becomes official,
she might ask for half of my money.
After thinking about it for days,
I had decided to trust her
and register our marriage.
That's what I thought.
But then you fooled around
with her, in my own house!
I'm never going to forgive you.
President! I'm sorry.
Burn in everlasting fire.
I'll catch up with you later.
Boss!
- Mr Bong! - Boss!
Boss, stop.
Mr Bong, are you all right?
What are you doing?
Boss.
Don't do this.
- Move. - No matter what...
Mr Bong did,
this isn't the way to handle it.
We can't make the movie without him.
Movie?
Isn't this dramatic enough for you?
I will finish this movie right now.
- Leave! - Boss!
It's about someone's life.
- I said leave! - Please, grant him mercy.
Didn't you hear me?
I can't leave...
without Mr Bong.
Do you want to join him?
You...
deserve to burn...
in everlasting fire, too.
Get them.
President.
Ms Oh, what are you doing here?
I have something to tell you.
I...
I lied to you.
Mr Bong didn't use me or
take advantage of me.
I...
seduced him.
Ms Oh.
I...
had feelings for...
Mr Bong.
What are you talking about?
Why are you talking nonsense?
How dare you threaten...
Living with you...
was very difficult...
and boring.
I just wanted to marry you...
and live a comfortable life.
That's the only thing that kept me going.
That's when I met Mr Bong.
I knew it would be the end
of me if you found out,
but I couldn't help myself.
I am sorry, President.
Ms Oh.
Don't bet your life on something like this.
Tell me now.
I will pretend this never happened.
I will cut my wealth in
half and give it to you.
I will let you do...
whatever you want.
Tell me it's not true.
Tell me it's not true!
President.
I am so sorry, President.
But the person I really love is...
not you.
It's Mr Bong.
President. Please spare his life.
Please don't kill him.
I will take responsibility for everything.
- How... - Please, spare his life.
How can you...
How can you say something like that to me?
You know how much I loved you!
Boss!
- Boss! - No!
- No! - Stay with me, Boss!
- Boss! Boss! Wake up! - This can't happen.
Call an ambulance.
- Yes, Sir. - Boss! Stay with me!
- Boss! - No!
Boss! Boss! Stay with me!
Boss!
Ki Beom.
What did you do to my dad?
Let go and I'll tell you.
Hurry up and tell me what you did!
I...
I am to blame.
What?
I...
I am the one who did this to him.
Let's talk in private.
What?
Ms Oh is in love with Mr Bong?
Is that really true?
Keep it down. We're in a hospital.
Where is Mr Bong, that
useless piece of jerk?
Where is he?
Are you going to go beat him
up at a time like this?
Your dad is in surgery. You
need to be here for him.
I didn't know something that hideous
was going on in my own house!
Ki Beom!
Gosh.
Are you serious?
Gosh, it was crazy.
It was unbelievable.
If it weren't for Tae Soo,
Mr Bong would've been long dead.
What about President?
He still hasn't woken up?
I heard he's either getting a
surgery or some kind of procedure.
I'm not sure which one.
Anyway, you need to fix the truck first.
I heard you will start selling
food on that truck tomorrow.
Yes. I should fix it.
Because of his hypertension,
it seems that...
he went into a state of shock.
He had a ruptured cerebral aneurysm.
But fortunately, he was brought
to our hospital in time.
He only had to undergo a minor surgery.
Dr Kim. Will my father be okay?
He will be fine once he wakes up, right?
We will know for sure...
when he wakes up.
We need to observe him for the time being.
How dare you come in here?
Get out. The sight of you disgusts me.
Ki Beom.
I know that I did something terrible.
But...
please let me stay beside him.
You got some nerves.
Do you think my dad wants to see your face?
Leave while I let you walk out of here.
I'm letting you go only because I
don't want to make things worse.
So get out now!
I will go as soon as he wakes up.
Please, Ki Beom.
You really don't get it. Get out.
- Get out. - Ki Beom! Ki Beom!
- Ki Beom, please! - Get out!
Ki Beom, please!
Ki Beom! Ki Beom!
Ki Beom!
What am I going to do?
Please!
Dad.
Wake up.
You didn't know what a
conniving witch she was.
You said she was smart, beautiful,
and elegant. You made such a fuss over her.
You loved her with all your heart.
Look at you now.
She really fooled you, didn't she?
Get up...
and say something.
Darn it!
You should've waited for me.
Why are you doing all this by yourself?
I heard from Sung Koo.
How is President doing?
He needs to gain his consciousness.
Gosh, even so!
How could you just leave like that?
You're always getting involved
in other people's business.
A person's life was at stake.
What else could I have done?
Honey, I know it's in your nature...
to help people in need.
But what good is that if it makes
things difficult for your family?
Since a person's life was at
stake, I will let this one slide.
But I won't let it slide again.
Do you realise what an important
time this is for our family?
I don't want you to get involved
with Choongshim from now on.
Thinking about what they
made us go through,
makes me shudder.
- Okay? - Gosh.
Don't worry. It won't ever happen again.
From now on, I will only
think about the food truck.
eat kimchi fried rice.
You really know how to talk
yourself out of things, don't you?
Is there anything I can help you with?
That's right.
We need to fix up the truck.
Thanks for remembering,
but while you were saving someone's life,
the children and Sung Koo fixed it up.
They did?
Do we need to move that?
What else do I have to do?
The weather is beautiful today.
It would have been nice
if I went and helped you.
- It's all right. You stay here.
- All right.
I hope you make a lot of money, Dad.
Good luck.
You will be rich, my son.
Let me know when you move locations, okay?
Be careful not to catch cold, Mum.
Call me if something happens, Dad.
- Okay. - I'll see you later, Choon Boon.
Goodbye.
Here comes Soo Min's Kimchi Fried Rice!
- Let's go! - Let's go!
Bye!
Earn a lot of money!
Check on the production company
often and keep an eye on Mr Lee.
I'm sure he's still keeping
in touch with that Mr Bong.
- I'll do that. - Okay.
What's that?
President of Choongshim Construction.
- Show your face. - Come out.
- We want to talk to you. - Come out!
- Let go! - He's the president. Move!
Are you Baek Ki Beom, the president
of Choongshim Construction?
Sir, please go upstairs.
What is it? What is this all about?
I will tell you about it upstairs. Hurry.
- Let's talk! - What are you doing?
We're from Manbok Shophouse.
There's something we need to say.
Please, head on up. Security!
- Sir. - We have something to say!
- Mr Baek! Let's talk!
- I have something to tell you!
Manbok Shophouse will be redeveloped?
It's my first time hearing about this.
Boss started this project just recently.
Why didn't he tell me about it?
He said you were going
through a lot of things.
He said he would let you take
over once it was settled.
- What do those guys want?
- It's about compensation.
They think the compensation was too small.
- They already filed a lawsuit.
- They filed a lawsuit?
There are always people like them.
They always get in our way.
I will take over this project.
Bring all the documents related to this.
Why don't we just do it our way?
They are filing lawsuits...
because we are being too easy on them.
We could take care of this
situation in no time.
You idiot! We're not gangsters.
We are businessmen.
You're not thinking straight.
I am sorry.
Young Il.
Keep a close eye on them
and report back to me.
And arrange a meeting with the lawyer.
I'm going to take care of this.
- Do you understand? - Yes, Sir.
(Soo Min's Kimchi Fried Rice)
Is it because the weather is cold?
There's no one passing by.
It's already 1pm.
If we don't make money during
lunch, we've wasted half a day.
This is why I told you we
should go in front of a school.
They are on vacation. We
won't be making money there.
And they said a dish like this sells
better around office complexes...
because employees miss homemade meals.
Is that right? Then let's
wait a little more.
They will come.
- Welcome. - Welcome. What can I get you?
Sir?
What's wrong with him? Do you know him?
I've never seen him before.
He's a strange one, isn't he?
You can't sell food here.
Do you want to pay a fine?
What do we do?
Gosh, this is such a hassle.
Show me your identification.
All right. All right.
I'm sorry.
We didn't sell anything today
so please let this go.
You can't sell food here.
We will get complaints.
I am sorry. We will close now. I am sorry.
- Please let it pass. - We are sorry.
- I'm sorry. - Hurry up and leave.
- Okay. - You can't block the street.
We will move now. We didn't
even sell one bowl yet.
Ki Beom.
Your father still hasn't woken up.
Yes.
Okay.
Why are you still here?
Although...
I did a terrible thing,
I can't leave...
President like that.
I will stay here and repent
my sins until he wakes up.
When he wakes up,
I will quietly disappear.
I can't understand why you're
doing this all of a sudden.
When you did something like that,
you must have known that
this day would come.
Do Kyung.
Please, let me meet him once.
Please,
let me meet him one last time.
Meet him in your next life.
Don't let Ki Beom catch you
and put yourself in danger.
You should leave for your own sake.
Goodness.
Why are we having a barbecue party?
For you to work in the cold,
you need to be strong.
So you need to eat well.
- I bought these. - Really?
My Soo Min bought meat for us?
How can I afford to buy meat when
I get such a small allowance?
He bought the meat and I
bought the vegetables.
- Gosh. - Help yourselves!
Of course. My boy is so thoughtful.
Let's eat. Let's eat, Mum.
- Here. - Wow. Here.
Let's eat.
It looks delicious. Thank you.
How many bowls did you sell today?
100 bowls? 200 bowls?
Hey, it was just their first day.
Actually, it turned out much
better than we imagined.
Our customers went...
wild about our fried rice. Right, Honey?
Yes, it was very popular.
We will settle down soon.
So don't worry about us.
I hope it works out so that you can...
buy me a mink coat and take me abroad, too.
Gosh, Mum.
Should we make a toast?
- Okay. - Okay.
To our health.
- To our health. - To our health.
Thank you. Thank you for the party.
It's delicious.
What's going on?
- Come on, Dad. - What is it?
You should get a massage. Take a seat.
Okay. Thank you, Soo Min.
- Goodness. - Here we go.
- I will set it for you. - Gosh.
Does that feel good?
It feels very good. Goodness.
Soo Min! Why are you being so nice today?
- Do you need money? - No, that's not it.
I'm always nice to Mum and Dad.
- Right, Dad? - Of course.
My kids are the best.
This feels so nice. Gosh.
Are you going over the numbers?
Honey. We sold four bowls today.
We were out in the cold the whole day...
and all we earned was 16 dollars.
When we deduct expenses, we
won't have anything left.
The family's so excited. How
can we go on like this?
Should we lower the price?
Is it too expensive?
But other places charge
five dollars for a bowl.
Maybe it doesn't taste good.
Should we change the menu?
Gosh.
I haven't met anyone that
didn't like your cooking.
Then what's the problem?
Gosh, this is only the start.
It's not easy to do well from the start.
It will get better.
We will sell 10 bowls tomorrow
and 15 bowls the day after.
Then, there will come a day
when we sell 100 bowls a day.
Let's not expect too much for now.
We need to look on the bright side.
You're right. I just became
anxious all of a sudden.
It's okay.
Ms Oh!
Are you mad? How can you come here?
I couldn't leave without you.
Run away with me.
Let's not do this.
You and I...
are already over.
I thought you said you loved me.
You even said so in front of President.
Well, that's...
It was so that I could save you.
Please, don't do this to me.
I have to stay by his side.
You call this staying by his side?
You can't even go inside.
Even still,
I can't leave like this.
I'll regret it...
for the rest of my life.
I feel guilty.
Please, wake up and smell the coffee!
You might be in danger.
Did you see that? Ki Beom just passed by.
This is our reality.
If he finds out that we're here,
who knows what will happen.
That's why you should leave right now.
Ms Oh!
Please, I'm begging you.
I'll wait for you...
at the terminal. Meet me at 12pm sharp.
No, don't wait for me.
I won't show up.
I'll wait until you do.
I'll wait for you every single day.
Why isn't he waking up?
What if he never wakes up?
Don't say that.
The doctor came by earlier...
and said that we need to be patient.
Dad.
Wake up.
You should get back on your feet...
and get revenge on those who betrayed you.
Doesn't it make you furious...
to just lie here?
Yes.
What?
The tenants sent in another petition?
Do they want to see me go crazy?
All right. I'll be there.
What is it?
It's just work.
With your dad sick,
you really need to take the lead
and look after the company.
You said that you don't want to be
someone who just holds the title.
You can live up to your title now.
Of course.
That's why I've been trying
to be more responsible...
and focused at work.
You just watch.
I'll show everyone.
That's not what I meant.
I'm telling you to rebuild your life.
Forget the past and make an honest living.
Don't forget.
This is your chance to show Hyun
Ji what an amazing dad you are.
I got it.
I'll take care of it all.
Do Kyung,
you're my wife.
Take charge...
and do what you want to do.
The time has come...
for us to spread our wings.
(Soo Min's Kimchi Fried Rice)
- Are you all right? - Yes.
Welcome, welcome.
Do you want some kimchi fried rice?
Oh.
You were here before, weren't you?
What's the problem?
I told you, didn't I?
I didn't believe you, but you were right.
When will you ever stop bothering us?
I'm not sure what you mean.
Are you running your own business...
in front of our shops
because we won't leave?
I'm not sure I follow what you say.
We know that you are the head
of the gangsters at Choongshim.
Excuse me, there must
be a misunderstanding.
My husband has nothing to
do with them any more.
Do you think we'll fall for that?
You don't remember me, do you?
Or did you do this to so many
people that you can't remember?
Do you know me?
- Where did you see me?
- Do you really not remember?
Because of you, my dad...
Stop it.
You're wasting your breath.
No matter what you do,
we won't leave Manbok Shophouse.
This is our home.
We won't let you gangsters
steal it away from us.
Let me make myself clear.
I won't let you do that to me again.
Honey, what's going on?
You stay here for now. I'll be right back.
Where are you going? Honey?
Honey!
I need to be on my way soon.
- Take care. - You too.
- Aren't you cold? - I'm fine.
- Hello. - Hello.
- Thanks for the help.
- No problem. We'll get going.
- I'll see you later. - Bye.
- See you. - It's so cold.
Why did you wait outside?
- It's fine. - Let's go inside.
Be careful.
Customers don't come out when it's so cold.
I know.
(Chul's Snack Bar)
Go inside and stand by the heater.
Okay.
- Welcome. - Welcome.
Who's the owner here?
I'm the owner. What's the matter?
I heard you wouldn't take our alcohol...
because you already signed a
contract with another company.
Yes, they offered a better price.
What?
Then,
how much do you think
our protection fee is?
You already ripped us off for years!
I think it's enough.
What did you just say?
Watch your language, Mister.
Should I make sure you don't
say such a thing again?
Should I?
Please don't do this!
Get off of him.
Dad, are you okay?
I'm fine. Don't call the police.
You're the boss here, right?
Please make them stop!
I think it'd be best for you to leave.
Please.
You jerk!
Look here, Kid.
You shouldn't talk like
that to your elders.
Don't touch my son!
You asked for this.
Dad!
Are you all right?
Let's make sure this doesn't happen again.
From now on,
you'll only buy alcohol from us.
Do you understand?
Yes.
We're done here.
Tae Soo.
Yes.
What did you find out?
Choongshim is planning...
to redevelop Manbok Shophouse.
They're kicking them out...
but are offering a measly
amount of compensation.
No wonder the tenants aren't leaving.
They have filed lawsuits.
It's a big mess right now.
I can't believe...
that you just happened...
to start your business in
front of Manbok Shophouse.
That's why they thought
you had other intentions.
I think...
it'd be best for you to change locations.
Sung Koo.
Do you remember that German bar?
- Which one? - Five years ago,
Dong Pal started an alcohol business...
and tried to steal our customers.
We went to that bar and gave them a scare.
Right!
The German bar? Yes, I remember.
That owner's son was a smart one.
I know. That son...
runs a snack bar at Manbok Shophouse.
He's looking after his father.
He looks like he's about a
year or two older than my son.
Back then,
he must have been furious...
that we did that to his dad.
He would have just gotten into
high school five years ago.
He would have been confused...
and scared.
I'm sure he's still hurting
from what happened then.
But they're about to get kicked
out because of Choongshim.
Come on.
What are you thinking about?
So what do you plan to do about it?
After working on the food
truck for a couple days,
I realised how much I've
been ripping others off.
We've been sucking the life
out of people like them.
Goodness.
Well...
I understand where you're coming from.
But we have nothing to do
with Choongshim any more.
So there's no need to think about that.
We have problems of our own.
What can we do?
You're right.
I have no idea how I ended up here.
Gosh. You're getting drunk.
Let's go home now. You
have to work tomorrow.
All right. Let's go.
Get up. Let's go.
Goodness. Let's go.
Dad, you're home.
Yes. My handsome son, you're still awake?
- Dad. You drank, didn't you?
- Well, yes...
Drink this.
Thank you.
Mum will scold you again.
Even water tastes sweet and delicious...
when you give it to me.
Dad, you're stressed, right?
What?
Dad.
I didn't mind it when you
worked at Choongshim,
but I'm proud of you now.
Cheer up.
Okay.
I know what you're trying to tell me.
Sleep well.
Okay. You too.
Are you serious? Is business that slow?
Yes. Mum and Dad aren't
telling us anything...
because they don't want us to worry.
Goodness. I'm just speechless.
Aunt. Shouldn't we do something to help?
Of course.
I have a great idea.
- Sung Koo. You'll help us, right? - Yes.
But with what?
Try our kimchi fried rice! It's
the best fried rice in Daejeon.
It's made with homemade kimchi
and rice grown in Korea.
Try our kimchi fried rice!
- Honey. - Yes?
What are you thinking about? Is
there something worrying you?
No, it's nothing.
Try our kimchi fried rice!
It's the best kimchi fried
rice in Daejeon. Try it now!
What if we don't sell anything again today?
Goodness. How can it be this slow?
- Hello!
- You guys startled me. What's this?
It's cold today. What are
all of you doing here?
You and Tae Soo don't really
know how things work.
Don't you agree, Mr Radish?
Regardless of how good the food is,
nothing will sell without marketing.
Don't you agree, Ms Cabbage?
We're here to help you hit the jackpot!
So what are you going to do?
We're here to spread the
news about your fried rice.
- Experience the homemade taste!
- It's the best kimchi fried rice!
- Kimchi fried rice! - Kimchi fried rice!
- The best kimchi fried rice. - Try it now!
- Try our kimchi fried rice.
- Kimchi fried rice.
- I'd like three to go. - Thank you.
- Thank you. Thank you so much.
- Kimchi fried rice!
- Try our kimchi fried rice!
- Kimchi fried rice! - I hope you enjoy it!
- Thank you for waiting.
- It will be a few minutes.
Come to Soo Min's Kimchi
Fried Rice and experience...
the most delicious kimchi
fried rice in Korea.
You and me.
The two of us.
What happened to us?
Things got tangled up,
and everything is a mess now.
I think about how cold you were...
and I once again...
Gosh.
Am I writing lyrics or a diary?
Baek Hyun Ji, what's wrong with you?
You're acting so immature
about getting dumped.
(Yoon Soo Min)
What's this?
Hi, Hyun Ji. It's me, Soo Min.
Hi, Soo Min. What's up?
Come and try my parents' kimchi
fried rice at their food truck.
Food truck?
I know you have tons of followers.
Please promote Soo Min's Kimchi Fried Rice.
That's right! Your boyfriend is here now.
Come to Soo Min's Kimchi Fried Rice.
Try the kimchi fried rice.
It's very delicious.
Come to Soo Min's Kimchi Fried Rice...
Give me some. I'll help you.
Gosh, seriously.
I'll use my looks to promote your food.
- Give me some.
- It's okay. I'm almost done.
Wait. I don't want to
be immature about this.
But I need to know why you dumped me.
Why did you?
I already told you. I want
to focus on studying.
Do you think I'll believe that?
Your dad left Choongshim and
does a food truck business.
I know that it had something
to do with my dad.
But that's what happened
between our parents.
Not us.
You didn't have to do this.
I'm begging you.
Stop showing up like this and
stop making me feel miserable.
Please.
I went through a lot to
arrange this meeting.
So let's stop being hostile
towards each other.
Let's meet each other half way.
You said you'd listen to our request.
Have you changed your mind now?
Now that I've heard what you want,
let's talk about it.
Protests and lawsuits will
just exhaust both parties.
What we want is simple and clear.
We want to be properly compensated...
according to the Commercial
Building Lease Protection Act.
We're not trying to be stubborn.
We've already compensated you!
- Calm down.
- Nothing is getting through to him.
Beob Kyu!
You're the ones who are being unreasonable.
Let's go.
Don't waste our time like this again.
I hope you know how important
time is for people like us...
who live from day to day.
Let's go.
Goodness. What a headache.
My father is already enough of a headache.
I'll meet their leader and
try to talk to him again.
You stay out of this. Ki Beom.
Let's do what we do best.
Things like this keep happening
because we're trying to change.
Why should we take a more difficult
road when we have a solution?
What are you going to do
if it gets us in trouble?
Gosh. I'm really torn.
Yes, Do Kyung.
What? My father?
What are you talking about?
Why would he disappear?
I don't know. I stepped out and when
I came back, his bed was empty.
Did you inform his doctors?
They've informed everyone at the
hospital and are looking for him.
Let's go. We should look for him too.
What do you mean President disappeared?
What happened?
Why are you still here?
Have you seen him?
Why would I have come
here if I had seen him?
- Where did he go? - Tell me the truth.
Did you do something to my father?
Why are you doing this to me?
- Why would I do anything to...
- How can I believe you?
How can I trust someone like you?
You jerk. What are you doing?
- Dad! - How dare you yell at Ms Oh!
Stop being rude to her.
President.
Here. This is the steamed
bun that you like.
Eat it before it gets cold.
It's really sweet.
Ms Oh. I'm sick of staying
here at the hospital.
Let's go on a date. We
can go shopping, too.
- President. - Dad, are you crazy?
You're going to do what with this woman?
Did you forget what this woman did to you?
Quiet.
Why are you being so rude to Ms Oh!
Let's go. This way.
It looks like he lost his memory.
This is a rare case.
We can't rule out mental distress.
He needs to receive regular treatment.
We'll also do a few additional tests.
The most important thing
is for him to rest.
If the patient wants to be
discharged, he may do so.
I'll speak to you later.
Thank you.
You did something to him, didn't you?
No wonder you wouldn't leave.
What did you do to a sick old man?
Ki Beom.
That's enough.
You'll wake him up.
Gosh! You drive me insane.
I said, we should go on a date.
Why did we come home?
They say you need rest.
Don't treat me like a patient.
I'm completely fine.
Well, I'm a little tired.
Are you?
You should have told me.
Sit down, sit down.
Dad.
- What's wrong with you? - What?
Don't you remember what she did?
I'm more concerned about
what you did wrong.
What did I do wrong?
All you do is cause trouble.
Stay here, Ms Oh.
I'll get you some tea.
I'm okay.
It's okay.
There's no need for that.
I was going to...
leave when he woke up.
But it all happened so suddenly.
I'm not sure what to say.
Just don't say anything.
You're driving me crazy.
Since it came to this,
Ms Oh should...
take care of President so that he can rest.
What are you talking about?
She's not staying.
We don't have any other choice.
I'm home.
Hi, Hyun Ji. You're late.
- How's Grandpa? - He got discharged.
Dad.
Can we talk?
My princess!
What do you want to talk about?
- Dad. - Yes.
I have something I want to ask you.
Can you be honest with me?
Well, what is it?
Were you the one who kicked out...
Sung Min's dad?
What are you talking about?
Why would I do that?
Let me rephrase that.
Did you do something to Sung Min?
Did he say something?
Did he say that I did
something wrong to him?
No, I'm asking you because
he won't tell me.
There's something for sure,
but he won't tell me.
He's avoiding me.
Hyun Ji, I didn't do anything.
Really? Can I trust you?
Of course.
Dad.
I hope you never disappoint me.
You know what I mean, right?
Of course.
(Stop the redevelopment project,
Choongshim Construction)
What are you doing?
Oh.
- What is this? - It's...
It's galbi.
Cook some for your dad.
You should have some, too.
Are you kidding me?
What are you trying to pull?
Do you think you can bribe
us with something like this?
You're from that German bar, right?
I guess you finally remembered.
There are no words...
that could express how sorry I am.
Are you going to be me for forgiveness?
What happened...
to your dad?
After what happened to our store,
he fell ill from the shock.
You gangsters...
broke my family apart.
By the way,
what did Choongshim Construction say?
Do they want you to leave?
I'm sure that's what they said.
That's how it was like when I was there.
So what?
Are you telling me...
to give up if I don't want
to end up like my dad?
Leave if that's all you have to say.
Hi, Tae Soo.
Why are you coming out from that room?
You should go in.
Eun Ok's sick.
What?
Honey.
What's wrong?
You're burning up.
Get up, let's go to the hospital.
Goodness. There's no need for that.
I took some pills and I feel fine now.
The fever's coming down.
You need to rest at home for a few days.
What are you talking about?
What about our business?
You need a break.
I can work with Sung Koo.
We have your sister, too.
Don't say that.
I can't let my will be broken.
I sure there will be many
more days like this.
How can I take a break every time?
You're so stubborn.
I feel so much better after
seeing my handsome husband.
Honey.
Thank you for working so hard.
I feel like you've finally
got on the right track.
It puts me at ease.
Although I'm physically tired,
I can sleep well.
Then, why are you sick?
Go to bed.
You have to get well for you to work again.
You need to sleep, too.
Let's go out early tomorrow.
I went out early today,
and it seemed like there were...
a lot of people passing our food
truck on their way to work.
Let's try to get more
customers in the morning.
Okay, let's do that.
Go to bed.
(Please allow me to get through the day.)
We know that you are the head
of the gangsters at Choongshim.
There must be a misunderstanding.
My husband has nothing to
do with them any more.
I don't want you to get involved
with Choongshim from now on.
Thinking about what they
made us go through,
makes me shudder.
Okay?
After what happened to our store,
he fell ill from the shock.
You gangsters...
broke my family apart.
Let me make myself clear.
I won't let you do that to me again.
Gosh, it's so cold.
And there are no customers.
That's weird, I thought we
would have more business.
How are you feeling?
You still have the chills, don't you?
It's not that bad.
We still have time until lunch.
Go get some rest.
No, it'd be a waste of time.
Then stay here.
I'll go get you some honey tea.
Thank you.
Get out of the way.
You still don't get it, do you?
What are you doing?
Why are you still in business?
You should leave since you
received compensation.
I told you, we need proper compensation.
Look at this punk...
talk back at me.
Are you trying to play us...
to get more money out of it?
I don't know what your talking about.
- You little... - Don't you dare touch him.
I'll call the police.
Please, call the police for us.
Let's ask them who's here illegally.
We don't have any reason to budge
until our case has been tried.
Our attorney told us that
we can win this case.
I was going to do this peacefully,
but if you're going to be
like this, we can't help you.
Shall we start?
- Boys. - Yes.
Stop it!
Hey! Stop it now!
Beob Kyu, what do you think you're doing?
Seriously.
It's none of your business. Stay out of it.
We're doing business right now.
You have no right to be involved in
any matters related to Choongshim!
If that's the case, do it right.
Stop bothering innocent people.
You can't do this, Tae Soo.
You think you can do whatever you
want because you've left Choongshim?
I don't want to deal with you any more.
Just leave.
- Tae Soo! - Leave! Are you deaf?
Fine. I can come back another day.
- Let's go! - Yes, Sir.
We'll see you later, okay?
If you move out before that,
it'd be better for all of us!
Are you okay?
You have to be careful
in situations like this.
I know that you're angry, but
your safety is more important.
I'm moving my food truck.
I came to say goodbye.
I hope that the misunderstanding
can be cleared up.
Keep your chin up.
I don't know what to tell you.
Did you plot this with them?
Are you playing good cop bad cop?
All I can say is that I'm sorry.
What do you mean there's
nothing you can do?
You can help us.
What's wrong with you? You're
asking a gangster to help us?
You held a high position when
you were at Choongshim, right?
Then you should be able to help us.
No.
My husband doesn't do that any more.
He has nothing to do with Choongshim.
Honey.
Tell them.
You promised me to never get
involved with Choongshim again.
I'm...
I'm sorry.
I'm not in a position to help you.
Everyone, I'm so sorry.
I hate to say this to you,
but you won't be able to win this battle.
End it here.
I don't want you to get hurt.
No.
Whether you help me or not,
I will fight Choongshim.
I can't back off now.
Let's go. We should to back
to our food truck now.
Hurry up.
What? Tae Soo got involved?
Why would Tae Soo get involved in this?
Well... I don't really know.
Anyway, because of Tae Soo,
those jerks at Manbok
Shophouse think they can win.
He makes my life difficult
even after leaving Choongshim.
Well, shouldn't we do something about it?
You're right.
Write your name and sign at the bottom.
What is this?
(I, Yoon Tae Soo, will never
get involved with Choongshim.)
Goodness.
Is this a joke? Are you seriously
asking me to sign this?
I'm doing this because I can't trust you.
Sign it. And report to me even
when you go to the bathroom.
I couldn't just walk by, so I
said a few things. That's all.
It was a good chance to clear up the
misunderstanding with them, too.
Then you could've just talked to them.
You made me wait and...
Why were you listening to
them ask you for help?
My heart sank when I saw you hesitate.
This way.
Hey! Tae Soo!
Hello, Eun Ok.
What's this?
"I, Yoon Tae Soo, will never
get involved with Choongshim."
Yes. This is great.
Eun Ok, I've always known
that you're the wise one.
Why are you here?
I came her for the kimchi fried rice.
Why else?
Can I get two servings?
Are you done for the day?
Why would we close up already?
I'll make it for you now.
Thank you. That looks good.
Spare me a second.
What do you want to talk to me about?
Stay out of things that are
none of your business.
Just focus on your own business.
Do your job properly.
Why can't you give them what
they rightfully deserve?
Doing so won't hurt Choongshim at all.
Rather, it'll improve the company's image.
Tae Soo. Everyone is telling
me what to do these days.
Dad lectures at me. Even Do Kyung
and Hyun Ji tell me what to do.
And now, you're going to
join them and lecture me?
Mind your own business and make fried rice.
People's lives were ruined because of us.
Have some decency and don't
take them down again.
Stop worrying about other people.
Worry about keeping your own life!
- Are you threatening me now?
- I'm not threatening you.
I'm giving you a word of advice.
Anyway, this is the last
advice I'll be giving you.
You know what's next, right?
What if I tell you that I don't know?
Here's your kimchi fried rice.
Thanks, Eun Ok.
You should go.
I'm sure Tae Soo understood
everything you said.
Yes, I shall.
Tae Soo. I'm going now.
Beob Kyu, let's go!
Goodness.
Fine. I'll sign it.
Mr Choi. What are you talking about now?
What have I done to them?
Why are they suing me now?
Gosh. This is making my blood boil.
I'll get back to you.
Are they suing you?
They're targeting me now because
they haven't been able...
to get anything out of Choongshim.
These jerks. They have no idea
what they're dealing with.
Ki Beom. Let's teach them a lesson.
We've been too easy on them.
Hello?
It's me, Chul, from Manbok Shophouse.
Who? Chul?
The gangsters from Choongshim...
are vandalising our store right now!
Can you help us?
Please help us!
- Chul, it's... - Please help us!
You're the only one who can help us.
- Stop it! - Move out of the way.
Chul. Chul!
What's going on? Manbok Shophouse?
- They called you? - Yes.
I think Choongshim sent some guys.
That boy is Sung Min's age. He was
probably staying up all night to...
protect his shop.
So? Are you going to run over there?
Gosh.
Are you?
Goodness.
Well...
I promised you I wouldn't.
I'm not going.
Go back to sleep now.
- Honey. - I'm not going.
I'm getting myself a glass of water.
Go back to sleep.
Get off of him.
You're the boss here, right?
Please make them stop!
You don't remember me, do you?
I won't let you do that to me again.
You can help us.
You held a high position when
you were at Choongshim, right?
Then you should be able to help us.
Can you help us?
Please help us.
You're the only one who can help us.
I don't want you to get involved
with Choongshim from now on.
Thinking about what they
made us go through,
makes me shudder.
Honey.
Thank you for working so hard.
I feel like you've finally
got on the right track.
It puts me at ease.
Although I'm physically tired,
I can sleep well.
No.
My husband doesn't do that any more.
He has nothing to do with Choongshim.
Write your name and sign at the bottom.
Why were you listening to
them ask you for help?
My heart sank when I saw you hesitate.
Go.
I must have been destined to be...
a wife of a gangster.
I thought 18 years was enough.
I wanted to live like a normal person.
But I guess it's not in the stars for me.
I won't be able to stop if I go now.
I'll have to help them until the end.
You think I don't know that?
Go.
Go save the country or go save a man.
Do whatever you want.
- Honey. - Go!
Go before I change my mind.
(Sweet and Scary Family)
You'll be going behind bars.
Drop the lawsuit against Manbok Shophouse.
Did you stick your nose in
someone else's business?
Will it get you in trouble?
You're not living this life alone.
You need to look around and help others.
Mr Park called and said
that he's going to quit.
How can you fight without a lawyer?
If you want to win, you need to toughen up.
We will lose if we don't unite.
You need to question me
at the police station?
You don't have to be someone I'm proud of.
But don't be the person I am ashamed of.
Mum, let's move back to our old house.
For the last three years,
I was really happy...
and thankful.
Just let me go.
Why are you waiting for someone
that's not going to come?
We have to leave this
place if we want to live.
Attacking them first can
be our best defence.
I apologise.
I calculated the compensation,
and it turns out you should
be getting twice the amount.
We want you out of this.
With money and power, you can do anything.
Boss!
The Family Court is always full.
(Go Dong Mi, never had a boyfriend)
You should be suspicious.
Reasonable suspicion is important.
(Baek Da Jeong, soon to be divorced)
Bring me the big ones. As big as melons!
(Hong Ae Ran, soon to be married)
(A romantic comedy with a cheerful energy)
(Happy Ending Once Again)