- Right, who wants a shot?
- Me!
25p a go.
Pay Pinball.
Get in a line.
Get in the back, you.
Money.
Do you not want a shot?
Get in the queue.
Have you paid?
Sure you've paid?
Money.
Can you see anything?
See the big one?
That's Saturn.
- Can you see it yet?
- No, still stars.
- Still stars.
- There?
- How about now?
Stars.
That big one, that's Saturn.
You can tell by its rings.
Next.
Who's paid?
Pinball, have they paid?
They only get five seconds
because they only paid half.
- What do you see?
- Stars.
I'm putting 25p
in your pocket.
Get out of here.
Move.
You know how long a day is up there?
10 hours, 14 minutes.
Fuck all time up in Saturn
if you want to do anything.
- There's not much time, young man.
- Next.
You looking for any cheap fags?
What kind are they?
Make you look better
than you already do.
Hiya, ladies. Do you wanna buy
any cheap fags?
These will prevent heart disease.
Over 60, even help you
with a hard-on.
Thanks for doing business.
Cheap cigarettes?
Cheap fags?
Tom, those boys
are back in again.
Hey, you two. Come on.
That's two or three times this week.
You've been up here flogging stuff.
We're only trying to keep
your customer satisfied.
Out the door,
Simon and Garfunkel!
Don't get in a strop, you cunt.
You want some?
Here's to you, Mrs. Robinson.
- How did you get on?
- Fucking buzzing.
- Magic.
- What you got?
- Empty bag.
- Do you want this load?
- Shit, it's the coppers.
- Bastards!
What do you want to do?
Do you want to stand about?
- Hold on a minute.
- Liam, where are you going?
- What are you doing?
- What's he doing?
All right, mate?
- Is it all right to come out?
- Brand new. Yeah. Come on.
- What the fuck?
- You little bastard!
- Oh, fucking brilliant!
- Fuck's sake!
Don't you use
your fucking mirrors?
How am I supposed to see
a bike parked there?
Fucking hell,
look at the state of it.
It's a fucking gateway.
Where's my helmet?
There's the wee bastard there
with your helmet.
You bastards!
- He's coming. Go!
- Stop!
For fuck's sake.
Quick!
Give it up, boys.
Stop!
Oh Christ, look at the time.
Do you know what time it is?
We're late. That's what time it is,
you little prick.
What did I tell you?
You never listen.
Where were you?
Is that all you can say?
Your granddad's talking to you.
You know your ma's
gonna be worried sick, don't you?
She's gonna be sitting
in the waiting room,
wondering where the fuck we are.
Put that in your mouth.
- Top of your teeth.
- Tell him to fucking do it.
Just do as you're fucking told.
I've had enough of you today.
Stick up these in your gums.
Hurry up.
Press it and flatten it.
Okay, the other side.
Let's see it.
Look at me.
Smile.
Let's see you fucking smile!
That's better. Like a friendly
little hamster the boy is.
When we get in there...
happy families, okay?
I'll go for coffee,
come back with the coffee.
Wee accident, coffee spills.
I jump up.
Granddad jumps back, right?
In all the confusion,
you kiss your ma, pass it over.
Have you got that?
Can you take your cap off?
Thanks. Just lift your arms up.
That's great.
Just grab your stuff.
- Come on, Liam. Hurry up.
- Table five, guys.
Hi, son. All right, Dad?
All right, darling, how's it going?
Good to see you, hen.
All right, angel face?
Did you think we were not coming?
It's good to see you.
We got a bit held up, didn't we?
He's in one of his moods.
What you sitting all the way
over there for? Come on over.
His face has been tripping all the way
here. Been like that all day.
How have you been getting on
at school?
School!
He's turned into
a right regular little scholar.
He hasn't seen the inside
of a school for nine months.
Who fancies a cup of coffee then?
- Yeah, I'd love one.
- Milk and one sugar?
We've missed her, son,
haven't we?
Are you all right, Mum?
What's wrong with you?
Come on, you can tell me.
No, I'm all right.
Somebody giving you
a hard time in here?
Are you clean?
You know I've been clean for years.
What are you saying that for?
What the fuck
is this all about, then?
Stan set it up.
It's for the women in here.
It's not for me.
Stan set it up for the women,
and he's getting a fortune
off their boyfriends.
You're caught with this,
it's six months minimum.
You can't last
another six months in here.
Do they strip search you?
They pick out a couple of us
at random.
What if they pick you?
Just swallow it.
I've done it before.
This isn't going on anymore.
It's finished.
You already took the rap once
for that bastard.
He's gonna be pissed
when I don't do this.
Whatever he says,
don't get upset.
Liam, don't start, eh?
Oh, for fuck's sake!
Liam, give your ma a hug.
Sorry about the language,
I can't believe myself sometimes.
Like a bull in a china shop!
I can't believe I just did that.
Here, drink your coffee.
Rab, go and get us another cup.
I'll sit with my wee friend here.
So what do you think
of your boy here then?
Wanna give your ma a kiss?
- Fucking tell him.
- Give your mum a kiss.
What do you think, Gramps?
Do we have a laugh with him or what?
He's a laugh a minute.
A right wee comedian.
Don't need a telly when he's about.
Kiss your fucking mother.
- See you later, Mum.
- Liam, please, don't.
Listen, by Christ...
see, if you don't kiss your mother goodbye,
you little cunt,
I'm gonna boot your fucking arse
all the way to fucking Greenock.
Now kiss your fucking mother,
you little cunt!
Stan, calm down.
See you later, Mum.
Let him go.
Do you know how much
that's fucking cost me?
- Give us the gear.
- You want it?
- Hand it over.
- Fucking get the gear.
You fucking twat!
Don't hit him in the face.
His fucking ma will see it.
You fucking idiot!
That's fucking enough, right?
Where's the fucking gear?
Next time you will be walking
like fucking Charlie Chaplin.
I'll break your legs,
you little cunt.
It never went
as far as that.
It's over the fence there.
You bastard!
For fuck's sake!
A fucking Laurel and Hardy fucking family.
Get over the fucking fence.
My fucking balls are caught,
you cunt!
Fucking feeble, you cunts.
Just you wait!
- Hi, Liam.
- All right, Hazel, love?
- What's wrong?
- Nothing, hen.
You sure?
I've been keeping an eye out for you.
Are you all right?
Sure?
Take a bag. I phoned Chantelle,
she knows we are coming.
Hey. boys.
That's your lot. You get it,
get this fuck and don't come back
near this school again.
My fucking caring grandfather, eh?
My own fucking flesh and blood,
you fucking old bastard.
I love your fucking grandfather.
He's so funny.
Here, you old bastard.
How's your balls, you old cunt?
Are they sore?
You'll give the place a bad name.
Fuck off.
Did you dye
your hair as well, blondie?
Who was that?
- What was that all about?
- They started it.
Don't forget
I've gotta live here.
- Hello.
- Get in.
Stop staring.
Who's the bird, Chantelle?
The bird can speak for herself,
wee man.
- It's Suzanne.
- That's a nice name.
That's my brother Liam
and his pal Pinball.
I met Suzanne
at my night class.
- What night class?
- The call center one.
- It's that one we were gonna join.
- It's that 0800 one.
Where are you going?
There's no rush.
Sit down.
- I can make tea.
- No. It's all right.
Chantelle, I'll phone you.
I'll phone you
if I can get your number.
See you later.
What are you like?
Has she left?
Don't go to the window.
Is she there?
- Is she there?
- Hey, man, look at that.
Get away
from the window.
No, Calum,
we need to see this.
- What have you done?
- I'm telling you, I tripped.
You didn't trip.
Turn around.
- What happened to you?
- I fell.
You did not fall.
This'll sting.
Easy, Chantelle.
You haven't asked me
about Mum yet.
I don't need
to ask about her.
If you're good for wee Calum,
you can stay.
No, I'll pay my way.
Don't you listen?
If you're good for wee Calum,
you can stay.
And I won't be playing
social workers.
I won't be taken
for a ride.
We share the cooking
and the housework.
There will be no swearing.
It's bad for Calum.
There will be no smoking.
No farting-- bad for Calum.
Turn around.
They won't take you
back at school?
That's one way
of putting it.
What about
the Children's Panel?
I'm not up for a review
'til Mum gets out.
Why don't you come
to my call center class?
It doesn't cost nothing.
And they might take you on
when you're 16.
Pinball might be a priest, eh?
Look at the state of you.
Look at yourself.
You gonna get yourself
sorted out?
Liam, look at me.
You gonna sort
yourself out?
- Aye.
- Promise me?
Get it, get it,
get it.
Calum, my man.
Who's that pal?
Is that daft Pinball?
Where did you get that?
Pinball's been driving about looking
for one with a child seat all day.
No chance.
Chantelle will kill us.
No, she won't.
How she gonna find out?
Calum, are you coming in?
Course you are. Come on.
Come with Pinball,
won't you?
I mean it,
none of your crap.
If she finds out,
she'll go mad.
Go.
Ready, Calum?
Are you all right,
wee man?
You're a prick.
Fucking get hold of it.
You fucking idiot!
- We've got the wee man in the back.
- Calm down, it was miles away.
- You all right, wee man?
- Sorry, Calum.
For fuck's sake.
What are you fucking
turning it up for?
Here, here, stop here.
Hold on, Calum.
I'll be back in a minute.
- Where are you going?
- I'm gonna look at this place.
Where are you going?
Six grand.
It's all right, man.
What are you doing?
Oh look at it, man.
I'm gonna look at this.
Look at that, man.
Two bedrooms,
telly, microwave.
You'd get six
around that table, no bother.
Oh, look at that view, man.
Oh, yes, man.
This is the stuff. Imagine being here
at night with a clear sky.
Fishing rod. Couple of cans,
couple of hens as well.
Suzanne to keep
you company.
No cunt telling you
what to do.
Year's supply of pizzas.
Oh, lovely.
Mum would love this, after all that time
cooped up in that fucking cell.
Paradise, man.
All right, Mum,
it's your handsome wee boy here,
sending you a tape
to cheer you up.
I'm sitting here
with a few of the boys--
Pinball, Nighttime,
Sidekick-Joint employees
of the month.
The fastest pizza slingers
in the west.
"And that's official,
by the way!"
Me and Pinball
were in the country today.
See this wee place we found.
Right by the water.
Brilliant for a picnic, Mum.
I'm gonna take you there
as soon as you get out.
Just 10 more weeks,
we'll be together.
- What was it like, Pinball?
- A lovely view. You'd love it, Jean.
As soon as you're out,
I'm gonna take you there.
Your wee man's doing brilliant.
What a laugh he is.
- All right, boys?
- All right.
- I'll see you later. I need to go home.
- Hold on.
I'm making a cassette for my ma.
You want to say hello?
- No bother.
- Go on, Suzy.
Hello, my name's Suzanne.
I hope to meet you soon
and good luck.
See you later.
What's all the fuss about?
What are you all doing?
Where are you going?
Is she there?
Oh, there she is.
- Pinball, come on.
- Is she not stunning?
You got the night lenses
on them glasses?
I know, stunning.
Pinball, that's the best sight
you could ever imagine.
- I'll be having that sight soon.
- You wish.
- She'll be mine.
- Sidekick, say something.
Hope your porridge
isn't too lumpy, Jean.
What? I'm serious.
What are you all laughing at?
A lass is getting changed
in the house over there.
- Let us see.
- No, she's away.
She's away,
it's all right.
- What did you see?
- Nothing. Not a thing.
- See her tits?
- No.
There's your dad
with your grandpa.
- He's not my fucking dad, all right?
- Stan, then. Sorry, mate.
- He could be your dad.
- Fucking shut up!
Fucking arsehole.
- Who's that?
- That's Slobodan.
- Who?
- Slobodan McTavish.
- Who's that?
- Scullion, you fucking dickhead.
Hold these.
I'm gonna wind this cunt up.
Your grandpa?
How the fuck would my granddad
have a phone?
- Look at him.
- Give me them.
Hello, Stan speaking.
What can I do for you?
Excuse me, sir. Can I interest you
in some double-glazing windows?
Not today, son.
What about a fitted
kitchen, then?
I've told you, I don't want fuck all.
You know what I mean?
What about our new top
of the range dildos?
Because you sound
like a bit of a cock-jockey.
Who the fuck are you, little...
Cunt?!
Look, he's fucking angry.
- Think he knew it was me?
- No.
He's passing Scullion
some dough.
That means
they're gonna get a delivery.
Fuck's sake.
Fucking dancer, wee man.
This is our score.
I know where
they stash the drugs.
- We could get it, no bother.
- What are you talking about?
The gear,
I know where it is.
You wanna break
into Stan's house?
Yeah, get the gear.
You're nuts.
Don't be stupid.
What's wrong with you?
You know how to cut it.
I may be daft, but I'm not dumb.
It's a daft idea.
I could get
a caravan for my ma.
I know your ma,
but I'm not even thinking about this.
- We're getting nowhere with the fags.
- I'm happy with the fags.
We're getting fucking coppers.
Look at the state of this place.
- I know the state of it.
- Think of the caravan.
The fucking money
we're gonna get here.
Look, mate,
this is big fucking bucks.
The caravan, plus plenty left.
We won't get near it
with the money we have.
What, 50-50?
- Fucking 50-50. What do you think?
- I should think so.
- So where do they stash it?
- Under a board.
- In the house?
- No, in the kennel with the dogs.
The dogs?
I'm definitely not doing it now.
Oh, fuck off.
The fucking dogs are there.
- You're a fucking shitbag.
- You said you'd get rid of them.
Fucking move.
Hairy Balls. Here, boy.
It's not worth it.
They'll rip you apart.
Fucking shush.
Come here.
Here, boy.
No Balls, here, girl.
Give us the sweeties.
That's No Balls, there,
that's the lassie. Give her one.
- Here, feed them.
- I'm not feeding them.
They're not gonna touch you.
Hairy Balls, come here.
No Balls, whatever,
come here.
Keep them fuckers there.
Here, take it, here.
Wait there.
What are you doing?
Come on.
Liam, I'm serious.
Liam, come here.
What are you doing?
So what did you tell the police?
Just left them a message
they couldn't ignore.
It must have been
a good message.
They'll need
to take the dogs out first.
The coppers
won't go anywhere near them.
That's what the hobbies
will be for.
Fucking idiot.
They're taking this fucking seriously.
That's the CID.
The police are going nuts
because they can't find anything.
He's fucking going nuts
because he thinks they've taken the smack.
Fucking dancer, man.
Oh, fucking hell,
Liam, man.
Hey, Gramps,
are your balls still sore?
Have a look at mine,
you cunt.
They've been in his mouth
and you just put them on my face.
- Give us a kiss, Pinball.
- Fuck off.
Do you want a shot?
No, man.
Can't risk losing any of this stuff.
How much do you reckon
we've got here?
Good bag.
It's good stuff and we can sell it.
Two grand.
We're gonna get that caravan.
Don't worry about that.
I used to watch my dad
do this sometimes.
He was good at it.
My teacher always used to...
wonder how I was so good
at fucking maths and fuck all else.
I wish I could tell her how.
Sure it's safe in here?
It's only me and my big brother.
No cunt else comes in here.
Anyhow, he's not into this.
You'll need this, mate.
Definitely.
I'm not wanting it.
I'll use my head.
These cunts will have a go,
trust me.
- I'll be carrying anyway.
- I said I'm not wanting it.
And another thing...
not using.
I'm fucking serious,
by the way.
- We're not junkies, right?
- I know.
And all of this goes
to the caravan.
Yeah, don't worry.
- Shake on it.
- Kiss on it.
- I'm fucking serious.
- Yeah, so am I.
Shake on it.
Do you want to buy
any gear?
No, pal. Last time I was here,
I got ripped off.
- Do you want to see the bags?
- No, I told you.
Do you want any, lads?
What about the cameras?
All right, Mum,
it's me.
I just put the wee man
into his bed.
Chantelle's away at her night class,
so I'm landed with him for the night.
See how big
he's getting, Mum.
Sometimes he looks
right at you,
right into your eyes,
as if you're the only person
he's ever met.
Anyway, big news is we're selling fags
by the barrow load.
We're raking it in, Mum.
So I might have a wee surprise
for you when you get out.
Just 61 days, Mum.
The day before my birthday.
Here's another one
of your wee favorites.
I'll come see you soon.
Maybe I'll take the wee man.
Cheerio, Mum.
That's 4,500
to be payable
by the 30th of November.
You'll need to get
Mrs. Maguire to sign here.
When will she be back?
She won't be back
for a couple of months.
She's on a refresher course
down south.
What's her contact number?
She doesn't like to be disturbed.
It's a pretty intensive course.
What's her employment?
If you don't mind me asking.
She's part of the prison service.
See you later. Bye.
- You're a pure brass neck.
- How?
- How are you gonna pay for that?
- Do I ask about your financial affairs?
- Did you get it?
- Black and white.
But how are you gonna
get all that money?
- I'm the businessman.
- In what?
I just struck a deal
with this guy from Bristol.
He's gonna bring us up fags,
van loads of them.
- So fags will get you that kind of money?
- I've got us this far, hasn't it?
He's been selling stuff since he was seven.
I'm always falling over boxes of stuff.
Calum, wait for me.
Don't drop him.
You get the gate.
That's it.
Run, run...
Wait 'til I get the door, mate.
Get it open.
I wanna get keys cut
for all of you,
even Nighttime.
Man, the picnics
we're gonna have in here.
Go on, settle there. Get in there.
Calum. We'll get a picture.
- Hands off my sister.
- Sorry.
Hey, you.
Keep your hands to yourself.
Get in a bit closer.
Cheese!
I'm going out with your sister,
by the way.
You might fall.
Come on.
- You'll fall on these stones, Calum.
- Walk very slowly then.
See, shall I hold
your hand?
That was a nice one there.
That's the record so far.
That was about 15,
16 I got there.
Where are you gonna get the money?
Four and a half grand?
We'll get it.
- What, by November?
- Aye.
- Don't think so, Liam.
- Trust me.
He's got Chantelle's eyes.
She was gorgeous
at that age.
She was a really good baby.
I tell him about you
all the time.
- No, you don't.
- I do.
I've put your photo above his cot
so he'll know when you get out.
She's lovely.
- He's beautiful, isn't he?
- He looks like you.
He doesn't.
Chantelle's dying
to hear from you, Mum.
You should write her
a wee note.
She can't stand me.
Anyway, got
a wee surprise for you--
got a big surprise for you.
- What is it?
- Take it.
- Let me see it.
- I'll bring it up next time.
- Show me.
- No, I'll take it next time.
What is it?
- What is this?
- It's a caravan.
- It's our caravan.
- I know it's a caravan, but...
Not the council's, not the bank's.
It's ours, Mum.
Ours.
I've bought it.
- This must have cost a fortune.
- I'm getting paid a fortune.
- How much?
- Don't worry about that.
I've already paid the deposit
and the first installment.
Looks lovely,
doesn't it?
Nobody to annoy you-- no junkies,
no police. Just me and you.
And Chantelle and Calum if they want.
There's plenty of room in it.
All you need to do
is sign for it.
It's in your name.
It's yours.
Sign here.
Have you really thought
about this?
- Are you sure?
- I'm positive. Just going to sign?
Sign. Aye.
And another two.
How many is that?
- How many is that?
- That's 42.
Fucking hell!
They must be making a fortune.
Yeah, definitely.
If we caught them off
that wee shortcut,
we could do more business in an afternoon
than we could in a week.
Do you know who stays there?
Big Jay fucking Ellis, serious coconut.
We'll be careful
about that--
keep a lookout a couple of days
and then we'll do the business.
You want
throwing out a window?
Stabbed in the balls?
A pitbull set on you? Don't be daft.
All we need is a couple of days
to make the contacts.
Cut them off there, do the business.
Then we'll lay low somewhere.
Where, one of your daft fucking planets?
They'll find us there as well.
I could lose
the fucking caravan.
Fuck your caravan!
Know what?
Fuck you. I'll do it myself.
- And don't come back to me fucking.
- Fuck you, you prick.
You'll fucking never do it.
Fucking nutcase.
Where are you off to?
- I'm going down the road to get stuff.
- I've got a bit of gear here.
- Any good?
- Brilliant. Best of stuff.
- Sure?
- Better than that cunt Ellis' anyway.
Give us a toke.
- All right, boys.
- Hi, wee man.
- You looking for any gear?
- What you got?
Good idea.
Give me my fucking gear,
you prick.
Hard man, eh,
you prick?
- Give us my fucking gear.
- Fuck you.
I'll be all right.
Give me my fucking gear!
I'm telling you,
you fucking stay back this time.
I'm gonna fucking kill you!
Now fucking stay down!
- Fucking dickhead.
- Arsehole.
- Fucking done my nose.
- I think my nose is broke.
- It's all right.
- He's broke mine, too.
Don't fucking worry about it.
- Give me my fucking gear.
- He's a fucking nutter!
I'm gonna kill
this bastard.
- Give him the stuff.
- Give him fuck all.
Give us the fucking gear!
You fuck off!
I'll fucking have him!
You want that caravan,
don't you?
Fucking nuts, mate.
Nuts.
How many times
have I done this?
- Done what?
- This.
"Hey-ho, hey-ho,
orphan weans have to go."
Do you remember?
At the children's home?
"Where's your mummy?"
Remember you ran out
and you fought three big boys?
They all thought
you were brave.
But I didn't.
I was screaming
through the window.
And I heard
your arm snap.
When they let you go, you still
managed to laugh in their face.
You didn't fight them
because you were brave.
You fought them because you just
didn't care what happened to you.
That's what broke my heart.
It was just
another kicking for you.
How can you really care about us
if you don't care for yourself?
Turn around.
Turn around!
What am I supposed to tell
the wean in the morning?
You tripped?
Some junkie stole your fags
and nearly killed you?
All wee Calum's got in the whole world
is me and you.
Nobody else.
What happened to us
isn't gonna happen to him.
Never.
Over my dead body,
and I swear it.
I want peace
in this house.
Hi, Suzanne.
How are you doing?
You fucking prick.
She said she sent me a text.
She wants a date with me.
- Don't talk shite.
- She fucking does. She wants me.
You two better be
on your best fucking behavior,
because we don't even
want you to be here.
Right, the bar's clear.
Fucking stand there.
Don't fucking break anything.
Just fucking stand in peace,
wee man.
Just fucking
shut your mouth, son.
Stop fucking ogling at the pool.
Fucking get your arse in line.
How are you,
gentlemen?
- I told you-- Al Capone.
- What did you say?
Say that again,
you wee fanny.
Al Capone.
Cheeky wee cunt.
Give him a cold shower.
Hey, hold on.
He's nothing to do with it.
I'm the one you want.
I organized everything.
- Sit down.
- What are you gonna do to him?
Fuck him.
Sit down.
Show me your arms.
Do it.
- Aye, he's clean.
- Good.
- How old are you?
- 15.
Who supplied you?
Are you afraid
we'll shop you?
I don't do that.
Ever.
I don't need to.
I do need to know
who supplied you, though.
Do you know why
I'm asking you that?
- In case somebody else tries to muscle in.
- Is that the case?
I stole it from Stan.
Stan Irvine?
Aye, he's going out
with my mum.
I knew he stashed it in
with the dogs, so I stole it.
And my granddad's teeth.
Could be true.
He's blaming a bent cop.
It is true.
I set him up.
I only phoned
the police to cover me.
Stan's not the sharpest.
So you thought we were gonna tell him
and you were gonna take a tanking?
He doesn't bother me.
But he might take it out on my mum.
That's some chance,
wee man.
You stay away
from our fucking shops.
Especially Big Jay Ellis's.
Now you might be
a breath of fresh air, kid,
but there's a lot of fucking wasters
out there trying my patience.
Do you know
what initiative is, kid?
Laughing at your boss's jokes?
We might just get on.
Give me my fucking trainers.
Next time, you'll be leaving here
with two broken legs.
Get to fuck!
You're getting no trainers.
- Fuck's sake. I'm fucking freezing.
- Couldn't keep it shut, could you?
- Give me your jacket.
- Fuck off. You'll get it wringing.
- Look at the stare of you.
- Fuck you.
Look, there's your fucking pal.
I'm gonna fucking get him back.
It looks like it too,
you fucking idiot.
If we prove we can do this,
and that's a big fucking "if,"
he's gonna give us
a regular supply.
The more we sell, the bigger the cut.
Just like a business.
See, they want reliable dealers,
no fucking junkies that are using
more than they're selling.
What's wrong
with what we're selling now?
What happens when it runs out?
Where are we gonna get the gear from?
How do we know
it's not shite?
- The guy's cool, man.
- No, he's a cunt.
You saw the health club.
He's a fucking different class.
And then he'll do you on
just like that. Trust me.
Who cares?
All we need is a couple of months.
Stick together, no fucking about,
and we're rolling in it.
What happens
to me and you?
We do it together, don't we?
A fucking partnership.
- I don't trust him.
- We can learn from this guy.
Yeah, learn to arse lick.
Look, fucking make up your mind
or I'll find somebody else, right?
Do you wanna end up a waster
like your old man?
Or do you want
to do something?
- Have a chip.
- Fuck off. He's still a cunt.
A rich cunt.
So, what's next, then?
I tell you,
we've gotta prove ourselves.
We've gotta sell more
than anybody else without getting caught.
We've gotta move fast,
that's the secret.
- I can get a fucking motor, no problem.
- Too flash.
I've fucking got it.
What?
Tell me.
Gonna fucking tell me?
Mopeds.
I'll be back
in two minutes.
You'd better be, because I've got
another delivery to do.
Better hurry up, all right?
- A tenner.
- Right.
It's brilliant stuff,
I'm telling you.
Have you got a phone number
so I can contact you?
Where is he, man?
- Hurry up.
- I'll be back in two minutes.
Fuck's sake, man.
A bit of speed,
come on.
Second left,
then first right.
- Fuck off. I've not got time for a detour.
- Fucking hurry up. We need to take this.
- I'm not fucking doing it.
- I mean it.
Hello, Nighttime?
This is fucking ridiculous, by the way.
This cunt's taking his time.
I've been out 20 minutes
and only delivered one pizza.
He's here.
I need to go.
Fucking move!
Fuck's sake.
- I told you two minutes.
- You've been up there fucking five.
Fucking hurry up.
Move!
Fuck's sake.
Fucking arsehole.
Calm down, man.
It's not my fault and I'll tell you now,
this is fucking bad for business.
Yeah, and I've got pizzas here
fucking freezing.
Fuck's sake.
If you drove half as much as you talk,
we might get somewhere.
Fuck, fuck, fuck.
For fuck's sake,
where have you been?
Sorry if it's caused
any inconvenience.
An hour and a half. I fucking phoned
for that a fucking hour and a half ago.
- I had transport difficulties.
- I'm trying to go for a pint
and fucking only want a pizza. You could
have got one from Italy quicker.
- I got held up.
- You think you're Dick Turpin or what?
- Sorry, mate.
- Hope it's the right fucking pizza.
And it's fucking freezing. You know
what you can do with your fucking pizza?
Stick it right up your arse
and that will heat it up a wee bit.
Now fuck off
out of my sight.
- What is this? Funghi or Hawaii?
- Funghi.
No bother.
I can't read your writing.
Where have you been?
- Calm down, man.
- There're 16 orders here not been done.
Have a word with him.
He takes ages.
- We took a wee detour.
- Where, Western Europe?
Fuck's sake,
we've got a reputation to protect--
the slickest,
the fastest--
and all destroyed
in one night.
- How much in tips do you make a night?
- That's nothing to do with you.
Before I came on board, how much in tips
did you make a night?
Five, six quid,
it all depends.
That's fucking pish.
Do you want your money or not?
Come here.
Plenty more where that came from
for you both if you stop fucking greeting.
- Is that for me?
- And him.
We can make a compromise
if it works like this.
He's all happy now.
He's fucking shut up now.
- You cut that gear yet?
- No, I'll do it a bit later.
Sitting there on your lazy arse.
Go and get the gear cut.
Don't talk about lazy arse.
I've been in here before fucking you.
Exactly. Go get the fucking gear cut.
What are you doing here?
- I'll cut it later.
- Better be cut tonight, by the way.
Get out!
Fuck's sake.
Oh, look, my wee brother's
all grown up.
He's turning into a man.
What a man gotta do
for a bit of privacy?
What are you shaving, son?
Fucking look at that.
It's not funny.
You missed a bit.
Get out!
- Don't you want me to do it for you?
- Get out!
I'm being serious.
Do you want me to help you?
I'm serious. Get out!
Did you ask
what they wanted us for?
Just said be there
for half 9:00.
- Are you worried?
- No, we're all right.
Did they sound fucking nervous
or angry or something?
What have they gotta be angry about?
We're fucking doing good business.
Fucking raking it in.
Just be cool, my man.
They're on time anyway.
Just play it cool, right?
Hi, Jack.
Hi, Tony.
- Where do you think you're going?
- What are you fucking doing?
- See you later, son.
Liam, come on-- fuck!
Tony, what's going on, man?
Fuck's sake, man.
Liam!
Come on-- fuck.
Fucking hell!
Fuck's sake.
You wanna dump
that wee prick.
That's my best pal
you're talking about.
If you want to go anywhere,
drop him.
He's right, Liam.
Listen to Tony.
Do you know this man?
- Aye, Scullion.
- Scullion.
- Be sure to remember his face, okay?
- Yeah.
Hello, Maureen.
Hi, it's Tony.
We'll be there in a minute.
Just wait at the back door, okay?
See that door?
Maureen's the barmaid.
She'll let you in.
She'll have something
for you.
Scullion's in there
with his team.
You wait 'til he's half pissed
and goes for a slash.
You follow him into the bog.
We'll make sure nobody gets in.
He's not gonna expect nothing
from you. Okay?
- Okay what?
- You're gonna do him in.
- You mean, kill him?
- Aye.
You're doing him,
wee man.
You're in with the big boys now, son.
Off you go, son.
You Okay?
Good.
If you'd just like
to come through here.
Listen, the bar's through here.
Your guy's out there,
just sitting over there at the bar.
The toilet is through there.
Have you got that?
I've got something
for you.
I'll be through
at the bar,
and I'll let you know
when he's coming through, okay?
See you soon.
Liam.
He's gone now.
Put it down!
It's all right, big man.
Nearly had my fucking
knackers off there.
You've got balls, son.
You're one of the team.
You're all right,
you're all right.
Fucking bastards.
I thought you were after
my fucking tadger, son.
Liam, see that?
You can fucking keep that.
Because you done
fucking brilliant!
Get this boy
a fucking drink!
Chantelle, what did you bring?
Did you bring sconies?
What do you normally take
to a picnic?
- Did you bring juice?
- Aye.
- Hands off. You're not getting any.
- I'm dying of thirst here.
That's for the picnic.
- What's she like?
- Tell him, Calum.
You're not getting any
'til we go to the picnic.
What happened?
Liam, what's happened?
I want to go over
and see what's happened.
- Just you stand there.
- What happened, Liam?
- What's he doing?
- I don't know.
Don't go in there,
Uncle Liam!
Don't!
Who would have
done this to you?
You stand there
with Suzanne.
You've upset the wean.
Come out.
I'll fucking kill him.
Open this fucking door, Stan!
You're fucking dead!
Get out here!
- Piss off!
- Open the fucking door!
He's not fucking here.
Get him fucking here,
you old bastard!
- Fuck off, you stupid wee cunt!
- Tell him to get fucking out here!
He's not fucking here.
Hey, you, fuck off.
Away back
to your wee hovel.
You old cunt. Tell him when I get
my hands on him, he's fucking dead.
Fucking shut it.
What? Put your teeth
in your gummy old fucker.
Shut up.
You just try that.
You fucking try it
and I'll come down there.
Fuck off.
You fucking dare!
You dare!
See you, you cunt.
You stupid wee
fucking boy you!
See you,
you monkey wee cunt.
You fucking wait
'til I get a hold of you.
You stupid
wee fucking arsehole!
You just wait
'til I get a hold of you!
You skinny wee cunt you!
A fucking mess
you've made here!
No, I am all right, Mum.
We're just gonna stay in with Liam,
me and Chantelle.
He's just had a little bit
of bother today.
Nothing, don't worry about it.
I'll tell you tomorrow.
Mum, it's all right, don't panic.
I'm fine, Mum, aye.
I don't need my pajamas,
I'll get some of Chantelle's.
- Is that all right?
- I've nothing clean.
You'll need
to get some of Liam's.
It's shut.
The doors are already locked.
Bye, Mum.
She's a pure
little bletherer.
Sounds all right.
She's a pure nightmare.
They'd better stop
that noise out there.
They're gonna wake
that wean up.
Who is it, Liam?
- Douglas.
- Who?
- Fuck me.
- Who's Douglas?
Nobody.
The pair of you, stay in here.
You'd better not be
causing trouble in my home.
Who is it?
Douglas' car, wee man.
Who's got it? Pinball's got it.
I told you
I'd get revenge on the prick.
- What the fuck are you all about?
- Fucking magic.
Are you fucking stupid?
Fuck off,
you fucking brown-nose.
Do you know
what you've fucking done?
We're fucking dead
if you don't take this back.
What are you talking about "we"?
You and me are no more.
- You're a fucking idiot.
- We'll fucking see.
Do you know who he is?
You're a daft wee fucking boy.
- Fuck off. I'm out of here.
- Fucking hold on!
Am I fuck.
Get out of my road.
I'm gone.
Fuck!
You fucking knob.
Don't fuck with me.
Don't you give me
a cold shower!
Let's go!
Come on!
All right, kid?
Look, Mr. Douglas--
Hi, can I get you
a coffee?
- Yeah, espresso.
- And for you, sir?
- The same as him, please.
- Sure.
I swear on my nephew's life
we'll pay every penny back.
Never mind that.
I've just bought your pizza place.
Put it in Tony's name.
- You bought Franco's?
- Aye.
I want you to buy
three new bikes,
sort out some good boys
and run the show.
When does your ma get out?
Three weeks.
- What are you gonna do about it?
- Fuck knows.
If she stays with Stan, she may as well
get a season ticket for where she is.
I'm trying to get
another caravan lined up.
Forget about it.
I rent out flats.
One's come free.
It's modest.
Nice views
over the river.
Decent neighbors.
You can take
your ma there.
And if it works out,
and I think it will, Liam...
you can buy it
over a period of time.
Why are you doing this?
You work for me, I take care of you.
Easy as that.
You can have these...
as soon as you take care
of that wee prick, Pinball.
Look, Mr. Douglas, he didn't know
what he was doing.
He's had a hard time.
His dad was a junkie.
I'm all he's got.
I'll sort it out. I swear.
He'll come and apologize
and I swear I'll pay back every penny.
Both of us.
If you can't deal with this,
you get out now.
He's like a brother to me.
Listen, an opportunity like this,
for somebody like you,
only comes once.
Are there any flats up here
where the junkies stay?
- Just the end one.
- Up there?
- Yeah. The end one.
- Cheers.
- Any of you seen Pinball?
- No.
I'm fucking serious.
Any of you know where he is, tell me.
We haven't seen him.
We haven't seen him anywhere.
Mate, wanna sign my stookie?
All of you get out.
I want a word with him.
Stay here, lads.
Don't move.
- Get fucking out.
- Don't move.
I said get the fuck
out of here.
Get the fuck out, all of you.
I mean it.
Get out.
I'm not in the fucking mood.
No bother.
Hold on. Wait.
In case somebody steals it.
Fuck's sake.
I'll get my jacket, too.
- See you later, pal.
- See you later, Pinball.
Brown-nose.
Don't move.
What's that
on your nose?
A speck of shite--
rich man's shite.
Shut the fuck up.
We need to talk.
Here to do me in,
are you?
Do me in, go on.
Fucking do me in, go on.
Put one arms behind my back.
I'll give you a chance.
Muhammad Al Pinball, eh?
"Fly like a butterfly,
sting like a bee."
We're in trouble.
Fucking calm down.
Put your fucking hands up.
- Pinball, listen to me.
- You like that?
Go on,
put your hands up.
Have you got anything in here?
Any drugs?
- What's this?
- Put it down.
A blade.
What you gonna do with that?
You gonna go like that?
- And that?
- Fuck off, put it down.
Put it down.
So you were here to do me in.
Here you are.
Take it.
Are you fucking man or mouse?
Fucking take it.
I'll help you.
Ready?
The caravan...
that's right,
fucking Pinball burnt it.
It wasn't Stan,
it was me.
- No way.
- Don't fucking move.
I knocked a motor can
of petrol.
Boom!
Up she went.
A fucking shame so it was.
Don't fucking move.
You fucking hurt me.
I'd have done anything for you.
Fucking anything.
But you fucked me about, didn't you?
You don't believe me?
Fucking get back.
You want the chance now?
- There you are, fucking do it.
- Fucking bastard.
You're still not doing it?
I'll fucking do it then.
Because you fucking put me
through pain. A bit of this?
What the fuck
are you doing?
Do you see
what you've done?
What the fuck
are you doing?
- Give me the knife.
- Leave it.
You came to fucking
do me in.
Fucking clown,
what did you do that for?
My fucking pal,
and you came to do me in.
You were gonna do it,
weren't you?
Ambulance, please.
119 Mitchell Street.
- Fuck your ambulance.
- Hurry up, please.
What the fuck,
you stupid bastard!
Let me see your face.
- You were gonna do it.
- I wasn't gonna do anything.
You stupid bastard.
Tony-
All right, mate.
It's been done.
Two tenner bags, mate?
- There you go.
- Cheers.
And here's your pizza.
Excellent, by the way.
Thanks a lot.
Hi, Angela.
- What do you think you're doing?
- I'm selling pizzas.
- Pizzas, aye, right.
- Honest.
You're not selling pizzas,
you're selling drugs. I've seen you.
- It's only pizzas.
- She's got a wee boy in there!
- I'm in a hurry.
- I'm not finished with you.
You know she's got a wee boy.
Do you know what you're doing to her?
You're scum, that's what you are,
and I'll be doing something about it.
I've got some news.
- I came first in my test.
- You did?
Brilliant.
I've got myself
a wee job in the call center.
- That's great, sis. I'm proud of you.
- It's only part time, mind.
And Suzanne's mum's gonna help me
with Calum. I'm dead chuffed.
See that guy we sell the fags for?
He rents out flats as well.
He's really pleased the way
I'm running the pizza shop.
He's offered me a flat
for when mum comes out.
Right.
That's great.
It's what you've always wanted.
It's got everything in it--
new washing machine, central heating.
There's plenty of room for you
and Calum as well.
Why don't you just give her
one more chance?
She didn't want me.
She didn't want you.
She was only a wee lassie then.
- And nothing's changed.
- You're not giving her a chance.
How many chances
has a wean got to give?
Your problem is
you're far too hard on her.
- She's desperate to see Calum.
- You're lying!
I got a set of keys
cut for you.
These are yours.
Come on.
I don't know.
What's holding you back?
I'm scared.
I know you think
it's for the best.
It is for the best.
A new start for all of us--
you and Calum away from here
and my mum out of jail.
I don't know.
Open the door.
I didn't mean
to upset you.
I'm just thinking
of you and Calum.
Come on,
open the door.
No, I'm all right.
- Please open the door.
- No.
I'll give you a cuddle.
- So, what time is she due out?
- Half 10:00.
Hello?
All right, Tony.
How are you doing?
Aye.
Did you see Stan for us?
Are you sure that cunt's
not gonna turn up?
Cheers, Tony.
I appreciate it.
All right, mate.
Ta. See you.
It's a long time since
I've been down this side of town.
- You better get used to it.
- What are you talking about?
- Where are we going?
- It's a surprise.
You'll find out when we get there.
Do you know
where we're going, driver?
Don't ask me.
My lips are sealed.
- Liam, where are we going?
- It's a surprise.
Who lives here?
Just opposite
this set of stairs.
This is brilliant.
Here we are.
- Are you kidding me?
- No.
Go on, just open it.
Have a look.
I still think
you're kidding me.
I'll show you
the kitchen.
Built-in oven
with microwave.
Dishwasher.
Very nice.
Very classy.
Balcony.
Imagine this
in the summer, Mum.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
Let's see the bedroom.
Your dressing-table.
Your ensuite bathroom
just through there.
A bathroom in my bedroom.
- And a shower.
- Like it?
I don't know what to say.
Don't need to say anything.
It's all yours.
Does Stan know
about this?
Give a big warm welcome back
for wee Jean.
We've all missed her
very much.
So, Jean,
this is a song from me.
A big one from Robbie Williams,
"Let Me Entertain You."
- Any sign of Stan?
- No. I've not seen him.
- Keep an eye out for him.
- I will. Aye.
- You look nice.
- I know.
Cheers for coming.
- How are you, young man?
- Watch your fingers.
- Looking smart.
- Where have we to go?
In here?
Oh, look, there's Suzanne.
Chantelle, you came.
Thanks, love.
It's good to see you.
- How are you?
- I'm all right.
Look at your lovely suit.
Come to see your granny, Cal?
We don't call him Cal.
His name's Calum.
- What do you mean?
- His name's Calum.
Do you want
a little drink?
"You Stole the Sun
from My Heart."
Come on,
I wanna see you all dancing.
- How are you?
- I'm all right.
Good.
It's nice to see you again.
- How have you been?
- All right.
- Is he asleep?
- That's him asleep now.
No point disturbing him.
You should just stay the night.
It's a shame to wake him.
We'll stay.
- Morning.
- What are you doing up so early?
- You're just up late.
- Where's Calum?
- He's still in bed.
All the excitement last night
must have tired him out.
My head's fucking pounding.
Are you gonna stick the kettle on?
Is Mum up yet?
What's wrong with you?
She's gone.
Wee walk will do her good.
Think she had one too many last night.
No, Liam, she's gone.
Gone where she normally goes,
the same usual as always.
Liam, calm down.
This is your fucking doing.
What did you say to her?
I never said nothing to her.
- Get out of my fucking way.
- Calm down!
Where's my fucking other shoe?
Liam, let her go.
She'll drive you mad.
Let her go, for Christ's sake.
Listen to me.
It's not that she doesn't care.
She can't care.
She's a fucking crazy
mixed-up lost soul
and she's gonna ruin you too.
I saw you talking to her last night.
What were you saying to her?
- If you drove her back to Stan--
- Drove her back to Stan?
If it's not Stan, it'll be somebody else
and somebody else!
I've never seen her
as happy as last night.
Stop lying to yourself, Liam.
Where's my fucking trainer?
- Give me my shoe.
- Liam, calm down.
- Give me my fucking shoe.
- Please, Liam.
- It's me that cares for you.
- So that's your fucking game?
- Worming your way in here.
- We need you.
Your twisted fucking lies
drive my ma away.
I'm not like that!
You've never liked her.
Never gave her a fucking chance!
I gave her too many chances,
you know that.
"We don't call him that.
His name's Calum"--
rubbing her face in it
in front of everybody.
Liam, listen to you!
- What did you say to her?
- I never said nothing.
Just give me the fucking trainer.
Give me the trainer
before I'll do something I'll regret.
- Go on, then.
- Don't make me do it.
Go! Just like Granddad,
like our fathers! Like Stan!
Like all the other losers
destroying everything they touch.
Like our mum!
Join the club.
Be one of them,
because that's what you are!
Liam, don't!
You fucking poisoned wee cow!
I fucking swear to God.
Look at me.
By the time I get back,
you'd better be out of here.
Do you hear me?
- Are you on?
- Aye.
Gilmore Street, Greenock, pal.
Where's my ma?
What the fuck you want here?
You wanna see your ma?
Big man here,
the boy's come to see you.
What are you doing here?
- You come for another hit?
- No, that's not it.
- Mum, let's go.
- I can't.
Never mind what he,
Chantelle or anybody says.
- This is so sad.
- It's just me and you, Mum.
- Son, you don't understand.
- Nothing matters, come on.
I can't.
- Fuck's sake.
- Stan, don't.
Don't be scared of him.
He can't hurt us anymore.
Come on.
Where's your bag?
Fucking hell!
- Liam, come here.
- You're wasting your time, son.
- Shut up.
- You wanna get him fucking told?
- You keep winding him up.
- Telling me to shut up?
- Come storming in here--
- Come on, Mum.
I can't.
- I've got a flat. It's a fresh start for us.
- I can't.
Chantelle's gone. I've got rid of her.
It's just me and you.
Do you think your mother wants
to fucking move in with you?
- You make her fucking stomach turn.
- Shut up.
Liam, go on.
I'll come and see you later. Please.
- Come on, Mum, let's go.
- I can't. You don't understand?
Say bye-bye to your mother.
You know what you can do, son.
- Leave him.
- Fucking sit down!
- Don't talk to my mum like that.
- Send one of your fucking little tapes.
"Mummy, I love you..."
Tell him about the caravan.
What did you say about the caravan?
"A field in the middle
of nowhere. Great, eh?"
- It wasn't like that. Don't listen.
- It was like that.
Tell him what you fucking mean.
Tell him the fucking truth, Jean.
That is the truth, son.
And your silly wee fucking house?
Think you're fucking going up
in the world in fucking Gourock,
with a view across the Clyde?
I won't shut up.
I love you. He doesn't love you.
I need you, Mum.
"I love you."
Well, I love your ma
and she loves me.
Get that through
your fucking thick head.
There's the fucking door.
Now leave!
- Stop it!
- Do as you're told, pal.
Fucking leave, son.
Fucking little bastard, you.
What are you doing?
- Liam!
- Bastard!
What have you done?
Stop it!
Liam! Stop it!
Fucking look at me!
No, stop it!
- I'll kill the cunt.
- What have you done?
Oh my God!
Get a fucking ambulance.
The fucking bastard
stabbed me!
Hi, Liam.
It's Chantelle.
Are you okay?
- Where are you?
- I don't know.
Is it true?
Everybody's looking for you.
The police have been round.
What a waste.
It's your birthday. You're 16.
Did you know that?
What are you gonna do?
My batteries are running down.
I love you, Liam.