- Hi, Spike. How are you?
- Hi, Jack.
She sounds good today.
Come on, boy.
Hi, spike.
- Hi, Kay.
- Seen Jack?
Yeah, he's out front.
Wesley, get over here.
How you doing, Ethel?
- Hi, honey.
- Hi, honey. How are you?
Good. Hope you're hungry.
I'm starving.
Think you can make that any louder?
- Busy day, honey?
- The same old stuff, sweetheart.
How cheap can you get?
Tramp!
- I think she's a singer.
- Singer, my foot.
Saturdays are rotten when you work.
Tell that to the bill collectors, honey.
Free enterprise is killing me.
- I can't make a dime in that dump.
- I know, babe. My feet are killing me.
We'll settle down with a business.
Doing something decent.
I'm going to sell the Egyptian. It's a curse.
There's got to be something else
I can do besides run a cheap dance hall.
Biscuits, honey, coming in or what?
There's fine smoking pleasure
in fine tobacco...
and lucky strike means fine tobacco.
So round, so firm...
he said, "Do you want the job?"
- Want a balloon?
- Thank you.
It's a war! We're at war!
The goddamn Japs bombed Hawaii!
The Japanese have attacked
Pearl Harbor, Hawaii, by air...
President Roosevelt has just announced.
The attack also was made
on naval and military activities...
in the principal islands of Oahu.
I have a boy at sea on a destroyer.
For alll know,
he may be on his way to the pacific.
- Two of my children are in...
- Mrs. Roosevelt's son's on a destroyer.
Many of you all over this country...
have boys in the services
who now will be called upon...
this american's going to die
with perfect nails.
- You cannot escape things.
- Ethel, hand me that hammer.
I'm telling you, the light's
going to show through that thing.
They said this is how you're supposed
to do it on the radio, hon.
I don't think
it's going to do a bit of good, sweetheart.
- You're probably right.
- Let me give you some help.
There. I did it, Jack.
I'm going to get you another beer.
I'm signing up tomorrow. I've got to.
I knew you were going to say that.
Honey, snap out of it, will you?
Pearl harbor's one thing,
but the japs aren't going to land here.
How do you know?
First of all, the fishing's been real lousy
off santa monica pier this year.
Second of all, I won't let them.
- What if something happens to you?
- Listen to me, Kay.
Nothing's going to happen to me.
But I've got to go.
Damn it, they started it.
We've got to finish it. We've got to.
I've got to go.
- It will be all right.
- Promise?
I promise.
Now, let's see.
A seaman third makes $18.75 a month,
plus $5.00 sea duty.
That's $23.75 I can send you home
every month.
Prices might go up because of the war,
so be careful how you spend it. Okay?
- I was thinking I could take something on.
- Like what?
A job. Penney's is looking for salesgirls...
I don't want you doing any such thing.
I don't want you working.
I just want you to be safe.
What am I going to do if I don't have you
to do things for anymore?
That lid sure is swell on you, Kay.
I bought it to see you off.
I know you like red.
- Yeah, I like red.
- Section five, move out!
I don't know what I'm going to do
without you, honey.
God, me neither, Kay.
Section five, let's move.
Bye, Jack!
I said to myself, "Frankie Parker,
you better get out of here...
"if you ever want to be somebody."
You sing real nice.
- Thank you.
- My unit's shipping out tomorrow.
No fooling.
Here. Find yourself another girl, okay?
Good luck, sweetie.
Biscuits, you said
I could sing tonight, remember?
I got to get a big name up there.
What do you mean, a big name?
You said I could sing tonight.
I got a gold mine here.
This could be a first-class hall
if I play it right.
I'm talking helen forrest, ginny simms,
jo stafford. Not Hazel zanussi.
- Know who goes dancing during a war?
- No. Tell me.
- Everybody.
- Biscuits, you told me...
- here you go, boss.
- Thank you, knuckles.
- She takes a good picture, doesn't she?
- Jesus!
So the girls go for me. Is that my fault?
No, I just thought that you and I
were going to get respectable.
- Remember that?
- It's finished. Satisfied?
Now, haven't you got something to do?
I sure do.
Women wanted for war production work
here in our city.
Why?
More and more men are being called
into the armed forces.
Their jobs must be filled, and filled now.
And who can fill them? You. You women.
You're the ones who must fill them,
who can give our boys what they need.
A thousand more planes.
More and more tanks, and more ships.
Good afternoon.
Malcolm Macbride,
from my battle station to yours.
I want to take this opportunity
to welcome all the many new associates...
to the Macbride aircraft company
here in santa monica.
We are engaged
in a great world struggle...
to maintain our american way of life
as we know it.
The contributions you make at Macbride
will ensure our victory.
Again, welcome,
from my battle station to yours.
They got some pretty tight spaces
on those bombers.
You'd be good at that.
Are they asking for references?
You're breathing. That's good enough
for them. They're using everybody.
"My dearest darling, I love you.
"I miss you so much I can hardly stand it."
I've just got to get this job.
Believe me, I do.
- I believe you.
- I've got a kid to feed. Her name is Peggy.
Isn't she sweet.
My husband would kill me
if he knew what I was doing.
I'm Violet Mulligan.
Over here!
- You gotta have your high school diploma.
- I've got it...
Attention, new employees.
Long hair is dangerous.
So for safety's sake,
cut your hair or wear a hair net.
- Swing shift, 60 cents an hour.
- Swing shift?
Swing shift: 4:00 to midnight. Okay?
- Great.
- Here's your diploma.
Here's your handbook.
Please read it thoroughly. Next, please.
- Small world.
- Tiny.
- We're neighbors. The Balmy Palm.
- Yeah, I know who you are.
I thought we could go home together.
You've got a lot of nerve, you know that?
Every time I walk past your place...
all you and your husband can do
is make wisecracks about me.
What the hell do you think I am?
Deaf, dumb, and blind?
This itty-bitty thing is not a thumbtack.
It's what we call a rivet.
And this is a rivet gun.
But we don't want you
shooting anybody with it, do we, boys?
Get serious here for a moment.
Riveting is real suited to you gals...
because women
are used to repetitive tasks.
Believe me, ladies,
as strange as all this may seem...
after training,
you'll use these tools as easily...
as you would a can opener
or a sewing machine needle at home.
- Those are your skinners.
- What?
Your skinners. Your reamer.
- Your bucker-upper.
- Right.
Come on.
Here. Hit it.
Very good.
Very good. Let's do a couple more.
- I think I learned it.
- Okay.
My god! What have I done?
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
Listen to her!
- Sure, it's ladies' day.
- Bull's eye.
- I could have gone right through you!
It's all right.
Come on, let's go outside.
I'm your leadman.
Just take a deep breath
and you'll get your confidence back.
Okay.
Maybe I just should've stayed at home.
Oh, balls. Look, you... I mean... I'm sorry.
That's okay. My husband used to say that
all the time, "Oh, balls."
- It's okay.
- Is he dead?
No.
You okay?
- Yeah. I'm fine, thanks.
- I'm going to watch you for a while.
When you get nervous,
you can hurt yourself.
Okay, thank you. Thanks a lot.
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
Hey, moon!
Darn it.
Move it or lose it, toots!
- I missed my bus.
- Tough.
Yeah, that would've been
about 20 minutes ago.
- You need a lift?
- In that?
It's all I got.
You sure get tired by the end of the day.
- That's my trumpet.
- I'm sorry.
Hold on.
I bought it from a guy
who went to the army.
My husband's in the navy.
Oh, boy.
Hi.
We made it.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Bright and early.
4:00 p.m. It's all so turned around, isn't it?
- My name's lucky.
- Kay walsh.
All the above.
Lucky, that's a funny name.
How did you get it?
I better not tell you. It's kind of dirty.
Evening, Mrs. Walsh.
- You just stick with it, Kay.
- I will. Thanks.
Guess what, spike? I'm working now!
What are you doing? You're crazy!
Hazel, what are you doing?
There's only perverts out at this hour.
Get out of my way!
You okay?
I think the bike's messed up. Look at it.
I'll give you a ride home.
If you don't leave at the count of five,
I'm calling the cops.
- One, two, three...
- you're making a big mistake.
...four...
- quit that racket!
- What's going on out here?
Are you all right? What happened?
- What the hell is going on?
- It's nothing, spike.
It's not the japs or anything.
Just go back to bed.
I like your hair.
Thank you.
Jack would have a heart attack
if he saw me.
- Who's Jack?
- My husband.
Right. Mr. Personality.
- I should go home.
- Wait. I made this for you.
My name is Kay. What's your name?
- Hazel.
- Hazel?
Yeah. It's my mom's name.
I'd watch you go to work all the time
just to see what new outfit you'd wear.
Thanks.
Are you a singer?
- What is this?
- Hot milk.
- Yeah, I'm a singer.
- I knew it.
Didn't even tell Biscuits about my new job.
- Biscuits?
- Just some guy I used to know.
- It's Jack, in uniform.
- Right.
If he knew where I was working,
he'd wouldn't believe it.
He'd never picture me
riveting and drilling...
riding motorcycles.
I needed a ride.
- It's none of my beeswax.
- I didn't do anything wrong.
All right, I'm not your husband.
- It was just a ride, and that was all.
- All right! Jesus.
I guess I better get going.
Got to work tomorrow.
You got a little mustache.
- Don't worry about that guy.
- What guy?
The one you used to know.
You'll find somebody else.
See you later.
Almost five months
since entering the war...
- the government has proved...
- over there.
There's a space.
What are you doing?
Buddy, who the hell do you think you are?
I'm going to tell you who I am.
I'm moon willis.
I've worked at this damn place
for 12 long years.
This is my parking space.
I ain't about to lose it...
to a bunch of fly-by-night women like you.
You don't belong here, none of you!
What's his trouble?
We were just coming in here.
I saw that parking place...
and then he pulled in...
- you haven't quit yet.
- No. We have to win the war, don't we?
I just try to pay the bills
and stay out of trouble, myself.
- What's troubling you?
- I'd like a left-handed lock wire plier.
Lou, we got another patsy!
Stick out your left hand.
There. Now you got
a left-hand lock wire plier.
- Got it?
- Yeah, I got it.
Now remember it.
All you gotta say is, "listen, you big ape.
"You ever pull that on me again,
I'll slap your ears off."
"Listen, you big ape."
Back to work, ladies.
Listen, you big, fat ape!
Yeah.
- Where's my left-hand lock wire pliers?
- Listen here...
- Listen?
- You big...
- big what?
- Big fat...
She's so gorgeous.
Have a seat.
Sorry.
- Thank you.
- Hi.
- How you doing?
- The days are getting longer.
- What does that mean?
- I don't know.
- What did you say it for?
You seem a little uncomfortable.
Where's your motorcycle?
I'm taking my poke at hitler. Saving gas.
Where are you from, Kay?
We're from lowa,
my husband Jack and me.
I'm playing my horn tonight.
You want to come hear me?
- No. I have a million things to do.
- I'm not bad.
- It's a cute little place, next corner.
- No. I have to write Jack a letter.
- And I have a lot to do.
- I understand.
So what about you? You like good music?
- You addressing me?
- Correct.
You're barking up the wrong tree, mister.
My mother always said someday
I'd meet a wonderful girl like you.
See you tomorrow, Kay.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
...taking us one step closer
to the big victory!
Okay!
- Talk to you a minute, Kay?
- Sure.
- Some guys can't take "no" for an answer.
- Yeah, I know.
You said it.
I think our line is moving really fast,
don't you?
Last chance, Kay.
Kelly's, saturday night.
Lucky lockhart and his hot jazz trumpet.
It's great working with you...
and I think you're the best leadman
on the line...
and I just know you're a swell fellow.
But you've been asking me out every week
for the last five months...
and I keep having to turn you down.
People are beginning to talk.
I'm just trying to improve
your taste in music, Kay.
But you won't
have to turn me down again.
Don't be late or I'll dock you, Mrs. Walsh.
Attention, please.
We have just received news
of another tragic loss.
The Japanese have sunk the USS Carrier Hornet...
defending guadalcanal.
I know many of you swing shifters
have husbands...
sons, and sweethearts on guadalcanal.
We must work harder to help turn the tide.
Signing off.
If he asks me out tonight,
I'll tell him not to bother me anymore.
It's up to you.
Maybe you could come along,
just to keep things safe.
Why not? Come on.
What're you gonna do?
You're off tomorrow.
You're gonna sit at home?
I thought I could whip up
a batch of victory fudge.
Look, honey, you don't need me.
I got faith in you.
You do?
Sure.
I really like you, Hazel.
A lot.
- Gee, Kay, I really like you, too.
- No, I really like you...
All right, don't get sentimental on me.
- You wanted to tell me something?
- Thank you.
- I think you're a swell guy.
- I think you are terrific.
You know, there are a lot of great girls
at the plant.
- Millions.
- Single gals.
Lots of them, too. So?
Spike and Ethel, my landlords.
What's the matter?
What's wrong?
- Kay?
- Sorry.
- Wait a minute.
- Excuse me.
- Are you all right?
- I'm fine.
What're you doing? Wait a minute.
Taxi!
Excuse me.
- Wait a minute!
- I can't...
- what the hell...
- I can't. I'm married.
- So what? So that's it?
- It's wrong.
Come on, Kay.
It's your own life.
You've got a right to be happy.
I can't.
I'm married. Don't you understand that?
Don't you get it?
Please...
go away.
- Come on, I'll give you a ride home.
- No.
Come on, Kay.
Just come out of the alley.
Suit yourself.
Kay, Hazel, look!
I got another letter from al.
And it's only two months old.
If you had me to keep you company
you wouldn't need vitamins.
All these guys think they're god's gift,
every last one of them.
- Sweetie, it's always been that way.
- You're right.
There she is.
Mrs. Sherman. Ladies.
Are you Mrs. Jeannie sherman?
Yes.
The wife of cpl. Albert sherman,
glendale, california?
I'm sorry to inform you that...
- Oh, god.
- I'm sorry.
I've never done this before.
Associates...
Congratulations for having surpassed
our 1942 quota.
Celebrate a good year's work
at the swing shift jamboree.
Remember, the swing shift jamboree...
this saturday night
at the egyptian ballroom.
United States Naval Forces
have destroyed...
twenty-three Japanese warships
and transports...
peewee, where did you get that dress?
The museum?
No good?
You got a swell shape, sweetheart.
Why are you afraid to show it?
- Jack doesn't like revealing things.
- So? Let him wear it.
- I don't want to go to the dance anyway.
- Good. Me neither.
- You like it up or down?
- I like it up.
That's the war news tonight,
for November 17.
I just thought since it's down the street,
you know, that little place...
The Egyptian Ballroom?
I've had it with that place.
I wouldn't be caught dead there.
Me, either. Dumb idea.
The egyptian ballroom.
Swing shift jamboree.
Stupid. God.
We could just stay home
and do something.
Sure.
We could clean out your kitchen drawers.
Sure. We could do that.
They'll probably think
we're stuck-up for not going.
- So?
- Who cares?
- I don't care.
- I know.
Okay.
Got any aces?
Are you absolutely sure
you don't want to go?
That dress looks ridiculous.
- It does?
- We'll work on it.
I'll fix you up.
I'm getting it!
- Hi, Hazel.
- How are you doing?
- I thought you'd never make it.
- Come on!
- Who's the new girl?
- Not right now, okay? Later.
Honey, is this check okay?
- Care to dance?
- Yeah, sure.
I didn't think I was ever gonna
see you again, but you show up.
Here we are back at the egyptian,
just like old times.
- I knew I shouldn't have come here.
- Not true.
You're got to see
what fate has in store for you.
'Cause just when you think you're through
and life has got you beat...
it comes right back to you,
stronger than ever.
And everything's good again. Just like us.
I came here tonight
to be with my friends, Biscuits.
There's plenty of nice guys at the plant...
we have swell times.
And you don't look so beat to me.
This place is doing great.
You probably got all the money
and the girls you can handle.
- What you've always wanted, isn't it?
- It's what I always wanted.
Why don't you go on inside
and enjoy yourself with your new friends?
I think I'd like to just finish my cigarette,
if you don't mind.
Someday I'm going to do something
that'll surprise you. You wait and see.
I don't know much about music,
but you were just terrific.
Thanks. I really am a musician.
I'm not a mechanic.
- Working at Macbride's is killing me.
- Why aren't you in the service?
- I'm a jap spy.
- Aren't you ever serious about anything?
What is there to be serious about?
Everything. The war, the nazis...
winston churchill.
I think you look prettier
without all that stuff.
You're too good-looking for that.
Do you want a ride home?
Get inside. I'm getting wet.
Gosh, I'm freezing.
And I'm starving.
- That's not all.
- What else am I?
- For one thing, you're all wet.
- I know.
Your make-up's probably
in your nylons by now.
- What did you think I was going to say?
- Nothing.
You know me better than that.
I'd have made an unacceptable suggestion.
Come on, you always do that to me.
What's your suggestion?
I happen to make the best cheese omelet
in the world.
- Change your clothes.
- How about you?
Change into what?
- This?
- Forget it.
Or this?
- I'll catch pneumonia first.
- It's this or this. Take your choice.
- How much longer? I'm starving.
- Hold on another minute.
- Why?
- Here's why.
Lucky, you're pretty good.
Stop it. It's just a little something
I whipped up.
- You do this to me all the time.
- Lucky, the things you do.
- How about a little supper music?
- Sure.
Skylark.
No good?
No, it's okay. I just play it a lot
when I'm alone, that's all.
Too loud?
Do you know this?
This old mouthpiece.
It's getting hard to hit the high notes.
No excuses. Really.
Aren't you gonna eat?
In a minute.
I looked all over for you at the jamboree.
Never did get to dance with you.
Would you like to?
Did you meet Jack in high school?
Four-year letter man. In what?
Basketball, baseball, track, football.
- He was quite an athlete.
- He still is, I'm sure.
How come you never asked me
if I was 4f?
I don't know.
Just in case
you ever wondered about it, I am.
The army turned me down.
- I flunked my physical.
- I'm sorry.
Don't be. It's not worth it.
I'm not sick. I'm just 4f.
- 4f, that's all.
- It's not like they called you a dirty name.
It isn't.
Skip it. If it hadn't have been for the war...
nobody would have said a thing
about my bad heart.
Besides, it doesn't bother me.
Yeah, I can see that.
It bothers me a little.
Mainly with making girls nervous.
Making girls nervous? How?
- If you saw me do something strenuous...
- you wouldn't want me to worry.
- Exactly.
- That's very considerate.
Thanks.
I just want you to enjoy yourself naturally.
You were just so sure
you could get me into bed...
you didn't want me to be nervous
about your bad heart.
- I don't have a bad heart.
- I'm telling you, I don't care.
I don't know how
you even let me get into this.
- Get you into what?
- You know what.
- I don't have to spell it out.
- I'd like to think you helped.
- We made love to each other.
- Repeat that.
I'm not gonna make myself any clearer.
Are you telling me
I'm the one responsible for all this...
when you've been asking me out forever
and I keep saying no?
- And all the time you meant yes.
- I didn't. I meant no.
Somebody around here said yes.
- I said yes because I felt sorry for you.
- Sure, and there's a war going on.
- Get out of here!
- What's it look like I'm doing?
- Do it faster, then.
- I won't even put on my shoes.
- I never want to see you again.
- Slow down.
Never.
- Who is it?
- Me.
I don't know what we're talking about.
We've got to go back to work in 12 hours.
I don't understand why it had to happen
in the first place, that's all.
World war ii?
No.
Why did we have to end up
working together?
- Kay, are you all right?
- I'm fine.
I just wondered.
I'll never see you again...
except monday through friday
from 4:00 till midnight, every swing shift.
If you were any kind of gentleman...
I'd what? Work graveyard?
What?
You wouldn't know so much about me.
Everywhere. In my work, in my life.
How do I ever get rid of you?
You can't, I hope.
Is that bad?
I don't know.
I guess we're in it.
For the duration. Oh, boy.
You don't have to get rid of it.
You just blew your nose.
We made those.
- Sweetheart.
- Yeah?
- Good morning. What's up?
- Allies into palermo. Axis on the run.
- You want one?
- Sure.
Out joy riding,
using up that black market gas?
Yeah, spike, that's what you use
when you go joy riding.
Lucky and Hazel invited me
to go to the beach.
They must have thought
I was getting lonely.
Bye, lucky. Thanks.
- Goodbye, honey.
- Goodbye, sweetheart.
See you soon, hon.
You ought to come next time, spike.
We had a real swell time.
That's good. Set it at 25.
Where do we stand now on this?
Kay was so wonderful, wasn't she?
Good night.
Five guys. Yeah, like that.
- Lucky, you seen Kay?
- Yeah.
She got called to personnel
before the shift ended.
- I think they're going to give her a medal.
- She saved Violet's life.
Guess what?
They're making me a leadman.
- Leadman?
- Yes!
They said I was fast on my feet.
Macbride shook my hand.
I told him the line was moving too fast,
that's what happened.
They just smiled
and handed you a promotion, right?
I thought you'd be proud of me.
So we're still going to get together
later on?
Sure.
I am proud. Really.
- Thanks.
- Good night, lucky.
Here it is, girls!
- Look!
- We're here.
This is wonderful.
This is better than anything.
This place...
the music...
dancing with you.
It's pretty damn good.
I wish it could be like this forever.
Why not?
Isn't it unusual for somebody
with your amazing looks to be a riveter?
No, it's amazing for someone
with my unusual looks to be a riveter.
- Touche.
- Touche?
That means you wounded me. Slightly.
You've got quite a line in palaver:
The come-on, the french lesson.
You're quite a dancer.
What's your room number?
There you go,
beating around the bush again.
Paging smn amtzis,
Sgt. Mccloud, smn Touie.
If I came on a little bit strong, I apologize.
Hi, Hazel.
- Surprised?
- Yeah.
- All right, who's this guy?
- Pardon me.
Pardon me, sir.
- Isn't your...
- beat it, buddy.
Propel your french elsewhere, sir,
and au revoir.
That means scram, all right?
Good evening, Mrs. Zanussi. Seaman.
Beat it, all right?
Same old light touch, Hazel?
I don't know why I did that.
Smn Touie? What...
something in our life
keeps bringing you and me together.
I'm shipping out tonight.
- Tonight?
- Yeah. I'm glad, though.
Because now I can tell you I'm sorry.
For frankie, the broads,
the promises, everything.
- I messed up real bad with you, Hazel.
- You talk like you're going to die.
Come on, Touie. Let's go.
Take care of yourself, Hazel.
- Happy new year, doll.
- It's almost midnight.
Out of uniform, buddy?
I don't have a uniform, buddy.
Don't push me! Take a hike!
Is that what you want?
You want a piece of me, asshole?
Come and get it!
- Wait a minute!
- No!
Ten, nine, everybody!
Eight, seven, six, five...
four, three, two, one!
Happy new year!
June 6, 1944, d-day.
American, british, and canadian troops
landed in northern france this morning.
Stand by
for general eisenhower's broadcast...
as the allies launch this great invasion.
Soldiers, sailors, and airmen
on the allied expeditionary force...
you're about to embark upon
the great crusade...
toward which we've striven
these many months.
In company with our brave allies
and brothers-in-arms on other fronts...
you will bring about the destruction
of the german war machine.
The elimination of nazi tyranny
over the oppressed peoples of europe...
and security for ourselves
in the free world. Good luck.
And let us all beseech the blessing
of almighty god...
upon this great and noble undertaking.
Associates, back to work!
- Happy birthday!
- Thanks.
- The shirt's from Hazel.
- Really?
Just give me a minute. I'll be right back.
I forgot something.
- Thanks.
- You're welcome, lucky.
All right.
- What is it?
- My contribution to your musical career.
You like it?
Jesus, Kay.
- Baby, thanks.
- You're welcome.
It's me!
Kay, I'm home!
- Who wants a beer?
- I do.
- Hi.
Is my wife here?
Is Kay here?
Kay, look who's here.
Watch this.
- I don't believe it.
- I'm on liberty.
- I brought you a rose.
- Thanks.
- This is lucky.
- Hi.
- Lucky, nice to meet you.
- And Hazel.
We all work together.
- Come on, let's...
- excuse us.
We're shipping out again in 48 hours.
Couldn't tell anybody we were coming in.
Couldn't breathe a word about it.
- How about that?
- That's something.
Kay, where...
- what is it, honey?
- Who's the leadman?
Anybody I know?
- Yeah, it's somebody you know.
- Who is it?
- It's me. I'm the leadman.
- You?
See.
I got a promotion.
- That's great.
- Thanks.
I came in to try on my civvies
and see what they felt like...
- but they didn't seem to be here.
- I'm sorry, honey.
This closet, it's full of equipment and stuff.
It's like fibber mcgee's closet.
But they're in boxes...
no. Don't bother with it, Kay.
I can't wear them anyway.
I'll just wear them in the house.
I'm sorry. My gosh.
What a mess.
Congratulations.
Thanks.
- You got it.
- Yeah, I got it.
- Got it all over everything.
- Good job.
Thanks.
Did you have a good rest?
Sure did.
- Welcome home, honey.
- Thanks.
So are you going to change that?
Sure, honey.
So, like I said, congratulations. Congrats.
- For what?
- You know.
- What did you say you were making?
- $1.35 an hour.
- What did you say about overtime?
- I didn't.
Beats me, anyway.
Beats me all to hell. Here's to you, kiddo.
And that guy you work with...
what's his name?
Lucky.
- There's no question about that.
- What do you mean?
He's stateside. He's not in uniform.
How lucky can he get?
I don't think he'd call it lucky.
The next time you go to work,
ask him what he'd call it...
and where I might stand in line to get it.
What would you call it, Jack?
I'd call it cheating, Kay.
I went to war!
- I know.
- So who else got lucky besides lucky?
Didn't it mean anything?
That you're my wife?
Of course it meant something.
I tried to wait but everything in this house
reminded me of you...
sure, baby.
Blame it on the war.
It's everybody's excuse.
I'm not the same.
And neither are you.
I'm sorry.
I was wrong. I'm sorry.
Do you love this guy?
Jack, please forgive me.
- Moon told me about that.
- See you tomorrow.
What the hell are you doing here?
- Thought you were sick.
- Talk to you a minute, Hazel?
Sure.
Come on, Violet, let's go pick up Peggy.
Good night, Hazel.
Listen, I'm playing at kelly's
later on tonight.
Want to come?
I don't think so.
All right.
- Suit yourself.
- You going to be all right?
Never better.
Is this seat taken?
One scotch.
- You're leaving so early...
- I couldn't sleep.
I got to get out of here.
- Did you read my note?
- No.
What does the note say, Jack?
What's it say?
I can't believe what you've done.
Honey, I'm sorry.
All right. Let's get out of here.
"Dear Kay...
"I don't understand what you've done,
but I guess you're right.
"Everything changes.
"I'm different, you're different,
the whole world is different.
"I don't know what's right anymore.
"I guess we both
have a lot of thinking to do.
"I'll try and write
when I'm not so confused.
"They say the war will be over soon.
"I hope so.
It's sure taken its toll on all of us.
"All the best. Jack."
What did you think of the guys
I played with last night?
They were okay. You were better.
They're heading back east
in a couple of weeks.
I could probably work it out
to go with them.
What's the matter, Hazel?
It's not gonna be so hot
telling Kay about this.
What's the big hurry in telling her?
Besides, I'm the one
with the broken heart, remember?
I don't think I can look her in the eye
until I do.
Wait a minute!
Come in.
God. I don't even recognize the place.
- Would you like some tea?
- Some tea?
I'll take some tea.
Jack's mother gave me this tea set
when we were married.
Really? It's lovely.
Thank you.
Cream?
Yes, please.
Sugar?
You got sugar?
How many sugars?
No sugar. Thanks.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Sandwich?
Kay, seeing you with Jack
made lucky nuts.
I was lonely. It's not gonna happen again.
Who would have thought
this would happen to us?
What are we gonna do about this?
We'll all be friends.
What else?
All right!
Thank you.
- Waiter.
- Hold on.
Honey, don't you think
you'd better take it easy?
- Why? We're celebrating, aren't we?
- What are we celebrating?
Everything. Friendship.
So, here we are.
- You still blow a mean horn, lucky.
- Glad you liked it, Kay.
Hazel liked it, too. Didn't you, haz?
- Fresh circle.
- Fresh circle?
Another round.
To lucky and Hazel.
Kay and Jack.
Here's mud in your eye.
- Kay, why don't you slow down?
- Don't tell me what to do.
Isn't it funny how things happen so fast?
You've had too much to drink,
so why don't you slow down?
Isn't it?
Yeah, it's funny.
All the time
that lucky and I were together...
and all the time that Hazel and I
were best friends, I never knew.
It wasn't like that. I told you,
it happened all of a sudden.
Come on. I thought you said
we were gonna be friends.
Friends are the most
important thing, right?
- Here's to good music.
- Right, Hazel?
Lots of things are important.
But friends are the most important thing.
Good friends. Friends you can trust.
You mean like husbands are supposed
to be able to trust their wives?
- Tone it, Hazel.
- Will you shut up!
The way your love life was going, I don't
blame you for taking what you could get.
Thanks, Kay.
What about you, Jack, and lucky?
That made a real pretty picture.
That was me and Jack and lucky!
This is me and you and lucky!
All right, that's it. You two don't need me.
Nope, I'm going.
You're on your own, sweetheart.
- There's a word for you.
- Stay away from me!
Only I can't say it.
Yes, I can. Whore!
- Did you call me a whore?
- See anybody else I could be speaking to?
- You're the whore, sweetheart.
- You're a bigger whore!
I've slept with someone's boyfriend,
but I didn't spend two years...
putting a knife in my husband's back.
You're the whore.
What do you know?
You never had a husband or boyfriend!
You never had anything!
There's nothing wrong with me, Kay.
I don't care what happens to you or him.
So why don't you just go away, okay?
Ride?
- Where to, sweetie?
- Wait a minute.
Get your hands off me! Get away from me!
Let's just go.
- I was in love!
- Shut up!
- Come on, Kay. I'll get you home.
- Don't touch me!
How're you gonna get home?
If I can build a goddamn airplane
I can get myself home.
How do you feel?
I feel sick.
I called Macbride's this morning and quit.
I'm leaving.
You want this back?
No. I'd really like you to keep that.
Me, too. Thanks.
Come with me, Kay.
I can't.
Bye, Kay.
Mabel Stoddard's husband is in the pacific.
She took this job for the duration.
Mrs. Stoddard, how do you like your job?
I love it.
How about after the war?
Do you plan to keep on working?
As I said, when my husband comes back,
I'm gonna be busy at home.
Good for you.
Each returning serviceman
will get his job back when the war is won.
You girls and women, you'll go home,
back to being housewives and mothers...
as you promised to do
when you came to work with us.
Your lives will return to normal.
Thank you.
Attention, please.
The ceremony commemorating
the last sbd dive bomber...
produced by Macbride's
will start in a few moments.
Associates, we share
a great moment in history.
Japan has surrendered. The war is over!
Associates...
excuse me! Can we have
some quiet, please, for Mr. Macbride?
Associates, I want to thank each
and every one of you...
for a job well done!
They dropped us, just like that. I knew it.
...knowing you have done your part
to bring peace to a strife-torn world.
Especially you girls
who've given so much...
good luck to you.
...now you can become
housewives and mothers again...
to make homes and families
for all our returning heroes.
"Last hired, first fired."
They're taking away
the best job I ever had.
A year of welding school.
Shirt?
"Dear lucky,
I was cleaning house yesterday...
"when I came across these pictures
of our going-away party at Macbride's.
"I thought you might like them.
"I haven't heard from Jack in a while,
but I've been notified...
"of his fleet's arrival next week.
I'm hoping for the best.
"I know things got muddled in the end...
"but I just want to say thanks
for so many things.
"I sure hope things are finally
going your way. Good luck, Kay."
Please forgive me.
You're forgiven.
- How did you get here?
- I borrowed spike and Ethel's car.
Come on. Let's go home.
- Can I help you with this, or anything?
- No, I got it.
Put your bag down.
I went to the store
and got something special for dinner.
Unless you'd rather go out.
Where is he?
It's over.
That's good news.
I know I hurt you, honey.
I love you.
Still working?
They let us go when it was all over.
That makes two of us.
We're both out of a job.
I just love you so goddamn much.
I love you, too.
- Jeannie, what's this?
- It's called dip.
- Yeah?
- You stick a potato chip in it.
- Hi, how are you?
- How are you?
Everybody, I'd like to introduce
to all of you...
this is my new husband,
archibald Touie.
How do you do?
A washer?
All electric.
It tore a shirt the other day.
- Hi, everybody.
- Kay!
This is Jack, my husband.
He just got back.
I'm Clarence. Welcome home, boy.
- This is Annie.
- Hi, Annie.
The government's promised us
a new ranch house in the valley.
- They're building a whole bunch of them.
- Ranch house, terrific.
They're all alike, too.
With these servicemen coming back,
there's gonna be a large need for housing.
Hi, I just wanted to say...
congratulations.
Thank you. This is my husband,
archibald Touie.
- Biscuits Touie.
- Nice to meet you.
- Excuse me.
- Okay.
- So you were in the pacific?
- You bet. Yup.
You hear about these new ranch houses?
I just want to forget about the past
and start all over again.
With another little one on the way,
I'm sure glad Deacon has a job.
Remember that first day
when we were all standing in line?
I was so scared.
- I thought they were gonna laugh at us.
- They did laugh at us.
- Well, we showed them.
- We sure did.
We showed them.
Here's to Kay and Jack,
Jeannie and Bobby...
Clarence and Annie, Violet and Deacon...
and Hazel and me.
And all of us.
And no more war. One hell of a future!
All right!
We showed them, didn't we?
Boy, did we ever.