I'm always included
in everything.
My mother says
it's not healthy
to eat so late.
So what do you do?
I eat on the card table
in my room with my sister
because that's what
children are supposed to do.
Says you.
All right, young people
I don't want to have to
call you children, ok?
So let's start finishing up.
Come on, let's go.
Let's gather up
our things, boys.
Oh, billy, what a perfectly
wonderful pig.
How did it get
into central park?
Search me.
Let's put it away,
all right?
Eli, let's go over here.
Peter,
let's put our papers away.
Juju.
What's the matter?
Aren't you doing well today?
How come?
Those are very strong colors.
I can't draw any people.
I bet you can.
I bet they're
just in their houses
till they're ready
to come out.
How about it if tomorrow
I help you bring them out?
Ok.
Let's gather up our paints.
All right,
I want everything picked up.
Let me see
what you did today.
I made a picture of the guy
on the skateboard.
And I made my skater fall down
'cause he was showing off
and it made this guy mad,
so he socked him.
And busted his head.
Oh, he did not.
I want everything picked up.
I don't want to see
a paper towel.
a gum wrapper.
There are plenty of
paper towels for everybody
if you take just one.
Jeannie Griffin,
I am talking to you.
Willful waste
makes woeful want.
Miss penny! Miss penny! Miss
penny! Quiet. Quiet everyone.
How can you hear instructions
if you're making such a hubbub?
Quiet! Silence!
Did you hear what I said?
What?
I said maybe we ought
to let 'em blow off steam
before we put 'em
back on the bus.
Maybe a game
of follow the leader?
Yes, follow the leader.
That would be fine.
Michael.
All right, everyone put their
supplies into the big box
and then line up
behind Miss Dorsett
for a game
of follow the leader.
No, no. Back this way.
Ok, everybody.
Come on. Peter.
Come on, girls.
Now, let's not shove.
Goodness sakes,
I'll get squashed.
Ok, here we go.
Is everybody ready?
Let's go.
oh, my god, Sybil.
For heaven sakes, what
are you doing in the water?
Sybil.
What?
You went exactly the opposite
way from fifth avenue.
The bus driver is very angry.
Now, come out of the water,
Sybil. We're going to be late.
All right. Now, children,
you form up in a line
right over here.
Quickly, please. Come on.
I couldn't figure
out what happened.
All of a sudden, you were
running in the opposite direction.
I yelled. I hollered.
Oh, Sybil,
look at your shoes.
I-I don't feel very well.
I think I'd like to go home.
Maybe you ought
to see the school nurse.
No, I can cope.
Because, Sybil, I don't know
if I can cover for you.
I mean, if we're late and
the homeroom teacher asks me.
I'm sorry. I- I'll
see you tomorrow, all right?
Sybil.
All right, kids.
Come on, let's go.
Hey, you're gonna turn into a
banana, you keep livin' on fruit.
Ha, Mr. Darwin says we're
just a bunch of monkeys anyway.
Yeah, but they eat
lots of protein, too, Sybil.
They eat roots, nuts, bugs.
Oh, I have lots of bugs,
thank you.
How much do I owe you?
That's, uh, one nickel,
half a dime.
I don't think so.
Oh, come on, will you?
If these had
anymore bruises on 'em,
I'd have to send 'em
to the hospital.
Go ahead.
Thank you, Mr. Rizo.
Have a good day.
hi, Miss Dorsett.
School let out early?
So it seems.
Uh, when did
the piano move in?
Today, 2nd floor, front.
It's loud, isn't it?
It don't stop
by 10:00 tonight,
they get my foot
through the door.
how could you embarrass me
in front of them all that way?
Get away.
Please, get away.
I will not get away.
I will stand here
till you explain yourself.
I don't even know
what I did. I don't-
don't you plead ignorance
aloud on me.
Out, out, out.
I had to get out.
What?
no!
That's not a chord.
This is a chord.
You can't sharp a "g".
What's the matter with you?
I've got more brains
in my little finger
than you've got
in your whole body.
You didn't cut
deep enough, did you?
Now, we gotta get you
to the hospital.
I see
one eye
and-and another one
and some glasses
and
some red kind of hair.
Mmm-hmm. Now, tell me when
you see my fingers wiggle.
I see- I see a picture frame
and a...
there's a doctor,
a lady, is in it.
Oh, yeah.
You see a circle, right?
There's a circle, and it's
dark on the sides of it.
I see a white coat.
It's a white coat.
What's the matter? Does
my white coat bother you?
I see some fingers wiggling.
You have a ring.
A married wedding ring.
Mmm-hmm.
You have a little girl
all your own?
No.
You have a little boy?
Mmm-mmm.
Is it fun talking like a
little girl, Miss Dorsett?
What?
What just happened? Jetlag?
I cut my wrist.
That's right.
Why, don't you remember?
Yes, of course.
I'm in New York.
I'm in a hospital.
Mmm-hmm.
I've cut my wrist.
Am I through? May I go?
Well, I'd like to finish
the neurological exam.
Why is there a neurological
exam? I've cut my wrist.
I think you have the
charts mixed up. It's, uh...
no, it just seems
that when the surgical
resident was patching you up
he thought you seemed kind of
confused, so he called me in.
Don't you remember?
And I asked you how I could
help you, and you took my hand.
You came right on in here.
Don't you want to stay?
Come on.
Let's finish it up, ok?
Here.
Tell me what you smell
in these little bottles.
Cloves.
Mmm-hmm.
I...
I know I should
smell something-
no, you shouldn't.
It's water.
Oh! Disinfectant.
It's all right.
What's the matter? You smell
something like that before?
Yes.
I'm sorry.
You asked me something?
No, you were just telling me
about your symptoms.
Your, uh, tunnel vision and
your bumping into walls and...
yes. Yes, I know.
Sometimes, when I'm heading
for the door, by mistake, uh...
what is it?
This is your office?
Yes.
No!
Without looking at your watch,
tell me what you just said.
Is it so important?
Yes.
I said,
"is this your office?"
That was a half an hour ago.
It's nighttime now.
I didn't...
I didn't want you to know.
Yes, you did.
Nobody knows.
Somebody knows now.
All right?
Do you remember anything?
Do you remember
the vocabulary test
or saying the numbers
backwards or any of that?
No, I don't. I don't.
None of it?
No.
You don't know whether
you've been here for an hour
or a day or a week, do you?
I don't think
it's been a week.
Has it been a day?
No.
I cut my wrist.
Mmm-hmm.
And I don't know how.
And then I was here,
talking to you.
Mmm-hmm.
Have I hurt somebody?
Have I done something bad?
No.
No, of course not.
Have you always
lost time like that?
I'm so awfully
ashamed, doctor.
It's all right.
I've always been like this.
Always.
And I used to think
that everybody was like this.
That they would just naturally
wake up and be someplace else
or a whole lot older
or wearing another dress.
Once, I woke up,
and I was 2 years older.
And...
it was very hard for me
to get through college.
I want very much
to be a teacher.
I wanna give
something to somebody.
You understand that?
Sure.
I substitute teach
because I'm gonna get
my m.a. In art.
It's in art.
It never happened before
in front of the children
but things have been getting
a lot worse lately.
I can't do anything.
I can't study.
And then,
I woke up,
and I was in the water.
And the children saw me.
Sybil.
Please don't touch me.
It hurts me.
It hurts to be touched?
Here, have a crying towel.
No, thank you.
I don't cry tears like people.
You must have cried like
people once upon a time.
Here. Sybil, come on,
sit down.
You know,
I think the fear
that you're suffering from
is very, very deep.
And I think
your-your symptoms,
your-your tunnel vision
and your blackouts
are a result of that fear.
It's a kind of hysteria.
You see?
Yes.
You understand,
if you are-are
too scared to face something,
then it just makes perfectly
good sense to blackout
and then you never have to
know what you're scared of.
Nothing scares me.
Listen, would you like to
come back and see me again
on, um, thursday?
Uh, my name is Dr. Wilbur
by the way.
Is it expensive?
No, not in the clinic.
I think you can afford it.
I have to ask my father.
He's here on his honeymoon.
My mother died a while back.
He remarried.
Have to show him
the sights tomorrow.
If you can call
lunching at the museum
cafeteria the sights.
Well, I must say this is
sure a delightful notion.
Eating by a real roman pool
in the middle of New York city.
I better not say
"roman" out loud.
The pope might
jump out and eat dad.
Now, you quit that.
Well,
what's the native custom?
Do we stack our trays
or eat right off 'em?
Well, I'm setting
my place proper.
Wait, willard,
till I slide a napkin
under your plate.
There, now,
isn't that more homey?
Here, you see
how she babies me?
Well, he is a baby.
Just a big, strong,
sweet old baby.
But he's just what
the doctor ordered.
Aren't you, lovey?
How do you
like Chicago, dad?
Oh, fine.
Um, plenty to do.
Oh, my spaghetti
looks yummy.
Nice and crusty
and tomatoey.
What did you take, Sybil?
Just chicken salad?
No, it's tuna.
Oh.
That's a puny kind of lunch
for a growing girl.
I don't want you
to skimp on your food.
Well, I stopped growing
a long time ago, dad.
It's fine,
a gracious sufficiency.
Thank you.
We, uh, thank thee lord
for all thy bountiful
blessings. Amen.
Amen.
But, oh, the prices
of everything here.
I nearly die every time
a waiter brings the check.
That's what you get
for looking, huh?
Of course, things
are dear in Chicago, too.
It's hard to make ends meet.
Hmm.
When we lived
in Willow Corners,
you could eat
a meal like this.
Oh, I used to get
your mother to...
God rest her soul.
To go down to
the green-green comet cafe
and ordered a whole
covered dinner on a sabbath
so she wouldn't have to cook.
Yes.
And why,
what with the roasted chicken
and yellow gravy and the
fixings it didn't come to $1.50.
Dad,
l- I have an illness.
It's what you and mother
called my moodiness.
And it's getting
worse and worse.
It will be
the end of everything
unless I can do
something about it.
I'm sorry to bring you
in on this, frieda,
but you're not blood family
and I don't seem
to be able to get dad alone.
Well, uh, I feel like family.
Goodness.
Dad, there's a lady,
a doctor,
and l- I've talked to her.
She can help me
in the pursuit of me
and she thinks that
that's a useful pursuit.
Willard, you said yourself
we have a perfectly
good spare room
and all her things would fit
in there just perfect.
Nothing will fit perfect
anywhere until I fit perfect.
I'm sorry.
I'm going to the restroom.
I don't want it said
that I influenced anything.
Between a rock
and a hard place, Sybil.
I mean, you know
how the church views
the practitioners
of the mind.
I'm very frugal.
If I give up
my luxuries, television,
and I don't read after sunset
and i
- and I use the stove only occasionally to cook 3 days at a time,
I could- I could get by
on what you send me.
The devil hath power
to assume a pleasing shape.
She's not the devil, dad.
Now, l-I know that.
I don't know that about anyone
except the people
in our own congregation.
She's a reputable doctor.
First thing
you know it's drugs,
then a hospital
full of lost souls.
That's the way they
begin it, Sybil. Oh, lord,
I think I'm trapped.
The final preparation
for the holocaust.
It's armageddon, Sybil.
"And it shall rise up
in the east
and the rivers
shall flow as blood."
Sybil!
I'm sorry. Oh, dad,
I'm-I'm sorry.
I can pay for it. It-it-it
surely is-is about $2.
What is the matter with you?
Sybil. Sybil.
Sybil! Sybil!
Sybil!
Now, tell me when you see
my fingers wiggle.
The devil hath power
to assume a pleasing shape.
I've cut my wrist.
You know how our church feels
about the practitioners
of the mind.
What's the matter?
My white coat bother you?
Always. Always.
I was always like this.
First thing
you know it's drugs,
then a hospital
full of lost souls.
It's all right.
It's just disinfectant.
The final preparation
for the holocaust,
the armageddon, Sybil.
I always thought
that people would just
naturally be someplace else
or wearing another dress
or be a whole lot older,
like when I was in the 3rd
grade and my grandmother died
and-and I wasn't anyplace
for 2 years.
I just wasn't anyplace,
not anyplace at all.
Would you like to come back
and see me on thursday?
What is the matter with-
it's all right. I've got it.
Yeah.
Who?
Vicky who?
It better be an emergency for
"just Vicky" at 3:00 in the morning.
Ok, put her on.
Dr. Wilbur?
Yeah.
That window is beginning
to look awfully good to Sybil.
What window? Who are you?
I'm Sybil's friend.
It's very high, Dr. Wilbur.
It's up 4 floors.
You'd better come quick
to the staton hotel-
hold on a second.
Hold on, ok?
Staton hotel-
hold on. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute. Hold on. Yeah.
All right,
it's the staton hotel,
136 west 125th street.
Opposite the roslyn.
Ok.
What is she doing in harlem?
Vicky?
Leave me alone.
Vicky, let me in.
It's Dr. Wilbur.
Thank you.
Sybil?
Oh, no.
I didn't want to do this
in front of you again.
It's all right.
Listen, would you
just wait downstairs, ok?
Where is this?
Have I missed thursday?
Did I miss thursday?
That's all right.
Where's your friend Vicky?
I don't have a friend Vicky.
She has a friend Sybil.
What kicked it off this time?
I lost my job.
And l-I tried to ask...
my... my...
yeah? You asked your father
about seeing me.
What happened?
What did he say?
Sybil?
The people. The people.
The people.
The people,
they're everywhere.
There, there, there.
They're everywhere.
No, you keep them
away from me.
I will, I will,
I will do it. I will do it.
He doesn't care.
Sybil.
I hate Sybil. I hate her.
Who are you?
I can do anything.
I can do anything I want to.
I can walk on the furniture
if I take my shoes off
like that and like that
and like that.
And I can walk on the chair like
that and like that and like that.
And you can't stop me. I promise
you, Sybil, I wouldn't stop you.
You can't stop me. I won't
stop you. It's all right.
It's all right.
It hurts me!
What hurts? What hurts you?
Where does it hurt?
I have to get out.
No, wait!
I have to break the glass.
No, no, no, no.
No, we don't-don't
break glass.
You won't let me out, and you
won't let me have any peace
and you leave me alone
and it hurts,
and you don't
leave me alone, it hurts.
Who are you talking to?
Who am i?
Who hurt you? Oh, please,
I have to get out. Get out.
I have to get out. We'll just go
downstairs, we'll get in the taxi
and then you'll be out, all
right? No, no, no, she's there.
When she's there,
the people are there.
Who's there? Who is there? The
people. I don't wanna see them.
I don't wanna feel them.
Where is Sybil?
I don't wanna know.
Where is Sybil? Tell me.
I have to get out.
I have to feel the glass.
No, no. No,
no. No, no.
I have to feel the-
don't break it.
I see the knob.
I see the knob
on the white house.
On the white house,
I see the knob.
And the shades
are pulled down.
I live right there.
Right there.
201 west 4th street.
Willow Corners, Wisconsin.
I live right there.
Right there. Right there.
That's harlem.
I don't know
where the other glass is.
It's in Dr. Quinoness'
instrument case,
and it's all white
and shiny knives.
And my momma says,
"I will take you
"to play with monica
and cheryl
"because you like monica
and cheryl."
And my grandma says...
my grandma says...
my grandma says, "you-you
go like momma says."
My grandma's good.
She's good.
She loves me.
I'm afraid! I'm afraid!
There's nothing
to be afraid of here.
They never forget anything,
and they listen
to every sound.
And they're everywhere,
and they're everywhere.
They're in this room
and that room
and everywhere you look,
who?
And everywhere-
the people.
The people. No! No!
No, don't make me go there.
I don't wanna go
up there, please.
Please don't make me
go up there.
I won't go up there. Please.
Please don't make me
go up there.
Go where? Go where?
Please.
It's not happening now.
Please don't do this.
Well, here we are.
Oh, look, who else got here.
Daddy'll take you upstairs,
won't you, daddy?
Where's cheryl and monica?
They'll be here later, Sybil.
Your mommy'll bring you some
ice cream, won't you, mommy?
You're just going upstairs
for a little nap.
What kind do you like? You
can have any kind you like.
Now, hush now.
Double, double.
Easy does it. Double dip.
That's it. That's it.
Come along.
No!
No! No!
Now, now, big breath,
big deep breath.
No!
Now, I can't do anything
if you're gonna to fight me.
No!
All right,
there's plenty of air.
Now, there just seemed
to be no air
because you were breathing
air mixed with ether.
They have to use 2 cans of
ether to take her tonsils out
because she's a real
strong little girl.
Right, right,
and a mad little girl, too.
They lied to you,
didn't they?
Yeah, they got you there
under false pretenses.
They're gonna kill her.
That's what they're gonna do.
No, they're not
going to kill you.
And why do you keep referring to
yourself in the third person, hmm?
Because she's Sybil.
But my throat hurts, too.
And who are you, sweetie?
Will you tell
Dr. Wilbur now?
Dr. Wilbur's too far away.
No, no.
Dr. Wilbur's right here.
Dr. Wilbur just seemed
very far away
because all good
and safe things
must have seemed
very, very far away.
Dr. Wilbur, a white coat?
That's right,
but I'm not wearing it now.
Hi. Everything's ok now.
You just try
and get some sleep, ok?
I wanna be your little girl.
Please, take me to your house.
Oh, honey, your mommy and
daddy love you very much.
They'd miss you.
Just try
and get some sleep, ok?
You take me, please.
Honey. Honey, please,
just-just try to sleep, ok?
Hello.
Here's your mommy, Sybil.
Everything's all right now.
Hello.
How's my little girl?
Look what I brought you,
Sybil.
Sybil?
Don't you turn
your back on me.
I'm talking to you.
Sybil. Sybil.
You're...
no cuts. No bruises.
I busted it all to pieces.
You're all in one piece.
It's all right. It's all right.
It's easier to fix windows
than little girls.
Little girls are more
important than windows?
This little girl
certainly is. Sure.
I got something to tell you.
It's about Sybil.
She puts guck
all over her hair
'cause she has gray hair.
I don't. I'm natural.
You like the way I look?
I have a real pretty face.
See me in the mirror?
And a little nose
and all my freckles
and my bangs.
I'm only 9.
Do you believe me?
Yes, I believe you.
My name's Peggy,
and you're my Dr. Wilbur.
Tell me about your patient.
You think she's really
a multiple personality?
Erna, I know she is.
I've-I've met
one alternate, I know.
And I've talked to
another one on the telephone.
Such a compliment that they should
reveal themselves so quickly.
Erna, the-the waking self,
the Sybil part,
is very repressed
and-and-and very troubled.
A grim-grim person,
but the-the other one,
the-the little Peggy,
is just enchanting.
She's-she's, uh,
she's just adrift in time.
She doesn't know
that she's in New York
and she's-she's absolutely full
of misconceptions about everything.
How are you
going to treat her?
Psychoanalysis.
Which one?
All 3.
That's unprecedented.
Why are you
the big pioneer?
Well, why did you
teach me to be?
Be careful.
Connie, be careful.
Don't fall in love
with her illness.
Or she could be obligated
to seem just more complex
than she is
just to keep your approval.
You know,
they are not little girls.
They're defenses
that belong to somebody else,
pieces, fragments,
only illusions.
And they are acting out
a drama
that has nothing
to do with you.
Well, I know that.
So you mustn't act out one that
has nothing to do with them.
Oh, for instance?
For instance,
you are not their mother.
It wasn't easy to heed
my friend's warning.
Every time Peggy leaves my
office to disappear into the city,
I have the most awful urge
to call her back
because I know that New York
doesn't exist for her.
She lives in the small midwestern
town of her memory 20 years ago
where there weren't any taxis or
buses or strangers to harm her.
And whenever
the city swallows her up,
I wonder if I'll ever
see her again
until, by some miracle, she
or Sybil appear on my doorstep.
I wonder what she does
and how she lives
or who she sees.
hush-a-bye
don't you cry
go to sleep-y
little baby
when you wake
you will have
all the pretty
little ponies
blacks and bays
dapples and grays
coach
and 6 a-little horses
hush-a-bye
don't you cry
go to sleep-y
little baby
hey, Sybil Dorsett!
Wanna pet my horse?
Come on, ma'am. Now, have
no fear or trepidation.
We've fallen on hard times,
him and me,
since we were the finest
roping team in all the west
and it kind of looks like it's
gonna be the dog-food factory
unless some kind soul believes
in us enough to take a ride.
How about you?
Would you take
your hat off for a second?
Think you've seen me
in the pictures?
Oh.
I didn't know you did this.
I knew you did that.
What?
Paint. That's an art book,
isn't it?
"Turner." yeah, I knew
you were an artist.
I've seen you painting
in the middle of the night.
I don't do that. I haven't
painted in a long time.
Yeah, you do. I watch you.
From window to window,
right across our backyards.
Each window a stage
in this theater of the absurd
which we call life.
You never have company.
You eat by yourself.
You still play with dolls.
And you watch me, too.
I've seen you over there
with the lights out
seething with passion
on those hot summer nights.
I don't happen
to be seething with anything.
I'm just trying to keep
my electrical bill down.
I have to go.
Well, wait.
Why?
Say, "w-a-t-e-r," and I'll
tell you where you come from.
Do I have to?
You want your book back?
Water.
Illinois. Iowa.
It's Wisconsin.
I really have to go.
Oh, come on, Sybil. Get in,
I'll give you a free ride.
Oh, excuse me. I'm sorry.
Well.
Well, that's the 2nd time
you've said it,
so I guess
you want me to ask.
How do you know my name?
My little boy Matthew
is in love with you,
and he wanted
to write you a letter.
So I walked around the corner,
looked at all the names
on the bells
and you're
the only single on 5.
I never got a letter.
No, we never sent it.
We both forgot
he hasn't learned to write.
Look, I got
an italian sausage sandwich.
It's really too big for me,
and he won't even touch it.
Who are you?
I haven't got a clue
but it's called
Richard J. Loomis.
And just like my horse here,
I cannot inflict harm.
Oh.
Hey, you're a linguist.
I only know pig latin.
Yes, I was bilingual
as a child. French.
That's all I remember, and I'm
sorry to say it's all wrong.
Raised in paris.
Come on, pony.
Paris? Ooh-la-la!
Yes.
C'est bien.
We played hopscotch
in the bois.
We had cafe au lait
for breakfast
and porridge,
if you can believe it.
Of course, we had
an english nanny.
Yeah?
Yes.
Did she say, "bois," too?
You got me there.
Hello...
oh, oh, what's your name?
Oh, I'm sorry.
You don't recognize my voice.
I'm Vicky.
Victoria, Sybil's friend.
Victoria antoinette scharleau.
Allo. Allo.
Hello.
Good to see you.
Allo a vous, too.
Well.
Well, come.
Come, right in.
Merci. Merci.
Oh!
Quel jolI bureau!
Oh, thank you.
Um...
asseyez-vous.
Ou? Sur this couch
ou sur that couch?
Comme vous voulez.
Je choose this couch.
I don't blame you
for not remembering.
It was months and months ago
since I called you
from that dreary
little harlem hotel.
Mmm-hmm.
Well, tell me, um,
where's Sybil?
Sybil is a bit embarrassed
about the financial
arrangements.
Since you've been seeing her
in your practice privee,
she doesn't know
how she will ever repay you.
She'll repay me when
she gets herself together
if you'll excuse the pun.
Yes?
Dr. Wilbur,
mmm-hmm.
Peggy is very worried.
She thinks that perhaps you
think she wants to hurt you
because she breaks
the windows.
Well, I don't.
No, she wouldn't hurt anyone.
She'd been so hurt herself.
I wouldn't hurt anyone either,
not by word nor deed.
I don't even like to hurt
someone's feelings.
Do you know?
If someone calls me Sybil by
mistake, do you know what I do?
I look in their face
and I say, "yes. Yes."
Or, "oui. Oui.
You're speaking to me?"
Because it hurts to be
embarrassed, do you know?
Mmm-hmm.
Sybil is such
a lamentable creature.
Why do you say that?
She can't do anything.
She starts to paint,
she can't paint.
She wants to play the piano,
she can't play the piano.
She won't have fun.
The woman refuses to have fun.
She's afraid of people,
you know.
I'm not. No.
I simply adore people.
Do you know,
the other day, she wanted
to take a ride in the park
with that attractive
young man, uh, Richard Loomis
who lives across the yard?
She was afraid
to take his hand.
She's afraid of hands.
So is Peggy.
I had to go.
I'm not afraid of hands.
I'm not afraid of anything.
No, sir.
Whose hands are Sybil
and Peggy afraid of?
Don't you dare tell.
Next worse thing to being a
fibber is being a talebearer.
You tell, and I'll fix it so you
ain't got nothing to tell with.
Vicky,
did your mother ever hit you?
Oh.
Mine? No.
My mother
is an absolute angel.
She lives in paris,
you know.
She'll be coming for me soon.
We'll be together,
all my brothers and-
is Sybil's mother
not an angel?
Do you like my hair?
It's called a french twist.
I do it myself.
I look a great deal
older than 13, don't i?
That's because european
children mature so much sooner.
But I'm so thin.
This suit just hangs on me.
Maybe Sybil
isn't feeding you enough.
I never complain exactly.
But all she eats
is rotten fruit.
That's all she's eaten
all month long.
Her daddy forgets
to send her the check.
Lots of times, her daddy
forgets to send a check
and that makes Peggy
very, very mad,
and she barges into the stores
and smashes all the crystal,
and Sybil has to pay for it.
But I don't care.
Did you have breakfast
this morning, hmm?
Sweetie, are you hungry?
If I stand very, very erect
with a certain air of dignity
you can't tell
how thin I am, can you?
Come on. I'm gonna
make you a sandwich.
I see the wheels
going round and round.
Why do they do that?
Why do they go round and round against me?
They're not going around
against you.
They're just
making a recording.
Remember Peggy said
I could when she was here?
Yes, I know,
to help Sybil.
Mmm-hmm.
Because she seems to have so much
more information than Sybil does.
Oh, I have more.
I have more than Peggy.
I have more than anybody.
I know everything.
Every thought she thinks,
everything she does, I remember.
She can't remember.
She mustn't remember.
That's why it's very,
very important
that you don't tell her
about us.
It would be too big
a shock for her.
She's not ready to take it.
Here.
I have a peanut butter and jelly
sandwich for you and some banana bread
and a big glass of milk.
Now, I want to see you just
eat and eat and eat, all right?
Thank you.
Mmm-hmm.
Milk is good
for growing girls.
That's right.
Lots of mummies
aren't like you.
are real tricky.
Vicky,
do you remember
Sybil's tonsillectomy, hmm?
I saw. I was there.
It made, uh, Sybil's
throat hurt, didn't it?
Yes, very much.
Mmm, hurt so bad she had to
whisper and she couldn't talk.
Talked like this
all the time.
Funny thing is, it made
Peggy's throat hurt, too.
Now how come
both their throats hurt
if, if all of you are
different people?
Vicky?
I know. I'm thinking.
Don't I have
lovely table manners?
Notice how delicate
my hands are.
The pinkies,
it's called continental.
Hmm, yes, it's lovely.
Tell me, are you related
in some way, all of you?
I know where I am. I'm in new
york. Lots to do in New York.
Museums to go to,
concerts-
do you think that
Sybil and Peggy
share the same mother
and father?
Now how are they related?
Hmm?
Are they sisters?
Or are you all parts
of the same person?
Don't be silly.
It can't be that.
No, it can be that.
You can all be aspects
of the same person.
All pieces of Sybil.
No, no.
We're all people.
You can see us.
Look around.
There's nobody else here,
just you and me
and the sink
and the dishes and the door.
Nobody else here.
Do you believe me?
Sweetie,
I believe that you believe.
Come on,
you have your sandwich.
Questions, questions,
questions. My goodness, so many.
Look, you even have questions
in your eyes right this minute.
I'd like to ask you
a question.
Ask me.
What's love?
Sweetie, don't you know?
No, I don't.
Please tell. We all
want to know, all of us.
Who's all of us?
Everybody
that lives with Sybil.
Who are the others, Vicky?
Are there more besides you
and-and-and Sybil and Peggy?
Vicky?
I hear you.
Are you seeing them now?
Yes.
I don't want to,
but I can.
It was so nice a moment ago
when they weren't here.
I need to know what you're seeing, sweetie.
If I don't know who you
all are and what you want,
I can't help you
as easily as I'd like.
Vicky?
Help, help, help, help.
We all keep hoping
things will get better
but i, I don't think Sybil's
going to live that long.
Why, sweetie?
Why do you have
this awful feeling of doom?
Because of Marcia.
Marcia's going to
kill Sybil someday.
Let it come. Let it come.
We're walking corpses.
We start dying
the moment we're born.
Who's Marcia?
Why does Sybil need Marcia?
Vicky?
One of them
plays the piano.
She's the prettiest.
She's the only one
with any joie de vivre.
What's her name?
No.
Mustn't tell you.
Mustn't tell any more.
I shouldn't have even
told you about Marcia.
Why not?
Why are you so afraid to
tell about the others, Vicky?
Who told you it was wrong
to tell people things?
Who said it was dangerous
to tell?
Vicky?
Mustn't tell.
Can't tell.
There are guards
around the palace.
Sweetie, even the guards
around the palace
will tell
if the queen's in danger.
Marcia appeared
for the first time
at the session
the following thursday.
She admitted trying to kill
Sybil in the harlem hotel
and was sorry
that Vicky stopped her.
She allowed me to photograph
her, as the other's have
saying that she wanted this
picture published with her obituary.
When I asked her why she thought
about suicide so obsessively
she pretended to lock her
lips and throw the key away,
then proceeded to draw scenes
from a recurrent nightmare,
as though this were a secret
way of revealing information
she couldn't give me openly.
By drawing
her dreams in silence,
nobody could eavesdrops
on her,
and that seemed to be
a constant dread
that someone would find out
that she'd confided in me.
In the dream,
a child comes upon,
uh, a lost kitten
in the tunnel of a great park
and then she discovers, uh,
a box where other kittens
have been abandoned.
The child is-is overwhelmed
with-with love and pity
and-and runs off with the box
in order to save the kittens.
Suddenly,
she sees a dead cat,
which horrifies her
because it's been beheaded.
Both the head and body
come to life and pursue her.
Marcia said they all shared
the same nightmares
but that Sybil
doesn't remember any of them.
The dreams
are all of entrapment
and relentless pursuit.
Large families of children
awaiting some
terrible retaliation.
Loneliness,
the hopelessness of rescue.
Paralyzing fear
pervade everything.
When I suggested
that the kittens
might be
the various aspects of Sybil,
that she's trying to
bring me for protection
and that the cat might be her
desire to destroy again and again
some unspeakable tormentor
who won't stay dead,
Marcia became so fearful,
she dissociated into Peggy,
who wanted to escape with me
to Amsterdam to get away
from what she calls
"the people."
I look at all the faces,
furious, terrified Peggy,
sepulchral little Marcia,
Vicky with her social ease
and uninterrupted memory,
and Sybil,
and I wonder,
what there was back there
that could've caused
such a shattering.
What could've forced her
to thrust onto creatures
she doesn't even know exist
all those capacities
in herself she must deny?
And why is it so vital
that she deny them?
What was the torment?
Who was the tormentor?
Hey, Sybil.
I know you're there.
Why don't you come over?
We can go downtown.
You can, uh,
see me in action, ok?
I'll buy you a hotdog,
sauerkraut, pickles.
You like pickles?
I don't go out at night,
but thank you anyway.
Oh, come on. Look, uh,
it's just for a little while.
I only gotta go down
and play the intermission
and if it doesn't rain, uh, you
know, I'll catch them going out.
Catch them for what?
By day,
I'm a central park cowboy
but by night, a tone-deaf
wandering minstrel.
Street musician.
Say yes.
Sybil can't say yes.
Vanessa, you go.
You like music.
You may go, Vanessa.
Richard?
Richard.
Richard!
Hey.
Ok, but look, I'm not any
good at jumping over fences,
so where do you live?
Uh, the gray house,
apartment 5c.
Ok.
Hi.
Guess what I am.
Uh, a kumquat.
No.
A donut with ears.
Um...
a smile that went looking
for a boy, and found one.
No.
I'm a clown.
A clown.
Sybil, this is Matthew.
Matthew, say hello to Sybil.
I know Sybil.
I watch her
through the window.
He's a little wound up
at the idea of company.
I really love your apartment.
It's, it's all lit up.
Sybil bibble dribble.
Matthew, simmer down.
Sit!
Matthew.
Now, don't let appearances
deceive you.
I am really not company.
You know what I am?
I'm a princess who's been
asleep for 1,000 years
in a forest
called simmer down.
And you know why?
That's because a wicked witch put
an evil spell on my ice-cream cone
the very day I was born, and if
a prince doesn't come along soon
and break
the spell with a kiss,
I guess I have to go on forever
looking like Sybil bibble,
and I wouldn't wish that
on a dragon, would you?
Oh, I'm getting so sleepy.
See you blinking.
That's because princesses
always blink in their sleep.
They have to stay alert
for the palace revolution
which is liable
to take place any moment.
If you wake up,
I'll show you my toys.
There's only one way.
Ok. Enchantment's broken.
Say goodnight to Sybil.
That's not Sybil.
Sybil stayed home.
Ok, but we still
gotta get you next door.
So here's bear-bear.
And how about night-night.
And doody.
Can't forget doody, ok?
And wash you face,
or there'll be smiles
all over your pillow.
That wouldn't be
such a bad thing
to wake up to sometimes,
would it?
What?
Smiles.
All over your pillow.
I've been wondering
why you wear
that outrageous smile
all the time.
People think you're smiling,
they smile back
and that makes them
feel good.
So they put
more money in the kitty.
See how crass.
Clever, clever man.
Of course,
my face doesn't get tired
so I can keep
grinning away all night
and never have to smile
at all.
Do you make
fabulous amounts of money?
I mean,
just tons and tons of money?
Well, over $5,000
last year, tax free.
And that was just on the sidewalk
in front of carnegie hall.
That's fabulous.
Plus I get compliments,
you know,
from the great
and near great.
I have an autographed picture
from Lawrence Welk that says
"good luck and success,
always."
Now, that really makes
me feel neat, you know?
Like all my years at julliard
were really worthwhile.
Once, I yearned to be
a concert pianist.
What stopped you?
I couldn't find
the right piano.
I mean,
should it be a steinway
or a bechstein grand?
I didn't know.
You are 12 years old at the
most, and I gotta kiss you.
2 gentlemen in one night.
Fancy that.
I got blue paint
all over your lip.
Oh.
Got it. Got it.
Ok.
My mother wanted to be
a concert pianist, too.
Yeah?
Yeah.
The biggest
disappointment in her life
was when her sister faye
got married first
and left her behind to demonstrate
pianos in the family music store
instead of being
allowed to pursue
her dreams
like she'd been promised.
That was in Willow Corners,
Wisconsin.
That's my natural habitat,
believe it or not.
Willow Corners, Wisconsin.
Yeah.
My goodness.
After that, mother would just
punish the music, you know.
She'd just sit there
and bang on that piano
and call out
the time out loud
and call out those notes
like she hated them.
You know,
just bang on the piano.
Yeah, love and hate.
Peanut butter and jelly.
I used to hate
my late wife
who I speak of
with a certain irony
so as to keep a total
collapse at a distance.
I wish
you wouldn't mock yourself.
You wanna hear about it?
'Cause I'd like to tell you.
You would?
I'd like to hear.
I just didn't think
I should ask.
Beep-beep with the horn.
Choo-choo with the train.
Crash-crash with the car.
All broken.
As Matthew says
when I drop a dish.
Anyway, uh,
her name
was Janie.
And she was 19.
And, uh, I never thought
I was gonna be able
to cope with anything
after she got killed.
And I hated her
for finking out.
But one thing it taught me.
You're never ready
for what you have to do.
You just do it.
That makes you ready.
It's New York. Nobody cares.
This is us.
It is?
Yeah.
Oh.
hey rig-a-jig
kiss a little pig
follow the band
hey rig-a-jig
kiss a little pig
follow the band
join in
and follow the band
my husband is a cabbie
is a cabbie, is a cabbie
my husband is a cabbie,
is he
all day he strips gears
strips gears, strips gears
and at night he comes home
and drinks tea
hey rig-a-jig
kiss a little pig
follow the band
hey rig-a-jig
kiss a little pig
follow the band
join in
and follow the band
give me a bite.
hey rig-a-jig
kiss a little pig
follow the band
hey rig-a-jig
kiss a little pig
follow the band
join in
and follow the band
you stop that now.
There's not a thing in the world
the matter with those shoes.
What- are they so small,
daughter?
Maybe they pinch.
No, I greased them myself.
There's plenty of room
to grow in.
Feel the toe.
Then why is she screaming so,
I want to know.
I can't tell you.
I'm not supposed to tell you.
Now you just collect yourself,
young lady,
or we'll be late for church.
We'll be late for church.
Beg your pardon?
You just collect yourself,
young lady.
I won't go!
I can't tell you! I won't go!
Hey, man, hold my guitar.
Take care of it.
People, why do they do it?
Why do they do it? Why do
they do it? Why do they do it?
No moss growing on that girl.
There's no moss
growing on that girl.
I don't wanna go.
I wanna get out.
Don't touch me.
I'm going to go
run away down.
Don't touch me.
Sybil!
Get out.
Gotta break the glass.
I must break the glass.
The people just gotta get out.
Get out!
No, no, don't touch me.
I know. I know. I know.
Write, then you can see.
I know. I know. Hold on.
I have to do it.
I have to do it, young lady.
You just lay still.
Just lay still.
If I lay still, it hurts me.
Oh, it hurts me.
I did it. I did it.
Sybil.
What?
You ok in there?
Sybil.
Who's that?
Who that who say, "who that"?
Who that who say,
"who that who say,
who that'?"
Richard Loomis, hello.
Hello.
I don't understand.
Do you need to?
Well, I'd like to
but I don't have to.
Have I mentioned Danny?
No.
Who's he?
We were children together.
He was
an outcast like me, only,
in his case,
it was because he danced.
I used to be sort
of an outcast, too,
because I couldn't
pronounce my s's.
Whenever I feel especially
warm toward somebody,
especially grateful,
I think of Danny.
He had kind of
a holy forbearance.
Even at the age of 9 or 10,
how he got it in that
benighted town, I'll never know.
He never asked
for explanations.
Never. He just accepted.
Dance with me.
I'd get in awful trouble.
I have to stand up in church and tell
it out loud in front of everybody.
I want my arms about you
the charms about you
will carry me through
to heaven
I'm in heaven
and the tears
that crowd around me
through the week
seems to vanish
like a gambler's
lucky streak
when we're out together
out together
dancing to the beat
thank you.
Am I gonna see you again?
You don't have to be polite.
I never am.
Hey.
Um, kiss a clown,
get a smile on your pillow.
I don't sleep with a pillow.
It's bad for your spine.
Your hand at least?
Burning kisses. Burning.
What did I do?
Isn't that nice?
Mmm-hmm.
Sometimes, he, he plays songs
that are like happy and gay.
One time he played, um,
with a song in my heart.
You know that one?
Uh, it goes...
you know. Yeah, right.
I always knew
I'd live life through
with a song in my heart
I can see you have
a lovely voice.
One time, we went to the park,
you know,
'cause we were
gonna play catch
and then one of the boys
came out
because he wanted
to play catch.
And Richard thought it was
me, so he went over to Mike
and he kissed him right
smack dab on the lips.
He went... and Mike went...
what is a boy-
wait a minute.
Do you mean
some of the others are boys?
I wasn't supposed
to tell you that.
Now Vicky's
gonna be mad at me.
Vanessa, I don't understand.
It hurts.
When Richard
kisses Sybil, it hurts.
Why is that?
Why does love hurt?
Love doesn't hurt, sweetie.
Love heals.
It smelled
like disinfectant.
What smells
like disinfectant?
The hands
in the green kitchen.
Like that stuff you made Sybil
smell that time, remember?
Mmm-hmm.
I just love you to death.
Bushel and a peck,
a hug around the neck.
Now, you just
come on over here.
Let me give you a hug,
honey.
That's a girl.
Don't hang back like that.
No. Isn't that fun?
Just tickle, tickle,
tickle, tickle, tickle.
And tickle, tickle,
Then there'd be a big pinch.
But I wasn't hurt by love
because I came later.
Besides that, I was quick
as grease lightening
and I could always get away.
Sybil had a dream
she could play,
but I can really play.
dreamer
you have easter...
you have easter bonnet.
I love easter bonnet.
Play it for me, will you?
Oh.
You could do it.
ok.
I'm ready.
Ok. Ok, wait, wait.
Ok. Start again.
in your easter bonnet
with all the frills
upon it
I'll be
the grandest fellow
in the easter parade
I'll be all in clover
and when they look me over
I'll be
the proudest fellow
in the easter parade
on the avenue
fifth avenue
Vanessa,
what's the matter, sweetie?
I'm not Vanessa.
I'm sorry, Peggy,
but you popped out so fast.
What's the matter, sweetie?
It was my idea
and she stole it.
I wanted to sing easter
bonnet really, really bad.
Well,
you can sing easter bonnet.
I don't want to.
I wanna dance.
Well, fine.
And I want you to watch me.
All right. All right.
I'm all eyes, all right?
Ok.
All right.
Vanessa will be my stage man,
and you're gonna watch me.
Ok. Ok.
heaven, I'm in heaven
and my heart beats
so that I can hardly speak
and I seem to find
the happiness
I don't, I don't find
happiness anywhere.
We'll find it, Peggy.
It just got lost someplace.
I want to sit
in the big chair with you.
Well, you can come sit
in the big chair with me.
Ok.
Dr. Wilbur, would you help me?
I can't see anything.
What's the matter?
Why can't you see anything,
honey?
There's dish towels
around my eyes,
and they're around
my wrists, too.
Dish towels?
Yes.
Here, come on.
Here. There you go.
All righty?
Yeah.
Here. Is that better?
There. Ok.
Well, now, how did
the dish towels get there?
I don't know.
I'm scared of dish towels.
Well, dish towels are just
inanimate objects, Peggy.
Will you call me "sweetie"?
I'm sorry, sweetie, but, now,
dish towels don't just
jump up and
tie themselves around
little girls' faces
and around their wrists.
They have to be put there
by somebody.
Just hands, not somebody.
Well, honey, the hands
have to belong to someone.
Now who-who did
the hands belong to?
Just hands.
Well, you want to take off the
dish towels and look at the hands?
Why don't we do that?
Will you do that?
Will you help me?
Sure.
Ok. Now zip and zip.
Now,
the dish towels are off.
Now, will you look at
the hands?
No. I don't want to.
I don't want to.
Well, try. Try.
Just try looking
at the hands, ok?
Can you see the hands?
Hmm?
Now can you see the arms?
Up to the elbows?
And up to the shoulders?
Can you see the neck?
Now can you look at the face?
No. There isn't any face.
There isn't any face.
The hands did it or the towels
just did it all by themselves.
I'm scared. I'm scared.
I know. I know.
I know, but if we look at the
scary stuff, it'll go away.
Oh, it hurts me.
It hurts me.
I know,
but we have to find out
what did the hands do
to make that hurt.
Oh, come on, Peggy.
You don't have to do that.
Oh, my god.
Keep away from the window.
Remember, you promised you
wouldn't break glass in my office.
Hands and the people
and you could see them
and they walk and they talk
and you can hear them
and, and "a" sharp and "c".
Oh, oh, it hurts me.
Who are the people, sweetie?
What hurts? What hurts?
I will. I gotta get out.
I gotta get out. Peggy!
I will. I will. Glass break.
Where are you? Where
are you, Peggy? Tell me.
The kitchen,
the kitchen, the kitchen.
It's all green.
And the sink and the table
and the light, you can see it.
And the shade, and the shade,
and the piano in the living room,
and the piano
in the living room.
And the people, and you
can't get away from the music,
and it doesn't
make any difference.
Oh, don't hook me.
Don't hook me.
Hook you with what?
Don't hook me. Don't hook me.
I know. You got a big hook.
You got a button hook.
You're gonna hook me. You're
gonna hook me. No. No. No.
Peggy, who are you talking
to? No, you won't let me out.
You won't let me break glass.
You won't let me draw.
And you won't let me draw.
Yes, I'll let you draw.
You won't let me draw.
I'll let you draw.
You won't let me draw
because I'll draw my way out.
I'll draw my way out.
And all the people
and the colors.
And the people
You won't be mad.
No, no. Draw.
I'll draw my way out.
You watch. You could watch.
Vicky would say "may," but
I can say "can" if I want to.
The people, the people,
the people.
It's all purple. And it moves
and you watch them
and you see their feet.
And you have to get away.
And there's another
and another and another.
And the music, it goes around
and around and around and around
and over and down like that,
and then like that.
And you could see,
you could see,
and the people have hands.
Peggy, who are the people?
I don't know. I don't know.
They're just people.
And it's like that
and like that and over
and around and like that
and like that.
And you can hear it,
and you can hear.
And it goes sharp, sharp.
It goes sharp. "a" sharp.
"A" sharp and "f" and "f"
and-and-and "b" and "d"
and-and-and-and-and
brahms and beethoven.
And-and-and-and-and-and
Brahms and-and-and the New
World Symphony and Dvorak.
And Dvorak, you can hear it.
You can hear it.
Oh, oh, mustn't waste paper.
Mustn't waste paper.
Paper is valuable.
Yes, it is. Yes, it is.
It's valuable. It's valuable.
You can see now.
You can see the people.
You can see the people now.
You can see them.
You can see.
Oh.
It's all right.
Oh, god,
how did I get under here?
How did I get under there?
You have to stop me
from doing this.
I can't go on.
Sybil, how do you feel?
Relieved, a little.
Hmm, I'm not surprised.
You've accomplished
a great deal.
Sybil, come and sit down.
I wanna show you something.
Come on. Sit down.
Now, you told me that
this was a picture
of the people.
Who drew that?
That's my mother.
That's a picture
of my mother.
Look, the little wisps
of hair there and,
and you can't see her eyes.
Her eyes always scared me.
Did you do that?
No. No, I didn't do it.
Look. Look, the little bow and
hairpins she always wore in her hair.
And-and there's
the button hook.
I don't remember.
Button hooks scare me.
Like they're gonna get me.
Button hooks are good things.
What about dish towels?
Do dish towels scare you?
How do you know
about dish towels?
Do they scare you?
Yes.
But now dish towels are good
and useful things, right?
Sybil,
love is a necessary thing.
But now if a voice says,
"c-come here, I love you"
and then a hand reaches out
and pinches you like that, hard,
then-then love is spoiled
by that hand, isn't it?
And-and-and music, now that's
something that-that you love very much
and you miss very much
because somehow that was spoiled
for you, too, by the hand.
We don't know how,
but-but we're gonna find out.
And that hand
belongs to the people
and the people
was your mother.
The people,
I cannot see the people.
Oh, Peggy, stop that!
What?
Oh, Dr. Wilbur,
it's getting worse.
This is getting a lot worse,
isn't it?
How do you know
those things?
I don't tell you them.
And who does those drawings?
You do.
Oh, but you do them
as other people.
Do you understand?
Mmm-mmm, mmm-mmm.
You do them as other parts
of yourself no, I don't.
...who are still children.
No, I don't.
It's true.
No, it's not. It is not
Sybil, you've got to understand.
It is true. This is not possible.
It's possible.
Mmm-mmm.
In fact,
through most of the analysis,
I've been talking to you
through them.
They all have names and they
come here and they protect you.
They keep your appointments
and they're the ones
who pour out this information
that you're afraid to face. Oh, no.
You've got to understand
that, Sybil. No, it's not true.
It's true. It's not true. No,
it's not. No. It's not true.
Sybil.
Everything you care about
survives in those parts of you
that your mother
wasn't able to reach.
Your music, your painting,
even your ability to love,
they survive there.
Sybil, I want you
to hear something.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to let you hear
yourself play the piano.
I can't play
the piano anymore.
I used to play it.
I can't play it anymore.
Well, this is a part of you who
calls herself Vanessa, and she can.
She plays beautifully.
I don't wanna know about her.
Sybil.
We've got to make
this real for you.
Doctor, I don't think
that I can take it.
My hands are going numb.
There's no danger for you.
There is no danger.
There are no dish towels
tying your wrists now.
My heart. My heart.
That's only adrenalin.
There is nobody here
to hurt you, I promise.
Nothing bad is going to happen.
It's gonna make it better.
Please, Sybil,
just relax and listen.
that's Vanessa.
And she's got all your music
for safekeeping.
that's me?
Playing mozart?
Mmm-hmm.
And you played Sibelius, too.
You played Finlandia.
Don't you dare tell.
Next worse thing to being a
fibber is being a talebearer.
That's my mother's voice. That's my
- that's my mother's...
that's my mother's voice.
That's my mother's voice.
Sweetie, that's not
your mother's voice.
That's you imitating your...
Sybil?
Sybil!
What the hell
did that monster do to you?
What happened
in the green kitchen?
Hello. Erna.
Listen, I need your support.
I, uh...
Sybil has dissociated
into a baby.
I can't get her back.
A baby.
Oh, l-I was too eager.
I pushed her over the edge.
Well, I can't get her hypnotized.
If I could, I'd-I'd contact Vicky,
but she won't focus
on-on-on-on anything
and-and she doesn't
understand a word I say.
She's-she's preverbal.
Yeah, but what if
she stays like that?
No. No. No hospitals.
No, not with her history.
Could you?
Could you please, Erna?
I hate to drag you out on
a night like this, but l-I...
oh! Hold on a second.
Dr. Wilbur, uh,
I'm getting her a snack.
Sweetie, how do you feel?
A little woozy. Hungry.
Well, there's-there's food
in the kitchen.
Go get some cheesecake
or something.
I'll be there in a minute.
Oh, Erna, it's ok. It's ok.
Onward and upward,
she came to as Sybil.
Sybil Dorsett,
psychoanalytic session 251.
I'd hardly breathed
a sigh of relief
about Sybil's making her
spontaneous reentry out of the baby,
when, suddenly, we're facing
this ghastly season of mirth.
Christmas seems to be
a stressful time for Sybil.
The other personalities
have been stirred
into a kind of
frenzied wakefulness
and some who've been dormant
until now have come out.
One of them, Mary,
is a devout,
old-fashioned
little homemaker
who seems almost the reincarnation
of Sybil's grandmother.
I wish you all
a happy holiday.
Joy in the new year.
Nobody answers, Vicky.
Mary, this is New York.
This is not Willow Corners.
Don't be upset.
Let me carry
the portfolio for you.
It's getting awfully heavy.
Thank you, dear.
I can vaguely
remember what's in it.
Everything's been
getting so dim lately.
Must be senility.
Angels.
They're only decorations,
Mary.
Grandma's with the angels.
So am I.
Am I going to
see grandma, Vicky?
Not yet.
We're going to see
Dr. Wilbur first.
Come away, Mary, please.
Marcia promised that she'd
send me to grandma soon.
Why doesn't she do it?
I'm getting
Come in.
Oh, Vicky, come on in.
Dr. Wilbur.
Pardon me for
barging in on you like this.
I'm sorry, but it all
seems to be falling apart.
I don't seem to be able
to control things any longer.
It's all right.
Tell me about it.
Marcia is constantly
thinking of suicide.
Mary thinks
she's in heaven.
And Sybil has invited Richard
over for Christmas dinner.
Now, I know she isn't able
to handle it. I know this.
It's all just awful.
Well, what made it go awful?
What happened this time?
Hmm?
It's Christmas.
The trees and the windows
and everybody all cozy.
Everybody having to
rush around, hurry before...
before what?
We've made you this.
It's a Christmas card,
for you.
For our Dr. Wilbur.
Thank you.
Sorry about the color.
Sybil tried
for red and green,
but it just
kept getting purple
and she wasn't able
to stop it.
Do you know what she did?
She took the crayon, and she
just scrubbed on the paper
and scrubbed on it like that,
and she grit her teeth
and then she wadded it up
and threw it in the trashcan.
We rescued it.
We-we tried
to make it prettier, you see.
Peggy added the red,
and we smoothed it out.
We-we all tried.
Thank you. Well, sit down.
I've brought you these, too.
But you mustn't tell her.
They're our paintings.
We do them at night.
We hide them
on a secret shelf
on top of the closet
that Mike made.
We want you to have them
for safekeeping.
The way you say
that Vanessa keeps the music.
Because something awful is
going to happen. I can feel it.
It's going to fall apart,
or-or blow up,
or there's going
to be an earthquake.
Sweetie, there's not going
Or a tidal wave, or-or a glacier,
or something. I don't know what.
Just something awful
is going to happen.
The end of the world is not
what you're afraid of, Vicky.
Please keep them
for safekeeping. Please.
All right.
Thank you.
Vicky, safekeeping from what?
Hmm?
Now, what is the connection
between purple
and Christmas
and things blowing up?
Hmm?
What did mother do
to make the purple?
There are guards
around the palace.
Vicky, we've got to get past
the guards around the palace now.
I mean, we have to get down
to the bottom
where everybody is joined
together and remembers everything
and it's all right to say it.
Now, you know
there is a way to do it.
We've discussed
the way before.
Yes, I know.
Hypnosis.
Yes.
Sybil's daddy
wouldn't like it.
Well, what about Sybil?
Is Sybil listening now?
She- she's so awfully afraid,
doctor.
I think she would
almost do anything
if it would help make us
not be so afraid.
Good.
All right.
Come on.
Just lie here,
put your feet up and relax.
It's all right.
What would you
like to look at?
Nehemiah, the little horse
that Peggy made you.
All right.
Here, come on, lie back.
Put your feet up.
That's right.
Now you just relax.
Relax.
And when you're ready,
you look at Nehemiah.
Here,
you will look at Nehemiah.
Sybil's heart is pounding so.
It's all right.
You will be with me, and we
will take this up together.
You'll be safe.
Now just relax.
Look at Nehemiah.
Now, you're going to sleep.
Deeply, deeply asleep.
All right?
Now, we will come
close to the purple.
You will remember
but you won't feel the hurt.
The hurt is in the past.
Now, when did
the purple happen?
5 years old.
Any particular day?
Day before Christmas,
like now.
All right.
Now, when I touch
your left shoulder,
you will listen with the
others while I speak with Sybil.
Sybil.
Yes.
Are we going
to grandma's room?
Is that where you were?
I like it there.
It's nice in grandma's room.
All right.
When I count to 5, you
will be in grandma's room.
You count with me. 1.
2.
3. count with me.
4.
5.
I'm right here, Sybil.
You can go to her.
What is it, dear heart?
My grandma.
You can go to her.
She's dead.
This is a memory, sweetie.
Guess who's here, grandma?
Give me a hint.
Sugar and spice
and everything nice.
Is this, by any chance, my
little downstairs neighbor?
Is this my Sybil?
You guessed right.
Grandma.
I love my grandma.
You can say it to her
if you want to, sweetie.
I love you, grandma.
Little round scissors,
I found them.
Good! Hurray!
What are you doing
with the little scissors?
Cutting.
Cutting what?
Little picture of Santa Claus.
And I stay inside
the lines real good.
Like this.
And I make a little star
out of tinfoil. Like this.
And my grandma's
real nice to me,
and she doesn't holler at me,
and I don't have to be afraid
in my grandma's room.
No.
It's all right, sweetie.
You're still with your grandma.
A beautiful star.
See how it twinkles.
I make a good Santa, too?
It all right?
Oh, my.
You didn't cut a whisker.
He looks so happy.
I don't think he liked being
cooped up in that old magazine.
Can I paste him on my star?
That a good idea?
Wonderful.
You show me.
You can show me.
Then he can twinkle way up
high on my tree where he will-
Sybil!
You come down here,
young lady!
You've been pestering
that old woman long enough!
I don't want
to go downstairs.
You can face it, sweetie.
There's too much purple.
We're gonna
go downstairs together
and you're gonna remember
the purple
and this is the way
you're gonna remember it.
Maybe there's
nothing to remember.
Sweetie, you're going
down the stairs,
and I'll be with you.
Chocolate.
Chocolate chippie.
That's right. Come on.
Watch your feet.
You know how clumsy you are.
Come on.
Have a nice trip.
See you next fall.
Hattie, is Sybil all right?
It's just
one of her falls, grandma!
Oh, grandma,
what big ears you have.
Here.
Made 4 dozen for that poor
woebegone floyd family
'cause it'd be a bleak Christmas
if nobody helped them out.
Come on. Keep momma company.
"Under the spreading
chestnut-tree
"the village smithy stands
"the smith,
a mighty man is he
with large and sinewy"
sinewy.
Momma.
"His hair is crisp"
crisp? I never noticed that.
All these years,
I never noticed that.
Lettuce is crisp.
"Lettuce head
go to bed
"your nose is red
your name is Fred
I'll kill you dead"
momma.
I'm busy.
Look what I made
for the Christmas tree.
What do you mean made?
Oh, that's just
a picture out of a magazine
with a piece of tinfoil
stuck to it.
Grandma says it's pretty.
I go hang it
on the Christmas tree.
I told you not to
run through the house!
I'm sorry.
Yes, well.
"Words are cheap
hills are steep
sorrow's deep"
oh, for the wings
for the wings of a dove
far away
far away would I roam
oh, for the wings
for the wings of a dove
far away
far away far away
would I roam
momma, come see what I did.
You didn't go hang that thing
on that tree after I said that?
Said what?
Take it off.
Take it off!
You go away first.
Reach around me.
Go on. I dare you.
Come on. Come on,
reach around me.
I told you not to
run in the house.
Don't you cry.
Don't you make faces.
Don't you get mad.
Mad dogs get mad, not people.
Now, don't worry.
I'm not gonna hit you
this time.
This time
I'm only gonna kick you.
You are so adorable
when you do that.
You look just like
a little baby crab.
What are you going to do?
Draw a picture?
Uh-huh.
Who for?
Momma's Christmas stocking.
Oh, what a lovely thought.
Even if I don't like made-up
things as much as factory ones.
When I'm a big girl,
I go work in a factory
and make you
something real pretty.
oh, Christmas tree
how lovely are
thy branches
come on, sing.
not only green
when summer glows
but in the winter
when it snows
well, who ever heard of a
green chicken with purple feet?
Can you picture what
kind of eggs that lays?
Set a platter of them in front of
grandpa some fine sabbath morning,
he'd sure take that for
a sign now, wouldn't he?
"Armageddon!"
oh, Christmas tree
you are the tree
most loved
how oft
you've given me delight
when Christmas fires
are burning bright
you think it's just
sunshine and singing
and pretty colors
when you grow up?
Well, I should say not.
You are bad.
You are spoiled rotten.
And you better learn quick.
Mine! Mine!
Wanna break glass. Wanna break
glass. Hey! Wait a minute. Here.
Here, you wanna tear something
up? Come on, tear it. That's it.
I loved my colors.
Of course you did.
My colors are me.
Those are my colors.
Sweetie, hasn't it
ever occurred to Sybil
that good mommies
don't hurt their girls?
Mommies put your fingers
in the meat grinder.
No, they don't.
Not good ones.
Mommies are only good
when other people around
not when they get you alone.
Dr. Wilbur doesn't hurt you
when you're alone, does she?
No, Dr. Wilbur thinks that
little girls should be happy,
especially little girls who can
paint green chickens with purple feet.
Momma.
What's the matter, sweetie?
What's happening?
My wrists are going numb.
Can you tell Dr. Wilbur
about it? Tell me about it.
Well, tell me about it. Tell
me. What's happening? Tell me.
What's happening, Peggy?
You better say,
"God is love," real quick.
God is love.
Because God hates bad girls.
And if they're real bad, he
takes them before their time.
Where does God take
bad little girls, momma?
Where, momma?
He takes them way up into the
dark and leaves them there.
He lets them
drown in the wheat.
They can't breathe
and they die.
And that's what's
gonna happen to you.
Have to do it.
Uh-huh. Yes, ma'am.
Have to.
God is love.
Who got you out, Sybil?
Daddy.
Momma told him the little
boy down the street did it.
What did daddy say?
Daddy said, "oh."
Daddy always believed momma.
You didn't tell daddy
the truth?
No, not supposed to.
Momma would send me to God.
What are you doing?
Drawing with
my purple crayon.
Why? So someone will know I was here.
Sweetie, that bad end-of-the-world
feeling is not the end of the world.
It's just the coming
of your own anger
and the color
of that anger is purple.
I don't want it.
I'm afraid of it.
I know, but avoiding it is
just what's getting in the way
of your doing anything.
Don't you be mad at momma,
or she'll get you.
No, sweetie.
She won't get me.
I'm stronger than she is.
And I'll get just as mad
at momma as I like
and I'll stay
mad at her for you
until you are able
to do it for yourself.
All right, we're gonna leave
Willow Corners now.
I don't ever wanna
go back there again.
We're coming back
into the present.
You're 6, 14, 21, 29.
This is too fast.
It's all right to come into
the present, sweetie,
because I'm in the present.
Your mother is dead and buried
in a grave in kansas city.
Mother's dead?
She's dead.
It's all right.
Now you'll only remember
what it's safe to remember.
I'm so anxious.
Sweetie, you've survived.
That you've found such a
creative alternative to insanity
is miraculous
and it-it will protect you
till you don't need it anymore.
But what if I can't
cook dinner for Richard?
I'm so worried
about being embarrassed.
You're protected, sweetie.
Vicky wouldn't let
you be embarrassed.
She'll call on
one of the others.
Vanessa's more comfortable
with Richard than you are.
I envy her so.
And now I'm gonna suggest that
when you wake up in the morning,
and it's Christmas,
you will have
a beautiful day.
A day that's all yours, that you
can do anything you like with.
Paint pretty place cards
for Richard and Matthew
and put red candles
on the table.
Oh, it'll-it'll be so nice.
Hands, please.
Can we reach? Yeah, I guess.
Ok, ladies first.
Um, I wish...
well, my wish is taken care
of because you're both here
and that's my wish.
I wish for a red dump truck.
Love, joy,
and peace to us all.
When in doubt, eat.
So let's begin.
I used to hate
Christmas at home.
All those aunts and uncles
sprawling around, too full to move
winding their watches
and saying,
"don't you think
it's about time
we got this show
on the road?"
I think I'll see
about the chicken.
Stay, please.
It won't run away.
You know, sometimes it's nice
to be quiet for a change.
I feel all out
here some place.
I feel like I'm floating
around outside myself.
I think I'd feel closer
if we talked long distance.
We have time.
We'll get there.
Where are we going,
daddy?
Not that kind
of getting there, Matthew.
Anybody interested in
a drumstick?
Me, please.
Hello?
This is long distance.
This is long distance
calling Miss Sybil Dorsett.
Hello.
Hiya, Slats.
Uh, my name is Lefty.
How do you do, Lefty?
Well, uh, I'll tell you.
Don't trace this call, see,
and don't ask no questions.
Before I go on the lam
with my sidekick here
Matt the rat,
I, uh...
I want you to slip me the key
to the downstairs door
so I can get back in.
Ok, Slats?
'Cause I don't like
long distance.
Slats?
You still there?
I think so.
Yeah, well, uh, you gotta
give me an answer quick.
I don't want you
to be disappointed, Lefty.
I got no expectations, Slats.
be right there.
Oh, Vanessa,
you look just fine.
You know, a key wouldn't do
much good against all this.
You need a scaling ladder.
I guess it's called security.
Open your Christmas present.
Oh, Richard.
"Oh, Richard."
I thought we agreed
we weren't gonna do this.
I'm a congenital liar.
Oh!
Remind me never to let you
take off a bandage.
Well, if I'm very careful
and don't tear it,
then I can draw
on the back of it.
You draw on the whole thing.
It's only watercolor paper.
Oh, Richard.
It's the most beautiful paper.
Thank you.
I want- I want you- you
don't have to say anything.
The nightgown says it all.
You want closeness,
that's all.
I never
exactly had closeness.
Love, I told you one time,
you're only 12 years old.
Now, anything more
would be illegal.
You mind if I undress?
I'm really interesting.
We had male models
in art school.
Ok.
Well, I don't think this bed
was made for masculine shoulders
because there's
no room for me.
There's room.
There is.
Well, well, well.
I think I'm gonna fall out.
Lefty.
Slats.
This is a very
unexpected Christmas.
Yeah. For me, too.
When you talk,
your chest vibrates
like a piano
with the hood down.
o, tannenbaum,
o, tannenbaum
you're tickling my ear.
oh, Christmas tree
how lovely are
thy branches
hey, come on. It's ok.
Wake up. You're dreaming.
Come-come- come on.
Let me help you down, ok?
I don't want to see
the kitty cat.
There is no kitty cat.
I don't want to see it.
No, don't.
You got suction cups
on your toes or something?
It's not there? It's not there?
The kitty cat is not there?
No.
I don't wanna see it. I
don't wanna see it. No, don't.
You're not Danny.
No.
The people. The people.
They watch. They watch.
Now,
what're you talking about?
Out, I will get out. I will go
some place. I will go some place.
I'll go to- I'll go to
New York. I'll go to New York.
You're in New York.
I'll find my Dr. Wilbur.
She'll be glad to see me.
Who's Dr. Wilbur?
She'll know what to do.
I have to find purse.
Purse.
Who's Dr. Wilbur?
That's all right. I'll hitchhike.
I'll hitchhike. I want my suitcase.
You'll hitchhike where?
You can't go anywhere
unless you are somewhere and
you don't know where you are.
Suitcase. I want my suitcase. Sybil!
Sybil, who is Dr. Wilbur?
Don't do this to me!
Who is-
don't do this to me!
They said not to
go to the movies.
The movies were...
do I go to the movies? No.
We went to radio city
this morning.
Sybil, is Dr. Wilbur
a psychiatrist?
Were we talking about art?
Were we talking
about the ballet?
I can't cook dinner.
Oh!
Is this Marcia?
Is she doing this to me?
It's not the end of the world.
It's the end of me.
Sybil.
Stay. Don't leave!
information, l-I need a-a
number for a Dr. Wilbur.
A psychiatrist.
nothing matters now.
thank you.
Hello.
Who?
Richard Loomis?
What's the matter?
Well, how did the dinner go?
Yes, well, the thing
about it is, you see,
you probably don't know
who you're dealing with.
So I'm gonna have to, uh...
to break
a professional confidence.
Oh, my god.
My little boy tried to tell me
that, you know, in different words.
If she's feeling the way that you
say she is, she's probably Marcia.
So you can just feel free
to call her by her name.
But would you tell her
something for me?
Tell her I said
it's perfectly ok
to think about
killing herself
but would she please just
wait until I get there.
She's on the roof.
I gotta go.
Sybil.
There is no Sybil now.
Don't you come near me.
I won't.
Hey, l-I don't think
we've met yet.
My name is Richard. Hi.
Aren't you gonna tell me
who you are?
Well, I've been talking
to Dr. Wilbur
and she thought
that maybe you were Marcia
so I'm gonna
call you Marcia, ok?
How-how are you,
Marcia?
That's a very pretty scarf
you have on.
You're trying to get me to
wait until Dr. Wilbur gets here.
Well, it won't work.
Marcia!
Marcia. Marcia, you know, that
- that's an awfully long fall down there.
It's 5 stories. Now,
I'm only considering Matthew.
D- d-do you know Matthew?
He likes you.
He loves Vanessa.
No, not-not-not
just Vanessa.
H- he knew about all of you long before
I ever did. I mean, he sensed it.
Anyway, he said to me, "daddy,
Sybil is just stuffed with people."
He did?
Yeah.
I guess that's because
we're all children, too.
Yeah, and-and you see,
the point-the point is
that- that's-that's Matt's
window right down there.
That's the lair
of Matt the rat, Slats,
and-and if- and if you land
down there in that courtyard,
that's what Matt is gonna
remember for the rest of his life.
His good friend
looking like-
then I'll go over there, on the
other side, where he can't see.
Where? Over there? That
- that's a street. You might hit somebody.
I won't know them.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, yeah,
that-that-that makes sense.
You move back over there.
Where? Where? Here?
Further.
Here?
And promise me now, you promise
me you won't try to stop me.
Well, I promise.
No! You promised.
You promised.
I told you
I was a congenital liar.
Don't. Don't trap me.
It will get worse.
It'll get worse.
Let me do it.
Oh, please. Please,
why won't you let me do it?
Why won't you let me do it?
The people, the hand.
And the people.
Their hands, and the water.
The water, and the water.
You just lay still,
young lady.
You just lay still.
You move a muscle and...
you move a muscle and...
I can see it. I can see it.
In the kitchen. In the kitchen.
It's all green, and it's
dripping, and it's in the sink.
I can see it. I can see it.
It's not cold enough,
young lady.
It's not cold enough.
You just lay still.
Please, don't!
I know who you are. I know
who you are. You're Danny.
You're Danny. I know Danny.
Uh-huh.
Danny likes me.
I like Danny.
He dances for me,
and he sings.
He dances.
He sings like Fred astaire.
lovely I know him.
I know him. I know him.
never, ever change I know
him. I know him. I know him.
I know him.
keep that breathless charm I know him.
Don't touch me.
You're burning my skin off.
Sybil!
Why are we here?
Marcia's trying to kill herself.
She's trying to kill you.
Don't hold me.
Don't hold on to me.
Sweetie, sweetie, sweetie.
Please let her do it.
It's all right.
I'm afraid to let her go.
Sybil. Sybil!
Dr. Wilbur. It's all right. It's all right.
Dr. Wilbur.
Ok, just hold on a minute.
Dr. Wilbur. Let me get...
dear, it's all right.
Oh, your coat is so pretty.
It's all right.
I'm gonna give you... you're gonna
get your dress dirty, Dr. Wilbur.
No, no. No. I'm gonna give you
some sedation is what I'm gonna do
and it's gonna make you feel
better and take away the hurt, ok?
Dr. Wilbur,
please let her do it.
No, no. No, no, no.
Please don't get
your dress dirty.
Don't get dirty, please.
You look so pretty.
Oh, I'm scared of that.
Scared.
It's ok.
I'm scared.
No, it's all right.
There, ok?
You have 4 earrings.
Yeah, I got 4 earrings,
but I only got 2 on.
That's just the medicine, ok?
Give me a hand.
Come on, sweetie.
All right.
All right?
Yeah.
Ok.
Come on, sweetie.
Is he gone?
I don't want him to see me.
It's all right.
Here. Come on.
There you go.
He's so thoughtful.
You know, if he goes to get
a glass of water for himself
he never just brings one.
He brings 2,
and then he says,
"I thought maybe
you'd be thirsty."
Isn't that thoughtful?
Mmm-hmm.
Isn't that considerate?
That's quite considerate,
yes.
You don't find that
very often nowadays.
What is it I felt
for my grandma?
Was that love?
Yeah, that was love,
sweetie.
And Danny, was that love?
Mmm-hmm.
That's what it is
with Richard then.
Dr. Wilbur.
Mmm-hmm?
Is it all right if i
don't see him again
until after we pull
ourselves together?
Mmm-hmm.
I don't know how to tell him.
I think he'll know
without you telling him.
$0.21 a pound.
All right, I'll take it.
Pay the girl.
I'll go inside.
Go inside.
Ah, that's nice.
There, that should drive the
winter out of the corners.
Yeah. I, uh, I passed the park
on the way to work this morning.
There was a guy cutting
the grass. I got one whiff
and already I'm thinking about
2 weeks in the mountains, huh?
Have a care, Mr. Rizo.
Spring is the mischief in us,
as the poet says.
Yeah. Have a good day.
Richard moved away.
Did I tell you?
No, Marcia did.
How did that make you feel?
My kitty bothers me.
I ask you how it feels
to have Richard move
and you tell me
your kitty bothers you.
That's interesting.
Let's not talk about it. It'll
just open up a whole can of peas.
No, what it might open up
is a whole nest of kittens,
which is something
we've avoided
every time you've
dreamed about them.
Now, maybe there is
a connection
between your anger
at Richard moving
and your-
there isn't any anger.
Sweetie, your anger
at the headless cat.
Curiosity killed the cat,
so don't wonder.
Curiosity didn't
tear its head off.
Now, who did that?
You wanted to get
rid of momma, right?
That's one theory.
There are a million theories.
You pick one.
I'll agree to anything.
I see.
You always say, "I see."
You know,
Marcia was so afraid
of wanting to kill momma
that she almost killed herself
for just having the thought.
I don't know Marcia.
I'm not interested.
Marcia told me about a memory
she had about a little box.
Why do I have to remember
something that didn't happen to me?
Why can't I blank out?
Because you can stand some of
those feelings now, sweetie.
You're getting stronger.
Now, can't you tell me
about the little box?
It started to grow.
It got bigger.
That's right.
And it grew bigger until it
was big enough to put momma in.
In fact, it turned
into a coffin, didn't it?
I did not wanna
get rid of momma.
I wanted to get rid
of the hurt.
I wanted the hurt to
go away, not momma.
I didn't mean anything bad.
Sweetie, it's not bad to wanna
get rid of something that hurts.
And momma was
just one big hurt
with a name attached to it.
It was still my momma.
That was
an accident of nature.
Sybil,
a wish can't kill people.
Now, if the world
has to turn purple
and little children
have to kill themselves
because they wish
their mothers were dead,
there wouldn't be
anybody left on earth.
Sybil, you're not
listening to me.
You're thinking about
suicide again, aren't you?
Why do you
wanna kill yourself
instead of doing
what we have to do?
Why do you wanna kill this
wonderfully
creative organism
before you've
even begun to live?
I don't like it
when you're angry.
I'm not angry. I'm definite.
You insult me, my dear.
You insult my heart.
Well, just look at me.
Can't you see what I am?
I have looked at you
and looked at you
for month after month after
month and I have seen you.
You haven't seen anything.
And I wasn't thinking
about suicide.
I was thinking about
what a charade this is.
Dr. Wilbur,
I can't go on like this.
You better sit down.
I have a big shock for you.
It's a lie.
The whole thing.
I don't have
multiple personalities.
Not even one.
It's just me.
I don't- I don't even know
why I got started.
All the things
I told you about my mother,
they're all lies,
every one of them.
She spoiled me rotten,
watched me every single second.
You know,
it interests me, Sybil
that the denial comes at
this particular time.
This is not a denial.
Excuse me, sweetie,
but it comes on the eve
of my Chicago lectures
which must seem like some
kind of abandonment to you
the way Richard
abandoned you.
No, it's nothing like that.
And 2, we are at a place
where the most
terrifying memories of all
are just below the surface.
Dr. Wilbur, excuse me,
but this simply is not
denial or resistance
or any of those
patient tricks.
It is an admission
of culpability.
I'm sorry.
I know I owe you a fortune,
and you'll be paid.
But to go on like this
would be very cruel.
You're too good
a person for that.
So I think what I should do is
take my father up on his offer
and stay in that
sunny little room
where all my things
will fit just perfect
as the famous frieda says.
Are you Sybil?
Of course I'm Sybil.
Who else would I be?
What happened in
the green kitchen?
That's my cue to
turn into Peggy, right?
Dr. Wilbur, there is
no Peggy to turn into.
Do you mind if I test that?
Hypnosis? Be my guest.
All right, would you
lie down on the sofa?
Sur le couch?
Only Vicky's supposed
to know that, right?
"Now, dear heart,
"I want you to
look at Nehemiah.
"You will look at
Nehemiah, sweetie,
and I will ask to
speak to the others."
I've really gotten it down,
haven't i, doctor?
In my Chicago hotel room,
I started to think
that Sybil's denial
might actually have been
her first breakthrough.
Maybe the selves
had banded together
to stop me from
taking Sybil down
to the most
dangerous place of all.
Hello. Yeah, I'd like another
Chicago number, please.
Well, I'm sorry, but I'll
just have to keep on asking
until somebody puts
a phone book in here.
I've got 2 bibles
and no phone book.
The person I'm looking for
isn't in the bible.
A Dorsett, willard Dorsett.
You understand,
Mr. Dorsett, I just wanna
tie up some loose ends,
so to speak.
So you came to
the horse's mouth.
Is that it?
It seemed
the sensible thing to do.
I, uh...
I do recall a bruise or 2
from time to time.
I see.
Well, tell me, do you recall
a broken larynx?
Well, now you say it,
it seems I do.
Ran into a clothesline,
I believe.
Oh, who said that?
My wife, I suppose.
She dried the wash out back.
Now, by wash, you mean, uh,
things like-like sheets and towels
and things like that?
Sure.
Something... so you'd have
to hang them up pretty high
in order to keep them
off the ground. Hmm?
Is that right?
That's right.
Yeah.
Well, it seems to me it would
take an awful lot of determination
for a little 4-year-old
to get her throat up,
you know, high enough
to break her larynx.
Wouldn't you say?
When you stop to
think about it.
You know, Mr. Dorsett,
I have here
a catalog of
hurts.
And what I'd like to stop
and think about is, uh,
how Mrs. Dorsett explained
the rest of these.
Or perhaps even if, uh...
did you ever ask Sybil?
Uh, sometime when you
were alone together with her
and she maybe felt
a little freer to confide?
Did you? I don't get the
drift of this conversation.
Well, I'll give it to you.
I... what I'd like to know is
do you think it's possible
that your wife inflicted
these injuries herself?
Absolutely not.
You understand,
what I mean is,
do you think there was
anything in her personality,
in her character-
absolutely not.
That was a fine woman.
I'm sure she was
a fine woman,
but even the finest people
can get very sick,
Mr. Dorsett
and what I'm talking about
here is sickness.
Now, was she ever sick?
Uh, emotionally sick,
I mean, not-
I know what you mean.
I live in the same century you
do. I beg your pardon. I'm sorry.
She was nervous.
Not sick, just nervous.
She just talked so much,
that's all.
She'd tell poems out loud,
and get up and dance in
restaurants, things like that.
Just too big a head
of steam, that's all.
Frustrated with
the small-town life
or me or something.
I don't know.
She'd get
real low sometimes.
"Low down and blue,"
she'd call it.
One year, she just sat
quiet that whole winter.
Wouldn't even feed herself.
Got so bad I drove her up
to the state hospital.
Well, then what happened?
What did they say?
Oh, they
said she had
the paranoid schizophrenia.
Well, Mr. Dorsett, that's...
that's very sick.
It's-it's...
it's certainly too sick
to be raising a little girl.
They-they were wrong,
you see.
Well, Hattie told me herself
a- after I got her home
that all that doctor did
was sit and stare at her
the whole time
she was with him.
Said if anyone was gonna
tell her she was a loony,
he better get someone to do
it beside one of the loons.
Well, you can't argue with
the logic of that, now can you?
You call that sick?
Excuse me.
Could you tell me
if Dr. Quinoness
still is, uh, living in
Willow Corners, in town?
You bet.
Straight on into town.
Corner of 4th and Maple.
4th and Maple? Thank you.
Yeah.
I hope you don't mind
carrying the oatmeal cookies
but Julia gets pooped
on these stairs now.
Old places are
built for goats anyway.
Well, I appreciate your taking
time out to see me, Dr. Quinoness.
Not taking time out
from much.
Well, here we be.
The museum.
Used to be the only surgery
for 40 miles
till they built the hospital
out on route 9.
I use it now mainly because
the sun lasts longer
than any other room
in the house.
Lately, I've become
greedy about sunlight.
Please sit.
Thank you.
Yes, I seem to
remember hearing
that Sybil was
in New York City.
Of course, nowadays, with all the
family either dead or moved away,
don't keep tabs like I used to. Thank you.
She, uh,
has a nervous condition,
has she?
Mmm-hmm. Yes.
Ah, little Sybil.
Little sparrow of a thing.
Not surprised
it's come to that.
You know,
she had a nervous mother.
So I understand.
Hattie. Pillar of the town.
Did everything.
Well, I would appreciate it if i
could see Sybil's records, doctor.
Well, I don't know
what light that would shed.
You see, l-I never,
never treated her for nerves
only for the usual
childhood aches and pains.
I understand, but l-I would
consider it a great courtesy.
I don't know that
I have anything.
Let me see.
Dorsetts.
Dorsetts. Oh, yes.
Here we are. Sybil.
Tonsillectomy.
I remember that.
She fought so hard
we could hardly get them out.
Torn ligaments,
right shoulder.
Fractured clavicle.
Palm of right hand
burned on stove.
Fractured larynx.
Beans stuck up her nose.
Gas inhalation.
Usual childhood
aches and pains, huh?
Did you ever speculate?
You know,
you can live too long, doctor.
I never told anyone this.
Sybil came to me
with a bladder complaint.
Very unusual in
a little girl.
Couldn't pass her water.
I had to catheterize her.
If you did a gynecological
on her right now,
I'd wager you'd see
what I saw.
Scarification of
the inner wall,
destruction of
certain tissues.
I don't believe
she can ever become a mother.
You know, the good Lord
ships us into this world
not a whole heck of a lot
better than the U.S. mails.
But the hand of the Almighty
had nothing to do
with what I found
inside that child.
You've been very generous,
doctor.
You wanna give me
a tip, doctor?
If I can.
In your...
in your trade, you hear
a lot of confessions.
Dr. Quinoness,
it was a long, long time ago.
How do I find absolution?
it happened, sweetie.
Those are
the crayon scratches you made
when momma put you
in the wheat bin.
They were your cry for help.
Your purple anger.
It doesn't seem real.
Well,
it happened.
I can't believe you went to
all this trouble after I...
I didn't mean to
be mean to you.
Oh, I know that.
It's just I was afraid.
Not of what we
talked about so much.
Can you tell me now?
I was afraid of the hope.
The hope?
The hope that I
might get well.
You began
to make me believe
I could, almost.
For a while,
I could see myself
painting,
or playing the piano or...
yes?
Being with people.
Then I realize
that the only way
that hope can ever be real
is you.
And if you're the only hope,
and this is the only way,
and if it doesn't work,
then I'm a goner.
I just...
I have to be with people,
Dr. Wilbur.
I know that.
I've never really
been let in most places.
Well,
Richard let me in for a while
and you let me in a little
because you have to.
But then,
when he left
and you were gone
I realized that
there wasn't a house
in all of New York
that I could go in.
Quite honestly,
I...
I hailed a cab
a couple of times.
I thought I'd make
up for it somehow.
I'd eat less or something.
Because I had to
talk to somebody.
And one cab driver
talked to me.
He was very interesting.
We drove around
for about 15 minutes.
Yes?
And he drove me by here.
And I looked up
in your apartment
to see if there
was a light on.
I know that was wrong.
Why?
I don't know. It seemed like an
invasion of your privacy somehow.
With a look?
I know it's silly.
No, it only means
there was
a wish that went along
with the look
that you think
it was wrong to have.
Maybe somebody else
had a wish
just for a second.
Would you look
the other way, please?
Sweetie,
it helps me if I can see you.
Then I'll look the other way.
It has to do with a dream.
It has to do with you.
Mmm-hmm.
You and this little girl.
This funny little girl
with a scrunched-up face.
And she's very young,
so what she feels is...
well, maybe it's excusable.
What does she feel?
She's too young to realize
that you're a doctor,
not her friend.
Go on.
Well
she wants to sit beside you
in your big chair.
And she asks.
And she does.
But she's just
a little girl, understand,
and it's just a dream.
What worries you about her?
I'm afraid to tell you.
That you feel
satisfaction in the dream?
It's not a dream, Sybil.
Every time you
come here as Peggy,
you sit here in
this chair beside me
and you put my arm
around you,
and you rest your head
on my shoulder
and you feel satisfaction.
Oh, I couldn't.
I know you couldn't,
but Peggy can.
And you allow it?
Of course I allow it.
Sometimes being close is the
only nourishment that counts.
It seems like too much
to do for her.
Well...
don't you think I might be
doing it for myself also?
Don't you think, uh,
I might do it
because I enjoy
being allowed
to express
my affection for you?
You mean for her.
No, for you.
For Sybil,
for the totality of you.
Don't you know that?
I love your courage.
I love your humor.
I love your talent.
I love your tenderness
with other people.
I love your quickness.
I love your company.
I love you.
Now the only thing that's
holding you on that chair
is the law of gravity.
Sybil, do you know what those
wet things are on your face?
Oh.
Those are
Sybil's first tears.
The first ones you've had
since grandma died.
I loved my grandmother.
I know you did.
I love you, too.
Would you like me to
tell you a true story?
Well,
once, a long time ago, when i
was a little girl in Montana,
I was lying out on
the grass one day
just looking at the ants.
And the grass was sweet
and deep and soft,
and the sun was
warm on my back,
and the insects were
buzzing and it was...
everything was drowsy.
And all of a sudden,
I saw one ant
who was struggling to pick up
this grain of sand
that was far too heavy
for it to lift.
And he struggled
and he struggled.
And pretty soon,
another ant came by
and together, the 2 of them
lifted the grain of sand
and started to carry it away.
Well, I got so excited
that I hollered to my momma,
and she ran out
and she flopped down in the
grass beside me and she said
"now, isn't that miraculous
"how much 2 creatures
can accomplish together
when they care
about each other."
And your mother
was beside you?
Mmm-hmm. In the grass.
Watching ants?
On a summer's day.
Helping each other.
It's too green.
Why did God have to make
everything green?
Green trees, green grass.
Green kitchens.
I'm not even gonna
look at the green.
I'm just gonna
look at the blossoms.
Sweetie, I know
this is the most
difficult hurdle of all,
but we've gotta get into that kitchen
now and face what went on there.
I'm too scared of that.
You're just scared
of being scared.
You survived it
when it happened,
and you'll survive
remembering it.
You know how much
relief you felt
when we faced
the other things,
the hands, the-the people,
and Christmas?
So we will face this,
too, finally,
and-and-and
leave it behind forever.
Leave all that pain behind.
And we'll find a nice
quiet place for a picnic,
and we've got all
your painting things,
and we're just
gonna let it happen, ok?
Ok.
Did we bring Nehemiah
in case we need his help?
Mmm-hmm. He's with us.
What is it, sweetie?
What's in the way?
I don't know. I can't see it.
I can feel it. It's
fear.
Peggy's petrified right now.
This is the first stroke
I've dared to paint.
Oh, Dr. Wilbur.
What?
This is coming.
Just allow it, sweetie.
Just allow it.
Oh, it's like
waves,
waves through me.
It's awful.
Allow it. Go with it.
Oh, no, no.
Go with it.
Just allow it, sweetie.
Oh, is this Peggy?
It's only a hint of
what she feels, sweetie.
She feels much
more than that.
Oh, it's the worst feeling.
Oh, it's so awful.
Just go with it. Try to
go with it. Stay with it
and see if you can find out
what's underneath.
Can you remember?
What's underneath it,
sweetie?
I'm scared.
No.
What is it?
What are you looking at?
It's all green.
And the people, the people.
Peggy, where are you?
Are you in the kitchen?
Have to do it.
It's dripping.
You can hear it dripping.
I know. There's even
a rust spot under the tap.
Have to do it.
What does momma
have to do?
Every morning. Every
morning, after I eat my prunes
and everybody's gone,
she pulls down the shades.
She pulls down the shades
so nobody will see.
And she's got me
tied up on the table.
Oh, it's so cold.
That's because
it's metal, sweetie.
And the water, the water's
running. The water's running.
It has to run a long time
till it's cold enough.
What does she
need cold water for?
She gives me an enema.
It smells all disinfectanny.
Oh, my god.
And my feet, my feet are
tied to the broom handle.
Why? They're tied to the broom handle.
Why?
So she can pull me up
and pull me up and
tie me to the light.
To the light. To the light.
She's gonna bring it.
Oh, no. No, please.
Please, it'll tear me.
It'll tear me.
Oh, get it away.
What will tear?
What's she bringing, sweetie?
What's she bringing?
What is it? What will tear?
What is she bringing?
The knife and the buttonhook.
The knives.
I can see them.
Oh, please.
It's all right, sweetie.
It's all right.
Once we're through this,
you'll be at the beginning
of everything good.
But we've got to
get through this.
It's all right, sweetie.
It's all right.
Oh, oh. Oh, dear lord.
Oh, dear lord.
When I grow up, I will have
lots and lots of children
and I will be good to them.
Go away. Go away.
Oh, and I will let them do
what they want to do.
And they can bring the
neighborhood children over to play.
And they can play
all over the house
if they want to.
I don't care.
They can play in the sunroom.
Oh, please, don't do this!
And they can run in the house
if they want to. I don't care.
And my children can make any
color chickens they want to.
And I won't put their heads in
the oven and turn on the gas.
And I won't burn their hands
with the hot iron.
And I won't throw the shoe
and hit them in the throat.
I won't hurt them
with the buttonhook
and the knives and
the rubber tubes.
And I won't put
a flashlight inside of them
and say,
"you better get used to it
"because that's what men
will do when you get older.
"They'll put things inside of
you, and they will hurt you."
I don't wanna grow up, and
I don't wanna be like that.
No, no, no.
No, no. No, please.
Please put me down.
Don't take me in there.
Please. Please.
Where is she taking you,
sweetie? Where is she taking you?
Oh, it hurts me.
And the music, and Brahms and
Beethoven and Bach and-and Dvorak.
Dvorak and the New World
Symphony, and you can't get away.
And they're coming closer,
and they're marching.
Don't you let go, young lady.
You hold your water.
Hold your water till
the very last note.
I am Sybil.
And I remember.
And I hate her.
I hate her.
I want to hurt her.
I want to stomp on her
and tear her apart
and cut her arms off
and put things inside her
and kill her.
How could she do that to me?
Oh, god.
I hated her so much.
I wanted her dead.
I still do.
I do. I want her dead.
Oh, Dr. Wilbur, help me.
Help me. This scares me.
She had reached
the center of the maze
and come out whole.
Anger could be
her friend now.
Green and purple
were only colors.
She didn't need to
fear them anymore.
You can remember
without pain now.
Without pain?
None of you will ever
have to feel the pain again.
I think it's time
you meet the others.
1.
2.
3.
Falling asleep.
4.
Deeply, deeply asleep.
5.
Now, I'd like to speak to all
of you, and Sybil can listen.
How do you all feel
about meeting Sybil?
Hmm?
Well, is anybody there?
Vicky?
Yes.
Peggy?
I'm here,
but I don't wanna be.
How about the rest of you?
Dr. Wilbur,
we wanna know,
if we meet Sybil
will we still be able to give
a baby to a girl
like daddy did?
Who is that?
I'm Mike,
and sid's here, too.
And we wanna know if we'll
be able to do that like dad.
Well, you boys have a problem
because you live in a woman's body.
You're not built like that.
We will be
when we're big.
Well, how are you
gonna manage that?
We'll push it out.
Well, I think that's
easier said than done.
Well, you can help.
Mike, can we set
this problem aside,
sweetie,
until you all meet Sybil?
'Cause what she needs right
now is to know all of you
and to understand how much
you've all been helping her
and how much more
you can help her
when you all
join hands together.
All for one and one for all?
Mmm-hmm.
Will you still like us then?
I'll love you.
Would you put
your arm around us?
Sybil, are you ready?
You're the doctor.
Who would you
like to meet first?
Well, I've always
wanted to meet Vicky.
All right.
Vicky.
Vicky come on out, sweetie.
bonjour.
Vicky, here's Sybil.
Look, she has her arms
out to me.
She's smiling.
Look how pretty her hair is.
Does she wanna be friends?
Vicky, do you wanna
be friends with Sybil?
Uh-huh.
You think you'd like to
have Vicky with you always?
Yes.
I've always needed
someone like Vicky.
You went on ahead for me.
Whenever I didn't have
the strength to do something,
you'd go on and do it for me.
I like her, Dr. Wilbur.
Yes, she's a part of you
that's very steady
and very likeable.
Will she be with me always?
Mmm-hmm.
Vicky will be
with you always.
You and she
Let's don't say
anything to spoil it.
It's so nice like this.
It's so nice to
have a friend.
And she came right to me.
The others will come to you.
Now the others
are right here,
and they will
come to you also.
Here's Marcia, dear.
Come, girls.
Clara, helen, margie.
And this is Vanessa,
who kept your music for you.
Sid, Mike, hop out, boys.
Nancy.
Nancy kept waiting
for the end of the world
and she's the one
who dreaded armageddon.
And Mary,
the memory of grandma.
Sybil Ann.
Sybil Ann,
don't be shy, sweetie.
Here's Sybil.
Come on, Peggy.
I'm afraid to
meet Peggy right now.
She's afraid of scaring you.
She didn't mean to
break the windows.
She got it confused
with something else,
with getting out
of the kitchen.
How do you know that?
She's speaking
to you, isn't she?
Where is she? Is she there?
Of course.
Peggy.
Oh, come now, Peggy.
Don't be silly.
I don't think I'm ready yet.
Dr. Wilbur?
It's all right, sweetie.
I'm still here.
Is that all she is?
Just that little thing?
I'm not a little thing.
I'm a person.
I'm sorry.
You don't be afraid of me,
and I wont' be afraid of you.
What have you got
behind your back, Peggy?
Haven't you got any hands?
I got fists.
Oh, my.
Look at those knuckles.
They're so white.
It's all right, sweetie.
It's all right.
In accepting
Peggy into her arms,
Sybil began the deepest
healing of her selves.
In embracing Peggy,
she embraced herself.
In calming her, she was
calming her own heart.
As I watched her
becoming mother to herself
I felt my own long
motherhood ending.
I released what
I had held so long.
I celebrated the beginning
of her emancipation.
I let go.
Our work together
lasted 11 years.
Today Sybil lives peacefully
in a small college town
where she's
a professor of art.
There's not
enough time in the day
for her to do
everything she wants
but that time,
in every sense, is her own.
She tells me she's happy.
I know she's free.
colors of dreams
ribbons of rhyme
come out, come out
wherever you are
willows and winds
that whisper words
of a spring so near
a summer so far
mirror, mirror
in my mind
there's so much to see
walking through
your silver rooms
I remember
me