[Guitar strumming softly]
♪ ♪
[rock music]
- PRAISE THE LORD.
PRAISE THE LORD.
FIFTEEN YEARS
IN A WHEELCHAIR
AND SHE ROSE UP.
ROSE UP BY THE POWER
OF THE SPIRIT!
BY THE SPIRIT
IN THIS ROOM.
OH, THE SPIRIT, THE SPIRIT,
THE SPIRIT.
OH, THE SPIRIT
IS ALL OVER THIS MAN.
HECTOR,
YOU ARE BEING RELEASED.
YOUR FOOT IS BEING RELEASED
FROM THE PAIN.
WALK AND TAKE YOUR HEALING,
HECTOR!
CLAIM YOUR HEALING
IN JESUS' SWEET NAME!
OH! OH, THE SPIRIT
IS ALL OVER HIM.
GLORY TO HIM! GLORY TO HIM!
GLORY TO HIM!
THERE IS AN ANOINTING
ON THIS HOUSE TONIGHT.
- DEAN.
- WELCOME.
I'M SO GLAD
THAT YOU'RE HERE.
DID YOU HAVE ANY TROUBLE
FINDING IT OR ANYTHING?
- NO. NO.
- OH, I'M SO HAPPY YOU CAME.
HE WAS JUST TALKING
ABOUT... OH, WAIT.
SHH SHH.
- BEG THE LORD TO TOUCH YOU.
- ASK HIM NOW
WHILE THE HOLY SPIRIT
IS OVERFLOWING IN THIS ROOM.
SAY TO HIM,
"LORD, I DON'T WANT IT ANYMORE."
- I DON'T WANT IT ANYMORE.
- "YOU TAKE THE PAIN."
- YOU TAKE THE PAIN.
- "I AM YOURS.
WASH ME CLEAN."
- I AM YOURS, WASH ME.
SAY IT, DEAN.
- I CAN'T LIVE THE CHRISTIAN
LIFE WITHOUT YOU LORD!
I NEED YOU TO LIVE YOUR LIFE
THROUGH ME!
THERE'S A YOUNG MAN.
HE'S DULY INFIRMED.
- COULD BE YOU, DEAN.
- HE'S NOT A BELIEVER.
HE'S NOT ONE OF US.
HE CAME HERE OUT OF DESPERATION.
YOU'RE IN PAIN.
YOU'RE IN HELL.
YOU DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHY YOU CAME
OR EVEN IF YOU SHOULD HAVE,
BUT YOU ARE WELCOME.
NOW I'M GOING TO POINT YOU OUT.
I'M GOING TO POINT YOU OUT.
THIS HAND IS BEING GUIDED
BY THE HOLY SPIRIT.
YOU'RE OVER HERE.
DON'T BE AFRAID.
DON'T BE FRIGHTENED.
HE'S CALLING YOU.
HE'S HEALING YOU.
THE LORD IS HEALING YOU
RIGHT THERE.
- IT'S YOU DEAN.
- YOU ARE BEING CALLED.
- HE'S POINTING AT YOU.
- YOU MEAN ME?
- YOU ARE BEING HEALED
RIGHT NOW.
- YEAH, STAND UP.
- STAND AND RECEIVE IT.
- STAND UP.
YOU ARE BEING CALLED.
- COME ON, DEAN.
THIS IS YOUR TIME.
THIS IS IT.
- STAND UP.
- YOU CAN DO IT.
- STAND UP
AND CLAIM YOUR HEALING.
YOU HAVE HEART DISEASE
AND YOUR NAME IS JERRY.
- WHAT?
- IT'S ME.
- I'M JERRY.
JERRY, THAT'S ME.
- IT'S ME. HE SAID ME.
- NO. THAT WAS ME!
- REJOICE. REJOICE.
- AAAAH!
[Kicks car]
FUCK!
[Exhales]
[Grunts]
[Sighs]
- [Muttering]
- CAN I BUM A SMOKE?
BRENDEL?
- [Muttering]
- AH, THERE YOU GO.
THANK YOU, MY GOOD MAN.
I'LL GIVE YOU
AN OLD CARTON RIGHT HERE.
- [Muttering]
- YEAH, MAN.
WHAT THE HELL
IS THAT, BRENDEL?
YOU GOT A FEVER
OR SOMETHING, MAN?
[Shuddering]
[Gasps]
- THERE HE IS.
YOU LOOK
LIKE YOU GOT SOME REST.
GOOD, GOOD.
GOOD MORNING, HARV.
EGGS?
- YEAH, I'M NOT AN ASSHOLE.
GET ME FIRED?
- HARV, I DIDN'T GET YOU FIRED,
REMEMBER?
IT WAS YOUR HEART.
IT'S THE OLD TICKER, HARV.
- PROMISED ME YOU'LL HELP ME.
- I DID HELP YOU HARV.
I GET YOUR MEDICINE, REMEMBER?
I FEED YOU.
MAKE SURE YOU SEE THE NURSE,
OKAY?
DEAN.
- WHAT'S UP, PADRE?
WHEN ARE YOU GOING
TO GET ME INTO AN SRO?
I NEED A BED.
- STICK AROUND.
I GOT SOME FORMS FOR YOU
TO FILL OUT, ALL RIGHT?
I MIGHT HAVE SOMETHING
FOR YOU.
GOOD TO SEE YOU.
I HAVE THE DEL VISTA
ASSISTED LIVING CENTER.
I TALKED TO THE GUY TODAY
AND HE'S READY
TO TAKE YOU ANYTIME YOU WANT.
SO YOU CAN GET OUT OF HERE.
- NO WAY.
THAT'S A FUCKING
NURSING HOME, PADRE. NO WAY.
- IT'S NOT A NURSING HOME,
DEAN.
- LOOK,
THEY HAVE APARTMENTS.
THEY HAVE APARTMENTS
FOR THE HANDICAPPED.
- I'M NOT ENDING UP LIKE THAT.
NO WAY.
- YOU'RE NOT ENDING UP
LIKE WHAT?
- LIKE THAT.
- YOU DON'T HAVE
TO BE DOWN HERE, DEAN.
- I EAT DOWN HERE.
- EVERY TIME I SEE YOU,
YOU ASK ME FOR AN SRO.
YOU'RE DOWN HERE,
AND YOU'RE LIVING IN YOUR CAR,
AND YOU DON'T HAVE TO, DEAN...
THAT'S YOUR REALITY.
NOW FILL THIS OUT.
AND MEDICAL IS IN THE BACK.
DO SOMETHING
TO HELP YOURSELF.
THERE'S ONLY SO MUCH
I CAN DO FOR YOU.
- DEAN.
DEAN, I KNOW
YOU WERE DISAPPOINTED,
BUT DID YOU FEEL
THE LORD'S ANOINTING
IN THE ROOM?
HE WAS THERE.
- YEAH, YEAH.
I'M POLISHING MY TAP SHOES,
RENE.
- DON'T GIVE UP, DEAN.
YOU JUST... YOU HAVE
TO BE PATIENT.
YOU JUST HAVE
TO KEEP SHOWING UP.
REMEMBER THAT GOD'S TIME
ISN'T OUR TIME,
BUT HE IS ALWAYS ON TIME.
AMEN.
- THAT'S FUCKING PROFOUND.
- YOU KNOW, IT'S ONLY WHEN
YOU'RE FULLY OPEN TO JESUS...
- I'M NOT OPEN! I'M CLOSED.
I'M CLOSED FOR BUSINESS, RENE.
SO TAKE YOUR FUCKING
COLLECTION PLATE...
[glass shatters]
HEY! HEY!
HEY, THAT'S MY SHIT.
COME HERE!
- DEAN, LET HIM GO!
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO.
LET HIM GO. LET HIM GO.
- HEY! COME HERE!
COME BACK HERE!
- DEAN, LET HIM GO!
LET HIM GO. LET HIM GO.
- HEY!
- DEAN, LET HIM GO.
- FUCK!
- LET HIM GO.
- FUCK! MOTHERFUCKER!
- HEY, THOSE ARE DEAN'S.
THAT BELONGS TO DEAN.
GIVE THAT BACK TO HIM.
THAT'S IT.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
THIS IS WHAT
I'M TALKING ABOUT.
THIS IS WHY I DON'T WANT YOU
PARKING HERE.
I WANT YOU
TO FILL THOSE FORMS OUT, DEAN.
- DEAN. ARE YOU ALL RIGHT?
- YEAH.
- I GOT... I GOT YOUR SHOE.
DEAN, I KNOW THAT GOD FEELS
A MILLION MILES AWAY
RIGHT NOW, OKAY?
I KNOW WHAT THAT FEELS LIKE.
I'VE BEEN THERE.
I'VE BEEN THERE MYSELF.
BUT THIS IS THE TIME
WHEN YOU HAVE TO BELIEVE
MORE THAN ANYTHING.
THIS IS THE TIME
WHEN YOU HAVE TO BE OPEN
IN YOUR HEART TO JESUS
AND HE WILL COME.
- YOU REALLY
THINK YOU'RE GOING TO GET UP
AND WALK ONE DAY, RENE?
YOU REALLY BELIEVE THAT?
- YES, I DO.
- GUY'S A FUCKING IDIOT.
- HE'S JUST TRYING TO HELP.
- WHAT AM I GOING TO DO?
LIKE, I KNOW...
LIFE'S BULLSHIT, MAN.
THERE'S NO WAY OUT.
- THERE IS A WAY OUT,
BUT YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO FIND IT.
[Cheers and applause]
- ALL RIGHT, LET'S GIVE IT UP
FOR DJ SHY.
SO THERE'S ONE MORE.
- HEY, DJ SHY,
THAT WAS TIGHT.
MY BAND IS AUDITIONING
DJS TOMORROW.
I WOULD LOVE
TO CHECK YOU OUT.
- LET'S GIVE IT UP
FOR DJ "DELICIOUS" DEAN.
- OH, NO, WHY'D YOU STOP?
THAT WAS SO GUTTER, MAN.
KEEP GOING.
- L-I CAN'T.
THE... THE TABLE'S TOO HIGH.
- OH, SHIT.
WELL, I'LL FIX THAT.
- NO, NO, NO.
DON'T WORRY ABOUT IT.
I WAS JUST MESSING AROUND.
LEAVE IT. YOU CAN LEAVE IT.
- JUST GET THAT SIDE.
- WAIT. WHOA WHOA WHOA.
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
HEY, DON'T TOUCH THAT.
WHAT THE HELL DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE DOING?
- LOWERING THE TABLE.
- COULD YOU PUT IT BACK,
PLEASE?
- I'M HELPING MY FRIEND.
- OH, YOU'RE HELP...
- WILL YOU LOWER IT
ON THAT SIDE?
- I'M NOT GONNA TOUCH IT.
TAKE YOUR HANDS OFF IT
AND PUT IT BACK.
THESE DESKS ARE SET
AT REGULATION HEIGHT,
ALL RIGHT?
THIS IS FOR DJS
THAT COULD STAND.
- DON'T GO THERE, MAN.
THAT'S SO UNCOOL.
HE'S THE BEST THING
WE'VE HEARD ALL NIGHT.
WHY DON'T YOU JUST GIVE HIM
A CHANCE?
- THIS IS HIS CHANCE, OKAY?
I'M SORRY.
- YOU KNOW, YOUR BAR
IS NOT ACCESSIBLE.
I COULD TOTALLY REPORT
YOUR ASS.
- WHY DON'T YOU TAKE IT UP
WITH LEMMY, ALL RIGHT?
I DON'T OWN THE PLACE.
- I'M SUPPORTING TALENT.
WHO YOU SUPPORTING?
THE FUCKING FUCK HEAD COMMITTEE
OF FUCKS?
- GOOD NIGHT. THANK YOU.
DON'T COME BACK.
- DELICIOUS,
WAIT, WAIT, WAIT.
THAT GUY IN THERE
WAS A JACKASS!
CHECK IT OUT.
I HAVE A BAND
AND I REALLY WANT YOU
TO COME JAM WITH US TOMORROW.
- WELL, I DON'T PLAY
WITH BANDS.
- BULLSHIT.
ONLY ON THE SNYDE DIVER REMIX
AND THE INDIE FATIGABLE
SCRATCH CLOWNS FOR A YEAR?
YOU ARE
THAT DELICIOUS D, RIGHT?
OR IS THERE...
IS THERE ANOTHER ONE?
- YEAH.
IT'S ANOTHER GUY.
- I KNOW I'M GOING
TO SEE YOU TOMORROW.
- BRENDEL?
BRENDEL.
BRENDEL?
- OH, I WAS TRYING TO GET
TO INGLEWOOD.
I'M JUST FEELING
A LITTLE BIT LOST.
CAN YOU GIVE ME A HAND?
- I'M... I'M... I'M JUST TRYING
TO GET TO INGLEWOOD.
- YOU... YOU DON'T KNOW ME?
- I CAN'T SAY I DO.
- LET'S GET YOU
WHERE YOU NEED TO GO.
COME ON. COME ON HERE.
THIS WAY.
- THAT'S BESIDE THE POINT.
THE GUY'S GOT NO SOUL.
WE NEED SOMEBODY
WITH A GROOVE.
- I'M JUST SAYING.
- OH, THAT'S GOOD.
LET'S JUST HIRE A DUDE
BECAUSE HE'S YOUR...
HEY,
WHAT ARE YOU DOING HERE?
- I CAME TO AUDITION.
- WHO ARE YOU?
- THAT'S DELICIOUS D.
HE'S WON LIKE SEVEN
SCRATCH BATTLES.
HE USED TO PLAY AT RAZY
OVERCLIMB'S EVERY FRIDAY.
- SHIT, MAN. NO.
I HEARD OF DELICIOUS D.
DUDE, FUCK.
YOU SCRATCHED
ON THE BALL SHRED REMIX
FOR SNYDE DIVER.
- SCRATCHED AND MIXED.
YEAH.
- HOLD ON, MAN.
YOU'RE NOT EVEN ON THE LIST,
ARE YOU?
- HE'S ON MY LIST.
AND HE'S GOING TO PLAY
BECAUSE HE ROCKS.
- THE STAIN,
WE NEED YOU, MAN.
[Ringing bell]
- A HERALD FOR THE INFIRM.
- THIS IS THE STAIN.
THIS IS DELICIOUS D.
HE PLAYED
ON SNYDE DIVER'S RECORD.
- SNYDE?
- YOU WANT
TO HEAR ME SOLO FIRST
OR YOU GUYS JUST WANT
TO JAM?
WHAT DO YOU WANT TO DO?
[Jamming]
- SHUT THE FUCK UP!
WHAT THE FUCK IS THAT?
WHAT HAVE I TOLD YOU
ABOUT THE FUCKING PHASER?
- GUYS, GUYS...
GUYS. OOGIE!
I'M SORRY.
WHERE'S THE HOOK?
WHERE'S THE MELODY?
- WHERE'S THE MELODY?
WHAT FUCKING MELODY?
WE NEVER TALKED ABOUT A MELODY.
- WE WERE KEEPING IT
FREE FORM.
THERE IS A PLACE FOR...
- FUCK THE MELODY!
WE'RE ANTl-MELODY.
- YOU KNOW, WE ARE STILL,
LIKE, DISCOVERING
WHAT IT IS THAT IT IS
THAT IT'S GOING TO BE.
- OH, FOR FUCK'S SAKE.
- NINA, WE ARE NOT DOING
SOME CORPORATE GIG
WITH OUR TUNES
JUST TO GET SIGNED.
- WE HAVE A&R PEOPLE COMING.
IT HAS TO BE ACCESSIBLE.
- THIS HAS TO BE A FULL,
MULTILAYERED BARRAGE
TO THE SENSES.
- AND THIS IS A GIMMICK.
- WELL, TAKE YOUR SUIT EARS OFF
FOR A SEC, HON.
IT'S FUCKING COOL.
- WHO IS THIS GUY?
AND CAN WE GET A REAL DJ
IN HERE?
- HEY, FUCK YOU, BITCH.
- SHUT THE FUCK UP, MAN.
- YOU FUCKING STUPID...
- OI!
- YOU'RE AUDITIONING,
YOU FUCK!
- I'LL BE IN TOUCH.
- NINA, NINA.
GET SONICA.
- THAT WAS SMART.
- WHAT THE FUCK ARE WE SUPPOSED
TO DO WITH YOU?
- DOUCHE BAG.
- WHAT THE FUCK IS THAT?
- HELLO, DEAN.
DO YOU HAVE A MINUTE?
- MY MAN, MY MAN.
FATHER, THIS IS HIM.
- REALLY?
- THIS IS THE MAN.
HE'S THE ONE.
LOOK, YOUNG UN,
YOU RAISED ME UP.
- BRENDEL'S HAD
A SPONTANEOUS HEALING, DEAN,
OF HIS... OF HIS GOUT
AND HIS ALZHEIMER'S.
- WHAT ARE YOU
TALKING ABOUT, MAN? WHAT...?
- I DON'T KNOW WHAT THIS IS.,
LISTEN, PLEASE.
I MEAN, YOU DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU DID.
MY MAN, LOOK, YOU GOT
THE HEALING TOUCH.
- I GOT NOTHING
TO DO WITH YOU, MAN.
- I WANT TO THANK YOU.
NO, I WANT TO THANK YOU.
- I GOT NOTHING TO DO
WITH YOU!
I DIDN'T DO ANYTHING.
- OKAY.
ALL RIGHT.
LET'S BREAK IT UP HERE.
THERE'S NOTHING TO SEE.
DEAN HAD NOTHING
TO DO WITH THIS.
DEAN?
- [Coughs]
SO YOU'RE ONE OF THESE GUYS
WHO HAS, LIKE, A HUGE CHIP
ON THEIR SHOULDER
AND THINKS THEY CAN GO AROUND
AND GET MAD
AT WHOEVER THEY WANT,
WHENEVER THEY WANT?
- NO. NO.
- THAT WAS REALLY FUCKED UP
THE WAY YOU TALKED TO NINA.
I MEAN, BECAUSE LIKE IT OR NOT,
SHE DOES SHIT FOR OUR BAND.
AND, YOU KNOW...
- I SHOULDN'T HAVE DONE IT,
ARIEL.
I SAID THAT, OKAY?
- I MEAN, I WANT YOU
IN THE BAND.
I REALLY DO, DEAN.
AND I THINK
YOU HAVE SOMETHING
THAT'S REALLY AMAZING.
BUT YOU'D HAVE TO LEARN
HOW TO NAVIGATE YOUR,
YOU KNOW, YOUR HOSTILITIES
AND SHIT.
'CAUSE WE HAVE SO MUCH SHIT
COMING UP
AND YOU CAN'T JUST BE, LIKE,
FLYING OFF THE HANDLE.
I MEAN, WE'RE GONNA GET SIGNED
AND WE'RE GONNA PLAY OUT
AND DO AMAZING THINGS.
- I CAN DO IT.
- I DON'T KNOW
IF YOU'D BE READY FOR IT.
- I WILL NOT FUCK IT UP.
- I LIKE PAIN KILLERS.
DO YOU MIND?
- NO.
- I DON'T THINK
I HEARD YOU SAY SORRY.
- ARIEL, I'M SORRY.
- OKAY.
I COULD TALK TO THE STAIN.
YOU KNOW,
I HAVE A WAY WITH HIM
AND HE RESPECTS MY OPINION.
- WH... ARE YOU SERIOUS?
- YEAH.
SHOW UP AT THE GIG AT 9:00
AND YOU CAN BE IN THE BAND.
- JUST LIKE THAT?
- COOL.
- THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
- LET'S DRINK.
LIVE IT, LOVE IT, KILL IT.
- HEY! HEY!
HEY! WHAT THE FUCK!
- BE CAREFUL.
- GET OFF ME, MAN.
LET ME GO! LAY OFF!
WHAT THE FUCK!
- CAREFUL.
- WHAT THE FUCK!
- GET HIM.
- GET THE FUCK OFF!
AH! FUCK!
GET THE FUCK OFF ME, MAN!
GET OFF! LET GO!
- COME HERE.
- WHAT DO YOU FUCKIN' WANT?
WHAT DO YOU WANT, WOMAN?
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
- MY SIGHT.
I WANT MY SIGHT. PLEASE.
PLEASE, HEAL ME.
I WANT TO SEE MY CHILDREN.
- WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
LOOK, I CAN'T HEAL YOU.
- YES, YOU CAN DO IT.
- LOOK, I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU...
- YOU CAN DO IT!
- I DON'T KNOW
WHAT YOU THINK I CAN DO.
I CAN'T DO ANYTHING.
- YOU CAN DO IT. YOU CAN DO IT.
- ALL RIGHT! ALL RIGHT!
JUST TELL HIM
TO GET OFF OF ME.
JUST GET OFF.
- LET HIM GO.
- THIS IS SO FUCKED UP.
THIS IS SO FUCKING STUPID.
YOU GOT ME
ON MY FUCKIN' CAR, MAN.
- I WANT TO SEE MY CHILDREN.
PLEASE, MY CHILDREN.
OH, YES.
OH, GOD. THANK YOU.
THANK YOU.
OH. OH. OH.
AAAAAAAAAAAAAH!
- WHAT WAS THAT?
WAS THAT ANDREW?
- AAAAAAAH!
[Grunts]
- WHAT HAPPENED?
WHAT HAPPENED?
- IS SHE DEAD?
- SHE ALL RIGHT?
- I SEE.
I SEE YOU, FATHER.
- [Coughs]
- COME ON. COME ON.
FUCK! FUCK!
- YO! YO! TOUCH ME, MY MAN.
- YOU CAN HEAL ME, RIGHT?
PLEASE. PLEASE. COME ON, MAN.
- CAN YOU HEAL ME?
- COME ON, MAN.
CAN'T YOU HEAL ME?
COME ON. I KNOW YOU CAN.
PLEASE.
JUST GIVE ME A CHANCE,
MAN.
- PLEASE HELP US.
- [Groans]
- OH, SHIT!
WHAT THE...?
- OH, I'M SORRY.
L-I JUST... I WAS AFRAID
THAT THINGS
WERE GOING
TO GET STOLEN AGAIN.
OH.
- THANKS. THANK YOU.
- MY GOODNESS,
I DON'T KNOW HOW YOU...
HOW YOU SLEEP ON THIS THING.
IT'S LIKE SLEEPING
ON A BOARD.
OH. GOODNESS ME.
- THANKS.
- EXCUSE ME.
SO DID YOU HEAR THE ONE
ABOUT THE BLIND WOMAN
WHO WAS HEALED BY A MAN
IN A WHEELCHAIR?
RETINITIS PIGMENTOSA.
AN INCURABLE DISEASE.
BUT SHE'S CURED.
- [Exhales]
YOU REALLY BELIEVE THAT?
I MEAN YOU...
PEOPLE CAN DO THAT?
- WELL, DEAN, I-I HAVE NEVER
SEEN ANYTHING LIKE IT
IN ALL MY DAYS.
- IT DOESN'T WORK ON ME.
- FATHER JOE?
YOU GONNA HELP ME? HUH?
YOU... FATHER JOE.
- MORNING HARV.
- YOU GOING TO SHARE THAT?
YOU GOT A MINUTE,
DON'T YOU?
- NO, I DON'T.
I GOT NOTHING FOR YOU.
- OKAY, HARV.
- CAN YOU HELP ME?
- I CAN'T HELP YOU, MAN.
- NO?
- I CAN'T HELP YOU.
I CANNOT HELP YOU.
- LET ME JUST TALK TO YOU
FOR A MINUTE, HARV.
- OKAY.
AH... AH, HELL.
HE'S GOT NO TIME FOR ME.
- JESUS.
- HARV'S...
HARV'S GOT A TERRIBLE HEART.
YOU THINK
YOU COULD JUST TOUCH HIM?
- DON'T DO THAT TO ME, MAN.
DON'T DO THAT.
- YOU'RE RIGHT.
I'M SORRY. SORRY.
IT WAS WRONG OF ME.
I'M SORRY.
DEAN, I KNOW SOMEONE
YOU COULD TALK TO
WHO KNOWS MUCH MORE ABOUT THIS
THAN I DO.
JUST THINK ABOUT IT, OKAY?
- IN OUR FAITH,
THERE'S A LONG HISTORY
OF THESE VERY SPECIAL MOMENTS.
AND GOD HAS FREQUENTLY CHOSEN
THE MOST UNEXPECTED PERSON
TO CARRY THEM THROUGH.
- IT'S A REAL,
A REAL PRIVILEGE, DEAN.
- WELL, IF IT'S SO REAL,
WHY DOESN'T IT ALWAYS WORK?
- AH, WELL,
THERE'S A DUAL VIEW HERE.
ANYTHING IS POSSIBLE WITH GOD,
BUT GOD MAY NOT WANT TO GIVE YOU
WHAT YOU WANT.
- WHY?
- BECAUSE GOD CARES
FOR YOUR SOUL.
AND WHAT YOUR SOUL NEEDS
MAY NOT BE WHAT YOU WANT.
- BUT COME ON, MAN,
THAT'S NOT COOL.
- WELL, I THINK YOU'RE ASKING
THE RIGHT QUESTIONS, DEAN,
BUT YOU'RE NOT WAITING
FOR THE RIGHT ANSWERS.
THERE'S ONLY ONE ANSWER.
PRAY.
- LOOK, MAN, I DID PRAY.
ALL RIGHT?
I TRIED PRAYING.
IT DOESN'T WORK.
- I THINK YOU WERE BARGAINING
FOR THE HEALING, DEAN.
AND THAT IS NOT
THE SAME THING.
I THINK YOU SHOULD SAY HELLO
TO GOD.
- YEAH, WHAT IF I'M PISSED OFF
AT GOD?
WHAT IF I THINK GOD'S
BULLSHIT?
- I WOULD SAY HELLO FIRST
AND THEN TELL HIM HE'S BULLSHIT
AND YOU'RE PISSED OFF.
LOOK AT ME, SON.
GOD IS TRYING TO SAY HELLO
TO YOU
AND TO TELL YOU
THAT HEALING IS POSSIBLE.
NOW HOW ARE YOU GOING
TO RESPOND?
BECAUSE
THAT'S THE BIG QUESTION.
SOMETHING MAGICAL,
WONDROUS IS HAPPENING
THROUGH YOU.
YOU'RE HAVING A CALLING
IN THIS LIFE
AND THAT, MY SON,
IS YOUR HEALING.
- WHAT IF YOU DON'T WANT...?
I MEAN, I DON'T WANT THAT.
YOU KNOW, WHAT IF YOU DON'T WANT
A CALLING?
- I THINK YOU SHOULD TRY
THIS GIFT.
- YEAH, BUT WHAT ABOUT MY MUSIC?
THAT'S MY CALLING.
- THERE'S NO DIFFERENCE
BETWEEN YOU BEING A MUSICIAN
AND HEALING.
- WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT?
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
GO AROUND TOUCHING PEOPLE?
- WHY NOT?
- AND BE A DJ?
I MEAN, YOU HAVE A CALLING.
YOU HAVE A GIFT.
DO IT, TRY IT.
- HOW?
- COME DOWN TO SKID.
DEAN,
I HAVE NO LACK OF PEOPLE
WHO NEED HEALINGS
DOWN IN SKID ROW.
DO A FEW DAYS DOWN THERE.
- BUT I DON'T WANT EVERYBODY
KNOWING ABOUT IT, PADRE.
THEY'RE ALREADY COMING UP TO ME.
YOU SAW IT.
- HOW ABOUT I GIVE YOU
A HOTEL ROOM?
THAT'S WHAT I'LL DO.
I'LL PUT YOU UP IN A HOTEL ROOM
FOR A FEW DAYS.
WHEN I CAME DOWN THE SKID,
IT WASN'T
TO BE A FEEDER'S ALLEY.
I WENT DOWN THERE TO BUILD
A STATE-OF-THE-ART
HOMELESS SHELTER.
I COULD FEED PEOPLE,
I COULD GET THEM
OFF THE STREETS,
I COULD EDUCATE THEM,
AND I COULD PUT THEM BACK
INTO SOCIETY.
I DON'T WANT TO SUSTAIN MISERY
IN SKID ROW.
- DO YOU THINK I...
DO YOU REALLY THINK
I COULD BE HEALED?
- ENTIRELY POSSIBLE.
- ALL RIGHT.
- RIGHT.
- I GOT TO GO NOW.
I REALLY GOT TO GO.
- GO WHERE?
- I GOT THE GIG.
- OKAY, LET'S GO.
LET'S GO.
- CAN YOU DROP ME OFF
AT THE GIG?
- SURE, WHERE? THE GIG?
- THE MOTEL.
- WHAT MOTEL?
- THE MOTEL
YOU JUST OFFERED ME.
- YES, DUH. SURE.
[Live music]
♪ ♪
- WHO IS IT?
ON THE TURNTABLES.
WHO'S SCRATCHING?
- DUDE,
THAT'S MAESTRO SONICA.
- FUCK. FUCK. FUCK!
- THAT WAS FUCKING RUBBISH.
AND YOU'RE ALL FUCKING FIRED
IN THE MORNING,
UNLESS I WAKE UP
WITH A CLEAR HEAD.
WELL, WELL, WELL.
LOOK AT WHAT THE CAT
ROLLED IN.
YOU'RE COMING
IN THE BACK DOOR, D?
ARE YOUR TROLLING
FOR CRUMBS?
FUCK OFF. GO ON.
- MY ONE AND ONLY GROUPIE,
DEAN.
- WHAT THE HELL
ARE YOU DOING HERE, MAN?
- DUDE, MAN, YOU FUCKING
FRIED YOUR FUCK UP.
- WE GOT OURSELVES A DJ.
SORRY.
- LET ME TELL YOU SOMETHING,
MAN.
THE ALTAR BOY,
HE DOESN'T GRAB FROM THE POINTY,
PUNTY, PUFFED UP,
PIOUS, POPE PAN.
HE'S OFF TO THE SIDE
JUGGLING HIS TRINKETS.
- DUDE, HE JUST SAID
"PUFFED UP POPE."
DUDE, DEAN, COME ON, MAN.
JUST PUFF
ON THIS PIECE PIPE PAL.
- [Chuckles]
[Sizzling]
- OW!
- WHAT THE FUCK, MAN?
- WHAT THE FUCK
WAS THAT, MAN?
- AH! AH. FUCKING BURNED ME.
- ASSHOLE.
YOU GOING AROUND
BURNING PEOPLE NOW?
- WHAT THE FUCK
ARE YOU DOING MAN?
- OW!
- FUCKIN' CUT THE SHIT, MAN!
[Band members shouting]
- DEAN, GET OFF HIM!
- DEAN!
- GET THE FUCK OFF HIM, MAN.
WHAT KIND OF FUCKING FUCKED UP
SALMAN RUSHDIE DUBIOUSNESS
YOU TRIPPING ON MAN?
GET THE FUCK OUT OF HERE.
GET HIM OUT OF HERE.
- WAIT, WAIT DUDES.
DUDES! DUDES! BROS, MAN!
FUCK, DUDES.
- WHAT THE FUCK IS THAT?
- WHAT?
- FUCK THAT, MAN.
- I DIDN'T DO IT.
IT WASN'T A FUCKING TRICK.
- WHAT THE FUCK WAS THAT?
- SHIT, BRO.
- HEY!
WHAT THE FUCK WAS THAT?
WHAT WERE YOU DOING
IN THERE?
I TOLD HIM THAT YOU AP...
YOU THINK THEY GIVE A FUCK
WHAT I'M SAYING?
[Throws down wheelchair]
ARE YOU A-A MAGICIAN?
DO YOU NEED ME TO HELP?
- NO, I DON'T WANT
YOUR FUCKING HELP.
DID I ASK FOR YOUR HELP?
- SO, WHAT, YOU TO COME
TO PEOPLE'S PLACES,
LIKE, DOING PARTY TRICKS
AND SHIT?
- YEAH. YEAH.
IT WAS A PARTY TRICK. OKAY?
IT WAS A STUPID
FUCKING PARTY TRICK
AND JUST FORGET
YOU EVER SAW IT.
WHAT ARE YOU DOING? GET OUT.
GET OUT OF THE FUCKING...
GET OUT
OF THE FUCKING CAR, ARIEL.
- NO. [laughs]
- GET OUT OF THE CAR!
- [Laughs]
YOU'RE NOT GOING TO WIN
THIS BATTLE.
[Laughs]
ARE YOU OKAY?
I'M SORRY. OKAY?
SO THIS IS WHERE YOU LIVE?
- YEAH.
- I LOVE IT.
I LOVE SLEAZY MOTELS.
IT'S LIKE HELL WITH A...
WITH A WARM LIGHT.
SO WHAT'S YOUR SECRET?
HOW DID YOU DO THAT...
WITH OOGIE?
DID YOU REALLY HEAL HIM?
- I DON'T KNOW HOW I DID IT,
ARIEL.
- HUH. IT'S A CURSE.
[Chuckles]
- DEAN, THIS IS MARIA LUPITA.
SHE HAS EMPHYSEMA.
SHE HASN'T SPOKEN
TO HER FAMILY.
HER FAMILY HASN'T SPOKEN
TO HER IN YEARS.
SHE'S ALONE
IN THIS WORLD, DEAN.
- AH!
THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
[Applause]
- THANK YOU, JESUS!
- AMAZING. AMAZING.
- A MIRACLE.
IT'S AMAZING.
- I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
- I DON'T WANT TO HEAR
THEIR NAMES ANYMORE, OKAY?
OF THE PEOPLE.
OR WHAT THEY HAVE.
LIKE THE MEDICAL HISTORY
AND ALL THAT.
NONE OF THAT. NO CHITCHAT.
JUST BRING THEM TO ME.
- DEAN, I GOT TO TELL YOU,
IN ALL MY WORK, NOT IN AFRICA,
OR THE FAVELAS IN RIO,
OR WORKING HERE FEEDING
THE HOMELESS
HAVE I EVER SEEN THE GRACE
THAT I SAW TODAY.
IT'S A REAL BLESSING, DEAN.
I-I-I HOPE
YOU UNDERSTAND THAT.
- MMM. HOW MUCH MONEY
DID WE MAKE TODAY?
WITH THE DONATIONS?
- DEAN, I-I CAN'T PAY YOU
TO LAY HANDS, DEAN.
THAT'S GOD WORKING
THROUGH YOU.
I CAN'T... I CAN'T PAY YOU
TO DO THAT.
I'M ALREADY PAYING
FOR YOUR HOTEL ROOM.
- YEAH, $39.99 A NIGHT.
- WHICH IS A FORTUNE FOR US
DOWN HERE.
DO YOU KNOW HOW MANY PEOPLE
I CAN FEED
WITH THAT KIND OF MONEY?
I KNOW... I KNOW IT'S...
HOW ABOUT...
HOW ABOUT I GIVE YOU A FEW
EXTRA DOLLARS A DAY?
JUST TO HELP OUT
WITH INCIDENTALS.
TOOTHPASTE. GAS.
- HOW MUCH?
- MA... $40... $42 A DAY.
- ON TOP OF THE $39?
- ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
- $42 TOTAL?
- $42.
- WELL, I DRIVE A GUZZLER,
PADRE.
YOU KNOW WHAT IT TAKES
TO FILL THAT TANK?
- OKAY. WELL, HOW ABOUT...
HOW ABOUT...
I DON'T KNOW.
WHAT... WHAT $40... $43?
$43?
LET ME JUST WORK
THIS OUT HERE.
- I MEAN, I'M NOT TRYING TO BE,
YOU KNOW... I JUST...
- I KNOW. I KNOW, DEAN.
IT'S JUST A LOT OF MONEY FOR...
I... I... I COULD PROBABLY...
I COULD PROBABLY SWING $40...
$44? $44? $45 A DAY.
- YOU CAN'T GO $50?
- $50?
$47. $47.50.
- $47.50?
HOW ABOUT $48?
- OKAY, MAKE IT $48.
WE'LL ROUND IT UP TO $48.
- $48.
- WILL THAT...
THAT'S GOING TO BE ENOUGH?
- OKAY.
- GREAT. GREAT.
SO I'LL MAKE A NOTE OF IT.
$47.50 PER DAY.
OKAY, $48 PER DAY.
PER DAY.
- WHAT ADAY. WHAT ADAY.
IT'S UNBELIEVABLE.
SO MANY PEOPLE...
SO MANY PEOPLE WERE HEALED.
RIGHT THERE IN FRONT OF ME.
THINGS HAVE TOTALLY CHANGED
AROUND DOWN THERE.
I AM GETTING A HUNDRED TIMES
MORE DONATIONS NOW
THAN EVER BEFORE.
- HOW DOES DEAN FEEL
ABOUT THAT?
- GOOD. HE'S GOOD.
BUT, YOU KNOW, YOU CAN'T FIX
EVERYBODY ON THE SKID.
AND BESIDES THAT,
YOU'RE WAY OVERDUE ON A RETREAT.
NOW, YOU KNOW THAT
AS WELL AS I DO.
- UH-HMM.
- I WANT YOU TO GET
ON A RETREAT SOON.
YOU'RE A LITTLE TENSED UP,
JOE.
- OKAY. ALL RIGHT.
- PROMISE?
- AS SOON AS THIS IS DONE.
- OKAY. THEN FINISH
YOUR SANDWICH.
- I'M STARVING.
- YOU CAN SAY TO YOURSELF
"WITH ALL I HAVE,
"I'M GOING
TO BLESS SOMEBODY ELSE.
"AND IF I DON'T DRIVE
WHAT I DRIVE
AND LIVE WHERE I LIVE,
IT DON'T MATTER."
[Knocking at door]
"I JUST WANT
TO HELP SOMEBODY ELSE."
CAN I PREACH LIKE I FEEL IT?
[Knocking at door]
- WHAT'S UP?
- ARE YOU ACCEPTING VISITORS?
- [Giggles]
- YOU GONNA INVITE US IN?
- WHAT'S GOING ON?
- OOGIE'S NO LIAR.
I MADE HIM TAKE A LIE DETECTOR
TEST ANYWAY.
- IT'S FUCKING TRUE, MAN.
HE MADE ME TAKE A FUCKING
LIE DETECTOR TEST.
- I KNOW THIS GUY.
HE DOES IT ON THE SIDE.
I'M NOT A BELIEVER, D.
I'M NOT EVEN SURE THAT I CARE.
BUT I'VE GOT TO KNOW.
ARE YOU FUCKING WITH US?
- I SHOULD NOT HAVE DONE IT,
OKAY?
I SHOULD NOT
HAVE DONE THAT.
- NO. YOU SHOULDN'T
HAVE DONE IT, BUT YOU DID.
YOU WANT TO SHOW US.
AND I WANT YOU TO SHOW ME.
LOOK.
NOTHING UP MY SLEEVE.
RIGHT.
- THE STAIN, NO. DON'T.
IT DOESN'T WORK LIKE THAT,
MAN.
I'M SERIOUS. COME ON.
DON'T DO IT.
IT DOESN'T WORK LIKE THAT, MAN.
- THAT'S GOING TO HURT, BRO.
- I'M SERIOUS.
- OH!
- [Laughs]
- THAT'S FUCKED UP, MAN.
WHAT, YOU'RE GOING TO PUT HIM
THROUGH THIS SHIT AGAIN?
- OW! FUCK!
- FOR FUCK'S SAKE, MAN.
- OW!
- I KNOW. I KNOW.
- BURN YOUR OWN FUCKING ARM,
YOU FUCKING PSYCHOPATH.
- I KNOW.
THAT'S REALLY FUCKED.
- [Laughs]
- STOP FUCKING LAUGHING, MAN.
YOU SAID YOU WERE GONNA
BURN YOURSELF, MAN.
- COME HERE.
- LET ME SEE THAT.
- GIVE IT TO ME.
GIVE IT TO ME.
- RIGHT.
- FUCK.
- DO IT, MAN.
- AH.
- I WANT TO SEE THIS.
I NEED TO SEE THIS.
SHUT UP, OOGIE.
- THAT REALLY BURNS.
- THAT IS SUCH
SOME FUCKED UP MOJO.
- FUCK, MAN!
- COME HERE. LET ME LOOK.
- NO, MAN. NO. NO.
- OH, MY GOD.
- NO WAY, BRO.
NO FUCKING WAY, DUDE.
WHAT? NO, MAN.
NO WAY. NO WAY. UH-UH.
NO, MAN. I'M NOT
IN YOUR FUCKING BAND, NO.
NO... UH... NO. NO.
- HE'LL GET OVER IT.
- HE'S SO SENSITIVE.
- LOOK, D, I WAS DOWN
WITH YOUR SHIT
THE MINUTE I HEARD IT.
I THINK THAT'S KNOW.
- TOTALLY.
- YOU GOT SERIOUS
FUCKING ATTITUDE DYSFUNCTION.
[Closes door]
BUT THIS SHIT, MAN...
THIS IS EPIC. THIS...
WE COULD DO THIS TOGETHER, MAN.
THE ONLY WAY FORWARD
IS TO BE REAL...
IS TO DO SOMETHING ICONIC.
IT'S NOT CREATED
BY CHOREOGRAPHERS
OR SOME LAME LONDON DESIGNER'S
BALL SACK.
- THAT'S WHY YOU CAME?
- WE COULD HAVE FUN
WITH THIS, D.
- NO.
- TITILLATE THE MASSES.
- I DON'T TITILLATE.
I'M A TURNTABLIST.
YOU WANT ME IN YOUR BAND,
IT'S 'CAUSE I'M A FUCKING
TURNTABLIST.
- WE WANT YOU IN THE BAND, DEAN,
BECAUSE OF YOUR MUSIC.
WE WANT A LITTLE OF THIS,
A LITTLE OF THAT,
A LITTLE OF THIS.
- NO, I'M NOT GOING TO BE
SOME SIDESHOW FREAK.
- WE WANT YOU IN THE BAND.
- DEAN, COME ON, MAN.
YOU ARE AN ARTIST.
- DEAN.
- WE WANT YOU IN THE BAND.
[Knocking on wall]
DO YOU HEAR THAT, D?
THAT IS OPPORTUNITY
KNOCKING.
YOUR LIFE IS IN YOUR HANDS.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING
TO DO, BROTHER?
All: AND LEAD US
NOT INTO TEMPTATION,
BUT DELIVER US FROM EVIL.
FOR THINE IS THE KINGDOM,
AND THE POWER,
AND THE GLORY,
FOR EVER AND EVER. AMEN.
- MOVE THE TENTS HERE SO I CAN
DEAL WITH INFIRM PEOPLE.
WHAT ABOUT THE BIBLES?
WHAT DID WE DO WITH THE BIBLES?
GET THE BIBLES. KYLE?
KYLE? WHO? WHO?
- FATHER CHARLES?
FATHER CHARLES?
- THIS IS YOUR LUCKY DAY.
HE'S COMING.
HE'S GOING TO BE HERE.
YOU'RE GONNA GET...
YOU'RE GONNA GET
YOUR OLD TICKER HEALED TODAY.
TODAY'S THE DAY.
TODAY IS THE DAY.
MAKE SURE THE PEOPLE
ARE OFF THE STREETS, OKAY?
WE GOT TO GET THESE PEOPLE...
WE DON'T HAVE PERMITS.
WE HAVE NOTHING.
- I HEARD YOUR SERVICE
ABOUT YOUR FRIEND.
PLEASE, I WILL DOUBLE...
I WILL DOUBLE THE BUILDING FUND
FOR YOUR CHARITY.
YOU UNDERSTAND?
DOUBLE FOR MY DAUGHTER.
HE MUST SEE HER. ALONE.
I DON'T WANT THIS.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND?
PLEASE.
I WILL DOUBLE THE FUND.
I HAVE TO SEE HIM.
- I'LL DO MY BEST.
- PLEASE. PLEASE.
- I WILL.
YOU HAVE MY WORD.
MEET... MEET ME HERE.
MEET ME IN ONE MOMENT.
CAN YOU MAKE SURE THAT SHE'S
COMFORTABLE SOMEWHERE?
PUT HER... PUT HER IN THE TENT
FOR A MOMENT, OKAY?
HE'S HERE?
- OH, MY GOD.
[Applause]
- IT'S A BLESSING.
IT'S A MIRACLE.
- ONE MORE HEAL.
- IT'S NOT HAPPENING.
NO.
IT'S NOT HAPPENING.
I'M SORRY.
IT DOESN'T ALWAYS HAPPEN.
DOESN'T ALWAYS WORK.
- DOESN'T ALWAYS WORK.
IT DOESN'T...
DOESN'T ALWAYS WORK,
EVERYBODY.
IT'S... IT DOESN'T
ALWAYS WORK.
THAT'S THE LORD
WORKING THERE.
PRAISE THE LORD, OKAY?
NEXT. UNBELIEVABLE.
- ALL RIGHT,
YOU DON'T HAVE TO FALL.
THEY'RE ALL FALLING NOW.
- [Speaking native language]
- WHAT?
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
- [Speaking native language]
- SHE WANTS YOU
TO TOUCH THE CLOTH.
IF YOU TOUCH THE CLOTH,
SHE COULD TAKE IT BACK
TO HEAL HER HUSBAND.
- [Speaking native language]
- THEY DID IT IN THE BIBLE.
- THIS IS INSANE, MAN.
I GOT TO GET OUT HERE.
I'M NOT DOING ANYTHING.
- DON'T YOU SEE
WHAT YOU'RE DOING?
- YOU'RE DOING GREAT.
- I'M FEELING ANYTHING.
- DON'T YOU SEE?
- ALL RIGHT. ALL RIGHT.
- THE HOLY SPIRIT IS FLOWING
THROUGH THIS HELLHOLE, DEAN.
CAN'T YOU ALL FEEL IT?
- [Speaking native language]
- OKAY, HERE YOU GO.
HERE YOU GO. OKAY.
- [Speaking native language]
- THANK YOU. THANK YOU.
IT'S OKAY, DEAN.
THIS IS WONDERFUL.
IT'S WONDERFUL
WHAT'S HAPPENING.
OKAY, WHO'S NEXT? OKAY.
LET'S START OVER HERE
WITH THE LINE.
COME TO THE BACK
OF THE LINE HERE.
- I NEED A BREAK.
WE'LL COME BACK.
- THERE'S SO MANY PEOPLE.
- I NEED A BREAK.
- OKAY. OKAY.
LET'S LET HIM HAVE A BREAK.
LET'S... LET'S...
JUST... JUST MAKE SOME WAY.
MAKE SOME WAY, FOLKS.
MAKE SOME WAY.
- HEAL ME, BROTHER.
- GET OFF ME.
- HOLD... HOLD ON, EVERYBODY.
HOLD ON. MAKE SOME WAY.
- EXCUSE ME. EXCUSE ME.
- JUST GIVE HIM SOME AIR, OKAY?
HE NEEDS A BREAK.
- THIS IS GETTING, LIKE,
PAINFUL, MAN.
I'M SERIOUS.
I DON'T UNDERSTAND, ALL RIGHT?
HOW MUCH MONEY
HAVE YOU TAKEN IN?
YOU CAN RAISE MY WAGE.
- DEAN.
WE'RE GONNA RENEGOTIATE.
I COULD BE DOING THIS
ON STAGE, MAN.
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
- I TOLD YOU I CAN'T PAY YOU
TO DO THIS. WHAT?
- CHANNEL TWO IS HERE.
- NO. NO.
THERE'S NOTHING
HAPPENING HERE.
THERE'S NOTHING TO REPORT.
- WHY CAN'T I TALK
TO THE REPORTERS?
I'M THE ONE
THEY WANT TO SEE.
- WE ARE NOT TALKING
TO REPORTERS.
WE'RE GOING
TO ADVERTISE YOU NOW?
LOOK AT THIS.
IT'S ALREADY OUT OF CONTROL.
YO, YOU'RE THE ONE WHO TURNED IT
INTO M.A.S.H.
I NEVER SAID I'D DO THIS!
- OKAY, HOLD ON.
JUST STAY BACK EVERYONE.
- MOVE. MOVE.
NO, NO, NO, NO, NO. NO!
NO, FUCKING WAY!
NO! MOVE! NO!
MOVE!
NO. MOVE.
- DEAN.
- TOUCH ME.
- HE JUST NEEDS A BREAK,
EVERYBODY.
LET ME JUST TALK TO HIM
FOR A MOMENT.
DEAN, DEAN, YOU GET BACK HERE
RIGHT NOW.
- I AM NOT TOUCHING
THAT GUY!
- ONE MORE, DEAN.
- NO FUCKING WAY!
- ONE MORE.
- IF I AIN'T GETTING UP,
HE AIN'T GETTING UP!
- IT'S NOT RENE FAUBACHER,
DEAN.
IT'S NOT RENE FAUBACHER.
- YOU SAID DO THIS
AND I GET HEALED.
- OKAY, THAT'S IT.
THAT'S ENOUGH.
ALL RIGHT? NO MORE.
LISTEN TO ME, DEAN.
LISTEN TO ME.
THERE IS A MAJOR
CONTRIBUTOR HERE
WHO IS OFFERING TO MAKE
A HUGE DONATION TO THIS SHELTER
TO HELP PEOPLE...
REALLY HELP PEOPLE...
IF YOU LAY HANDS
ON HIS DAUGHTER.
PLEASE. PLEASE.
- WHERE IS HE?
- HE'S... HOLD ON.
HOLD ON ONE SECOND.
ZAHEEDI?
IS MR. ZAHEEDI HERE?
CAN YOU BRING MR. ZAHEEDI?
THIS IS MR. ZAHEEDI.
DEAN O'DWYER.
- WHAT IS IT? WHAT'S WRONG?
- MY DAUGHTER, MY CHILD.
SHE HAS CEREBRAL PALSY.
- MM-HMM.
- FROM BIRTH.
SHE'S BEEN SUFFERING.
L-I CAN'T SAVE
MY OWN CHILD.
IF THERE IS ANYTHING
THAT YOU CAN DO...
- HOW MUCH?
- NO. NO. NO.
- WHAT'S THE...
WHAT'S THE OFFER?
- NO, DEAN.
THAT'S REALLY BETWEEN HIM
AND THE CHURCH.
- I OFFERED $250,000.
IF... IF... IF SHE'S HEALED.
IF SHE'S HEALED.
- FOR THE SHELTER.
- TWO HUNDRED
AND FIFTY GRAND?
PAY ME.
- I'M SORRY. WAIT. WHAT?
- GIVE ME THE 250 GRAND
IF YOU WANT ME TO DO IT.
- I'M SORRY.
- NO, NO, NO.
YOU DON'T NEED HIM.
YOU NEED ME.
- CAN I TALK TO YOU
FOR A MINUTE?
- YOU GOT YOUR CHECKBOOK
ON YOU?
- DEAN?
- NO.
CAN I SPEAK TO YOU
FOR A MINUTE?
- I'M OUT OF HERE.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- I JUST WANNA HELP MY CHILD.
- HOW CAN YOU DO THIS?
- YOU WANT YOUR DAUGHTER HEALED,
FOLLOW ME. FOLLOW ME.
LISTEN UP EVERYBODY.
[Chanting "Dean"]
- ALL RIGHT, YOU WANT IT?
YOU WANT IT?
COME TO THE FUCKIN' SHOW.
COME TO THE SHOW.
[Chanting "Dean"]
[Rock music]
- ♪ AND THE DAYS
HAVE FINALLY COME ♪
♪ WHERE THE PRETTY LADIES
LAY IN SEIZURE ♪
♪ A FILE OF RATS ♪
♪ HAVE PAID FOR CROWS ♪
♪ SO COME ON,
TOUCH THIS HAND ♪
♪ AND DON'T YOU EVER
LET IT GO ♪
♪ DON'T YOU EVER LET IT GO ♪
♪ ♪
♪ WHEN THE ANIMALS
STOP PELTING ♪
♪ IN ABANDONED SUBMISSION ♪
♪ AND THE RAVENOUS COME CLEAN
WHEN THEY FALL IN REMISSION ♪
♪ WHEN THEY FINALLY GIVE IN
AND THEY FEAST ON THIS CROW ♪
♪ WILL YOU... WILL YOU GENUFLECT
IN A SPINDLE OF FEATHERS? ♪
♪ DON'T YOU EVER LET IT GO ♪
♪ DON'T YOU EVER
LET IT GO ♪
♪ I SAID TOUCH THIS HAND
AND DON'T YOU EVER LET IT GO ♪
♪ YEAH, YEAH, COME ON UP HERE
AND TOUCH THIS HAND ♪
♪ TOUCH THIS HAND
AND DON'T YOU ♪
♪ DON'T YOU EVER LET IT GO ♪
♪ I SAID TOUCH THIS HAND
AND DON'T YOU ♪
♪ DON'T YOU EVER LET IT ♪
♪ DON'T YOU EVER LET IT GO,
GRIP IT TIGHTER ♪
♪ GRIP IT TIGHTER,
YEAH, YEAH ♪
♪ GRIP IT TIGHTER ♪
- OH!
♪ AND GENUINELY,
I WAS APPRECIATIVE OF THE FACT ♪
♪ THAT THEY CAME UP
ONE BY ONE ♪
♪ AND MAYBE YOU SHOULD TAKE
THEIR LEAD ♪
♪ MAYBE... MAYBE YOU SHOULD ♪
♪ MAYBE YOU SHOULD COME UP ♪
♪ MAYBE YOU SHOULD ♪
♪ MAYBE YOU SHOULD COME UP
ON SIDE, COME UP ♪
♪ HOLD IT... HOLD IT BACK ♪
♪ SO HELLO TO HIM, HON ♪
♪ MAYBE YOU CAN'T ARCH
YOUR EYEBROW ♪
♪ BUT LOOK HIM IN THE EYE ♪
♪ BUT I'M GONNA TOUCH
THEIR HAND ♪
♪ TOUCH THEIR HAND
AND COME UP ONE BY ONE ♪
♪ WATCH YOUR STEP NOW ♪
♪ I KNOW IT'S A LITTLE SLIPPERY
DOWN THERE ♪
♪ SO COME UP HERE
AND TOUCH THEIR HAND ♪
♪ EVERYBODY HOLDING HANDS ♪
♪ EVERYBODY,
NOW YOU COME UP ♪
♪ ONE BY ONE NOW, COME ON,
NOW DON'T TRIP ♪
♪ WATCH YOUR STEP NOW,
WATCH OUT NOW ♪
♪ IT'S A LITTLE SLIPPERY DOWN
THERE SO COME ON ♪
♪ COME UP HERE ONE BY ONE ♪
♪ I WANT YOU TO COME UP HERE
ONE BY ONE ♪
♪ AND NOW I'M CALLING YOU,
MY CHILDREN, THAT'S RIGHT ♪
♪ I WANT YOU, EVERYONE,
COME UP HERE ♪
♪ DON'T YOU EVER LET IT GO ♪
♪ COME ON UP HERE,
COME UP HERE ♪
♪ DON'T YOU EVER LET IT GO ♪
♪ COME UP HERE ♪
♪ DON'T YOU EVER, EVER,
EVER LET IT GO ♪
♪ DON'T YOU EVER,
NEVER LET IT GO ♪
♪ NEVER LET IT GO ♪
THAT WAS FUCKIN' ROCK STAR!
STAIN, MAN...
- YOU'RE A FUCKIN'
ROCK STAR BRO.
- I AM THE FUCKING LORD
THY WANT OF COME.
- OH!
- THAT'S FUCKIN' RIGHT.
I FUCKIN' CHRISTEN THEE
DOUBLE D DELICIOUS.
NINA, NINA,
IT FUCKIN' WORKS.
I TOLD YOU IT WOULD WORK,
YOUR DOUBTER, AND IT WORKS!
- I SMELL IT.
DO YOU UNDERSTAND
WHAT HAPPENED TONIGHT?
YOU ALL GAVE BIRTH TONIGHT.
AND NOW WE HAVE A CHILD.
- DUDE, WE HAVE A CHILD.
WE... WE BROUGHT A NEW LIFE
INTO THE STALE FUCKIN' WORLD
OF ROCK.
- YOU WERE ALL BRILLIANT.
STAIN,
IT WAS YOUR NIGHT, BABY.
- TOO FUCKIN' RIGHT, IT WAS.
- YOU DID IT.
YOU TOOK YOUR PLACE.
- TOO FUCKIN' RIGHT, I DID.
- CHUCK, A POWER MAN.
BRASH.
OOGIE, I COULD TASTE YOU.
ARIEL, YOU HAD WINGS
ON YOUR BACK.
I COULD SEE YOUR WINGS.
AND YOU...
YOU SEXY MOTHERFUCKER.
- THAT IS RIGHT.
I CALLED HIM FORTH.
I PLUCKED HIM HENCE.
- STAIN, MY LOVE,
YOU HAVE TO WRITE A SONG.
A SONG
THAT WILL SUPPORT OUR D
AS HE ROLLS DOWNSTAGE.
BECAUSE WHEN WE TOUR,
WHICH WE WILL,
OUR BABY'S GONNA BE NAMED...
"HEALAPALOOZA."
- HEALAPALOOZA, EH?
- HEALA-FUCKIN'.
OUR BABY.
OUR FUCKIN' BABY.
I AM BRINGING ABOUT
THE DIPHTHONGS EXPERIENCE
TO THE PEOPLE.
LET'S GET SOMETHING STRAIGHT,
NINA, LOVE, ALL RIGHT?
I WANTED DEAN IN THE BAND
FROM THE BEGINNING
BECAUSE OF HIS SCRATCHING.
THIS MAN IS AN ARTIST.
NOT SOME SIDESHOW FREAK.
HE'S NOT GONNA SELL HIMSELF OUT
TO A LITTLE MAGIC HANDS TRICK.
THE BAND IS THE MUSIC.
WE WILL OVERRIDE THE SHOW
INTO SOME DISPLAY
AND BE RESPECTED.
BUT, D, DUDE, YOU MAY END UP
A PATHETIC JOKE.
ARE YOU COOL WITH THAT,
MAN?
- FUCK IT.
LONG AS I'M GETTING PAID.
- DO Y'ALL HEAR THAT?
ARE WE CLEAR, NINA?
- YEAH.
- GOOD.
- I'VE GOT PHONE CALLS
TO MAKE.
- YOU THINK I'M A SELL-OUT
SIDESHOW FREAK?
- WHAT DO YOU CARE?
AS LONG AS YOU'RE GETTING PAID,
RIGHT?
- OH, FUCK IT, ARIEL.
WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
GO BACK TO LIVING
IN MY FUCKIN' CAR?
- THAT'S GOOD.
THAT'S GOOD.
YOU'RE OWED. YOU'RE OWED.
YOU'RE OWED, RIGHT?
YEAH, EVERYBODY OWES YOU.
- YOU'RE SO FULL OF SHIT!
I'M ABOUT TO PUT
YOUR CRAP ASS BAND
ON THE FUCKING MAP!
I'M GONNA GIVE EVERYTHING
YOU WANTED!
WHAT'S ALL THIS PURITY
COMING FROM YOU?
- YEAH, MYBAND! MYBAND!
MY FUCKIN' BAND,
YOU MOTHERFUCKER!
YOU FUCKIN' PIECE OF SHIT!
YOU HAVE GOD'S GIFT!
DO YOU EVEN CARE
ABOUT THOSE PEOPLE, DEAN?
DO YOU EVEN CARE WHAT HAPPENS
TO THEM?
WHO THE FUCK ARE YOU?
I KNOW MY PLACE IN THE WORLD.
WHAT THE FUCK ARE YOU?
PIECE OF SHIT.
- I'M SO GLAD YOU DECIDED
TO LEGALLY JOIN THE FOLD.
- I CAN NEVER FIRE YOU EVER.
DEAN, LOOK, THERE WERE 17 SICK
OR INFIRM PEOPLE
IN THE AUDIENCE
THE OTHER NIGHT.
TWELVE OF THEM SAID
THEY WERE HEALED.
NOW IF THAT'S AN INDICATOR,
THEN YOU'RE MISSING 28%
OF THE TIME,
WHICH IS A MARKETING
NIGHTMARE.
AND THAT MEANS
THAT I HAVE TO DEAL WITH IT,
WHICH YOU SHOULDN'T HAVE
TO KNOW ABOUT.
BUT I'M THE ONE WHO'S TAKING
THE RISK.
I NEED SECURITY.
YOU'LL SEE.
IT'S A PRETTY STANDARD CONTRACT.
SEVEN-YEAR NEGOTIATION CLAUSE
ON MY END,
PLUS A FEW EXTRAAMENITIES,
BECAUSE I'M SO HANDS-ON.
AND WE CAN TALK
ABOUT SWEETENING YOUR END.
HOW DO YOU FEEL
ABOUT A SIGNING BONUS, HMM?
GOOD. YOU READY?
- IT'S CALLED "HEALAPALOOZA."
DOWNTOWN,
THERE'S A BUZZ GOING ON.
A NEW BAND CLAIMS TO HEAL PEOPLE
DURING THEIR SHOW,
ACTUALLY PHYSICALLY
HEAL THEM.
FANS ARE SWEARING UP AND DOWN
THEY'VE RECEIVED HEALINGS
FROM THE TOUCH OF THE BAND'S DJ,
DELICIOUS DEAN.
- THE CONTROVERSIAL
HEALAPALOOZA TOUR
IS GAINING MOMENTUM
OF TRUE BIBLICAL PROPORTIONS.
ARTY PUNK-ROCK BAND,
BURNT THE DIPHTHONGS,
DENIED ACCUSATIONS
THAT THEIR ONSTAGE MIRACLES
ARE NOTHING MORE
THAN A PUBLICITY STUNT.
IN FACT,
THEY CLAIMED THE SHOW
IS REALLY
ALL ABOUT THE MUSIC.
HE TOUCHED ME
IN DIFFERENT PLACES,
BUT THEN HE FOCUSED
HIS ENERGY
WHERE I TOLD HIM
I HAD MY TUMOR.
I WOULDN'T SLEEP WITH HIM
THE WHOLE TIME.
- THE BIZARRE SCRATCH ROCK
HEALING PUNK SHOW
HAS SPARKED A RIOT
AND EVEN A RELIGIOUS PROTEST.
BUT IT'S ALSO BEING CALLED
"NEW CHURCH"
BY ITS SURPRISINGLY DIVERSE
FANS.
- DELICIOUS DEAN IS GOD.
- DESPITE THE GROWING NUMBER
OF ATTACKS FROM DOCTORS
AND THE AMA DENOUNCING
THE SHOW AS A HOAX
AND PROJECTED TICKET SALES
REACHING INTO THE MILLIONS,
IT'S NOT HARD TO SEE
WHAT FANS ARE LOOKING FOR.
A NEED TO BELIEVE.
A NEED FOR SOMETHING MORE
FROM THEIR MUSIC.
SOMETHING IN THE FORM
OF A TOUCH
FROM THE BAND'S MESSIANIC
SUPERSTAR.
[Cheers and applause]
- SHE JUST PULLED ME
RIGHT OUT OF THE CROWD,
SAID "JUST PUT
THE NECK BRACE ON."
UGH. SHIT. EASIEST $100
I'VE EVER MADE.
SHE MADE YOU
SAY SOMETHING TOO?
- MM-HMM.
- WHAT'S UP?
- NOTHING.
[Crowds cheering]
- WHERE THE FUCK HAVE YOU BEEN?
AND WHERE THE FUCK IS ARIEL?
WE FUCKING REHEARSED THIS.
YOU ENTER BEFORE ME.
LISTEN TO ME, FUCK HEAD.
I MADE YOU, YOU CUNT.
I PUT ON THAT FUCKING STAGE.
YOU JUST GET OUT THERE
AND TURN YOUR FUCKING TRICKS.
[Crowds clapping
rhythmically]
[Cheers and applause]
- COME ON, YEAH!
LET'S FUCKIN' HAVE IT.
♪ THEY SAID I WAS TORN ♪
♪ WHERE THE WATER
HAD STOPPED ♪
♪ IN THE CRADLE OF FUSES
WAITING FOR A FINAL SOLUTION ♪
♪ ELIMINATE THE ACCENT ♪
♪ DO I DIMINISH THE THREAT? ♪
♪ SOMETIMES I NEED YOU ♪
♪ JUST TO STAY
A LITTLE UPSET ♪
♪ DO YOU OR DON'T YOU ♪
♪ WANT TO BELIEVE? ♪
♪ IT'S NOT WHAT YOU WANT ♪
♪ IT'S WHAT YOU NEED ♪
♪ ♪
- WE'VE GOT A LITTLE MAGIC TRICK
FOR YOU TONIGHT.
A LITTLE CRACKER JACK ACTION
AND SIDESHOW ACTION.
THAT'S RIGHT, DEAN.
THEY'RE CALLING FOR YOU, MAN.
GIVE US A LITTLE BIT
OF YOUR FUCKING
MAGIC HANDS TRICK.
THAT'S RIGHT. FUCKING HEALING.
- SHUT THE FUCK UP.
- COME ON. HA HA HA.
THIS IS ALL ABOUT
THE HEALING.
COME ON THERE, MAN.
WHAT ARE YOU GOING TO DO?
GIVE THEM A HEALING, DEAN.
- SHUT THE FUCK UP.
- HEAL THEM.
HEAL THEM, DEAN.
- FUCK YOU, THE STAIN!
- USE YOUR MAGIC HANDS.
- FUCK YOU.
- GIVE THEM
YOUR MAGIC HANDS, MAN.
- COME HERE! RIGHT HERE!
- GIVE THEM YOUR MAGIC HANDS.
- LET HIM GO. COME ON.
- COME ON.
- LET HIM GO.
WHERE IS IT?
- COME ON.
- HEY, ARIEL. ARIEL.
DUDE, STOP.
STOP, STOP, STOP, STOP.
DUDE, STAIN.
DUDE, DUDE, DUDE,
GET THE FUCKING PARAMEDICS.
SHE'S OD'ING.
SHE'S FUCKING OD'ING MAN.
FUCK. DUDE. ARIEL.
FUCK, MAN.
- HERE.
RIGHT HERE
IS WHERE HOMICIDE BEGINS.
IN THESE PRECIOUS MOMENTS,
WHEN LIFE-SAVING DECISIONS
COULD HAVE BEEN MADE,
WHAT WAS ON THE MIND
OF THE ROCK STAR,
DEAN O'DWYER?
WHAT WAS HE THINKING
AS ARIEL LEE
LAY AT HIS FEET,
TAKING HER LAST BREATH?
WAS HE THINKING,
"WOW, WHAT A SHOW.
HOW ARE WE GOING
TO RECREATE THIS?"
BECAUSE I CAN TELL YOU THIS,
HE WAS NOT THINKING
ABOUT ARIEL LEE
BECAUSE IF HE WAS,
HELP WOULD HAVE GOTTEN
TO ARIEL LEE
AND SHE MIGHT BE HERE TODAY.
AND THAT, BY DEFINITION,
IS MANSLAUGHTER.
- THIS IS A TRAGEDY
TO SAY THE LEAST.
WE ARE ALL ABSOLUTELY
DEVASTATED.
DELICIOUS D'S ACTIONS
WERE SELFLESS AND HEROIC
AND WE ASK FOR YOUR SENSITIVITY
AT THIS TIME.
ARIEL LEE DID NOT DIE
BECAUSE OF NEGLECT.
ARIEL LEE DIED
BECAUSE SHE OD'D.
- THEY WERE...
PEOPLE SAID THEY WERE HEALED.
- DEAN, MAN, YOU SHOULD HAVE LET
THE PARAMEDICS AT HER
BECAUSE YOU COULDN'T HEAL HER
OR WHATEVER HAPPENED.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED.
MAYBE YOU DID TOO MUCH.
- JUST REMEMBER,
YOU ARE UNDER OATH,
SO JUST...
JUST TELL US THE TRUTH.
- I SAY
HE IS THE LIVING EMBODIMENT
OF ALL THAT IS GOOD
IN HUMANKIND.
- WE ALL WANT TO KNOW
THERE'S GOOD IN PEOPLE.
AND I'M NO EXCEPTION
TO THAT.
THE CROWD WAS CHANTING
FOR HER TO BE HEALED.
THEY THOUGHT IT WAS ALL PART
OF THE SHOW.
I GRABBED THE MIKE
TO CALL FOR HELP,
BUT POWER HAD BEEN CUT
TO THE STAGE
AND THE PARAMEDICS
HAD BEEN BLOCKED.
I DIDN'T GET TO SAY
WHAT NEEDED
TO BE SAID THAT NIGHT.
SO I'M GOING TO SAY
WHAT NEEDS TO BE SAID NOW.
AND IT'S SOMETHING
I'VE BEEN ASKED NOT TO SAY
BY DEAN O'DWYER
AND NINA HOGUE.
OBJECTION.
- YOUR HONOR, SIDEBAR PLEASE.
- AND THAT IS THAT HE'S A FAKE.
- SIDEBAR.
- HE'S A PHONY.
- OBJECTION!
- HE'S A FRAUD.
- ORDER!
- THIS CHARLATAN SON OF A BITCH!
- BAILIFF, REMOVE HIM.
- HE CAN'T HEAL SHIT!
IT WAS ALL A FUCKING ACT!
YOU WERE ALL DUPED!
- ORDER!
- HE NEVER COULD HEAL!
YOU BOUGHT A FUCKING LIE!
WELL, WELCOME
TO THE FUCKING SHOW!
- AS THE RELIGIOUS
AUTHORITY FIGURE
WHO FIRST ENCOURAGED
THIS GIFT,
YOU CAN TESTIFY TO DEAN'S
HEALING TECHNIQUE
AND HIS INTENSE
CONCENTRATION,
WHICH WOULD HAVE BEEN
INTERRUPTED BY THE PARAMEDICS.
IN THAT REGARD, THAT MAKES YOU
OUR EXPERT WITNESS.
- AND CHARACTER WITNESS
DESCRIBING DEAN'S EARLY HEALINGS
ON SKID ROW.
HOW SELFLESS HE WAS.
HOW PURE HIS MOTIVES WERE.
MR. O'DWYER HAS GRACIOUSLY
AGREED FREE OF CHARGE
AND FOR A DESIGNATED PERIOD
OF TIME
TO COME DOWN TO SKID ROW
AND LAY HANDS
ON WHOMEVER YOU WISH.
- IN EXCHANGE
FOR MY TESTIMONY?
- YES.
- NO. NO.
- CAN I SPEAK TO DEAN ALONE
FOR A MOMENT PLEASE?
- YOU DO WHAT YOU THINK
IS RIGHT, FATHER.
BY THE WAY,
JUST SO YOU KNOW,
I'M A MARYMOUNT GIRL
AND I-I HAD THE CALLING
TO BE A NUN,
BUT I LOST MY WAY.
MAYBE SOMETIME WE'D GET TOGETHER
AND TALK ABOUT THAT.
- CERTAINLY.
- THANK YOU, FATHER.
- SOMETHING ELSE, HUH?
- I, UM,
I BROUGHT YOU SOMETHING.
SHOW YOU SOME OF THE GOOD WORK
YOU DID.
THAT MEXICAN WOMAN
WHOSE HANDKERCHIEF YOU TOUCHED,
YOU HEALED HER HUSBAND,
DEAN.
YOU HEALED HIM.
THE CLOTH,
IT CARRIED THE POWER.
I SHOULD HAVE TOUCHED
HEALAPALOOZA HANKIES, HUH?
SOLD THEM
AT THE T-SHIRT BOOTHS.
THEY'RE TRYING TO SAY
THAT I KILLED SOMEBODY.
THAT'S BULLSHIT.
THEY'RE JUST COMING AFTER ME
BECAUSE OF WHO I AM.
ARIEL WAS A JUNKIE.
SHE TOOK A BUNCH OF PILLS.
AND I DID EVERYTHING I COULD.
I THOUGHT IT WAS WORKING.
- IT'S HARD TO KNOW,
ISN'T IT?
- OKAY. ALL RIGHT.
LET'S MAKE IT RIGHT.
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOU?
WHAT CAN I DO FOR YOUR SHELTER?
HOW ABOUT THIS?
[Tears out check]
THE LORD WORKS
IN MYSTERIOUS WAYS.
THINK OF ALL THOSE PEOPLE
YOU'LL BE ABLE TO HELP.
- I-I OWE YOU AN APOLOGY,
DEAN.
I MISUSED YOU.
- IT'S OKAY. I FORGIVE YOU.
YOU WANT TO HELP ME?
DO THIS.
DO THIS FOR ME.
- I'LL TESTIFY FOR YOU.
I'LL TESTIFY
TO THE HEALINGS THAT I SAW,
BUT THAT'S IT.
I WON'T BE
YOUR CHARACTER WITNESS
BECAUSE I-I WON'T GET
ON THAT STAND
AND SAY THAT...
THAT YOUR MOTIVES WERE PURE.
- WHAT WERE MY MOTIVES?
- I DON'T KNOW, DEAN.
ALL I KNOW IS THAT YOU ABANDONED
THOSE PEOPLE
WHEN THEY NEEDED YOU.
YOU ABANDONED THEM
TO BECOME A ROCK STAR.
- THAT'S WHAT YOU'RE
GONNA SAY?
- I'M NOT GONNA LIE.
- OH! NO!
NO, YOU CAN'T LIE.
YOU'RE TOO GOOD FOR THAT.
YOU CAN'T CON PEOPLE.
YOU DON'T USE PEOPLE
FOR YOUR OWN GLORY.
YOU DON'T DO ANYTHING
LIKE THAT.
WHAT IF ON CROSS-EXAMINATION,
MY LAWYER ASKS
WHAT WERE YOUR MOTIVES?
TWO HUNDRED AND FIFTY GRAND.
- THAT HAS NO BEARING
ON ANY OF THIS, DEAN.
- OH, YES, IT DOES.
- NO, IT DOESN'T.
- OH, YES IT DOES.
- NO.
- YOU ARE THE INSPIRATION
FOR THIS WHOLE THING.
PAYING FOR MIRACLES.
WHERE DID I GET THAT FROM?
SO LET'S JUST SAY, FATHER,
THAT YOU'RE GONNA GET
ON THE STAND
AND YOU'RE GONNA TELL
THE FUCKING TRUTH.
- THE TRUTH IS IS THAT YOU
PROSTITUTED YOUR GIFT.
- NO, THE TRUTH
ISYOUPROSTITUTEDME.
- THAT IS NOT TRUE.
- PROVE IT ISN'T.
CAN YOU PUT YOUR HAND
ON YOUR BIBLE
AND SAY YOU DIDN'T DO THAT?
- DEAN, I HAVE ADMITTED
MY WRONGS, ALL RIGHT?
BUT I AM NOT
GONNA REPEAT THEM.
- [Scoffs] THAT'S GREAT.
THAT'S REALLY FUCKING HOLY
OF YOU, FATHER.
[Tears check]
I'LL SEE YOU IN HELL.
- FUCK YOU. FUCK YOU.
FUCK YOU!
FUCK YOU, DEAN O'DWYER.
YOU THINK, WHAT... YOU THINK...
YOU THINK...
YOU THINK THIS MEANS ANYTHING
TO ME?
YOU THINK YOU CAN BUY ME?
YOU THINK I'M FOR SALE?
I'M NOT LIKE YOU.
YOU'RE NOT GONNA RUIN
MY LIFE TWICE.
- YOU SOLD ME OUT!
FOR YOUR OWN FUCKING SAINTHOOD!
- I TRIED...
- AND YOU'RE DOING IT AGAIN
RIGHT NOW!
- I TRIED TO SAVE YOU.
I TRIED TO GIVE THAT GIFT
TO THE PEOPLE...
- YOU DIDN'T DO ANYTHING
FOR ME!
- WHO IT BELONGS TO.
YOUR GOD-GIVEN GIFT,
MY FRIEND.
- YOU'RE A BULLSHIT PRIEST!
YOU ARE A FUCKING FRAUD!
- HOW DARE YOU.
YOU ARE THE MOST SELFISH...
- I AM OUT THERE EVERY NIGHT
FOR THE MASSES!
YOU'VE GOT A GOD-GIVEN GIFT.
AND WHAT DID YOU DO?
YOU USED IT FOR YOURSELF!
- IS EVERYTHING ALL RIGHT?
- FORGIVE ME.
EXCUSE ME.
- AND THAT IS WHY YOU ARE HERE
TODAY, FATHER.
NOW, FATHER,
I CAN'T HELP BUT NOTICE
THAT YOU ARE IN YOUR CIVILIAN
CLOTHES TODAY.
- YES.
- MM-HMM.
NOW, IS THERE ANY PARTICULAR
REASON FOR THAT?
- I'M ON A LEAVE OF ABSENCE.
- OKAY.
BUT YOU ARE AN ORDAINED
CATHOLIC PRIEST
THESE PAST 16 YEARS.
- THAT'S CORRECT.
- OKAY.
NOW, THE CATHOLIC CHURCH
BELIEVES
IN HANDS-ON HEALING.
IT IS DESCRIBED AS A GENUINE
GIFT OF THE HOLY SPIRIT.
SO NOW, FATHER ROSSELLI,
CAN YOU, AS A MODERN PRIEST,
COME BEFORE US TODAY
AND SAY
THAT HE HAS THE POWER
TO HEAL?
BECAUSE IT ALL COMES DOWN
TO THIS:
IF DEAN O'DWYER CANNOT HEAL,
THEN THIS WAS A SHOW
AND A TALENTED YOUNG WOMAN
IS DEAD BECAUSE OF IT.
SO, FATHER,
IN YOUR EXPERT OPINION,
DOES DEAN O'DWYER
HAVE THE ABILITY TO HEAL?
- GOD.
GOD IS THE ONLY HEALER.
- OBJECTION, YOUR HONOR.
SPECULATION.
- HOW CAN THAT BE SPECULATION
WHEN I'VE ASKED
YOUR OWN WITNESS TO...
- WE ARE NOT SPEAKING
OF A METAPHORICAL HEALING HERE,
YOUR HONOR.
- ORDER. ORDER!
- HE IS MAKING A MOCKERY
OF THIS COURT.
- I'LL HAVE ORDER IN MY COURT,
COUNSEL.
- PERMISSION TO REDIRECT
THE HONOR...
- COUNSEL!
- THE WITNESS.
YOUR HONOR, PLEASE.
[Jail door shuts]
- WHAT'S UP?
- HOW ARE YOU?
I WANNA HELP YOU GET OUT OF HERE
AS QUICKLY AS POSSIBLE.
PROGRAMS
FOR DISABLED PRISONERS
ARE LIMITED OBVIOUSLY,
BUT THERE ARE SOME,
AND I THINK
YOU SHOULD GET INVOLVED.
- I GOT NOTHING BUT TIME
IN HERE.
AND I WANTED
TO BE SO PISSED AT YOU.
BUT ALL I CAN THINK IS HOW BAD
I FUCKED EVERYTHING UP.
NAH, JUST TAKE YOUR TIME,
DEAN.
KEEP YOUR NOSE CLEAN.
- WHAT THE HELL
WAS I THINKING?
YOU KNOW,
WHAT WAS I DOING?
WHAT WAS I SUPPOSED TO DO?
YOU WERE SUPPOSED
TO LET THE PARAMEDICS COME UP
AND DO THEIR JOB.
THERE'S... THERE'S ONE PROGRAM
IN PARTICULAR
THAT I... THAT I THINK
YOU'D BE GOOD FOR.
IT'S A... IT'S A WORK DETAIL.
YOU GET TO LEAVE PRISON GROUNDS
TO DO COMMUNITY SERVICE.
- YOU KNOW IF I GOT OUT OF HERE,
I DON'T KNOW WHERE I'D START.
I GOT NOTHING.
I CAN'T HELP MYSELF.
I CAN'T...
I NEED HELP.
I NEED...
- SORRY, DEAN.
I TRIED
TO CONTROL YOUR GIFT.
I WANTED TO BE MORE
THAN WHAT I WAS
AND I WANTED YOU
TO BE SOMEONE YOU WEREN'T.
I'M NOT A PRIEST ANYMORE,
DEAN.
- LOOK...
I KNOW YOU THOUGHT
YOU WERE HELPING ME,
BUT NOTHING HELPS.
MAYBE YOU CAN'T HELP
EVERYBODY.
- NO, NO. YOU KNOW WHAT?
YOU KNOW WHEN YOU HELPED ME?
- WHEN YOU FED ME.
YOU FED ME.
YOU FED PEOPLE.
A CRIPPLED WORK PROGRAM?
WHAT ARE WE GOING TO DO?
- HANG ON A SECOND.
- GET BACK OVER HERE!
- LET'S GO, GENTLEMEN!
- LET'S MOVE IT!
MOVE IT! COME ON!
- THAT'S REALLY NICE.
- HUH?
THE SHIRTS.
THEY PRETTY NICE.
I LIKE THE GREEN.
I LIKE THE RED.
I CAN GET BOTH OF THEM
AND WEAR THEM FOR CHRISTMAS.
- YEAH.
- WE NEED THE SWEATERS.
WHERE ARE THE SWEATERS?
- EXCUSE ME.
- YES. HELLO.
- HI. DO YOU CARRY SWEATERS?
- YES.
- SOMETHING FOR HIM
WITH LIKE A TIGHT WEAVE
AND A BRIGHT COLOR.
THAT'D BE GREAT.
- DO YOU LIKE THESE?
THE STRIPED ONE?
- OH, YEAH, STRIPPED ONE.
YEAH.
I'M SORRY. YOU KNOW WHAT?
THE... THE... LET'S TRY THE PURPLE.
- PURPLE?
- YEAH.
- OKAY. THIS ONE?
- NICE.
THAT LOOKS NICE.
- OH, WOW.
THINK IT'S SO COOL.
BEAUTIFUL.
DO YOU LIKE IT?
- IT'S SO NICE.
- IT LOOKS GOOD?
- SO NICE.
- HO! HO!
- WHAT?
- OH, MY.
- ARE YOU OKAY?
- SWEET JESUS.
- NO, NO.
- HONEY.
HONEY, THIS IS IT.
- NO.
- THIS IS IT. YES.
OH, SWEET JESUS. YES.
- YES.
- YES?
- YES! OH, MY.
- HALLELUJAH.
- OH, MY GOSH.
- HALLELUJAH!
HALLELUJAH!
- COME ON.
LET'S GO OVER HERE.
[Chair lift lowering]
- GOT IT BACK THERE?
- OKAY, BRING HIM UP.
[Chair lift raising]
- PUT IT BACK
THEN LOCK IT DOWN.
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA.
WHO ARE YOU?
- O'DWYER.
- 1264 PARIS C.
- WHAT DID YOU SAY
YOUR NAME WAS AGAIN?
- JUST LET ME
ON THE BUS, MAN.
- WHOA, WHOA, WHOA!
HOLD ON.
I DON'T KNOW WHAT TO TELL YOU,
BUT YOU'RE NOT ON THE LIST.
LOOK, I DON'T KNOW
HOW YOU GOT THE OUTFIT
OR WHAT KIND OF PRANK
YOU'RE TRYING TO PULL HERE,
BUT THIS
IS A STATE FACILITY BUS
AND THESE ARE CONVICTED
PRISONERS.
SO WHAT YOU'RE DOING HERE
IS NOT A JOKE,
IT'S ACTUALLY A CRIME.
- ALL RIGHT, THAT'S FUNNY.
- WHAT, HAVE YOU LOST
YOUR MIND?
I HAVE SEEN EVERYTHING NOW.
YOU BETTER RUN ALONG.
LOOK AT THIS.
IT'S SO BAD OUT HERE,
WE GOT A GUY BEGGING
TO COME WITH YOU.
- ALL RIGHT.
I'LL TELL YOU WHAT,
YOU GO DO LIKE A STICK UP
OR SOMETHING LIKE THAT
AND WE'LL FIND A SEAT
FOR YOU, OKAY?
- OKAY.
- LET'S GO.
[Shuts door]
[Engine starts]
- [Chuckles wondrously]
HA! [laughs]
HEY, MAN.
HEY, MAN, HOW MUCH
IS THIS?
- YOU CAN HAVE THAT SHIT
FOR FREE, MAN.
- ARE YOU SURE?
HEY, THANKS, MAN.
REALLY.
SEE YOU.
[Loads cassette]
[Bee Gees' I Started A Joke]
♪ ♪
♪ I STARTED A JOKE ♪
♪ WHICH STARTED
THE WHOLE WORLD CRYING ♪
♪ BUT I DIDN'T SEE ♪
♪ THAT THE JOKE WAS ON ME ♪
♪ OH, NO ♪
♪ I STARTED TO CRY ♪
♪ WHICH STARTED
THE WHOLE WORLD LAUGHING ♪
♪ OH, IF I'D ONLY SEEN ♪
♪ THAT THE JOKE WAS ON ME ♪
♪ I LOOKED AT THE SKIES ♪
♪ RUNNING MY HANDS ♪
♪ OVER MY EYES ♪
♪ AND I FELL OUT OF BED ♪
♪ HURTING MY HEAD ♪
♪ FROM THINGS THAT I SAID ♪
♪ 'TIL I FINALLY DIED ♪
♪ WHICH STARTED
THE WHOLE WORLD LIVING ♪
♪ OH, IF I'D ONLY SEEN ♪
♪ THAT THE JOKE WAS ON ME ♪
♪ I LOOKED AT THE SKIES ♪
♪ RUNNING MY HANDS ♪
♪ OVER MY EYES ♪
♪ AND I FELL OUT OF BED ♪
♪ HURTING MY HEAD ♪
♪ FROM THINGS THAT I SAID ♪
♪ 'TIL I FINALLY DIED ♪
♪ WHICH STARTED
THE WHOLE WORLD LIVING ♪
♪ OH, IF I'D ONLY SEEN ♪
♪ OH, YEAH, THAT THE JOKE
WAS ON ME ♪
♪ OH, NO ♪
♪ THAT THE JOKE ♪
♪ WAS ON ME ♪
♪ OH ♪