Kyoto, 1865
After moving
to the Nishi Honganji Temple,
the Shinsen militia was recruiting.
In the beginning,
they drew most of their troops
from several regional dojos.
But this yielded dubious results.
Now men were handpicked.
Next!
Who's the boy?
Him?
A merchant's son.
Not a spy?
He was recommended by his master,
Senzaemon Hamano
of the Shingyoto school.
He was his assistant
after graduating.
His background?
His family
are the Echigoya's,
textile dealers.
He's their third son.
Name?
Sozaburo Kano.
Soji has his hands full.
I have his family tree.
The Echiyoga family
is from minokano.
In the service of lnaba
during the civil wars.
Utanosuke Kano, notably,
was an outstanding warrior.
His descendants went to Echigo,
then Kyoto.
In spite of their change in class,
they kept the samurai name, Kano.
Look.
He's the last one.
His name is Hyozo Tashiro.
He's from the Kurume clan,
and the Hokushin Itto school.
He was recommended
by our man Shinohara.
Like Kano,
he fought his way through
all the early rounds undefeated.
Okita won, but he had
a run for his money.
Only those two are worthy.
What do you think, Hijikata?
Kano and Tashiro.
Fine.
And you, Ito?
I agree.
I don't think
we should be judging them
on swordsmanship only.
But since that's your policy...
The Shinsen militia
must put down uprisings.
Kano, Tashiro.
To the Commander's quarters.
There are no subordinates here.
Come closer.
Kano, how old are you?
Eighteen.
Eighteen?
Don't lie to us.
What's the difference?
Well... he doesn't often
react like that.
He doesn't have that leaning.
You assisted your master?
I'm a novice.
No, you surprised me out there.
You've got talent.
You're Tashiro?
These are troubled times.
I expect you to maintain order,
at any price.
I'd like to take Kano as my aide.
Fine. That's the custom.
And Tashiro?
Let's assign him to the First Unit,
under Okita.
They'll break him in.
Fine.
Tomorrow, Seijuro Muto
of the Fourth Unit
is to be executed.
One of them could take care of it.
Toshi,
why not Kano?
CODE OF CONDUCT
NEVER BETRAY THE SAMURAI WAYS
NEVER DESERT THE SHINSEN MILITIA
NEVER BORROW MONEY
NEVER BE INVOLVED IN CIVIL SUITS
NEVER FIGHT FOR PERSONAL MOTIVES
ANYONE VIOLATlNG THIS CODE
MUST DISEMBOWEL HIMSELF
Kano.
Yes?
Tomorrow morning at 8,
a man from the Fourth Unit,
Seijiro Muto,
guilty of borrowing money
and passing it off
as a loan to the militia,
will be beheaded.
You will perform the execution.
- Understood?
- Yes.
If you don't know how,
ask someone.
Shinohara will be observing.
I'm honored.
That's how they test newcomers.
Why you? Why not me?
Their code of conduct is fine.
But their code of battle...
When a captain falls in battle,
his men must follow him
to the grave.
Absurd. One life isn't enough.
They put that in after
the Imperial Palace battle.
Why did you join?
Kano...
Can't you sleep?
Without sleep,
you can't perform tomorrow.
Have you ever killed a man?
Have you ever made love?
He must've killed before.
Forgive me.
He's got courage.
No, something other than courage.
Who's there?
Tashiro. I enlisted yesterday.
I was jealous of Kano,
who enlisted along with me.
I came to watch.
Executions are not open
to the public.
I submit to your punishment.
Five days detention.
FIVE DAYS LATER
It's over. Back to your unit.
Should I apologize to someone?
To the Commander?
lt'll keep until tomorrow.
Tashiro.
Sozaburo.
In my cell, I kept calling you.
For help?
No. I called my true love's name.
Are you cross?
Why are you smiling?
Did you miss me?
I'll come to you tonight.
- Don't you like me?
- Excuse me.
Cry out?
Or shall I do it for you?
I don't want to die
without making love to you.
move away.
In that case,
I'll take you to Gion.
- Gion?
- If you prefer women.
I don't prefer women.
Haven't you ever known a woman?
NO SECRETS ON HEAVEN AND EARTH
EVERYONE KNOWS IT
WITHIN A MONTH
RUMORS
KANO'S NEVER HAD A WOMAN
SOME MEN ARE COURTING HIM
NOTABLY,
FIFTH UNIT LEADER,
CAPTAIN TAKEDA
AND TASHIRO,
WHO JOINED WITH HIM.
HE AVOlDS TASHlRO
STlLL, HE LIKES BEING
THE OBJECT OF DESIRE
AT 18, HE KEEPS HIS LONG LOCKS
A PROVOCATlON FOR ME
SENSITIVE TO HIS CHARMS
ONE MUST FEEL SORRY FOR TASHIRO
Soji.
What are you doing?
Playing with kids?
Yes, they're catching fish for me.
What for?
To eat.
Soji, how have you been feeling?
I was only sick
after the battle at Ikedaya.
About Tashiro and Kano...
Oh, that?
Not my cup of tea.
One man loving another...
During the entry contest,
who was stronger?
Sozaburo Kano.
Hijikata.
What did he think, coming here?
Nothing, really.
He liked the smell.
The smell? The smell of blood?
During Ikedaya,
you were on watch.
You asked if the Choshu were crazy
for wanting to set Kyoto ablaze
and take the emperor captive,
to have him with them.
Did I really say that?
They're not crazy,
they're quite lucid.
Where high-spirited men gather,
arguing back and forth,
for days on end,
about illusions,
they come to believe
that the shogun
can be easily overthrown.
The militia is no less utopian.
It emanates a certain energy.
Young men are drawn to it.
It takes a madman
to know a madman.
And you're the leader of the pack.
Is Kano here?
Have a go?
I'm grateful for your guidance.
Enough.
Tashiro.
Tashiro, don't hold back.
Very sloppy.
Is that the work
of an expert swordsman?
match over.
Soji's right.
Tashiro is really
one notch below Kano.
You two fight.
That's strange.
Those two... are lovers.
No doubt about it.
BEFORE LONG,
RUMOR:
KANO AND TASHIRO ARE LOVERS
They're coming.
The militia is coming.
That's Commander Kondo!
The militia!
Thank you for protecting us.
Thank you.
Sozaburo,
tell Toshi...
Tell the Lieut. Commander
to come see me.
I must go to Choshu.
Or rather Hiroshima.
For battle?
No, to testify against them.
What good will that do?
We have orders to invade them.
All clans must band together,
for financial reasons.
What are you doing there?
Testifying.
Tell me the truth.
Toshi,
I leave you in charge.
Who's leaving with you?
Ito, Takeda and Ogata, I think.
Ito?
Since his arrival,
he's spread unrest in the ranks.
In your absence,
I shall keep a tidy house.
I've heard
that Soza...
that Kano has taken a lover.
I wouldn't know.
What does it matter?
Are you worried?
No, but this sort of thing
has happened before.
There was a lot of trouble
last year, during Ikedaya.
Hearts inflamed by passion.
It must not happen again.
Beautiful.
Are you with the militia?
Yes.
From what school?
Pure Land Buddhist.
No, in swordsmanship?
Swordsmanship?
I'm from the same school
as Okita and Hijikata,
but I'm not very good.
Actually, I'm terrible.
You're not a monk then?
You're with the militia?
That's right.
Please forgive me.
The look on Kondo's face!
Who was with him?
I'm not at liberty to say.
Captain Okita.
Don't call me captain.
How old was he?
About 60, I guess.
Are you joking?
Even Kondo is only about 30.
No one here is that old.
He said he was
from the same school as you.
I've got it. Genzaburo Inoue.
You should kill yourself
for such an affront.
He is our senior member,
but he's 43 or 44.
- You said 60.
- I'm sorry.
Forget it.
It's his own fault - he looks old.
What is his post?
He's captain of the Sixth Unit.
Commander Kondo,
Lieut. Commander Hijikata, old Inoue
and myself are from the same dojo.
and the Tennenrishin school.
Some say we have
a lock on the militia.
That's not our intention.
I understand.
It's true of course.
He's no good with a sword.
When you spar with him, go easy.
THIS ADVICE PROVED DIFFICULT
TO PUT INTO PRACTICE
You're the one
who asked my religion, right?
I inquired about
your swordsmanship training.
I didn't know who you were.
Forgive me.
If you say so.
Little Religion!
I don't have time
to coach you now,
but we'll get to it soon.
Thank you.
THEN, ONE DAY...
Little Religion!
Ready?
I'll show you.
Call that a samurai?
- Who are you?
- After them!
What happened?
I don't know.
Two of them. Dubious characters.
They've got a nerve coming in here.
What did they say about us?
Call that a samurai?
Unforgivable.
Was that all?
Also, that's the best
the Shinsen can do?
Our guards heard them,
but thought they were invited.
They let them go.
Long ago, people dared enter.
But now that we're
to maintain order,
no one should ever get inside!
I'm sorry.
Punish me as you see fit.
It's my fault.
Captain Inoue had no part in it.
Kano, don't lose your head.
Calm down and await orders.
Get back to work, all right?
One had a scar on his chin,
and a crest of three stars.
The other was about 25.
He had a strange crest -
crossed battle-axes.
Crossed battle-axes?
I haven't seen that often.
We're not certain,
but they may have Higo accents.
If they are from Higo,
they may want to avenge
their comrades from Ikedaya.
Find out.
Right away.
Whom did they see
sparring in the dojo
at that moment?
Captain Inoue and Sozaburo Kano.
They must've been mocking Kano,
for his inexperience.
Inoue.
Toshi.
Let your assistants
do that for you.
I do.
But I do it much better.
You must set an example
for your men.
You think so?
I wanted to speak to you,
about today's incident.
I'm sorry.
No, it's not your fault at all.
But we must find out
what they were after.
I'm assigning you and Kano
to settle this matter
as quickly as possible.
I'll handle it.
By the way,
why were you sparring with Kano?
Little Religion...
I told Sozaburo
to spar with Capt. Inoue.
You did?
Let me serve you a drink.
You're my guest.
Leave us. We have to talk.
Why were you holding back
against Inoue?
I wasn't.
Stop. I was watching you.
I've seen all your bouts.
He can't possibly compete with you.
You weren't yourself.
Of course I was.
Is it because of his position?
I'm not criticizing.
We all bow and scrape to them.
That's how they retain authority.
We're only equal in theory.
Anyone who doesn't agree,
who wants out,
is killed.
That's what happened
to Yamanami last spring.
He was one of the first
of the militia's commanders.
On the eve of his death,
a woman cried
at the window of his cell.
A woman with small feet.
But I'm digressing.
Do you know
why I was watching you so closely,
how I knew you were holding back?
Kano...
Do you know?
Why?
I'd give my life
to wake to the nightingale's song,
after holding you in my arms
all night long.
Sozaburo, make my dream come true.
Someone might come in.
I'm not to be disturbed.
Don't tell Tashiro.
So it's true...
You're lovers.
Yamazaki, any news?
Are you still here, Capt. Inoue?
Nothing on the crests?
It takes time.
I told him it was no use
staying here,
but he won't leave.
We've placed men all around town,
and we've let it be known
we're looking for them.
Capt. Inoue, you can't possibly
roam around like Sozaburo.
Are the crests his only clues
in the search for those two men?
No. They had Higo accents.
Twice a day,
he goes to the Ogawa Inn,
on the east side, near the bridge.
Please, sir.
may I?
Just in time. Follow them.
But where are you going?
Fine. I'll report to you in Gion.
Waiting for someone?
Yes. A company aide.
- See anything?
- Nothing.
This way.
What do we do?
Go to the inn.
Now?
Shouldn't we wait
until we know more?
Never wait to pull a weed.
Where I come from,
the racoons dry in moonlight.
They take good care of their hides.
I see.
What do foxes do?
There's a den at the Hino temple.
The foxes who live there
are very smart.
Whenever they buy sake,
they pay for it.
- With leaves?
- No.
With real tarnished coins.
They're very clever.
Lieut. Commander Hijikata's family
had a gardener.
His name was Genzaburo.
He grew potatoes.
The townspeople called him
Potato Gen.
The kids from the next village
would swim across the river.
They'd steal potatoes from him.
When he died,
they attended his funeral,
covered by huge leaves.
People thought they were
river sprites.
I didn't.
Why not?
Because among them,
among all these kids,
I recognized Hijikata.
It's me, Soji.
Why are you dressed like that?
It's not my choice.
It's your fault.
my fault?
Capt. Inoue.
You pushed him to desperate lengths.
Desperate?
Yes. He's left with Sozaburo Kano,
for the Ogawa Inn,
where the Higo men gather.
He's ready to die.
He hasn't got a chance.
You know him.
He wanted to make up for his error.
That idiot!
Send him reinforcements,
immediately.
I'll be along with other troops.
When fighting indoors,
choke up on your sword.
What do you mean?
Both hands up near the guard.
Never aim for the head.
You might hit a ceiling
or bust a doorframe.
- You've done that?
- Like this.
Near the guard?
Wait for the right moment to attack.
If you miss,
back up and come again.
Of course,
it's easier said than done.
Open up!
Official search.
I figured as much.
They followed us.
How many of them are there?
It's hard to see,
but I think there's two of them.
Two?
Go get the others.
I'll be right there.
They wouldn't attack with only two.
must be at least ten.
What's the matter?
One moment, I'm coming.
Shinsen militia.
What's your hurry?
move over!
I'll show you the way.
Come along.
This way.
See, there's no one here.
- Still warm.
- Warm?
You must be mistaken.
Let's try the back door.
The back is on the river.
- madam.
- What?
We're going down.
must we?
Get me five lanterns and a ladder.
Why so many lanterns?
There you are.
I see now.
Not bad, eh?
Take a look down there.
See anyone?
No one.
I'll go down then.
my leg's broken.
Who's there?
In the name of the Shinsen militia.
Kano!
Hang on.
You're coming around. Sozaburo.
Finally. I was worried.
I feel better now. You all right?
On December 22nd of that year,
Commander Kondo
returned from Hiroshima.
A banquet in his honor
was held that evening.
Delicious.
Kyoto sake is the best there is.
The Choshu clan is feigning loyalty
to the emperor and the shogunate.
But they've got a secret agenda.
They're arming for combat.
The shogunate is too weak.
They should attack now,
smash them, occupy the land,
before it's too late.
But, Commander Kondo,
last year,
Choshu served
the isolationist cause,
combatting foreign invaders.
Every patriot praised their valor.
Do you support isolationism?
Yes, of course.
Then you should be
more tolerant with them.
Foreign cannons being,
unfortunately, more effective,
in coastal areas,
Choshu batteries were wiped out.
And you believe
the shogunate should eliminate
an already suffering clan?
A samurai does not behave that way.
A samurai does not behave...
You mean that it's beneath him?
Exactly.
A true samurai is distinguished
by his sense of forbearance.
Or, to put it more simply,
by his mercy.
I know what you meant.
I'm sure you do.
As our journey progressed
you understood me better and better.
Hijikata...
I assure you, Hijikata...
What?
Well that... Commander Kondo...
the more he saw of the deplorable
situation in Choshu,
the more his opinion changed.
I believe our commander
is the only one to restore order
to the reigning confusion in Kyoto.
Is that so?
What's your opinion?
About this issue.
It doesn't interest me at all.
Excuse me.
I'm glad to see you again.
I thought you were laid up.
I was ashamed to face you,
but I changed my mind.
You've been apprised?
In a general way.
I apologize for the deaths
and injuries caused
by my blundering.
Your injury?
I fell from a ladder.
How is Kano?
No damage to that pretty face?
Why were you coaching him?
Do you, too, have that leaning?
Not at all. But...
But?
I'm beginning to see
how certain men can be unsettled.
Sozaburo...
I wouldn't do that.
Sozaburo, are you that much
in love with Tashiro?
Why?
Even with me?
you remain somehow attached to him.
Leave him.
I can't.
He keeps clutching?
Not really.
Then why?
I'll kill...
you...
No, not you.
Lieut. Commander, it's Yamazaki.
Is it that urgent?
One of our men has been killed.
I'm coming.
Right here.
The one who found him
recognized the uniform.
The magistrate notified us.
Who was it?
I'll go see.
He's from the Tenth Unit,
his name is Tojiro Yuzawa.
Fatal wounds to the back and belly.
Yuzawa?
I've met him somewhere.
- The murderer?
- No one knows.
We thought it was
a Satsuma or a Tosa,
but there was an eyewitness.
They're easy to spot.
And it wasn't one of them.
Then who was it?
One of our own, I fear.
Did Yuzawa have enemies
within our ranks?
I'll find out.
I wonder if he leaned that way.
Leaned which way?
A lover of men.
It's common practice
where he comes from.
But from the way he looked...
Nothing yet. Sorry.
It's getting late.
We'd better get back.
I'll bring you some tea.
About Sozaburo Kano...
Sozaburo?
Is he the lover of one of our men?
Who do you mean?
Besides Inoue of course.
Hijikata, take care of this.
Take care of it?
Kill him?
Do you have no pity?
Kondo,
you're not in love with him,
are you?
Toshi, you misunderstood me.
I didn't say kill him.
I'm merely suggesting
you talk to Yamazaki,
have him acquaint Sozaburo
with women.
That's all I'm saying.
Why does he still have those locks?
lsn't he old enough to cut them?
I'll do my best.
Why are we both
so indulgent with Sozaburo?
So I take him
to the geisha district?
That's right.
But with what money?
The militia can hardly afford it.
His family must provide for him.
This is for you.
Kano.
Sgt. Yamazaki.
How are you healing?
Can you wear the mask now?
- Yes.
- Glad to hear it.
How about a drink, to celebrate?
Want to go to Shimabara tonight?
No, l...
Don't be so stiff.
It's time you had a little fun.
It would do you good.
I'm busy tonight.
With who?
Tomorrow then?
No, l...
Kano!
He turned down all my offers.
All of them?
- Very amusing.
- Why?
Sozaburo
must be afraid
you're making advances.
I have no such intention.
Be patient.
I have no doubt
he and Tashiro are lovers.
And many have courted him.
Yuzawa, Takeda...
Gunpei Yomo.
And there are others.
It must disgust him to think
you're doing the same thing.
Win his confidence with kindness.
He's still just a baby.
That's not much of an excuse.
Kano!
I'm busy.
ALL THINGS COME TO THOSE WHO WAIT
ABOUT ONE MONTH LATER...
- About Yuzawa...
- Yes.
What?
He courted me.
So he too had that leaning.
And did you consent?
Never. Of course not.
Who are you involved with?
Nobody.
You're involved with no one?
I have no doubt, personally,
that Sozaburo and Tashiro
are lovers.
It's you I love.
You're mistaken about my intentions.
I'm not making any proposition
of the kind.
I'm only trying
to show you the pleasures
of being with a woman.
And that is Hijikata's wish as well.
For you future.
Do I have a future?
Don't you think about that?
Why does a rich man's son
join the militia?
To have the right to kill.
Kano, come to Shimabara tonight.
Captain Takeda, too.
He courted you as well?
Don't confuse me with them.
Lieut. Commander Hijikata,
I give up.
Consider it a militia assignment.
But...
You're a lucky man!
Sgt. Yamazaki...
Would you take me to Shimabara?
I'm free tonight.
Really?
I must make one condition.
I want it to be clear.
We're going for the girls.
I know.
Then we're on for tonight.
Yes.
No, don't...
What?
Nothing.
A girl who's gentle and kind.
I have what you need.
No, I want the best.
The best?
He's a son of the Echigoya's,
of Oshikoji.
- Him?
- You know him?
By reputation. In that case,
I will reserve
Shimabara's best girl for him.
I see. For a son of Echigoya,
but not for a samurai.
Not at all.
It's both together.
And for you, Yamazaki?
No one.
I'm coming only as chaperon.
I'll drink sake,
in a separate room.
As you like.
Did you strap break?
Put your foot here.
Can you walk?
more or less.
Should I call a palanquin?
No, don't...
Palanquin!
To Shimabara, Wachigaiya's.
I'll be back.
Thank you.
Come in.
There you are.
We've been expecting you.
This way.
There you are.
Where is Omatsu?
I'll bring you tea.
No tea. Sake.
Listen.
I've already told the boss.
Sozaburo Kano, who's with Nishiki,
has already been with men,
but never a woman.
This is his first time.
A tough case.
I trust you'll see to it
that all goes well.
I'm not staying.
I understand your request.
Has Sozaburo Kano
returned this morning?
About two hours ago.
Sgt. Yamazaki,
it was a catastrophe.
He made such a terrible ruckus.
He kept asking for you,
and he wouldn't speak to the girls.
We finally calmed him down,
put him to bed.
But he left without doing anything.
I'm sorry.
I think he really wanted
to sleep with you.
Deplorable.
Why not sleep with him tonight?
You're crazy!
I'm joking.
Come back and see us yourself,
put this behind us.
No, I'm working late today.
You're making a mistake!
I'm with the militia!
I've asked the captains
to find out who's lost his dagger.
It isn't mine.
If it were yours,
I wouldn't be here.
I was informed this morning
that Hyozo Tashiro
isn't carrying a dagger
with his sword.
Hyozo Tashiro?
I see...
You're in a terrible spot.
He must think
you stole Sozaburo from him.
He sees you as his rival.
Jealousy among men
is a horrible thing.
Especially since Tashiro
was his first lover.
You dared steal him away.
I didn't steal anyone!
I know.
Tashiro was a foot soldier,
wasn't he?
Even less.
He was servant to a tenant farmer.
Perhaps he acquired
these practices there.
A samurai can be undone
by the love of men.
He must be Yuzawa's murderer.
One is tempted to take pity on him,
but we can't just let this go.
Let's kill him.
He's touched by a certain madness.
Who knows what problems
he can make for us.
Some would exploit this
to create divisions among us.
Hijikata, this must be kept secret.
But who will kill him?
Sozaburo Kano.
That's a little...
cruel.
Can he manage alone?
Tashiro is his equal.
Yes, he can do it.
I'm not so sure.
He could be killed, in fact.
Go as observers.
You and Okita.
That should be enough.
me?
What a burden.
Me? Kill Tashiro?
I'll do my best.
What can he be feeling?
You'll be alone.
We'll be watching from afar.
But... if it goes wrong,
we won't be able to step in.
We can only watch. Understand?
Kano.
Why do you keep those locks?
No reason.
Cut them off.
Let me keep them a while.
Why?
I made a vow.
Right here is fine.
Why Sozaburo Kano?
Kondo decided.
Why?
I don't know.
Could he be in love with him?
He's not like that.
You know very well.
Still...
Still what?
He doesn't look at him
the way he looks at the others.
Neither do you.
Me and Sozaburo?
Soji, could you be jealous
of Sozaburo?
I was brought up
by you and Commander Kondo.
I'm not jealous.
What about the two of you?
What do you mean?
There's a tacit understanding
no one comes between you.
The spirit of the militia.
Anyone who tries to step in,
or if Kondo makes a friend,
you nip it in the bud.
Soji, shut up!
I've just read a good book.
The doctor told me to rest
so I read
Tale of the Rain and the moon,
including A Vow Between Two men.
The story of a scholar
who takes care
of a samurai who'd fallen
ill while traveling.
After a while, they grow close
and take an oath
of everlasting friendship.
But the samurai
must return to his group.
Se he leaves,
promising he'll return
the following year, September 9th.
Time passes.
Chrysanthemum season comes around.
The morning of the 9th,
the scholar and his mother
prepare flowers, sake and fish.
But the samurai doesn't come.
The scholar's mother
tries to comfort him, in vain.
He comes outside his house.
The moon is behind the mountains.
All is dark.
He's about to go back inside
when he sees a man in the shadows.
The samurai has come.
He shows him inside.
The samurai seems strangely
sad and quiet.
He won't eat or drink.
Suddenly he says
he no longer belongs to this world.
On the journey home,
he'd been taken prisoner.
He couldn't escape.
So he killed himself
and kept his promise.
His spirit was carried on the wind.
Lovely.
Yes. And the moral is,
avoid frivolous people
and surround yourself
with friends you can count on.
I think the two men in the story
have feelings of love.
Otherwise, why kill yourself
in order to keep your word?
Even the title suggests it.
No...
What is it?
Nothing.
Soji,
could it be you're in love
with Sozaburo?
What?
You know I'm not like that.
Yes, but...
Why do you read that kind of book?
And why
do you think all this up?
I don't understand these people.
I hate them.
I hate Tashiro and Sozaburo.
I can't stand them.
The sound of their voices
gives me a chill.
But I love beautiful stories.
Don't you, Hijikata?
Here they are.
You betrayed me.
You murdered Yuzawa
and ambushed Sgt. Yamazaki.
There is proof.
The rules say you must die.
What proof do you have?
Could we have been mistaken?
Sozaburo, you killed Yuzawa.
You stole my dagger
to implicate me.
Forgive me.
What did he say?
I couldn't hear.
Tashiro was completely thrown.
What did Sozaburo tell him?
Even if we heard,
we wouldn't have understood.
Perhaps they were words
shared by lovers.
I forgot something.
I must go back.
Soji...
You didn't love Sozaburo
but he loved you.
Destroy him.
Okita!
Sozaburo was too beautiful.
men took advantage of him.
He was possessed by evil.