Shh-hh.
# I've got rhythm #
# I've got music #
# I've got my man #
# Who could ask
for anything more? #
# I've got daisies #
# In green pastures #
# I've got my man #
# Who could ask
for anything more? ##
## Got rhythm, got rhythm,
whoo, got rhythm #
- # I've got rhythm #
- # Got attention, whoo, ow! #
# Got rhythm, got rhythm #
# One, two, three #
# Who could dance with us
or who could stand with us? #
# Look at us tonight,
we lookin' fabulous #
# Freshed it up to def
and we just movin' #
# Out on the town putting on
our dance shoes-in' #
# One foot in
and one foot out #
# Sexy salsa,
what's that all about? #
# Well, listen, after I take it back
to old schoolin' #
# Like Lena Horne,
all them cats was coolin' #
- # I've got rhythm #
- # Whoo! #
# I've got-got-got rhythm #
# M.C. will lead
but, yo, I can't take it #
# When that young thing
like to shake it, shake it, shake it #
# When she move forward
then she back that thing up #
# And I got a beat on point
and live on something #
- # Come on... #
- # 'Cause my hood is greasy #
# It ain't easy #
# But for tonight
gonna be a'ight #
# Whoo-whoo #
# One, two, three ##
Ladies and gentlemen.
## I've got my man #
# Who could ask
for anything more? #
# Who could ask for #
# Anything #
# Mo-o-o-o-ore? #
Jay, get out here.
Your father needs to use the bathroom.
Aw!
Help clean him up
for me, Jay.
You good, Pop?
You got it, Pop.
Oh Pop!
Come on, man.
Gigi, catch it.
- One mike break.
- Hide my purse
so when somebody tries to steal it,
at least they have to work for it.
This puppy's got
a bark, kids!
# One-two, one-two,
one, two, three... #
Thank you.
Now it is with great pride
that I introduce
the highlight of the evening...
our student exhibition!
Blaine Academy students,
please, take the floor.
Dancers ready?
Don't forget the new turn.
- # Let's go #
- # Talk to 'em, Drag #
# Look here, dawg,
I'm d-r-to-the-izzay #
# I'm born a "G," if I ain't in
the club, I'm on the streets #
# And if I ain't in the Benz,
I'm on my feet #
# And I'm probably
the most slept on on the East #
# But I'm still in the club,
throwin' it up #
# Fightin' break out in the club,
they knowin' it's us #
# Damn, who dat?
Drag and 'em, same nigga #
# Walk through any block
and don't know half of them #
# I like it when the girls grab the boys
and their bodies get loose like this #
# I like it, I like it,
I like it, I like it ##
## That's why
I ask the Lord #
# In heaven above #
# What is this thing
called love? ##
- ## Whoo! #
- # Let's work... #
# Jae Millz... some call me
"The Statue" #
# Worldwide hustler
but I'm from the area #
# Rose gold sit on my neck,
rose gold sit on my wrist... #
Let's go, let's go.
What're you trying
to pull, son?
I ain't pulling nothing, man,
it's a real ticket.
It just got wet, that's all.
Just turn around
and go home, all right?
Hey-hey!
Look, man, I paid for my ticket,
you're gonna let me in.
I am?
Come on, man.
Get off me!
Hey-hey, get off me, man.
- Ah! Get off me.
- Calm down, son.
- What's going on here?
- I got it, Augustine.
- It's under control.
- This fool won't let me in.
Watch your mouth. You're not
going in this dance with your attitude.
For what? The ticket's real. Everybody
else's punkass is going in there.
Everybody else's punkass does not
have your history, Jason Rockwell.
- That ain't even right, man.
- Keep talking.
Give me a reason to kick your butt
out of my school. Give me one.
Whoa!
You!
Whoa, what?!
What's poppin',
playboy?
Whassup?
What, you good?
Yeah, I'm cool.
Yo, what's up, man?
Ain't seen you since
your brother's service.
- Almost a year now, dawg.
- Yeah, almost.
You're not dancing?
- No.
- Miss James punked you again?
Sh... whatever, yo.
Check it... we rolling.
You down?
That ain't yours, man.
Looks like Miss Principal
left you a little present, baby.
She in there
enjoying your party.
You feel me?
Whatcha gonna do?
Gonna get
some justice, right?
Now's your chance, son.
Know what I'm saying?
Take the goddamn iron and leave
this bitch a little message.
I ain't messing with you, man.
You're reckless.
Pussy!
- Oh shit!
- Damn! Bag that shit, brother.
Hit that shit!
- Oh, that's gonna be expensive, boy.
- Just smash that!
- Let's go, dawg!
- Shit.
Is that your car, man?
No.
So what you
running up on me for?
What was he thinking?
- # You wanna see how we flow? #
- # Here we go, here we go #
- # Gimme dough and do a show #
- # Your guy nearly got mad #
- # Here we go, here we go #
- # Timberland and Dirtbag #
- # Here we go, here we go, yo #
# Here we go, yo, here we go,
yo, here we go, here we go #
# They call me dirty dirty
but I shine so clean #
# Push birdy birdies
but I got a new scene #
# Me and Timmy T
droppin' out a limousine #
# While the girls throw their hips,
they zipping their blue jeans #
# We slip in their blue dreams,
and it feels so good #
# I shouldn't have another
but I thank I would #
# My location, conversation,
relation that made me hood #
# The rotation of my records
every second made me good #
# I ain't trying to have relations,
Dirt trying to wood #
# Strong penetration,
it hurts when it's good #
# Should I choose you
or your girl? I choose both #
# Call Timmy and enforce,
my nigga, it's time to go #
- # You want to see how we flow? #
- # Here we go, here we go #
- # Gimme dough and do a show #
- # Your guy nearly got mad #
- # Here we go, here we go. #
What you here for?
A funeral or somethin'?
I don't want it pimped,
I want it fixed.
All right, you've got somewhere to be
and it is not in my hallway.
Get there and get there fast.
Paul Lopez, put a belt
in those pants.
I do not want to have
to see your drawers. Good morning.
Chin, if I see you on that cell phone
one more time, it's mine.
Eddie French, in my office,
you know why.
Augustine, have you made a decision
yet on my calculus lab?
Joe, do you really think I can get
special funding for your six kids
when I have all the rest
of them to worry about?
My six are the ones that have a chance.
They're smarter than...
You know how I feel
about "smarter than."
There's kids out there selling drugs,
doing the calculus in their heads.
Now if you want to open up
that lab to the rest of them,
- maybe we could swing a grant.
- Are you serious?
Yes, I'm serious.
Augustine, we have to honor the kids
that are excelling, not neglect them.
Joe, we operate on limited resources...
morning, Gretchen.
Yo, son, who died?
Apparently,
your manners.
Excuse me, sir,
was that lady the principal?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
Uh-huh.
You mean "You're welcome,"
right?
Uh-huh.
And what's this I hear about you
bailing out on detention today?
I'm not giving up my math club time
to babysit a bunch of delinquents.
Excuse me, those kids need
your attention as well.
But the ones who try
actually deserve it.
Yo, son, what the hell
you do that for?
She wasn't carrying nothin'.
She could've opened the door
her damn self.
It's called courtesy.
Yeah, well, it makes you
look like a punkass.
- You think so?
- Damn straight.
Man, punkass moves like that
won't get you no play around here.
Trust me, I've tried it.
Oh, I've got plenty of play.
You're kidding, right?
Did you see that?
Every single one of them
smiled at me.
Yeah, but you didn't
get no numbers.
I didn't ask
for no numbers.
Whatever.
What about Kline? He hasn't
taken detention in months.
- Out with the flu.
- Cranky-butt Lewis?
- Jury duty.
- Again?
- What are you looking at?
- Mr. Dulaine.
- Friend or foe?
- Too early to say.
But check this out.
He's been doing that
for everyone.
And he stands every time
a woman walks past.
Freak.
It's just my luck.
Have security standing by.
Mr. Dulaine.
Come on in.
Eddie, sit your ass down.
So what can I do for you?
You're not a parent, you're not a sub,
you're certainly not a cop.
How can you tell all this?
If I depended on the students to tell me
what's going on, we'd all be in trouble.
I've got five minutes,
Mr. Dulaine.
Yeah, um...
I ran into one of your
students on, eh, Saturday night...
- How nice for you.
- Yeah...
he was vandalizing
private property.
Did you file
a police report?
No.
I felt I should
come to you.
It's the wrong move.
I try to prevent crime from happening,
but once it does, the police are
who you want to talk to.
So... good day.
That's it?
That's it for me.
Gretchen'll show you out.
Oh oh oh,
hold on, uh...
who should I talk to
about this?
Probably one
of your students, right?
You must have a lot
of angry kids at this school.
Now if your kids were
as important to you as your car...
Excuse me for caring
about my car, Mr. Dulaine.
And do not talk to me about angry kids
like you are some kind of expert.
This is my school. I decide
what is or is not a priority.
And these kids?
Are they your priorities?
Honor roll?
Those kids are dead,
Mr. Dulaine.
Each and every one of them
killed since I have been here.
I keep them right there
to remind me of why I'm tired,
and why I keep
coming to work
and why I have
no time to waste.
I'm sorry. Sorry.
Please excuse me.
- Mr. Dulaine?
- I would like to help.
There are numerous ways
community members
can help the students
of John Drake High School.
There is a tutoring program.
There's Big Brothers.
There's the math center, the language
skills lab, book club, DARE outreach...
Y-yeah, I-I'm sure
these are fine programs,
uh... but I have
my own methods.
All right, uh...
I want to teach
your kids to dance.
Believe me, the one thing
they do know is how to dance.
- Ballroom?
- What did you say?
He said, "ballroom."
Uh, yeah.
Waltz, fox-trot,
all the basics.
It would be great for them.
Okay, where is
the camera?
If you are talking about teaching
my kids the fox-trot,
I must be on television.
All right, um,
your kids, your call.
Thank you.
Good morning.
Mr. Dulaine! Wait.
If you are serious,
I just might have
an opening for you.
You meet me back here
at 3:00 sharp.
3:00?
I'm not a particularly
patient woman, Mr. Dulaine,
either you want
to help out or you don't.
I'll rearrange my schedule.
I see you sneaking out
on me, Joe L.
We have kids in there
for everything
from stealing someone's bag,
to cheating on exams...
Hector, home safe...
to possession,
vandalism, to rearranging
somebody's face.
Basically, if you get...
hat! Hat!
If you can think of a way to cut
a corner and collect a dime,
the kids in detention are all over it
before we have had our morning coffee.
- Detention?
- You said you wanted to help.
Believe me,
these kids could use some.
Everyone else calls them
the school rejects.
They're in here
for the rest of the term.
In case you were wondering
why the scenic tour,
detention's far
from a beauty spot,
but it's the only space
we have available
after some knucklehead
burned up the study hall.
On purpose?
I got five bucks saying
you won't be back tomorrow.
Miss James,
what, you springing us
for good behavior or something?
No, I'm not, Mr. Epps.
Listen up, everybody,
this is Mr. Dulaine.
Mr. Dulaine here is
running your detention
and you will do
whatever Mr. Dulaine says.
That's what you think.
- Yeah, right.
- They're all yours.
Hey, gimme, gimme the ball.
- Let's go, man.
- Wow! Right there.
Yo, follow that queen.
Let's go.
Pay attention,
pay attention.
Okay, a'ight.
My name is
Pierre Dulaine.
But you...
you can call me Pierre.
- Pierre?!
- You don't sound French.
Yeah, uh...
my mother was Spanish,
my father was French.
I understand
six languages.
- I speak five.
- Give me that.
All of them
with a Spanish accent.
Um, so...
you are?
Sir.
That's Jason Rockwell.
Yeah, but you
can call him Rock, Pierre.
What about you,
mademoiselle?
LaRhette,
LaRhette Dudley.
Very nice
to meet you, LaRhette.
So what kind
of teacher are you?
Yeah, what'd you do
they made you run detention?
- I asked to be here.
- Punkass move number two.
I teach...
ballroom dancing.
- What?!
- Ballroom dancing?
And you... are going to learn
ballroom dancing
here in your detention.
Nothing this wild
ever happens in English.
Or biology.
The wildest thing yet
is that I said yes.
You did what?
I'm gonna arrange you
by height.
You... and you.
Yeah, together.
- No freaking way.
- Ooh!
Mr. Epps, was it?
And the lady to your right,
let's have you and you together.
You two together.
Hol-hold on a sec.
Why I can't be with her?
Not at this time, sir.
Yeah, bu-but everybody know
Danjou can't dance.
- Are you a dancer, sir?
- What, tu no sabes? I can shake it.
Then I suggest you shake it
with the partner I assigned.
Look, nobody wanted to host
the detention hall.
- This is a joke.
- If I turn it over to Mr. Dulaine,
we get our detention
halls for free.
Detention is meant
to be a place
where the kids who need to spend
extra time in school do just that...
spend extra time in school.
Not dancing around.
Joe, do you know
any of our students
that are gonna want
to do ballroom dancing?
Absolutely not.
Exactly. I think I just discovered
the cure for cutting class,
and for cheating, and for any
number of miscreant behaviors.
- To the fox-trot!
- You and... yes, you, together.
- Hold up, that's my cousin.
- I can't dance with my cousin.
- Yeah, man.
You know what? Me and Big Girl
can switch. I'll dance with Monster.
Oh no, man...
And you, sir, will be with
this lovely lady over here.
- No, he won't.
- Ooh-ooh.
- More cousins, right?
- Hell no!
- Uh-oh.
- Yo, I can't dance with him, for real.
- Put me with anybody else.
- All right...
- She's trash, that's why.
- You shut the hell up.
Hey hey hey hey.
Yo, roll up!
I don't want
to be here anyway.
- Hey, hold...
- Bye.
We're out of here, son.
All right, we are
finished for today.
Argh... tsk!
Did you see what happened
to my bike?
Nope.
"Nope, nope."
How does this work in
with the lesson schedule?
And the new students
and Caitlin's cotillion?
And Morgan always wants
more time before a competition.
We can rearrange.
It'll be fine.
- That's your plan?
- Mm-hmm.
"It'll be fine"?
Just when this place was
starting to do well, Pierre.
These kids probably don't even
want what you're offering.
Did you ask them?
- Did you?
- Huh-uh.
- Pierre! Pierre, we have an emergency.
- We'll talk about this later.
Ahem, ladies,
what a pleasure.
Hey.
- We've got to do something, Pierre.
- Mother!
She's not getting any better,
in fact she may be getting worse.
Oh, she'll be fine, Mrs. Spencer.
She just needs a little time is all.
Time's running out.
This cotillion is a huge event.
Now Caitlin's father and I
have spent a fortune on the party.
All of our friends are coming and I will
not have her looking like a...
I just... I just want Caitlin
to feel secure all right?
I understand. Please.
Maybe I'm not made to dance.
Caitlin, do you like dancing?
Then you were made
to dance.
Mr. Dulaine, I want
to dance more than anything.
It's just... I know I suck.
No no!
My mom and dad paid
so much for my lessons...
Right there is the problem.
You need to dance for yourself,
not for anybody else.
All right.
Very slow, all right?
# Are you ready?
Ready ready #
# I need everybody to report
to the dance floor right now #
# All my ladies say one, two,
hands in the air #
# Put your right hand up,
put your left hand up #
man, man #
- # It's whatever, whatever #
- # Get it poppin', get it poppin' #
- # Whatever, whatever #
- # Get it poppin' #
# It's whatever,
like a four-alarm blaze #
# And I'm hotter than...
that work at the Days Inn #
# People try to make hits
that make people bop #
# I make hits they play,
then people be shot #
# Whatever, whatever,
whatever, whatever #
# Whatever. #
- I know.
- she's on the other line right now.
- May I ask who's calling?
- Let me call you back.
- Good morning.
I believe you owe me
five bucks.
And I believe
I am seeing things.
A little early for detention.
Thank you.
Yeah, uh...
we need to talk.
This is LaRhette's
twin brother.
He was an honor student,
but we lost him to drugs.
He was a good kid,
just poor as hell.
He got in the way of a crew
led by this fool... who's Rock's brother.
Raymond Rockwell was the most
screwed up evil kid I ever knew.
What started out as a fist-fight
turned into a little gang war
and when it was over,
some kids were hurt, some were dead.
Tybalt slays Mercutio.
This isn't Shakespeare,
Mr. Dulaine, it's public education.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
You know who wrecked
my car, don't you?
Might have been
either black or Hispanic.
Let me know if you remember.
# The way you sip your tea... #
- Shoot me.
- What is this?
- # The memory of all that... #
- Man, what's that noise?
That noise is the work
of the great American songwriters
- Ira and George Gershwin.
- Who?
Some of the many amazing
artists you'll be dancing to.
Yo, man, I need the remix.
All right, everyone, stand up!
Step forward.
# The way you haunt
my dreams #
# No no, they can't take
that away from me... #
All right. Maybe I'll just give you
a chance to absorb Gershwin.
#... meet again
on the bumpy road to love #
# Still, I'll always #
# Always keep
the memory of... #
He likes it.
# The way you hold
your knife... #
Okay, can you
turn it off now?
Excuse me?
I am afraid I can't hear you.
# The way you've
changed my life #
# No no, they can't take that
away from me #
# No, they can't
take that away #
# From me... #
Classic ballroom consists
of these dances...
the tango,
the rumba, fox-trot,
swing, standard waltz,
merengue and, of course,
the Viennese waltz.
These dances were danced
by the fiercest warriors.
Oh, the Viennese waltz?
Sounds fierce.
All right, all right,
how many of you think
this style of dance is weak?
Two votes for me.
Ladies and gentlemen,
you have been misled.
Miss LaRhette,
would you do me the honor?
Nah, I don't think so.
Mademoiselle,
please, come on.
Okay...
in ancient times,
it was believed
that any man
who could kill
with speed and accuracy
should be able to dance
with grace as well.
Ballroom dancing is...
for kings and empresses.
It is the dance of strength,
of romance and love.
- Thank you, it was lovely.
- Uh-huh.
I believe the appropriate answer
to that is, "You're welcome."
Uh-huh.
- All right.
- Look, son,
you're talking about a bunch
of rich white folks, slave-holders.
I mean I've never seen
Martin Luther King...
You're right, you're right,
you're right. Correct.
- You know?
- Some were.
But the tango, the milonga,
and even the rumba
were first danced
in some form by Africans.
- Oh-ho!
- Here we go.
Why is it that every time
you want to fly something by us,
you claim it's got ties
to Africans,
but every time you get scared or mad,
you blame it on African killer bees?
- African Ebola virus.
- Right.
Freaking West Nile fever.
All right, all right,
what if I told you
these dances will
make you look very cool?
I'd say you're full of shit.
- What is this, Mr. Rockwell?
- A doctor's note.
I can't dance,
I got a heart condition.
I see... interesting man,
your doctor.
Not many physicians write
notes on three-holed paper.
- Busted.
- Partners, please.
No? All right.
No, hey, okay, hey hey!
Now, ballroom dancing
is about two bodies
moving as one.
I'm down with that.
Gentlemen, please,
take your partner's hand.
Hold up, how the hell do
I know where his hands have been?
- Here, I'll show you, see?
- Oh, no no!
- Now you know.
- No. No no no.
That is not right.
- Now that's "ball" room.
- You are nasty!
Welcome to
the fox-trot, people.
- Step a little closer.
- # I've got rhythm... #
- All right.
- # I've got music... #
Yo, why we got to use that?
My grandparents don't even
listen to that stuff.
That stuff give us
the perfect fox-trot rhythm.
- # Who could ask for anything more? #
- Good good.
Now, ladies,
start on the right foot,
- going backward.
- # I've got daisies... #
Men on the left,
stepping forward.
- Two slow steps back.
- # I've got my man... #
- # Who could ask for anything more?
- Two quick ones to the side.
It goes like this... slow, slow,
- quick, quick, slow, slow.
- # Old Man Trouble... #
- Quick, quick, slow, slow.
- # I don't mind him... #
- # You won't find him... #
Quick, quick, good.
- # Around my door... #
- Come on, guys, quick, quick.
- Stop!
- # I've got starlight... #
Sir, sir, sorry, just let me
just show you, eh?
Everybody! Please.
Why I always got
to demonstrate it?
- Because you can do it.
- # I've got my man... #
- # Who could ask for anything more? #
- Slow, slow,
quick, quick, slow, slow,
quick, quick...
Slow, quick, quick...
hi, Mommy.
Go in back.
I'll be there in a minute.
- Kids eat?
- Baby had a second bottle.
I fed them at like 6:00.
We'll talk when I'm through.
Slow, slow,
quick, quick, slow...
# New eyes grilling,
your blood's spilling #
# Tell me, little homie,
what's the reason? #
# That can lead
to freeway squeezing #
# What you fake it for? #
# Here we go... one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven #
- # Kick in the door #
- # Yeah and rhyme for the legend #
# Seven, six, five,
four, three, two, one #
# This is my twelfth album,
but your man's not dizz-un #
- # What you want? #
- # Defaces the coupes and the Lincs #
- # What you get? #
- # Top models that Garbo in the mink #
# Whoever want it,
I take it to the brink #
# It's funny but I needed Philly money,
we had a link, let's go #
# New eyes grilling,
your blood's spilling #
# Tell me, little homie,
what's the reason? #
# That can lead
to freeway squeezing #
# What you fake it for? #
# 24s killin',
ain't no ceilin' #
# Move, little homie,
see the hootchie leaning #
# L.L., I keep
birdies feenin'. #
- What you doing?
- Why the hell's the music off?
- Here he is... life of the party.
- Dude is so whacked.
Here we go.
Du-lame.
You don't have to stop.
That was amazing.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Now guys, why can't you put that emotion
and energy into my style of dance?
That's impossible, man.
Really, why so?
'Cause your music sucks.
It's corny. There ain't
no feeling in it.
- No feeling?
- Huh-uh.
How can you say that?
- Lena Horne, Joe Williams,
- Who dat?
Nat King Cole... these songs are
all about love.
Maybe you love different
than we do.
Look at you, you're all
flowers and things.
Talk to your woman all sweet, saying
shit trying to make her feel nice,
well, we ain't got
no time for that.
We want to get right down
to the ill na-na.
Love is universal,
my friend.
We just may look for it
different ways,
hearing different songs.
Yeah, whatever.
This is what you think
about love, right?
# Won't you fly me
to the moon... #
- Hmm... smooth, romantic.
- # And let me play among the stars... #
I would call that a love song.
I could dance to that.
Dance to this.
# Now shake that ass out #
# Make that cookie pop,
shake it down to the floor #
# And make that cookie drop,
shake that ass out #
# Make that cookie pop,
shake it down to the floor #
# And make
that cookie drop #
What you think about that,
Mr. Ballroom man?
# She want it on the ball,
use your dirty little head #
# To hustle on the floor... #
I didn't see you
on the floor today.
If you're not going to dance,
why bother even showing up?
If I don't go to detention,
then I can't go to class,
and then I can't graduate.
What d'you want
from me anyway, man?
I know you know who I am.
Glad to know you are so observant.
Now, if you'll allow me...
Hold on, man.
Don't be doing me no favors.
I don't owe nobody nothing,
I don't get down like that.
So I'm-a ask you again...
what you want from me?
I think a simple, "Thank you for
keeping my ass out of the slammer"
might be appropriate,
Mr. Rockwell.
Nobody gives something
for nothing.
I'll see you in class...
tomorrow.
All right, let's begin.
Caitlin, are you all right?
Would you be all right if you were me
and you had to have a cotillion?
Don't lie. It's like everyone here
is a beautiful swan
and then boom,
I'm the butt-ugly duckling.
Sweetie, if you don't
want a cotillion,
why don't you just tell
your parents to call it off?
I'd want one
if I could move like her.
It's like sex on hardwood.
I would kill
to dance like that.
Uh, excuse me a second.
Morgan?
# Now run and tell your mama
and your daddy how your shit is weak #
# 50 deep... damn nigga,
this ain't what you want in life... #
I mean, the deepest
darkest parts of me,
like the blood
through my veins and arteries,
- we see the fact...
- Yo.
# The presidential shit
is what I mean #
# Chop, chop... yeah,
I'm back on the block, on the block #
# We've got it ready
for you straight... #
Check this out!
Check Mr. Dulaine,
just getting his flirt on.
You can't do that.
Thank you, Morgan.
- Did you see that?
- How'd you do that?
That was amazing. I've never
seen anybody move like that.
I'm sure.
- Teach me how to do that.
- Okay.
All right, all right.
Listen, listen to me,
listen to me now.
Try to get her number.
How many of you men would like
to handle a woman like that?
- Ooh.
- Two times for me.
Good good.
And ladies,
how many of you would like the power
to drive your man to distraction?
Why are you showing us
what Miss Uptight could do
when she got parents who give her
lessons and the other crap she wants?
- That was not the point.
- Oh, it ain't?
No. You could be
just as good.
If you work at it,
of course.
And for those of you who already
think you'll be good enough,
there is a citywide competition
at the end of the term.
Now, the winning couple
splits $5,000.
Hold on, hold on, are you
talking ducats?
- Uh-huh.
- Five Gs?
- That's right.
- Yeah, I'm with that.
But I thought you said it wasn't
about the money, teach.
Money for dancing?
But only if you're good, right?
Yeah, only if you're good.
- Positions, please.
- Let's get busy.
- Let's review the fox-trot.
- Yo, I thought we were gonna tango.
Oh, no no no no,
the tango must be earned.
You, Mr. Ramos,
cannot handle the tango.
- Yet.
- Ooh-ooh.
Heard you had
a hell of a class today.
I love the tango.
How do you hear
about my class?
I hope you understand
what you're doing, Pierre.
Yes, I understand very well.
Just be careful
of what you're promising.
Everyone is entitled
to a little culture.
To me, dance is like life.
No, that's where you're wrong,
Mr. Dulaine.
Life, for these kids,
is like a fight to stay alive
and a hustle to make ends meet,
not ballroom dancing.
All right, ladies and gentlemen,
thank you very much.
See you on Thursday, okay?
Thank you.
We need to talk schedule
and financing...
- Mr. Dulaine.
- Yeah?
Morgan said the kids you teach uptown
are a bunch of no-talent losers.
Ah, you can't always believe
what Morgan says.
I'd really like
to join them.
# Fall back, get down,
lay down #
# Sit down, stay down,
head round #
# Hey now... does a nigga
wanna get a little off his mind? #
# I'm a nigga
that'll hit a nigga off his time #
# Brains in the air,
flame to the hair #
# 'Cause the game ain't fair,
and I'll take it there #
# With the right one, baby #
# Got that?
We tryin' to light one, baby #
# I run shit here... #
What the hell
are you looking at?
# I run shit here... #
- # If you wanna see me prove it... #
- What?
- She was staring at me.
- # Watch how quick a nigga lose it #
# Make you get all my shit
and have you fearing for your life... #
- The furnace is whacked.
- All right.
Class, this is,
uh, Caitlin Spencer.
She'll be joining us
for the day.
Yo, thought we saw
the last of your visitors.
Well, Caitlin is... different.
Think of her as
a foreign exchange student.
Hold on, where did
the equipment come from?
- Oh...
- Didn't you...
Yeah, I bought it
from a friend.
- Yeah.
- Uh-huh. You're trying to tell me
you actually bought
all this for detention?
No, well...
- Yeah, it's all good.
- I got it for Christmas.
We'll pretend I believe you.
Now, put on something
I can work with, please.
And guess what?
Positions, please.
All right, here we go.
All right.
Eyes over here,
eyes over here.
Today, we rumba.
And... quick, quick, slow.
Quick, quick, slow.
That's the basic rumba.
Eddie... Eddie!
Dance with Caitlin
so I can show you.
Oh, man, no, hell no,
I'm not dancing with her.
Look, I know I'm not the best dancer
in the world or anything,
but your girl right here
is just pitiful.
Yeah a-a-and another thing...
we don't need any more
white-bread tourists
seeing how the other half lives.
We don't.
White bread? I'm sorry,
do you own a mirror?
All right, Ramos,
you dance with Caitlin.
I'm so fly I can make
anyone look good.
- Thank you, sir.
- Uh-huh.
All right.
Attention and...
quick, quick, slow.
Quick, quick, slow.
- Quick, quick, slow.
- How are you doing?
Quick, quick, slow.
- Quick, quick, slow.
- You like this?
Nice jump.
You could have used that
in class today.
Rock!
Just a second.
The night you destroyed
Augustine's car...
- why did you do it?
- Because it felt good.
That's all?
Why are you
in my business, man?
It's hard to lose someone
you love. It hurts.
It's easy to think that something in the
street can fill the bad feeling inside,
but you know what?
It won't.
You need to stop acting
like you know my life.
Stop assuming I was
talking about your life.
What are you doing here?
Not everyone has
ulterior motives.
In my world they do.
And if our worlds ain't that far apart,
you would understand that.
You come around here
with your fancy suits on,
your slick little dance moves, you think
you're better than us, don't you?
- No no, you don't know who I am.
- Oh, I don't know anything, huh?
You can know about me,
but I can't know anything about you?
I got work.
You're late again,
Rockwell.
Yeah, I know, I've been getting
caught up with some stuff at school.
I-it's not going
to happen again though.
Damn right it won't.
Let me take this opportunity to thank
all of you for being with us.
Good luck with the decisions
that you make now.
You know, why do you stay
with someone who cheated on you?
It seems to make no sense
and yet...
How come you're here?
- I got fired, Ma.
- What did you do?
Where's the food at?
- I gave you money for food, Ma.
- Now you know I tried, Jay.
- I try, I can't do it all...
- Come on, I don't want to hear that.
- I can't do it myself...
- Hey-hey. What's with all the yelling?
- I'm hungry, Pop!
- You, lower your voice.
Where's the food at?
And why am I busting my ass all day
while you in here
drinking on yours?
- You know I'm sick.
- I know you're drunk.
You've been like that ever since
Ray died. That ain't no excuse.
People out there sicker than you
still supporting their families.
...You have in a sense
the same sickness...
You know what?
You ain't even worth it.
That's why I'm busting my ass
at school every day
to make sure I'm
nothing like you.
If that's the reason you're not leaving
the person who's cheating on you,
then for your own sake,
you should seek help.
If you don't, then you're cheating.
You're cheating yourself.
You get out of this house.
Get out!
Yo, G!
Whassup, man?
Say... you wanna ride?
Yeah.
# See, I know
you like my swagger #
# Oh, you know I'm strapped
when I come through #
# Chain hanging
like Ali Baba, oh #
# Know me,
you know how I do #
# The way that I move #
# You're never gonna get it,
'cause I'm too smooth #
I thought you knew #
# You're never gonna get it,
'cause you ain't got a clue #
get it, get it. #
Thank you very much,
ma'am.
# I wanna spaz out,
throw a brick #
# Sucker-ass, liquored glass
house in the suburbs #
# I know the time comin'
child support gonna bust in #
# To try to find
somethin', but no... #
- # I know your mama don't understand #
- What are you doing here?
# I ain't getting busy dissin' events,
but she knows... #
I'm here for dance class.
Oh, you think
you're one of us now?
- No.
- Oh, you want to go back downtown
and tell your little rich-ass friends
what it's like to slum with us?
- No.
- Then what?
Look...
I want to be here...
not because I'm slumming,
but because I feel better
up here than I do where I live.
So what you got
in the suitcase?
# Stop, mami, work that ass out
and get it on the floor... #
# I spit fire
till the day that I die-a... #
Gimme that mike, dude.
What are you doing, man?
- I'm flowin'.
- You can't rap.
# Hey, lemme hear you say
I like that, yeah... #
- What happened to George and Ira?
- Hey, they retired, man.
Demo time!
# Lemme hear you say...
I like that, yeah #
- # What ya think about it? #
- # I like that #
# Yeah, what ya think
about it? #
You're looking
a little confused.
It's simple really. We scratched
two different joints together.
But the underbelly
of the beats are all the same.
- See, watch.
- # Yeah, what you think about it? #
Yeah, it's the bottom beat
that I'm dancing to now.
But I can
change it up though.
- Yo, E! Flip it.
- #... Rose gold sit on my wrist #
# Dash, no, you and your...,
you better stop ##
## I like it when the music come on
so we can just rock like this #
- # Yeah #
- # I like... #
# I like it when the beat just pumps
so we can just move like this... ##
I mean, it's simple.
You can take out the underbelly
and dance to the top
of the beat,
or you can take out the top
and dance to the underbelly.
It's crazy, right?
It's tight.
Yes. Yes...
## If I ain't in the club,
I'm on the streets... #
two songs...
- working together?
- Yeah.
# I like that... #
This is a beautiful
idea, yeah.
Yeah, it is.
Which means,
we could use, let's say...
your music with...
- my music and then back to your music.
- Wha-aat?
Let me try something.
Uh, this one.
- All right, see if this works.
- A'ight.
- Number four.
- This better be something new.
# The way you wear your hat... #
Now these are the basic
beats for salsa, right?
Good good,
now I want you to fall in
and count with me.
- # No, they can't take that away... ##
- Underbelly of the rhythm only.
All right? Good.
Now, partner it up.
Yeah yeah, come on.
# Your boy's crazy, man... #
Eyes off of the floor.
Your soul is not
in your feet, all right?
- # Lemme hear you say it... #
- # The way you wear your hat #
# Wonder... wonder...
wonder what's the winning #
# Homie, you'll always
be a runner-up... #
Monster, you're too big.
Every move you make,
it's like the Rocky Mountains.
- I'm sorry.
- Mr. Pierre, I need another partner.
- All right and...
- # They can't take that away... #
Wanna dance with me?
Better not. Didn't you see
what just happened?
They call me Monster
for a reason.
I'm just not made
to dance.
- Monster, do you like dancing?
- Yeah, I guess so.
Then you were made
to dance.
## I like that #
# I like when the music
come on #
- # So we can just rock like this #
- # I like that #
# I like it when the beat just pumps
so we can just move like this #
- # I like that... ##
- Whoa!
What is the name
of that move you just did?
It ain't got no name. What you're
looking at is history in the making.
- Good, just do it.
- ## Follow the leader #
# Rose gold sit on my neck,
rose gold sit on my wrist #
# You and your...,
you better stop #
Guys...
why don't you try
just to dance together?
You know, try.
Come on.
## Follow me into a solo #
# Get in the flow
and you can pitch it like a photo #
# Music makes mellow, maintains
to make melodies for M.C. s #
# Motivates the breaks #
# I'm everlasting,
I can go on for days and days #
# With rhyme displays that engrave,
deep as x-rays #
# I can take a phrase
that's rarely heard #
# Flip it,
now it's a daily word... ##
All right, walk forward.
Everyone and...
## Let me hear you say,
now you know what I'm 'bout #
# Come on, let's go,
whatcha think about it? #
# I like that,
I like it, I like it #
# Let me hear
you say, yeah #
- # Whatcha think about it? #
- # I like that #
- # I like it, I like it #
- # Let's work #
# Come on. #
- See ya later, black.
- All right, man.
The place is always
a mess around here.
You never listen
to me no more.
Is that too much to ask?
Get your old lazy ass up away from that
TV and do something around here.
I thought Santy Claus was
supposed to foot the bill for the tree.
He does ordinarily,
but this year we're doing it for him.
You just try and think of yourself
as one of Santa's little helpers.
Who is it?
It's Woodley.
You know, your mama's friend.
My mom's not home yet.
Yeah, I know,
she told me to wait.
A'ight.
Take a seat
if you can find one.
There's a branch on the right
side that spoils the shape.
- Which one?
- This one right up here.
Fred, would you go down in the basement,
get your saw and cut that off for me?
It's a little unbalanced.
Oh, now, honey, maybe we can
hang something there.
He don't have to go all the way down
to the basement to get a saw.
Look, honey, the tree has
to be balanced, you know that.
We can't have
one branch out like...
I ain't gonna ask you where
you're getting this money from.
It's none of your business.
My mom said
she was coming.
- What, you want a soda or something?
- Huh-uh.
Just tell me something.
Where do you sleep?
Right here.
The kids share the bedroom.
You wanna
make some money?
Come on, you know
what I'm talking about.
You're your mama's
daughter, ain't you?
Whatever you've got with my mom has
to wait till she get home, all right?
Come on, mister.
I didn't mean no harm by it.
Yeah, whatever.
Nasty...
Listen, I offered to pay you.
- Get out! Get out!
- I should just take it from you.
What you're gonna do, girl?
What you're gonna do?
- Get off of me! Get off of me!
- Hey!
- Mommy!
- What's going on here?
# When I was just
a little girl #
# I asked my mother #
# Who'll I be #
# Will I be pretty? #
# Will I be rich? #
# Here's what
she said to me... #
# Que sera, sera #
# Whatever will be #
# Will be #
# The future's not ours #
# To see #
# Well, well, well, well #
# Come #
# Que sera #
# Que sera... #
What the hell
are you doing here?
I could ask you the same thing,
but I could already see.
# When I grew up
and fell in love... #
You know what?
Leave it on, I'm gonna go.
But you didn't answer my question...
what are you doing here?
Oh.
Well, I was down the hall, you know,
practicing my fox-trot
and then I heard your music,
so I figured...
Go to hell!
You wanna know why I'm here?
'Cause I can't go home.
My pop's been drunk
ever since your punkass brother
- and his friends rolled up on Ray.
- Don't talk about my brother!
He was sick to begin with, then your
dumbass brother had to do some...
- I said, don't talk about my brother!
- He was a crack dealer.
He only dealt to bring food
into our house.
- Ever since my daddy...
- "Daddy"?!
How do you even know
who your daddy is?
- Everybody know your mom is a ho.
- Don't talk about my mama!
Hold it.
What's going on?
Step away from her.
Hello?
What?
You could have warned me you told
them I was your father, I mean...
Don't trip, nobody cares about who
your real pops is around here anyway.
Obviously not.
Where I come from,
when a person gets woken up in the
middle of the night, they get answers.
So what you want to know?
Let's start with...
why call me?
You're the only one I could think of
who might come down and get me.
Need I ask you why you were
living in the boiler room?
Man, if she never came down there,
everything would have been cool.
Unbelievable.
You know...
maybe you two have more things
in common than you think you do.
My son, come on.
Hey, man, it's just
for the night, you know,
so don't think I'm gonna come
to your class or anything.
An-and we ain't kicking it.
We ain't friends.
I got it.
And maybe I snore a little,
I don't know...
Oh, that's okay,
'cause I know I snore.
It's a nice place
you've got here.
I'm gonna have me a spot
like this someday...
someplace clean.
You can get
whatever you want, Rock.
No, only some people get
the shit they want.
That's true.
And those are the people
who show up to get it.
Anybody ever tell you
you talk too much?
Yeah...
they did.
Good night.
- That's not the point.
- No, the point is they need help,
not suspension from school.
Oh, really, please tell me,
Professor Dulaine,
exactly what kind
of help it is they need?
So, as your principal has
made me your executioner,
you will report to me every
morning here at 7:30 A.M.
- for a private session.
- What?!
Whatever problems you have with each
other, you can work out as partners.
Sometimes the best way
to conquer an enemy
is to get right up
in his face.
I'd rather be dead
than up in his face.
You know what?
I feel the same way.
You know, guys,
you're lucky.
Common emotions
can be very powerful.
This is an excellent beginning,
starting now.
Please, take
the dancing position.
Please... come on.
Let's see this.
We are just going
to move, very simply.
Let's just, uh, walk.
No no no.
LaRhette, the man leads.
It is the woman's job
to follow.
Oh, so if he gets to lead,
then he's gonna think he's boss?
No, but he's not. You see,
the man proposes the step.
It is the woman's choice
to accept
by following.
Now, to follow takes
as much strength as to lead.
Good? All right.
Let's do it again.
Come on, come on!
Now, Rock, just walk.
Just forward, just walking.
Yeah, forward.
Just walking, like that.
Here you go.
Yeah, you know how to walk.
Now walk back.
There you go.
# You're dancing,
you're dancing... #
In the corte position
of the tango,
you must hold
your partner much closer.
Now boys, don't get too excited.
And girls, don't get too scared,
all right?
Now, your leg goes here, gentlemen.
And ladies, your upper right chest
touches his, like so...
- You're so far back. Move up.
- Uh, yeah.
The top of your thighs
must stay
glued to each other
for perfect balance.
That way, this is possible.
Good flys.
Come on,
dance together.
There are multiple
positions for the tango.
So where're you going?
- What's up, yo?
- What are you doing here?
Some hottie in the office
gave me your 411.
- I-I was eating... supper.
- After me, huh?
Are you all right?
I'm a'ight. It's just, uh...
it's just for a player like me,
man, I gotta keep
them girls on lock, you know?
Uh... what exactly
are you saying, Kurd?
Me and Big Girl, man...
you know, with the thighs
touching together and shit?
Is that a problem?
Hell yeah, it's a problem.
I'm done for if the homies
find out I like her.
Uh, uh... just...
thank you.
Everybody else
thinks Big is, well,
you know, not exactly
the hottest female around?
It is only what
you think that matters.
Yeah, easy for you
to say, man.
- You already a freak.
- Thank you.
Look, I don't know
how it happened.
One day, it was
just like whoa!
Uh, listen, having the courage
to follow your heart...
- Yo!
...is what makes a man a real man.
- That's what...
- Whoa, yo man, who's this hottie?
Uh, that is my wife.
Thank you.
- Your wife?
- Yes.
Lucky man.
Where's she at?
She died, five years ago.
Oh. So uh...
so are you like Buck Wilding
anyone else now?
No, I am not.
The waltz.
It cannot be done without trust
between partners.
Well, then it's just
not gonna happen.
But trust must
be earned, LaRhette.
- Good luck with that.
- All right, I have something here
that is gonna help.
Don't put that thing
on my eyes!
I'm asking you to do
something very courageous.
Besides dance with him?
There. Come on.
Now Rock, you have the...
over here.
You have the opportunity
to use
every bit of strength
and skill you possess,
not to dominate her,
but to take her on a journey.
It is a lot to ask.
If and how
you take the journey...
that's entirely up to you.
He's gone?
Yeah.
- You down?
- I guess.
Wrong way.
You always start forward
and I start back.
- All right, yeah. I can figure it out.
- I'm just trying to help.
I wish he'd tied that thing
around your mouth.
- You ready or what?
- Okay!
- Okay.
- O-kay.
- I saw that.
- What?!
- What are you smiling for?
- Shut up, I'm not.
All right, you're not.
Set it down right there.
All right, hit it, Tommy!
All right, people, no street shoes
on the dance floor, please.
# Hey you! #
# Come out here
on the floor! #
# Let's rock some more #
# Come out-a here
on the floor #
# Honey, let's rock
some more, yeah #
# Now when you get out here,
don't ya have no fear #
# Put your hands on your hip
and let your backbone slip #
# And work out! #
# Ah, ma-mama, move up! #
- # First step #
- # Honey, move back #
- # Second step #
- # Shuffle to the left #
# Third step... #
- Cool!
- # Wobble to the right #
# Fourth step... #
I mean, it's corny
but, you know, it's cool.
# But it's a natural fact #
- # Ha! I like it like that... #
- Right, practice your turns!
# Yeah-hh #
# Round and around
and around and around #
and around and around... #
# Round and around
and around and around #
and around and around... #
# Ahh-hh, ahh-hh #
- # Ahhhhh! #
- Um, 5:30 p.m.
- Hello, Morgan, how are you?
- # Don't you know, don't you know? #
Get dressed
and join them on the floor.
You're kidding, right?
- Uh... no.
- # Where we stop, nobody knows, yeah! #
# The band is swinging
on the stand #
# We're moving in, we're moving out,
then we'll step back now... #
Can I talk to you
for a minute?
Uh, certainly.
- In private.
- # Yeah-hhhh... #
- Okay.
- # Baby, let's shout! #
# Shout, baby!
Shout shout #
- # Honey, let's shout! #
- # Shout, baby #
- # Ah, baby, let's shout! #
- I have just one small question.
What the hell
are you doing?
Well, it's kind of complex
to explain what's going on.
# Shout all night long!
I gotta have it... #
- Bounce, dawg, I'm cuttin' in.
- What?
Don't talk about me like I'm invisible.
I'm standing right here.
Well, what?
This dance taken?
# Work all night long... #
Come on, man, don't trip.
Dance.
# Work out, baby #
- # Work, baby, work out #
- # Work out, woman #
- # Work, baby, work... #
- # Shout and turn the joint... #
You know what? By the time
the Academy students warm up,
the other kids
will be done...
I'm so sorry.
- Sorry.
- You all right? You cool?
No no, I'm-I'm not cool.
Look around you.
This is an advanced class,
a real class.
You guys are just taking up
time and space I paid for.
You see that? That's what
ballroom dancing looks like.
What you're doing
doesn't even come close.
Yeah well, let's see who
comes close at the competition.
The competition?
You guys are going to compete?
Yeah. What, you surprised?
Worried maybe?
- What's going on here?
- If you want to shell out
200 bucks apiece to get
slaughtered, fine by me.
Hold on, man, hold on.
$200, what is she talking about?
Everybody,
back on the floor, come on.
- What for?
- Excuse me?
Hell yeah, excuse you.
What you teaching us, dude?
Some bargain basement two-steps
while these kids got the real moves?
No no, Ramos, Ramos,
the steps are all the same.
They've simply been doing them longer,
that's all. C'mon, c'mon.
How are we supposed
to compete with something like that?
- Game over, let's roll.
- No no no, wait wait wait!
No no no, you've been
wasting our time, homes.
Making goddamn fools
out of all of us.
You knew all along
we couldn't do this thing.
That is not true!
What I have taught you has value.
Where?
Not where I live.
I can't believe this...
you've got fourth percentile
general math and reading scores,
and you've got kids
wasting time dancing around.
I've got no choice
but to report you.
That's yours.
It was like, uh, constructed
in the 1920s.
I didn't know
you liked architecture.
Oh, you like architecture?
How'd you like my bedroom?
Shut up! Why are you
such an ass?
Forget both of you.
I can't take this no more.
- What the hell was that, man?
- Forget you too, man.
Leave your love-triangle
problems to yourself.
This sucks.
Good afternoon, everyone.
Positions, please.
Yo, dance class is over, man.
No, it is not.
It is just beginning.
Your dancing is becoming...
so good
that I neglected to tell you,
and I am sorry for that.
But if you really want
to compete...
you're gonna have to kick
some serious ass to win.
These kids have been dancing
for years.
And there is
a whole city more
who are better
than they are.
Yeah, so what the hell
are we supposed to do?
Surprise them.
Everyone competing
expects nothing... nothing from you,
so you have nothing to lose,
except everything
you have achieved so far.
Look, I'm being honest
with you,
competing
on any level is tough,
and good dancers
make it look easy.
So what we need to focus on now
is not winning or losing,
but doubting.
So if you're not sure,
then sit down,
just stay home.
But if somewhere
you see a dot,
a glimmer of belief
in yourselves,
then you might have
what it takes to win.
You really think so?
Oh yes.
It is the strongest
secret weapon there ever was.
Yeah, well,
belief is fine and all,
but what about
that $200 entrance fee?
I mean I can believe all I want,
but I still can't make
a dollar out of 15.
I'll find a way to handle it.
- You would do that?
- Even for the school rejects?
It's funny...
I look around this room
and all I see is choices.
Choices waiting to be made.
Not a single reject.
Maybe a punkass or two.
I'm in.
Well?
You guys with me or what?
Mr. Dulaine?
Miss James needs to see you.
Miss James.
"Terminated."
These are the parents
of the kids in my class?
No, they're not. This is a meeting
of the Parent Teacher Association.
Oh.
So none of you have even seen firsthand
what my class is all about, right?
Okay, stop calling it a class,
it's detention.
These are the kids that need
the most help of all
and you're with them
doing the cha-cha-cha...
What are you doing
to help them, Mr. Temple?
Don't pretend you care
about these kids.
Let's be clear here.
What exactly is this about?
What this is about is wasting time with
something that is totally impractical.
When are these kids ever gonna
ballroom dance? It's ridiculous.
It's impractical,
as you say.
It's creating a dividing line where some
kids are entitled to learn about art
and are entitled to your time
and others are not.
Please, Mr. Dulaine, we've all heard
enough of your dance-is-life philosophy.
I get it.
To do something,
anything, is hard.
It's much easier to blame
your father, your mother,
the environment, the government,
the lack of money,
but even if you find
a place to assign the blame,
it doesn't make
the problems go away.
I'm trying something new.
I'm trying it.
So now you're gonna come to this school,
tell us about our kids,
our problems and how
you're gonna fix them with a box-step?
No.
I'm just gonna show you.
Uh, Augustine,
please, could you?
Mr. Dulaine!
This is absurd. Augustine!
Joe, shut up,
it's my body.
All right.
Don't worry.
We're gonna just move.
Here you go...
just like this...
very simple.
And now we're gonna walk
a little bit.
Yes, we're gonna walk,
we're walking.
Are we walking?
No, we're dancing.
So you know how to walk,
you know how to dance,
yeah.
You see...
if she allows me to lead,
she's trusting me.
But more than that,
she's trusting herself.
Now, if your
16-year-old daughter
is strong and secure
and trust herself,
how likely is she to let
some idiot knock her up?
And if your son...
can learn to touch
a girl with respect,
how will he treat women
throughout his life?
Beautiful.
Thank you.
We've got names on this piece of paper
of parents who have decided
- to terminate your class.
- So, ladies and gentlemen,
this is what I do here
at this school. I teach dance.
And with it, a set of rules
that will teach your kids
about respect,
teamwork
and dignity.
And that will help to give them a vision
of the future they could have.
A vision of the future
they could have.
Are there any questions?
Do you teach adult classes?
I suppose the studio
could cover all the fees.
Great.
Are you sure you really
want to do this?
T-A-N-G-O.
I don't care
if you think this is stupid,
all right?
Count it out
so you can feel the beat.
Let's go.
Don't give up.
T-A-N-G-O.
They'll be giving you
points on technique, style
- and originality.
- T-A-N-G-O.
Better if you put them
together now.
T-A-N-G-O.
Danjou, what is wrong with you?
You're not even trying.
I don't know why you're wasting my
man's time, you ain't winning nothin'.
Leave him alone, okay?
He's getting it.
No, homes, I'm getting it.
I got it, Mr. D.
Both of you are so stupid.
That's it!
You boys will be banned
from the competition
unless you can all
work together.
How are we
gonna do that?
From this point on,
you will both partner Sasha.
You will equally decide
who dances what.
You sweat through it,
you work it out.
Positions, please.
Let's go.
Come on.
And guess what?
Count it out...
T-A-N-G-O.
T-A-N-G-O...
Hey.
Hey, what's up?
What you doing?
Just trying to get
a head start,
because I've got math stuff
to do when I get home.
By the time I get
my baby brother fed,
get Donny
through his homework...
So it's just you and your mom
handling stuff at home?
Look, if you're
about to crack on my mom...
No, it's not even like that.
I don't mean no disrespect.
What I said before about
your mom, that was just before.
Yeah, it is just me
and my mom handling stuff.
My pops left when me
and Treyvaughn were 12.
My mom was pregnant
with Donny.
We did a'ight
for a minute, but...
then the last few years,
Treyvaughn decided to start helping out.
Before Ray got hit,
my pops got sick.
So I had to start working.
Where you work at?
I'm just doing some odd jobs
for a family friend right now.
Hey, LaRhette.
I'm sorry about what happened
to your brother.
Yeah, me too.
For yours.
Stand clear
of the closing the doors.
So what's the deal? You going
to the competition next Saturday?
I can't, it's the same night
as my cotillion.
Oh...
what's a cotillion?
A stupid dance where the whole world
gets to look at you
and see what a throwback
you are.
Come on now, you ain't
hardly no throwback, Caitlin.
So do you have someone
to take you to this cotillion?
Yeah, this stupid
jerk cousin I hate named Philip.
Forget it, why don't you
just let me take you?
I'd love that, really, but...
I don't think I can.
I mean, it's cool we dance together
after school and everything,
but there is just
no way anyone,
especially my mom,
would understand.
Oh, it's okay.
Would you be willing
to help me practice for it anyways?
# Whoa #
- # Can you feel it in your body, oh? #
- # Can you feel it? #
# 'Cause I can feel it
in my body, oh #
- # It feels good to my body, oh #
- # Oh, this is it #
- # You've got to keep it moving #
- # Don't stop #
# Once you get moving,
don't quit #
- # Next thing you know you on top #
- # You on top #
- # So hop to the rhythm that we... #
- # Rock #
- # Get loose and express what you got #
- # What you got #
- # At least you've got
to give yourself a shot #
- # A shot #
- # Hey, never give up, and... #
One, two, three.
# Can you feel
the hi-i-igh-i-igh? #
# I can feel
the hi-i-igh-i-igh #
# Can you feel
the hi-i-igh-i-igh? #
# I can feel
the hi-i-igh-i-igh #
# Can you feel it? #
- # Can you feel it in your body, oh? #
- # Can you feel it? #
- # 'Cause I can feel it in my body-o #
- # I can feel it #
- # Feels good to my body-o, we go #
# To my body,
to my body, to my body-o #
# Body, to my body,
b-b-body-o #
# Dabadada-dada #
# Dabadada-dadada... #
# Talatala-talatala-
doo-be-doo #
# Laladadoo-ladadadah. #
Oh yeah, Black Eyed Peas
on The LIZ.
If you feel it,
I can feel that.
Traffic on the eights,
on 800 W-LIZ.
- Hey, I got a question.
- What's up?
So...
are you gonna do the competition
with me or what?
Pierre wants me to waltz
and I need a partner.
You want me to do it?
I'm asking you, right?
Why? Does what
I want count now?
No.
You know what? It'll be worth it
to see their faces when we all roll up.
They'll probably
hide the orchestra.
You think there's gonna
be a orchestra?
Yeah, I mean... I guess.
Oh!
- My bad.
- It's all right.
You know, you look
different when you dance.
How?
Like calm, like...
like you're at peace
or something.
Well yeah, that's 'cause
when I'm dancing
I'm in my moment.
What's that mean?
It's just this place
where it gets all silent
and I forget
about everything bad.
And it just feels good.
All right, come on.
And one and two
and three...
All right.
Don't do it anymore.
- All right.
- Don't do it anymore.
This is like Elvira's dress.
- Those are mine... be careful.
- Cool!
Not this bright
pink one, I'm not!
Put that one down, because it
does not go with my dress.
- You look good.
- Hmm.
- Wow! Sexy.
- Hello hello.
Okay, try this one.
Tina?
Thank you.
# Let me tell them, let me show them,
let me tell them #
# Ya ya-ya-ya ya-ya-yah... #
Fasten this up.
Nice.
You know, it kills her
when you do that.
What was that?
Tina... the hand
on the shoulder thing...
it kills her.
Look, I know how you love
to talk about...
romance and magic and two bodies
moving as one and everything.
But let me see if I can
make you understand something...
she likes you.
- Look what I found on the street.
- Eddie, Eddie...
I'm just playing, Mr. D. These was
on hold for my brother's wedding.
But we've got to be
real careful with them,
get them back on time or my ass
is family history, you feel me?
Hey, look what I got, y'all.
Whassup? Whassup?
- Ah!
- Shoot it, shoot it!
Man, shoot it!
Oh-ho-ho no.
On Saturday?
You said this Saturday?
Yeah, this Saturday, fool.
- Shoot it.
- He's being lazy.
Yo, you playing or what?
Get up, get up!
Game point, game point.
Nice bike.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Good evening and welcome
to the 25th Annual
Grand Ballroom Competition.
I see many many
familiar faces here tonight.
And a whole lot
of new black ones.
So at this time,
if you'd like to warm up,
please, take a partner and join me
on the dance floor
for our first all-in waltz.
Our orchestra this evening is
under the direction of Frank Laurence.
Please, give them
a very warm welcome.
Man, she knows she wrong.
You ought to give it to her
though, the girl is bad.
- Dancers, ready?
- Ready?
Yo, Ease,
this don't feel right, man.
- If somebody comes...
- You shoot 'em.
What d'you think I gave you
the piece for? To play with?
I ain't about
to shoot nobody.
So what you gonna do?
Dance 'em outta here?
Give me that back.
If you're gonna punk out,
punk out now. You understand me?
Like your
goddamn brother, dude.
He got hit because he punked.
Now I'm not saying
that I did it, so...
you gonna be like him, huh?
Huh?
No.
Good.
Handle your business, man.
The next category
will be the salsa.
Dancers, ready?
Whoa, dawg.
Come on, man.
What you gonna do with that?
What'd you do that for?
Doing what my brother should have
done when he had the chance.
I'll kick your ass!
Man, we gotta go!
You know who you're
messing with, son?
- Huh?
- We gotta go, Easy.
I'll hit his ass again.
Get off of me.
You messed
with the wrong brother.
Leave that fool there.
Come on, man, let's go.
Numbers 14,
212 and 346
remain.
All others,
please clear the floor.
Presenting our next deb...
Oh my God, here she comes.
- Caitlin Spencer.
Don't freak out.
Please, don't freak out.
Don't screw up.
Please, don't screw up.
Please, don't freak out.
Don't freak out, please.
Don't freak out. Don't freak out.
Please, don't freak.
Just make it to Philip now.
That's all you have to do.
Where's Philip?
Please, don't freak out.
Don't freak out. Please don't...
Oh!
That's not Philip.
Now, come on,
we've got to bounce.
The next dance is the tango.
All competitors, please.
- I better take this one, son.
- No, I got this. I got tango.
Yeah, but you can't
dance it, junior.
Look, Sasha, you decide
who the better man is.
Danjou, come on.
Remember,
ladies and gentlemen,
that the $5,000 grand prize
is awarded
to the couple scoring the highest
in any single round.
And I'll announce the winners
at the end of the evening.
And now... the tango.
Are you holding up?
I'm fine.
I'm sure he's got
a good reason.
It's not even about him.
It's me.
I feel so stupid.
People have been leaving me
hanging my whole life.
I don't know why I thought
this would be different.
You really made me believe magic
can happen anywhere, Mr. D.
I guess you just
didn't mean with me.
- Very well done.
- Yeah!
Please show your appreciation,
ladies and gentlemen,
for these wonderful dancers
as we wait for the results.
Numbers 111
and 213 stay.
All others,
please clear the floor.
Couple 111 took home
the $5,000 grand prize
last year in this category.
Morgan Fisher
and Travis Drake.
Danjou, I don't think
we can beat them.
I'm sorry, but I don't
know what else to bring.
Listen, you need to stop
worrying about what they got
and bring to the floor
what we got.
Joining them is couple 213...
Mr. Danjou Epps
and Miss Sasha Keane.
This is their first appearance
at this competition
and we wish them well.
And now let's turn it over to
Frank Laurence and the orchestra
with our tango selection
this evening..."La Cumparsita."
What?!
# How much I'd like
to take you home #
to take you home... #
## Introducing
the best of the best #
# And when the kick drum kick
and it's in your chest #
# And then it gets
real deep within it #
# We gonna get 'em, we shake
and vibrate, and take the rhythm #
# Work-work-work-work
work-work-work-work. #
Whoa!
Now that's
what I'm talking about.
Thank you.
- Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
- Bravo!
Well! Wasn't that exciting?
Let's see what
the judges have to say.
The judges have awarded
Miss Fisher and Mr. Drake
straight 10s
in all categories.
Unfortunately, as this is a competition
for couples and not teams,
Miss Keane, Mr. Epps
and Mr. Ramos could not score.
What?!
The round, therefore, goes to
Morgan Fisher and Travis Drake.
- That's a bunch of bull!
- This perfect score
puts them firmly in the lead
for the grand prize
again this year.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you.
Miss Fisher, if you please.
Let's call this round
a tie.
- It better be a tie.
- A tie!
I've never seen anybody move
like that in my life.
I'm sure.
That was a very
convincing performance.
I'm a pro.
- That's a very unexpected development.
- Yes!
So, ladies and gentlemen,
a tie.
The grand prize may be
shared this evening.
Never a dull moment
in ballroom dancing
as you can see.
Our final competitive dance
is the waltz.
- Excuse me.
- I'm sorry, sir.
I've really got to get in here.
I'm in the competition.
Excuse me, sir, look, sir,
I'll deal with it, okay?
Thank you.
- Where's LaRhette?
Oh, Mr. D, I already know what
you're thinking, man, but I showed up.
I'm here, you know
what I'm saying?
Mr. D, look, sometimes you talk
about making choices
and everything and tonight I probably
made a real wrong choice,
- but...
- Here.
Thank you, Pierre.
You ready?
Pierre, I never thought
it was possible.
Honestly, Augustine,
I had my doubts.
It took a lot of work.
But it was worth it.
I have to thank you
for allowing me to do this...
Oh, don't start your thank-you speech
just yet, Dulaine.
We need to make
your program permanent.
And it's going to take
even more work.
I'll see you in my office
Monday morning at 9:00.
# It was fascination #
# I know #
# Seeing you alone #
# With the moonlight above #
# Then I touch your hand #
# And next moment #
# I kiss you #
# Fascination turned... #
# To... #
# Lo-o-o-ve. #
That's it
for the competition, folks.
It's been a wonderful evening
and while we wait for the waltz scores
and the grand prize results...
- Miss James.
...let's relax and have some fun...
- Hey Rock, are you enjoying yourself?
...with one more dance.
Yeah, yes I am, uh...
about your car...
you know something
about my car.
As you make your way to the floor,
ladies and gentlemen...
I'm real sorry, Miss James.
...let's take a moment to thank
our hosts again this year:
- Let's not spoil tonight.
- the beautiful Lamont Hotel.
- It's okay.
- As always, it gives me great pleasure
- to introduce our fine musicians...
- For now.
...led by the incomparable
Frank...
Oh, shut up.
It's time
for the tie-breaker.
# Put your hands up #
# Go! #
- # Baby wanna ride? #
- # You know she'll get it #
- # Hey baby, wanna ride? #
- # You know you're fated #
# Hey baby, wanna ride?
Let's ride #
# Sure you can dance,
I'm-a chill, I'm-a smoke #
# But you know how they think when they
drink from that Hennessy and cokes #
# When they drip on my kicks,
man, they got me like, uh! #
# She act like she
couldn't hear me right #
# When I came in the club,
all the people go good #
# I just came in the club
just to leave with her #
# Swizz got to calm me down
like, yeah #
# Money frontin'
in the back, say #
# Found Thunder,
what does Shiggy say? #
# He said he didn't care,
then he called her a... #
# Drag back
in the swing of things #
# I'm back up in the club
but I ain't got to bring my things #
# And I like the way
she shake that thing, yeah #
# Might be easy for you
to break that thing, yeah #
# And I stay in a New York
state of mind #
# Let me see you dance
one more time #
# We about to party,
hands in the air #
Care to dance,
Mr. Dulaine?
Uh...
let them have this one.
I'll sit it out.
# Yes, I love to dance #
# I don't wanna stop #
# I can feel the heat #
# Ooh, it makes me hot... #
What if we just...
walk?
- # Hey baby, wanna ride? #
- # You know she'll get it #
- # You know you're fated #
# Hey baby, wanna ride?
Let's ride... #
# I can do that,
I can do that #
# I can do that, I can do that #
# I can do that,
I can do that #
- # Hey baby, wanna ride? #
- # You know she'll get it #
- # You know you're fated #
# Hey baby, wanna ride?
Let's ride... #
# Throw your hands up #
# What? #
# Yes, I love to dance,
I don't wanna stop #
# I can feel the heat #
# Ooh, it makes me hot #
# Yes, I wanna let go #
# But I'm in control #
# I'm ready to ride #
# Watch my body go #
# Ooh-ooh, ah-ha #
# I know you wanna see me
do my dance #
# Ooh-ooh, ah-ha #
# Come and check me out
as I do my dance #
# Ooh-ooh, ah-ha #
# I know you like the way
I do my dance #
# Ooh-ooh, ah-ha #
# Watch me
as I work it, Wisin #
- # Hey baby, wanna ride? #
- # You know she'll get it #
- # You know you're fated #
# Hey baby, wanna ride?
Let's ride #
# I can do that,
I can do that #
# I can do that, I can do that #
# I can do that,
I can do that #
# I can do that, I can do that... ##
## Yeah, that's right...
oh, you gotta show me that #
# Could you... could you...
could you teach me? #
# Show me that again? #
# Could you... could you...
could you teach me? #
# You take the lead #
# Straight up, do you have rhythm
underneath your feet? #
# Does the beat flow through
that fine body? #
# Do you enjoy
sweating all on me? #
# Did you just bust
that move freestylin'? #
# Do you do much
choreographin'? #
# You're widenin' out, boy,
great timin' #
# I like a man
who can dance #
# Shake it, shake it,
twist it like you're breakin' #
# Pop it like your bones
are dislocated #
# Ride me like you hold me,
turn me around slowly #
# Drop me to the floor,
pull me up again #
# Shake it, shake it,
twist it like you're breakin' #
# Pop it like your bones
are dislocated #
# Ride me like you hold me,
turn me around slowly #
# Drop me to the floor,
pull me up again #
# You rock me, swing me,
bang me #
# Teach me how to... how to
how to flow, how to roll #
# What have you got? #
# Teach me how to...
how to... #
# Could you... could you...
could you teach me? #
# Teach me how to dance #
# I can do that,
I can do that #
# I can do that, I can do that #
# I can do that,
I can do that #
# I can do that, I can do that #
# Excuse me
while I check out your style #
# You move so good,
all I can do is sigh #
# You're making me
start to fantasize #
# Shake it, shake it,
twist it like you're breakin' #
# Pop it like your bones
are dislocated #
# Ride me like you hold me,
turn me around slowly #
# Drop me to the floor,
pull me up again #
# Shake it, shake it,
twist it like you're breakin' #
# Pop it like your bones
are dislocated #
# Ride me like you hold me,
turn me around slowly #
# Drop me to the floor,
pull me up again #
# Straight up, do you have rhythm
underneath your feet? #
# Does the beat
flow through that fine body? #
# Do you enjoy sweating
all on me? #
# Did you just bust
that move freestylin'? #
# Do you do
much choreographin'? #
# You're widenin' out, boy,
great timin' #
# I like a man
who can dance #
# Shake it, shake it,
twist it like you're breakin' #
# Pop it like your bones
are dislocated #
# Ride me like you hold me,
turn me around slowly #
# Drop me to the floor,
teach me how to dance #
# Could you... could you...
could you teach me? #
# Teach me how to...
how to... #
# Could you... could you...
could you teach me? #
# Teach me how to dance,
let me get your number please #
# I don't care
if there's a fee #
# Book me now,
I really need #
# You to teach me
how to dance #
# Swing me, bang me #
# Teach me how to...
how to... #
# How to roll,
what have you got? #
# Teach me how to dance #
# Teach me-ee... #
# Teach me how to...
how to... #
# Could you... could you...
could you teach me? #
# Teach me how to dance. #
# It was fascination #
# I know... #
# And it might have ended #
# At the start #
# A passing glance #
# A brief romance #
# And I might have gone #
# On my way #
# Empty-hearted #
# It was fascination #
# Oh, baby #
# Yeah-hey #
# My fascination, girl #
# Oh-oh #
# Turned to lo-o-o- #
# O-o-o-oh-oh-ove #
# Fascination #
# I know... #
# And I might have gone #
# On my way #
# Empty-hear-rr-ted #
# Fascination #
# Oh #
# And I know #
# I know, baby #
# And my... my fascination #
# My fascination #
# Turned to lo-oo-ve #
# Fascination, oh... #
# My... my... #
# My fascination, girl #
# Turned to love. #
Download more subtitles from http://subscene.com