Who are you?
- What?
Come out!
I'm asking, who are you?
- Me? Ivo. And who are you?
Are you alone here?
- Yes.
A Russian?
- No, Estonian.
What's an Estonian doing here?
- It's my factory.
What are the crates for? Bombs?
No. For tangerines.
Tangerines are good.
Ok. You have anything to eat?
We're hungry.
Food is in the house. There.
- Come, let's go.
Sit.
Who do you have at home?
- Nobody. I live alone.
Come in. Take your seats.
We'll sit, grandpa,
but better pack the food,
we'll take it with us. - Ok.
And don't be greedy.
See what a beautiful girl.
- Yeah, a beauty.
Where's your family?
You don't have anyone?
They all went home
when the war broke out.
Home where?
- To Estonia.
Why did you stay?
Didn't want to.
Your daughter?
- Granddaughter.
And don't comment. Don't dare.
Didn't mean to. Ibrahim!
What's this?
Food.
You are a good man, grandpa.
Shame that you're that old.
It's a pity that
brave men like you get old.
So what's going on there?
War's raging?
Yeah, man.
Go away to your Estonia.
Not everyone are nice guys
like us.
Does anyone live in these houses?
- No, they're all deserted.
Only in the one by a plantation,
there's one.
But he has nothing
but tangerines. I'm helping him.
We don't care about tangerines.
But you have a nice crate
business here. Good for you.
Margus!
Yeah, wait a minute.
Who were they?
- Some Caucasians. Wanted to eat.
They didn't come to me.
- I know.
Listen, did you manage to agree?
- Yeah.
They promised to send
20 soldiers on the 7th. For one day.
Damn, one day's not enough.
- Clearly.
We'll pick as much as we can.
I'm already on it.
Good. If we wait too long, we won't
get a damn thing out of here.
In a few days it may be
pretty fierce up here.
Those two also said
it'll be war soon.
My major said the same.
If I make ten crates today,
we'll have 200. Enough?
I don't know. Look for yourself.
Some 50 more would be needed.
Alright.
Don't kill yourself with work,
it's five days till the 7th.
The sooner the better.
War news from the radio.
Margus!
- Yeah.
You didn't get shot?
- No.
What happened?
- I don't know.
This one drove by first,
that one was chasing, shooting.
Hit the fence, damn,
it's all ruined now.
I was up the tree...
I mean, hid myself.
Then they shot from something,
bazooka, I guess.
Damn, it drives you crazy here.
What was it? - Calm down.
He's wounded. Go take a look
at the van. And be careful.
Easy, easy...
So how is it?
- All dead.
Well, Georgian dzhigits,
where are you? - Easy.
How is it there in the heavens,
sons of bitches? - Enough!
Don't shout, or you will die.
Barely managed
to stop the bleeding.
But Ibrahim was killed?
- Start the car.
The bastards killed him, right?
- Yes.
We'll go and bury him now,
but you try to calm down.
We'll get a doctor for you.
And try to move less.
Be careful, grandpa,
look out for a tail.
The rest of the Georgians
may follow.
Don't worry, lie quietly.
Give me my gun.
- What for? No one will come here.
Give. Anything can happen.
- I told you, they won't come!
Check their pockets,
maybe you'll find some documents.
What for?
- Their relatives may come looking.
We can take them
to their grave then.
You're right.
The Georgians are mere boys.
But that one isn't.
Yeah, mere boys.
You know what, let's bury
the Georgians together
and the bearded one
separately here.
Then we'll know who's where.
- Alright.
That Georgian is alive!
Don't worry, it's us.
Who's that? Ibrahim? Alive?
- No, it's not Ibrahim.
Who then?
Get some water and a clean towel
from the kitchen cupboard.
There's a shell fragment
in his head.
We need Juhan now,
otherwise he won't survive.
The other one
needs a doctor, too.
Get Juhan quickly
and we need to tow away the van.
It's easier with three of us.
- I've got a good cable.
Wait!
See that he won't tell anyone.
Who does he have to tell?
Everyone's gone.
His wife.
- She's already in Estonia.
How are you?
In pain?
- Not too bad.
Thanks to Allah, slightly less.
Who did you carry in?
A Georgian. Gravely wounded.
What? You out of your
fucking mind, grandpa?
I'll whack him anyway.
Wasted effort.
Alright, I apologise for that
word, but they killed my friend.
And you didn't kill two of his?
Or can't count?
Should have killed three.
Anyway, I will set that right.
No point in treating him.
No point.
How is he?
- The Chechen will heal in a week.
But the Georgian, I don't know.
Depends on his body.
What shall we do with the fragment?
See that he gets the shots
in time. - Don't worry.
Why is he raving all the time?
- Raving is good.
He may even survive.
I'll come back same time tomorrow.
Did he eat?
- Some. He's asleep now.
Shall we go?
- Wait. I'll lock the Georgian's door.
We don't know what the madman
may come up with.
Let's go! Grab the wheel.
Turn the wheel right! Right!
Very good!
Going, going...
I thought it would explode.
They explode in cinema.
- Cinema is a big fraud.
How's it going?
- Not bad.
Made 20 crates,
you can take them.
You know... These wounded men
will ruin our business.
So what shall I do now?
Kill them?
No, I didn't mean that.
Just saying. - Quit whining.
How much did you pick?
- Yesterday's crates are full.
Very good. Did you
drop by my house?
Yeah, I brought the key.
- Could have left it under the stairs.
What if someone finds it?
- Who's going to look for a key?
They'll take down the door
if they want to.
How are they?
- The Chechen is well.
Ate everything there was.
Seems to be recovering.
And the Georgian?
Did you measure his temperature?
- What for?
His head is all hot, raving all the time.
Leave the key.
Shall I help you
to carry the crates?
No need. I'll manage.
Do your own things.
Went to see the van. You can
barely spot it from the road.
What were you thinking?
- I'll whack him anyway, grandpa.
Lock him under a thousand locks,
I'll get revenge for my friend.
It's a holy thing for us,
you don't understand this.
To kill a sleeping man,
even if he's unconscious,
is a holy thing?
Didn't know, really.
Then I'll kill him
when he can stand again.
It's going to rain.
No, it will not.
They'll be here soon.
- They who?
Georgians. Or Russians.
And tangerines
will remain on trees.
You know what they call this war?
The Citrus War.
- Meaning?
Meaning who will get
my tangerines.
Come on.
They fight for the land.
- Where my tangerines grow.
You have gone out of your mind
with your tangerines.
As soon as the tangerines are sold,
I'll go to Estonia. It's free now.
The Georgian came to.
Thank you.
Thank you for everything.
Try not to speak much.
My head is aching very much.
- Don't worry.
I'll give you a shot
and it will be better.
Well, the bastard woke up?
Who's that?
- Don't mind, he's a lunatic.
I'll whack him anyway, grandpa.
- Listen to me!
No one can kill anyone in my house,
unless I want it to happen!
But if you think to do it anyway,
you'll have to kill me first.
Come on, grandpa. You saved me.
- You heard what I said.
Well, then. I give you my word
that I won't kill him in your house.
But as soon as he goes out,
I'll do my thing.
I will hope to see you in Estonia.
When will you leave?
- A car will come in the morning.
Be careful then.
- No big deal,
half an hour to the airport,
and on from there.
Godspeed.
What are you doing here?
Sell your tangerines
and come along.
The former life is gone.
That's it. The end.
You know very well
why I'm staying.
You better think of
your granddaughter.
Mari is well,
I don't worry about her.
Juhan. Thank you.
Medicines are in the closet,
I left the instructions there, too.
Take care.
Up already?
- I'm better. Can't lie anymore.
My clothes suit you.
Easy, easy!
You must eat a lot.
Recover your strength.
- I'm not hungry.
I'm telling you, eat!
Want SOl'T1€ tea?
- Yes.
Thank you for saving me.
You're welcome. Eat.
I apologise once more for
the bad word I said back then.
I'm nervous. But usually,
we honour old people. Very much.
Apology accepted.
Your wound is painful?
- Not much.
Where did you bury my friend?
- In the woods.
What's your name?
- Ahmed.
But you are not interested
in my name?
I am.
- I'm Ivo.
I'm a Chechen, a soldier.
A mercenary?
- Yes.
Understood.
You have a family?
- Yes.
I went to war because of them.
I get paid well.
Went to war because of them?
- Don't start to moralise.
I told you that I honour
old people,
but it's none of your business.
None, Ivo.
Correct, I'm Ivo.
Ivo...
Where's my gun?
- In a safe place.
You get better, I'll give it back.
Even trophy guns of the Georgians.
These are yours, too, right?
I want to ask something.
- Ask then.
I have to tell you,
if I give my word of honour,
I rather die than break it.
- Right. I'm like that, too.
So I don't have to lock
that door anymore?
Listen, Ivo, you, an Estonian,
are rather dying
than breaking your word.
You are asking me, a Caucasian,
a mountaineer, if I keep mine?
For us, it means everything.
I promised not to kill
in your house, so I won't.
Very well.
But an Estonian or a Caucasian,
it does not make any difference.
Ivo, why didn't you leave
for Estonia?
But that is none
of your business, young man.
Our work is completely pointless,
if we won't get any help.
I have only picked two crates
during that time.
Can't pick any more.
If the help will not arrive
tomorrow, we are screwed.
What did the major
exactly tell you?
That they'll come
if something will not happen.
If something does not happen.
Unless they are stationed
somewhere else. They won't be.
They've been guarding the entrance
for two weeks.
Why should anything
happen tomorrow?
I don't know.
It sure would be strange
if soldiers would pick
tangerines in wartime.
You are strange.
The major promised.
Well, God help us. I hope, too.
Don't worry, Ivo.
They will come.
War news from the radio.
Easy, easy.
No hurry.
Good boy.
Sit down.
How are you feeling?
- Head is slightly spinning.
It's nothing.
We found this in your head.
And these in your pockets.
SOITIE tea?
- Yes.
Ahmed, drink up your tea.
It will cool down.
Ok then, enemies.
He's Ahmed, he's Nike.
Pleased to meet you.
You know, Georgian, you may
know already, don't be afraid.
I have promised to our saviour
not to kill you in his house.
So if you want to live,
don't go out.
Don't even extend your head out,
as I will chop it off at once.
But can he pee out the window?
Enough!
Enough.
I'm sorry, Ivo.
So they didn't come?
Some tea?
Well, don't worry
about the tangerines.
It's idiotic anyway to start a
tangerine business in wartime.
He doesn't happen to be
your relative?
Margus!
Come in, why are you
standing there?
I don't know,
I thought you got mad at me.
Forget it. Come in.
Let's sit outside.
The weather is fair.
I don't want to leave them
alone for too long.
You are not afraid
they will kill each other?
The Chechen gave his word.
And you believe him?
- I do.
But the Georgian?
- He, too.
Well, since you have their word...
Don't be surprised, there are
people worth their word.
And both of them in your house?
- Leave it alone.
Maybe you want to send
one over to my place?
No, the skirmish took place
at your gate.
They broke your fence.
You can see the van from
your house, and so on.
No, it's safer at my place.
- Yes, quite.
Come to my place this evening.
The boys will retire early,
let's get a drink. - Agreed.
So, this evening?
Don't get mad at me, but maybe
you'll come to Estonia with me?
Ivo, maybe we could find
another melody? It drives me crazy.
But I like it. I'm listening.
But what sort of music
do you like, Georgian?
I don't like this one.
- Georgian music?
I like Georgian music.
- And Georgian land, too?
Where's the Georgian land?
- Here.
The one you are sitting on,
is Georgian land.
You're sitting on Georgian land.
- No.
I'm sitting on an Estonian chair.
- Very funny.
Yes, on an Estonian chair
standing in an Estonian house
that's standing on
an Abkhazian land.
Listen, did you go to school
at all? Do you have schools?
What?
- I'm asking if you have schools.
What are you smirking at, alien.
What have you lost here in Georgia?
I'm here to protect a tiny nation
from evil aliens like you!
It seems that you really
don't have schools there.
You don't understand a thing.
Don't know a thing.
Didn't study any history?
Haven't read any books?
I'm not going to be offended by you,
I don't care what you're blabbering.
You are safe here,
blabber all you want.
Ok, let's go outside right now!
- You can't even walk!
I could kill you with a rag.
Wouldn't be too manly.
Recover first, then we'll see
what'll be left of you.
You son of a bitch!
Don't brag if you're not
good for it! Fucking maggot!
Get lost from my country, cunt!
- I'm telling you, idiot,
it's not Georgian land!
Go ahead, sleep. You don't have
much time left. - Enough, Ahmed!
Sorry, Ivo, but will you tell him
to shut up, too?
You will shut up soon!
Quiet...
Good morning, Ivo!
- Hello.
How are you?
- Recovering.
That's good
And where's
your enemy? Still sleeping?
No, the enemy's not sleeping.
Good morning.
How's your head?
- Pain is almost gone.
While standing.
It's difficult to lie.
But you can take an example
from a horse. Sleep on your feet.
Am I talking to you?
- Do horses talk at all?
Some humour.
Suits your intelligence well.
Ok, I'll behave.
SOITIE tea?
- Yes.
Shall I pour you, bro?
On your head?
- You don't want to try.
Again.
Thank you.
Ivo, is this your daughter?
No, his granddaughter.
What's her name?
None of your business.
- There are cars approaching.
Ahmed, they are Abkhazians.
If they enter,
will you give him away?
No, I have to kill him myself.
- Good.
Then we tell them he's Ibrahim.
and you killed all the Georgians.
You're not asking me?
Ivo, give me my gun!
Quit your foolish talk.
You can't talk, because you
caught it to your head. That's it.
You know why
you have to be silent?
Because first, they will shoot me.
Even if I curse Georgians,
you will stay quiet.
So, he can't talk
after getting wounded.
Hello, Ivo.
- Hello, Aslan.
Listen, we saw
a Georgian van
over there in a chasm
near Margus' plantation.
And there is a car
here at your place.
Oh, Margus. You're here.
So what happened?
Where are the Georgians?
All killed. Chechens wasted them.
But we saved two Chechens.
They are here, wounded.
- In your house?
Come in, I'll introduce you.
- Right, I'd like to shake hands.
Come in.
Here you are.
Sit, don't get up, brother,
you're wounded. - I'll live.
Aslan.
- Ahmed.
He's Ibrahim, but he can't talk,
was wounded to his head.
Well, I'll be... Fuck 'em.
How is it? Got hurt
and tongue isn't working?
Stupid. A brick fell
on my neighbour's head,
and his legs stopped moving.
There are spots in your head
that move all parts of your body.
Like here, maybe, is a leg spot,
and here, one for hands. Get it?
He didn't get a damn thing!
I have good vodka. Sit down.
- No, Ivo, we're off to the front.
They say it's
total mayhem there.
And what will happen?
- We'll flush the fuckers away.
You doubt it?
- No, Aslan, of course not.
These guys are helping.
How many Georgians were there?
- Three.
They saw us on the road
and started to shoot.
We turned around, they followed.
Then Ibrahim caught a bullet
to his head, we rammed a fence
and drove into the plantation.
I managed to hit the bull's-eye
with a bazooka. - Well done, Ahmed.
The bodies are in the van?
- No. We buried them in the woods.
Throwing them out on a road like dogs
would have been right for them.
Aslan, they're humans
as well, very young ones.
Well, let it be.
You get well. Most important is
that he could talk again.
As soon as we feel strong enough,
we'll join you.
Thanks, Ahmed, we're brothers.
Aslan...
Do something good.
I know it's a bad time,
but Margus is about to lose
a huge crop of tangerines.
A major here promised
to send people, but couldn't.
Maybe you can help.
We'll share the money afterwards.
How many people do you need?
- 30 maybe, 40 would be better.
No problem. Day after tomorrow
the people will be here.
We'll stay by the river
for three days.
And money is not needed,
a few crates of tangerines will do.
Thank you, Aslan.
We'll be waiting.
Day after tomorrow.
I give you my word.
Look, Ahmed, the Georgian
is outside. Want to kill?
Won't bother to kill him today,
somehow.
Margus! Aslan promised to send
40 men day after tomorrow!
This is very good.
Coals only, Margus. No flame.
- I know!
Are you cold? Want a jacket?
- No, thanks, Ivo, I'm not.
What are you planning to do
when you recover? Back to war?
You don't know?
- I do.
So, everything's ready.
Try it and tell me, have you had
anything like this before?
We'll try.
You have never eaten it?
- Try first, then talk.
Delicious.
You, Georgians,
can't make shashlik.
You think you can,
as well as everything else.
Everything else?
What is it then we can't do?
Many things.
- Well, for example?
For example, you can't fight.
At all.
Laugh all you want.
You can't, but are still fighting.
And lose every time.
Now this is really funny.
That's a lot of crap!
I'm telling you, you are uneducated.
You know nothing about history.
- It doesn't change a thing.
Can't make shashlik, can't fight.
It's a fact.
I'll show you what I can do.
Go ahead,
kill me as you promised.
We're not in the house.
Go ahead, try.
You'll see what a Georgian
is capable of! Let's go!
Alright. Let's see.
Calm down!
Sit down.
Sit!
Enough of that.
Or I swear, I saved you both
and will kill as well.
What is it with you, guys?
Kill you, kill you...
Who gave you that right?
Who?
- The war.
Moron!
Shall I pour you?
- Go ahead.
Not for you, yet. You're sick.
Well, symbolically.
I don't drink at all,
don't pour me any.
What shall we drink to?
- To death!
Go ahead, Margus.
I can't drink to death.
Why? It's their very mother.
They are the children of death.
I'm sorry, Ivo. It will not
happen again, by Allah's name.
What does it matter where you will
kill each other, here or there.
You recover, go back to the front
and kill there.
It's silly to make you sit
at the same table.
I'll drink to life.
- No. To death.
I proposed a toast to death!
Margus?
- Yes.
Did you solve your
tangerine problem?
Eh, I'm probably annoying you all
with my tangerines. - Not at all.
You see, it's not about money,
although it's big money.
It's just that a beautiful crop
will perish... A pity.
Well, we can help you.
- Yes.
Come on, I have
plenty of helpers anyway.
Let's check on Ivo,
he probably felt offended.
Ivo's not offended,
Ivo's pissing.
They probably bombed Aslan
by the river.
Perhaps you'd eat something.
Good morning!
- Morning.
Hello, Ivo.
- Hello.
I'd like to give you some money,
for going back to Estonia.
What are you talking about?
I can't take that sort of money.
What sort?
- That sort.
But I'm a mercenary, it's my pay.
We honour the Christian religion.
- We honour other religions, too.
But why are you suddenly talking
about religion anyway?
No reason.
Who were the other Georgians
for you?
Why are you asking?
- I'm curious.
Not very close friends. We met
here. But they were good guys.
Ibrahim was like a brother to me.
We grew up together. - I'm sorry.
We need some firewood. I'll bring.
- Sit, let me.
No, I'll go and take
a little walk, too.
I'm sorry, too, that your
copatriots were killed. Good guys.
Could have taken it,
he meant it from his heart.
I'll go help him.
Let me help.
- No, I need exercise.
You're looking at the picture
of my granddaughter awfully often.
Why?
- I'm not. You're wrong.
No, you are looking.
- Frankly, she's very pretty.
I don't seem to be able
to keep my eyes off her.
Sorry, Ivo.
She's even prettier in person.
Her name is Mari.
She means everything to me.
Mari lives in Estonia?
- She used to live in this house.
She left with the others,
when war broke out here.
Why didn't you leave?
Hard to fare this place well?
You love it here?
I love it. And hate.
Do you have a family?
- Just my mother.
My father died ten years ago.
Brothers, sisters?
- No, I'm alone.
And what were you doing
in peacetime?
I'm an actor. I play in a theatre.
- Seriously?
In cinema, too?
- Rarely.
They almost don't make films
over here anymore, no money.
And then decided to go to war.
- Yes. Felt obliged to and went.
Didn't even tell my mother.
When the war is over,
I'll come back to Tbilisi
to see you acting. And then we'll
sit down and remember these days.
And remember Ahmed.
- No, Ahmed will be there with me.
And will clap for you.
Come here! You!
Don't show yourself! Sit quietly!
Where are the guns?
- There, under the bed.
But don't touch them.
What are you fucking smirking at?
Georgian? - I'm not Georgian.
Sure?
- He's yours, guys.
Stay there, old man!
- I'm a Chechen.
Then say something in Chechen!
Came to fight on your side,
was wounded and he cured me.
Comrade officer,
I know your major. - Quiet!
Are you an idiot or what?
Say something in Chechen!
Say something, motherfucker!
And what does that mean?
No, he's Georgian alright.
You're deaf or what?
- It's 'motherfucker' in Chechen.
Fucking shoot him!
- Don't, he is yours!
I said, quiet!
Execute my command!
Captain, maybe he is ours?
- Don't!
Nika, throw me a gun!
Cover me!
That's it, Nika, that's it!
They're dead.
Margus!
Motherfucker...
Finished?
- Yes.
There's only this cross of yours.
Like this?
- Yeah.
And Nika?
- We'll bury him elsewhere.
Where?
- Beside my son.
What did he die of?
- Was killed when the war broke.
By whom?
- God knows.
He went to the war at once.
To protect our land, he said.
I tried to talk him out of it,
explained that it's nobody's war,
but he wouldn't listen.
So the Georgians killed him.
- Yes.
But what difference does it make?
- How's that?
You buried a Georgian
next to your son.
Ahmed, does it make
any difference?
Answer me!
- It doesn't.
So, going straight home?
-I miss my family.
Ivo, tell me...
If it would have been me killed,
not Nike,
would you have buried me
beside your son, too? - Yes.
A bit farther away though.
I really don't know
how to thank you.
Go! I don't like farewells.