Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Even when my father passed away...
I couldn't do anything for him.
Jin Ho...
No matter how much I run,
I'm still in that same spot.
Jin Ho, are you crying?
Jin Ho, don't cry.
[Episode 7 - Coming Out]
What happened?
What did we do?
What was it again?
Does that mean he's interested in women now?
Then me? In me?
What about me?
You're going to work?
Last night...
It seems I was rather drunk.
If I did anything I shouldn't have...
Do you not... remember anything?
So you don't remember anything about
owing me money either?
I gave you five 10,000 won bills,
that's 50,000.
No... no, that's alright.
I was joking.
What kind of man are you,
to still behave so properly when drunk.
You were no fun at all.
If I did something wrong...
Please forgive me.
I drank too much last night.
Between friends, why concern yourself
so much about this.
It's alright, go to work.
Right.
He must have mistaken me for his lover.
No matter how drunk he got...
How can he do this to just anyone?
Park Gae In, are you an idiot?
A fool?
Why... Why does everyone treat me like this?
What did I do so wrong?
Everyone...
Why is everyone making me so miserable?
Thank you very much.
Jin Ho...
To me...
You're like a friend, and a father.
That's what you are.
Welcome to this house.
That's not the way.
No matter how much you want to succeed,
if you're doing this to use
Teacher Park's daughter,
you're a really bad person, Hyung.
It means there's nothing you won't do
to succeed.
There's not much luggage.
Yes.
No need for packing materials,
just the car will do.
Yes, then please come on Saturday.
You're moving out of Sanggojae?
Yes.
There's no reason for me to stay longer.
Yes, you did well.
If you keep staying there,
it will only upset you.
Right, take a break for now,
and let's begin anew.
I'll make a few calls to see what we can do.
There's plenty of people who want
to work with us.
By the way...
I was wondering if we should try this...
You know my mother,
she has a distant relative working
in the canteen of the presidential palace.
If we talked to that person,
and proposed a remodeling project of the
presidential palace, what do you think?
You don't find it funny?
Should I have laughed?
You... you really...
You really have no sense of humor.
Take this and go.
What's this?
We're at work here.
To use polite speech at work,
don't you even know that much?
It's an advance for the recreation
room design.
The rest is being prepared and
will be transferred to you,
according to the curator's orders.
Yes, Jin Ho.
Are you alright?
You left just like that last night,
I was worried, so I'm calling.
I wanted to buy you a drink.
I'm sorry.
Today is kind of...
Don't be like that,
it won't take a lot of time.
I have a prior appointment.
I guess there's nothing to be done then.
In any case,
keep up the good work, Jin Ho.
That...
What was that about?
What do you mean Jin Ho abruptly
left yesterday?
Didn't you know?
I thought you were roommates?
Yesterday, the Dam Art Gallery project
announced
the qualifying entry criteria.
All that Jin Ho had been preparing
to this point,
has been for naught.
No matter how much I run,
it's a waste of my energy.
Jin Ho, are you crying?
You're always like this.
Pretending to be nice and caring,
but in the end, you only see what
you want to see.
Oh well,
I guess Jin Ho had no reason
to tell you about such things.
[The landlady]
The number you have dialed
is not answering.
Hey, you.
From now on, this is where you live.
A hyung that looks exactly like you
lives here too.
He has long legs like you.
Look at this guy,
he's even carrying roses!
From now on, your name...
will be Jin Ho.
I've decided that.
I like this changing feeling
Even though we squabble every day
You know well how I feel
Too salty!
You roll however you want,
but I can accept it all
For me, it's only you
My lonely heart must have gone crazy
My two eyes only see you
It's only until Saturday,
Jeon Jin Ho.
There's no reason for you
to stay any longer.
Ta dah!
It's not much,
but eat plenty.
Exactly what ingredients did you use?
It's daegu-tang*.
(*spicy codfish soup)
So where are all the fish sleeping?
Well, about that,
when I put the fish in the water,
they still resembled a fish,
but slowly they started disappearing,
these guys.
Look at the way you stirred it,
you must have stirred the fish away.
It's the thought that counts, isn't it,
the intentions.
In the future, just...
show your intentions.
That's what I'm like!
Even when it's so tough that I want to cry,
when I'm seated before a wonderful meal...
Let's eat this and be strong!
Right, I can do all this.
Fighting!
These are the thoughts I have,
and then I feel recharged.
Then by eating and recharging,
live a fulfilling life.
Jin Ho, you too...
Pluck up your strength by eating!
Then, let's eat.
Please don't fall as you run,
always carry painkillers with you,
don't cut your hand while cooking.
You can take over cutting the ingredients.
If I fall, you can help me up.
If I'm out of medication,
you can help me buy it too,
what have I got to worry about?
Until when will I be living here?
What's wrong, Jin Ho?
Suddenly...
It sounds like you're about to
move out soon.
I was never going to stay here forever.
That's right.
That's true, but...
Even so...
to hear you suddenly say such things...
it feels weird.
I'm not moving out immediately,
so just eat up.
When I think about you leaving,
I lose my appetite.
You should change that too.
Forming overly deep attachments to people,
clinging onto them.
I'm that kind of person.
I guess I'm starved of affection.
Are you working?
Can't you tell?
I'm going to take out the trash...
So?
It's a little heavy,
can't you come with me?
You call that heavy?
I mean, we could go out, take a walk,
relax a little, it'll be nice!
I relax by working.
It's not like you have anything
to work on now...
What did you say?
No, nothing.
Do you have time tomorrow?
Tomorrow, why?
Let's take a last test tomorrow.
A last test?
Whether the training has been
of any use,
I want to do an overall assessment.
How?
I'll pretend to be your boyfriend,
you should treat it as a date with a man,
and make use of what you've learned so far.
So you're saying we'll go on a date?
It's not a date.
It's the last test.
But then, don't you have to go to work?
I have the day off.
Then tomorrow, I'll turn into
a flawless beauty,
and give you a shock.
Look forward to it.
Chang Ryul.
Gae In.
Chang Ryul, what are you doing here?
It's nothing, I'm off.
I'm leaving now.
Why do you keep coming here?
I just end up coming back.
Even though I know I can't
look you up anymore,
I feel so helpless and suffering,
I came towards you without realizing it.
I also want to have someone
I can share everything with,
but no one wants to listen to me, Gae In.
But you've always...
listened to me seriously.
Chang Ryul,
if you hadn't betrayed me,
I probably would have
always been a listening ear.
Gae In...
Actually...
My mother...
My mother, she...
Your mother?
What mother?
Why?
Did she pass away?
After divorcing my father,
the man she remarried
worked for some kind of international
cooperative agency.
If my mother leave for Africa this time,
I might never see her again.
Africa.
That's pretty far away.
Because of my father, she couldn't
attend my wedding,
she said she wanted to meet
her son and daughter-in-law.
She said it might be her last chance.
But these words,
shouldn't you be telling them to In Hee?
We're completely over, the two of us.
In Hee said,
she fell for the me in your imaginations.
You made me out into
the most perfect person in the world,
giving her misconceptions.
A person like me,
only to Park Gae In would he be
the most perfect person in the world.
Park Gae In.
I'm coming in.
Did she go on that walk alone?
That's right.
It's ridiculous, I know it too.
I'm crazy, aren't I?
To ask this of you,
isn't something a rational person would do.
Sorry, Gae In, I'm sorry.
Just treat me as a rabid dog.
Chang Ryul, you crazy person.
But my stepmother,
whenever I get beaten with
a golf club by my father,
she rushes over to block him.
Her hands were always covered with bruises.
Gae In, I...
I know this is completely insane...
But right now,
there's no one I can depend on but you.
You're really something.
How could you ask such a thing of me?
Actually...
My step mother
is the real mother who gave birth to me.
Your birth mother?
I thought she had passed away?
My father...
had me illegitimately through an affair.
So I was registered under my mother
who passed away.
It sounds incredible but...
This last request from my mother...
I really hope to fulfill it.
Hey, Jin Ho.
Our date...
Can we do it some other time?
My friend just called me,
said she had just given birth.
But this friend's mother is far away,
and she has no relatives either.
In that situation,
I really should go and take care of her,
such is the case.
Aren't Young Sun and In Hee
your only friends?
Well, really, Jin Ho...
My social circle isn't so narrow!
Wait...
Could it be,
because our date is cancelled,
you're not happy?
Why should I be?
I got to avoid an unpleasant task,
this turned out well.
The way you put things...
It was you who asked me out
on a date first!
It was you who bothered me left and right
about making you into a woman.
In this case, let's just end it all.
That was what I meant.
Jin Ho, do you always have
to speak so coldly?
I know.
You're frustrated because of work.
You...
Don't you know how to get mad?
Just get angry!
Fool.
Can't you be more truthful towards a friend?
Is this all you're good for?
Jin Ho!
Where are you going?
Why do you want to know?
Sorry...
I was the one who broke off the date,
but I got mad first instead.
I'm sorry.
But as for that last test...
You'll still let me do it, right?
Where are you going?
Won't you take me with you?
Stop fooling around, keep your head
in the car!
Jin Ho!
I bet you've never shouted out loud
like that even once.
Even when you get mad, you just keep it in.
When you're sad, you keep it in too.
Do you think I'm like Candy*.
(*from manga Candy Candy)
That's what I'm saying.
Since you're not Candy,
why do you keep your sadness and
loneliness inside?
I'm neither lonely nor sad.
Bottling it up will make you sick.
Here.
Now even if you were to shout
I won't hear a word,
so just let it all out, yeah?
Like that.
Come on!
Louder!
Stop fooling with me,
you're all gonna die!
Like that.
You go ahead and do it.
I'm telling you to give it a try!
It will really make you feel good inside.
That's my wish,
I'm telling you to give it a try!
Don't do that!
You'll cause an accident.
You're using friendly speech!
Jin Ho!
Let's drop the formalities from now on.
If I drop the formalities with you,
who knows what you'll ask of me in future.
Okay, in that case, we'll go for
that one in future.
For now, just give shouting a try.
It's my wish!
Just once, do it just once!
Louder!
Jin Ho, are you a man?
Even a woman can do better!
Like that!
Yah! You're all dead!
All right!
Yah! You guys are all dead!
Louder! Be a man!
Here.
So, after having given it a good shout,
don't you feel better?
A friend like me,
it's good to have one, isn't it?
Since we're already out,
shall we do the last test?
I'm not in the mood.
Precisely, since you're not in the mood,
so we should loosen it up!
Aren't you curious about my results?
I'm confident about doing well.
Park Gae In.
Yes?
Don't fall for me.
Because I won't love you.
Yes...
That's...
That's... evident, isn't it?
Is this the test, right here?
I'll have to get into it.
Please continue.
So here we are,
established lovers of many years.
I'm going out with you
because you look like a girl
I used to date.
I can't forget this girl.
No matter how hard I try,
I can't erase my memories of her.
Perhaps in the future,
I might call you by her name,
ask you to behave as she used to...
Would you be alright with that?
That woman...
You must have loved her a lot.
Yes.
I'll do it.
Because I love you a lot,
the requests of the one I love,
I'll try my best to fulfill.
Hey, Park Gae In!
Is this what I taught you?
How have you changed?
You're as much of a fool as before,
what's different about it?
No, I...
I couldn't help it...
The words came out on their own...
because you begged me so sincerely...
How long do you plan to live
to please others?
Then...
What should I have done?
To love...
is to throw your pride away.
Love does not ask you to discard
your pride.
It's about protecting a person.
Don't do this in future.
Don't believe people so easily.
Don't fall in love so easily.
Don't forgive easily either.
Please...
Become stronger.
I'll do that.
I'll try harder.
Then you shouldn't have accepted
that jerk Chang Ryul's request.
You'll never change.
This all I have to teach you.
Why?
Don't you believe me?
I'll work hard!
I can change!
Jin Ho, if you can't believe in me,
who will?
Go on in.
What about you, Jin Ho?
There's somewhere I have to go.
Will you be late?
I'm not sure.
Although my eyes keep searching
for that person
Although my heart keeps constricting
in pain
I believed that it wasn't love
I'm just a little lonely
Is what I believed it was
Like a fool, why didn't I figure it out?
Like a fool, why did I let you go?
Like a fool, my heart that's overflowing
with tears
Finally, it has finally come to know
That my love belongs to that person alone
Please...
Be stronger.
That person is
The only one I love
That person is the only one who lulls
my heart to sleep
Like a fool
I've finally figured it out
That it keeps calling for that person
Because I can't live without that person in my life
Was this...
Did you...
Don't forget...
that roses have thorns.
When you come to understand this,
I'll consider that you've passed.
Hey, that...
I've looked at the Jin Sun high school
sports centre project,
the conditions are better than expected.
I see.
And also...
Yes, Kim In Hee?
Manager seems to have gone to the villa.
I'll send you details of the address,
so you can look him up.
When Director Choi went to
the chairman's office,
they got into a quarrel.
I heard this from the secretary's office.
So I think there's still a chance.
Please don't give up.
In any case,
thank you very much.
Good luck, Jin Ho!
I thought the Dam Art Gallery project
was finished for us.
Why does Kim In Hee still call?
Unni, what's up so early in the morning?
Unni?
This is good.
That's right, from today,
my gay disguise will be revealed.
Young Sun, I'm a perfect man.
Get it?
You're doing fine?
Ah, that's right!
I noticed the last time that
your skin wasn't very good,
so I got you some vitamins and cosmetics.
Just drink this with water.
Once your skin is ruined,
it's hard for it to regain its former state!
Thank you, Unni.
But, Unni...
I have something to confess.
What is it? Tell me, tell me.
Actually, I...
am a perfect man.
Really?
Of course not...
Well, you don't look like one,
Seriously...
Actually...
I also have something to confess.
What, what, what?
I haven't even told Gae In because
I'm so embarrassed,
I...
What do you think of me, as a woman?
What?
Whether I see you as a woman?
No!
I just think that someone like you
might be able to tell me objectively.
As a woman, my charms,
are they lacking?
Unni, what are you saying?
Unni, you're awesome!
Unni, you're really very good!
Isn't it?
You're the best!
I really... receive facial treatments often,
and go to the gym regularly!
Unni, your body is perfect!
Unni, you're... perfect!
Isn't that right?!
But then, why are you asking me that?
It's just... nothing.
So as a woman, I'm... good?
Very good!
Really?
Meeting you has really been
a real blessing to me!
I need to use the restroom.
Unni, don't forget this.
You're so thoughtful.
What do I do now?
I'm getting addicted to acting gay.
Waiter!
Did you just get off work?
What are you rushing about for?
I told you the last time,
my friend...
has just given birth.
Now I have to rush to see her now.
Then shouldn't you have gone and
come back earlier?
Of course I have!
I've been there and back,
but the baby threw up in my hair.
So I came back to watch my hair,
and I'm returning there now.
Be on your way then.
Park Gae In.
Why are you spouting such lies again?
In Hee, you sure have a good appetite.
Because you're a curator,
I was worried you'd be picky.
Yes, Mom, In Hee has always been like this,
when confronted with good food,
she forgets everything.
That's right, they say people
who aren't picky about food
also get along well with people.
But then, In Hee,
you don't say much, do you?
Besides saying "hello" when you came in,
you haven't said much since then.
I'll get you more!
Say something!
Why are you only eating?
Didn't you bring me here just to eat?
Even so...
Delicious, isn't it?
In Hee, you eat so well, it makes me happy.
In Hee, let's have a long chat after dinner.
How you first met Chang Ryul,
how he proposed to you,
from the first to the last,
I'm so curious about everything!
Mom, I'll tell you about all that.
In Hee has always been introverted,
so she doesn't say a lot.
What are you doing here?
You're really pathetic, Park Gae In.
I heard you were going to battle it out
with Jin Ho?
How did that turn out?
Dam Art Gallery?
Of course I'd have liked to do that.
But Dad was, as usual, one step ahead of me.
In his typical manner.
Your father? What did he do?
He went and talked up to
MS Group's Chairman Choi,
and deprived Jin Ho even of
the chance to take part.
That's good then!
Because of the long-standing family feud,
I was afraid that you, the younger generation
would also be affected.
Why are you standing there?
Come on here!
I have something for In Hee...
This.
I received this when I married
Chang Ryul's father.
I want to give it to you.
No, it's alright.
Oh, how pretty!
It suits you so well!
Really pretty...
It really is!
Thank you so, so much for today.
Why are you giving this to me?
Mom gave it to you.
She gave it to In Hee.
In Hee...
has no right to receive this.
I have no reason to either.
Gae In, even so...
Since my mother gave it to you,
do what you will with it.
Do I even have to deal with such things?
Whether you throw it away,
or give it to In Hee,
you can deal with it yourself.
Gae In!
What happened, did you choke?
What on earth did you eat when
you were supposed to go visit a newborn?
Over there,
I finished eating all the food
people brought.
I guess I ate too much.
Go in and sleep.
Jin... Jin Ho!
I still don't feel very well.
Can you help me prick my finger?
I don't know how to do that.
It's really simple.
You just have to prick me with
a needle right here.
If it's so simple, do it yourself.
Well, that...
It's kind of scary to do it myself.
I... No way, I can't do it.
Jin Ho, quick, give it a jab!
Right here?
No, at this spot here.
You know it so well...
Right here?
Yes.
Were you planning to pierce through
the finger?!
But there's really a lot of black blood
coming out...
Did... Did I do it well?
Yes.
It's alright now, isn't it?
J.. Jin Ho!
Your father and Chang Ryul's father,
did they know each other?
How did you know that?
I suddenly remembered,
I think Chang Ryul must have
mentioned it long ago.
What did that Chang Ryul say this time...
I don't know about the concrete details.
Chang Ryul's father
used to work at my father's company.
But then...
Chang Ryul's father cooperated with a rival,
and stole the company rights
from my father.
So that's what it is...
When Jin Ho, you said
you needed to be tougher on yourself...
What's the use of being tough on myself?
Even if I pushed myself hard to keep up,
I'm still only jogging in place.
Don't give up!
It's not like you.
Slyly manipulating behind the scenes,
preventing you from taking part,
doesn't that make you feel wronged?
About that...
how did you know?
That...
I heard people talk about it at the Gallery.
Said that because of Chang Ryul's father's
machinations,
this happened to you.
Go to bed.
That is...
Jin Ho.
Let me make you something delicious.
Didn't I say the last time?
Even when there's something very tiring
and wrongful,
when you're sitting before
a full table of dishes,
you think that everything will be alright,
once you eat and regain strength.
You'll feel your energy come back to you.
Be strong, Jin Ho.
Why don't you start by not eating
all kinds of rubbish yourself.
[It's In Hee. This is the address of Director Choi's villa.]
[Number 153, Chungpyung Myunsangchun-ri,
Gapyung-gun. Good luck!]
Grab a fishing rod and sit next to me.
What?
With you glaring so fiercely like that,
you're scaring all the fish away.
Ah, yes.
Have you tried fishing before?
No.
Take this.
What's this?
The fish here...
like this best.
They're still alive.
Give it here.
You surprised me, Director Jeon.
I thought nothing scared you.
Why...
aren't you talking about
the Dam Art Gallery project?
It's the reason you came, isn't it?
Right now, becoming your friend
might be the better option.
Have you...
ever made a love declaration?
Having lived so long,
I've only done it once.
I've also liked someone before.
Mine was a junior at university.
Mine too.
How did it turn out?
The problem was with me.
Before falling in love,
there were so many things I felt
were worth doing.
Do you regret it?
Well...
As for me...
Because that person used to work part-time
at the university library...
Without skipping a day,
I'd go to the library every single day.
Then I naturally confessed my feelings.
Even though it didn't last long,
we fell in love.
And then we broke up.
Not much of a story, is it?
Why...
did you break up?
To that person,
my love was like a poison.
That's why,
I suggested the breakup first.
The last time,
that handkerchief I lent you
was the only present I have
from that person.
Such a precious gift...
Why did you...
I suppose it's as you said,
so that we could become friends.
Because I've done everything I could,
I have no regrets.
The night sky I can see while sitting
on Sanggojae's floor.
I think I'll miss it a lot.
In that case,
all you have to do is to live here
for a long, long time.
You're here?
Oh, Hyung, this...
What's this?!
Isn't this Jin Ho hyung's?
Precisely because it isn't his so
I'm wearing it,
you have the same one too?
Because Jin Ho hyung has the same one,
I bought the same one too!
Are the two of you going out?
Well, Hye Mi likes him, so I'm copying him!
In future, whatever Jin Ho hyung
wears or eats,
I'll copy him.
Hyung!
Don't give this shirt to Sang Jun!
He's going to stretch it!
This kid...
Tae Hoon, if you
continue not recognizing the boundaries
between work and personal situations,
you should just quit.
Wasn't Jin Ho hyung a bit too cold with me?
It was because you're copying
his dressing style like this!
You... too...
are copying his dressing...
I'm different, Kid!
My relationship with Jin Ho...
has a secret side you know nothing about.
Jin Ho, are you crying?
What would real love taste like?
Is it a sweet feeling?
What would a kiss that consumes
the darkness be like?
Would the sky light up...
What on earth am I doing?
But that...
what do you mean by that?
Even if I'm not here,
someone will take care of things for you,
so don't worry and keep up the progress.
But then why suddenly...
Could it be...
because of the Dam Art Gallery?
Because of that,
Director Jeon must be quite worried, right?
Yes.
The Dam Art Gallery,
I'd like to challenge it.
If it works out, I'll remain here.
But if it doesn't,
I'll have to leave.
Director Choi!
That's why I came here to tell you
in person.
Just in case,
I don't have time to say goodbye
when I have to leave.
Well, then.
Director Choi!
Fighting!
The concept has been finalized, hasn't it?
Do you think they'll like it if we barge
in there without an appointment
and offer to give a briefing about
our concept for the Dam Art Gallery project?
Kid.
Is that person someone for whom
we should set aside a time especially?
In order to settle this well,
we'll have to be thick-skinned about it!
Understand?
That girl...
Wasn't she the one who ruined your wedding?
Chairman, what excellent vision you have,
how can you remember a person
you've only seen once?
How did you know it was Park Gae In?
What she's doing here...
go and find out.
Yes.
You see, what did I say?
Looking him up without making
an appointment wouldn't work.
Chairman!
I've found out!
Park Gae In is the daughter of
Professor Park Chul Han.
Director Choi asked her to
design the childrens' recreation room
and especially invited her.
What?
Who is whose daughter?
Park Gae In is Professor Park Chul Han's
daughter.
You ditched Park Chul Han's daughter
and went to get married with
some unknown nobody?
What's with that?
Do you know who Park Chul Han is?
He's a legend among legends
in the construction field,
and you dumped the daughter
of this legend?!
Father, whoever's the daughter of whoever,
is that important now?
What did you say?
Have you done anything right?
Oh, I really...
Is there really no more hope for
the Dam Art Gallery project?
Don't even mention it.
When I tried looking up the homepage
just now, it had been closed down.
It looks like the participants aren't
very happy about it.
After a few days, I'm sure
a confirmation will be out.
In any case, I think you should take
that shirt off.
It really doesn't suit you.
You're starting on this again?!
Take it off, I said take it off!
I don't want to look like
a couple with you!
It really doesn't suit you, quick!
Hey, the coffee!
You spilt my coffee!
You might as well take it off, then.
What's there to take off?
Take it off!
I have no other clothes besides this!
I don't care, just take it off!
Really, don't be like this,
I beg you, seriously.
Just take it off, Hyung.
Take it off...
Gae In.
This is...
Don't tell me...
The two of you...
No, no...
Let me explain.
Sang Jun, how could you do this?
You know very well what Jin Ho
is going through now.
As Jin Ho's lov...
I'm really disappointed, Sang Jun.
I really wanted to wish your love well.
- How could you...
- What's happening?
No, that is...
Gae In, she...
misunderstood my relationship with Tae Hoon.
You know you're the only one for me.
Are you shy because Gae In is here?
You and Tae Hoon should really...
You're jealous, aren't you?
Get out!
Well done.
A two-timing cad like that shouldn't be
forgiven easily.
We were never going out together.
The two of us.
What?
You misunderstood from the start.
G.. G...
I...
am actually not...
You know,
we really had a misunderstanding just now,
I really don't have such a relationship
with Tae Hoon.
He's just a man.
That guy is really...
I nearly forgot why I came here!
I just came from a meeting with Director Choi.
The Dam Art Gallery project might
turn out well after all,
so he said not to worry.
That's why I came here.
He said he'd use his position as a stake.
Using that as a stake to fight it out,
he's sure to win, isn't he?
That's why,
don't feel too down about it.
You could have just called
to tell me such a thing.
Your smiling face,
I wanted to see it directly.
Yes. Yes.
Park Gae In still hasn't returned
to the art gallery.
Yes.
He's next to me.
Yes?
It's Park Gae In!
She's getting off from Jeon Jin Ho's car?
What relationship do the two have?
It's because of me.
She knows I don't get along with him,
so this is her revenge.
I don't think that's the case...
Chang Ryul!
Hey! Joe!
How long has it been now?
I know, right?
I heard you came to Korea.
I heard you got married?
That's right,
she a curator in this art gallery,
isn't she?
Yes, well...
I got married, didn't I...
But then how did you know about that?
Oh, Director Choi,
I kind of know him.
My friend is also considering holding
her personal exhibition here,
so I came with her to check it out.
Is that so?
You know Director Choi?
Just a little, on exchange.
In any case, because we weren't
of the same kind,
we weren't very close either.
A different kind?
What do you mean by that?
Well... Director Choi is... special.
Special?
I don't understand.
What's that supposed to mean?
Well let me ask you something.
Do you know what he likes?
I don't know, you tell me.
If I'd known it meant to much to you,
I'd have returned it to you sooner.
I'm sorry about that.
Since you've returned it,
it's all right.
I've heard from Park Gae In.
For the Dam Art Gallery project,
you're going against the management
and threatening to quit.
Whichever way it turns out,
I wanted to thank you.
Do you know?
Whenever I'm with you,
I feel strangely happy.
I feel the same way when meeting you.
Then you must know I like you.
I like you too.
Is that true?
Yes.
You're a very attractive person.
Come on, Joe, just spit it out!
What is it?
Ah, never mind, just forget it.
Man, what's your problem?
I was wondering about that anyway,
so you've got to tell me what
he likes, okay?
Well... You'll never be able
to fulfill his desire.
What Director Choi likes is...
A man.
I'm sorry but...
What did you just say?
It's as you heard,
from the first time I set my eyes on you,
my heart stirred.
And that day,
when I heard about your preference,
I felt there was a fateful connection
between us.
Surely not...
Then...
I didn't...
wish to make another declaration.
But since we're in the same boat,
I believed you'd understand me.
That's why...
I gathered up the courage to confess now.
I'm not...
asking you to rush into a decision now.
Slowly...
we'll give each other time,
to get to know each other first.
Oh my... and who might this be?
I thought a little nothing company
like yours
would surely have been eliminated from
this project already.
How is it that you still have things
to do here?
I'm not in the mood to speak with you,
so just go.
It's not it, is it?
It couldn't be.
The almighty Jeon Jin Ho wouldn't stoop to
pretending to have queer leanings
in order to seduce Director Choi, would he?
If you want to fight it out,
you shouldn't stoop to underhanded means.
Why are you always hovering around here,
you make me sick!
What's this now?
Were you trying to prove something?
Well, I'm disappointed, really disappointed.
Jeon Jin Ho, you're a disappointment.
I didn't think you were the kind of person,
who would make use of the fact
that Director Choi was gay.
I've never made use of him.
Then what is it?
Are you going out with him?
Why are you always coming in
and out of here,
you make me sick!
Answer me.
Admit that you're making use of him.
If not,
are you really gay?
Answer me.
That's right.
I'm...
gay.
Is that what it is?
You're really... not even a man?
What are you going to do?
If he knew you were like this,
how would your late father feel?
His only son,
letting such a thing happen to
the family line.
But then,
when did you start being like this?
You should really have told me earlier!
If I'd known, even out of pity for you,
I'd have given way for you,
and not snatched things away.
- And also...
- Stop it!
What are you, to sneer at this person?
Gae In!
What have you done so great
to despise this person?
It's not like Jin Ho wished to be born
this way.
Enough.
Only a man who loves women is a man.
Isn't a man who loves another man
also a man?
So you're saying you're a real man?
Because you're such a man,
you broke my heart like that?
I said stop it!
Jin Ho...
Gae In!
What's wrong with you now?
Let go.
Jin Ho.
Let's talk.
What's there to talk about?
I have nothing to say.
Get lost.
Park Gae In!
What on earth is your relationship
with that jerk?
Why are you always with that dirty jerk?
So now you'd even go out with gays?
Dirty?
What's so dirty?
Why would Jin Ho be dirty?
Be it a man or woman,
love is between two people.
You're just a nothing who's never
loved another.
So who are you?
To say that Jin Ho is dirty.
Gae In...
What's... wrong with you?
You weren't even like this when we broke up!
Even at the wedding hall,
you never even slapped me!
So what are you doing now?
That's right.
I was like that then.
Even when I was forced to suffer
such indignities,
I was a fool who couldn't even say
a word in my own defense.
But no more of that now.
I suppose Jin Ho must have changed me.
That person is...
That person is
That person is the only one who lulls
my heart to sleep
Like a fool
I've finally figured it out
That it keeps calling for that person
Because I can't live without that person
in my life
Brought to you by WITH S2
Written In The Heavens Subbing Squad
This is a FREE fansub. NOT for SALE!
Get it for FREE @ withs2.com
Main Translator: aceyyy
Spot Translators: soluna413, fore
Timer: hisashino
Editor/QC: snoopyvkd
Coordinators: mily2, ay_link
Are only men who love women
to be considered men?
So please park somewhere
and just breathe deeply.
You'll do that, right?
Sang Jun oppa,
is it possible you like men?
You know something...
Could it be I'm really in love with you?
What is it you want to say right now?
I want to start over with you.
C-c-com-coming out?
Congratulations.
On getting another chance.
Dam Art Gallery? Why?
To meet with Director Choi.
Are you going on a date?
Do I appear to be someone who would use
this project as bait to win over someone's feelings?
Han Chang Ryul...
is my son.
Do you really want to start over with me?
Park Gae In!
I...
have something to say to you.
Should we...
stop being just friends?
Jin Ho sunbae.
Watch dramas legally at
dramafever.com | crunchyroll.com