.:: La Fabrique ::.
synced to Temple.Grandin.HBO
My name is Temple Grandin.
I'm not like other people.
I think in pictures
and I connect them.
There she is!
Temple!
It's hot!
Come on, dear. You're holding up
the other passengers!
I can see the heat!
Do people live here?
The wolf is growling
and the man with the shotgun
says to Illya Kuryakin,
"Would you like for me
to open the gate?"
I'm sorry, Temple, you lost me.
"The man from U.N.C.L.E."
"The gazebo in the maze."
The wolf is growling
and the man with the shotgun
says to Illya Kuryakin,
Would you like for me
to open the gate?
"Would you like for me
to open the gate?"
You okay?
Aunt Ann, what is this place?
Just holding pens.
You don't have those
on the east coast.
Is this where they slaughter them?
Yes, it is.
"Would you like for me
to open the gate?"
Yes. Yes, please.
Open the gate, please, Temple?
Would you like for me
to open that gate?
Come on, Temple.
Temple made it okay.
- Say hi to your uncle Mike.
- Hi, Temple.
I just been tellin' Billy here
all about our summer visitor.
Are you a cowboy?
Excuse my niece.
That's not how we greet people.
You know better than that.
Hello, I'm Temple.
It's very nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
Ma'am.
Thanks for this.
I'll replace it tomorrow.
No rush. I got spares.
Do you get
"the man from U.N.C.L.E."?
Let me show you your room.
These okay here?
All my science fiction books
are there.
- How do I know this is my room?
- Because we say so.
It's your room.
So, you excited about college?
That's something.
Thank you.
I can't eat that. I have colitis.
I get it from nervousness.
- I eat pudding and jell-o.
- I know.
Your mom said.
So you didn't answer
Mike's question.
Are you excited
about going to college?
I want to stay in high school.
I like my science teacher.
Dr. Carlock's very smart
and he's been to college.
So I don't understand why I have to move
to learn what he probably already knows.
The desert spoons and teaspoons
go in different sections.
I did that.
Your uncle can't tell them apart.
And sometimes I can't either.
They're different.
Yes, they are.
I think it's time for bed,
young lady.
We get up with the rooster
around here.
You got everything?
This is my room.
Yes, it is.
- So good night.
- I don't want you to do that.
I'm sorry. I forgot.
No hugs.
Good night then.
Hello?
- Did I wake you?
- Of course not.
- Who is it?
- It's Ann!
Guess what I found balled up in
the bottom of Temple's closet?
A lovely summer frock
she didn't want?
It's taken me an age to iron it.
I'll mail it in the morning.
You couldn't get her to pack it,
not sure I can get her to wear it.
The other one came off
the minute she arrived.
How is she?
She's good.
Tell me.
She...
She got tense
when Mike mentioned college,
but then she calmed down
and she went off to bed just fine.
Stop worrying.
Temple's my job for the summer.
Worry about the others.
I'm sure
she's gonna have a great time.
You do remember, though,
something's gonna set her off.
I could really use a hand here!
So any idea
what your major might be?
Science. Probably psychology.
You don't have to decide just yet,
do you?
- It's better than boarding school.
- That's great.
- Lots of choices.
- Danny's looking at you.
He can see all around
without moving his head.
- So how do you know where he's looking?
- His ears.
He points his ears
where he's looking.
See?
He's lookin' at you, aunt.
And he's lookin' at those cowboys.
See? Now I got his attention.
Now he's looking at me.
You're right.
How'd you figure that out?
What are they doing?
What is this thing?
It holds her still
so Billy can inoculate her.
What happened to it?
It calmed down.
They just like it.
It gentles 'em.
Stand still and they'll come to you.
Won't harm you.
Just curious.
Can't help themselves.
Are you worried about
keeping up with the other students?
- I'm not stupid.
- I didn't say you were.
- Is it moving away from home?
- Hold it straighter.
Why don't you want to go to college?
People.
I don't understand people.
At least the people at school
know I don't understand them
and some of them
are my friends anyway.
What don't you understand?
Girls get all goofy over boys.
They talk about silly pop groups
and clothes and say things like,
"why are you so grumpy?"
When I'm happy.
And I say, "I'm happy". And they say,
"You don't look happy".
And I say,
"Can't you see I'm thinking?
And can't you see I'm sad?"
And I don't know
what they're talking about.
What do you look like
when you're happy?
Like this.
No, you didn't look like that
when you were telling me about
"the man from U.N.C.L.E."
You looked like this...
That's funny lookin'.
Happy.
And that's you angry.
Angry.
Happy.
I'm happy in that one.
I'd say more satisfied.
Satisfied.
Maria, can you give me a hand here?
Close it on me.
- Let's get you out of...
- Close it on me!
- Don't be silly!
- Please!
Close the sides.
Please!
Harder! More!
Did you see Temple's handiwork
at the gate?
Isn't that the darndest thing?
Hi, darlin'.
All these years Ann's been bugging me.
Like I could ever come up with that!
Is that it?
Is that what Temple's been using?
Yes, it is.
I know, it looks horrible,
but it helps her.
I'll go find Temple.
That's mine.
That's Temple's.
She's had a great summer.
You won't believe what she's fixed.
She's wonderful with the cattle.
I appreciate that.
I should warn you,
she has her mind set on staying.
That's not an option.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to attack you,
especially when you've been
so generous all summer.
How was your trip, mother?
You made good time.
It was long.
Thank you for asking.
You ready for college?
I think I'd rather stay here.
We've talked about this.
Sweetheart, you're gonna be fine.
No one expected it.
It's nothin' short of a miracle.
It's a miracle!
{\Franklin Pierce College
1966}
This way.
- Can I get that for you?
- Thank you.
224.
This is you.
I don't have a roommate.
Your roommate is coming
in another couple of weeks.
Remember?
Everyone else has a roommate!
Why don't you just think of it
as a chance to settle in, sweetheart?
Then I'll go back home!
I know that this
is strange and new,
- but you're going to be all right.
- I don't want to stay here!
Try and stay calm.
It's all right.
Try and calm down, all right?
I'm going to give you
a moment to yourself.
- What's wrong?
- Is she all right?
Interested in playing
with other children?
No, not really.
Plays with toys, dolls?
She loves to rip things.
And no speech yet at the age of?
Four.
She's four.
Not yet.
I'm sure it's just a phase, but...
Your child is clearly autistic.
Autistic.
- I'm not familiar...
- She's an infantile schizophrenic.
Infantile?
So when would she grow out of it?
I mean, what's the next step for...
We generally recommend
an institution.
For how long?
I'm not sure I would like that.
I really...
- I wouldn't wanna miss her first words.
- She probably will never speak.
And I'm afraid
there is no course of treatment.
I'm talking about
institutionalization.
But...
She was a perfectly normal baby
and then later she changed.
So I need to know how, why.
I'm not sure you'd... Perhaps
if you had your husband call me.
My husband is a very busy man
and I graduated from Harvard,
so why don't you try me?
I'm sorry.
It's been suggested that it may be
a lack of bonding with the mother...
That at a crucial phase,
the mother was cold, aloof,
when the child most needed
physical affection.
But that is not what happened.
We have another child
and she is not like this
and I did not do anything different.
Temple rejects me.
I want to hug her
and she won't let me.
I'm supposed to have done this.
Then I can undo it.
- You just tell me what to do.
- As I said,
I recommend institutionalization.
Here is a list of facilities
that we recommend.
Dah-og.
Temple.
Dog.
Cah-at.
Cat.
Temple, try.
Mah...
... me.
Mom...
I know you can hear me.
All right.
I think mommy needs
a five-minute break.
Avez-vous lu la page, Mlle Grandin?
I don't want to study French.
I want to learn science.
Read the page, please.
Read it.
And what did it say?
"Jean-Paul Sartre
naît le 21 juin 1905,
à Paris;
fils unique,
il vient d'une famille bourgeoise:
- son père est polytechni..."
- You...
You learned it?
I just looked at it.
Then I have the page in my mind
and can read off the page.
I see pictures and connect them.
I only eat jell-o and yogurt.
I only... I only eat
jell-o and yogurt!
Excuse me?
I'm your roommate.
What are you doing?
It's a machine I just made.
Feels like a hug.
Do you want a hug?
It feels really good.
So when you got in your machine,
did it make you feel like a cow?
No, I didn't feel like a cow.
But it gave you pleasure.
It made me feel good, gentle.
- The hug made you feel good.
- Yes.
But you don't like
to be touched by people.
Do you like to touch yourself?
Touchin' myself's okay.
But when the squeeze machine
touches you,
- it feels better?
- Yes.
It gives you release?
Yes, there is release.
But I need it!
- I built it! It's mine!
- What's all the noise?
- Wait! Stop it!
- Pervert.
- Got it?
- Yeah, I got it.
23 hours,
59 minutes and four,
three, two, one,
zero hours, Mr. Solo!
What are you doing?
Stop!
I said stop!
She says she's not going back
after spring break
unless she can take it with her.
Are you still there?
Yes, and I really don't think
it's a good idea.
It works for her.
It's everything we've been
struggling to get away from.
They were perfectly clear.
No devices in her room.
Could there be a better way to mark her
as a weirdo and an oddball?
Just let us try, okay?
So that's it.
- It makes me gentle.
- She's different after just 15 minutes.
A different person?
How can you explain that?
I can't explain why the machine works,
but I know it's not sexual.
- As Temple says, it calms her.
- This does convince me
we're not equipped
to deal with Ms. Grandin's needs.
It makes her a better student.
She's able to concentrate,
to interact more easily.
This isn't very scientific.
- There is no empirical evidence...
- I can do an experiment.
I can see how it works
on other people, measure heart rates.
I think it'll work on everyone.
Let's talk frankly.
I'm not sure you can get anything
from being at Franklin Pierce.
Listen to what she's saying. She wants
to do her own science experiment,
something that you can evaluate
in her psychology course.
I have a pen and a clipboard.
Time.
Do you feel: A, claustrophobic;
b, constricted;
c, no different;
d, comfortable;
e, relaxed?
What was the one before last?
D, comfortable.
Yes, I'm quite comfortable.
C, no different.
A, claustrophobic!
I guess I feel relaxed?
Very relaxed.
"F" for "freak".
Hello? Hampshire country school?
I need to speak to Dr. Carlock!
Dr. Carlock? Yes. Please hold.
Oh, please, I'll take these.
I'll take these. Welcome.
Excuse the mess.
We just had a staff meeting.
Oh, good. They're here.
Temple Grandin, I would
like you to meet Mr. Hodges.
He is our mathematics teacher.
I'm Temple.
It's very nice to meet you.
This is mademoiselle Davide.
She is our French teacher.
Hello, I'm Temple,
it's very nice to meet you.
Hi, I'm Dr. Carlock.
I teach science.
Are you a scientist?
I'm Temple,
it's very nice to meet you.
- Are you a scientist?
- I used to work for N.A.S.A.
Temple's very interested in science.
I'd like to meet Belka and Strelka.
The first dogs
to come back from space alive.
- That's right, in...
- Sputnik V, august 20th, 1960.
We're changing schools mid-term
because Temple's been expelled.
I'm sorry,
why was she expelled, again?
Hitting another child with a book.
There's no excuse,
but I will say this in her defense,
I have never seen her strike
unless she's been provoked.
And other children have taunted
and bullied her constantly.
They make fun of her
because she doesn't
understand their jokes.
She spins to comfort herself.
She talks fast, often too fast,
and she talks repetitively
and then the children
called her a tape recorder.
She'll go into a panic attack
- and then they make fun of that too.
- Excuse me.
When was she diagnosed autistic?
She was four,
but I sometimes wonder
if that's correct.
Why do you say that?
You've seen her. She's bright.
We have a lot of experience
with children with special needs,
emotional problems,
neuro-behavioral issues
that we've made a number...
- I think that because...
- I'm so sorry.
I really have wasted your time.
I just can't do this to her.
Mrs. Grandin.
Mrs. Grandin, please! Can I
speak with you for a moment, please?
You don't strike me as a person
who would abuse their child,
or deny them love and care...
Now you wait.
I have done everything
that I can for Temple,
and if it isn't good enough,
then it just isn't good enough.
But you cannot to begin
to imagine the chaos,
the upheavals, the tantrums,
and the pain.
Her pain.
You seem to be acting as if...
you have done something wrong,
when...
it's obvious
you've done everything right.
I think she's terrific.
I know it's difficult
when as parents,
we want our children to be everything
we hoped for them to be and,
if they're not,
we think it's our fault.
And there's never ever anybody
who understands
what we're going through.
That, it makes you feel alone,
right?
Mrs. Grandin,
I'm not an admissions person.
I just teach science,
but I feel this school
might be the right place
for your daughter.
I'd love to have her here.
The doctors wanted me
to institutionalize her.
I don't know.
Dumping her at a boarding school
feels like another way to give her up.
But it's not.
It's just the first step
in getting her out into the world.
You saw the children making fun of her
and you want to protect her.
Of course I do.
What parent doesn't want to?
But at some point,
she's going to hit...
life head on.
And trust me,
we know how different she is.
Different, not less.
Different, but not less.
You watch.
You'll make friends
and you're gonna ride horses.
What are you doing in with Chestnut?
No one is to go near that horse!
Can he be my horse?
He likes being hugged.
I want to ride him!
You'll ride.
Just not chestnut.
"Le pain est un aliment de base
"dans de nombreuses
sociétés humaines."
"Il est...
Say, "il est".
Il est...
Why are so many fish in France?
French fish!
Excellent work.
Really excellent work.
French fish!
- What happened here?
- She hit him for no reason!
Come on, let's go.
- And he's done it before!
- Stop. Temple, stop.
Temple, Tim will be punished
for what he did,
but you cannot hit people.
You understand that?
Good.
To really get that through to you,
you'll not ride for two weeks.
But that's not fair!
Two weeks.
There's nothing there.
And he's been like this
for three hours?
I don't think there's anything
anybody could have done.
I'll send the boy around with the truck.
Can you do that?
I'll take care of it, Dad.
Where do they go?
I don't know.
Heaven,
maybe, somewhere.
Temple, when...
animals and people die,
they stay with us in our minds.
We can still see them.
So I think it would best
not to remember Chestnut like this.
I see it the day I arrived.
I see grooming Chestnut.
I see a picture of a horse
just like Chestnut in a book.
We passed a Chestnut horse
on route 119 near a feed store.
On a calendar at Aunt Ann's,
there was one in Life magazine
opposite the page of Mr. Kennedy.
Can you bring everything
you've seen to your mind?
- Sure.
- Even if it were...
an everyday object like say shoes?
I see all the shoes I've worn,
my mother's and other people I've met.
You have three pairs,
one needs a new heel.
I see the newspaper ads,
TV ads and...
Can't you?
This girl has an amazing mind.
Try teaching her math.
Her algebra's hopeless.
Or French.
"Why are there so many fish
in France?"
I want to show you something.
She thinks in pictures.
That's why she does so well
when she can see
that are being discussed.
Like...
biology?
Or shop.
Those are concrete things.
But language or algebra?
It's just gibberish to her.
What's that?
Do you want to see your French fish?
"The eels ate."
"Il est."
"Eel ate."
Ils sont, il danse, il pense.
French is full of "eels".
And this is what she sees.
She's an amazing visual thinker.
Let me work with her.
Fine.
We have five minutes left.
Who wants to see a movie?
JD, will you do the projector?
All right.
Now everybody watch very carefully
because this one
is all about optical illusions.
It comes as a distinct shock
to most people
when they realised
how limited and how curated
the human senses really are.
In this house, faces at the window
seem to come in assorted sizes.
Looks like Mr. Povey, doesn't it?
But there's nothing wrong
with the faces.
It's those windows
and what they're doing to your brain.
All right, here we go.
A small one and a tall one.
Let's see
if we can even things out a bit.
- How do they do that?
- Sit down!
Temple, sit down, please.
That is the question, isn't it?
"How did they do that?"
Well, that's this week's assignment.
I want one page, at least.
- A full page?
- All right, two?
All right, one page.
They mess with the perspective!
That's right, Temple.
And it was a room built
with distorted perspective.
But how?
Do you think
you could figure it out?
Maybe if you visualized it?
And if you build one,
I'll give you extra credit.
Weirdo!
Does she have to chalk the walls?
Look at her.
- I can't do it!
- I think you can.
But I can't!
I know.
I shouldn't shout.
But measuring perspective
didn't work!
These are the specifications
you need.
Success, Temple?
Give me a clue, please!
You have to think
of all the features in the room,
The walls, the floors, the ceilings,
the doors.
Got it!
But as you can see,
the horses are the exact same size.
And here is the room!
Temple, congratulations.
I think this deserves
a round of applause.
I think it deserves...
a celebration.
Five,
four,
three
two, one.
Now here's a question:
if I wind this up,
and then let go,
why doesn't the propeller stay still,
and the body of the plane
spin around?
That's simple.
The resistance of the wings.
That's absolutely right.
And watch this.
With no wings,
and just one plane of resistance...
You have a helicopter!
You're absolutely right.
You have a very special mind,
you know that?
You see the world in ways
that others can't,
that's quite an advantage.
And you know something?
If you weren't such a goof,
and you developed this talent,
you could easily go on to college.
What would I do at college?
With your mind,
anything you wanted to.
Just pick a subject.
Cows.
- Do they have colleges with cows?
- They do.
And horses and pigs
and goats and sheep.
It's called "Animal Husbandry".
Animal husbandry.
It deals with the care of animals.
Really, anything you wanted.
You could study people, psychology.
I'd get to understand people?
Well, that's the idea.
I'll stay here.
Think of it as a door,
a door that's going to open up
onto a whole new world for you
and all you need to do
is decide to go through it.
{\- Miss grandin?
- }First off,
I talked to my old teacher Dr. Carlock.
He said I should stress that it wasn't
that I hadn't done the work
because I had,
but I'd collected way too much data
and backed it up
with far too many citations,
that I needed extra time
to make it coherent.
Look at these results,
you'll see that it's not just me,
but a majority of people
who become calmer when using my machine.
And that really makes
a clear case for me keeping it.
And I should get a good grade.
- Did your...
- Certainly more than a pass.
Did your previous teacher
suggest the good grade?
That's me.
Leave it with me.
This is very important work!
You used a control group?
They were tested resting, seating
most of them got bored.
Page four.
This is excellent.
I think it will be a good grade.
So I keep my machine.
In that case, I'll stay.
I would imagine your new roommate
will want a say in whether
you keep the machine.
That's my squeeze machine.
Do I have to move it?
Don't ever move it
and I'll always know where it is.
It's almost time
for The Man from U.N.C.L.E..
They play it in the rec room.
Do you want to watch it?
- You can't watch The Man from U.N.C.L.E.
- I do.
I'd love to watch it.
Will you show me where it is?
Yeah, sure.
Kuryakin's tryin' to open the door,
but it's locked.
And now the floor's sliding
under the room.
There's a big drop
to lots of spikes!
The kids in the room hissing.
- Do you like Star Trek too?
- Yes.
Who's your favorite?
Mr. Spock.
We have a lot in common.
Maybe we can watch it on the radio.
- They broadcast it for the blind.
- They do?
Let's watch it on the radio.
You're quieter now.
Is that because you're
in your squeeze machine?
I was just getting out.
Is my voice that different?
It is to me.
Remember, I see you
through your voice.
Do you remember a lot of voices?
Of course.
I remember the sounds of places too.
We're the same,
only you have sounds
and I have pictures.
I'm off to class.
I have French class.
I hate it.
It's why I'm in my squeeze machine.
Your squeeze machine
doesn't bother me.
I know.
Bonne chance.
Good luck.
Thank you.
Excuse me. Is this seat taken?
I've always wanted to understand
the gentleness
that other people feel
by being hugged by their mothers.
Now I've made a machine
that lets me do that.
It feels like
a wire gets reconnected,
like something gets repaired.
If it wasn't for my machine,
I wouldn't be standing here today.
Instead I'd be hiding in my room
or spinning in circles
to calm myself
or hitting someone.
When I was younger,
I closed myself off from people.
I didn't even speak
until I was four.
There's a high falutin' name
for that condition:
autism.
Because of my machine,
I'm able to know
the kindness and love
that have been given to me
to reach this point in my life.
Today more than ever,
I realize I have not walked alone.
And I thank not only my teachers
but my friends and family as well.
As in the words
of the song from Carousel.
This is my door.
It opens to another world.
Arizona state students,
gather around.
Come on, everybody.
Come on down this way.
There we go.
Come on in closer.
Gather around so you can hear.
All right, class, listen up.
This is Don Michaels.
He runs the feedlot.
Thanks.
What we got here at any one time
is about 50, 52,000 head of cattle.
They gotta weigh 650 lbs
to get in here.
During months they spend here,
they'll put on another 400 lbs
before they move into the big house
for slaughterin'.
While they're fattenin' up,
we gotta keep 'em healthy.
So the first thing we do
when they come in and off the range
is put 'em through a dip.
Get rid of any bugs.
Excuse me there, buddy.
You okay?
That's a girl.
Are you here?
I was listening to the cattle.
Why are some mooing
more loudly than others?
I never heard so much mooing!
I've been around cattle
all my workin' life.
About all I can tell you is,
that just like females,
cattle love to yammer and gossip...
or sulk.
It's always just one thing
or the other.
- Like I was sayin'...
- There must be a reason.
I reckon' you could get
Dr. Doolittle on out here.
He probably could tell you.
While missy here is listenin'
to what are sayin' to each other,
why don't you boys step over here
with me and see a dip in action?
Now the biggest problem you got
with a dip vat
is that cattle can swim alright
unless they tip on over.
Then them babies'll drown
real fast on ya
unless you get a hold of 'em
and haul 'em out.
There you go!
This is what I was tellin' ya.
Jesus!
Come on. Earn your money!
Hold 'em up!
We're gonna lose that baby.
Roy, get a rope on this heifer
and drag it out!
There you go. You'll see inside.
It'll take more than that
to kill a cow.
Do you lose many?
We got to run 300 of 'em in an hour.
In a week, we'll lose one or two maybe.
We're doin' pretty good.
Dr. Doolittle,
how you holdin' up?
Too much for ya?
They like to walk in circles.
What do you know, boys?
Cattle like to walk in circles!
Dang, give that girl a prize.
It calms 'em down to walk in circles
away from the handlers.
Maybe you oughta wait out here
when we go inside.
Then when we have it in the cage,
it just takes one knock to the head.
So, Doolittle,
what do you think?
Where does it go?
Meat processing.
No, where does it go?
It was here, now it's meat.
Where did it go?
Professor,
I think maybe your young lady
oughta consider another line of work.
Mooing?
You want to do research
and write your master's on mooing.
Cattle like curves.
They don't moo at curves.
Miss Grandin,
when we accepted you,
we were impressed you had excelled
at your previous school.
A master's thesis on mooing
strikes me as a lowering of the bar
And I will not be the first person
to give you an easy ride
because of your autism.
- Come up...
- Cattle are prey animals.
My autism allows me
to understand prey animals well.
I can visualize
the flight zones of cattle.
A handler outside the flight zone
can keep an animal circling
in a calm and orderly manner.
But stepping into the flight zone
panics the cattle.
And they change from soft moos
to loud mooing.
Prey animals don't make noises
that will draw attention to 'em
unless they're warning
other members of the herd.
They're warning each other
they're going to be slaughtered?
The loud mooing is the same
whether they're gonna be dipped, driven
around a hard corner or taken to slaughter.
They have no idea
what's gonna happen to 'em,
- We agree.
- but they're spooked.
Spooked cattle don't act straight.
They get bruised, scraped, drowned,
that all costs money.
It takes a good half hour
to calm a herd,
that costs money too.
It's not a good way to run
a stockyard.
I believe what's good for cattle
is also good for business.
Get the yard to sign off on it.
You mean Don.
That's who's in charge.
Sorry, ma'am.
No women on the lot.
My name is Temple Grandin.
- I'm a grad student at Arizona State.
- That's the rules.
I'm a grad student at Arizona State
and I was here last week.
Complaints from cowboys' wives.
They don't want no women.
I'm just doin' my job.
Ma'am, you're holdin' up the line.
You'll have to turn around
and take it on off the lot.
Please.
Don't come back!
John Richmond, press,
Ranchman Magazine.
Go on in.
It's a door.
It's another door.
Thanks, take care.
- Good mornin'.
- Go on in.
- Mornin'.
Hi, Sanch.
Good to have you back.
A long time since you worked here.
Yeah, it does.
- What's this, Purple Heart?
- It is.
We're real proud of ya.
Jeez, you didn't get all these
just diggin' latrines.
- No, sir. I was in Khe Sanh.
- Good for you.
Excuse me, sir.
I need you to sign my master's thesis.
- How'd you get in here?
- They just waved me in.
What are you gonna research?
Agitation in cattle.
Would that be mooing?
You believe that crap?
Since cattle are prey animals,
loud mooing is a sign...
No way.
Come on, let's get some coffee.
Did you bring back
a little china gals with ya?
No, they wouldn't let me
bring back one on the airplane.
You girls
got the coffee ready in here?
- We got a man that's thirsty.
- Come on in!
Do you have another entrance?
Pardon?
No, ma'am.
Do you have any jell-o or yogurt?
In the cooler.
Right behind you, darlin'.
By eating weaker and slower ones,
lions keep antelope population
strong and in proper proportion
to all other animals.
Light.
Shadow.
Reflections on puddle.
I've eaten bulls' testicles!
Ate 'em in my aunt's ranch...
Regularly!
This is a waste!
You gotta remember
to drink out here.
I have data
on things that make 'em balk.
Shadows, reflections on water,
- chain glinting in the sun.
- Is that right?
They won't walk in shaded areas.
They must see where they're goin'.
I've lots of important information,
I need Mr. Michaels to sign off on it.
Don?
Don don't sign nothin'.
- I need Mr. Michaels...
- You're not hearin' me.
Don don't sign nothin'.
I sign everything around here.
His signature...
but I do the signin'.
I'm not even sure if Don can write.
Say...
you're interested in cattle
and how they act,
you shouldn't
just hang around feedlots.
You should be out on ranches,
auctions, rodeos...
that sort of thing.
Got the big steer here. 1,000 lbs.
Let's go!
20. 25. 25 and a half.
- He's 25 and a half, 75.
- He looks mean.
25, 75. 30. 30.
Sold him on pat 17.
Look at his mama here.
Now, 75, I got 25.
25. 25.
27 and a half.
He's 27. 30.
32 and a half. 35.
Sold 'em.
Pat 21. Pat 21.
A good magazine.
Take a look.
Help you out
with all kinds of cattle questions.
See you back here
in about 5 minutes, OK?
Excuse...
It's all doors to new worlds.
Excuse me, sir?
Sir?
Very pleased to meet you.
Temple Grandin, bachelor of science,
doin' my masters at Arizona State,
studying in Scottsdale feed yards.
I was wondering if I could interest
the Arizona Farmer-Ranchman periodical
on a thesis I'm writing
on control systems and cattle
and why some work better than others
and how they can tell the difference.
How'd you get on with old Don Michaels
over at Scottsdale?
I told him
I've eaten bull testicles, sir.
I will read anything
you send in, Miss Grandin.
In fact, here...
Take my card.
You address it directly to me.
It's open.
Sir, Scottsdale feedlot signed off
on my cattle agitation study.
Smells like half the herd
signed it first.
No, sir.
Cattle can't do that.
And I don't need the magazine.
I'm a subscriber.
I just wanna make sure
you saw my article
on mooing as a guide
to cattle agitation.
Full thesis is still at the typist,
but you should have it by Friday.
Well...
Master of science.
Master of science
and animal science.
Fantastic.
I bet you're glad to be back east.
- I like the west.
- Oh, so do I,
but it isn't home, is it?
What will you do with your masters?
Your mother mentioned teaching maybe.
Great new school
over West Medford way.
I have a lot of more research to do
and things to write.
Right, you've been published.
You remember Scott?
Over here.
- Be right back.
- Our oldest boy.
New York Magazine's
taken a piece of his.
You remember Scott?
He used to spit in my jell-o.
I'm sure he didn't.
Tell Scott about your writing.
I published two articles
in the Arizona Farmer-Ranchman.
- The Ariz...
- Arizona Farmer-Ranchman.
One was on good moos and bad moos.
The other was on head restraints
and cattle chutes and killing pens.
Really badly designed.
Just terrible systems.
Just...
It's lovely to see you, Temple.
Bye.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas!
I need my squeeze machine!
I hate parties!
There are too many people
and no one listens to me.
They keep giving each other looks
and I don't know what they mean.
They're just uncomfortable.
People don't wanna hear all those...
- details about cattle.
- Well, I do.
I wanna be with cattle.
Sweetheart...
I don't want you to avoid people.
- They make me feel bad.
- Then ignore them!
You are the only
Master of science in the room.
And I am so proud of you.
Look at me.
Do you know if people...
tell each other things
with their eyes,
this is me telling you...
that I love you...
and I respect you.
I will never learn how to do that.
I know.
Damn it!
You are not allowed in here.
- I'm doin' research for article.
- We put up with you sneakin' in
when you was at Arizona State,
but you're done.
No college,
no insurance coverage, no access.
There are many articles
I'd like to write for you.
Firstly, how cattle can be introduced
into dip vats on their own accord.
- Secondly...
- Hold on, Miss Grandin.
Firstly, your articles
have been greatly appreciated.
I got a lot of calls.
Folks think you talk sense.
Secondly, I told you
I would read anything that you write.
Thirdly, young lady,
you need another set of clothes
- when you come in town on business.
- I need to be a press person.
Can I get a press pass?
You askin' for a staff job?
I ain't got but four staff,
and two of them
are bookkeeping and distribution.
No, I don't wanna work here.
I wanna be with cattle, I need a pass.
Well, we can do that.
But like I said...
Mary-Anne?
Get in here.
Sir?
How's that workin'
for ya, Miss Grandin?
It doesn't itch.
I like it a lot.
That's my rank.
They'll be able to see that.
Damn it!
Use it, Temple.
You stink.
Thank you.
Miss Temple Grandin?
I'm Ted Gilbert,
from John Wayne's red river feedlot.
- Hello, very pleased to meet you.
- I've been reading your stuff.
How'd you like
to put it into practice?
See, I lost my designer
and I need a new cattle dip.
Can you do it?
It's pretty simple,
but, I gotta present plans
in five days.
Sure!
- Very clever. How did you find this?
- I see things and put 'em together.
And all this?
To lead the cattle in.
Happy to follow a curve
thinking goin' back
where they came from.
- If you say so.
- I do.
- How long will it take you to do it?
- I have two or three more before this.
- But I need it by tomorrow!
- Everybody needs it tomorrow.
- I won't work quicker if you watch.
- I wanna watch.
This here is Red Harris
from Cattle Magazine.
Very nice to meet you, Mr. Harris.
He can't make the grand opening,
so we could give him a sneak preview.
So, Temple, will you put some cattle
through your dip while I'm here?
Hey, open the gate!
So if the handlers walk slowly clockwise
outside the chute,
then the cow will walk counterclockwise
through the chute.
See? They'll just follow that curve.
The cattle just keep calmly walking
thinking they're goin' in circles
and followin' their buddies.
And they're happy to follow a curve
because they think they're going'back
to where they came from.
They're okay because it's grooved
and they know they won't slip.
So when they take the next step,
their center of gravity
makes them drop calmly into the dip
and they just walk
through the water.
I don't usually tell people
what I'm gonna write,
but, Miss Grandin,
this is a masterpiece.
- I don't want you to do that.
- I'm sorry there, Temple.
Now, look, I want you to be dressed in
your best outfit tomorrow mornin', okay?
Just look at this thing.
It'll take us forever
to get them through here.
J.D., I want you
to get the torch and red,
and I want this out, this out,
I want those panels lined up
and we're gonna run 'em straight in.
Come on.
You two come with me.
- Grab the other end of this.
- Now hold on!
Look at this! I mean, look at that!
Who'd build somethin' like that?
Jess, get me some sheet steel.
We're gonna slide these puppies in here.
- Where's that sheet steel?
- Hurry up!
Let's go.
Get up.
- Put 'em over and get 'em out of here.
- She's here.
Don't keep worried, boys.
I'll take care of her. Pick it up.
Some dip you got here.
Who put steel on that slope?
Cattle can't walk on steel!
That's designed
so they'll walk slowly!
'Scuse me, little miss.
We just had three head drown in here.
That's your fault! You killed 'em
'cause of your stupidity!
And why ain't they comin'
through the curved chute?
That'd take us all day little lady!
Hey, that's my shirt!
If it's smooth, they'll follow it!
If there's stuff on it,
they'll get scared!
You can't hang things!
- You wacko!
- Put it all back the way it was!
Temple, what's goin' on here?
They killed three cattle
because of their stupidity!
They ruined it!
Just a minute!
Cattle aren't dangerous!
And they're predictable.
- it's not hard to design...
- What are you doing in California?
But the cowboys
would rather prod 'em and scare 'em.
Did you drive all night?
I designed a dip vat
at John Red River feedlot
based on the way cattle
see and behave
and the editor of Cattle Magazine
said it was a masterpiece
but the cowboys
killed three cows in it. Three...
in five minutes
because they wouldn't
follow my design!
- Would you like to sit down, or...
- I can't protect the cattle...
Would you like a cup of tea?
... system from the moment they enter
to the moment they get slaughtered.
- You're talking about a slaughterhouse?
- Of course they'll be slaughtered.
Do you think we'd have cattle
if people didn't eat 'em every day?
They'd just be funny-lookin' animals
in zoos.
No, we raise them for us.
That means we owe them some respect.
Nature is cruel,
but we don't have to be.
I wouldn't want to have my guts
ripped out by a lion.
I'd much rather die in a slaughterhouse
if it was done right!
- It seems to me that you should be...
- We can easily do it in a way
where they don't feel pain
and they don't get scared.
- And their cortisol levels...
- Did you hear what I said?
I think you're the one
who should design the slaughterhouse.
I know a slaughterhouse that's a mess
and I know exactly how to fix it.
It's a door.
It's another door.
Can I help you?
Hello, it's very nice to meet you.
I'd like to tour your slaughterhouse.
Excuse me?
Hello, it's very nice to meet you.
I'd like to tour your slaughterhouse.
We don't do tours, ma'am.
I designed a drip vat
at John Wayne's red river feedlot
- that the editor of Cattle Magazine...
- Security? Can I get security?
I'm so sorry to leave this message
on your answering machine,
but I thought you'd want to know
that your friend
Dr. Carlock has died.
I just saw him!
Apparently, he'd been sick
for some time.
You can call me anytime.
Bye, sweetheart.
I just saw him.
What are they doing?
They're paying their respects.
It's a way of saying
thank you and goodbye.
I said goodbye when I saw him.
This is a final chance
to say goodbye.
- Are you all right?
- I'm leaving now.
- It isn't over yet.
- I said goodbye when I saw him.
He's not there.
I've got him in my mind.
Do you know where they go?
No, I don't.
Okay.
I'm gonna go now.
Drive safely.
There you are, ma'am.
My, that's a pretty blouse.
I hope you don't mind me sayin' so.
Some people think I'm forward,
but, if I like somethin',
I just come right out
and just compliment 'em.
It's nice to get a compliment,
don't you think?
Thank you. It's very nice to meet you.
I'm Temple Grandin.
Well, it's nice to meet you too.
I'm Betty.
Well then, there we are.
Are you waitin' to meet somebody?
No, I have trouble with automatic doors
sometimes when I'm nervous.
I'm autistic.
My son is artistic and he's got
the same thing with airplanes.
Come on.
You just come along with me.
All right.
Come on.
And I'll make sure
that they stay open.
All right? You are safe now.
You're safe.
My pleasure.
Are you a horsewoman?
I mean, you know, your shirt?
I like horses,
but I work with cattle.
I designed a dip
that Cattle Magazine called brilliant.
Oh my golly,
my husband read about you.
He works over at Abbot.
- Abbot slaughterhouse?
- Yeah. You heard of it?
I wanna redesign it. I went there,
but they wouldn't let me meet with them.
But I have several ideas
about how to make a new facility
that will be much more
humane and efficient.
I guess you just have
to meet my husband then.
How wonderful
that we bumped into each other.
A door opened and I went through it.
Yes, you did.
And I held it.
This looks like an airport for cows.
I didn't mean that as a compliment.
And conveyor belts for cattle?
Do you have any idea
what the cost is on this?
And you've got
solid walls and floors.
We have those slatted for a reason.
- It's cheaper.
- I'm sorry.
It's clear you don't have the experience
to design something like this.
The walls are solid so the cattle
won't be distracted
by light or movement outside.
They balk at unexpected things.
I'm sure that's nice for the cattle,
but the cost, miss...
How much money does it cost you
to pay handlers to prod the cattle along
and then hold 'em back
when they stampede?
How many times a day do your chutes stop
because of pile-ups?
How many cows break a leg
and bring everything to a halt?
With my system,
there'd be none of that.
There'd be a steady calm flow.
That sounds great, but you don't have
any idea of whether it'll work.
But I do.
I'm like Nikola Tesla or Thomas Edison,
I know it will work
'cause I've been through it
a thousand times in my head.
I can see a chute
just as the cattle will
because my autism lets me do it.
I can walk through a plan
in my mind,
examining every beam
and every rivet.
You just see a plan,
but I'm walkin' through the whole plant.
Okay, the cattle go
through series of solid curves.
The floor is solid too... grooved.
The chute gets smaller,
but the cattle won't mind.
They don't see any danger.
They think
they're just gettin' into another truck.
The stairway leads
them gently upwards.
The floor becomes a conveyor.
A rest rises up to meet their chest
so they're comfortably carried.
They'll be very calm.
Nature is cruel,
but we don't have to be.
We owe them some respect.
I touched the first cow
as it was being stunned.
In a few seconds, it was gonna be
just another piece of beef, but...
In that moment,
it was still an individual.
It was calm
and then it was gone.
I became aware
of how precious life was.
And I thought about death
and I felt close to God.
I don't want my thoughts
to die with me.
I want to have done something.
Thank you for inviting me.
You were the one person
I wanted here.
Other people would have been overwhelmed
by what they were seeing.
It would have confused them.
I knew you would be the only one
able to sense what was really going on,
who could feel
what I was trying to accomplish.
There are a lot of things
I can't understand,
but I still want my life
to have meaning.
I don't know that I want to hear
from any more experts.
If you will please let me finish.
Will you please let me finish?
With intensive psychotherapy,
an autistic child can be treated...
But the Rimland report plainly shows
autism isn't a psychological problem.
Calm down.
Calm done, sweetie.
It would be better
if you could get her to sit calmly.
Try to control her.
But we were told self-stimming is good.
It eventually calms them.
Self-stimming is self-comforting.
Self-stimulation...
Rocking, spinning, rolling...
Well, I think spinning is good.
And rolling too.
Self-stimulation does seem
to eventually calm the nervous system.
It can be a way to compensate
for not being held.
And being held
by another person is scary,
but rolling
or being held by surfaces
produces the calming effect
that ordinary children get from a hug.
How old's your child?
Well, I don't have children.
No, I'm autistic.
And I need the sensation
of being hugged.
And I've developed a machine
that I get into
and hugs me
and I'm different afterwards.
I'm more social.
Well, I didn't speak
until I was four
and now I have a B.A. and a masters
and I'm studying for my doctorate.
Please don't shout!
Please!
Most autistic people
are very sensitive
to sounds and colors.
Over-stimulation hurts.
People talkin' too much at once,
you know, can cause us to panic.
How did you get cured?
Well, I'm not cured.
I'll always be autistic.
My mother refused to believe
that I wouldn't speak.
And when I learned to speak,
she made me go to school.
And in school and at home,
manners and rules
were really important.
They were pounded into me.
I was lucky.
All these things worked for me.
Everyone worked hard
to make sure that I was engaged.
I mean, they knew I was different,
but not less.
You know, I had a gift.
I could see the world in a new way.
I could see details
that other people were blind to.
My mother pushed me
to become self-sufficient.
I worked summers at my aunt's ranch.
I went to boarding school
and college
and those things
were uncomfortable for me at first,
but they helped me
to open doors to new worlds.
Excuse me, please,
but we want to hear everything.
Are you a scientist?
- You cannot hit people.
- Think you can figure it out?
Four, three, two, one.
I have a pen and a clipboard.
- Think of it as a door.
- Just take one knock to the head.
I don't understand
why people are cruel for no reason!
You have a very special mind.
You see the world
in ways that others can't.
Miss Grandin, this is a masterpiece.
A door opened and I went through it.
Yes, you did, and I held it.
I'm Temple Grandin.
{\Temple is a professor
at Colorado State University}
{\and lectures worldwide
on autism and animal handling.}
{\In North America,
over half the cattle}
{\are handled in humane systems
she has designed.}
www.sous-titres.eu
synced by rogard to Temple.Grandin.HBO