Your boss has given you this factory.
What do you think?
So he's the main character
in this story?
Hasn't this blocked all chance of a
workers' revolution in the future?
Is his act unique, or a general
modern world tendency?
A general tendency, I think
Can such acts, as symbols of
a new source of power...
...herald the transformation of
all humanity into the bourgeoisie?
The bourgeoisie will never turn
all humanity into bourgeoisie
So the not very original answer is:
No matter what he does, even giving
away a factory...
...a bourgeois is always wrong
- Is that it?
- I don't want to reply
This bourgeoisie is making
revolutionary changes...
...in our situation
It's identifying all humanity
with the bourgeois class
It no longer faces a class struggle...
...using the army, the nation
or the church
Then it would fail; it would lose
its natural allies
You must answer the new questions
raised by the bourgeoisie
Of course
What are the answers to these
questions?
God led the people about
through the way of the wilderness
ARRIVING TOMORROW
Pietro, how about some music?
Well, do you feel better?
It was nothing.
Sorry. I'm afraid it's all rather
makeshift
It's fine
It's been a real invasion
I used to sleep in this room
when I was little
I'm here
Sorry
Your friends are calling you
You're a serious player
These are my friends
What's the time?
I don't know
- What does it matter?
- It's six o'clock
It's about a sick man like me
Even in this disagreeable situation
Ivan Ilich found comfort
Gerasim came to wash him, Gerasim
was a clean, fresh peasant boy
What are you reading?
His life was his and his alone
It would take longer to duplicate
his goodness than to create a star
The godhead which had come
without my hoping for it...
... has not returned, and will
never return again
I like speeding. Now I'll show you
what the car can do
I believe you, but I'm not young
any more
You're not Gerasim...
...it's difficult to face you
There are two reasons
I must talk to you
Firstly, there's my moral sense
Then there's a sort of confusion
within me...
...which maybe I can only clarify
by talking about it
You have seduced me, Lord,
and I have let myself be seduced
You have violated me
and you have prevailed
I have become an object of daily
derision, everyone mocks me
For I heard the defaming of many,
terror on every side
"Denounce him, and we will
denounce him"
All my friends awaited my downfall,
saying:
"Perhaps he will let himself be
seduced...
"...and we shall take our revenge
on him"
What did you say? So you do talk!
I must go. Tomorrow
I don't know myself any more
Because what made me the same
as others has been destroyed
I was like all the others,
maybe with many faults
You've made me different by taking
me from the natural order of things
While you were near,
I didn't realize it
Now I understand, you're leaving...
...and knowing I'm losing you
makes me aware of my difference
What will become of me from now on?
The future will be like living with
someone nothing to do with myself
Maybe I must probe the depths of
this difference you have revealed...
...which is the innermost anguish
of my being
But whether I desire it or not, won't
this set me against everyone?
I realize now that I've never had...
...any real interest in anything
I don't mean some special interest
Not even ordinary interests,
like my husband's in his work...
...or my son's in his studies,
or Odetta's domestic cult
I had no interests
I don't know how I could lead
such an empty life, but I did...
If there was anything...
some instinctive love of life...
...it dried up like a garden
where nobody goes
That emptiness was filled
with false, mean values...
...with a hideous load of false ideas
Now I realize it, you've filled
my life with a total interest
So, in parting, you're not destroying
anything I had before...
...except perhaps my chaste bourgeois
reputation. What do I care?
But what you yourself gave me...
...love in my empty life...
...by leaving me you're
destroying it completely
By knowing me, you've made me
a normal girl
You've made me find the right
solution for my life
Before, I didn't know men,
but I was afraid of them
I loved only my father
But now, in leaving me, you're
making me worse than before
Did you want that? Now the pain
of losing you...
...will cause a relapse more
dangerous than the sickness I had...
...before this brief cure
your presence brought
Before, I didn't understand
this illness, but now I do
Through the love you gave me
I've become aware of my illness
Now how can I replace you?
Is there anyone who can?
I don't think I can go on living
You must have come here to destroy
The destruction you've caused in me
couldn't be more complete
You've simply destroyed the image
I always had of myself
Now I can't see anything at all...
...that can rebuild my identity
What do you suggest?
A scandal like death in the eyes of
society...
...a complete loss of myself
How can this be for a man
used to the idea of order...
...of the future and, above all,
of ownership?
- I'll carry it
- No, I'll carry it
Then let's carry it together
- Have you a tape measure?
- At once, miss
Time to eat, miss
I can't help it. It's beyond my
expertise. Sorry
Open your fist, miss, please
How pathetic! I'm a real shit!
I'm not eating
You must eat. It's good
I don't want to
Why don't you want to eat? It's good
At least tell us what you want to eat
We must try to invent new techniques,
unrecognizable...
...which are unlike any
previous method...
...to avoid childishness, ridicule...
...make our world unlike any other...
...where previous standards
don't apply...
...which must be new,
like the technique
Nobody must realize that
the artist is worthless...
...that he's an abnormal,
inferior being...
...who squirms and twists like a worm
to survive
Nobody must ever catch him out
as naive
Everything must be presented
as perfect...
...based on unknown,
unquestionable rules...
...like an madman, that's it
Pane after pane, because I can't
correct anything...
...and nobody must notice
A sign painted on a pane...
...corrects, without soiling it...
...a sign painted earlier
on another pane
But everyone must believe...
...that it isn't the trick of an
untalented artist, impotent artist
Not at all. It must look like
a sure decision...
...fearless, lofty and
almost arrogant
Nobody must know that a sign
succeeds by chance... is fragile
That as soon as a sign appears
well made, by a miracle...
...it must be protected,
looked after, as in a shrine
But nobody must realize...
...that the artist is a poor,
trembling idiot, second-rate...
...living by chance and risk,
in disgrace like a child...
...his life reduced to absurd
melancholy...
...degraded by the feeling of
something lost for ever
DOWN WITH ALL STATES
DOWN WITH ALL CHURCHES
UP WITH PAINTERS OF...
Blue reminds me of him
But obviously blue isn't enough,
it's only a part
Who can permit me such mutilation,
what ideology can justify it?
Weren't my first miserable attempts
at portraits better?
Look at the state she's in,
eating nettles
Lord, what a scandal
I don't smoke
Which is the road back to Milan?
Turn left, then straight on
What would happen to me if...
...I stripped myself of everything,
gave my factory to the workers?
Let's go
Don't be afraid, I didn't come to die,
but to weep
Not tears of sorrow
No, they will be a source...
but not a source of suffering
Go away now