Jerk it back, Gramps!
Pull!
What's that?
Nothin', just a piece of wood.
Damn!
What happened?
The propeller's bent!
Dad!
What happened?
The propeller has to be changed
and the boat's all rotted.
We'll get 100,000.
If we demolish it,
we'll get 100,000 euros!
When will you earn that
with this work?
Dad, see how good
the old people in town live?
They go fishing, they have fun
and put their money in the bank.
You're the last one doing this work.
Sermon over?
Go take a nice walk.
Okay, bye!
Rest in peace.
On behalf of
my daughter-in-law Giulietta,
my grandson Filippo,
my son Nino and his wife Maria,
I thank all my relatives and friends
for coming together
in memory of my son Pietro,
who disappeared
at sea three years ago.
Filippo, you look good
inside this suit, you know?
I remember it on your father.
You're just alike.
Take care, okay?
Whose scooter is that?
It's even got the keys.
Try starting it up.
It starts.
- Ride it, you know how?
- Sure.
- Nice, like it?
- Yeah, a lot!
Take it, it's yours.
- Mine?
- Yours!
Thanks, Uncle!
Go on, take it for a ride.
Go, Filippo, take off!
Okay, I'm off to work, bye.
Bye, Dad.
How about coffee? Like to come in?
That kid seems a little rudderless.
Let Filippo spend more time with me,
please...
Filippo spends time
with whoever he likes.
Maria, let's go?
Bye, honey.
Where did you get that old clunker?
It's no clunker,
it's brand new, it's mine.
Lemme try it, I'll give it a go.
That's enough, give the scooter back.
What are you doin'?
You're dead! I'll kill you!
You're dead!
Get lost, don't touch the car.
Don't worry, it can all be fixed.
Ma?
Where is she?
Sit down I have to talk to you.
I want to paint the walls
and rent the house
to tourists this summer.
Fishing's no kind of living anymore.
The boat's become
an old hunk of wood.
It's worth more
demolished than afloat.
Meantime...
we can take tourists
around the island.
Then, when summer's over,
we'll demolish it.
With the money we get,
we'll start a new life.
We were taught to fish.
Filippo has to learn
other things now.
Ma, what's with you?
We have to leave this island.
I want you to see other things,
different, new things,
talk to different people.
- Wouldn't you like that?
- I dunno.
I dunno.
What? You're smokin', Ma?
Ma!
All these cigarette butts,
this wall all ripped off...
I don't know you anymore,
you're actin' like a lil' kid.
You don't even talk correctly.
That's it, I'm leaving,
I'm out of here!
Lil' kid!
What happened?
What did you get in to?
You broke it already?
- It wasn't me.
- Who, then?
Franco and his friends.
- And what did you do?
- I threw stones at them.
- Can the scooter be fixed?
- You gotta learn to fight back!
You've got to hit hard!!
Come along with me.
- Get movin'!
- My scooter?
Leave it there, get moving!
What are you doing?
The guy who starts it, wins.
Let's go.
Let's go!
Give it here.
Gramps!
What's wrong?
I'm not going on land.
You're not going on land,
but to the hospital.
What can be that serious?
Serious...
There's something for sure.
Ernesto,
if you feel sick again on the island,
I won't be able to help you.
You could write a prescription,
I'll go to the pharmacy,
get the medicine and I'll be okay.
Will you stop acting like a kid?
You need a hospital.
Turn that friggin' phone off!
Ernesto, listen to the doctor!
We go to the hospital,
do this check-up
and we'll stop worrying.
What are you scared of?
Scared? I'm not scared of anything,
I'm relaxed and calm
and I'm not budgin'.
Knowwhat, Dad?
I can't deal with you!
Good... get some fresh air!
Anyway, the visit's over, right doc?
I'll see you out.
See what I found,
from when you were little, remember?
Knock it off!
Up there, Filippo!
Come on, guys!
Hello, welcome to the island.
Interested in an apartment in town?
25 euros per person.
Go get the Texan girl!
Lentils, calamari,
lasagna, baked pasta,
it's all delicious.
Ask Marco for anything you need,
he's in a yellow T-shirt.
Would you like an apartment in town?
It's all remodeled, new.
There are boat rides,
my son does them.
- Boat rides!
- You'll see the grottoes.
Let me through.
Marco, get into position there.
Thank you, Captain.
- No one's stopping.
- Go away.
I'll go make sandwiches.
- Baked pasta, lasagna...
- How much?
Twenty-five euros per person,
it's cheap.
You'll be losing
a lovely two-bedroom apartment.
Hello.
Welcome.
Come in.
Leave your backpacks there.
Are these porcelain?
It's the family's collection.
There are wedding pictures too.
- This is you?
- Yes.
This is the courtyard.
- Nice garden!
- Thank you.
They like it!
Guys, they haven't got a sea view.
They haven't got air conditioning.
Do you have a boat?
We got a boat, we got fresh fish,
we got my mom's cooking,
we got everything.
My name's Giulietta.
Maura.
- Stefano.
- Marco.
- Where are you from?
- Padua.
- I'm from Arezzo.
- Milan.
- How old are you?
- Nineteen.
- Twenty.
- Me too.
- You're the same age.
- Cut it out!
I say it's fine,
we'll take it.
It's a deal.
I forgot, if you need anything,
we're right here.
- In the garage?
- Yes.
Okay, thank you.
- Did you tell them the price?
- Yes.
- What did I tell you?
- What?
Don't touch me in front of people.
Get me, Ma?
We're alone now, can I get my fill?
Knock it off!
Go away!
Stop doin' that.
Cut it out.
- Let's have a toast.
- Okay, a toast.
We'll toast to my son Filippo,
who fished three nice tourists today.
Three!
None at all, if it weren't for me.
Great, Filippo!
The little blonde?
Pretty, isn't she?
Yeah, she's pretty.
- The blond is pretty.
- What's her name?
Maura.
To Maura!
To Maura.
- Such elegance!
- Thanks, you too.
Thanks! Where are you going?
Just around.
- Ice cream?
- No, we're getting drunk tonight.
Fine!
We're here, sit with us?
Look who I found.
Can we go out in your boat tomorrow?
I'm going fishing
with my grandpa tomorrow,
the day after's okay,
but we leave at 9 a.m.
Will it offend your grandpa
if I go topless?
Top... what?
Topless.
Wear what you like.
She means without the top part.
Maura's asking if she can go
bare-tits
on the boat with your grandpa.
Last night I spoke
to Teresa on the phone.
Remember my cousin?
The one in Trapani.
No.
She said we could
stay with her for a while.
There's no lack of work there.
I don't want to destroy Dad's boat.
Sweetheart, we have no choice.
I have to work.
Here, on the island,
I can work only two months a year,
cleaning houses for tourists.
And you too,
what's your future here?
I'll take tourists out on the boat.
In summer.
We both have to work, winter too.
And what do I do?
Be alone my whole life?
Stay here with me,
wouldn't you like that?
Yes, I would.
And when you get married?
Marry! I'll never marry anyone!
Who'd marry me?
Gramps, come see!
Look!
Coast Guard, can you hear me?
Over.
Go ahead.
Who's calling the Coast Guard?
Motor fishing vessel, Santuzza here,
we're twenty-five miles south-east,
we spotted a boat
with illegals, what do we do?
Remain in the area.
Keep the boat in sight.
Do not approach them.
They're jumpin' in the sea!
A patrol boat's in the area.
Get the life vests ready.
If we take them aboard,
we'll get in trouble.
I've never left people
in the sea, come on!
Get closer.
Careful.
Take my hand.
Pull!
Pull the line.
Pull the kid up.
Grab him.
The woman.
Grab the woman.
Gramps!
What's wrong with my grandpa?
Hurry, take the helm,
get back to land fast.
Good, breathe!
Push!
Go!
Hi, we're ready.
For what?
The boat ride, with your grandpa...
- At nine.
- You forgot?
Yeah!
Wait here.
So?
I told them
we'd go out in the boat today.
Nowwhat?
Let's take them,
so they stay away from the house.
You're leaving me here alone?
Lock the door, don't open to anyone,
we'll be back in a few hours.
Hurry back, please!
Don't worry.
Thank you.
No... no thank you.
Understand what I say?
Little.
Now you rest,
eat and then go.
Okay?
Eat.
Yes, eat and then go.
Good morning!
- Good morning.
- Watch your head.
- We sit where we want?
- Where you want.
What's this guy want?
- Good morning.
The registration
for this vessel, please.
- Pucillo Pietro?
- Pucillo Ernesto.
- Where's Pucillo Pietro?
- That was my son, he died.
No title transfer papers.
You spotted the illegal aliens
on the south coast?
Yessir.
Why didn't you say
you'd taken four onboard?
- Didn't they come to the police?
- Yes.
But you're obliged to report them,
didn't you know?
- I got no practice with laws.
- No practice!
Then you'll have to practice up.
Could I see your license
to carry tourists?
I don't have one.
I'll have to seize the boat.
You can't be serious!
I'm more than serious.
This boat gives us our only income.
No permission to carry tourists
and, an even greater
breach of the law:
Aiding and abetting
illegal immigration.
Do you know the Law of the Sea?
Should I have let
those people drown?
Things have changed,
tell your colleagues too.
The craft will be sealed,
turn over the keys.
So, you want to ruin us!
The keys.
What's this? Get this off!
Have it out with me.
- Who's this?
- No, who are you?
Calm down, kid.
Calm down,
looks like a stuffed squid!
- Don't ruin your life.
- Get lost!
Move it!
Calm down, if you don't want trouble.
Good, keep him inside.
Come to the office
to read and sign the report.
Please get off, thank you.
Let's go, come on!
I'll smash everything!
They seized the fishing boat,
fuckin' cops!
Calm down and tell me!
Is it true that saving people at sea
is forbidden?
I knew it!
- Take them away.
- I don't knowwhat to do.
Keep them far from the house.
- What happened?
- Nothing, forget it.
What's this about illegal aliens?
Come on, let's take a ride.
There we go, good girl!
She smells your hands.
She was born with your hands.
What happened to Ernesto
could happen to any of us.
So we have to protest,
make them hear us.
All of us together...
have to pay a visit
to that stuffed squid they sent us.
We have to quit taking them aboard,
that's the point, pure and simple.
My father taught me
to save lives at sea.
But I have to teach my kids
they gotta change course
when black skin's in the water.
Why do you say that?
Have you ever changed course?
No, but if they seize my boat,
what do I do?
Come eat at your house?
Why, have you ever gone hungry?
I say... how's it possible
for a fisherman to starve,
when he's got his sea?
There used to be sixty of us,
the sea was busting with fish.
Each of us
had at least seven, eight kids.
We all went barefoot, full of lice,
but the important decisions
were made all together.
With due respect to you elders,
there aren't many
of us fishermen left.
In your day there were
lots of fish in the sea,
but nowwhen we go out,
instead of fish,
we fish live bodies
and lots of dead ones.
Excuse me, men,
I'd like to know
why you have to take them aboard.
The law says we mustn't do anything.
A patrol boat gets them,
pulls them aboard
and takes them back
where they came from, that's it.
But it's us who's here and these
new rules go against our own.
We live on a reef
in the middle of the sea
and we have to respect
the laws of the sea.
It's always been so
and has to stay so.
Sorry, men,
but we also live on tourism here
and tourists don't like
seeing these half-dead illegals
as they enjoy their vacations.
These people pay
and want peace and quiet.
Let's talk straight, all these
illegals and these landings
are bad publicity for us.
Mr. Publicity is here!
They're bad publicity for us!
Do you think we should let them drown
for publicity?
Isn't there a chairlift, Filippo?
We're here.
What did we come here for?
To see my animals,
I haven't seen them in so long.
This is Rosina.
This is Glorina.
Her horns are broken, happens.
Come on, it's damned hot
and stinks of shit!
- Maura, do something.
- Fili, let's go to the sea!
Yeah, but to the sea!
To the sea, to the sea!
- Sure?
- Yeah, we'll go to the sea.
C'mon, let's swim!
So...
We, from here...
to here...
two years of journey.
Then sea.
Nowwhere are we?
We're not on the globe,
this island is too small.
Done.
- How much?
- Twenty euros.
Have a good day.
- You're a lifeguard now?
- No, just helping my uncle.
What do we do?
How about two cots and an umbrella?
Sure.
Will we go back to the boat?
Yes, with my uncle,
we'll take a nice boat ride.
Everything okay on the beach?
- How's it going, gents?
- Fine.
Is it true some illegals
landed here?
Who says that?
They seized a boat
right in front of us!
Yeah, I heard that.
But the boat was seized
because he had
no license to carry tourists.
Illegals don't land here anymore.
Here there's just fish
and fabulous sea beds.
Enjoy your vacation,
no illegals here!
There aren't any.
They say lots of things
here on the island.
Where's the mike?
So!
Testing...
An announcement for all vacationers.
In half an hour,
we'll all meet here at the kiosk:
Sail the island,
swim with shearwaters
and diving competition, okay?
Maria, give us some music,
what's this morgue?
We're not doing the right thing.
What's the right thing?
We have to go to the Carabinieri!
Carabinieri? Great idea!
So they'll seize the house too.
If we report them now,
they can't do anything to us
and we come out clean.
Clean?
Clean!
Don't make me do things
I don't want to.
Then I'll go.
Whatever you decide,
wait at least one more day.
Wait for what?
We're wasting too much time,
we have to act fast.
Hello, come along!
Come here.
What's this, a protest?
Even if I'd wanted to help you,
after this mess
there's nothing I can do.
Come back tomorrow for the report.
Goodbye.
Goodbye!
You are blessed.
You saved me,
now you are my sister.
Sister? Blessed?
Hon, you have to go.
Go...
Exactly, you got to go.
Go to Turin.
Turin?
My husband work.
- Your husband works in Turin?
- Yes.
How I go to Turin?
Easy to say!
Maybe you don't get it,
you've got to cross the water.
You take the boat,
then a train, then a bus.
Sounds easy?
How can you ever make it to Turin?
Anyway I don't care,
just so you leave here.
The law says I can't help you.
If I do, the police will jail me.
No, police no!
Please!
What are you doing?
She's your sister,
why did you do that?
She's not my sister.
He not want the baby.
We long time in jail in Libya.
All women and children together.
At night, police would come.
Children see.
My husband sent money
for the police of the jail
and for the boat.
Many days at sea, no food.
The boats see us and not stop.
The boats see us...
they always go away.
I not tell my husband
about the baby.
What name did you give her?
She has your name.
What is your name?
Which one's yours?
Why are you being sneaky?
Get in, hurry.
Why should I hurry?
- Is it yours?
- Yeah, sit down.
No, it's not yours! Whose is it?
Are we stealing it?
- It's yours? No.
- You gotta be quiet.
- Quiet?
- It's not mine.
We're not stealing it!
Sure, we're stealing it.
The owner won't get pissed?
No, he won't.
How do you know?
- I know everything.
- You do?
Yeah.
- What's this thing?
- It's a fishing light.
A fishing light, you can see the sea,
the reefs, the dolphins.
- Let's turn it on.
- Later.
We can't see a thing.
Isn't it dangerous?
No! You talk too much.
- If there's a sandbar?
- Cut your yakkin', enough!
- My head hurts, you talk too much!
- Can't I ask anything?
Good grief, holy Lord Jesus!
Look.
Beautiful!
Do you smoke?
What is it, drugs?
Yeah, drugs.
Have you got a girlfriend?
No, I want to stay free for now.
Free from what?
Free.
What is it?
Why did you leave me in the dark?
What's going on?
Get in, hurry!
Get in.
- What's going on?
- Hurry!
Sit down tight.
C'mon, start up!
Let go!
Let's get out of here!
We'll capsize.
Let's go.
Stop it, Filippo!
Stop it!
Get out.
What do we do?
We have to go to the Carabinieri.
Let's go straight to the Carabinieri.
Let's go, we have to do something!
We have to do something!
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Shut up!
- Shut up?
- We have to do something!
- Go home.
Home? Someone probably drowned,
let's call the police.
Get home! Let go of me!
Where are you going?
You fell asleep on the beach?
Wake up.
Come on, we have lots to do.
Let's go.
Filippo, we have to comb the beach.
I'm talking to you!
Just sit in the sun
and relax, everybody.
Nothing's happened,
stay where you are.
I'm talking to you, Filippo.
Filippo, come here!
I'll never share my food with her.
I don't even want to touch her.
Promise you won't try
to hurt her again.
When Dad sees us coming with her,
he'll send us both away.
If Dad's the man we saw leave
five years ago,
he'll understand.
What's going on?
Open up.
I wanna stay here, alone.
You locked it? I haven't seen you
for two days, open up!
Open up!
Open up.
No, Ma!
Let me come in.
Ma, go away!
Go away, Ma.
Rhythm, guys!
A sail around the island,
aperitif at sunset!
Rhythm!
Dad! How are you?
Fine.
I'd like to borrow
your van for two days,
I'm going to the hospital.
Finally! I'll take you, wait for me.
- I'll go with Giulietta and Filippo.
- When?
This evening.
Get the keys from Maria,
I'll come say goodbye later.
Let's say goodbye now.
See you in two days.
Guys, are you ready?
Let's go.
The terra firma is waiting for us.
We're ready. Go.
Now.
Sorry, Giulietta.
Lie down.
Head down.
Faster, Ma!
What do we do?
What happened?
It's mayhem, some illegals
landed to the west.
They found two hidden under a truck.
It can't be done tonight.
Let's go home,
it's not the right night.
Come on, get it started.
Stop!
Get out.
Get aboard, hurry.
Hide!