Hey, boy.
(whinnies)
All right, come on.
Come on, Rowdy.
Whoa. Think that's
a bear in there?
It's only a rabbit.
You ain't never even
seen a bear.
Whoa.
You got some imagination
on you for a horse.
Come on.
"Total points
each varsity season."
"Greatest strength."
It's offensive, sure.
"Most memorable game."
"200-word essay"?
Bridle itches you, huh, boy?
Hungry, huh?
Look, I don't got any carrots.
I said, I don't got any.
You got that carrot detector
working full blast, don't you?
Here.
Way you're jumping these days,
nobody'd ever believe
you were a cow horse.
We'll ride some more
when I get back
from school, OK?
Hey, Mace?
Yeah, here.
Hey, Mace, what happened
to your 50 points
before breakfast, man?
I got to do this
instead today.
You'd better get changed
for school
if you're gonna make it.
Do what instead?
It's a questionnaire for...
I ain't gonna shout.
You come in here.
I'm changing.
You told me to change.
Well, when you're done
changing, genius.
That's changed?
Can't you tell school pants
from riding pants?
You'd better get
yourself washed, Tex.
Yeah, yeah.
What do you want to go
to Indiana for, anyway?
Well, number one, they got
the best basketball team
in their conference,
if not the Midwest.
Number two,
it's not in Oklahoma.
And number three, I got a shot
at a full scholarship.
Are you defrosting?
Just broke.
It's cold in here, too.
It's turned off.
I haven't paid
the gas bill in a while.
What happened to
all that money
we made last summer?
Oh, I blew it all
on a fun-filled week
in Acapulco.
What the hell do you think
happened to it?
Food for us, food for Rowdy
and Toyota, electric bill.
OK, OK.
I mean, how far do you think
a couple of hundred bucks
is gonna stretch?
Well, Pop's coming back soon,
now that rodeo season's
almost over.
Oh, that's been
another big help,
Pop sending home
all that fabulous money.
He did, Mace.
Four months ago.
That's not so long ago.
He's only been gone for five.
You'd better get goin'
if you're gonna make the bus.
Uh-uh. I'm gonna ride
with Johnny. Don't worry.
Pop's coming back.
See you in school.
(motorcycle approaching)
Yo, Tex.
(honks)
Go! Let's move it!
You're supposed to meet me
out on the road.
I'd like to have
breakfast too,
you know. Let's go.
Yo, Tex, you left
your books, man.
Hey, there's your sister.
Oh, Johnny, Cole said to tell
you to be home by four
to help him flush
his radiator.
Oh, damn. I was gonna go out
to the gravel pits today.
I'll flush out
your radiator, baby.
Hey, Tex.
Ugh, I think his horse
needs a bath again.
Oh, no, see, that's just me.
I'm a quarter horse by birth.
Yeah? I know which part, too.
See ya.
That sister of yours
is pretty and everything.
She must be a pain to have
around the house, though.
Yeah, well, we was all
thinking of pitchin' in
and buying her a dog
to be mean to.
Tomorrow we'll be talking
about "Paterson,"
the epic poem Williams
wrote about his hometown
in New Jersey,
which, who knows,
may inspire one of you
to write an epic about Bixby.
Now, before you all
race away for lunch,
let me remind you
that your book reports
are due on Friday.
And, Tex McCormick,
I don't want to see you
turning in another report
on Smokey the Cowhorse.
You've done it twice already.
Yeah, but I read it
both times.
Well, read another book
by the same author.
You mean that guy
wrote another book?
In the library.
Oh, wow.
See you later.
Way to go, man!
Hey, Mace.
Ah, the heat's back on.
Yeah, I went down
and took care of it.
Good. Sure wasn't
looking forward to
burning up the furniture.
Food.
You left school early today,
huh? You feel all right?
Yeah.
I just cut the afternoon.
Mr. Supergrand cut
a day's school?
I guess that makes it OK
for me to cut, huh?
I guess it don't.
So, did you go fishing?
No, I didn't go fishing.
I'm gonna go out the back
and get Rowdy and Toyota
workin' on some oats.
If they don't get fed pretty
soon, I'm tellin' ya,
they're gonna be tearin'
down the fence.
They ain't there.
Well, if they're out
in the pasture,
I'd better get 'em in here.
I sold 'em.
No, you didn't.
Yeah, I did, and I got
a good price for 'em, too.
I'm gonna give you
another chance, Mason.
Where are them horses?
I told you already.
I sold 'em.
I don't know why you think
I'd start lying to you
this late in life.
Don't you ever close doors?
No wonder I can't pay
the gas bill.
Who'd you sell 'em to?
I ain't gonna tell you.
Those people bought a horse.
They didn't pay to have
some kid come bothering them.
Mace, Rowdy's mine.
You just can't sell
something that isn't yours.
You can't live
on no money, either.
They got a good home.
I made sure of that.
Now, they're gone,
so shut up about it.
Mason, you'd just better
get those horses back.
I ain't getting them back!
We couldn't have kept feeding
them much longer anyway.
Either they would've starved
to death or we would.
Just shut up about it.
You get those horses back.
I ain't getting them back.
Texas, you better quit it!
(shirt tearing)
You know, you're strong, Tex,
but you never could fight
worth a damn.
Come on.
I'm gonna get my horse back.
You ain't gonna find him!
I told ya!
If Pop was here, he wouldn't
have let you sell them!
If Pop was here, I wouldn't
have had to sell them!
That's the point!
(Johnny) Yo, Tex.
Hey, where you going? Hey!
What happened to you?
Rowdy.
What happened? He get hurt?
Mace sold him.
He sold him
and he sold Toyota.
I'm gonna find him
and get him back.
Well, were you
going home later?
Not until I find my horse.
Tex, that's nuts.
He's my horse.
Yeah, I know,
but he could be anywhere
and you can't just
sleep on the road.
Why don't I take Jamie home
and then I'll come back
and pick you up? OK?
Look, don't you two
understand English?
He's my horse
and I'm gonna find him.
I ain't going back...
I ain't going back
until I find him.
Yo, Tex, wait up.
Get lost!
Get in the truck.
No.
Come on, damn it. I've had
enough with you tonight.
I got a rope here.
I'll tie you up and drag you
home if I have to.
He's right around here,
isn't he?
That's why you wanna
stop me, right?
Yeah, he's right around here
and you're gonna find him.
And he won't be sold anymore.
Pop'll come home
and we'll all be happy.
And we won't have to brush
our teeth or go to school
ever again.
Christ, you're dumb.
Come on, get in the truck, OK?
(car door opens)
Hey, man.
Hi, Robert.
Johnny and sis told me
what happened.
How's Texas doing?
All right.
Heard you two had...
Yeah, just short of
a major war, yeah.
(Mason) Come on in.
You know, Cole could've
bought those horses
for Johnny or Jamie.
Yeah, that would have
completed the Collins'
vast empire pretty good.
Johnny's got enough for Tex
to be jealous of already,
don't you think?
Ah, can't see where
Tex'd get jealous.
I mean, Johnny's always
following him around
like some kinda puppy dog.
Yeah, like a rich puppy dog.
Ah, kids don't think
about money that much.
They do when you gotta
sell their horse.
I didn't mean to hit him
like that, though.
It's not like
it was his fault.
It wasn't anybody's fault.
It sure as hell was.
It was my pop's fault.
He ditched us here.
You know, I almost quit school
last quarter to get a job.
They might have
let you quit school.
They'll never let you
quit basketball.
I can't play basketball
if I gotta get a job
to take care of Tex.
Coach Jackson's got me in
for a scholarship at Indiana.
Scouts don't even
come to Bixby.
He's gotta send 'em
a film of me playing.
I tell you, if I make it
through this season,
I am gonna get out of Bixby
and I ain't coming back.
Did we get any mail today?
Couple more bills.
If you're hot to pay 'em,
it's OK with me.
Nothing from Pop, huh?
(Mace chuckles)
Pop would send us bills
if he thought we'd pay 'em.
I think he's hoping
we'll forget we got
a father out there.
Yeah. Well, he's gotta
come back,
especially if you're
going off to college.
(¶ musical car horn)
Hey, it's Lem.
Hey, Lem.
Hey!
T for Texas!
How you doing, man?
Hey, Kareem!
Finally got us a man
from the big city.
When did they let you out
of Tulsa? Where's Connie?
Oh, Connie's back in Tulsa.
She's with another man.
Hey, what do you boys feel
like doing tonight, huh?
Another man?
Yeah. They're in bed together.
Course, the guy's only
a couple of hours old.
(yells)
All right!
You mean you had your baby?
No, Connie did
all the having.
I just paced a hole
in the damn floor. (laughs)
Tell your folks yet?
No, Mason, we figured
we ought to wait
till we'd been married
nine months.
Come on, guys, get your coats.
Let's go tell some people.
Come on.
I can just see Cole
breaking out the champagne.
Cole don't have
to know about it.
I been in Cole's house
a thousand times
without him knowing about it.
Yeah, well,
I guess you do have to
have a few more people
congratulate you.
Getting an entire woman
pregnant like that.
I like how you put that.
Johnny says Cole's been
on the warpath all week.
Hurry up, it's Cole.
Shh!
(whispering/giggling)
(thunderclap)
Open up. Open it up.
What the hell's going on?
What's going on?
It's almost 12.
Hey, would you guys be
a little more hospitable here?
We got our common-law
articles now.
Hey, boy or girl?
Boy.
Whoo-hoo!
Hey, what does he weigh?
What does he weigh?
I don't know what he weighs.
Kid just got born, man.
You wanna put him
on a diet already?
How about a little
celebration?
Yeah! Give me that!
Hey, I'm gonna go get Jamie.
You guys, you better keep it
down. My dad's still up.
Oh, I ain't scared of Cole.
Well, good, Mace.
I'll tell him you're here.
(whispering) Hey, Jamie.
Oh, I thought you were Johnny.
Well, I ain't Johnny.
(Jamie giggles)
(man) Jamie, you
still in bed?
Come on, cut it out.
Get in the closet.
Yes, Dad?
Jamie, what was that noise?
I think the wind
blew the door shut.
I told you to leave
the window closed at night.
I can't sleep
when it's closed.
Well, you won't be able
to sit if you don't.
You leave this shut,
you hear?
I'm not deaf, Cole.
Good night.
Hey, you do have a reason
for being in my bedroom
in the middle of the night?
Uh, yeah. I... Well...
Don't look so scared.
I got my nightgown on.
I'm not scared.
Scared of what?
Getting what you came for.
Oh, no, no.
See, Lem showed up.
and he's over in Johnny
and Bob's room.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Boy or girl?
It's a boy.
Ah.
I'm sitting there, right?
And this nurse comes in.
She goes, "Hey, are you gonna
be like her coach in there?"
And I says, "Her coach?"
I says, "What is this now?
A sport or something?"
"We compete against
the other moms, see who
can have their kid first?"
I said, "No way, baby. I'm
sitting in that waiting room,
and I'm gonna read
some old  Time magazine
about 20 times over
before I go in there."
Hey, Jamie.
Hey, Lem.
Congratulations.
Thank you.
You get caught in a storm
on the way?
You're just lucky she didn't
have it loaded with ink
this time.
No, what he's lucky is that I
didn't have my BB gun with me.
(Tex) No, where I'm really
lucky is Cole didn't catch me
over there.
Whoa! Instant death.
You are a little young
to be hiding men in closets,
aren't you, now?
I wouldn't mind
if most of 'em stayed hid.
So, you had a boy, huh?
You're damn straight.
Yeah, well, don't worry.
If it'd been a girl,
you could've kept on trying
till you got what you wanted.
Oh, Jesus!
Don't get her started
on that femalism stuff.
Feminism.
Boy, I'm glad Connie don't
mess around with that stuff.
I tell you what, Jamie -
you're a real good kid
and everything,
but you don't know
nothing about what
a woman's supposed to do,
like being a wife and a mother
there, so just cool out,
little girl.
Yeah, well, good luck,
but personally I don't think
the two of you
could raise a cat.
You got a kind word for
everybody, don't you?
Hey, lay off, Mace.
Kid's only five hours old,
for God's sake.
Yeah, and probably smarter
than the both of you
put together.
(Mason) Hey, Jamie.
Sorry.
Tell Connie I'll baby-sit
as soon as
I learn how to drive.
Oh, yeah, sure, I'll tell her.
(Cole) What's all
that noise up there?
Hey, that's Cole.
Hey, congratulations.
Oh, hit that light.
Hi, Dad.
(laughter)
(Tex) I'm telling you,
Cole jumps on those guys
like a duck on a June bug.
(Lem) I tell ya, I'd be
a little bit uptight too
if I was 48
before I threw my first kid.
Well, it's too late
for you, Lem.
Yeah, right!
Hey, listen, you boys
got to come by now
and see Connie and the kid,
all right?
Oh, I almost forgot.
Pass around the cigars, huh?
No, not for me.
I'm in training.
You're gonna have to teach
my kid to fast break now.
Right.
Listen, remember,
the next time you farm
boys hit the big city,
come on by, all right?
Yeah, sure. Thanks a lot.
See you at the fair.
OK, Tex?
All right.
Not me,
but say hi to Connie.
OK, buddy.
Take care, Lem.
You know, if you smoke
that thing, don't come
hollering to me
in the middle of the night,
dreamin' something crazy.
Nah, I won't. Last time
I smoked one of these,
I damn near fell off my horse.
Hey, what'd you mean
when you said you're not
going to the fair?
It'd just be the same thing
as last year. Waste of money.
Well, I'm going,
and I'm taking the pickup too.
No way. The way you drive,
you wouldn't last ten minutes
in Tulsa.
You haven't got a license,
anyway.
I will drive you
and I'll give you five bucks.
Don't bother asking
for any more.
It's pretty neat
about Lem, huh?
When Connie got pregnant,
everybody acted like it was
the end of the damn world.
I thought you were happy
for them.
Oh, yeah, I'm delighted.
Man gets to pump gas all day.
He's married to a girl
he could half-stand to talk to
when he was
going out with her.
He gets to scramble around
for money.
I don't see why the guy can't
have a baby if he wants to.
Yeah? Well, it looks like
he can, even if he doesn't
want to.
You know, that Jamie's
smart-ass enough
to make you crazy,
but at least she ain't dumb.
Night.
You want to see the horses?
Nah, I don't feel like
checking out any horses.
You wanna hit Bill's?
Yeah, why not?
Whoo-hoo-hoo-hoo!
Yee-haw!
If we fall out, I hope we
land in the girlie show.
We can't, man.
You gotta be 18.
Knock off rocking the car.
You hear me?
You morons! You wait till you
get down out of the car!
They don't care how bad
they louse up the ride
for everybody else
as long as they can have
their stupid fun.
(laughter)
If you're gonna kill yourself,
you can go to the Mad Mouse
as far as I'm concerned.
Whoo! Whoo-hoo-hoo!
Oh, we burned him!
Either that
or he had a seizure.
You kids came from
a sideshow or something?
How you doing?
Hi.
We just made a jailbreak
off that Ferris wheel
over there.
Hey, you guys been to
the fortune teller yet?
I'm not wasting my money
on that junk.
He's afraid she's gonna
tell him something
he doesn't want to hear.
I'll pay for it.
No, I'll pay for it.
It's my own damn fortune.
Sit down, please.
Cross my palm with silver.
Oh, you want me to pay you?
When is your birthday?
October 22nd.
I'll be sweet 16.
Give me your palm.
Your far past.
You are a fourth-generation
cowboy.
Your next year. Change.
My best advice: don't change.
Your future.
There are people who go,
people who stay.
You, you will stay.
"Change" and "don't change"?
What do you mean?
You may think to yourself
one yes-or-no question.
Yeah, yeah.
I'm sorry.
The answer is no.
Good night, then, Tex.
Go to bed, man.
Tex, where in the heck
you been?
(slurring) Just went
down to this party.
Friend of Bob's.
I only stayed
for a few minutes.
I think I'm sick.
I think you're drunk.
Good night.
(moans)
Remember that last fight
Mom and Pop had?
Right before she died?
She ended up walking
out there in the snow.
I could hear 'em
shouting at each other.
Tex, you couldn't
remember that.
You weren't even
three years old.
I remember it anyway,
or I sort of remember.
I'm tellin' ya,
everybody was so tall.
I wanted to go out there
and stop it,
but I couldn't reach up
to the door knob.
And after that,
I don't remember it all.
Well, there's not much
to remember.
She stayed out there a couple
of hours and came back in.
A few days later, the doctor
said she had pneumonia
and put her in the hospital.
A few more days
and that was it.
I'm gonna get some sleep.
You think you can you get
undressed by yourself?
Yeah, I'm fine.
(car door slams)
Oh, my head!
Mace, Bob and Johnny
both came home drunk
last night.
Oh, no.
I'd like to know why.
Well, they were drinking,
I imagine.
I know Bob,
and I'm not sending him
to college to be an idiot.
Now, we've got that straight.
Now, Bob wouldn't get drunk,
and if he did,
he wouldn't drive.
And he sure as hell
wouldn't let Johnny drink.
Well, except for them coming
home drunk last night like
you said, that sounds fine.
Somebody got 'em drunk.
Wasn't me.
I happen to be in training,
which means I'm in bed
every night by 10:00.
I wouldn't touch a beer
if I was dying of thirst.
Why don't you ask Robert
what happened?
I did.
He said it was his fault.
Says he took them over
to some party somewhere.
Well, maybe he's
telling the truth.
He does that sometimes.
Keeps you guessing.
Now, don't you get smart
with me, Mason.
I'd like to talk to Tex,
if you don't mind.
Yeah, well, I do mind.
I mind a lot,
as a matter of fact.
Don't you have enough kids
of your own to hassle?
How old are you, Mason?
18. I'll be 19 this summer.
I haven't seen your Pop
around here much this year.
His work requires him
to travel.
What is this call?
The census?
Two boys living out here alone
without the sign of an adult.
Now, that's really something.
I bet the state welfare people
would like to know about this.
And if anybody was to call
at County Juvenile Bureau...
If everybody was to mind
their own business,
we'd be doing just fine.
I would appreciate it
if the two of you
didn't associate with my kids
from now on.
Well, you tell that to them.
I don't believe that stuff.
Not associate with his kids!
Probably afraid
we're gonna corrupt 'em all.
from dirty magazines
to 3.2-beer in my face
my whole life!
(Tex whimpers)
Tex?
You lose something?
It's sort of nice down here.
It's kinda cool and quiet.
Oh, well, maybe you'd like
to come have breakfast
under the kitchen table,
so you'll be on time
to get under the school bus.
You'd like that,
wouldn't you?
Anyway, I can't make it
to school today.
I woke up sick. I think I got
a 24-hour virus or something.
You got an 80-proof hangover,
that's what you got.
I can't make it
through a day of school.
Everything's spinning around
in here.
Well, then maybe you'll
sit still for once.
Tex, I don't want you
missing any more school.
You hear what Cole said about
that Juvenile Authority
and all that?
You think that ain't for real?
You're a minor without
a guardian, remember?
I thought you were
my guardian.
As far as the damned court
is concerned,
I'm as underage as you are.
How about if we go
to Indiana, then?
Nobody said nothing
about "we" going to Indiana.
I don't even know
if I'm going.
Coach sent them that film
and I haven't heard
a damn thing.
They're gonna want you,
though. I know that.
You're probably
the best high school
basketball player...
Tex, I'm trying
to explain to you.
We are not both
going to Indiana.
Why can't I come?
Because what am I
supposed to do with you
when I'm going to college?
Where are you gonna live?
In my locker?
So you're gonna go
and I'm gonna stay here?
That's the deal, huh?
Nobody's going nowhere
if you bring a couple
dozen social workers
down on our necks.
Grow some brains, will ya?
You want to stay off
some youth farm somewhere?
Start thinking ahead
five minutes at a time
now and then.
That's all you
care about, huh?
Is going off and being
a big basketball star.
Well, it beats staying here
and being a screwup.
OK, guys, that's it.
OK, I like it.
Oh, you added some color
to it, I see. Good.
Just be careful
when you're gluing it.
Nice. Nice texture.
Oh, yeah, I like it a lot.
Smooth that out a little bit.
How's this coming?
(girl) Fine.
That's good. Very good design.
I like that.
(teacher) Good. I really
like how it's taking shape.
That's just fine.
Grade it, quick!
It's going fast.
You'd better grade it.
Tex, setting fire to school
property is not a little joke.
I don't care what
that property happens to be.
Now, what if something on
that desk had caught on fire,
or somebody's clothes?
Yes, ma'am.
Were you angry
with Mrs. Germanie
because you thought you
couldn't do a good sculpture?
No, I don't think
there was any psychology
involved in here
if that's what you're asking.
I just think my sculpture
looked better on fire.
Tex...
No, ma'am, really.
If you'd have seen it,
you'd probably agree with me.
How are you and your brother
getting along?
We're doing great.
Mason, you know, he's always
after me about eating right
and studying and everything.
Have you heard
from your dad?
Oh, Pop, yeah. Yeah,
well, when he goes away
on one of his trips
- which he doesn't
go for long -
but, you know,
when he does go away,
he always makes sure
he sticks a little note in
with the check
that he sends us,
just to let us know
how he's doing.
I could suspend you for this.
I'm gonna let it
pass this time,
but please do not
let me see you
in this office again
this quarter.
(chuckles) I'll probably be
in there again this week.
Yeah, well, good for you.
Here.
What do you mean?
Well, I don't know, Tex.
I mean, it seems
I can catch enough hell
as it is, without going
around looking for more.
Man, you're starting to sound
like Cole or somebody.
And what's wrong
with that?
Nothing.
You're the one
who goes around round
griping about him
all the time.
Now you sound like you
believe him about me
and Mace being so bad.
Now, look, Tex, you leave Cole
out of this, you hear?
(school bell)
Bitch about your own,
if you ever see him again.
I left it in my locker.
Can I give it to you later?
Hey, I want to talk to you.
Sure.
Yeah, well, some place
a little more quiet.
Now, when are you and Johnny
gonna stop being so stupid
and start talking
to each other again?
I don't know.
People thought we sounded
pretty stupid even when
we were talking to each other.
Yeah. Well,
this is ridiculous.
It's been two weeks.
I certainly wouldn't
let a little argument
get between Linda Murphy
and me.
I thought your best friend
was Marcie.
That was last month.
Yeah, well, if I went around
switching best friends
every month,
I guess it wouldn't matter.
But this matters to me.
And you think it doesn't
matter to Johnny?
Look, he's gonna be
out dirt-biking
after school today.
If you two don't stop
being so... so asinine,
I'm not gonna speak
to either one of you.
Oh, wow, that just might
put me off my feed.
You know, Tex,
you really are cute.
Oh, Tex, you're so cute.
Shut up.
You're so cute.
He's so cute.
Hey, Mike.
How are you ropers doing?
Got a beer?
Tex, do you want
a cigarette?
No, thanks.
(man 1) Hey, how come none
of us was around when you
jumped the creek?
(man 2) Not my fault.
Must have been Sunday.
(man 3) He was crazy, man.
That little dirt bike of his?
He'd need a 350, at least.
Fergus can't ride.
Well, I'd do it now,
except I'm low on gas.
Your bike couldn't make it
across the creek
if it had wings on it.
What the hell are you saying?
(revs engine)
Hey, Johnny!
Hey! Johnny!
Anything broken?
I don't know, man.
I don't think so.
Man, you could've
been killed.
(Tex) He hit a bump, man.
Anybody can hit a bump.
Bike looks all right.
What's the matter, Johnny?
The water too cold
to go swimming?
Let me give that bike a try.
Clear a path.
Come on, Rowdy.
(whooping/cheering)
Man...
Ow... (spits)
Are you all right, Tex?
Yeah, I'm all right.
Boy, you're crazy!
You OK?
Yeah.
Oh, look at that.
That's somethin', huh?
Yeah, I made it over.
I didn't do it
with damn wings, either.
(Johnny) That was great, man.
Here you go.
Um... I'm going in to Tulsa.
You wanna come?
Yeah. You think we
can go see a movie?
Yeah, maybe.
(opens door)
You can go while I'm at
the hospital if you want.
Hospital?
Yeah, I got to
get some tests.
Drop you off at the mall.
What's with you?
It's not cancer or anything,
is it?
Cancer?
You think that's all people
go to hospitals for,
is cancer?
Well, then, what is it?
Probably nothing serious.
Don't worry about it.
If I thought it was
some kind of big deal,
I would've told you.
I don't lie to you, remember?
Tex!
Hey, Tex!
Are you deaf or just dumb?
Hi.
Hi, yourself.
Bargain hunting?
Nah. So, what's happening?
Going to a movie.
Cole's gonna pick us up later.
Is it a good movie?
I don't know.
I haven't seen it yet.
That's right.
Yeah. What are you
doing here, anyway?
I'm just killing time.
Hey, Jamie, come on.
We're already late.
Yeah, well, it certainly was
interesting talking to you.
I gotta go.
See you later.
God, he is so cute.
So, what'd they say?
Got an ulcer.
Ulcer? Is that serious?
Well, it could get serious.
Could get pretty goddamn
serious, yeah.
How'd you get an ulcer?
I don't know how I got it.
Doctor said that I'm not
supposed to let things
get to me.
However you do that.
And I take these.
What are they?
For pain.
You getting pains?
Yeah, I got pains.
Last week after practice,
I was spitting up blood.
Oh, no, man. Are you
gonna be able to play?
Yeah, for the time being.
(whistles)
Well, hi, Mace.
Hey.
God, I haven't seen you
since forever.
Hey, Tex. How you doing?
How you doing?
Oh, you guys haven't
seen the baby yet.
Oh, just let me tell Lem
you're here, OK?
Lem!
It's OK, it's just
Tex and Mace.
Oh, great!
Hey, fellas, how you doing?
I didn't think you guys'd
ever come visit me.
How you doing? Hey, Tex.
How you doing?
Just great, man.
What do you think?
Yeah. These are Daddy's
old friends, yeah.
This is Tex and this is Mason.
They came all the way
from Bixby just
to see you, sweetie.
Yeah, how about that?
Yeah, they did.
Hey, Tex, you wanna hold him?
Well, I never held one
before, but...
Well, go ahead.
He won't bite. Here.
Be careful.
Hey, Lukie. Hey.
It's all right.
It's kinda like
holding a puppy.
Ain't much heavier than
a basketball, is he?
He's almost as round.
(laughs)
Don't dribble him
though, OK?
He's the one doing
all the dribbling.
(cries)
It's all right.
It's all right, sweetie.
Is he house-broken yet?
Must be fun training him, huh?
Tex, he's not a horse, OK?
Oh, yeah, by the way,
guys, I wanna show you
something else, OK?
We'll be right back, honey.
OK.
See you later, Luke.
See you, Connie.
Say bye, Lukie.
Say bye. Say bye.
Yeah, it's all right.
¶ Da da da-da da-da!
Couple of weeks ago.
What do you think, man?
Gas jockeys must be getting
better wages these days.
That's good enough, man.
I had an eight-track in there.
Got ripped off
the day I got it, though.
Yeah? Where?
Over at ORU stadium.
Should've known better.
Lem, how much
you been dealing?
I'm not dealing, man.
I'm just helping some friends
get hold of a little grass
and speed.
You know, it's no big deal.
Yeah, right.
Hey, look, don't get high
and mighty with me, Mason.
I'm just a go-between.
It's not like I'm out
selling it on Peoria Avenue
or anything.
And I reckon you don't
use it much, either.
Oh, yeah.
I'm real hooked, you know.
Next thing you know,
I'll be stealing car stereos.
Come on, man.
Hey, I've seen you about
as high as anybody else.
How about Joe Ray's party.
Remember that, man?
Look, when my kid gets older,
I'll cool it.
Oh. Mm-hmm.
Yeah, well, look, maybe
it's a little bit easier
on you, buddy.
You ain't got a wife
and kid to feed.
You don't have people
depending on you.
Come on,
let's go for a ride.
What do you think he is,
a baboon?
Who? Me?
It ain't a big deal, Mason.
Come on, let's go
get some pizza.
No, we'd better
get going back.
You wanna drive?
Yeah. All right!
Come on, let's say good-bye
to Connie.
When you're, like, making out
with a girl and stuff,
how do you know when it's OK
to go any further?
How much further
you been going?
I didn't do it
going anywhere yet.
But I'm just thinking,
you know, just in case.
Uh-huh.
Well, don't worry about it.
You keep going,
she'll tell you when to stop.
You planning on being
the school stud or something?
You've been going
all the way, right?
No, I never done that.
(car horn blares)
Don't tell anyone.
But I thought
you and Bobby...
Bobby hasn't gone
any further than I have.
Everybody talks.
If you believe everything
you hear in a locker room,
you'll never wise up.
Probably had a lot of
chances, though. Right?
Yeah.
I've had plenty of chances
to end up like Lem.
If you're thinking about
Jamie, you might as well
forget it.
Why? Just 'cause they
got money and we don't?
What's the difference?
You know,
money isn't everything.
It ain't the money.
Because you're Tex
and she's Jamie.
Thanks a whole goddamn lot.
You wanna pick up this kid?
We're headed for Bixby.
Step in the right direction,
anyway.
How about yourself?
Going to the state line.
(chuckles) Had all
the 3.2-beer
you can take, huh?
Yeah, that's right.
I want me some full-proof
Budweiser,
so how about we just keep
going to that state line?
Let's all take it easy, huh?
Isn't this kind of extreme?
I mean, sooner or later,
somebody would've been
going to the state line.
Yeah, when you got people
looking for you,
you can't really wait
till then,
so I decided to
make it sooner.
This sucker is loaded,
in case you're wondering.
No doubt in my mind.
(coughs)
Hey, man, you OK?
He's great.
You just keep driving
at the speed limit,
he's gonna be fantastic.
(crowd shouts)
Nobody said,
"Let's go cruising
for a pizza." Move it!
Nobody saw you.
Roll up that window.
I could've been in East Texas
by now. You know that?
Except I had some business
to take care of.
I thought I did, anyway.
Guy keeps telling you
you're just like
a brother to him.
And he finds out
you sell enough speed
to make lunch money,
and he drops it down on you
for five years' worth,
no time off.
Somebody screws you like that,
you screw 'em right back.
Right, cowboy?
Yeah.
I mean, I don't know.
It came time to do it
and somehow
it just didn't seem like
it was worth the effort.
He's lying there, going,
"Go on, finish it off."
Let him walk around
with a hole in him.
He can whistle through it,
all I care.
One more mile an hour
and Stretch here gets dead.
(siren)
Throw down your weapon.
Tex, duck!
(gunfire)
(Mason) Ah!
That guy had a gun
on my brother.
(policeman)
You guys all right?
Been an APB out on that guy.
Someone saw you drive
through Bixby with him
and called it in.
He just escaped
from McAllister now.
I tell you what.
Now, that punk would've
killed you all
if he'd had the chance.
You're either real brave,
real stupid or real lucky.
(Tex) Been hearing that
all my life.
(overlapping dispatch voices)
Is he dead?
Yeah, he's dead.
Hey, man, you OK?
Oh, yeah,
I never felt better.
...shootout, leaving
Mark Jennings, the escapee,
dead from police gunfire.
The convicted drug dealer
killed a trustee
during his escape
and wounded another Tulsa man,
before kidnapping
two local teenagers,
Tex and Mason McCormick,
demanding to be
driven to the state
line in their pickup.
15-year-old Tex McCormick,
drove his truck into a ditch.
If it's that guy
from the Clarion,
tell 'em to forget it.
Hello?
Hey, Johnny,
pretty slick, huh?
No, no, no, I'm on now. No.
Yeah. Get off the phone
and watch. See you later.
Hey, that's us.
Take it easy. You don't
have your own show yet.
(female reporter) So why
did you pull off the side
of the road here?
Because, see, he had this gun
on my brother.
I thought he was gonna shoot
him or something, so I just...
Yeah, I was scared.
I was...
I was really scared.
Were you scared?
No, I wasn't scared.
What a stupid question.
Will you ever pick up
a hitchhiker again, or...?
I don't know. I don't think
they're all bad, you know.
You know,
'cause I hitchhike sometimes.
You look pretty cool.
I sound funny, though.
Tex, one final question.
Where'd you get those dimples?
Well, God gave me my face
but he let me pick my nose.
I can't believe you said that.
one of the youngsters
you saw in the videotape...
No injuries for Mace;
he'll be able to suit up
for the game
against Eastmont next week.
I bet you liked that, huh?
What's the difference?
(phone rings)
Tex!
Hello?
Hey! Hey, Pop!
It's Pop. He saw us on TV.
Pop?
Hey, Mace, I think it's him.
It's not him. If he left
at 6:00 in the morning.
He wouldn't even be here.
Hey, Pop! You look great.
Boy, have you grown.
Either that or I've shrunk.
So how's the rodeo season?
Aw, heck,
I'm too old for rodeo.
So, what you been doing?
Oh, just... messing around.
Howdy, Mace. I see you're
mad at me as usual.
Now, why don't we just
have the explosion now
and clear the air?
All right.
I've been known to explode.
Like when we hadn't heard
from you and all the money
was gone,
and the gas got shut off
and I had to sell the horses.
You sold your horse?
Yeah, I sold my horse
and Tex's, too.
Oh, Mace, I'm sorry.
I would've thought
about the money,
but I didn't figure
I was gonna be gone so long.
Yeah, well, I'd like to know
how long you're planning
on staying this time.
You're not giving him
any reason for staying!
You just shut up!
Well, I reckon
there ain't much I can say.
I quit the rodeo.
All I can say is
I'll be staying.
And all you can do is
give me a chance to prove it.
I'll tell you what.
Let's start off by getting
those horses back.
All right!
Well, I don't want mine back,
but you can get Rowdy back
for Tex.
That's a promise, son.
Come on.
(Tex) You made sure
I wouldn't find them, huh?
That's all I would've needed,
you getting busted
for horse theft.
I'm gonna go out back
and see my horse.
Yeah, you go say hi
to Rusty.
Rowdy.
Yeah, Rowdy.
Me and your brother
are gonna talk
the universal language
to this gentleman here.
Hey, Rowdy. Hey.
They got you jumping barrel
and everything out here, huh?
I'm gonna take you home.
Hi. Who are you?
Well, this used
to be my horse.
Well, you're not the boy
we bought him from.
Yeah, I know.
That was my brother.
See, uh... it was an accident.
He wasn't supposed
to sell him,
but he didn't know.
Well, we knew
we were buying him.
My dad paid for him
fair and square.
I know.
So he's my horse now.
Did you used
to ride him western?
Yeah.
I ride him jumping.
He really seems to like it.
I used to jump him.
We used to go out
in the fields, though.
We used to jump big logs.
I showed him at a show
a couple of weeks ago.
Yeah? How'd he do?
He took a third.
I had a pony before,
but he died.
He's really been a good horse,
once we got a little weight
off him
and we got his coat in shape.
He's real smart for his age.
Never did much show-riding
with him.
I didn't think
I'd want another horse
until I got him.
Right, Gentleman?
Gentleman?
He likes you.
Yeah, I know.
I guess you heard
the same thing we did.
They don't want to sell him
because the kid--
Save your damn breath.
Where's Pop?
Let's get outta here.
Still saying good-bye.
Turns out the guy's
a real rodeo fan.
Great.
I'm gonna get you for this,
Mason. I hate you.
(Pop) Let's go, boys.
I'm gonna get you back
for this.
I haven't been this mad
at anyone in my whole life.
Yeah, well, you're young yet.
Shut up.
(cheering)
(jeering)
(crowd shouting/jeering)
(whistle blowing)
You get him out of there!
We got him.
I gotta see how he is.
Bixby Spartans!
You OK, boy?
It's a miracle you stayed
in there as long as you did.
Those guys wanted to hang your
head in the hunting lodge.
Try bending it now. Slow.
Aah!
They gonna bench
that damn clown?
(coach) Yeah.
And you too, I guess.
(doctor)
It's not too serious.
Can I go back in?
Oh, no way, Mason. I'm sorry,
you won't be playing again
for a couple of weeks.
It doesn't matter anyway.
Indiana never sent
that application.
Yep. Deadline's next week.
I'm sorry, Mace.
You deserved it if anyone did.
Yeah, well,
I guess a full ride was
a pretty steep order
for a Bixby farm boy.
Oh, hey, Tex,
you wanna trade clothes
and shoot a few baskets?
Sure, Mace.
Take it easy now.
You're not gonna be good
to anybody with a messed-up
right arm.
Is this your boy?
Don't know yet.
Depend on how much
he's gonna cost me.
I didn't know a quarter horse
like you'd come up
with such a lanky racer.
His mama was a thoroughbred.
That's it. Just keep it in.
Just hold it right like that.
Tighten up here.
What time are you meeting
Johnny and Bob?
(Jamie) In an hour
at the carwash.
We got time for a Coke
or something.
They sell Cokes round here?
Well, you had a Coke at
the game, and I ain't thirsty.
What are you
if you aren't thirsty?
Um...
I don't know.
It feels kinda weird.
Yeah.
Hey, Jamie...
I think I love you.
I think me too.
What's the matter?
I'm not ready for that,
and I mean it.
What did you let me get
started for, then?
How was I supposed to know
you were gonna be in such
an all-fire hurry?
I was curious.
Curious?
I'm burning up over here,
and you're curious.
Tex, right now I think
you're the only boy
I'll ever feel this way about.
But how am I supposed to know?
I mean, this last year
has been so crazy.
One minute I hate everybody
and if they don't like me,
they can just go jump.
And then the next minute,
I love everybody
and I'm scared that maybe
they don't love me back.
Well, I don't know.
Maybe Cole's right.
Maybe I am too young to get
messed around and stuff,
but I tell you,
I'm confused enough these days
without throwing sex
in the deal.
I wasn't thinking of this
as just sex.
How about when we get older?
Maybe we could get married
or something.
I can see me marrying you.
You could?
Yeah.
It would last about a year.
(Jamie laughs)
Guess old Mason was right.
What?
It's like
that fortune teller said.
You're one of the ones
that's going.
Yo, Tex, do you think
this is worth it?
They're not gonna find out
who did it.
Even if they do,
what are they gonna do?
Send us down the principal's
office for a lecture?
(Johnny) There,
that's the last one.
(Tex) Come on, I don't wanna
miss the fireworks.
OK, folks, let's get it
together here.
I know everybody's
a little nutty this week,
but believe me,
there is life after finals.
So let's get everything
off our desks
except for a pen or pencil
and two pieces
of loose-leaf paper.
(makes explosion noise)
(crackle of caps)
(screaming)
(Johnny and Tex laugh)
Cathy, somebody has put caps
in the typewriters.
And you two were laughing
just a little bit too early,
weren't you?
Who, me?
Well, you boys must think
it was so nice of the county
just so you could
have your fun,
play your little jokes.
Hello, Mr. Collins.
Mrs. Johnson.
I might've known
you'd be behind this.
Ever since the first day
you came around,
I knew you'd be trouble
for Johnny.
And I've been getting awful
sick of you getting Johnny
in all these messes.
Well, you ought to be
just as sick of Johnny
getting Tex into 'em.
I'd say it's 50-50.
Well, hello, Mason.
I don't recall inviting you
to this meeting.
Don't you have a class
you're supposed to be in now?
I didn't know
if my dad was coming.
She called him.
He'll be here.
Tell me the truth.
Was this your idea
or Johnny's?
Yeah, and the time they
threw that shopping cart
off that roof
into that swimming pool,
that was Johnny's idea,
as I recall.
I told you this friendship
was just gonna keep
lousing you up.
Now, I want you to promise me
that you'll end it right now.
No.
What?
No, sir.
Mr. Collins,
just so you'll know,
I'm gonna suspend
both of these boys
for the next three days.
They can make up
their quarter finals
next week,
but I'm gonna take 10 points
off each of the tests,
and I'm gonna recommend
that the high school
put them in separate classes
next year.
Well, I would think that's
the least you'd wanna do.
When I get this one home,
I'm planning on
taking a lot more away
from him than just
10 points on a test.
You come with me.
Hey, Cole Collins.
Where you been
keeping yourself?
I been keeping myself at home,
taking care of my family.
You ought to try
that sometime,
if the demand
for rodeo clowns slows up.
Come on.
(Mrs. Johnson) I appreciate
your coming down, Mace,
and I really do think that...
Hey, everybody.
What seems to be the charges
against this here outlaw?
Well, what we did was,
we put some of those caps
on some typewriter keys.
Start the day off
with a bang, huh?
Yeah, that sounds like
one of them crazy things
I used to do when I was a kid.
Yeah, you were the one
that told me about it.
That's right.
If you'll excuse me,
Mr. McCormick,
I think I'd like to talk
to Tex in private.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Johnson.
I didn't think this would
cause this much trouble.
because there are gonna be
no more free chances for you.
Do you know that I almost
expelled you today?
Really?
Yeah, that's right.
And I've considered it before,
but I haven't done it
because I like you.
But I also like having
a halfway decent school here,
and if you make me choose,
I'm gonna choose the school,
now, aren't I?
Yeah.
I wanna talk to you
about a job.
Huh?
Mr. Kencaide, over at
the Kencaide Quarter
Horse Ranch,
he called up here
a couple days ago,
asking about hiring some kids
for summers and after school.
Does that interest you?
Now, he made it very clear
he's not looking
for any bronco busters,
just somebody to look
after the horses.
And for some
godforsaken reason,
I thought you might
behave responsibly
in a job like that.
What do you think?
Yeah, it might be
all right.
Just don't make me sorry
I recommended you.
Well, I take horses
real serious.
I hope there's something
you take seriously.
Because it may be
the only thing
that'll save you.
OK, you heard my punishment.
You can go on home now.
Take your family with you.
(Pop) Now, Mason, you know
better than that.
I was never one to stay around
town and go to PTA meetings.
(Mace) OK, so you
can't take Tex serious,
You don't care
what happens to him.
(Pop) Yes, I do.
(Mace) Well, how do you
think I feel
when I see you be nice to him
like he's some damn puppy?
What's gonna happen
when I go away? Make it
easier on me, at least!
He's my brother,
even if he's not your son.
Who told you that?
Nobody had to tell me.
I know when you went
to prison and I know
when Tex's birthday is.
Is that true, Pop?
Tex, listen...
(Mason) Tex, I didn't
mean it like that.
I'm gonna split.
I'll see you guys later.
Jesus, Mace.
Hey, Tex! Tex! Hey, kid!
Hey!
Man, where are you going to?
Wherever you're going, Lem.
Well, that's OK by me
'cause I'm bored, man.
Let's get outta here.
Can't you make this thing
go any faster?
Yeah.
Let's do it.
Now, back there, I was looking
for Dwayne Kirkpatrick,
trying to buy some of that
third-generation homegrown
he's got.
You seen him?
No.
I get a hundred bucks a lid
for that stuff in Tulsa, man.
Hey, I gotta make a stop here
on the way home.
Make it.
Well, actually, you know,
I'd kinda like it
if you went in there with me.
A couple of deliveries
got switched around,
and I gotta go explain
to these guys.
And, you know,
I think it'd be smart
if I didn't go in there
by myself.
I don't care.
Be nice if you looked
a little meaner, you know?
(chuckles)
But I think it's gonna
work out OK.
If there's any hassle,
we'll just split.
You must have burned
these guys pretty bad?
Burned 'em? Who do you think
you're talking to, man?
A nice guy like me?
It's just a mix-up,
you know, like when a computer
sends you a bill
by mistake or something.
I'll work it out.
If there is any hassle,
they'll be sorry,
'cause I really feel like
making somebody sorry.
Kid, I like your attitude.
Hey, man.
I was starting to wonder
about you. Who's your friend?
He's a connection from out
in Dixie, man. He's cool.
Tex, this is Kelly.
Kelly, Tex.
Tex.
Would you excuse us?
Why don't you just
make yourself at home?
Hey, man, I'm really sorry
about this mix-up.
Mix-up? Hey, man,
don't come in here
talking about any mix-up.
You owe us.
Hey, man, I thought
we were pretty square.
I don't know
how you got that.
I mean, I don't think
you're quite aware
how things are done
around here.
Now, you're not hanging out
in some schoolyard
out in cowtown.
Now, those kids
out there, man,
you give them something
gives them a headache
and they think
they're getting high.
But this is Tulsa,
and we got ways
of doing things.
I know that.
I mean...
Man, you come into town
and ten minutes later,
you're everybody's
best friend.
And then ten minutes
after that,
you're pulling a burn.
I don't like it.
You know, Kelly, I admire
this sense of high drama
that you have
in your life now,
but you're crazy.
I mean, man, I didn't expect
you to come through that door
without a couple of ounces
of clean crystal, right,
and not some garbage
about a mix-up.
An honest mistake, man.
Now, look...
You look, man. You come around
here with some samples
and then you come back
with the delivery,
and that delivery is crap.
Now, that is no mix-up, man.
That's a burn!
What do you think
we are, man? Stupid?
We have been waiting
a week, man.
Keep it down, man.
What's going on, man?
Listen,
I'm getting outta here.
This guy's nuts.
What do you think
you're doing?
I told you already.
I'm leaving.
Then he's gonna narc.
He's gonna narc.
Oh, he's not gonna narc,
Kelly. Come on, man.
(Lem) Kelly, Kelly, it's cool.
Really. Come on, man.
All right, now,
hold it right there.
Jesus Christ, man.
(gunshot)
(Kelly's friend) Oh, hey,
look, man. It's cool, OK?
Everything's cool.
I mean, we'll be cool,
and you be cool.
Just leave, OK?
I'm gonna kill him.
Tex, come on, man,
you don't wanna kill him.
Let's just split.
Let's get outta here.
Not till I settle up
with him.
You have settled up, Tex.
Texas, come on, man,
let's go.
OK, we're leaving.
You wanna stop us,
you're both dead.
It's OK. It's cool.
Everything's OK. It's cool.
That's a nice bunch of friends
you hang out with.
Ah, jeez, Tex, man. What if
he hadn't have missed you?
But he didn't.
Oh, my God, man.
(Lem) Great, man.
This is fantastic.
What am I gonna do?
What do you got
to be mad about, Lem?
Man, I got to get you
to a hospital.
They're gonna ask all kinds
of questions,
they're gonna call the cops.
What if they wanna look
in the car, man?
I got stuff in the trunk.
Come on, man,
get the hell outta here.
Hey, man, what are
you doing, Tex?
Tex, what are you doing, man?
Get outta here!
(drops in coins)
Hello?
Hi, Jamie. It's Tex. Um...
Yeah?
I can't remember
my phone number.
Do you... I don't know
my own number.
Do you...
Do you know my number?
Tex...
Tex, are you drunk
or something?
No, I just got shot.
Listen, I gotta talk to Mace.
Did you say you got shot?
Yeah, one of Lem's
doper friends, you know?
(Cole) Tex, is this some kind
of a joke or something?
Uh, no, sir.
Listen, can I talk to Jamie?
(Cole) Tex, where are you?
Um... I'm over
at the shopping center
across the street from...
It's the hotel that looks like
the castle, you know?
(Cole) Tex, hang up the phone.
Tex!
Come on, man. Come on.
Come on, let's get you
to a doctor, man.
Come on.
Is Tex McCormick here?
How much blood has he had?
1500cc's.
We're taking the x-rays
to surgery, Doctor.
Surgery ready?
(man) Yeah, they just called.
Hey, Mace.
I don't hate you, man.
I don't hate you.
I...
We got some signs
of life here, Mace.
Hey, I want a Coke.
He's OK.
Hey.
Don't move your arm.
You're gonna pull
that thing loose.
What is this?
That's to help you
grow some more blood.
You lost a lot of it.
Just lay it down
and be still now.
Relax. That's a boy.
Hey, look, Tex.
I'm gonna hold off
on that college stuff
for a while.
A year or two, maybe.
Pop's got a lot of
traveling to do,
and I can't exactly see
leaving you
while you're still
in high school.
So anyway, you'll be stuck
with me for a little while
longer.
Mace, how about giving me
and Tex a little time here,
will you?
Yeah, I'll get you
that Coke.
I wanna tell you
about your mama, Texas.
Aw, look, you don't
have to, Pop.
I figure the truth will be
a lot better than
what you might be thinking.
Now, about this bootlegging
business I got mixed up with.
Now, Clare never wanted
to have anything
to do with that.
She'd just say,
"Sooner or later,
sure as hell,
you're gonna get caught."
She was right.
They busted me
when Mace was just about two.
So when you were in prison
she was out screwing around?
Don't talk about your mama
that way, boy.
She was 19, she was alone.
I was sitting in prison
with my back to the wall.
That was real smart,
wasn't it?
Anyway, she told me
she was gonna have a kid.
And when I got out,
I wanted her back anyway.
She never cared anything
about that guy.
She was just trying
to get even with me.
She was sorry for it later.
Sorry for it, huh?
I don't mean for having you.
She always loved you
just like she did Mace.
When you paid more attention
to Mace than me,
was that why?
I reckon.
Well, you look plumb
tuckered out there, Tex.
You get some rest, boy.
Get some sleep.
Now, Mason's gonna come by
and see you tomorrow.
He ain't going nowhere now,
so he'll have a lot of time
to come and see you.
Behave yourself, boy.
(woman over PA) Dr. Gilbert,
Dr. Stanley Gilbert,
please call Emergency.
This where they keep
the bodies?
Hey, Tex.
Hey, Mace.
Yeah.
Congratulations.
Thanks. For what?
Indiana wants ya.
Full scholarship.
What are you talking about?
You don't look very pleased.
They only gave you
the red carpet.
But I never even applied.
They didn't even send me
an application.
Well, you got in.
I presume you are going?
Well, yeah.
Congratulations.
You deserved it.
Oh, by the way, that guy
I talked to in admissions
says you've got good taste
in reading.
Huh?
He said Smokey the Cowhorse
is his favorite book, too.
Hey, there, long, tall Mace.
What brings you out
to the old spread?
Thought the country air
might clear my head.
I keep doing things
and then plumb forgetting
about 'em.
Seems I wrote myself
an application a while back
to go to some fancy
university-type college
back east in Indiana.
What did they say?
It seems I'm in!
Great.
The only thing
I can't figure out is
how I ever got through
the essay part.
Well, like you said,
Jamie Collins, she ain't dumb.
You guys gonna take
the classes for me, too?
I guess I could've
screwed you up pretty good.
Yeah, well, you had reason
to be mad at me.
I don't know. I think
I was mostly scared.
I mean, running off
and everything.
I thought I'd stay around here
and go to JC a while.
Then it wouldn't matter
if Pop evaporated again.
He's not a bad person, Mace.
Yeah, well, he ain't
much of a father.
Well, you ain't, either,
and you've been trying longer.
If you stay, you'll hate me
in a couple of years.
Listen, I gotta
get back to work.
Take care.
Hey!
Nah. You'd better practice.
It's rough where you're going.
Yeah, well, it's pretty rough
where you're staying.
But I'll make it.