I have cancer.
I have the right to medical parole.
You think you get to enjoy privileges
because you have cancer?
If you die early that would be letting
you off too easily.
I can't tell if it's dependence or love.
I'm scared I'll break up with him
again in the future.
Or he'll leave me behind again.
When I was fighting for my life,
I only had you in my mind.
But that kind of feeling
may not be that of lovers.
It seems you still can't forgive me.
In today's training,
I want you to get through the obstacles as
fast as you can and subdue the man in red.
Understand?
The next team, get ready.
The last team, get ready.
Stop. The drill's over.
Is something wrong?
From your micro-expressions,
you don't appear to be frustrated by love.
I understand we shouldn't
bring our emotions to work.
But don't you feel anything
from being lovesick?
Have you been hurt so badly that
you're slow to react?
You're slow to react.
You've had your heart broken after all.
You should go out and drink
so you won't be so bored.
You'll feel better then.
I'll drink with you.
No, thanks.
I'm working the morning shift tomorrow.
Even if you're fine,
you can still grab a drink.
You're human. You must miss her a bit.
I'm working the morning shift too tomorrow.
You know me.
I'm working the morning shift tomorrow.
How can I go and drink with you?
Look, Brother Man, what time is it now
according to your watch?
5:56pm.
Mine says 5:57pm.
Don, what about yours?
5:55pm.
What does that prove?
Everyone's watch has a different time.
Some are a minute fast
and some a minute slow.
Whose watch is the most accurate?
Even the most accurate watch
in the world can be off.
If the error is less than a minute,
people can't say you're late, right?
Brother Man, sometimes you don't
need to be so serious.
I don't agree. A minute is a minute.
Don't belittle these 60 seconds.
Listen. Lots of things are decided
within a matter of seconds.
Even a second can decide
the latter half of a person's life.
I'm different from you.
You like crossing the line.
I can say you're just lucky
you never get into trouble.
I won't take any risks, OK?
We're just going for a drink.
You don't need to debate it so seriously.
If you want to debate,
do it when we're drinking tonight, OK?
That's right.
I know you guys care about me.
Will deal with my problem with Ka-ka
in due course. Thank you.
Hey, it's six o'clock sharp. Bye.
Remember the beef hotpot with Ho-ho
and Hang-hang tomorrow night.
Bye.
Good morning.
You came in so early?
First, I need to meet some inmates.
Secondly, I wanted to tell you that
even though I went out drinking last night,
I still came in on time this morning.
I even feel really sharp.
Why do you guys keep bothering me?
We care about you and Ka-ka...
OK. Got it. But we're at work.
Don't talk about personal matters, OK?
So the review board
is reviewing the inmates again.
This sentence review system is
quite good.
It gives those who are truly repentant
a chance to turn a new leaf.
I agree. Have the inmates said anything
to your welfare unit recently?
It's Yip Sai-heung again.
He keeps asking me for medical parole.
I have to tell him time and again that
there's no such thing.
You know how wicked this guy is.
Neither the Security Bureau
nor the Commissioner will
approve his early release.
There must be a reason for that.
I told you he's evil by nature.
If he had a tinge of kindness,
I'm afraid he won't show it
until the last minute of his life.
But he seems to have changed recently.
Scholar told me that he's been reading
Buddhist scriptures.
He'll ask Scholar to explain to him
the words he doesn't understand.
Control calling Man Sir.
Inmates in BB ward are fighting.
BB ward? If it's Yip Sai-heung again,
he's really changed. Get down to business.
Hey, get up.
Stop fighting.
At first we thought he hit Puny.
Actually Wing did.
Puny sat on his radio by accident
and broke it. He got mad and hit Puny.
I don't understand why
Yip Sai-heung would save Puny.
Let me ask him.
Yip Sai-heung, how are you?
Still alive.
Why did you save Puny?
Didn't you want him dead?
I'm just concerned about your condition
since you're sick.
Why did you take the risk?
I got a letter from my wife.
She's eloped with another guy.
I'm sick. But I'm not afraid of that.
I have to spend the rest of my life here.
But I didn't feel like my life is over.
But my wife...She's everything to me.
You have to spend
the rest of your life here.
That means I'll be like a widow
for the rest of my life.
It's such a long time.
How can I endure that?
I breaks my heart to see you like this.
She's been my support all along.
Now she...
If this had happened in the past,
I'd ask my underlings to beat someone up
to vent my anger.
But what's the use of venting my anger?
Will my wife come back?
We've been married for years.
I know her temperament well.
Once she's left, she will never come back.
Now I understand what it means
to lose everything.
Like Ho Wan said, this is karma.
This is karma.
I've read the letter to Yip Sai-heung.
His wife has really left.
He's been reading
Buddhist scriptures lately.
I think Ho Wan has inﬂuenced him.
Wow, Yip Sai-heung
has become a Buddhist?
That's really incredible.
He often says this is karma for him.
There have been similar cases before.
Take Ho Wan for example.
A tragedy happened in his family.
So his temperament changed completely.
I think Yip Sai-heung is showing
a similar tendency now.
When a person encounters
an extremely frustrating event,
he will think about his life.
I think he's been enlightened.
You two are too optimistic.
He will never change.
I know people like Yip Sai-heung too well.
How could he change so easily?
I don't agree.
I've worked in CSD for so long.
I've heard of similar cases
even though I've never really seen one.
Nothing in the world is absolute.
I believe a person can change.
I've worked in CSD for so many years.
That's why I can smell when
something doesn't tally.
I don't believe Yip Sai-heung would change.
Brother Man,
don't you just look at evidence?
Now you're saying you can smell it?
Of course evidence is important.
But sometimes intuition
is really important too.
Some experts have done studies.
The intuition of a seasoned professional
is very close to the sensitivity
of his professional judgment.
I really can't argue with you.
Has it ever crossed your mind that
you're prejudiced against Yip Sai-heung?
You think I'm that kind of person?
You almost died in the previous incidents.
It's true that there wasn't any evidence
to tie him to them.
But everyone thinks he did it.
Don't you hate him?
If I were you, I would be
somewhat prejudiced against him.
Do you really think of me like that?
And we've been friends for so many years?
The bread's been delivered.
But I haven't put it on the shelf yet.
It's OK. Just go.
You're going to dinner with your son.
Enjoy.
OK. Thank you very much then.
Ho, you have to help me.
What's the matter? Come over here.
I wanted to see you a while ago.
They made me traffic drugs.
I'm so scared.
I really don't want to do it again.
But they beat me up and threatened me.
I really don't know what to do now.
Take someone over there and look for her.
You two come with me.
I know the one in back. He's CSD.
He and that woman often harass Angel.
I know one of them too.
When I was in Stanley Prison,
he wrote an adverse report on me.
He wouldn't let me go to my dad's funeral.
Please do something to help me.
Ho-ho, what's the matter?
Someone's forcing her to traffic drugs.
Hey, don't go.
You came to see me because you want to
live like a normal person.
Turn yourself in and quit drugs.
I can't. I can't go to jail.
I've been there before.
Don't think jail is like hell.
Jail is a place where you can
reflect on yourself quietly.
Go there and do some soul searching.
Then you can turn a new leaf
when you're released.
Coco, don't be scared.
Ho-ho will help you.
Well support you too.
You've done something illegal.
Even if you did it under duress,
the consequence will still be the same
if you're arrested.
You'll still go to jail.
Testify against those bad guys now.
It'll be better than just leaving.
We'll all help you. Don't be scared.
That darn cripple.
Last time our joint was raided.
Did she tip off the police?
So they know each other.
Brother Kwan, something's wrong.
Coco appears to be listening to them.
What if she rats on us?
Let's get out of here.
Coco, why are you still hesitating?
The chance is right here.
Don't make a mistake again.
Sorry Madam Chi.
You came here just
because I needed to give a statement.
No problem. The police just asked you
to assist in their investigation.
You're discharging your duty as a citizen.
Don't feel like you owe me one.
I think I'll be seeing less of
Man Sir and Yung Sir in future,
because I keep running into
my old friends.
I don't want to give them trouble.
You're doing good deeds as a good person.
You think you're doing bad things
and giving people trouble? You're so wrong.
You were amazing just now
when you were trying to convince Coco.
You were so persuasive. I can't be
as persuasive as you.
You mean I went to jail before
so what I say is more convincing?
Ho, actually you just lack confidence.
We've already asked you to come to
our private gatherings.
But it seems you still
label yourself as bad. Don't you think so?
I know you care about peoples feelings.
That's why you think of yourself this way.
But you really don't need to do that.
I feel bad seeing you've
given yourself so much pressure.
Thank you very much, Madam Chi.
I'm so grateful to you.
Hearing you say that means I can do better.
You can be happier.
Take what happened today for example.
I want to give you ten likes.
Thank you, Madam Chi.
Did I compliment you?
But you do have good taste
for choosing such a good girlfriend.
I'm a quality product too.
That's why she chose me.
Product?
You think you're buying fruits?
If I were a fruit, I'd be a durian.
Rough outside but good inside. Eat me.
Let's go, durian.
You're a peach.
You're beautiful both outside and inside.
According to you,
Ho-ho has really changed completely.
I'm happy for Q.
I'm happy for you too.
You had a hand in correcting Ho-ho too.
As Wu Sir in STI said,
when we've corrected an inmate...
We don't just correct her...
We may have saved a family...
Or those around her.
Ho and Q make a nice pair.
What about you and Man Sir?
Why bring that up? We're working now.
Let's talk about work.
Don't talk about our personal matters.
You're really so different now.
You have the air of a madam all the more.
You've really gained experience.
I feel like a re-formatted computer.
Now I look at the world from a new angle.
At the same time, my capacity is bigger
so I can download more programs.
I don't get it.
In the past, when I had free time,
I would go out and play. But now I read.
Because reading helps me
understand the world better.
So you've completely changed too like Ho-ho.
Actually why did you come here today?
Oh, Killer Whale's being released
in 6 months.
So I came to talk to her about her
housing arrangements when she gets out.
OK.
She may be getting out soon,
but I don't think she's repented yet.
Wu Sir said before that putting an inmate
in jail is for the peace of society.
Then what about releasing someone
who hasn't repented yet?
Wu Sir didn't touch on that.
Madam Yiu, we've collected all the books.
Put them back on the shelves
according to their classification.
Yes. OK
Madam Yiu, shall I put this
Monte Christ in the Religion Section?
It's Monte Cristo.
Le Comte de Monte Cristo is a novel.
It goes under Literature.
Sorry. My mistake.
That's a good book.
Borrow it next time.
Thank you.
The main character of the novel
broke out of prison.
Aren't you afraid they'll copy him?
Do you have anything on tonight?
I'll buy you dinner.
So nice?
Are you coming?
OK.
OK. I'll call you when I'm off.
When your number is called,
come out and get your book. 391092.
I thought someone had to find a new job.
382126.
She's done so many wicked things.
But she's back unscathed.
302394, 345675.
Isn't she afraid that
there's a ghost in the cell?
You got me killed.
I'm so scared.
I want you to die and keep me company.
Killer Whale, what are you talking about?
Madam, my breath will stink if I don't talk.
Am I not allowed to talk?
369249.
Ouch. Why did you trip me?
You didn't watch your step.
You tripped me.
You'll have no children, darn woman.
What did you say?
What did I say? I'm not afraid of you.
Stop it or I'll use pepper spray.
Madam, I need a doctor. I'm hurt.
OK. Thank you.
Killer Whale is hopeless.
She's asking the other inmates to give her
cigarettes again as a protection fee.
The inmates say Pui-hung won't give in.
So she often stirs trouble with Pui-hung.
She's doing it again?
It won't help to catch Killer Whale again.
She's prepared to stay here
for the full term.
She's not afraid of forfeiting remission.
Even though she'll be released,
she'll come back in very soon.
Not necessarily. I fell before.
But I could still stand back up.
Nothing's absolute.
Tam Yuet-king is the most difficult inmate
we've come across in recent years.
She has no respect for discipline at all.
She keeps breaching the rules.
A lot of colleagues have lost hope in her.
I'm glad that you still have
such a positive view of her.
I feel that no matter how bad she is,
there's still hope.
Do you have the confidence
to make her reflect on herself
before she's released?
Madam, I'm ready and willing to try.
Good. Keep me posted of the progress.
Yes, madam. I'll get back to work.
Tam Yuet-king.
Have some tea please.
Thank you.
Angel, the boss said your recent
performance has improved a lot.
Those guys haven't come to see you anymore?
Are you OK?
I broke up with Kuen.
Really?
He sells ketamine and traffics drugs.
My best friend died
because she took ketamine.
I told him that he could do anything.
But he must never sell drugs.
He didn't listen to me. So I ditched him.
Angel, it's good that you know
drugs aren't legal.
But actually you shouldn't do
anything illegal.
I know.
I mean I hate pushers most.
Actually the supervision order
isn't just about observing the curfew
and doing your job well.
Its objective is to help you
correct yourself and turn a new leaf.
As long as you really want to
do the right thing,
you'll still have a bright future.
I understand.
Madam Chi, dinner service is about to start.
I need to get ready.
OK. Work hard then.
OK.
I thought you were so nice to ask me here.
But it's because you have work here,
and it's convenient.
That's why you want to eat here.
Don't say that.
I just have a tight schedule for work
and personal arrangements.
But I'm off now.
We don't need to talk about work.
OK. Let me see what to order.
Voice call. Don.
Let's have all-you-can-eat. It's a bargain.
Really?
Voice call. Don.
OK. Let's not talk about work.
Let's talk about personal life.
You phone keeps ringing.
Why won't you answer it?
Nothing. They're just cold calls.
You're really bad at lying.
I don't want to answer someone's calls.
Tell me everything please.
I don't want to guess.
It's Yung Sir.
You two have quietly started a revolution?
I don't know if that's the case.
Actually we almost started.
But before that...
You two quarreled?
No. I lost faith in him
before we even started.
I had a crush on him first.
But then when he found out,
he kept asking me to give him a chance.
So I agreed to spend some time
observing him.
Miss Chi, I really can't believe this.
Brother Don is so nice.
Why are you still hesitating?
I don't like his stubborn attitude
towards his dad.
He has no patience at all for his dad.
But he's so patient
when he deals with the inmates.
Also, he cares a lot about other women.
I don't get it.
OK. I'll tell you everything.
He says he doesn't approve of Ally.
But whenever Ally's in trouble,
he'll immediately go help her.
You're already so jealous
even before you two have begun.
Just now you said he kept asking you
to give him a chance.
If he didn't like you, why would he do that?
How would you understand?
He said he likes me.
That puts me under a lot of pressure.
Today there's Ally.
Maybe there'll be someone else tomorrow.
It appears you're being overly sensitive.
Brother Don has done nothing wrong.
But we come from two different worlds.
I admit I feel inferior.
But think about it. He likes fine dining.
I just go to cafes.
He wears designer outfits and cologne.
I just bought this shirt from an outlet.
What you said just now is so superficial.
Don't be so shallow.
When two people are with each other,
it's communication and sharing that counts.
Compromise on what you like to eat
or wear when you're together.
You're stopping even before you've started.
You wont be happy in the future.
But I really feel like I'm not his match.
You're free to think that.
But don't keep it to yourself.
You have to tell him about it.
Only then is it fair to him.
Actually you feel inferior because
you think he might spurn you.
Tell him everything right from the outset
and show him who you really are.
If he really doesn't like you for that,
then he doesn't deserve your love.
Answer it.
I'll pretend I can't hear it.
Hello.
You're home?
Sweetheart, dinner's ready.
Come on. The food's getting cold.
Come on. Let's start eating.
Dad, Mom.
This is my colleague Yung Wai-chun.
Uncle, Auntie, how do you do.
Sweetheart, you should have told us
you're coming home with your friend.
Hey, go in and get changed. Sorry.
It's OK.
We need to.
I brought you here
because I want to show you my home.
You took me home before.
I didn't dare get out of your car
outside my building
because I was afraid
you'd find out too much about me.
I've lived here for over 20 years.
It's a mess, isn't it?
My dad likes collecting
newspapers and magazines.
All the furniture here is second-hand.
Take this chair for example.
My friend didn't want it.
So she gave it to me.
My dad and mom didn't go to school.
Dad suffers from chronic renal disease.
He needs dialysis every day.
Mom hasn't worked in years.
So the three of us live on my income.
The food we eat has to be cheap.
And it has to be filling.
We have no requirements at all
about our clothes.
When I go to dinner with you guys.
I sometimes feel pressure,
but I need to make friends.
You may find my home a disgrace.
But all three of us are good citizens.
Let me finish first.
I want to tell you that
if we're really together,
I won't covet your money.
We'll go Dutch when we go out.
But if there's a formal occasion, I'm sorry.
I may not be able to go with you
because I don't have any nice clothes.
This ﬂat may be worn,
but I believe there's a stow
behind every item here.
You really cherish them too.
Just now when I came in,
I felt the warmth of your family.
That's something I don't have.
You said the food you guys eat
is very simple
and the clothes you wear are cheap.
I don't see a problem there.
A person's character is the most important.
You may wear designer clothes
and drive a nice car,
but if you heart is wicked,
I won't think you're noble at all.
So I don't think you have a problem.
You mean you don't mind the fact that
I'm no match for you?
If you think that again,
I really will mind.
Mom.
What?
We won a can of abalone
in the lucky draw earlier.
Can we eat it tonight?
Sure.
Wait. If it's so formal that
you have to treat me to abalone,
I want to know what our rating
is now. I mean from 1 to 10.
Well...5.
5 plus 5 equals 10, right?
You wish...
Dad, why are you wearing a suit?
We have a guest.
Your friend's here.
Mr Yung, please join us for dinner.
Right.
I'll get you a bowl
and a pair of chopsticks.
OK. Thank you very much.
Mr Yung, have a seat please.
I'll get you a chair.
I'll get it.
You sit down too.
Donald, you've never taken the initiative
to ask me to tea.
I can't believe that as soon as you do,
you introduce me to your girlfriend.
You've shown respect for your dad.
Excuse me. I don't remember your name.
You're called...?
Chi Chun-kwong.
Uncle, please call me Kwong.
Chun-kwong. Your name is really special.
I'll remember it.
Actually it wasn't my idea
to ask you to come out today.
It was Kwong's idea.
Really? That's good.
At least you still remember this place.
You asked me to come here.
When you were a kid,
we came here every week.
Your favorite food was
the baked tapioca custard.
Actually it was also Kwong's idea
to come here.
She read your autobiography.
She said you often mention this cafe.
She also said that you talk about me
all the time in your book.
She's jotted it down.
She said you mention the words "my son"
63 times,
"my son Wai-chun" 78 times.
There are 428 pages only in your book.
I realized how important I am to you.
Today I want to tell you that
I refused to see you all along
partly because of Candy, you and me.
I don't want people to talk about us anymore
Most important of all,
I'm different from you.
You may want fame and fortune.
What we want is really simple.
We want to train the detainees well
so when they're released,
they won't harm society again.
As long as we can train a detainee well,
there's one person less
who will jeopardize our society.
This is the difference between you and me.
Guys, a Buddhist master is giving a lecture
on Buddhist scriptures later.
Raise your hand if you're interested.
If you want to become a Buddhist,
you should go.
The topic I'm going to
talk about today is "Fate".
You may have all
asked yourselves this question...
I can't believe Yip Sai-heung
would be so attentive.
I think his appearance has changed
since he converted to Buddhism.
He doesn't look as fierce as before.
He looks more human now.
One looks the way one thinks.
Some people work hard their whole life.
They may do something extreme.
From the perspective of Buddhism,
everything is the karma of
a person's good or evil deeds, because...
Sorry, master. I need to interrupt you.
OK.
Yip Sai-heung, you passed a slip.
You want to make trouble?
Man Sir, what trouble have I made?
On the floor.
Stop killing and become Buddha.
Man Sir, I just wanted to share this saying
with everyone. Is that a sin?
This phrase appears to be innocuous.
But it could be some kind of code.
Also, it's against the rule
to pass anything around.
So you've breached the rules.
Since you've done something wrong,
you should apologize to this officer.
The conflicts between human beings
can be solved with forgiveness.
A person's fate...
I'm sorry, master.
Man Sir, it's true that
I really hated you before.
I wanted you dead. So I kept picking on you.
That's why your prejudice against
me deepened.
But Master Yeuk Hung is really right.
The more you hate a person,
the more sinful you become.
The more you can’t let it go,
the more you'll suffer.
Seriously, I'm really exhausted.
I don't want to fight anymore.
Man Sir, I'm sorry. This is my fault.
Please give me a chance.
It's good that you've apologized.
I hope you will remember
what you said today.
Don't forget everything
when you wake up tomorrow
and go back to square one.
Sorry for interrupting you, master.
Actually, master was right.
Interpersonal conﬂicts
can be solved through forgiveness.
Yip Sai-heung already apologized.
Did Man Sir have to stand so firm
over just a hand shake?
Could it be that
Man Sir was thinking about his image,
that's why he didn't shake hands with him?
But I've known him for so long.
He's not that kind of person.
Why make it so complicated?
Man Sir never makes any allowance.
This is his style.
Give you some allowance? No way.
Please follow the rules strictly.
Don't say that.
You're not in Man Sir's shoes.
How would you know his difficulties?
He must have a reason for what he did.
Maybe he thinks that
if we don't stand firm,
the other inmates will think it's OK
to make mistakes if they apologize. Right?
Wai, you're relatively new here.
I've worked under other team leaders before.
They all said Man Sir's strict.
Did you notice that Yip Sai-heung
usually makes trouble in the Left Division?
He seldom does so in the Right Division.
Do you know why?
Why?
It's because he picks on Man Sir.
You mean if Man Sir weren't so strict,
there might not be so many people
working against him?
Yes.
But if he's too lenient,
Yip Sai-heung would push his luck.
Is it because Yip Sai-heung was unruly first
or because Man Sir was too strict first?
Guys. Stop discussing this.
It won't be good if Man Sir
hears this when he comes back.
OK. Yes, sir.
Yes, sir...
Sorry, sir.
Bye.
Chiu, come in my office.
OK.
Sit down. You've worked under me the longest
I want to hear what you think.
Do you think I should have shaken hands
with Yip Sai-heung just now?
I think you should have.
There was no harm in doing so.
First, it would send
a positive message to the other inmates.
They would see that if they truly repented
and really behaved,
there'd still be a chance and hope.
Secondly, it can also encourages
the colleagues.
They'll think you're compassionate.
That's a way to boost morale.
I understand what's on your mind.
The problem is I don't believe that
Yip Sai-heung would change for the better.
But it's a fact that he saved Puny.
He often reads books on Buddhism
and chants the Buddhist scriptures.
We all think he's changed.
He's not as violent as he used to be.
He looks a lot more benevolent now.
Benevolent? He's not benevolent. He's sick.
So he looks pale and less belligerent.
That's why he can’t talk as loudly.
If you're talking about benevolence,
Scholar is really benevolent.
It would be too strict
to compare him to Scholar.
Scholar has been here for almost 30 years.
Yip Sai-heung came here
only two years ago.
Sometimes when I work under you,
I feel the pressure too.
It's hard to strike a balance
in everything we do.
Regardless, I trust your experience and I
will follow your way in handling things.
Actually you don't need to strike a balance
all the time when you talk to me.
I want to hear your honest opinion.
Why don't you tell me if
I give you guys a lot of pressure?
If what I say is said
on behalf of the colleagues,
then I can't tell a lie
because I have to represent them.
Yes. Sometimes it's a bit tough
working under you.
If there's nothing further,
I'll get back to work.
I've worked under other team leaders before.
They all said Man Sir's strict.
You mean if Man Sir wasn't so strict,
there might not be so many people
working against him?
Yes. Sometimes it's a bit tough
working under you.
Even the most accurate watch
in the world can be off.
If the error is less than a minute,
people can't say you're late, right?
Brother Man, sometimes you don't
need to be so serious.
Human beings aren't robots.
Same for romance.
There are no manuals or rules to follow.
What a coincidence?
Right. I just came out for a walk.
Join me for a drink?
OK.
Hi.
Joe is a neighbor in Stanley.
He really likes to travel like me.
He even writes travel books.
He's amazing.
Really? When did you meet
such an interesting neighbor?
Just now when I was jogging.
We're neighbors.
We must meet more often from now on.
When are you going on holiday?
I can give you some advice.
Great.
Hey, I see a friend.
I have to go say hello.
You make friends with strangers
on the street.
You're even having drinks with him.
Aren't you afraid hes a bad guy?
He's a neighbor. It's daytime now.
What can happen?
If I thought it was dangerous,
I wouldn't have sat down
for a drink with him.
I'm afraid your judgment is wrong.
Have you forgotten what happened with Fei?
I've learned a lesson.
You think I should refrain from
making new friends?
I'm just worried about you.
You get close to people so easily.
You may want to go on an adventure
with him again.
You know when you're in the mood,
you drink a lot.
I'm afraid something bad
might happen to you.
I was really right. You never change.
Just now I tried very hard
to understand your point.
In the past when you didn't like
me doing something,
I would smile at you in a silly way
and say something cute to pacify you.
Then I would run away in a jolly manner
as if nothing had happened.
So we never quarreled.
That's because of our seniority.
You were always right
and I was always wrong.
But it's different now. I'm a big girl now.
I'm no longer the Ka-ka from before.
I went out with you. Then we broke up.
We've been through a lot, right?
I'm more mature now.
I know a mature person should communicate
with others in a fair manner.
Just now you kept challenging me.
From my perspective, you were so rude.
Perhaps you don't know how to
respect others. Do you understand that?
I always thought I was clear-minded.
Actually I have so many blind spots.
I'm inﬂexible. I give people pressure.
I stress out my colleagues. I'm so disliked.
I'm not welcome.
Now...You two carry on. I have to go.
Hey, your friends leaving so soon?
He said he has something to do.
OK.
It seems like the rain's getting heavier.
I better go home and get an umbrella.
Wait for me here, OK?
OK.
You look after Hang-hang.
Hey, what are you guys doing?
Take your hands off. Go.
Go.
Why are you taking us? What's going on?
Shut up.
Hang-hang.
Your call cannot be connected right now.
Please call again later.
What's the matter? What are you guys doing?
What do you want?
Hush...So you told Coco to tell on us?
Do you know you don't quit drugs.
You take them.
Kid...Kid.
Big Brother, the kid can't hang in there.
Hang-hang.
Shoot him up with drugs.
Don't do it please.
You can do anything to me.
Please leave Hang-hang alone.
I beg you please.
Well? I'll run the car
over your other leg then.
No. Don't do that. Ah...
Are you really scared?
I wont inject your son with drugs.
I wont break your other leg.
But you must cooperate with me.
Ho-ho, why did you ask me
to come out so urgently?
Why can't I tell Q?
Ho-ho, are you OK?
Why did I help Coco?
If I hadn't helped her,
this wouldn't have happened.
I'm really so stupid. So stupid.
Ho-ho, don't leave.
Tell me what's going on, OK?
Don't follow me. Go away.
I wont inject your son with drugs.
I wont break your other leg.
Cooperate with me. Take this
and shoot it into Man Sheung-shing.
What does he have to do with this?
Just do it. After you've done it,
I'll give your son back to you.
Otherwise you can prepare
a body bag for him.