(Doorbell rings)
(Door rattles)
- Is it any warmer?
- No, it's really cold.
You'd better take those to Mrs Parnell.
It look me longer than I thought.
Here are the birds.
Darn. They should have been in
ten minutes ago.
- The avocados were too hard.
- I've made some soup anyway.
The doctor always enjoys a bit of soup.
I don't believe
Mrs Ebury's mother's coming,
but would you leave the extra bird in
just in case?
Or you could have some cold
tomorrow with a nice jacket potato.
You know I don't like potatoes.
(Doorbell rings)
(Door opens)
- Dr Stevenson.
- Parnell.
(Woman) We'll never get a cab
and it'll be pouring in an hour.
Oh, Mother.
You'd better leave your coat on, Mother.
I can't eat with my coat on, can I?
You should have worn
something warmer.
I have something warmer underneath.
Your hair's lovely.
Did you do something different?
Yes, well, I went to a new shop
in the Bower Building.
I like the blue in it.
It's getting nasty again. I wager
we'll have snow before the week is up.
- Well, help yourself.
- Thank you, dear.
Frances. You look happy.
Well, Doctor, how goes it
with the bedpan set?
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
- We've missed you on the green.
- I'll be back soon enough.
- It's caught up on my bracelet.
- Let me help you, Mother.
(Whispers) Excuse me.
- How did you come up?
- We took the lift.
I had to walk. There was
an out-of-service sign on the elevator.
It brought us up all right.
- David never reads signs.
- David.
...never economy. And mark my words...
- David, no more politics.
- How are the dogs doing?
- (Guests chatter)
- I'll get the crystal.
(Guests chatter)
(David) And in all fairness
to the parties concerned...
David.
- (Laughter)
- Oh, the squabs.
(Woman) They must be frozen.
Are they frozen, Frances?
It's not squab. It's Cornish game meat.
- Cornish game birds. I love them.
- Yes, they're very good.
And when you come to me, Frances,
I'll have some of that fatty skin that's
fixed to the bottom of the platter.
This wine's delicious, Frances.
It sounds very interesting. I'll tell you
one thing that's always puzzled me.
- Why is it...
- Oh, Mother.
I did taste it. It was delicious.
- It tastes sour.
- Well, then, don't have it.
Thank you. I'll take some
from the other side, dear.
(Female guest) Oh, God, yes.
(Guests chatter)
(Woman) David, please. David.
(Man sneezes)
- (Sneezes)
- (Woman) Can't you control yourself?
Calm down. You're getting it
all over the carpet.
- (Coughs)
- Parnell, take the cup. What a mess.
(Woman no. 2) Can't you stop it?
(David) It must be something in the room.
(Woman) He's allergic to pollen.
(Man) But there isn't any,
at this time of the year.
It's starting to rain.
(Man) Yes, I suppose it is. It's been doing
it on and off for two months.
(Woman)
Well, could he be allergic to rain?
I read somewhere that people
catch colds from germs,
not from getting wet and being cold.
Rubbish. I always catch cold
after I've been wet or had a chill.
- What about it, Doctor?
- Well, actually, Frances is correct.
(Frances) There's a boy
sitting out there in the rain.
(David) He's a damn fool.
He'll be sneezing next.
(Doctor)
It's not as simple as all that, though.
Moisture has a great deal to do with it.
The amount of moisture
one takes into one's lungs.
- (Frances) Someone should ask him in.
- Frances, what a curious thing to say.
I'm glad your mother's not alive
to hear a remark like that.
He doesn't even have a coat.
Well, nobody's forcing him to sit
out in the rain. Perhaps he likes it.
He's just a boy.
Perhaps he has nowhere to go.
(Woman) You're being sentimental. One
would think you'd never read the papers.
Come on, David. We must go.
You'll want to nap
before you go off to bridge club.
- Shall I call you a cab, Mr Ebury?
- Yes, perhaps you'd better.
Perhaps the doctor could drop us.
I'm not leaving for a few minutes.
I want a word with Frances.
Please. They're going to have such
trouble getting a taxi in all this rain,
and we can always talk another time.
I particularly wanted to speak to you.
Well, aren't we going to see each other
Friday afternoon?
- We're bowling, aren't we?
- Not if this weather holds.
(Woman)
We're right on the way to your office.
Please.
Right.
(Rain pours outside)
- I don't think Frances looks well.
- I hardly noticed.
(David) Oh, she's always looking tired.
(Woman no. 2) She should take royal jelly,
one capsule every morning.
(David) What on earth's that?
(Woman no. 2)
What the queen bees make.
Which is what they eat.
(Door opens and shuts)
(Man) We're on our way.
I put the bowls out for soup.
- Don't forget to turn it off.
- I won't.
(Door shuts)
(Frances) Hello!
I'm talk...I'm talking to you!
Come over here!
Yes! YOU
(Bird squawks)
(Foghorn sounds)
I saw you from my apartment.
I've been watching you in the rain.
Would you like to come upstairs to
my place, to my apartment, and get dry,
just until the rain stops?
I'll meet you right at the end down here
and we can go up to my apartment.
The rain should let up shortly
and I can dry your things.
It's right this way. Just follow me.
(Bells chime)
(Vehicle sounds horn)
Are you a student?
Do you go to school?
Can you hear me?
You understand what I'm saying?
Let me take your shoes off. Here.
Muddy.
Would you like a bath?
A hot bath? You want a hot...
Come with me.
(Water runs)
Come and stand over here.
Here.
Come, let's take off your shirt.
Sit down.
(Clock ticks)
Would you like me to fix you
something else?
Are you still hungry?
I know.
Oh.
Well, it really looked quite nice before
Mrs Parnell transferred it to this plate.
She has a thing about taking leftovers
and putting them
from one plate to another
so she can wash up the first one.
I made it myself.
I made it yesterday.
There's, er...pineapple and cream
and sponge cake.
It's really quite good.
Oh.
I'm sorry.
I wish I knew your name.
Your name.
Er...
I'm Frances.
Frances Austen.
You must think that
I'm a compulsive talker.
But it just seems so odd to sit here in
silence, with you not saying anything.
(Organ plays out of tune)
(Playing stops)
Do you DWI?
Are you fond of music?
I have a...a small record collection.
Perhaps you would
like to hear something?
Would you come...come with me?
Would you come with me?
My mother had
a large collection of records
but most of them are stored
in the spare room.
I keep my collection here.
Perhaps there's one you'll like in it.
Oh, there is one in particular
that I think you might like.
I took a course in music appreciation,
at one time,
and now I try to spend
half an hour to an hour every day
listening to something I really like.
(Music plays)
(Music stops)
Do you want me to play this?
Do you want me to put that
on the record player?
(Music plays)
(Music stops)
(Phone rings)
(Frances) Hello? Hello, Uncle David.
Did you?
Well, what kind of an envelope was it?
Yes, all right.
Well, hold on and I'll have a look.
I'm trying to remember.
Where did you sit?
Yes, perhaps it slipped
down the side of the sofa.
Hold on. Yes, just a moment.
(Rain falling outside)
No, I don't see it.
Yes, well, certainly.
I'll have a long look tomorrow, then.
Yes, tomorrow. Goodnight.
(Rain falling outside)
Are you really asleep?
I've made up a bed for you
in the spare room.
You can stay if you like.
If you want to.
I don't know if you have a home or not.
I expect you have a room somewhere.
You don't have to, now. It's only an idea.
But your things won't be dry till morning.
(Rain falling outside)
But it is warm here and there is a bed.
Besides...
...it's still raining out.
Goodnight.
(Door shuts)
(Door rattles)
Morning.
I thought you might be tired of eggs
so I've made you something different.
There.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Er...
I've made you coffee. But if you'd
prefer tea, it's simple enough to do.
I have to go out and do some shopping.
I have to get some things,
but you know where the bathroom is
and if you're still hungry, you can go
out and make yourself something else.
L...l shouldn't be longer than an hour.
(Clicks)
(Toilet flushes)
(Clock ticks)
(Footsteps)
Oh!
Come see what I bought for you.
You found Parnell's jacket, did you?
They're for you.
Try them on. Try the trousers on.
They're very fashionable,
don't you think?
I got them at the young men's shop.
Oh, that's very nice.
It's difficult to buy for somebody,
when you don't even know
what colour they like.
The shoes?
I would have gotten leather,
but the man says it's difficult
unless you have the person there to fit...
Oh! There's the socks.
Perhaps, er...
...you don't wear socks
with those kind of shoes...
Up. UP-
Let me see. Oh, it's very nice.
The colours are very nice.
These are presents from me to you,
and you're welcome to take them
with you when you go.
I'll go fix some lunch.
(Cutlery clinks)
(Frances)
I hope you like your chicken cold.
Usually, l...l like to prepare it myself,
but I didn't have time today,
what with the shopping and all.
I wish you could speak.
It's so difficult to know what you want
or what you're thinking sometimes.
You know, I have this friend.
He's a doctor.
His name is Charles
and he does some psychotherapy.
He actually made this woman, who
was convinced that she couldn't walk,
ride a bicycle.
I remember, one morning,
er...my girlfriend
and I, my best girlfriend,
we decided that we would play truant.
So, we rode our bicycles right up
to the front gates of the school
and then we turned
and went the other way
and we cycled and cycled
and cycled for miles,
until all of a sudden, where should we
end up but right back in front of the gate
and who should be coming in at
the same time, but the English teacher.
You see, we had made a complete circle
and ended up
right where we started from.
She was very masculine...
- (Clock chimes)
- ...our English teacher.
But quite, er...pretty.
And many of the girls
had crushes on her.
I like to make a habit of, er...
turning this on early
so that it's nice and warm
when I get into bed.
I bought this for myself. My mother
would never have one, you know.
She was afraid that, er...she would
be electrocuted in her sleep.
She was very old,
my mother, when she died,
and I'm afraid she was a...a trifle senile.
Were you warm enough last night?
I wish that I had another one
of these to give to you.
Would you like that?
I could pick up one,
if you would like one.
I'll have Mrs Parnell
pick up one tomorrow.
She does that kind of thing for me.
She's coming in tomorrow,
Mrs Parnell. Do you understand?
She's coming in tomorrow, Thursday.
She comes in on Tuesdays
and Thursdays.
Now, there is no need for us
to explain why you're here.
She works for me. This is my home.
I don't have to explain anything.
They used to work for my mother,
you see.
Goodnight.
Er...I'll bring you breakfast first thing
tomorrow morning at the same time.
If that's all right.
It's been a lovely day for me.
I'm very glad you're here.
Goodnight.
(Distant foghorn sounds)
- (Chatter)
- (Dog barks)
(Pop music plays)
(Running upstairs)
(Man) Do something useful.
Hold the baby, will you?
Here, let's take these off.
That's a good girl.
- Pop goes the weasel!
- Come on, honey.
Where are they?
- Bedtime.
- Bedtime?
Bedtime.
- Oh, there she goes.
- (Baby cries)
(Music plays)
- Hey.
- (Man) You owe me five bucks for that.
(Low chatter)
(Music drowns speech)
(Baby cries)
(Low chatter)
(Man) Can't you stay to help your mother?
(Woman) Turn the kettle on
if you're going in the kitchen.
(Music playing)
- (Baby cries)
- Aw, good girl.
(Woman) Hey, wait a minute.
Here's Nina's dress. Take it to her.
(Dog barks)
(Foghorn sounds)
(Water lapping)
(Wind chimes)
- (Foghorn sounds)
- (Distant bell)
(Wind chimes)
(Woman) Damn it, the cat...
- Will you get out of here?
- (Foghorn sounds)
Why don't you knock?
- (Wind chimes)
- (Foghorn sounds)
- (Waves lapping)
(Woman) Mm.
(Bell sounds)
Mm.
- (Foghorn sounds)
- Mm. Mm.
Mm.
- (Foghorn sounds)
- (She moans)
(She pants)
(She moans)
(Moaning subsides)
- (She moans)
- (Foghorn sounds)
(Bell sounds)
(Foghorn sounds)
- (Wind chimes)
- (Foghorn sounds)
You can come in now.
Come on.
(Wind chimes)
Close the door.
(Foghorn sounds)
You're not gonna put that sweater on.
- It scratches.
- But I'm cold.
- (Door slides)
- Just a minute.
OK.
(Bell sounds)
- (Foghorn sounds)
- Where have you been?
I've been sitting in Tatlow Park
for two days, waiting for you.
- I see you brought my dress.
- Yeah, Sue picked it up for you.
You're burning those things again?
Ooh, God.
- You mind if I just smoke mine?
- Yes, I do.
- Where are those papers?
- They're on the shelf there.
- Found them.
- They're done.
- (Foghorn sounds)
- I think.
Oh, Jesus.
Move, move, move, move, move.
Hey, give me that.
It's got my eyelashes in.
(Distant bell)
- Did you see Mom?
- Yeah, I saw her.
- How is she?
- She's fine.
It's me that nearly drowned.
Sorry to hang you out,
but we had a chance to cop some shit
in Seattle, so we hitched down.
- They're good.
- Have a cookie, man.
Nice.
Hm.
Can't you just have a cookie?
Do you have to smoke that crap?
I can't stand the smell of that smoke
and you know it.
(He grunts)
- What are you doing?
- I'm cold.
- I could have frozen to death.
- Move over.
How much grass
did you put in these things?
Will you move over?
- (Foghorn sounds)
- Anyway, I got picked up in the park.
- Pigs? For what?
- Did you bring some food?
There's bread and cheese in there,
and it wasn't the law. It was a lady.
Mm, mm.
Do you want to hear about this lady
that picked me up and gave me a bath?
- A real bath?
- (Distant bell)
- A bubble bath.
- A bubble bath?
- How much did she pay you?
- Pay me for what?
You know, for services.
I mean, it's a well-known fact
that there's a service charge
when old ladies take young boys in
for sexual purposes.
That's right. It's like if your sister here
had any dough, she'd be paying me.
(They laugh)
- (Bell sounds)
- How long did you stay with this lady?
Till now, tonight, and she wasn't old.
- I never said she was old.
- Hey, she must have been pretty good.
Listen, it was a hell of a lot better
than staying here or at home.
I had my own room and my own bed.
So, then, why did you leave,
if it was so groovy?
- (Nina) Ow. Mm.
- (Foghorn sounds)
I don't know.
I guess I just got tired of not talking.
Christ. You mean, she didn't talk to you?
She didn't talk? That's all she did.
I was the one that didn't talk.
You're doing your number again, right?
Hey.
You're doing your thing?
You're doing your number?
(Nick) What thing?
(Nina) He's got this thing. He's been
doing it since he was a little kid.
He doesn't talk. I mean...
I mean he doesn't talk for days.
- So, why did you leave?
- He told you.
Um...what did he tell her?
He told you. He didn't tell her anything.
He didn't...he didn't talk to her.
Oh.
(They laugh)
She's a very strange lady. I've never
in my life heard anybody talk so much.
(Clock ticks)
(Mrs Parnell)
I've never seen such a beautiful day.
Crime to stay indoors.
You startled me.
9.30, my usual time.
Would you like a cup of coffee?
I'm afraid I didn't make tea this morning.
No, thanks, clear. I'll get started.
What would you like me to do first?
Make up the bed in the spare room.
Make it up? Someone coming to stay?
No, I slept there last night.
(Chuckles)
(Clock ticks)
Oh, you haven't eaten your breakfast.
No, I wasn't hungry.
(Clock ticks)
Why don't you go back to bed
for an hour while I clean up?
No, I think I'll take a bath.
Let me know when you want your lunch.
I'm not hungry.
Why don't you have a cup of bouillon?
That won't hurt you. It goes down easily.
I don't want anything to eat, Mrs Parnell.
You go ahead and have your lunch.
(Doorbell rings)
Yes?
Look here, you hop it.
We're not buying anything.
Come in, please. It's all right, Mrs
Parnell. It's a friend of mine. Come in.
Please sit.
Sit down. I'm glad you came back.
This for me? Thank you.
It's cookies? Are they from a bakery?
They look home-made.
Did you make them yourself, then?
Let me take your coat.
Do you want me to finish
cleaning up in here?
No, you can leave the rest today.
If you have anything you want to do,
please feel free to go ahead.
Why don't you have your lunch and go
ahead? Are you hungry? Would you...
(Mrs Parnell) Do you want me
to get you some lunch?
No. You get yours.
You get your own. I'll get ours.
I'll put these on a tray
and we can eat in here, all right?
Mrs Parnell, I wish you would
have something to eat.
I'm all right. You're busy.
I don't want to be in the way.
Don't be silly. You could at least
have a cup of coffee.
Where is that corkscrew?
Here.
(Clock ticks)
Do you want to use that wine?
That's the very good wine. The one
the doctor likes with his steak.
Yes, I want the very good wine.
What could I have with the cookies?
Perhaps I... I could have some fruit.
Would you just finish that
for me, please?
(Clock ticks)
- These cookies don't look very nice.
- I think he made them himself.
But they're all burned.
Someone's been scraping them.
Please. I wish you wouldn't go on
about the cookies.
- You're not going to have to eat them.
- And I wouldn't.
I'm sorry. I didn't mean to snap at you.
It's just that everything's
coming up at one time.
Parnell and I will be in
for your bridge party.
No, I think everything's
been changed around.
I think I'm going over there or they're
coming over here the week after.
I can't remember right now.
(Door shuts)
Huh.
(Tuts)
Lord. You must...
I'm not dressed.
Well...excuse me.
I must go get dressed.
Will you excuse me, please?
(Screams)
Did I frighten you?
I frightened you.
(She laughs)
You know what I was doing?
I was playing blind...
...man's bluff.
Yes, blind man's bluff.
You know how to play that?
We used to play it in school.
You know what this is that I found?
You have three guesses.
One.
No.
Two.
No, it's not that at all.
That's my school...
...uh...
...necktie.
(Snorts)
(Giggles)
See, that's the, er...that's the red.
That symbolises the flame...
...in my heart.
Here. You wear it.
It's very lovely on you.
And this is my harmonica. I found
it in the drawer, you see. Yes.
- (Blows notes)
- Very good.
(She laughs)
Let me have it.
I want to show you how...
I used to have to stand
in front of a mirror in the...
I mean...
Oh! Yes.
Yes.
That's it. Through...through the loop.
That...that's right. That's very nice.
Thank you.
Do you like that?
Oh...
...come here.
(She blows mouth organ)
(Mouth organ squeaks)
Ah. Oh, Oh, Oh!
No.
I'm sorry. Come on, get up.
Come on. Up.
Here.
Straight-ahead.
(Plays mouth organ)
There.
(Door opens)
(Frances) 'I have to go out.
'I'm afraid that I will be gone most
of the day. I have an appointment.
'There's this bowling tournament
'and it's just a club thing, you see,
but I feel that I have to be there.
'If you're hungry, there's plenty to eat
in the kitchen. You just help yourself.
'I should be back around eight o'clock.
'I promise that I won't be
any later than eight o'clock.'
(Woman) How much longer do we have?
(Woman no. 2)
You have an appointment, don't you?
No, I didn't have one before I got here.
She just told me to sit down and wait.
But there seems to be
so many people in and out.
(Woman no. 2) You might as well
just make yourself comfortable.
Just relax. You seem a little bit nervous.
(Woman no. 1) Worst of all, I was here
last week and spent two hours waiting.
Finally they sent me home.
- Really?
- So, I guess this man's pretty busy.
He seems to have
an interesting product.
Austen, Frances Austen.
I have an appointment.
- (Woman no. 2) Have you children?
- (Woman no. 1) I have four children.
That's plenty.
It's lovely, lovely,
but, yes, I've had enough
and I don't care to worry
about enlargement.
(Woman on tannoy) 'Dr Devlin
to emergency room.'
Are you taking the pill?
Well, I think, the pill...
I've heard stories.
That the, er...that the little thing
that fits up inside, right?
- Yes, the coil.
- Yeah.
I understand that every once in a while
they deliver very healthy babies.
After four of those
I think I'll try the very safe one.
Except I understand they put
pounds and pounds on you...
They do actually put ten pounds
on you. What are you going to ask for?
Well, I was hoping to get...to get the pill
because I sort of assumed
that they would just listen to your heart
and take your blood pressure.
- Oh, no. They have to examine you.
- Oh, do they?
- Always.
- Oh, they do?
- (Tannoy) 'Dr Johnson, line five.'
- It's not that bad.
- You've never had it done before?
- Yes, I have.
That's why I was sort of...
That's interesting. It's been years
since anything like that's bothered me.
I'm nervous, I guess.
I've already been through it once.
It's been a long time since I had
my first one, I can tell you.
I can imagine.
How many children do you have?
I wouldn't think you'd be nervous
after having...
Oh, no, I'm sure I wouldn't
if I had any children.
- But I don't have. I'm not married.
- Oh, I see.
I think that's very good.
If more girls came to a place like this
before they got themselves in trouble,
their lives'd be a lot easier on them.
I really don't know anything
and my mother will never talk about it.
Well, no. Every time I use...
Like, uh...the diaphragm
didn't work for me
and when it's condoms,
I don't know, whatever happens...
I think that men get all excited
and put them on wrong or something,
because two of my children
were born with those
- so anyway...
- They take it very seriously.
Somebody told me that in every box
there's one with a hole in.
That's sad.
You've been married
a couple years now?
Well, I started with the intrauterine device,
but, believe it or not,
my husband said he could feel it.
You mean some men
are bigger than others?
Yeah, you could say that.
I thought they were all, within reason,
about the same size.
No, just like girls, they're all different.
Well, I think that'd be right,
because if you want a diaphragm
you have to get...fitted for one.
Well, maybe they'll give you
the diaphragm.
If you don't feel good,
they're still going to make you...
- No, he wanted to get me the pill...
- But I think it's naive...
Just a minute.
Don't forget your umbrella.
- Well, I think the pill...
- Bye.
- ...would be easiest.
Yes, it is the easiest
but sometimes it puts weight on you.
Let's face it,
are you ready for ten pounds?
You just have to be
a little more careful.
- (Woman) Miss Austen?
- I've never really had a problem...
Miss Austen?
If I had to lose weight,
I probably couldn't do it.
If you go right to the end of the hall.
It might spoil the whole thing.
You get all jazzed up and they have
to go in and do all that junk for you.
Well, if you're there, the guy's trading...
Oh, come in.
Do sit down.
May I have your card, please?
Thank you very much.
Ah, let me see now. Miss Austen, is it?
Yes.
Er...single?
Yes, I'm going to be married.
Oh, how nice.
Have you ever been pregnant?
- No.
- Well, that simplifies everything.
Dr Mackenzie is going to examine you
and he's considered very good.
Will you come with me?
Oh.
Well, that wasn't so bad, was it?
Come in. There you are.
Now, if you'll just take your clothes off
and put on that gown,
the doctor will be with you in a minute.
(Knocking)
(Knock)
Oh, for Christ's sake.
What are you doing here?
- Where is she?
- What are you doing here?
What do you mean? I want to see.
Where's the war hero?
I think he's working.
Hey, is this your room?
Not bad.
Come on, Nina. You're gonna get me
in a hell of a lot of trouble.
What's this crap?
Will you put it down?
She could be back here any minute.
Frances, you're late. I tried to phone.
- Yes, I know. I am sorry.
- There was no answer.
- I had some errands to run.
- It's very damp today.
- Oh, Miss Austen, you're here!
- Yes, I won't be a moment.
Good afternoon, Miss Austen.
You got here.
We were worried about you.
Oh, yes.
- Frances, you're late.
- I know.
(Speech drowned out
by aeroplane overhead)
For crying out loud!
You can't take a bath.
- Get your little grubby hands off!
- She's gonna walk in here any second!
I'm gonna take a bath.
Now leave it alone.
But you can't. She's gonna walk
in the door any minute now.
- You had a bath.
- That's different. She gave it to me.
I'm gonna have a bath.
- You're gonna get in a lot of trouble.
- She's not gonna mind, I'm sure.
- After all, I am your big sister.
- Oh, come on. Will you cut it out?
I mean, it's not like I get a bath
every day or anything like that.
I can't have a bath in the houseboat.
There's one at home
if you want to use it.
(Nina) You should talk!
Hey, come on. You know I spend a hell
of a lot more time at home than you do.
This lady keeps her bathroom
equipped with junk.
Hey, don't use any of that.
She's gonna know it's gone.
- Good. Maybe she'll think you used it.
- Oh...
Come on. Just hurry up, all right, please?
She sure has some nifty things.
I don't know when she's gonna be
home. Will you please hurry up?
I'm gonna take my time!
Now will you relax?
I told you, it's not like I get to take
a bath every day or something.
Little wretch, depriving your sister
of a bath...
(She sighs)
Get me a...get me something, quick!
Get me a towel!
There's one right behind you.
I know, but I'm using it. Get me
something quick! Quick, quick, quick!
Oh!Oh!
- Here! Here!
- (indistinct)
Well, get it! My eyelash is coming off.
Hey! What the...
My pants are on! What are you doing?!
Ha-ha-ha!
All right, that's it for you now, kiddo!
That's it for you!
You know who should be in here,
don't you?
- All right, now you're gonna get it.
- No!
Oh!
Now, you know we gotta cool it
because she's gonna see this stuff!
(Coughs) I wish I had my boatie.
Remember my boatie?
I remember your duck. You remember?
The duck was yours. The boatie was
mine, kid. It was a submarine.
- Get over, John.
- Mom, you stand here.
(Man) It's cold out here.
That's a dandy.
Mid-season form.
(Woman) We're by the lane.
- (Man) Here I am doing all the work.
- (Man no. 2) Let it go to the other end.
(Woman) More or less from here.
(Man) Oh, yes, it's quite easy.
They won't know the difference.
- (Woman) Do you want to hold my coat?
- (Man) I'll hold you too.
Well, are you having a bad day?
It's much too cold for this.
This'll warm you up.
- I think it's going to rain.
- Oh, I don't think so.
- (Frances) How much longer will we be?
- Just another hour, that's all.
- I wish Nicky was here.
- Well, he isn't.
I wish anybody was here.
Mm, I wish you weren't my brother.
Well, I am. Now will you come on
and get dressed?
Ha.
- Do you wish I wasn't your sister?
- Now, what's that supposed to mean?
Do I excite you?
How about going by the house?
How long's it been since
you've seen Mom? Along time.
(Laughs)
Come here.
Huh?
- Come here.
- What for?
Well, I have this...
this stiff neck.
Mm...
Jesus, Nina.
You know, you're really crazy.
I do excite you,
because you're afraid of me.
Oh, for crying out loud.
Where does it hurt?
OK.
Come on, sit down.
Hm?
Uh...gentle!
Higher.
Come on.
Hon.
What?
You've got some sleep in your eye.
- For Christ's sake!
- (Laughs)
- (Frances) You needn't see me up.
- (Charles) Oh, don't be silly.
(Frances) To tell you the truth,
I'm not feeling very well.
I think perhaps I caught a chill tonight.
(Charles) We'd better give you
something for that, then.
(Frances) Maybe it's only that I'm tired.
(Charles) Mm-hm, now, look, Frances,
you know I've been angling
to get you alone for some time now.
(Frances) I wouldn't object
at any other time, but it's so late.
(Charles) It's only 9.30.
(Lock clicks)
- May I have a brandy, please?
- Yes, help yourself.
Thank you.
(Glass clinks)
I'd like a brandy and soda, please.
Certainly.
(Clock ticks)
- Got a headache?
- No, I don't.
I don't have a headache.
(Charles) You soon will have,
if you don't relax.
(Clock ticks)
I'm just tired.
(Charles) Frances.
We've known each other
for some time now.
May I say something
that, coming from a stranger,
might seem somewhat impertinent?
I've never discussed your personal life.
Our friendship, and I think of it
as a very sincere friendship,
has only just grazed the surface.
What I'm trying to say is that
this isn't just a sudden whim.
It's something I've given
a great deal of thought to.
I'm sure that at times you've felt
the need of another person's love.
(Man) OK, I want you just to bend your
knees now and wiggle on down the table
and then put your feet out here
in the stirrups, just like that.
That's fine. That's good.
Now, see if you can just wiggle on
down a little more, OK?
- (Charles) 'You all right?'
- (Frances) 'Yes.'
(Charles) 'Are you sure you're all right?'
(Frances) 'Yes, it's just been
a long, trying day, that's all.'
(Charles) 'Frances, people always
tell doctors their problems.
'They never seem to realise that,
well, doctors have problems too
'and loneliness is a problem.
'I am lonely, Frances. I'm just like other
people. I need someone to care about.'
(Frances) 'Charles, I'd much rather you
wouldn't go on with this conversation.'
- (Charles) 'I'm sorry. I didn't...'
- (Frances) 'I'm sorry.'
(Charles) 'Frances, I hope
you didn't misunderstand.
'When I used the word love...'
(Man) That's fine.
Your ovaries appear to be normal.
(Charles) 'I didn't mean I...
'What I meant was warmth,
understanding, affection.
'I didn't just mean... I hope you don't
think I would be so presumptuous.
'I would never do anything to offend you.
'Perhaps, in time,
your feelings might change.'
(Frances) 'Charles, please.
'I'm afraid it's my fault.'
(Man) and that's all there is to it.
- I'd better go.
- Yes.
(Charles) May I phone you tomorrow,
please?
Sleep well.
(Door shuts)
(Door creaks)
Are you awake?
I can't sleep.
It was such a long, tiring day for me.
I suppose that I am too tired
to go to sleep.
And then, too, it is strange, knowing
that someone else is in the house.
I'm so used to being here alone.
I wonder...
...do you think that I'm lonely?
I am, you know, but, um...
I don't think about it.
I remember my mother never stopped
saying how lonely she was
after my father died.
She kept talking on and on,
always reminding me
how little company I was for her.
But she was an old woman
and senile and it's...
I don't think about it.
Old people disgust me
with their feelings, sometimes.
I wonder, do you think that I'm old?
Do you think that?
(Clock chimes)
You know, er...
...I have this friend.
Er...he's a doctor...
...and he wants to make love to me
all the time.
All the time.
I find him very unattractive.
But he still wants me.
I don't like to have him touch me.
He reminds me of an old man.
He smells like an old man.
I've known him for, Oh, ten years
and it's always been the same.
Always the same.
He's immaculate.
His shirts and his shoes.
Do you remember the shoes that
you wore the first day you came here?
The shoes,
you had no laces in your shoes,
and then you went without socks.
I've never seen anyone go about
without socks before.
It gave me such a peculiar feeling.
His shoes are very well heeled...
...and shiny...
...and rather small,
and when he sits, you can see his
maroon garters that hold his socks up
and he has a terr...terrible habit
of plucking at the creases...
...in the knees of his trousers.
Do you know the kind of person
that I'm trying to tell you about?
I expect he needs me.
But I have never felt the slightest bit of
desire for him, even out of loneliness.
He disgusts me.
I wish I knew whether you were
really asleep or just pretending.
You are very clever
at pretending not to understand.
Do you mind if I lay down on the bed?
I'm not going to get under the covers.
I'm just going to lay on the top.
Just here, just like this.
I want to tell you something.
If you feel you want to make love
to me, er...it's all right.
I want you to make love to me.
(Whispers) Please.
(She screams)
(Screams)
(Man) "Old Red Warm Body Rub
for fun-loving people.
"It gives a slippery sensual effect.
"Works into the skin with rubbing,
providing..."
(Man no. 2) You enjoy reading things like
that, don't you? You really do enjoy it.
(Man no. 1) "it comes in a four-ounce jar..."
What do you mean when you said
that she's not like you?
- What do you mean?
- What are you trying to say? Spit it out.
A few minutes ago,
you said she's...she's not like you.
- What did you mean?
- She's different.
(Nina) OK, she's different.
You said she's different.
She's got a very strange attitude
towards sex, first of all.
She makes a big deal out of it.
Hey, listen, maybe I ought to go over
there and spend a little time with her.
Yeah, maybe you'd better go home
and stop freeloading up here.
Freeloading? You just had one hell
of a meal. Who do you think paid for it?
- Nicky, we haven't had it yet. Relax.
- What's the difference, anyway?
He's gonna get it. He's got an obligation.
- My country's not at war.
- Oh, come on, man. That's shitty.
That is shitty. You apologise to Nick.
Tell him you're sorry.
Oh. Now, look that face.
Another eight weeks of not talking.
Hey, where are you going? You
haven't even had your sandwich yet.
- Let him go.
- I'm not gonna let him...
Will you let him go?
I mean, it's not surprising.
(Nina) 'You're always hassling,
the two of you.
'Look, I'm sick of this thing,
this in-between thing.'
(Police sirens wail)
(Distant sirens wail)
(TOY squeaks)
(Distant foghorn sounds)
(Water running)
(Lock clicks)
You slept later than usual.
I'm running a bath now.
(Door shuts)
(Hammering)
(Tap)
(Door rattles)
(Window rattles)
(Door creaks)
Don't think I can't get out of here.
I can get out any time I want.
And if you think by keeping me here,
I'm gonna get in bed with you,
you're wrong.
If I want a girl or anything,
I'll just go out and get one myself...
...and I might not come back.
(Clock ticks)
(Window rattles)
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
I don't want you to be angry with me.
I want you to stay here.
I want things to stay the way they are.
You can understand that, can't you?
I can't let you go.
Not now.
(Whispers) Sorry.
(Lock clicks)
(People chatter)
(Man) Sweet. Ha-ha-ha!
- (Man no. 2) My sister.
- (Man no. 1) You've got a sister?
- (Man no. 2) She does.
- (Chuckles)
(Man no. 1) Where would you get a sister?
(Man no. 2) I'm serious.
(Low chatter)
(Man no. 1) Eighty stitches.
The last time Eunice took
one of her old institution trips,
she stayed out there for three weeks.
(Men murmur)
Yeah?
She's pretty good.
She's sad.
- Well, I went down there...
- Yeah?
Well, you know, she is.
She's...
I tell you, I tell you,
this time she's finished.
Does she try keeping house?
Oh, man.
- She can't work. What can she do?
- Eighty stitches?
- Annie doesn't care.
Eighty stitches.
- She's...she's a dead chick.
- Mm.
(Toilet flushes)
Excuse me.
Do you happen to have the time?
No, I'm sorry. My watch is being fixed.
I think it's around 11 o'clock.
- Do you have some blush-on?
- What?
You know, blush-on,
stuff you blush on your cheeks.
- No, I'm sorry. I don't have...
- It's OK.
Are you alone?
I mean, are you meeting anybody?
No one in particular. Why?
Because, then, I have this...l have
a friend, a young friend, a man.
He's staying in my apartment, he can't
get out and I was wondering if you...
- What?
- ...if you would come home with me.
He's very lonely. I was wondering
if you would come home with me.
- You'd pay me?
- Oh, yes, of course I'd pay you.
Oh, wow. You are really something, lady.
You really are something. You've been
following me around, haven't you?
You've been watching me.
You know I'm a working girl, don't you?
Yeah, I'm a working girl, but I'm not a
pervert. So, leave me alone, will you?
Just leave me alone. Find your own
thing, but stay away from me.
(They laugh and chatter)
You know what's going on
in that bathroom?
What?
- There's a chick who's a pervert.
_
_ “h” 'WEN
Something else
you might not understand.
- She want to pay you?
- Yeah.
- It's your sister.
- (They laugh)
Probably wouldn't even make much.
- Have some of it.
- You could take a shot at that.
(Men laugh)
Come on.
Nobody's gonna worry about it.
Oh, that's her, is it?
Try the next one down the block.
It's the best dyke hangout in town.
(They laugh)
The lady needs some help.
Hey, where you going, man?
Where's he going?
Oh, come on. He's such a pig.
(They laugh)
Miss? Lady!
Wait a minute.
- I think I can help you.
- I don't believe so, thank you.
I understand you're looking for a friend?
No, I'm not looking for anyone now.
Look, I know my way around here
and I just thought I'd help you.
I suppose you think it's peculiar
or unusual that I should be asking.
I don't think
anything's peculiar or unusual.
You see, I have a man friend
who's staying in my apartment
and he couldn't come out himself
so he sent me.
How much you think he'll pay?
I don't know. I'm sorry.
We didn't discuss such a thing.
Whatever you suggest, I expect.
Things are pretty tight, I think...
anything safe'd probably cost him
30, 35 dollars.
Yes, well, I'm sure that he would be
willing to pay that. I'm quite sure.
I know a couple of places. Let's try 'em.
(Woman) Ducky, don't be mad at me.
(Ducky) Why shouldn't I be? You were out
all night again, till five this morning.
(Woman)
Well, I had to go and see my sister.
(Ducky) Oh, come on.
Why don't you just sit down here
and I'll work this out?
All right.
(Women murmur)
- My name's Burt.
- I know. What do you want?
I want to get a companion for her.
(Ducky)
Your sister has a phone, doesn't she?
Yes.
Why the hell didn't you use it?
That's what I want to know.
- What's your name, lady?
- I'm sorry?
- She gotta be nice, man. Pretty.
- How much will you pay?
Well, the gentleman said, er...30, 35.
50. 50 minimum for what you want.
- OK, we want to see her first.
- Go and get Sylvia.
AI, get the lady a coffee
while she's waiting.
No one in here's better than her.
(Ducky) I just want to know one thing...
What was he like?
That's all I want to know.
- (Woman) The young man was nice.
- Mm.
(Women murmur)
Madam, could I interest you
in a pamphlet?
The word of the Lord is written in here.
Read these two paragraphs.
You, sir, are a penitent.
Read the word of the Lord
as written in there. Bless you.
Right.
Aren't you beautiful?
Could I interrupt you for a moment
and offer you this pamphlet?
The true word of the Lord
is here revealed.
You shall find inner salvation and
happiness, if you read these few words...
(Ducky) Will you get the hell out of here?
Madam, you do not say,
"Get the hell out of here," to the Lord.
Knock it off and get the hell out of here!
Bless you, ladies.
The Lord will forgive you.
Over here.
This lady here wants you.
It's not for me. You understand?
- Where?
- It's at her place.
(Ducky's friend)
I didn't think about your needs...
OK.
OK?
You have to pay him now.
(Whispers) Oh, I'm sorry.
(Other women murmur)
(Ducky) I want to know one thing.
I want to know what...
Hey, lady. You got to pay
for your coffee. Fifteen cents.
- (Ducky) Can I choose where we go?
- (Friend) Yeah.
(indistinct)
(Meter clicks)
(Lock clicks)
(Door shuts)
(Lock rattles)
Would you come with me, please?
(Whispers) Please.
I'm sorry. I don't know your name.
Sylvia.
Yes, er...
...this is the boy that I told you about.
(Door rattles)
Oh, what? Are we locked in here?
Yeah, she's pretty handy
with the old key.
Am I supposed to be for her or for you?
Did she pay you?
Yeah.
How much?
20 bucks.
That's very generous.
I mean to me, not to you.
Oh.
Mm-hm.
Hm.
(Springs creak)
What is she? One of them voyeurs?
She looking through a little hole
somewhere around here?
- Are you looking at us, lady?!
- No, no, no, no.
She's...she's just a little mixed up,
that's all.
Yeah, well, I don't dig
those freak scenes, anyway.
But you look OK.
- (Laughs)
- Take it easy, all right?
- Oh! Take your sweater off.
- OK. All right, all right!
- Ha-ha!
- All right. Hold on for just a minute.
Wait. Listen, listen.
Let me go to the bathroom.
Hold on one sec. Hold on.
- There, that's right.
- All right.
OK, just hold on one second.
She's sure as hell not paying you
by the hour, is she?
(She moans)
Mm-hm.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing. Nothing's the matter.
- Nothing, that's right.
- It was something.
- Look, just...
- You're not concentrating.
Look, do you have to talk so much?
What is it? It's that freaky lady, right?
She's got you all upset.
Now...
Mm.
What are you...what are you
doing here with her?
Well, she's got me locked in,
for one thing.
You mean she's got you here
against your wishes?
If we're gonna carry on a conversation,
why don't we get up and get dressed?
Oh, mm.
Don't you like Sylvia?
- (Boy and Sylvia murmur)
- (Clock ticks)
(The boy) Go on!
(Sylvia) Cause when I get out of here,
you're coming right home with me.
OK? You've got to come with me.
- (Boy) Huh?
- (Sylvia) You've got to come with me.
- (Boy) Well, I don't know.
- (Sylvia) Well, I don't know(!)
- (Boy) We'll see. We'll see, all right?
- (Sylvia) Mm, mm, mm!
(Boy) Just hold on now
for one second, please.
- (Sylvia) Don't you...
- (Boy) All right.
(Sylvia laughs)
Oh. Oh.
- (Sylvia) Let me get a little feel.
- (Boy) All right.
Don't you like Sylvie?
(Clock ticks)
(Grunts)
(Sylvia murmurs)
' (Boy) Huh?
- (Sylvia) Oh.
(Sylvia) Now just you relax.
(Clock ticks)
(Sylvia) Don't be a little baby.
(Sylvia murmurs and laughs)
(Sylvia moans)
(They breathe hard)
- (Sylvia cries out)
- (Boy) What are you doing?
Stop it! Stop it!
(Sylvia cries out)
(Cries out)
(Shrieks)
Oh.
Were you frightened?
You don't have to be frightened now.
Oh, I'm so sorry.
There's no need to be frightened now.
Now, I've told her to go. I've told
that girl to get her things and go now.
There's no need for you
to be afraid now, you see.
I told her that you didn't like her
and that she should go.
And I said, "He doesn't like you
"and you should go."
Don't be afraid. Oh, please.
And you can stay with me now.
You don't have to be afraid. All right?
You can stay. There's no need to be
afraid now. You can stay with me.
All right.
I want you to make love to me.
Please.
Please, stay with me.
Mm.
I want you to make love to me.
Please.