(Emotional Trip with Poets)
(In Hadong, the literature capital)
(The members enjoy the trip as poets.)
(They are put through vicious training to become one.)
(The journey is all but pain though.)
(They heal through their own poems.)
(Poets' Spring Picnic)
(They play for a variety of prizes.)
("Drop Water Buckets")
(The penalty was water slaps.)
(Everything they experience serve as inspiration.)
(What will the rest of their journey look like?)
(They head to base camp.)
What's this smell?
I smell bulgogi.
Why do I smell bulgogi?
- I smell anchovies. - Director Yoo.
- Anchovies... - Stir-fried anchovies.
- No, I smell anchovy broth. - Are you hungry?
Joon Ho hasn't been able to eat.
He stinks more since he's on an empty stomach.
What smell?
- There's no need to pick at him. - Hold on.
My gosh.
- This is beautiful. - It's a mansion.
Welcome to my house.
- No, it's my house. - It's beautiful.
- What's that puppy doing there? - It's my house.
- Come on in. - Hi.
Look at the puppy.
- Yellow Teeth. - Hi, Yellow Teeth.
Hi, there.
- Hello! - Hello!
- Look, it's your dad. - He's adorable.
- Hello. - Your dad's here.
- Jong Min. - He's adorable.
Hi dear.
- We're here... - Hello.
in Jeongdong Village of Hadong.
The stream in the village is Akyang Stream.
It's a small village located on the flatland of Hadong,
and has been around the longest.
80 homes of 180 people currently occupy it.
- That's more than I expected. - Me too.
The name of this week's special is...
Emotional Trip with Poets.
We heard that a famous poet...
is a resident of the village,
so we invited him to join us.
Is it for real this time?
He might make us wear costumes again.
Please don't.
- Hold on. - Come on out.
You've got to be kidding.
(A mysterious bamboo hat)
As of now, you are the wandering poet Kim Sat Gat.
Please put on the robes.
Is this how it's done?
Tie the straps inside the robe first. Like this.
Dong Gu knows due to his time on period dramas.
You look like a martial arts expert.
For some reason, you look extraordinary.
He does.
(You're supposed to be Kim Sat Gat.)
The proper attire...
makes you all look like the wandering poet.
You look cooler when your face can't be seen.
That's right. Like this.
Wandering poet Kim Sat Gat traveled the country,
and left many poems wherever...
his feet took him.
Guys, it's "Bamboo".
Call me MC Kim Sat Gat.
- Go. - "Just let it be as it is."
- I can rap to it. - What's up?
"As the wind blows, as the waves break."
"However your life is, just live it."
"Right or wrong, just see as it is."
"When hosting guests, don't stretch money too thin."
I have a bad feeling about this.
"Follow the market price when buying or selling goods."
"Everything in this world never goes as planned."
"So live your life just like how it is."
Do we have to sell something?
- We'll recite our poems for food. - We have to beg?
We'll be selling poems.
I love how clever you have become.
As poets, we can read between the lines.
Don't you agree?
Today's "Dinner Game"...
is called "Wandering Poet Kim Sat Gat".
Just like you read in the poem "Bamboo",
you'll be roaming around Jeongdong Village...
like wind and water...
playing charades with the village people.
You will have to get three correct answers in time.
You can get 1 food per 1 house.
It's really hard. Do you remember?
Old people are quite bad at charades.
You can't just get the food for free.
When you complete the mission,
ask the player's name...
and make an acrostic poem out of it.
(That's a good idea.)
An acrostic poem?
Make an acrostic poem only out of the first name.
Joon Ho, laugh like this.
(Laughing)
(My gosh!)
(How dare you...)
- Like this, for example? - He got me.
Joon Ho and Tae Hyun are one team.
Jong Min and Defconn are one team.
Dong Gu and Joon Young are one team.
I don't think we will get that much food, though.
- How many minutes do we have? - All right.
- You have 1 hour. - In 1 hour.
Are you ready? Let's begin.
- Let's go! - Let's go.
- Hang on. - Please let us know when the time is up.
I'm a poet who wanders with the winds and clouds.
Anybody here?
We're travelers just passing by.
Hello, sir.
(The old man welcomes them with a warm smile.)
We'd like to play a game with you.
If you answer our questions correctly,
we're going to write you a poem as a present.
I think I can't do it. I can't understand you well.
- Shall we try anyway? - What if I lose?
It's fine even if you lose.
If you don't say the correct answer, we'll starve.
If you answer 3 questions correctly in 1 minute,
we can get some food from you.
So I shouldn't answer it correctly to keep my food.
- No way! - No!
You should! I haven't eaten anything today.
I haven't eaten anything since morning.
Ready, go.
- What is this called? - This.
- Wrinkles. - Yes!
That's correct.
(The game got off to a flying start.)
Sir, what is this?
(He imitates a dog pooping.)
It's about dogs.
It's a proverb. You can't find this when it's in need.
- You can't find dog poop when it's in need. - Yes!
(You're the best!)
What's another word for "idiot"?
Another word for "idiot"? Fool.
- Thank you. - You're really good.
You've got good sense.
Since you're hungry, I should give you some food.
- Yes. - I'm starving. I haven't eaten anything yet.
- Let's go have a look. - Let's go.
(He gladly invites them to his house.)
- Thank you. - Thank you, sir.
Take this.
- We can bring only one food. - Only one food.
(Right then, his wife shows up.)
Hello, ma'am. We played a game with your husband.
- I see. - And he answered the questions correctly.
You look more handsome than on the television.
- My goodness. - We can bring one food...
- that you give us. - One food?
- There are eggs. - It's very well-organized.
- There's kimchi as well. - What about some spinach?
- There's seasoned spinach. - There's a lot of food.
Choose anything.
You have some meat here as well.
(Tae Hyun looks through the food in the fridge.)
- They look delicious. - Can we take a look?
- Look at this. - What is that?
(He found an awesome dish.)
Gosh. Look at that.
- Oh my goodness. - How lucky we are.
(They found it.)
- My goodness. - What's that?
(Is it also jeon?)
Is it also...
Oh my goodness!
Why did you want to give us spinach when you have this?
(Upset)
- It might be for her husband. - That must be it.
I'm not sure if it's tasty.
Come on. It looks tasty.
(It looks delicious.)
I'm not sure if it's enough. Do you want this one?
I think it's enough. Leave some for your husband.
(Peeking)
It seems like he's quite upset.
(I'm fine. Take as much as you want.)
- Gosh - Would that be enough?
- Thank you. - This is enough.
(He writes an acrostic poem with her name.)
Sir, you should read this to her.
(Expectant)
- I'm reading this? - Yes.
Please read it while holding her hands.
- Do I have to... - Come on. Hold her hands.
(They hold each other's hands.)
- Let's go. - "Bong".
"What a lucky man I am."
- "Im". - "I'm lucky to have you, sweetheart."
(Shy)
It's an acrostic poem of "Bong Im".
Young Bae loves Bong Im.
(I love you.)
- I love you. - I love you.
Thank you so much for the food.
We don't need any more food.
- Thank you, ma'am. - You're welcome. Goodbye.
Thank you.
How about this place? Tae Hyun, how about this place?
- It's a food truck. - There's a man.
- We don't have time for that. - I'm sorry.
(Defconn and Jong Min visit the first house.)
Is anybody there?
(Luckily, someone is at home.)
- Hello. - Hello.
(Confused)
- We're from One Night Two Days. - Two Days.
- This is Kim Jong Min. - Hello.
(They're the people from television.)
Could you please introduce yourself? What's your name?
My name is Ha In Soon.
- Your name is Ha In Soon. - Ms. Ha In Soon.
Thank you so much for making good memories with us.
I'm happy to see you personally out of the television.
- Why don't you give her a hug? - Ma'am.
(Jong Min gives her a hug.)
- Goodness. - Good job.
I laugh every time you are on the television.
(Jong Min is an expert at entertaining old people.)
- Let's give her the questions. - Let's begin.
We will begin the game now.
Ready, go.
Ma'am. What's the vehicle?
(Luckily, a cultivator is in the yard.)
- A cultivator. - Correct!
- Ma'am, it's... - It's the underwear.
- What is this in English? - This.
- That? - This.
- Money pouch. - No.
- It's an underwear. - You wear it inside.
- "Undies". - Right. What is another word for it?
(What's another word for "undies"?)
We'll skip this question.
(Na Hoon A)
- I don't know why I'm like this - It's a singer.
(The answer is on the tip of her tongue.)
- He's a singer. - I don't know.
Never mind. Next.
What is it called when it suddenly rains a lot?
- Three syllables. - A shower.
All right. Now...
(This is...)
(They never discussed this beforehand.)
- Shim Hyung Rae. - Shim Hyung Rae.
(I have no idea.)
Skip this one.
- You failed. - Why?
"Undies" and "panties" are the same.
- That should count. - It should.
- Ma'am, they're the same, right? - Yes, they are.
- "Undies" and "panties" are the same. - Exactly.
(The director is cornered.)
We call them "undies". We never call them "panties".
See? They don't call them "panties".
- They speak dialect. - Exactly.
- Are you sure? - Yes. I also call them "undies".
So she got three answers correctly, right?
Okay, I take your point.
- We got all three right? - Yes.
We did it.
- Good job. - We made it, ma'am.
(It's all thanks to you.)
(She goes into the house to get some food.)
- You did a great job. - "Undies" is correct.
(He feels like he's fooled.)
Take this.
- What are these? - They're eggs.
- That's a lot of eggs! - Don't worry.
- These are... - Aren't they the eggs of an argus?
- They are too many. - We don't need so many.
- Please take some back. - Just eat all of them.
Just give us six eggs.
Then how about this?
We'll bring the leftover back.
You don't need to bring them back.
That's really nice of you.
(They're both nice to each other.)
Just eat them. They're tasty.
- But... - Boil them and eat. It's tasty.
- Ma'am. - They're fresh.
They're too good to eat.
Whenever I eat the egg, I'll remember her, Ha In Soon.
- Thank you, ma'am. - You're overreacting.
- You should make an acrostic poem for her. - Sure.
- Since your name is In Soon... - Yes, it is.
Let's start with "In".
- You're warm-hearted and beautiful. - There you go.
Here comes the best part. "Soon".
In Soon, we love you!
Do you like it? Thank you.
- Stay healthy. - Stay healthy, ma'am.
- Thank you. - Thank you for the eggs.
No other food can beat our eggs.
Argus eggs are rare. That's a big house.
Is anybody here?
- Hello. - Hello.
- We're from One Night Two Days. - Hello.
Take off your hat and bow to her.
Thank you for welcoming us.
I've been watching you on the rooftop.
- Really? - Yes.
- Now, let's play... - Right.
Don't cut in line.
Hey, we came here first.
- Go away. - Go away.
- Hello. - You look familiar.
(Joon Young and Dong Gu suddenly interrupt.)
- Welcome. - Get ready.
(She's happy to see the young men.)
- Step aside. - Did you guys fail?
We're here because we heard you are a great cook.
Let's start.
You should guess 3 answers correctly in 1 minute.
- Please give me the easy ones. - Ready, go.
(Hair perm)
- It's a way you make your hair curly. - Curly hair.
- "Hair perm". - Correct.
This is a proverb. What does one's enemy get?
- One's enemy gets more rice cake. - Correct.
- She's good at this. - It's a bear from China.
- Its eyes are dark. - It's...
- What was it? It's black. - It's black and white.
- It has six letters. - Hurry up.
- It has two letters. - I don't know.
- Let's skip it. - Skip it.
What's the clothing you wear on the New Year's Day.
- Seolbim. - Yes!
- What's her name? - Let's make a poem.
- Do it after we play the game. - No.
What food would you like to give us?
I'll give you seasoned vegetables.
- Seasoned vegetables? - Yes, it's very tasty.
- It's bitter. - It tastes bitter?
- It makes you healthy. - It's bitter.
We should come back later.
I admire your writing skills.
- Right. - Ta-da.
(What dishes will the lady give them?)
Dried whole persimmons and dried half persimmons.
- Thank you so much. - Here you go.
Can we eat it as it is?
- Of course. - Thank you.
- It's the local crop. - All right.
- Thank you. - You're only allowed one.
- Don't be absurd. - They're the same thing.
One's just cut in half.
- You're being ridiculous. - Only one.
- These... - They're the same thing.
They're both persimmons.
You can give them one out of the two.
Why can't I give them both? They're the same.
All right. How about this?
I think these look better.
Really?
Let's go with the dried whole persimmons.
Ma'am, thank you so much.
We'll get going then. Thank you.
Thank you and be healthy.
Is this a car wash?
(Dong Gu and Joon Young are in search of another dish.)
- Hello. - Hi.
- Hi, sir. - Thanks for coming all the way.
- Have you eaten? - Not yet.
- What's on the menu? - Are you delivering Chinese?
(Are you delivering Chinese?)
(A Chinese restaurant delivery box)
- Hello, ma'am. - We're from One Night Two Days.
- Welcome. - We're here to ask for some food.
I have nothing special except for seasoned baby aster.
I only have vegetables.
What about pork cutlet?
Hold on a second.
Would you like some?
- My gosh. - We're good with just the vegetables.
All right. Let the game begin.
What do you receive to relieve tension in your muscles?
- "Anma". - In English, ma'am.
- How should I know? - Give us another word.
- Here. - That's nice.
A massage!
(The husband got it right.)
- Ma'am, what's this? - A wink.
That is correct.
(Her husband couldn't help but look how she reacted.)
Next question.
- Did I see the answer? - You did.
Hold on a second.
- She's... - She's a middle-aged actress.
She's quite short and says this famous line. "It's me."
"It's me."
- Jeon Won Joo. - That is correct!
- They got all three correct. - Nice!
- You guys were great. - Thank you.
They were quick to answer.
(She packs them a box full of seasoned baby aster.)
That's a lot.
That's more than enough.
(She gives them a generous amount.)
Thank you so much.
(We'll enjoy this.)
(Dong Gu tries some on the spot.)
- Is it good? - It's tasty.
You can smell its sweet aroma.
It's delicious.
What was this again?
It's seasoned baby aster.
Could I ask your name, sir?
It's Oe Su.
"How could you do this to me?"
"Every Wednesday."
(What on earth was that?)
"He has..."
"very good looks."
(He sure has a good eye.)
There we go.
You should sign it with your pen name, Beef Tongue.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
Thank you for the vegetables.
Take care.
Is there a place where we can ask for meat?
- No. - I see.
Ma'am!
Excuse us.
- Hello. - Hi, we're from One Night Two Days.
Your time starts now.
(Plastic surgery)
You change your face with surgery.
The double-eyelid surgery?
- No. - Your entire face.
- Plastic surgery? - That is correct.
Toast "this" on a flash of lightening.
- Swish. - Beans?
- That is correct. - Correct.
- What Boseong is famous for? - Sorry?
Boseong is famous for something green.
- Green tea. - That is correct!
- Nice! - Yes.
You were amazing, ma'am.
(Dong Gu kisses her in gratitude.)
We'd appreciate some steamed rice.
- Steamed rice? - Yes.
At their age, they should eat plenty.
- Thank you. - There you go.
Thank you so much.
("Your innocent smile brought us happiness" by Dong Gu)
- How about this way? - Let's head into the alley.
- Here. - All right.
Hello. Anyone here?
- My goodness. - Hi.
- Hello. - It's nice to meet you.
Thank you for all your hard work.
We're sorry for rushing you.
Ready and go!
(The charades begin.)
(My goodness, don't be this way)
Jang Yoon Jeong.
(Jang Yoon Jeong)
A couple part ways after marriage.
- A divorce. - That's right.
You never know...
- Your luck. - Your luck.
(They're the best!)
- Unbelievable. - You were first to finish the game.
(They had chemistry like no other team.)
Thank you so much.
I'm afraid we've yet to obtain steamed rice.
I'll cook some right away then.
Don't you have any leftover steamed rice?
- I do, but it's not much. - That's fine.
Should I write a poem with the name "Young Jun"?
I'm afraid we don't have the time.
"I love you."
Could you hold your wife's hand?
"My sweet Hyang Soon."
- "Soon". - "You are pure and mesmerizing."
"I love you."
Could you say that looking into her eyes?
I love you.
(You're embarrassing me.)
Thank you so much.
Take care then.
Thank you.
- The pleasure's ours. - Thank you.
- Take care. - Thanks.
I think we have time for one last stop.
I think someone's home.
Is anyone home?
- Hello. - Hi, ma'am.
Hello.
Ma'am, is she your daughter?
Wait. Play charades with us.
Can you play charades with us?
Hi, I'm Joon Ho.
- What's your name? - It's Kyu Ri.
- Kyu Ri? - I see.
If you answer correctly, we can receive food to eat.
You just have to guess the answers.
It's okay to get it wrong.
Ready, go.
Who teaches classes in school?
- What was that? - The teacher.
That is correct.
It's an animal that hangs from a tree like this.
- Its nose is black. - Three syllables.
- Its fur is gray. - A koala bear.
Where do you go when your teeth hurt?
The dentist.
(They'll receive another dish thanks to clever Kyu Ri.)
Kyu Ri, thank you so much.
You're a genius.
- Do you have ramen? - Yes, we do.
- Let's take that. She can cook it for us. - Ramen?
Ma'am, can you cook us some ramen?
We're a real nuisance.
You have only 8 minutes. Get it done within 8 minutes.
Ma'am, we have only eight minutes.
That can be done.
(She even adds in clams.)
(While the ramen cooks...)
"Kyu Ri, you're the future..."
- "Leader." - I like that.
- It's good. - You have five minutes left.
Ma'am, five minutes!
It's cooking right now.
See? It's cooking away.
(She cooks it as if it's for her own children.)
- Thank you so much. - We love you.
- Bye, Kyu Ri. - Always be healthy, ma'am.
Take care.
We did so well.
(They return to base with food from the locals.)
- Tae Hyun. - Yes?
- Good job. - You too.
The others should receive a penalty. They're not here.
- Just so you know, we gave up pork belly. - Exactly.
- My goodness. - Ma'am!
You can't leave just yet.
- Hello, ma'am. - Hi.
- Hello. - One Night Two Days.
- Nice to meet you, ma'am. - This is our team.
- Look who it is. - This is Jong Min.
- We'll get right to the game then. - Right.
- Let's go. - I'm worried that I won't get anything.
You can do it. Everyone else managed to do so.
Your time starts now.
Someone who can't sing.
- He can't carry a tune. - A tone-deaf.
- Nice. - That is correct.
Which network does our show air on?
- The Korea... - Which network are we on?
KBS1.
- KBS1. - That is correct.
- Next question. - Come on.
She said "KBS1".
- Then... - KBS2.
- Omit the number. - KBS.
That is correct.
What do you take when you can't poop?
- It's a medicine. - A medicine.
- You're almost there. - Constipation medicine.
(Success!)
You did great, ma'am.
- Thank you. - That was amazing.
- Can we come inside? - Can we?
We asked after stepping inside the house.
Are those strawberries?
We'd love that.
Argus eggs are very good for you.
You and your husband should try some.
(While Jong Min writes a poem,)
(the husband makes the coffee.)
Sir, that's more than enough.
We're fine with just that.
I boiled a whole pot of water though.
(He ends up giving everyone a cup.)
- Here you go. - This wasn't necessary.
Are you going to take it away? He made it for us.
- He's right. - I'll only allow one cup.
(Take that!)
You all should have a cup of coffee too.
Thank you, sir.
(He makes sure the staff all gets one too.)
It's not easy to notice the entire staff.
(Meanwhile...)
Goodness.
(She's making fried eggs with blue eggs.)
(It's all so that they can have a warm dinner.)
- You should leave some for yourselves. - It's okay.
Please keep a few.
- Here. - It's all right.
No, we won't accept it.
- You have a big crew. - It's okay.
- Take this then. - We're good.
Don't forget the salt.
- Take care. - Thank you.
Thank you!
- Make way. - Make way!
I'm worried that we have too much.
(They return to base with a generous amount of food.)
Now it's time for you to have dinner.
I hope your boxes are full.
We were able to feel the generosity...
- and love of the locals. - I agree.
- They wanted to give us more. - Right.
- It was hard saying no. - I know.
I'm happy that...
we were able to write them heartfelt poems.
Even if they didn't have food, I wouldn't care.
I was glad I could give them something.
You gave them something?
I don't even know what I'm saying.
I'm so hungry.
Joon Ho needs to eat something.
I know.
He didn't eat a single meal today.
All right.
Let's see what kind of food you got.
- Joon Ho and Tae Hyun. - We got...
What's that?
This is amazing. We got this at the first try.
- At the first try? - Is it good?
We got jeon.
- Gosh. - We got a good one at the first try.
I can't believe this.
- Jeon? - Is it warm?
I'm not sure if I should let you see this.
Defconn would be very excited.
What? What is it?
- It's pork belly meat. - Gosh.
Pork belly meat?
(When they were at Young Jun and Hyang Soon's house...)
("You never know your luck".)
I should give them pork.
- Pork? - Did she say pork?
Do you have pork?
(She gave them two hunks of pork belly beat.)
How could you get those?
We even got a frying pan to cook it.
That's amazing.
Where did they get it?
This is the last one.
When we didn't have enough time,
I told them we didn't have rice and kimchi.
- Did you get soup? - What kind of soup?
It's ramyeon.
- Ramyeon? - She even cooked it for us.
- Ramyeon? - Yes.
It smells great.
Is that it?
- Yes. - We should hurry.
I don't want our ramyeon to get soggy.
It's our turn.
- You have a lot of kimchi. - You'll be excited.
You can eat this with pork belly meat.
- Is it green onion kimchi? - Green onion kimchi.
Look at the color.
It's a lot.
You should have left some for her.
- Why did you get it all? - You took it all.
You should have got a portion of it.
I told her not to give us all of it,
but she insisted on giving all of it to us.
- We had no choice. - What is he doing?
You can also eat this with pork belly meat.
It's aged kimchi.
It's kimchi again.
- That's not true. - All you have is kimchi.
- It'd be too salty. - Right.
What's that? It's spring vegetables.
This is spring vegetables.
- Spring vegetables? - It's good.
It's very savory because of sesame oil.
I'm sorry, but are you eating them without rice?
I don't think you have this.
Is it rice?
It's rice.
- It's a lot. - Rice with beans.
It wasn't easy to get rice as they usually cook rice...
- just before they eat. - Right.
It was hard.
That's very tempting.
It'd go well with our food.
All right.
I don't think Jong Min has any food.
You'll be surprised to see what I have.
We have...
- Show us. - First.
(What food do they have?)
At our first try,
we met a big fan of Jong Min.
That's right.
In fact, there was a small controversy.
The answer was panties, but she said undies.
They are the same though.
(The food they get is...)
- Fried eggs. - Undies?
- Wow. - Yes!
There's more.
Do you remember the color of these eggs?
- What's that? - These are blue eggs.
Blue eggs.
They grew it themselves.
We got fried eggs and boiled eggs.
Why did you bring them all?
She insisted giving us all.
That's a good one.
It must be delicious.
We got dried whole persimmon kept in the fridge.
It tastes like dried whole persimmon sherbet.
- Sherbet? - It's cool.
- It must be delicious. - It's dried whole persimmon.
It melts away in your mouth.
- It's good. - I tried it earlier.
And...
Jong Min, take this.
This is for dessert.
All you have is desserts.
Why is that?
- They are very fresh strawberries. - Why?
- Is that it? - Wait.
Will you eat only fruits?
- Do you have something else? - Yes.
We have something more.
On the way back to the base camp,
we got some ramyeon.
That's good.
Are you going to eat them uncooked?
(Frozen)
How are you going to eat it?
Well, I will...
That's ridiculous.
Are you going to eat pork belly meat raw?
- You won't get a pot. - So we brought...
this frying pan to cook it.
- You should have brought a pot. - I won't eat yours.
There was a controversy over this ramyeon.
- What? - Why?
All right.
Defconn and Jong Min...
arrived at around 6:30pm.
- Stop it. - What's going on?
Why would you say that?
I said you had one hour.
You were late.
- That's not true. - Hey.
If they told me time was up,
we would have come in time.
The director told us...
- it was okay to get more food. - Right.
But I gave you one hour.
If you told us we were going to be late,
we would've come in time.
He's right.
We had to stop cooking ramyeon as the time was up.
We had only two minutes left, we came running.
Then you should have...
brought the ramyeon uncooked.
We just came back without stopping anywhere.
I didn't know that either.
- Let's take a seat. - We should listen to him.
Why are you doing this to me?
I overreacted.
- He said he overreacted. - Listen to him.
As Jong Min and Defconn arrived late,
we should take back the ramyeon.
We will give you something else.
This is the main dish.
We'll give you dried whole persimmon.
Dried whole persimmon.
The residents gave them to you, so I won't take it.
But you'll have to share it with other members.
- Dried whole persimmon? - No, ramyeon.
- That's nice. - Yes!
(It's a windfall for other members.)
We should share all the foods.
- We can't do that. - Give us some rice.
Instead,
I will give you a pot.
That's good.
We'll cook it and share it with you.
- That's good. - Our ramyeon is getting soggy.
Can you wrap it up?
I don't want to eat their ramyeon.
Now you may start eating dinner.
(Despite their unannounced visit,)
(the local residents greeted them with a warm smile.)
(They gave the members more than enough food.)
(Thanks to their loving hearts, the dinner is ready.)
(Joon Ho and Tae Hyun got ramyeon, pork, and jeon.)
(Dong Gu and Joon Young got kimchi and baby aster.)
(Jong Min and Defconn got all sorts of desserts.)
- Enjoy. - Enjoy.
The ramyeon has seafood in it.
Seafood?
(He tastes ramyeon first.)
This is delicious.
(Blowing)
(Joon Ho skipped meals the whole day.)
Wow!
It's so good.
(He lets out exclamations of delight.)
Joon Ho.
We have six fried eggs here.
I want to share them with other members.
- I see. - I'll give you some eggs.
That's nice.
If you insist,
I'll barter with you.
- We have boiled eggs too. - Okay.
We have fried eggs.
These are boiled eggs.
It looks good.
(Although they don't have much,)
(they share what they have with others.)
Bring some of it.
(It is now a decent meal.)
Can I get more rice?
- Do you want more? - Is it kimchi?
(They share the residents' love.)
Enjoy.
- Thank you for the food. - Thank you.
Thank you for the food.
Thank you.
Here you are.
They have various kinds of jeon.
- This is delicious. - I like this.
Right.
(It's hot!)
What is this?
This is so good.
They are so generous.
I'll eat it with green onion kimchi.
- Wow. - It's so good.
(He eats pork with green onion kimchi.)
This is great.
It's amazing.
(Everyone feels happy eating dinner.)
This is like a party.
He's right.
Help yourself.
I'll eat this.
(Satisfied)
This is nice.
How does it taste?
It's like homemade food.
It's the taste of love.
You're eating love?
I eat a lot of instant food.
And I eat Western food a lot too.
It's so good to eat some homemade food.
I know.
(They missed Korean food.)
She cooked this jeon...
for her husband.
She put all the ingredients on skewers...
- Right. - I'd say I'm eating her love.
That was poetic.
I'm eating her love.
(Love is all around the tables.)
Are strawberries in season now?
Look at the strawberries. They are so red.
- It's so good. - It's so red.
It's delicious.
They are so fresh.
Did they add food coloring or what?
I love the color.
It looks like a strawberry...
on a cake covered with syrup.
You're right.
Did they add food coloring or what?
I love the color.
It's very sweet.
I love it.
We have to finish all the food.
I love the strawberries.
Thank you for the food.
- Thank you. - Thank you.
Thank you very much.
We really enjoyed it.
(After dinner, they are gathered in the village hall.)
We have six poets here.
We are traveling...
in Hadong with the poets.
- Are we still poets? - Of course.
- Are we still poets? - Yes.
I didn't know that.
So we brought in...
real poets this time.
- Gosh. - You're lying.
I won't fall for that.
Stop it.
Before meeting famous poets,
you will appreciate their poems.
Bring it in.
What's that?
I know what it is.
Is it a children's poem?
(It has cute drawings and poor handwriting.)
(They seem to be children's poems.)
Are these children's poems?
I don't think so.
I think mothers wrote them.
He's right. It'd be children...
or old ladies who just learned Hangul.
(Who on earth wrote those poems?)
It looks like children's writing.
I want you to read the poems one by one.
Pooping, can you read out one of the poems?
"I was going to sow beans,"
"but I had to study Hangul..."
"so I came running hurriedly."
"I'll sow the rest later."
"I think pheasants will peck at my poem..."
"as well as my beans."
I know what that means.
Is that a pheasant?
- It is. - It's a pheasant.
It means that a pheasant ate all the beans.
What does the last part mean then?
(What could it possibly mean?)
I think it means "like mine".
"I came running hurriedly" sounds so cute.
- "I came running hurriedly". - To study Hangul.
So she was on her way to learn Hangul.
It looks like she just learned to write.
- Kang Jeom Soon. - Read the next one.
It's by Lee Soon Ja.
Tae Hyun, please read it.
"Lee Soon Ja."
"I planted cucumber and eggplant."
"They grew quickly and bore many fruits."
"I started studying at Jeongdong School..."
"when I was 72 years old."
"I'm very grateful for the two teachers..."
"and I'm going to study diligently."
"If there's a good path I should follow,"
"I will without asking questions."
- It shows her determination. - It's great.
It's a nice illustration. She drew it so well.
Do you see those eggplants?
- She seems to be artistic. - She must be.
We have the last poem here.
- "In the World". - Dong Gu will read it.
"The best words in the world are..."
"from the teachers."
"The best faces in the world are..."
"the smiling faces."
"My face reflected in the mirror smiles."
"My teacher's face is pretty like a flower."
The teacher must be so happy.
She's very loved by her students.
She expressed herself using...
- auditory and visual imagery. - What?
She described faces and sounds.
Pardon?
Let's bring out Jeongdong Village's poets.
Please come out.
- They're here. - The ladies.
Ma'am.
(Hadong Jeongdong Village's...)
(3 female poets enter.)
- Hello. - Nice to meet you.
- It's good to see you. - Hello.
(They greet people one by one.)
- Hi, Jeom Soon. - Hello.
Goodness.
Please introduce yourselves.
Hi, I'm Kim Gil Ja.
Welcome everyone. Thanks for coming.
- Hello. - I'm Kang Jeom Soon.
Hello, ma'am. And?
- Hi, I'm Lee Soon Ja. - Hi.
You came all the way for three old ladies.
Don't say that. We were so moved.
Your poems are beautiful.
- You're embarrassing me. - I'm serious.
You must be learning to write.
Are you learning to write?
- Yes. Twice a week in the evening. - Okay.
- On Tuesdays and Thursdays. - I see.
(Class is held at a village hall twice a week.)
(The village elderly has Hangul lessons.)
Please take a look.
(She's their passionate teacher.)
(The students are even more passionate than her!)
(I got a perfect score!)
(This is Jeongdong Village's Hangul School.)
Did good things happen after you learned Hangul?
- Of course. - You're now able to read.
Before I couldn't write letters or send texts...
- to my kids or grandchildren. - I see.
It was so frustrating. I heard they taught Hangul.
So I decided to learn it no matter what...
and study as hard as I could until I'm able.
- You're amazing. - I'll stop only when I can't walk.
You wrote "Studying is needed in my life".
You mentioned it in your poem.
- Ma'am. - Yes?
I guess you hated pheasants when you wrote that.
Of course. I planted beans...
and they kept eating them.
- Pheasants ate them? - Yes.
- Were you late for your class... - Yes.
because you went to plant beans?
I tried to make it on time.
Is that why you ran super hard?
- I did. - That part was great.
Ma'am, there's something we don't understand.
What does the last line mean?
- This last phrase. - We don't understand.
They're eating my poems too.
- I see. - They're eating her poems.
- That's very poetic. - They're eating the poem.
The pheasants are eating the beans...
and also her poems.
They're eating up her time too.
(Everyone is surprised by her ingenuity.)
- She is really creative. - That's amazing.
That poem written by Kang Jeom Soon...
won the Flower Prize at the national elderly...
exhibition of illustrated poems.
(She won the Flower Prize.)
- Flower Prize. - She deserves it.
- Her poems is beautiful like a flower. - Yes.
- A flower-like poem. - Yes.
She's a fan of One Night Two Days.
- I always watch it. - She was so happy to see us.
Do you watch it every week?
Yes. I watch it every day.
Which one do you like the most?
What? I love you all. You're all funny.
But please pick one.
- What? - Please choose one.
(Who's Jeom Soon's favorite?)
It's so nice to see everyone here. I'm happy.
- Thank you. - I'm so happy.
You're all funny. I like you all.
She likes us all equally.
We have three poets with us.
Today's "Sleeping Indoors or Outdoors" game...
will be played with Jeongdong Village poets.
It's "Poem under the Moonlight".
- It's a poetry reading. - Poetry reading.
It'll be a poetry reading under the moonlight.
Poetry reading on a rainy night.
How do we play?
1 poet and 2 members will make a team...
and write a poem.
We'll make the teams now.
- You guys... - Is it like before?
prepared gifts for the poets, right?
- Yes. - What?
(Did we prepare gifts?)
- Before... - That's right.
(Who did?)
- Before coming here... - That's right. Yes.
- I see. - Yes. We prepared them.
(It can't be.)
- We had to do that. - Yes.
(You jerks.)
That's right.
(You said you'd give us nice gifts if we worked hard.)
(That's why we ran...)
He almost got him.
(and endured unbearable pain.)
(Gifts were acquired after hard work.)
(That's why we couldn't take the gifts.)
That's why you didn't let me put it in my trunk.
Are you talking about the coffee mix?
(Dumbfounded)
You're taking the gifts away.
What do you mean? You earned those...
for these ladies.
(We can't tell the ladies...)
(they can't have the gifts.)
I have a really great gift.
(He feels bitter.)
- It's a massage mat. - Look at his face.
(I already decided where to put it.)
- Please bring out the gifts. - Bring them.
(Here they come.)
(He's dispirited.)
(They prepared various gifts...)
(without meaning to.)
All right. Here are all the gifts.
As you see, there a massage mat.
(Tae Hyun's gift is a massage mat.)
Joon Ho brought detergent.
- It's a set of detergents. - It's clean.
Si Yoon prepared...
- a gift card. - It's worth 300 dollars.
You can use this when you go grocery shopping.
- Joon Young prepared... - It's gold.
- It's a gold necklace. - It's real gold.
- It's solid gold weighing 7.5g. - Goodness.
(Laughing)
You didn't smile when you saw my gift.
But you're all smiling now.
I can't help but smile after seeing gold.
- Well... - There's toilet paper too.
(She doesn't even look.)
This is really... Ma'am.
- Please look here. - Yes.
(She shows no interest.)
Ma'am. I have coffee mix.
(Okay. You can drink it.)
Great. Thank you.
- It's gold colored coffee mix. - Okay.
(I have a lot of those at home.)
- All right. - Got it.
First, the ladies will choose...
one of three of you with the nicer gifts.
(They pick a paper with their names on it.)
Just pick any one.
Okay. The first team.
- All right. - Dong Gu and Lee Soon Ja.
Kim Gil Ja is with Jung Joon Young.
Kang Jeom Soon is with Cha Tae Hyun.
- Okay. - Kim Gil Ja gets the gold!
(Gil Ja will have the gold she so wanted.)
- I'm sorry. - Everyone's happy.
(Now they choose the less nicer gifts.)
Let's just pick in order.
- Defconn. - Goodness.
Kim Gil Ja is with me.
- Okay. - Lee Soon Ja is with Jong Min.
- It's all good. - His is detergent.
(The final teams of "Poem under the Moonlight".)
Daily supplies.
I will tell you the topic of...
"Sleeping Indoors or Outdoors".
The topic for your poem is...
My Story.
- "My Story"? - My Story.
The ladies will write poems...
based on the lives they led.
Do we write it?
The ladies will write the poems.
You will draw pictures.
- You can help them with pictures. - We can color.
All right. You'll go to your partner's house.
You'll write poems there and reconvene here after.
(They'll start writing their poems for the reading.)
(Off to the ladies' houses.)
Let's go, ma'am. Where is your place?
(After the fun meeting)
We'll go to your place now.
(Joon Ho and Joon Young head to her house.)
Today's theme is "my story".
- It makes me worried. - It has to be your story.
I'm worried.
(She's worried about the theme.)
It'll be hard to turn it into a poem.
It's not an essay, but a poem.
I think if she starts writing,
it'll naturally become a poem.
As I study,
I'm not sure when enough is enough.
The pleasure of learning is great, right?
It is great.
That's why I thought I should learn...
- no matter how hard it is. - You're right.
- We're here. - This must be your house.
Yes. This is my house.
- What is that? - All right. Hi, doggy.
I think you surprised the dog.
No. We're just guests. All right. Don't bark.
Gosh. Here is her work.
She made drawings.
She made drawings here.
- She won many awards. - She did.
I see you won a grand prize.
"Hadong Adult Literature Education Awards".
You won it with your poem.
It was on our local newspaper.
You were on the newspaper? You're famous here.
- No, I'm not. - Here it is.
Here. "Illustrated poems that show what life is".
The newspaper bannered an article about you.
It's my poem about a pheasant pecking my writing.
- We have to write a poem now. - We do.
I know. What should we write about?
- We'll think of something as we talk. - Yes.
I'm sure we will.
- Hello. - Please let us look around a bit.
Sure. Go ahead.
- Can you show us around? - There isn't much to see.
- Thank you. - Sure.
(It's a private space of one person.)
- It's nice. - I'm sorry it's a bit messy.
- Hold on. Is that your husband? - Yes.
That's his portrait I drew.
You drew this yourself?
- The teacher helped me. - Still.
(She drew her late husband's portrait.)
You're a good painter.
You drew it on November 30, 2011.
- She looks pretty. - Look at this picture.
(They looks for a new side of her.)
When was this?
It's a long time ago.
That was at the Chrysanthemum Festival in Asan.
(Their conjugal affection is shown on it.)
- We were in Asan. - With your husband?
Yes.
(It brings back her old memories.)
Do you have any old pictures?
I'm not sure if it's here.
I have to look for it.
Let's take a look.
This is a very old photo album.
- Shall we see it in the living room? - Okay.
- All right. - Hi, kitty.
- Adle, come here. - Hi, kitty.
- What's his name? - Adle.
- Adle? - Yes.
I heard it's a name of a singer in a faraway country.
- You mean Adele. - Yes. Adele.
- It's Adele. - It's Adele.
(She's a world-class singer who won two Grammy awards.)
- I thought she said, "Adle". - It's Adele.
- Adele. - Adele.
(I'm shy.)
- All right. Now, this is... - Gosh.
the life story of Kim Gil Ja, the poet.
Gosh. Don't call me a poet.
- Let's take a look. - All right.
It has all her memories.
When was this?
It's a very long time ago.
- It was around the time we got married. - I see.
- Were you 20 when you got married? - No. I was 22.
- You got married when you were 22? - Yes.
How did you meet your husband?
It was an arranged marriage.
- It was arranged. - Yes.
- How old was your husband then? - He was 27.
These are pictures of him when he was young.
(In the faded photo album,)
Aren't they?
(there are moments of his youth.)
- Gosh. - This is him.
This is your husband, right?
(I miss those days.)
Why don't you tell us about the old days?
The old days?
Let's hear about Poet Kim Gil Ja's love story.
- We should hear it. - There was no love back then.
- We lived the way we were told to. - Really?
Our parents told us when we should get married,
and whom we should marry.
There was no such thing as love.
All right.
"There is no love."
(Laughing)
- Love is... - Gosh.
- Love does exist. - Really? I'm sorry.
Love does exist. That's not what I meant.
I'm just saying we weren't in love when we met.
When you first met your husband,
how was his first impression?
- My husband was handsome, - Yes.
but I wasn't pretty. If he had seen me,
he wouldn't have married me.
He married me because he hadn't seen me.
Did you get married without meeting?
We did.
That's how things were back then.
You just promised to marry each other without meeting.
- That's right. - How about before the wedding?
- Please be honest. - I made a hole on the door,
and took a peek.
- A hole on the door? - In the countryside,
the doors are made with paper.
- You can make holes. - We could make holes.
(He loves this kind of things.)
It's true.
I hope you'll include this in your poem.
- "Secret"... - "Secret Love".
(They think of the same title.)
"Secret Love".
Please show us what you did.
- Gosh. - Please make a hole.
You made a hole.
- And... - Go around, Joon Young.
- He was standing over there. - Okay.
- I was peeking like this. - Hold on.
Were your friends there with you?
Many people were there including the matchmaker.
I'll be the matchmaker then.
Let's see.
It's the man standing on the yard. He's the one.
I didn't want to marry him.
I suddenly felt I didn't want to marry him,
but the matchmaker insisted that I should.
All right. I just...
- got inspiration. - That's what happened.
Place the paper closer to the camera.
There is something peculiar about the sight.
- Is it? What do you mean? - Move it a bit.
- Isn't it the same? - No.
(He somehow looks handsome.)
It makes your heart flutter a bit.
- It really does. - If you peep through the hole.
You must've felt thrilled.
I didn't really know. I was too young.
Gosh, but you did take a peek.
I did take a peek, but I didn't really feel anything.
I was only 22. I didn't know anything.
(You must've been thrilled.)
Be careful. The water is dropping here. There's a step.
(It's a cozy and peaceful house of an old couple.)
(Her study is in the corner.)
- Is this the room? - Yes.
- Gosh. - This is her study.
(It's filled with the pleasant smell of books.)
She must study here. She's amazing.
(It's her cozy study.)
(She wrote each character carefully,)
(and studied hard every day.)
- I can see that... - It's a lot.
Yes. There are sketchbooks,
and many books...
- she studied. - This is a notebook.
We'll put these aside for now.
Are these all poems?
- We studied... - Gosh. It's your new poem.
We studied last night, and the teacher...
told me to write it, so that's what I wrote.
Is it okay to take a look?
It's just embarrassing.
- It shows her sensibility. - Yes.
Gosh, I think...
She is a poet of love.
"The person I love the most is..."
"my husband whom I've whispered love..."
"under the same blanket. I love him the most."
- "Under the same blanket". - It's embarrassing.
I'm too old for that. I'm embarrassed.
- Hello, sir. - Gosh. We must've woken you up.
- Hello, sir. - Gosh.
(It's her husband, the love of her life.)
What do you like about him so much?
The person I need the most...
is my husband.
- Gosh. - I need him more than my children.
You need him more.
- Of course. - You must really love him.
I think that's the best thing. I really do.
When were you born?
- I was born in 1944. - I see.
That means you went through the Korean War.
- Yes. - You went through it.
Could you tell us a bit?
When the Korean War broke out...
- Did they attack this region? - They did.
I had just entered elementary school.
- At that time? - Yes.
I entered the school in the spring,
and a plane bombed our school in June.
- Goodness. - A plane?
I was only a little girl,
and I went to school without knowing anything.
It was a mess with dust and fallen trees.
- Gosh. - I didn't know where the teachers were.
That was the last day I went to school.
(She couldn't go to school anymore.)
I didn't know how to read and write.
You didn't get to learn.
No. I didn't get to learn.
I thought if I study hard now,
I wouldn't get lost in the bus at least.
You're right.
You have told us many interesting stories.
Is there anything you want to write about?
I'm thinking about...
how I didn't know how to read and write,
and how I started to learn at this age.
If I could,
I would learn as much as I can.
Why don't I write a poem...
about that?
(She wants to write about the pleasure of learning.)
- Gosh. - We're half done already.
When did you get married? How old were you?
- I moved here when I was 20. - 20?
- You were 20. - Yes. That's when I moved here.
We were poor back then,
so I had to work to make a living.
I had no time to learn how to read and write.
I see. Did you have to work all the time?
- Yes. All I did was work. - What kind of work?
- It's farm work. We grew bracken. - Farm work.
You missed the chance to learn.
Yes, I did. I couldn't learn even when I was 20.
Now you know how to read and write.
Don't you have things you want to do now?
It didn't matter how capable I was.
I wanted to learn how to drive,
but I couldn't take the written test.
- That's true. - I couldn't get the license.
I wanted to get a driver's license.
- I understand. - That's what I wanted to do.
After watching taxi drivers drive, I realized that...
(When she sees taxi drivers...)
- it's not hard to learn to drive. - Right.
I can't because I'm not literate.
It can be something about cars.
Which type of car would you like?
There's a small Jeep.
You know what a Jeep is.
- There's a small one. - Yes.
- It's a small one. - It's small indeed.
It's very small.
It's that color.
Do you mean this red?
You also decided on the color.
I don't know if it's called a Jeep.
- Do you mean a vehicle that you can load? - A Jeep?
There is no trunk.
It looks short.
Right, there's a small one.
- A red Jeep. - Whom will you ride it with?
I'll commute to the farm with it.
You'll park the red Jeep by the farm.
- You'll drive home after work. - Right.
- Is it for work? - Yes.
Okay.
I can see you riding a small, red Jeep.
- I'm not sure. - Is it this car?
I bet you'll ride it.
Yes, it's the small one.
Right.
It's a car with four doors.
(You're smart.)
It's this car.
Will I get to drive a car someday?
Yes, you will.
Today's title is called "My Story".
When did you separate with your husband?
It's been 10 years.
- 10 years? - Yes.
Do you still miss him a lot?
I don't miss him too much.
I'm close to being 80.
(She endures another day without him.)
I have an idea.
What if I write a letter to my husband?
(A letter to her husband?)
(That sounds good.)
It's a good idea.
It's an excellent idea.
Isn't it?
- It's excellent. - I don't have much to say,
but I'll tell him that I'm well.
What? Goodness.
(She's a real poet.)
- What kind of... - It's the best.
reaction is that?
Correct me if I'm wrong.
Sure.
Will you write what you can?
Write what you think of, and we'll add on.
Gosh, my head itches.
(She's nervous.)
- I don't know how to write. - She's cute.
That's why I have a headache.
(While Kim Gil Ja writes her poem,)
(Pooping and Blank Page make her a stamp.)
Please make it for her.
(The summer night deepens.)
Which pen name will you choose?
She's busy.
Let's give her a pen name.
How about Adele?
- Adele? - What?
- Kim Gil Ja. - Adele?
Isn't it good?
- It's okay. - Her pen name is Adele.
Pick one that's easy to carve.
Choose a simple one.
(You carve while I write a poem.)
Adele sounds good.
(Poet Adele gets in the mood and writes a poem.)
(She pours her heart into it.)
(Each word comes from her longing.)
(She writes with sincerity.)
(Her poem is one of a kind.)
(Her love poem fills a page.)
This is all I can write.
- Pardon me? - Take a look.
Correct things that are wrong.
"It's been 10 years since I moved to Hadong."
"I love meat so much."
(It's an error.)
I meant to write "air".
(She corrects herself.)
Is meat good?
I meant to say "air".
It's "air".
Is there good meat in Hadong?
(What's Hadong meat?)
Do you like beef?
(Hadong has good meat.)
I had to write so quickly.
- I need more time to think. - That's true.
Take your time.
Do you also like meat?
Yes, I do.
Everyone likes meat.
(She makes a confession.)
(This is Lee Soon Ja's study.)
(She writes about joy in learning.)
Is this your schedule?
Is it your schedule?
Yes.
Do you like to exercise and take photos?
(She has a busy schedule.)
You study until 10pm.
You haven't written your schedule in April.
No.
(She writes it on the first day.)
(He marks something.)
It's at 6:25pm.
It's on KBS2.
- Is it channel seven? - Right.
I see.
(She promises to watch the show.)
(She gets back to her writing.)
(Meanwhile, Jong Min and Dong Gu...)
Look at those.
- May we take a look? - Let's see.
Let's see them.
She studies a lot.
Wait, these are her diaries.
There are diaries and dictation notes.
May we take a look at them?
It's embarrassing, but go ahead.
(She's embarrassed.)
Thank you.
(They take a sneak peek.)
(After learning how to write,)
(she writes in her diary every day.)
"I put out the peppers to dry on the rooftop."
"After lunch,"
"I played cards under the tree."
Do you play cards?
(She gets caught.)
"We had corn and soda,"
"which the neighbor brought. They were delicious."
(She put a lot of effort.)
You'd be a great student.
That's why she regrets not being able to study.
I can understand.
(She finishes writing.)
When you feel amazing,
you can do this.
Do this.
Try this, ma'am.
Try it. It's what many young people do.
That's right.
When you meet your neighbors...
and they say, "I saw you on TV."
(Respond with this gesture.)
Did you see me?
If they say, "I saw you on TV"...
Is it funny?
This is the sign for our team.
Okay.
Do you remember your mom?
Of course I remember my parents.
- Is that so? - Also,
- I remember my brother. - Your brother?
Whom would I call my brother when he's not here?
I can't call him.
Let's say you buy a car after getting your license.
I know your mother isn't alive anymore.
Your brother isn't alive, is he?
Where would you like to go with...
your mother and brother?
I'd like to go after I learn.
Where would you like to go?
I'd take them to sightseeing...
in the world.
In the world?
The world is nice.
Is there anything they haven't seen,
- Right. but you've seen it?
Is there anything you want to show them?
The world got better.
These days,
people take a trip with their parents on the weekend.
They go to Ssanggyesa or to eat.
My generation couldn't do that for our parents.
I regret it.
Would you like to go anywhere?
I couldn't buy them anything.
I couldn't give them an allowance.
I regret not being able to do that.
Have you seen cherry blossoms...
with your parents...
when you were a child?
No, I haven't.
That's why I regret it.
These days,
people take their parents to somewhere nice.
At that time, we couldn't go.
We couldn't because we were poor.
How about writing something based on imagination?
How about you write a letter to your mother?
Write a poem for your mother.
A poem?
You haven't written anything to your mother.
Now that you learned how to write,
you can write something to her.
Now that I learned how to write,
I can write...
a letter to my mother.
Then...
I lived this long.
I finally write to my mother.
I lived a good life.
I'd give you money,
buy you delicious food,
and nice clothes.
I couldn't do them before,
but finally I can.
Shall I write that?
It's my dream. I'll write about my dream.
That sounds good.
How do I write "red"?
- Red. - Red.
- Red? - Yes.
(She writes carefully.)
That's correct.
- Is this correct? - Yes.
What's the next character?
- Red? - Right.
- D. - D.
- Is it D? - Yes.
- It's D. - Is this right?
- Is this right? - D.
- Did you say D? - Yes.
Is this correct?
Red.
- That looks interesting. - Red Jeep.
Jeep?
- J. - It's J.
- It's Jeep. - Right.
(Her heart flutters.)
- Is this right? - Yes.
That's correct.
- It's P. - P.
- P. - That's right.
It's P.
It's "Red Jeep".
(They write each letter with sincerity.)
(What kind of poems did they write?)
Have a seat here.
Please sit here.
(They lead them to comfortable seats.)
- Here's a blanket. - I don't need it.
Please take it.
I'm dressed warmly, so I don't need a blanket.
It's cold. Let's get under it together.
- We're good ma'am. - Here.
- Joon Ho's not cold. - Don't be ridiculous.
We'll cover ourselves together.
(They get under the blanket together.)
This is how close we've gotten.
- It's cold. - This isn't necessary.
- Here. - Thank you so much.
(Thank you.)
(Poem under the Moonlight)
Welcome to the first...
One Night Two Days Poem under the Moonlight.
(They'll recite their poems under the moonlight.)
This is nice.
Am I supposed to read mine in front of everyone?
First up is Kim Gil Ja.
Please call her Poet Adele.
(Poet Adele)
Is she the Adele of Hadong?
(Adele's my name.)
I'd like to write a letter to my late husband.
(A letter to her late husband)
That's a great idea.
(The words she wasn't able to say to him)
(She wrote one word after the next.)
(A poem for her husband)
You can start by saying the title.
(Joon Young helps her relax.)
This is "Confession".
"Dear my husband."
"It's been 10 years since..."
"you left me."
"It's been 10 years since I moved to Hadong."
"Thanks to the fresh air here,"
"I've been able to stay away from hospitals."
"Life hasn't been bad I guess."
(Life hasn't been bad I guess.)
"Jeong Yeon, how are you doing over there?"
"I'm curious..."
"if you're in good health."
(How are you doing?)
(Today, I finally get to tell you how much I miss you.)
"I'm curious."
"Mi Jung, Hyang Sook,"
"Jin Seok, Bong Seok,"
"and Jeong Yeon are all doing great."
"Byung Min and Da Min too,"
"so don't worry about them."
"I hope you'll hang in there until I join you someday."
"What I wasn't able to tell you in person,"
"I finally get to tell you..."
"today."
(The words she wasn't able to say to him.)
"I love you."
(She delivered the heartfelt letter very calmly.)
- That was amazing. - It really was.
What an amazing poem.
You wrote a letter.
- It's for my late husband. - Your late husband.
(When you profess your love)
(And hug the one you love)
She said it calmly, but it came from the heart.
- It was sweet. - It was a love poem.
I loved it.
She bravely read it although she was first.
- I agree. - It's not something that's easy to do.
- These represent her and her husband. - The flowers.
She draw roses.
Anyway, you just heard from Poet Adele.
Thank you.
She has a pen name too.
It's Velvet.
(Poet Velvet)
- She's Velvet. - Velvet.
- Velvet? - Like Red Velvet?
She should have one too. How about Blackpink?
- She loves pink. - Blackpink it is then.
Blackpink?
- Next up is... - Blackpink.
(Next up is Lee Soon Ja.)
Poet Blackpink.
Soon Ja has wrote many poems so far.
She writes one every day.
(Her fully packed schedule)
(After she learned how to read and write,)
(she spent every day enjoying the education.)
(A passionate student and poet full of joy)
(She'll write a poem about the happiness of learning.)
(A heartfelt poem)
(What did she come up with?)
- Should I start? - Sure.
"A Day as Happy as Today".
"As a girl, I didn't receive education."
"I had no friends."
"I was very lonely."
"My parents believe that women shouldn't..."
"leave the house at night."
"So every night after dinner,"
"my father would stand guard outside..."
"our front gate."
"Out of loneliness, I cried many nights."
"Then finally I was offered an opportunity..."
"to learn how to read and write."
"Studying at Jeongdong School..."
"brings me such happiness."
"A day like today."
"I wish many future days are just as happy as well."
"Being so happy, I can't help but laugh."
- My goodness. - It sounded like a confession.
Her days of crying is over.
Her crying is now in the past.
I was able to feel just how happy studying makes her.
(A warm poem that conveys her happiness)
- Thank you so much. - Thank you.
- I knew it'd be good. - Dong Gu.
- I loved the title too. - She delivered.
- It was amazing. - I loved how...
she was able to make it rhyme.
This looks like a sign of a seolleongtang restaurant.
(A seolleongtang restaurant)
Don't you agree?
I know. It could be on the menu of one.
Last but not least, Kang Jeom Soon is up.
Velvet, it's time to read your poem.
- Here. - Let's go.
- What could you write about? - My mother.
I'd like to write a letter...
to my mother.
That...
- It's red. - Right.
(Thanks to Tae Hyun and Defconn...)
- Red. - Like this?
(She writes from the heart.)
It's a red car.
Yes, a red one.
(She's always wanted to drive a red car.)
- Does this look like a person? - It does.
(She draws a younger self of hers.)
- In the past? - That's right.
(A poem that's more like a dream)
Kang Jeom Soon.
(It's now time to listen to her dream.)
"The Red Jeep".
- Jeep. - "The Red Jeep".
- "My dream..." - It's how old people say it.
"My dream is to buy a car."
"I don't know Hangul very well yet..."
"which is why I can't dream of getting..."
"a driver's license."
"I want to buy a small car though."
(She wants to but a small car.)
"Mother..."
(Mother)
"I want to drive..."
"my mother to places."
"I want to..."
"I want to go see the cherry blossoms bloom..."
"in Hwagae."
"I want to drive..."
"my mother to places."
"I want to go see the cherry blossoms bloom..."
"in Hwagae."
("The Red Jeep" by Kang Jeom Soon)
(She was never able to take her mother to see flowers.)
(She'd love nothing more than to...)
(accompany her mother there at least in her dreams.)
She meant to write "seeing flowers" here.
What an amazing poem.
- You did great. - Is it a poem?
In her dream, she wants...
to buy a car and take off.
- That's why she drew this. - You did great.
So it's a dream of hers.
Yes. If you look closely,
you'll see her brother and mother.
Is she behind the wheel?
That's right.
(She is driving herself.)
I love all their drawings too.
Please give it up for Kang Jeom Soon.
- Thank you, ma'am. - It was bad.
No, you did great.
Here in Jeongdong Village,
our ears were blessed by masterpieces.
Tae Hyun, isn't it a wonderful night?
Now...
Here...
Here we have three awards.
The first award category is...
the Best Emotion Award.
I love how that sounds.
The Best Emotion Award.
Poem under the Moonlight.
The Best Emotion Award goes to...
Kang Jeom Soon. Congratulations!
(Best Emotion Award, Kang Jeom Soon)
- The winning poem is "The Red Jeep". - Go on.
- "The Red Jeep". - Nice.
We're sorry it's not actually a red Jeep.
- Here's your trophy. - Congratulations.
(Her small but sweet dream)
Can you give an acceptance speech?
- Here. - I'm so happy right now.
- She's happy. - I can't tell you just how much.
- Thank you. - Congratulations.
Ma'am, let's take a photo together.
Ma'am, do you remember what I showed you?
In 1, 2, 3.
(She celebrates with a hip-hop hand gesture.)
- Nice. - Thank you.
- I taught her that. - Yes, he did.
- That's what I taught her. - Congratulations.
- Jeom Soon, congratulations. - Thank you.
- Ma'am. - Like this.
(Congratulations)
Defconn taught me this.
- This? - Awesome.
- Again, congratulations. - Best Emotion Award.
Next up is Best Expression Award.
(Best Expression Award)
The award goes to Lee Soon Ja!
- Soon Ja! - Congratulations!
- My goodness. - Congratulations.
Congratulations, ma'am.
I'm so embarrassed.
My goodness.
- Congratulations. - Congratulations.
Thank you.
Thank you so much for the award.
This really makes my day.
I'll remember this...
for the rest of my life and live happily.
- Congratulations. - That was very poetic.
She's very expressive.
The next is Best Impression Award.
This award goes to the team...
that touched everyone's heart with the sincere story.
It's possible that one receives more than one award.
It's possible Gil Ja doesn't receive any award.
- Please don't be disappointed. - I'm fine.
- I'm fine. - One can receive more than one award?
Yes. Soon Ja or...
- Jeom Soon can receive another one. - I see.
Best Impression Award.
I wonder who receives it.
(Best Impression Award)
- Give it to Gil Ja. - What?
- Poet Adele. - Poet Adele.
Best Impression Award goes to...
Poet Adele.
(Kim Gil Ja receives the award.)
(The poem for her husband touched everyone's heart.)
I said I don't need to receive one.
Thank you. Thank you.
Well...
I'm happy to receive it, although I'm fine without it.
I'll keep it forever.
I think we were helping them by...
not doing anything.
That's right.
She introduced us...
the air and meat of Hadong.
- Why are you hitting me? - Stop saying that.
- I'm sorry. - You keep saying that today.
What a beautiful night, ma'am.
- Thank you. - Congratulations.
Her poem was touching.
Thank you for your hard work. Thank you.
Thank you.
- Ma'am. - It was moving.
Let's go home.
(The heartwarming trip is over.)
("Fall in Love" by Hong Dae Kwang)