A camera I picked up by chance
one day changed my life.
Resignation letter
Name: Kim Jiwan
It's not too late. You should
give it another thought.
RAINBOW
I thought I could start making films
right after I had resigned.
A wishful thinking.
Green light is on.
Now you can cross.
Crossing is dangerous.
Please wait for the next light.
It's been 5 years I've been
taking up any jobs in this field.
At last I have my own business card.
I've talked to the investors.
Either action or comedy.
The genre needs to be clear.
Anyway black comedy won't work.
This part of your script is weak.
It's relevant to the conflict.
So we need to redo the plot.
Otherwise financing will be difficult.
What do you think, Director Kim?
- Mom.
- What's up?
We've got lots of ants at home.
- Ask dad to catch them.
- He's asleep.
Use the tape and crush them with it.
Yeah.
- Where are you?
- In the office.
- Still working?
- Yup.
Si young said to buy
some tape on your way.
Ok.
Hi, mom.
- Where's dad?
- In the bedroom.
How's your work?
Not bad.
You've been saying
that for five years.
Nothing's been done
since you quit your job.
How much longer
will your script take?
Until it's done.
My mom's an idiot
- 20 million won!
- 10 million won!
This is a story about a woman,
who had once hit rock bottom.
300,000 won!
- 250,000 won!
- 150,000 won!
Zero!
Turn the damn light off.
Director Kim, how about
one more revision?
Sorry. I can't do it anymore.
I've been working on
this script for three years.
That's 15 drafts till now! Fifteen!
You promised me you'd start casting.
Please start casting.
Well, it's not my decision to make.
If we work hard... Like a beaver,
we will make it someday.
- So...
- I don't want to live like a beaver.
Then let's put it on hold.
- What do you mean "on hold?"
- We should store the script away.
You think it is some wine?
- Hi, Hojun.
- Oh, Jiwan.
- Director.
- Yes.
So, what I meant was that
my script is commercial, okay?
Yes. Please get in!
Hey, Hojun.
Jiwan, I'm so sorry about earlier.
It's an important meeting.
- That's alright.
- How's your movie going?
- Pretty good. We'll start shooting soon.
- That's great.
I feel terrible if my film
went ahead of you.
Sorry, I have to go!
So, did you quit your job?
Forget it. Gifts? Passion?
It's all nothing without luck.
You focus too much on only one thing.
Try a new approach!
But there was a story
I wanted to talk about.
What was it?
Ants. A story about ants.
I'm scared of them.
Trying to burn down
the whole house?
Look at this!
All this, for a damn movie!
Go to the theater instead!
Hurt? It'd be so cool if the bruise
looks just like a baseball.
- Hey!
- I've thrown some curve balls.
Ah, welcome to Otaku's room
My mom's belly is
the size of Mt. Bukhan
Ah, we are one weird family
Mom doesn't have a movie to shoot,
but she calls herself a 'director'
And because of her, dad
doesn't go to the theater
Mom won't even take a shower now
Oh, she's... Walking on two
feet An Australopithecus
Mom, you're being a real bum lately.
I'm waiting for your movie,
but all you do is sleeping.
Cast me when you start shooting.
- I want to be Passerby No. 3.
- Why Passerby #3?
I just like the number three.
But you must pay me.
Cabbages. Banana for sale!
I used to interview bands
to make a film about them.
And I realized that their struggle
was the same as mine.
A band plays on stage.
Scene 40. At a concert hall.
Eunju is looking at singer on stage.
Her body is like a sound booster.
- It's boring. Really sucks.
- Hey!
Buy me an electric guitar
if you seal the contract.
What about moving
to a bigger house?
I gave up on that.
Buy me one, okay?
Alright.
- What are you doing?
- Working.
On what, this time?
You're not going to the office lately.
Did you get fired?
You dunno nothin' You dunno nothin'
Nothin' damn it...
You have to work tomorrow.
How could you drink so much?
Work?
You can go instead of me.
Ha, I want to quit, too.
It's me.
- Did you read it?
- Yup.
How was it?
Not bad. I see you've
been working hard.
You can tell? I saw a pig in my dream.
Exactly, it was pig's feet.
It's a lucky dream.
Wake up, dummy!
You want some pork hock?
So hot.
Last year was worst.
So, what did you write at
the previous company?
I arranged a nice room
especially for you.
It's really big!
Is this really all to myself?
You deserve it.
Here, this is the schedule.
From July to December, script revisions.
Casting by next February.
Pre-production begins in March,
and the shoot starts in May.
Look over it and give
me your opinion.
- Ok.
- Oh and...
Your business card.
- Everything's so fast here.
- Fast is good. Time is money.
- Let's make this happen, OK?
- Yes.
I see you have an eye for guitars.
I'll get you this when my
movie hits the jackpot!
Getting a job and buying
it myself will be faster.
Turn it down!
Schedule
Come in.
- How do you do?
- Yes?
I'm a director, Ahn Changnam.
I use the room next door.
You directed the film,
Myung-ja's Friday, right?
Ya, that's me.
Please have a seat.
Use this up quick,
before the movie's dropped.
- Excuse me?
- What the hell am I saying...
I heard your script is good.
Show it to me.
Sure.
- Coffee?
- No, thanks.
- He must be your son.
- That's right.
I'm expecting a baby in three months.
Saw the ultrasounds.
- Congratulations!
- Thank you.
- See you again.
- Okay, bye.
Feel free to stop by
my office anytime!
Okay!
One. Two. Three. Four. Five.
1st draft
2nd draft
3rd draft
4th draft
5th draft
Just 5th drafts, and shooting!
The hero spent his youth
in a detention center.
He served time for
murdering his own father.
With this secret behind,
he works as a deliver boy.
One day, he finds a guitar.
And he becomes
a successful musician?
- You get the picture!
- Not bad.
No, not a detention center.
It's too depressing.
Hero has got to be from the middle class.
Audience wants something more positive.
Then, his mother is a doctor.
Father is a guitarist killed himself.
Oh, nice! And he has gift
for memorizing music.
- Sense of perfect pitch?
- Bingo!
Way to go.
- How about age?
- Fifteen.
- Not good.
- Then, eighteen.
The movie has to draw 2 million tickets.
So make him in twenties.
Yes?
- Hello.
- Hi, Director Ahn.
Please have a seat.
Just a few more left.
This room is so empty.
This is the third company I've joined.
I didn't bring my stuff.
I never know when I'll be fired.
But you've already
made your debut.
Yes, but making the second
one isn't so easy.
- I never really see you working.
- I never revise my scripts.
Why not?
People say I shouldn't
'cos it'll make it worse.
I've edited it only once in a year.
It's better to build up
strength during that time.
You need to have good stamina
after the shoot begins.
- Here.
- Ok, thanks.
So, how's your script coming along?
- Oh, I have to make it more commercial.
- Commercial?
For new director, the most crucial thing is...
bringing out your own color.
Genuine color.
What are you doing?
I was sketching the opening scene.
Alright, Director.
Let's go watch the show.
People jumping around.
People sitting still.
People walking around.
Everywhere was the stage.
Hi, honey.
- What is this?
- Musical score.
- This is a score?
- Yeah, I found it.
My goodness...
I want to give it a try.
A story about a rainbow.
Title: Rainbow
- Sure?
- Yes, I am.
One is lonely.
- Good morning!
- Good morning, Ms. Choi.
So, how's my script?
It was quite interesting!
Combining drama with fantasy
was unique. Nice job.
Hello.
- Hello.
The two are trying.
I'm not really sure.
It's been two months already.
Sir... Mrs. Kim hasn't
grasped the concept yet.
Director's intention seems...
- Sir, the tone of the movie...
- What was the tone you...
- Well, that's not my decision to make.
- Of course not, sir.
And yet, the plot's conflict
needs to be clear.
- Oh, the conflict is...
- Yes, it's unclear.
Also, in terms of marketing,
this movie is tough.
When there are three people...
Thought about how the audience
will see this movie?
It always becomes political with three people.
Sir, Mrs. Kim still lacks commerciality.
So I'll do my best...
Are you insisting that we proceed?
Shall we try a different approach?
Well... I think this project
needs a basic makeover.
Do you mean...
What are you doing?
Can you make a genre movie?
- Genre? The genre is fantasy.
- Which does not work in Korea!
- But I can do whatever...
- Stop it!
You're overestimating the investors.
They make decisions based on statistics.
Think they'll understand your script?
Belief is more important than numbers.
Look Director Kim. Think straight.
Nobody understands
this psychotic fantasy!
Will you making this film alone?
Forget this whole hallucination.
Hallucination? I really saw it.
Stop pushing me with
your shitty imagination!
Shitty imagination?
Sorry about that.
Want to know what the reality is?
Go on with "Rainbow",
and you'll be gone forever.
If you want a touch of
"reality," go ahead.
Director Kim.
Do you want to hit
rock bottom again?
Are you so great?
You haven't even
made your debut yet.
Got any idea what's going on lately?
We are talking about 'survival.'
It's a war out there.
And that time table is
the life span I spared you!
It's all up to you.
From today, forget about "Rainbow".
How to Write a Script
"There has to be an event
within ten minutes."
"And the characters
have to transform."
"Heroes must have a definite goal."
"But does everyone live with
a clear goal and motive?"
"A scriptwriter's promise
to the audience is weak."
Oh, trust me!
Once you pass this boring part,
I will give you thrills!
"Every action must have
an explicit reason."
Damn it! There 'ARE'
actions with no reason.
Mom, I joined the band at school.
You did?
My seniors are nice guys,
they don't smoke.
Good for you.
We'll throw a concert.
But I won't be a part of it.
- Why not?
- I have stage phobia.
You need to overcome that.
Shall I go see you practice?
Mom, don't even think it.
- Why?
- You embarrass me.
Hey!
Shit...
I've never seen anything
like this before.
Me either. I just liked
the first few cords.
No lyrics.
I'll come up with one.
These cords are way over your head.
Can you play this, huh?
Just stick to your practice,
you little twirp!
Look at this. Must be new brand.
How much was this shit?
- Hey, I'll keep this one!
- Give it back!
Hey! How dare you look
straight back at me!
When you're talking to me?
It's the forth button.
Don't you fuckin' hear me?
Have you gone deaf?
Bloody hell! You're just
a backup! Go practice!
You can't even sing,
you useless piece of shit!
I heard the film industry is bad these days.
Is your company ok?
The company's holding up fine.
That's good to hear.
But are you okay, too?
Hey, you're home.
Have you picked the song yet?
- Where's your guitar?
- I lent it to someone.
And not taken away from you?
Piss off!
Si young, why are you
talking to me like that?
What's wrong? I'm in my teens.
Adolescence comes with a hostile,
rebellious attitude!
How could you say
that to your mom?
Yes! Rebelling is a privilege
for distressed teenagers!
You... You... Forget that
I changed your diapers?
How can you do this!
What's going on?
Nothing.
Would you look up my script?
That's fine.
- How's it going?
- I'm printing out new script.
You are always working so fast.
It was your request.
You know what?
Well... Let's give up on this.
Pardon?
Do you know 'Cultwo Pictures'?
They've already launched
a project with the same theme.
They've even finished casting.
All top stars.
Nothing's working out for me lately.
But still, there must be
something different.
The story's much the same.
So I gave another thought to
that "Rainbow" script of yours.
And it might actually work.
You said it won't work
with the investors.
Well, I can tell you
from my experience.
Nothing goes as expected.
Who knows? It might
all come out differently.
We have to be the first one.
Before someone else does it.
I heard of this band, 'Rainbow'.
Let's find them.
Big Star is born.
My mom's an idiot
Rainbow
I'm the guitarist, Park Jiwon.
Song Namhyeon, on base.
Noh Yunan, on the drum.
My name is Kim Jiwan.
Nice to meet you.
I saw your show on the Internet.
I hope you're not offended by this...
Isn't it a show rather than music?
You must've watched some old stuff.
I used to smash up and reassemble
guitars over and over again.
But now I can't anymore.
This crazy bastard
became a grown-up.
Where do you practice?
We used to practice
on the street mostly.
Sometimes we'd sneak
into the lecture hall.
We used to argue
with the guard for that.
But it wasn't all that bad.
Yeah, it was alright.
When we first came to Seoul,
we performed here.
We used to get paid 1,000 won by each person.
And there were times we had no one.
But we took it as a chance to practice.
Put this in your bag.
Creativity Booster
Being a film producer sucks, too.
It does. Not so different
from the service jobs.
And yet, what job isn't
tough in this world?
We can do this.
I believe in you.
Just write whatever you want.
Your true color is most important, okay?
Oh, gray hair!
Have I got any?
We're turning forty next year.
It's been over three years
since my first film.
Have you got any idea what
being a film producer is like?
I have to worry about the director.
And listen to the boss.
Get bashed by investors.
I'm not even
getting paid on time.
I'm not a boss. Just a soldier.
Cheer up, soldier.
Hey! If I wanted to,
I could have just fired you!
But I believe in you.
You are a good person.
And you're a genius.
You'll make this happen.
- Genius?
- Yeah, genius!
All directors are a genius.
Well, I'm flattered.
What are you doing, mom?
Ah, nothing.
Let me hear you play again.
I'm not good yet.
Cords are complicated.
Come on, one more time.
Buy me an effector. Then I'll play.
I'll think about it.
Gone to Chicago Film Festival.
"Creativity Booster, how to summon
the God of Creativity."
"Stick a spoon on your forehead
and smother a plate."
God comes to me.
What are you doing?
Our hero needs more tragedy.
In terms of making profit,
there needs to be a big
scene within 20 minutes.
Shall we make someone die?
It's too unrealistic.
Who do you have in
mind for the actor?
He's not going to attract any money.
Something ordinary? I want something
extraordinary. That's why I chose you.
I have to think about the result.
You asked, what is a movie?
Why do you ask me such a thing?
Come on, eat.
Just write whatever you want.
How's it coming along?
So-so.
How many scenes are done?
Nobody understands
this psychotic fantasy!
I'm still working on the first scene.
Alright. Take your time.
- Are you sure?
- Yup.
You need energy to write.
Eat plenty.
- Have any other ideas for a movie?
- Pardon?
I don't see any music film
making a hit lately.
And why are there so many of them now?
But if you consider it
as a whole genre...
The '200 Pounds Beauty.'
That was a nice movie.
Can you make it like that?
Not many days left till December.
A promise is a promise. Schedule...
I'm not a machine! I need time!
- Are you angry at me?
- Yes, I am.
That's okay. It can happen.
Come on.
So you've got some temper too.
That's cute.
Directors are so selfish. They only
care about their own steak.
Just kidding. Don't take it so seriously.
You see. I'm not selfish.
Just a meat lover.
Directors have to move swiftly.
But you seem to have trouble.
- Pardon?
- Young directors catch on to things fast.
Who looks after your son
when you're out like this?
Don't you find film-making to be tough?
Soon, you might be in a tight spot.
Then I'm forced to choose
either the right or easy way.
Excuse me?
Nothing. Forget it.
Everyone fears a loss.
But the anxiety,
doubts and distrust that grows feeding
on this fear are viruses.
Be careful. Not to be infected.
Congratulations on receiving
the Best Director Award.
Thank you. I still have
a long way to go.
By the way, I recently
wrote a new script.
- Oh, you wrote it yourself?
- Yes, and I was thinking...
- Hi, Producer Choi, it's been a while.
- How are things going?
Not bad. I haven't seen
you around these days.
Oh, I've been quite busy.
Hold on. I'll call you again.
Yes.
Hello.
We wrote new song. Would you
like to come hear our new song?
Behind this wall of hazy glass
I can't see any more.
What it is that I'm doing
All these confusing thought
And mindless mind
All these things that surround me
Can't believe myself
No one believes me
No one believes what I say
All these confusing thoughts
And mindless mind
All these things surrounding me
Please help my script get
approved for production.
If it doesn't like the last time...
If it doesn't...
I shall not forgive you!
Let's make it brief
and straight forward.
Opinions, please.
I don't know what this
is trying to say.
It's not bad, but it's not
commercial enough.
I feel that it needs more focus.
For a film about music,
it's lacking a love line.
It'll be hard to cast actors.
People won't watch this.
There are better movies.
I feel that we shouldn't
proceed with this.
You've been working hard.
But if you really want
realism in your movie,
you should make documentaries.
Films about music
aren't easy to make.
So you've made an easy choice.
Jiwan... Is this because
I'm a meat lover?
Jiwan, it's been a pleasure
to work with you.
- You know what I'm saying, right?
- No, I don't.
If you were in my shoes,
you would've done the same.
You know what?
There was something
I wanted to talk about.
People.
Story about people.
Sorry.
I got the bill.
It should be entertaining. That's all it takes.
But is your script entertaining?
You should've made your debut.
When Korean films were thriving.
It now takes more than just
a script for new directors.
These days, thrillers are in.
You should try that.
Sorry. We're really
tight on our budget.
You never look back.
That's the problem.
Drink this.
Don't just sit around. My friend needs
someone to shoot her wedding video.
Stop wasting your energy!
Make money!
I heard what happened.
Yeah, not so lucky.
- How's your work coming along?
- Oh, I start shooting soon.
The casting was done so quickly.
That's really good.
Yeah... My daughter must
be my lucky charm.
Like me, you should wait for your chance.
And not revise your script all the time.
I mean, you work too hard.
But it's about "doing it right."
Rainbow. Nice title.
This is like your baby.
How can you just throw this out?
How did this happen?
We have a gangster
in our house now.
- He beat the hell out of his senior!
- What?
That bastard took my guitar.
Shame on you! Are you
going to school to fight?
All this music nonsense.
You are quitting that band!
- No!
- How dare you?
No! I'm not quitting!
Why are you doing that?
He loves that band.
You can't tell him to quit.
Band?
I won't let him be like you.
- What?
- You want him to become like you?
When are you going to stop it?
This is all because of you, mom!
You... Is this so damn
important to you?
You think you can be a director?
You're just a loser.
Feels nice to walk with a camera
after so long, huh?
Oh, I think they're shooting a movie.
Let's check it out. Hurry!
Jiwan!
Hey, keep those people off the set!
Oh, it's you!
- You know him?
- Yes...
It's you, Jiwan, right?
It is you! What are you doing here?
Are you shooting somewhere near here?
- Oh, I'm scouting for locations.
- I see.
Hey, meet my assistant director.
Nice to meet you.
So now you're finally making
your debut. Congratulations.
Oh, could you do me a favor?
We need an extra.
This person didn't show up.
I know you can act.
- Okay?
- I'm not sure...
Could you give her the script?
Thank you, Jiwan!
Here is the script.
So, this man tries to start a fight
with you, another passerby.
That guy is your counterpart.
You just need to walk.
Scene 72. Cut 13. Take 1.
Ready! Action!
Hey you.
Come here.
Lady, where are you going?
Ma'am, I said, where are you going?
I don't know.
Cut! NG!
That must've hurt a lot.
Are you ok?
Where are you going, ma'am?
I said, where are you going?
I don't know.
Cut! NG!
Where are you going?
I said, where are you going?
I don't know.
Cut! NG!
The tide is coming in. Hurry up!
I said, where are you going?
I don't know.
Cut! NG!
I said, where are you going?
I don't know.
Cut! NG!
Where are you going?
I don't know.
Cut! NG!
Ma'am I said... where are you going?
I don't know...
Cut! NG!
Jiwan, who would react like that?
Is a movie some joke?
One more time.
- We are giving it another go.
- Hurry it up!
Take fifteen.
Ready! Action!
Where are you going?
I said, where are you going?
I don't know!
It hurts! Why'd you hit me!
You told me to "just walk."
"Where am I going?"
Don't know, don't know, Don't know!
I said I don't know! I don't know!
You think I'm a joke?
You think I'm an idiot
because I'm always smiling?
You think I'm a joke?
I feel the pain, too!
It hurts! Hurts! Hurt! Hurt!
Cut! Ok! Wow! Great improvisation!
- This one's good!
- Yes.
- Jiwan!
So you liked getting slapped?
It's embarrassing.
You are now a masochistic idiot.
Yeah, I am an idiot.
Ms. Passerby!
Where did you want to go?
You don't know?
You got your guitar back?
That asshole transferred
to another school.
Why?
Because he's embarrassed.
Rumors are spreading that
a junior beat him up.
I'll play the guitar for the concert.
My song has been approved.
- What song?
- I'm not telling you.
Are you also singing?
You bet.
- The girl got angry and she's out now.
- Why?
She won't sing my music
because it's shitty.
But you have stage phobia.
Won't that be a problem?
- You got smacked by someone?
- Oh, no.
Are you gonna keep standing there?
You're interrupting my practice. Get out!
Where are you?
You said you were coming.
Skip your class!
Forget it!
No one's here.
It's the rain.
No, it's because we
have no girl in the band.
That's a good thing.
Gundam Man and the Idols
Thank you for coming to our concert.
Now for the best band at Songmyeong
Middle School, Gundam Man and the Idols.
On guitar, Park Jaehee!
On the drums, Im Chanseok!
On guitar, Baek Siyoung!
And I'm the bassist,
Park Joohyeong.
The first song is called 'Passerby #3'.
Hey!
Turn up the volume!
Can't hear a thing!
Walking aimlessly on the streets
So many tiring miles for my dream
Nobody knows who I am
I've always been around
I can go anywhere
Passerby #3 walks along the street
Nobody knows who he is
Nobody knows who I am
I've always been around
I can go anywhere
Forget that dream of yours
Just walk and go
Passerby #3
Nobody knows who I am
I've always been around
I can go anywhere
Nobody knows who I am
I've always been around
I can go anywhere
Mom, what's loser?
A person who has nothing to lose.
- How about winner?
- A person who has nothing to win.
Then which one are you?
- Just a passerby.
- What?
- A person walking by.
- That's whack.