1
00:00:23,796 --> 00:00:26,348
The history of man is defined by war.

2
00:00:27,758 --> 00:00:30,598
And war by the men who fight it.

3
00:00:31,740 --> 00:00:34,442
What if we could create a better man?

4
00:00:34,947 --> 00:00:36,420
Someone did.

5
00:00:37,262 --> 00:00:41,705
The Agent program was
initiated in August of 1967...

6
00:00:41,706 --> 00:00:44,394
by a man named Peter Aaron Litvenko.

7
00:00:45,297 --> 00:00:49,240
It's purpose was to create
the perfect killing machine.

8
00:00:49,242 --> 00:00:54,117
Human beings without emotion,
or fear, or remorse.

9
00:00:55,807 --> 00:00:58,594
The resulting subjects were called Agents.

10
00:01:00,493 --> 00:01:02,991
The Program was a success.

11
00:01:03,491 --> 00:01:08,334
But the price of creating men without
humanity, was Litvenko's conscience.

12
00:01:08,737 --> 00:01:12,445
Applying his brilliant mind
to his flight, he vanished.

13
00:01:12,848 --> 00:01:16,668
Fearing that it would be exposed,
the Govt shut down the Program.

14
00:01:16,870 --> 00:01:20,155
And surviving Agents drifted
into shadows.

15
00:01:20,957 --> 00:01:24,737
Realizing it's potential, many
tried to re-start the Program.

16
00:01:26,911 --> 00:01:28,311
All failed.

17
00:01:30,797 --> 00:01:34,593
So they focused their efforts
on finding the one man who could.

18
00:01:35,296 --> 00:01:38,553
The task fell to
Dr. Albert Delriego.

19
00:01:38,854 --> 00:01:41,458
A ruthless, and efficient man.

20
00:01:43,578 --> 00:01:47,834
Bu Litvenko had disappeared
and even he couldn't find him.

21
00:01:50,030 --> 00:01:53,059
Then, 6 years into his search...

22
00:01:53,061 --> 00:01:56,277
Delriego made an unexpected discovery.

23
00:01:58,079 --> 00:02:02,894
A single photograph, which would
become the key to finding Litvenko.

24
00:02:04,336 --> 00:02:07,013
No-one had ever imagined,
that in the end...

25
00:02:08,748 --> 00:02:12,386
it would come down
to one, little .. girl.

26
00:02:16,167 --> 00:02:17,876
SALZBURG - AUSTRIA

27
00:02:17,982 --> 00:02:20,396
SYNDICATE INTERNATIONAL
- RESEARCH FACILITY

28
00:02:28,520 --> 00:02:32,464
Sir, we have a match in Germany.
Verifying database.

29
00:02:47,003 --> 00:02:48,467
REMOTE ACCESS
- UPLOAD VIRUS

30
00:02:50,307 --> 00:02:53,396
ATTENTION, EVACUATE THE BUILDLING
- SECURITY ALERT

31
00:02:55,284 --> 00:02:56,501
Lock all files and evacuate.

32
00:02:57,387 --> 00:02:58,863
Sir, we have to leave now.

33
00:02:59,364 --> 00:03:02,056
- What the hell is going on?
- I don't know, sir.

34
00:03:03,484 --> 00:03:04,984
REMOTE TRACKING
- ACTIVATED

35
00:04:30,492 --> 00:04:32,865
I want to know who's doing this.
I need answers.

36
00:04:55,784 --> 00:04:57,222
Give me an update.

37
00:04:59,116 --> 00:05:00,591
I said give me an update!

38
00:05:03,631 --> 00:05:04,952
I said!

39
00:05:21,510 --> 00:05:25,731
I supposed I should be flattered.
I didn't think I merited a contract.

40
00:05:26,414 --> 00:05:27,615
You don't.

41
00:05:31,796 --> 00:05:34,760
You know? I hunted an Agent once.

42
00:05:35,783 --> 00:05:37,419
For four weeks.

43
00:05:39,720 --> 00:05:41,729
Most rewarding catch
of my career.

44
00:05:42,134 --> 00:05:45,834
Your employers are attempting
to re-start the Agent Program.

45
00:05:47,059 --> 00:05:48,820
And you're here to stop them?

46
00:05:49,937 --> 00:05:51,093
You're too late.

47
00:05:51,865 --> 00:05:54,344
We already have Litvenko.

48
00:05:55,747 --> 00:05:58,435
He's currently working
on next-generation units.

49
00:05:58,637 --> 00:06:01,628
He's not.
Because you haven't found him.

50
00:06:04,287 --> 00:06:06,847
Where is Katia van Dees?

51
00:06:09,638 --> 00:06:11,873
I have a chip implanted, here.

52
00:06:12,984 --> 00:06:16,920
If my heart stops beating, my security
detail will come through that door.

53
00:06:18,305 --> 00:06:19,839
You need me.

54
00:06:20,641 --> 00:06:24,297
No. I only need pieces of you.

55
00:06:24,500 --> 00:06:26,953
The information I require
is in two places.

56
00:06:27,355 --> 00:06:29,396
Your secure database...

57
00:06:29,398 --> 00:06:30,997
And inside your head.

58
00:06:32,687 --> 00:06:34,507
Berlín, they found her in Berlín.

59
00:06:36,257 --> 00:06:37,544
That's all I know.

60
00:06:41,333 --> 00:06:42,671
Okay, okay.

61
00:06:42,673 --> 00:06:44,786
File 5-1-7.

62
00:06:44,788 --> 00:06:48,689
Acess code:
G21-12-57.

63
00:06:50,221 --> 00:06:51,221
Thank you.

64
00:06:52,522 --> 00:06:54,944
But you won't find her.
She's a ghost.

65
00:06:54,945 --> 00:06:55,945
I will.

66
00:08:47,214 --> 00:08:52,807
HITMAN AGENT 47

67
00:08:54,742 --> 00:08:56,254
SINGAPORE

68
00:09:10,606 --> 00:09:12,284
Delriego is dead.

69
00:09:12,941 --> 00:09:14,139
What happened?

70
00:09:14,140 --> 00:09:15,966
We think it may have been an Agent.

71
00:09:17,568 --> 00:09:20,305
Delriego was close to
finding the girl.

72
00:09:20,907 --> 00:09:23,202
Get to her before he does.

73
00:09:24,898 --> 00:09:29,047
BERLIN - GERMANY

74
00:10:15,044 --> 00:10:19,049
He lived in Berlín between
1989 and 1990.

75
00:10:19,550 --> 00:10:23,425
There must be taxes paid,
rental records, or something.

76
00:10:23,516 --> 00:10:24,787
You know his name?

77
00:10:24,823 --> 00:10:26,184
I don't have a name.

78
00:10:28,223 --> 00:10:31,395
Look, he would've been 49, 50.

79
00:10:31,497 --> 00:10:35,436
Blonde hair, 1.74 metros,
75 kilogramos.

80
00:10:35,538 --> 00:10:36,838
Like this.

81
00:10:44,353 --> 00:10:45,474
Sorry.

82
00:10:46,758 --> 00:10:48,346
Without a name or an address...

83
00:10:52,259 --> 00:10:55,249
Nothing I can do for you.
If he is missing...

84
00:10:55,251 --> 00:10:57,505
May I suggest you try the police?

85
00:10:57,507 --> 00:10:59,949
The police won't help me.
Why do you think I'm here?

86
00:11:00,050 --> 00:11:02,687
And all you're doing is telling me
what you cannot do.

87
00:11:02,689 --> 00:11:05,853
You have to realize that millions
of people have lived in Berlín...

88
00:11:05,855 --> 00:11:07,809
over the past 25 years.

89
00:11:08,611 --> 00:11:13,071
I can't be expected to sort through everyone
of them for your mystery man, can I?

90
00:11:14,580 --> 00:11:17,447
It's 19,467,000 population

91
00:11:17,448 --> 00:11:21,504
That's 62.2% Slavik origin.
And 49.2% male.

92
00:11:21,507 --> 00:11:24,613
1.2% between the ages
of 49 to 50.

93
00:11:25,147 --> 00:11:29,593
That's 71,291.
That's something, isn't it?

94
00:11:32,420 --> 00:11:34,844
There's nothing I can do
to help you, Miss.

95
00:11:37,908 --> 00:11:38,945
Okay.

96
00:11:44,487 --> 00:11:45,813
Who is he?

97
00:11:47,948 --> 00:11:49,708
This man you have to find.

98
00:11:50,009 --> 00:11:51,647
What is he to you?

99
00:11:53,668 --> 00:11:54,916
I don't know.

100
00:13:13,792 --> 00:13:15,201
To or From?

101
00:13:16,504 --> 00:13:19,180
Everybody who comes here
is running.

102
00:13:19,550 --> 00:13:22,645
Either to something, or from it.

103
00:13:28,965 --> 00:13:31,497
I see a lot like you.
Runners.

104
00:13:31,700 --> 00:13:34,942
They come to me thinking a new
passport, means a new life

105
00:13:35,458 --> 00:13:36,914
This is not good.

106
00:13:37,216 --> 00:13:39,574
- It's perfect.
- The date strip's been demagnetized.

107
00:13:39,576 --> 00:13:42,807
- The ony place this gets me is holding cell.
- If you want better you pay more.

108
00:13:44,355 --> 00:13:47,210
Or I put a word out that
Tobias sells bad paper.

109
00:14:10,608 --> 00:14:12,571
Be careful, little girl.

110
00:14:12,972 --> 00:14:15,231
This world is a dangerous place.

111
00:18:13,302 --> 00:18:14,546
MATCH FOUND

112
00:18:36,706 --> 00:18:37,707
100% MATCH

113
00:18:42,714 --> 00:18:45,794
47, it's Diana.
You have company.

114
00:18:45,796 --> 00:18:47,867
- Who is he?
- A Syndicate asset.

115
00:18:48,082 --> 00:18:49,516
Name, unknown.

116
00:18:49,518 --> 00:18:51,882
Technical capacities, unknown.

117
00:18:52,036 --> 00:18:53,041
He found her.

118
00:18:53,043 --> 00:18:55,263
- Means he's good.
- You're better.

119
00:18:55,265 --> 00:18:56,965
I'm sure you can handle him.

120
00:18:57,766 --> 00:19:00,421
You have 48 hours
to terminate both targets.

121
00:21:09,392 --> 00:21:10,392
Sorry.

122
00:21:15,249 --> 00:21:18,017
You do know that stealing's a crime,
don't you, Katia?

123
00:21:18,702 --> 00:21:21,042
That is your name, isn't it?
Katia Van Dees?

124
00:21:21,043 --> 00:21:22,903
- My german's not...
- Are you some kind of cop?

125
00:21:22,905 --> 00:21:25,018
- No.
- How do you know my name?

126
00:21:25,219 --> 00:21:26,219
I'm John.

127
00:21:26,612 --> 00:21:27,817
John Smith.

128
00:21:27,920 --> 00:21:30,522
- I'd like to buy you a cup of coffee.
- Not interested.

129
00:21:31,280 --> 00:21:32,459
How about in living?

130
00:21:33,706 --> 00:21:35,298
Are you interested in that?

131
00:21:36,802 --> 00:21:39,273
Walk away or I'll scream.

132
00:21:39,276 --> 00:21:40,977
He won't care.

133
00:21:50,549 --> 00:21:52,333
He's here to kill you, Katia.

134
00:21:52,949 --> 00:21:54,454
And I'm here to stop him.

135
00:21:54,845 --> 00:21:58,129
I know you don't have any reason to trust
me but look at him. Look at how he moves.

136
00:21:58,130 --> 00:22:01,211
Look at the shadows on his coat. Look at
his eyes, and tell me that I'm lying.

137
00:22:01,398 --> 00:22:03,005
Why would anyone want to kill me?

138
00:22:03,106 --> 00:22:05,827
For the same reason you're trying to look
for someone you can't find.

139
00:22:06,843 --> 00:22:09,154
The man I'm looking for,
Do you know where he is?

140
00:22:09,155 --> 00:22:10,555
No, but you do.

141
00:22:15,698 --> 00:22:17,166
Waht do I have to do?

142
00:22:17,167 --> 00:22:18,851
There's a maintenance door.
The north end of the driveway.

143
00:22:18,852 --> 00:22:21,846
It's been unlocked for us.
We're going to head there now.

144
00:22:21,882 --> 00:22:25,239
Go through the corridor, up the stairs.
To a car will be waiting for us.

145
00:22:27,803 --> 00:22:28,803
Run!

146
00:23:58,395 --> 00:23:59,395
Move.

147
00:24:01,435 --> 00:24:02,779
Franco, we're coming your way.

148
00:24:04,275 --> 00:24:05,968
Hurry! Hurry!

149
00:24:08,279 --> 00:24:09,295
Where's the Agent?

150
00:24:09,297 --> 00:24:10,992
He's right behind us!
Move, move!

151
00:24:18,937 --> 00:24:21,406
- Katia, are you hit?
- Who the fuck are you people?

152
00:24:21,407 --> 00:24:23,236
Come down, Katia!
You're safe.

153
00:24:23,637 --> 00:24:24,994
We've been sent to protect...

154
00:24:44,475 --> 00:24:47,247
I work for a corporation called,
Syndicate International...

155
00:24:47,248 --> 00:24:49,529
- And I'm here to protect you.
- From who?

156
00:24:50,032 --> 00:24:51,894
His name is 47.
And he's an Agent.

157
00:24:51,895 --> 00:24:54,467
And right now the only thing standing
between you and him, is me.

158
00:24:54,669 --> 00:24:56,781
If you don't do everything I
say, everything...

159
00:24:57,248 --> 00:24:58,497
He will kill you.

160
00:25:00,562 --> 00:25:01,562
Let's go!

161
00:25:09,969 --> 00:25:11,425
We'll be safe here.

162
00:25:12,254 --> 00:25:16,317
EMBASSY OF
THE UNITED STATES OF AMÉRICA

163
00:25:17,012 --> 00:25:18,284
Identificatión, please.

164
00:25:18,286 --> 00:25:20,157
Purses open and in plain sight,
please.

165
00:25:23,502 --> 00:25:24,963
Put down your weapon!

166
00:25:25,518 --> 00:25:27,504
On the ground!
Hands where we can see them!

167
00:25:27,507 --> 00:25:29,134
- Don't move!
- Cuff them!

168
00:25:31,337 --> 00:25:33,348
You're coming with me.
Grab the pack.

169
00:25:34,772 --> 00:25:35,772
Move!

170
00:26:02,308 --> 00:26:04,731
Miss Van Dees, is it?

171
00:26:07,191 --> 00:26:10,024
You mind telling me why you're here?
Because your friend in there wouldn't talk.

172
00:26:10,026 --> 00:26:13,004
He's not my friend.
I don't know who he is.

173
00:26:14,094 --> 00:26:15,002
Alright.

174
00:26:15,004 --> 00:26:19,980
Maybe we can start with why he discharged
a firearm in from of my embassy.

175
00:26:20,644 --> 00:26:22,180
Soemone was trying...

176
00:26:22,405 --> 00:26:24,832
I think that someone
was trying to kill me.

177
00:26:26,379 --> 00:26:29,147
John was trying to .. help me.

178
00:26:31,399 --> 00:26:33,630
Does this someone have a name?

179
00:26:39,783 --> 00:26:42,053
Something wrong, Miss van Dees?

180
00:26:44,048 --> 00:26:45,445
Miss van Dees.

181
00:26:46,617 --> 00:26:47,861
He's coming.

182
00:26:52,154 --> 00:26:53,355
Shit.

183
00:27:06,713 --> 00:27:07,714
Freeze!

184
00:27:08,365 --> 00:27:09,392
Hands in the air!

185
00:27:13,374 --> 00:27:14,374
Sanders.

186
00:27:30,191 --> 00:27:33,069
Blaser R93 LRS2 rifle.

187
00:27:33,070 --> 00:27:35,386
Custom configured right hand twist.

188
00:27:36,718 --> 00:27:41,090
4-24x50 sniper scope, and...

189
00:27:42,910 --> 00:27:44,349
hair trigger.

190
00:27:44,650 --> 00:27:45,868
Very nice.

191
00:27:47,148 --> 00:27:48,148
Come here.

192
00:27:48,249 --> 00:27:50,403
Almost as the nice as 45s...

193
00:27:50,406 --> 00:27:53,569
and these very special knives
you walked in here with.

194
00:27:55,236 --> 00:27:56,960
You like riddles?

195
00:27:57,661 --> 00:27:59,123
Yeah, me neither.

196
00:27:59,425 --> 00:28:01,124
I hate them actually.

197
00:28:01,493 --> 00:28:04,971
But you, my friend,
are a riddle to me.

198
00:28:05,046 --> 00:28:08,773
Because I've run your face and prints
through every database we have.

199
00:28:09,009 --> 00:28:10,445
And you know what we found?

200
00:28:11,438 --> 00:28:12,530
Nothing.

201
00:28:16,479 --> 00:28:17,625
So...

202
00:28:17,826 --> 00:28:20,068
Why don't we start with your name?

203
00:28:22,034 --> 00:28:23,526
47.

204
00:28:24,839 --> 00:28:25,998
That's not a name.

205
00:28:26,200 --> 00:28:27,451
No...

206
00:28:27,610 --> 00:28:29,629
But it is mine.

207
00:28:30,698 --> 00:28:31,698
Okay.

208
00:28:32,296 --> 00:28:34,358
Alright, Mr. 47.

209
00:28:34,727 --> 00:28:36,741
What exactly are you?

210
00:28:36,777 --> 00:28:38,219
An assassin.

211
00:28:38,754 --> 00:28:41,000
An assassin, okay.

212
00:28:41,376 --> 00:28:44,466
And you're here to kill who, exactly?

213
00:28:45,252 --> 00:28:47,298
You have a girl here.

214
00:28:47,990 --> 00:28:49,858
I don't know what you're talking about.

215
00:28:50,241 --> 00:28:52,322
Do you love your family?

216
00:28:53,638 --> 00:28:55,159
My family?

217
00:28:55,196 --> 00:28:56,233
Yes, your wife...

218
00:28:56,450 --> 00:28:58,253
two small children.

219
00:28:58,754 --> 00:29:00,027
You love them?

220
00:29:01,172 --> 00:29:03,458
We're not talking about me,
we're talking about you.

221
00:29:03,493 --> 00:29:05,561
No, we're talking about life.

222
00:29:05,597 --> 00:29:07,074
And death.

223
00:29:07,110 --> 00:29:10,502
Do .. you .. love them?

224
00:29:11,717 --> 00:29:13,073
Alright.

225
00:29:13,456 --> 00:29:16,373
- Maybe we should start over.
- I believe you do.

226
00:29:17,995 --> 00:29:20,411
That's why, you should let me go.

227
00:29:21,663 --> 00:29:26,606
Now you listen to me very carefully
Mr 47, or whatever the fuck your name is.

228
00:29:27,030 --> 00:29:30,177
There's a lot of ways that this
can end and that's entirely up to you

229
00:29:30,180 --> 00:29:34,680
But you can be goddamn certain
that it's not gonna end the way you

230
00:29:34,681 --> 00:29:36,296
Because the last time I checked...

231
00:29:36,298 --> 00:29:39,898
You're locked in here with me,
and I'm the one with a gun.

232
00:29:40,641 --> 00:29:43,401
No, Mr. Sanders.

233
00:29:44,166 --> 00:29:46,355
You are locked in here with me...

234
00:29:46,870 --> 00:29:49,341
And you just brought me mine.

235
00:30:12,375 --> 00:30:14,950
Do you love your children
enough to die for them?

236
00:30:25,490 --> 00:30:26,490
Freeze!

237
00:30:33,237 --> 00:30:35,133
Let's go.
Let me help you.

238
00:30:39,589 --> 00:30:41,883
Two suspects
one male one female...

239
00:30:41,885 --> 00:30:44,432
Broke out of
Interrogation rooms 1 and 2.

240
00:30:45,965 --> 00:30:48,883
They're armed and dangerous.
Proceed with caution.

241
00:30:55,112 --> 00:30:56,112
Sargent.

242
00:30:57,987 --> 00:30:59,444
Is everything alright, sir?

243
00:31:00,927 --> 00:31:02,028
Sir?

244
00:31:04,325 --> 00:31:06,061
Hurry! Hurry!

245
00:31:15,665 --> 00:31:16,865
Get out!

246
00:31:17,123 --> 00:31:18,224
Move!

247
00:31:36,210 --> 00:31:38,199
You want to tell me
what's happening now?

248
00:31:39,418 --> 00:31:41,183
What the fuck is happening?

249
00:31:42,647 --> 00:31:45,920
The man you're looking for,
his name is Peter Aaron Litvenko.

250
00:31:45,955 --> 00:31:47,091
Who is he?

251
00:31:48,663 --> 00:31:50,227
Your father.

252
00:31:52,701 --> 00:31:54,118
Tell me about him.

253
00:31:55,359 --> 00:31:57,002
I don't know much.

254
00:31:57,117 --> 00:32:00,472
Only that he's a genecist,
an expert on human biogenetics...

255
00:32:00,474 --> 00:32:03,159
who spearheaded a
program of experimentation.

256
00:32:03,888 --> 00:32:05,900
What kind of experiments?

257
00:32:06,001 --> 00:32:08,098
The kind that created killers.

258
00:32:09,423 --> 00:32:13,528
The engineered human beings
by targeting specific genes.

259
00:32:13,665 --> 00:32:18,280
The resulting subjects were faster, stronger,
more intelligent than normal people.

260
00:32:18,369 --> 00:32:20,349
They programmed out pain, fear,.

261
00:32:20,350 --> 00:32:21,606
Even love.

262
00:32:21,654 --> 00:32:23,735
They called them Agents.

263
00:32:23,942 --> 00:32:27,310
And your father was one of the
lead scientists of the Program.

264
00:32:27,311 --> 00:32:29,006
You can't be serious.

265
00:32:29,883 --> 00:32:31,591
What does this have anything to
do with me?

266
00:32:31,592 --> 00:32:33,244
And why do they want to kill me?

267
00:32:33,246 --> 00:32:35,835
Kriton Technologies
has re-started the Agent Program.

268
00:32:35,837 --> 00:32:37,350
They're building Agents right now.

269
00:32:37,352 --> 00:32:39,036
Like 47, maybe worse.

270
00:32:39,138 --> 00:32:42,353
They belive that you're the
key to finding your father.

271
00:32:45,102 --> 00:32:46,629
I don't understand.

272
00:32:46,631 --> 00:32:48,566
Your father knows their weakness.

273
00:32:48,573 --> 00:32:50,267
He knows how to stop them.

274
00:32:56,246 --> 00:32:57,445
Katia!

275
00:33:38,616 --> 00:33:39,961
You okay?

276
00:33:39,962 --> 00:33:40,963
No.

277
00:33:46,441 --> 00:33:48,805
Is your name really John Smith?

278
00:33:51,568 --> 00:33:52,929
It's Brian.

279
00:33:54,204 --> 00:33:56,947
Well, at least you didn't
say I was Agent 46.

280
00:33:56,982 --> 00:33:58,359
No, that's someone else.

281
00:34:01,790 --> 00:34:03,373
Come here. let me help you.

282
00:34:21,749 --> 00:34:23,555
You're going to be alright.

283
00:34:25,971 --> 00:34:26,971
No lie?

284
00:34:28,760 --> 00:34:30,052
I'm sorry.

285
00:34:30,779 --> 00:34:31,779
For what?

286
00:34:32,080 --> 00:34:34,156
For having to tell you
who your father is.

287
00:34:35,394 --> 00:34:37,204
Well, you told me the truth.

288
00:34:37,507 --> 00:34:40,153
That's more than anyone ever has.

289
00:34:41,659 --> 00:34:44,501
Why is it that they think
I can find him, John?

290
00:34:45,148 --> 00:34:46,138
Doesn't matter now.

291
00:34:46,140 --> 00:34:47,241
But it does.

292
00:34:48,616 --> 00:34:50,350
Tell me what you know.

293
00:34:50,932 --> 00:34:52,288
I know that you're in danger.

294
00:34:54,404 --> 00:34:56,921
The best thing you could do
right now is hide.

295
00:34:57,136 --> 00:34:59,379
I've been hiding my entire life.
Please...

296
00:34:59,657 --> 00:35:00,973
tell me what you know.

297
00:35:03,898 --> 00:35:05,846
I'm authorized to protect you...

298
00:35:05,948 --> 00:35:08,014
Katia, not find your father.

299
00:35:16,942 --> 00:35:17,942
Don't do this.

300
00:35:18,042 --> 00:35:19,044
I have to.

301
00:35:19,653 --> 00:35:20,653
Okay.

302
00:35:24,700 --> 00:35:27,129
When we were researching your
father, we found a file.

303
00:35:28,655 --> 00:35:30,451
It mentiined you. It said that...

304
00:35:31,131 --> 00:35:32,394
Said what?

305
00:35:33,004 --> 00:35:34,300
It said that he changed you.

306
00:35:35,601 --> 00:35:36,902
Changed me, how?

307
00:35:37,002 --> 00:35:39,894
It said that he had enhanced
your survival skills.

308
00:35:40,897 --> 00:35:43,493
It's why we think you've been
hiding...

309
00:35:43,495 --> 00:35:47,790
Why you've been able to stay
off the radar, been to stay alive.

310
00:35:48,463 --> 00:35:50,630
- That's why I was always afraid.
- Yes.

311
00:35:54,608 --> 00:35:55,604
Jesus!

312
00:35:55,606 --> 00:35:57,807
They think I know how to
find my father.

313
00:36:03,810 --> 00:36:04,810
What is this?

314
00:36:05,111 --> 00:36:06,617
It's my father's life.

315
00:36:16,139 --> 00:36:17,802
What else do you know about him?

316
00:36:17,837 --> 00:36:19,063
Just what I told you.

317
00:36:19,129 --> 00:36:21,872
You must have something.
How old is he?

318
00:36:21,974 --> 00:36:22,974
Seventy two.

319
00:36:23,617 --> 00:36:24,694
Where was he born?

320
00:36:24,797 --> 00:36:26,087
Ukraine.

321
00:36:27,210 --> 00:36:28,751
Medical conditions?

322
00:36:29,422 --> 00:36:32,731
He was diagnosed with rheumatroid
arthritis in his 40s.

323
00:36:33,613 --> 00:36:35,484
Somewhere warm, then.

324
00:36:37,397 --> 00:36:38,397
What else?

325
00:36:39,712 --> 00:36:40,970
Lung cancer.

326
00:36:44,758 --> 00:36:48,466
Last known sighting was
in a hospital Seúl, Korea in 2011.

327
00:36:49,126 --> 00:36:52,609
He was engaged in some clinical trials...

328
00:36:52,610 --> 00:36:55,191
in something called nanomolecular
inhalation therapy

329
00:36:57,422 --> 00:36:59,242
He was stage 3 then.

330
00:37:00,900 --> 00:37:03,575
So, travel will be difficult.

331
00:37:06,107 --> 00:37:07,265
Does he have money?

332
00:37:08,464 --> 00:37:09,729
I think so.

333
00:37:09,832 --> 00:37:13,246
Somewhere warm with advanced
medical facilities.

334
00:37:13,247 --> 00:37:14,447
A city.

335
00:37:15,205 --> 00:37:16,205
Hobbies?

336
00:37:20,607 --> 00:37:21,899
What does he love to do?

337
00:37:22,340 --> 00:37:23,341
Orchids.

338
00:37:26,029 --> 00:37:27,856
He was an expert in orchids.

339
00:37:32,125 --> 00:37:34,020
What languages did he speak, John?

340
00:37:34,858 --> 00:37:38,436
English, Russian, Mandarín and Tamil.

341
00:37:40,704 --> 00:37:41,982
Why Tamil?

342
00:37:42,231 --> 00:37:44,794
Because your mother was from Sri Lanka.

343
00:37:58,612 --> 00:38:00,341
You know where he is, don't you?

344
00:38:07,826 --> 00:38:08,826
Katia.

345
00:38:12,086 --> 00:38:14,595
YOu told me you wanted to do this,
and I told you I would do it with you...

346
00:38:14,597 --> 00:38:17,288
but if you want my help, you
have to tell me where he is.

347
00:38:59,051 --> 00:39:00,733
We've lost the girl.

348
00:39:01,133 --> 00:39:06,214
You told me that your John Smith
would be adequate.

349
00:39:07,118 --> 00:39:08,862
We underestimated this Agent.

350
00:39:10,647 --> 00:39:13,760
Find Litvenko,
whatever it takes.

351
00:39:14,698 --> 00:39:17,645
And, Garad, better this girl dead...

352
00:39:17,747 --> 00:39:20,640
Than this Agent finding Litvenko
before we do.

353
00:39:26,103 --> 00:39:27,104
Katia.

354
00:39:29,588 --> 00:39:30,722
Katia.

355
00:39:43,440 --> 00:39:45,463
Do you know why you're still alive?

356
00:39:46,683 --> 00:39:48,777
Because I chose not to kill you.

357
00:39:52,959 --> 00:39:54,173
But they will.

358
00:39:55,619 --> 00:39:57,633
After they use you
to find your father.

359
00:39:59,130 --> 00:40:00,803
What do you know about my father?

360
00:40:03,235 --> 00:40:04,532
As much as you do.

361
00:40:06,242 --> 00:40:07,322
Everything will be alright.

362
00:40:08,985 --> 00:40:09,985
No!

363
00:40:15,177 --> 00:40:16,989
Time to make a choice, Katia.

364
00:40:17,594 --> 00:40:20,467
Them or me.

365
00:40:23,398 --> 00:40:24,768
Why should I trust you?

366
00:40:24,999 --> 00:40:28,202
You don't have to.
Just trust you memories.

367
00:40:30,358 --> 00:40:31,709
Take my hand.

368
00:40:35,042 --> 00:40:38,144
You remember the day you ran away, Katia?

369
00:40:38,146 --> 00:40:39,148
Peter, we have to go!

370
00:40:39,150 --> 00:40:42,342
Your father's lab?
The car rides?

371
00:40:45,218 --> 00:40:46,319
Easy.

372
00:40:46,320 --> 00:40:48,247
The last time you saw your mother?

373
00:40:48,450 --> 00:40:52,049
No! No, no, no, no!

374
00:40:59,882 --> 00:41:01,203
You were there.

375
00:41:02,795 --> 00:41:03,796
Yes.

376
00:41:05,453 --> 00:41:07,515
Yes, we were part of the same Program.

377
00:41:17,903 --> 00:41:19,178
We have to go.
Quickly!

378
00:41:22,224 --> 00:41:23,224
Run! Quickly!

379
00:41:24,536 --> 00:41:25,980
Good, get down there.
Get down, please!

380
00:41:25,982 --> 00:41:26,982
Papá!

381
00:41:26,985 --> 00:41:29,240
Live.

382
00:41:37,993 --> 00:41:39,991
He left me.
Why?

383
00:41:41,614 --> 00:41:44,414
Find him.
You can ask him yourself.

384
00:41:49,192 --> 00:41:50,236
Untie me.

385
00:41:52,085 --> 00:41:55,213
You have a lot to learn, Katia.
We don't have a lot of time.

386
00:41:56,086 --> 00:41:57,152
Untie yourself.

387
00:43:12,997 --> 00:43:14,118
That took you too long.

388
00:43:14,625 --> 00:43:15,905
I didn't know that was a test.

389
00:43:16,276 --> 00:43:17,437
Everything is a test.

390
00:43:17,639 --> 00:43:19,707
Keep taking these, you'll fail.

391
00:43:20,195 --> 00:43:21,339
Hey, I need them.

392
00:43:21,740 --> 00:43:23,925
What you need is a clear head.

393
00:43:24,197 --> 00:43:25,717
Stop fighting what you are.

394
00:43:25,719 --> 00:43:26,718
And what am I?

395
00:43:26,720 --> 00:43:28,774
Keep asking questions,
you'll probably be dead.

396
00:43:30,162 --> 00:43:31,169
What am I?

397
00:43:32,458 --> 00:43:34,390
You're the same as me, only better.

398
00:43:34,790 --> 00:43:37,019
Bullshit!
I'm just Katia van Dess.

399
00:43:37,020 --> 00:43:39,461
You speak French, Spanish, Mandarín.
Where did you learn them?

400
00:43:39,563 --> 00:43:41,294
HOw did you free yourself from the rope?

401
00:43:43,312 --> 00:43:45,043
You've been programmed.

402
00:43:45,746 --> 00:43:49,101
And your name isn't Katia van Dees.
It's "quatre-vingt-dix".

403
00:43:49,402 --> 00:43:50,869
French for "90".

404
00:43:52,469 --> 00:43:54,582
So I'm 43 versions better than you?

405
00:43:56,419 --> 00:43:57,421
So they know?

406
00:43:57,423 --> 00:43:59,460
If they knew,
you'd be the target.

407
00:43:59,563 --> 00:44:00,616
Come on, let's go.

408
00:44:07,986 --> 00:44:11,922
If you need my help to find
my father, Why did you shoot me?

409
00:44:12,784 --> 00:44:15,414
I didn't shoot you, I marked you.

410
00:44:20,229 --> 00:44:21,408
There is so many.

411
00:44:21,411 --> 00:44:24,513
If I shoot one, the rest will converge.
So what do we do, Katia?

412
00:44:25,635 --> 00:44:26,635
Avoid them.

413
00:44:28,257 --> 00:44:30,719
NO, suppress your fear.
And face the threat.

414
00:44:32,524 --> 00:44:37,086
YOur father programmed you to see and hear
everything at extremely hightend levels.

415
00:44:40,900 --> 00:44:43,935
You process that information
to anticipate a threat.

416
00:44:50,719 --> 00:44:51,983
So anticipate it.

417
00:45:07,277 --> 00:45:08,277
Katia.

418
00:45:13,768 --> 00:45:14,769
There.

419
00:45:46,061 --> 00:45:47,242
Area Four, all...

420
00:45:57,655 --> 00:45:58,657
Katia.

421
00:46:01,040 --> 00:46:02,040
Now.

422
00:46:09,286 --> 00:46:10,706
I need you to step out there.

423
00:46:10,708 --> 00:46:11,710
Why?

424
00:46:12,793 --> 00:46:13,995
To draw them toward you.

425
00:46:14,297 --> 00:46:15,820
They're going to shoot me!

426
00:46:16,916 --> 00:46:18,410
They're not going to shoot you.

427
00:46:21,606 --> 00:46:23,415
You want to see your father again?

428
00:46:26,517 --> 00:46:27,517
Trust me.

429
00:46:36,353 --> 00:46:37,667
I ahve a visual target lock.

430
00:46:38,271 --> 00:46:39,471
Moving in.

431
00:46:46,926 --> 00:46:48,302
Hello, Katia.

432
00:46:54,910 --> 00:46:58,183
I'm only going to ask you once.
Where is your father?

433
00:47:02,962 --> 00:47:05,830
I want you to know, I'm a
big fan of your work, 47.

434
00:47:05,833 --> 00:47:07,509
It's an honor to meet a legend.

435
00:47:09,658 --> 00:47:12,372
I thought you could only
be a legend after you are dead.

436
00:47:12,682 --> 00:47:13,862
Oh, but you are.

437
00:47:14,593 --> 00:47:16,316
You just don't know it yet.

438
00:47:18,513 --> 00:47:20,928
Feeling pretty good for
a dead man, John.

439
00:47:21,130 --> 00:47:23,378
- Almost as good as you.
- Yeah?

440
00:47:24,774 --> 00:47:26,635
Well, the thing is I'm special.

441
00:47:27,169 --> 00:47:28,171
Let's see.

442
00:47:48,890 --> 00:47:49,928
Pretty crazy, huh?

443
00:48:11,981 --> 00:48:13,731
I'm better. Say it!

444
00:48:15,673 --> 00:48:16,774
Say it!

445
00:48:18,611 --> 00:48:19,758
You're not.

446
00:48:23,614 --> 00:48:24,738
You missed.

447
00:48:24,739 --> 00:48:26,037
No she didn't.

448
00:48:51,202 --> 00:48:52,257
You made a mistake.

449
00:48:52,259 --> 00:48:53,786
He had a gun to your head.

450
00:48:54,189 --> 00:48:56,710
And he didn't pull the trigger.
He wanted me to know he beat me.

451
00:48:57,192 --> 00:48:58,412
Well, what the fuck is he?

452
00:48:58,514 --> 00:49:01,870
People just don't walk away from
four bullets. They just don't.

453
00:49:02,211 --> 00:49:04,551
Subdermal titanium body armour.

454
00:49:05,551 --> 00:49:07,691
Injected under the skin
in liquid form

455
00:49:07,693 --> 00:49:09,594
It's flexible, extremely strong

456
00:49:09,996 --> 00:49:13,529
He had his nervous system heightened.
Wired for speed.

457
00:49:14,557 --> 00:49:16,705
I've heard of these Syndicate experiments..

458
00:49:18,166 --> 00:49:20,025
If they can do this with him...

459
00:49:24,291 --> 00:49:27,386
Now, will you tell me
where Litvenko is?

460
00:49:27,789 --> 00:49:30,218
Swear to me that you're not
going to hurt him.

461
00:49:31,279 --> 00:49:32,279
Swear it.

462
00:49:33,056 --> 00:49:34,587
Alright, I swear it.

463
00:49:35,976 --> 00:49:37,225
Diana, did you hear that?

464
00:49:37,426 --> 00:49:39,861
I did. Send me the link to the asset.

465
00:49:41,520 --> 00:49:43,614
If you lie to me, I will kill you.

466
00:49:44,911 --> 00:49:46,596
I'm not that easy to kill.

467
00:49:51,835 --> 00:49:52,997
He's in Singapore.

468
00:49:55,404 --> 00:49:57,624
Syndicate headquarters are
in Singapore.

469
00:49:58,697 --> 00:50:00,375
He's hiding in plain sight.

470
00:50:26,973 --> 00:50:28,853
- Yes?
- It's Diana.

471
00:50:28,854 --> 00:50:30,907
I need you in Singapore
as soon as possible.

472
00:50:31,010 --> 00:50:32,420
I'm on my way.

473
00:51:04,264 --> 00:51:05,838
Singapore

474
00:51:15,934 --> 00:51:16,933
Yes?

475
00:51:16,935 --> 00:51:19,120
Litvenko's in Singapore.
They're on their way.

476
00:51:21,521 --> 00:51:24,620
Thy're coming. Scan the
re-entry points.

477
00:51:24,922 --> 00:51:26,123
Yes, sir.

478
00:51:45,183 --> 00:51:47,574
The Syndicate ties into those
cameras, isn't it?

479
00:51:47,677 --> 00:51:49,337
They're tied to everything.

480
00:51:50,673 --> 00:51:52,936
Will you hold this, please?
Thanks.

481
00:51:53,500 --> 00:51:55,209
How do you fight against that?

482
00:51:55,464 --> 00:51:57,709
By playing the odds,
doing the unexpected.

483
00:51:57,741 --> 00:52:00,844
Take nothing for granted.
Everything you do has a reason.

484
00:52:01,541 --> 00:52:02,765
What does that mean?

485
00:52:03,820 --> 00:52:05,918
Jacket. Give me your bag.

486
00:52:06,320 --> 00:52:09,706
Right now,
it means avoid those cameras.

487
00:52:10,264 --> 00:52:11,264
Okay.

488
00:53:33,336 --> 00:53:36,359
08/14

489
00:53:45,578 --> 00:53:47,429
I know, that took me too long.

490
00:53:52,716 --> 00:53:53,942
Ask you a question?

491
00:53:54,651 --> 00:53:56,595
Am I going to end up like you?

492
00:54:30,081 --> 00:54:31,082
Bombs?

493
00:54:32,360 --> 00:54:33,361
Moths.

494
00:54:34,476 --> 00:54:36,194
Italian wool, they love it.

495
00:54:51,698 --> 00:54:55,176
TARGET LOCATED

496
00:55:19,058 --> 00:55:20,058
Did it hurt?

497
00:55:23,085 --> 00:55:24,085
Yes.

498
00:55:25,765 --> 00:55:26,765
You all...?

499
00:55:27,166 --> 00:55:29,376
The barcode is given to
us when we are born.

500
00:55:32,210 --> 00:55:33,211
The number?

501
00:55:33,213 --> 00:55:34,701
When we become Agents.

502
00:55:50,605 --> 00:55:52,614
He'll be there in the morning,
at about 9:00.

503
00:55:53,217 --> 00:55:55,262
It's when the orchids
are in full bloom.

504
00:56:01,725 --> 00:56:03,012
You know he's dying?

505
00:56:06,643 --> 00:56:07,927
Lung cancer.

506
00:56:09,631 --> 00:56:11,868
He needs an inhaler
now to breathe.

507
00:56:28,277 --> 00:56:29,790
Are you human?

508
00:56:33,195 --> 00:56:37,195
Is just that John said you're incapable
of feeling fear or remorse

509
00:56:37,230 --> 00:56:39,463
It's all been suppressed.
Is that true?

510
00:56:41,166 --> 00:56:42,165
Yes.

511
00:56:42,168 --> 00:56:43,260
What about love?

512
00:56:47,087 --> 00:56:48,575
I am what I need to be.

513
00:56:48,576 --> 00:56:49,646
What does that mean?

514
00:56:49,948 --> 00:56:53,280
In this job, sometimes
it's better not to feel anything

515
00:56:53,383 --> 00:56:55,459
I'm not talking about the job

516
00:56:57,971 --> 00:56:59,152
I think you're lying

517
00:57:01,318 --> 00:57:04,120
I don't believe you can just
turn off fear or love

518
00:57:04,122 --> 00:57:05,502
I don't believe anyone can.

519
00:57:05,804 --> 00:57:09,014
You're either a person or something
else. Which is it?

520
00:57:09,490 --> 00:57:11,871
Are you asking me, or yourself?

521
00:57:15,304 --> 00:57:17,508
You can't fight who you are, Katia.

522
00:57:18,899 --> 00:57:20,020
You'll lose.

523
00:57:20,921 --> 00:57:23,784
Is that what happened to you?
You fought who you are, and you lost?

524
00:57:28,723 --> 00:57:30,099
People can change.

525
00:57:30,895 --> 00:57:32,237
Don't put your faith in me.

526
00:57:34,278 --> 00:57:36,002
You'll be disappointed.

527
00:57:38,764 --> 00:57:40,465
I still have a job to do.

528
00:57:42,629 --> 00:57:43,630
Which is?

529
00:57:45,126 --> 00:57:47,488
Right now, I need to sleep.

530
00:59:34,885 --> 00:59:38,251
When I get anxious, and I can't sleep,
I take things apart.

531
00:59:41,320 --> 00:59:42,320
I'm sorry.

532
00:59:44,493 --> 00:59:45,866
Don't ever do that again.

533
00:59:50,939 --> 00:59:52,049
Were they Syndicate?

534
00:59:52,153 --> 00:59:53,302
No, free-lance.

535
00:59:53,405 --> 00:59:54,586
Friends of yours?

536
00:59:56,444 --> 00:59:58,680
So, the Syndicate doesn't
know we're here?

537
00:59:58,716 --> 01:00:00,918
There's a open contract out on
us. What do you think?

538
01:00:02,191 --> 01:00:05,279
Here, try not to take this apart.

539
01:00:10,534 --> 01:00:12,874
- Smells bad.
- Robert, please!

540
01:00:12,909 --> 01:00:15,635
- How did they find us so quick?
- You tell me.

541
01:00:15,836 --> 01:00:18,762
- No games.
- What makes you think this is a game?

542
01:00:22,685 --> 01:00:25,124
The cameras in the Terminal
didn't see me.

543
01:00:30,789 --> 01:00:33,496
But the one outside, near the
exit, did.

544
01:00:35,234 --> 01:00:36,887
Getting pretty good at this,
aren't I?

545
01:00:37,089 --> 01:00:38,790
No, you're sloppy.

546
01:00:38,792 --> 01:00:40,390
But, I'm going to have an attack.

547
01:00:40,492 --> 01:00:43,217
Bee a good boy.
Here, take your inhalor.

548
01:00:43,253 --> 01:00:44,319
It'll be alrght.

549
01:00:52,175 --> 01:00:53,176
Excuse me.

550
01:00:57,477 --> 01:00:59,240
- Where did you get that?
- I traded it.

551
01:00:59,341 --> 01:01:01,067
- For what?
- Your knife.

552
01:01:21,138 --> 01:01:23,290
Bring Litvenko
and the girl to me.

553
01:02:30,707 --> 01:02:31,999
You shouldn't have come.

554
01:02:34,124 --> 01:02:35,525
You know who I am?

555
01:02:43,588 --> 01:02:45,913
You are your mother's daughter.

556
01:02:49,269 --> 01:02:50,889
Why did you leave me?

557
01:02:55,073 --> 01:02:57,500
I wanted you to have
no part of what I was.

558
01:02:58,001 --> 01:03:00,108
I wanted you to live.

559
01:03:02,865 --> 01:03:04,328
You had no right.

560
01:03:05,038 --> 01:03:06,833
To walk away from you?

561
01:03:09,390 --> 01:03:13,135
To turn me into this isolated,
afraid thing that I am.

562
01:03:13,171 --> 01:03:14,439
You had no right!

563
01:03:21,243 --> 01:03:22,646
Walk with me, Katia.

564
01:03:30,357 --> 01:03:32,455
I loved your mother very much.

565
01:03:33,156 --> 01:03:35,171
She was a light...

566
01:03:35,372 --> 01:03:37,376
In a very dark world.

567
01:03:39,025 --> 01:03:41,383
And more than anything else..

568
01:03:41,682 --> 01:03:43,222
She wanted a child.

569
01:03:43,625 --> 01:03:45,925
But she was unable.

570
01:03:46,914 --> 01:03:50,445
So, we broke every rule we had...

571
01:03:50,870 --> 01:03:52,274
and we made you.

572
01:03:57,625 --> 01:04:00,227
We knew that if you were discovered...

573
01:04:00,529 --> 01:04:04,359
They would take you from us,
so we gave you...

574
01:04:04,460 --> 01:04:06,828
the tools to be free.

575
01:04:09,491 --> 01:04:10,935
This isn't freedom.

576
01:04:11,603 --> 01:04:13,568
No, perhaps not, Katia.

577
01:04:14,188 --> 01:04:16,834
But it is necessary
for your survival.

578
01:04:17,471 --> 01:04:21,400
NOw, I don't expect you to understand...

579
01:04:23,825 --> 01:04:27,178
But I do ask that you
find it in yourself...

580
01:04:27,614 --> 01:04:30,166
to forgive an old man's selfishness.

581
01:04:31,038 --> 01:04:32,292
And if I can't?

582
01:04:33,383 --> 01:04:38,529
You will, because you are the
reflection of the woman I loved.

583
01:04:47,575 --> 01:04:48,694
I'm ready.

584
01:04:49,490 --> 01:04:50,586
Get it over with.

585
01:04:53,174 --> 01:04:54,301
Do it now.

586
01:04:55,635 --> 01:04:57,494
He's not going to kill you...

587
01:04:58,678 --> 01:04:59,961
father.

588
01:05:01,857 --> 01:05:03,958
Yes he will.
It's inevitable.

589
01:05:04,160 --> 01:05:07,715
Killing is what he is programmed to do,
and who he is.

590
01:05:08,032 --> 01:05:10,290
Isn't that right, 47?

591
01:05:11,588 --> 01:05:12,588
You're wrong.

592
01:05:14,334 --> 01:05:17,502
We determine who we are
by what we do.

593
01:05:24,232 --> 01:05:25,426
You believe...?

594
01:05:26,374 --> 01:05:28,386
You have a choice?

595
01:05:29,527 --> 01:05:32,190
I believe that's
what makes us human.

596
01:05:34,059 --> 01:05:35,686
Then it seems...

597
01:05:36,509 --> 01:05:38,386
that you and your brother...

598
01:05:38,588 --> 01:05:41,413
have a lot to teach
this old man.

599
01:05:44,272 --> 01:05:47,402
I guess I gave you
family, after all.

600
01:05:51,428 --> 01:05:52,429
Move!

601
01:06:29,716 --> 01:06:30,942
I got you.

602
01:06:35,456 --> 01:06:36,456
Seal the building.

603
01:06:42,126 --> 01:06:43,126
Go!

604
01:06:46,924 --> 01:06:48,965
- What do they want?
- More of me.

605
01:06:49,000 --> 01:06:51,006
Why would anyone
want more of you?

606
01:06:59,393 --> 01:07:01,910
One and Two stay on him,
Three and Four cut him off.

607
01:07:29,521 --> 01:07:30,521
Cut him off.

608
01:08:07,571 --> 01:08:09,432
They're boxed in,
they've got nowhere else to go.

609
01:08:09,434 --> 01:08:10,837
Right or left, Katia?

610
01:08:15,226 --> 01:08:16,469
Straight ahead.

611
01:08:17,944 --> 01:08:19,409
Trust me.

612
01:08:29,514 --> 01:08:30,584
Holy shit!

613
01:08:36,175 --> 01:08:37,765
I want this building sealed!

614
01:08:39,257 --> 01:08:40,898
Perhaps you should consider shooting him.

615
01:08:41,687 --> 01:08:42,971
Subdermal body armour.

616
01:08:42,974 --> 01:08:45,222
What, they actually got that to work?

617
01:08:45,257 --> 01:08:46,324
Yup.

618
01:08:48,076 --> 01:08:49,834
Drive the fucken car faster.

619
01:08:51,845 --> 01:08:53,176
Faster! faster!

620
01:08:53,211 --> 01:08:54,507
We won't be able to make it.

621
01:08:54,830 --> 01:08:55,835
Trust me.

622
01:09:18,772 --> 01:09:21,641
I want all units on station.
We'll take them in the city.

623
01:09:33,823 --> 01:09:36,414
- This is never going to end, is it?
- I'm afraid not.

624
01:09:36,862 --> 01:09:38,139
He will never stop.

625
01:09:38,143 --> 01:09:39,108
Who?

626
01:09:39,144 --> 01:09:42,855
Antoine Le Clerq.
He's the Syndicate chairman.

627
01:09:44,604 --> 01:09:47,133
What if we kill this Le Clerq?
Will it end then?

628
01:09:47,321 --> 01:09:48,331
We can't.

629
01:09:48,433 --> 01:09:49,901
Maybe not, but you can.

630
01:09:50,004 --> 01:09:54,550
Nobody ever gets close enough
to LeClerk to kill him.

631
01:09:55,423 --> 01:09:58,724
He nver leaves his protected offce.
Nobody ever goes in.

632
01:09:58,760 --> 01:10:00,793
He's surrounded at all times
by security.

633
01:10:01,537 --> 01:10:02,537
Fourteen.

634
01:10:03,945 --> 01:10:05,888
That's how many Agents
have tried.

635
01:10:06,182 --> 01:10:07,255
All are dead.

636
01:11:44,950 --> 01:11:46,775
Help me! Help me!

637
01:11:46,877 --> 01:11:48,684
- Get up!
- I can't walk!

638
01:11:48,685 --> 01:11:50,688
Come on! You can do it!

639
01:11:50,691 --> 01:11:52,489
Get up.

640
01:11:52,524 --> 01:11:54,094
- Sorry.
- I'll get help.

641
01:11:54,365 --> 01:11:55,361
Take her away from me!

642
01:11:55,363 --> 01:11:58,968
- Take her! Come on!
- Take here! Please!

643
01:11:58,970 --> 01:11:59,970
Come on!

644
01:12:01,849 --> 01:12:04,320
Please! Get her out of here!

645
01:12:04,321 --> 01:12:05,858
No! No!

646
01:12:05,860 --> 01:12:06,860
Take her!

647
01:12:35,644 --> 01:12:37,206
Hello, doctor.

648
01:12:46,123 --> 01:12:49,582
What the hell did you do?
We have to go back!

649
01:12:50,615 --> 01:12:51,942
He was all I had.

650
01:12:51,945 --> 01:12:54,262
- I have to help him.
- You can't.

651
01:12:54,297 --> 01:12:56,617
Damn you, you piece of shit!

652
01:12:57,566 --> 01:13:00,491
- I should kill you.
- Yes, but you won't, because you're weak.

653
01:13:00,727 --> 01:13:05,549
You're nothing more than a scared little
girl, who's only real gift is running.

654
01:13:05,695 --> 01:13:06,695
Damn you.

655
01:13:30,114 --> 01:13:32,310
DNA sequences, Doctor?

656
01:13:35,012 --> 01:13:37,313
Adaptive mutated bacteria fissures

657
01:13:37,720 --> 01:13:41,012
The epistasis rings?
Transfer RNA?

658
01:13:46,058 --> 01:13:48,031
Come on, Doc.

659
01:13:53,787 --> 01:13:55,206
I don't want to do this.

660
01:13:56,230 --> 01:13:58,587
Believe me, you don't want
me to do this either.

661
01:13:59,845 --> 01:14:02,023
So tell me what I need to know.

662
01:14:02,436 --> 01:14:03,563
Tell me...

663
01:14:03,663 --> 01:14:07,473
how to make an Agent.

664
01:14:15,471 --> 01:14:17,420
This is just experimental, Doc.

665
01:14:18,443 --> 01:14:20,151
I've seen it work...

666
01:14:20,153 --> 01:14:23,641
And believe me when I tell
you don't want to be the one.

667
01:14:25,534 --> 01:14:27,196
You're a bastard.

668
01:14:27,898 --> 01:14:28,898
I know.

669
01:14:29,000 --> 01:14:30,879
No. you don't.

670
01:14:31,846 --> 01:14:35,032
You're a result of
inferior techonologies.

671
01:14:35,671 --> 01:14:37,015
A failed experiment.

672
01:14:38,088 --> 01:14:41,485
An Agent's advantage is not
his body, John Smith.

673
01:14:41,588 --> 01:14:42,849
It's his mind.

674
01:14:43,949 --> 01:14:47,391
You will never be as good as him.

675
01:14:50,250 --> 01:14:51,263
Inject him.

676
01:15:18,493 --> 01:15:22,197
For fuck's sake Doctor,
give me what I need.

677
01:15:42,740 --> 01:15:43,742
Shit.

678
01:15:49,204 --> 01:15:50,347
Mr. Chairman.

679
01:15:50,651 --> 01:15:51,651
Are you alright?

680
01:15:52,024 --> 01:15:53,549
No, I am not.

681
01:15:53,551 --> 01:15:55,044
I need the Chairman's detail.

682
01:15:55,046 --> 01:15:56,818
The Chairman is out.

683
01:16:04,092 --> 01:16:05,535
911.

684
01:16:05,537 --> 01:16:07,414
Emergecny Services, please.

685
01:16:07,866 --> 01:16:09,712
Can I have your location, please.

686
01:16:10,988 --> 01:16:12,044
Dose him again.

687
01:16:12,046 --> 01:16:13,319
You could kill him.

688
01:16:13,883 --> 01:16:15,092
Do it.

689
01:16:16,396 --> 01:16:17,605
Oh, fuck it!

690
01:16:20,605 --> 01:16:21,708
It's the Chairman.

691
01:16:24,249 --> 01:16:25,249
What's happening?

692
01:16:26,396 --> 01:16:28,143
What's he doing out of his office?

693
01:16:34,365 --> 01:16:35,366
It's quite enough, John.

694
01:16:35,964 --> 01:16:38,462
You can wait outside,
all of you.

695
01:16:42,070 --> 01:16:43,635
It's okay, John.

696
01:16:58,649 --> 01:16:59,708
Petya.

697
01:17:01,389 --> 01:17:02,550
Can you hear me?

698
01:17:08,125 --> 01:17:11,299
I am going to be completely
honest with you.

699
01:17:14,018 --> 01:17:15,522
I admire you.

700
01:17:16,612 --> 01:17:19,988
YOu have created something unique.

701
01:17:21,170 --> 01:17:24,158
A better human being,
and I want it.

702
01:17:27,310 --> 01:17:32,377
I have bet my wealth,
my company, my reputation...

703
01:17:33,740 --> 01:17:38,624
Everyting on the success of this program.
You understand?

704
01:17:39,717 --> 01:17:43,353
Good thing I sold your stock, then.

705
01:17:45,256 --> 01:17:49,148
You and I are so very different.
You know this.

706
01:17:49,584 --> 01:17:51,166
You're wrong.

707
01:17:52,307 --> 01:17:54,534
People can change.

708
01:17:55,726 --> 01:17:56,726
No.

709
01:17:58,559 --> 01:18:00,133
No, not people like us.

710
01:18:01,767 --> 01:18:03,300
What you did...

711
01:18:03,302 --> 01:18:06,137
When you chose to play God,
can never be undone.

712
01:18:07,926 --> 01:18:10,432
You can't run from what you are.

713
01:18:10,894 --> 01:18:12,553
So I should...?

714
01:18:12,855 --> 01:18:14,712
Embrace it?

715
01:18:15,096 --> 01:18:19,392
Re-start the Program
with you as it's head?

716
01:18:20,080 --> 01:18:21,128
Yes.

717
01:18:26,977 --> 01:18:30,721
You always were a small man, Antoine.

718
01:18:32,807 --> 01:18:36,419
A derivitive thinker, at best.

719
01:18:38,269 --> 01:18:43,127
This desperation suits you.

720
01:18:54,786 --> 01:18:56,551
The key to everything...

721
01:18:58,502 --> 01:19:02,253
is in your mind,
and you're going to give it to me.

722
01:19:03,818 --> 01:19:06,661
Tell me how to build an Agent.

723
01:19:08,314 --> 01:19:10,557
You don't want an Agent.

724
01:19:12,492 --> 01:19:13,926
Then, What do I want?

725
01:19:13,929 --> 01:19:15,257
An Army.

726
01:19:16,010 --> 01:19:18,915
And I won't give it to you.

727
01:19:21,209 --> 01:19:22,790
Then you're going to die.

728
01:19:23,319 --> 01:19:25,211
I'm already dead.

729
01:19:28,749 --> 01:19:31,449
Yes, what about your daughter?

730
01:19:32,571 --> 01:19:34,570
You don't have her.

731
01:19:35,003 --> 01:19:36,424
No, but I will...

732
01:19:36,883 --> 01:19:38,498
eventually.

733
01:19:39,022 --> 01:19:43,571
Give me what I want
and I'll leave her in peace.

734
01:19:43,859 --> 01:19:48,606
I give you what you want
there won't be no peace.

735
01:19:48,875 --> 01:19:50,470
Mr. Chairman.

736
01:19:54,146 --> 01:19:55,461
Where is he?

737
01:19:55,816 --> 01:19:57,187
How did he get into our system?

738
01:19:57,189 --> 01:19:58,390
I don't know, Mr. Chairman.

739
01:19:58,391 --> 01:20:01,802
I'm assuming by your reaction,
that you know who I am

740
01:20:02,123 --> 01:20:03,187
What do you want?

741
01:20:03,589 --> 01:20:04,589
To make a deal.

742
01:20:04,791 --> 01:20:07,193
- You have nothing I need.
- You're wrong.

743
01:20:07,918 --> 01:20:10,611
You want what's inside
Litvenko's head...

744
01:20:10,613 --> 01:20:12,573
But he won't give it to you.

745
01:20:13,570 --> 01:20:14,771
I can.

746
01:20:14,972 --> 01:20:15,972
How?

747
01:20:16,727 --> 01:20:18,217
Window.

748
01:20:24,250 --> 01:20:26,433
You want the next
generation of Agents...

749
01:20:26,694 --> 01:20:29,530
but you've been
looking in the wrong place.

750
01:20:29,723 --> 01:20:33,470
You thought the girl was
the only way to find Litvenko.

751
01:20:33,793 --> 01:20:36,077
A means to an end.

752
01:20:37,181 --> 01:20:38,478
The truth is...

753
01:20:41,012 --> 01:20:43,031
She is the end.

754
01:20:46,915 --> 01:20:49,978
That's right, everything you need.

755
01:20:50,531 --> 01:20:52,385
The strength, the speed...

756
01:20:52,387 --> 01:20:54,624
the intelligence, is right there.

757
01:20:55,283 --> 01:20:57,635
Locked inside her DNA.

758
01:20:59,507 --> 01:21:03,251
So you want to trade him for her?
Why?

759
01:21:03,509 --> 01:21:06,867
Because I always
close my contracts.

760
01:21:07,083 --> 01:21:08,083
Fuck you.

761
01:21:10,253 --> 01:21:12,251
There's a helipad on the roof.

762
01:21:12,742 --> 01:21:14,629
Get him someplace secure.

763
01:22:21,046 --> 01:22:23,829
- Heading up to the Safe Room.
- I want all teams to Floor 40.

764
01:22:23,830 --> 01:22:25,271
That's not going to be enough, John.

765
01:22:38,533 --> 01:22:41,054
No. You stay with me,
protect me!

766
01:22:41,240 --> 01:22:42,912
So many choices.

767
01:22:43,313 --> 01:22:45,094
And only one right answer.

768
01:22:45,650 --> 01:22:47,313
What's it gonna be?

769
01:22:47,416 --> 01:22:50,035
Emotion or duty?

770
01:23:32,459 --> 01:23:34,289
It was too quick.
Fire Dept was here too quick.

771
01:23:34,292 --> 01:23:36,538
- Someone called them before the crash.
- What does that mean?

772
01:23:36,639 --> 01:23:38,862
It means he was never
in that helicopter.

773
01:23:46,206 --> 01:23:47,407
Get them out.

774
01:24:55,381 --> 01:24:56,862
What was your mistake?

775
01:24:56,964 --> 01:24:58,775
I don't make mistakes.

776
01:24:59,469 --> 01:25:04,155
You needed me to know
that you were better than me.

777
01:25:25,060 --> 01:25:26,224
Where is he?

778
01:25:29,661 --> 01:25:30,860
On the roof.

779
01:25:36,807 --> 01:25:39,432
When this is done, I will kill you.

780
01:28:05,639 --> 01:28:07,994
Your mother would be proud of you.

781
01:28:08,478 --> 01:28:09,479
What?

782
01:28:11,793 --> 01:28:12,793
Nothing.

783
01:28:13,295 --> 01:28:15,582
I doubt you'd understand.

784
01:28:16,487 --> 01:28:17,546
Doesn't matter.

785
01:28:17,748 --> 01:28:19,440
We'll find her.

786
01:28:19,640 --> 01:28:21,418
I believe you will.

787
01:29:09,503 --> 01:29:11,633
Confirm target termination.

788
01:29:11,722 --> 01:29:12,815
Target...

789
01:29:13,117 --> 01:29:15,669
Le Clerq, Antoine...

790
01:29:15,945 --> 01:29:17,657
terminated.

791
01:29:17,872 --> 01:29:19,351
And the other?

792
01:29:20,919 --> 01:29:22,706
Second target?

793
01:29:26,599 --> 01:29:27,600
47?

794
01:29:28,302 --> 01:29:29,574
47!

795
01:29:30,742 --> 01:29:32,634
Second target?.

796
01:29:37,054 --> 01:29:38,474
Le Clerq.

797
01:29:38,926 --> 01:29:41,257
He was your target the whole time?

798
01:29:42,454 --> 01:29:46,108
Everything that you told me,
was you'd have a diversion?

799
01:29:46,533 --> 01:29:47,731
It was necessary.

800
01:29:47,732 --> 01:29:49,667
What? to kill a single man?

801
01:29:49,973 --> 01:29:50,973
No.

802
01:29:51,954 --> 01:29:55,640
To put a stop to the Agent Program,
once and for all.

803
01:29:57,477 --> 01:29:59,103
And to set you free.

804
01:30:01,506 --> 01:30:03,293
Your father loved you, Katia.

805
01:30:04,111 --> 01:30:08,552
He understood that LeClerk would not
rest once he knew who you were.

806
01:30:09,730 --> 01:30:11,613
That he would hunt you down.

807
01:30:13,115 --> 01:30:16,003
So he did what any parent would.

808
01:30:17,096 --> 01:30:18,901
He died to save his children.

809
01:30:27,187 --> 01:30:29,148
This is your mission, isn't it?

810
01:30:35,143 --> 01:30:37,742
We determine who we are,
by what we do.

811
01:30:46,192 --> 01:30:49,167
There is a building full of
highly-trained operatives...

812
01:30:49,169 --> 01:30:51,604
who will be on their way up here now.

813
01:30:52,349 --> 01:30:53,549
You're wrong..

814
01:30:53,664 --> 01:30:54,954
There's just one.

815
01:31:11,894 --> 01:31:13,659
Diana says Hello.

