Whoo!
Yeah!
Sync & corrected by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
The waltz was revolutionary
in the late 18th century
because it was the first time
couples faced each other
when they danced.
It was a scandalous display
of public intimacy.
Public intimacy--
I like it.
Count!
One, two, three.
He's stepping on me.
- That's not true.
- You just keep
putting your feet underneath
mine when I lift them.
You know where I'm gonna put my foot?
Why are we doing this?
Because you need to face each
other and try to work together.
We do work together.
Yes, not always harmoniously.
Couldn't we do something like
synchronized swimming instead?
Deeks.
What?
It's just like this,
except for you would be in a bikini.
Ouch!
Sorry.
I was thinking about bikinis.
I'm listening!
Ready?
One, two, three.
Posture, grace,
floating as one.
It's kind of hard to float
when you're in heels. Ow.
Think of your partner.
Well, it's kind of hard
when all she keeps talking about
is high heels and bikinis.
Maybe Kensi should lead.
Isn't that what she's doing?
Really?
I would love to teach the two of you
the traditional Viennese waltz,
with each other as partners.
She's kidding.
No, she's not.
Agent Hanna,
take your partner by the waist,
back straight.
Do I need to repeat myself?
Hetty, you...
Hetty.
Sorry, guys, but approval's
just come in, Hetty.
NCIS has been granted
permission to enter Mexico.
Well, you'll be briefed en route.
Grab your go bags.
Wheels up in 20 minutes.
And make sure to return
the heels, Ms. Blye.
You guys owe me big-time.
Anything you need.
Anytime you need it.
Señor Hector Ramirez.
I.D. matches.
Seaman Brandon Davis.
He was reported for
unauthorized absence
from the USS Enterprise six weeks ago
when the carrier was stationed
off the coast of Sudan.
Hmm.
He's a long way from North Africa.
Huh.
What makes this guy so special?
The company he keeps.
You know him?
Paul Green.
He's a British arms dealer.
Sells to Al-Qaeda,
Hamas, Hezbollah.
Motorcycle tracks come from the South.
Looks like they lead north
to the U.S. border.
We're looking for a wooden box
roughly foot-and-a-half long,
a foot wide,
about six inches high.
No.
Box is long gone.
Drag marks.
Something heavy.
Case of handguns isn't worth
dragging across the desert.
Got a shell casing.
Choke marks.
Green's got them, too.
Okay, so one bike goes down.
Green and Davis fight over
who's gonna be left behind.
More like who's gonna keep the box.
Davis wins, then somebody
shoots him from over there.
It's got to be over 400 meters away.
7.62 caliber.
Shooter's no knucklehead.
He knows what he's doing.
These ATV tracks--
they lead north, too.
To the U.S. border.
Okay, so what's this all about?
Whatever's inside that box.
Border's four miles away.
Whatever's inside that box
is already inside the country.
You two follow the
shooter's ATV tracks.
Gracias.
Okay, you know how
I don't do well over 100 degrees.
I get xerosis.
Deeks, that sounds like an STD.
No, no, not an STD.
It's dry and scaly skin.
Like a lizard.
Lizards love the desert.
You don't have any sunscreen, do you?
Preferably something with, like,
a moisturizer, hypo-allergenic.
I can't believe he's gone.
We were high school sweethearts.
How long were you married to Brandon?
Three years.
Had you heard from
him since he went UA?
No.
I told the MPs this
a hundred times already.
I'm not believing it.
Because he went UA,
I don't even get his pay now.
Karen, Brandon's body
was found with an arms dealer
affiliated with several
terrorist organizations.
We think they
were trying to smuggle
something into the country.
It's a matter
of national security.
You don't need
to protect him anymore.
Unless you're involved.
I wasn't involved.
But you do know something.
Somebody was paying Brandon
to take a box from Sudan
across the ocean on a cargo ship
into Guatemala and up here.
He said it was like
private security work.
If you're sneaking across the
border, it's not security work.
We had no money.
And... I'm pregnant again.
So, he said
we'd never have to work
another day in our lives.
For bringing one box into the country?
He said he wanted me
to be ready to leave town
and not tell anybody
where I was going.
Knowing Brandon,
I think he was going to steal the box
when he crossed the border.
Do you know what was in it?
Everything we'd ever want.
All our dreams.
You want to share?
The box was filled with gold.
My cop instincts are
definitely kicking in.
Yeah, what are they telling you?
Something isn't right.
Wait a second.
Why'd they stop following us?
Is it 'cause of the wolves?
Yeah? Are there
wolves out here?
Awesome.
Ever heard of the Chupacabra?
Yes.
Body of a bear,
the spine of a stegosaurus,
claws like an eagle, lives in
the desert, eats tourists?
You are Shaggy
from Scooby-Doo.
No, no, they call this
the Devil's Path.
This area is so dangerous,
the Mexican police
don't even come here.
Okay, this area, Deeks,
is the United States of America.
What? We're in America?
Yes! That's why
they stopped following us.
The border's right back there.
Oh, well, that's fantastic news.
Oh, no!
It's a wild boar. Shh!
Think it's a feral pig.
No, no, no, don't look at it directly.
Show submission.
Just walk away very quietly.
Whoa, what the hell?
Whoa.
It's following you.
What does he want?
I think she's in love with you.
Oh. Well, of course she is.
You want to know why?
Because she has fantastic taste.
Here, pretty girl.
Huh? What's your name?
You come to the desert often?
I bet you do.
You keep it toned?
You look good.
Hey, Deeks.
Think I found something.
All right, you stay here.
Don't go changing.
I got cop work.
What do you got?
ATV tracks stop here,
but the truck tracks start there.
There could have been
a ramp right here.
Looks like he put the ATV in
the back of a pickup truck
and headed north to the highway.
Hang on, baby.
¿Señor Deeks, cómo está?
Eric, I'm sending some pics
to my skydrive.
Bueno.
See if you can I.D. the tracks.
All right, pork chop, can you describe
the bad guys in the truck?
Can you describe them?
Uh-huh. And what about the other one?
Ah, Kensi, I-I think,
I think she saw one of them.
All right, got a match.
BF Goodrich 245/75R17.
Comes standard
on six different trucks.
But only one with dual rear wheels.
Ford F-350.
Eric, also take a look at the tapes
from the cameras on Interstate 8.
It's the first highway north of here.
And go back about 24 hours.
Will do.
Thanks.
You going to put lipstick on that pig?
Don't you listen to her.
She's just jealous.
Don't make promises you can't keep.
I'll see you soon.
You're beautiful.
I'll miss you.
See, I know how
to let a girl down easy.
With respect and honesty.
Yeah, you change your
cell phone number.
That's why I don't give them
my home address.
Aha.
That's why she likes you.
Why is that?
Same species.
You get the ballistics report
on the round taken
from the dead seaman?
Coming in now.
The ammo was a custom load.
Shooter's a pro.
Somebody knew the box
was coming across the border,
sent the shooter
to kill the two couriers.
And take the gold.
Nell, how much gold
are we talking about?
Well, from the cell phone video,
the box was roughly nine
by 16 inches, six inches tall.
That would make it about 300 pounds,
for a value of...
Looks like someone
has a secret admirer.
Uh, we're somewhere in the ballpark
of eight-and-a-half
million dollars.
Whoa.
Arms dealer?
Bringing it in to buy more weapons?
Or it could be a payment from a sale.
Why take a chance with all that money,
taking it across open desert?
So, working off the
estimated time of death
of seaman Davis, there's only
one Ford F-350 with dual wheels
heading west on Interstate 8.
I traced the license plate
to an auto repair shop
in east L.A.,
and according to L.A...
Nice flowers.
Eric.
Sorry.
Uh, according to LAPD, um, the shop
is owned and operated
by members of the La Masa
Mexican drug cartel.
Address is on your phones.
Thanks, Eric.
Happy Birthday.
Not my birthday.
I actually knew that.
Uh, so the flowers are for...?
No occasion.
So somebody sent you flowers
just because.
Uh-huh.
So somebody did send them.
No, they just grew there.
Why are you so surprised
that somebody would send me flowers?
I'm actually not surprised.
At all.
Shooter's truck.
License matches.
What do you guys want?
Federal agents.
We got a couple questions
about that truck.
We can't answer any questions.
You got a carry permit for that?
Yes, I do.
You just answered a question.
You answer questions very well.
You shouldn't underestimate yourself.
So why don't you give us
the key to that truck,
or we can all wait
around here for a warrant.
If that happens, who knows
what else we'll find here?
I'm pretty sure
you know the drill.
One phone call-- hour
and a half, tops.
It's all done electronically now.
You'll have a dozen agents
crawling all over this place.
Well, you do what you got to do.
But I'm asking you to leave...
Now.
They got drugs or cash
on this property,
and they're not going to
want to lose it to a search.
Guess they're not going
to let us drive out of here.
You got them?
Yeah, I got them.
You okay?
Yeah.
You?
- Excuse me.
- Little help here.
Hi.
What's your name?
Jaime.
I don't got a gun.
You okay?
I'm great.
I just can't breathe.
You don't realize how heavy
a car is until you're under it, huh?
Yeah, I guess not.
Clear?
Yeah.
Come on.
You good?
Yeah.
You guys know
I wasn't shooting at you, right?
For that, we thank you.
Can we ask you a question?
I'm not supposed to talk to cops.
Well, don't think of us as cops.
Think of us as the guys
who just saved your life.
Means you owe us, Jaime.
Who owns that red truck?
My boss.
Where's he?
Been in Mexico for the last week.
Did you maybe lend that truck
to someone, say,
day before yesterday?
Come on, guys.
Do you have any idea
how horrible it would have been
to be crushed under this truck?
Your insides would
have squirted out like
a broken toothpaste tube.
Who'd you lend the truck to?
My boss was hired by somebody--
I don't know who--
to steal some box.
So he sent his guy.
Name?
Hey, you got to understand,
nobody trusts me
with important information.
And that's their mistake.
They're clearly not a
good judge of character.
Your boss sent his guy who...?
He does the, you know, the...
hits for him?
Yeah.
So one might call him a hit man?
He went down to the border
to kill these two guys
and take the box in exchange
for half of the contents.
Thank you, Jaime.
Now we have to cuff you.
With handcuffs?
Uh, most likely.
I still owe you guys?
Jaime, we saved your life.
That's a big debt to pay.
Where did your boss hide the gold?
Gold? What gold?
From the box.
There's no gold in the box.
You remember what was in it?
Of course I do.
I'm not stupid.
We don't think you're stupid.
Jaime,
we're your biggest fans.
Now, what was in the box?
Brown heroin.
We're a drug cartel, homes.
Damn, you guys don't know nothing!
I guess we don't.
So he does hits for the cartel.
Picks up the car for the job
and then he drops it back
with you at the garage.
Yeah. I only saw the guy
maybe four times.
What's he look like?
He looks full-on Indian.
But I heard he was part Mexican.
If he wasn't part Mexican,
he don't work for us.
Are we even yet?
Close.
Is there anything else
you can tell me about him?
Anything at all?
Slick, dresses nice,
makes very good money killing people.
There's always work
when you got skills.
Truth.
Jaime, I don't want
you to hurt yourself,
but I want you to try
really hard to think about
what he looked like.
He wore red cowboy boots.
And he had these
badass wristbands with
a monkey on it, held bullets.
Eric, there's a shop
called red monkey;
they do leather work for bikers
and rock stars.
You should check it out.
Very low-level
encryption.
Give me a minute to break it.
And logo's coming
to your phone.
That's it.
Badass, right?
Badass as Matthew Broderick.
Who's Matthew Broderick?
A badass.
I'm in.
Looking at the Internet
sales orders for red monkey.
Looks like the wrist bandoleros
were custom orders.
Hmm.
They only made three.
One went to Florida,
the other to Europe...
And wouldn't you know it, one
has an address in downtown L.A.
Coming to your phones.
You know what, Jaime,
I think we're even.
My debt for you
saving my life is paid?
Yep.
Oh, that's great.
'Cause I don't think
I know anything else.
About anything.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Thanks.
It's been real.
Yeah.
Hey, you guys are cool.
So are you.
Huh.
Hey, guys!
Little help here!
So you in a thing now?
Like, uh, with another person.
Like, a relationsh...
Don't say the r word.
I don't have to be in a...
In a R word.
...To get flowers.
No. No, of course not.
You could-- I mean,
you could get flowers
for a lot of other reasons.
A lot of other reasons.
Like if I was...
Like if you... die.
There you go.
Mm-hmm. Or if you
have major surgery.
There's another one.
Have you had major surgery?
I have not.
And you are clearly not dead.
Well...
So that, uh, leaves the "R" word.
Uh-huh.
I have to go talk to Hetty.
Wow.
- Penthouse.
- Somebody's getting paid.
Yeah. Look at this place.
Federal agents!
I got a body.
Bedroom's clear.
- Clear.
He's dead.
Slightly warm.
Red cowboy boots, wristbands.
No obvious cause of death.
Anybody else noticing
a reoccurring motif
in all these paintings?
Rifle's a 7.62 caliber.
High-powered scope.
Probably the weapon
that killed Brandon Davis.
He's got some kind of powder
around his nose.
We got powder here, too.
Looks like he might've
taken a taste and died happy.
Eric.
Eric!
Comms are down--
too much steel.
What's up, G?
Where is the box?
Couple hundred pounds--
that's like moving a safe.
That's not exactly
a one-man job.
Uh...
Somebody used a dolly.
Indents lead straight out the door.
Let's check the building
security cameras.
That's our box.
It's the same floor as the shooter.
I recognize that.
What?
Can you zoom in on his face?
On this guy.
Sudanese tribal scars.
So someone from Sudan
pays Davis and Green to
bring a box into the U.S.
They think it's gold.
Then somebody pays a Mexican drug gang
to steal it
because it's really heroin.
But then the Sudanese
steal the box back.
Something's still missing here.
Is this a live feed?
Yeah.
He's working the lock.
Could be one of the Sudanese.
Maybe they're coming back.
Maybe they forgot something
in the apartment.
Kensi, Deeks.
Comms are still down.
Hey, Sam?
Kensi, you've got company.
Kensi...
Hang up.
Please, don't make a sound.
Are you digging the art
in this place as much as I am?
I mean, it's bold, and it's cool.
I mean, why isn't there
more cool art, you know?
Oh, there's another one.
I want to show you this one.
This is my favorite
'cause it's the perfect
combination of girls and guns.
Let me make this perfectly clear:
If you harm her,
this is going to be
your last day on earth.
Who are you?
Federal agents.
Drop your weapon.
Agent Sam Hanna.
Turn around,
slowly.
Michael.
So this is Michael Saleh?
Nice to finally meet you.
And you, too,
agent G. Callen.
You know what this is?
This is warm and cuddly,
but we're forgetting he nearly
just killed my partner.
Meet CIA operations officer
Michael Saleh.
Wish I could say it was a pleasure.
Sorry about that.
Wait, and you guys
know each other how?
Michael and I have been working
undercover in Sudan
on the CIA task force for over a year.
Over a year?
Oh, so that's what those
long-weekend dive trips were.
When you went to Cancun
with my SEAL buddies.
It actually makes me feel
a lot better,
knowing why I wasn't invited.
That's not why you weren't invited.
Uh, uh, don't speak 'cause right now
I'm feeling really good
about our friendship.
So... this is Deeks?
- What?
- Yeah, yeah, this is...
Wait, what did he tell you about me?
Nothing.
No, come on.
Well, he once mentioned something
about falling in the canal in Venice.
The cana...the canal. That was...
You remember that.
That was a good time.
Yeah.
Phew.
Good time.
I've been tracking this box
since it left the Sudan,
into Guatemala and into Mexico.
They kill him?
My guess is, he snorted the heroin.
He snorted it?
There was no heroin in that box.
So, what was in it, then?
He died from radiation poisoning.
The box wasn't filled
with gold or heroin.
The box was filled with uranium.
Sudan contains the third-largest
supply of uranium in the world.
The uranium ore was shipped from Sudan
to Iran, and returned to the
Sudan in a highly refined state.
Looks like powder-- that's why
the shooter snorted it.
So Al-Qaeda hired others
to transport
the uranium-filled box
because constant exposure
to the uranium will kill you.
Everybody that gets close to it dies?
No, they were carrying it close
to their bodies for weeks;
short-term exposures
won't hurt you.
Everybody was told there was
something else in the box.
Their greed motivating them
down the garden path.
You recognize any of these guys
from the elevator surveillance tape?
They stole the box
from the shooter's apartment.
No. They don't look like
any known Al-Qaeda operatives
from the Sudan.
They could've come
to the U.S. years ago.
They may have green cards
and citizenship by now.
So, what are we looking at here,
a dirty bomb?
From the residue on the table
I don't think so.
The powder was too fine,
the dispersal pattern would be small.
Then what's it for?
Oh, look at that.
Oh, yeah. A little-little gift.
Hmm.
Did you have a surgical
procedure in the last hour?
Uh, no.
And I am not dead,
in case you were wondering.
See, 'cause that's funny
that we both got flowers
on the same day.
It's odd, isn't it?
It's a real coincidence.
It's weird.
It's very weird.
Mm-hmm.
You might say.
Okay, I sent the flowers to myself.
Oh.
I really like flowers,
and no one has sent them
to me in a long time,
so I sent them to myself.
That's great.
Why is that great?
No, it's not great.
It's, um...
It's sad... it's sad that you
sent them to yourself.
Like you did?
I...
I didn't send anything to my...
I don't...
Okay.
Okay...
I gave the flower to myself.
I'm shocked.
I mean, I know why I sent
the flowers to myself,
so... what's your excuse?
When I saw that someone else
had given you flowers, I...
I-I felt...
Um...
Competitive?
Competitive.
I felt competitive.
Competitive with you.
That's a good word for it.
So, I took the flower
from Hetty's desk.
You took a flower from Hetty's desk.
Yeah.
She cuts them herself.
It's a big bunch.
Hetty will never miss it.
Hm-hmm.
I'm doomed, aren't I?
You sacrificed yourself
to compete with me.
Facial-recognition
got a hit on one of the guys
from the elevator.
He's got a Sudanese passport.
Samir Abbas.
I have a home address
and work address.
Currently working at Anderson & Kirk's
Technical Services.
So, what's going on?
I'm pretty sure my cover
in the Sudan was compromised.
How?
There may be a leak inside the agency.
Any idea who?
I don't know.
You're not CIA...
I believe your cover is still safe.
But I can't go back to the Sudan.
Of course not.
It means
when you return,
you're going to be on your own there.
Sorry.
I think it may be time for me
to get out of the field anyway.
I'm sure your wife
would appreciate it.
Oh, more than you know.
Oh, believe me, I know.
Eric found one of them.
Kensi, Deeks, take the back.
Federal agents.
We're looking for this man--
Samir Abbas.
He works here.
I got him.
Federal agents! Freeze!
Both hands where I can see them.
Both hands!
Clear.
Ah, that was noisy.
It's the uranium.
There should be a lot more than this.
Where's the rest?
What is this place?
What do you do here?
We service large
air-conditioning systems.
They're building an RDD.
A what?
A radiation dispersal device.
The uranium has been processed to a fine powder.
They're gonna
put it in an air-conditioning
system somewhere.
Thousands of people could ingest it
before anyone even knew it was there.
It could render
buildings uninhabitable
for a millennia.
The CIA calls it
real estate acquisition.
It's 9/11 without knocking down
buildings.
There's still two guys
out there with the uranium.
The attacks are going down right now.
But where?
37 air-conditioning companies
that are big enough
to handle large structures.
2,500 employees.
Bringing up the company's ID photos.
Running facial-rec now.
Got one.
Oh, actually, I got two.
All right,
Saif Molla and Hafiz Hussein.
Chapman Point Heating and Air.
- Address?
- On your cell now.
I'm going to try to get into
the company's cameras,
see if I can find Hafiz Hussein
and Saif Molla.
Okay,
I'll check their work schedules.
Sam, according to the work schedule,
Saif Molla and Hafiz Hussein
are at work right now.
I cannot find Molla or Hussein
on any of the company's cameras.
I don't think they're there.
They're not there 'cause Molla
and Hussein have a work order.
Molla and Hussein
are not in the building.
They're out on a job site.
Where?
Looks like they're taking
some old units to be recycled.
That's clearly not the target.
It's going to be somewhere big,
somewhere public.
Okay, got the last one.
Jonathan Debaki,
Lamont Heating
and Air-Conditioning.
Got it.
That's him.
That's Debaki.
Federal agents!
Don't do it!
Freeze! Hands against the truck.
He's got the uranium.
Where were you going?
Huh? Where's the target?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Callen, Sam,
they're targeting
the convention center.
Get me LAPD-- they need
to evacuate the building.
LA Gamer Expo going on right now.
There's 30,000 people in there.
Remain calm
and please exit the building.
Eric, check the schematics
and get me to the AC system.
You need to get to the other
side of the main lobby.
Remain calm
and please exit the building.
Keep going straight ahead.
Remain calm
and please exit the building.
Go down the stairs
directly in front of you.
Halfway down the hallway,
there's a door on your left.
That leads to the maintenance area.
Federal agents! Freeze!
I got him!
Drop it.
I said drop it.
Praise Allah!
Sam, stay back!
Stay back.
We're going to get you to a hospital.
Eric, I need an ambulance and a
radiological decon team, fast.
Sam, it's in the air;
you shouldn't stay here.
There's no point, my friend.
There's no point. Go.
Please, Sam.
Stay here.
Federal agent!
Step out where I can see you!
Don't do it!
G.
Clear.
Where's Saleh?
I should've stayed with him.
I'm sorry.
Any idea where he went?
I picked him up on a camera
exiting the building, but...
then he disappeared.
How long does he have left?
Maybe a few months.
Depends on how much
uranium he's ingested.
Saleh is a trained CIA operative.
If he doesn't want us to find him...
Michael has a wife
and a seven-month-old baby.
He might've gone to be with them.
I just spoke with
a friend at the agency.
The CIA made sure
Saleh was decontaminated,
as best they could.
So where is he now?
He didn't want his wife
and child to watch him die,
so he's returned to Sudan
to continue his work with the CIA.
He thought he was compromised.
It's not safe for him there.
It doesn't matter anymore.
He's using
what little life he has left
to defend the United States.
Then I'm going there, too, Hetty.
Of course you are, Sam.
There's a gulfstream five
fueling and preparing
to take you to the naval air
station in Sigonella, Italy.
From there,
transport will be arranged
to take you to Sudan.
You know I should be with him.
For now, it's a CIA task force.
I don't have to tell you to be ready.
No, you don't.
Of course not.
Sync & corrected by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com