Pierrette was twenty-two that day
That's no age to die, people say,
as though there were a right age
Who could have done it?
No one, as usual
She probably fought back
A mistake; panicked, the man
killed her without meaning to...
... losing his head over a few francs
in her bag
They'll find the killer some day...
... but no one will hold her
in his arms again
...nine, ten, eleven, twelve...
See? You're all right now
Before I question you...
...tell me why people don't like you
They don't, it's true; but then,
I don't like them
That’s no reason
What did you do?
Nothing. I'm not very sociable,
and they don't like that
Conversations die away when I go by
I prefer silence, anyway
You're weird
See? You're just like the rest
of them
Pierrette Bourgeois was murdered
nearby
A taxi-driver saw a man
run towards this block...
...not very tall, in a dark overcoat.
Curious, eh?
She was a very lively girl, everyone
says so... Pierrette was always lively
She was so pretty when alive
I had to tell her fiancé
Life is horrible
I was just joking
Like you, she lived alone
Like you, she was unsociable...
...and never talked to anyone
She was weird
Has it got to you?
You're a real man when you kiss me...
I love it
Will you give me a child?
Several, if you like
Let's walk a bit; I've been
shut up all day
Listen, Alice...
Why didn't you fix things?
It's not my fault... I did speak
to my father about us
He'd like to meet you
- How about that job for me?
- Don't rush things
Be patient
You're important to me, you know
Don't treat me like this, Emile
Where’ve you been? Five minutes,
you said
Like a picture of me?
I've something to tell you, Alice
It came to me just now as I woke up...
I think it's serious
You'd better know the truth
Will you marry me? Yes, I want you
to be my wife
Don't knock yourself out
- What do you mean?
- You don't have to sweet talk me
- Don't you believe me?
- No, but I love you just the same
- You're weird
- Yes, I know
We'll try again
Begin, please
Was it him, or not?
It could be, but I'm not sure, sorry
I can go home, then?
Backwards!
Please blindfold me, Mademoiselle
Nine nights, is that right?
Don't worry, Paul; I always check
Some places I'm not hated
You have a record
Six months for indecent assault
That’s not going to help your case
Hire isn't your real name?
No, it's Hirovitch
My grandfather changed it
Tell me, how long is it since
you came inside a woman?
How old would she have been...
seventy, eighty?
She’d been around for ever
People loved her, this little old lady
who spent all her time...
...feeding the pigeons
Shut up!
Going from park to park, distributing
birdseed by the handful
All the park-keepers knew her
and were touched
A photographer wanted to market a
postcard of her surrounded by pigeons
She agreed
She became famous
One day it emerged... maybe she
left a note...
...that the birdseed was poisoned
For years, she’d been killing pigeons
Her neighbours didn't believe it,
she seemed so nice
Come on, you'll catch cold
Like someone else?
- Should I get Rosa?
- Not Rosa, not Jasmine, not anybody
I'm sick of screwing you sluts!
I don't need help, leave me alone
You needn't be afraid; I'm no hoodlum
I'm Monsieur Hire
I thought it was empty
I never use the lights
You can see everything
If you hadn’t moved that time,
I'd never have known
You took advantage
- All I did was look
- You frightened me that night
I thought you wanted to hurt me
Why would someone like you...
...spy on people that way?
I might have reported you
I might, you know
You might, but didn't
Why are you afraid of me?
You can't imagine how I've suffered
I lied; I didn't mind you watching me
It's nice
With someone else, it wouldn't be
But you're sweet
How can you say that?
You don't know me
Sit by me and let's talk
Don't you want to?
- Have you been watching me for long?
- Yes, every night
When I go to bed, what do you do?
Nothing. I wait
- What for?
- I don't know. I sleep very little
So you watch all the time?
You know all about me?
Not all, certainly, but some things
What’s your favourite moment?
When I undress, or...
- Go now, don't stay here
- I'm sorry, I thought...
Get the hell out!
That’s more like it...
but not so sharp
It's a quieter, more rarefied scent
Waiter, the same again, please
- Drinking makes you look lovely
- lf I look lovely, then kiss me
Do you still want to marry me?
- How about tomorrow morning?
- What’s all your hurry?
I'm serious; marry me right away
I knew you didn't mean it before
Say something
The cops called
We swore not to talk about that
They know nothing
No one saw me
We won't mention it again;
I had to tell you
Don't worry, we'll be together
You're so beautiful
I love you enough for both of us
I brought back your scarf
- Why not pick it up? It's yours
- Why mine?
It seems very you
Yours would be cleaner, of course
Those stains are Pierrette's blood
Your neighbours said it was yours
I do have one like it
In that case, show it to me
Certainly
New, isn't it?
I rarely wear it; it's so dreary
New, in effect
Anything else? Good night, then
A note's under the mat
She’s gorgeous...
...and no fool, either
I'm so sorry...
...about what happened the other day
I know neither of us means the other
any harm
Will you lunch with me on Sunday?
Just the two of us together. Alice
Don't you ever tidy up?
- What are you doing here?
- We had a date this afternoon
Sorry, I had a late night;
what time is it?
Midday, but I've to meet my aunt
instead
I thought I'd be nice and warn you
I miss not seeing you, so as I've
half-an-hour to spare, here I am
You smell nice
Sorry, I'm a bit late
- Have you been waiting long?
- No. I'm so glad you came
You're not cross with me?
My nerve almost failed me
when I left the note
I find that hard to believe.
Shall we eat?
I love stations. Especially this one...
...watching, imagining...
That man who’s early, filling in time...
...the old lady looking for her train...
...the young woman meeting her lover...
...or maybe walking out on him...
Young women can be so unpredictable
I love watching people
- I'm sorry, that was tactless
- It's all right
I often come here alone. This is nicer
In Lausanne, you know it's spring...
...when people set about repainting
their shutters
They like life to be beautiful
- Do you know Lausanne?
- I've never been abroad
I arrived a few months ago,
a country girl
An old aunt met me at this station
She put me on the right suburban train
The woman I work for at the dairy
collected me
That’s all I've seen of Paris
Emile doesn't take me anywhere.
He's my fiancé
- I know
- You know him?
I know of him
I've seen him... he's often at
your place
You're right, stations are wonderful...
I know pretty much everything
about you
I have a house in Lausanne, not large
but nice, and I own it
I don't use it, not at present
Some day, I'll move there...
...and won't come back
- Why are you laughing?
- I almost didn't come today
I thought we'd have nothing to say...
...but there’s so much
I want to show you something
Just look through it; you'll see my
apartment. I've been there ten years
I'd rather you kept this
- Does Emile know about me?
- No, and he’s not going to
- How can you love that boy?
- I don't know... he’s my fiancé
I don't want to talk about it;
let's just enjoy being together
It's too late for that
Why go on play-acting?
We both know you're not here
for my company
You're intelligent, Alice
Don't say you don't understand
Or do you just not want to?
I'm cold. Won't you take me
in your arms...
...love me a little?
- Could you love two men?
- Why not?
You'd go to any lengths, then?
Kiss me, please say you will
You're so sweet to me...
I can't believe how sweet
All for the charming Emile's sake?
Was I watching that night...
...when he woke you...
...having just killed Pierrette...
...and you hid his bloody raincoat?
Yes, I was watching as usual...
...and I saw everything
Will you still be nice to me...
...still want to take me lovingly
in your arms...
...still let me watch you
as you undress?
Why don't you tell the police?
Because I can't
Some evenings, alone at home,
I find myself unable to stop crying
I've never told anyone this
At those times, I come here
Scents and smells all mingle
I never ask for a particular girl,
perhaps to avoid becoming involved
I sit here, close my eyes and wait
When the girl comes in, I can tell
who it is by her scent
My eyes remain shut
She is close, and gently starts
to undress me
She is naked, with just a towel
around her waist
Sometimes, her breasts lightly brush
my back...
...a furtive sensation I adore...
...the skin so silken
I never know where her lips
will caress me
Then, as my desire mounts...
...she lies beside me,
unknotting the towel...
...and offers herself to me,
legs slightly parted
But that’s over
These women find no favour with me now
Why tell me this?
I happened to see you,
and it's all changed
Soon, I couldn't tear my eyes
from your window
I no longer frequent those women...
...because I'm in love with you
I love you, Alice
That’s why I'll say nothing
to the police
I'd have denounced Emile, but for you
But it was an accident...
Legally, you're an accessory,
and I couldn't bear to lose you
I love you too much
You mustn't love me...
you can't, it's impossible
Don't worry, everything’s going to be
all right, you'll see
- It's late, I'll see you home
- No, I'll go alone
As you wish, Alice
Let me go, there are cops everywhere!
I'll hide with François
- What about us?
- Forget it
- You can't leave me
- Can't you see the mess I'm in?
I hate you
Come on, they’re after you!
- You promised me
- You're well out of this
- I'd have followed you anywhere
- You mustn't, Alice
What are you waiting for?
Remember, I love you
I see only one solution.
Will you go away with me?
He isn't worthy of you
I can make you forget him
I'll be patient if you love him
more at first
You will learn to love me in time;
I won't rush you
You can trust me to protect you
No one will ever love you as I do
I'll devote my life to
making you smile again
I love you so much
I'm a man of my word, Alice
I'll never desert you
Here's your ticket
The train leaves at 7.12
I'll wait at the station
- Where did they go?
- Pardon?
Stop putting on your act;
I'm sick of it
Why go on refusing to talk?
Don't you realize it'll be
pinned on you?
Oh hell, why should I care what
happens to a poor fool like you?
I was sure it wasn't you,
but I was wrong
But for her...
...I'd never have known
Cleaning your flat, she found
Pierrette's bag
Hidden in a cupboard
Not very clever... was it,
Mademoiselle?
It's just shock, Monsieur Hire
She didn't see you as a killer
Nor did I, but that’s always the way
The question I must ask is: Do you
admit to having hidden this bag?
Well, Monsieur Hire...
...yes or no?
You'll think me a fool, Alice,
but I don't feel any anger...
...just a deathly sadness
But never mind
You gave me my greatest joy
This isn't funny any more
Bring your case
Dear Inspector
When you read this...
... Alice and I will be far away
You'll find in the locker the raincoat
Emile wore when he killed Pierrette...
... picked up and hidden by me when
he threw it away that night
Technically an accessory,
Alice had nothing to do with it
To protect her innocence,
I'm taking her away
Please don't try to find us
We are happy together...
...and nothing else matters
Monsieur Hire