- Good afternoon, miss.
- Good afternoon.
- Is that it?
- That's it right enough, miss.
Granny calls it the devil's work.
Well, I can't say I've ever heard it called that before.
Stand back, now.
Did you know, if you touch it,
your hair stands on end?
You are not going anywhere near it,
young lady.
(BELL RINGS)
Come on.
Is it true you've been sacked, sir?
No, it's not true, Fenton.
Tuck that shirt in, please.
So why are you leaving
before the end of term, sir?
That is for me and the headmaster to know
and for you to wonder at, Smith.
- Well, there's definitely no more Greek.
- Correct, Johnson, there is no more Greek.
The headmaster, in his wisdom,
has decided there are more useful subjects.
Come on, hurry up, all of you.
Classes start in one minute.
(GRUNTING)
- Where would you like it, Mrs Spence?
- Where do people usually put it?
- It would normally go in the sitting room.
- That's not entirely helpful in a house like this.
What do you think, library, drawing room,
morning room, stamp room, old parlour?
Let's put it in the drawing room for now.
This way.
Is it easy to work?
I would suggest that I discuss
the technical details with Mr Spence.
He's in London.
Besides, my brother-in-law can barely boil a kettle.
I don't think he'll be much use.
(KNOCKING)
Do you need any help, sir?
No, thank you, Seaton.
I think I can manage. Run along.
I'm glad there are no hard feelings,
John.
It was a difficult decision,
but Major Hulton has a young family.
Yes, of course, Headmaster, and French conversation
is a more practical subject for the boys.
I see that.
- Is that all you're taking?
- It's all I need.
- So, a walking tour?
- Yes. Thought I'd see a bit of the world, what's left of it.
- I've always wanted to visit...
- Quite.
- The romance of the road and all that.
- Yes.
Are you sure I can't
call you a taxi?
Er...no. Thank you. I thought I'd start
as I mean to go on. My train isn't till six.
- Mmm. Well...
- Ah. Au revoir.
Sync, corrected by icephoenix
www.addic7ed.com
(LAUGHTER)
Excuse me...
'Scuse me. Could I...
Here's your change, sir,
and your room's ready whenever you are.
I... I... I don't think this is...
Hello?
Bloody hell...
You're not the devil by any chance,
are you?
No.
But I think this might be
your change.
Thank you.
Come into the light,
where I can get a proper look at you.
The landlord thought that I...
Well, you can hardly blame
the poor chap.
That is incredible, don't you think?
I mean, who the hell are you?
Er...John. John Standing.
Who are you?
Er... Johnny Spence.
Pleased to meet...
No, completely astonished to meet you.
You got time for a quick one?
Come on, my shout.
We'll probably discover we've got
dozens of cousins in common.
- Do you have many cousins?
- No, not really.
I have a herd of them. Don't get on
with a single one. Scroungers, the lot.
- Thank you. That's for you.
- Thank you, Mr Spence.
This should keep us going.
You're not rich by any chance,
are you?
Er... no, not at all.
I was in a brothel once in Paris.
Had a set of twins that cost 1,000 francs an hour.
I don't think we're quite in that league yet. Circus,
maybe, cabaret. What do you think? Cheers, anyway.
- So, where are you from?
- Wales.
Mmm...
- Father?
- Dead now. Worked down the mines all his life.
Oh, you don't sound like a Taff.
My dad wanted me to go to university.
It was his dream.
I went up before the war,
got my degree
and came back talking like a bishop,
as he used to say.
Well, then, we're definitely not related.
I can't remember passing an exam in my life.
- Smoke?
- Thank you.
- So, what about family? Married?
- No. No, I'm not.
You must have some relations?
- Just a maiden aunt in Fishguard.
- Mmm.
- You lucky dog.
- You haven't met her.
What I wouldn't give to be in your position.
To your freedom. Long may it last.
- Is there enough?
- There's plenty.
But there's still no word from him?
- No.
- Something's happened. I know it.
This'll stop you worrying.
- Mrs Paul thinks that he's missed the train.
- Oh, what would she know?
Nobody in this house
understands my son except me.
Johnny doesn't like to fail.
They're happy about the booze...
as long as we drink out of these.
I've spoken to the kitchen. Ordered two large steaks,
very well done, mashed potato and gravy.
- Cheers.
Mmm... So, a walking tour?
- The open road is your oyster and all that?
- Yes. I have a few ideas. How about you?
Oh, a funk, a complete funk.
Had a bugger of a day in town.
I was on the train on the way back,
and I thought,
"What the hell am I doing, going home like
a lamb to the slaughter?" so off I got.
Here I am.
What about your family?
Won't they be worried?
About me? Never.
About themselves, definitely.
Waiter! More of your delicious tea.
No, greed.
That's what makes the world go round.
Men, women, children... Whatever you do,
it's never enough, is it? No-one's ever satisfied.
- It doesn't take much to satisfy me.
- Well, you're lucky. The world's your playground.
Mine hangs round my neck
like a rope.
Ignore me. It's not every day you get to talk to
yourself without being carted off to the funny farm.
I'm actually rather enjoying it.
I'll do this.
- It is extraordinary, us meeting like this, isn't it?
- Yes, I suppose it is.
Don't you think there's something
special about now,
this moment between the death of one monarch
and the coronation of the next?
- What do you mean?
- Anything's possible.
The throne's empty.
No-one's in charge.
- To anarchy.
(GASPS)
- Is that Daddy's plate?
- I hardly touched it.
He'll be cross with you.
(SIGHS)
I know.
Give me the pieces
and I'll tell him it was me.
Then he'll be cross with you.
I think there's a place in town
where we can get it mended,
then he'll never know at all.
Of course Plato believed that
every man was split in half
by Zeus so he couldn't
compete with the gods,
which means everyone has
a twin somewhere in the world.
It's just a question of looking for them.
- You're not a professor, are you?
- Teacher. Er... ex-teacher.
Oh, what time is it?
I have to go to the station.
We've got plenty of time. Anyway, all your things
are at the pub. We left them there.
- Sir! Your coats, sir!
- Oh, yes. Well done.
Thank you. That's mine.
That's his.
- I can't wear this.
- Of course you can.
I haven't worn one of these
since I was ten.
Look at that, perfect fit.
Could have been made for you.
What was that you said
about the gods?
When they keep us apart, we're nothing,
but together, we can rule the world.
(WHISTLE BLOWS)
(CYCLE BELL)
(DOOR OPENS)
- Well, what's the verdict?
- There isn't one.
- What do you mean?
- Exactly that. We haven't heard. He's disappeared.
He checked out of his club in London
yesterday morning.
He was booked on the 12:15. George met the train.
He wasn't on it or the next three.
And he didn't telephone the house?
If we're to keep to the plan,
I should issue notices this morning.
- It's going to be a hell of a business.
- Yes, I know that, Arthur!
But now we just have to wait.
I can't give the authorisation without him.
You know what my brother's like.
(GROANS)
It's ridiculous, this rule about not
having a fire in the morning.
Why economise on wood
when we live in a forest?
Perhaps you'd have a word
with Charlotte?
And have her give me one of her looks?
No thank you.
Anyway, it's your responsibility.
- I've had some fresh toast made for you, Miss Spence.
- Thank you, Charlotte.
Mr Spence has just telephoned from a
public house in Peterborough.
- What's he doing there?
- It's a bit early, even for Johnny.
He had to stay the night there.
He was feeling indisposed.
Did he say anything
about the contract?
No.
Will that be all, Mrs Spence?
Er... yes, Charlotte. Thank you.
He won't be back for hours now.
Inconsiderate bastard.
(KNOCK AT THE DOOR)
Who is... Who is it?
It's me, sir. George.
Oh, my God...
I'm... I'm sorry, who is it?
Could you please open the door, sir?
It's locked.
Perhaps you might consider
unlocking it, sir.
No, it...
(THUD)
Um... I...
- I think you must have the wrong room.
- We'll have you out of here in a jiffy, sir.
- Let me help you get dressed.
- What?
No thank you.
I'm quite capable of dressing myself.
Please? I'll be quite all right.
- Shall I get you some coffee, then, sir?
- No.
I'm so sorry. That was um... That was very rude.
I just need to find my things.
I understand, sir.
- I'm sorry. Someone seems to have stolen my clothes.
- I made you one of my specials.
- Right, um... I think I should...
- Back in one, sir. Always the best way.
(GASPS)
That's very good.
What is it... was it?
- Vodka mainly, sir. Just how you like it.
- Thank you.
You should get the landlord up here.
I need to sort this out.
Don't worry, sir. I've had a word,
and his discretion is assured.
Fine. I'll do it myself.
Ah, just the man. Look... The fellow
I met last night has run off with all my things.
- I can't find my wallet...
- Don't worry, sir.
You settled everything
very generously last night.
No, no.
The man who paid last night wasn't me.
- I mean, we swapped coats, but...
- Don't upset yourself, Mr Spence.
I'm... I'm not upset,
and I'm not Mr Spence.
- I'll just put your things in the car, Mr Spence.
- No!
Er... put them wherever you want.
They're not my things.
Wait here.
Look, I'm not who you think I am.
Look, you can ask me any question you want.
I wouldn't know the answer.
I don't even know who you are.
Don't...
My God...
That's a Silver Wraith.
That's incredible.
Four-speed transmission,
coachwork by Hooper. Am I right?
It's beautiful.
Are you intending to drive, sir?
- Could I?
- Of course.
If you want to.
(METAL GRINDING)
Oh, my God! I'm...
I'm so sorry! I didn't...
Perhaps it would be better
if I drove, sir.
I'm... I did... I didn't see...
Oh, my Goodness! I'll...
I'll pay for the damage of course. I'm...
- All will be all right once we get you back, sir.
- I'm so sorry.
- We'll be home before you know it.
- Yes. Er...
I'm...
- Johnny! Johnny!
- Sorry?
I haven't got time to talk. It's the Williamson dinner at six.
One of us has to be there.
- What the devil's happened to the car, George?
- Entirely my fault, sir.
Well, it can come out of your wages.
Come on! I've got to go!
Would you please stop shouting?
It wasn't George's fault. It was mine.
I'll pay for the damage.
I haven't got time for this.
I'll take your bag upstairs, sir.
Thank you.
Daddy! You're back!
I've missed you so much!
I have terrible news.
Mrs Simpson is dead.
Mrs Simpson is dead?
That... that is terrible news.
- You don't look very upset.
- No, no, I am. I am.
I didn't even know she was ill.
Would you come up and see her
after my bath?
- You mean she's here?
- Of course.
I told Father McReady he couldn't bury her
until you came back.
You just have to promise that
you'll come up.
I promise.
Yes, it's him.
Darling?
- God, you look a mess. Where have you been?
- He really was ill.
You might at least apologise.
We've been waiting all day for you.
- I was so worried.
- Aren't you going to kiss either of us?
Look... Um...
there's been a mistake.
I met whoever you think I am last night
and we had a few drinks... too many, I'm afraid,
and then, this morning, when I woke up,
he had stolen my clothes and my luggage
and my wallet,
and taken off without any explanation.
Anyway, I came here this afternoon
to find out exactly what was going on.
(SIGHS)
He's been drinking.
I can smell it from here.
- I'm going up to change for dinner. Come on, Frances.
- Pl...
Did you talk to Paul?
He's been in a state all day about the contract.
- Is he the one who was just rude to me?
- It's not funny!
You might at least have telephoned.
There you are, Mr Spence. Her Ladyship has
asked me to send you up the moment you arrive.
- I'm not Mr...
- Please don't keep her waiting.
We were expecting you yesterday
and she's getting quite anxious.
Was there anything else you wanted?
No, no. Nothing at all.
I am, of course, going upstairs.
(DOOR OPENS)
- Annie?
- Oh, my God!
- What are you doing? Are you mad?
- I'm...
Annie's just getting me some shampoo.
She'll be back in a minute.
You are an idiot.
Mmm...
Come and find me after dinner.
Paul won't be back till late.
I've made sure of that.
(KNOCKING)
Annie, dear, can you come and help me?
I want it properly rubbed in.
Yes, madam.
You disgust me!
Her Ladyship was most insistent on
seeing you immediately, sir.
- Right.
- She's expecting you for supper.
Why don't I take this from you,
and you lead the way?
Shall I?
You beastly boy.
Come and give your mother a kiss.
Father McReady, would you think me
rude if I cut short our little game
so I can talk to my prodigal here?
- No, of course not, Your Ladyship.
- What's the tally now?
I think I owe you 2/4 pence,
Your Ladyship.
How very thrilling.
We must make a note of that so we don't forget.
Where's my little book?
Well, I'm sure you and Johnny
have a great deal to discuss.
- In nomine Patris et Filii et Spiritus Sancti.
- Amen.
Good to have you safe home, Johnny.
- Enjoy your dinner.
- Thank you.
Now, come and sit beside me.
What's the matter?
You look ill.
What have you done with your tie?
- I'm sorry, I'm feeling a little...
- Hungover.
Serves you right.
I suppose you found some little tart
to amuse yourself with last night,
though goodness knows why you had to
go to Peterborough to find one.
So, did you settle with
the Levertons?
Did you agree the new contract?
Don't play the fool with me, Johnny.
Did you or didn't you?
Yes, I did.
Good.
Oh, I knew you could manage it.
Paul is such a baby.
I knew that if you talked to them,
you'd make them see it our way.
You're a Spence.
The only one in this house,
as far as I'm concerned.
Ah... where's my present?
Johnny, I'm not in the mood.
I need it. We expected you yesterday.
(KNOCKING)
That'll be Annie, ma'am.
I trust you haven't let me down.
Now, tell us what's happening
in London.
Who did you see?
What's the gossip?
I don't see why you're acting
so surprised.
When has he ever behaved
any differently?
- Perhaps he really was ill.
- Oh, don't be so bloody naive!
Well, I think I'll go up
and leave you to it.
Tell Charlotte, if you ever see her again,
that I won't be needing anything else.
Good night.
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right. I'm fine.
You have to stand up to my brother,
otherwise he just takes advantage.
Yes, I know.
I think I'll go up too.
Good night.
Do you have it?
Her present.
Shall we get it?
That'll be the one.
Nearly ran out.
We were expecting you yesterday.
Is that all you got?
It's not going to last very long.
(SOBS)
(SCREAMS)
Oh! You gave me a fright!
- I'm... I'm so sorry.
- Standing in the dark, I thought...
- I'm sorry. It's entirely my fault.
- No, I shouldn't have barged in.
I thought you were with your mother.
I'm sorry.
Could you undo me?
Please?
I was so worried.
I thought something
must have happened.
Did it?
- Did... Did what?
- Something happen?
- No.
- Oh.
Good.
Thank you.
- Did you speak to Piglet?
- Who?
She was waiting up for you.
You all right?
You're very quiet.
Would you like me to run you a bath?
You must be exhausted.
No.
No. Thank you.
- How... How are you?
- All right, I suppose.
Charlotte is being beastly to everyone.
It seems to be my fault.
I don't see Piglet
from one day to the next.
She leads a completely secret life.
Did you say anything to her
by the way?
She's been acting particularly oddly
since you left.
What about you?
How was it?
The business with the contract.
Oh, um...
let's not talk about that now.
Of course.
I'll be done in a minute.
I know I'm going on and you hate that.
- Darling, I...
- What?
What?
No, it's nothing.
You said darling.
I'm being silly.
Ignore me. Sorry.
I think I'll pop out for a while.
I'm not very tired.
Do you have to?
Yes.
- What the hell are you doing?!
- I'm just popping out for some air.
I left my door open for you.
You've been away over a week.
I wanted to see you!
Why do you think I told Paul to
go to that dinner alone?
I thought we could spend some time together.
It's hard enough in this madhouse.
- You'd rather spend the evening with your mother?
- I didn't have much choice.
I thought you'd come to me afterwards
instead of wandering round like a ghost.
Can we talk about this
in the morning?
You can be a real bastard.
- I'm very s...
- Don't touch me!
It's no good now. There's no time anyway,
even by our pathetic standards.
(CAR APPROACHES)
See? That's him now.
Go on, go.
Get some bloody air,
and leave the rest of us to suffocate.
(THUMP)
Ow!
You didn't come and say good night.
- That hurt!
- You promised.
I'm sorry.
If you don't come up by the time I count to 50,
I swear I'm going to jump.
- Get back inside now!
- Don't say I didn't warn you.
One, two...
- Get back inside!
- Three, four,
five, six, seven,
eight, nine...
You're lucky I'm not dead.
What on earth did you think
you were doing?
You said you'd come up.
Well, I... I was busy.
- I'm very sorry.
- You promised.
I said I was sorry, and I am.
Very well.
I forgive you. Kiss?
You smell funny.
- What sort of funny?
- Funny, like a doctor.
I thought you were never
coming back at all.
Why?
Because you said if things got too difficult,
you'd disappear.
Hmm...
Stop!
What's the matter?
This is Mrs Simpson.
Oh, Mrs Simpson the goldfish.
(SNIFFS)
Oh...
She's certainly dead.
What would you have done
if I had disappeared?
Topped myself.
- You don't even know what that means.
- Of course I do, silly!
Children don't kill themselves.
Then why did you run upstairs
so fast just now?
Because you might have slipped.
I was holding on.
Now, pass Mr Rabbit.
Thank you.
Now you can tuck me in
and make me snuggly.
And you can promise not to
do anything silly like that again.
- Only if you promise.
- What?
That you'll never go away
and leave me.
Look...
Um...
I can't make that promise,
I'm afraid.
Well, you must just hope
for the best
that you stay at home
and that I stay alive.
If I do have to go away,
whatever the reason,
I promise I'll tell you first.
Cross your heart and hope to die?
Cross my heart
and hope neither of us has to die.
Now, go to sleep.
Eee! Eee!
- What's that?
- Mr Rabbit saying good night too.
Good night.
(SIGHS)
Is that you?
Yes, it's... me.
Yes, it's me.
Is this for me?
It says F for Frances.
Oh, then I suppose so.
Can I open it?
Oh, it's beautiful!
Did you have it made specially?
I love it. Thank you.
Will you put it on for me?
Yes, of course.
Good morning, sir.
- Mrs Spencer, I hope I'm not disturbing you.
- Not at all.
- I'll go and get dressed.
- Right.
Oh, thank you... George.
Ah... where...
where is everyone?
Your brother's at the foundry, sir.
He's expecting you at er... ten.
And your sister and Mrs Paul
are at breakfast.
- And Her Ladyship?
- Indisposed, sir. Likely to remain so the rest of the day.
I... er found this
in your waistcoat pocket, sir.
- Ah... Good morning... Annie.
- Good morning, sir.
- I was just on my way to breakfast.
- Oh, sorry, Mr Spence.
Thank you.
Morning.
- What are you doing?
- Nothing.
Can you have a word with Charlotte about having a fire?
It's ridiculous that there isn't one.
Would you like me to light one?
- Did you enjoy your fresh air last night?
- Yes, thank you.
Daddy brought presents for everyone.
Mummy got a locket with a picture of his face on it.
- I'm not sure you should be...
- Is this one for me?
- It says an L on it.
- Ah... well...
And this is for you
and for Auntie Nina
and one for Auntie Blanche
and my one.
Charlotte's Web!
Just what I wanted!
- Thank you.
- Pleasure.
I suppose you think that's funny?
You really don't care about anyone,
do you, except for yourself!
- Can I open her present?
- No, you can't.
(DOOR OPENS)
George is waiting out front, sir,
when you're ready.
Thank you. I'm coming now.
- Can I have it?
- Absolutely not.
"To my darling B. XXX"
Isn't it pretty?
(SNIFFS)
That stinks.
May I offer my congratulations, sir?
- What for?
- The Leverton contract.
Your mother gave Mr Paul the good news
this morning.
Ah.
There'll be
quite a celebration tonight, sir.
Well done, sir.
I'm sorry.
I couldn't keep it a secret.
It's been like Christmas.
I don't think anyone's done
a scrap of work all day.
Welcome, sir.
Come on, how did you do it?
I just couldn't believe it.
I hardly know myself.
It's incredible that
they accepted our terms.
- Well done, sir.
- Thank you
- Have you got the contract?
- Er... no, not with me.
But you did sign it?
There are some details to finalise.
They'll send it on.
A letter arrived for you this morning.
That's probably it.
I want to hear the whole story,
but I've got to go to the bank.
I had a tricky meeting with Thornton
while you were away.
- Congratulations, sir.
- Oh, thank you.
Arthur, can you make sure
everyone gets back to work?
Sorry about last night.
I had a bit of a spat with Nina.
I wasn't quite myself.
Jolly well done.
I really mean that.
Just the sort of thing your father
would have pulled off,
if you don't mind me saying so, sir.
I felt, well, that sometimes,
you didn't understand
the lives of the men and women here.
I'm happy to admit I was wrong.
It's a terrible thing
for a man to have no work.
Yes, I know.
We will need some funds by next week
to cover the wages.
The accounts are all here, sir.
Mr Paul and I went through everything
ourselves yesterday.
And again, congratulations, sir.
Thank you.
Don't worry, I'll get him.
Darling, you haven't even changed,
and it's half past seven!
Everyone's about to go in.
- I'm not very hungry.
- What are you doing?
Trying to understand these reports
about the glassworks.
- I thought that was Paul's job.
- I'd like to understand them myself.
- You still have to eat.
- Sandwich, maybe? Glass of water?
You are in an odd mood.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be.
It's rather nice to have to
look after you for a change.
We could take a picnic upstairs.
Just us.
I'll tell them I'm not feeling well.
They're used to that.
I used to have to stop boys having midnight feasts.
Here I am eating one.
- I didn't know you were a prefect.
- I wasn't.
I mean, I was. I just wasn't a...
very good one.
If Charlotte finds out about all this,
I'm dead.
So is Annie. She caught me in the larder,
but I managed to persuade her that my cause was just.
She's very excited at
the news about the foundry.
You're so clever to have
managed that.
The trouble is I haven't.
- Oh.
- That's why I was reading all those papers.
Did you know there was a report before the war,
commissioned by my sister from a chap called A Farr?
- Alice Farr.
- Actually, it's rather good as a matter of fact.
Why don't you go back to your papers
while I get this cleared up?
- Let me help.
- No. Thank you. I'd rather do it myself.
- No, please.
- I mean it!
- What are these doing here?
- I was reading them last night.
It's a bit late, isn't it?
Look, I'm sorry about yesterday.
I didn't know what I was doing.
Really! I think you knew exactly
what you were doing.
What would you have done?
What would I have done?
I probably wouldn't have seduced
my sister-in-law for a start.
About the Leverton contract.
Whatwould you have done if
they had refused to accept our terms?
- What does it matter? They've signed.
- But if they hadn't, what then?
I would have done anything to keep
the furnaces burning. You know that.
It's madness to rely on a single contract.
You should never have allowed us to be in this position.
I read that report last night.
I didn't fully understand it,
but he seemed to take it seriously.
He did until you told him not to.
Are these Alice's designs?
You complete shit!
Crockett wants to know about
the shoot on Sunday.
He's suggesting starting at Begley End this year
and driving up towards Moorcroft.
They walked it yesterday,
and they say the ground's solid.
He'll be here at 11:00
to go over it with you.
Sounds good. I have to go into town at ten,
so maybe you could take care of it?
Well, of course,
if that's what you want.
And I have a hair appointment.
We can go in together.
I'll just go and get ready.
I'll see to Crockett, then.
Do you have to go in?
I have some things to sort out
in the bank.
Well, you'll find them much more amenable.
They were very pleased about the contract.
Good.
Ah, yes. Mayfair 242.
I'd like to speak to Sir Matthew Leverton.
It's Mr Spence from Century Glass.
Well, you'll have to interrupt the meeting.
He'll want to hear this personally.
- Can I come into town with you?
- I'm going on business.
Please? It's really important.
On second thought, that's a very good idea.
Of course you can come.
Sorry we're late.
Mary Lou is coming with us.
Very important mission, apparently.
Nothing I could do.
- We need to talk.
- Yes, of course.
- Alone.
- Right.
- Can I sit in the front?
- Yes.
- Where are you going?
- Argyle Street. That junk shop.
- Look after her.
- Yes.
This is the last one.
That's everything we have.
- You sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
But I think it would be better to discuss
any queries you may have with Mr Thornton
when he returns.
There's definitely nothing else?
No other account?
No, sir. That's everything.
What's this? There seems to be something
in this account, quite a lot.
In fact, £1 million.
I'm sorry, sir. This account is in the wrong file.
I shouldn't have brought it out.
It says Spence at the top.
Um... that's because
it's your wife's trust fund.
Are you saying
that's gone as well?
No, sir. The principle sum
has not been paid out
- because of the terms of the marriage settlement.
- What terms?
- Perhaps I can make an appointment...
- Do you know who I am?
Of course, Mr Spence.
There can hardly be anything irregular about
discussing my own marriage settlement, can there?
No, sir. I suppose not.
- Well?
- Well...
I'm not completely familiar
with the document,
but my understanding is that
the money is only to be paid out
in the event of your wife
conceiving a male heir,
unless, of course,
she should predecease you.
A male heir?
Sir Alfred was most insistent.
So a granddaughter
wasn't good enough for him.
It would appear not, sir.
Thank you, Mr Myerson.
My coat.
There is one other thing.
There's a painting up at the house.
I'd like it valued.
- Yes, sir. I'm sure that can be arranged.
- You've been most helpful.
Sorry, excuse me.
Do you know where Argyle Street is?
I'm looking for a little girl,
my daughter.
Upstairs?
Thank you.
What are you doing here?
Um... I'm looking for a little girl.
The gentleman downstairs indicated...
You should never send a child here.
It shows lack of respect for
your family.
- I've missed you.
- Where is she?
The child? She left half an hour ago
with the chauffeur.
So, did your wife like our
petit cadeau?
Did she think I painted
a good likeness of you?
Er...yes. Yes. She... She um...
- She loved it as a matter of fact.
- So she's happy?
And what about me?
Did you find Bela's little present?
- The perfume?
- Yes. Did you find it?
- I gave it to my sister.
- What? Does she still hate you? Why?
- It was a mistake.
- That must have been a surprise for her.
Yes, it was.
- Did it make her happy?
- No, it didn't.
- Then we are both unhappy.
- Oh!
What are you going to do about this?
- Where's your father?
- Still in the bank.
(SIGHS)
Well, we're not waiting.
George can come back for him.
Get in, and take that out of your mouth.
- That little girl of yours is adorable.
- Yes, she is.
- Why was she here?
- She wants me to mend something for her.
A plate from your regiment.
She thinks you will be angry
it is broken.
Oh, so that's the big secret.
- You're not angry?
- No. Why should I be?
She seemed to expect it.
She loves you,
but she fears you also.
The truth is I'm the one
who should be afraid.
She almost jumped out of a window
because I didn't say good night.
I think she loves me.
It's quite an unusual feeling.
You're in a strange mood.
Did something happen in London?
What do you mean?
I don't know.
You seem different.
You were different just now.
- How?
- Not sure.
Gentler, perhaps.
I like that.
- People change.
- That's not so usual.
I'm the proof.
I don't think we know what we're capable of
until we're given the opportunity.
That I do believe.
I have seen what people are capable of
if they are given the opportunity.
- That's why I'm here.
- Why are you here?
We agreed, no stories.
Please? I'd like to know.
You would not understand.
The English do not know what it is like
to be occupied by an enemy.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't be.
That was a long time ago.
But now, you are the hero of war,
with your plate from your loyal men
to their brave captain.
I don't feel very brave.
You're ticklish.
You've been lying to me all that time?
I told you, people change.
You mean ticklish one day,
not ticklish the next?
I don't think that's possible.
- Ahem.
- How did you know I was here?
They said at the bank that you left before lunch,
so I thought I might find you here.
- Oh, I see.
- There's a funeral to attend, sir,
and I'm under strict instructions to
ensure you're not late.
FATHER MCREADY: Our father in heaven,
who notices even the falling of a sparrow,
must surely, then, have noted the
untimely passing of Mrs Simpson.
We commend her to His care, and ask His comfort
for those on earth who mourn her passing.
In the name of the Father,
Son and Holy Ghost. Amen.
- Amen.
Throw some on there.
Come on, Piglet.
I think it's an early bed for you tonight.
Do fishes go to heaven?
I'm sure they do.
There are rather a lot of them.
Well, if you'll excuse me, I need a chance to
even the score with your mother before she has her rest.
Could I possibly have
a word with you first, Father?
Yes, of course.
It's true a priest cannot reveal
the secrets of confession?
That is correct.
- Can I make one? Please.
- Now?
Well, it is possible.
God's ear is everywhere.
How do I begin?
Dear me, Johnny!
I know it's a long time, but you must remember.
We learnt it together.
- Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
It is a very long time
since my last confession.
- This is going to be a little unusual.
- I think it already is.
I want to talk about
me and my sister.
I see. Go on.
- I think you understand why.
- I do?
Do I? Oh!
- That unfortunate girl, the glass designer?
- Yes.
Yes. That's exactly it.
Alice, wasn't that her name?
Alice Farr.
Quite.
Terrible, quite terrible.
I think, in some ways,
what happened was my fault.
It certainly was not!
The coroner was very clear that no-one
in the family was in any way to blame.
The girl was of unsound mind,
with no respect for the sanctity of her own life.
Your sister, as you know,
took it very personally.
Too personally, in my view,
and your mother agreed.
And then, of course, there was the
very sad business of the poor child.
Never drew breath, of course,
but because of the girl's selfish act,
it could not enter the presence of God
because it carried the stain of mortal sin.
Surely, if there was sin,
it was that of the father?
The father, whoever he was,
had, of course, sinned,
but he can be forgiven.
He would just need to confess
and be given absolution.
- And can he be forgiven for what he did?
- Of course.
You can be forgiven for anything,
provided you make a proper act of contrition.
- Thank you, Father. That was very helpful.
- But that wasn't a confession.
No. No.
Would you mind awfully if I had some
time alone with my mother this evening?
No. No, of course not.
My vow was poverty.
Thank you.
(KNOCKING)
How was the funeral?
Very moving.
I heard about your performance
at breakfast.
It made me laugh.
- What were you thinking, giving your sister perfume?
- I wasn't thinking.
Anyway, Frances loves her locket.
Why the sudden concern for that
barren stick of a girl?
She's not barren.
She has a very beautiful daughter.
Exactly, and that nearly killed her.
Sometimes, I wish it had.
- No, you don't.
- Don't I?
Don't pretend you haven't
thought of it yourself.
If she'd died,
you needn't have worried about a son.
You'd have inherited everything and the family
and the foundry would have been safe,
which is why we chose her
in the first place.
- Is it?
- Well, you know it is.
Well, if we want to keep the foundry safe,
we have to pay the wages,
so I'm thinking of selling the
Vermeer in the study.
Really?
- You don't mind?
- Of course I don't mind.
Although I don't see how it will help.
It's a fake, as you well know.
You've left it a little late to play the saint,
my dear.
The best pictures went long ago,
with the land.
- So, how do you expect to survive?
- I don't.
It's the end for houses like this.
No-one can support them any more.
I mean, look at poor Freddy Thynne,
opening Longleat to the public.
Well, I don't intend to be around to see
strangers gawping at this house.
Zeus once decided to punish a king by
setting out a huge feast in front of him every day,
but each time the king
reached for something to eat,
a winged harpy snatched it away from him,
and so he starved in the face of plenty.
There's a banquet
in front of you here.
There are no harpies,
but you're all still starving.
The inevitable has to be accepted.
Does it? Or is the inevitable something
that comes in a syringe of morphine?
I take my pleasure where I can,
just as you take yours.
What if we stopped, both of us,
just for one day?
Why don't you come down
and greet your guests tomorrow at the shoot?
This house needs you.
It's too late to change.
We are what we are.
I can't see anything at all.
It's like that night we drove to
Inverness on our honeymoon.
Oh, my goodness!
Look, there's a man!
- Oh, yes.
- What are they saying?
- You have to turn up the sound control.
- Oh, yes. Sorry.
TV: New coins for the coronation of
Queen Elizabeth.
The design of the new coins has
already aroused spirited controversy,
with some commentators saying that
Her Majesty looks too girlish.
(TV OFF)
I'm sorry.
There's something I want to say.
I haven't been
strictly truthful with you all.
I didn't do a deal with Leverton's
in London last week.
I did one this morning.
It isn't a very good arrangement.
In fact, it's pretty bad from our point of view.
So it was a lie all along?
- Why?
- I was a coward.
What I should have done...
What I'm trying to do now is ask for your help.
It's a bit late for that,
don't you think?
I don't see what we can do.
- We shut it down. That's his plan.
- Abandoning the foundry won't save us,
and even if it did, what kind of life would it be
if we can eat when everyone else is hungry?
That's not something
that bothered you before.
So what are you suggesting?
We find a way to raise some finance
while we come up with another plan.
I read Alice Farr's report last night,
and I think it could work.
- You said it was completely impractical.
- I was wrong.
Blanche will never agree.
I don't understand
what you're trying to do.
Make it better.
Well, you can't.
I have to try.
Blanche,
no-one can bring Alice back.
Don't you dare bring Alice into this.
You know nothing about her.
You never understood her
for a single second.
Do you remember when
you set fire to my doll's house?
You did it because I loved it.
Because it was mine.
Because you were jealous.
Just like you always are,
jealous of anything you can't have.
Well, Daddy can't buy a new one
and make it better this time.
I know that.
She loved me.
That's what you couldn't bear,
wasn't it?
So you had to have her.
Alice wasn't like us.
She had no idea how people like us can behave.
It drove her mad.
And because of me and...
what I had done,
she felt she couldn't turn to anyone?
Not even you.
You may not believe it,
but I know how that feels,
and I think you do too.
We can't bring Alice back,
but we can think about
what she might have wanted.
We can make the ideas she believed in real,
and that way, something survives.
(SOBS)
- That's new, isn't it?
- No. I just haven't worn it for a while.
- Can you turn the light out, please?
- Yes.
(SNIFFS)
Oh, not now.
- Your Ladyship?
- Not tonight.
I feel too tired to be tired.
If you're sure.
(GENTLE KNOCKING)
I just wanted to say good night.
Good night.
I...
I liked your speech.
Thank you.
- You're a very surprising man.
- I don't think my sister was impressed.
Give her time.
Do you think you can find the money?
I don't know, but I intend to try.
I just wish there was
a way I could help.
You have. I wouldn't have had the courage
to say anything without you.
Good night.
J...
- Yes?
- I did something very silly.
- Please, you don't have to explain.
- No. I want to tell you.
I broke your regimental plate.
It was completely stupid of me,
I just touched it somehow,
- and it broke.
- I know.
It was my own fault.
You've every right to be angry.
I don't mind if you are.
I'm really not angry.
I know I've been a terrible disappointment
as a wife.
None of this would be happening
if I'd had a son.
I'll make it up to you somehow.
- I will find a way. I really will.
- Don't worry about anything.
Please, just go to bed.
Of course.
- I didn't mean to annoy you. I'm so sorry!
- No, you haven't. I'm... not.
- Stop fiddling about, woman, and come help me.
- What do you need?
I need to get up
and I need to get dressed.
- Are you sure?
- Of course I'm sure.
Do I look like someone who isn't sure?
Let me help you.
- You're looking very good, if I may say so, sir.
- Thank you, George. I wish I felt the same way.
- I'm not looking forward to this.
- Don't worry, sir. You'll beat your record. You always do.
- Darling?
- Excuse me.
- What do you think?
- You look wonderful.
Ugh, kissing!
Can I go to town with Auntie B? Thanks!
Make sure you're back
in time for the lunch.
I'm so happy.
I'd almost forgotten
how beautiful it is.
- What would you like to wear?
- The tweed, of course.
It's the shoot today.
You didn't take the pistol out
by any chance?
- Certainly not. Why?
- It's gone missing.
One of the keepers
must have borrowed it.
- Morning.
- Good morning. Thank you.
- Morning, sir.
- Thank you.
- Ooh, that's a little heavy.
- Well, it's your gun, Johnny.
- Yes, of course. I'll manage.
- You can try mine if you like,
but you're always so rude about it.
- Why not?
- I'll try yours, then.
- Always wanted to.
- That's much better.
Sawyer, come here, boy.
- Good dog.
- Come on. Come.
- That's not like Captain.
- Captain, come on. Come here.
Something must have spooked him.
Never mind,
Sawyer can look after us both.
- I thought that was a brave thing you said last night.
- Thank you.
(DOGS BARKING)
Morning.
(CAPTAIN WHIMPERS)
What's the matter?
Have they left you behind?
Don't you worry.
We'll soon have everything back to normal.
What's that scratch
on my rear bumper?
- It's being attended to, ma'am, I assure you.
- It had better be.
Now, let me be. I can manage this.
Darling, what are you doing here?
Is something the matter?
- What on earth are you wearing?
- Don't ask. I've had a terrible morning.
You really are quite remarkable.
Thank you so much.
For what?
Everything.
Listen...
I know how much you love me,
so I want you to do something for me,
something very, very sinful,
but it'll make everything right
for all of us.
For you, for Piglet
and for me.
That's what you want, isn't it?
Of course.
Good.
(SIGHS)
Come and sit down.
Please.
I want you to write something for me.
Will you do that?
I want you to write,
"To my darling.
I love you so much.
To my darling..."
I know what to write.
(GUNFIRE)
Where is everybody?
They must have already
gone to the barn for lunch.
- We'd better get a move on.
- I just need to do something.
- I'll be quick.
- All right. I'll wait in the car.
I'm told you've been shooting
like a girl all morning. Is this true?
No, no. He borrowed one of my guns
instead of using his own.
That's the problem.
He's just too polite to admit it.
I've never heard him
accused of that before.
(JINGLING)
Ladies and gentlemen,
on behalf of my family,
I'd just like to say how pleased
we are to see you all here today.
I'm told we have
a record kill this morning.
Why aren't you at
the head of the table?
I thought Paul would do it better.
Another minor record is that,
for the first time in living memory,
I've managed a fractionally higher tally
than my brother Johnny.
He'll make a fool of himself.
Just you wait.
And, finally, if you would join me
in raising a glass to my mother,
who is here today,
looking so radiant.
To your very good health.
- Lady Spence.
I've spent too long away
from this family.
I don't seem to recognise anybody.
Even you look a little odd,
now I come to think of it.
Mummy,
I didn't expect to see you here.
I'm not dead yet.
What have you done with Frances?
Isn't she here yet?
Excuse me. Sorry.
- Darling, where's Mummy?
- You know.
- What do you mean?
- I saw you.
Where?
Just now, with Mummy,
giving her Granny's medicine.
Why do you keep
changing your clothes?
Oh, God...
- Where's Frances?
- Isn't she at lunch with you?
No, she's not.
Frances? Frances!
Darling?
Charlotte! Quickly!
- How much has she taken?
- Enough. Lift her.
We need to get her blood pressure up.
If she stays unconscious for too long,
she'll stop breathing.
- Why wasn't it kept locked up?
- You know perfectly well that it was.
Now, leave her to me,
and go and telephone for an ambulance.
Now.
Please don't let her...
I won't.
- You'll just have to be patient, Mr Spence.
- It'll only take a moment.
Let them do their job.
You heard what the doctor said.
- I need to speak with her.
- Later. You've done everything you can.
- How is she?
- She's going to be all right.
Johnny found her in time.
- Thank God.
- Do they know what happened?
- No, not really. How is everyone?
- Yes, gone at last.
I don't think anyone
suspected anything.
- Do you know, I just saw something rather odd.
- What's that?
That artist...
Do you remember, we met her together,
the one from France?
What about her?
I just saw her in reception.
She looked terrible, like she'd been in a fight.
- Are you sure it was her?
- Yes, of course.
She's gone now.
That's what was so odd.
I asked the nurse where you were, she got up and left.
That's how I noticed her.
Oh, God...
- What? What's the matter?
- Can I take your car?
- Of course.
- Stay with Frances.
Don't leave her alone with anybody,
and I mean anybody, not even... me.
I'll be back as quick as I can.
(CRASH)
I told you what would happen
if you came back.
- Wait, please.
- Why?
Because I'm not Johnny.
There are two of us. We...
He's someone I met and we swapped places
because of the way we looked,
and I know that sounds absurd.
You are the ticklish one.
Yes, I suppose I am, although that might be
hard to prove at the moment.
I knew you were different
the moment you touched me,
but I did not believe
it was possible.
I didn't mean to deceive you.
Is that because of me?
No, because of me.
- I'll survive.
- Do you know where he is?
He just tried to kill my...
He tried to kill Frances.
I need to find him.
He went to his foundry last night.
Thank you.
Who are you really?
A teacher.
A mother.
I had to leave my child behind when I fled.
I think it's time to go home.
Don't you?
I'm not sure I know
where home is any more.
Don't worry, you will.
(DOOR CREAKS)
Mr Standing...
You'll have to excuse me.
I'm just finishing a rather primitive supper.
You look quite
the country gentleman.
So, how did you find me?
Bella.
Of course. You have been busy,
haven't you?
Yes. I'm afraid I lost my temper with her,
but you can hardly blame me.
You've taken our little experiment
further than I expected.
Your effect on Frances
was quite remarkable.
I don't think I've ever
been kissed like that before.
I congratulate you. You certainly
made everything much easier for me.
- What did you do to her?
- I didn't have to do anything, thanks to you.
She's always been very persuadable, but,
of course, you already know that.
I can't blame you.
I'd have done the same. In fact, I did.
I assume you're here
about the money.
Don't worry, you'll get your share.
Frances's father is a very rich man.
I can afford to be generous.
There is no money.
She's not dead.
Not possible. I gave her enough to kill a cow,
appropriately enough.
I want you to go away
and leave her alone.
Oh.
So you want it all, do you?
That's a little greedy,
but no more than I expected.
You've become almost as
good at being me as I am.
- I'm serious.
- Yes. So am I.
Now, take off those clothes.
We're going to have to change back.
- No.
- I mean it!
I don't need you. I need my clothes.
Now, take them off.
So you're going to kill us both?
- Was that always your plan?
- God, no. Do I look like an idiot?
I never even thought you'd make it to the house,
let alone into my bed.
No. I had you bleating your unlikely story
to a baffled country policeman
then being sent on your way.
But I did get curious,
so I rang the house after a couple of days.
When Charlie answered and said I was out,
but would be back in an hour,
I realised the walls
had been breached,
and I had the perfect opportunity.
You're not the only one.
This last week has been
the most extraordinary of my life,
and I love your family,
every single one of them.
- You have no idea how lucky you are.
- Oh, God...
You are pathetically sentimental.
My family are too selfish
to love anyone but themselves.
I've lived long enough with them to know that.
Now, would you hurry up?
What will you do with me?
Ashes to ashes and all that.
There'll be no trace of you
by morning.
(GUNSHOT)
FRANCES: Darling, what happened?
I've had such terrible dreams.
You're safe.
Have I disappointed you again?
You've never disappointed me.
You're the most extraordinary person
I've ever met,
and I'll never forget a moment
I've spent with you,
and, whatever happens,
I want you to know that I love you.
What's the matter?
You're shaking.
Don't worry about me.
Just rest.
Rest and get strong.
Sleep.
You've changed.
Do you know that?
Have I?
I don't know.
You seem harder.
To me at least.
You never loved me at all,
did you?
I don't think I did.
So you have changed.
You don't even pretend any more.
Paul wants to take me abroad.
France, Italy, everywhere.
He's suddenly full of ideas
for the business.
- He thinks I can help him.
- I think that would be very good.
- Really?
- Yes.
Well, I've never travelled.
I've never been anywhere,
what with the war and everything.
I'm terrible at languages.
- What use would I be to him?
- You'd be just what he needs.
You looked so strong together today
at the lunch.
He really loves you.
You know that?
I'm still bloody furious with you,
you know.
I know.
- Stay with her.
- Of course.
- She's asleep.
- Where are you going?
To see Mary Lou. I made a...
I made a promise.
Frances will be all right.
Yes, I know.
I don't think I knew what it meant to
have a brother until today.
Thank you.
How is Frances?
Better. Sleeping.
I read the note she left.
She must have felt so alone.
It made me think about
what you said about Alice,
having no-one to turn to.
You're right.
When it mattered, we all failed her.
Including me.
I've decided to accept your offer.
- You'll take over the foundry?
- Yes.
- I'm glad.
- There would be a condition.
- Anything.
- That you never set foot there again.
- Paul and I will be in charge.
- I completely agree.
What will you do about finance?
Come on, there has to be
something here we can sell.
She's asleep.
Please don't wake her up.
Eep-eep.
Good night, Mr Rabbit.
Tell me what she saw this afternoon.
I said you were helping her mother.
That's what she believes.
Thank you.
But it wasn't you she saw,
was it?
What do you mean?
I know Johnny better than anyone.
He loved me.
In his way, but as he grew older,
I faded like a photograph.
I became invisible to him.
But he wasn't to me.
I saw everything that he did.
And then something changed.
The child sensed it.
Said you smelt different.
I didn't believe it at first,
but, this afternoon,
when you found her on the bed,
I saw your face.
Then I was sure.
I'm leaving.
I came back because
I made a promise
I would tell Piglet first
if I ever had to go away.
Please tell her one day
that I tried to keep it.
Is he coming back?
- No.
- Ever?
- Then why are you leaving?
This isn't my house.
- It isn't my family.
- Isn't it?
This Princess Elizabeth
wasn't meant to be queen
any more than her father
was born to be king.
Sometimes,
nature or fate take the decision.
Perhaps it will be the making of us.
(PING-PONG BALL BOUNCING)
PIGLET: Five, six, seven, eight.
Very good!
(LAUGHTER)
Ooh...
Are you all right?
You need to be careful
in your condition.
I'm fine, just a little out of breath,
that's all.
Come on! It's about to begin.
George! Charlotte! Annie! Everyone!
Sync, corrected by icephoenix
www.addic7ed.com