Darling?
Oh, darling.
But sex.
You are 23.
Not an easy age
for abstinence, is it?
Tolstoy does not approve
of sexual relations.
I know this.
He despises them, in fact.
Well, I don't mean
to belabor the point,
but last summer
I arranged for a manservant
who proceeded to ruin
two housemaids, just like that.
He was very upset.
This would not be a problem
with me. I'm a vegetarian.
I am celibate.
I'm also a vegetarian.
My dear boy, if you were to become
Tolstoy's private secretary,
you would be given a great gift.
Vladimir Grigorevich,
please know
that I understand what a privilege this
position presents.
But since becoming a Tolstoyan,
I have become so eager to learn,
to discuss ideas,
to perfect my very soul.
Yes. Well...
We have a lot to do if we are to get his
work to the people.
We?
Yes, we.
If we can encourage the spread
of passive resistance,
just think of it, Valentin.
Thousands of ordinary
Russians
casting off centuries of political
and spiritual oppression.
In the name of truth and freedom.
Truth and freedom. Yes, yes.
But, still, there are
many, many enemies.
Enemies?
Come.
The czar's police.
Now, you will be followed
when you leave here,
and the Church will stop at nothing
to bring him back into the fold.
And then, of course,
there is the countess.
Her dogged attachment
to private property,
her public criticism
of our movement.
But the point is
he needs a man of your
intellectual gifts around him.
Someone who understands
his goals.
And they still won't
let me see him.
They keep me under
house arrest.
I have another task for you,
my dear.
I want you to keep
a diary for me.
I need to know what goes on
at Yasnaya Polyana.
Mm-hm.
You let me know
who visits the house,
any talk of the copyright to his work,
any contact with the Church,
anything the countess says.
Anything?
She's very, very dangerous.
Whoa, whoa.
Godspeed, my boy.
And remember what I said.
Mm-hm.
Write everything down.
Driver!
Walk on. Whoa, whoa.
Good morning, countess.
Are you rolling? Are you rolling?
I am.
Countess? Countess?
It doesn't matter.
If my heart stopped beating,
I'd still go riding today.
Your pulse is
my responsibility.
No. It's mine.
Fine.
If you must ride,
I insist you wear a coat.
Even the sun is cold today.
Oh, this!
This is impossible!
These people are parasites!
"The Countess Tolstoy
is estranged from her husband.
They barely speak."
And they gossip
about us in Paris.
"They do not share a similar view of
religion or politics."
You think that's inaccurate?
I think it's none of the world's
bloody business.
What are you doing? Why do you write down
everything we say?
Don't do that.
Dushan Petrovich,
you are scribbling again.
Oh, Leovochka, why do you insist on
dressing like that?
What do you mean, like what?
Like the man who looks after sheep.
It wasn't meant to offend you.
You're a count, for God's sake.
Darling,
where are you going?
Riding with Sasha.
Don't expect us for lunch.
Lev Nikolayevich,
you've forgotten your coat.
Dushan, are you fretting?
Yes, because you refuse
to look after yourself.
Telyatinki was created
by Vladimir Grigorevich
as a center for the movement.
We're all equals here, you know,
as Tolstoy teaches us.
This is a place of freedom.
It's a beautiful day.
Yes, but we'll pay for it.
Toolshed is there.
That's the meeting room,
and this is the dormitory.
I found it!
Afternoon.
Yes, hello.
You are expected at Yasnaya Polyana
in the morning,
first thing.
First thing?
You'll need to be on the road early.
It's nearly two hours away.
I look forward to it.
Yes. You're lucky.
We're all envious.
I'll see you in the morning.
If we're spared.
Right.
And out.
In.
Emma, can you come?
We need you in the house.
Come in.
Brought you a glass of tea.
That's very kind of you.
It's your first day.
Enjoy it.
You met Sergeyenko?
Last night, yes.
What do you think?
I thought he seemed
very sincere.
Thank you.
What?
Is that what you think?
I think that...
I think I've just arrived.
What was your name?
Masha. But you should
still say what you think.
I mean, not just about him.
Like we all should.
Yes.
Excuse me.
Thank you for the tea.
He's a sorry, old, tight-assed
stick-in-the-mud,
but, yes, he's sincere.
Hello?
Out of the way.
Ah. Excuse me.
You.
You're the new secretary?
Yes.
Valentin Fedorovich Bulgakov.
Papa is out. You can wait
upstairs in the library.
I am so glad you're here.
I'm so glad.
God bless you.
Pardon me. I'm mortified.
I sneeze sometimes
when I get nervous.
Yes.
Now, Vladimir Grigorevich has already
written about you at lengths.
I don't need that.
What I do need is your help.
My manifesto against
the government is hard work.
They commit their idiotic abuses
faster than I can catalog them.
Yes.
And then there's the new book,
the compendium.
Vladimir Grigorevich
told me all about it.
He says that you say that all the world's
religions share common truths.
It's very exciting.
No, one truth.
One single organizing principle.
And can you guess what that is?
Um...
Eh?
Love. Love. Simple.
Yeah, but I want
to talk about you.
How are you?
And how was your journey?
Come, sit down.
I was born on that sofa.
No, no, sit, sit.
Myself, my brother, my children,
five or six of them, at least.
Right here.
Congratulations.
Well, I've read your essays.
How's the work progressing?
My boy, what is it?
Oh, I've upset you in some way.
No.
Was it the sofa?
I mean, it's only a sofa.
The sofa's wonderful.
I...
I'm very happy.
Mm-hm.
You're very kind to me.
You see, I am no one,
and you are Lev Tolstoy.
And you ask me
about my work.
I'll fetch you a glass of tea.
Yes.
Now, you rest.
Yeah, because there's work
for both of us to do, together!
Yes.
God.
This machine, it really is
the most extraordinary thing.
Mama, these people have nothing.
No, it's not for lack of land
that the muzhiks live in poverty.
It's because they have no willpower and
they drink too much.
I am not suggesting
they be given land.
Private property is the root
of the problem.
We should be giving ours away.
God. Giving it to whom?
Yes, exactly.
I mean, this is ridiculous.
You think because the peasants are poor,
they're somehow morally superior.
I believe that wealth
corrupts us all.
Yes, I do.
Mm. It's a keystone
of the movement.
Oh, God, I know
all about the movement.
If the peasants
had money,
they wouldn't surround
themselves, as we do,
with footmen costing
10 rubles a month.
No, they'd spend it
on drink and whores.
Valentin Fedorovich.
Mm.
What do you think?
Tea.
You think that 50 years from now, people
will eat while grown men walk around
waiting on them
hand and foot?
I th... I think...
That's good.
Bless you.
Stop scribbling.
I mean, you all think
he's Christ, don't you?
He thinks he's Christ.
I'm not...
I don't believe Lev Nikolayevich
is Christ.
Christ is Christ,
but, uh...
But what?
I do believe
he's one of the prophets.
God speaks through him.
I recognize the cadence
in his voice.
Oh, God, this is unbearable.
No wonder I feel lonely.
I'm surrounded by morons.
Ma, you're being ridiculous.
Oh, am I?
I have to sit here and listen to this talk
of love and God and equality,
knowing all the time,
full well,
that Count Generosity
here is about to give away
everything we own.
Now, why do you keep
going on about this?
Why do you think that we should profit from
the work I'm doing now?
Which is only meant
for the sake of the people.
Stop writing!
Stop writing now!
In defense of my gift,
please let me demonstrate.
It's quite remarkable, really.
In the same way now,
a society of hunger,
full of segregation...
I understand,
not only with my mind, or heart,
It's... It's your voice.
but with my soul,
that the existence
of tens of thousands...
It's your voice.
It's wonderful.
It's wonderful!
It's tiresome.
Another remarkable invention
will supersede it.
Please excuse me.
No matter what all the learned men
in the world say...
Lev Nikolayevich is
something of a Luddite, I fear.
It is a crime.
And one committed not once,
but constantly.
I knew that I, with my luxury...
That's better.
That's nice.
That's very nice indeed.
Do your parents often speak
to each other so bluntly?
Mama doesn't understand
my father's goals,
not since his work as a novelist
became secondary.
His commitment to the
spiritual life offends her.
They've fought
about it for years.
Well, I'm sure
she means well by it.
I see a fine young man
before me. Clear eyes,
nice features,
rather handsome
in a peculiar sort of a way.
Th... Thank you,
countess.
Oh, please, call me
Sofya Andreyevna.
We don't stand on formality here,
as you may have noticed.
No, no. So many
young men nowadays
spoil their good looks
with loose living, but you...
Ooh, you're a real
Tolstoyan, I can tell that.
Well, thank you. I have to say,
I admire your husband immensely.
Oh, very good.
Excellent. He likes that.
Well, his ideas are beautiful.
Social justice, the very concept...
Yes, yes, he's very grateful for the help
you've been giving him.
He told me that himself.
I think he's rather surprised
that a young man like you
can be quite so diligent.
You know, when he was your age, he was
whoring in the Caucasus.
Couldn't get enough of it.
Yes, he wrote all about it.
He even gave me a copy,
so I could read all the details.
Would you like some more jam?
Yes, thank you.
Have you read War and Peace?
Yes, many times.
Hmm.
Twice.
You know, when Lev was writing it...
Oh, this was ages ago,
long before Chertkov created that
monstrosity
at Telyatinki,
over all that fake religion
and revolutionary nonsense.
What do you think of
Chertkov, by the way?
Well, I think that he's...
I think he's given me
a wonderful opportunity.
Yes, but you can see
what a pompous fool he is,
what a self-serving
puritanical idiot.
I must say, it's been very pleasant
since he's been locked away in his house.
Right.
So, anyway, when he was
writing it, in the mid-'60s,
he used to bring me pages
to copy every day
because I was the only one who could
understand his handwriting or his notes.
Do you know I copied out
War and Peace six times?
Six times?
I could understand
his intentions too.
So every afternoon, we'd have tea
and we'd discuss changes.
And I'd say to him,
"You know, Natasha wouldn't speak to Prince
Andrei like that. No woman would."
Or, "Pierre's too simple here.
He's not an idiot."
You know,
things like that.
But I don't count anymore.
You must help me,
Vladimir Fedorovich.
Oh, Valentin Fedorovich.
I only want what's best for
my husband and my family.
If it was for me alone,
I could tolerate the situation,
but I cannot stand by while they steal my
children's inheritance.
Well, I don't believe anybody
wants to do that.
I don't. I mean...
Theft goes against the very
principles of Tolstoyan thought.
I have a little gift
for you.
You...?
Mm.
It's a diary.
You know, everyone
should always keep a diary.
Yes, it's a very popular
activity around here.
You're teasing us.
But I trust you'll
write the truth.
Well, that may
not be so easy.
Oh, nonsense. You've been listening to
your friends at Telyatinki.
No, no, just write what
you see around you.
What you see.
You're finished
for the day?
Yes, he didn't need me
this afternoon.
I thought I'd come back here
and lend a hand.
You know, Lev Nikolayevich
considers himself a liberal
but he doesn't approve of
women doing physical labor.
Don't you find that reactionary?
No.
I find it sweet.
I find you reactionary.
What do you talk about
when you're with him?
We, uh...
Why are you blushing?
I'm not.
We talk about me.
Really?
Yes.
He wants to know about
my family, my upbringing.
My connection to God
and my relations with women.
Ooh.
What relations
are these?
All right, it's all right.
Phew.
Well done.
I had a lover
before I came here.
He was headmaster of
the school where I taught.
He was married.
He was happily married.
It was difficult.
We could make love
only at school.
At school?
In the gymnasium,
after the girls had gone.
I see. I see.
Oh! There you are.
Have I upset you?
No.
No, I find you...I... I appreciate
your frankness.
But you disapprove of me?
No!
I see it in your eyes.
Not at all.
No. Pfft. I think
sexual behavior
and intercourse,
how two men,
or two women,
or men and women,
animals,
combine their physical parts,
I find it completely neutral.
Listen to you.
You're a prig.
You're just like Sergeyenko. I mean, why
else would they have hired you?
That's not fair.
I don't care if it's fair.
It's true.
That's it.
I'm going.
Do as you like.
Valentin
Fedorovich?
Yes?
You forgot
your horse.
Yes.
Where's Papa?
I had a dream last night,
about a Tartar girl I knew in the war.
A girl who died?
No, no, no. Just a girl
I had sexual intercourse with.
Oh?
Sometimes, we did it
twice a day.
God bless you.
I've never forgotten
our time together.
The positions of our bodies,
and the taste of her.
It was a long time ago. Really,
you mustn't torture yourself.
Torture? You are a virgin,
aren't you?
Well, I try to be.
I mean, I try to be...
To what,
to be a good Tolstoyan?
Let me assure you that
I'm not a very good
Tolstoyan myself.
You should think twice before asking
my advice on anything.
"Torture."
Kalya was her name.
She's an old woman now.
White hair, old body,
like me.
Hardly remember
my name, I suspect.
She may even be dead.
Do you think all that
meant something?
What do you mean?
Well, I mean,
that little romance.
Was there
some meaning to it?
Well, I think you
would say...
I mean, I think I've read where you say
that the physical body is not real.
That it's all
an illusion.
Oh, I say a lot of things.
But what do you say?
What do you think?
I don't know.
I don't know, either.
Oh, smell that.
Lilac.
Precisely. Lilac.
Scent gets stronger
when the sun goes down.
Does it?
Papa!
He's free!
He's coming back!
My friend.
He has come to try again to persuade
your father to change the will,
to give the copyright
as a gift to humanity.
The reptile.
Papa's not in his right mind.
He can't defend himself
against these thieves.
You're a fine son, my darling.
None of this fake chastity
or made-up religion.
I wish all my children
had turned out like you.
Vladimir Grigorevich,
what a surprise.
Sofya Andreyevna.
I'm happy to see you.
And I'm happy to make you happy.
Come, come, my friend.
Now, we have a great deal
to talk about.
I'm happy to have a moment
alone with you, Valentin.
There seems to be some confusion.
What do you mean?
Well, you send me neverending
commentary on Tolstoy's writing,
and that's all very interesting,
but not very useful.
See, I need to know what
goes on with Sofya Andreyevna.
You must see by now
how committed she is
to undermining her husband's
best intentions.
It's not quite so obvious to me.
The woman understands
nothing of what we're doing.
We simply want to distribute
Tolstoy's writing
to the widest audience
possible.
I can only be of limited use
to the master
if I don't know
what's going on.
The survival of our movement
depends upon it.
You value our work?
I do.
The ideals we share?
It's why I'm here.
Very good.
Good morning, darling.
Good morning.
Do you mind if I join you?
No, of course, of course, my dear.
You know,
it's quite insane, my darling, how people
are making fun of you.
Hm? What are you talking about?
Even the muzhiks.
I heard them laughing
about it in the horse barn.
Hm? About what?
Laughing about what?
About the fact that you've
developed a senile crush
on a fat,
middle-aged flatterer.
Your passion for Chertkov
has become a standing joke.
I have a great affection
for Vladimir Grigorevich.
Let them laugh
if they find it so amusing.
It's not amusing, darling.
It's sick. It's not normal.
I mean, you hang on
his every word.
We have a great deal
in common.
You have nothing
You are a genius, and he is
a sycophant and a pervert.
Because he understands
what I'm trying to do?
Because he tries to
help me accomplish it?
He's just using you.
You just can't seem to see it.
Oh, this is
absolute nonsense.
That bald, obese, idiotic man, you...
It is impossible for you
not to distract me!
Now, leave me alone, for God's sake.
You're like a spoiled child.
Do you love me, Leovochka?
Of course I do.
Then why do you
betray me like this?
Why do you say that?
Because of the will.
The new will.
There's no new will.
Does Chertkov have it?
There is no new will.
Yes, but that's why
he's here, isn't it?
You talk about it, you and your boyfriend.
You plan for it.
You have no heart for the people who
really love you.
You'd rather be seduced by charlatans and
deluded by flatterers,
all in the name of love. You can't even
love your own children.
You can't even love me.
Where is it?
There is no new will!
Then promise me
there never will be.
I have told you the truth.
Now let me work.
Will you?
Fine, I'll go to the station
and I'll throw myself under a train.
Madam Tolstoy
becomes Anna Karenina.
See how the press
will like that.
Oh, this is unbearable. You don't need
a husband, you need a Greek chorus!
Masha...?
Shh.
Masha...
Mmph!
Hm?
Move your book.
What?
Your book.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. Ahem.
Is it okay?
Mm-hm. Mm-hm.
Yeah?
Mm-hm.
What? What is it?
What is it?
You really are a virgin?
Oh, no, no, no.
I'm teasing, I'm teasing.
It was wonderful, really.
I could do it again.
Let me try again.
It was wonderful.
Really?
Yes.
Hold me.
And up.
That's good. Pull it, your side.
There.
Keep it tight.
That's it, stretch it
so we can read it.
Right, push it right firmly down
into the ground.
We don't want it to blow over.
That's good.
I'm sorry.
Hi.
Oh...
Why did you come here,
Masha?
What do you mean?
You don't follow any
of the rules here.
Because... Because
it's not about rules.
Not for Tolstoy, anyway.
Valentin Fedorovich.
What is it?
Open the door.
I'm currently indisposed.
Yes, well,
Lev Nikolayevich
is downstairs.
He wants to see you.
Tell Lev Nikolayevich
I'll be down in a moment.
Yes. And tell Maria Filipovna
we could use another hand
in the kitchen.
If I see her, I will.
If you see her, yes.
And if you're going to behave like
rabbits, you should go live in the woods.
Shh!
I'll go first. Give me
five minutes, yes?
Come on. That's a boy.
That's my boy.
You too, come on.
You're wonderful, you're
just wonderful, wonderful.
And you too, you too, son.
Look at the love
in him. It's like...
Jesus suffering
the children.
All that.
I know, an old man's
a very ugly thing. Yes.
Hey, my boy! Hey!
Come and kiss me.
And who's this?
Maria Filipovna.
Oh, you're both
looking so well.
Life here obviously
agrees with you.
God bless you, boy. What are you nervous
about now?
Sit down. Sit down.
Oh, Masha, my dear.
Valentin tells me that you are the great
treasure of Telyatinki.
He claims you're
a very gifted teacher.
We're happy to have you with us.
What are you doing?
What do you mean?
You just killed a living thing.
Do you have
something to say?
It's absurd, that's all.
What are you saying?
I'm sorry, but it's a mosquito.
Forgive him. He can't help it.
He's a much better
Tolstoyan than I am.
That's not the message
we want to send.
Please, have your seat.
Very well.
Papa, from Mother:
"Nerves dreadful. Stop.
Insomnia. Stop.
Pulse 100. Stop.
Please come home."
So...
are you ill? Or what is it?
Oh, I'm much better,
now you're here.
It's no good, you know, all this.
You frightened everyone.
Really? No, I don't
believe you. Not you.
I'm your little bird.
You know the sounds I make.
Then that was some
sort of love call, I suppose.
Brought you back to me.
Why? Why, why,
why do you do it?
We live in the country, you insist on
making it an opera house!
What's wrong with
a little peace now and then?
Look at me!
This is who I am.
This is what you married.
We may be older,
maybe we're old,
but I'm still your
little chicken.
And you're still my big cock.
Oh, for pity's sake.
Let me make you crow.
Hm?
Cock-a-doodle-doo.
Oh, come on,
let me make you sing.
Cock-a-doodle-doo!
No. No.
No, no, no.
Cock-a-doodle-doo.
Let me make you sing.
Do you love me?
I do, I do. I do.
I want you to love me.
I do.
I must say you do look
beautiful in the firelight.
You mean
I look beautiful in the dark.
Masha.
You wouldn't look at me.
Heh. I...
It was difficult,
in front of the others...
It wasn't difficult
in your bed
when it was just
you and me in front of God.
I'm not sure
I was aware of God.
So I made you forget God?
No. Never.
Yes. Yes.
Only for a moment.
You forgot your rules
and you remembered love.
You make it sound very simple.
It is simple.
I mean, what we did
is what men and women do.
It's what they have done,
it's what they'll continue doing.
We touched each other.
When we stayed close together,
something passed between us.
Something real.
And that's a betrayal
of what?
Nothing.
But you're afraid.
All your ideas.
Ah, she wants to question
you about the new will.
But how does she
even know it exists?
Well, she claims that Lev Nikolayevich
said she could look at the draft.
Well, uh, he is obviously
not thinking clearly.
And now we have to contend
with her petty grasping.
It doesn't seem
that petty to me.
I beg your pardon?
Ah...
He's her entire life. The work,
in her mind, is theirs, together.
And you're her advocate?
You have been taken in
by her celebrity.
I was worried about this.
I'm simply talking
about their history.
Nothing... Nothing more.
We have to see her. Hm?
Act as if nothing has happened.
Nothing has
happened.
Sofya Andreyevna. At last, you honor us
with a visit.
Well, I'm curious to see how things are
progressing here at Telyatinki.
Well...
What is it?
Ah, your mustache is...
No, it's just a problem
with the wax.
Vladimir Grigorevich, let me come straight
to the point.
I don't wish to
be your enemy.
On the contrary, I am delighted that my
husband has found a friend
who understands
and shares his ideals.
I just want
what's reasonable.
I want an opportunity
to evaluate the new will.
If you agree, then I'm sure
we can be friends.
You are very kind, Sofya Andreyevna,
but I can't help you.
Not without specific instructions from
your husband.
Oh, he has agreed.
Hasn't he, Valentin?
No witness you produce can change my
position, I'm afraid.
But I will, of course,
speak to Lev Nikolayevich
at the first opportunity.
Very well.
I want us to be
friends too, Sofya.
Lev Nikolayevich is the most valuable
thing in the world, to both of us.
We should endeavor to set things right
between us.
Give him peace.
Let him work.
Yes.
Mm.
Valentin Fedorovich, would you
accompany me to the house, please?
I...
Uh, I'll accompany the, ahem, countess back
to the house
and be back in time
for supper.
Masha will be overjoyed.
Valentin Fedorovich, you've been keeping
something from me.
Have I?
You can tell me anything,
Valentin.
I love a romance.
That's... It's nothing.
Really, it's nothing.
A young woman
in your life is nothing?
Masha is a friend.
A lover?
A very... A very good friend.
See, you forget that
I'm an experienced reader,
so I can read your face,
every letter.
It's beautifully clear.
Really?
Do you love her?
I think perhaps I do.
Yes.
It's not something
they'd understand,
these so-called disciples
of my husband's.
They've never understood
a word he's ever written.
What do they
know about love?
Let's try to be as efficient
as possible, get the job done,
and get back.
Whoa!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Did I scare you? Are you all right?
Fine.
I'm sorry.
I got back as soon
as I could.
It was a strange day.
Lev Nikolayevich is...
I love to listen to him talk, but today
I could barely concentrate.
All...
All I could think about
was you.
I think I've confused you.
No.
I think I've confused us both.
I... I was stupid.
I was afraid,
but I'm not afraid anymore.
Whoa.
What are you...?
Masha.
I love you, Masha.
Here.
Masha.
Masha! I have...
In my heart,
I have committed the act
of copulation many times!
Please know it was never
like it was with you.
I'll wait for you, then.
You will?
Give me this.
What?
What are you laughing at?
It's a problem with the wax.
I think I look just like him.
You're happy.
Well, of course I am.
Love and be loved. That's the only reality
there is in the world.
He said that?
Yes, Tolstoy said it,
but I'm saying it.
I'm saying it, Masha,
because you make me know it.
I look into your eyes
and I can see the future.
I think you're the bravest
person I've ever met.
You amaze me.
You believe more
than I know how to.
I love you.
You're pure, Valya.
You're what
I came here to find.
Ivan, who's wearing
that awful perfume?
I understand this is difficult.
It is a delicate situation.
This way.
This must be discussed now.
It cannot wait any longer.
Whatever happens,
Mother mustn't find out.
Shh.
I hate to say it, but the countess has
become more and more dangerous.
Oh, not dangerous. She's concerned for
the welfare of the family.
And we're concerned
with the welfare of mankind.
You've been more
than reasonable.
Have I?
Of course you have.
She already controls
the income from your property.
Please, listen to him, Papa.
He has our best interests at heart.
We are speaking only of the rights to
your words, your ideas.
With all love and respect,
the countess is too interested
in making a profit from your work.
She's my wife. She's part of me.
We've been together all these years.
But you're more than a husband and father.
She must understand that.
The best interests of the people
are one with your own.
You belong to them.
She won't.
She'll never understand.
What is she doing?
She's unstable.
I wonder if she isn't ill.
It's sadly more
than probable.
I know it's hard for you, Papa,
but you must be realistic.
Her behavior is extremely alarming.
Do you truly think that she is fit to
control the final disposition of this will?
Well, I don't... I don't...
How dare... Aah!
God!
Oh, God.
What are you doing?
You're all plotting against me,
in my own house too!
I bear you 13 children.
How can you
betray me like this?
Somebody, help me up.
Go ahead. Go ahead.
Why don't you give everything
we've got to him?
Your fat little catamite!
"What will it be, my dearest darling,
my Vladimir Grigorevich?
My wife's heart on a platter?
Her kidneys, with salt?
But of course, my dear Chertkov.
Whatever pleases you.
The china, the estate,
permanent copyright
on anything I've ever written?
Oh, anything for you,
my love."
Give that to me.
No.
Give it to me, you little weasel!
Sofya!
Give it to me! Give it to me!
Sofya.
Now...
Can I have...?
Can I not have some...?
You'll kill him, Mama.
Well, that's what you want,
isn't it? You want him to die!
Lev.
It's all right, it's all right.
Let's get him out of here.
You don't deceive me
for one moment.
I know exactly
what you're doing.
I want to see the will.
It is my right as his wife
in the sight of God.
What are you afraid of?
You.
I'm afraid of you.
The press are
bloodthirsty, Sofya.
Had I wished,
I could have demolished you.
You make it easy.
Then tell them anything
you want. Go ahead. Ruin us!
I have too much respect
for Lev Nikolayevich!
You're lucky!
Why can't my husband
see you for what you are?
If I had a wife like you,
I would've blown my brains out!
Or gone to America.
I hope you're feeling better.
Mm.
Do you like the opera?
Yes.
I'm very sorry
about everything.
This aria is so beautiful.
It's about a woman who's been abandoned
by the man she loves.
Everyone finds that
very moving...
in the opera.
Our life together
has become intolerable.
Sit down, Valentin.
Really, I'm expected
at Telyatinki.
No, no, no, please.
Come, enjoy your dinner.
We've just had a disagreement,
like all married couples.
Despite good cause for it,
I have never stopped loving you.
Of course.
But God knows
you don't make it easy.
Why should it be easy?
I am the work of your life,
you're the work of mine.
That's what love is.
I should go.
No, sit down.
Oh, so that's what love is?
Eh?
Does that surprise you, boy?
I thought it might be
a touch quieter, but...
God bless you.
Bless you.
He's right, though.
If we can't live a decent, quiet life,
if I can't work and find some
peace, then I shall go away.
Go?
Not to Chertkov, but I shall go.
Go where?
Dushan says you're killing me!
Then go!
Go anywhere you please!
I hate you!
I hate what you've become!
Countess.
Go. No.
Dushan!
Oh, God.
Countess?
Countess! Is she all right?
Is she all right?
Sofya. Sofya, are you all right?
Open your eyes.
Oh! Oh, my back!
Oh, my... Oh!
Oh, my back.
You're lying on a fork.
Sit up and you'll
improve markedly.
If you'll be good enough
to take her upstairs.
Come along, countess,
come with me.
Masha.
I'm sorry.
It was terrible there today.
They loved each other so much,
I'm sure of it, I'm sure they do,
but you see what it becomes,
and you just wish that you could...
Is something
the matter?
Masha?
I'm... I'm going back
to Moscow.
What?
Chertkov spoke with me
this afternoon.
He said I could
be more useful there.
Which means...
Means he's punishing us.
He's punishing me.
He's punishing me for befriending
Sofya Andreyevna.
This is Chertkov.
We've both disappointed him,
but I don't care.
I don't care either,
but you can't leave.
I'm going to talk to him. I'm going to
make him make you stay.
No. I want to go.
Yes. What?
I'm leaving the movement.
Sit down, sit down.
You can't leave Tolstoy.
I'm not.
You can't leave.
No, I'm not.
When I read his confession,
it moved me, Valya.
Yes.
When he was searching
for freedom.
Freedom from anger,
freedom from attachment,
freedom from all the superstition
and the nonsense of the Church.
I mean, it moved me
so much.
And that's what I thought
it would be about.
I mean, isn't that
what it's about?
Freedom and love?
They mix it all up.
Come with me.
Please?
I can't.
I'm going to my room.
Wait.
Masha.
Masha, please. I can't.
I need you.
I know you do.
I know.
A-Y. A-Y.
A-Y.
What was it?
I don't remember.
Was it your...?
No, no, no.
You rest now.
You rest.
Is everything in order?
Good afternoon,
Lev Nikolayevich.
Is it?
Remember that this will ensure
that your complete works
will live in the public domain.
Monumentous.
Your works are the birthright
of the Russian people.
And now they will
possess them forever.
Yes?
I need a pen.
Oh. Of course, of course.
I, uh...
What?
I don't seem
to have a pen.
You're a secretary.
How can you not have a pen?
He's a secretary too.
Ask him.
Valentin Fedorovich,
do you have a pen?
I...
Yes.
Yes, I have a pen.
Are you all right?
I'm a conspirator.
Nothing more.
Lev Nikolayevich.
May I ask you a question that has nothing
to do with the work?
Of course, my dear.
Do you love your wife?
You see, when I was
courting Sofya,
she was so young
and so pure
it just seemed impossible
that I could ever have her.
I didn't want to tell her
how I felt, and yet...
I wanted to tell her
nothing else.
So I wrote down
a string of letters
and asked her
if she would decipher them.
At first, she was completely
confused and thought it was
some sort of game or something.
So I gave her a clue.
One clue.
"The first two Y's," I said,
"stand for 'your youth,"'
and that was all I said.
And then...
the most miraculous thing
happened.
She simply spoke
the phrase:
"Your youth and your desire
for happiness
cruelly remind me of my age
and the impossibility
of happiness for me."
The entire phrase, my phrase.
As if she'd read my mind.
In that moment, we both knew
we would always be together.
And for the first few years,
we were
incredibly,
terrifyingly...
happy.
And now this.
I'm leaving Telyatinki.
Really?
Yes. I'm going to Moscow.
She's leading you around
by the nose, my boy.
Look, you say that
the movement is about love.
And it is. The love
that he teaches us.
The love that binds
all mankind together.
I've never met mankind.
I've only ever met men or women.
Imperfect men, imperfect women.
Yes. But Lev Nikolayevich
also teaches us
that love cannot be weak-minded.
It cannot be stupid.
Go. We will miss you.
Our naive sentimentalist.
Keep clear.
BO Y:
Give it to me.
Leovochka?
Hm?
Kashnikov wants to buy the rights to
your work after your death.
Oh, then I shall try and die
as soon as is convenient.
Oh, come on, don't be silly.
Come, look.
Look, he has offered
1 million rubles.
How can you not be pleased?
I don't write for publishers,
I write for people.
Well, where are
you going?
Valentin is in the library.
He wants to see me.
Fine! Fine, go ahead and let your
wretched family starve.
I don't see anyone starving
in this house.
On the contrary,
our privilege revolts me.
Well, you're the first
to the trough!
Always have been.
Now, what is it, my boy?
You look unhappy.
What do you
want to tell me?
Sofya!
What are you doing?
How could you
do this to me?
You're not well.
You... You just hurt me
again and again.
You tear pieces off me
until there's nothing left.
I don't know who I am anymore.
I read your diary.
I know what
you've done.
You behave like this,
I have no choice.
Now give me the gun.
No!
Please, countess.
Give me the gun, please.
I'd like you to
stay here tonight.
Yes, of course.
Valentin.
Get up.
What?
He's leaving.
Shh!
Pack essentials only.
Nothing that isn't
absolutely necessary.
Please, we must hurry.
Where will you go?
Your coat, Papa.
We don't need a plan,
we just go.
A lantern, I think.
It's very dark tonight.
And the apparatus
for giving an enema.
Everything's ready.
Dushan, you all right?
Please, go steady.
You all right?
Papa?
He's changed
his mind.
He's going back
to the house.
Do you want
to go back?
No.
This life is behind me now.
Help me up.
Yes, of course.
Give this to Sofya.
Yes.
Be well, be well.
Don't cry, don't cry.
I'll send for you when I can.
Drive on.
He's gone.
For good?
I think so, yes.
Oh, Sasha, darling, I know you know
where your father is.
So, darling, please,
this is not a time to
play games, please?
Countess, I have this for you.
My position in the house
has become intolerable.
What I'm doing now is what
people have commonly done,
leave their worldly life behind
to spend their last days
in peace and solitude.
The pond.
Mama!
Countess!
Please, Mama!
Please understand this
and don't come after me,
even if you find out where I am.
Your coming would only
make our position worse
and would not alter my decision.
Mother!
I beg you to forgive me
for everything I've done to you,
just as I forgive you
with all my soul
for everything you've done to me.
Countess!
Mama!
I have her!
Here! Here! Take her! Take her.
Mama!
Ivan, Ivan, go to the house.
Get a doctor, quickly, quickly!
Turn her.
Turn her over, come on.
Oh, God. Thank God.
Ivan, go to the station.
Find out which train he took.
For God's sake.
Come, come, come.
Let's get you to bed.
Ready and up. There we...
Let's go, there.
Thank you.
Here, tea.
She's exhausted
herself.
She slept for
nearly four hours.
Well, I'm glad she can sleep.
The pain subsides a little.
The noise subsides
a little.
Come in.
A message, miss.
For me?
From your father.
My darling Sasha, I have stopped
to rest at Shamardino.
I'll wait for you to join me here.
Please ask Valentin to stay
and look after your mother.
When you arrive, we'll continue
the journey south together.
Your loving father.
They've all gone.
I'm here.
Oh...
You're writing to your girl.
Oh, how lovely.
I'm not sure she is my girl.
But you believe
you'll see her again.
I very much hope so.
Yes.
I know you know
where he is, Valentin.
Sofya Andreyevna...
I won't ask you to betray his trust.
I just need you
to go to him. I do.
I have to see him.
I have to talk to him.
I won't make a scene.
You can promise him that. I...
I just want to see him.
"Tolstoy abandons home,
whereabouts unknown."
"The sage of Yasnaya Polyana
takes flight."
That's Tolstoy.
I hope it's not
too much for him.
Ah... Where are we?
It's all right.
Everything's fine.
Shh, shh, shh.
Let me take your temperature.
Come on.
Be mindful of these steps.
We've come
to the end of the world.
This is the stationmaster.
He's very kind. He said we may have
his home for as long as we want it.
There are no inns nearby,
so we are lucky.
Yes, very lucky.
Yes.
You'll be comfortable
here, Papa.
The rest of us, we'll find cots,
or sleep in the station.
And then we'll be on our way.
Yes. Yes, Papa.
We'll be on our way.
Excuse me?
I'd like to send
a telegram, please.
Uh...
At Astapovo. Stop.
Tolstoy ill. Stop.
Temperature high.
You can send it to Countess Sofya
Andreyevna Tolstoya,
Yasnaya Polyana, Tula Province.
Please come back.
Concern for Lev Nikolayevich's
health has been expressed
by people as diverse as
Mr. Henry James
and Mr. Joseph Conrad.
Lev Nikolayevich's temperature currently
stands at 40 degrees Celsius.
That is 104 degrees
Fahrenheit.
His blood pressure, which is hypertonic,
is 180 over 100.
However, it should be added,
Lev Nikolayevich's manner
and mental acuity
Bulgakov!
is as great as ever.
Where is he? Take me to him.
This way.
He left. It's astonishing.
He actually finally left.
He was very sick, too sick to travel.
It's a triumph for the movement.
He looks so small.
Papa.
Oh, it's you.
My dear friend,
what is all of this?
Well, I needed
to see you.
Thank you.
We have so much to do.
Have you seen Sofya?
I've made a point not to.
She'll come.
I don't know when she'll come,
but she'll come. I know that.
And we'll be ready.
Ready for what?
I'm sorry, but I'm afraid
it's time for your enema.
Don't apologize,
my friend.
Your enemas have become the
news of the world.
My only concern is getting
the copy back to London in time.
Good morning, gentlemen.
I'm sure you will all be
as relieved as I am
that Lev Nikolayevich slept
a relatively peaceful night.
His temperature remains
40 degrees Celsius.
And his blood pressure
is also hypertonic.
That having been said, however,
his mind remains agile
and full of fortitude.
It's the countess.
Of course, we have to remember...
Is she here?
It's the countess.
Let's see.
Where is she?
It's the countess!
Which car is it?
The Countess!
There she is.
Countess Sofya.
She's coming this way.
Not before she stops to tell them lies,
catalog my atrocities.
Let me talk to her.
I want to see my husband.
Yes.
I'll, um...
I want to see him now!
Countess! Countess!
Oh, Valentin.
I want to see him, please.
I'm not sure now
is the right time, countess.
Yes, it is.
It's the right time for me.
Have you had any contact?
It might be a better idea, countess,
I really think, if you just waited...
He only left because of you.
Countess!
I want to see my husband.
He's too weak
to see you now, Mother.
He's not too weak to see you.
Not too weak to see that... Pfft.
Do you really want
to do this here?
So I am the leper outside the gate, while
he sleeps with the devil himself.
Chertkov is here because Father
asked him to be here.
Is that true?
Yes.
Well, did you tell him that
I nearly drowned in the pond?
We didn't need to.
It's been in all the papers.
Please, let me take you back.
What did he say?
He said that if you killed
yourself, he'd be upset.
He'd be upset?
Horribly upset.
But he could not have
acted other than he did.
I want to see him.
He's my husband.
He's not your husband.
Oh, you're unbearable.
And you are a stone-hearted
bitch of a daughter.
I lost five children!
Why couldn't one of them
have been you?
Did she just say that?
Are you finished?
Valentin, would you
take me back, please?
Yes, of course.
Please, make way.
Make way. Make way.
I've behaved rather badly, haven't I?
No, countess.
No, don't worry.
Here. For you.
Is this clean?
Of course it's clean.
Dushan,
what's the matter?
Listen to him.
I'm supposed to be
a doctor, for God's sake.
Sofya?
What is it?
She's come, hasn't she?
She's here.
You're imagining things.
Sasha!
Where is your mother?
She's at home.
If she wants to see me,
I can't refuse her.
Yes.
Is she going to come here?
I don't...
There's no way to...
There's no way to what?
I'd like to send
another telegram, please.
At Astapovo. Stop.
Tolstoy ill. Stop.
Heartbreaking. Stop.
Please come.
You can send it to Masha...
Maria Filipovna Melinova.
You lied to him.
Keep your voice down.
He wants to see her.
You heard him say it.
And what exactly do you
think she'll bring him here?
I don't know. They've been
married for 48 years.
I'll tell you exactly what she'll bring.
Vanity, fuss and noise.
She promised me
she would not...
Promised you what?
What, what?
You've seen her at
close quarters, my boy.
Do you really think that she's
capable of restraining herself
from acting like a madwoman?
They have a whole life together.
Why do you have to deny that?
You have become a victim
of her romantic nonsense.
And you willfully forget that she wants
to destroy everything we do.
She travels here with that
unctuous little priest.
We'll keep the priest away.
These people are vultures, Valentin.
And they wait to descend
till the very last moment
to welcome him back
to the Church.
This is their fantasy.
Keep the priest away.
A deathbed recantation.
Do you have any idea
the damage that that will do?
Everything that he has
dreamed of,
everything that we have
worked for will be gone.
A simple, noble death
is what we want.
That's what he wants.
No, you want
to create an icon.
And you want people
to kneel in front of an
image that you create.
But he doesn't want that.
He never has wanted that.
It'll give him no peace.
He wants to see her.
Let her come.
I will do everything in
my power to prevent that.
That image
you want to create,
it's going to look
more like you than him.
Valentin?
It can't be right.
His fever is down.
Yes.
But, uh...
his pulse,
you see, it's...
My dear.
Shall I call her?
He wouldn't know
who she is anyway.
Yes.
Bring a coat. It's cold.
Countess. Countess, could you
give me some information?
Countess, is he dying?
Is he dead?
Leovochka!
Leovochka, my darling.
Oh, my darling,
please forgive me, please!
I'm a fool. I'm a selfish woman,
but I love you, darling.
Please believe me.
Please, please understand me,
and please forgive my
wickedness and my badness.
Mother.
Control yourself.
Am I shouting?
You have to control yourself.
Yes.
Yes, I will.
You don't speak, but I hear you.
Do you love me, Leovochka?
I never stopped,
my little bird.
And you will never stop?
No.
Never.
Nor ever leave me again?
No, never again.
Good.
Let's go home.
First cessation.
Second cessation.
Shh. Shh.
Ten minutes after 6
in the morning,
a great soul passed
from our world.
Lev Nikolayevich Tolstoy...
Masha.
Masha. Oh, Masha.
I'm sorry, but he is gone.
I know.
But I came for you, Valya.
I came for you too.
God go with you,
Sofya Andreyevna.
God bless you!
We'll pray for you, countess!