Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Magic Stars Team @ Viki.com
♫ Waking up before midnight, I’m as confused as the ocean ♫
♫ The stars forget to shine ♫
♫ We were children ♫
♫ We’ve been children born on this boat ♫
♫ The ark that people talk about is like a small boat ♫
♫ You could hear whispering through deck ♫
♫ Its flag sways in rainstorms ♫
♫ But humans’ endless disputes ♫
♫ push you and me to two most distant sides with ♫
♫ heresies, extremes and abandoned regrets ♫
♫ When have that thousands of thousands layers of color ♫
♫ quietly blossomed through the end of dark night? ♫
♫ On the top of clouds, ♫
♫ that ray is like a crown ♫
[Magic Star]
~ Episode 50 ~
Bai Ze!
- Hey!
- Hey! Bai Ze!
- Bai Ze!
One's body, hair, and skin were given by one's parents.
You want us to kill ourselves.
I can't do it!
If you are able, kill me!
What did you say?
I said for you to kill me!
Bai Ze!
- Bai...
- It's fine.
Don't worry. It will be fine. I can control the situation.
This is what you asked for.
I gave you a chance to kill yourself but you refused it.
Then don't blame me if you will be in heart rendering pain under my sickle.
I have grown to this age but never really felt heart rendering pain.
Just let me feel it then.
Die!
Bring it on.
I'm fine.
Huh?
Eh?
- You are fine, right?
- I'm fine.
He is just a hallucination.
That's why he really can't kill us.
Only we can kill ourselves.
Then was I almost tricked by him earlier in committing suicide?
And also, only a person like you will get scared like that.
So embarrassing.
Hmp! You all actually saw through it.
You are Bai Ze, right?
I have a letter here that your father, Bai De Ming, left before he died.
I'll give it to you then.
Don't take it!
Could it be that you don't want to see
what words your father left you?
Don't believe him, Bai Ze.
Have you forgotten? When we were in the Royal Tomb,
Luan Jia exactly used this kind of trick to lure everyone to release her.
In here, the trap she loves to use the most is to let people unable to resist temptations
and take the initiative to release her.
That's right.
You rascal, just you wait!
- He's gone.
- Hey, if Bai Ze touched that letter, what would have happened?
I don't know, either.
Maybe his soul would have gotten stolen by him and gotten locked up.
It is also possible that nothing would've happened.
Zhan Xiong Fei, how did you know that this was a trap?
I don't know, either. Maybe an intuition.
Enough already. Stop feeling so happy about it.
If you ask me, it must be because you are so used to tricking and swindling others
that you give no attention to these little tricks.
You are the one who tricks and swindles. I was just able to see through it.
How come you are like this?
I am just like this, so what?
You are even answering back? If you are able, then hit me.
- Hmp!
- How can I dare to hit you?
You haven't even accepted my request yet.
- Accept what?
Accept to be my--
I'll tell you guys later.
Oh...
Let's go.
- I can't walk anymore. I want to drink some water.
- Hold on for a little while longer.
- We will be there soon.
- I don't even have the energy to talk anymore.
Maybe there is something to eat in front.
It won't help either if we keep sitting here.
- Hurry and move.
- Let's go. Hold on for a little while more.
So tired.
- I can't move anymore.
- Hold on.
Can't move anymore!
I don't want to walk anymore.
Zi Su...
Just sleep.
Once you are asleep, you won't be able to wake up again.
Stop right there!
Laughing Netherworld?
How come it's you again?
You... How come you are awake again?
Could it be that you are a descendant of Master Luan Jia?
Hey, Zhan Xiong Fei, hurry and wake up!
We were tricked by Laughter Netherworld!
Bai Ze, wake up. Bai Ze!
Yuan Shuai. Yuan Shua! Wake up!
Wake up, Zi Su! Zi Su!
Are you very anxious right now?
If anything bad happens to them, I will...
Stop wasting your energy.
Just you? You will never be able to hit me.
But I will also show you some mercy.
I'll give you one chance to change fate.
This way, you don't need to fall
into an endless void like them.
The method is also very easy.
You change it by yourself.
Can you see this?
This book is all inclusive.
Everyone's fates are inside it.
Right now, no need for money or your life.
I'll let you change it for free.
Just once.
Look at it.
After looking at it, you will know your fate just like them.
You actually want to bewitch me.
Hey... This... How come this didn't work on you?
This book has no effect on me.
But it seems to be very useful to you.
Hey, Miss!  You... don't touch it.
This book is quite dangerous.
It can suddenly explode. Put it down first.
It was you who threw this to me.
Just put it down first. We can amicably discuss things.
There's nothing to discuss.
Hurry and let my friends wake up from their dreams!
They can't immediately wake up just because I let them wake up.
Put it down first. Let's talk about other things first.
Do you have dreams?
Dreams?
Stop your nonsense.
If you won't change it for me, I'll change it by myself.
Don't. Don't. Don't. Those were just things made up by me.
If I really can change them, then how come I didn't change mine first?
Just put it down first.
We can discuss things amicably.
If you won't change it, then I'll tear it.
Don't!
Ha? Ha!
Don't...
Don't stop? Sure.
Not don't stop.
Stop! Stop!
When did I become Ting*?
(* means stop in Chinese.)
Don't! I know that your name isn't Ting Ting.
Don't tear! Don't tear it anymore!
Don't tear it anymore!
M-My life is already this hard.
How come you are still bullying me?
What I said is all true.
Hundreds of years ago, I was also like you all; a sincere youth.
The me that time was very optimistic, worked hard to learn,
focused on getting achievements and fame.
I only wished that one day, I can top the civil examination
and do some achievements for my family and the country.
But I never thought that corrupt officials were rampant and oppressive.
They switched my exam answers
and gave it to a descendant of the Prime Minister.
So pitiful.
Telling a story?
Don't tear.
I am talking about myself.
Afterwards, I hid inside the mountains.
I thought about this from all angles and read books as my companion every day.
I read the Book of Changes and the Chinese Prophecy Book to research on the truth of the world
and these philosophies.
Do you really think I am illiterate?
Don't tear!
I subsequently spent several days thinking from all angles.
Finally one day, I reached enlightenment.
Hence, I took up my pen and paper
then predicted and wrote the destiny of the citizens of the world.
At this time, a monster suddenly appeared in front of me.
He had a very fierce and ugly appearance and he took me away
to write books of praises for him to be distributed to the world.
My conscience made me refuse him.
He then took me away and placed me in a bitter cold hell
until Master Luan Jia came to save me.
You say, isn't my... my life very hard?
Enough already. Stop talking.
Can you make my friends wake up or not?
Why is my life this hard?!
How come a distinguished Death Deity is crying now?
Wh-Why can't I cry?
I am also human.
Oh, right. I am not human.
Even if I am not human, I also have feelings and desires. I can also cry!
Don't cry now.
Are you saving my friends or not?
Yes. Yes. Okay. I have a solution. I have a solution.
You have to return the book to me first.
Give it to me. Give it to me.
Return it to me first before I can save them.
- Give it to me...
- What are you doing? Let go.
- What are you doing?!
- Let go.
- Give...You give it to me...
- Laughing Netherworld.
- Huh?
Look at what this is.
[Laughing Netherworld]
Miss, are you really going to make all of us perish?
- A Ji Ya!
- Are you alright?
- Are you all alright?
What happened?
We all got bewitched by Laughing Netherworld.
- It's him again.
- Where is he then?
It's a long story. I'll tell you all about it later.
Look. What is that?
Let's go inside and take a look. Let's go.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Magic Stars Team @ Viki.com
Welcome to the Icy Snow Castle.
I never thought that you were able to get through all four levels.
You really are good.
Stop pretending to be good.
Whether true or not is fine.
What can you all do to me?
That was just a test given to you by an imaginary world
while the real me is in front of you all.
What can you really do to me?
The Icy Babel Tower will soon be fixed.
By that time, I can go defend myself to Supreme God.
Let him know the crimes of you humans
and give me back justice. When that time comes,
all three worlds will walk into destruction with me.
Luan Jia,
to tell you the truth, I sincerely pity you.
I won't fall for that trick of yours. Just drop it.
How about this instead? If you can make me laugh,
I will let you all go.
I think that even the funniest joke
will not be able to make the corner of your mouth go up.
The reason that I pity you is because you can only see the weakness of humans.
You cannot see the good thing about being human.
Shut up.
Humans all know that deities should love them.
I really don't understand.
An individual like you who destroys the world and plunges people into misery,
what right do you have to call yourself a deity?
I told you to shut up!
- Zi Su!
- Older Bro Fei!
If my guess is right, you also loved this land once.
You also loved a man before, Emperor You Ran.
Don't say it anymore!
In the past, you and Emperor You Ran were so in love.
I never thought that just because of the Magic Stars, you made a grave mistake
and suffered punishment from Heaven.
That's why the legends were all true?
The Emperor told me that the 9-winter disorder of the royal descendants is this kind of symptom.
It was contracted because of this skeleton
and unable to be cured for thousands of years.
These were all what Emperor You Ran deserved.
That time, I went through hardships to steal the Magic Stars for him.
But in the end, what? Just because of individual selfish interest,
he used the power of the Magic Stars to bring disaster to the world.
Aren't these all grudges thousands of years ago?
Haven't you thought that since so many years have passed,
why not letting yourself off and just forget about him?
I also wanted to forget him.
But he is like a spirit that's always by my side.
As time goes by, the torment lasts longer.
Even if you can't forget him, you should have at least forgiven him.
Forgive?
He never even said sorry.
How am I supposed to forgive?
Tell me, how can I forgive him?
Okay. I will bear the consequences.
- A Ji Ya!
- Don't.
Since I am the descendant of Emperor You Ran and you can't forgive him,
just let me die for my ancestor to pay for his crimes.
What are you doing?!
Little Jia.
Emperor You Ran.
Little Jia,
sorry.
It's really you.
Forgive my betrayal one thousand years ago.
I continued to be punished by Heaven and sealed inside the skeleton.
I have been repenting for a thousand years.
I pray to get Heaven's forgiveness.
But the thing I want to get the most is your forgiveness.
After all, a thousand years have passed.
All of these are debts I made, I should be the one to pay for them.
It's really you.
You left just because you wanted to.
You betrayed me just like that.
And now, you even want to beg for my forgiveness.
Very soon... I will use the divine power of the five Magic Stars
to destroy that so called Heaven and Earth,
and you will witness all of these things.
I will let you admit that I am right.
Little Jia, why must you do this?
Why must you decide for everyone's fate on behalf of Heaven?
You will be punished for this.
I already have been punished.
I had enough.
Today, I will decide everything.
Previously, I, Luan Jia, was so in love with you
but your heart was with the world.
In the end, you got what you wanted; obtained the world and
became the human's emperor. But what about now?
Look at now. Won't the world soon still be plunged into chaos?
I know that I was wrong.
But when I self examined my fault,
everything was already too late.
Little Jia, stop now.
I don't want you to become like me in the future;
regretting, suffering, being in non-stop anxiety.
You're wrong.
I don't plan to live to begin with.
After I destroy this world,
I, Luan Jia, will also cease to exist.
Then just let those people go.
Could it be that you really are this heartless?
Put it down.
Until now, you are still helping them.
While you haven't made a grave mistake yet, hurry and stop this.
Never.
If you dare to stop me again,
I won't spare you, either.
Must you really do this?
Weren't you this resolute in refusing me back then?
Little Jia, if you give up in destroying the world,
I will stay by your side forever. Never betraying you.
At this step,
can we still... still continue our past love?
Little Jia...
Luan Jia!
You devil! You actually used ice and snow to seal the whole capital.
And then next, you used the Snow Spots Disease to cause trouble.
I will let your body shatter!
Qian Yi Shou, I am going to kill you!
Little Jia.
Emperor You Ran!
Emperor You Ran.
Little Jia,
I know that you have forgiven me.
Yes.
Don't talk anymore.
I won't let you leave me.
What should I do?
If I can be allowed to return
to the time I saw you for the first time,
I will re-choose
to give up fighting for the Magic Stars, and
give up in battling to rule the world.
I just want to stay by your side.
Ma Da Dao! Wake up! Are you crazy now?! It's me!
After 1,000 years,
I thought I had already let everything go.
Right now, what I can be sure of is...
I want to be with you.
Magic Stars?
Thank you, Teen Heaven Strategy Envoys.
Zhan Xiong Fei, I'm leaving the Magic Stars to you to protect the Emperor.
This is also my main reason for stealing the Magic Stars from the start.
- A Ji Ya!
A Ji Ya, are you alright?
Where is this?
- Why am I here?
- Why did you hit me?
- What happened?
Why did you hit me?
You are conscious now.
I still find it a bit unbelievable. This Luan Jia still wanted to destroy the world a while ago.
Right now, she just suddenly disappeared.
I think that maybe she can now be with Emperor You Ran forever like she always wanted.
She finally was able to find her faith back.
That's way more important than living.
Did I... see love earlier?
I'll go get the Magic Stars.
- Xiong Fei!
- Zhan Xiong Fei!
- Older Bro Fei!
Xiong Fei, are you alright?
Fellow Heaven Strategy Envoys, I'm going to pick this ready-made treasure now.
And also, I'm going to do another good thing. That is to send you all to your death!
Lord!
This place will be collapsing soon! Hurry and escape!
Don't run!
Lord, here!
Hurry!
Buddy... Buddy...
Buddy, come out.
Go. Go.
Go...
I can't leave anymore.
Qian Xun is a good woman,
but I don't have that fate.
You must treat her well.
The person she is waiting for is you.
You never were a chivalrous person.
I really want to hit you!
Go!
- Ma Da Dao...
- Leave...
Qian Xun is still waiting for us to go back and drink wine with her.
Being able to meet her in this lifetime is a blessing I earned from my past life.
You must treat her well.
Or else...
I will not let you go even as a ghost.
What are you saying?!
Let's go.
- I won't leave! I can't leave him!
- Ma Da Dao!
- No!
- It will collapse soon!
Ma Da Dao!
- I don't want to!
- If we still don't leave, it will be too late!
- Go now! Ma Da Dao!
- Leave.
- Go!
- I can't leave!
- Qian Yi Shou!
- Hurry and go, Ma Da Dao!
Qian Yi Shou! I'm not leaving!
I'm not leaving! I want to die with him!
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Magic Stars Team @ Viki.com
- Zha Bu Ha!
- Gu Li!
Gu Li!
You are finally back.
How are you? Are you doing well?
How were you able to return?
Good thing A Ji Ya and her friends destroyed the Icy Snow Castle.
I then had a chance to escape.
- Gu Li!
- Let's not separate anymore forever.
We will not separate forever.
Eunuch Cao, it's really great.
It must be that the Heaven Strategy Envoys were able to eliminate that cold devil Luan Jia.
Congratulations, Your Majesty! Heaven really was watching.
The citizens can be saved.
Once Bai Ze and the others return, I must really reward them.
Your Majesty,
this demon youth Zhan Xiong Fei...
Eunuch Cao,
stop gossiping in front of me next time.
One must be straightforward and upright.
I dare not.
The sealing of the capital previously by ice snow really woke me up.
Zhan Xiong Fei detests evil and dares to take responsibility just like Bai Ze.
Just to get the Magic Stars, he almost died numerous times.
Then tell me, is Zhan Xiong Fei being from the demon or human clan still important?
That's right. Since time immemorial, heroes comes from the youth.
One doesn't need to ask their whereabouts.
Their background is naturally not important, not important.
- Don't move!
- What are you doing?
Are you trying to revolt?
How dare you all!
Men!
Stop shouting already!
Old thing, hello.
Just those measly imperial guards of yours, they all have been bribed by my Lord.
Ding Song, you... you are publicly revolting?
You are making it sound so bad.
I just want Emperor to cooperate with me in completing a huge endeavor.
Do what endeavor?
Actually, very easy. I just want to see your head.
Ding Song, you old traitor!! I'll fight with you!
Eunuch Cao! Eunuch Cao!
Let an old thing like you taste how it feels to be frozen, too.
Lord, I think this damn Emperor will surely be unwilling to submit to you.
I so want to see how a distinguished Emperor dies.
Lord, I have 100 ways to kill him.
Emperor, do you still have any questions?
Don't be too happy yet.
The Heaven Strategy Envoys will come to save me.
Or course.
How can I not let those teens accompany Your Majesty
to go to the afterlife?
- Take him!
- Tie him!
Your Majesty, look.
Does this imperial robe suit me?
Traitor, just you?
Aren't you afraid of being laughed at by the world?
I'll give you some advice.
You won't be able to stably occupy this kingdom.
What you said is quite reasonable.
Forget it.
If you ask me, it's fine not to sit on this throne.
Do you think I really want to compete with you for this emperor's throne?
You said that the world will laugh at me?
Let me tell. I am here to conquer them.
I am going to use the power of the magic stars to open the gates to the demon world.
By that time, the mortal world will become a huge slave world
and I will be this world's master.
Don't be rash.
If you go out like this, it will also not provide any help.
Leave with me first and then let's think of a way.
Let's go.
You're wrong.
The world has chivalrous and just people.
No one will submit to you.
Someone will naturally stand out to resist you until the end!
That's why, I don't mind killing half of the people in this world.
Traitor!!
The hearts of people are confused and dirty anyway.
It should be cleansed already.
My Emperor,
just lessen your words.
I'll have to trouble you to bask in the sun and get blown by the wind here.
Suffer hunger and cold, and suffer pain
until your Heaven Strategy Envoys come to save you.
You will then be released from your suffering.
You two... are you trying to make me your bait?
I already told you that I surely will let that group of Teen Heaven Strategy Envoy
accompany you to the afterlife.
Traitor!
Your Majesty, hurry and use this chance to look at this wonderful scenery.
After three days, by noontime, I will send you to your death.
Zhan Xiong Fei! Yuan Shuai!
Thirteenth Older Sis!
You guys are back.
Something huge has happened to the capital.
Ding Song is back.
Ding Song is back, isn't he?
What really happened in the capital?
Ding Song arrested His Majesty and placed him in the public square.
He wants to execute him.
Huh?
Oh, right. Where is Zhan Xiong Fei and Zi Su?
They are both inside.
Don't say so much anymore. Let's hurry and discuss how to save His Majesty.
Let's go.
Oh, right.
Where is Qian Yi Shou?
How come I didn't see Qian Yi Shou?
You will never see him again.
He pushed me away and saved me.
But he instead got toppled over by an ice post and suffered grave injuries.
My life was given by him,
but he himself didn't survive at the end.
He's dead.
Are you saying he's dead? Are you saying he's dead?!
What else did he say?
Did he mention me?
He said that in this life time, he only loved you.
And also,
he asked me to take care of you.
Hey, isn't it not good for us to be here?
The most dangerous place is the safest place.
- Do you have an idea already?
- No.
But I feel that we can find something here.
My older bro has already been tied in the public square for one whole day.
Let's just make our move during the night.
No. Ding Song is very scheming.
He surely placed ambushes in the public square.
No matter if we go during daytime or nighttime,
as long as we go, we surely will just be walking into his trap.
Then... Then what should we do?
Ding Song has controlled the whole capital.
He surely has assigned guards around the public square.
How could that be?
Those imperial guards used to be very loyal subjects.
How could they be following Ding Song's orders now?
Right now, there are only a few people left in this world who has faith.
They only listen to the strong one.
Ding Song has already obtained the five Magic Stars. He is already unrivaled.
Zi Su, we cannot face him head on.
Bai Ze, can this wooden bird fly?
Of course, it can.
Can you make a huge one overnight?
You were thinking in the same direction as me.
I'll go look for materials.
I'll go, too.
Lord, it's already noon time.
Ma Shun, let me make a bet with you.
Guess from what direction those kids will come from.
Lord, I dare not make this bet with you.
Because if I do, you surely will lose.
I am guessing that those rascals Zhan Xiong Fei and his friends have died inside the Ice Bound Valley.
Or else, how come after leaking the news for three days, we haven't seen even their shadow?
Even if they are still alive, they surely have gone home to drink milk.
Your Majesty, did you hear that?
I am afraid that the Teen  Heaven Strategy Envoys that you are putting too much of your hopes on
have forgotten you, their master.
Lord, the prisoner is gone.
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Magic Stars Team @ Viki.com
♫ How long can my friends around me to accompany me? ♫
♫ I’m tired of hearing those comforting words ♫
♫ I’m pulled between courage and collapse repeatedly ♫
♫ I cry out to myself to hang in there ♫
♫ I’m still awake at 3 in the early morning ♫
♫ I can only expect for a good night sleep but not having it ♫
♫ If I’m not careful, I’ll be disturbed once I think about you ♫
♫ Memory has been overturned into a kind of sin ♫
♫ Having loved one very much is wrong but so what ♫
♫ Loneliness is also just a process ♫
♫ We still have next person waiting for us ♫
♫ I’ll remember those wonderful things ♫
♫ Shedding tears isn’t need ♫
♫ Thank you for your choosing ♫
♫ Don’t force myself to give blessing ♫
♫ Be a mature person ♫
♫ Having loved one very much is worth the pain and so happy ♫
♫ I need to learn to let go those I can’t part with ♫
♫ Having loved one very much is wrong but so what ♫
♫ Loneliness is also just a process ♫
♫ We still have next person waiting for us ♫
♫ With a little regret, I’m more complete ♫