There's the bridge.
And the train tracks are just there.
This is the way?
Yes.
And from there, which way is north?
That side.
We walk there?
You going to
the United States?
Yes.
Yeah, right .
- Thank you .
- I hope it all works out .
- Take care .
Thank you.
Now do everything I do .
Eyes open !
Pay attention !
Come here!
Come on! Let's get up?
Quick !
We take this?
Wake up!
Don't just stand there, man !
Move!
The last .
Come on you !
Shit !
You said you'd go up
first.
I was ready to climb
and you just stood there .
And what do you want ?
We run up over you?
Wake up, man.
The train has left us
back here and it was your fault .
I don't want to return to Guatemala.
Here, it's very good.
But further north ,
is really cool.
This is pretty good.
Look .
And you , Juan?
what do you want to do over there?
If I tell you, it won't happen .
- And what is this guy ?
- I dunno ...
He's gone.
Guys!
Here comes the train!
Run!
Climb ! This time we won't miss!
Now, it's easy!
Run!
Climb ! Climb !
Go ! Fast ! Up !
Safe ! hold on !
Move up !
Hang on though !
Up !
Osvaldo ...
Samuel ...
Juan .
It's hot !
Super hot .
- I'm at the top .
- It burns!
How to cool it , no?
- Oh , I'll drive it .
You're crazy .
Shit , move !
You can see everything
from up here . Amazing !
Here you can see the mountains .
Careful you don't fall .
That's cool !
Thank you.
Thank you .
Thank you very much .
Fifty .
Five .
- Sixty .
- Another five .
Thirty-five.
Seventy -nine .
What you got?
Where are you going?
She's going to see her boyfriend .
I think she likes him .
He'll snake you, man.
Are you hungry ?
Want to eat ?
Yes ?
Come on.
I'm not sharing my food
with him .
He didn't help us at all.
You too, man . You haven't helped
anything. And are eating.
Take it.
Want some water ?
Here.
What?
Why's he meddling this guy?
He's not even aware of it .
- Here ?
- Calm . Relax .
My Heart ?
My heart is fine.
Well
How you say?
And your heart ?
What is " lek " ?
What's " lek " mean?
Only " lek " even alone ?
Oh, yeah !
Pass me one of those .
What?
Very cool, no?
Wow , these 're great !
That is my dream .
They are all cool .
What are you doing here?
Stop following us.
Leave the guy alone.
You're not nice.
Oh , these are very good .
Did we get enough to
pay for two of them ?
Very good .
So yeah, we do.
And then think about it .
It's really great .
- Wait a minute .
- There's more over there .
Do what I tell you.
More down , down ,
down .
Down , dude .
A little more ...
Ready ! Here !
Oh , what a beautiful ...
Ah, little puppy !
Smile , both!
Shane .
Look .
The flag came out great .
Could you not pull any other face?
Oh ! This guy seems ugly
anyway , Indian .
Give him , man.
Stop it .
Juan , give it back .
Damn ignorant Indian.
- What's that ?
- What?
What is your problem?
Why defend this guy ?
He's not with us .
Would you like it if I did the same
with you ?
You went too far .
Get up.
This Indian is with you ?
- No.
- Yes
- Yes or no ?
- No.
- He's Guatemalan .
- And where are you from ?
- From " Sueños de Oro "
- And where is that?
Near here .
So we'll see.
Show me your papers .
- We don't have them .
- Well, you're in trouble .
Move it . Faces the wall.
Fast !
Against the wall. Move!
Come on! You!
against the wall.
Spread your legs .
Look !
- These boots are good , huh ?
- Very good .
Sit !
You too.
Take off your boots.
Boots, off !
Quickly !
Ah , yes, yes , yes .
- Yes
- Hand me that bag !
Remove them !
" Sueños de Oro " ...
So , you want to get rich
in the U.S. ?
You'll have trouble now.
Come on!
You too.
Come on .
Drop it .
Say that to your mother ,
asshole .
Here we go!
Come on!
Over there .
The Gospel of Jesus Christ
invites everyone to come
the nearest evangelical church
to accept the word of God
and the Gospel of Jesus Christ.
Approach the Evangelical Church
and accept the Word of God and
the holy Gospel of Jesus ...
Come , here we have good shoes .
cheaper in all
Guatemala !
STOP
WELCOME TO MEXICO
This way.
Come across here ,
that has no guards .
Guys, from now on ,
Anyone who is not smart
will be left behind.
Got that?
Alright .
I'm staying.
Why?
You should come with me .
Son of a bitch ! Stop
follow us. I've had enough!
We're here because of you .
It's your fault
Samuel's gone .
Here we go .
I'm done traveling
with this Indian.
We share all three, understood?
So quiets there.
Juan !
Stop !
Stop!
Juan !
That's it.
I'm going alone .
If you start, I'm leaving.
For me,
it's both or none.
Juan , where are we going now?
- Which one?
- I don't know , wait.
And this ?
Juan ...
Time to wake up .
Pretty good boots , huh ?
You son of a bitch .
I'll break your neck!
Run, people , run!
What are you laughing at ?
I won't give you anything .
Why do not you kill ?
I can not .
This idiot thinks
that he can kill just by talking .
Look .
Tree.
Root .
Look .
Cobweb.
Eyes .
Ear.
Osvaldo .
Osvaldo , no.
No. Sara .
- Yes , Sara .
- Sara .
Sara .
My Heart ?
Okay .
I like that.
I like it here .
And yours?
I do not understand you.
I do not know , " taiv " .
What's this ?
Watch out!
- The branches ! The branches !
- Beware the branches !
The most precious liquid.
Immigration , folks! Watch out!
Run, run , run!
Stop , you fuckers !
On the floor , you motherfucker !
Cut his balls !
This way. Quick, quick !
Over there , by the curtain .
Under the bed .
Under the bed , fast!
You will teach them
because they are new .
They do not know how to cut .
Tell them to make a big pile .
And to cut close to the ground .
- And clean up the mess .
- Okay .
What's this ?
What do you mean ?
What will
you thinking?
What?
You want this one?
What's this ?
No, no, no .
No.
His Indian shit .
What?
Come on.
You seen Chauk ?
Have you seen him ?
Chauk .
Chauk !
Chauk , what you got?
What?
Cigarettes ?
I have a king size
or you want a menthol ?
You just press .
I already showed you how to do .
I better to thee
'll end up confusing me .
Here ! Here !
Hey ! Hey ! Look here .
Thank you !
Fast ! Fast !
- Come down , you fuckers! down !
- Move it! Fast !
Come on down ! Quick, quick !
Come on! Move!
Arise ! Fast !
Move! Are you listening ?
Come on! Come on!
In a row . Here .
Move!
Over there!
Fast !
Watches, coins .
Whatever you have with you .
- What have hiding .
- Pocket knives , guns, bombs .
All looking down.
- In the truck!
- In the truck , quick ! Now !
Come , come !
Come on, rise !
Come here .
This is a girl .
We'll see .
Sure !
Look here , boss!
Thought we were
idiots , right ?
Calm .
Everything will be fine, my pretty.
Do not move.
See this .
I bet she's a virgin .
Piece of shit !
Juan !
Hold it !
Juan ! Chauk !
- Juan !
- Take it !
- Juan ! Chauk !
- Come on!
Juan !
Shut up !
Welcome to real men , bitch !
Come on!
Let's get out !
And I didn't even see
to where they took her .
Water !
Has everyone .
Calmly .
Calmly ...
How was the journey ?
Who needs food ?
Please do not go away .
The train will arrive soon .
Will be here in a day or two .
So no need for you to stay on the track.
Better to come the shelter .
We have a shelter .
We are here ...
Hands off !
We are here in Arriaga .
Here we go
Mexico City ...
From Mexico City we
go to Mexicali ...
And then we go on to
Los Angeles .
What are you looking at?
Amen
Guys, happy eating .
- Thank you .
- You too .
Brother .
Shit , Chauck !
You learned to speak Spanish.
But I'm not your brother .
Chauk . Come on.
Now . Come on.
Brothers .
In this world, nobody is
better than anyone.
We come from nothing
Return to nothingness .
Do not mourn for the dead
Who are gone forever.
Take care of those who remain
And if they can help
When you say goodbye
In a final farewell to this world
Do not cry
because nobody is eternal
Nobody returns from the deep sleep
And what Italian football team
is your favorite ?
- Barça .
- The Italian Football ?
Hey ! Can I have one?
Sure , take it.
What's up, man?
You are Guatemala , no?
Yes.
And what are you doing here ?
Going up north .
So am I.
You miss
Guatemala ?
- No.
- No? I miss it a lot .
How much money have you got to cross ?
- A hundred .
- Hundred ?
Dude, that won't be enough
to even pay the " coyote " .
Look I have a cousin
who has a business .
Nothing big.
But it pays well .
- And what's the job?
- A porter .
You could stay there
if you want.
Okay, Vitamina?
- How many?
- Thirteen .
You're screwed .
- Do't spend it all .
- Okay .
Leave your backpacks
Here in the middle.
Everything you have :
mobile , keys ...
Everything .
Each of you will give me a
number of a person in the U.S. .
If you cooperate ,
you'll leave here alive .
Where do you come from ?
Nicaragua , sir ,
but I don't know anyone ...
All " Nicas " , please
over here with him .
- Where are you from?
- Honduras.
Great .
All Hondurans there.
- Where are you ?
- Guatemala , Zone 3 .
To the corner .
In the corner , all alone.
El Salvador ?
Hands against the wall.
Frisk them .
Look .
I am also in Zone 3 .
Go away .
What are you waiting for?
He's with me .
You're from where?
He stays.  You leave.
Come on.
Out, Outside .
The rest of you , turn around,
hands on the wall.
Very high,
so I can see them .
Who will be the first
to give me the number ?
You ?
What do you want ?
- I came to see Vitamina .
- What for ?
- I want to talk to him .
- Wait, wait .
- Wanted by Vitamin .
- Who?
A tough little kid .
Vitamina , someone's looking
for you .
As the boss said , asshole ,
tell me the name and number
someone in the United States .
This is your last chance .
Give me the number , you idiot !
What is it?
He will not be any help to you .
- Who?
- The Indian .
How do you know ?
He speaks no Spanish .
Why so much affection
for this little Indian ?
I owe him one .
For what?
Answer me, you little shit !
This is the price of your friend?
Move in!
A problem boss ?
He came to pays a ransom for the freedom
of his friend.
Look, at that, what fortune.
Where'd you get that ?
- Earned it .
- You stole .
- Worked .
- Where did you steal?
- I did not steal .
What about you , huh !
Take off your shirt !
- I have nothing .
- On your knees !
You too!
Look into the eyes of one another.
That's what will happen .
Only one will leave.
And you will decide who .
Get it?
Who goes ?
You ? Or will he?
Who will leave?
Answer me, you little shit !
Him
Very well .
So be it .
A. ..
Two ...
What guts , huh ?
You're a little man.
You have twenty seconds
to leave.
Fast !
Before I change my mind .
Out !
Open the door .
Ah , " taiv " means snow,
then?
How's it going?
We're going to Los Angeles .
How old?
- I am 16 .
Okay?
Take this .
Put on the backpacks .
Inside.
Come on!
Quiet , huh ?
The Police is there.
We'll have to wait for
the shift change .
They're gone .
Now then , let's go!
On the floor .
Nobody move ,
fuckers .
Get up !
On the floor ! On the floor !
Up ! Come on!
Now !
Runs , Chauk ! Come on!
Fast ! Run!
Fast !
It feels like there's
a zoo in my stomach .
As if a lot of animals
were running
all over my body ...
The thrill of being finally passing
to the other side .
I feel that ...
everything we will see on the
other side will be full of good.
Everything will be alright ...
and we get
up and go where we want .
Fast, little fuckers !
Pass me the backpacks .
You have arrived to
the other side now.
Come on!
And now ?
Come on.
Chauk !
Chauk , get up!
Arise , Chauk !