When he passes me,
I cannot see him;
when he goes by,
I cannot perceive him. (Job 8:14)
A man was fishing all night.
He kept catching
and releasing the fish.
Another man asked
why he kept doing it.
He answered,
"I'm looking for the damn fish
I almost caught yesterday."
Another fisherman thought about
the fish being caught and released.
He wondered if any of them was the one
the man almost caught.
He decided to stop chasing
after his wife.
You read it.
Say something.
I like the beginning
and the ending.
That's it?
Interesting
but not well-written.
Another fisherman told Sinhyo
unbelievable things about his runaway wife.
The man didn't trust him,
but he wanted a listening ear.
Luckily, Sinhyo wanted to listen,
ready to believe anything.
Jungsuk said strangers told
him about his wife's real identity.
It was like a huge secret
at first but didn't matter now.
She was an 'Avian Kind',
which went extinct a million years ago.
Sinhyo wasn't surprised
and kept listening.
You only went fishing, right?
You didn't tell uncle about me
not being at the carpenter's shop?
Anybody come to the shop,
looking for my wife?
Who else but you?
Hello?
Father's not home.
He doesn't read just anything.
How else should I call it then?
Why are you cussing?
Can you lend me a book?
What kind?
Dad told me to ask you.
He said smart people
know everything.
Garim's dad was father's student.
After his divorce,
he came to live at 'Wuyeonje'.
Father got him a teaching job
but he could never stick to anything.
Weird, long names.
Something "ski" and "skaya".
It's about a father and
son loving the same woman.
It's good.
So complicated.
The characters are like you.
Slow, long, complicated...
You're like a Russian novel.
Did you show him my manuscript?
You're rude, like on the phone.
Don't send it to him.
He doesn't like getting random stuff.
Think you know all about him?
I know him better than you.
Is it so hard to ask him to read it?
It just won't happen that way.
Don't you get it?
No other writers could understand
me except your dad, Gijin Kim.
I'm not trying to prove anything
but if he reads it,
I'd be happy to die today.
Then write it again and send it.
He wouldn't read
a line of your poor writing now.
I'm not kidding.
Do it again and send it.
Tell me how.
The plot could be interesting
but the writing itself is terrible.
I'm not a writer but
shouldn't writing be properly clothed?
I... never studied,
never went to school.
Teach me.
He came with a revised
script every week
and went home with assignments,
like a good student.
I wasn't bold enough to
ignore my dad's literature.
So I created a Drama Society.
We performed 2 or 3 times
a year in front of friends.
So fucking awkward.
Jehye was the only one
who wasn't a friend.
She started revising scripts and
memorized lines with us.
She asked questions.
Perhaps, she didn't notice.
Unlike her, we were
trying to escape reality.
Why do you never
perform your dad's work?
She always asked questions
and never talked about herself.
Why the same play
all year around?
How about posters?
I only knew her age,
that her major was nursing and
that her father is a pastor.
Why do we drink while
talking about others?
When I asked her a question,
she would simply stare
back with an open look.
What's wrong with you?
Want a fight, asshole?
Fuck!
I can't beat you!
Stop it!
Fucking nerds.
Don't hit me!
Even my father never lays
his hand on me.
Stop!
What's wrong?
The fucker insulted Gijin Kim.
"His philosophy reflects
the shortcomings of our time."
How is that an insult?
I can't voice my own view?
If you want to understand, study!
Asshole!
Stop it!
Go inside.
All you read is his works.
That's the extent of your
understanding, moron.
Everyone likes his works.
Tell Sunghwan I'm off.
I've read it all,
your writing.
Which ones?
All of them.
"Hammer", "Whispers in the Ear",
"Potion of a Thousand Years".
Do you want to
read my other stuff?
It was her first time
to express her view.
A rare thing. She realized
it as it was happening.
He took her to the carpenter's shop.
It was cold and far,
so when they arrived,
they were sober.
I can write
all night like this.
I can't sit at the desk
after working all day.
You live here?
My uncle sent me here.
I have to earn a living.
I never read other novels
besides Mr. Kim's.
I did check out other books,
but I couldn't finish them
unlike Mr. Kim's.
Am I too dumb to write?
You're brilliant.
To me... you're a genius.
Sinhyo asked me to introduce
other writers besides my dad.
I recommended those
staying at 'Wuyeonje'.
He read Garim's father's works
and asked to meet him.
Been waiting for us?
It was both hard
and easy to read her.
She was expressionless,
but somehow her eyes
were so expressive.
I learned that you can express
a lot without saying or doing much.
When we went to catch the bus,
she mumbled, "There is a shortcut."
Without waiting for us,
she went ahead to the Bamboo Forest.
We are the only ones
allowed to trespass.
Who's "we"?
People at 'Wuyeonje'.
Anybody live there?
A shaman used to.
Garim told us about the shaman
and about her potion.
She said the shaman's father's father and
his father's father made the potion
that fakes death
and raises one 3 days later.
Grind, mix and boil it.
The potion can fake death for 3 days.
I heard it took more than
1,000 years to make it.
The shaman made it?
You fall for such stories?
You made it up?
I took the bus back.
Kyungmi Lee made her
debut when she was 19.
She was a shoe factory worker.
It was the first time
for Gijin Kim to let a young,
female writer to stay at 'Wuyeonje '.
She didn't talk to us
on the way back.
She was different
with the writers at 'Wuyeonje '.
She wasn't talkative,
but by simply answering questions,
she dominated discussions.
How dare he call it trash cos
it's not about "the suffering of our times"?
Everyone's entitled to
their view but
why did he say it after
being on the judge panel?
He's making a point that the book's
success is thanks to him. Pathetic.
They seemed to be
discussing mundane stuff
but their talks were filled
with social views
- and literary philosophy.
- He said I lost my objectivity.
I said it depends on
one's mark in life.
I never considered myself special.
Kyungmi told her life stories
in relation to her book;
her labor union involvement and
the attempted rape by her step-dad.
She was serene and
persuasive, like her books.
Are you a writer?
Only writers who have published
are allowed here.
I'm just here with a friend.
I could tell.
You're so young,
but talented.
I didn't go to school properly.
Show me your works.
They're available
at the bookstore.
I'm also a writer.
I'm curious how you did it,
being so young.
I didn't get a good education.
I want to learn but
don't know where to begin,
who to ask.
Everyone's so smart.
It's hard to follow
what they are saying.
Want to look at my writing?
Next morning,
father called and told me to fetch
a package from the post office.
I left early.
I thought others were asleep.
Off to school?
On vacation.
Where are you going?
Going for a walk.
Where to?
I'll give you a ride.
I finished the books.
Huh?
The books you lent me.
Want more?
What were they?
Russian novels.
Ah...
Then how about French novels?
Japanese novels are also good.
You know a beech tree looks like?
Well... I've never seen one.
All your books mentioned
the beech tree.
How come you don't know
what they are?
How can you recommend those books
when you don't know that tree?
I went to the public library to
look up the beech tree.
He must be running errands
for his dad.
Doesn't Mr. Gijin Kim
come here often?
He rarely comes.
Even when he does,
no one knows.
Did you read my stuff?
Yes, more interesting that I thought.
You have no shame,
showing it to everyone.
That's it?
Where are you going?
I have a class in Gwanju.
Teaching or attending?
You must be teaching as
you're a writer despite being young.
Your manuscript's on my desk.
It's faster to take the shortcut
than waiting for the bus.
I heard 'Wuyeonje' people are
the only ones allowed to trespass.
I wish I could become a writer
and live at 'Wooyeonje'.
What did you think of my writing?
The stories were so ridiculous.
You mean it wasn't good?
I'm not as talented as you.
That's not for me to judge.
All the villagers take this path.
It used to be quiet
because of tramps.
You know so much.
I envy you.
So young yet so knowledgeable.
To build something,
shouldn't you work on the foundation first?
Talented or not,
to build something,
you need a good foundation.
And then,
you need good soil.
Giving advice to a person
without any foundation
is pointless.
Wow, how do you know that?
Being so young and
without a good education?
He talked about his childhood.
His mother killed herself after
killing his abusive father.
He didn't consider himself unlucky
but if it takes self-reflection
to be a writer,
that's what he'll do from now.
He kept talking about his life;
how he survived
with the help of relatives,
how he had to do hard work.
His story was shocking
but predictable.
He never considered
his life as a topic for writing.
He said we're all meant to
suffer to a certain degree.
So...
Dismissing reality can also
become a form of expression.
Garim never told anyone
about not going to school.
Nobody paid attention to her,
but she hated having to
explain herself to anybody.
Her friends also liked listening to
Garim talk about them.
She thought her life
wasn't special or painful.
Isn't everyone's life that way?
She hated thinking deeply
about her life.
Talking about others was fun.
Compared to Russian novels,
the world was full of shorter,
simpler and chaotic stories.
I want to know
what people think of me.
I have an idea.
A shaman buried a
1,000-ear-old potion near here.
If you drink it, you'll die for 3 days
and then come back to life.
You saying I should take it?
If they think you're dead,
they'll reveal their true feelings about you.
Any side-effects?
You believe this story?
What if you find it?
When should I take it?
Take it near those
whose feelings you're curious about.
Why aren't you
at school anymore?
You don't like talking?
You talk a lot, though.
I just listen.
If you listen carefully,
you end up whispering back unconsciously.
It's different from talking.
I have to go to the cram school.
O.K.
I'll tell you if I find it.
How long are you staying here?
Don't know.
There isn't a time limit
for writing a book.
Working on a book?
What's it about?
Another story about factory girls?
Abused Women?
You know what?
I'm not like you.
I don't babble on about my work.
Why follow me all day?
If you have nothing better to do,
study grammar,
spelling and punctuation.
I didn't get a proper education.
I'm sorry but I get sensitive
when writing a book.
I wish I could help.
But I'm too preoccupied.
Sinhyo was envious of Kyungmi:
her artistic sensitivity
when she writes,
her cool attitude to all the praise
and that she's a writer
working at Wuyeonje.
He never considered his work
to be shameful or meaningless.
But after meeting
the writers at 'Wuyeonje ',
he realized his work
might never get published.
Sinhyo left
without a word next morning.
He didn't reappear for a while.
Nobody asked about
his whereabouts.
After 2 months, he came back.
He'd been in his hometown.
Sungmin went to art school
but performed music.
Jihyun also majored in art,
but she also played music.
Maybe that's why they kept
on dating and breaking up.
I wasn't sure if they were in love.
Nothing seemed different whether
they were dating or not.
We' re going out.
For real?
Yeah.
We broke up.
Really?
Really.
We got back together.
There was something
different about Sinhyo.
He was always restless
but when he came back,
he wasn't the same.
He talked about the past 2 months.
He seemed excited,
but not the way he used to be.
He worked as if work is a blessing.
Sweating and quenching his thirst,
he believed it'd
somehow change him.
His stay at 'Wuyeonje ' changed him.
Being a writer doesn't have
a special meaning, he thought.
He worked like a man with
no other purpose in life.
He decided not to chase
after his wife.
He was determined to
forget about her.
You weren't around, so...
Hope I'm not bothering you.
I was worried about you.
Sunghwan said you were
out of touch for long.
Do I have to be with you?
No...
I don't want to give you
any pressure.
Don't get me wrong.
I thought about what I'm doing.
I thought Mr. Kim could
understand my work,
but turns out that's
not the solution.
I...
I really think your writing is...
I thought all I need were wing
but that wasn't it.
I'm only a puppy.
If a tiger gets wings,
he can soar high
and devour eagles.
If a puppy gets wings,
what difference does it make?
I still like your writing
more than anything.
No other writing made
me stay up all night.
I couldn't put it down.
I read "Avian Kind" many times.
I don't know what you
mean by a puppy and wings.
They are amazing.
You should keep on writing.
There's no meaning in writing.
They have meaning to me.
I don't care if you think
you're good or not, but keep writing.
I said his imagination
was phenomenal,
however good others may be.
His imagination was
beyond our time.
I half-understood what
I was saying but he was moved.
He explained how he got
the idea for "Avian Kind"
from writer Jungsuk Kim.
He went to his hometown having
decided to write again.
He told his uncle that
he's quitting his job to write,
that he's only there to write.
His uncle sighed, disappointed.
Never slept more than
4 hours in the last 2 months.
My fingers kept on moving until
the finger prints disappeared.
So?
Any difference now?
It's not complete.
I worked one and half months
on the one you read.
Working on something new now.
The main character's based
on you.
Me?
More beer?
Yeah.
What are you talking about?
Nothing much.
I love your music.
When you have some time,
let's hang and listen to music.
I want to hang out with
cool people like you.
I didn't get a good education,
you see.
Cut it out.
She's Sungmin's girlfriend.
No, we broke up.
Really?
Really.
Always wanted to date a musician.
Don't take it too seriously.
I just love your music.
Do you always categorize
women you're interested in?
Sorry?
He's in trouble now.
Do you always sort
women into jobs like musicians,
students or homemakers?
I haven't dated many women.
What about Jehye?
What?
What's going on
with you and Jehye?
I thought she was staying with you.
I came to find him.
What you doing?
Cooped up at home
since you came back.
Get lost.
I guess you did hang out
with college kids in Seoul.
Go, dumbass!
I brought this pretty girl
who was looking for you.
You said it was a pretty girl.
Like someone bewitched,
he slept, smoked and
wrote in the same position.
I wasn't worried.
It's only that I wasn't a big help.
I never lived my life for
someone else before.
You may not understand.
I don't.
But I hope you do understand.
Is this meant to be fun?
If it weren't for me,
he'd have collapsed.
He spent the month without
seeing the sunlight,
in the same position.
I didn't want to stop him.
It may be hard to believe,
but it's the first time I feel I'm doing
something meaningful in life.
It's been over a month and
something amazing is happening.
I wish you could read
his works again.
Someday, he will be appreciated.
Why are you doing this?
Not everything
has to have a reason.
Don't worry,
I chose this.
If you want,
I can leave.
Do you like me?
You like my writing?
I'm not the type to love
or hate things.
I just know your writing's good.
I want to share this moment
when you're creating something.
Never knew city girls were this easy.
Always wanted to live a meaningful life,
even for a moment.
I may never save anyone but
I can help someone
create something great.
What's that?
Your fingers hurt.
Once you get used to it,
it'll be easier.
Too noisy.
Working on something new?
Yeah.
A famous writer's son secretly
rewrites his father's work.
He sends it secretly by post.
To his father?
It arrives months later sent
from a different name.
The son thinks it's much
better than his father's.
Two emotions clash,
love and hate towards his father.
The son kills himself
and no one knows.
His father's reputation
soars sky high.
Great.
It's like a Greek tragedy.
The son's suicide sounds cheesy.
But can't come up
with a better ending.
Still, it's beautiful that he dies.
A pastor's daughter
shouldn't talk like that.
The new piece is incredible.
It's still rough yet,
it sweeps up your emotions.
His writing opens up
a mysterious world.
This shall be a masterpiece.
You might think
the suicide is ridiculous and immature.
If some story continues after suicide,
that will be great.
On my opinion.
All tragedies have time.
As time goes on,
it either becomes a tragedy or comedy.
Your music has such beauty.
Makes you wonder
what'll happen after a long time.
Can't you keep
your thoughts to yourself?
Right,
right!
Why can't I do that?
Why am I so talkative?
Do you like novels?
No, I don't.
Wait,
you don't have to like them,
but can I show you my work?
You really hate novels?
Ok, I'll read it.
I've always wanted to
date a musician.
He seemed more confident.
There was something
different about him now.
What's this?
Give it to me later.
Skim through it.
I made changes.
Except for the opening and ending,
not much had changed.
Still rough but there
was a sense of direction now.
Maybe he's different
because of what he wrote.
Maybe I knew all along
this day would come.
Now people will be drawn into
his world of ideas.
You' re Sumin, right?
We met last week.
We have met but...
Remember?
The concert?
We met at Wuyeonje.
Oh, right!
I'm sorry.
I knew we'd met.
Do you still write?
Bits and pieces.
Still showing it to everyone?
Taking the bus?
The subway.
I need to go.
Call me.
So absent-minded.
I didn't give you my number.
Where are you going?
Home.
And you?
Going home.
Want to come?
To my place?
No, to my place in Paju.
Heard of it?
So rural.
Outside Seoul it's all like that.
I love it here.
The factory where
I used to work was near here.
Back then,
I was desperate to get out
but it's good to be back.
I can write here.
What are you working on now?
It's about a famous writer
and his son.
Mr. Gijin Kim?
I don't have anyone
particular in mind.
How can you not?
You see what you see
and hear what you hear.
I finished it this morning
and decided to show it to
the first person I meet today.
Doing something for the first time
is always good, right?
Sure I can read it?
Told you.
I was going to get the
first person I find to read it.
You hit the jackpot.
It was different
from her other works.
A love story but hard to
tell if they're in love.
Obscure but I was sure
critics would like it.
Complex but there was
strength in its clarity.
Scenes with the lovers
made me uneasy.
This was how successful
writers write.
Enjoying it?
Pretty good.
I think I get it but
I'm not sure.
Want to stay for breakfast?
Being with her in the room
felt uneasy and comfy.
Like reading her work.
It felt new.
If you want to work at 'Wuyeonje',
let me know.
I am not even a published writer.
I meant you can stay
in my room there.
Do you use that in a war?
Of course.
This helps?
Even against tanks?
It'll be tough to be
in love with me.
Are you 100% sure?
Fuck,
you can't expect certainty
from a man.
Why did I kill my love?
Why did I have to?
It wasn't on purpose.
You're like someone
born to kill him.
Was it on an impulse
or planned?
I'm not sure.
I don't understand.
She can't be caught
or understood by people.
I know it's tough but we're not
here to do something easy.
I don't want to do this any more.
We've been doing
the same play for 2 years.
I don't want to pretend to be doing
something worthy when we're not.
Are you still seeing Sinhyo?
Why do you ask?
I think it's better for you not to.
Why?
You know.
You are regretting it.
Such a strange man.
He seems to hear and know everything
but doesn't say anything.
Why does he bring it up now?
So strange.
How come you're here so early?
I wanted to stop
by before school.
Good job.
Think you're my girlfriend?
No.
As soon as you finish,
I'll focus on my studies.
Lucky bastard.
An assistant!
Whatever.
What will you do?
Want to work at 'Wooyeonje'?
Do you think working there
will make any difference?
Better get going
before others come.
Dare to kick me out?
Sinhyo decided to write
at 'Wuyeonje'.
He went there.
What are you looking for?
Still believe the story
about the potion?
Nothing to lose by believing it.
Want some help?
Must be near here.
Go.
You'll jinx it.
Oh, I'm bad luck?
What are you doing here?
I'll be using the
room for a while.
What?
That chick let you do that?
Yeah.
Odd.
I couldn't write
a word since I came here.
Have some dumplings.
Since you're here,
we have drink.
Don't be cooped up in the room.
You seeing Kyungmi?
It's not like that.
What's it like then?
Don't date writers, especially
someone like Kyungmi.
So tiresome.
Did I tell you?
What?
Same old story.
Don't.
I went fishing
for 3 days nonstop.
Not a bite the whole time.
But the guy next to me kept
on catching the fish.
Strangely,
he kept letting them go.
Weird, huh?
Like he was making fun of me.
What happened?
I asked why he kept
releasing the fish.
He said he's trying to catch the one
he caught the night before.
I got so frustrated, ended
up drinking for 3 days.
Why are you telling
the story now?
Strangely,
after listening to the story,
I had a strong urge to drink.
I was like a neutered animal.
I just drank.
Though I came to write,
I couldn't do a thing.
I was haunted by dreams.
I drank when I woke up.
I became sober only to sleep.
It was hard to tell
dreams from reality.
I tried writing
when I was sober,
but couldn't write a word.
After 3 days of drinking,
I realized 'Wuyeonje '
wasn't the place for me.
Going back?
Yeah.
Want to go ice fishing?
No, I'm leaving.
Leaving already?
Yes.
Did you find that potion?
It was just to kill time.
If you find it, do share it.
Change the beginning
and ending a bit.
If you add a minor theme,
the contrast will become
greater in "Avian Kind".
You read it?
It was was around.
The structure's good but,
it may be due to your personality,
your writing's not
sensitive and too naive.
Too stubborn,
overshadowing other strengths.
Why are you saying this now?
Did we ever have time to talk?
Garim said things
no others told me.
I took her to the bus stop.
I never expected I'd have this
meaningful conversation with her.
She critiqued my loose plot.
Density doesn't come from
sentence structures
but from each letter and period.
If you treat words carelessly,
your writing loses its impact.
Where did you learn that?
You don't even go to school.
You can't learn stuff like that
at school.
Amazing.
If I was like you at your age,
I'd have done great things.
Garim could become a greater
writer than her dad.
Despite the lack of education,
she was talented like Kyungmi.
But she wasn't uncomfortable
to be with unlike Kyungmi.
Maybe it was because Garim had no
intention to become a famous writer.
Sinhyo didn't have anywhere to
go in Seoul, so he went to Kyungmi's.
After the talk with Garim,
it felt right to work
at Kyungmi's place.
I'm not sure where he is.
He wasn't at 'Wuyeonje '.
He 'd already left.
Please, can you show
the scripts to Mr. Gijin Kim?
I know it's not easy,
but I have to do it for him.
What are you doing?
What am I doing?
I am the landlady.
What's wrong?
What are you doing?
I'm the landlady.
What you looking at, asshole?
She wasn't getting
the recognition she deserved.
She wasn't sure
but she thought it's because
of her age and background.
She wasn't nominated for any
of the literary awards.
Some panel judges took her out,
saying they'll cheer her up.
But in fact, they were hoping that she'd
make a fool of herself after drinking.
She ended up
losing control and
criticized authors old enough
to be her father.
Think I'm a joke?
Weirdo!
Being weird doesn't mean anything!
You are nothing.
You'll never make it.
Other guys won't
tell you that point.
You'll never make it.
You obsess over tiny things,
can't see the big picture.
Neither a poem nor a novel.
Nothing in Korean literature will
embrace your style.
Give up.
Let me sleep over at yours?
Got nowhere to go.
I heard you left 'Wuyeonje'.
I showed him your work.
You can see him
at school tomorrow.
I love your songs.
I love a woman who loves music,
who can play the guitar.
Sick and tired of hearing that.
Hey, show me some affection.
Stop it.
Don't you want to see
my father tomorrow?
Ah, your father.
Asshole,
why didn't you show it
to him earlier?
I'm so excited.
You have no idea.
If it weren't for your dad,
I'd have been dead by now.
Have you read
Mr. Gijin Kim's work?
Told you,
I don't read novels.
So hot!
I so want to date a musician.
How old are you?
How much older was Yoko
compared to John Lennon?
Do you know how much
John Lennon earns each year?
So worldly.
I can also be worldly.
We'd make a great duo.
Get out.
Go and sleep on the streets.
Asshole!
Fuck it.
Can't you even pretend
to pity me?
Stupid fucker...
Grow up.
I wish I could live recklessly
like you.
Why did you show it
to him now?
Afraid of me getting
approved by your dad?
People who have much and
know much are such morons.
Stop it.
I'm going.
I wish I could live doing
whatever I want.
Grow up.
Can I...
go see your father tomorrow?
A miracle.
He came to dawn prayer.
He was drunk.
I shouldn't be coming here drunk.
I was praying that God would
let me see him again.
I quit my job,
got no place to go.
If I go back,
they'll kill me.
I am so tired.
As I got warm,
sleep came over me.
Heard verses from the Bible,
from the Gospel of John.
Peter asked how
other disciples would die.
Jesus said,
"Why does it matter to you?"
With that, I fell asleep.
In my dream,
Garim talked about my novels.
I talked about Kyungmi's works,
and Garim asked why it matters to me.
Go in.
He read them all?
Just go in.
Thanks.
Nobody was really nice to me.
Nobody really taught me anything.
Don't expect too much.
He did say he read it.
You're Sunghwan's friend?
Yes.
Why did you write that?
To amuse people?
I don't know why you wrote this.
It could be different from
what you're used to...
I've seen a lot of things like it.
Not sure why people write
this sort of trash.
Written words remain,
while spoken words disappear.
Think hard and then write.
It's better to
see him being hyper.
My heart breaks seeing
him like this.
I can't do anything.
I've done all I can.
Stay here
if you have nowhere to go.
Can you go to your hometown?
Not sure.
I don't want to.
Stay.
I'll help you.
I first read Mr. Kim's work
in middle school.
It was a page turner.
I read everything he wrote
and anything about him.
I started writing.
I didn't mean to become a writer.
I...
wanted to meet him.
I thought if I do,
my life would change.
I don't know why.
Maybe I was fooling myself.
I don't know who to blame.
It's no one's fault.
Stay.
I had to let him go.
I had a feeling he'd back someday.
Thought about going back to
uncle's but if I went back,
I felt everything would be over.
I tried to kill time for now.
But it wasn't easy either.
Though it was tough,
I wanted to read
Mr. Kim's works again.
I also read the other
'Wuyeonje ' writers ' stuff.
Flipping through literary magazines,
I found Kyungmi's writing.
Garim's father, Kyungmi,
and others at 'Wuyeonje ' knew
why my writing couldn't be published.
Maybe I knew too.
Neither a novel nor a poem,
lacking coherency and style.
A bastard.
Life's unfair.
I didn't choose to be born this
way and nor did my writing.
I dreamt about meeting
Mr. Kim for past 10 years.
Now, I have nowhere to go.
I used to think being cold and
hungry wasn't a problem.
Now I was afraid of hunger
and the cold.
What are you doing here?
So cold...
I was dying to get some rest.
I'll get a job soon.
You can finish it now.
I threw it into the river.
I remember everything.
Jaehye rewrote everything
from her memory in 2 days.
Sinhyo got back to work.
He wrote as effortlessly as
he was breathing.
What's the title?
Haven't decided yet.
I wish you never do.
I'll show it to Sunghwan
when I'm done.
Why?
Want to see Mr. Kim again?
I decided while writing.
When I'm done, I'll give it
to Sunghwan then, go home.
Sinhyo finished writing
the last chapter that night.
Jaehye read it over
and over all night.
Want some medicine?
No.
I just need to take some rest.
I'll copy this tomorrow.
Don't.
I'll give it to
Sunghwan tomorrow.
That's why I'll make
copies tomorrow.
I said no.
What if you throw it into
the river like the last time?
I said no!
I'll give it to Sunghwan!
What are you saying?
We wrote this...
together.
Bullshit.
Leave it.
He'll leave tomorrow.
He may never come back this time.
That night,
I had a vivid dream.
Garim talked
about my work in the dream.
Garim showed me the potion.
She said I could take a sip,
saying my work may
seem different afterwards.
What are you doing?
A sedative.
You were in pain.
What?
Why?
I don't want to see
you leave or suffer.
Some day,
people will appreciate
you and your work.
It'll make you sleep
like a dead man
for 2 or 3 days
or as long as you want.
Drink it, if you want.
The world will be
different when you wake up.
Why?
You, too?
It won't be painful due
to the sedative.
They'll think we killed ourselves
after writing the last book.
I wrote a will.
What?
I don't want to see you
leave or suffer.
I want our work to
be remembered forever.
Fuck!
What the hell!
I... I didn't write it for this!
27 years later,
Sinhyo woke up again.
I heard on the news
that he woke up.
It was like a miracle.
But miracles happen to
those who yearn for them.
I was praying for that miracle.
Sinhyo Kang,
often called the author of our era,
regained consciousness
after 27 years.
Experts say it's a mystery that
can't be explained
by current medical science.
I woke up from a deep slumber.
Was it a dream within a dream?
Everything feels like it
happened yesterday
and yet things seem distant.
Was the sky always so transparent?
Sinhyo, can you hear me?
- Do you recognize us?
- Sinhyo.
Can you look us?
Sinhyo.
Sinhyo, can you hear us?
Can you hear us?
"The author who die in 20th century
awoke in 21st century"
I don't care much about what I wear.
Didn't know baldness ran
in our family.
Was it the potion?
What happened to my hair?
You look the same to me.
Just like in the old days.
Ready?
Since waking up, people
suddenly want to talk to me.
What do they want to know?
My dreams from 27 years
or 27 years before the sleep?
My friend said
you can use it for now.
He's a great fan of yours.
You came back to life
without any warning.
No time for us to prepare.
You should stay with us,
your family.
I didn't live with you before.
Now, press this.
Oh, I see.
You must be tired.
Minsu will come to go shopping.
Got the card, right?
Have dinner with us.
Yes.
Here's the card and some cash.
You swipe it.
Swipe?
Swipe what?
Give it to the cashier
and they'll do it.
Youngsters imagine
their future within
the boundaries
of their circumstances.
Yet, if you get old suddenly,
you don't remember
what you imagined.
I wanted to take time to
think about my future.
I wasn't in a rush.
I'd been asleep for 27 years,
so no need to hurry now.
Hello?
Did we really make it to
the semi-final at the World Cup?
Moron.
Why are you asking me?
Call the Soccer Association?
And what would I know
about Kim Il-sung's death?
Let me know
if you need any books.
Anything else you need?
I need more time to
find out what I need.
You'll see when you get to the firm,
but it's mostly relatives.
It's been over 10 years.
Someone asked
for a copyright consent.
We were lucky that
our family's in publishing.
Your writing's superb but
packaging is everything now.
You never met the person?
Uncle talked on the phone.
He wanted to see your writing
but there was nothing left anywhere.
That must have upset you.
Dad got a call to
go to the station.
No one was there but the scripts.
Not even a note.
So if that person had
claimed it was his writing,
we couldn't have done anything.
The living legend thing was perfect for
marketing but now you're awake...
Once I decided to let time pass by,
I gained a peace of mind.
I noticed many things
to enjoy in life.
I was once lost in time
but time had moved on
without waiting.
It was strange.
Despite the passing of time,
people's taste doesn't change.
People like my works not
because they understand.
It's natural for the world to
change but also surreal.
Why don't you visit the settings
of your books for photo shoots?
That'd be simple.
We're publishing a book,
so why photos?
Because you aren't writing at all.
Why don't you
explain things properly?
I did.
You weren't paying attention.
Always talking fast.
So confusing.
O.K., don't do it, then.
I'll do it.
Why is everyone
in such a rush?
He's caught in time but
everything else changed.
His body is older but
he stayed the same.
A stark contrast.
He looks like a sullen
young man in his 20's.
I need some fresh air.
Being in Paju brought
back memories.
Though there weren't
much remaining of the old Paju,
I walked as
if it'd rekindle old memories.
I remembered
what I did with Kyungmi.
Paju...
Have you heard of Paju?
You're Sinhyo Kang, right?
We've met.
I don't recollect.
You came to our school.
I give lectures at many schools...
I am a fan.
I study Korean Literature.
You know what I'm doing?
I'm writing a paper on you.
Really?
I knew you wouldn't believe it.
Such a coincidence.
I believe it.
The world is full of surprises.
Can I have your number?
I'm no good at expressing myself.
I'm actually ecstatic now.
Sleep is important.
If I have questions,
can I call you?
Where have you been?
Where is he?
He's gone.
We're going to a barbecue.
Join us?
No, thanks.
Frankly,
I have no idea
what you're saying.
You're the photographer,
so do what you want.
But trying to capture time?
Amplify the contrast?
What are you saying?
I don't know.
I came up with the project.
You aren't just a writer
the best known
21 st century's sleeping beauty.
I'm interested in you.
Interested?
What?
Are you in right mind?
Do you know
how much older I am?
Mentally,
you're 27 which makes me older.
Have you read my books?
I don't read novels.
But I read yours.
Very interesting.
I drank for the first time in 27 years.
Memories came abruptly.
Memories of not belonging anywhere.
I drank and talked.
Strange.
I am doing the same things,
but people look at me differently.
I'm acting as I did at 27,
but at 54.
no one thinks I'm foolish.
The age difference between
Yoko Ono and John Lennon?
Funny!
Recognize me?
Have you met Sunghwan?
No.
I thought that'd be
the first thing you'd do.
Excuse me.
You must've been good-looking.
Not a big shot,
but such a player.
I had nothing to lose.
I used to hit on any girls.
I like older men,
hate rookies.
I stopped aging at 27.
This place is still there?
It was taken last spring.
Good to see some things
stayed the same.
I kissed a famous writer there.
If you were a player back then,
I can imagine what's it
like for you now.
She was just 20.
Heard of her?
She was good.
She thought she was a genius.
I don't know why I was
drawn to someone like her.
It's natural.
To me you're a genius.
Hello?
Sorry to wake you up.
You said I could call you
if I had a question.
What is it?
Is it true Jungsuk Kim's
the model for "Avian Kind"?
Did you intend to overlap
characters in "Whispers in Ears"
and "the Potion of
a Thousand Years"?
Did you know you'd come back
to life like the main character
in "Russian Novel"?
You know what time it is?
Oh dear, so many girls
are into old men.
Did you say the main character of
"Russian Novel" comes back to life?
They don't let men in
as it's a women's college.
I had a word with the professor.
I want to study your writing
at grad school.
Did I bring the wrong books?
I brought everything
including first editions.
Can you help me?
As I said, I may not seem it,
but I'm so honored.
If I can help you in any way,
I'd love to.
I want to learn more
about your works.
O.K.
Have you heard
of author Kyungmi Lee?
Yes.
How about Mr. Gijin Kim?
He's famous, but
I'm not into his writing.
I was about to call you.
Did you tamper with my book?
What are you saying?
Did you tamper
with my manuscripts?
Why would I?
Didn't you rewrite it?
You didn't do anything?
Anyway...
These pictures look good.
We can add pictures of the settings
and stories about them.
You said it'd be a few pictures.
It can be about memories with
Gijin Kim at Wuyeonje.
Stories from your past.
I think it would be great.
I was never an official
writer at 'Wuyeonje'.
I only met Mr. Kim once.
That's not important.
You did work there.
People are interested now
but who knows what'll
happen in the future.
We have to rake in as much
as possible while we can.
Always thinking
of ways to sell me out.
The 21 st century is
all about business.
You know art
and I know business.
Business is this big
and art this little.
She last published in 1994.
She immigrated to New Zealand.
Except for the article for
the Women Writers' Society,
there is no more.
My prof heard she's
in another country.
1994 is when "Avian Kind"
was first published.
I had trouble
finding her last work.
The library didn't have it.
I hunted it out
at a used book store.
I'd given up
if school doesn't have it
but as I said,
it's is such an honor.
Stop saying that.
O.K.
Kyungmi was well-received
even after that.
So why suddenly immigrate?
Jungsuk Kim was found by
at a fishing pond in 1998.
No one knows if it was
an accident or suicide.
It's either Kyungmi or Jungsuk,
I thought.
The only ones talented
enough to tamper with mine.
We think life is ours.
With some time,
we realize we're only a part of
the big river called life.
It flows through us,
but water becomes a stream
and streams to a river,
and finally the sea.
Life doesn't belong to us.
When the miracle you've longed
for finally happens,
your sincerity may be faded.
Would I have made
the same choice,
if I'd known what'd happen?
Kyungmi immigrated in the year
my first novel was published.
I thought it was her at first.
She knows me well
and writes well.
But the more I thought about it,
the more convinced
I became it wasn't her.
Definitely,
this is not my work.
Why didn't you call me first?
You haven't changed even
after such an experience.
She's my girlfriend.
Don't peep at her.
You sure know
how to get Seoul chicks.
I hit on him, actually.
I'm mentally in my 20s,
so I can date her.
I wish I could be like you.
Remember the girl who came
when I was writing?
Yes,
she went to all
that trouble for you.
What happened to the scripts
she gave you?
Did you have them?
No.
I wasn't interested.
Wouldn't have understood it anyway.
Hello?
I searched all night.
Nothing new on Kyungmi
but lots on Jungsuk's accident.
I don't remember it well,
cuz I was little.
Many memorial services.
He has a daughter.
Head of a memorial committee.
Does this help?
I know you hate it when I say this
but I'm honored to work for you.
If you can possibly tell
my professor about what I've done...
Do I sound weird?
No.
I'd be thankful if you can...
You don't have to but...
Hello?
Surprised to hear from me?
You're a celebrity, so yes.
I found your number easily.
Guess it's one of
the perks of being famous.
I wondered why you contacted me.
It feels like yesterday.
You told me
a lot about my writing.
It helped me a lot.
Well, let me see...
I remember you were interesting
and close to Sunghwan.
That's all.
What did I say?
You don't remember?
You...
made such
a difference in my life!
How can you not remember?
I even thought you were
greater than your father.
Really?
Never mind.
Pointless to discuss it now.
You and Sunghwan were so alike.
Really?
Both long and complex...
like Russian novels.
I realize how fear drives me
away from life.
I was trying to avoid a small fear.
Now it's become huge.
Who tampered with my works?
After all these years,
if I find out who,
will anything change?
Did you write them on your own?
Just...
it doesn't seem like it was
written by one person.
Hey.
Yes?
What you said in class.
Tell me more.
You'd know about it
better than me.
I'm asking your opinion.
I'm a bit disappointed.
I had big expectations
before I saw you.
Hello?
Sorry.
Had to get the kids ready
for cram school.
No worries.
I have lots of time.
Life keeps me busy.
I forget things.
But I think I remember
what happened.
Only Sunghwan knew
I stopped going to school.
He said I should go.
He tried to teach me useful things.
You really don't want to
become a writer?
If I asked a question,
he tried to find the answer for me.
He was stuffy like that.
I liked your writing.
I asked Sunghwan,
if you can be a novelist
like my dad.
It was a simple question.
You two were friends.
He's quite serious.
He pondered and started to talk.
What did he say?
Things I told you.
I don't remember much.
I was just rambling on.
So what you said
at the bus stop...
They weren't my ideas but
what Sunghwan said.
Why?
Why did you tell me that?
Didn't you know?
I had a crush on Sunghwan.
I thought it's
what he wanted to tell you.
You know him.
He didn't know how to
say important things.
He's a complex maze
many characters,
long lines,
like a Russian novel.
My busy schedule
was just an excuse.
I wasn't intending to
find Sunghwan.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Do you happen to know
Sunghwan Kim?
Why do you ask?
He's a friend of mine.
He's not here.
Things didn't work out for him.
He was swindled
and lost everything.
Loan sharks threatened
to kill him.
Don't know what he's up to.
He worked here for a bit
but not now.
He lost everything?
Right.
Still, he's the son of
the great Gijin Kim.
Some say he's in his hometown.
What are you doing here?
Think of it as a coincidence.
Can't you be more respectful?
I'm disappointed.
What?
How dare you be so rude?
Think everything should be
laid out for you?
Stop!
Who the hell are you?
I'm also here to find something.
What?
What do you know about me?
You're here for Mr. Sunghwan Kim?
Me too.
If you see him, tell me.
I'll do the same.
He went to Damyang.
Why are you looking for him?
Where's Damyang?
Aren't you going to
tell me anything?
Depends.
This isn't for fun,
you know.
He must be keeping
a low-profile as he lost everything.
Aren't you going to
tell me the truth?
What?
Why you're looking for him?
Take a guess.
I like her.
She's my style.
You aren't his daughter, are you?
A novelist with such a poor
sense of imagination.
Should've known better than to ask.
Awesome.
What's your major?
I'm in high school.
What?
Why didn't you tell me?
You never asked.
Tell me
why you want to meet him.
I have something for him.
From my mom.
Mom?
Who's your mom?
Play your game right.
I love her style!
Why are you seeing
such an old man?
I know.
Call me a crazy bitch.
Wuyeonje had become a village center
after 3 different owners.
I don't want to stay at other places,
though here's no memory left.
And old memories are still
in my mind after 27 years.
There's a strange hut.
You never read my novels, huh?
Although I came to find him,
I wasn't in a hurry.
He was somewhere
and I knew we'd end up meeting.
The rewriter had to be him.
It was done just
as Garim had said.
It was a cold wintry night,
perfect for reminiscing.
If he rewrote it,
why didn't he claim as his own?
It was almost a new creation.
With his skills,
why didn't he become
a writer like his dad?
Why is it called
"the Russian Novel"?
I didn't give name the book.
Why do you think
it's called that?
I doubt we'll find him.
You find him
and give it to him.
Too cold.
They're from my mom to him
and these from Sunghwan to her.
This is what she asked me
to give Sunghwan.
to give you.
Why didn't she give it
to me in person?
Who's your mom?
Do I remind of anybody?
Oh, my.
How old did you say you are?
Don't worry.
I'm not your daughter.
Right.
Can't be.
My mom's Jehye Lee.
The more you try to avoid fear,
the bigger it gets.
Your awakening was
something I always wanted.
But I didn't have the courage.
Perhaps you thought
I died with you back then.
I kept thinking you aren't mine.
It wasn't easy.
I wanted you to be free,
to be appreciated.
But I knew you'd leave.
Still, I did what I did
thanks to my youth.
I thought you died that night.
I was anguished and guilt-ridden.
I wanted your work to
be re-evaluated.
I couldn't do it,
- so I turned to Sunghwan.
- It's strangely beautiful.
But story itself
isn't easy to follow.
There's a fatal weakness.
Help him please.
What?
I want you to re-write it.
Did he ask you to do this?
He's...
dead.
I think I killed him.
As I rewrote it,
I realized neither
of us could be a writer.
Unlike him,
I didn't have the reckless desire
to shout to the world.
I realized it as I was writing
under someone else's name.
The new version is different.
I don't know
how this could happen.
If I publish it,
I could be greater than my father.
Of course, I could never
recreate this again.
Hard to believe
but it took 10 years
for him to do it.
Can you imagine
what happened to him?
I feel guiltier towards
him than to you.
I don't have the courage to
see you two.
Give my letter to Sunghwan.
I've lived in Shanghai
for 20 years.
Even if I have
the courage to see you,
I'm too sick to travel.
If you'd woken earlier,
it may have been possible.
But miracles happen at
the most opportune time.
Is it the title?
The Russian Novel?
Yep.
Why?
It's long,
complicated
with many characters.
A fisherman was
fishing all night long.
He kept catching and
releasing the fish all night.
A fisherman was
fishing all night long.
Sinhyo walked to the pond asked,
why he was releasing
the fish he caught.
The fisherman said,
"I'm looking for the damn fish
almost caught yesterday."
When he passes me,
I cannot see him;
when he goes by,
I cannot perceive him. (Job 8:14)
- from Go the to his son