Say, can you tell me,
where Commander
Wadlow's office is?
Has... er... has America
come into the war?
I don't know.
All I asked was-
Yeah, yeah, I heard you,
Captain. Just over there.
Thanks.
You going to drive
a tug for us, captain?
Commander Wadlow?
In there, sir.
Thank you.
- Yes?
- Ross.
Oh, yes, of course, Commander Ross.
We've been expecting you.
My name's Wadlow.
You couldn't have come at a better time.
You know the type of thing,
of course?
Not exactly.
Well, sorry, but as you volunteered,
I should've thought...
I didn't exactly volunteer.
I'm a sergeant in the Canadian Army.
All I know is, they gave me this
uniform and told me to report here today.
I see. But you have commanded
ocean-going tugs?
Not for 10 years.
I think that's why they picked me.
No doubt.
Well, you might call this enterprise
the Red Cross of the ocean.
You're in the rescue business now.
If some lonely, unhappy
cargo ship gets torpedoed
or can't keep up with its convoy,
you pop out onto the briny deep
and bring your lame duck in.
And everybody aboard's
ever so grateful.
That's all there is
to it really.
Sounds simple.
Now I know why they picked me.
We're getting so much business
from the States these days,
that we have two full crews
and two captains for each tug.
You relieve each other, see?
Your ship's the W-88.
Actually, she's in dry dock for repairs
at the moment, so you can take it easy
for the next few days.
I see.
I'm here!
Let's have the vulgar details
and I'll run along.
Excuse me, will you?
Nice of you
to drop by, captain.
You've got a Dane
with a cargo of high explosives
and a torpedo
in number one hold.
Sounds dull. Besides, it'll
take eight days there and back.
I don't think
I'll go this time.
You!
I think so!
Ha!
Amigo! Ha-ha!
Hey, just a moment,
just a moment.
What exactly are you
doing here, anyway?
Don't tell me you've
taken Walter's place?
- I don't know, I-
- Oh, no.
No, you can't do that
to him. He's a nice man.
Don't tell me you've fallen for that
nonsense about the Red Cross of the ocean?
Just what are you
doing here, anyway?
Now you'll never believe me-
Couldn't wait for America to come in?
You're an idiot!
Get out of it, man!
Get out of it!
I'm sure your lame duck
must be getting impatient by now.
And we don't want all that nice
imported gunpowder getting damp, do we?
Goodbye, Captain Ford.
I'm going.
Good. What about going out
right now with Captain Ford?
Actually, if you watch him closely, then do
exactly the opposite, you'll have it all down pat.
Ha-ha! Yes, David, come with me and after you've seen
what it's like, you can come back and tell him to...
Sir, SOS from W-40.
Where?
I don't know. She broke off.
Well, call her.
Who's on her?
Raymond.
Get me air-sea rescue.
Yes, do. Just another day in
the Red Cross of the ocean.
Come on, idiot!
Hello?
Yes, one of our tugs,
I'm afraid. W-40.
Its last known position
was 50 north, 30 west.
What would you say
hit that tug?
- A dive-bomber, a U-boat. Who knows?
- U- boat, most likely.
- You run into many?
- Oh, yes.
Not the ones who lay the ducks low,
they usually keep going after the convoy.
But Jerry's got a lot of mine-laying
subs in the neighbourhood.
Once they smell blood, they
come after us like vultures.
They call this
U- boat alley, my boy.
But once we reach the dock, we'll
be all right because she's got guns.
She's got guns?
Don't we have guns?
Just what sort of a navy
do you think we've got here?
What's the story?
We've got a Danska with a
cigar in number one hold,
and a load
of high explosives.
- That's nice.
- This is Captain Ross.
He's taking over W-88.
My mate.
We've met.
Square up that tow rope!
Aye-aye, sir.
All coming back to you
in dribs and drabs?
Like I'd never been away.
- Clear that filthy deck!
- Aye-aye, sir!
What is that?
You asked about guns. Don't go too
near her, she's on a hair trigger.
- Yes, but what is it?
- This is our gun.
But they're not all like this?
This is a single-barrel
Pom-Pom, 1926.
'26 was a vintage year
for Pom-Poms.
Don't worry, chum.
The ducks are all armed now and their
stuff's heavier than the U-boats.
Jerry won't surface anyway
within the duck's range.
So, once we reach her,
we're safe as houses.
Yes, I've seen
some of your houses.
- Nice pigsty you've got here.
- Thank you.
All ready when you are, skipper.
- Everyone here?
- All but Ibbetson.
This time he's
really in trouble.
All right, get going.
Right, sir.
Is the gentleman
staying aboard, sir?
I think so.
All right.
What's the matter with him?
Oh, nothing.
He's just tired.
Port a little.
Port a little, sir!
Chris, have you ever had a duck blow up
on you while you were coming alongside?
No. But we do lose a few tugs
that way from time to time.
Thanks for
asking me along.
Watch your step here.
I don't want to have to put
a boat over the side for you.
All right, lads. Couple up!
Signal, sir.
Message from the duck?
Not likely.
That's the one thing they
mustn't do, break radio silence.
That's the most important
item in envelope "D".
Envelope "D" is a sealed instruction
they get when they leave harbour.
What to do when unable
to keep up with your convoy.
Such as?
Skipper flashes a code signal
to his group leader,
puts out his fires if he has any,
keeps radio silence so as
not to give the position away,
and just tries to be patient
till we come and get him.
That's about it.
What happens
if we get torpedoed too?
Oh, no. We never get torpedoed.
Jerry's not going to waste any
torpedoes on us. We're too small.
Besides, their mine-laying
subs don't carry torpedoes.
Why didn't you tell me that
in the first place?
Because they've got a deck gun that's big
enough to blow us clean out of the water.
Any other questions?
You all right?
Yeah, sure.
You've been away
a long time.
If you don't feel well,
why don't you go lie down?
Don't be embarrassed, old boy.
I'm all right.
It's getting a bit cramped up here.
I think I'll go and stretch my legs.
Thanks.
Give it to the skipper.
I'm sorry. Take mine.
No, no. Never mind.
Junkers diving fast!
Action stations!
Green one!
Green one, sir!
Fire!
It won't be long now.
Here, get used to it.
She's got herself a very nice fire.
Think she can last?
Who knows?
But we'll be inside her range
in a mile or two.
I just hope her guns
haven't been damaged.
- Starboard 20!
- 20 starboard, sir!
Well, it's his turn to run now.
I'd like to get one. Just once.
Now all we've got to do
is to bring that mess in.
Steady on, there!
Get the line-gun ready!
- Line-gun ready!
- Line-gun ready, sir!
- Don't fire till I tell you!
- Aye-aye, sir!
Fire!
Be as quick as you can
with the connecting up!
I prefer to connect
to your anchor cable!
When I've connected up
the main throw...
Watch the lines from your wires!
Smoke, Kane?
No.
Well, home and dry.
This time, anyway.
My knees are like jelly.
What's the matter?
It always hits me
like this after it's over.
Right now, my stomach's
doing a Morris dance.
If I get home before I'm sick,
I'll be all right. How do you feel?
Fine.
- Big man, eh?
- You wait.
Come on,
let's have some coffee.
Don't thank me, commander.
It's all in a day's work.
What did you think of
it all, Commander Ross?
Very interesting.
Good. Then you'll be glad to hear
that your ship's out of dry dock now.
Perhaps you'll go along and see it
tomorrow and meet your opposite number,
- Captain Van Dam.
- Sure.
Aren't you in the least
a little bit ashamed?
Just a moment,
gentlemen.
You've forgotten
your little pink pills.
Oh, here. Get yourself
a good night's sleep.
- I don't use them.
- You will.
Meanwhile, you can sell
them anywhere in town.
That reminds me, Commander. We've
got you billeted at the Grand Hotel.
Come now, not the
Black Hole of Calcutta?
That's no way
to treat an ally.
Come home and have
breakfast with me, anyway.
Where do you live?
I've got an apartment. Two
rooms and a bath. Best in town.
Naturally.
Captain Ford.
Yeah?
I want to thank you
for saving my ship.
Not at all.
Better luck next time.
Look, all you have to
do now is go in here,
fill yourself up
one little old report,
and you can go out and get
as plastered as you like.
- Thank you.
- Not at all. Bye.
Hello, my fairy
godmother!
- Oh, it's you, is it?
- Well, that's something.
She worries about me, poor
dear, every time I go out.
I owe her money.
Fill her up,
there's a good girl.
- You haven't paid for the last lot.
- Yes, I know.
And you owe me for last
week's newspapers too.
Tomorrow. All claims
settled in full tomorrow.
Have you got a cigarette, love?
Yes, love.
Come to think of it, you're the
first guest I've ever had here.
I'm not surprised.
How did you get
a place like this?
That's not all I've got.
Where are you?
- Oh, Chris!
- Darling.
How did it go?
Easy. A Dane on fire.
He behaved very well.
Have you been all right?
Why didn't you tell me
you were going?
Because you look
so pretty when you sleep.
Oh, this is Stella.
This is my old American
friend, David Ross.
You've heard of lend-lease. They
meant him. He's finally arrived.
- Hello.
Tell her how I pulled you
out of the Panama Canal that time.
No, but I'll tell her
how I pulled you out.
Yes, of course.
After you threw me in!
You took advantage
of a drunken man.
Sit down. I'm going
to wash. Then you wash.
And then we'll all have the best baked beans
on toast in the whole uncivilised worid!
Please sit down, captain.
Thank you.
It's nice here.
Yes.
- Are you on tug boats, too, captain?
- Yes.
I haven't started yet, really.
As a matter of fact, I haven't
been on one for ten years.
Until this trip.
You were out with Chris?
Yes.
You'll be very good.
I hope so.
Do you know Chris a long time?
I beg your pardon?
Have you known Chris a long time?
Oh, we used to run
into each other a lot,
when the worid
was young and gay.
- He's a very nice man.
- Yes.
What did he mean when he
said you were lend-lease?
I don't know.
I guess I'm an over-aged destroyer.
Hm?
I'm afraid I was in too much of a
hurry when I picked this jacket out.
It's tight under the arms.
Take it off, be comfortable.
No, it's all right.
Let me see it.
- Come on, take it off.
- No, no, really.
Take it off.
I can alter it for you.
I think I can help you.
Come with me.
Here. Put this on.
What's going on?
His jacket is too tight.
I'm trying to find him another one.
Does it fit?
Yes.
Don't say it does, if it
doesn't. Try the arm holes.
- Hm?
- Yes, it's fine.
Good. Give it to me.
Oh, the toast.
- Sh! Sh!
- Chris, I'm sorry.
I'll tell you about it later.
Go on, take a bath. You won't
care for the tub at the hotel.
I'm sorry.
I was just thinking, you're going to
look over your ship tomorrow, aren't you?
Well, the very best of luck
with old Van Dam.
- Van Dam?
- Hm.
Oh, yes,
the other skipper.
- What's wrong with him?
- Oh, nothing, nothing.
Don't be silly, Chris.
Van Dam is a very fine man.
Oh, he's a very good boy.
He owns W-88, by the way.
He sneaked her out of Holland from
under the nose of the whole German navy,
and he brought her over here
practically single-handed.
- It's just that...
- Oh, you'll find out.
You're a very funny man.
Don't worry, you'll be all right.
The first time is the worst.
I'm all right. I...
I'm tired, I guess.
Will you take your
sleeping pills now?
No, no pills. I'm taking David on
the town. We've got to celebrate.
You're going out?
Yes, it's reunion time!
I haven't thrown him
in any canals lately.
All right.
Don't keep him out too
long, please. He must sleep.
If he doesn't, he'll go to pieces
again if he has to sail tomorrow.
What do you mean, "go to pieces"?
I've never gone to pieces!
Don't mix me up with someone else!
I'm sorry.
All right, I'll be home early.
I'll get ready.
I won't keep him out too late.
- Thank you.
- He must sleep.
Finished.
It looks very nice.
Yes, it... feels better all the
way around. Thank you very much.
Okay?
Yeah, ready.
Goodbye. And thanks for
the meal, I enjoyed it.
You're welcome.
You must come again.
Thank you.
Chris?
Eh?
What...?
Don't drink too much.
No, my love, no!
What do you think of Stella?
Can't hear you.
You're lucky.
Yes, I am.
You're wondering
about this, aren't you?
Whatever you think,
you're wrong.
I wasn't thinking anything.
You listen to me, because I want you to
know. I want you to know about Stella.
She was going to marry a
tug driver named Westerby.
Philip Westerby.
I knew him. Not too well.
Anyway, he got his
the day before the wedding.
A chum of mine, Hal Van Barger...
That's his jacket
you're wearing, I think.
He heard about the flat going
and he hopped up and got it.
Things were worse then
than they are now.
People were actually
sleeping in the gutters.
Anyway, she stayed on
with Van Barger.
Don't ask me why,
I don't know.
Maybe because he was
a tug man, too, like Westerby.
Maybe because she could tell he was
just about to crack, which he was.
Maybe she just didn't have anywhere
else to go and didn't much care.
I don't know and I don't care.
Anyway, Van Barger gave
me the key to the flat.
He said if anything happened
to him, he wanted me to have it.
He said we poor sinners on the tugs
deserved a few breaks along the way,
and we ought to keep
the flat in the family.
I know what you're thinking,
but you're wrong!
- I wasn't thinking anything.
- Yes, you were.
I think it's fine.
How do you know?
How could you?
You don't know what it's like to have
someone like that waiting for you on shore,
waiting for you
to come home.
What happened
to Van Barger?
Oh, he went out
to pick up a Greek...
When he got there, the
Greek wasn't there anymore.
But a U-boat was.
Ah, look at this.
Time to refuel!
You'll be quiet when you go in
to get your suitcase, won't you?
Okay.
You couldn't just drop it
down to me, could you?
Let's just have one for the road.
Good job we did get home early. We
might have to go out again tomorrow.
- Idiot.
- Hm...
Here.
Here, take this.
Put it away somewhere
and forget about it.
I don't want it.
- Take it!
- No! No!
When Van Barger gave me a key,
he made me promise to have another
made just as soon as I ever used it,
and to give it
to someone on the tugs.
But I didn't know who to give
it to. I want you to have it.
And I said I didn't want it.
- Here, you take it.
- Keep it.
You have to keep it, because I have
to keep my promise to Van Barger.
Give it to somebody else.
Make me a promise right now, that the
moment you use it, if you ever have to,
that you'll get another one made
and you'll give it to someone.
Someone on the tugs, someone who's
all right, someone who needs it.
You know what I mean.
Then you make them promise.
Yes, but the war
may go on a long time.
- You're crazy.
- You'll outlive everybody.
Anyway, I don't want it.
You want me
to break your nose, huh?
- You promise?
- I promise.
And then if anything does happen to
me, you'll... you'll look after Stella?
- You'll see that she's all right?
- Nothing is gonna happen to you.
We'll drink to that,
because in my considered opinion,
none of us is going to come out
of this alive, including you.
Thanks.
I hope you know what time it is.
We don't want to wake Stella, do we?
You know something
funny, David?
Stella, she's... she's
wonderful, she's so good to me,
but... but sometimes I...
Here, hold this.
Sometimes I don't think
she knows which is which...
Philip, Hal Van Barger, me.
It's all mixed up.
It's confused.
Do you know
she called me Philip once?
I didn't say anything.
She couldn't have told by my
face, I'm sure, it's just...
It's as if we're all
the same man.
And I don't know
which one.
I don't know which one
and I don't care.
That's strange, isn't it?
Tell me something.
Why does she wear
that wedding ring?
- Yes.
- That's funny, isn't it?
Hm...
What do you think
you're doing?
I'm not dead yet,
you know!
Sorry.
Here.
Sh!
See? Home early.
Yes.
Stella...
Night.
But you must sleep, darling.
I'm not sleepy.
I want to talk.
I'm a captain, you know?
I say talk, everyone talks.
And I say we talk now.
Sit down, please.
What shall
we talk about?
Hm?
I'd better make you
some coffee.
No, no! No coffee!
I don't want any coffee.
Come on, come on.
Oh, Stella, you're very good to me.
I love you.
I wish you'd marry me.
You want to... marry me?
Please.
We're full up.
I'm supposed to be billeted
here. My name is Ross.
Ross?
Right.
You'll have to share a room,
we're cramped for space.
I know. Same in London.
You're in 77.
Canadian, are you?
An American, I think.
This way.
It does not work.
Er, this way.
You've a nice warm room
next door to the kitchen.
Good.
And you get a towel
all to yourself.
That's nice.
There you are, captain.
There's your bed
over there, up on top.
Do I get that
all to myself too?
- Killed himself last week.
- Who?
Captain Walters,
the man that had that bed.
He was a tug-boat
man like you.
Swallowed a whole box
of sleeping pills.
Long sleep, huh?
Anything else you want?
Yes, I'd like that towel
you were talking about.
Oh, one thing at a time.
I've only got two legs.
Here's your wash basin.
The lavatory's down the hall,
you know what I mean?
Yeah, thanks a lot. Here.
- Keep it.
- I don't need it.
I didn't ask for you.
All I want is peace.
That's good enough
for me too.
And you'll get it, captain.
You'll get it before
you know what hit you.
Read the casualty lists.
Hey!
You mind turning off
the light, captain?
I'm sorry.
Captain Van Dam?
- Yes?
- I'm Captain Ross.
I heard the ship was ready, so I
thought I'd come down and look her over.
Captain Ross, you've come
to look her over. Good, good.
She's the best ship on this
base, and she deserves care.
Some people here like to live
in a pigsty, but I do not.
So you will please be good enough to
tidy up your mess when you come off duty.
Yes, of course.
I'm glad we understand each other.
Made any sorties yet?
Sorties? Oh, yes, I've
been out with Captain Ford.
- Did you like it?
- Not very much.
Why not?
I'd like it better if we had
some decent guns.
Guns?
Why do you want guns?
I don't like the idea of being shot
at and not being able to shoot back.
It makes me nervous.
That is because you have
the wrong approach to this work.
Stretcher bearers on the battlefield
cannot shoot back either.
That's quite a thought.
My dear fellow, war has nothing
noble or sensible about it.
It's simply an epidemic
of madness.
And anyone who takes part in it
is a lunatic and a murderer.
There's a lot in what you say, captain,
but I don't think it would be of any
particular comfort if you happen to get hit.
There are many ways
to avoid being hit.
For example, when I hear
the first shell coming,
I very often turn away,
go full astern
and sail backwards.
That way, I make myself
a smaller target,
and at such a distance, it is difficult
to tell in which direction I'm going.
Then I change course, zigzag,
and if necessary, repeat.
And you've never been hit, captain?
Never.
Any particular reason for this
ship having been in dry dock?
Her superstructure was shot away,
but that was your predecessor's
contribution, Captain Walters.
Why do you think
he killed himself?
It was an accident.
He drank a great deal.
I don't think he knew
what he was doing.
I trust you're not
a drinking man.
Have you met your crew?
No, I had them called.
I thought I'd take her out
for a dry run today.
Then I will leave you to it.
She's very lively on the rudder.
You must remember to give her counter-wheel
the moment you start pulling her around.
Thanks.
Her engine's
absolutely first class,
but there is a choke
in bilge pump.
You might tell
your chief engineer.
Thank you.
Hansie, Hansie.
And we go for a walk now.
Sit, sit. This is yours now.
I'm all right, thanks.
Er, Captain...
we were talking
about being shelled.
Yes.
Only this...
in this work, one must learn
how to live with fear.
You mean,
you're afraid, too, sometimes.
Yes.
But I believe in God.
Let me tell you something.
There are two kinds of fear.
In the one,
no matter how great your terror,
you pray to God,
and then you struggle desperately,
even superhumanly, to survive.
With the other,
you are so frozen, so paralysed,
that you cannot move.
and accept the death blow
without a quiver,
almost with thanks.
That is the dangerous fear.
You see, my friend, there is only
one enemy who really matters:
the enemy within yourself.
And only one thing to fear:
self-betrayal.
And, forgive me, but you must
remember that your crew is afraid too.
So, for that reason
more than ever,
you must be both
their captain and their father.
If they respect you
and have faith in you,
they will still be afraid
but not so much.
And above all,
no drink,
and no bad women.
Drink will destroy
your judgement,
and that kind of woman
will bring you bad luck.
You see, my friend,
in times like these,
it is much harder to command
than to be commanded.
This isn't exactly
my first ship, captain.
Of course. Oh, here is your
crew. They're a good lot.
But like the others of this branch of
the service, sadly lacking in discipline.
Goodbye.
Do you sing?
Sing?
Yes. We are lacking a baritone
for the church choir.
And we begin rehearsals
for Christmas next week.
I'm sorry, I don't sing.
Oh. Pity.
Good luck.
6-4, this one's fresh from school.
Always expect the worst
from life, my boy.
You won't be disappointed.
- What's wrong, chief?
- Your horoscope bad today?
Watch it! Watch it!
I'm the mate, sir. Weaver.
How do you do?
Mr Grogan, the chief engineer.
Aye, sir!
- The bo'sun, Mr Baker.
- Aye, sir.
Well, I'll give you
the complete list later, sir.
I want to see
just what this ship-
I want to see just what this
ship can do this afternoon,
so be prepared for
some lively manoeuvres.
That goes particularly
for you, chief.
Aye-aye, sir.
All right, let's get moving.
Make ready for sea, bo'sun.
Stand by, fore and aft!
Let go of everything, forward!
Hang on to
your after springs!
Slow astern.
Slow astern, sir.
Let's go, aft!
Half ahead.
Half ahead, sir.
I'm not convinced the Almighty intended for
tugs to be placed in the hands of Americans.
But we shall see
what we shall see.
Engine room.
Engine room, can you
give me a little more speed?
We're full speed now, sir.
Yes, I know, but I'd like
little more, please.
I can't answer for the boiler, sir.
Naturally, I'll take
the responsibility for that.
Aye-aye, sir.
More speed!
We've got a sporting gentleman
aboard. More speed, he wants!
Full astern.
Full astern, sir?
That's what I said.
Full astern.
Full astern?
I knew it!
He's run her onto some rocks!
I knew he was an amateur
the moment I saw him.
Full ahead.
Full ahead, sir.
From full astern to full ahead?
Playing games, is it?
Enjoy yourself!
The man's mad.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, sir.
She's a bit lively
on the rudder.
You have to watch
the counter-wheel on the turns.
Engine room,
thank you very much.
You can take her down to
your normal cruising speed now.
Aye-aye, sir.
Handles very nicely.
Yes, thank you, sir.
We'll be going home.
You can take a fix.
Oh, right, sir.
28 years I've been at sea,
and never, ever
had a day like this one!
Oh, er...
There you are, sir.
Well, sir, you... er...
You certainly kept us
busy today, sir.
Yes. Thank you very much. Now I know
what she can do in evasive action.
Yes, sir.
That's right, sir.
She's good ship.
You couldn't expect her to do
any more and still be called a tug.
And a beautiful engine, chief.
You've every right
to be proud of her.
Right you are, sir.
By the way,
check your bilge pump, will you?
I think you'll find
something wrong there.
Aye-
Aye-aye, sir.
- Bo'sun!
- Aye, sir?
How does it behave?
Sir, it's terrible. It's a proper witch.
You never know what it's going to do.
Put it on the top of your list
for a complete overhaul.
List, sir?
Yes. Haven't you a note book
with a list of things to be done?
No, sir.
My bo'suns always have
a note book and a list.
Get one, Baker.
We'll charge it to petty cash.
Aye-aye, sir.
I'm not quite as particular
as Captain Van Dam,
but I do want everything on this
ship operational at all times.
Aye-aye, sir. I'll get that note
book as soon as we get ashore.
She's a nice little ship,
isn't she?
We were doing better than
16 knots some of the time.
Very nice, indeed.
Sir, I'm...
I... I'd just like
to say that...
Yes?
Well, I'd just like to say that I'm...
very glad to be serving under you.
Weaver, do you sing?
- Sing?
- No, I don't, sir.
Good. I think
we'll get along fine.
- Hello.
- Oh, hello.
I... er... just came by
to return this.
- Who is it?
- David!
Yes, he's got your pipe.
My pipe? We've got enough
of everything, haven't we?
- Of course.
- Come in, we're having a party!
What's the occasin?
You suspect something,
don't you? Tell him.
We are going to be married.
Well, that's wonderful.
I wish you both all the happiness
in the worid. You're a lucky man.
- I'm a lucky man.
- Go on, kiss the bride.
Go on! You're going to
be the best man, kiss her!
- He's shy.
- Go on, kiss him.
There, that's a very
good best-man kiss.
Now, you watch me give my girl
a first-class husband kiss.
David, now ring up headquarters,
tell them where you are.
I'll open the wine, then
we'll eat, drink and be happy,
because we're all
wonderful people!
Stella, where's...
where's the corkscrew?
- The corkscrew?
- I don't remember.
I don't think we have one.
I'm sorry, it's my fault.
I should have thought of it.
Never mind,
I'll use something else.
Don't, you'll break it.
Nonsense. I've done
this millions of times.
Look, I'm bleeding!
Stop it!
Now... don't say
you told me so.
Go wash.
Change your shirt.
Yes. Yes, I'm sorry.
Yes?
Yes, it's Ford speaking.
Thanks a lot. You couldn't
have chosen a better time.
Yeah. Right.
Oh, wouldn't you know it!
Keep my share warm,
I'll be back Tuesday.
David, stay and keep Stella
company, there's a good fellow.
No, I'll see you to the ship.
You'll what? Why?
Please.
Well, I've asked you a dozen times,
and you've never wanted to.
I know, but tonight
I do want to.
Let's save it till daylight,
the sun's shining on the waters.
I'll have the boys sing us a shanty
as we shove off.
Chris, please.
Look, let's skip dinner tonight.
I'll see you later.
Now what's all this about?
I'm afraid.
Of what?
Now, now. This is an easy one. It's just
off the coast. I could swim out to it.
Please?
All right.
But we must get a move on.
- Good luck!
- Thanks.
Oh, captain, they've been calling you.
You've got an SOS too.
You're to get to
headquarters right away.
Thanks.
Here's your lame duck, here.
200 miles west of Bishop's Rock.
About 24 hours steaming.
That means daylight,
I'm afraid.
A bit awkward for you on your first time
out, but I'm sure you'll be all right.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
What have we got, sir?
A freighter on fire.
If I'd known you were going to carry on
like this, I'd never have let you come down.
You've never behaved
this way before.
Just because we're
going to be married.
Well, I may change my mind.
That's better.
Now you go home and try not to
get lost in the dark, won't you?
Good girl.
- Skipper.
- Yes?
- Ready when you are, sir.
- I'll be right out.
Oh, Weaver?
I thought we were supposed to have the new
armour plate for the wheelhouse windows today.
Yes... yes, I know, sir.
They just didn't come.
They'll be here soon, I hope.
I'm sure they will. Okay.
How far do you
make her out now?
About 5 miles, sir.
Keep your fingers crossed.
Sir!
Hard to starboard!
Engine room, give me
everything you've got, flat out!
Aye-aye, sir!
Port, 20!
Full astern!
That would've been dead centre, sir.
- Full ahead!
- Full ahead, sir.
- Full astern.
- Astern, sir.
- Port, 20!
- 20 to port, sir.
Who told them
to stop shooting?
- Hard to starboard!
- It's jammed, sir!
Come on, get on it, son!
Port, 20!
The Marines have landed.
How did it go?
Can't complain.
Kane, you'd better take over
until further notice.
Okay.
What happened?
We were strafed.
- Which of you is skipper of W-88?
- He is.
Thank you very much, skipper.
I must say, you fellows
certainly know your job.
Thanks... Thanks very much.
Fill out your report there, will you?
How did it happen?
I told you.
We were strafed. Twice.
We were on our way home.
He was too slow taking cover.
Got it on the second run,
right across here.
Knocked him
right over the side.
He was probably dead
by the time he hit the water.
Said he was getting married.
Yes, I know.
Somebody'll have
to tell his girl.
I know her. I'll do it.
- Did he give you the key?
- Yes.
Well...
Have a good time.
As long as it lasts.
Waiting for Number 12?
Yes. Is she out?
She's never out, that one. Not even
to do her shopping. I do that for her.
You try again, captain.
Stella?
I'm sorry.
They were strafed.
He was hit by machine-gun fire,
and he fell overboard.
Would you like some coffee?
No, thanks.
There isn't much in the house,
but I can open a tin.
I'm not hungry, thanks.
I could give you
some soup or a sandwich.
I really don't care
for anything.
Look, they tried to find him.
I... I checked.
They searched
as long as they could.
They were sure that
he was dead when...
when he went
over the side.
When do you want the flat?
I... I don't want it,
it's yours.
No, it's your now.
You promised him you would take it.
Otherwise, he would not
have given you the key.
I know all about it.
Yes, but I don't want it. I...
I wouldn't think of it.
The rent is paid until
the end of the month.
The chimney should be cleaned.
There is enough hot water
if you're careful.
Oh, the woman downstairs
will do your shopping.
You must watch her,
but she's kind.
Or you can do it yourself.
The shop's are not very far.
Fruit and vegetables are scarce-
Please! Please!
I'm sorry, I...
I mean, I know you're upset and
trying to make it easy on me, but...
This conversation about food and flat
and shopping and fruits and vegetables-
They're always hungry
when they come back.
They?
I thought we were
talking about Chris.
Chris is dead.
They are all dead.
Yes, they are,
aren't they?
You know something?
I think that first
impressions are the best.
Now I know where I am.
How would it be
if I moved in tonight?
I told you, the flat is yours.
And what about you?
Would you stay
if I ask you?
If you like.
And he was going
to marry you.
Maybe in a way it's
better that he got killed.
Oh, I see.
You're shocked.
I'm sorry.
I didn't think all those rules
were so important any more,
now that people are so busy
killing each other.
If you want anything, you can...
telephone me at the hotel or send a note.
Stay here as long
as you want.
If you want to go some place else,
I'll help you make the arrangements.
Thank you.
Goodnight.
Want a bottle
of whiskey, captain?
No. No, thanks.
- Canteen price.
- You save money.
No, thanks. Goodnight.
Stingy basket!
Get moving here! Fire!
Ruddy thing's stuck, sir!
Get up some steam.
There isn't time. Full ahead!
Fire!
Heave!
If we can't hit them at this range,
we can't hit anything!
300 yards. They've never been
this close before.
Heave!
Why aren't
they shooting?
I don't know.
Why aren't we shooting?
Fire!
- Fire!
- Action stations!
Fire, why don't you?
Come on, start firing!
What's the matter here?
What are you playing at?
What's the matter with you
down there? Fire! We can hit him!
It's jammed again, sir.
Engine room?
Engine room,
give me everything you got.
And if you mention the word "boiler",
I'll... I'll shove you into it!
I want that gun fixed.
You're the captain,
give the order.
I could've got that sub,
if I'd had a decent gun.
Yes, I'm sure
you could have.
They know we can't hurt them.
He came right alongside.
So you said.
Confidentially, we've just got the story
on this sub that's been worrying you.
It isn't a mine-layer at all.
It's an old French training ship that the Germans
have taken over and are using for the same purpose.
I should imagine they were giving the
new boys a chance to look you over,
that's what
it sounds like to me.
A training ship?
The captain's an old gunnery instructor
whose name, of all things, is Hasenfratz.
Would you believe it?
You mean, we're being
used for target practice?
Exactly.
Old Hasenfratz couldn't ask for anything
better. You make perfect targets.
You're small, but not too small, fast-
But not too fast, yes!
I don't think we should let it
be generally known, do you?
Then why did you tell me?
I thought it might be
of some help to you.
The only thing that might be of some
help would be some decent guns.
So why don't you try to get some, instead of
sitting there playing with that silly lighter?
There's no need
to be offensive, old chap.
You may not believe it,
but I've done my best.
I've been pleading for guns
ever since I was sent here.
By now, I'm sure they're filing my
reports in the nearest wastepaper basket.
The fact is, we don't have them.
We haven't any decent guns to give you.
There simply aren't enough to go round.
We haven't even got the new
armour plating we've asked for.
Look, you may
as well know it.
Every time a freighter's
left behind, it's written off.
Every time you bring
one in, it's sheer profit.
I'll go on pestering them for guns
till I'm black in the face
and they kick me out
to get rid of the buzzing in their ears!
But if you want my honest
opinion, you won't get your guns
till every merchantman in the
allied fleet has been fitted out.
I'm sorry, but that's how it is.
If it's any consolation to you,
you might care to consider
that you're not the only one.
- I'm sorry.
- It's all right.
No, no, I'm really sorry.
It's so hot in here. How
would you like to get some air?
On the beach, like?
That's nice.
I've heard that one before.
The only social service I do
is on a dance floor, sailor.
Congratulations, captain.
Thanks.
Moved into the flat yet?
No, I haven't moved
into the flat yet.
Hey, captain. Do you want a bottle
of whiskey? The best of Scotch?
Yes.
- How much?
- Canteen price.
One pound.
Er... three pounds.
Listen, Hasenfratz,
I happen to know that canteen price
is a pound, one pound!
The canteen is closed.
It's three pounds.
How would you like it
if I broke your neck?
It'll still be the same price.
Three pounds.
Happy dreams, captain.
Well?
Here comes another one.
I'm sorry.
I lost my balance.
And that's not all I lost.
When I came here,
I lost my... dignity,
and I lost my self-respect.
You know what I mean?
I'm drunk.
I'm drunk, so I'm going home.
Home to the Grand Hotel.
Room 77.
Don't send me
to Room 77, Stella.
I'll get sick to my stomach.
Thank you.
You know, everybody thinks they're
different. We're all the same.
I'm no different
from Chris or Van Barger.
Or that other fella up here.
Knock, knock. Who's there?
You know, you've got enough jackets
in there to open up a clothing store.
Hi, Philip.
It's too bad you are what you are.
But you are, aren't you?
You come with the flat, don't you?
Hey, Stella.
You had a hunch that Chris
was going to get it, didn't you?
I could see it on your face.
You had a premonition.
Can you always tell?
Number, please.
218, please.
Once upon a time, there was a
little man by the name of Hasenfratz-
If there are any calls
for Captain Ross,
he can be reached
at this number.
407.
- Thank you.
That was a brave thing to do.
I'm not brave.
I'm scared.
For the first time,
I'm really scared.
For the first time, I know
what Chris was talking about.
You know, they're all scared.
But I'm a captain.
I'm not supposed to be scared.
What did he tell me for?
I didn't want to know.
Who wants to be a target?
That's inhuman.
There's no dignity.
There's no...
That's no...
No...
Stella!
Don't go away.
Where are you going?
Too bad.
Hi.
Hello.
How did it go?
All right.
I, er...
Er... thought the place
could stand some flowers.
They are very pretty.
Thank you.
I'll go and wash.
I know you must be hungry.
He says:
"Water pressure damaged,
"fire in bow is out of control
and nearing forward oil tanks.
"Can you help?"
In what particular way?
I think he means, can we
help put out his fires, sir.
I was afraid you were
going to say that.
Okay. Tell him we're coming
with every bucket we've got.
What's he saying now?
He says he's very sorry and he
hopes he doesn't blow up in your...
Face.
- Port a little!
- Port a little, sir!
The line-gun ready?
Be quick as you can
with the connecting up, please!
Steady as you go!
- Steady as you go, sir!
- Fire hoses standing by, sir.
There's a line coming!
Let's go, forward hoses!
Midship hoses!
Ready, hoses!
Line-gun! Fire!
Please be quick
with your connecting up!
Weaver,
is your insurance all paid up?
Yes, sir.
You're a very smart fella.
Ready, sir.
Take it away!
Stand by and single up!
Hurry up with the towing spring there!
Anything I should
know, captain?
No, you're all set.
You can shove off anytime.
Thank you.
How did it go?
Good luck.
You've ordered the Pom-Pom overhauled
again. You know it is a waste of time.
Probably, but I still like
a gun that shoots.
And I hear you have
moved from the hotel.
You don't really have to bother
keeping tabs on me, captain.
That woman is bad luck.
She'll kill you.
Like she's killed all the others.
Oh, er, captain, do you sing?
No better than the last time
you asked me. Sorry.
Oh, yes, yes, yes. I remember. Pity.
Come, Hansie. Now we go to work.
Goodnight, sir.
Goodnight.
Night, sir.
Let go forward!
Let go aft!
...there seems little to report since our
last bulletin. And that is the end of the news.
- Oh, I'll get out of your hair.
- No, it's all right.
This is awfully good chocolate.
Thank you. Not as good
as we have at home.
Oh? Where's that?
Switzerland.
But you have an...
you have an Italian accent?
I know, because I come
from the Italian side.
I've never been to Switzerland.
They say it's beautiful.
Oh, yes, it's lovely.
I lived on a farm
very high up in the mountains.
Like Heidi?
There was a little lake,
very pretty, always blue.
You must miss it?
No.
My family are dead
and I had no friends.
Must have been lonely.
Perhaps I was.
When I was very small,
my grandmother told me a story
about two lovers who
were separated by the sea.
And they used to send each other
letters in little boxes on the tide.
I thought it was a wonderful story.
I wrote "I love you" on a little
piece of paper and I put it in a tin,
and one morning I went down
to the lake and I let it float away.
I hoped that someone on the far shore
would find it and write back to me.
Did they?
No. Would you like
some more chocolate?
No, thanks.
I'll get your sleeping pills.
Goodnight.
Fire!
Fire! He's right on top of us!
No! No!
No!
No...
Mine!
- Hard to starboard!
- Hard to starboard, sir!
Hard to port!
Blow it up!
Make sure we're clear!
David, the telephone!
David!
It's all right, darling, I've got it.
I beg your pardon.
Sorry, I was talking
to someone else. What is it?
Oh, nothing really.
I just thought you might like to know the
United States of America have come into the war.
No kidding! On which side?
I think that's in rather
poor taste, old chap,
considering they're your people
and they've done more-
Forgive me, commander. I guess
I'm not quite awake. What happened?
It seems the Japanese bombed
some place called Pearl Harbour.
Did a lot of damage too.
Lots of casualties, I'm afraid.
Oh, I'm sorry.
They must be crazy!
What is it?
It's all right, darling.
It's good news in the long run.
- Yes, isn't it, darling?
- See you soon, darling.
What is it, David?
What did he say?
Come here, I'll tell you.
Tell me now!
America's come into the war.
Does that mean that
you will get better guns?
I hope so.
Right now, I'd like
to get some breakfast.
It's a-possible?
It's possible.
Hey...
Philip?
Philip...
Oh, dear God! Philip!
Oh! Forgive me, Philip!
Oh, forgive me!
Home and dry
in an hour, sir.
This is all highly irregular.
There is something wrong?
Yes, well, you see, you were reported
killed in an air raid almost a year ago,
and it'll be
a fearful mess to untangle.
Oh...
Well, what can we do?
Well, what was it
you wanted anyway?
Well, I... I thought
I could do some kind of work
at home on parachutes,
perhaps... anything.
Oh, yes, I see.
Right, fill out this form,
will you, please?
Thank you.
It's bound to cause
a great deal of confusin.
Well, I'm very sorry.
Hey, where are you?
Stella?
- Oh, thank goodness!
- She told me you were back.
- I've been out shopping.
- Oh, so I see.
It was exciting.
I'll bet.
How do you like
my new dress, hm?
I love it.
You know, a woman at the Labour
Exchange said I was killed by a bomb,
and she was very angry with me.
Oh...
How pretty. Thank you.
You're welcome.
Are you all right?
How did it go?
Fine. No trouble.
Hasenfratz never
showed up at all.
Why didn't you wake me
when you left?
Because you look so pretty
when you're asleep.
I... woke myself up... anyway.
- Did you?
- Yes.
When I came in
and you weren't here,
I thought you'd gone away.
Never.
Never go away.
If you're going to be
doing the shopping,
going in and out,
you'll need a key.
I've got an extra one.
I had one made. I've just been
carrying it around with me.
I think you ought
to have it from now on.
Would you marry me, David?
Only if you'll marry me.
You were very good to me.
You put me to bed,
and you didn't ask questions.
There's no sense in asking
questions if you know the answers.
- Do you?
- Yes.
I would like to tell you...
more than you know...
about Philip and afterward.
Some other time.
We have got lots of time.
We've got all the time
in the worid.
Yes, we have.
I can't understand it. I got
a merit badge for this once.
Never mind now. Look.
Happy Christmas, darling.
And very merry Christmas to you.
Shall we open
our presents now?
No. Later.
Except this one.
This is all for me?
Hm.
It's very nice.
Open it.
I haven't anything
nearly as nice for you.
I'm not afraid.
Now sit down.
No, sir. Not until I get
this roaring fire roaring!
There's one last hope.
I don't know why this always works.
But it creates a draught or something.
You see, it's possible.
See, I told you it would work.
We... better go down to the shelter.
Yes.
# In fields where they
Lay keeping their sheep #
# Nol, Nol ##
Don't leave anything around.
And it's time that poor dog went out.
- David.
- Yes, darling.
What is it?
Nothing. I...
Oh, the food is all spoiled. I am
sorry. Shall I make you some chocolate?
No, thanks. Not for me.
I'm tired. I think I'll go to bed.
Shall we open our presents now?
Let's do it in the morning, huh?
All right.
Are you going somewhere?
Would you mind
if I go to midnight mass?
No, I don't mind. It's late.
I'll walk you to the church.
No, I'll be all right.
No, I'll walk you to the church.
No, please.
You need your rest.
What's the matter?
Nothing. I wasn't sleepy.
Was it a nice mass?
I didn't go in.
I didn't think I had the right.
Excuse me. Your telephone seems to have gone
out of order in the raid, and they sent me over.
Skipper, we've got a job.
It's Van Dam's turn.
Yes. They can't find him.
They want us right away.
Okay.
I'll go on ahead.
So sorry.
I'll make you some coffee.
I don't think there's time.
Where are you going?
I want to go with you to the pier.
It's too late. I...
I don't want you coming home
alone so late.
You can see me off some other time.
Don't worry.
Nothing to worry about.
David, please.
I said no.
Go to bed, you hear?
David... don't go.
Look, I don't believe in premonitions,
yours or anyone else's!
And I'll tell you something else. A
man once told me you were bad luck.
And I don't believe that either!
Then there was Chris.
He said that none of us
would get out of this alive.
But if that's true,
then there's nothing.
Nothing to hope for, nothing to believe
in. We've just been kidding ourselves.
It's not true!
I'm not like the others!
I'm not going to wind up just
another jacket on a hanger in there!
And I'm not going to die!
Not tonight, anyway.
Go to bed.
Lord, what a mess!
Just listen to him squeak.
What's the story on Van Dam?
I don't know.
He hasn't turned up.
We're hoping it's nothing
to do with the bombing.
Okay, what have I got?
Freighter on fire.
In position 50 north, 9 west.
That's not a duck, is it?
It is.
- Sending an open SOS?
- Yes.
- Another one.
- No. I'm afraid it's yours.
Don't be silly. He hasn't
been squeaking all this time.
Is he crazy? He'll have every U-boat
in the North Atlantic swarming all over him!
I can only think he's forgotten
to open his sealed instructions.
He's one of your people.
It's our first all-American convoy.
Carrying guns,
oddly enough.
Why don't you tell them?
What have you
got them for?
We can't, sir.
His receiver's not working.
I'm not going.
Why should I?
What do I tell my crew?
"This is the end of the line"?
"There isn't a chance in the worid, but let's
all go out and get killed because we're heroes"?
"Hurry for the Light Brigade"?
W-86 has just come in.
I'm sending her out as soon as
I can get another crew together.
I'm afraid it's bad luck all round,
but I'm sure you'll make the best of it.
Sure.
Let's get moving W-86.
Stand by to cast off.
All right, let's get moving.
Skipper-
How about getting
this ship ready for sea?
Skipper...
Yes?
On the radio, that duck's
sending out an open SOS.
Yes, I know.
Well, they're not really going to send us
out, are they? I mean, it's hopeless, isn't it?
There's no point to it, is there?
Maybe if you were to talk
to them at headquarters...
Sparks, when I want
your advice, I'll ask for it!
Get back to the radio.
Yes, sir.
Sorry, sir.
Sparks...
Nothing.
Hey!
Here.
We're ready, skipper.
All right, shove off.
Always the same?
Always to end like this?
Is there no pity?
Please.
Please?
I can't see what he's firing at.
- Have we got a chance, skipper?
- We'll be all right.
I don't see how
we can be, frankly.
- Sir!
- Yes?
He says they've used up all their ammunition
and you can't depend on him for covering fire.
Does he say
how many subs he's got?
No, sir.
That does it.
Engine room! Engine room!
Secure the bulkheads!
Hard to port!
I said hard to port!
She's fouled, sir.
She won't turn except to starboard.
The engine room's gone and
the boiler's going any minute.
All right, abandon ship!
Get out! I'm going
to ram them! Get out!
Abandon ship!
"Tug... blew up... ramming sub.
"What... happens... now?"
Operator?
Sir?
See if you can reach W-86.
Steady as you go.
Dead slow.
Dead slow, sir.
David?
I'm sorry.
He gave you the key?
Yes.
Look, look, I'm all right. Let go!
You'll stay here
until that's stitched up.
I've got to get home!
Are you the guy that rammed that sub and saved
my ship? Mister, I want to shake your hand.
Why did you break silence?
Why didn't you follow
your instructions?
Instructions?
I never had a chance
to open them up.
My chart room was busted
wide open on the first shot.
I think it would be a good idea if you two
fellow countrymen kissed and made up, don't you?
Or shook hands, anyway.
Look, I want to thank you.
I really want to thank you.
I want to show you somebody who'll never
forget what you did for them tonight.
Oh, this lousy war.
Yeah, and yours is
only three weeks old.
Get out.
Get out!
# The flat-foot floogie
With the floy doy #
# Floy doy, floy doy
Floy doy, floy doy #
# The flat-foot floogie
With the floy doy... ##
I looked everywhere for you.
This was my last stop.
How would you like to go
fifty-fifty on the flat?
She's gone.
Where?
London. I took her to the station.
- How was she?
- All right.
She asked me
to give you this.
She said you forgot.
When did she leave?
About now, I guess.
Don't be a fool!
She's gone!
Ticket, please.
Thank you.
Sorry, too late!
- Let him go by!
- His girl's on that train!
I'm sorry, boys, it's too late.
Look, give him
a break, will you?
I'll find her.
When I get back to London,
Sure.
I will!