THE AUCTION
Come on, pal.
Need me today, Mr. Gagnon?
You can clean out the pens
in the main barn, OK?
Morning, neighbour!
Léo Savard's selling off his farm.
Interested?
You got company coming?
My oldest, her husband and the kids.
- And your other daughter?
- Frédérique?
With her, who knows?
I don't hear from her much.
Maybe she'll show up and surprise me.
But I doubt it.
Here. You'll have some dessert.
That's nice of you. Thanks.
I let myself in. It was open.
You're about to enter the 21st century!
Gagnon & Sons is going high-tech.
Humanity's highest achievement
right here, Gaby.
You can enter all your bills
and expenses as soon as they come in
and do your audit trail.
It'll save you time and paperwork.
I'd rather you went on doing it for me.
It's already crowded here.
You'll see, Gaby. It's a cinch.
- How much do I owe you?
- Gaby, Gaby... It's repurposed.
The kids at the youth centre refurbish them.
Dedicated bicycle thieves and gamers.
You should drop by.
This is the third one I've picked up.
The punk told me
they're for non-profit organizations only.
I said: " It's for a farm, you twit!
Any less of a profit,
and it'd be a charity!"
He wants your company's
registration number.
That little punk
can take his number and shove it.
I'm unloading their junk
to help them out.
That's the last they'll see of me.
I'm done with community service.
The bullshit never ends.
We'll check later to see if it works.
The family still coming this weekend?
Good! That'll make this dad happy.
With them fancy city folk.
How much for the computer?
I told you, it's free.
We gotta hook you up to the Net
so you can ogle naked girls.
What do you think?
Say hi to everyone for me.
Need anything from the city?
No, I'm going into town later.
Call me if you get bored.
Stay here, pal!
Hi!
Where's your husband?
He's swamped at work.
He couldn't make it.
Well, well, well!
What do we have here?
Who are these two big boys?
I'll unbuckle you in a minute.
How are you?
You want to go see the sheep?
You haven't seen Grandpa in a while.
- I wanna go on the four-wheeler...
- We will.
I'll take the bags in, OK?
Want to hold him?
Sometimes he wiggles around a lot.
He won't hurt you.
You have to feed him this way.
Hold it up.
There. See?
Frédérique didn't want to come?
Couldn't she afford the train?
I would've paid.
I offered her a ride,
but she never called back.
It's like she doesn't want to see us.
Guess we're not important enough.
- Do you ever see her?
- No more than you.
You both could try harder.
She should get to know her nephews.
You're sisters, just the two of you.
I'm out here,
but you're in the same city.
Not the same world, though.
She's always busy with her theatre friends.
Me, it's the kids, our friends,
Steve's family.
Do you ever see your relatives?
Your brothers?
You should make an effort.
Try to see each other.
Or at least touch base occasionally.
That's easy enough.
- Can I have more cake?
- Not tonight.
Let's go.
They'll get confused.
No, they won't. Their dad's English.
I guess.
So what's new here?
Nothing's new. It's all old.
I'm getting lazy.
Lazy? Three days off in 40 years.
I was lucky. It could've been two.
I haven't been here in months.
Something must've changed.
I don't know.
I lost a lamb this morning.
My neighbour bought a new tractor.
That's new.
No idea how he'll pay for it.
The new ones cost a bundle.
You're better off
keeping the old clunkers going.
How's your husband?
How's business?
He works a lot.
He's often out of town.
He meets with potential investors...
a lot.
In Toronto?
Toronto, Vancouver, New York.
He's on the road.
- Who's outside?
- The Bouchard kid.
Irène and Jean-Marie's boy.
He does chores on weekdays.
It gives me a break.
It's Saturday.
Yep, it's Saturday.
I've tried telling the sheep,
but they don't get it.
I asked him to come
so I could eat with you.
We'd be best friends in no time.
I promised them each a lamb
if you moved back.
Dad!
Want to go see the pond?
Let's walk to the pond.
You go. It's been fun.
Come on, let's go.
Grandpa wooed girls there
when he was young and handsome.
Come on!
We're gonna see some frogs.
I know where they are.
- Where are they?
- In the pond.
You're leaving already?
Wait until tomorrow.
You came all this way.
It's a six-hour drive.
I'd rather head out.
Will you visit your mother?
I saw her a little while ago.
She spent a week with us.
- You could come to Montreal too.
- You know I can't.
We'll try to come back soon.
Bye, sweetheart.
You'll come back
and see the sheep, right?
I left Steve.
We've decided to separate.
I wanted to tell you last week.
I just couldn't.
I would have left long ago,
but I got pregnant with Thomas.
I want to keep the house.
It's better for the boys.
Steve doesn't want it.
He'll take the condo downtown.
I need money.
To buy out his half.
Can't he just give you the house?
He's in debt. He has to sell.
Don't you have any savings?
I'm in debt too.
We can't keep up with the payments.
Isn't your house paid for?
The cars, the house...
We don't own any of it.
I thought with your assets, the land...
you could take out a loan.
I need about $200,000.
It's a lot, I know.
I can pay you
when things are back to normal.
Otherwise,
I'll feel like I'm back at square one.
I'm thinking of the boys.
I'm surprised.
I thought you were fairly well off.
But why don't you move back here?
There's room. I'll take care of you.
Dad, I've told you a thousand times:
We're not going to live here.
A loan...
I'm up to my eyeballs with the farm.
I'll see what I can do.
I've helped your sister with her
rent enough times. It's your turn.
Don't worry.
You need to keep the house, I know.
I'll help you out.
I promise. I'll take care of you.
Mr. Gagnon, we've reviewed your file.
Unfortunately, your application was denied.
Your net annual income is $10,000.
You're close to retiring.
But I have the land as collateral.
You already have a loan
and a line of credit.
Even with your land
and farming operation,
we are unable to grant you a loan.
I think you suspected as much.
Move, move, move!
Hello?
Hi, Marie.
What about the boys?
Yes, I went to the bank.
There's still some stuff to settle,
but I can get the money.
Don't worry, OK?
Things'll get better.
It's just a rough patch.
I'll let you know.
Bye, Marie.
$300, gentlemen!
$325! $350!
400 bucks!
$400! Who'll give $425?
$500!
Do I hear $525?
$525!
How about $550?
$550!
Anyone give me $575?
$575! $600?
$600! $625?
$650? $650! $675?
$675!
$700, I have 700 bucks!
Last offer $700!
Sold to the gentleman over there.
A bargain, gentlemen.
Do I hear $200 from anyone? $150?
$125, thank you.
Anyone want to give me $150?
$150! $175?
$175! How about $200?
$200 for you.
Do I hear $225?
$225! $250?
$250! Do I hear $275?
$275! Do I hear $300?
$300! Who'll give me $325?
$325! $350? $350!
Lots of people came out.
Yep.
There comes a point in life
when you have to hold a funeral
to see people.
I'm real happy to see you, Gaby.
Everybody's here. I'm glad.
Got your eyes on anything?
How you holding up?
To tell you the truth,
I haven't slept much these past few days.
But that'll change.
What'll you do now?
We'll rest.
We'll have to rest.
Here's the heifer you've been waiting for.
A descendent of Starbuck, my friends.
Have a look.
You've seen her mother
and grandmother at the shows.
I'm sure we'll be seeing her too.
She's just one year old.
So who'll give me $1,500
to get the ball rolling? $1,400?
I've got $1,200. I'll take it.
$1,225! Who'll go $1,250?
$1,275!
$1,300 for this magnificent creature!
$1,400! No, $1,425!
Do I hear $1,450?
Turn her around. Have a good look
at the legs on this one!
$1,450! Do I hear $1,475?
$1,600! Who'll give me $1,625?
$1,625! $1,650! $1,675!
Do I hear $1,700? $1,700!
Gaby!
I'll be in the house!
- So naked girls aren't your thing?
- Take it with you.
It's just gathering dust.
I can't find this month's latest power bill.
Top of the pile next to the green folders.
I was wondering...
How much could I get if I sold?
Sold?
Sold what?
If I sold off the farm.
Not you, Gaby.
Just a rough estimate.
You know roughly how much.
Almost nothing.
If you sell off the farm and everything on
it, and I mean everything...
your herd, the land, even the house...
Your land's worth something, but that's it.
And it's not flat.
You can't take a crop off it.
After you paid off your loan
and line of credit,
you'd have almost nothing left to retire on.
It's not enough.
You farmers have nothing to fall back on.
On a guess,
I'd say things'll be tight once you retire.
Unless you're lucky and croak young.
And where would you go?
No places to rent around here.
And you in the city? No way!
You can't afford to quit.
You have to keep at it till you die,
like everyone else.
My brothers were smart to get out in time.
What do you mean? You love it here!
You've got your sheep.
The Bouchard boy helps out.
I'd like to spoil my girls.
So Marie asked you for money again?
They are splitting up.
You never see them.
The girls don't need you anymore.
Your little princesses are all grown up.
They have you wrapped around
their little fingers.
They're kids.
You've done everything for them.
You paid for everything...
their education and every little whim.
And you always went without.
You don't need to do that now.
I admire what you've done for them.
But you can't go overboard.
Be reasonable.
Reasonable?
They still need me, even at 30.
I'm still their father.
OK. I've heard about enough.
You can't sell. That's crazy talk.
Not you, Gaby.
Everyone else can sell, but not you.
You have the nicest sheep farm around.
Not a word to anyone, OK?
Who would I tell?
Enough of this. Time for a drink.
Here's to your farm, Gaby!
We're here.
Right this way.
This is the owner, my good friend Gaby.
Hello. Welcome.
You can pay Gaby directly,
and then you can go in
and take your pick.
But you have to pay him up front.
Did I say how much? Great.
So let's head inside.
We'll follow Gaby.
He'll show us the way.
This way. Go right on in.
That one?
Is this one good?
More than a dozen families
have moved into town.
They've been hired to clear underbrush.
Hard work doesn't scare 'em.
They pay cash. Nice!
I took them to Jean-Marie's slaughterhouse.
When he saw the priest with that knife
and his whole delegation -
maybe 25 of them...
Poor Jean-Marie!
He wanted to kill the ewe
with his baseball bat!
They were horrified, you can imagine!
You should've seen it:
Babe Ruth and the Muslims!
So I can make this a regular thing.
I'd be glad to help.
No. I'm happy we did it,
but once is enough.
The law says
if you slaughter an animal yourself,
you can buy directly from the farm,
no middleman.
We can do it legally.
All aboveboard.
Make some cash.
It doesn't pay.
Everything all right?
I have some errands to run in town.
Mr. Gagnon?
Thanks for agreeing to see me.
Is it too late for breakfast?
I'd like some breakfast.
Right, I'll start by giving you my card.
There.
So, we're here today
to do an initial evaluation
of your establishment,
so you know what your assets are worth
and to consider some tax-related questions.
I'll also tell you about my team.
We take over,
prepare the herd and your machinery
so you get top dollar.
We do all the advertising,
the auction notice,
the website and the catalogue.
We put together the catalogue,
the inventory and so forth.
We believe your life's work
should be entrusted
to a team of professionals.
So...
Gaby!
What the hell is this?
You went ahead on your own?
An auction?
"Gagnon & Sons Farm Auction.
Land, home and equipment.
"Everyone welcome.
1214 Rural Route 3."
You're selling it all off, Gaby?
Have you gone crazy?
Your home! Your father's land!
Your goddamn sheep, Gaby!
Where will you go?
Where will you go!
Here's your goddamn farming newsletter!
Calm down.
I have to find an apartment.
I told you,
don't leave your junk in the hallway!
Put your crap away!
I won't warn you again.
This is it.
Here's the bedroom.
It has to be cleaned and repainted.
The tenants left yesterday.
It hasn't been fixed up yet.
There were eight of them.
A bunch of kids from up north.
Took off without paying.
It's always the same.
Either they skip out,
get kicked out or die.
Same difference, anyway.
None of them come back
to apologize or pay up!
Look! They left all their empties.
At least I can turn them in for the deposit.
So that's that.
If you decide to take it,
I'll need references.
I'm calling about the apartment for rent.
Is that per month or per week?
Are you nuts?
That's not exactly a palace
you've got there.
Jesus, is there a pool or something
that's not in the photo?
Thing you're god's gift?
What's your name?
I'm not threatening,
I'm asking your name.
Want me to come over?
Give me the address!
Right. Screw you!
There's not much at that price.
I'm out of ideas.
Why are you looking at dumps like this?
You're not some dog.
There's a place on the highway
near the bridge.
That's an old folks' home!
No, it's not. It's social housing.
With old people in it.
So it's an old folks' home.
Well, that's convenient. I am old.
Just until I find something better.
The apartments are no different.
See?
They take people 50 and up
and it'll be clean.
Until I find work in town.
Why not check in to the cemetery now?
I'm not going.
My wife's waiting for me.
She'll think I'm having an affair
'cause I'm hanging out
with a 63-year-old has-been.
Keep an eye on him.
Don't let him run off.
We had a common room,
but no one used it,
so we closed it up.
No common room.
Just private apartments.
Here it is.
This is the kind of unit we have.
Got any kids, Mr. Gagnon?
Yes. Two daughters.
They won't visit you here.
They'll come at first,
but all of a sudden they'll stop.
I want to be straight.
It won't be any different for you.
When a car pulls up here, it's a big event.
You look too sturdy to be moving here.
It's temporary,
until things get back to normal.
Are the neighbours quiet?
Hard to get any quieter.
You must be wondering
what that musty smell is.
The lady before
never opened her door or windows.
I can't stand that smell.
- What did you use to do?
- Sheep farmer.
So you must be used to shut-in smells.
By sheep, you mean lambs?
Well, I can show you
the other units if you want,
but trust me, they're all the same.
No need, I've made up my mind.
I'll take this one,
with the window and the balcony.
It's done.
Bravo.
I saw the "For Sale" sign.
Are you selling the house or the farm?
Everything.
Why? Interested?
Of course I'm interested.
Are you buying or just snooping?
You can't up and sell the farm!
You should have talked to us first!
I have to get rid of my dog.
Any chance you'd take him?
I can't. I've already got mine.
And they don't get along.
I can't put him down.
Ridiculous, huh?
I've done it plenty of times,
but this time I can't.
You know, François talked about you
the day before he died.
Before he pulled that stunt.
He said you still
walked your land every day,
that you never stopped doing it.
He would've been sad to see you leaving,
selling off such a beautiful farm.
He loved your farm.
I think he was jealous.
I don't know how
I'm gonna manage on my own.
You should hire the Bouchard boy.
I'd be grateful.
He's a good worker, reliable.
You won't feel so alone.
And I'd be glad to think
I found him another job.
OK, I'll call him.
Come on!
Yes?
- Is it for this dog?
- Yes.
Is he sick?
Is there some other problem?
How old is he?
Ten.
- To euthanize him?
- Yes.
It's $25.
How do you do it?
Gas cylinder. Takes about 15 seconds.
I'll take him out back.
I'll do it at 3:00.
It's $25.
Give him to me.
Dad left the land to all three of us.
It's the only thing he left us.
All we got was Mom's silverware.
You've been earning a living
here on Dad's land for 40 years.
That's perfectly fine.
But now, if you sell it...
we think we deserve a share.
It wouldn't be fair for you to keep it all.
I've run this place by myself for 40 years.
You wanted nothing to do with it.
You left me to take care of everything.
You were happy I took over.
You don't know what hard work
and sacrifice mean.
You've never been around,
never lost a moment's sleep
over the farm.
It's none of your business.
Just leave me alone!
- Go away.
- Don't be like that, Gaby.
I said get out!
Thank you.
- How are you?
- Fine.
How about you?
Can I help you?
It's for Frédérique.
I was wondering what to get her.
She doesn't wear jewellery.
I thought maybe a watch.
Women's wristwatches are over here.
This one? Which one do you like?
This one's more understated.
It's more her style.
- Doesn't she have a watch?
- I don't know.
This one's pretty.
I'll take it. It's nice.
Shall I gift-wrap it?
You're going to wrap it?
I can do it.
If you want to.
You drove a half-hour just for this?
I wanted to talk.
Talk?
Can we go somewhere more private?
Now?
If you can.
I have to stay here.
André's busy in the back.
I'll call you then.
Yes, it's better that way.
The watch!
Right, the watch.
I'm selling the farm.
Still have that old sweater?
I never wear it, so it's like new.
My clothes never get worn out.
Do you see the girls very often?
I saw Marie a little while ago.
How about you?
I see them whenever I go to Montreal.
Pretty often.
I talk to them on the phone.
I saw Frédérique in a play.
She's really good.
What got into you?
What did the girls have to say?
The girls? If they had anything to say,
they should've spoken up sooner.
They don't know yet.
And I don't want you to tell them.
The farm means nothing to them.
They're busy with their own lives.
Frédérique might care.
Frédérique? I never hear from her!
What about your nephew Marc?
Marc? He couldn't care less!
I encouraged him,
but he's just like his dad.
And my other brother...
You always said a farm
should be passed down, not sold.
Sure, but nobody wants it, Françoise!
Nobody wants it.
You should've talked to them.
I did everything I could. I tried.
You can still live in the house.
I'm selling that too. I have to.
I'm renting an apartment.
- An apartment?
- A little one-bedroom place.
I'm going to try
and find work here in town.
Why did you come?
I want us to get back together.
Have your lost your mind?
In your apartment?
I'm with André.
Remember André, my husband?
I'm your husband.
Get back together?
I hope that's not why
you're selling the farm!
Good gosh, we split up 20 years ago!
I've moved on.
Honestly!
I have to go.
I don't know what you'll do
without your farm. I don't get it.
Is the lady coming back?
Dad?
Your friend Louis called me.
He said maybe I should come see you.
Why are you doing it?
Is it Marie?
Did she ask you for money?
Does she know?
I didn't tell her.
I don't want her to know.
She'd feel terrible.
When your mother and I got married,
we said my dad's farm would be there
to get us over any bumps in the road,
the tough times in life.
It brought us such happiness.
And we thought it would be there
for you and Marie.
But thinking back, I realize
that all the problems I've had in life
are because of this farm.
You understand?
First my brothers left.
Then your mother.
Because of the farm.
She couldn't stand it.
She was suffocating.
And then you two left.
Gagnon & Sons kept me up
every single night.
It did its best to make me miserable,
to make me feel guilty.
But it's my farm, and nobody else's.
It kept me here.
It's been dragging me down all my life.
Now, it's my turn to get my due,
what I'm owed.
I never had any sons to help me out,
but I have two daughters I love.
Everyone always said that my life
was my farm, my land.
But they were all wrong.
My life is my children.
It's you two.
Fathers need to give to be happy.
We're like that.
I want you to live your life
the way you want to, that's all.
Your sister needs money.
I thought this would be best.
Marie's taking advantage of you.
I know.
She's always been like that.
She can take advantage of me.
I don't mind.
I'm proud of you two, you know.
I'm glad you got out of here
and did something else.
I don't want you to give up acting,
or the big city.
- You've never even seen me on stage, Dad!
- Not because I didn't want to.
Now I can go see you.
The auction is tomorrow.
I'm selling the herd, the buildings,
the equipment and machinery, the house.
I don't want any of it.
Now I can come to Montreal.
Going home already?
There's no rush.
I can stay a day or two.
All week if you want.
The Texels you see here,
the 3-year-old ewes,
are guaranteed pregnant since September.
There are eight ewes in all.
We're selling them individually.
How much do I hear for these fine ewes?
Who'll give me $200?
I've got $100 to start.
Anybody say $125?
$125! Do I hear $150?
$150! Do I hear $175?
We're still at $150, boys.
They're worth so much more!
$175! Do I hear $200, folks?
$200! $225?
Do I hear $210 then?
$210! $220?
$220! $230...
$260, guys.
That's too low for purebreds like these!
$260! Do I hear $260?
$270! Do I hear 280$?
$300, thank you!
I have $300 for the ewe.
Do I hear $310?
If nobody can top $300,
that's gonna be the end of it!
Sold! $300 for the ewes right here, folks!
OK! Bring me the next lot, boys.
We're ready!
Louis bought something.
To make you happy, I bet.
My blue compressor.
He's wanted it for a long time.
He kept asking for it.
They sold the herd.
Where are you gonna put all this?
I'm renting a storage locker in town.
For most of the furniture.
My apartment's pretty small.
Your apartment...
You have a computer?
Louis brought it. I don't use it.
- Does it work?
- I don't know.
I'll come see you in Montreal.
Promise.
I bought you a present.
A watch.
You can open it on the train.
A watch?
How did it go?
Not great is an understatement.
I'm here for my new compressor.
Pleasure doing business with you.
Call me if you get bored.
Come on, pal.
We received the papers
from your real estate agent
and the offer on the land.
The papers for the loan
are all ready to sign.
My daughter should be here any minute.
She called earlier.
She was held up,
so we made other arrangements.
We'll fax the documents
so she can sign them.
No need for her to come all this way.
Here we go.
I just need you to sign here.
And here.
Your initials here.
Subtitling: CNST, Montreal