In my younger
and more vulnerable years,
my father gave me some advice
that I've been considering ever since.
"When you feel like criticising anyone,"
he told me,
"remember that all the people in this
world haven't had your advantages."
In consequence, I'm inclined
to reserve all my judgements.
It was by chance that I decided
to spend the summer
on that slender, riotous island
that juts out into the Long Island Sound,
20 miles due east of New York.
I lived at West Egg on the, well, less
fashionable side of the courtesy bay.
My cousin, Daisy Buchanan,
lived in one of East Egg's
glittering white palaces,
with her husband Tom,
whom I'd known in college-
They had spent the years since
their marriage drifting unrestfully,
wherever people played polo
and were rich together.
Nick Carraway!
Nick, it's about time.
I'm not sure how to operate that thing.
If you'd said, we'd have sent the
motor cruiser for you.
How are you?
- Is this all yours?
- Some of it belongs to Daisy.
- Where's your place?
- Across the bay.
Just a little cottage
I got for $80 a month.
$80 a month!
Our beer bills at New Haven
were more than that.
You forget,
I am now just a struggling bond
salesman on Wall Street.
Nick?
- Is it really you?
- It is.
My dear lost love!
I'm paralysed with happiness!
Jordan, this is my second cousin
once removed, Nick Carraway.
Does that mean we kiss when we greet?
I hope it means we do.
Tom says you've come from Chicago.
Tell me everything.
- Do they miss me?
- The whole town is desolate.
How gorgeous!
All the cars have their left rear wheel
painted black in mourning,
and there's a persistent wail all night.
Let's go back tomorrow, Tom.
I love a persistent wail.
Well, I love a drink.
Come on, let's all have a drink.
I've been lying on that sofa
for as long as I can remember.
You live in West Egg.
I know somebody there.
- I don't know anyone.
- You must know Gatsby.
- He's my neighbour.
- Gatsby? What Gatsby?
Come on, Daisy.
Why candles?
In two weeks,
it'll be the longest day in the year.
Do you watch for the longest day
in the year and then miss it? I do.
- We ought to plan something.
- All right. What'll we plan?
What do people plan?
Look at that...
My little finger, it's all black and blue.
You did that, Tom.
You didn't mean to, but that's what I get
for marrying a brute of a man.
- A great big hulking brute of a man.
- I hate that word "hulking".
Even in kidding.
- Hulking.
- Please, let's not start one of those.
Nick, have you read The Rise
of the Coloured Empires by Goddard?
- Why, no.
- Fine book. Everyone should read it.
See, the point is
that if we don't watch out,
the white race will be
utterly submerged... No, that's so!
We, the dominant race, must watch out,
or these other races will take control.
- We've got to beat them down.
- Daisy, it's all been scientifically proved.
You see, we're Nordics.
You are, and I am, and...
Excuse me, sir.
Thank you.
Excuse me.
Any Way...
We're responsible for everything
that made civilisation.
Art, science, and all that.
I love to see you at my table, Nick.
You remind me of a...
A rose, an absolute rose. Doesn't he?
You're Jordan Baker,
the golf champion...
Don't talk. I want to hear what happens.
- Is something happening?
- You don't know?
- I thought everyone knew.
- I don't.
Tom's got a woman in New York.
She might have the decency
not to phone him at dinner time.
Couldn't be helped.
There's a bird on the lawn.
I think it's a nightingale, come over
on the Cunard or the White Star Line.
He's singing away.
It's romantic, isn't it, Tom?
Yes, it is romantic.
It had been a golden afternoon.
I had the familiar conviction that life
was beginning again with the summer.
By the autumn, my mood
would be very different.
- Goodnight!
- Come back soon!
I would want no more privileged
glimpses into the human heart.
Only my neighbour, Gatsby,
would be exempt from my reaction.
Gatsby, who represented everything
for which I have an unaffected scorn.
For Gatsby turned out all right
in the end.
It was what preyed on him,
what foul dust floated
in the wake of his dreams.
At least once a fortnight,
a corps of caterers came
with several hundred feet of canvas
and enough coloured lights to make
a Christmas tree of Gatsby's gardens.
There was music from my neighbour's
house through those summer nights.
In his enchanted gardens, men and girls
came and went like moths,
among the whispering
and the champagne and the stars.
I believe few people were actually
invited to these parties, they just went.
They got into automobiles
which bore them to Long Island,
and somehow
they ended up at Gatsby's door,
come for the party with a simplicity of
heart that was its own admission ticket.
After that, they conducted themselves
according to the rules of behaviour
associated with an amusement park.
About half way between
the two Eggs and New York,
the motor road hastily joins the rail road
and runs beside it a short distance,
presided over by the eyes
of Doctor T J Eckleburg,
set there by some wild wag of an oculist
to fatten his practice in Queens.
This desolate area is a valley of ashes,
a fantastic farm
where ashes grow like wheat.
Come on in. I want you to meet my girl.
Wilson!
Wilson, old man...
- How's business?
- Can't complain.
- When will you sell me that car?
- Next week. My man's working on it.
- Works a little slow, don't he?
- No, as a matter of fact, he doesn't.
If you're not interested in buying it,
I'm sure...
...that I can find someone who is.
I didn't mean that, I just meant that...
I figure I could fix it up and turn a profit.
Myrtle Wilson,
this is Nick Carraway. Nick...
Mr and Mrs Wilson.
Why don't you get chairs,
so someone can sit down?
Sure.
I want you to get on the next train.
All right.
I'll meet you in the city.
I really could use that car.
Think I got a buyer for it.
That's fine... Fine.
I'll make sure my man stays right on it.
Nick. Mrs Wilson, nice to see you.
Bye.
Tom!
Hello, Nick.
Stop! Stop here.
I wanna get one of these dogs.
I want one for the apartment.
They're so nice to have.
- What kind are they?
- All kinds.
What kind would you like, lady?
I'd like one of those police dogs.
That's no police dog!
That dog's not exactly a police dog,
he's more of an Airedale.
Look at that coat. Some coat!
That dog will never bother you
with catching a cold.
I think it's cute. How much is it?
That dog?
That dog will cost you $10.
- Is it a boy or a girl?
- That dog?
That dog's a boy.
That dog's a bitch! Here's $10,
go buy ten more dogs with it.
- I'll leave you.
- No, you don't!
Myrtle'd be very hurt if you wouldn't
come up to the apartment.
Come on. I'll call my sister Catherine.
People say she's beautiful.
- What about our appointments?
- Wall Street will be there tomorrow.
Really, Myrtle, that dress!
I think it's adorable!
It's just a crazy old thing. I slip it on
when I don't care what I look like.
It looks wonderful on you,
if you know what I mean.
I think if Chester could
get you in that pose...
I think he could
really make something of it.
I'm Catherine, Myrtle's sister.
People say we look like twins,
but I don't think so.
I'm Nick. Won't you sit down?
I told that boy about the ice.
These servants! You really have to
keep after them all the time.
- You live down on Long Island, too?
- Yes, in West Egg.
Really?
I was down at a party in West Egg
about a month ago,
at a man named Gatsby's.
- Do you know him?
- I live next door to him.
He's German.
Really. The cousin or nephew
or something of Kaiser Wilhelm.
That's where all his money comes from.
- Really?
- I'm scared of him.
- Why?
- I'd hate him to get anything on me.
- What a cute dog!
- Darling!
Excuse me, Myrtle,
could you come here?
Neither of them can stand
the person they're married to.
- Can't they?
- Can't stand them!
What I say is,
why go on living with them
if they can't stand them?
Come on! Kiss that adorable little thing!
Myrtle's been living over that garage
for 11 years, you know.
And Tom's the first sweetie
she ever had.
I was on a train to New York,
to see Catherine and spend the night.
Tom was sitting opposite me.
He had on a dress suit
and patent leather shoes.
And I could see
he was a real gentleman.
I couldn't keep my eyes off him.
Every time he looked at me,
I had to pretend to look
at the advertisement above his head.
When we pulled into the station,
he was next to me,
and his white shirt front
was pressed against my arm.
I said, "Well,
I'll have to call a policeman."
But he knew I was lying.
I was so excited. When I got into the taxi
my head was swimming.
I felt as if some very tiny, cold, little fish
was swimming in my veins.
All I kept thinking was, I kept thinking...
You can't live forever!
it was the best day of my life.
Myrtle...
What did you do to him?
Big, clumsy...
- What did you do?
- Don't ever call me clumsy!
Myrtle, don't slam the door in my face.
Get out!
Please.
But, you see, it's really his wife
that's keeping them apart.
She's a Catholic,
and they don't believe in divorce.
I have the right
to say her name any time I please.
- Daisy! Daisy! Daisy!
- Shut up.
I can say whatever I want to!
Daisy! Daisy!
Daisy.
- Some chocolate cake, madam.
- Thank you very much.
- Sorry we're late.
- Okay, hurry up.
- Get dressed!
- Be right back.
I'm going to arrange a marriage
between you and Jordan.
I'll sort of fling you together,
lock you up in the linen closet
or push you out to sea in a boat,
all that sort of thing.
I have no money. Would Jordan
marry a man with no money?
Of course not!
On...
Well... It'll just have to be
an affair, then.
We don't know each other very well,
do we? Even if we are cousins.
- You didn't come to my wedding.
- I wasn't back from the war.
- Well, I've had a very bad time, Nick.
- Mummy!
Hello, sweetheart!
Let me tell you what I said
when she was born.
She was less than an hour old
and Tom was...
...God knows where.
I woke up out of the ether
with an utterly abandoned feeling,
and I asked the nurse
if it was a boy or a girl.
She told me it was a girl.
And so I turned away my head and wept.
"All right," I said. "I'm glad it's a girl,
and I hope she'll be a little fool."
That's the best thing
a girl can be in this world,
a beautiful little fool.
Here you are.
- Having a little heart-to-heart with Nick?
- Yes.
I think we talked about the Nordic race.
Yes, I'm sure we did.
It sort of crept up on us,
and first thing we knew...
Don't believe
everything you hear, Nick.
My, my, my!
She is the most immoral young lady
I have ever seen.
- Mr Carraway?
- Yes?
Mr Gatsby would be honoured
if you'd attend his party.
Thank you!
- Hello, Jordan.
- Nick!
I hoped you'd be here.
Your cousin Daisy has a craving for you,
but I'm going to borrow you for tonight.
I never care what I do,
I always have a good time.
When I was here last, I tore my gown
on a chair and he asked my name!
- Who's he?
- Gatsby, of course.
Inside of a week, I got a package
from Croirier with a new gown!
- You keep it?
- Sure.
I was gonna wear it tonight,
but it had to be altered.
It was gas blue
with lavender beads, $265!
There's something funny
about a fellow like that.
He doesn't want
any trouble with anyone.
- Who?
- Gatsby.
Somebody told me...
Somebody told me
they thought he'd killed a man once.
Killed a man?
I heard he was connected with
the government during the war, a spy.
I heard he was in oil, from a man
who grew up with him in Texas.
I knew somebody
he grew up with in St Paul.
Look at him sometime,
when he doesn't know anyone's looking,
you can see it in his eyes.
I bet he did kill a man.
- Which one is he?
- He never really goes to his own parties.
Just looks in to see who's here,
then disappears.
God knows where he is!
- You know I always want pheasant.
- Of course, madam.
Good evening! I'm your entertainer.
I just got married,
to the fattest girl you ever saw.
She was so fat, when she sat on
a drugstore stool, she had a hangover.
She hated to wear dresses,
always skirts. When she walked...
Thank God, it's a fight.
Let's get out.
This is much too polite for me.
Excuse me, sir.
- Would you mind following me?
- I don't understand.
Just follow me, please.
Excuse me.
I was invited.
Mr Gatsby sent a man over
with an invitation.
I live right across over there,
right across the lawn.
Are you sure
you've got the right person?
Yeah.
Excuse me...
How do you do, old sport? I'm Gatsby.
Nick Carraway. It's a pleasure.
You live in the cottage across the lawn.
I tried to buy it once.
- I've been trying to find you, but...
- I'm afraid I'm not a very good host.
Truth of the matter is
I don't much like parties.
I thought we should get acquainted,
since we're neighbours.
- I hope you're enjoying yourself?
- Yes. Thank you.
- If there's anything you want...
- No, everything's fine...
Good.
It's a lovely night for the party.
Yes.
Was there anything else?
No, no...
I just thought perhaps we should meet.
Yes.
Excuse me.
- Shall I...
- No, no...
Yes.
What?
I don't give a damn
what Philadelphia wants.
If that's his idea of a small town,
he's no use to us.
No.
I'm sorry, old sport, it was business.
Yes. Well, I've taken up
too much of your time as it is.
- Any of my guests you'd like to meet?
- No, thank you.
Perhaps we can have lunch?
Tomorrow?
- Fine.
- Good.
See you then.
Grand, isn't it?
What do you think?
Beautiful, isn't it?
Yes.
- Like to drive it?
- I don't think I'd want the responsibility.
Get in.
Look here, what's your
opinion of me, anyhow?
I hadn't really thought about it.
Let me tell you something about my life.
I don't want you to get
the wrong impression from stories.
Why me?
I'm the son of wealthy people
from the Midwest, all dead.
Where in the Midwest?
I was raised in America but educated
at Oxford. It's a family tradition.
My family died,
and I came into a great deal of money.
Then I lived in many European capitals,
trying to forget something sad
that happened long ago.
And then came the war.
I was promoted to Major
after I distinguished myself in battle.
Every Allied government
gave me a decoration,
even little Montenegro,
down on the Adriatic Sea.
Turn it.
"Major Jay Gatsby,
for valour extraordinary."
Why are you telling me this?
You don't make much money, do you?
You sell bonds?
- I try to.
- I run a small business on the side.
I thought you might want to pick up
an extra bit of money.
What kind of business, exactly?
I'd like you to meet a friend of mine.
This is a nice restaurant
but I like across the street better.
- It's too hot over there.
- And small, but full of memories.
- What place is that?
- The old Metropole.
Filled with faces now dead and gone.
Filled with friends, gone forever.
I'll never forget
when they shot Rosy Rosenthal.
There were six of us.
Rosy had eaten and drunk a lot.
A waiter says,
"Somebody wants to see you outside."
"All right," says Rosy, starts to get up.
I pull him down.
"Let the bastards come in here.
"Don't you make a move
out of this room."
It was 4 a.m. If we'd raised the blinds,
we could've seen daylight.
- Did he go?
- Sure he went!
He said, "Don't let the waiter
take my coffee."
They're on the sidewalk,
shot him three times, drove away.
- Looking for a business connection?
- We'll talk about that later.
This is a friend. We'll talk another time.
I beg your pardon,
I had the wrong man.
Gatsby...
Excuse me, please.
He has to telephone.
Fine fellow, isn't he?
- Handsome, and a perfect gentleman.
- Yes.
He went to Oxford College in England.
You know Oxford College?
Have you known Gatsby a long time?
Known him? I made him.
I made his acquaintance
just after the war.
So poor, he wore his uniform
'cause he couldn't buy clothes.
But I thought,
"That's a man to bring home,
"introduce to your mother
and your sister."
I see you're looking at my cuff button.
Finest specimen of human molars.
- Well, that's a very interesting idea.
- Yes.
Did you... Were you
and Mr Rosenthal close friends?
- Thick like that in everything.
- I'm sorry.
Why? Let us show friendship for a man
when he's alive, not after he's dead.
After that, my own rule
is to let everything alone.
Everything's fine.
- I enjoyed lunch.
- Don't hurry.
You're very polite,
but I belong to another generation.
You sit and discuss your sports
and your young ladies and...
As for me, I'm 60 years old and
I won't impose myself on you any longer.
He becomes very sentimental
sometimes.
What is he, anyway? A dentist?
Meyer Wolfsheim?
No, no... He's a gambler, old sport.
He's the man who fixed
the 1919 World Series.
I never thought a man fixed it.
I imagined it just happened.
- He just saw the opportunity.
- Why isn't he in jail?
They can't get him. He's too smart.
Look, I“.
- Let me get this.
- Nonsense.
Nick! Where have you been?
Daisy's furious you haven't called.
- This is Mr Gatsby. Mr Buchanan.
- How are you?
How does a bond salesman
afford to eat with business types?
I just came down here
to have lunch with Mr Gatsby.
- This is where you hide.
- Jordan!
Listen, I have the most
astonishing thing to tell you!
He wants to know if you'll ask Daisy
to your house and let him come over.
- Who?
- Gatsby.
If that's what he wanted,
why didn't he ask me?
I think he was afraid.
He's waited so long,
he thought you might be offended.
Why me? Why didn't he ask you
to arrange the meeting?
He wants her to see his house.
- You live next door.
- That's ridiculous.
I think he expected her
to wander into one of his parties.
But she never did.
Then he began asking people
if they knew her.
I was the first one he found.
He says he's read the papers for years,
just to catch a glimpse of her name.
I wonder why.
Daisy ought to have
something in her life.
- Does Daisy want to see him?
- She's not to know about it.
You're just supposed to invite her to tea.
But does she want to see Gatsby?
Your cousin will thank you,
thank you, thank you...
Nick!
- Your place looks like the World's Fair.
- I was looking in some of my rooms.
- I spoke to Miss Baker.
- Yes?
I'll call Daisy tomorrow and invite her
for tea. What day would suit you?
What day would suit you?
I don't want to put you to any trouble.
- Come in out of the rain.
- No, I have to go back.
- What do you...
- What about the day after tomorrow?
Well... I have to get the grass cut.
- You mean my grass.
- Right.
They are connected.
- There's that other thing...
- What thing?
Our business relationship.
Any favours that I do for you
don't need any payment.
Well, thank you. Goodnight, Nick.
Nick, my darling!
Where are you calling from, China?
I can barely hear you.
Of course I'll come.
Don't bring Tom?
Tom who?
Yes... Goodbye, my darling.
Thank you.
- Mr Carraway?
- Yes.
Mr Gatsby sent me over
to cut the grass.
Yes, quite all right. Go ahead.
- From Mr Gatsby.
- I know.
- Pass.
- Everything all right?
- The grass looks fine.
What grass? It looks good.
Do you have all you need in the way of...
- Tea.
- Will this do?
Yes, of course.
But I took the liberty of...
I took the liberty of...
I took the liberty
of having some things sent over.
- I'm going home.
- What for?
There's nobody coming. It's too late.
Don't be silly.
It's only five minutes to 4:00.
This is a mistake.
This is a terrible mistake.
Is this absolutely where you live,
my dearest one?
I adore it!
- Are you in love with me?
- Yes.
Is that why I had to come alone?
That is the secret of Castle Rackrent.
It's delicious, Nick!
- And what beautiful flowers!
- That's funny.
White... My favourite colour.
Daisy, I'd like you to meet my
neighbour, Mr Jay Gatsby.
- Mr Gatsby, this is my cousin Daisy...
- We've met...
Before.
We haven't met for many years.
Eight years...
Next November.
Well...
Shall we have some tea?
- it's stopped raining.
- Has it?
- What do you think of that?
- I'm glad, Jay.
- Would you like tea?
- Nick, darling! I feel...
Today's like someone's birthday.
Let's have champagne.
I want you both to come to my house.
I'd like to show her around.
- Sure you want me to come?
- Absolutely.
Nick, I'd just like to wash up.
Look. My house shows up well,
doesn't it?
It's splendid.
It took me three years
to earn the money that bought it.
I thought you said
you inherited your money.
I did, old sport,
but I lost most of it in the big panic.
In the panic of the war.
- What business are you really in?
- That's my affair.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry...
I've been in several things.
The drugstore business, then oil.
I'm not in either one now.
- That huge place over there?
- Do you like it?
I love it! But how do you
live there all by yourself?
I keep it full of interesting
people, night and day.
People who do interesting things,
celebrated people.
It's beautiful.
Beautiful.
- Excuse us!
- Quite all right.
Klipspringer was left over
from a party in April.
He was here two weeks
before I knew he'd moved in.
- Did we interrupt your exercises?
- I was asleep, at least I had been...
- Klipspringer plays the piano.
- I hardly play at all...
We'll go upstairs
and he'll play for us. Yes?
Of course I'll play the piano.
- Um, I really am out of practice.
- Don't talk so much. Play!
Jay!
All these clippings about me!
That's a souvenir of my Oxford days.
It was taken in Trinity Quad.
The man on my left
is now the Earl of Doncaster.
Yes?
Well, check with Wolfsheim.
Just do it. I can't talk now.
- Here you are, old sport.
- Thank you.
Come here, quick!
Look at that!
I'd like to get one of those pink clouds
and put you in it and push you around.
I've got a man in London
who buys all my clothes.
He sends over a selection
of things each season.
Spring and fall.
DAISYI
I've never seen
such beautiful shirts before!
- You are a rotten driver!
- We missed it, didn't we?
- Hello, Mr Wilson.
- How are you?
Fill her up, please.
You ought to be more careful,
or not drive at all.
Let other people be careful.
Takes two to make an accident.
Suppose you meet somebody
as careless as you?
I hope I never will.
I hate careless people.
That's why I like you.
40 cents, please.
Thanks very much.
Myrtle?
- Do you remember?
- I do.
When an hour alone with you
was an impossibility.
- My parents!
- No.
Other officers...
Driving up to your great house,
honking, calling out for you.
I remember one on the porch,
waiting in darkness so complete
I couldn't see his face.
They meant nothing.
An hour of your time,
away from the others.
Now you have it, Jay.
All those officers,
what were their names?
You remember their names?
Parts of their names. Not their faces.
Silly young men.
So silly, to let an 18-year-old girl
into their hearts.
Sentimental.
You were never sentimental, Jay.
I can't believe it's all here!
Everything that's happened to me.
I collected them.
Your debut after the Armistice,
pictures of you in shining cars,
every ball you attended.
I wore out a hundred pairs of slippers.
Come and sit by me, Jay.
I will.
Why do you stand or sit
as far away from me as possible?
I find it difficult...
To be close to me?
It's been a very long time
since I've been able to look at you.
I wish you had your uniform still.
I would wear the same gown I wore
when you were my favourite beau.
We'd dance right here in the great hall
of this preposterous house of yours!
My sweet young Lieutenant Jay Gatsby!
I do still have my uniform.
Then you are a sentimental man.
And Tom? Did you love him?
- Tom who?
- Your husband.
- I know who you mean.
- Why did you marry Tom?
I don't want to talk about Tom!
Or my wedding.
It makes me sad.
And I want to be happy.
- You used to like to make me happy.
- You didn't love him?
It was fine for you, wasn't it?
Crowding into my life,
riding in my white car.
Wearing your romantic uniform that hid
who you were, where you came from.
Breaking my heart
with your impossible love!
Going off to your adventure...
I told you I'd come back for you,
in my letter.
You said you'd wait.
I'd waited so long!
We were so close
in our month of love.
Why did you marry him?
Mr Tom Buchanan, son of
Mr Torn Buchanan of Chicago, Illinois,
blew into my life with more
pomp and circumstance
than Louisville ever knew before.
He came down with a hundred people
in four private rail road cars.
He hired a whole floor
of the Muhlbach Hotel, he just
blinded me with excitement.
He gave you a string of pearls.
Valued at $350,000.
Jordan Baker told you that, didn't she?
Traitor!
Well, what else did she tell you?
Did she tell you
how she found me that night?
Lying in my room, drunk as a monkey,
with a bottle of Sauternes
in one hand and...
My letter in the other.
"I never had a drink before," I said,
"but, how I do enjoy it."
I pulled the $350,000 string of pearls
out of the waste-paper basket and said,
"Here, dearest, you take them back
to whoever from Chicago they belong to,
"and tell him, tell them all,
that Daisy's changed her mind."
Daisy's changed her mind!
Next day you married Tom Buchanan,
without so much as a shiver.
You know what Jordan did?
She ran a cold tub
and dropped me into it, dress and all.
And I couldn't stop crying
but I wouldn't let go of your letter.
I hung onto it and hung onto it.
Until it came to pieces in the water...
Melted away like snow.
Why? Why didn't you wait for me?
Because“.
Rich girls don't marry poor boys,
Jay Gatsby.
Haven't you heard?
Rich girls don't marry poor boys!
Well, I see the Chester Beckers
are here.
And the Leeches.
There's that man Bunsen.
I knew him at Yale.
How are you?
Despised him.
The Hornbeams, Willie Voltaire.
How are you?
Nice to see you.
Thank you.
Good God, look!
A clan of Blackbucks in the corner.
- Flipping their noses up.
- Practically all of East Egg here.
- Hello.
- Lsmays, how are you?
Mr Chrystie, sir, how are you?
Nice to see you.
My wife, Daisy. Jordan Baker.
Mr and Mrs Chrystie.
Hammerheads, too.
- Look, Beluga, the tobacco importer.
- And Beluga's girls.
This is mixed company.
West Eggers. I recognise some of them.
Mrs Pole...
And Mr and Mrs Mulready
right behind her.
Look, darling, over there.
Cecil Roebuck.
Cecil Schoen, right there. This is Gulick
in the blue suit, the State Senator.
That's G Earl Muldoon,
whose brother strangled his wife.
There's James B "Rot-Gut" Ferret.
Look here, young Nick Carraway!
- Been seeing a lot of Gatsby lately.
- Nick!
- How are you, Nick?
- Fine.
- Nice to see you.
- Daisy, you look lovely.
- You too, Jordan.
- And me?
- I'm running away to Africa with Nick.
- Very nice.
These things excite me so! If you
want to kiss me, I'll arrange it for you.
Just mention my name.
Or present a green card...
Jay Gatsby. I'm so happy to see you.
- I believe we've met before.
- Absolutely right. I remember it well.
About three weeks ago.
Absolutely right. You were with Nick.
You must see many people
you know here.
- Yes.
- Actually, we don't know a soul here.
- Senator Evans. Mrs Buchanan.
- How do you do?
- And Mr Buchanan, the polo player.
- Colonel.
- I've never seen so many celebrities!
I like that man,
with the sort of blue nose.
- He's a rather small producer.
- Well, I like him anyhow.
I'd rather not be "the polo player".
He'd rather look at all those
famous people incognito.
They're in some new Broadway show.
Go ahead. If you want to write down
any addresses, here's my pencil.
- Daisy!
- It's all right. You have my permission.
Jordan will chaperone.
You'll keep watch, won't you?
For a fire or a flood or an act of God?
Kiss me.
Hiya, Buchanan.
Sharks in my hair!
There are sharks in my hair!
- Have you seen Daisy?
- No, I haven't.
- But Jordan told me she was with you.
- She was with Gatsby and some people.
Tell me, who is this Gatsby fellow?
Some big bootlegger?
- I heard he was a relative of the Kaiser.
- Nick...
I figure he's just a bootlegger.
A lot of these newly rich people
are just bootleggers.
- Not Gatsby.
- No...
He must have strained himself
to get this lot together.
- At least they're interesting.
- Where have you been?
- Up dancing.
- I don't have to ask who with, do I?
- It wasn't Beluga, the tobacco importer.
- Give it to me.
Where is he now?
Without a shirt,
without a shirt.
- Who, Beluga?
- No, not Beluga. Gatsby.
- He had a phone call.
- Really?
I want to know who he is
and what he does. Get in the car, now.
- Now.
- Now, Daisy.
I can tell you what he does.
He owns a lot of drugstores.
- He built them up himself.
- Get in the car.
Without a shirt...
Daisy! Get in!
Goodnight, Nick.
Without a shirt, goodnight.
See you, Nick. Get in the car.
Without a shirt, without a shirt
Thank you for staying, Nick.
- She didn't like it.
- Of course she did.
She didn't have a good time.
I'll fix everything...
Just the way it was before. She'll see.
You can't repeat the past.
Can't repeat the past?
Of course you can!
Find out where his
money comes from.
What clubs he belongs to.
Who his parents are
and where they live.
And his women.
I want to know about his women.
- Put on your uniform.
- That's foolish.
Good! Let's be foolish.
Put on your uniform and we'll turn out
all the lights except for a single candle.
And I'll let you tell me you love me.
Do you remember that night?
That still October night.
I've felt married
to you ever since.
I knew that if I could kiss you...
If I could kiss you...
I love you, Jay.
Did you know that I bought this house
just to be across the bay from you?
Don't say that. I'll start to cry again.
Jay!
It's the colour of the light on your dock.
But... You know I can't wear it.
You wear it for me.
- I'll love you forever.
- Kiss me.
Be my lover.
- Stay my lover.
- I'll be your husband.
Husband and lover.
Hi... I'm from the New York Journal.
Wanted to ask you some questions
about your neighbour.
- Mr Gatsby?
- What sort of questions?
I was just wondering if you've
seen anything interesting going on?
No.
I've been hearing his name a lot
the last couple of weeks.
Seems he and Meyer Wolfsheim...
You know that name?
Got something big cooking.
- I don't know what you mean.
- This is unofficial. It's my day off.
I like to come out here sometimes
on my day off.
If you want to know something,
why not ask Mr Gatsby?
When curiosity about Gatsby
was at its highest,
the lights in his house failed to go on,
one Saturday night.
Are you closing your place down?
No.
I hear you fired all your servants.
Daisy comes over quite often
in the afternoon. I don't want gossip.
You seem to attract it.
They say you killed a man.
Just one?
And you?
- Have you ever loved anybody else?
- No.
Of course, you could
never love anybody but me.
I love the way you love me.
I don't want you to go home to him
any more. I want to tell him.
We'll tell him.
I promise.
Soon.
I read somewhere that it's...
The sun's getting hotter every year.
Seems that the earth
is going to fall onto the sun.
Actually, it's just the opposite of that.
The sun is getting colder every year.
Excuse me, sir.
Mr Davis Goff is on the telephone.
Excuse me.
You know I love you.
You forget there's a lady present.
- You kiss Nick, too.
- What a low, vulgar girl.
I don't care.
Mummy!
Blessed precious!
Come to your own mother
that loves you!
Now... Say, "How d'you do?"
How do you do?
Say, "How d'you do?"
You dream! You absolute little dream!
Yes. Aunt Jordan's
got a blue dress, too.
How do you like Mother's friends?
Do you think they're pretty?
Where's Daddy?
She doesn't look like her father,
she looks like me.
She's got my hair
and the shape of the face.
Come, Pammy.
- Goodbye, sweetheart.
- Goodbye, Mummy.
- Daddy!
- How's Daddy's little girl?
I met all Mummy's friends.
That's my good girl.
You run along and I'll see you later.
Well...
What'll we do with ourselves
this afternoon?
And the day after that?
And the next 30 years?
Don't be morbid! Life starts again
when things get crisp in the fall.
But it's so hot!
And everything's so confused!
- Let's all go to town.
- That's an idea.
You look so cool!
You always look so cool.
I mean, you resemble
the advertisement of the man...
All right.
I'm perfectly willing to go to town.
Why don't we all go to town?
Come on. If we're going, let's start.
Let's have some fun! It's too hot to fuss.
I don't get the idea of going to town.
Women...
- Get these notions in their heads.
- Shall we take anything to drink?
I'll get some whisky.
I can't say anything
inside his house, old sport.
She's got an indiscreet voice.
- It's full of...
Her voice is full of money.
Jay Gatsby!
- Shall we take my car?
- Is it a standard shift?
Yes.
Then why don't you let me take your car,
and you take mine?
- There's not much gas.
- There's plenty.
If we run out we can stop at a drugstore.
You can buy anything in a drugstore.
Daisy, ride with me in the circus wagon.
No, you take Nick and Jordan.
We'll follow.
- Did you see that?
- Did I see what?
I've investigated this fellow, you know.
- And found he was an Oxford man.
- Oxford like hell!
- He wears a goddamn pink suit.
- Nevertheless, he is an Oxford man.
Oxford, New Mexico!
Or something like that.
Well? Let's have some gas!
I'm sick... I've been sick all day.
Do I have to help myself?
I'm sorry.
Mr Buchanan, I was wondering
when you'd let me have your blue car.
How do you like this one?
I bought it last week.
- It's a nice yellow one.
- Like to buy it, would you?
Big chance!
No, but I could use the other.
I need money pretty bad right now.
- My wife and I want to go West.
- Your wife wants to go?
I just got wised up to something funny
the last few days.
That's why I need the...
That's why I want to go away.
That's why I bother you about the car.
That's enough gas.
How much do I owe you?
$1.20.
I'll let you have that car.
I'll send it around tomorrow afternoon.
I love New York on summer afternoons
when everyone's away.
There's something sensuous about it,
a little ripe, as if all sorts of funny fruits
are going to fall into your hands.
- Where are we going?
- How about the movies?
It's too hot! You go,
we'll drive around and meet you after.
We'll meet you on some corner.
I'll be the man smoking two cigarettes.
We can't argue about it here,
so you follow me to the Plaza Hotel.
We can order five bathrooms
and take cold baths!
Me!
Open another window!
- There aren't any more.
- Then we'd better phone for an axe!
The thing to do
is to forget about the heat.
You make it worse by crabbing about it.
Why not let her alone, old sport?
You wanted to come to town.
- That's a great expression of yours.
- What is?
That "old sport" business.
Where'd you get that?
Tom, if you make personal remarks,
I won't stay here a minute.
Imagine marrying anyone in this heat.
I was married in June.
Mr Gatsby, I understand
that you're an Oxford man.
- Not exactly.
- No, no...
- I understood that you went to Oxford.
- I went there, yes.
It was an opportunity
they gave officers after the Armistice.
Were you in the war?
No, I wasn't in the war.
I want to know what kind of row
you're trying to cause.
He isn't causing a row, you are!
Please, have a little self-control.
Self-control?
Have a little self-control?
I suppose the latest thing
is to sit back and relax,
while Mr Nobody from Nowhere
makes love to your wife, is that it?
Well, if that is it, Daisy, count me out.
Because let me make myself clear.
People begin by sneering at family life,
and family institutions,
and before you know it,
we'll have intermarriage
between black and white!
- We're all white here.
- I've got something to tell you.
- Please, don't!
- Listen...
- Please, let's all go home.
- No, no!
- Let's all go home.
- Nobody's going home.
I'm going to sit down right here,
and I'll listen to what it is
that Mr Gatsby has to tell me.
Yes.
- Thank you.
- Sir.
Well?
Your wife doesn't love you.
She's never loved you. She loves me.
- You're crazy.
- She married you because I was poor.
She was tired of waiting,
it was a mistake.
- She's never loved anyone except me.
- That's a goddamn lie.
Daisy loved me when she married me.
She loves me now and I love her now.
I'll admit she gets confused and involved
in things she doesn't understand.
I also have been known to go on a spree
and make a fool of myself.
But I have always come back.
And in my heart, I always love her!
You are revolting!
Do you remember why
we left Chicago?
Why don't you tell the story
of that little spree?
Just tell him the truth. Just tell him!
Tell him you never loved him
and it will all be wiped out. Forever!
How could I love him possibly? I...
- You never loved him.
- I never loved him.
- Not on our honeymoon?
- No!
And not that day that I picked you up
in my arms and I carried you
all the way down
from the Punch Bowl,
so your little feet wouldn't get wet?
Open a window!
Daisy...
- Daisy, I love you.
- Please, don't.
You want too much!
I love you now, isn't that enough?
I can't help what's past.
I did love him once, but I loved you, too.
Loved me, too?
There are things between Daisy
and me you'll never know.
Things that neither one of us
can ever forget.
I'm going to take better care of you now.
You're not taking care of her any more.
- I'm not? Why's that?
- Daisy's leaving you.
I am, though.
No...
She's not leaving me.
Certainly not for a swindler who'd
have to steal a ring to put on her finger.
No!
- Leave me alone!
- Daisy!
And I know what your drugstores are!
He and Meyer Wolfsheim
bought up drugstores,
to sell alcohol over the counter.
But they're just small change.
He's got something new with Wolfsheim
that everyone's afraid to talk about.
Well, he's lost her now.
Want any of this stuff?
Nick?
Jordan?
- Nick?
- What?
Want any?
No.
This presumptuous
little flirtation is over.
I just realised...
He doesn't know her
like I know her.
Today is my birthday.
I'm 30.
- Gimme that key!
- Stay here until we go West.
- Like you wanted.
- I never wanted to go with you!
You was crazy about going West.
The only crazy I was
was when I married you!
You did marry me, Myrtle.
I thought you were a gentleman.
I found out you aren't fit to lick my shoe!
You didn't even have your own suit to
get married in, and you never told me!
I couldn't help it because
I couldn't afford to buy a suit.
What you're trying to do
is not right, Myrtle.
I'm a trusting kind of fellow.
I don't think no harm to nobody.
But when I know a thing, I know it.
Maybe you think you can fool me, Myrtle.
Maybe you can.
But you can't fool God.
God sees everything.
That's an advertisement.
You're so dumb,
you don't know you're alive.
I'm not so dumb I don't know
what's right from what's wrong.
Myrtle!
Are you all right?
Get away from me!
No!
Wreck.
That's good.
Wilson'll finally have
some business at last.
We'll just pull in and have a look.
Just a look.
- M-A-V-O...
- No, R. Mavro.
- R-O...
- Could you listen to me?
- What do you want?
- What happened?
An auto hit her. Instantly killed.
She ran into the road. Swine didn't stop.
There were two cars.
One coming, one going, see?
- Going where?
- One going each way.
God!
It was a big yellow car.
A big yellow car. New.
- You see the accident?
- Yeah...
- Hold it...
- No.
The car passed down the road,
going faster than 40. Going 50, 60.
- Going through here fast.
- Which way did it go?
God.
Come on, let's get out of here.
Her left breast was torn off.
Son of a bitch!
He didn't even stop his car.
You know that?
Daisy's home.
Nick, why not come in
and have something to eat,
and then you can take the car on home.
There's nothing more we can do tonight.
- Won't you come in, Nick?
- No.
Nick...
- Goodnight, Nick.
- 'Night.
What are you doing?
Just standing here.
- Did you see any trouble on the road?
- Yes.
- Was she killed?
I thought so.
I told Daisy I thought so.
- Why didn't you stop?
- It was a terrible shock for Daisy.
Daisy... Christ!
I just want to wait here and make sure
he doesn't try to bother her.
He won't touch her.
He's not thinking about her.
I don't trust him, old sport.
I'll wait all night if necessary.
Maybe you got some friend
I could telephone for, George?
I knew there was something.
You got a church you go to sometimes?
I knew it when she came back
with her nose all bust and bleeding.
Maybe I could call up the church
and get a priest to come over...
...to talk to you, see?
I don't belong to any.
You ought to have a church, George,
for times like this.
You must have gone to church once.
Didn't you get married in a church?
Long time ago.
Look in that drawer there.
She had it wrapped up in tissue paper.
In a place where she hides things.
We ain't got a dog.
She ain't got a dog.
She's got a dog leash
with diamonds on it.
My God!
Then he killed her.
Who killed her, George?
- He murdered her.
- It was an accident.
It was the man in the car.
She said he was coming for her.
Then he didn't stop.
Maybe I ought to call up the church.
Which church should I call, George?
I'll go find out some names
of churches, George.
I told her... God sees everything.
I'll read some names of churches.
I didn't mean it... I didn't mean it.
I warned her.
I'm sorry.
I'll fix it right.
All right? I'll make it right.
I'll do it.
I'll do it...
Nick.
Nothing happened.
I waited till about 4:00.
She came to the window.
She stood a minute
and then turned out the light.
Have you got a cigarette?
Just one.
We'll share it.
Imagine what this island looked
like when those Dutch sailors first saw it.
Fresh green...
Like a dream of a new world.
They must have held their breath,
afraid it would disappear
before they could touch it.
You didn't see that woman.
She was ripped open, and you drove off!
All I can see is Daisy.
All I can think about is Daisy.
She was so frightened,
I tried to grab for the wheel but she...
It was Daisy?
Daisy was driving.
She was very nervous
when we left New York.
She thought it would help
steady her to drive.
This woman rushed out.
It happened in a second.
It seems she recognised the car.
It seemed like she wanted
to speak to us.
Thought we were somebody she knew.
Daisy's never really needed me before.
I don't think
she ever loved him.
That house of hers in Louisville...
It was the most beautiful house
I'd ever seen.
All that crystal
and silver.
It was full of a kind of...
It was...
It...
You must remember, old sport,
that she was very excited.
He tried to make me look like a sharper.
She didn't know what she was saying.
Of course, she might have loved him.
For a minute,
when they were first married.
But loved me more even then, you see?
In any case, it was just personal.
You ought to go away a while,
to Montreal or someplace safe.
- Go away? Now?
- Just till it all blows over.
I can't leave! She'll be coming
just as soon as she can get away.
I suppose so.
You stay right there. I'll handle this.
Who is that man? Do you know?
That's Mr Wilson, ma'am.
From the garage up by the big sign.
Pammy, you must
wear that dress.
I won't!
Do as you're told.
If you don't, I'll tell your mother.
- Mummy!
- Be a good girl.
Mummy, I don't want to wear this dress.
I hate this colour!
Hush, blessed precious, don't cry!
Don't cry!
Beautiful little fools can wear
whatever colour they like.
Summer's almost over.
Sad, isn't it?
Makes you want to...
I don't know... Reach out and...
Hold it back.
There'll be other summers.
How about a swim?
Maybe later?
- I'll call you around noon.
- Fine, old sport. I'll be at the pool.
Nick...
Thank you.
They're a rotten crowd.
You're worth the whole
damn bunch put together.
I love you, Jay.
You know I love you-
Daisy?
I'll remember the rest of that day
as an endless drill
of police and photographers
and newspapermen,
in and out of Gatsby's house.
A rope across the main gate, and
a policeman by it, kept out the curious.
But little boys discovered
they could enter by my yard.
There were always a few of them,
open-mouthed, about the pool.
Mrs Buchanan, please.
- We need instructions from someone.
- Can't find any next of kin.
- There's a very strict ordinance.
- When do you expect her?
- If there's no instructions...
- I'll give the instructions.
- Who's this?
- He's the neighbour.
Any idea how I can reach them?
- What neighbour?
- Next door.
I can't say.
I was his friend.
The Buchanans
left this afternoon.
Thank you.
All I could think of
was his extraordinary gift for hope.
A romantic readiness such as I have
never found in any other person,
and which it is not likely
I shall ever find again.
The following day, I phoned Wolfsheim.
I was sure he would come
to the funeral, but all he said was,
"Let us show friendship for a man
when he's alive, not after he's dead.
"After that, my rule
is to let everything alone."
I remembered him saying that before.
But I was waiting for a letter
or a phone call from Daisy.
Is this...
Is this
my son's house?
I saw it in the Chicago newspapers.
He was in all the Chicago newspapers.
I didn't know how to reach you,
Mr Gatsby.
Of course...
We was broke up
when he went from home.
But I see now there was a reason for it.
He knew he had a big future
in front of him.
Ever since he made his success
he was very generous to me.
He was only a young man.
But he had a lot of brain power. Here.
If he'd lived...
He'd have helped build up the country.
Yes, that's true.
I just...
It just shows you, all this.
It just shows you.
Who is this girl?
I didn't know what you'd want,
Mr Gatsby.
- Gatz is my name.
- Mr Gatz.
I thought you might want
to take the body West.
Jimmy always liked it better down East.
He rose to his position in the East.
He had a lot of friends here.
Are you one of his friends, Mr...
We were close friends.
I found this.
It's a book he had. When he was a boy.
It just shows you.
"Schedule of Resolves:
"One...
"Practise elocution,
"poise, and how to attain it.
"Two...
"Study needed
"inventions.
"Three...
"Save five dollars. " He crossed that out,
said three dollars...
. . per week.
No more smoking or chewing.
Be better to parents."
...one God,
world without end. Amen.
She didn't send flowers,
no message, nothing.
- How could she?
- She could, if she'd wanted.
They're careless people,
Tom and Daisy.
They smash things up
and retreat into their money,
or vast carelessness, or whatever it is
that keeps them together,
leaving other people
to clean up the mess.
I had lunch with them today.
They're going to Europe for a few weeks
while their new house
is being prepared.
I'm going away too,
only I'm going back West.
- I'm too squeamish for the East.
- Is that why you threw me over?
Something about bad drivers?
And taking two to make an accident.
Nick, how are you? Nice to see you.
Aren't you going to shake my hand?
What's the matter with him?
- What did you tell Wilson, Tom?
- Wilson?
I told him the truth.
If I hadn't told him who owned the car,
he would've killed me.
Nick...
Gatsby had it coming to him.
He ran over Myrtle
like you'd run over a dog
and never bothered to stop his car.
Nick...
I've had my share of suffering, too,
you know.
I went back to Myrtle's flat
and I looked at that
little box of dog biscuits.
And I sat down and cried like a baby.
Tom... Don't you realise...
Nick!
How lovely to see you!
I've been meaning
to call you for days,
but I've been so busy with the house,
you can't imagine.
You have to come and see us
as soon as we get back.
You'll be our first guest. Promise.
We've got to go. Nick, Jordan.
You know how I love
to see you at my table.
Daisy!
I thought of Gatsby's wonder
when he first saw
the green light
at the end of Daisy's dock.
He had come a long way to this lawn.
His dream must have seemed so close
that he could hardly fail to grasp it.
He did not know
that it was already behind him.