- Good afternoon.
- Sir.
If the telephone rings from Austria,
nobody can talk to the king
except the emperor. Understood?
If anybody telephones from Russia, find me.
- Who'll make the first move?
- Got any money?
Of course. How much do you want?
- Is this a bet?
- No, I never bet.
Four will do.
If you've lost your heir
to the throne, as Austria has,
you feel you have to do something.
So you declare war on who you imagine
is responsible. Serbia.
- But you don't really mean it.
- How come?
The Austrian generals and the German generals
are on holiday.
- So are we.
- Absolutely.
You don't declare war
when everyone's on holiday
and not have them return.
It's show. That's how it will stay,
so long as Russia
doesn't get everybody excited
and decide to mobilise its army
to come to the aid of Serbia.
Germany would feel it had to make a move,
and we wouldn't approve of that.
Who knows what we would do?
But there's no chance
of any of this happening
because the Russian emperor
finds it hard to make decisions.
The end of Sandringham time in London.
All clocks will show the same time
as everywhere else.
Don't look so worried.
Germany will back down by the end of the day.
Your Majesty.
- He hasn't rung yet?
- No, Your Majesty.
I like small rooms.
It reminds me of my time at sea.
- You don't mind me staying?
- No, Your Majesty.
Georgie!
You gave me such a start!
I thought it might be news.
I'm afraid I've no news,
except I must speak to Papa.
- I cannot go to naval college.
- I cannot change Papa's mind.
And neither will you. Today is not the day.
Today is certainly not the day.
I'm ensuring every piece
of furniture in the collection
has the correct label,
the correct date
- and its place of origin.
- There'll be good news.
We'll hear from the Germans.
Everybody expects good news.
There are only a few hours left. It's possible.
Johnnie!
Johnnie, quickly,
it's Georgie on the telephone.
- I can hear you.
- I haven't said anything yet!
- I hear you very well.
- I'm ringing you
because there's extraordinary business.
We might be about to go to war.
Did you hear that?
- When?
- When? Well, now!
I see. When will the foreigners come?
I hate looking at that machine,
waiting for it to ring.
Good evening, gentlemen.
What a business, eh?
Every time the telephone rang today,
I thought it was them backing down.
Three times it was the Portuguese ambassador.
I was saying, "Don't put him through!"
He's probably talking to His Majesty right now!
But it's to the wire, gentlemen.
Right to the wire.
Everybody's completely worn out.
I'm still not at all sure you're going to win.
- The bet.
- I never did make a bet.
I don't know what needs
to happen to make me win.
We thought it would be over by 9:00.
It's 11:30 and we still don't know.
Why are they making so much noise?
The military want to show what they can do.
They want to give the Germans
a short, sharp shock.
Very little time to go, gentlemen.
Come in, gentlemen.
So that's it.
I Just lost.
Dear Lord, make this war...
- a very short war.
- Do something for your country!
- Be a soldier!
He's too fat!
- Johnnie.
- Let me get on the train.
This is the way to travel!
My brother! My brother is here!
He's a sailor now.
Lalla!
When we knew we were seeing you off,
we went on a great shopping trip.
We've got our marching orders too.
We're moving to a new home, not far away.
- I wish I was staying with you.
- It's a big adventure for us.
A trip to the railway station
and then to actually sit on a train!
It's the highlight of the year.
Except we're not going anywhere.
It's already gone on longer than they said.
Johnnie. Johnnie!
Come away from there. Come away at once!
We haven't travelled
all that way to look at that!
Talk to your brother.
Don't stay long at your new school.
Say you've had enough.
I'll get away as soon as I'm able.
Please shine a little bit first, Georgie.
I'll dazzle them, but in a way
that shows I don't fit in.
Georgie, you'll behave yourself.
It will be tremendous. It will be exciting.
Come on.
Johnnie, there's a present for you at home.
It was too big for me to carry.
What on earth is...
- A music machine!
- Oh, dear!
Why are we moving, Mr Hansell?
So Lalla can look after you better.
And nobody need see us.
We'll be shut away
in purdah from everything.
- What's the matter with you?
- We had to do it in a rush.
You have had days to do this!
I've no patience with their complaining.
I insisted on taking a full household with Johnnie.
Look at you!
You have all become so idle
with your moaning and your grumbling.
Perhaps we should start from scratch.
So, this is it.
It's smaller than I expected.
There's certainly a lot to do here.
What a place to end up in!
Remember, at the double!
At the double! At the double!
Aghh!
Today will be marvellous,
for we are doing the Armada.
What more could we want?
We will be on the deck of those ships.
We will be on those cliffs too.
We'll be as close to Sir Francis Drake
as one of his bowls.
We will be Queen Elizabeth
as she knights Sir Francis.
We will feel the fire
and excitement of those times.
They will impress themselves
so deeply on all of us
that we will find inspiration
for what we have to do now.
Why are you dressed like that?
Isn't it obvious?
- Aren't you too old?
- Absolutely not.
Anyway...
- I think my precise age
is rather hard to guess.
Come on, Johnnie.
Come on, help me. Help me.
You have to drink now. Drink. Drink!
It's horrible, but they said
to give you this if one came on.
That's it. It's mustard water.
That's why it's yellow.
Oh, no.
That's it. I'm never using that again. Never.
Never, never.
That's a terrible, terrible treatment.
I shall never use that again.
I'm sorry, leaving you
with the boy at such a time.
Don't say anything.
- Well...
- No! Don't bother to explain.
You've never wanted to go
to the war before. But there we are.
I will manage.
I assure you, I will manage.
And when you come to visit us, goodness...
- you will not believe what progress
we will have achieved.
See you soon.
Au revoir!
Yes, a little better.
Very good.
Really good.
Stop! Johnnie...
Look, it's your mother!
- What are they doing?
- Wait here.
Your Majesty.
We were passing, ma'am.
What a surprise to see you.
Indeed. I didn't know
you came this far on your walks.
We're collecting food.
Food for munitions workers.
Chestnuts. Something
additional for them to eat.
I'm also collecting metal.
Spare metal objects, scrap metal.
It's useful for the war effort, anything metal.
If you have any at the farmhouse,
collect it together.
Yes, ma'am, I will do that.
Johnnie is here, ma'am. I could
have him brought down for you.
Just for a moment.
It's a while since he saw you.
He's made such progress.
I will see you tomorrow.
We will be there tomorrow
at three o'clock exactly.
She's never late.
There she is!
How could we ever have doubted?
Your Majesty.
I'm glad there's a little sun for you, ma'am.
As you see, it's quite light and pleasant.
- Why is ivy growing there?
- Sorry?
I don't understand.
You shouldn't let ivy grow.
It's chaotic. Makes things untidy.
Thank you.
That's a reasonable amount.
Well done.
You have grown, Johnnie. I had no idea.
You have grown so quickly.
I thought you would like to see
what Johnnie's been doing.
That's why I put his maps and drawings up.
Is that really how you see your cousin Nicholas?
We must make sure no Russian ever sees that.
And your father wearing a giant crown.
So much bigger than his head. How very odd.
Johnnie?
I have been trying to teach him a little.
I visited two factories today.
I don't mind the noise and heat.
I would do five in a day if I could.
It is extraordinary how few people
are good at organisation
at a time when we need it most, above all.
Johnnie...
Why have you not included that
with the metal?
That is Johnnie's gramophone.
His brother gave it to him.
Everybody is making sacrifices.
He will not miss it.
We will add it to the other things.
Johnnie, ask your mother.
Ask her not to take it.
Go on!
Johnnie, please ask her.
Ma'am... Ma'am!
I implore you not to take
Johnnie's gramophone.
It will, with respect, make no difference
to the war at all.
But for Johnnie it is of such importance.
Please listen, ma'am.
He gets such Joy from it.
Of course, Lalla, if it means
that much to the child.
You may have it, Johnnie.
I shouldn't have taken it.
Clearly, I shouldn't have.
God willing, when next we meet,
there will have been
some real military results
for us to cheer.
Johnnie, wave to your mother.
Wave!
At the double, gentlemen!
You can open the blinds now.
Where are we? I thought
we were at the big house.
We are at the big house, Johnnie.
Come in, my little one.
Oh, here you are.
Come and kiss your grandmama.
It's so long since I've seen the tiny one.
Your Majesty, he is so pleased to be here.
It's very dark.
Yes, it is. I keep the curtains drawn.
I hate what they have done to the garden.
Your Majesty, he's Just done these.
They are for you.
- The family.
- Charming.
Delightful.
And a good likeness, after a fashion.
There they are, the real pictures of them.
I remember when they did that photograph.
It took ages to get it right.
My sister brought him up so very well.
Nicholas's behaviour
has always been excellent.
It's a pity Vicky didn't
do the same with Wilhelm.
But if only, don't you think, my tiny one?
If only we could get the family together.
Get your papa, Cousin Wilhelm and Nicholas
all together in a room.
We could have it all sorted out.
There'd be no need for fighting.
That would be very good.
We should do it soon.
Now, we must get a ball.
All boys must kick a ball, mustn't they?
- I will ring.
- Ma'am, I will go
because time is so short, I know.
Oh, my dear.
What times these are.
But we have a plan, don't we?
Now you can open the curtain.
Open that one, Johnnie.
That will do no harm.
Pull it all the way back, my little one.
Your father is having a shooting party.
He hasn't had one for so long.
Some guests have already arrived.
Please bring some news.
Bring some news.
Oh, God, bring some news.
Please bring some news.
Bring some news.
Johnnie!
Oh, it's you.
Hello, stranger.
Forgive me. You've caught me
talking to myself.
Johnnie!
I talk to myself quite a lot.
It's not bad is it, talking to yourself?
Johnnie!
One doesn't do it, no,
if one can possibly help it.
I'm Just waiting for some news.
Some very important news about somebody.
It must come. It surely must come.
It will come, I'm sure.
Johnnie...
There you are.
This is no time to go wandering.
- I'm taking you home.
- No.
Absolutely at once.
Johnnie.
Ah.
- My other tiny little one.
- Mama. What a Journey!
I couldn't get away from London.
So many cables from the front.
I'm going there myself very soon.
My God,
we'd better make some headway.
These are Johnnie's things.
He was here half an hour ago.
Johnnie was here?
Poor little fellow.
Not able to do much.
Ah, you're looking at that.
Does look like me, doesn't he, in that picture?
The funny thing is, Just this week
I've made Nicky a field marshal
of the British army.
I've given him that rank to encourage both of us.
My brother William left for France last week.
He should be at the front by now.
It can't be any worse than being here.
The Spanish Inquisition. The ultimate tyranny.
The rack stretching
everybody that opposed them.
Who does that remind you of?
Does it not remind you
of the foe we are confronted with today?
Of the extraordinary barbarity
the Germans have been reduced to
in order to bolster their losing position?
The mutilation of Belgian women we know about.
The cutting off of the hands
of Belgian babies for trophies,
sometimes nailed to the barrack room walls.
And now, when we thought
things could not get worse,
we hear about the Germans
inoculating French prisoners with tuberculosis.
Deliberately contaminating those gallant men
with this deadly disease.
Ah, we're hearing from the back
for the first time in months.
Can I ask, sir, how you know about this?
I am surprised that you
above all need to ask that.
The authorities have found this out.
It is now published in the newspapers
for the nation to read...
Ah, there's more, is there?
These stories have been verified
by witnesses?
Famous personages have verified them.
That is why they are published.
That is why there is such a strength of feeling
taking hold against the Germans
and all manner of German things.
Run!
If you don't run,
you will not reach anywhere.
I have to get out of here.
- Your Majesty.
- We commend you.
Your Majesty.
There's a misunderstanding
with the driver. He isn't here.
I think he's doing something with the motor car.
We will wait here, then. He will not be long.
Germans are keen on keeping time, aren't they,
Your Majesty?
I believe that is said to be the case.
Being German yourself, I expect
you knew that very well indeed.
Love to keep all sorts of clocks, I'm sure,
Your Majesty.
Being German, can you tell us
why we're still fighting a war?
Can you tell us that, Your Majesty?
- Why are we still fighting?
- Forgive us. He is not well.
I am English, from tip to toe, from toe to tip.
I am English, from tip to toe.
Georgie!
I didn't hear you come in.
You gave me such a start.
Forgive me, Mama. I have
a few days' break from college.
Yes, I remember. I was Just somewhere else
for a very brief moment.
I noticed these lovely things
which weren't here before.
Yes. I've worked hard to
recover them for the collection.
They had been given away
to all sorts of people.
This is Derby, isn't it? About 1830.
Very good, Georgie. Its date is 1823.
It's very beautiful.
- You've labelled everything.
- Yes.
Of course, your father was not brought up
to find solace in such things.
He doesn't find everything
modern hideous, like I do.
So I have to appreciate this all on my own.
Sir.
For some reason, they've turned the heating off.
The king thinks it will help win the war.
It sums up his knowledge of naval warfare!
I've never been so freezing indoors!
And only water to drink.
Ah! Naval life is obviously
suiting you, young man.
You'll have a ship of your own
before the year is out.
My teeth have never chattered like this.
I'd have given anything not to come today.
You look well, young man.
You'll be a rear admiral
by Christmas, no doubt.
Young man, you look remarkably well.
Running circles round them at naval college?
I'm much impressed by what I see here too.
A leaking ceiling, but it has not been mended.
Every penny has been spent where it matters.
Young man,
your father setting an example
by switching off the heating isn't popular.
No, they hate it.
Don't ask me how I am, please.
I will do no such thing
and you will return the compliment.
- You won't ask me either.
- No, I will not, sir.
Is it true? The stories about the Germans?
The French prisoners being given tuberculosis.
The Belgian babies. The corpse factories.
The Germans distilling glycerine
from the corpses. Is it true?
You're the only one who will tell me.
Let us Just say...
- some of it is true.
We will know more at the end of the war.
Just so long as we win it, of course!
- Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
I have some news for you, young man.
Your cousin, the Tsar, has Just abdicated.
The Emperor? He's abdicated?
What will happen to them?
We've agreed they can live in England.
Two courses.
We only serve two courses.
And no alcohol, as you can see.
The fish is an attempt at
my favourite dish, Bombay duck.
We can't get the ingredients,
so they've used kippers.
It's pretty disgusting, I think you'll agree.
It's refreshing to have
small portions. So appropriate!
I heard the most stupid remark
I've ever heard last week.
The most stupid remark?
That is quite a claim.
What was it and where did you hear it?
Well, I forget exactly where,
but I heard the most foolish comment.
That there are rumours going round,
amongst the people and so forth,
that the royal family must be pro... German
because you have a German name!
What's that? What are you talking about?
There are rumours circulating
that we are supporting the Germans
because we have a German name.
It's so ridiculous, isn't it?
What do they want, for heaven's sake?
For us to change our name?
Hm?
You're not saying much. What do you think?
Do you want us to change our name?
If the situation remains the same,
it may Just be a possibility
that needs to be considered.
In everybody's interests.
Never!
Aghh!
We've been having so many more
of these now, Johnnie.
That's it.
In between, you do so much.
You have grown so much.
Do you think anybody at all remembers us?
- Remembers we're here?
- Of course.
The war could end and they'd forget to tell us!
You know, I often look at you, Lalla,
and I think, "She's still quite young.
"She shouldn't give up on a husband.
"Is this how she'll spend her life?"
All the service you've given them!
Children, that family.
You never will understand, Fred.
I am glad to be here.
It's important what we're doing with Johnnie.
And at some stage, they will have time for us,
to see Johnnie's progress.
You've spoken to that man
from the college of arms?
Mr Farnham... Burgh. Yes.
It's been suggested
that since your family's name,
Saxe... Coburg... Gotha,
belongs to the house of Wettin,
some name derived from that,
like Wippo, Winter or Wetmoor,
would be appropriate.
- We'll be a laughing stock.
- I need a moment, Papa.
- I said in half an hour.
- That was two hours ago, Papa.
I have absolutely no time! No time at the moment!
Every single moment is taken up all day.
Every minute.
Time is running away and nobody will do anything!
I'll talk fast. My real abilities, whatever they are,
are not best shown off at naval college.
I love music and art.
This is rubbish! You will be a sailor!
That's all there is to it. You will be in the navy.
You will spend your life in the navy
and there's a good chance
you will die in the navy!
I don't want the matter ever raised again!
It was a disaster, Mama.
We are in the middle of such a crisis, Georgie.
We are facing such change.
Our family name, even. It never occurred to me
we would have to change our name.
All the family tradition...
I cannot bear
to see that being tampered with.
It offends me so much.
And the Kaiser is being removed
from his honorary position
as head of some British regiments.
That's right. We're fighting him.
You don't understand. What about afterwards?
I cannot help thinking about
what will happen afterwards.
If the pieces on which it was
built are removed, then what?
The houses of Europe were Joined.
- I have a suggestion.
- Which is?
- Edward III...
- We're going back that far?
My family has nothing in common with him!
Edward III was often known
as Edward of Windsor.
It has never been used as a dukedom.
So I suggest the name change
would be the House of Windsor.
I don't like it. Something bad
may happen if we do this.
Lalla! Johnnie!
- Johnnie!
- He has come back! To see me!
Georgie!
Your Royal Highness.
- Your Royal Highness.
- Your Highness.
- Impressive. What a household!
This is my estate.
We have 15 geese, four horses,
13 ducks and some chickens, but I don't like them.
You look magnificent in your uniform.
Don't say anything, but I've escaped.
Now, I have news for everybody.
Papa has rechristened the family
the House of Windsor.
The family has changed its name?
I can't believe that, Georgie.
Windsor? I think it's quite good.
I've got to get this horrible uniform off.
- What do you mean, escaped?
- It's all under control.
Things are happening so fast
in London. Amazing things.
The Tsar... Remember him, Johnnie?
The emperor fish with his absurd
swimming has given up his throne
- and will live in this country.
- Where will they live?
The emperor! I will see them, won't I?
Of course you'll see them, Johnnie.
Mama says I can stay a couple of nights.
Come on, Johnnie!
We agreed the Tsar and his family
could come to Britain?
To live here in exile.
Yes, the invitation
has been sent and accepted.
Many people disapprove of the idea.
There are certain articles in various publications.
A rally at the Albert Hall
celebrating the Tsar's fall.
It's becoming clear that because
the Romanovs are my family,
it's putting me in a very unfair position.
Unfair in the sense you are obliged?
Yes, because of our ties.
It may not be the correct course.
With things so uncertain...
- do you think it's possible
to withdraw the invitation?
The government might feel
it would be difficult to do.
You must go and see the prime minister.
They will come here from Russia,
the whole family?
- To my farm?
- To stay? Here?
That's a thought!
That would be something to see!
That's a wonderful thought,
you having the Russian imperial family here.
His Majesty also wonders where
they'd stay, how they'd live.
I'm sure His Majesty
could make one of his houses
available to the Tsar.
Hm?
None are available except Balmoral,
which is hardly appropriate at this time of year.
I think the Russian royal family
will think it quite appropriate
compared to some other destinations.
His Majesty feels that
since the arrival of the Tsar here
will be unpopular,
it puts him in an invidious position
because they are his family.
The king has always had warm feelings
towards his cousin the Tsar.
But he feels it would not
be wise for them to settle here.
It is being discussed, as you
must know, not Just in the clubs
but by working men and Labour
members of the House of Commons.
- I'm not concerned about them.
- His Majesty also feels
that the message sent to the Russian premier
that "The revolution was
the greatest Russian service
"to the cause we're all
fighting for" a little strong.
"A little strong"?
We need to be encouraging
to the new Russian government.
If the Bolsheviks take control,
they will pull out of the war.
Then the Tsar will face
a more interesting situation.
His Majesty wishes me to convey
the urgency of the situation
and the strength of his feelings.
I will let His Majesty know,
having consulted colleagues,
whether the government considers it possible
to withdraw the invitation.
And that one, behind.
Fat Mary, we used to call her,
your grandmother.
Johnnie's caught her likeness,
though he never knew her.
She was a great galleon,
coming down a passage.
She squashed everything.
Nothing was safe, especially not the crockery!
All these pictures Johnnie has done.
But this place is also full of you, Lalla.
What ridiculous talk, Georgie!
What is there of me here?
This is Johnnie's place.
And one day, he'll do a recital for your parents
- to show how far he's come.
- They'll never have time.
- I'm sure they will.
- They won't.
- You've no idea.
- When they're next here,
- they'll make the time.
- Listen to me!
They'll never see him!
They have no time for anything!
They don't know what they're doing.
Not my parents, none of them!
They don't know why they're still fighting.
- Don't talk about them so.
- Why not? It's true.
Don't lie to Johnnie
about them having time for him.
Why is he here, in this place?
So nobody can see him!
Nobody wants to see you again!
You're not too old for a thrashing.
You spent your life bringing us up
but never got anywhere with any of us!
- Just look at me!
- I will thrash you, young man!
You try! You spent your whole life with us.
Your whole life!
- Just you try!
- Georgie!
Georgie!
I'm going mad at the naval college.
I can't bear how stupid they think we are.
It's them that are the idiots!
Why can't Georgie stay with me?
I don't think the prime minister
will give us any news tonight.
Send him another note and ensure
a delay in the invitation.
Tell me.
I want to hear the absolute truth, however bad.
The news is not good at all.
You must prepare yourself.
It's possible the Germans
will break through in 24 hours.
And that could lead to everything being lost.
Today's news will be extremely vital.
You must go to the country as we planned.
I will wire as soon as I hear.
I will stay here.
Surely that would be best?
- I should be here with you.
- No.
Please, you must proceed as planned.
We must carry on as normal as much as possible.
Otherwise, waiting for the news...
Find it very difficult.
The wire will be waiting for you
when you get there.
I know I don't often say this.
I find certain things so difficult to say out loud.
But you mean so much to me.
Why are they stopping us?
Who are those people?
Your Majesty!
Your Majesty, we saw it was you.
Johnnie said, "There is Mama coming." It was.
Yes, that is a coincidence.
But I am in the most fearful rush.
There is important news from London.
Johnnie will Just show you something.
He has collected food and flowers.
We saw you doing it that day.
- We have to reach York Cottage.
- He'll bring them to you now.
I'm not ready yet, Mama. Don't look yet.
We're preparing something for you.
For you to hear.
Johnnie will give you a recital
when you have a moment.
Yes, we will arrange a date for that later.
Johnnie, I cannot wait a moment longer.
This is taking too long.
I do not have the time! I have to go. I must go.
It is news from the front.
The Germans have not
broken through our lines today.
The situation is still critically poised.
That is such a fine thing.
Come in, by all means.
My apologies for disturbing you so late.
No, Just burying my head in my stamps.
Especially calming before this big war council.
It's much better here in the country. Small rooms.
Always pleased to be in small rooms.
What an absurd idea palaces are!
- I have some news from Russia.
- Oh, yes?
I keep thinking about them.
What's happening to them is on my mind.
All of them shut away in that remote farmhouse.
It is a farmhouse?
Yes, kind of. It is on the edge of a town.
Can't help wondering how Alex is coping,
shut up in a farmhouse of all places.
For her that would be so difficult.
Sir, something has happened to the family.
They were awoken in the night by their guards.
They were probably told they had
to be moved for their safety.
Somewhere in the farmhouse...
Somewhere in the farmhouse
they were grouped together...
and they were all shot.
Not all of them?
- All of them were shot?
- Yes.
All of them.
Did we have a choice?
Do you think we had a choice
about letting them in?
We didn't know how it would develop.
Did we have a choice?
For the stability of the country,
I don't think we did.
We must remember it was
the government's decision.
Maybe that's what the public will be told.
But we know. Hm?
Would you please tell Her Majesty?
- That is too horrible.
- Yes, ma'am.
The children too.
What unimaginable cruelty.
- If there's something...
- Thank you.
You will Just leave me.
I think, Just for a moment, I will go in alone.
What do I pray?
I have nothing to say to the Lord.
Ma'am.
It is tomorrow.
I can't have got the days muddled.
We walked all the way on foot,
which is considered a good idea.
Her Majesty is expecting us.
- Your Majesty.
- Lalla, there's some confusion.
Today is the day of the war council.
It is most unfortunate.
But it may be possible
to do Just a very few minutes
for myself, Johnnie's grandmother
and the other children,
because they have not seen him
for a long time.
Do not stray out of the back corridors
while you are here.
There will be a great many
visitors here today, so...
Yes. Yes, of course, ma'am.
We will be very careful.
- Johnnie is here.
- Johnnie is here?
Now, Johnnie.
What are you going to do
when you stand before them?
Hm?
You're going to try to stay still.
Johnnie.
We are here for the shortest of moments.
I have the business of war to conduct.
Good day, my fine fellows. I will start...
I will start... I forget.
"I will start with some lines
from Alfred Lord Tennyson."
I will start with some lines
from Old Lord Alfred.
To me, methought,
who waited with the crowd,
there came a bark...
They're here already. Infernally early.
They must think we still
keep the clock fast. Idiots!
They can't even tell the time. We must stop!
Lalla, take Johnnie through the back corridors
to the kitchen,
- where they will find...
- No! Certainly not!
I have not finished!
Everybody must wait. Nobody can leave early.
Why is everybody so sad?
Everybody looks so old.
You've been fighting at the war too much.
What are you so sad about?
You're still here, funny things!
Who is that boy we're waiting for?
Johnnie got to give his recital.
And now, for the next part.
I will kick a football.
That's the way, Johnnie! Give them a blast!
My dearest brother. I've been
inspired by your recital.
I'll follow my artistic temperament.
Good!
If Johnnie can do it, I can do it.
Now the war has finished,
will anyone come to stay with me?
Not the Russians, clearly.
Because they're dead.
There are others that can come.
The Kaiser and the Austrian emperor are in exile.
They could stay with you, Johnnie.
See if you can catch me.
Johnnie?
Lalla!
My darling boy.
My darling clever boy.
I have telephoned your mother.
It is possible the Journey
from London may take too long.
He has gone, hasn't he?
My eldest sons came back safely from the war.
Who'd have thought it would be Johnnie?
Yes, ma'am.
Everything has changed so utterly.
And now this.
You did remove the ivy after all, Lalla.
The ivy, ma'am?
Yes.
I loved him.
I loved him so very much.
There was never a child like him, ma'am.
- I'm so sorry.
- No, Lalla, you mustn't worry.
Because he was... different...
I don't know how to say this.
He made you... He made me feel...
- Not confined.
- Yes.
- Is that how he made you feel?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Not that I felt confined...
- I know what you mean.
I shall miss him so very much myself.
I do already.
- Does that surprise you?
- No.
No.
Please excuse me.
I am so sorry, ma'am.
I'm all to pieces today.
My mother was always doing that,
breaking things.
Yes, I remember.
"...who also has taught us not to
be sorry, as men without hope,
"for them that sleep in him.
"We most meekly beseech thee, Father,
"to raise us from the death of sin
"unto the life of righteousness,
"that when we shall depart
this life we may rest in him,
"as our hope is for this, thy child John,
"and that at the general
resurrection on the last day
"we may be found acceptable in thy sight..."
"Grant this, we beseech thee, merciful Father,
"through Jesus Christ, our
mediator and redeemer. Amen."
Amen.
I don't think a day will go by
for the rest of my life
where I won't think about Johnnie.
Yes.
Lalla, I was thinking during the service.
I was thinking he was the only one of us
who was able to be himself.