Oh there you are, a sight for sore eyes.
- A sight for sore feet you mean.
Right you are. Goodnight.
- Goodnight, Spike. See you tomorrow.
Good evening, Mr Fiske.
- Good evening.
Which one is Peggy?
The third from the left.
Monte, she's a peach of a girl.
- I thought you'd like her.
Will she join us after the show?
U don't know.
- Why don't you send her a note?
I intend to.
Perhaps she has a friend?
That little blond on
her left was not so bad.
And the dark one on her right
and he redhead was alright.
As a matter of fact they're all alright.
- Let's go.
Of course, none of them
compare with Peggy.
David said every ticket is sold.
Lyndon Fiske is out there again.
Yep, for the 80th time.
He and Monte Van Tyle should
know the show backwards.
You certainly draw them in, Peggy.
Yes, both of them.
[ Female scream! ]
What's eating you?
Peggy, a buckle's killing me. See if
you can pull it out for me, will you.
Well Peggy, which is it to be?
Fiske or Van Tyle?
I wish I knew.
I think you're crazy if you
throw Fiske over.         - Think so?
I know so. The older ones are
safer .. if you know what I mean.
But Monte Van Tyle is very good looking.
And very, very rich.
So one day you'll get married
and then where will you be?
23 Skidoo. Ouch!
Can't you get that thing?
- Almost.
You know, every time I look out of
that box and see Monte there ..
My heart skips a couple of beats.
Does Fiske know about Monte Van Tyle?
- There's nothing to know.
Uhuh?
- No, there isn't.
Ouch!
- Wait.
It is also difficult.
I don't want to hurt Lyndon. But on the
other hand I don't want Monte to feel ..
Oh no dear. You want them both.
Perfectly natural.
You know if were you, I'd simply ..
- There it is!
Hand me that thing.
What will you have, Sefton?
- Bourbon.
Make it two.
Have you a pencil?
I'll scribble Peggy a note.
Yes. Don't forget to tell her.
One for the college friend.
In from the country to see the sights.
Good evening, Tom.
- Good evening, Mr Fiske.
Why hello, Monte.
- Good evening, Lyndon.
Mr Fiske. Sefton Hunt.
How do you do.
- How do you do.
Are you seeing the show?
- Oh, yes indeed.
Enjoying it?
I always do.
Always do?
You must be like Monte.
He's seen the show .. how
many times is it, Monte?
Twenty-eight.
- Twenty-eight?
My record is thirty.
- Thirty?
I'm two up on you, Monte.
Well .. all I can say is ..
If your reason is as good as Monte's.
Here is to your reason.
- Thank you.
Monte. Here is to your reason.
Mr Fiske.
I wouldn't be indiscreet
enough to ask which one it is.
But I hope it isn't the
second blond on the right.
Come on, Monte. We'd better be going if
we're going to get that note back stage.
Happy to meet you, Mr Fiske.
- Thank you.
Goodnight.
- Goodnight.
Goodnight, Monte.
- Goodnight, Lyndon.
Remember me to your mother.
- Thanks. I will.
Your last chance ladies and
gentlemen. Last chance.
Now watch closely, it's all
so simple. Which one?
Come on, which one will you have?
That one!
- This one?
No! The other one.
There is that one,
and there is that one.
You're wasting your time in the chorus.
If I could handle cards like
you do, I'd do it for a living.
My grandfather managed
to make a living at it.
Then they caught him holding five aces.
He died .. lead poisoning.
I learned everything from my father.
He could make cards talk.
Was your father really a gambler
on the riverboats?         - Hmm.
And did you used to go with him?
Of course it was a come-on.
Then one day they caught up with him.
Why, I still love cards but,
the chorus is safer.
Card for Peggy Martin
and he wants an answer.
Thanks.
Take my advice and stick to Lyndon.
Don't do anything I wouldn't do.
I couldn't if I wanted to.
It isn't in the cards.
Hey, you dropped one.
Wow.
The ace of spades.
Gee, I'm glad it didn't turn up in those
four. I wouldn't go out with anyone.
Say, give me that.
Hey, hurry up. You're holding
up the second act curtain.
Hello Lyndon.
- Good evening, my dear.
Did I keep you waiting?
- Not at all.     - Good.
Sherrys.
Are you worried about anything?
No. No, not at all.
That's fine.
I know of no-one who has less
to worry about. Thanks to you.
That's very sweet of you.
I've arranged a very
nice party for tonight.
How many times have you seen the play?
- Children .. children!
How about a toast, mister Fiske?
- Alright.
I'll give you a new one.
Here's to the ladies. God bless them.
We can't live with them.
And we can't live without them.
But there are exceptions to the rule.
- Oh yes.
And ..
You are the exception,
Miss Peggy Martin.
You know, you are looking
very lovely tonight.
I must .. my hair is probably a sight.
Quite ravishing.
Just the same, I think I'll fix it.
I didn't have time in the dressing
room. Will you excuse me?
Of course.
I think I'll go with you, Peggy.
- Come along, Dolly.
We'll be right back.
Paging Miss Martin.
See you later.
I'll be right with you, Dolly.
Monte, you shouldn't follow me here.
- What else could I do?
I heard the cleverest limerick today.
Really? Let's hear it.
- I don't know that I should.
Oh come on, let's hear it.
- It's terribly naughty.
Now I know we should hear it.
There was an old maid from Nantucket.
Yes, go on.
- See if I can remember the rest of it.
I had to see you.
If you'd told me sooner,
I may have arranged it.
Something very important.
- Nothing serious, I hope.
Very.
- What is it, Monte?
I love you.
You should be slapped for
scaring a girl to death like that.
He came up behind her and took it.
"He came up behind her and took it."
Ha ha. I must remember that.
Oh, that's corking.
What's the matter, Mr Fiske?
Didn't you think it was funny?
What?
Oh yes, yes. Very, very funny.
Waiter.
Let's have some more champagne.
Darling, consider yourself closely held
in my arms and very thoroughly kissed.
You do pick the strangest places.
- Embarrassed?
Of course.
- That's great.
Idiot.
When am I going to see you?
Tomorrow night?
I really shouldn't.
We'll go for a drive in the park.
Oh, I'd love it.
Well, say you will, then.
Alright.
Goodnight, dear.
- Goodnight, dear.
Oh and by the way.
Perhaps you'd better consider
yourself thoroughly kissed again.
Monte.
Then you do love me.
You know I do.
- That's all that matters.
Darling.
I could be so happy if ..
If what?
If I didn't feel that I were
hurting someone else.
Fiske?
He doesn't deserve to be hurt, Monte.
He's been too good to me.
Sometimes we have to hurt other
people to gain our own happiness.
But I am so happy.
Let's never mention Fiske again.
Promise me.
Dearest.
I am so utterly and completely yours,
you need never think of him again.
We'll start from scratch, darling.
My job from now on is ..
To make your life so beautiful you'll
never want to think of anyone but me.
That's easy.
And no more theater.
- Why not?
You see mother is an awfully good sport
but she is a little bit old-fashioned.
And I think the shock won't be quite so
severe if I don't have to say "Mother ..
"This is Peggy the beautiful chorus
lady and we're going to be married."
Married?
Oh yes.
Well, maybe I made a
bad job of proposing, but ..
That's what I meant.
Don't you want to marry me?
- Oh, of course.
That's all I wanted to hear.
But you don't know anything
about me, about my family ..
I know you are you.
That's all I need to know.
Monte.
Giddy up, Dobbin.
May I come up for just a moment?
No, dear.
I want to be alone just so
I can think about you.
Goodnight.
Will you telephone me the very first
moment you wake up tomorrow morning?
But I might awaken you.
Silly. That's what I want you to do.
Why, you startled me.
- I'm sorry.
I wasn't expecting you, Lyndon.
I dropped into the
theater but you'd gone.
I know. I left straight after the play.
- Yes, I know.
With Monte Van Tyle.
We went for a drive in the park.
Well it must have done you
good. You look radiant.
Lyndon .. I have something to tell you.
I know what you want to say and I
know how hard it is for you to say it.
You're in love with Monte.
Desperately.
But you don't want to hurt me.
I appreciate that, too.
You're making it so much harder.
- I don't mean to, dear.
So .. everything is over between us?
We've been very happy together.
And very comfortable.
I just want you to be sure. I don't
want you to make any mistake.
It can't be a mistake when two people
love each other as Monte and I do.
In a year, he may tire of you.
He may amuse himself with you
until the right girl comes along.
Then he'll marry her and ..
Over you will go.
- Oh, but you don't understand.
We're getting married next week.
Oh, I see.
Well, I've known the Van Tyle
family for a great many years.
Are you quite sure you
can make a go of it?
I'm no marrying his family.
He isn't marrying my family.
Do you think you can make him happy?
Oh, I'm sure of it.
Well, the very best
of luck to you, Peggy.
Thank you.
Needless to say.
I'm going to miss you terribly.
Lyndon.
Lyndon!
I want you to know how
very grateful I am to you.
You've been such a darling
- Thank you.
I love you Peggy, and
I'm afraid I always will.
Goodbye, dear.
- Goodbye.
You know, you almost make me
wish that I were a marrying man.
But I'm not.
By virtue of the power invested in me by
the city of New York, New York State ..
In the presence of these witnesses I
hereby pronounce you man and wife.
Two dollars please.
A little bit of Paris.
Peggy.
Do you realize I've spoken to you five
times and you haven't answered me?
Oh, I'm sorry, dear.
I want to talk to you.
- Of course.
Wait until I just get my chips.
Will you take them?
- Yes, we'll cash them later.
Let's sit over there.
- Alright, darling.
Isn't it thrilling?
I could live here forever.
- That wouldn't please me at all.
Why not?
It's so exciting.
- That's just why.
What do you mean?
When you gamble, you
seem to forget everything.
Even me.
Sweetheart.
- But you do.
It seems to take complete
possession of you.
That isn't good for you, darling.
Besides, I'm just a little bit jealous.
I don't want to share you with anything.
Not even gambling.
You know, my father once said.
That chance was the most
fascinating thing in the world.
It's in the blood, I guess.
But, oh my dearest.
If it upsets you one little bit ..
I promise never to do it again.
Honest?
- Honest.
You know, I'm convinced more than ever I
married the sweetest girl in the world.
Welcome home, darling.
This isn't ..
- Yep, it's all yours.
Oh but ..
- They started building the day we left.
Well don't expect me to say anything.
- Don't say a word.
The servants have strict orders
to keep themselves out of sight.
Until I've shown it
to you all by myself.
And if they disobey me.
Off go their heads.
You can carry this.
It's a custom for a bride to be carried
across the threshold of a new home.
Darling.
Here we are.
It's all .. it's all so
unbelievably wonderful.
I hope I don't cry.
Was there ever a girl lucky enough
to have a husband like you?
Well I don't know. I doubt it.
I want to show you upstairs first.
- May I take off my hat?
Well I don't know why not.
It's your house.
There.
- Come along.
And this is a very special room.
I cabled just as soon as you told me.
Do you like it?
Oh, Monte.
It will take all my life to
make you understand.
Just how much I adore it.
Our home.
Why .. I love it so much, I ..
I could just sit down
on the floor and ..
Pat it.
And here is an old friend of ours.
Why, it's the little cherub we
found in Florence.   - Remember?
He looks right at home, doesn't he.
Oh, Monte.
I never want to leave this house.
I want to live here always.
So you shall.
Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon.
Please tell Mr Van Tyle
his mother is calling.
Yes, Mrs Van Tyle.
Hello, mother.
- Monte.
You never told me. Not even a note.
I had to read it in the newspapers.
You've had our address for some time.
Don't argue. Tell me how they are.
You mean the baby?
Silly. Did you think I meant the cook?
Is this a peace offering
or just .. curiosity?
I rather thought the peace offering was
yours as you made the child my namesake.
That was Peggy's idea.
- Oh, bless her.
Monte, she will forgive me, won't she?
Uhuh.
Wait until you see the little devil.
She's got your mouth.
A nose like father's, Peggy's eyes.
And somehow she manages to
look just a little bit like me.
Oh, I can't wait to see her.
Come along.
Oh, she's a beautiful child.
What did you expect, mother?
- Conceited.
Not at all. Look at her mother.
As a matter of fact, she
doesn't look like either of you.
She's the living image
of her grandmother.
Sweetness.
Yes, darling.
Yes.
Oh little baby.
I always love dancing with Monte.
Thank you, dear.
It's mutual, I assure you.
Congratulations, darling.
Your party is a huge success.
Thank you, mother.
You're a lovely hostess.
I'm very proud of you.
Well Lyndon, this is a surprise.
You have neglected me.
- It's been my loss entirely, Eleanor.
I'm afraid I've neglected
most of my friends lately.
What have you been doing?
- Nothing.
Including a trip around the world.
I go from place to place
and do the same thing.
Nothing.
- You're depressed.
No, no. Just disinterested.
Hello mother.
- Hello, my darlings.
Here is my cure for that trouble.
Come and give me a big hug.
Oh dear, may I present an
old friend of mine - Mr Fiske.
My daughter-in-law.
How do you do.
Mrs Van Tyle.
And this is Eleanor.
Why, how do you do, Eleanor.
How do you do.
A cookie?
Darling, you mustn't beg.
Particularly not first thing
when you come in the house.
Oh, but after all, a cookies is an
enormously important thing in life.
Shall we go exploring dear?
Can't I ring for Jacobs?
Oh no. It is much more fun to explore.
Come dear.
You take me where you think there is
the best chance of finding a cookie.
You will excuse us?
- Of course.
My heartiest congratulations.
Thank you, Lyndon.
And thank you for smoothing
over a very difficult situation.
You need never worry on
that account, my dear.
It's evidently unnecessary to
ask if you've been happy.
Oh, is it so apparent?
- Oh, yes.
Tell me about yourself.
There is nothing much to tell except ..
That I've missed you.
I've missed you more that it is possible
for one human being to miss another.
But surely there has been someone else?
Oh yes. Attempts have been
made to console me, but ..
Well now, how shall I put it?
The remedy was more
painful than the ailment.
You've been abroad a lot, haven't you?
- Yes.
I'm back now to see my favorite surgeon.
He wants to do a little ..
Experimenting.
Oh, I'm sorry, Lyndon.
- It's nothing very serious.
You know, hospitals are
such dreary places.
I should appreciate it so, if you'd come
and sit at the bedside some afternoon.
Well I .. I'm afraid that ..
Well, we found the cookie jar.
Did you thank Grandma?
- Yes.
"Dear Peggy. Convalescence
is a dreary business."
"The doctor threatens to send me
to Europe and I may never return."
"Won't you drop in some
afternoon - for old time's sake?"
You must follow my
directions implicitly.
And if I don't?
Six months, possibly a year.
Perhaps.
Oh well. I've been everywhere,
seen everything.
I hope old man .. I haven't alarmed you.
No, no, no. Not a bit.
I must be running along.
Incidentally .. no more champagne.
No more champagne, huh?
Yes.
Pardon me.
How is he, James?
Very little change, I am afraid.
I came as soon as I got your message.
Shall I go right in?
Yes, ma'am. He is expecting you.
Please don't get up.
Oh, but I shall.
Let's sit here.
How are you feeling?
Nothing changes except for the worse.
I'm to be exiled. Baden Baden.
Hmm. A stupid existence.
But it won't be for long.
You are probably right my dear.
It won't be for long.
I'm glad you finally decided
to come and see me.
For the last time.
So you're passing sentence on me too?
If I must.
I made one great mistake in my life.
Ever giving you up.
You couldn't very well help it.
I could have asked you to marry me.
That was my great mistake.
If I hadn't been so sure of myself.
I wouldn't be alone now.
And Peggy, I need you.
- Please ..
I should never have
let you go my darling.
Never.
You are the one person
on earth I have loved.
Loved passionately, devotedly.
And I always will love you.
Always.
Right through to the end.
You are being unfair.
- No, wait.
I should have known we
couldn't go on being friends.
Peggy, I am desperate.
It's cowardly perhaps,
but I can't face it alone.
I can't live without you.
I can't and I won't.
I'm sorry, Lyndon.
But I am going now.
And I'm never coming back again.
Alright.
I told you I'd love you
right through to the end.
Lyndon, you mustn't!
Lyndon! You mustn't.
You mustn't, I tell you. You mustn't
kill yourself. I won't let you!
Stop it!
[ Gunshot! ]
You killed Lyndon Fiske.
- That's not true!
I had no reason to wish him
anything but happiness.
I didn't do it, I tell you.
I didn't do it!
Manslaughter.
Twenty years.
Oh, I'm sorry, dear.
But after all, she did
go there to see him.
How often, you don't know.
She was unfaithful.
- That's not true.
Whatever you or anyone else may think.
I still believe in my wife.
I came as soon as I could.
I want to thank you, Monte.
For all you've done for me.
You see, they are taking
me to Auburn tomorrow.
Let's sit down.
It can't change things.
But it would help me to know that ..
You believed I told the truth.
I do.
I never believed anything
else for an instant.
I'm glad of that.
I wish it were possible for you
never to think of me again.
That's the way I'd like you
to go ahead with life.
You see.
You have the baby to take care of.
She's so very little.
She won't even remember
me after a while.
Don't tell her unless you have to.
Or someday some stupid
fool will probably tell her.
Then the truth would be better.
You can be the best
judge of that, Monte.
Just try to protect her.
I will.
And I'll always stand by.
Ready. Waiting to help you.
I'm going now.
No.
Don't say goodbye.
Goodnight, Peggy.
See you tomorrow.
- Pleasant dreams.
Goodnight.
Killed in action.
Poor Monte.
Besides the fact that you declined to
take financial help from Mr Van Tyle.
His mother left the sum
of five thousand dollars.
To be given you in the
event of her death.
That was very kind of her.
I shall need it.
Mrs Van Tyle understood, I believe ..
That you would make no attempt to
communicate with your daughter.
Eleanor has been taught
to think of you as dead.
I understand.
I'm sorry.
You intend to leave New York, I suppose?
I promise you shall never
hear from me again.
Would you mind cashing that for me?
Of course.
If you will just endorse it, please.
You see, the reporters at the hotel make
it impossible for me to return there.
I shall have to buy some other things.
There you are.
I want everything.
A manicure, a massage.
The color of my hair changed.
Henna is the very latest shade, Madame.
Henna?
Alright.
I want to go out of here a
completely different person.
Very good, Madame.
Emily.
You may start.
Madame.
There is the new woman.
Good afternoon.
Delightful weather, don't you think?
The old ocean is as still as a millpond.
Looks like a record crossing.
How blue the water is.
Have we left out anything?
I'm afraid not.
Yes, you forgot to ask me to
take a stroll around the deck.
I was coming to that .. how about it?
No thanks .. later, perhaps.
Would you like to have a
cocktail with me before dinner?
Yes, I'd like to.
Alright.
I'll see you at the bar. What time?
Six-thirty.
- Fine.
Pardon me, Mrs Stone.
- Yes?
It is our unpleasant
duty now and then ..
To warn passengers against
certain other passengers.
Really?
That Mr Blaine.
Happens to be a professional gambler.
Oh.
How interesting.
A very amusing and a charming
sort of person, to be sure.
But not one with whom to play cards.
I trust you will forgive me.
Thank you so much for telling me.
If you find me playing
with him, don't be upset.
I can afford to lose
whatever I shall lose.
Just for the experience.
A packet of cigarettes, please.
- Yes, sir.
Thank you, sir.
I'm out, thanks.
- No more for me.
It's my deal, Mr Blaine.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Just you and I?
I'm afraid so.
Do you mind if I change the cards?
- No, no. Not at all.
Steward.
- Yes, sir?
Two new decks please.
- Yes, sir.
Eyes hurting?
- Terribly.
The smoke is bothering me.
You know Mrs Stone, it is very
seldom that one finds a woman ..
With the sense of
gambling that you have.
Have you played long?
Since I was a child.
I used to play with my father
and my grandfather.
I can believe that.
You play a man's game.
That's one of the nicest compliments
you could pay me, Mr Blaine.
Not at all.
The difference between our stacks shows
that it is more than mere flattery.
Let's hope the new
cards change your luck.
Thank you.
Shall we raise the limit?
You are the loser.
Let's try a round of table stakes.
Alright.
Jack bets a hundred.
Another hundred.
You'd better watch out.
I think you're bluffing.
I check.
Let's see.
You have a possible straight.
Five hundred.
Five hundred?
On what, may I ask?
- On a hunch.
In that case I'll raise you five.
That makes a thousand.
Ready?
- Ready.
Can you beat a pair of jacks?
It's your bet, Mr Blaine.
Don't tell me you're going to stay?
Frightened?
I bet a thousand.
A thousand .. and a thousand more.
Thinking of calling?
Why should I when I have you beaten?
You would accept my IOU I hope?
Certainly.
Alright.
I'll call.
Three jacks.
Straight.
Have a cigarette?
- No thanks.
Not just now.
A beautiful night, isn't it.
Very.
You'd better keep this.
The ace of spades has
never brought me any luck.
Besides, I wouldn't want to
spoil that nice deck for you.
Thanks.
It does take quite a bit of time
to work up a deck like this.
As for this IOU.
Perhaps we'd better file it.
With my present state of finances.
I'm sure it's much more valuable
to the fish than it could be to you.
Broke?
Yes, but don't let that worry you.
Will a thousand see you through?
Thanks.
You'll get it back.
Let's flip a coin. Double or nothing.
Alright.
Heads.
Tails it is.
We're even.
Now I'll have a cigarette.
I would like to know where
you learned to play cards.
Let's proceed on the basis
of "no questions asked".
Just as you say.
I like you.
Thanks.
Do you think we'd do better if we teamed
instead of working against each other?
Why not?
Then you want to proceed
on a business basis only?
That's right.
You are a very attractive woman.
And I am only human.
I can keep my head.
Can you keep it for both of us?
- Hmm.
Alright.
We'll try it out and see how it works.
I'll chance it.
It's a gamble, like
everything else in life.
I'm out.
I check.
Two hundred.
I'll raise you two.
I'll see you.
You are certainly lucky, Mr Blaine.
He certainly is. I've never
seen anything like it.
It is my deal.
Bonsoir, Madame.
- Bonsoir, Monsieur.
[ French language ]
Well this looks like a celebration.
It is.
- What for?
Don't you remember?
- No.
In honor of our partnership.
That is two years old tonight.
Ah, that was sweet of you to remember.
Not at all.
It was a great night for me finding you.
That goes two ways.
Thanks.
Well, now the mutual admiration
society can sit down and have supper.
Peggy.
I love you, dear.
You mustn't, Bill.
Why not?
I seem to hurt anybody
whoever cares for me.
I'm not worried about that.
But I don't want to be hurt either.
You gamble on everything else.
Why not love?
I'm going to keep on trying.
Come on.
Hello, Bill.
Hello, Peggy.
Can you spare some good news?
When do we sail?
- This news is different.
I know how you feel
about staying in New York.
And this means staying.
Now don't say you won't do
it until I tell you what it is.
Come on, get your hat and
coat on. We're going places.
Alright.
This chap Bonelli has taken
over the entire house.
He owns it and he knows the best people.
It's going to be the class
Speakeasy of New York.
It's a perfect layout.
What are you going to be, a bartender?
I've always wanted
to be a hat-check girl.
Now don't be silly, Peggy.
Look.
He's arranged for
gambling on the top floor.
I have the concession.
I thought we were "we"?
Here is the big idea.
There has never been a woman
blackjack dealer in New York before.
That's what Bonelli wants.
You as the dealer.
It will be a sensation.
How about all those people on the
boats whose bankrolls we've taken?
You've run that risk before.
I don't like this staying in New York.
Well Peggy, listen.
Oh.
This is 56th Street.
Don't you feel well?
I'm alright.
Come on, let's go in.
Be nice to Bonelli, Peggy.
He can do a lot for us.
What's the name, please?
- Blaine.
Oh yes.
Well, this is a pleasure.
Mrs Stone - Mr Bonelli.
I've heard about you for a long time.
How do you do.
What do you think of this?
It's amazing.
The dining room is over there.
The bar is in here.
What you'll be interested in,
is the top floor.
What?
Yes.
By all means, let's see the top floor.
You got a great spot here, Bonelli.
Yes, and I think we're
going to do great business.
Now this is the blackjack room.
Your room, Mrs Stone.
Go right in.
Make yourself at home.
And the room just back of this.
Is where we have the
wheel and the tables.
What do you think of
the layout, Mrs Stone?
Mrs Stone.
What did you say?
A pretty swell layout, don't you think?
Yes, I think you've done it beautifully.
So you're all set come with us, eh?
No, I'm afraid that ..
- Now come on, now.
Bill here has told me how
you like to keep travelling.
But this is a set-up that
you can't afford to miss.
I'll tell you what I'll do.
I'll go in the office.
And you talk it over
with the little lady.
I'll see you later.
- Alright, Bonelli.
Peggy dear. We can't afford
to pass up this proposition.
You don't seem to realize we're broke.
We've been that way before.
I know, but things are different now.
Nobody travels on boats anymore.
And besides, we don't
have to stay here always.
When do we start?
- That's the girl.
Bonelli opens tomorrow night.
Lets go inside and tell him it's okay.
- Alright.
Again.
That's enough.
Nineteen. Pay twenty.
Take it away.
You are too lucky.
- Not always.
Leaving?
Oh I'll be back after a bit.
Make your bets, please.
Well Eleanor, fancy seeing you here when
there is gambling going on upstairs.
I'm not even going near the place.
I like my happy home too much.
You know the only serious row Henry and
I had on our honeymoon was over gambling.
Lose too much?
- Partly that.
He says I go sort-of crazy when I
gamble. I never know when to stop.
I promised him I'd never gamble again.
Is Henry here tonight?
No. The poor dear couldn't
come. He had to work.
I came with Freddie and Alice.
I saw Freddie upstairs.
He's losing his shirt at blackjack.
Is the game straight?
- Oh, as far as I know.
A whiskey and soda, please.
Come on up with us in a
while and watch the game.
I'm going to stay down here where I am
safe and the gambling bug can't bite me.
How much you win, Freddie?
- I'd rather not talk about it.
As bad as that?
- Worse.
How would your luck run tonight?
- I'm not even thinking of such things.
Come on, be a sport.
Play these chips for me.
Get thee behind me, Satan.
- But why not?
Say do you want me to be driven out
into the cold by a stern husband?
No, sir.
Henry and I sail for Europe tomorrow
night. I'll not let anything spoil that.
But you wouldn't be gambling really.
- Oh no?
No, you'd be sort of .. well, my broker.
I give you the money. You gamble for me.
If you win I'll pay you a commission.
- And if I lose?
I'll pay you a commission anyway.
That will make it legal.
Oh I don't know.
- Oh, it's that woman dealer?
She has a jinx on me.
- I've heard of her, Good, isn't she?
Marvellous, but I'm
sure you can beat her.
Don't be so sure.
But you make me feel I'd like to try.
- Good. Here.
I think I'll take chance my own money.
- Alright, but play my chips. Come on.
Nineteen, pay twenty.
That cleans me.
There you are, Eleanor.
Well, I've brought an expert
to play for me, Mrs Stone.
And I warn you, you're both good.
Don't do any boasting
until I see what I can do.
What are these?
- Fives.
Alright. Let's start easy.
Twenty dollars.
Seventeen, pay eighteen.
Well, let's call it a night, Eleanor.
- No, I want to go on.
The table is closed for tonight.
- Why is it closed? Why should it be?
You're a thousand to the good.
That's fine. Now it's running
my way. Why should I quit?
I want to play and Miss Stone
said the table is closed.
Why is the table closed?
- I'm not feeling well.
I'm winning and she wants to quit.
I'll take it over.
- No, Bill.
I want to play and I
want to play with you.
Why of course Miss Stone
will deal for you.
She will be only too
glad to deal for you.
Go on, Peggy.
Would you excuse me just a
moment, please. I'll be right back.
Bill.
- Are you crazy?
That girl has you stuck
for a thousand dollars.
Now go in there and get it back.
- I can't do it.
You can't do it?
Peggy, I don't know what this is about but
you must go in and win that money back.
She's had her fun, let her pay for it.
Alright.
I'll teach her a lesson that will stop
her gambling for the rest of her life.
Hit me.
Hit me again.
Had enough?
You've got to quit, Eleanor.
You're 5,000 in the hole.
I know I am. I'm going
to win it back. I must.
Go on, deal.
You are over.
Don't you think you'd better stop?
I never stop until I win.
Deal.
Hit me.
Give me one more thousand
at least, please.
Mrs Burgess, $15,000 is a lot of credit.
I'm afraid I can't extend you anymore.
But you have to give me a
chance to win some of it back.
Don't you think you've had your chance?
Haven't you learned anything
at this table tonight?
Eleanor, please.
Oh he'll divorce me, Freddie.
- Nonsense.
He swore he would.
Who is going to tell him?
Where else can I get $15,000?
Why not come back this afternoon
after you've had some rest?
We can talk things over.
- Oh could we?
Certainly.
About three o'clock in my office.
- That's the best idea.
Come on, Eleanor. Please.
Maybe she's learned her lesson.
I hope so.
Bill.
Let's see those IOUs.
Let's tear them up.
Tear them up? What for?
Her husband has plenty of money.
- I say we tear them up.
What do you mean? We don't own
this place. We're only working here.
And besides, it isn't just us she owes
the money to. There is Bonelli.
You could talk it over with him.
Do you think I'd be sap enough to ask
Bonelli to tear up IOUs for 15 grand?
But she is so young, and inexperienced.
What do you care?
What does she mean to you?
I don't see anyone running after you
with thousand-dollar bills to give you.
I don't want her to have
to go to her husband.
I can't see why not.
- Bill.
Won't you do it if I ask you do?
At least give her time.
Or this might ruin
that girl's whole life.
Alright, Peggy.
Let's forget about it tonight.
I'll slip in there later and
talk to them about it.
Thanks.
What luck?
- Nothing doing, Peggy.
I've got to collect.
Don't be too hard on her, Bill.
- I said I've got to collect.
Mrs Burgess wants to see you.
Alright.
Good afternoon, Mrs Burgess.
- Good afternoon.
Come right up to my office.
Hello there.
Hello.
You're not sore are you?
I mean, about the little girl.
I'm sorry I couldn't see it your way.
But never give a sucker a break.
She had her fun.
And her husband can
afford to pay for it.
But she's such a kid.
Well, maybe it will do her good.
It will teach her a lesson.
That's what I'm hoping.
That's the girl.
Now you're too clever a woman
to worry about those things.
You know what I said to
myself when I first saw you?
I said .. there is a woman ..
That a man with a heart ..
And ambition ..
Could make a lot out of.
Thanks.
This is just as unpleasant
for me as it is for you.
The fact remains that you lost $15,000.
I accepted your IOUs and
I have to make them good.
I'll pay you every cent. I promise you.
- When?
Well .. I wont have any money of my
own for another six months you see.
Do you expect me to wait until
then? I want the money now.
I can't give it to you now.
I haven't got it.
Well get it.
- But where?
From your husband.
You don't understand.
He swore he'd divorce me if I ever
gambled again. He would too.
My dear, you should think of those
things next time you go gambling.
There won't be a next time.
My dear Mrs Burgess,
we're not getting anywhere.
I want $15,000.
You say you can't pay it.
Shall I phone your husband or will you?
- Please don't do that. Please.
You don't know what you're doing.
Hello?
Give me another few days
at least before you tell him.
I want to speak to a
Mr Henry Burgess please.
No, he doesn't know me.
It's personal and very important.
What's that?
Stop it I tell you. Stop it!
Stop it I tell you! Stop it!
[ Gunshot! ]
He was telephoning my husband.
Wait out there.
Bill .. Bill ..
The drawer was open.
I saw the gun there.
I reached for it.
- Stop!
But you don't know.
That's what my mother did.
She shot a man.
Killed him and went to prison.
Died there.
- Stop it.
Now listen. I must get you out of here.
Oh, but I can't.
I've killed him.
He's not dead. And lucky
enough for both of you.
How soon can you leave town?
We were going away tonight.
My husband and I were
sailing for Europe at twelve.
But now ..
I'll take care of that.
I'm not going to have your life
ruined the way your mother's was.
I never expected you to be my friend.
Perhaps one day you'll look back and see
that I was the best friend you ever had.
Now then.
Take these things and get out of here.
Are you ready, Madame?
- Just a moment.
Ready?
Is Blaine inside?
No, he went out.
I've got a wad of dough I
want to put in the safe.
He locked the door when he left.
I got a passkey.
Barney, take this deal for me.
Excuse me please, will you.
Bill won't like it if you open
the safe without him being here.
Well, that's just too bad.
I did it.
I wondered if maybe
Mrs Burgess didn't bump him off?
You can forget about her.
Can I?
Sit down.
- What are you going to do?
Wait here until I get
rid of the customers.
How did it happen?
I told him I was through with him.
And he squawked?
Yes.
He pulled a gun.
We struggled.
And the gun went off?
That's too bad.
You had plenty of nerve to come
back here and deal at this table.
Instead of making a run for it.
I had my reasons.
What do you plan on doing now?
I don't know exactly.
I did plan to leave town.
You don't have to.
I can take care of Blaine.
A couple of boys will
drop him out of  car ..
The police will just say ..
Another guy taken for a ride.
You know.
I can't afford to lose you.
And you can't afford to go.
You and I can make plenty
of real money together.
And I'd like to have you stay here.
Always.
I never want to leave ths house.
I want to live here always.
So you shall.
And so I shall.
So I shall.
T-G