Mr. Frank.
Mr. Frank?
Kraler?
Mr. Kraler.
Miep.
My good friends.
Oh, it-
it is so good
to see you home.
We had heard nothing.
I'm alone.
You must
come home
with us...
and rest now.
You must stay with us.
No, Miep. I can't
stay in Amsterdam.
Mr. Frank,
this is your home.
Amsterdam
is your home.
It has too many
memories for me.
Everywhere there's
something, Miep.
Everywhere.
Even seeing
you and Mr. Kraler.
Forgive me. I shouldn't
talk to you like this
after all that you did.
We would
do it again.
Everything's gone-
the book.
They took
everything...
except some papers.
We saved
your letters
and papers.
Please burn them.
Burn everything.
I- I...
told Anne
if I got back here,
I'd find her book.
Anne's diary?
It's where she left it.
"The ninth of July, 1942."
1942.
Is it possible, Miep?
Only three years ago.
"Dear Diary,
since you and I are going
to be great friends,
"I will start
by telling you
all about myself.
"My name is Anne Frank.
"I am 13 years old.
"I was born in Germany,
"but since my family
is Jewish,
"we emigrated to Holland
when Hitler came to power.
"Things went well for us...
"until the war came,
and the German occupation.
"Then things got very bad
for the Jews.
You could not do this,
and you could not do that.
We had to wear
yellow stars.
I had to turn in my bike.
I couldn't go
to a Dutch school anymore.
I couldn't go to the movies
or ride in an automobile,
or even on a streetcar,
and a million other things.
But somehow we children
still managed to have fun.
This morning Father
woke me at 5:00...
and told me
to hurry and get dressed.
We were going into hiding.
I was to put on
as many clothes as I could.
It would look too suspicious
if we walked along
carrying suitcases.
We were going to disappear,
vanish into thin air.
I'm living
a great adventure.
Three other people
were coming in with us.
Father knew them,
but we had never met them.
Something's
happened.
They have three miles
to walk.
Mother-
They've been
arrested. I know.
Will you
stop that?
Mother! Father!
We're here.
See?
Mr. Van Daan.
Hello, hello.
Mrs. Van Daan. Peter.
Mr. Frank.
There were too many
of the Green Police
on the streets.
We had to take
the long way around.
Did you introduce yourself?
My daughter Anne. My wife Edith.
Hello.
Margot.
Mr. and Mrs. Van Daan.
Hello.
Oh, and this is
our son Peter.
So, now, please,
let us take off
some of these clothes.
Good morning.
Hello, Mr. Kraler.
Good morning,
Mr. Kraler.
Mr. Frank.
Ah, you're all here.
That is good.
We had hoped to have
everything in order.
Please, Mr. Kraler,
don't even think of it.
After all, we'll have
plenty of leisure to arrange
everything ourselves.
I brought some sandwiches
for your lunch.
Thank you, Miep.
The canned goods are here,
and your stores
of dried beans and potatoes.
I'll get you ration books
this afternoon.
Ration books?
If they see our names
on ration books,
they'll know we're here.
Don't worry.
It won't be your names
that'll be on them.
Father!
The Westertoren!
Anne, no!
You must never
touch a curtain.
Never.
No one must ever
touch a curtain,
day or night.
If someone on the streets
should look up, or someone
in those houses should see,
we would be lost.
Please remember,
it's not only our lives
that are at stake,
but also Miep's
and Mr. Kraler's.
You have but 13 minutes
to get settled.
Thank you.
Miep or I will be up each day
to bring you food and news.
Come, Miep. We must go.
Good-bye for now.
How can we thank you?
I never thought
I'd live to see the day...
when a man like Mr. Frank
would have to go into hiding.
When you think of the-
Good-bye.
Thank you,
Mr. Kraler.
Good-bye, Miep.
Good-bye.
Anne!
It's all right.
I have on three more.
Excuse me,
Mr. Frank.
What did he mean,
just 13 minutes?
Before
the workmen come.
Now, while the men are
in the building below,
we must have
complete quiet.
Every sound can be
heard down there,
not only in the offices
but in the workrooms too.
The men come at about 8:30,
they leave at about 5:30,
so to be perfectly safe,
from 8:00 in the morning
until 6:00 in the evening...
we must move about up here
only when it is
absolutely necessary,
and then
in stocking feet.
We must not speak
above a whisper.
We must not run any water.
We cannot use the sink
or even- forgive me-
the W.C.
The pipes go down
through the workrooms.
No trash must ever be-
No trash must ever be
thrown out which might reveal
that someone is living up here.
Not even
a potato peeling.
We must burn everything
in this stove at night.
This is the way that we must
live until it is over,
if we are to survive.
Until it is over.
After 6:00
we can move about.
We can talk and laugh,
have our supper,
read, play games,
just as we would
at home.
Now I think it would be wise
if we all went to our rooms
and were settled before 8:00.
Mrs. Van Daan,
you and your husband
will be upstairs.
I regret that
there's no place up there
for Peter,
but he'll be here,
near us.
- And where am I?
- You and Margot will be in there, Annele.
Excuse me, Mr. Frank.
Yes?
Where do you
and Mrs. Frank sleep?
This room is also our bedroom.
Oh, no.
You take the upstairs.
It's not right.
It's your place.
We'll sleep down here.
I've thought this out for weeks.
It's the best arrangement.
The only arrangement.
Uh, Edith?
Hmm?
You must have
some rest, dear.
You didn't
close your eyes
last night.
Please go in
the girls' room with Margot.
How about Anne?
I feel fine.
I'm going to help Father.
This way,
Mrs. Van Daan.
Excuse me.
Up here.
Mr. Frank.
- Mr. Frank?
- Peter?
- Do I still have time
to get some water for my cat?
- Have you got a cat?
Go ahead, but be quick.
You only have five minutes.
He couldn't live
without that cat.
I didn't know
you had a cat.
I love cats.
What's its name?
Mouschi.
What is it? Mouschi.
A him or her?
It's a tom, and it
doesn't like strangers.
Well, I'll have to stop
being a stranger, won't I?
Is he fixed?
No.
Well, you ought to
have him fixed to
keep him from fighting.
What a nice cat.
Where do you
go to school?
Jewish Secondary.
That's where
Margot and I go.
Yeah, I know.
I've never
seen you around.
I used to see you
sometimes.
You did?
But why didn't you
ever come over?
Oh, I don't know.
I'm sort of a lone wolf.
Can't be
a lone wolf here.
Wonder what our friends
will say when
we don't show up today?
I had a date
with Sanne.
Do you know
Sanne de Vries?
No.
Sanne's
my best friend.
She's thin like me.
They always yell at us,
"Anne and Sanne,
the skinny bananas."
You took off
your star.
That's right.
You can't do that.
They'll arrest you if you
go out without your star.
Who's going out?
Help me.
I'm helping.
- What are you going to do with it?
- Burn it.
That's funny.
I don't think I could burn mine.
I don't know why.
You couldn't?
Something they make you wear
so they can kick you around?
I know.
But, after all,
it is the Star of David, isn't it?
Annele?
It's almost 8:00.
Don't you want to come
and sit with us, Peter?
It's going to be a long day.
No, thanks.
This is fine.
You won't forget
to take off your shoes,
will you?
Peter.
It's nice
to have you with us.
Yes, Mr. Frank.
See you later.
Do you know he went to
the same school that-
It's comforting to think that
Mr. Kraler and his secretary...
are down there below us
in the office.
Our protectors,
we call them.
I asked Father
what would happen to them
if anyone found out...
they were hiding us.
Father said they would suffer
the same fate that we would.
We are over
an old spice factory.
You can smell the spices
all through the building.
Sieg heil! Sieg heil!
I read A Tale of Two Cities
through in that first day.
"It is a far,
far better thing I do...
"than I have ever done.
"It is a far, far better
rest that I go to...
"than I have ever known.
The end."
It was the saddest book
I ever read.
It is us,
Miep and Kraler.
Good evening, Mr. Kraler.
Good evening, Miep.
Evening, Annele.
Hello. Hello.
Hello.
Oh, Mr. Frank.
Yes?
This is the box
you asked for.
Thank you.
Good evening, Mr. Kraler.
My dear friends,
you are so quiet up here.
I thought
you'd gone out
for a walk.
Can you imagine me?
I didn't talk.
I hardly moved for
one whole day. I wish they
could hear that at school.
- Mouschi! Mouschi!
- Peter!
Mouschi!
Shh!
Shh. Annele.
Annele!
Peter,
I'm warning you.
[Mr. Frank]
Please, quiet.
Margot. Margot!
What are these?
You don't have to
whisper.
Oh, there you are.
It's such a nice cat.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Annele.
There's a box there.
Will you open it,
please?
You know how I'm going
to think of it here?
As a boardinghouse.
A very peculiar
boardinghouse.
Father, my film stars!
I was wondering
where they were.
And Queen Wilhelmina.
How wonderful.
There's
something more.
Go on.
Look further.
A diary.
I've never had a diary,
and I've always wanted one.
Ohh.
A pencil?
I'm going downstairs
to get a pencil.
Anne, no.
But there's nobody
down there now.
It doesn't matter.
Don't ever go
beyond that door.
Ever?
Never.
I'm sorry, Anne.
It isn't safe.
I see.
It'll be hard.
I know that.
But always remember this,
Anneke:
there are no walls, no locks,
no bolts that anyone
can put on your mind.
As a matter of fact,
just between us, Annele,
being here has
certain advantages
for you.
For instance, remember that
battle you had with your mother
on the subject of overshoes?
You said you'd rather die
than wear overshoes.
Remember?
Well, what happened?
In the end,
you had to wear them.
Now, for as long
as we are here you won't
have to wear overshoes.
Isn't that good?
And the piano?
You won't have to
practice on the piano.
I tell you, this is going
to be a fine life for you.
It's an odd idea for someone
like me to keep a diary.
Not only because
I have never done so before,
but because it seems to me
that neither I, nor for
that matter anyone else,
will be interested
in the unbosomings
of a 13-year-old schoolgirl.
Still,
what does that matter?
I want to write.
But more than that,
I want to bring out
all kinds of things...
that lie buried
deep in my heart.
First of all, I expect
I should be describing...
what it's like
to go into hiding.
But I don't really
know yet myself.
I only know it's funny
never to be able
to go outdoors,
never to breathe
fresh air,
never to run
and shout and jump.
Wednesday,
the 23rd of September, 1942.
The news of the war is good.
Stalingrad
is still holding out.
The Russian offensive continues
in the Moscow area.
It's safe now.
The last workman has left.
Whee!
Anne!
I'm first
for the W.C.
It's 6:00, Margot.
School is over.
Where are
my shoes?
Have you seen my shoes?
- What shoes?
- You're gonna be sorry.
- I am?
- Anne dear.
Wait till I get you.
I'm waiting.
Stop! Peter. Ouch!
Anne! Peter!
Hey,
where are you going?
Going to give Mouschi
his dinner.
Peter!
Anne dear, I think
you shouldn't play
like that with Peter.
It's not dignified.
Who wants to be dignified?
I don't want to be dignified.
You complain that I don't
treat you like a grown-up,
but when I do you resent it.
I only want
some fun.
I don't know
what's the matter
with that boy.
Give him a little time.
He isn't used to girls.
Time?
Isn't two months time?
I could cry.
I wonder where Miep is.
She's usually so prompt.
Margot, come and dance
with me, please.
I've got more work to do,
Anne.
You know,
we're going to forget
how to dance.
When we get out,
we won't remember a thing.
Where's Peter?
Where would he be?
With his cat.
He hasn't finished
his lessons, has he?
Peter.
- Peter!
- What is it?
Your mother says
to come out!
I'm giving Mouschi
his dinner.
I'm feeding my cat.
You know what your father says
about you wasting
all your time with that cat.
I haven't even looked
at him since lunch.
I'm only telling you.
I'll feed him.
You stay out of here.
And I mean out.
Is that any way for you
to talk to your little girlfriend?
Mother,
I asked you,
would you please not say that?
Look, he's blushing.
He's blushing.
Please. I'm not, but-
Leave me alone, will you.
What did I say?
You act like it's something
to be ashamed of.
It's nothing
to be ashamed of to have
a little girlfriend.
- That's crazy. She's only 13.
- So what? And you're 16. It's just perfect.
Your father is 10 years
older than I am.
Mr. Frank, I warn you,
this war lasts much longer,
we're gonna be related.
Mazel tov.
I haven't seen my cat
since lunch.
I'm giving Mouschi
his dinner.
My little Mouschi.
I couldn't live
without my precious Mouschi.
You wonderful cat,
you!
All right,
Miss Quack-Quack.
What's that?
Miss Quack-Quack!
Heard all about you.
How you talk so much in class,
they call you Miss Quack-Quack.
You're the most intolerable,
insufferable boy I ever met!
Quack-quack-quack!
I'll give it to you
good!
Quack!
- Ooh!
Anne dear,
you're hot.
You're warm.
Are you feeling all right?
Mother, please.
You don't have a fever,
do you?
No.
You know we can't call
a doctor here, ever.
There's only one thing to do:
watch carefully.
Prevent an illness
before it comes.
Let me see your tongue.
Mother, this is
perfectly absurd.
Anne dear,
don't be such a baby.
Let me see
your tongue.
Otto.
Anne.
You hear your mother,
don't you?
Come on, open up.
Quack.
Anne.
Otto.
You're all right.
I think there's nothing
the matter with our Anne
that a ride on her bike...
or a visit with
her friend Sanne de Vries
wouldn't cure.
Isn't that so, Annele?
I keep wishing
that Peter was a girl...
instead of a boy.
Then I'd have someone
to talk to.
With all the boys
in the world,
why did I have to get
locked up with him?
Is it someone?
Is it Miep?
It's strange
we don't hear.
Maybe she got hurt-
the flak.
She'll come.
I wish
she'd get here.
I'm going crazy
without cigarettes.
Anne, you got an "excellent"
in your history paper today...
and a "very good"
in Latin.
Yes, but how about
algebra?
Well, I have
a confession to make.
Up until now I managed
to stay ahead of you
in algebra.
Today you caught up
with me.
We'll leave it to Margot
to correct.
Isn't algebra vile,
Father?
Vile.
How did I do?
Excellent,
of course.
Anne, Anne, please.
Your French composition today
was wonderful, just wonderful.
Mrs. Van Daan,
may I try it on?
No, Anne.
It's all right.
Really.
But please,
be careful with it.
My father gave me this coat
the year before he died.
He always bought me
the best money could buy.
Mrs. Van Daan, did you have
a lot of boyfriends...
before you
were married?
Anne, that's
a personal question.
It's not courteous
to ask personal questions.
I don't mind.
Anneke, our house
was always swarming
with boys.
- When I was a young girl-
- Oh, no. Not again.
Shut up!
One summer we had a big house
in Hilversum.
The boys-
The boys would come
buzzing around like bees
around a jam pot.
When I was 17-
Well, we were wearing
our skirts very short
in those days,
and I had
such good-looking legs.
I still have. I may not be
as pretty as I used to be,
but I still have my legs.
How about it,
Mr. Frank?
All right,
all right.
We see them.
I'm not asking you.
I'm asking Mr. Frank.
Mother,
for heaven's sakes.
Oh, I embarrass you too,
do I?
Well, I only hope
the girl you marry
has as good.
Anneke, my father
used to worry about me with
all the boys hanging around.
And he used to say to me,
"If any of those boys
get fresh,
"you just say to him,
'Remember, Mr. So-and-so,
remember, I am a lady."'
Look at you,
talking that way
in front of her.
Don't you know she puts it
all down in that damned diary?
So what if she does?
I'm only telling
the truth.
Haven't you
finished yet?
No.
Oh. The thinker.
Leave him alone.
All right, all right.
I'm a dunce, a hopeless case.
You're not hopeless.
It's just that you haven't
got anyone to help you
like Father helps Anne and me.
Well, if I-
Well, if we could help-
What about it, Peter?
Would you like to study with us?
Shall we make
our school coeducational?
Thanks. Yes.
Mr. Frank, you are an angel,
an absolute angel.
Why didn't I meet you
before I met that one there?
I... think
it might be better...
if you went
into your room,
Peter, to work.
Excuse me.
You listen to Mr. Frank.
Mr. Frank is
a highly educated man.
It's after 8:00.
Where are they?
At least one of them
should have come.
They'll come. Don't worry.
Don't tell me.
I know something's wrong.
Isn't it bad enough around here
without you sprawling
all over the place?
If you didn't smoke
all the time, you wouldn't
be so bad-tempered.
Do you see me smoking?
Oh, you already smoked up
all the cigarettes?
One package.
Miep only brought me
one package.
It's a filthy habit,
and this is a good time
to break yourself of it.
- Oh, stop it.
- You're smoking up
all our money!
Will you shut up!
And what are you
staring at?
I never heard grown-ups
quarrel like that before.
I thought
only children quarreled.
This isn't a quarrel.
It's a discussion.
- And I never heard children
so rude before.
- I, rude?
Yes!
Anne,
drink your milk.
The trouble with you is,
you've been spoiled.
You need a spanking.
Remember, Mr. So-and-so,
that I am a lady.
Mmm, you're
the most aggravating-
Why aren't you nice and quiet
like your sister Margot?
Why do you
have to show off
all the time?
Let me give you
a little advice, young lady-
men don't like that in a girl.
Do you know that?
A man likes a girl who will
listen to him once in a while.
A domestic girl
who loves to cook and clean-
I'd cut my throat first!
I'd open my veins.
I'm going to be
remarkable.
I'm going to Paris
to study music and art.
Paris? Yeah, yeah.
I'm going to be an actress,
or a writer, or a dancer.
Look what you did.
I'm so sorry.
You clumsy little fool!
This is the coat
my father gave me!
I'm so sorry.
You ruined it.
What do you care?
Ruined it!
I could kill you!
I could just kill you!
Petronella.
Liebchen, Liebchen.
It's only a coat.
Anne, you must not
behave in that way.
It was an accident.
Anyone can have an accident.
I don't mean that.
I mean the answering back.
You must not
answer back.
They're
our guests.
You don't hear Margot
getting into any arguments
with them, do you?
Try to be
like Margot.
And have them
walk all over me the way
they do her? No, thanks.
I don't know what
happens to you, Anne.
If I had ever
talked to my mother
as you talk to me-
Things have changed,
Mother.
People aren't
like that anymore.
"Yes, Mother." "No, Mother."
"Anything you say, Mother."
I've got to
fight things out
for myself.
But-
Make something
of myself.
It isn't necessary
to fight to do it.
Margot doesn't fight.
Margot!
That's all I hear.
"Why aren't you like Margot?"
Everything she does is right,
and everything I do is wrong!
You're all against me,
and you worst of all!
I don't know how
we can go on living this way.
I can't say a word to Anne,
she flies at me.
You know Anne.
In a half hour she'll be out here
laughing and joking.
And, uh-
I told your father it wouldn't work-
two families.
But no, no,
he had to ask them.
Shh.
Every time
I hear that sound,
my heart stops.
It's Miep.
Father!
Yes?
It's Miep.
Here's your list.
Is it Miep?
Yes.
At last I'll have
some cigarettes.
Miep's here.
I can't tell you
how sorry I am
about the coat.
Don't worry.
Hello, hello.
Miep.
Mr. Kraler!
When Mr. Kraler comes,
the sun begins to shine.
Dirk has had
to leave.
Dirk is Miep's fiancé.
He had to go into hiding
in the country
to escape a labor call-up.
But he has let me
have the radio for you.
He shouldn't have.
Oh, it was
too dangerous.
Look!
♪♪
Our blessed radio.
It gives us our eyes and ears
out into the world.
We listen to the German station
only for good music.
The Axis forces
in the Western desert-
And we listen to the BBC
for hope.
Ceaseless attacks
by our land
and air forces...
are now
in full retreat.
The Eighth Army
continues to advance.
That's good.
All right, Peter,
now let's see what they
have to say about the Nazis.
Berlin.
Sieg heil! Sieg heil!
Sieg heil!
Must we listen?
All right, Peter.
That's enough.
The Green Police.
They've found us.
Hmm.
Ah.
Huh.
Hmm.
This way,
Mr. Dussel.
It is Kraler.
Please open.
And Miep.
Oh, bless them.
They are here.
And Miep, yes. Open, please.
Well, we had
a visitor last night.
A visitor last night?
Yes, yes.
A thief.
It was a thief?
Did you
hear him?
Yes, we heard him.
He was
right under you.
- In the office right under here.
- We did not know.
We thought it was
the Green Police.
Are you sure, Miep?
You were, of course,
quiet?
We didn't move.
We hardly breathed
all night.
That is good.
It was close.
Too close.
He went through everything.
The desk and the files.
And he found the safe, but
he could not get it open.
He was looking for
our ration card supply
from the Underground.
Somebody knows.
They're in that safe.
They'll come back.
Get rid of that safe.
Get it out of here.
Yes. Put a sign on
the door:
"Burglars, do not come back.
The safe is gone."
Jokes, yet.
Mr. Frank,
I must talk to you.
Yes, of course.
Maybe it's the radio.
We should get rid of
the radio.
Put it in the stove, burn it.
If the Green Police
found that radio-
And they'd find her diary.
We'll burn that too.
Not my diary.
My diary goes,
I go with it.
Where is it?
If they find us,
they might just as well
find the diary, the radio.
What'll be
the difference?
Usually, when I come up here,
I try to bring good news.
Yes, I know.
Something has happened.
A man came to me.
He told me that
he has a Jewish friend- a dentist.
He begged me,
could I find him a hiding place?
So I have come to you.
I know it is a terrible thing to ask,
living the way you are,
but could you take him in?
Well, of course
we will.
His name is Jan Dussel.
Dussel. Wait a minute.
I think I know him.
It's fine to have him.
But, Otto, where are
we going to put him? Where?
There's so little food as it is,
and to take in another person-
We can stretch the food
a little, Mr. Van Daan.
He can have my bed.
No, thank you, Peter.
Margot will move
in here with us,
and he can have her bed.
- I'll get my things out.
Mr. Dussel.
Don't bump your head.
Come in, Mr. Dussel.
This is Mr. Frank.
Mr. Otto Frank?
Yes. Let me have
your things, please.
Thank you, Mr. Frank.
I leave you in good hands.
Mr. Dussel?
Hmm?
I must return
your coat.
What can I say to thank you?
Mr. Kraler and Miep,
they're our lifeline.
Without them, we couldn't live.
Please, you make us
seem very heroic.
It isn't that at all.
We simply don't like the Nazis.
We don't like their methods-
I know. I know.
"Nobody's gonna tell
us Dutchmen what to do
with our damn Jews."
We will be
up tomorrow to see that
they are treating you right.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, Mr. Kraler.
Good-bye, Miep.
Welcome, Mr. Dussel.
Thank you.
This is my wife, Edith.
Mr. and Mrs. Van Daan.
Their son, Peter,
my daughters Margot and Anne.
Anne.
How do you do.
Margot.
Please, Mr. Dussel,
sit down.
Thank you.
I'm dreaming,
I know it.
Mr. Otto Frank, here.
You're not in Switzerland, then?
Someone said that
you escaped to Switzerland.
And you've been here
all this time?
Ever since July.
Did Mr. Kraler warn you
you won't get much to eat here?
You can imagine...
three ration cards
among the seven of us.
Now you make eight.
Mr. Van Daan, you don't realize
what's happening outside...
that you should warn me
of a thing like that.
You don't realize what's going on
right here in Amsterdam.
Every day, hundreds
of Jews disappear.
They surround a block,
and they search
house by house.
Every day children
come home from school
to find their parents gone.
Hundreds are being deported.
People that you and I know-
the Hallensteins, the Wessels.
Oh, no.
You get your
call-up notice-
come to the station
on such and such a day and hour.
Bring only what
you can carry.
If you don't go, they come
and drag you from your home...
and ship you off to Mauthausen-
the death camp.
We didn't know
that things had got
so much worse.
Forgive me
for speaking so.
Do you know the de Vries?
They're gone.
Sanne and I
are in the same class.
Sanne is my best-
my best friend.
She returned home from school
to find her parents gone.
She was alone for two days,
and then they came
and took her away.
Gone?
With all the others.
Oh, no.
Some people named Meyerberg,
they lived near us-
I think we should
put this off until later,
Mrs. Van Daan.
I'm sure Mr. Dussel would
like to get settled now.
Annele, would you like to
take Mr. Dussel to his room?
If you’ll come with me,
Mr. Dussel.
Uh, forgive me
if I haven't expressed
my gratitude.
This has been
such a shock to me.
I always thought of
myself as Dutch.
I was born in Holland.
My father was born
in Holland,
and my grandfather.
And now after
all these years-
If you will excuse me.
It's so different
from what Mr. Kraler
tells us.
Mr. Kraler says that
things are improving.
I like it better
the way Kraler tells it.
Good night, Bubele.
Say good night.
Good night, Mother.
Good night, Mr. Frank.
Good night.
Do you have any children,
Mr. Dussel?
No, I never married.
Have you no family
at all?
No one.
How dreadful.
You must be terribly lonely.
Mm. I'm used to it.
I don't think I could
ever get used to it.
Didn't you even have
a pet? A cat or a dog?
No.
No, no. I have an allergy
to fur-bearing animals.
Gives me asthma.
Oh, dear.
What?
Peter has a cat.
He has?
He has it here?
Yes.
We hardly ever see it.
He keeps it in his room
all the time.
I'm sure it will
be all right.
Mm-hmm.
Well, I hope so.
I hope I'm not going to be
too much of a bother
to you, Mr. Dussel.
No.
I seem to be able to
get everyone's back up.
Oh, I always get along
very well with young people.
My patients all bring
their children to me...
because they know
I get along well with them.
So don't you worry
about that.
Thank you,
Mr. Dussel.
Good night.
I'll be back.
Good night, Mr. Dussel.
Careful.
Sieg heil! Sieg heil!
Sanne.
Sanne?
Halt!
Save me! Save me!
No, no!
Oh! No, don't take me!
Stop it. Stop it.
Save me.
Hush, darling.
Hush. It's all right.
It's all right.
Please, Mr. Dussel,
turn on the light.
It was just a dream.
You're here, safe.
You see?
Something must be done
with that child,
yelling like that.
Who knows who might be in the street.
She's endangering all our lives.
Mr. Dussel, after all,
Anne is not exactly
a trained, frontline soldier.
Please, Mr. Dussel,
go back to bed.
She'll be herself
in a minute or two.
Won't you, Anne?
Go back to bed.
Excuse me. I'm going to the W.C.,
the one room where there's peace.
Go back to bed now.
Would you like
some water?
Was it a very bad dream?
Perhaps if you
told me.
I'd rather not talk about it.
Try to sleep then.
I'll sit right here
beside you.
You don't have to.
But I'd like to stay
with you very much. Really.
I'd rather you didn't.
You'll be all right?
There's nothing
that you want?
Will you please
ask Father to come?
Yes, of course,
Anne dear.
She asks for you.
Edith.
Go to her, Otto.
She's still trembling with fear.
She wants nothing of me.
She pulled away when
I leaned down to kiss her.
The Green Police
broke down a door
and grabbed me...
and tried to drag me out
the way they did Sanne.
It's just a phase.
All girls turn to their
fathers at this age.
They give all their love
to their fathers.
You weren't like this.
You didn't shut me out.
So...
now, do you want me to
read to you for a while?
No. Just sit with me
for a minute.
Was I awful?
Do you think anyone outside
could've heard me?
No. Now lie down quietly.
So, like this.
Now try to sleep.
I'm a terrible coward.
I'm so disappointed in myself.
I think I'm really grown up,
and then something happens
and I run to you like a baby.
I love you, Father.
I don't love anyone but you.
Annele. Annele.
It's true.
You're the only one I love.
I've been thinking about it
for a long time.
It's fine- It's fine to have you
tell me that you love me,
but I'd be much happier
if you said that you
loved your mother as well.
She needs your help so much.
Your love.
We have nothing in common.
She doesn't understand me.
Whenever I try to
explain my views on life,
she asks me if I'm constipated.
You hurt her very much just now.
She's crying. She's in there crying.
Oh, Father,
I was horrible, wasn't I?
What's the matter with me?
Tell me.
Don't say it's just a phase.
Help me.
There's so little we parents can do
to help our children, Anne.
We can only try to
set a good example.
Point the way.
The rest you must do yourself.
I'm trying. Really, I am.
Every night I think back
over all the things I did that day
that were wrong.
Like putting the wet mop
in Mrs. Van Daan's bed.
And now this with Mother.
I say to myself,
"That was wrong."
And I make up my mind I'm never
going to do that again. Never.
I may do something worse,
but I'll never do that again.
I have a nicer side, Father.
But I'm scared to show it.
I'm afraid people
will laugh at me.
So the mean Anne
comes to the outside...
and the good Anne
stays in the inside.
And I keep on trying to
switch them around...
and have the good Anne outside
and the bad Anne inside.
It would be what I'd like to be...
and might be... if only-
She's asleep.
Thursday, the 29th
of October, 1942.
Mr. Dussel and I
had a great battle yesterday.
Yes, Mr. Dussel.
According to him, nothing,
I repeat, nothing is right about me.
While he was going on at me,
I thought,
"Someday, I'm going to
give you such a smack...
that you'll fly
right up to the ceiling."
Why is it that every
grown-up thinks he knows
the way to bring up children?
Particularly the grown-ups
that haven't any.
Monday, the ninth of
November, 1942.
Wonderful news.
The Allies have landed in Africa.
Churchill spoke
on the BBC from London.
Which they have so often
meted out to others.
Ah, this is not the end.
No, it is not even
the beginning of the end.
But it is, perhaps,
the end of the beginning.
The air raids are getting worse.
The British planes
come over day and night
on their way to Germany.
It's too much.
Just too much.
Suppose they hit
this house?
What will we do?
We can't go out
in the street.
What will we do?
If they hit this house,
your worries will be over.
That noise- that big explosion-
they hit one of the English planes.
It fell right in this block.
Peter!
It's far away from here.
Don't be nervous.
Look. Just look at them.
Why, Mrs. Van Daan,
this should be music to your ears.
Music?
Of course.
The more planes
the British send over,
the sooner the war will be over,
the sooner we'll be out of here
and home again.
I don't believe
it'll ever be over.
You know what I'd like right now?
A cup of tea.
Oh, yes, please.
You can't have tea
then for breakfast.
If you have tea now,
you won't have any tomorrow.
I don't care.
- Neither do I. Now, please.
- Me, too, please.
How about you, Mr. Dussel?
Would you like your tea now
or tomorrow morning?
Tomorrow morning.
Sure?
- Sure.
I'll take mine now.
The skylight!
Edith, come!
Peter! Peter!
Peter!
"Praised be Thou,
O Lord our God,
"ruler of the universe
who has sanctified us
with Thy commandments...
"and bidden us kindle
the Hanukkah lights.
"Praise be Thou,
O Lord our God,
ruler of the universe...
"who has wrought
wondrous deliverances
for our fathers in days of old.
"Praise be Thou,
O Lord our God,
ruler of the universe...
"that Thou has given us life
and sustenance and brought us
to this happy season.
Amen."
Amen.
Monday, the seventh
of December, 1942.
The Hanukkah holiday
came early this year.
"We kindle this Hanukkah light
to celebrate the great
and wonderful deeds...
"wrought through the zeal
with which God filled the hearts...
"of the heroic Maccabees
2,000 years ago.
"They fought against
indifference, against
tyranny and oppression...
"and they restored
our temple to us.
"May these lights remind us
that we should ever look to God,
"whence cometh our help.
Amen."
[All]
Amen.
"I lift up mine eyes
unto the mountains from
whence cometh my help.
"My help cometh from
the Lord who made
heaven and Earth.
"He will not suffer
thy foot to be moved.
"He that keepeth thee
will not slumber.
"He that keepeth Israel
doth neither slumber nor sleep.
"The Lord is thy keeper.
The Lord is thy shade
upon thy right hand.
"The Lord shall keep thee from all evil.
He shall keep thy soul.
"The Lord shall guard thy going out
and thy coming in,
"from this time forth
and forevermore.
Amen."
Amen.
May I have the hats, please?
Thank you.
Very nice.
That was very moving.
Sit down.
Where are you going?
There's lots more.
Songs and presents.
Presents?
Not this year,
unfortunately.
But always on Hanukkah
everyone gives presents.
Everyone.
That's right.
Like our
Saint Nicholas day.
No, not like
What kind of a Jew are you
that you don't know Hanukkah?
I remember particularly
the candles.
First one, as we have tonight.
Then the second night,
you light two candles.
The next night, three.
And so on, until there
are eight candles burning.
When there are
eight candles,
it's truly beautiful.
What I remember best
are the presents
we used to get.
Eight days of presents,
and, well, each day
they got better and better.
We're all here... alive.
That's present enough.
- No, it isn't. I've got something.
- What is it?
L'Chaim.
Presents.
Real presents?
She made it
herself.
Look at that.
Isn't it festive?
Isn't it gay?
Oh, that's beautiful.
For Margot.
Ah.
Read it out loud.
"You have never
lost your temper.
"You never will,
I fear.
You are so good,
but if you should,
put all your cross words here."
Aww.
Let's see what it is.
It's a new
crossword puzzle book.
It's one you've done,
but I rubbed it all out...
and if you wait a little
and forget,
you can do it again.
Clever, clever.
Thank you.
For Mrs. Van Daan.
Ah-hah.
I feel terrible.
I don't have a thing
for anybody.
It's hair shampoo.
I took odds and ends of soap
and mixed them with the last
of my toilet water.
Oh, thank you,
Anneke.
That was nice.
I wanted to write a poem
for all of them,
but I didn't have time.
That's all right,
Anne.
Yours, Mr. Van Daan,
is really something.
Mmm?
Something you want
more than anything.
Hmm.
- Cigarettes!
- Look at that.
Cigarettes.
Two of them.
Father found some old pipe tobacco
in the pocket lining of his coat,
and we made them-
rather, Father did.
Look at that.
Light it!
Go on and light it!
It's tobacco.
Really, it is.
There's a little fluff in it,
but not much.
It works!
Look at him.
Thank you, Anne.
Thank you.
Mr. Van Daan!
For Mother.
Hanukkah greeting.
"Here's an I.O.U.
that I promise to pay.
"Ten hours of doing...
"whatever you say.
Signed, Anne Frank."
- Ten hours of doing what you're told?
Anything you're told?
- That's right.
You wouldn't want to
sell that, Mrs. Frank,
would you?
Never. This is the most
precious gift I've ever had.
For Father.
Annele, I wasn't supposed to
have a present.
Look at that.
It's a muffler.
Oh, I know.
To wear around your neck
like an ascot, you know.
I knitted it in the dark each night.
I'm afraid it looks better in the dark.
It's fine.
Thank you, Annele.
Thank you.
Isn't it beautiful.
Lovely, huh?
Thank you, Anne.
- For Mouschi.
- [Mrs. Van Daan]
He'll like it.
And this is for you. Yourself.
From Miss Quack-Quack.
Go on. Open it.
Aren't you
going to open it?
[Mrs. Van Daan]
Come on. Show us what it is.
It's a safety razor.
It's not new.
Miep got it for me second-hand.
But you do need a razor now.
What for?
Look at his upper lip.
See?
He wants to
get rid of that?
Put some milk on it
and let the cat lick it off.
You think you're funny,
don't you?
Look, he can't wait.
He's going in to try it now.
I'm going to give
Mouschi his present.
Mouschi, Mouschi, Mouschi.
Enough.
And last, but never least,
my roommate, Mr. Dussel.
Something for me?
Capsules.
They're earplugs to
put in your ears...
so you won't hear me
when I thrash around
at night.
I made them myself.
Try them. See if
you can hear me.
Wait, I'll put- Like that?
Is that what you mean?
Are you ready?
What?
- Are you ready?
- They work.
They went in.
He can't get 'em out.
What's the matter with you?
Get 'em out.
Take 'em out.
I got 'em.
- Thank you.
And now let's sing
the song, Father.
Wait till you hear
the Hanukkah song,
Mr. Dussel.
♪ O Hanukkah, O Hanukkah
The sweet celebration ♪
Annele.
Annele, we shouldn't
sing the song tonight.
You see, Mr. Dussel,
it's a song of jubilation
and of rejoicing.
One is apt to become
just a little too enthusiastic
about it.
Please, let's
sing the song, Father.
I promise not to shout.
Very well, but quietly, Anne.
I'll keep my eye on you-
Oh!
Oh! I told you
not to come in here
with that cat.
Get out of here.
What's the matter
with you?
Haven't you any sense?
Get that cat
out of here.
Cat?
You heard me.
Get it out of here!
I have no cat.
Mr. Dussel!
It doesn't have to
be the cat.
Just the hairs on his clothing
from the cat is enough.
When he comes in the room-
Don't worry, you won't be
bothered anymore.
We're getting rid
of it.
At last, you listen to me.
I'm not doing it for you.
That's all in your mind.
All of it.
I'm doing it because
I'm sick of seeing that cat
eat all our food.
That's not true.
I only give him scraps.
Don't tell me.
He gets fatter every day.
Damn cat looks better than any of us.
Out he goes tonight.
No!
Mr. Van Daan,
you can't do that.
That's Peter's cat.
Peter loves that cat.
Anne.
- If he goes, I go.
- Go. Go.
He's not going,
and the cat's not going.
What's the matter with you?
It's Hanukkah.
Please, Anne, sing.
♪ O Hanukkah, O Hanukkah
The sweet celebration ♪
♪ Around the feast
we gather ♪
Annele.
I think we should first
blow out the candles.
Then we'll have something
for tomorrow night.
Father, you're supposed to
let it burn itself out.
I'm sure that God
understands shortages.
Praise be Thou,
O Lord our God,
who has sustained us...
and permitted us
to celebrate
this joyous festival.
Amen.
I think
they've gone.
They found us.
If they had,
they would be
up here by now.
I know it was
the Green Police.
They've gone to get help.
It may be the Gestapo,
looking for papers.
- Or another thief
looking for money.
I'm going down.
They may still be there.
Annele,
this is Saturday.
We have no way of knowing
what has happened down there
until Miep and Mr. Kraler come.
We cannot live
with this uncertainty.
Now, please. Please.
Get our money.
They say you can buy them off.
So much a head.
- Quick, go upstairs and get the money.
- Keep still.
You wanna be dragged off
to a concentration camp?
You gonna stand there
until they come up here and get you?
Will you keep still!
Someone go
and make Father come back.
Haven't you
done enough?
Please, Mr. Van Daan.
Anne!
Shh.
I lift up mine eyes
unto the mountains
from whence cometh my help.
My help cometh from the Lord
who made heaven and Earth.
He that keepeth thee
will not slumber.
He that keepeth Israel
doth neither slumber nor sleep.
The Lord is thy keeper.
The Lord is thy shade from-
- No.
I better go
and look and make sure.
Ja.
Pray that the Lord
shall keep thee from all evil.
He shall keep thy soul.
Hear me, O Israel.
The Lord shall guard
thy going out
and thy coming in.
[Mr. Frank]
He took the typewriter
and ran away in such a hurry,
he didn't stop to
shut the street door-
it was swinging wide open.
A watchman was passing.
Look. Tools.
Ja.
Meetz-meetz-meetz.
Meow, meow.
They had a burglary.
He got out
as he heard me coming.
- Meetz-meetz.
I will lock the door
and report it.
They've gone.
They've locked the door.
Thank God they've gone.
I'd just as soon they'd
take us than to continue
with this terrible agony.
I can't stand it.
It's all right, Annele.
The danger has passed.
Who says
the danger is passed?
Don't you realize that
we're in greater danger
than ever?
Please, Mr. Dussel,
will you keep still.
Thanks to this clumsy fool,
someone now knows
we're up here.
- Someone now knows
that we're up here hiding.
- It's a thief.
You think the thief is going to
go to the Green Police and say,
"I was robbing a place the other night,
and I heard a noise above my head"?
You think a thief
is going to do that?
Yes, he will.
You're crazy.
I think that someday
the thief will be caught.
He'll make a bargain
with the Gestapo.
He'll say to the Gestapo,
"If you let me off,
I'll show you where
some Jews are hiding."
That's what I think.
Oy!
He's right.
Oh, Mother,
let's get out of here.
We can't stay here now.
Please,
let's go.
Go? Where?
Yes, where?
Have we lost all faith?
All courage?
A few moments ago,
we thought they had
come for us, didn't we?
We thought it was the end.
Well, it was not the end.
We are alive. We are safe.
We thank Thee,
O Lord, our God,
that in Thy infinite mercy,
Thou hast again
seen fit to spare us.
Amen.
Annele.
The song, hmm?
How about the song?
♪ O Hanukkah
O Hanukkah ♪
♪ The sweet celebration ♪
♪ Around the feast we gather ♪
♪ In complete jubilation ♪
♪ Happiest of seasons
now is here ♪
♪ Many are the reasons
for good cheer ♪
♪ Together, together ♪
♪ Whatever tomorrow may bring ♪
♪ So hear us rejoicing
and merrily voicing ♪
♪ The Hanukkah song
that we sing ♪
♪ O hear us rejoicing
and merrily voicing ♪
♪ The Hanukkah song
that we sing ♪♪
Happy Hanukkah.
Saturday, the first
of January, 1944.
Another new year has begun,
and we find ourselves
still in our hiding place.
We have been here now
for one year, five months
and 25 days.
One of our family
has left us.
Mouschi ran away.
We're all a little thinner.
The Van Daans' discussions
are as violent as ever.
Mother still doesn't
understand me,
but then
I don't understand her either.
There is one great change, however.
A change in myself.
I read somewhere that girls
of my age don't feel
quite certain of themselves,
that they become
quiet within...
and begin to think of the miracle
that is taking place in their bodies.
I think that
what is happening to me
is so wonderful.
Not only what can be seen,
but what is taking place inside.
Each time it has happened,
I feel I have a sweet secret,
and I long for the time
when I shall feel that secret
within me again.
Annele. Peter.
A wonderful surprise.
Mr. Kraler
and Miep are here.
Oh, thank you.
You shouldn't have come.
You should have at least
one day to yourselves.
Don't say that.
It's so wonderful
to see them.
What is it?
Mr. Kraler.
- Happy New Year, Mr. Dussel.
- Happy New Year.
How are you, Margot?
Feeling any better?
I'm all right.
We filled her full
of every kind of pill,
so she won't cough
and make a noise.
Look what Miep has brought us.
A cake.
Mmm.
Cake.
Well.
I'll get some plates.
Thank you, Miepia.
You must have used
all of your sugar rations
for weeks.
It's beautiful,
isn't it?
It's ages since
I've even seen a cake.
Not since you brought
the one last year, remember?
It had "Peace in 1943"
written on-
"Peace in 1944."
- Peace has to come
sometime, you know.
- Here you are.
- Peace has to come
sometime, you know.
- Here you are.
Now, how many of us
are there?
None for me,
thank you.
Oh, you must.
Please, Miep.
Good. That leaves one,
two, three- seven of us.
Eight. The same
as it always is.
I left Margot out.
I take it for granted
Margot won't eat any.
Why wouldn't she?
I think it
won't harm her.
All right, all right.
I just didn't want her to
start coughing again.
And, please,
Mrs. Frank
should cut the cake.
What do you mean?
Well, Mrs. Frank
divides things better.
Just what are you
trying to say?
Forget it. We're wasting time.
No, no.
Don't I always give everybody
exactly the same?
Don't I?
Forget it, Kerli.
No, I want an answer.
Don't I?
Yes. Yes, yes.
Everybody gets
exactly the same.
Except Mr. Van Daan
gets a little bit more.
That's a lie.
She always cuts the same.
Mr. Van Daan, please.
You see, Miep,
what a little sugar cake
does to us?
It goes right to our heads.
Here you are,
Mrs. Frank.
Thank you.
You sure you won't
have any?
Very sure.
Miep?
No, thank you.
Really.
Cut the cake.
All right.
Thank you, Peter.
That's yours, Peter.
Maybe Mouschi
went back to our house.
Do you ever get over there?
Do you think that you could?
I'm afraid with
him gone a week, Peter-
Make up your mind.
Already someone has had
a big nice meal from that cat.
Mmm, it's delicious, Miep.
Delicious.
Well, I must run.
There's a party tonight.
How heavenly.
Remember now
what everyone's wearing...
and what you have to eat
and everything so you can
tell us tomorrow.
I'll give you
a full report.
Good-bye, everyone.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, Miep.
Hey, just a minute.
There's something
I'd like you to do for me.
Putti, where are you going?
Putti, what are you
gonna do?
Putti.
No, no, no.
Don't you dare
take that coat.
What is wrong?
Father says he's gonna
sell her fur coat.
She's crazy about
that old fur coat.
It's mine, you hear me?
My father gave me that coat.
I want the coat.
No, you have no right.
Get your hands off it.
Is it possible
that anyone can...
be silly enough...
to worry about a fur coat
at a time like this?
It's none of
your darn business.
And if you say
one more thing-
Peter.
Just a...
little discussion
on the advisability
of selling this coat.
As I have often
reminded Mrs. Van Daan,
it's selfish of her to keep it
when people outside are in
such desperate need of clothing.
So if you please
to sell it for us.
It should fetch
a good price.
And by the way,
would you get me cigarettes?
I don't care
what kind they are.
Get all you can.
It is very difficult
to get them, Mr. Van Daan.
But I will try.
Good-bye.
Bye, Miep.
Mr. Frank,
could I talk to you?
Something's happened,
hasn't it, Mr. Kraler?
What's happened?
If it is something
that concerns us here,
we'd better all hear it.
The children-
What they'd imagine would be
worse than any reality.
It is a man in the storeroom.
His name is Karl.
You knew him.
One day he came to the office.
He closed the door
and asked me,
"What do you hear from
your friend Mr. Frank?"
I told him there was a rumor
that you were in Switzerland.
He said he had heard
that rumor too, but he thought
I might know something more.
I did not pay much attention.
I- I tried to forget it.
And then yesterday...
we were coming out of
the storeroom out there.
I had started down
to the office.
I looked back.
He was standing,
staring at the bookcase.
He said, "I thought
I remember a door up here.
Was not there a door here
leading to the loft?"
Then he asked me for more money.
Twenty gilders more a week.
- Blackmail.
- Twenty gilders?
Very modest blackmail.
That's just
the beginning.
You know what I think?
He's the thief who was
down there that night.
That's how
he knows we're here.
How was it left?
What did you tell him?
I told him
I had to think about it.
What shall I do?
Pay him the money?
Take a chance
on firing him or what?
I do not know.
For heaven's sakes,
don't fire him.
Pay him what he asks.
Keep him here where you can
keep your eye on him.
Is it so much that he is asking?
I mean, what are
they paying nowadays?
He could get it
in a war plant.
Mm-hmm.
But this is not a war plant.
Mind you, I do not know
if he knows or not.
Offer him half.
Then we'll soon know
if it is blackmail or not.
And if it is,
we've gotta pay, haven't we?
Whatever he asks,
we've gotta pay.
Let us decide that
when the time comes.
This may be all my imagination.
You get to a point these days
where you suspect everyone
and everything.
What does that mean,
the telephone ringing
on a holiday?
That's my wife.
I told her I had to go over
some papers in my office,
to call me here
when she got out of church.
Good-bye.
Happy New Year.
Good-bye, Mr. Kraler.
I will offer him half then.
Thank you, Mr. Kraler.
You can thank your son for this.
Him and his damn cat.
That night. There.
I tell you, it's-it's-it's-
it's just a question
of time now.
Sometimes I wish the end would come,
whatever it is.
Margot!
Well, then at least
we'd know where we were.
You should be ashamed of yourself,
talking that way.
Think how lucky we are.
Think of the thousands
dying in the war every day.
Think of the people
in concentration camps.
What's the good of that?
What's the good of
thinking of misery when
you're already miserable?
That's stupid.
We're young,
Margot and Peter and I.
You grown-ups
have had your chance.
Look at us. If we begin
thinking of all the horror
in the world, we're lost.
We're trying to hold on
to some kind of ideals,
when everything- ideals, hope-
everything is being destroyed.
It isn't our fault
the world is in such a mess.
We weren't around
when all this started.
- Now you listen to me.
- So don't try to take it out on us.
She talks as if
we started the war.
Did we start the war?
You left this.
Thanks.
I thought you were fine
just now.
You know just how to talk to 'em.
I can never think when I'm mad.
I say too much.
I hurt people's feelings.
I think you're just fine.
Thank you, Peter.
That Dussel,
what he said about Mouschi,
about somebody eating him,
all I could think is
I wanted to hit him.
That's what I used to do
in school, but,
here a fight starts,
I just duck in my room.
You're lucky
having a room to go to.
His Lordship is always in mine.
When they start in on me,
I have to stand and take it.
You gave some of it
back to them just now.
I get so mad.
They've formed their opinions.
About everything.
But we're still trying to find out.
We have problems here that
no other people our age have ever had.
And just as you think
you've solved them,
something comes along
and, bang,
you have to start all over again.
I think your father's fine.
Oh, he is, Peter.
He is.
He's the only one
who's ever given me the feeling
that I have any sense.
Isn't it funny, you and I?
Here we've been together all this time...
and this is the first time
we've ever really talked.
It helps a lot to have someone
to talk to, doesn't it?
It helps you let off steam.
Any time that...
you want to let off steam,
you can come into my room.
I can get up
an awful lot of steam.
It's all right with me.
Do you mean that?
I said it, didn't I?
Good night.
May I come in?
No, Mr. Dussel.
I'm not dressed yet.
Oh.
Margot.
Hmm?
Tell me, am I terribly ugly?
Oh, stop fishing.
No. Tell me.
Of course you're not.
You've got nice eyes...
and a lot of animation
and- and-
- May I come in?
- Come in, Mother.
Mr. Dussel is impatient
to get in here.
He takes the room
for himself the entire day.
You're not going in again
tonight to see Peter, hmm?
That is my intention.
Aren't you afraid
you're disturbing him?
Mother, I have some intuition.
Then may I ask you
this much, Annie?
Please don't shut the door
when you go in.
You sound like
Mrs. Van Daan.
Oh, no. I don't mean
to suggest anything wrong.
I only wish you wouldn't
expose yourself to criticism.
I'm sorry, Mother.
I'm going to Peter's room.
I'm not going to let
Petronella Van Daan
spoil our friendship.
Just a moment, Mr. Dussel.
In my day the boys
called on the girls.
You know how
young people are. Peter's room
is the only place they can talk.
Talk?
That's not what they called it
when I was a girl.
I'm sorry, Margot,
that you have to be
the one left out.
I feel so guilty about you.
Why?
I mean, every time
I go to Peter-
into Peter's room,
I have the feeling
that I'm hurting you.
I know if it were me,
I'd be desperately jealous.
I am jealous a little.
Not of you and Peter.
I'm-
I'm only feeling sorry
that I haven't anyone...
with whom to-
to discuss my feelings.
Margot, I won't even-
Listen, you've found
a companionship,
and I want you to enjoy it.
Only... in my heart I feel
that I've got a right to share
feelings with someone too.
But I'm sure that Peter-
that that boy, he could just
never be that person for me.
Maybe there's nothing
to be jealous about.
Maybe I'm just
taking the place of his cat.
Will you please let me
in my room?
Just a minute,
dear, dear Mr. Dussel.
Well, here I go...
to run the gauntlet.
Thank you so much.
Look at her.
A lot of good it did me
to have a son.
I never see him.
Just a minute, dear.
I'd like to say
a few words to my son.
Do you mind?
Peter, I do not want you staying
up till all hours tonight.
You need your sleep.
You are a growing boy.
Anne won't stay late.
She's going to bed
promptly at 9:00.
Aren't you, Anne?
Yes, Mother. May we go now?
Listen for the chimes, dear.
Aren't they impossible?
Treating us as if
we're still in the nursery.
Don't let it bother you.
It- It doesn't bother me.
I suppose you can't
really blame them.
They think back
to what they were like
at our age.
They don't realize
how much more advanced
we are.
Already I know
what I want to do.
Don't you?
I want to be
a journalist
or something.
I love to write.
What do you want to do?
I know
what I'd like right now.
I'd like to make it to England,
get with the Free Dutch Forces
over there.
Peter, you wouldn't
try a thing like that.
You'd never make it.
I'd make it.
Only a few of the hundreds
that try do.
I know, but... I'd like to get in it
and- and hit back.
To just sit here, it's not for me.
You like Margot, don't you?
Right from the start
you liked her.
Liked her better than me.
Oh, I don't know.
It's all right.
Everyone feels that way.
Margot's so good.
She's sweet and bright
and beautiful, and I'm not.
I wouldn't say that.
Oh, no, I'm not.
I know that.
I know quite well
that I'm not a beauty.
I never have been
and never shall be.
I don't agree at all.
I think you're pretty.
That's not true.
A-And another thing.
You've changed.
From the first, I mean.
I have?
I used to think that
you were awful noisy.
And what
do you think now, Peter?
How have I changed?
Well, you-
You're quieter.
I'm glad
you don’t just hate me.
I never said that.
I bet when you get out of here,
you'll never think of me again.
That's crazy.
When you get back
with all your friends,
you're going to say,
"Now, what did I ever see
in that Miss Quack-Quack?"
I haven't got any friends.
Peter, of course you have.
Everyone has friends.
Not me. I don't want any.
I get along fine without 'em.
Does that mean you can
get along without me too?
I think of myself
as your friend.
No.
If they were all like you,
it'd be different.
Peter-
Hmm?
Did you ever kiss a girl?
Yes.
Once.
Was she pretty?
The girl you kissed.
I don't know.
I was blindfolded.
It was at a party.
One of those kissing games.
Oh.
I don't suppose that
really counts, does it?
It didn't with me.
I've been kissed twice.
Once a man
I'd never seen before
kissed me on the cheek...
when he picked me up
off the ice.
I was crying.
And the other was
a friend of Father's
who kissed my hand.
You wouldn't say those
counted, would you?
I wouldn't say so.
I know almost for certain...
Margot would never
kiss anyone unless
she was engaged to them.
And I'm sure too
that Mother never
touched a man before Father.
But I don't know.
Things are so different now.
What do you think?
Do you think a girl
shouldn't kiss anyone...
except if she's engaged
or something?
It's so hard
to try to think what to do,
when here we are
with the whole world
falling around our ears.
And you think,
well, you don't know what's
going to happen tomorrow.
What do you think?
Well, uh,
I suppose it-
it depends on the girl.
With some, n-no matter
what they do, it's wrong.
But others,
it wouldn't necessarily
be wrong with them.
I always thought that...
when two people-
I think I should go now.
That's right.
Good night.
You won't let 'em
stop you from coming?
No.
I might bring my diary.
There are so many
things in it I want to
talk over with you.
There's a lot about you.
What kind of things?
Well,
I wouldn't want you
to see some of it.
I thought you were nothing.
Just the way
you thought about me.
Did you change your mind,
the way I changed my mind
about you?
Well, you'll see.
Good night, Annele.
Good night, angel.
Good night.
Mm-hmm.
Outside there is
a quiet excitement.
Invasion fever is mounting
from day to day,
and people talk of nothing else
but the hope of liberation.
It had best come soon.
We here have had bad news.
The people from whom
Miep got our ration cards
have been arrested.
Mr. Kraler is in the hospital.
It seems he has ulcers.
I'm afraid we are his ulcers.
Miep has to run the business
and us too.
How very fortunate we are...
when you think of
what is happening outside.
I feel that spring is coming.
I feel it
in my whole body and soul.
I'm utterly confused.
I am longing-
so longing for everything.
Otto! Otto, quick.
He's stealing the food!
Edith, Edith!
Mr. Van Daan,
let me see that!
Mr. Van Daan, come-
Let me-
Give me-
What happened?
Mr. Van Daan. Mr.-
Look, the bread!
You dirty thief.
You good-for-nothing.
Let him go, Mr. Dussel.
Help me, Peter.
Let him go!
Peter, help me!
Putti,
what is it?
He was stealing the bread.
It was you.
And all the time
we thought it was the rats.
Mr. Van Daan,
how could you?
I'm hungry.
We're all of us hungry.
I see the children getting
thinner and thinner.
Your own son, I've heard him
moan in his sleep,
he's so hungry.
And you come down in the night
and steal food that should
go to them, the children.
He needs more food
than the rest of us.
He's used to more.
He's a big man.
And you!
You're worse than he is.
You're a mother,
and yet you sacrifice
your son to this man,
this-this-
Edith.
Don't think I haven't seen you.
Always saving
the choicest bits for him.
I've watched you.
Day after day,
and I've held my tongue,
but not any longer.
Not after this!
Now I want him to go.
I want him to
get out of here!
Edith.
Get out of here?
What do you mean?
Just that.
Take your things and get out.
You're speaking in anger.
You cannot mean
what you're saying.
I mean exactly that.
For two long years
we have lived here side by side.
We have respected
each other's rights.
We have managed to live in peace.
Are we going to throw it all away?
Mr. Van Daan,
I know this is never going
to happen again, is it?
No, no.
Ah, he steals once,
he'll steal again.
I want them to leave.
You go now!
Mother.
You're not putting Peter out?
Peter hasn't done anything.
I don't mean Peter.
Peter can stay.
I'll have to go if he goes.
That's my father.
He's no father to you,
that man.
He doesn't know
what it means to be a father.
I wouldn't feel right.
I couldn't stay.
Very well then.
Peter. No.
Mrs. Frank,
you would put us
out in the street?
You can find
another hiding place.
Where would we even find
a cellar- a-a closet?
Mr. Frank,
you told Putti...
you would never forget
what he did for you when
you first came to Holland.
You said you never
would be able to repay him.
If my husband had
any obligations to you,
he has paid it over and over.
Edith, I don't know you.
I've never seen you like this.
I should have
spoken out long ago.
You can't be nice
to some people.
There would have been plenty
for all of us if you hadn't
come in here!
No, no, Mrs. Van Daan.
Please.
We don't need the Nazis
to destroy us.
We're destroying ourselves.
Mother, please don't
send them away.
It's daylight.
And they'll be caught.
Supreme headquarters-
They're not going now.
- They'll stay until Miep
finds them a place to hide.
- Mrs. Frank, Mr. Frank, Margot.
Oh, no, no.
We haven't sunk so low
that we're gonna fight
amongst ourselves over food.
That's Anne.
That's Mrs. Van Daan,
Mr. Van Daan.
You see what he's doing?
"I'm still standing by
to bring you further news
of the invasion."
Did you hear that?
"For those of you who may not
have heard, let me repeat.
The landings began this morning
on the coast of Normandy."
It's started. Listen!
D-Day has come.
During the night
and in the early hours
of this morning,
an immense armada-
Listen!
4,000 ships and thousands
of smaller craft-
Peter, myself.
You're keeping all
the big ones for yourself.
No.
Yes, you are.
All the big ones.
Look at the size of that one.
That's mine.
And look at that one.
That's Mr. Van Daan's.
Well, look at-
Stop it! Stop it!
Stop counting potatoes!
It's Miep. Let me in.
Mr. Frank and Mrs. Frank!
Mr. Dussel, I beg of you,
don't let her see
a thing like this.
Well, this is-
Mrs. Frank-
The invasion has begun!
The most wonderful news.
[Man]
Only preliminary reports
have come in-
Did you hear?
They have landed!
On the coast of France.
In Normandy.
The British, the Americans.
They're all in it!
Dutch, French, Poles,
Norwegians, everyone.
D-Day they call it.
D-Day.
At last! Oh!
- It's me. Kraler.
- It cannot be Mr. Kraler.
- But it is Mr. Kraler.
Did you hear?
Isn't it wonderful?
When the nurse
told me the news,
I said to myself there’s
only one place for me to be-
with my friends.
♪ In the name of Orange
now open the gates ♪
♪ Our allies have landed ashore ♪
♪ We'll fight and we'll capture
our country again ♪
♪ And freedom is ours evermore ♪
♪ And freedom
is ours evermore ♪
♪ In the name of Orange
now open the gates ♪
♪ Our allies have landed on shore ♪
♪ We'll fight ♪
♪ And we'll capture
our country again ♪
Shh. Shh.
♪ And freedom is ours evermore ♪
♪ And freedom
is ours evermore ♪♪
Quick.
Before the workmen come.
I'll be up later.
Good-bye,
my dear friends.
Good-bye, Mr. Kraler.
Thank you, Miep.
Putti, what is it?
What happened?
I am so ashamed!
Oh, for heaven's sake.
Putti, don't.
Mr. Van Daan,
didn't you hear?
We're going to be liberated.
This is a time to celebrate.
To steal bread
from children.
Oh, we've all done things
that we're ashamed of.
Look at the way
I treated Mother-
so mean and horrid to her.
No, Anneke. No.
Oh, I was, Mother.
I was awful.
Not like me.
No one is
as bad as me.
Torpedo boats
join British warships...
and thousands of Allied planes
in laying down
an earthshaking bombardment.
Stop it!
Let's be happy!
Edith.
When I think of
the terrible things I said.
No, no.
You were right.
That I should speak
that way to you,
our friends, our guests.
Stop it! You're spoiling
the whole invasion.
Almighty God,
our sons,
pride of our nation,
this day have set upon
a mighty endeavor-
Lift up your hearts.
Out of the depths of sorrow...
and of sacrifice...
will be born again
the glory of mankind.
We are all in much better
spirits these days.
There is still excellent news
of the invasion.
And the best part about it
is that I have a feeling
that friends are coming.
Our beloved queen spoke.
She used words like "soon,"
"when I am back,"
"speedy liberation."
Who knows?
I may be back in school by fall.
Wednesday,
the second of July, 1944.
Fierce counterattacks
by enemy panzer divisions-
The invasion seems
temporarily bogged down.
Mr. Kraler is back in the hospital.
He has to have an operation.
It seems D-Day
was too much for him.
Thank you.
Here you are.
Ha ha. The joke is on us.
Miep tells us the warehouseman
doesn't know a thing,
and we're paying him
all that money.
Our dear vegetable man is on his way
to a concentration camp.
He was picked up today for
hiding two Jews in his house.
There's not much.
It was Mr. Hauk,
our greengrocer,
they arrested.
And the other news is...
the Gestapo have found
our typewriter that was stolen.
No.
Uh-huh.
They'll trace it back and back
till it gets to us.
You watch, you-
Everyone is low.
Even Father can't raise
their spirits.
I have often
been downcast myself,
but never in despair.
I can shake off everything
if I write, but-
and that is the great question-
will I ever be able
to write well?
I want to so much.
I want to go on living
even after my death.
There it goes again.
Mr. Frank, do you hear?
Yes, I hear.
This is the third time.
The third time
in quick succession.
It's a signal.
I tell you it's Miep
trying to get us.
For some reason she-
she can't come to us,
and she's trying to
warn us of something.
Please, Mr. Dussel.
Please.
You're wasting
your breath.
Something has happened,
Mr. Frank.
It's been three days now
that Miep hasn't been to see us.
And today not a man
has come to work.
There hasn't been a sound
in the building.
Perhaps it's Sunday.
We may have lost track
of the days.
You with the diary there,
what day is it?
I don't lose track
of the days.
I know exactly
what day it is.
It's Friday,
the fourth of August.
and-and not a man at work.
I tell you,
Mr. Kraler is dead.
That's the only explanation.
He's dead, and they've
closed down the building,
and that's what Miep's
trying to tell us.
She would never
telephone us, Mr. Dussel.
Please, I beg of you,
Mr. Frank, answer the phone.
No.
Just pick it up and listen.
You don't have to speak.
-Just listen and see if it's Miep.
For God's sake,
answer the telephone!
I've told you, no.
I'll do nothing
that might let anyone know
that we are in this building.
Mr. Frank's right.
There's no need to tell us
what side you're on.
If we wait here quietly
and... patiently,
I believe that help will come.
Mr. Dussel-
No, Mr.- Mr. Dussel-
Mr. Dussel!
Too late.
So we just wait here...
until we die.
I can't stand it.
I'll kill myself.
For heaven's sake,
stop it.
I think you would be glad if I did.
You want me to die.
Whose fault is it
we're here?
We could have been safe
in America or Switzerland.
But no, no.
You wouldn't leave
when I wanted to.
You couldn't leave
your precious things.
Your furniture.
That's right.
Blame it all on me.
It's all my fault.
Your hats, your shoes,
your dishes.
For your comfort
we had anything.
My comfort.
I never had anything
I really wanted.
Everything was
for your pleasure!
Look, Peter.
Look at the sky.
Aren't the clouds beautiful?
A lovely, lovely day.
You know what I do...
when I think
I can't stand another minute
of being cooped up?
I think myself outside.
I think I'm on a walk
in the park where
I used to go with Father,
where the crocus and
the jonquils and the violets
grow along the slopes.
You know...
the most wonderful part
of thinking yourself outside?
You can have it
any way you like.
You can have roses and violets
and tulips all blooming
in the same season.
Isn't that wonderful?
When I was outside,
I used to take it all for granted.
And now in here I've just
gone crazy about nature.
I've just gone crazy.
I think if something
doesn't happen soon-
if we don't
get out of here-
I can't stand
much more of this.
I wish you had a religion, Peter.
No, thanks.
Not me.
I don't mean
you have to be Orthodox...
or believe in heaven and hell
and purgatory and things.
I just mean some religion.
It doesn't matter what.
Just to believe in something.
When I think of
all that's out there,
the trees and flowers...
and those seagulls-
When I think of
the dearness of you, Peter...
and the goodness
of the people we know-
Mr. Kraler and Miep,
the vegetable man-
all of them risking their lives
for us every day-
When I think of these good things,
I'm not afraid anymore.
I find myself...
in God, and I-
That's-
That's fine, but-
When I begin to think, well,
I get mad.
Look at us.
Hiding out here
for two years.
Not able to move.
Caught like-
Waiting for them
to come and get us.
We're not the only people
that have had to suffer.
There have always been
people that have had to.
Sometimes one race,
sometimes another, and yet-
That doesn't
make me feel any better.
I know it's terrible,
trying to have any faith...
when people are doing
such horrible-
But you know what
I sometimes think?
I think the world may be
going through a phase,
the way I was with Mother.
It'll pass.
Maybe not
for hundreds of years,
but someday.
I still believe,
in spite of everything,
that people are
really good at heart.
I want to see something now,
not a thousand years from now.
But, Peter,
if you’d only look at it
as part of a great pattern,
that we're just
a little minute in life.
Listen to us, going at each other
like a couple of stupid grown-ups.
Look at the sky.
Isn't it lovely?
Someday,
when we get outside again,
I'm going to-
For the past two years
we have lived in fear.
Now we can live in hope.
And so it seems our stay here is over.
They've given us just a moment
to get our things.
We can each take a bag...
and whatever it will hold
of clothing.
Nothing else.
So, dear... Diary,
that means
I must leave you behind.
Good-bye for a while.
P.S.
Please, please, anyone,
if you should find this diary,
will you please
keep it safe for me,
because someday I hope that-
No more.
I had gone to the country
to try to find food.
When I got back,
the police were in the building.
We made it our business
to learn how they knew.
It was the thief
who told them.
We know the thief.
He was-
It seems strange to me now,
but we were all so full of hope
in the camp here in Holland
where they first took us.
The news of the war was good.
The British and Americans
were sweeping through France.
We felt sure they would
get to us in time to-
But...
in September
we were shipped to Poland.
The men to one camp,
the women to another.
From there...
they were sent to Belsen.
I stayed in Auschwitz.
In January we were freed,
the few of us who were left.
The war was not yet over, no.
It took us a long time
to get home.
Each time the train
would stop, we'd...
all get out, you know,
at a siding or a crossing, and...
walk from group to group.
"Where were you?"
"Were you at Belsen?"
"At Buchenwald?"
"At Mauthausen? Where?"
"Is it possible that
you ever knew my wife?"
"Did you ever see
my husband, my son,
my daughter?"
That's how I found out
about my wife's death,
Margot's, Van Daans',
Peter, Dussel.
But...
Anne-
I still hoped-
Yesterday I was in Rotterdam.
I met a woman there.
She'd been in Belsen...
with Anne.
I know now.
In spite of everything,
I still believe that people
are really good at heart.
She puts me to shame.