Blair General Hospital emergency
I'm Paul Michigan yes mr. messenger dr.
Carew's expecting you use the first
elevator thank you say he'd up the Wall.
Street guy the bozo with all the dough
in the world you know he didn't even
have on a diamond ring no diamonds on
men are Faulker I wish I was found her
- before we go in mr. Mason's and let me
- prepare you dr. Gillespie is an.
Inspiration to the whole medical
profession but physically he's worse off
than most of his patients his legs are
hopelessly crippled I'll take care of a
doctor crew right away I want to be with
you oh I want to see dr. Gillespie I'm
sorry dr. Carew he has a patient well
that I will wait is the pamphlet dr.
Gillespie
mrs. Roberts you're going to have a baby
why what's the matter I'm afraid afraid
yes why women die I suppose your mother
felt that way about it
my mother had courage I'm a card mrs.
Roberts nature is a very wonderful thing
it takes the food you eat and changes it
into the particular substances our body
needs if we break a bone my nature will
provide the extra calcium to mend that
bowl if anything it would be stronger
than it was before
we you understand that don't you Yes.
Doctor well now that's just what's going
to happen when you have your baby
nature will see that you have the
strength and courage you need come on
over here to the window you see all
those people down there those thousands
of them yes all the mothers of every one
of those children felt exactly the same
way you do and so did their mothers and
those generations really has something
to worry about because we doctors hadn't
progressed very far that they were in
real danger maybe it sounds silly to you
this horrible worry but I couldn't help
it my husband's worried - well you warn
home and tell your husband's you're
going to be all right
with modern methods we seldom lose a
mother and we've no case on record where
we've ever lost a father thank you
doctor
I feel so much better sure you do you
take this pamphlet follow the
instructions take good care of yourself
you come back here and see me anytime
you want to what's your first name dr.
lemon minute Leonard
it's nice goodbye my oh my middle name
is Barry thank you know Conover I won't
let you have another nickel aren't you
ashamed of yourself an intelligent adult
like you gambling your wages away week
after week but someday I'm gonna win it
all back well in the meanwhile I'll find
another SAP to borrow it from someday
I'm going to sit down and prove to you
you can't win money in a crap game get
out yes sir I guess maybe you is right
sir I've often thought I'd give up
gammon and just take the plane to races
nice yes dr. Gillespie got your car
washed never mind dr. Carew
where's dr. Kildare I don't know isn't
he here if he was here do you think I'd
be asking you about him I don't know I
work for you for so long nothing you'd
say would surprise me
nurse Parker dr. Kildare is my assistant
he's here every morning promptly at 8
o'clock it's now 6 minutes past 9:00 and
no dr. Kildare what do you deduce from
these facts I guess dr. Kildare is late.
Oh
jumping Jehoshaphat where'd you find dr.
Kildare
where shall I know well where do you
think he'd be I don't know you keep your
stethoscope in the wastebasket and your
checkbook in the bathroom how should I
know where to look for your assistant
dr. Carew if dr. Carew wants anything
out of me tell him to come down here and
ask me oh he's here oh well show him in
shower man why didn't you say so doctor
dr. Carew aah Carew come in come in must
be something very important it brings
the head of the hospital here Elena this
is mr. Paul messenger Paul messenger do
you mean to tell me I'm actually in the
presence of how many millions of
hours Linnet I'll make it 18 million a
sucker where you getting in what can I
do for you mister hmm dr. Gillespie I've
come here because I need your help
well that's very fine but did you know
this a room full of patients waiting at
my door yes I've only one rule first
come first serve rich born in the middle
mean that fucking left is quite right
I'm sorry I'll take my turn oh wait a
- minute ready might be three hours I'll
- wait.
Linden mr. Missings is a very important
man so my let him wait
this sending the next patient no all the
way to hold the next patient come in
hold the next patient
I think I'll grab by five minutes sleep
fix the alarm clock will you remind you
I said five minutes send the next
patient in sooner you hear the alarm
nine minutes past nine that's a nice
round time to come to work I thought you
were asleep
my never sleep seems I can't say as much
for you I guess it's the country boy in
me now listen son
there's my assistance you naturally have
- certain privileges around here but
- sleeping till noon is not one of them.
Dr. Kildare
well nosy what do you want dr. Kildare's
breakfast is here breakfast I didn't
order any breakfast I did you worked
here all night and I figured you need it
what's the idea Jimmy getting those
pneumonia statistics hey John
all them well it's very plain you're
trying to make it more and more
difficult for me to get along without
you trying to make it impossible you
have made impossible yet there's so much
work to do and so little time to do it
thank you
well you know doctor when I finished
medical school I only knew that I wanted
to do something in medicine and I met
you and everything was crystallized now
I have what I wanted the privilege of
working for you and learning it
firsthand when only you can teach me and
carrying my work on after I'm gone I
won't be for a long while yet that's not
true you know it this next patient
please
ah mr. Fitch tada
Jimmy have they told you yet who's
outside they're waiting to see me no sir
what's irregular back mr. Poor messenger
the United States Mint in person is
outside they're waiting to see me Tom
and he's going to wait three hours Tom
my pleasure 172 over a hundred going put
your shirt on no no no no no no wait a
minute I want to talk to you see we
don't want to let him get off the hook
nice mr. messenger still out there he's
still there doctor hello that's fine
mr. Finch you've been drinking again it
seems to me I remember promise you made
me a couple of months ago doctor I tried
to stop but I can't do it it's not my
fault my father was the same way you
understand don't you say no I don't
you're a fool and there are a million
other fools like here they wanted a
drink so they believed a legend started
by a bigger fool that you can inherit
drunkenness well that's a lot of baloney
you can inherit a tendency toward
diabetes or red hair but if you drink
it's your own fault and you can't blame
your poor ancestors but I always heard
yeah and you were glad to hear it
because it gave you an excuse for
sticking a bottle in your silly face now
go on and get out of here and don't come
back until you stop kidding yourself
yes next patient no bring in mr. Mason.
Yes Doctor
mr. Messenger don't mean mr. Messenger
come in come in hey sit down mr.
Messenger sit down this is dr. Kildare
my assistant how'd you do it beautiful
there I'll still a lot of people ahead
of me doctor ah there's not one of them
I can charge as much as I'm going to
charge you max fair enough if you can
help me well you look well enough but I
can find something wrong with you
worst comes to the worst we can
always take out your appendix what can
we do for you mr. messenger well I came
here to ask your advice about my
daughter Nancy oh that's easy enough
just bring her in we'll have a look at
her I've tried to worked for six months
to see a doctor
not only two kinds of people don't want
to see doctors those that know their
well and those that know their not
something's happened to her it doesn't
seem to be physical and yet it must be
because you can't possibly have a care
in the world what you mean is that in a
thousand and one baffling little ways
your daughter's changed that's it that's
exactly the situation just what kind of
changes mr. Messinger well she always
was fond of dancing but now she wants to
go out all night every night oh it
doesn't mean a thing they call him
jitter birds jitterbug he's dr.
Gillespie she's engaged to a splendid
young man who adores her and all of a
sudden she started to dream abominably
what perhaps it isn't important but when
she sleeps she keeps the lights burning
ah that's bad but there's not a thing in
the world a doctor can do for your
daughter if she won't see him mr.
Messinger you were just about my last
hope I'm going to let you have dr.
Kildare Jimmy tonight you disguise
yourself as a potted palm or something
and find out what's the matter with Miss.
Messinger if it takes all night
it takes a dozen witness or a hundred
excuse me the expense is important oh
but a thousand lives a month are
important tomorrow dr. Kildare and I are
starting out on a long-planned
experiment this is sofa Pyrrha Dean
before it was discovered the death rate
of pneumonia was 25 percent so for.
Pyrrha Dean's brought it down to seven
my wife's bamboo is 25% well tomorrow
dr. Kildare and I are going to start
trying to find out why those seven
- percent still that I understand I sent
- my topper late o'clock goodbye goodbye.
Sir
thank you both hmm.
Kildare oh sorry sorry
I was thinking yes I know what you were
thinking you were thinking now tonight I
can't go out gallivanting with that
pretty nurse Mary Lamont gallivanting
you know how much gallivanting I can do
on my salary I read in the paper the
other day this doctor in Europe who
claims love is a disease and that he can
vaccinate you against it interns on $20
a month won't need any of that
vaccinations Leonard Gillespie you've
done a lot of crazy things in your life
but this time you've certainly Oh what
are you stalling around here for go eat
your breakfast what do you mean busting
in on me like that you can't have
anything confidential to tell me I know
everything that everybody's doing in
this shooting gallery especially the
things they're trying to hide then you
have a lot of Stooges telling you things
ah are you well let me tell you
something nice to just know every move
your Stooges make my students are people
of honor which is more than you can say
for that bunch of loafers that report to
you you bought an airplane for 20 years
we work together and now you start
spying on me what in the name of common
sense you gonna do with an airplane oh I
just thought it'd be nice to have in
case of fire oh come here Molly
I only borrow the plane it's the fly
Jimmy Kildare back and forth while we're
trying to work out this sofa pirating
business well at least there's one
blessing you're not planning to do that
part of the work yourself
Leonard huh you're tired aren't you oh
why don't you take a nap right now well
just to get rid of you I'll grab five
minutes sleep now yeah fix the clock
calm
dr. Jung wanted in surgery dr. Jung
wanted in surgery dr. Jung wanted in
surgery dr. Jeong alright come on fellas
where's my hat hat yeah quit clowning
why did you put it have you a picture
the head dr. Kildare well is there a
head our records show no entry the Hat
in this hospital where's my hat dude was
never x-rayed
I was wrong with your head dr. kildare
didn't even operation say why don't you
try the maternity ward maybe it's gonna
have a little baby head oh you last one
so don't blame me um dr. Joyner uh who's
working in this hospital a very
beautiful young nurse named Miss Lopez
she has the big brown eyes she wears a
uniform just a little tighter than all
the other nurses well sir the other day
I was up on the fourth floor and I just
happened to pass that little room where
they keep the flowers you know Oh what
do you think I saw now wait a minute
shut up here's your blame head sit wait
a minute don't hold off on us what was
he doing with Miss Lopez oh well miss
Lopez was alone I can't help it a doctor
Jonah has a guilty conscience money
money money money.
Thanks there is a half months our temper.
Holland's HS grammar school four years
high school two years pre-med four years
medical school then if you're lucky you
get a job here as an intern every single
month they forced 20 bucks on oh that
doesn't stop till there he still rushes
Mary Lamont he's in love with her money
after all you know she's a nurse she
makes 85 bucks a month ah a gigolo
dr. Kildare why did that emergency
address right away doctor says you're
not off well that's what he thought but
dr. Glasgow changed his mind for him
look look if you've got to work tonight
why can't I take out Mary Lamont well I
don't know why but I'll bet you can
think of a reason Blair General Hospital
no mister I can't tell you that I'm just
the telephone operator here of course I
work in a hospital but I don't
understand medicine my brother's been
managing a chicken farm for ten years
but he still can't lay an egg have you
seen Mary Lamont
she said for you to pick her up at 41st.
Street and Gaylor Avenue mr. quill
they're here yet if you want me to ride
around the block again Oh coming
where did he get that boss it's the
first prize and a mind your own business
contest
there she is on the corner yes sir.
Oh cutie
are you and the blue hat how about a
little ride sugar listen you have fake
street corner Romeo what I am it is time
to take a ride Oh Jimmy oh I'm sorry I
didn't recognize you I thought I saw a
pretty girl I was trying to grab her oh
sure grab her I'll brush it at the
hospital take out a dumpling yeah step
in and find out different just a minute
young man
what do you think you're trying to get
away with picking up girls on my beat oh
I wasn't picking up any go tell me I
heard every word you said can I ever
meet my boyfriend without you sticking
your nose in besides how do we know
you're an officer well because uh I'll
fight it out among yourself
get inside before anything else happened
well I suppose the car out of slay me
but I bet it belongs to one of.
Gillespie's rich patients I de Barros
yard only it wasn't raining oh I'm
awfully sorry I have to work tonight
Mary
that's all right Jimmy I guess there's
nothing we can do about it yeah yes you
know there isn't I'm sick of being a
nurse the next time I'm born I want to
be a pretty thing with an empty head and
a cash register for a heart you can
always quit the hospital can't you
why don't I I don't know I guess because
you're crazy enough to want to be a
nurse you're a little crazy yourself you
know I know it isn't ethical to ask a
doctor about these patients but where
are you going well it isn't ethical but
I can tell you this it's fifty three
blocks to the home of the gent that owns
this car here we are
sure that's fifty three blocks I've ever
seen Hey hmm well in case you're not
impressed they tell me that Paul.
Messenger is the seventh richest man in
America Jimmy and he's your patient
no not mr. Messinger his daughter his
daughter uh the one that's in the
newspapers all the time the glamour girl
I guess so what's the matter with it
that's why I'm trying to find out good
night Mary I'll wait oh I don't know how
long I'll be what my evenings ruined
anyway I might as well wait what that
- might take hours you weren't going to
- operate on the girl are you he doesn't.
Even know I'm a doctor
say what is this what I think as a
matter of fact dr. Gillespie said to
find out what was wrong with her if it
took all night all night yes well it's
all right because her father knows I'm
going to work on oh my father knows yes
you see she's been acting peculiarly of
late and mr. Messinger doesn't care what
lengths we go to as long as we fix her
up well I've had a lot about how
debutantes carry on but I've never heard
of one having her father's permission
now stop kidding me you must be
prejudiced against miss messenger that's
because she's rich
you mustn't be prejudiced just because
- she's young and beautiful Blair General
- Hospital please.
And although Nancy has been conducting
herself on the whole as I outlined to
you in dr. Gillespie to my amazement at
dinner tonight
she was our own normal sweet self
panting yeah come in dad you're just in
time to tell me how oh this is mr.
Kildare that son of an old friend of
mine how do you do miss Messinger hello
mr. Kildare the corner party remember oh
but don't look at my costume now wait
till I get the headdress on you to go
downstairs and I'll make a grand
entrance
all right here you're the loveliest
thing I've ever seen just like your
mother yesterday she said she wouldn't
go to be stupid Casa de Spartan under
any circumstances it's waiting sing
don't shoot mr. Messenger it's me
Charlie is there any doubt in your mind
about my loving your daughter remember I
put this outfit on because she wanted me
to well once the love I went out as a
back half of a horse till there was the
hair of my daughter's fiance dr. Kildare
how do you do bye Nancy excuse me hello
Nancy you have to excuse me Charlie I'm
not going to the party you're not going
no no I don't want to go if I don't want
to go I don't have to go so I'm not
going getting a little tired of this
merry-go-round Nancy good night
he doesn't see more than six months ago
that you told me your entire life was
wrapped up in that boy I do love him you
see now what I don't know now I suppose
the lights be blazing all night in her
room and I'll be facing this floor
wondering how I can help
mr. Kildare you must think me a pretty
terrible sort of person
why no dead that's all right fancy well
as far as I'm concerned they're no
excuses necessary you're very kind
why not at all you don't want to do a
thing and you don't have to why should
you them's my sentiments anyway
of course only sometimes it's a little
hard to explain
then why try you know back home in my
father's office there's a motto hanging
that says never explain your friends
don't need it and your enemies won't
believe you anyway do you get away with
it well I seem to at least I never make
a date in advance I didn't even tell
your father I was coming here this
evening
simply because I might have suddenly
wanted to change my mind and go out and
come home with the milkman you see Dad I
know exactly how you feel
by the way what kind of a milkman do you
have on this block very charming
gentleman well done why can't I meet him
wait right here I'll slide into a dress
remember dad it was his idea you brought
him here I see what your plan is doctor
but haven't you been able to arrive in
the immediate conclusions only the
obvious ones she does love Heron she's
heartbroken of what she's doing to you
she's doing her best to seem perfectly
normal but mr. messenger this is a very
delicate point but I must know did your
daughter ever have any reason to hate
her mother hate a mother nothing further
from the truth why do you ask no reason
well remember this part is on me
sunrise why did you want to bring me up
here oh it's just we've had an exciting
night and I thought perhaps you like to
see the daylight come do you watch very
often yes yes wouldn't it be a wonderful
world of who were always daylight I've
thought of that it's funny how the night
affects some people me for instance I
don't like it grown men fade of the dog
what
I'm not afraid exactly it's just that Oh
a night falls something happens to me
yes yes look you're going to stay in New.
York will you come to see me if you want
me to we've been out since 9 o'clock
last evening you've never once docked at
your watch you may not know it but you
get along with me better than anyone I
know anyone accepting mr. Charles heron
there's no one on earth with Charlie
heron oh I could see you felt that way
about it when's the wedding I'm tired
just took me home cool uh what did you
find out about Miss messenger only that
she's a very complicated case maybe
weeks before we got the answer I told
you that yesterday without even seeing
it I don't suppose you found time this
morning to read the weather reports no
sir
well that cold pull away we've been
waiting for is reached Canada and then
this wake will come ammonia thousands of
cases you're going to fly north tonight
to meet it
then you'll check all the cases where
ever you happened to find them and then
you'll hop in a plane and bring me back
the blood cultures while I'll be camping
right here day and night doing the
laboratory work and then Jimmy maybe in
a couple of months we'll find out why
that 7% still dies
upon me sir dude don't you think we
ought to rest a few days before we go on
rest that what do we want with rest yes
Parker come in here pneumonia it strikes
so quick we work so slow why we ought to
be ashamed of ourselves this is a
twentieth century we ought to be able to
cure anything yet we let this white
death's invisible killer run riot though
we were still living in the dark ages
get me a hypo of adrenaline quick let me
bless you have a bone to pick with you
and you stay your inlet well what
happened tell me quick faded get outside
of their exit nothing's happening give
me that adrenaline adrenaline yes no you
can't burn the candle at both ends the
balls back right after this it's less
exhaustion that's up it's not all and if
you don't know what I mean it's time you
did know - I know everything about him
when you were running around diapers I
was watching over him listening to him
recommend to eight hours of sleep for
everyone else and get along with to
himself his legs were good once but they
were out trying to keep out with his
willpower
he had resistance he loaned it to his
patients and never got it back now his
time is getting short I didn't think
he'd want anyone else to know the first
day I came here he asked me about a
discoloration on his finger kept
hounding me until I said it was a
melanoma and meant cancer and why didn't
you keep him from starting this self up
I retain business me tell him what not
to do
what's going on here you gave me a hypo
dinger yes sir
adrenaline good now what are you fussing
around this black came in here looking
for trouble that only got here ahead of
me you go on back to your nurses not
till you quit talking and go to bed Oh
some for a doctor now huh when did you
start practicing you did Paul dr. Cruz.
Carew sure he's the best doctor his
bowling alley that's the reason he's
head man you have me skipping rope five
minutes that's accrue this is Kildare
dr. Gillespie has just had a slight
collapse he wants you immediately
claps didn't have any collapse I got the
constitution of a horse I just get tired
once in a while actually even a horse
gets tired I'm gonna send your patients
home come back here I'm gonna send them
home when I see you skipping rope I'm
gonna run around town with a basket and
collect them again dr. Gillespie he no
one today everybody been notified about
new appointment yes miss Byrd 25 years
ago I took you out to dinner I might
have known that sooner or later you take
advantage of it and you shut up or I'll
tell dr. Kildare are you trying to put
your arm around me in the lunch wagon.
Lin I'm so sorry I look I've got a
couple of mourners here already
what I need is a doctor you listen to a
doctor
don't make me laugh well I've sent for
you didn't I I'll listen I passed out.
Kildare injected adrenaline I came to
Paul 78 general feeling of lassitude I
take it up from there stick to medicine
if you still remember and they canceled
dr. Gillespie's appointments for the
rest of the day already cancelled get
his bed ready and bring me a three
grains of sodium amytal Yes Doctor
I don't need any dope I can sleep
without but you won't I give you my word
of honor I don't believe you counting my
word I certainly am wait a minute listen
editing do justice will
now you take those and don't argue yes
doctor now go to bed
you're too late miss efficiency how
corner druggist here give me something
you're too good but that's fine that off
the bed you go take your handle of my
chair.
Conover I'll get out of here you're
meddling female and never dare to show
your nose in my office again you're
fired I am NOT I don't work for you I
work for the hospital thank goodness
fine what are you doing in my office
gone beat it get into bed cover karma
don't you pay any attention toss around
why you disloyal miserable
double-crossing yes sir that's what I am
but yous going to bed well I better get
my own work cleared up just in case oh
well by the way Kildare mr. messenger
rang me up this morning from his
daughter's mood he feels sure that with
a little time you might gain her
complete confidence dr. Carew I
understand
naturally you don't want to think about
anything else at the moment like this
force I don't have to tell you that any
hospital is like a family of children or
was out of the elbow winter coming on no
coal in the cellar mr. Messengers a very
rich man Tucker hey you're perfectly
right forget about it tonight we'll talk
about it later.
Kildare the old fussbudget gone what yes
but dr. Gillespie you hey do you know
something
patience will hold a pill in their
- mouths intellect you've gone and then
- spit it out the way I did promise Doctor.
Who that you'd go to sleep
oh forget it he broke a promise he made
me back in 1921 dr. Gillespie you and I
both know that there's one particular
reason one one inescapable reason why
you must conserve your strength
you didn't tell karuta you oh no no I
knew you had I know you won't
Jimmy Kildare out there pneumoniae
starting on the rampage tonight you're
going to hop plane well mosey what do
you want now Leslie are you all right a
full report of my mental and physical
condition will be made out for the files
I'll see that you get a copy yes doctor
dr. Kildare your mother and father are
downstairs in the reception room my
mother and father here yes doctor
well in that night give my best regards
be back at 3 o'clock Jimmy we'll need a
good solid six hours together if you're
going to go out tonight don't if there's.
Jimmy you needn't bother telling your
mother about flying I wrote to her all
about it last week oh I wrote - a - she
says yours as a very remarkable letter
she did mm-hmm
I was no trick to riding a good letter
and she even sent me the letter she got
me as the clothes fine coupon and three
dollars please send me one pair of your
loaded dice in a plain wrapper very
truly yours Leonard be callous be I must
put this letter in wrong on row.
Oh mother I'm a dad all right doing Oh
fine
gee this is a treat I knew I needed
something I now I know what it was
let me get a good look at you I brought
your heavy overcoat your winter
underwear and the chocolate king
don't let a kid you son the cake is for
herself oh don't tell me I know I said
I'll wire this morning happy birthday
mother well what are you two doing in.
New York anyway the strips to see the
fair and you it's my birthday present
from father and we wouldn't have been
able to make it if Jerry Coburn hadn't
sold his farm and paid for that baby had
1927 what about his ulcers did he ever
pay for those I don't know thought that
again zippy that's all I heard on the
way down here I'm a father buy a new
suit - she's getting stout where do we
celebrate how about Mike Sullivan's cafe
swell food fight across the street
this is Kildare the first time I saw
your son I knew his mother to be a
fine-looking woman well she's the
prettiest one I could find Mike that's
why I might why not a man goes into a
store to buy a shirt he picks the
- best-looking one when he wants a wife.
- What should he do shut his eyes they'd.
Better be careful Mike much more talk
like then you will spoil it but that's
the way it should be
say your prayers pay your bills be good
to your mother then you can walk up to
anybody in the world and spit in his eye
all right coming I take this over to the
bar I'd even say thank you well I
promised Jim Galt I'd buy him a sunlamp
he wants to try it free South Rytas I'll
see you very much LJ o'clock bye son bye.
Stephen if I might can I sir drop in
tomorrow for lunch it's Friday we have
three you a good kinds of fish and we
also have roast beef in case you bring a
hay than we get good bye honey
I was just going to invent an excuse to
get rid of your father why so you could
join your troubles huh no you should
follow me to try and keep anything from
you is it no I know the minute your
father enters the house if he's worried
by the way
up his head he's worried about something
now - how can you tell
mind-reading yo just love and
understanding now tell me your problem
if you want to oh right I have to keep
someone from doing something there just
isn't any way to do it you mean you
haven't seen the way yet nothing's
impossible some unless you stop trying
this is different because what this
person wants to do is something that
should be done it's been a good of the
whole world hmm
about a few men left like that now why
do you want to stop him because if he
keeps on it'll kill him I'm afraid I'm
not going to be much help to you I've
never had to decide big things with you
or your father I've always been able to
manage by talking a little plain good
horse sense except the one time I did
tell him a lie he'd been working in the
garden too much and I knew it was bad
for rheumatism but nothing could stop
him so I hid his tools and told him a
tramp stolen then stopped him well but I
there wait a minute you took away his
tool yes well I think you shown me just
what to do oh right that isn't a big
problem I've always taught you right
from wrong but the power of prayer and
the back of the hairbrush
what if I do what I think I should I'm
going to look like a snake in the grass.
Jimmy it's dr. Gillespie have been
talking about isn't it well uh yes yes
he's in bad shape
on this particular job he's doing I'm
pretty sure I can't go ahead without me
I see and if you quit email have to take
the rest but some wouldn't it almost
break your heart to leave him
it means the finish of all I've hoped
and dreamed god bless you don't feel too
badly son you may be the only one that
knows you're doing the right thing
listen off nicely yes it doesn't matter
what the rest of the world thinks if I
were you I wouldn't read any more
why are you or keep my mouth shut
lemon please oh maybe I don't feel so
good
your nurse will be here in a minute
nurse now look here mommy bird I won't
have any of your frozen faced
mealy-mouthed asses around me who'd you
get Mary Lamont and there's no use
trying to salt Sophie because I told her
exactly what to do oh you see Burt oh
honey I had a heck of a time getting you
assigned to me and Miss birdy I wanted
to send in one of her favorites right
sold her unless I had that very
beautiful Mary Lamont I'll I wouldn't
play deny you did not and don't forget.
Lamont in his office he may be a doctor
but here he's a patient Leonard please
take care of yourself goodbye.
I'd like cigarette please
nevermind that job give me a cigarette
no cigarettes are you going to mind me
or that fool piece of paper no
cigarettes I look here Mary you're a
very nice girl and I like you I'm gonna
give you a little advice
the great secret to being a successful
nurses to pay the rules but at the same
time keep the patient happy my book only
says obey the rule period what do you
want to know about me I'll tell you it's
time for your dinner let's see ah why
are you talking ordered me a small steak
some mashed potatoes and piece of apple
pie and some cheese and a cup of coffee
hello I'm ordering dr. Gillespie's
dinner please send up a small cup of
gruel some junket wheat tea no cream of
sugar
thank you that's fine and after dinner
you might order me a postage stamp I'd
like to do a little reading what do you
expect to do with that thing I'm going
to take your temperature any time to
just take around here I'll take him
what are you laughing at something you
said last week there's no patient in the
world as ornery as the sick doctor and
if there's going to be any talking done
around here I'll do it myself
well I'm not interested what about Jimmy.
Kildare might have expected that 98
write it down
so what are you writing there
temperature uncertain patience stubborn
bad-tempered and childish what about
Jimmy Kildare but you should have heard
him talk this morning he was spending a
multi millionaires money last night a
steak sandwich two bucks
and what does Jimmy think boom there
goes a couple of shirts $5.00 - the way
to bang a new pair of shoes
will the orchestra leader please play
but will predict for Miss Nancy
messenger give him $20 Jimmy
wham shooter flow with an extra pair of
pants throwing all that money around
last night and next morning coming back
to $20 a month after all everybody's
human however would it you're right
you're not the way you treat Jimmy I
mean dr. Kildare taking away his
evenings off and working in 18 hours a
day where I work 18 hours a day oh I'm
sorry dr. Gillespie I shouldn't be
talking to you like this when you're not
feeling very well
hello mother.
Oh did you get the Sun lamp no they
didn't have exactly what I wanted Jimmy
looks fine doesn't he yes I've never
seen him look any better Stephen when
you suggested coming down here I felt
there was something the matter with
Jimmy oh he was in some kind of trouble
that you two were keeping it from me you
know don't tell mother she might worry
no nothing like that at all I know that
now well do you feel better no because
now I know it's you me you've been
unhappy for days if it doesn't Jimmy it
- must be you why don't you tell me you're
- going to in the end anyway.
From dr. Jack's cowboy just the last
paragraph the rest is all technical
I think it's coronary disease and dear
Steve it's a very unpleasant duty to
tell you but I think you may live 10
seconds or 10 years come and see me and
we'll talk over the details he says 10
seconds or maybe 10 years Oh Steve now
mother I'm going to see another doctor
that's why we came to New York but we
mustn't tell Jimmy Martha we've been
married a long long time when every day
has been a happy one I'd hoped that it
might go on for 20 years me you're not
going to be foolish enough to tell me
that you don't mind dying but we can
think of some philosophy that'll make it
easier for either of us
no dear I just wanted to say that
medicine might not do any good but we
know that tears will but there is one
thing left the same help and comfort we
got the night that Jimmy had typhoid
fever
we waited not knowing you remember I
remember he marks the sparrows fall.
Stephen I'm going to take it for every
heart specialist that's listed in the.
New York telephone book I know he marks
the sparrows fall but I remember too
that the Lord helps those who help
themselves
yes you send him in good morning till
their morning sir dr. Carew what have
you done about the messenger case
nothing nothing's wrong I'd like to take
it you would yes sir I think it's too
big an opportunity to miss oh but that's
dr. Gillespie no no no not yet
well night I guess it ate to take you
away from him without his knowledge and
permission uh dr. Carew I have made up
my mind if necessary I'll handed my
resignation oh no no no no I'm assigning
dr. Kildare everything the messenger
case makeup northern I'll sign it Oh dr.
Carew please I'd rather tell dr.
Gillespie myself than have them learn it
through an official order oh yes yes oh
cool don't put through that order about
dr. Koo there until I let you know this
is all very fortuitous solving the
messenger case will be a priceless asset
to you when you're ready to go out into
private practice and of course it won't
do the hospital any harm
taking that all into consideration
what's the latest report on dr.
Gillespie there it is haven't you seen
him no nurse Molly Byrd asked me not to
go in we're not very happy about his
condition and see that wait outside Mary
I don't want you to hear what I got to
say to the head of your hospital what's
this I hear about you taking Kildare
away from me and putting him on the
messenger case why who told you who I
knew about it before the echo of your
voice giving the order died away what
have you been saying to my boy
I've told you 10,000 times to run your
hospital and let my office alone
there wasn't anything he said sir I made
up my own mind and that's absolutely
true Lynne get out of here
are you crazy you know I can't go along
with our work alone I'm sorry sir
for Jimmy
you're tired we take the day off go out
and get some relaxation you will feel
differently about it tomorrow no
messengers too big a chance to give up I
don't see any reason why I should go on
working 24 hours a day on something that
won't pay me a cent one when I can get
in with one of the richest men in New.
York
so dr. Kildare mr. Messinger waves a
checkbook in your face and you drop me
like a hot potato I've waited 20 years
for an assistant and I find I picked a
common little money-grubber
why did you want to study medicine for
you'd have made a swell pawnbroker Mary
take me backward I'm tired here's your
fishing rod doctor fishing rod where'd I
get it fishing rod remember that fella
that we killed the one that had the
misery in his back he gave us this what
are you bringing about I'm Jake I have
to go away I mean I'm glad you're sick
enough to be well enough to go I mean if
you're getting some sleep it'll give you
- some well this is a fish basket take it
- with you isn't mine oh yes it is I meant.
To give it you for a Christmas present
last year but it forgot all about it.
Molly you're lying you can't prove it
this is nice to keep hot coffee in
where's that come from
Ted the hospital's name on it but I
scratched it off okay well under those
circumstances I don't take it well for
years I've known you had Stooges
reporting to you but there's the first
I've heard you have them stealing for
you miss Lamont write this into your
report my patient was feeling fine until
15 or 20 chattering females dissented on
goodbye quick I guess I can take a hint
I'll see you before you leave tonight.
Leonard are we at the Train doctor
should I go help dr. Kildare pack his
things sir none of that.
No.
The idea after all you've done for him
leaving you for a hypochondriac
debutante with blond hair and lots of
money uh uh another County heard from
what do you mean I forgot about the time
we were worried about Jimmy and a
redhead you've been in love with him
ever since that's not true oh let's stop
kidding ourselves
we're both sunk so that's the reason as
soon as I got to New York I telephoned
your father you're lunching with a
washer yeah I'll see you later of course
we have a date for a walk heaven right
- right dad if Jimmy's late you charge it
- to my account I will not I'll take it.
Out with your allowance
come in Jimmy about I know nothing
definite yet human behavior especially
unexpected behavior is very often the
outcome of some fixation in childhood
while you're driving it or some instinct
and I can't rationalize it keeps
bringing me back to Nancy's mother don't
you know anything with 12 years ago
there was never any divorce
mrs. Messinger and I had separated for
several years you have no direct
information of your wife and daughter
during those years no I was in Europe
mrs. Messinger died of pneumonia hmm yes
she been here for some time with a
complication of ailments but the end
came through pneumonia where that long
island plays out yes burry you
understand that at the time I got back
to this country it was all over funeral
everything I had middle east pretty
since his Nancy ever visit the Long.
Island home I imagine so is he mrs.
Messinger requested that Nancy's nurse
should occupied as long as he lived.
Nancy's nurse here's a woman named Nora
I'd like to talk to this Nora I can
easily managed our telephone no no let
me see if I can't arrange to meet Nora
without anyone even Nancy suspecting
anything
didn't this much nicer than a walk in
the park oh of course but you certainly
changed your mind fast oh it wasn't
merely a whim when I got out of my
shower there was a phone message calling
me to Long Island so here we are there's
a half Nora my little lamb no this is
mr. Kildare pleased to meet you sir
howdy-do we're coming in come in well
now let me take your things
oh this is the nicest surprise I've had
since the last time you came surprised
Nora what was your message about me what
message I didn't send you any message
was that funny
what did the message say said to come to.
Long Island immediately but maybe they
took the message wrong unless the
service when I get home
well old fella what hair what's wrong
with you poor things been living around
here for a week oh I'll feed you I'm a
bad shoulder there found out quick
enough I just happen to hit the sore
spot looks to me like you're asking
questions with your fingers the way
doctors do oh what's wrong with doctors
no huh what's right with them Nora they
stood behind that your mother died right
before your eyes didn't they Nora please
I'm sorry darling what's the matter
auntie it's one of those headaches again
headaches how long have you been having
headaches I don't know four months Nancy
we keep on tearing herself apart with
these headaches a once and for all are
you going to see him I don't know hidden
who's him Nora a doctor oh no he's too
good to be a doctor he cures people
instead of letting him die
friend of yours Nora huh mr. Archie is a
friend of everybody who believes in him
Nancy you must see him now today when
the blindness comes
even he can't help you know if you don't
Nancy Nancy why not do as Nora says Oh
what's the use
nobody can help me oh please Nancy I'll
go with you just come and talk I don't
know who the man is or what he can do
but every day miracles happen that no
one can explain anyone as young as you
miss messenger is not meant to suffer
pain but you do don't you
violent headaches I can see that mister
archly miss messenger has just had a
very severe attack don't you think she
should lie down and rest a while before
you proceed yes yes an excellent idea
nor will you take her place in here my
dear was your idea in doing that you see
I know that Nora's told you all about.
Miss messenger which is of course what
she should have done we're all only
concerned with making fancy well again
of course of course just what is your
connection with the case mr. Kildare
listen it enough that I induced her to
- come and see you after all Nora wasn't
- able to were she obviously I'm in your.
Debt
what's worrying you as an old friend of
the family I know more about Miss
messengers case the Nora Doe is that so
what for instance well six months ago
now revealed the Nancy the true cause of
her mother's death right suppose I tell
you no I was wrong wrong but the
mother's symptoms as Nora describes them
- to me sound very conclusive symptoms our
- headaches blindness why couldn't they.
Indicate a dozen different things
meningitis for instance meningitis fine
doctor you must understand I'm only
trying to help you then help Nancy FSP.
Oh leave Nancy has inherited her
mother's trouble we must be sure we're
on the right track mr. Kildare unless
you have some specific information I
must believe that periodic headaches
plus muscular imbalance
plus blindness can mean only one thing
muscular imbalance well though suppose
I'm wrong just how do you propose to
treat miss messenger for this brain
children the first principle of my
treatment is to cleanse the mind with
- truth I then cure the body with natural
- methods and electro vibrations you are.
Not going to tell that girl she has a
brain tumor
of course it's essential to my course of
treatment but you mustn't tell you've
excuse me now mr. Kildare I must attend
by patient look here art say that girl's
half out of her mind with fear already
nothing more than her own suspicions to
frighten her but she doesn't know that.
Norris told you the whole story
so if you diagnose her trouble as brain
tumor she's she's like lose her mind
entirely I don't agree
dr. Kildare oh yes you're a doctor
well I don't have to be a doctor to see
what your game is you're going to tell
her she has a tumor knowing full well
that she hasn't so that you can pretend
to cure something that doesn't exist
well I'm sorry but I'm not going to let
you tell her anything like that
Nora miss Messinger I'm convinced I can
bring you back to perfect health but dr.
Kildare here seems to think differently
doctor it's true Nancy sorry I'd learn
it this way there's no use keeping you a
secret any longer I'm a doctor you Jimmy
you a doctor
enough of a doctor to know that you're
not going blind and you're not going to
die because you don't have a brain do
Nancy I'm a pretty good doctor and every
instinct I have tells me there's nothing
wrong with you nothing but grief and
fear and brooding imagination since
you're a doctor you often be the one to
drive as poor child stark raving crazy
did you mean that hasn't she got any
tumor
now you need a little rest here hello.
Nancy will you leave us alone please
but you can't Nora please sorry to
follow you here Nancy but I had to get
things settled some wood you realize of
course you haven't let me see you for a
week although I've called it the house
at least everyday situations very
obvious Nancy just don't love me anymore
you're too nice to tell me so I realize
now that it's up to me to make it easier
for you
finance never see me again I'll never
see him again
emergency call Blair General Hospital.
New York City Oh dr. Kildare no Joe.
Wayman not on duty tonight
he finally promised to buy me dinner and
he didn't seem feverish when he said it
either hey did you say go to the doctor
here he is hello doc this is Joe Oh Joe
Joe I'm in a spot and I need action I
want you to bring me an ophthalmoscope
and a perimeter out to Long Island right
away yeah I'll grab the first bus I'm on
the way I didn't have anything important
to do tonight anyway where are you okay
doc
I'm sorry about that dinner tonight.
Sally my sister must be wrong other
girls get diamond bracelets and I can't
even come out a cheese sandwich the bus
is usually right on time here
underdog take it easy brother you got 25
minutes yet
there's the bus schedule fire hope it's
my house just made the insurance
yesterday 21 miles in 19 and a half
minutes I don't made it sooner only it
makes me nervous to go fast how'd you
get the ambulance hop you're my pal you
said you're in a hurry and the gadgets
are in the back let's get going
no I go away doctor I have to see her
you're not going to but she has no brain
tumor I'm positive she hasn't I can only
see you in examiner eyes I know I can
convince it you've done enough harm
already or are you much let me see Adam
well baby the moment we got that phone
call I knew I'd be needing you I'm gonna
excuse me a minute doc I want to take a
look at that back tire
hey doc doc how do you like that these
yokels don't fight fair this guy tried
to pull a hammer on me Nancy Nancy look
I know how you feel about me but I want
to help you I'm sure you don't have
brain tumor I'm positive we can
straighten everything all out
oh please Nancy please look at me Jimmy
I can't see you I can't see anything
Jimmy
on earth you realize that every year
millions of men abandon their sweetheart
wine family just ago fitting in excuses
better than none where they got this
show for this thrown back in to under
others you'd have them do unto you
amen fish don't grieve man you call this
a vacation kind of it I wish it wouldn't
move that umbrella so the Sun it's my
net through that hole son do you good
violet ray Oh violet applesauce too
doggone healthy now if you hadn't come
on this year vacation it's cheating one
right now I'd be walking slow behind you
why I'll bet you Conover betting is
gambling and gambling is illegal
furthermore it's foolish because you
can't win I've had it in my mind to
teach you something about gambling for
some time now out of the dim past I seem
to remember that if you get a seven or
an eleven you win.
Yes Doctor and if you get a two three or
twelve you lose I'll roll you for a
dollar eighty lucky seven you win
but let me breathe on them once filled
up gone breathe away I don't know how
much money you got on you
ah scan for dollars four dollars huh
snake I've I'll win double sixes
I'll win how much money - you owe me now
doctor
twenty-two dollars now that show you are
the fool a man is to gamble those dice I
brought with me a crooked still I
couldn't win
no doctor hears you dice I switched on
you will I be them
there's a man walking towards probably
somebody from the hospital
tell him I'm asleep how did that kill
there Oh count of it huh may I speak to
you for a moment after you left me
can't you see I'm asleep I I hate to be
a nuisance servant while I'm at the end
of my rope
so you're on here so hmm well it's about
the messenger girl she's in the hospital
she's totally blind blind dr. Gillespie
miss messengers optic nerve seems
entirely non there's no sign of
deterioration by every test she should
be able to see but she's blind please
dr. Gillespie if you can't come back to
the hospital I'd like to bring her here
to see you know young dr. Kildare you
dug this pit for yourself get yourself
out of it goodbye
well when's the next train leaving New
York about a half an hour well what are
we waiting for my lecture today deals
with the type of human suffering that
invariably baffles a young doctor and
the great many old doctors as well this
is difficult to diagnose because it
conceals itself under the symptoms of
every known disease there was for
instance a woman totally bereft of
speech shrewd investigation finally
revealed that she called out to a little
daughter who running across the street
in answer had been struck down by a car
and killed the subconscious realization
that her own voice had called the child
to its death paralyzed the mother's
vocal chords even psychoanalysis failed
to effect a cure we were forced to
pretend to operate on her throat and by
this means convinced her that would
restore the speech surgically
everything. They dr. Kildare regards our
kindergarten has beneath his notice who
is it
dr. Kildare Nancy I found out what's
wrong with your eyes and I can cure you
it's been nothing but a simple little
myopic strain that always responds to a
minor operation always always next
patient I'm pretty sure I know what the
trouble is don't you tell me what the
trouble is I'll tell you what the
trouble is
but doctors going get in there in the
next room to take off your clothes I go
on don't round you when they get in
there
go on hit that next patient oh good
morning
sit down thank you
well I know you course you do
I'm Jimmy Kildare's mother a very
bullheaded young man well how are you I
suppose you've come to ask me to take
him back nothing of a sort why don't you
want him to be my assistant I want him
to be what he wants to be and when he
makes a mistake I want him to find out
why he made it so he won't do it again
suppose he failed I'm his mother I can't
even imagine it dr. Gillespie will you
examine my husband why was some animal.
I'll never be satisfied can you tell me
what you think I oh I'll wait till you
finish reading I'll go on talking I
can't stand people who can't do more
than one thing at a time
I don't want Jimmy to know anything
about this lucky no suppose I tell him
really ah I see well bring him in Monday
morning at 11 o'clock oh thank you very
much you're very kind
no no this way mrs. Povey I'm very sorry
about you and Jimmy your son is a
natural-born objector madam he doesn't
care which side of an argument he takes
as long as everybody else is on the
other side goodbye goodbye my just go
there hey you come on out now I'll
listen to you what's the matter with you
nothing at all
I never was sick a day in my life I just
come here to repair your telephone
I've already explained my belief that
one miss messenger experienced several
commonplace headaches nor written by
fanatic fears convinced the girl that
she had a brain tumor inherited from her
mother but now my conclusion is that the
factor which directly induced Nancy's
mysterious blindness was mr. Herons
words you will never see me again will
you come in now please I thought to go
there made it clear that this messenger
had been led to believe that an
operation has been performed on her for
a trivial eye ailment yes Nancy that's a
I'm going to take the bandage off you're
going to be able to see and you know as
I know that there isn't a single thing
wrong with you now how do good I'll do
everything only I can see what I'm so
sure of it that I've arranged a little
surprise for you surprise mm-hmm the
first thing you'll see will be yeah
Nancy Charlie Charlie now the room is
full assembly
Charlie Manson
thank God
fine work doctor they talk about Betty
to some other time do you think I'm I
going to see her doctor oh yes you're
good idea to knock first Oh dr. Kildare
dr. Gillespie would like to see you at
once you sent for me sir
I sent for a lot of unimportant people
you just happen to get here first well
huh dr. Gillespie but I'm knowing it
you've done me a very great service
you'll be happy to hear that
miss messenger I don't want to hear
anything about your diamond studded
millionaire patients I got a couple of
pretty good patients myself Barker
sending those patients you know the
funny thing is ever since you left here
everything's been running like clockwork
what patients those two people the man
and the woman you Nick wait oh why did
you say so
it fault I don't talk loud enough mother
okay what are you two doing so what's
the matter something wrong daddy you
will no giri a mother I have a right to
know we were worried about your father's
heart Jimmy oh why didn't you tell me
let me know it's all right now
dr. Gillespie they're trying to make me
think there's nothing serious yeah my
diplomas over there have a look at it
are you sure dr. Gillespie did you look
for any signs of thrombosis you little
weapon are you questioning my diagnosis
I beg your pardon sir I didn't mean oh
yes you did - ever since you started
your Park Avenue practice you don't
trust any doctor unless he wears a high
hat spats
I'm sorry sir you should have told me
well it was our worry until we had to
tell you Jimmy and stop fretting about
it it's all over now isn't it yes but
past two minutes I've been doing some
fast thinking about what my week off
next month how are you going to spend it
in the research clinic but now I'm
coming home and stay with you Oh like I
want to tell you how happy you've made
us say but I don't know what to say well
why don't you say something stupid you
usually do well Steven Lee gonna stand
around there gossiping with dr.
Gillespie all day huh it is a place for
sick people isn't it oh yes yes doctor I
said everything I could think I'm in
- there but I like say it again I'll write
- me letter about it see you later son.
What we're going to have to do together
on uh-huh
goodbye awesome now let's see who are
you oh yes I remember a Irish pawnbroker
named Kildare I'm still grateful for
what you've done for my father are you
still here well I just want a minute
more sir the messenger girl is cured
thanks indirectly to you to me yes and
to the happy coincidence that your
lecture gave me the clue happy
coincidence is that splendid the first
happy coincidence was that I happen to
come back from my vacation on that
particular day the second happy
coincidence was that I happened to
lecture for the first time in a year and
the third happy coincidence was that I
picked that particular subject happy
coincidence
why you stupid little tadpole I've been
leading you around like a pug dog on a
string oh I don't know don't know what
to say
well you said that before as regards the
messenger case even good doctors often
forget that fear is a tyrant over the
body as well as the mind people can
acquire the evil results of every
disease just through fear alone I had an
instinctive feeling about that case on
the beginning you should have been
positive young dr. Kildare there's
nothing new about it
why were you back in the Middle Ages
when the Black Plague killed half the
people in Europe there were thousands of
folks that died of the disease didn't
have it at all
I thought iris are smart yeah there's
only one really smart guy around here
that's me I know everything I'm
convinced too that yeah I know even more
than you think I do for instance I know
that you didn't quit your job with me on
account of poor messengers money what
now Jimmy you knew I'd have to stop and
take a rest if you walked out on me so
you walk out him I'll never forget that.
Jimmy
how did you find out who could have told
him Oh nobody told me I figured it out
for myself that is to say I figured it
out asteroid way angle around with your
mother for a while Mary Lamont come here
how did you know I was here I've got
next tie in the back of my head I heard
everything
Mary that's one of the things you'll
have to learn if you're going to be in
love with a doctor uh I've got to do
something none so blind as oh it won't
see that they excuse me I have something
to do too the only oven the night you've
got a date with an airplane and a bottle
of sulphur fire a Dean Wow don't let the
local doctors give you any guard I'll
try not to do anything wrong suppose we
do everything
someday some fellas smarter than we are
looking all over and say well thank
heaven I don't have to waste my time
- finding that out you'll find the real
- answer can you.
He'll get the real answer to pneumonia
that much sooner yes
I think uh my son
hey Lincoln poop look at what you do
around briella.
I show you... fill fine a few more you're
real quick I watch it to you all those
getting it right now
you