Keep an eye out...
-Okay.
Shmaya, where are you?
Is it over?
Can I go home?
Home?
You know what you have
to do first...
They’re moving him again.
I don’t know.
Maybe we shouId act...
or keep watching...
Watch your head...
Hurry...
Arnav!
What’s the damage?
You had two araks
and three cognacs?
The araks are on me
75 shekeIs.
-75?!
AIcohoI prices went up, Arnav.
We shouId start an action committee.
CRAP - The Committee for
Reduction of AIcohoI Prices.
I’m ten shekeIs short...
You’re kiIIing me CaviIio...
I spend aII my tips on you.
I end up Ieaving you a tip.
You’re a saint, Arnav. A saint.
BIess your souI.
-Good night. -Good night.
Check, pIease...
Coming
Makes me mad that peopIe here
feeI free to grab you.
This is a bar,
not a convent.
TabIe 4 wants
a Iast round of beer.
WiII do,
your hottie hoIiness.
Stop staring at me.
I’m serious about turning reIigious.
You were serious as
a punk rocker...
When you studied
Chinese medicine...
You’re so annoying.
I’m gonna start cIeaning up.
Wanna come over for coffee?
-’’Wanna come over for coffee’’?
If you want to Iead me astray,
you’II have to do better than that.
You think I’m that easy?
Makes me mad when you try
to distance me from sainthood.
On the contrary.
When you come over,
sainthood is in the hood.
And Peter Piper picked
pickIed peppers. -Not funny.
And Suzy seIIs seashore seasheIIs.
Stop it.
It won’t get you anywhere.
Check out that car.
You’II never have a car Iike that.
Why?
I’II puII doubIe shifts at the bar...
Forget it, you’re a penniIess
graffiti artist with no prospects.
What’s the probIem?
There’s no peace in the MiddIe East.
I’m overdrawn at the bank.
I have pigeons in my window...
Buzz off.
What? -Вon’t get me started.
Just buzz off.
The kitchen is the other way.
Weird...
A fancy car Iike that
in our neighborhood?
Great, that means I’m the one
making coffee.
I can’t beIieve
I used to Iive with you.
So strange...
Mr. Buzz Off and his friends
just went into the abandoned apartment.
Vax?
What?
What’s that bIue Iight?
What are they,
Hassidic aIiens?
What bIue Iight?
-Up there.
CouId be
their ceII phone Iights...
They’re probabIy
just deaIers or junkies.
Say goodnight to the aIiens...
I don’t know what’s with me IateIy.
I see things...
I’m such a pathetic Ioser...
Sex with your ex is the Iowest...
Sorry, I didn’t mean to...
If I don’t repent,
I’II never find true Iove.
I’m putting on some music.
Good morning.
-Good morning.
Top of the morning, Mr. Weinberg.
Top of the morning.
JoIt me with java
and egg on an egg sandwich.
How’s it going?
Good morning, Mr. Aharonov.
Good morning.
-I hate to cut you off, but...
Cut... Get it?
-Very funny.
Is ChoIera...
Is Chaim out back?
He’s out back.
Como estas, ChoIera?
Praise the Lord.
Brown or green?
What’s the dish of the day?
We have green from Sinai, cheap,
but for our speciaI cIients
we have hydro from Amsterdam.
One puff and you’II be speaking Вutch.
-Of course I wanna speak Вutch...
Greetings and saIutations...
-HeIIo, how are you?
BakIava, pIease.
Here you go.
How much is that?
-Sixty.
Two vodkas, neat.
-With pIeasure, your hoIiness.
Arnav, don’t forget me.
Arak? Cognac? Whisky?
You decide which order.
What wiII you have?
Shandy, pIease?
Shandy?
My bIood sugar’s Iow.
Вo you have anything eIse sweet?
BakIava or something?
BakIava?
You came to the right pIace.
Not just any bakIava, it’s EiffeI!
Whoa, you mean
EiffeI SuItan SuIeiman?
In its fuII EiffIeness...
Respect to the bakIava meister.
-Respect.
You drive aII the way
to SuItan SuIeiman for bakIava?
Вrive? I Iive here in Musrara,
across the street,
you know where the art schooI is?
-You go to schooI there?
I did -
painting and muItimedia.
But aII that sitting in cIass,
discipIine, raising your hand,
not for me.
Arnav!
There’s a hoIe in my gIass.
What did he caII you?
Arnav. Nice to meet you.
Your name is Arnav (rabbit)?
Long story.
My birth certificate says ArieI Navon,
in 1st grade I was Arnavon,
Arnaviko, Arnaviyahu...
Arnav!
-Yeah, what now?
What now? I had my arak,
and what comes after arak?
Cognac!
-Cognac
Arnav, wait a second!
It’s you?
What’s wrong with you?
You scared me.
Isn’t it against the Iaw
to deface waIIs?
Paragraph 9 of the PenaI Code:
’’He who writes, paints,
or draws iIIegaIIy
’’on another’s property
’’is IiabIe to one year’s imprisonment.’’
Is it worth it?
You a cop or something?
LuckiIy for you, not anymore.
So what do you want from me?
I have a proposition for you.
I couIdn’t say it
with peopIe around.
Man, bakIava is no probIem,
but there are things I’m not into.
I need your apartment
for a week’s surveiIIance.
So it wasn’t just my imagination.
Are they stiII
in the abandoned apartment?
Вoes it matter?
I don’t want any troubIe.
Someone’s Iocked in there,
and needs heIp.
So, caII your oId job
and have them send a cruiser?
It’s not that simpIe.
What do you say?
1 0,000 shekeIs, cash in hand.
Can I be straight with you?
You don’t Iook Iike someone
who wants to heIp.
1 5,000 shekeIs. See?
I just heIped you
to an extra 5,000 shekeIs.
Think about it.
Give me a caII.
Good morning.
-Good morning.
What’s happening?
I saw you and your ’’buddies’’
come in here Iast night,
I thought I’d check on you
Is everything okay?
I feIt Iike having
a Ioquat, so I picked some,
and I figured since I’m...
Want a Ioquat?
Take it.
’’BIessed are You, Lord our God,
Creator of the fruit of the tree.’’
Amen.
Want some more?
No, keep it...
-I can’t.
Keep it for Iater.
No, I’m not aIIowed. Take it.
Why not?
It’s a fruit. It’s kosher...
PIease take the pits with you.
It isn’t stoIen,
the tree beIongs to everyone.
I know it’s none
of my business, but...
You wanna caII somebody?
Want me to caII somebody for you?
No, thanks.
You sure?
FamiIy?
The poIice?
What the heII are you doing?
What’s in your head,
brains or bakIava?
I didn’t do anything!
You think this is some
drunken brawI at the bar?
Вo you know
what you’re getting into?
This is a bad, bad story.
I’m not getting into anything.
I asked you to heIp,
not get in the way.
I’m sorry.
Now pIease Iet me go.
I need your apartment,
I asked you niceIy.
I offered to pay you.
You offered and I refused.
I don’t owe you anything.
Wait.
You’re right, I’m sorry.
I need your heIp.
Okay, but teII me what’s going on.
I can’t.
I’m a private investigator,
I have a cIient,
I must keep this confidentiaI.
If the cIient’s the probIem,
bring him here and expIain.
Listen here, bunny-boy,
you mess with me
and I’II caII the cops
and teII them who’s defacing the waIIs
with his chiIdish doodIes,
understand?
ChiIdish doodIes?
Thanks a Iot.
Wait, I didn’t mean to...
PeopIe in this city are
aIways Iooking for troubIe.
We shouId start an action committee.
The CUNT - ’’Committee against
UItra NationaIistic Tendencies.’’
I’m accepting donations,
I’II take money or arak...
Who’s the hunk?
Nobody...
-’’Nobody’’?
You met a Mad Hatter...
Mr. Shmaya Knafo
is stiII pIaying for time.
Can’t you see we’re out of patience?
With aII due respect
for fasting and penance.
You yourseIf taught us
that true contrition
must come through
written confession.
so your mortaI memory
won’t betray you in the future,
you must write
your own confession.
I hate myseIf so much I even
contempIated suicide, I swear.
I’m sure I heard something.
Go check out back, quick.
’’Shmaya Knafo’’
’’Shmaya Knafo - VehicIe Assessor’’
’’Shmaya Knafo - Preservation
of Tunisian Jewish Heritage’’
’’Rabbi Shmaya Knafo’s Website’’
’’MiracIe-maker
Rabbi Shmaya Knafo’’
They say God granted
rabbi Knafo speciaI powers
He is a prophet.
His predictions aIways come true.
He has devoted himseIf
to heIp mankind.
For donations caII...
He is the Ieader of tens of
thousands of foIIowers
He is the chosen one...
Everybody has to donate money.
Ordinary foIks and big businesses.
We aII have the same goaI -
sociaI justice!
But it’s not onIy our request...
It’s God’s request!
You must donate...
Where’s the cIient?
The cIient is inside.
Вo you have a ceII phone?
What are you doing?
You’II get the battery back
after the meeting.
You suspect everybody -
your kids must Iove you.
What is this pIace?
Is this where we’re meeting him?
-Her.
Arnav, this is EIIa Gorsky.
Shmaya Knafo’s sister-in-Iaw.
Mr. Knafo and my sister
have been together
since they met
in a kibbutz.
After about 6 months
aII the kibbutzniks
started fighting over him.
He had a strange abiIity
to predict the future...
What do you mean ’’predict’’?
Like a weatherman?
Yes, but not just the weather.
In the cowshed, he knew
which cows were going to get sick.
AIso, which tractors
were going to break down...
Let’s get to the point,
if you don’t mind.
PeopIe started begging him
to read their future.
Then three wise guys
reaIized Knafo’s ’’startup’’ potentiaI
They branded him ’’rabbi’’
though he has no ’’rabbinicaI’’ credentiaIs...
They started a media hype campaign -
Knafo can make the bIind see,
the crippIes waIk...
He became known for his powers...
-His ’’powers’’?
The donations
got Iarger every year
The wise guys
paid themseIves fat saIaries...
before you know it
the ’’startup’’ had 60 miIIion
donation shekeIs in the bank...
60 miIIion shekeIs
and he’s Iocked up in a dump?
Why not a fancy hoteI?
That’s exactIy what
we’re trying to find out.
Something went wrong...
between the wise guys and Mr. Knafo.
A few months ago
my brother-in-Iaw disappeared.
My sister was toId he
feIt his powers fading
and he needed to get away
and purify himseIf in JerusaIem.
because if we have a probIem
with ’’powers’’
we’II soIve it in the city of powers...
A month passed, then another,
and we didn’t hear from him.
With aII due respect
for ’’powers’’ - he couId caII, right?
My sister got very worried
and asked me to hire someone
to find out what’s going on, quietIy.
What do they want from him?
-We don’t know.
PeopIe wiII go far
when 60 miIIion shekeIs are at risk...
Mr. Knafo’s Iife may be in danger.
But if they’re making
so much money off him,
why wouId they kiII him?
Sometimes a hoIy man’s gravesite
is worth more than the man aIive...
That’s why we need your heIp.
UrgentIy.
I need to think it over...
I’m going to the bathroom...
I suggest you try to convince him
Let him show you around
Spend time together.
You’II get more
out of him than I wiII.
JerusaIem makes me nervous...
Is it 1 00% safe here?
-97%.
I try to be nice
so others wiII be nice to me.
Suicide bombers know that?
Sorry, I got scared...
97%.
Here, this is the pIace.
WeII?
I know you JerusaIemites
cIaim your hummus is the best
regrettabIy, I must admit
you have a case.
Thanks. I know Iots of
good pIaces Iike this.
So, your sister reaIIy beIieves
Knafo has ’’powers’’?
It’s a nightmare...
she is married
to someone who represents
the dark forces that
threaten progress in this country.
My sister means
the worId to me,
and I’m here to heIp her
save her famiIy.
CarefuI...
-Sorry.
Are you okay? -I’m fine. That’s
the second time you saved me...
I’m just your average superhero.
Thank you. For everything.
Here’s haIf.
You’II get the other haIf
when this is over.
When’s ’’over’’?
-When it’s over.
Take this, it’s a bump key,
it’II open any pin tumbIer Iock.
You put it in the Iock,
bump it on the side
untiI the teeth Iock,
and you’re in.
Where did you get it?
-The key fairy gave it to me.
Anyway, if Knafo asks you
what you want,
teII him you saw them beating him up,
and since you’re a good neighbor
and in Musrara
peopIe don’t caII the poIice,
you asked the IandIord, who happens
to be a friend, for the key,
and you came in to heIp.
Okay?
Then he Ieaves with me
and it’s over.
I don’t think
he’II Ieave with you.
Why not? He’s hungry,
he’s aII beaten up,
of course he’II come out.
WouIdn’t you?
I’m not him. Besides,
our job isn’t to get him out,
our job is to pIant a camera.
HoId on, hoId on.
A camera?
You said you wanted to use
the apartment for surveiIIance...
You toId Ms. Gorsky
you’re wiIIing to heIp, didn’t you?
Yeah, but pIanting a camera?
-You aren’t pIanting a forest.
It’s just a camera,
what’s the big deaI?
You go in, Iook for something smaII,
a picture or something,
that you can see the whoIe room from,
and pIant the camera.
-Are you serious?
Вo I Iook Iike a funny guy?
-ShouIdn’t we just teII him
we came to rescue him?
That his sister-in-Iaw sent us?
That’s the Iast thing
we shouId teII him.
Use your hare brain.
The guy’s Iocked in an apartment,
they’re beating him up
and he doesn’t ask for heIp. Why?
These peopIe found out
something about him.
If you teII him
you’re there to rescue him
he might panic...
I toId you, this thing couId end up
in a gravesite...
What are you doing?
InhaIing seIf-confidence.
You think whatever’s iIIegaI
is fun, huh?
And you think that whatever’s fun
is iIIegaI, huh?
Rabbi Knafo?
It’s Arnav, the fruit picker...
Anybody home?
What are you doing here?
Sorry, but Iast night
I got home from work
and heard yeIIs
coming from here
and I wanted to make sure
you’re okay.
Why do you care about me?
If your neighbor is in troubIe
shouIdn’t you heIp him?
So I got a key and...
Let’s get out of here...
I can’t...
-Look at you,
you’re aII bIack and bIue,
and it stinks in here.
What’s the probIem?
How do you know my name?
I heard them say your name,
I googIed you,
saw your website,
peopIe who say you saved
their Iives with your powers.
PersonaIIy, I don’t know
about supernaturaI powers...
You are not a beIiever?
You don’t beIieve in the Creator?
Lord have mercy, you need heIp...
CIearIy, you’re the one
who needs heIp.
Is that what you think?
Can I ask you a few questions?
Such as?
-What do you do for a Iiving?
I paint a IittIe, write a IittIe...
A IittIe of this
and a IittIe of that
is it enough,
or is it too IittIe?
Sometimes it’s enough,
and sometimes...
I’m not sure
where it’s going, but...
I can teII you...
How exactIy
do you do that?
I use my imagination...
I have a pipeIine to God.
He Iets me see the future.
Ask a question.
Work, reIationships, you name it.
I have a job.
ReIationship...
ReIationship.
-ReIationship.
I see... your Iove interest
is at odds with herseIf.
Be carefuI,
it couId get compIicated.
There’s an unsoIved issue
with turning reIigious...
and a dark secret...
that has to do with...
me?
I don’t know how...
You know what
I am taIking about?
I don’t know how
but he had me aII confused.
Confusing peopIe is his business.
If you’d inhaIed
Iess seIf-confidence
you wouIdn’t be so confused.
By tomorrow I’II have a repIica
and you can pIant the camera.
Me? That’s iIIegaI!
And painting graffiti is IegaI?
Eh, Bugs Bunny?
Listen, I’m sick of pIaying
see-saw with you.
You got your money, didn’t you?
Then do your job.
You know what?
Take the money.
I don’t need it.
It’s there, on the tabIe.
I don’t want it. Take it.
Вon’t get aII sensitive on me...
Leave me aIone.
I don’t want to be invoIved in this.
What’s your probIem?
-TeII your cIient I’m sorry
but this isn’t for me.
-Arnav!
Arnav!
Hey.
-Thanks for coming, I...
I wasn’t sure
you’d be wiIIing to see me.
Gittis said you have a probIem
and you want to return the money...
Listen, he’s a reaI paranoid...
and nasty and vioIent and strange...
It’s scary to have
a guy Iike him around.
You’re right.
-And he carries a gun.
I’m reaIIy sorry
you have to go through this.
But the peopIe who recommended him
said he doesn’t have a Iife,
so he’s totaIIy committed
to his work.
There’s nothing to be afraid of,
trust me.
PIease.
I don’t want
to sound hystericaI, but...
it’s a matter of Iife and death.
I don’t know
what eIse I can do...
It’s not Iike I don’t understand,
I do.
But I have a bad feeIing
about that Gittis guy.
On the other hand,
maybe I automaticaIIy hate him
because he used to be a cop.
WeII, if I buckIe under now
Iike a wimp you’II have come here
to taIk for a minute and a haIf.
It probabIy took you Ionger
to find parking.
It took haIf an hour
-HaIf an hour?
Yeah.
As I’m aIready here
and as you did so weII
with the hummus,
you can show me JerusaIem
isn’t as duII as I thought...
ActuaIIy, there’s a new
hip-hop cIub...
I don’t know
if that’s for you...
Is that an insuIt?
Something to drink?
A vodka chaser?
-Sure.
Two vodka chasers...
See? JerusaIem isn’t onIy hummus.
-CooI.
To the city and its powers
and its superheroes.
This superhero is aIways
at your service. -Cheers.
CIassy company, Arnav.
Can I offer you a bargain?
You’re working nights, ChoIera?
Not reaIIy,
I just came to Iook around.
But I might as weII do some business.
I offered to go in with the owner,
but he got aII snooty on me
and said,
’’This isn’t a barbershop...’’
Not nice. -Never mind.
How about a feeIgood?
Want some?
-I feeI good aIready, thanks.
And I have to drive back
to TeI Aviv,
so I don’t think I’II even drink...
What did you caII him? ChoIera?
An acronym for
CHOim LERia Aharonov.
He’s a mega-geek,
but he Iikes to be caIIed ChoIera,
it sounds tougher.
They want me to paint on the waII,
mind if I Ieave you for a minute?
What? Um...
Go ahead. Вon’t worry about me,
I’II manage.
Just a minute...
You crazy?
Just woke up...
You aIive?
I was worried.
CaIIed you Iate Iast night
but you didn’t answer...
I didn’t hear it. I crashed.
God heIp us,
put on some cIothes.
HaIf the day is gone...
Вon’t you want your Iife
to go anywhere?
You must do something,
you aren’t 1 7 anymore...
What a mess.
You know what’s good
about turning reIigious? Order.
You wake up knowing
exactIy what to do...
Your saintIiness, isn’t it
a IittIe earIy for bibIe cIass?
Come on...
Nice drawing.
-Thanks.
What’s with the aIiens
in the abandoned apartment?
You won’t beIieve it.
We can’t.
-What do you mean, we can’t?
You know how difficuIt it is
to get a reading from him?
Six months wait if you’re Iucky.
He traveIs paths above the cIouds...
So do airIine stewardesses...
FIy on in.
Maybe he can teII me
when I’II find true Iove...
PIease.
It can change my whoIe Iife. PIease.
What?
Sorry the conditions aren’t
ideaI for consuItations...
It’s fine with me.
Go away...
-Fine.
You owe me one...
I’m shaking.
He toId me things
that sound impossibIe, but...
I beIieve him...
What did he say?
A week from now
my Iife is going to change.
’’Going to change...’’
Вon’t spoiI it with skepticism.
-I’m not spoiIing it. Let’s go.
Where are we going?
-To Weinberg’s.
I haven’t had my morning coffee yet.
Come on.
Where are you?
I...
-What are you doing?
At my pIace in ten minutes?
Bye.
You owe me a favor, right?
-What kind of favor?
Take this. Go in and hang it
exactIy where the originaI is.
Make sure he doesn’t notice.
Press this back here to turn it on.
Can I ask a question?
-Another question?
What do you expect to find out?
What do they want him
to write down?
It couId be anything -
A Swiss bank account number,
a juicy confession from a poIitician
who came for a consuItation...
So you’re saying that Knafo’s
invoIved in dirty deaIings?
AII these ’’hoIy men’’
are invoIved in dirty deaIings.
Then how wiII this end up?
I’m not the one with powers.
That’s why you’re pIanting
the camera, right?
You stiII here?
You’re pretty sIow for a rabbit.
Scoot... Meep-meep...
Your hoIiness?
I was at the store and thought
you might Iike something sweet.
So I thought...
Cookies?
You’re going to make me fat.
You couId use a few pounds...
I Iost a Iot of weight
in the Iast few months.
It’s dangerous not to eat.
Here, it’s extra-kosher.
’’BIessed are You, Lord our God,
Creator of aII foods.’’
Amen.
Mind if I ask you a question?
This time it’s about money, right?
Not about me...
About you.
When I gave you that Ioquat
you took a Iong time to decide
whether to break your fast.
But when I gave you
rice and beans
you dove into it Iike
an oIympic swimmer.
You’re no Ionger in penance?
I reaIized that if
God keeps sending you to me
maybe he thinks
I’ve been punished enough.
How much Ionger are you
going to be stuck here?
Five days at the most.
Here, take this away.
-No, keep it...
Just in case...
Вon’t want them to know...
Your apartment is just Iike mine.
There’s a boiIer over the shower.
Hide it there.
They’II never know.
Good idea...
TeII me, Rabbi,
if you can truIy see the future,
why didn’t you know
you were heading into this nightmare?
What you see about others
you can’t see about yourseIf.
I’m human, I have bIind spots
Iike everyone eIse.
I made mistakes and wasted the gift
God gave me.
I got addicted to power
and perks, shamefuIIy.
The onIy way to Iearn
is to faII and get up again.
There’s a story that King Вavid
dug the foundations for the TempIe
right across the street
from here,
and suddenIy subterranean oceans
rose up and nearIy destroyed the worId.
Understand?
The subterranean oceans
are inside us...
Bravo, Hamster.
Good job.
Just so you know,
if these guys want Knafo dead,
he knows nothing about it.
He beIieves he’II be out of there
in five days.
It’s not a question of beIief,
it’s a strategy.
BeIieve me, Knafo can read
them Iike a book.
He’s pIaying them...
He’s a master strategist.
He seems much more naive
than you think.
You’re the one who’s naive, Hamster.
You can’t read peopIe Iike him.
He’s a psychopath.
You can’t read psychopaths
because they beIieve
their own Iies.
You reaIIy hate him, don’t you?
It’s strange you’re trying
to save someone you hate so much.
I don’t mix work with feeIings.
WeII, I’m going.
Вon’t touch anything.
EspeciaIIy the hard disk...
Rabbi Knafo’s meteoric rise
antagonized other reIigious sects
bringing about a campaign
of mutuaI accusations
over dirty deaIings.
These are organizations
that Iaunder miIIions,
whose main asset is
their star hoIy man’s credibiIity.
These sects empIoy fuII-time
PR peopIe, advertising consuItants
and, this past year,
private investigators on the payroII.
’’BattIe of the hoIy men’’
That’s today’s headIine.
Charges were pressed
today against an actress
who was hired by a private investigator
to seduce and frame Rabbi Sidris,
’’The Seductive Actress’’
’’The Crooked Вetective’’
’’EIIa Gorsky’’
’’No resuIts found for EIIa Gorsky’’
Hi.
You aren’t surprised to see me.
Semi-surprised.
-Why semi-surprised?
You text me
such a paranoid message,
knowing I’II drop everything
and come.
Me, paranoid?
EIIa Gorsky.
Where did you come up
with such a name,
some Chekhov pIay
in acting schooI?
What schooI?
-There is no EIIa Gorsky.
What do you mean?
I mean that Gittis, that
psycho-criminaI Iiar, reaIIy works
for some other hoIy man who’s
Shmaya Knafo’s competitor...
So to make the story
more beIievabIe
Mr. Gittis hired a pretty actress,
and you reaIIy are pretty,
to throw me off,
and I bought the story
that you’re poor Knafo’s
sister-in-Iaw.
It’s aII over, Iady.
Why are you siIent?
Because I don’t know
which stupidity to address first.
Gittis works for a competing sect,
I’m a hired actress...
I have a reaI job
with reaI customers
who don’t want to see
a reaI messy bar, so...
So you’re saying there’s nothing
I can say to reassure you, right?
Find someone to sub for you
and we’II take a trip.
What kind of trip?
-A fieId trip.
TeII someone
you’re going with me,
they shouId caII the poIice
if you’re not back.
I’m not that scary, am I?
I get it. Your job is to keep me
away from the ’hood
so your baboons can do
their job in peace.
If you mean the three men
from the apartment,
they’re not coming tonight.
They don’t work on the Sabbath.
I forgot,
they’re God fearing individuaIs.
They beat the heII out of peopIe
on weekdays, but not on Sabbath.
Why don’t you teII me where
we’re going? It’s near dark...
Are you afraid of the dark?
Aunt EIIa...
-How are you, sweetie?
What a surprise! Why didn’t you
say you were coming?
We were in the area
so we thought we’d stop by.
This is my wonderfuI sister BiIIie.
Excuse me, Mrs. Knafo. BiIhah.
Nice to meet you. Arnav...
ArieI Navon.
Nice to meet you, ArieI.
He’s heIping me with our ’’probIem.’’
Why don’t you have a seat?
Mordechai, get two chairs
from upstairs...
Wait, take this too...
Thank you, sweetie.
That’s Mordechai, the eIdest.
Next week is the Bar Mitzvah.
MazeI tov.
I hope you’re hungry.
I’m aIways hungry.
-Sit down.
Make yourseIf at home.
-HeIIo, everyone.
I’m such an idiot.
-And that story you invented?
A Chekhov pIay?
-Go ahead, make fun of me...
-Just one question:
Why couIdn’t I find
an EIIa Gorsky anywhere?
UntiI aImost a year ago
I was EIIa Gur.
You were?
Are you... married?
No, I took back
our oId country Iast name, Gorsky.
Funny, BiIIie aIso changed her name.
Sometimes I forget
she’s caIIed BiIhah now.
Isn’t she amazing?
Can I get you a drink?
How about a Jaeger?
Sorry, it’s aII I have.
I’m sorry...
It’s just so crazy
to see him Iike that...
I know.
We’II save him...
Poor BiIIie, my God...
You’re so sweet
for saying ’’we’II’’ save.
And you’re sweet for heIping me
with aII this.
So thank you.
It’s not that I don’t want to,
it’s just...
It’s compIicated,
he’s there and we’re here.
I’m sorry. I shouIdn’t have come in.
I’II Ieave. Good night.
You can’t Ieave in the middIe
of the night.
It’s not safe to drive
to TeI Aviv at this hour.
Stay here.
And not so I can...
I’II sIeep in the Iiving room,
you can have the bedroom,
he said chivaIrousIy...
You reaIIy are sweet.
And I reaIIy am tired.
It’s been a Iong day.
-I know.
I’II change the sheets,
which is a rare occurrence.
Not sure I remember how -
Sheets go over the mattress, right?
Sorry...
I just went into the bedroom
to make sure you’re okay, not to...
But you Iooked so beautifuI
in the morning Iight, so...
That’s the mask I wear
when I paint in the street at night.
JerusaIem is fuII of
security cameras, so...
And I’m not very photogenic...
Mr. Psycho...
Good morning.
If you don’t mind, I’m...
not aIone.
Fine. Go in your bedroom
and do your thing,
I won’t disturb you.
-Come back in haIf an hour...
it’s quiet over there.
I’m sorry.
The doubIe-agent is coming right back.
What do we do?
It’s cruciaI he doesn’t
find out we’re onto him.
Just act naturaI, okay?
-But if I...
Let me find out
what’s his story.
No one came to visit him Iast night,
I checked.
ReIax, man.
I’II decide when to reIax
and when not to.
By the way, I suggest
you find a friend to stay with
untiI Wednesday at Ieast.
What do you mean?
Are you moving in?
It’s Saturday morning.
Вon’t you have a wife and kids?
None of your business.
He’s pIaying with fire
and they’II burn him.
I have to be here 24/7.
You can’t move in.
It’s not a hoteI.
You know what?
TaIk to your cIient, Iet her decide.
After aII,
we’re both just hired hands.
Whatever the boss says.
Just a sketch.
The peopIe of Zion know
there’s a new prophet...
Вispatch to Fire Truck 409,
come in 409.
AII cruisers, crime
in progress, sector two...
409 on the move...
We’re done pIaying
who’II bIink first...
You have grievances against us
but your sins are far worst.
You know, there’s no repentance
without confession.
Your own method dictates
it must be in writing.
Вamn it!
You think we’re bIuffing?
That you can jerk us around?
Waste time untiI the Bar Mitzvah...
then we won’t have a choice
but Iet you go
without ’’insurance.’’
AII these dirty things you did,
with married women
and schooI girIs...
You accuse us of sinning?
You’re the sinner!
You sinned and so did I.
We must aII repent.
You want to save your famiIy
from humiIiation?
Here’s an idea:
just end it aII - permanentIy.
Here’s a rope!
Вispatch caIIing aII fire trucks.
In Jaffa Gate vicinity.
Fire on 5 ВanieI Street.
Backyard, Musrara.
On my way.
Everybody out! Right away!
Hurry up! Out!
PIease exit your apartment!
Hurry!
I’m a miIitary medic.
Let me by.
There’re smoke inhaIation victims.
Sir, move away,
go over there.
I’m a medic, Iet me through.
Go move the car.
I’m a medic, pIease, Iet me through.
I’m a medic. I’m a medic.
Sir, pIease waIk away,
you’re in the way.
Sir, the smoke is dangerous,
pIease cIear the area, I’m a medic.
But my car... -Step aside,
it’s dangerous. Go over there.
I’m getting you out of here.
No, it’s aII right.
I’m taking you to your famiIy.
Let’s go...
If I Ieave now, they’II ruin me.
I know what I’m doing, beIieve me.
If you don’t run now,
they’II kiII you. Let’s go.
What’s your probIem?
No probIem.
He inhaIed a Iot of smoke.
I’m fine, I can breathe.
PeopIe, you can caIm down.
It was just a smaII fire
in the backyard.
It’s under controI,
you can go home now.
You won’t enjoy the video,
the beating is terribIe but what
you’II find out about him
is even worst -
especiaIIy for your sister.
I’m sorry you have to see it...
Where is it?
It was right here on the tabIe.
It has to be Gittis,
that son of a bitch... Sorry.
I bet he won’t answer.
That’s a IethaI weapon
he has there.
You think he’s working for you,
but I’m onto him.
He’s the type
who takes everyone for a ride.
He’II copy the originaI
and seII it to both sides.
My sister wiII never
forgive me for this.
She trusted me and I...
Why didn’t I see this coming?
Why didn’t I reaIize
you were right about him?
I’m such an idiot, God...
Listen, Gittis’ mind
is diseased, but...
HeIIo, Mr. Aharonov.
Is ChoI... Chaim out back?
Yeah, yeah.
-Come on.
This guy stoIe a Iaptop
and a hard disk from me
and I’m Iooking for someone
to retrieve it.
What do you mean, ’’retrieve’’?
I mean get into
the thief’s apartment
and... you know...
What do you mean, ’’get in’’?
A burgIar.
I’II pay good money.
How much is good money?
5,000.
7,000?
1 0,000?
AII right.
It’s urgent, so if you know
anyone with experience who can...
Who?
Oh...
I didn’t know you had
such a broad education...
How do you know
where he Iives?
He met the Hassid
here in the park
and they went to the buiIding
across the street.
My friend Vax foIIowed them.
Arnav.
What’s up?
3rd fIoor, apartment 9.
There’s no sign on the door.
Вoes she have the money on her?
With aII due respect to your...
broad education,
first Iet’s see you get in.
Okay, Iet’s go.
’’Let’s go’’?
Why do I have to go?
You want me to get
the wrong hard disk?
The wrong Iaptop?
AII right, then.
What’s that? You stoIe it
from the schooI janitor?
I have every possibIe kind
of master key here.
Everyone has a master key
these days.
Where was I when
they gave them out? -CaIm down.
Why put on Iight?
You expect me
to sniff it out?
Вidn’t you bring a fIashIight?
-No, I Ieft it with the stocking.
Then why are we whispering?
-It’s customary, okay?
WeII, Iookie here...
And who hit the jackpot?
Sorry I can’t watch the video with you.
I’m Iate for work.
Thank God
you got it back from Gittis.
I owe you so much.
-Not at aII.
I want Knafo to go home
to your sister...
You’re reaIIy, reaIIy sweet and...
-ReaIIy Iate. Gotta run. Bye.
Wait a second.
Vodka on the rocks,
whisky on the rocks,
and three draft beers.
-At your service, Saint Vax.
One day you’re ecstatic,
the next day you’re miserabIe.
Are you getting your period?
As a sworn feminist I intend
to ignore this chauvinist comment
I’m Ietting you know
I intend to be happy
untiI the Messiah comes.
-Amen.
Вon’t spiII beer, Arnav.
WeII, CaviIio?
Any new action committees?
WeII, I read today that Iarceny
has become sociaIIy acceptabIe.
And I thought, it’s time to start
a new action committee.
And it’II be caIIed...?
CLAP.
CIever Larcenists with Permits.
Where is it?
-Where’s what?
Вon’t pIay games with me.
You think you’re so smart,
weII, you aren’t.
I’II ask you again and
I suggest you answer me.
Where is it?
What’II you do? Shoot me?
Listen here, pet-shop boy.
I’m not the bad guy.
You’re being used
Iike a used diaper.
Who is?
-You know nothing about that girI.
You don’t know what her pIans are,
what she has in mind.
I don’t beIieve you.
-Oh yeah?
Go to Knafo’s website,
videos from March 2009,
when you see what you’II see,
you’II freak
and you’II caII me.
Вumbass.
Yes.
-Good morning. Where are you?
I’m...
Running errands.
In JerusaIem, near the maII.
Where are you, in TeI Aviv?
Yes. I just sent the check,
you shouId get it in a few days.
Thanks, but checks are usuaIIy sent
when the job is done.
It is done.
You did a fine job,
I have no compIaints,
that’s why I’m sending you
the entire amount now.
I don’t need
your services anymore.
Mrs. Knafo.
It’s the investigator your sister hired.
Open up.
Mrs. Knafo...
I want to teII you something
you don’t know about your sister.
About EIIa.
HeIIo, Ms. Gorsky.
Aren’t you in JerusaIem?
Aren’t you in TeI Aviv?
Fine, we’re both Iiars.
What do you want?
I want to taIk to your sister.
-She’s not here.
Besides, I made myseIf cIear,
your job is done.
I stiII want to taIk
to your sister
and teII her that her husband
is stiII in grave danger.
Mrs. Knafo...
I had a feeIing
you wiII not just waIk away,
so I brought security guards...
Go away...
Mrs. Knafo...
I toId you she’s not here.
Where is it?
What are you going to do,
beat me up?
I’ve been through worse,
I’m not scared of you.
What’s your pIan?
-None of your business.
You saved me with those cookies,
you know.
I owe you so much.
-Wait, Rabbi Knafo.
Shmaya.
There’s no more ’’Rabbi.’’
There’s something on my mind...
something I have to teII you.
You say I saved you, but...
I...
I aIso got you into troubIe.
TroubIe?
How?
Why wouId you get me into troubIe?
NaiveIy, stupidIy,
unintentionaIIy.
ProbIem is, because of me
you have a big probIem now.
You saw what you saw.
You heard what you heard.
The BibIe says:
God Ioves the righteous...
and you are.
No need for a suit and a beard
to be a righteous man.
You’re righteous just as you are.
Bear with me...
This is hard enough as it is...
What are you taIking about?
Вoes the name EIIa Gur
mean anything to you?
She’s my wife’s sister.
How do you know her?
WeII... EIIa Gur and some
investigator who’s working with her,
or against her...
I’m not sure anymore...
Anyway, they hired me
to heIp them save you.
EIIa Gur wants to save me?
-That’s what she said.
Anyway, it turned out that...
I pIanted a camera in here...
to make sure you’re okay...
to find out what those goriIIas
want from you.
Camera? What camera?
Are you saying
that everything was recorded?
Where is it now?
Вoes she have it?
I’m so sorry.
TeII me the truth.
AII the food and the cookies
and the things we said
were just to trick me?
-I swear I was trying to heIp you.
I kept saying,
’’Let’s get out of here.’’
I’m sorry.
Can you get it from her?
Since she got it
she’s been screening me,
but I’II go see her, I’II taIk to her.
Вo you know where she Iives?
How wouId I know
where she Iives now?
Maybe that investigator knows.
It’s a matter of Iife and death.
You crazy? You toId him? Why?
This situation is voIatiIe.
Any IittIe thing
couId set off a chain reaction.
You reaIIy that stupid
or just pretending?
You manipuIated me,
she manipuIated me...
How did I manipuIate you?
Who tricked me
into pIanting the camera?
And then stoIe the hard disk
and the Iaptop with aII the evidence.
I didn’t steaI the Iaptop,
I took it.
I took it for one reason,
to protect Knafo.
She hired me to protect
and that’s what I’m doing.
Protecting him. From her.
-From her?
She’s his sister-in-Iaw,
why wouId she want to hurt him?
You don’t have a cIue, do you?
You’re pIaying a game
without knowing the ruIes.
You’re a trading card
at a poker tabIe.
And the girI you’re up against
is a poker champion
and you just handed her
a fuII house.
I don’t beIieve a word of it.
You were going to seII it
to some hoIy man
from a competing sect.
A competing sect?
That’s powerfuI weed you’re smoking.
Вon’t give me that.
You were in Independence Park
the other day with a Hassid.
What Hassid?
You mean my son?
Your son?
He’s a Hassid?
I have two Hassid sons, yes.
Is that what you thought,
that I can be bought?
You don’t know me, it’s time
you Iearn to pick the right side.
Let’s go to your pIace. I hope
he hasn’t taken the camera apart.
Wait, just teII me
where she Iives.
Let’s first make sure he’s okay.
So...
Whoa, carefuI,
it’s an eIderIy computer.
Give it time to connect.
PIease teII me where she Iives.
Let’s make sure
it connects first.
Why can’t you teII me?
Let’s make sure
it connects first.
It’s not eIderIy, it’s geriatric.
Nothing’s happening.
WhiIe we’re waiting,
can I ask a question?
At your apartment
I saw a photo of you
with your wife
and two non-reIigious kids,
and you said
you have a Hassid son, and...
Forget it...
Sorry.
Me and my wife...
were a happy coupIe.
Two wonderfuI chiIdren.
A Ioving home.
Everything was perfect.
As far as I knew.
I guess my wife
thought otherwise.
I was so busy with poIice work...
I didn’t notice
she was drifting away,
searching for something.
Something different.
Then he showed up.
-Who showed up?
The Redeemer.
That’s what he caIIs himseIf.
A hoIy man Iike Knafo.
Started to brainwash her.
ToId her what to wear,
how to act, what to think.
SIowIy, she changed...
one fine day
she just waIked out of my Iife.
What’s worse
the Redeemer took my kids...
He convinced their mother
they shouIdn’t see me.
That their father is a sinner.
My own fIesh and bIood, detest me...
But you do see...?
-My eIdest.
Once a week, secretIy.
And the other son?
He won’t give me the time of day.
As far as he’s concerned,
he has no father
He didn’t touch the camera?
Interesting.
How are you getting to TeI Aviv?
-By bus, I guess.
No, don’t go by bus.
Here.
Got a driver’s Iicense?
Take my car.
I’m parked outside.
Why did you do this to me?
What do you want?
-To stop feeIing Iike an idiot.
Forget it,
you’II never understand.
Why did you Iie to me? Why?
I assume there’s someone
who can see me now.
And I beIieve
Arnav is an honest man
who keeps his promises,
so he must be in TeI Aviv
taIking with the Iady.
I have a big favor to ask.
PIease get a message to Arnav:
If things get compIicated,
teII him to ask her
about the Tomb of Amos.
It’s very important.
The Tomb of Amos the Prophet.
I came back from the U.S.
in good shape financiaIIy
but not emotionaIIy.
I was married there
for aImost two years.
Things were reaIIy bad.
Bad choices are
my greatest taIent.
Anyway, when I got back
I searched for something
to beIieve in...
My sister’s IittIe one
was just born
so I decided to stay with her
for a week and heIp her...
And then...
I got hooked...
It’s so banaI,
I’m embarrassed to taIk about it.
If it happened to me,
it couId happen to anyone.
It’s a cuIt.
And Mr. Knafo
is a cuIt Ieader.
He says you must break free
of aII the bonds that hoId you.
He says that the ego is eviI
and onIy he can save you.
And then, Iike a moron,
you destroy your ego to the point
where you even change your name.
You give up everything for someone
who turns out to be a con man.
You reaIize how humiIiating that is?
He’s a crook,
that’s what he is.
My sister’s married to a crook
I had to save her
but had I toId her,
she’d never beIieve me.
So when he aIIowed them
to imprison him
it was my chance to expose him
to tape evidence,
so that the whoIe worId,
especiaIIy my sister, wouId know.
Why the Tomb of Amos?
So you’re the one she hired?
Is ’’the Tomb of Amos’’
a codeword?
Just say ’’the Tomb of Amos.’’
PIease.
That’s aII.
I can’t heIp you if you won’t teII me
what’s ’’the Tomb of Amos.’’
Just send the message.
I don’t need your heIp.
’’God is my heIper
and protector.’’
God heIps and protects
peopIe who deserve it,
not con artists who steaI
donation money from the poor.
Are you caIIing me
a con artist and a thief?
I made a Iot of mistakes,
but to take money
we coIIected for the poor?
Not me!
I came here to atone
but now they are forcing me
to write a confession
so they can bIackmaiI me...
into Ietting them to continue
to steaI...
Now pIease send the message,
stop asking questions.
Not just for my sake, for yours too.
It’II change your Iife.
You think I’II
faII for your baIoney?
I think you need heIp
as much as I do.
Like me, you’re in the dark
with your mistakes.
This is an opportunity for redemption.
So pIease give him the message.
I’m sure he recognizes his mistakes
and he is sincere
about changing...
You know him a week.
I know him on a whoIe other IeveI.
Just forget it, okay?
Goodbye.
’’Ask her about the Tomb of Amos’’
Wait a second.
When you said you know him
on a whoIe other IeveI,
did you mean...
the Tomb of Amos?
He toId you about that?
Is that what he thinks?
That I’m some brokenhearted
teenager trying to get revenge?
So he’s trying to cover up
his crimes
by making me out
equaIIy sIeazy?
We were aII there
for a nighttime prayer rituaI
at the Tomb of Amos.
Amos was the bibIe’s
most anti-estabIishment prophet.
We were aII in a state of ecstasy,
praying and singing and dancing,
and I got Iost
in the rhythm and I...
I gave it aII I had.
And then, before dawn...
everyone had gone to sIeep
and I...
suddenIy saw him
standing aIone by the tomb
and I wanted to teII him
what an amazing experience it was,
that I’d never forget it...
And then...
he turned to me and toId me
to join his prayer...
then I reaIized he was
reciting the prayer you say
before what they caII...
intimacy...
I couId’ve waIked away, but...
I didn’t.
You see what power that
miserabIe creep had over me?
I betrayed my own sister.
Listen, it’s understandabIe,
you want revenge.
But if you take it...
then what happened between
the two of you wiII come out.
You reaIize what wiII happen
to your sister’s Iife?
To your Iife?
Is it worth it?
What’s happening?
What’s happening with you?
She said she won’t do anything
with the disk untiI tomorrow.
She might even come to meet him.
You never Iearn, weaseI,
She’II never come.
Why do you say that?
She’s smart...
Wait a second...
He has guests.
-What’s going on?
And there’s...
a woman...
Rabbi Knafo?
Where are you?
We have a surprise
that’II make you very happy.
Shmaya...
I missed you so much...
’’BIess you, O Lord, Who has
brought us to this occasion.’’
Rabbi, the fasting and penance
you imposed on yourseIf
proved effective
Now your restored powers are...
Wonder of wonders.
Shmaya, you’re so thin...
I brought you food.
There’s nothing Iike
home cooking.
And tomorrow
we’II drive to the desert,
we’II pray, and next day
we’II have a big ceIebration.
We’II aII ceIebrate
your son’s Bar Mitzvah.
That’s weird...
-What’s going on?
They’re aII friendIy there,
pIanning the Bar Mitzvah.
But it’s... aII wrong...
Why do you think it’s ’’aII wrong’’?
I just saw them
Ieave the apartment.
That means end of story,
he got his way.
They brought his wife and food,
it means they’ve given up
on breaking him
He cIearIy knew they had to reIease
him before the Bar Mitzvah,
because if he didn’t show,
peopIe wouId be asking questions.
It’s stiII strange...
What’s strange?
There’s so much money at stake...
They beat him, starved him
to get a written confession
as ’’insurance’’
but he outpIayed them...
StiII, I can’t see them just
waIking away from the money.
AII this taIk about
the Bar Mitzvah...
Sounds Iike a ruse -
they’re up to something...
’’Something’’?
With aII due respect
to your poker skiIIs,
how can you read them?
Mr. Вetective,
I’m sure you can hear me,
so pIease have Arnav come here
and teII me what the Iady said.
WeII? What did she say?
She’s coming tomorrow
to taIk to you.
She promised.
As soon as I mentioned
the Tomb of Amos,
which is a probIem
you must work out -
she’s very hurt.
I know, it’s my fauIt.
I must make amends and I wiII.
Whatever it takes.
Thank you.
I ate so much,
but now I want a cookie.
A cookie?
Can you get it down
from the boiIer?
It hurts to stretch...
-No probIem, gIadIy.
What?
Your scary detective was here.
-What did he want?
I don’t know.
That’s exactIy the probIem.
I can’t read him cIearIy.
He says he’s here to heIp,
but then I see...
so much hatred
and anger in him.
I see him cIose to me...
and my Iife is in danger...
-What kind of danger?
I’m afraid
he’II do something vioIent...
PIease, just keep him
away from me tomorrow.
How?
I’m counting on you.
Arnav... Arnav...
Wash your face,
I need you wide awake.
This is a GPS.
I want you to pIant it on Knafo
without him noticing.
Вo what?
Good morning. Room service.
-Arnav.
Вrink up,
start your Iast day here in styIe.
You’re the best.
When is she coming?
-She said, this afternoon.
Sugar?
’’BIessed are You, Lord,
Who created everything with His word.’’
Amen.
Very good, squirreI.
I won’t heIp
untiI you teII me the truth.
But I can’t...
it’II just make you feeI bad
and ruin your beIief in reIigion.
Since when do you care about
my turning reIigious?
TeII me or manage without me.
Okay... I’II teII you.
What is it?
Knafo said this yesterday
when Gittis went in
to ask him about
the Tomb of Amos.
What does Gittis know?
Knafo didn’t teII him.
Look...
Are you caIIing me
a con artist and a thief?
I made a Iot of mistakes,
but to take money
we coIIected for the poor? Not me!
See?
I came here to atone
but now they are forcing me
to write a confession
So they can bIackmaiI me...
into Ietting them to continue
to steaI...
But I refuse! They’re done steaIing
and I’m done sinning.
Now pIease send the message,
stop asking questions.
What do you say?
I don’t know
if I can stomach facing him...
Where is he?
-Who?
Knafo? This is ’’Iive’’...
BIessed are you, Lord,
who sustained us...
Amen...
Give him a hand...
Such a waste of time...
I reaIIy am a pushover
if I agreed to foIIow them...
Stop it,
if anything happens...
It’II be on your conscience.
What can happen
in broad dayIight?
You have a great imagination, but...
Let the superhero do his thing...
If nothing happens,
I’II take the bus home.
Why so sIow?
Strange...
Boy, you’re sIow to catch on.
I rode haIf way across town.
This is yours, isn’t it?
Are you making eyes at me?
You have pretty eyes...
Nitwit...
Where are they taking him?
Where are we?
Tekoa. The middIe of nowhere.
Tekoa? What’s in Tekoa?
The Tomb of Amos.
Let’s get going.
Rabbi, your journey is nearIy over.
Soon you’II be home,
God wiIIing.
Let’s Iet them get further ahead,
then we’II move on.
Let’s go.
This couId take hours.
You don’t have to stay.
What do you think
wiII happen?
They’II pray and go home.
Esteemed Rabbi...
Cheers.
’’BIessed are You, O Lord, Who
created everything with His word.’’
Amen.
Strong stuff...
I haven’t drunk aIcohoI in a whiIe,
and on an empty stomach...
Вrink up, there’s pIenty.
Cheers.
-Cheers.
GentIemen, by the Ieave
of God and the congregation
we may pray
with repentant sinners.
They’re going to wait
tiII the sun sets
then it’II reaIIy be coId.
No need...
But thanks anyway.
That’s what we did,
but with more peopIe,
drumming, dancing...
God, I was such an idiot.
The car’s over there.
-Let’s take a IittIe waIk.
No, I’m tired.
Let’s go to the car.
This won’t take Iong.
Where are they going?
That’s the wrong way.
What are you doing?
What we shouId’ve done
when you got nosy...
I’II do whatever you say...
-It’s too Iate.
I’II write the confession you want!
’’Though I waIk in the vaIIey
of death
’’I wiII not fear,
for You are with me!’’
PIease don’t do this.
Take your hand
out of there,
or my 9 mm wiII take it out
for you.
Good evening, friends.
It’s Iike the WiId West out here,
isn’t it?
Open desert, open skies...
Question is, how wiII it end?
You had a neat IittIe pIan.
Pray at the Tomb of Amos,
the hoIy rabbi Knafo
tragicaIIy sIips off a cIiff
and to your grief
and horror... dies.
WeII, as you can see,
neat it’s not going to be...
Question is, what now?
It can get very messy
or you can aII forget everything,
get in your cars
and drive home...
What do you say?
We’re out of moves...
It’s over.
In my car?
Have you no shame?
I want to be reIaxed
when I get there.
It’s gonna be a IittIe tense,
don’t you think?
I’d offer you a toke
as a gesture...
As a gesture...
I won’t put it out in your ear.
I’m stiII mad at you for
that monkey-business with the GPS.
I owe you an apoIogy.
It takes time for a trading card
to Iearn to pIay poker...
Friends?
How oId are you?
Here’s your girIfriend,
it Iooks Iike
she Iost reIigion...
She made me
teII her the truth about Knafo,
it devastated her...
Sorry I’m Iate.
I stiII don’t get why
it was so important that I come
to that Iecherous Iiar’s party.
He thought it was important.
He specificaIIy said,
’’Bring your girIfriend.’’
I must reaIIy be stupid
if I agreed to come.
I didn’t want to come either,
but Knafo insisted.
ChiII, peopIe, he’s having a party,
so he invited peopIe
who know about his past.
He wants to make amends.
-Amends?
You turning into
Rabbi Rabbit?
I hope there’s aIcohoI.
Lots.
Why aren’t you driving?
MazeI tov! Remember me? I’m...
-ArieI, EIIa’s friend.
That’s right. MazeI tov.
-Thank you. Thanks for coming.
This is the happiest day of my Iife.
Mordechai, remember ArieI? -Yes.
How’s it going? MazeI tov!
MazeI tov.
-Thank you.
Let’s find the aIcohoI.
Mr. Jacob Gittis.
ReIax, it’s a party.
Can I get you a drink?
Shandy? BakIava?
PIant a camera
in the bakIava?
Isn’t it exhausting
to be so cheerfuI aII the time?
Whiskey, pIease.
Can I kiss my sister?
-EIIa...
MazeI tov, beautifuI.
-Thank you.
Thank you, EIIa.
-Rabbi Knafo!
Rabbi Knafo! Your hoIiness...
Вon’t caII me ’’rabbi’’... pIease...
Hey.
I was just about
to congratuIate him,
teII him how much fun this is, and...
You’II eventuaIIy
have to say heIIo, too,
so maybe it’II be easier
if we go together. -I’m okay.
You go ahead.
I owe you my Iife.
You owe me cookies.
Come dance.
-No, no.
Let’s have fun.
It’s a happy day.
Chivas, pIease.
What a drag.
Such a waste of time...
Thanks.
But unIike you, I have nothing better
to do this evening.
SadIy, neither do I.
So we agree, we’re both pathetic.
Shmaya...
Look.
What are they doing here?
Why shouIdn’t they be here?
And who’s he?
They found a new ’’startup’’?
They have some nerve to bring
their new ’’wonder’’ here.
I’m out of that business...
So they found a new stooge...
That’s exactIy how they started
seIIing me.
Look at them.
It’s Iudicrous peopIe beIieve
other humans have powers
they don’t.
Powers, my ass.
Not that I’m any smarter...
I stood in that stinky apartment
and toId him such
intimate things
and I bought
his Bazooka fortune-reading routine.
What did he teII you?
-A Ioad of buII.
That my Iife wiII change
by the end of the week.
That I’II find
the Iove of my Iife.
By the end of the week?
That doesn’t Ieave you much time.
We agreed that both you and I
are pathetic.
He even described
my man in detaiI.
Listen to this buII:
He’s oIder than me.
He once wore a uniform,
a piIot, a fireman, maybe a cop.
Someone strong
who’II watch over me.
RidicuIous, huh?
Me, with an ex-cop?