Operator, would you check it for me?
That line just can't still be busy.
All right. I'll hang on.
Sign here, please.
Yes, Mr. Groves?
Will you check on that shipment
of hobby horses and pinafores
to Jackson and Company?
- 'Certainly.'
- And try my home again, will you?
Yes, sir.
Hobby horses and pinafores?
What a dreamy place to work in.
Yes, I suppose it is.
Here's your book.
All right. Thank you.
- Well, there he is, huh, Jack?
- Yup.
- I like this change in the head.
- Thanks.
- Now all we have to do is find a name.
- I have a name for him.
Rex, the walkie-talkie robot man.
Uh-huh.
- Well, that's what he is. I like that.
- Thanks.
Pass the word around,
tell everyone how pleased I am.
You bet I will.
Rex, the walkie-talkie robot.
- Yes, Miss Walker?
- 'Your home number is still busy.'
- What about the theatre tickets?
- 'They're sold out for this evening.'
'Lf you stop by the theatre,
they may have a cancellation.'
I'll do that. I hope Mrs. Groves
hasn't made other plans.
- 'I'll try your home again now.'
- Never mind. I'm leaving.
I'm going home.
See you in the morning.
- Good night, everybody.
- Good night, Mr. Groves.
Hello?
This is Ellen.
Oh, Gloria, hi.
Mum said I could stay overnight
at your house.
Isn't that absolutely atomic?
Tommy?
Yeah, he invited me to the prom.
I turned him down.
Just because he's the basketball champ
is no reason for him to think...
Dreamy looking?
You call him dreamy?
But he's only 17
and he's already 6' 4".
- Will you give that back to me?
- If you don't hang up, you've had it.
Yes, I'll help you with your homework.
I get As in biology.
It's my favourite subject.
- The least you can do is let me finish.
- I'll count 12. One...
I've got to hang up now, Gloria.
It's my brother.
Now that he's old enough to go steady,
he's an absolute mental case!
- Well, I'll see you later. Bye.
- Eight, nine...
Ten, eleven, twelve.
Oh!
Well, when can I call for you?
About ten minutes? Fine.
Listen, Ann,
are you going to be wearing
my Kappa Tau pin?
Oh, swell.
Eh? Well, you of course.
What about you?
Say it again.
- Marion?
- Shh!
- Oh, I'm sorry, son.
- Okay, Dad.
I'll either have to put another phone in
or buy a flock of carrier pigeons.
I've been trying to call your mother
from the office for at least an hour.
Marion?
- Hello, Daddy.
- Frankie. Why are you dressed up?
Mrs. Rogers, did you iron my sash?
- I'm waiting for the iron to get hot.
- Be very careful with it.
The effect will be ruined
if my sash is scorched.
Just right.
- Suppose you stay and supervise?
- Super what?
See that I do it correctly.
Hello, dear. Oh, they're beautiful.
- Happy birthday, Mrs. Groves.
- Thank you.
- Mother?
- Yes, dear?
- Can I borrow your baby-blue scarf?
- May I...
- May I borrow it?
- Of course. It's in my drawer.
- Thank you. Hi, Dad.
- Hi.
Oh, they're lovely.
I'll put them in a vase.
I'll do that.
You get yourself dolled up.
- But, Cliff...
- I've got it all arranged.
We'll drive into Los Angeles
for cocktails at the Stoddard,
dinner at Bordeau's...
I remembered you mentioning that show
down at the Royal so I stopped by.
I was lucky.
Two seats, first row on the aisle.
Oh, I could cry!
Going to all that trouble,
and in the rain, too.
Don't you know tonight
is the world-shaking event?
- What do you mean?
- The recital of Frankie's ballet class.
- I can't find the scarf anywhere.
- Darling, it's here. There you are.
Thank you.
Look, I'm very grateful
that you were born.
And this is the one day in the year
that belongs exclusively to you.
At my age, a birthday is a time
to turn all mirrors to the wall.
Nonsense.
You're the female Ponce de Leon,
the original fountain-of-youth girl.
- You haven't changed since...
- Mama?
Yes, dear?
Will my hair glitter across the footlights?
- Like a glow-worm, darling.
- Come and help me with my sash.
Marion, Ellen can take her
to the ballet class.
- Ellen has a date.
- Mama!
Coming, darling.
I've got to help her.
Do you know how long it is since
we were in a theatre? Three years.
- Impossible.
- True. Now, you get ready.
I can't. She'd be so disappointed.
In Child Guidance...
Hang Child Guidance!
I'll explain to our little prima donna that
a mother is entitled to a life of her own.
I promised I'd take her.
- You'd want me to keep my promise.
- But...
- Princess?
- Yes, what is it? I'm in a hurry.
I guess your mother can't go
to the theatre tonight.
- How about you going with me?
- Thanks heaps, but I'm not in the mood.
- Gloria and I have emotional problems.
- Your mother told me you were busy.
- I'll need some money.
- Oh.
- Dollar all right?
- I guess so. Thanks.
Yeah, I'll see you in five minutes,
sweetheart.
Vinnie, I don't suppose
you could drive me?
- Sorry.
- Thank you!
I certainly don't see
what attracts poor Ann to you.
Son, I have a couple of tickets
for the Royal.
- I wonder if you'd like to go with me.
- Sorry but I got a date tonight with Ann.
Well, why don't you take Ann?
I hear it's a great show.
I wish we could but it's a double date.
Hello? Yes, Phyllis.
Mother, come on!
Ellen's gone over to Gloria's.
They're going to discuss
their emotional problems.
Goodbye.
- That's Mrs. Jenkins' car. Hurry.
- Coming, darling.
Oh, Cliff.
- Why don't you ask Ed to go with you?
- Yeah, that's an idea.
- Mother, please!
- Just a moment.
- Aren't you going to have dinner?
- We had a sandwich earlier.
I cooked a veal goulash
just the way that you like it.
All you have to do is warm it up.
Marion, let's go away
some place next weekend.
- Why, dear?
- I'd like a change.
I'm tired of the fog
and the smog and the rain.
- Maybe we can go to the desert.
- That would be nice.
Just you and I, alone.
Absolutely alone.
How's Tom?
Well, what ails him?
Stones? Well, how many?
The same thing happened
to a cousin of mine.
He had four stones,
about the size of mothballs.
I got to hang up
or I'll never get out of here.
Yes, yes. Goodbye, Selma.
Could you use a couple of tickets
to the show at the Royal?
Oh, Mr. Groves, any other time
I'd just jump at the chance,
but I promised my daughter I'd baby-sit.
- Good night.
- Good night, Mrs. Rogers.
Yes?
- Clifford Groves!
- Yes...
I'm sorry, I know we've met
but I can't...
Have I changed that much
in these 20 years?
20 years?
- Norma Miller!
- Yes.
I can't believe it. Come in. The rain...
- The rain has stopped.
- Well, come in anyway.
I hope you'll forgive the way I look.
I wasn't expecting anybody.
- I've been cooking.
- Turn around. Let me help you.
Thanks.
Go in, won't you? I'll be right back.
I must apologise
for not having recognised you but...
- You look so different.
- Compared to the plain girl I was?
- I didn't mean that.
- I was plain.
Flat-heeled shoes, no make-up.
Very plain.
- Norma Miller.
- Norma Vail now.
- Norma Vail?
- Uh-huh.
Well, come in and sit down.
- After all these years!
- Yes, all these years.
- I heard you were in New York.
- I have been.
Well, it's certainly wonderful
to see you again.
- It's wonderful to see you, too.
- How did you find where?
Oh, I tried phoning this house six times
but the line was always busy.
So I decided to disobey Emily Post
and surprise you.
It's the nicest surprise I've had in years.
The house is beautiful.
Warm and cheerful.
Just as I had imagined it.
The kind you always wanted.
Yes, I guess I did.
Where is Mrs. Groves?
I'd love to meet her.
Poor Marion. It's her birthday today
and I'd planned a little celebration.
I thought we'd go to dinner
and I had tickets for the theatre but...
she had to go out.
And the kids couldn't go.
They were busy. I have three of them.
I even invited the cook.
I don't suppose you'd like to go?
- Why, I'd love to.
- Really?
We just have time to make it.
I'll go get my coat.
Now, do you want
to go out for a smoke?
No, I don't think so.
This is fantastic.
So completely unexpected,
sitting here again like this.
- Don't you remember?
- No.
The day you cancelled all appointments,
closed the office,
and took me to a matinee
in this very same theatre.
You wanted me to see
my first show direct from Broadway.
The next day you spoiled it all
and made me cry.
You criticised my design
for the Indian doll and I burst into tears.
- I hope I apologised.
- No.
Then I do now.
- Are you still in the toy business?
- Still in it.
Are your offices far from here?
No, they're just a few blocks away.
Why don't you ask me
to skip the second act?
You don't want to see the rest of it?
Well, I'll let you in on a little secret.
I saw this show in New York.
- Oh, well, why didn't you say?
- Oh, come on, Cliff.
I'd love to see
what you've been doing.
All right.
Oh!
Oh, what a wonderful display!
- I hoped you'd like it.
- Oh, Cliff. I'm so proud of you.
A trailer.
I've always wanted
to live in a trailer.
Norma, come here.
Yell, "All aboard."
All aboard!
Works electronically.
It's got a built-in light.
Oh.
It's an exact scale copy of a real one.
It's got a whistle, too.
And what about that one?
It's got a hole in the chimney.
When it heats up, smoke comes out.
End of the line.
Oh, how charming.
I didn't think you'd still be interested
after all these years.
Why not? I design clothes
for live dolls now.
Oh?
For some time I've been in New York
with a chain of dress shops.
- I want to show you upstairs.
- Your workshop?
- Yeah.
- Good.
- I want you to meet Rex.
- Rex?
- Our robot man. He's our latest.
- Oh.
Here, I'll get the light.
We manufacture him
down at the other plant.
Here he is.
Rex, the walkie-talkie robot.
'I'm Rex, the robot,
the mechanical man.
'Push me and steer me
wherever you can.
- 'I'm Rex, the robot...'
- Oh, he's wonderful.
- And he talks.
- Yeah.
- Oh, I adore him.
- We have great hopes for this boy.
Oh, the children will be crazy about him.
Come on. I'll show you
the rest of the workshop.
I remember this.
- Oh, that old relic.
- Relic?
Oh, no.
Oh, I remember it so clearly.
We were walking along the boardwalk
at Redondo Beach
and there was
that little old Italian organ grinder.
He was playing a tune.
What was the name of it?
"Blue Moon".
And you suddenly got the idea for this.
Then we had dinner
at that fish place on the wharf.
I made sketches of it
on the table cloth.
What a time we had
buying the table cloth
so we could get it
into production right away.
Remember how many we sold?
Uh-huh. Two.
One to a fella who owned a monkey.
Trouble is, there weren't enough
fellas with monkeys.
Yes.
Oh, but, Cliff, you've done so well.
And you look so well, so happy.
You are happy, aren't you?
Sure. Sure I'm happy.
You deserve to be.
When I think of all the disappointments.
For a while I didn't think
I'd get out of the red.
I took a gamble.
Tried to use more imagination
than other toy makers. It paid off.
I'm not giving you a chance to talk.
Nothing much to tell.
Hard work. Years of it.
Up the ladder, step by step, so slowly.
You said your name's Vail now.
You're married, then?
I was.
No one should marry
out of loneliness.
But that was a long time ago.
One thing I've never understood is
why you quit your job as my designer.
You didn't even give me a week's notice.
I had my reasons.
Now, when am I going
to meet Marion and the children?
- Come tomorrow night for dinner.
- I have to be in Palm Valley.
- The desert?
- There's a conference at the inn.
Fashion experts from all over
will be there.
I have to make a speech and I dread it.
Why don't we meet over the weekend?
Marion and I plan to go out of town.
Oh, well, you call me when you get back.
I will do that.
Cliff, it's been a wonderful evening.
Yes, it certainly has.
You know, tonight...
...for a little while...
...time stood still.
Well.
Cliff?
Oh, I'm sorry. Did I wake you up?
Did you go to the theatre with Ed?
No, I didn't go with Ed.
- I went with...
- Did you enjoy the show?
- Yes, it was very good.
- Frankie was a big success, too.
She was cute as a button.
Good night, dear.
Good night.
All the new designs
are here in the portfolio.
- Never mind.
- But I thought you'd like to study them.
Mrs. Groves and I are getting away.
Let's leave business out of it.
Hello?
Just a moment, please.
- For you.
- Tell them I've gone.
It's Mr. Andrews
calling from San Francisco.
Hello, Mr. Andrews.
Very well, thank you.
How are you? Good.
We had one of our heavy mists, water
in the streets up over the hub caps.
How's the weather up there?
Sunny, eh? You don't tell me.
The walkie-talkie spaceman?
I'm glad you're impressed with Rex.
I think he's going to be a hot item.
When do you plan on coming down?
This weekend?
Sorry, Mr. Andrews. Mrs. Groves
and I plan to go to Palm Valley.
How about next?
Well, that'd be fine.
I'll see you down there,
Saturday afternoon late, at the inn.
It will be good to see you, too,
Mr. Andrews. Goodbye, sir.
You were going to forget business
while you were away.
I have no objection to spending time
with one of the biggest
department store owners.
Hold down the fort.
I'm sure you and Mrs. Groves
will have a good time.
- Hi.
- Ellen, get towels.
We'll need compresses,
and lots of 'em.
- Towels.
- And turn down Frankie's bed.
The bed.
- What's happened?
- Frankie twisted her ankle.
- How?
- She was skating.
Oh, Daddy, it's broken.
- I'll never dance again. Never.
- Sure you will, honey.
- It's just a sprain.
- The doctor's on his way.
Come on, Pavlova, I'll carry you up.
No, I won't be lame. I can't be. Watch.
Darling! Let me help you.
- I finally got her settled.
- I'm glad it wasn't serious.
We'd better get packed.
We want to get an early start.
Cliff, you don't honestly think I can go
to the desert tomorrow, do you?
Marion, we've planned this trip all week.
Besides, I have an appointment
with Andrews at the inn.
- I didn't expect Frankie...
- Frankie's enjoying her injury.
Children are apt to dramatise.
Dr. Kaufman said the swelling
would be down by tomorrow.
After all, the ankle isn't broken.
I don't care what Dr. Kaufman said.
I want X-rays made to be quite sure.
- That's ridiculous.
- And I couldn't relax
until Frankie sees those X-rays.
Oh, look, Cliff.
If I couldn't relax, neither could you,
so what would be the use
of my going down tomorrow?
Believe me, I wish I could go.
Frankie would feel terribly rejected
with both of us away.
That mustn't stop your going.
- I'll pack your things.
- No, never mind.
I'll wire Andrews, ask him to meet me
in Los Angeles one day next week.
It's just a shame that every time we plan
anything, something gets in the way.
I insist that you go.
Two days of sun and
seeing Mr. Andrews will be good for you.
You'll look so handsome
in your new jacket.
Mother! Mother!
Yes, dear? What is it?
What's the matter?
Ellen's got the lights on.
She's using my cologne.
- Get back in bed right this minute.
- My ankle!
- You see, dear?
- Give me back my cologne!
- Mother! Mother!
- Yes, I see.
Hello. I just have
a bag and a coat in the back.
You picked a nice weekend.
Three women for every man.
We call the cocktail lounge
"bachelors' paradise".
- I'm from Pasadena, too, you know.
- Oh?
Everyone says it's such a social town
but I don't find it so.
You lucky men,
you can always get around.
But when a woman's alone, she can't.
I suppose that's true.
- My, what an attractive jacket.
- Thank you.
My wife picked it out.
She has pretty good taste.
She even buys ties I don't mind wearing.
Oh, really? Excuse me.
I think I'll get some sunshine.
- Certainly.
- Another drink, sir?
Aren't you going to buy me a drink?
Norma! You stayed on!
After the conference I realised
how tired I was, so I stayed on.
- What on earth are you doing here?
- You gave me the idea.
- I didn't dream you'd still be here.
- Is Marion unpacking?
Frankie, our youngest twisted her ankle
and Marion felt she shouldn't come.
I'd have stayed home
but I have a business appointment.
A man's interested in Rex.
- Has he arrived?
- He'll be on the afternoon plane.
- Have you been horseback riding?
- Not yet.
- Why don't you come along?
- I haven't any clothes for it.
- I haven't been on a horse...
- What can you lose except dignity?
Don't worry, Mr. Groves.
Just ride her easy.
- Everything will come back to you.
- Amen.
- Oh, that was wonderful.
- Yes.
You know, Norma, it's so easy
for a man to slip into a rut.
Once he's in it,
he doesn't dare do things he used to do.
He doesn't feel the excitement he felt.
If anything, he feels scared of life.
But you know something? I feel
as if I just made my first touchdown.
And not a day older.
Excuse me.
Do you remember
a tune called "Blue Moon"?
You mean this old one?
- That's it. Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Remember this? Let's dance.
- I haven't danced in a long time.
- All the more reason.
- I've probably forgotten how.
- Mr. Groves, this just came for you.
- Oh, thank you.
- Andrews is not coming.
- Oh, Cliff!
Says he'll meet me next week.
Oh, what a shame,
after all you had planned.
- Maybe it isn't such a shame.
- Oh?
I couldn't relax with Andrews here.
This way I can get
some rest and some sunshine.
- Then you're not going home?
- My reservation is for two nights.
I might as well stay.
Why don't you stay, too?
Well, I don't have to rush back.
- But the only thing is...
- Please, for me.
I'd hate to be alone.
All right, I'll stay.
- Good night.
- Won't you ask me in for a nightcap?
I'm so tired I can hardly
keep my eyes open.
Let's breakfast late.
Better still, let's make it brunch.
- Fine. Call me when you get up.
- All right. Good night.
If your father's on business,
are you sure it will be all right?
He'll be glad to see us.
Won't a swim in a cool, blue pool
feel great, though?
Cool, blue pool? Boy, that's for me.
- Maybe he'll treat us to dinner.
- But if he has an appointment...
- Dad won't mind.
- Come on, step on it, old man.
Gosh, the wind has made
a mess of my hair.
- I'd like to freshen up.
- So would I.
Vinnie, why don't you get your father
and we'll meet you here?
- Mr. Clifford Groves, please.
- Shall I see if he's in, sir?
61, please.
- No one seems to answer, sir.
- Would you try Mr. Andrews?
- Mr. Andrews?
- Mr. Andrews from San Francisco.
- There's no one by that name here.
- Are you sure?
Maybe he's checked out.
I'm sorry. We haven't had a Mr. Andrews
from San Francisco all week.
- Would you page Mr. Groves?
- Certainly.
Boy.
- Would you page Mr. Groves?
- No need. They're together again.
She's with him. I saw him
in front of her bungalow.
Who's she?
Mr. Groves is at Bungalow 57,
Miss Vail's.
- Who?
- A friend of Mr. Groves, Miss Vail.
I'll just wait in his bungalow if I may.
Surely. That's 61.
Out that door and to your right.
Okay.
I don't get it. I just don't get it.
- You sure you heard?
- Of course.
Mr. Andrews is an old pal,
one of the biggest store owners.
He's interested
in one of Dad's new toys.
- You heard that clerk.
- I don't understand.
What about
Miss What's-her-name... Vail?
- I don't know her.
- Maybe she's the business associate.
Listen, I know what you're insinuating,
and cut it out.
You're talking about my father.
What do you say we go
and have a cocktail before dinner?
I'd better get my wrap.
It's getting chilly.
- Can I get it for you?
- No, thanks.
Here's my stole.
- Oh, I dropped my earring.
- Here, I'll get it.
- Ow!
- I'm sorry.
61. That must be Dad's bungalow.
- Ow, Cliff!
- Oh, I'm sorry.
You've got very pretty ears.
I've never noticed them before.
Sounds like they're having a good time.
Thank you.
Cliff?
You always used to wear a flower
in your buttonhole. Remember?
- But I looked like a floor-walker.
- Oh, nonsense.
Nobody's going
to know about this from me.
- I'm not that kind of a friend.
- Just shut up.
Let's get out of here.
- I wonder what's keeping them.
- Honestly!
And men say
they have to wait for women.
Oh, boy, is that pool
going to feel marvellous!
- It's happened before.
- What has?
- Oh, you know, that kind of thing.
- What kind of thing?
- I remember my uncle.
- I don't care about him.
He'd tell my aunt
he had a business meeting.
Then one day she caught him.
He had the sweetest...
I don't want to hear any more.
Oh, there they are.
- Let's get moving.
- What's the matter?
Where's your dad?
What is it, Bob?
Aren't we going swimming?
All right.
Add two and two and get five.
I can count, thank you.
How could you even think such a thing?
Think? I tell you, I saw Dad
and that woman and I heard them.
She's probably a business associate.
Business associates
scarcely act that way.
Sometimes you make me so angry.
You're like a suspicious child.
And you're gullible. It's obvious
he didn't have a business appointment.
I know your father.
He wouldn't lie.
I'm pretty disappointed in you,
Vinnie Groves.
How could you have left
without saying hello to your own father?
I'd have only been in their way.
It's been a wonderful two days.
I'm glad I stayed on.
New York was never like this.
Why do you stay there?
Why don't you come to California?
Well, I'd be foolish to, now that
I've made some sort of success.
Besides, New York
is where my few friends are.
I've never been one
to make casual acquaintances.
You're the only one I know out here.
Norma, when you married,
you said it was out of loneliness.
- Yes, that's right.
- Well, in all these years
haven't you met anyone who?
No. I guess
I just kept myself too busy.
Well, we've a long drive ahead of us.
We'd better get started.
Yes, I guess we had.
- No sign of him yet?
- No sign.
9:30. Should be back by now.
He should.
Look out, Ellen,
or you'll yank those drapes off the wall.
Just take your bow
and get off the stage, hmm?
Wish I could find something funny
to laugh at.
This used to be such a happy home.
Yes, such a happy one.
- Having fun, children?
- Oh, yes.
Sure, lots of fun.
Listen.
We can't let mother know.
Ann, this has got to be our secret.
And if...
He's here.
Be casual.
Don't let on that we know.
- Ann?
- Hmm?
- What should we do?
- Vinnie, this is none of my business.
And I've got no right to advise.
But since you asked me,
I'd say keep your mouth shut.
Why, your father's incapable of deceit.
He'll explain everything.
- I see you know everything about men.
- Shh!
- Oh, hello, everybody.
- He's still got the flower.
- Well, welcome back.
- Thank you.
- Nice to see you, Ann.
- Hi.
- Hello, honey.
- Hi, Daddy.
- Son.
- I thought I heard you come in.
- How nice you got home early.
- How's Frankie?
We had the X-rays taken.
It was just a sprain. She's up.
How tanned you are, and so relaxed.
- See what rest can do?
- Rest?
- I was on the go every minute.
- Did you close the deal?
- Did Andrews sign on the dotted line?
- No, he didn't.
He didn't even show up.
I got a wire saying
he was stuck in San Francisco.
- But I figured I might as well stay.
- Well, I'm glad you did.
- Doesn't Dad look wonderful?
- Didn't it get dull down there?
No, I ran into an old friend.
- You did?
- Good. Who?
Her name's Norma Miller.
She used to work for me.
Now she's a successful dress designer
called Norma Vail.
She was just out in California
on business.
I hope it's all right. I asked her
to come to the house for dinner.
- She wants to meet the family.
- Of course.
It was anything but dull. I hiked and
swam and even went horseback riding.
You must be stiff as a board.
- No, I feel great. I'm not stiff at all.
- You will be. A hot bath for you.
But I don't want a hot bath.
Cliff is such an innocent darling.
Well, I just knew he'd explain everything.
I'm not so sure he did.
What do you mean?
Cliff, why not ask Miss Vail
for tomorrow night?
Fine. I'd better go down and call her now
so she doesn't make other plans.
All right.
My hat's off to him.
- Just like Theodore Dreiser.
- What in the world?
- In "An American Tragedy".
- American what?
The scene where the man pretends
he's innocent
by the simple device
of telling just enough of the truth.
- Really?
- Oh, now, Vinnie!
I tell you, I saw...
He's not wasting any time calling her.
I'm never going to get married.
Miss Norma Vail, please.
Hello? Oh, hello, Cliff.
What?
Dinner tomorrow night?
Oh, that would be fun.
About 8:00? Uh-huh.
Oh, no, no, you don't have to bother.
I'll get a cab.
Well, if you insist.
All right, I'll be waiting. Bye.
Tomorrow night.
Vinnie, must we meet that woman?
What else can we do?
Come in, Cliff.
- Hello, Norma.
- Would you turn on the lights, please?
Thank you. My nails are still wet.
- Can I fan them for you?
- They'll be dry in a few minutes.
I was a little late getting home.
- Can you smoke while you dry?
- Thanks but I prefer my own brand.
Would you get one out of here for?
Oh, Cliff, I'm so sorry.
Think nothing of it, madam.
- Where on earth did you get this?
- Oh, I...
I came across it
before I left New York.
- I look like a wanted suspect.
- Nothing of the kind.
- You were a very handsome man.
- Where was it taken?
Oh, someone snapped it of us
at the annual picnic.
- Oh?
- Yes.
I looked so ghastly,
I cut myself out.
The picnic.
I remember. You mean,
you've kept it all these years?
Oh, well, you know
how women are about mementos.
Yes, I remember.
But you've spoiled all the fun.
- I wasn't going to show you until later.
- Until later?
Yes.
I brought it along to show to Marion.
Oh.
I suppose she has
lots of snapshots of you.
Yes, she has lots of them.
Well, I'll just leave it here.
We'd better go. I don't want to be late
the first time I meet Marion.
Thank you.
- I don't think Vinnie looks like Daddy.
- Yes, Frankie, I think he does.
It's hard for a family to see it.
I can't imagine Cliff with a butch.
- Thank you.
- I do see a resemblance.
You look like your father
when I first knew him.
Really? That's interesting.
I hope I look as pretty as Mother
when I grow up.
Darling, what a lovely compliment
coming from my own daughter.
Of course I want to look pretty.
Not to attract boys
but for the sake of my dancing career.
You may change your mind
in a few years.
I never will, Daddy.
Marion, did you know
Cliff wore a flower in his buttonhole?
He gave it up. He thought
he looked like a floor-walker.
I think Cliff looks very nice.
My father says
that if I keep up my grades,
- I can go to New York next year.
- That's fine.
- Is it your first trip?
- Yes, and I'm so thrilled.
- Oh, I hope you look me up.
- Well, I'd love to.
That's better than waiting for
a man to take you on a honeymoon.
Well, waiting is part of being in love.
Oh, it is?
I beg your pardon, if you'll excuse me.
Vinnie!
- May I be excused, too?
- No.
There's no reason
for you to be rude, too.
You know how she feels about dessert.
Thank you, Mother.
I'm sure you'll pardon me, Miss Vail.
Well, I won't pardon you,
so sit down, young lady.
- Frankie!
- I want to see what Vinnie's doing.
- He looks mad.
- Frankie, sit down at the table.
Don't mind Vinnie. He's a stupe.
Frankie, really!
He's been complaining
of a headache all day.
Ann, do you think
you could persuade him to come in?
Yes, Mr. Groves.
Miss Vail, would you forgive me?
Thank you.
Oh, that's right.
Mow down the entire garden!
- Ann.
- You coddled four-year-old child.
I couldn't help it. Did you see
that business with the flower?
"Waiting is part of being in love"!
You're out of your mind.
- You think I want to believe that?
- Yes.
I don't know why, Vinnie,
but you want to.
I know sordidness and you don't.
Hallelujah, Reverend Groves.
Vinnie, come on back to the table.
Sorry. No, thanks.
I'm positive your father hasn't done
a thing to be ashamed of.
But you know something?
I wouldn't blame him if he had.
There's no sense in talking to women.
They don't know the meaning of logic.
Vinnie!
I hear your recital was a great success.
It must be wonderful
to be a ballerina.
Oh, yes, thank you. Do you know
many famous dancers in New York?
A few.
But I'd trade every New York celebrity
for a family just like this.
- Thank you.
- Well, enough about me.
Ellen, what are your plans
when you finish high school?
She wants to study dramatics.
Ellen, you were asked the question.
What question, Daddy?
Ann, where is Vinnie?
- He went out somewhere.
- What's going on here tonight?
- Cliff!
- I'm to blame for that, Mr. Groves.
- Vinnie's been miserable all day.
- Why?
Well, I quarrelled with him this morning.
Naturally, he wasn't much
in the mood for company.
What did you quarrel with him about?
It's hardly worth mentioning, Mr. Groves.
Let's just talk about something else.
Miss Vail, don't you believe it.
- I'm sorry you have to leave so soon.
- Yes, the time has flown.
Don't forget,
I have the perfect dress for you.
3:00 in the Gold Room.
Ann, say goodbye
to your handsome beau.
- I had a wonderful evening.
- I'll see you out.
No, don't bother.
The cab is right there.
- Good night.
Mrs. Rogers outdid herself.
I think I'll give her a hand cleaning up.
Let me help.
Ellen!
- Who's there?
- I want to talk to your sister. Open up.
Impossible. She hid the key.
Ellen, open this door.
It's no use, Dad.
She's pretending to be asleep.
Please, please, leave me alone.
Dad, she wants to be left alone.
Ellen, if you don't...
Vinnie.
I think you owe your mother and me
an apology for your behaviour tonight.
I owe Mother an apology.
Ann, I've got to have
a serious talk with you.
- I've got to talk to you.
- At this hour?
Please, take a walk with me, Ann.
All right, Vinnie.
Vinnie, would you walk me home,
please?
- Yeah, sure. I won't be long, Mother.
- All right.
Good night, Mrs. Groves.
Thanks for a wonderful dinner.
Good night, Mrs. Rogers.
They quarrelled.
That's the wonderful thing about youth.
In a while they won't remember
what it was all about.
- There wasn't much to do.
- I did most of it between courses.
I think we'll have shrimp salad tomorrow.
Good night.
- That was a pleasant evening.
- It was a hideous evening.
Oh, darling, you're just upset
at the way they behaved.
- They had a love spat.
- That's no excuse for bad manners.
- I'm sure Vinnie and Ellen...
- Go ahead, defend them.
Coddle them
as if they were still in cradles.
Cliff, why are you so upset?
I'll tell you why. I invited an old friend
to our home to meet my family.
I hoped it would be a pleasant evening.
The children made it anything but that.
Why make a calamity out of it?
I am tired of the children taking over.
I'm tired of being taken for granted.
That isn't true.
I'm becoming like one of my toys.
Cliff, the walkie-talkie robot.
Wind me up in the morning
and I go to work.
Wind me up again and I come home
at night, eat dinner and go to bed.
Wind me up the next morning
and I work all day to pay the bills.
I know it's expensive with the children,
but I do try.
I'm not talking about expenses.
I'm talking about life.
My life. Our life.
I'm sick and tired of the sameness of it,
day in and day out.
Don't you ever want to get out,
move around?
I'm constantly moving.
That's how I keep my figure.
- What with looking after the children.
- That isn't what I mean.
I wish I knew what you did mean.
Then I could help.
Every time I plan anything for us,
you find some excuse.
Like your birthday and last weekend.
That wasn't an excuse. Frankie...
The children mean more to you than I do.
Oh, Cliff!
When we were younger,
we did so many things together.
We had fun. No two days were alike.
Life was an adventure but now...
If life were always an adventure,
it would be very exhausting.
Cliff, dear, don't stay out there so long.
You might catch cold.
Oh, what a day I have tomorrow.
I have to pick the laundress up,
return some books to the library,
take Frankie to the dentist,
do some shopping for the children.
Cliff? Cliff, dear, would you open
this jar of hand cream for me, please?
And the marketing.
- I think she's lonely.
- Who?
Norma Vail.
- Why do you say that?
- I sensed it.
Her life's exciting, successful.
Cliff, excitement and success never mean
as much to a woman as to a man.
Nor do they exclude the possibility
of loneliness.
You can bet she doesn't let boredom
into her life. You heard her tonight.
I also saw the way
she looked at this house,
the way she looked
at Frankie, Ellen and Vinnie.
- I feel sorry for her.
- You feel sorry for her?
She's missed
what every woman really wants.
I know she has a big job,
but tonight I was very proud and thankful
for my children and my home and...
...you, of course, dear.
Oh, I'm nice and sleepy.
Darling, please turn off the light.
Miss Norma Vail, please.
Thank you.
Hello, Norma? This is Cliff.
I want to see you.
I have to see you.
Yes, yes, I heard you.
Er... why don't you and Marion
have cocktails with me?
No, I want to see you alone.
Oh.
All right.
I'll meet you in the lobby at 5:00.
I'll be there. 5:00.
Good night, Norma.
Come on in.
Vinnie, it's almost 10:00!
I didn't close my eyes all night.
I've become an insomniac.
Me, too. Isn't it ghastly?
The situation has gotten worse.
Gotten worse? How?
- I heard him call her last night.
- You didn't!
- They're meeting at 5:00.
- What are we going to do?
- We've got to have a showdown.
- Oh, no. With Daddy?
Uh-uh. With her.
- When will that be?
- I don't know. Let's just wait and see.
But it's so terrible, just waiting.
I know.
But we've got to be patient.
Here, hand me my robe,
will you, please?
- If only Ann were on our side.
- Yeah, but she isn't.
I don't understand how she can be
so gullible about the basic facts of life.
'Miss Vail,
Gold Room, please.
'Miss Vail, Gold Room, please.'
We're not merchandising
$5.98 house dresses.
Try and get more distinction in that copy.
- How do I okay these forms?
- Exactly as I explained at the meeting.
Marion, Ann, I'm so sorry
to keep you waiting.
- Miss Byron, Mrs. Groves.
- How do you do?
Please have Mrs. Groves try on 234.
- This way, Mrs. Groves.
- Thank you.
- She'll look stunning in it.
- I need your advice.
- Vinnie has the insane idea that...
- Will you please look at this wire?
- Have I authority?
- I hired you as manager.
When I leave for New York next week,
you'll have to make decisions.
Before Marion gets back,
I want to tell you...
I simply must congratulate you.
Not since Antonelli's in Rome
have I been so impressed by such flair.
It's divine, a special place
for special people,
something Los Angeles always needed.
Goodbye, my dear.
And again, congratulations.
Thank you.
This has been a hectic day.
What's this all about?
Well, it's Vinnie.
He has the fantastic idea that...
I don't think I can even explain it.
But Ann, what's the matter?
There's Marion. I can't talk now.
Miss Vail, doesn't she look fabulous?
- Marion, you look lovely. Doesn't she?
- Yes, it looks beautiful.
It's much too youthful for me.
Well, I'm not exactly an ingenue myself
and I wear the same style.
Why don't you show it to Cliff?
I know he'll rave about it.
Cliff, rave? There speaks a bachelor girl.
After 20 years of marriage,
a husband never raves
about what his wife wears.
Oh, I think he would about this.
Please take it on approval.
Oh, I'm sorry. It's not for me.
So am I,
because you look beautiful in it.
Thank you.
Oh, Ann,
what were you so concerned about?
Well, it's all so unbelievable
to me that...
Well, Vinnie is just
imagining things and...
What things?
'Miss Vail, telephone, please.
Mezzanine office.'
- Excuse me.
- 'Miss Vail, telephone.
'Mezzanine office.'
Miss Vail speaking.
West coast editor of what?
All right, put her on.
Miss Duran, how nice of you to call.
Well, frankly I shudder
at the thought of your interviewing me.
Tonight? I'm sorry,
I have an appointment.
But... maybe I should try
to get out of it.
Um...
Shall we say 7:30 at my hotel?
Fine. Thank you.
Thank you.
I'm sorry you didn't think the dress
was right for you, but do come in again.
Thank you for trying. I really must rush.
Cliff isn't coming home for dinner.
A business appointment.
I'm picking Frankie up
and taking her to dinner and a movie.
- I hope we'll see you soon.
- Yes, of course.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
Come on, Ann.
Hello? Just a moment, please.
Mr. Groves?
It's for you.
Miss Vail.
Well, I'll take it in my office.
Hello, Norma. I was just leaving.
I'm terribly sorry but I'm afraid
I'll have to break our appointment.
Oh? Why?
Something just came up,
an interview.
Couldn't I see you later?
It won't take the whole evening.
I'm afraid it will.
I'll call you tomorrow.
Cliff, did you hear what I said?
All right.
He told Mother he had
a business appointment this evening.
- I don't believe it.
- I heard it with my own ears.
That's him now.
- Why, Mr. Groves.
- Good evening, Mrs. Rogers.
- Where is everyone?
- When Frankie heard you'd be late,
she begged her mother to take her out
for steamed clams and a movie.
Ellen's up in her room
and as for the love birds,
they're around somewhere.
Let me go!
What have I done now?
It's not so much what you've done,
it's what you've been thinking.
Ann, this is my problem.
Can't you let me
work it out my own way?
- If you love me...
- Love a child like you?
- Child?
- Yes.
Suspecting your father
of a cheap back-alley romance.
I thought I was going steady with a man
but you're just a little boy.
I'm surprised you haven't run to
your mother, howling your suspicions.
Just let me alone, Vinnie.
I can't love a man I don't respect.
Ann!
- Why don't you quit Therese?
- Start your own business on the coast.
Why stay in New York?
What's the attraction?
Are the men that much more attractive?
I've hardly had time
to make a comparative survey.
It's such a clear, cool evening.
The city must look beautiful.
- Oh, it does.
- I know.
Let's make Norma fall in love and marry.
Then she'll have to stay.
That would be bigamy. I'm already
married happily to 738 Madison Avenue,
Therese Originals...
Why, Cliff, what a nice surprise.
The man at the desk
told me you were here.
Oh, Mr. Clifford Groves,
Miss Duran, Mr. Carl.
Their slightest whim dictates what
women wear from Seattle to San Diego.
Cliff is a very old friend.
Persuade her she must never
go back to New York.
- Make her stay here, Mr. Groves.
- Open Vail Creations in Los Angeles.
It's getting late and we must go.
It's been a grand evening.
- Good night.
- I'll call you in the morning, Norma.
I've got to talk to you.
What is it?
I've fallen in love with you.
Oh, no.
No, this can't happen.
- I didn't mean for this to happen.
- But it has happened.
When I found you carried my picture,
I knew you were in love with me, too.
That's why you said
you couldn't meet me.
I did have an appointment.
You met Ruth...
No, you were afraid, weren't you?
After you called, I went home.
For years I'd always felt
comfortable in that house.
I sat down, I tried to read the paper,
I tried to relax, but I couldn't, Norma.
I felt desperate
sitting in my own living room.
I felt as though I were trapped
in a tomb of my own making
and all the years until today
were stones closing up the tomb
and I had to escape
because I was still alive,
alive and wanting you.
Oh, please, Cliff, please!
You said you were lonely.
You'll never be alone again.
You'll never go away from me.
Pardon me, sir.
This is our first trip to America.
- Is the Hollywood Bowl open?
- No, not till midsummer.
- Thank you, sir.
- Thank you.
- Can't we go some place?
- Cliff, let me alone.
- Darling, I love you.
- Please.
I beg you, let me alone now.
All right. When will I see you?
- Tomorrow.
- When?
After work.
I'll be waiting here.
Daddy!
- Mum and I had the coolest time.
- Yes, real cool.
We went to dinner and saw a show.
- It was dreamy, the positive end.
- Fine, darling.
You're an old stay-out. You just home?
I was home earlier
but I went out again.
Take these in to Mrs. Rogers.
Three dozen most heavenly shrimp.
I found them at the shopping centre.
They looked simply...
- Cliff, something wrong?
- Wrong?
- You sound funny. You catching cold?
- No, no, I'm all right.
- Why are you staying out here?
- I didn't feel like going in just yet.
- Cliff, is something wrong at the office?
- No, I just have a little headache.
- I'll give you some aspirin.
- I want to get some air.
Fine, we'll get some air.
Mrs. Groves, are the shrimp for?
- Ellen's doing well with her music.
- Yes, very well.
- I missed you tonight.
- Oh? But you had fun with Frankie?
Not really.
It was lonely dining without you.
The movie was so young and romantic,
I kept wanting your shoulder to lean on.
- Mother!
- It's always the children.
What did you do with my pyjamas?
Miss Vail, did the airline
contact your office?
They have your reservation
to New York a week from today.
Well, tell them to cancel it, please.
I'll be glad to, Miss Vail. How long
will you be staying on in Los Angeles?
I don't know yet.
Of course I sympathise with you,
but maybe it was all for the best.
Maybe Ann wasn't
the girl for you. Fate...
- There'll never be another girl like Ann.
- It's all out of our hands.
- Sometimes you lack understanding.
- Raising your voice won't help.
Everyone else round here is playing it
to the hilt. Why shouldn't I?
You're right. Arguing won't help.
- This has got to be done.
- What?
- Come on, get your coat.
- Why?
Do as I say.
- Vinnie, I'm scared.
- Come on.
We've gone too far to turn back now.
- Yes? May I help you?
- Miss Vail, please.
- Who's calling?
- Mr. Groves.
Just a moment, please.
- Will you ring Miss Vail, please?
- Oh, Vinnie.
Hello?
Miss Vail?
There's a Mr. Groves in the lobby.
Mr. Groves?
Yes, have him come up, please.
Will you go up, please? 618.
Yes, thank you.
620.
619.
618. Suppose he's with her?
Cliff, I just got...
Why, Vinnie, Ellen.
Come in.
What a nice surprise.
I just got back from work
a few minutes ago.
Could I get you something?
Some hot chocolate or some tea?
No, thank you.
We want to ask you something.
Yes?
Wouldn't it be better
if you went back to New York?
Why?
- Because of what's going on.
- Going on?
Yeah. Between you and my father.
I drove to Palm Valley
the weekend you spent with him.
I saw you, heard you.
And just exactly
what did you see and hear?
In your bungalow.
Both of you were laughing so...
...so intimate.
So intimate?
Oh, Vinnie!
Listen, children. In Palm Valley
two old friends met by chance.
They had some good talks,
laughed over old memories.
They had fun. That's all there was to it.
I want you to believe me.
Don't you?
I do.
But later, when Daddy came home,
Vinnie says he kept calling you,
at night.
He made a date
to see you yesterday.
I don't usually go around snooping
but I had to think of my mother.
Oh, yes.
Yes, it's always Mother, never Father.
That's unfair.
Your father has been neglected
for a long time by a family he loves.
- That's not true.
- You've treated him shamefully.
Everyone has taken him for granted
because he's a good man.
Do you know how much he loves you?
You should hear his plans
for your future, Vinnie.
And how his eyes shine
when he speaks about the princess.
Yes, in spite of your rudeness
the other night at the dinner table.
Do you think if you gave your father
half the love you give your mother,
you would have needed to come here
with your accusations today?
Why should Cliff need me
if he was given love at home?
Why would he go outside for it?
- We love Father.
- Then why neglect him?
Why do you take and not give back
one shred of love in return?
How many years do you think
a man will put up with that?
So that's why he fell in love with you.
Listen, Ellen...
Love is a very reckless thing.
Maybe it isn't even a good thing.
When you're young and in love,
nothing matters
except your own satisfaction.
The tragic thing
about growing older is that...
...you can't be
quite as reckless any more.
You begin to understand
what is important and what is not.
And to your father,
the most important thing, believe me,
is his family's happiness.
You couldn't be as blind
as not to have known that.
Can you blame anybody but yourselves
if he is thinking of leaving you?
Oh, Miss Vail, I know we're to blame.
But please...
Please don't take Daddy away from us.
Don't take him away!
I'm sorry. I'm late.
I have an appointment.
- Here's a sketch of the doll.
- It looks very nice, Mr. Groves.
- Could I see the doll made up?
- Do we have one in the stockroom?
- Show it to Mr. Mayer, will you?
- This way, please.
Watch your head here.
What about Rex, Mr. Mayer?
Send me a gross of them
and I'll see how he sells.
I have an appointment. I'll have to run.
Jack will take good care of you.
Remember that place
overlooking the ocean?
- Cliff, listen to me.
- I've been planning all day.
Do you remember that place
where we celebrated my first contract?
We'll drive there now.
We'll sit by the fire
and watch the storm on the ocean.
- I'm trying to tell you something.
- I'm sorry. What is it?
I'm flying to New York tonight
on the 6:00 plane.
Why?
- Norma, nothing makes any difference.
- Listen to me carefully.
20 years ago I left here
because I was in love with you.
Yes.
Norma Miller, the little girl
who couldn't face reality.
Today Norma Vail is leaving
because she can face reality.
- There's only one reality.
- No.
The only reality is 20 years
of Clifford Groves as a husband
and as a father.
20 years of my being a career woman
with an eye
to design and merchandising.
- Norma, I love you.
- No, no.
No, you don't love me.
It's your...
It's your search for youth,
to push back the years,
to feel carefree again.
And you can't, not ever.
None of us can.
That isn't life.
But you have a wonderful life
with Marion and the children.
And I, too, have a life.
And I'm going back to it.
You can't leave me.
And if I don't leave you?
What would you do
the day we're together
and you read in the paper
that Vinnie Groves is graduating?
You'll want to run from me
and be with him,
but you'll wonder if he'll see you.
And the day you hear
about the first professional recital
of that young dancer, Frances Groves.
You'll feel sick at not being invited.
And I'll feel sick for you.
- Norma!
- And Ellen's wedding?
- Stop it, Norma.
- Oh, no, her father isn't here.
He ran away with another woman,
remember?
At his age! The poor kid.
- Norma!
- Oh, face it, Cliff! I've had to face it.
You know you'll want
to see Marion again,
hear her voice, quarrel with her
over the bills and the children.
She's the one who belongs in your life.
Your first love.
And that's the way it should be.
It's such a good life.
What have I to give you
to take its place?
Be happy, Cliff.
You will be happy.
Norma!
Pardon me, Cliff, about the doll.
- I'm sorry.
- Mr. Mayer here...
Taxi.
Norma!
Ann. Ann, wait.
Let me explain.
I went to see Norma.
She's a wonderful woman.
Well, that's no surprise to me.
What do you want me to say?
That I've been a kid? I admit it.
And I was wrong
about Norma and Cliff, too.
What more do you want?
I've learned a lot in the last 24 hours,
but most of all what it means
to really care for someone.
Well, you needn't be so forcible about it.
I love you.
I never knew how to give love,
only how to take it.
I guess it's the hardest job to learn
in the whole world,
how to give love
and expect nothing in return.
Well, what do you know.
Long pants at last.
Oh, Vinnie!
- Ellen, where did you put my cologne?
- It's on the dressing table somewhere.
It is not. I looked.
Oh, yes, Gloria, hi.
- Where is it?
- You're too young to use it anyhow.
- That's what you think.
- It's Frankie being dramatic again.
- Yes, go on.
- You're the ham.
But Gloria, darling,
the question is, can a woman like me
love a basketball player all of her life?
Ooh, cut out the mush!
Oh, yes, tell me all about it.
- He did?
- Who did?
Oh, Gloria!
- Gosh, that's awful...
- Hi, Daddy.
Hello, Pavlova.
Is it still raining?
No, it's stopped raining.
Oh, Daddy, hi.
- Hello, Princess.
- I'll be through in a minute.
I'll be at your house at 8:00
and we can do our homework.
I want my cologne.
Yes, Gloria. Okay, see you tonight.
Bye.
Hello, Dad.
Hello, Vinnie.
- How are you feeling?
- I'm... I'm fine.
- I'm glad.
- My watch seems to have stopped.
- Dad, what time is it?
- Oh...
- It's a little after 6:00.
- Thanks.
Gloria and I have emotional problems
to discuss. New ones.
- Would you like a magazine?
- No, thank you.
Hello, dear.
Feeling better tonight?
What?
You've worried me these last few days.
It's not like you to be irritable.
I know.
- But I'm all right now.
- Good.
You know me better
than I know myself.
I should after a lifetime with you.
They make a handsome couple,
don't they?