The doctor's decision is...
Lillian Kramer stays on
in the marathon!
The doctor assures me Lillian
just has a slight sinus headache.
Headache.
For all that quack knows, she's...
she's got a brain tumor.
No, I don't think so.
I'm not exactly sure, but I think
it's different with a brain tumor.
Different symptoms.
Yeah? How do you know?
I saw it in a movie...
...with Anita Louise
and Richard Cromwell.
That's what she died of--
Anita Louise.
A brain tumor,
but it was different.
Everything just suddenly
got dim for her one day.
Until finally, she couldn't see at all.
She couldn't even see Richard Cromwell
when she kissed him good-bye.
Yeah?
Then what, she just died?
Kind of.
She just drifted off
listening to her favorite tune.
And then she was dead.
No pain or anything?
They probably lied.
Bobby?
Come on, kid.
Come on.
Come on, break's over.
- Tommy?
- Yeah, Sailor.
Kid's sleeping.
Frank, we got a dead one here.
Give me that ammonia.
- Do you know where you are?
- What?
- Give him another dose.
- No!
Leave him alone.
Are you all right?
Hang on to me.
- You sure you can make it?
- He's gonna be okay now.
- I asked him, not you!
- Sure.
Yeah, yeah, I'm all right.
Here.
Just like in marriage, folks,
these kids have got to get off
by themselves once in a while,
but exhausted as they are,
it's tougher to stay
on their feet alone,
so keep your eyes on them,
because it may be all over soon
for one of these brave,
struggling kids.
Get your hot dogs!
Hot dogs!
Red hots! Hot dogs!
Get your hot dogs!
Only a nickel!
Five cents!
Hot dogs!
Get your red hots!
- What's the matter?
- Get 'em off me!
- What?!
- Get 'em away!
What?!
Matron! Nurse!
- What's the matter?
- They're crawling all over me!
- Get them off me!
- There's nothing--
Help me, please.
- They're crawling all over me!
- You're all right.
- There is nothing wrong.
- Hold her down!
- What's the matter with her?
- She's squirreling.
Hold her!
Tell 'em to turn up the Victrola.
Please help me!
That won't help her none.
Shirl...
They're crawling on me!
Listen to me, Shirl.
Listen to me.
They're crawling on me!
Where are they? Tell me.
Tell me where they are.
Here, on your arm?
They're gone.
Here, on your shoulder?
- Yes.
- There.
They're all gone.
- They're all gone?
- Yes, they're all gone.
Better douse her in the shower.
Come on, honey, you're all right.
You're all right.
That's quite a technique.
I would've thought you'd put her
on display, charge a little extra.
No. It's too real.
Gloria?
I hope that little episode in there
didn't shake you up too much.
No.
Cigarette?
Ten minutes rest, folks,
and then the dance goes on and on.
Remember, one admission
entitles you to stay as long as you like.
So, while the kids are resting and being
attended to by our medical staff,
why don't you visit
our beautiful Palm Garden,
where we serve refreshments
of all types.
Thank you, thank you
Yowsah!
Yeah, that looks
kinda like her dress.
It is.
You can tell just looking at it.
Well, even if it is her dress,
it's ruined now.
There's nothing I can do about it.
But aren't you gonna try
to find out?
I mean, somebody stole it
and ripped it all up.
Maybe you should call everyone together
and try and find out who did it.
It wasn't one of the kids.
How do you know?
Because I took it.
- But why?
- For the good of the show.
That's what we're all
interested in, isn't it?
The show.
No, it's a contest.
Isn't that what it's supposed to be?
Isn't that what you advertised?
A contest.
Not for them.
For you maybe, but not for them.
You think they're laying out two bits a throw just
to watch you poke your head up into the sunlight?
Or Alice look like she just
stepped out of a beauty parlor?
They don't give a damn whether
you win or James and Ruby
or Mario and Jackie or the Man
in the Moon and Little Miss Muffet.
They just want to see a little misery out there
so they can feel a little better, maybe.
They're entitled to that.
Look at us.
We're all like this now.
Dirty, swollen feet, no sleep.
What do you want?
Isn't that enough?
Sure, as long as they can believe in it.
But how can they with Alice
looking like she's on her way
to a ball at Buckingham Palace?
She was breaking the spell.
Now she looks like she's supposed to,
so now they can believe in her.
Simple enough?
Why don't you go sack out
while you got a little break time left?
Yeah.
Robert?
Take me outside.
- We can't.
- Please.
Alice, break's almost over.
We can't.
Somewhere.
Please, anywhere.
Talk to me.
Alice...
Tell me things.
Talk to me.
Hold me.
My strap--pull it down.
Kiss me, hold me.
Talk to me.
Talk to me, Robert.
- What about?
- About you, about yourself
The buttons.
About where you grew up.
Tell me where you were born.
Chicago.
I was born in Chicago.
Chicago. I've never been there.
I can't imagine it.
Tell me about your family.
- What does your father do?
- He's dead.
He was a pharmacist,
but he died.
- It's caught, Alice.
- Pull it.
He caught the flu and he died.
It's caught.
I can't get it undone.
- What should I do?
- Pull it!
There.
Kiss me.
Touch me.
Kiss me, kiss me.
- Alice, somebody's gonna come in.
- It doesn't matter.
Kiss me.
Tell me about your--
Did you have brothers?
- Sisters?
- No.
I had a brother.
He died at the Somme.
Guess what his name was.
Try to guess.
- I don't know.
- Guess, guess!
- It's so easy.
- George. Robert.
- No.
No, wait, don't leave.
- Alice, I--
- Don't, don't.
After a few minutes,
play my favorite number.
- Well, shall we dance?
- Go to hell.
Perfect.
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
our own Russ Columbo--
Mr. Coley James.
Gloria?
Hot dogs!
Premier Mussolini was promoted
tonight, says Norman H. Davis,
American disarmament
representative at Geneva,
at a dinner in one
of the leading hotels of Rome
Signore Marconi, the inventor,
various members of the cabinet,
and Alexander Kirk,
American Charge d'Affaires
with members of the American
Embassy staff also attended.
Following cordial conversations
with the Premier
and his cabinet members,
Mr. Davis went
to Mr. Kirk's home, where they...
Don't touch me.
...results of the election
over the radio
Mr. Davis continues
his disarmament discussions today
with Italian experts in a long
interview at the Foreign Office.
In Boston, Anthony Bender, 43,
was allowed to vote,
but first,
he had to prove he was alive.
When Bender entered
the polling place,
he was challenged,
"Sorry, you can't vote here."
"Why not?" he asked.
"You're listed as dead,"
he was told.
Bender immediately produced
proof he was very much alive,
and officials decided
he could cast his ballot.
Firemen in Detroit
are still battling the fire
that has claimed the life of Johnny Sciutto
and his brother Guido.
Fire Chief DeCoine says containment
is not expected until early tomorrow morning
Damage is estimated
in excess of $41,000.
This is 50,000 watt
Clear Channel station KFI...
- Don't!
- in downtown Los Angeles.
And now,
a look at the weather.
Temperatures are expected
to drop to the middle 40s
in parts of the San Joaquin Valley...
Late night and early morning fog
is expected at all beach areas,
with temperatures in the low 50s.
Tomorrow should be
clear and warmer,
with a high of 64 downtown,
60 at the beaches, and 68...
I changed my mind.
Your partner's waiting for you
She was leaning against the railing.
She was completely relaxed,
completely comfortable.
I didn't have a perfect view,
but I could see enough of her face and lips
to see that she was...
...smiling.
One thousand hours!
And to help us
celebrate the occasion,
Jeff Maxon and his music!
Take it away, Jeff!
Yowsah! One thousand hours
of continuous dancing.
Forty-two days
of grueling, grinding,
gravity-defying gyration,
and here they still are.
Twenty-one courageous couples
still dancing
And how long before
one of them, and just one,
will survive to win
the monster marathon?
Gloria?
Who's that?
No one.
You wanna talk?
No.
I wish you'd go back to her.
How?
You know what she thinks.
That didn't happen.
- Wanna move on the other side?
- No.
- Sleep?
What the hell do you want?
- Anyone ever tell you you're--
- Yeah, they told me.
And don't forget, folks,
ladies free at matinee tomorrow.
Until 3pm, that is.
And I have an important announcement here
about John Hirschman,
reserved seat cashier.
He is now happily convalescing
at Santa Monica Hospital
after a severe attack of appendicitis
We know that you'll join us
in congratulations to him
and wishing him a speedy recovery
Thank you, thank you, thank you
Inside of the floor.
These people are paying to see you.
- All right.
- Come on.
I'm coming!
Moon belongs to everyone
The best things in life are free
The stars belong to everyone
They gleam there for you and me
The flowers in spring
The robins that sing
The sunbeams that shine
they're yours, they're mine
And love can come to everyone
The best things in life are free
Beautiful, beautiful!
How about that?
Wasn't that nice?
Our own number 68!
This is Ruby Fix, a lovely little lady
with an armful of charm
a roomful of courage,
and a houseful of hope.
And I know you all join me
in wishing her and her bundle of joy
a joyous ride through life.
I just hope it was worth it to ya.
We need the money.
It's celebrity time again tonight, folks.
A welcome
for Miss Helen Twelvetrees
and that rising young star,
Mr. Ross Alexander!
But every night is celebrity night
at the mammoth marathon.
Yowsah, yowsah, yowsah!
She looks like her kinda.
Who?
Like my aunt.
God, what a bitch.
He said he was gonna be here.
lf there was a prize for bitchiness,
she'd have won.
Glasses, short balding guy.
Pits, like from acne.
Christ, you should've
heard her screaming.
- "Get that mangy mutt outta here."
- He's assistant director.
"You ain't bringing no animal
into my boarding house."
He's going on a ten-day
western at Monogram.
I wouldn't have brought him
back there, anyway.
Maybe something for me in it.
Something, maybe.
He just followed me, that's all.
Maybe, maybe. Maybe.
And I wouldn't have kept him,
except she started screaming.
I hope he wasn't stringing me.
I said I'd tell her husband she was
screwing one of the boarders,
- Crumb.
- which she probably was
But he was sick inside
with something.
Her husband?
No.
The boarder.
No, for Christ's sake, the dog!
And it kept getting worse, so he'd shake
all the time and dirty himself all over...
and whine and cry all night long.
Stupid damn thing!
He kept whimpering
and hollering and wouldn't shut up.
I mean, what the hell is God doing
sitting around up there?
What the hell good is He if He can't
make one lousy sick dog shut up
and stop waking up
her goddamn boarders?
And you know what I did?
See, after everybody had gone to bed,
I carried him down to the parlor.
And she had this mohair sofa--
it was her favorite one.
And I fixed him a place on it.
What the hell, forget it.
You should be sleeping.
I'd just wake up.
You want anything?
Something for your feet?
How about a saw?
Is there anything the doctor can give you?
Something to make you feel better?
- What's he got?
- Some aspirin.
That's what I figured.
- Have you seen Joel?
- I seen him, all right.
Boy, that's a real sweetheart
you picked this time--just like that.
And I'm the one
that's gotta tell Rocky.
Cheers.
Don't give me any of that song
and dance crap! What's going on?
Just exactly what appears
to be going on.
I've shaved, I've changed,
and I am now packing.
- For what?
- I have a job.
It's not much of a job,
but it's a job.
Ten days in a Monogram western.
You bastard!
You're not running out on me!
No? Just stand there
and watch, sweetheart.
Will she make it?
After over 1,100 hours
of incredible endurance,
there she is, alone,
but still fighting,
still hoping,
still trusting--Gloria Beatty.
Seventeen hours--
that's all she has left.
Will she find a new partner
before those hours run out?
Will fortune reward
her pluck and spirit?
Will she make it?
I ain't quittin'.
I'm not gonna give up.
How are the tabs?
Pretty much the same.
Phone calls are down,
cleaning's up.
Yeah?
What happens
if I don't get a partner?
You've got 11, almost 12 hours.
I can count.
What happens?
You know the rules.
You could change 'em.
No. The crowd's got to have
something they believe in.
Once they quit believing,
they quit coming.
Anything else, but not that
Tommy, we got a dead one.
Just give him to me.
Here we go.
Jesus!
If two knees
touch the floor, she's out!
Come on! Come on!
Come on, Sailor!
Out! Take her away.
Miss Shirley Clayton.
We're going to miss you, Shirl.
Isn't that right, folks?
So long, Shirl, but don't despair.
Every heart in this room is with you,
and that's what really counts.
It's hard on all of us,
after we've lived all these hours
and weeks together,
to see one of these wonderful,
courageous kids fallout.
But life goes on,
and so does the marathon!
Three minutes left!
Three minutes of harrowing,
heart-breaking hustle!
Yowsah!
Over 1,200 hours
of continuous dancing,
and yet there they still are,
fighting, struggling to stay in the race
But the last three couples will lose
The last three couples
will be eliminated!
Yowsah, yowsah!
Come on, let's hear it, folks!
Let's hear it over there!
- What's the matter? What's wrong?
- My chest!
Come on, lean on me.
Put your arm around me.
Lean on me!
Where does it hurt?
What is it?
One minute!
It's just a little bit further!
Come on, you salty old bastard!
Where's the fight? Come on!
Come on, goddamn it!
Hang on to me!
I'm tired of losing!
Come on!
It looks like our sea faring man and our little
hard luck lady are in deep trouble.
Come on, goddamn it!
We're gonna make it.
Thirty seconds!
Walk!
Walk! Walk!
Walk, goddamn it!
Walk!
We're gonna make it!
- Five!
- Walk!
- Four!
- Come on!
Three! Two! One!
Scratch them three kids,
- and there are the losers!
- Sailor, we made it!
Get 'em to the spots.
- Arthur and Jean...
- Sailor!
Pattie and Don,
Dusty and Jessel...
We made it!
Let's have a big hand
for the losers.
Come on, folks, let's hear it
It looks like our ancient mariner
may have taken a little spill.
There's nothing to worry about
He's all right!
Leave him alone!
- Get her off me!
- No, please!
- Get her out of here!
- He's gonna be all right!
What are they doing to him?
He's gonna be all right.
I just had a message
from our house physician.
Nothing in the least serious
Just a case of heat prostration.
And I understand that Harry,
crusty old salt that he is,
wanted to stay on in the marathon,
but the doc says "no,"
and when it comes to something like this,
the doctor's word is law.
He's gonna be all right.
So long, Sailor.
But we know
you'll be back to see us
and to cheer the other kids on.
You have ten minutes
to enjoy yourself
in our beautiful Palm Garden.
But I'm not better off.
I'm sorry.
Alice
Oh, my God.
Get out of the way.
Get out of here.
Come on, move, dammit!
You can come out now.
Nobody's gonna hurt you
Don't you wanna come out now?
You might catch cold in there.
You don't wanna do that, do you?
Please.
I just wanna help you.
I just wanna turn off
the water, that's all.
I just wanna turn off the handle.
All right, I won't...
...if you don't want me to.
Tell me.
Whatever it is, you can tell me.
He...touched me.
Who?
Get out of here!
Is he dead?
Sailor?
You mean Sailor?
No.
You have my personal word
he's gonna be fine.
Someone screamed.
That was you, Alice.
Boy meets girl,
boy loses girl, boy gets girl!
That's the story
of our sweetheart couple--
Gloria Beatty and Robert Siverton!
Yowsah, yowsah, yowsah!
Now, I'm no Hollywood scenario writer,
but I know what
the end of this story should be.
Right, Robert?
Right, Gloria?
Wrong.
Does the prisoner wish to make a statement
to the court before sentence is passed?
No.
No, sir.
Come in, come in, kids.
Just sit down,
make yourselves comfortable.
I know this is your rest period,
so just sit down and rest.
I had a little notion, kids--
something that could help the show,
something could benefit all of us.
And in particular,
it could benefit the two of you,
and at the same time,
give the folks out there
something to get worked up about.
What are you gonna do--put us in cages
and let 'em throw peanuts at us?
All kidding aside--
Who's kidding?
The thing I want is I want
you two kids to get married.
Right here on the dance floor.
A public wedding.
I mean, you get divorced
right after the show, if you want.
It's just for effect.
What do you say to that, Robert?
- I don't know, I guess so.
- He says no.
Does she do
all the talking for you, Robert?
That's right.
Well...
Robert, maybe it'd be better
if just her and me discussed it.
Okay?
Yeah, sure.
But the idea is okay with you.
That's what you said, right?
No, sir, I didn't say that at all.
All I said was--
It's the same thing,
it's the same thing.
It'll just be a minute.
What's your problem?
You're afraid of getting married?
You're not happy until you've
screwed everything up, are you?
Wait a minute.
Wait, wait.
I'm not marrying anybody!
It's business!
Strictly business, for God's sake.
Look, you come out with something--
new clothes...
...plenty of free gifts, silverware,
waffle irons, toasters,
that kind of stuff.
What am I gonna do
with crap like that?
Sell it, hawk it!
Look, for God's sake,
I'm trying to help you a little.
Maybe you'll come out
with 2 or 300 bucks--that's something.
Unless you wanna walk out of here
with the pennies they're throwing at you
Yeah? And what if
just maybe we win?
Look, sweetheart, I've been
in this business a long time.
I may not know a winner
when I see one...
...but I sure as hell can spot a loser.
You son of a bitch!
Maybe.
Do you wanna come out of this
with a couple hundred bucks or don't you?
The winners get 750 apiece.
Right, less the bills.
What bills?
Look, this marathon
don't run itself, you know.
I got bills stacked up every day.
And I keep tabs.
You kids cost me money.
Extra laundry, cleaning, phone calls,
medical bills, you name it.
What is this?
The tabs on you and Robert.
You're charging me this?
Only if you win.
If you don't win, you don't pay.
I'm not out to cheat anybody.
Oh, Jesus.
Gloria, we have to get back.
What the hell's the point?
Right.
Where the hell's the other one?
Well, don't just stand there.
Why don't you help me?
What does it look like exactly?
Like this. What do you think
it's gonna look like, a necktie?
I'll tell you one thing.
I'm not leaving this
goddamn stink hole without it.
That's the last pair I got.
And I cut out streetcars
for a month to get 'em.
Is this it?
No, for Christ' sake, it's silk.
I found it.
Here, is this it?
Yeah.
Jesus, I'm sorry.
Gloria, don't...
Look, maybe you can
fix it up or something,
sort of sew it up or...
Gloria, let me see it.
Maybe you can sew it up.
I've still got 71 cents.
Maybe I can buy--
Shut up!
It's not
the goddamn stocking, anyway.
Forget it.
I used to love
to look at the ocean...
...walk by it,
just sit and listen to it.
Now I don't care
if I ever see it again.
That...or anything else.
What are you gonna do now?
Try the movies again?
No.
I'd never make it.
And maybe it wouldn't
make no difference even if I did.
Maybe it's just the whole
damn world is like Central Casting.
They got it all rigged
before you ever show up.
I know what you mean.
I know just what you mean.
Do you?
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna get off
this merry-go-round.
I'm so sick
of the whole stinking thing.
What thing?
Life.
And don't give me
no sunshine lectures.
I wasn't going to.
Then what were you
looking at me that way for?
I wasn't.
I was just trying to see your face
Well, keep looking.
Stick around for the end.
Help me.
Please. Please.
Tell me when.
I'm ready.
Now?
Now.
What happened?
Just move on.
Better things to do. Beat it.
Come on, let's go.
Let's go.
Why'd you do it, kid?
She asked me to.
Obliging bastard.
That the only reason
you got, kid?
They shoot horses, don't they?
Yowsah, yowsah, yowsah!
Here they are again!
These wonderful, wonderful kids,
still struggling, still hoping
As the clock of fate ticks away,
the dance of destiny continues!
The marathon goes on
and on and on.
How long can they last?
Let's hear it!
Come on!
Subtitles ripped by adamax