Hit me.
I'm serious.
I can't feel anything.
Hit me.
Again!
Do it harder!
Oww!
I can't feel anything!
This is so awesome!
I hear this little "wah-wah-wah"
inside my head.
That's your brain cells popping.
- Do it.
- You want me to do it?
No, no, no.
Hit me!
Harder! Punch me!
- Ohh!
Oww.
Hit me really hard.
Really.
- Okay. I'm gonna plunk you.
- Okay! Go!
- Aah!
- Oh, shit!
Oh! Oh, fuck!
Yeah!
Come on, Hampton.
Come on.
- Come on, baby!
]
Mom! Come on, it's 7:45.
Let's go, let's go.
I'm ready. Hey, Noel.
- Mason, come on!
- Come on, Mason!
- Where's the new backpack?
- It's already in the back seat.
Hey, wait. Let me fix this before
somebody gives you the wedgie from hell.
- Thank you.
- Mason!
What's up, guys? Hey, Noel.
- Bitch.
- What the hell?
- Annette!
Annette,you know
you're not allowed to wear that.
The teachers look mean here.
I promised myself I wouldn't get
anything lower than an "A." Careful.
- Puta.
- God!
How you doin', man?
Mason, guess what just happened.
- Ooh! Look at that shit! Damn!
- That shit is tight!
- Mason.
Hey. Um, guys,
this is my little sister.
Hi.
Look over there.
Man, there's Evie Zamora.
- Looks like she grew up this summer.
- No shit.
-  What's up, girl?
- Let's go say hi.
- Hey, be cool, dude.
What's up, Evie?
Come over here! We wanna talk to you!
- What's poppin'with you, girl?
- Damn!
Shit!
Now look up at me.
Oh, looks great.
Yeah.
Next time we'll do orange.
Hair gel, baby.
It's okay, Mom.
You can borrow mine... again.
Thank you.
Ooh, Rodney, I love your blue.
Hey, go like this.
-You guys hungry? I did Italian tonight.
Hey, what's happenin'?
Hey, where'd you put the cheese?
- Bye!
- Don't burn your tongue!
- Bye, Mel.
- Oh, thanks. So long.
Jesus. A two-dollar tip.
They ate half the lasagna.
Mom, you're way too generous.
- Did Dad send you the check this month?
- Lay offhim, Tracy.
He just started the new job.
- We're fine. I worked all week.
- What?
Oh, you'd look great...
with some honey-blond
entertainment streaks...
right here.
It's not fair. I can't be mad at you
when you do that.
- Here, Mom, listen to this.
- Mmm.
"He was crippled,
but only his body was cracked."
- Yoo-hoo!
- Tracy!
- Hey!
- Hey, Kayla.
Hi. The bus never came,
and then it did.
I have to pee,
and she hasn't eaten anything.
Well, that's okay.
There's some stuff on the stove.
Oh, great. Okay.
Then we'll go?
Tracy, I'm sorry. I just haven't
been to a meeting all week.
You know I need to go.
- I really want to hear your poem.
- No.
- Please start over.
- It's okay, Mom.
No, please, I really wanna hear it.
He was crippled,
but only his body was cracked.
It's not simple, nor is it
an easy matter to explain.
Let's just leave it at that,
she says...
and closes the holy book of lies.
She covers her eyes, denying to herself
what she thought happened.
Mmm.
Wow.
That's really heavy.
And it scares me a little bit.
It's beautiful.
We gotta talk about it
when I get back. Okay?
Hey, can we
have some of this cake?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
Shit.
That's Mario's cake!
He's 1 2 years sober!
- Tracy, I want a piggyback ride.
- Hang on.
Uh, Mom.
Mom, Mom, Mom.
I told you I can't baby-sit.
I have an I-Search project due tomorrow.
Baby, cut me a break.
You know I need to go.
- Keep coming back.
- It works if you work it.
- Right, baby?
- Bye, Mommy!
- Be good!
- Thanks again!
Evie Zamora. Hey, girl!
Evie Zamora
has really pretty skin.
She's got a scar from when she tried
to save her baby brother from a fire.
You guys,
she's not Wonder Woman.
- Hey,you guys! I'm wearing lip gloss.
I'll see you guys later.
He's so smart.
He knows German.
Nice socks!
- It's that girl Tracy from chem class.
Who let her out
of the cabbage patch?
Thank God
you're cleaning up your room.
You hungry, baby?
Mom, I'm not your baby.
Okay.
- Hey, what's wrong with those socks?
- Nothing.
Then what are they doing
in the trash?
I'm not gonna wear them anymore.
I need new clothes.
- How come?
- Because I look stupid! Hello!
Sylvia!
Sylvia! Stop!
Please!
Emergency!
Mom, this one's okay.
- This is good.
- Yes. Yes.
Mother scores.
Oh--
Now, I know I have another dollar
in quarters here somewhere.
Hey! Is this enough?
I could rinse these off.
Right on.
Okay, for the project
I'm doing J-Lo. What about you?
- I'm doing Usher.
- I have to go to the bathroom.
So, anyway,
I'm gonna try to, like--
Cute shirt.
Thanks. Cute belt.
Call me after school.
We can go shopping on Melrose.
Okay. Um--
Write your number on this.
Oh, my God!
- You get it?
- Oh! Yeah, wait. I have heard that one.
Yep, that one's good.
Oh, damn.
I have gymnastics today.
- Oh. Okay.
- Okay.
- All right. I'll see you.
- Give me a call, okay?
- See ya.
- Bye. Love ya.
I don't know.
I just wish she liked me.
- I've been there.
- Hey, Tracy!
- Mom wants you to clean your room.
- Okay.
The number you have
reached is not in service at this time.
What happened over here,
cockroachio?
Nothing, lifeguard boy.
Hey, come and clean
this shit up, Trace.
Really disgusting.
No, seriously, though, the pants without
the pockets make you look better.
Hi. I tried calling you, but
I was coming here anyway, so--
- Oh--
My phone didn't ring.
Bon appétit, darling.
Shit. You guys,
I only brought 1 0 bucks.
What?
I'm gonna go get a drink of water.
Loser.
What?
What are you talking about?
No! No, ab--
Hang on one second.
I'll get the number for you.
It's right-- Hang on one second.
I shouldn't be giving you the number.
You should have the number.
No. Name is Alberto.
I don't know.
It's some sort of, uh, 5 53 number.
Alberto. I don't know.
Something--
No,you just keep in mind
that you work for me.
I have 35 people coming tonight.
This is unacceptable.
I have to have
the heater working.
everything there.
No, this is not right.
Let's see, uh-- Give me one second.
It's 5 53--
It's not bad for,
like, 30 minutes.
- Sales clerks didn't see shit.
- You guys!
- You guys--
- Wait, wait, wait. Watch.
You guys,
I totally just stole this.
- No fucking way!
- From this lady over there.
- Let's see how much--
- Have you seen what's in it?
- Holy shit, you guys!
- Oh, my God.
I don't think I've ever seen
this much money in my life.
- Let's go shopping!
- Hell, yeah!
- One.
Dos, tres.
A few pairs of these.
That should cover that.
Keep the change.
Aah!
- Let's go!
- Yeah!
Hey, Mason.
Just out of curiosity...
who do you think
is the hottest girl in school?
I guess, um, Evie Zamora.
Guess who I hung out with today.
Bull.
Melrose Avenue.
What?
God, it's that hard to believe?
Mom, why are there
four places tonight?
Mom?
Honey, he just got back.
He's only coming for dinner.
Yeah. Tomorrow he's just
gonna tune up your car, right?
It needs it.
Why are you doing this to yourself?
Do you mind if I put this stuff
in your garage?
So, Brady, how was
the halfway house?
The same as the last one, Trace.
Yeah. Okay.
Here, hold on.
Evie, this is my mom.
No way.
She's like the hot big sister.
What do you want me to do?
- Can you take us to Melrose?
- Let's go.
We'll find some really cute platforms...
or maybe some of
that body glitter.
Mom, you can just drop us off
and go run an errand or something.
Oh.
Um... okay.
I guess that'll be all right.
Maybe for an hour.
I have to talk to
Evie's mom, though.
Brooke is just my guardian.
Great. Thank you.
Hey, wait a minute.
I haven't talked to Brooke yet.
Mom, please don't do this to me.
This is the best day of my life.
I'll kill you if you embarrass me.
Okay.
Hi. This is Melanie.
I'm Tracy's mom.
It's my ass that isn't fitting.
Evie, Brooke says you're not allowed
on Melrose without adult supervision.
- Well, you're here, aren't you, Mel?
- Yep.
I am.
What do you think?
Mom, do I look okay?
You look incredible.
You love the leopard fur, Mel?
Yep.
- But not for 7 5 bucks, baby.
- Why? Mom--
- Guys! This only costs $1 9.95!
This is it!
This is the digs, the nest!
My Mount Olympus, baby!
- Hey.
Hey, boys.
This is it. This is the dream place.
- Hey, Evie.
- Check this out.
The design is, uh, set up feng shui--
Dude, I want my $9.00 back.
Only way that movie
would've been decent...
was if Britney had her big-ass booty
hangin'all over the screen.
Yeah, man, with the car
blowing up in the background.
- Shit! Watch out, man!
- Hey!
Christ, I at least
wanted to see some tits.
- Your little friend is coming over.
- What?
Oh, shit.
- I'm Evie Zamora.
- Yeah, I know.
I'm Noel.
Pizza?
We love Hawaiian.
Don't you, Evie?
Hey, hey, hey!
Let's go, Trace.
Uh, you can't go to the park anyway.
Right, Noel?
You can't go either after dark.
You guys wanna get high?
Four bucks a hit.
- Let's trip.
- For sure.
Man!
Pay me back
when we get home.
What's up?
- You guys wanna buy some shit?
- Yeah. What you got?
Evie, I see spiders!
I see naked people.
My God!
Tracy!
Tracy! Come on.
Mom wants you home now.
- Tracy, get over here!
- I found her, Mom.
- Oh, you got it.
Uh,yeah, Trace, I got that game
that you wanted... finally.
I'm a lion!
Tracy! Tracy, come on.
You hounded me for two weeks
for this damn game.
Oh, no, I haven't.
I really haven't.
-Just--
Damn.
How long is this gonna last?
[ Evie Singing ]
Dropped acid at the park
Evie, I think--
I think my nose is melting off.
[ Giggling ]
Ooh!
Mel, she's a teenager.
Come on, baby.
- You want me to ground you?
- Yeah, you're gonna ground me.
You know you're not
allowed out after dark.
Can't I have any privacy?
-What, I'm not allowed to see your body?
-No, you're not.
Okay.
Well, after he leaves we'll talk.
Ifhe leaves.
Whoa. Slow down on that
apple cider, sweetheart.
Come here. Come here.
So, uh...
Mason says "good night."
[ Gasping, Coughing ]
[ Tracy ] What's going on?
Mom! What's going on?
Baby, go back to bed!
[ Girls Laughing ]
Come on.
Nice ass.
Oh, uh, no.
[ Laughing ]
- Mom!
- What?
I'm making your fave.
Mom, I have to go
to the bathroom now.
Can't you hold it a minute?
That's how you get a bladder infection,
you child abuser.
- That's dramatic.
- Let's just go pee outside, wussy.
[ Tracy Whimpering ]
French toast
is my favorite too, Mel.
Hampton is my baby!
- He's my baby.
- Hey, Mason.
Move your G-string down south.
Dude, no! That is so gross.
That's my brother.
[ Giggling ]
- Oh, my God!
- Maybe I'll marry into the family.
You'll be designing a habitat...
which the four of you
will live in for two years.
Find creative ways
to recycle the elements.
Think water supply
and power supply--
[ Boys Laughing, Muttering ]
And why are you late,
Ms. Freeland?
Sorry. Can't a girl
go to the bathroom?
[ Laughing, Snickering ]
All right, settle down, class.
Now, what I want--
Put the phone away!
[ Laughing ]
Mom.
Do you know the difference...
between point-slope form
and slope-intercept form?
How about ten dollars, guapo?
That's why I need to be here
at the library. They have tutors.
Hey, does her mom know?
She's 1 8, dude. Come on.
I know you're a nice guy.
Okay, cool.
Pick me up at 5:30.
Bye.
[ Squeals ]
Get on the chair.
Um... is this gonna hurt?
Oh, you haven't had
your tongue pierced.
[ Speaks Spanish ]
I only put it in when I need to.
Stick it out.
Just don't open your mouth very wide
when you talk. She won't notice.
I have to ask you something.
What?
Okay, um...
you never did anything...
with that crusty
tattoo guy, right?
Yeah. He ate my pussy.
Oh, my God!
Are you sh--
[ Giggles ]
I'm kidding, idiot.
-[ Car Door Closes ]
-[ Melanie ] Hey, ladies!
- Get a lot of studying done?
- We were researching, Mom.
I'm in charge of the gray water module
for the Biosphere II project.
Cool.
What module are you
in charge of, Evie?
I'm not in that class.
I'm taking advanced physics, Mel.
Well, I'm happy for him that
he's finally paying offhis debt...
but so what if he
has to work weekends?
You had to work
when you had two babies.
It's not like I need it for myself.
It's just that the kids--
- Mom. Mom!
- Can you guys say "hot"?
That was Mason's favorite shirt.
- [ Together]  Ohh, ohh
- Here we go.
You two aren't the only
J-Lo's in the house.
- Check out these sexy colors!
- That's great, Mom.
You need something to eat.
It's 4:00.
Something real.
I'll make some turkey and cheese
on whole wheat.
Evil food.
If you drink 1 0 glasses of ice water
a day, you'll burn 300 calories.
[ Melanie ]
Interesting.
[ Sighs ]
Mom!
Three strikes and you're out.
How many times you gonna
let him fuck you over?
[ Melanie ]
Hey!
-[ Bell Dings ]
- Where is my purse?
Cyn-- Cyn, go to the sink.
- I'll rinse your color out now.
- I-I know I left it here.
Baby, it's here.
Honey, find Cynthia's purse.
His clothes should not be here.
You promised Mason and me.
- No, I never promised--
- Yes, you did!
Baby-- Cyn, come on. You're cookin'.
You're cookin' with gas.
Let's wash off
really quick over here.
This is so fucked up.
[ Sighs ]
[ Melanie ] After this,
we'll cover your face back.
-[ Water Running ]
- Ow! God! You're burning me!
- Shit. I'm sorry.
- Ow! Fuck!
There. How's that?
Ooh, baby, you are blond!
That's weird. I thought I had
a bunch of 20s in here.
- I'm gonna have to write you a check.
- No, no, pay me next time.
Put a little gel on your hands...
and go like this
right before Larry picks you up.
Hey, if this gets you laid,
you owe me double.
Tracy Louise Freeland!
Conference time! Now!
You do not pull a scene like that
in front of a client.
Even Cynthia!
I'm on... the phone.
- Well, get off the phone.
- It's Dad.
He's with the baby.
[ Knocking ]
Don't ever start smoking.
Is everything okay, Mel?
Yeah.
No.
Evie, I'm sorry, but I think
it's time for you to go home.
I can't go home.
Brooke had a convention
in Bakersfield.
She said she sent you an E-mail.
I guess I didn't
check my E-mail.
I'm sorry, Mel.
I hope it's okay that I'm here.
Well...
I guess it's gonna
have to be, isn't it?
Her boyfriend hits me, Mel.
He grabbed my throat,
and he threw me against his van.
Oh,Jesus.
Where's your mother, baby?
She-- She passed away.
I didn't have a mother
when I was your age either.
I know how hard it is.
I do.
- Mom.
- What is it, baby?
Dad's on the phone.
He wants to talk to you.
They moved into the new place.
-[ Melanie ] How's the new house?
- It's an apartment, Mom.
So, are you taking them
Saturday night?
Whoa. That sounds like a big deal.
Congratulations.
- Why can't he take us?
- Well, sure, sure.
He's our fucking father.
- Um-- Oh, baby, I--
- [ Whispering ] He's never with us.
No, not-- not you.
You're going digital on me. Yeah.
Uh, I-I'll talk to you later.
- [ Phone Beeps ]
- So we're not staying with him?
Uh, he gets to go to
some black tie event.
Hey.
Something for--
Something for NASA.
He's gonna try
to have brunch on Sunday.
You get out, you.
Get out, you.
Terrific. Then we might as well
be on the fucking moon.
No. No.
My mom will kill me.
- She smokes.
- No shit. The same brand.
No shit.
Shh--
-[ Door Closes ]
- You want it so bad.
Look what I got
from the tattoo shop.
Let's do it right now.
Sewing kit.
[ Sighs ]
This is probably gonna hurt
worse than your tongue.
I don't give a shit.
Just do it.
[ Whimpers, Gasps,
Muffled Screaming ]
- Oh, fuck!
- What the fuck did you do?
[ Crash ]
- Everything okay, Evie?
- Yeah, we just spilled a Coke, Mel.
Trace, it's cool that
you're not scared of needles.
We can go and get tattoos.
More piercings.
[ Knocking ]
[ Melanie ]
May I come in?
Sure, Mel.
I've got a surprise.
I sewed on the leopard fur.
The fur was thicker at Red Balls.
These are tight, Mel.
Thanks.
It only cost six bucks.
Tracy, tomorrow...
you gotta sit down
and do all your homework.
Maybe you could go to Noel's.
She called a couple times.
I know, Mom.
I know.
Okay.
Good night,
my little beauties.
I love you, Mel.
Mom.
Don't go in my room
without asking me again. Okay?
Those are my favorite jeans.
I don't just waltz into your room
and screw around with your stuff.
When have you ever seen me mess
with anything that was yours? Mom!
Fuck her.
Yo, Evie.
- You ready?
- I'm going to the park with K.K.
Give me a sec. 'Kay?
- Go away!
-[ Chuckles ]
- What, do you wanna come?
- Yeah.
It's just gonna be me and K.K.
You know?
[ Giggles ]
You ready?
-[ K.K.] Stop bitin'me.
-[ Evie Laughing ]
[ Sighs ]
I love you, Tracy.
Evie.
[ People Conversing,
Laughing, Faint ]
[ Laughing,
Conversation Continue ]
- [ Laughing ]
- But are they real?
Opossums? Okay--
Excuse me.
Oh, hey.
Grab some oatmeal.
It's okay. I'm on a diet.
No, you should, uh, put some,
some chocolate chips in it.
It's actually very good.
Come on, Tracy. You know
you get mean when you don't eat.
Fuck you.
Come on, Evie. Let's go.
Hey, Evie, could you-- could you
just give us a little second?
- Yeah. Sure.
- Um--
Does Brooke have a boyfriend?
No. She dumped him.
When?
Last week or something.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah.
He's in Orlando.
Now, can I go to school?
Yeah.
It's okay.
All of the sudden
Medina has a ghetto booty?
I think she stuffs.
That slut ain't got shit compared
to these double cheeseburgers.
Shake it, don't break it, bitch.
- Fuck her.
- [ All Laughing ]
[ Astrid ]
Javi,you look hot.
- What up?
- Hey, Marcus,Javi.
- Hey, Evie.
-[ Astrid ] Hey, what's up, Marcus?
Hey, Tracy, can I holler at you?
Yeah.
[ Girls Murmuring, Chattering ]
I was wondering if, uh, maybe
you wanna go kick it sometime.
Yeah, sure.
- Okay, well, can I have your number?
- Yeah--
Um, here's my cell.
We'll be hanging around.
Straight.
See you guys later.
Bye.
[ Giggling, Screaming ]
- Go, girl!
- That is so cool!
Okay, I don't want him to come to
my house and see Mason and the loser.
Well, let's all go to my place.
-My aunt says only one friend at a time.
-Come on, babe.
I'm sorry, Astrid.
Let me call my mom.
Fine.
- Dude, they say it's two feet overhang.
-[ Laughing ] Oh,yeah?
- Good goin; buddy!
- Oh, my God.
- Don't tell me that they live here.
- No, they're old news.
- She's my cousin, not my mom. Got it?
- Don't tell them I like them.
Hey, boys! My friend
wants to suck your dick!
- Oh, my God.
-[ Boy ] Come over here, honey.
[ Giggling ]
That was so not cool.
- Here's my pad!
- Hey, babe.
Tracy, meet the lovely
Brooke LaLaine.
- Hello.
- Hi.
She's a cute one.
Oh, Tracy, your mom has been calling.
Honey, can you
get me another beer?
Yeah.
Um, Evie?
Um, it's okay.
So, you're a model?
[ Evie ]
She's a model-slash-actress.
Mmm, slash-bartender
who's about to be late for work.
- What time is it, honey?
- It's, like, 4:30 or 5:00.
Oh, shit. Hey, no more than one.
You got homework.
They were removing asbestos...
from the locker room
today, so-- Oww--
we got the whole gym period
to do our homework.
- Yeah, baby!
- [ Gasps ] Waah!
I love you, Christina Ricci!
[ Kiss ]
- Tracy?
- What-y?
You're going out with Javi!
[ Both Screaming, Laughing ]
Evie, goddamn it,
where's my other cutlet?
[ Hums ]
- Incoming cutlet!
-[ Tracy Giggles ] Nice meeting you.
Very nice meeting you too,
princess.
-  [ Phone: Melody ]
- Is that your phone?
Popular. Hello?
- It's Javi.
- [ Gasps ] Oh, my God!
Shh! Yeah, she's here.
You wanna talk to her?
Shh. Relax. Breathe.
Calm down. Shh.
Hey.
Uh, no, no,
I don't think I'm too busy.
Can we do something tonight
if Ruben comes?
Yes!
Hello? Come over right now.
Okay, bye.
You get to make out with Javi!
- [ Screams, Laughing ]
- [ Laughing ]
You don't know how to kiss,
do you?
Oh, no, no, no, no, no.
Yes, I do.
Me and Noel practiced
with Cruel Intentions, like, 50 times.
Right.
So, you want me
to prove it, lesbo?
Hell, no!
[ Laughs ]
[ Giggling ]
I barely even felt that.
Well, see if you
fucking feel this one, then!
Well... okay!
[ Giggling ]
[ Laughs ]
All right, honeys,
I'm outta here.
Uh, if Benny calls,
tell him I'll be down at Rene's.
Don't do anything
I wouldn't do!
[ Both Laughing ]
Remember the part when Josh is
smoking a joint with a beer, and he's--
- [ Sighs ]
- [ Laughs ] I don't remember that!
I don't either!
[ Laughing ]
You just made that up.
He jumped when that teacher
got a pencil stabbed through her hand.
- That wasn't even scary.
- Yeah, it was.
- What is this shit, man?
-[ Off]
Check this out.
[ Imitates Hip-hop Beat,
Scratching ]
Tr-Tr-Tr-Tr-Tracy
[ All Laughing ]
[ Hip-hop, Slow ]
[ Man Rapping ]
[ Sighs ] It's getting kinda hot
in here, don't you think?
[ Continues ]
[ Giggles ]
Mmm.
We are so perfect
for each other.
You know,
if everybody married someone...
from a different race...
then in one generation...
there would be no prejudice.
So, you had a good time?
Yeah.
But it tasted kinda nasty.
[ Both Giggling ]
What?
We didn't go over that one.
Want anything special
from the market?
-[ Engine Starts ]
- No, thanks, Mel.
I like everything you get.
Hey, Trace, do my back.
- Who's that?
- Luke.
Or "lifeguard boy."
His parents moved away
and left him the house.
Come on.
Hey, Luke!
[ Evie ]
Got any beer?
-[ Rock, Slow ]
- Luke, you are so lucky.
[ Pinball Machine Beeping ]
I want your house.
- [ Coughs ]
-[ Continues ]
You know, I think I'm gonna
call some of my friends.
How 'bout we make
a Luke sandwich?
Um, how about you're jailbait?
- Yeah.
- [ Chuckles ]
You know, I--
Luke, you know I'll never tell.
- Trace, would I tell?
- No, because Ruben would kill you.
- [ Chuckles ]
- Come on, Luke.
- No, look-- Danger.
- Come on.
Danger, Will Robinson.
[ Chuckles ]
Luke, it's not illegal to kiss.
Says who?
Tracy, come here. Check out
his white boy ghetto lips.
- Try it. Come on.
- No.
- Come on!
- It's Luke.
So? Come on.
You guys.
Go, girl.
Luke, where's your bong?
[ Moans ]
Right there.
Why don't you get back over here,
though, girl. Come here.
[ Continues ]
Feels good, huh, Luke?
You know you want it.
You know what?
Th-This-- Why don't you guys
get out of my house. Okay?
- What the fuck are you--
-Just get out of my house--Just stop.
- Now get out.
- Shit!
Get out of my house!
Now!
- Get off me, you fuckin' pervert!
- Pleasejust get out. Go.
- Luke, chill out!
- Take your fucking weed and get out.
- Could you give me a hand?
- Mom, I'm not your fucking slave!
[ Car Engine Starts ]
[ Car Door Slams, Tires Squeal ]
Shit!
Shit! My breath.
- Toothpaste. Toothpaste.
- Where the hell's the--
Hey!
Hey, open this door now.
What, Mother?
What do you want?
This is not how I raised you.
I want you to be civil to me.
And I want you and your stupid boyfriend
to get out of my fucking life!
- What is he doing here?
- Have you been drinking?
- No!
- She's always fucking drinking!
- Oh, like you never have!
- Hey, hey, hey. Come on.
-[ Evie ] You guys!
- [ Crying ]
- Ohh.
- Hey, Kayla. What's going on?
- Hey.
- It's okay.
Thought we'd just crash here for a
couple days, until my check comes in.
[ Coughs ]
I think I'm coming down
with diphtheria or something, so--
Yeah, sure.
Just for a couple of days.
Mason, can you find
your sleeping bag to give to--
Why not open a hotel, Mom?
You could get paid for all this.
Tracy, baby, this is just temporary.
[ Knocks ]
Wow. Where'd all
this stuff come from?
Brooke bought it for me-- us.
[ Kayla Giggling ]
Come on, Evie.
"Wanna bone."
Nice.
[ Kayla, Evie Giggling ]
What's the occasion?
She wanted to say
thank you'for...
taking care of me.
[ Giggling Continues ]
Baby, we have to
have a real talk.
[ Evie ]
Wanna go to the park?
- I have more homework to do.
- Yeah.
You should go
to more meetings.
No,you don't understand.
It's different this time.
She's starting--
She's starting to scare me.
[ Sobbing ]
I know, I know, I know.
Damn it, I know.
[ Sighs ]
I just--
I just wanna make it stop.
You know?
You fuckin' hard-ass.
That's why you're my sponsor.
[ Laughing ]
Okay, okay, okay.
I'm gonna try.
Okay, I'm gonna--
Okay, I'm gonna do it.
Yeah, baby!
Close your eyes!
- Oh, my God!
- Close 'em, close 'em. Ooh, lovin' it.
- You are a gold queen.
- Think that's enough?
Hey, guys.
What the hell?
Watch his head.
Look at that.
[ Tracy ]
Oh, my God!
See that?
It's, like, Zen chicken.
- That's weird, right?
-[ Laughing ]
It doesn't even move!
Chickens are cool, aren't they?
Cool.
Mom, no, I can't see that movie.
- Why?
- Because it's a bloody war movie.
I'm a pacifist, like Gandhi.
Why don't we just go see
theJack Black movie?
The Misadventures Of Ezekial Balls. '
- It looks funny. It's a giant pig.
- I won't be seeing that.
Come on.
It's supposed to be family night.
That's all right. We'll see separate
movies, we'll meet here at 1 0:1 5.
Two for the pig movie,
and two for the war movie.
Yes! Brady,
you are so awesome!
Look, I got popcorn...
and butter
in a separate foil packet...
for the-- for the little ones.
Thanks, Mom.
- Okay.
- Thanks, Mel.
- See you all here. Love you.
- [ Makes Kissing Sound ]
[ Brady ]
I thought that was our popcorn.
Hi. Can I get two
for Kandahar?
[ Man ]
Yeah! Uh-huh!
[ Giggles ]
- Bye, Mom.
- Later,Jack.
[ Screaming, Giggling ]
Come on, my little hooch.
Oww! Mothers,
lock up your sons!
[ Rapping ]
What's up, ladies?
How you guys doing tonight?
You guys having fun?
I got my ass beat
for what happened the other night.
- Oh, yeah?
- Hey,Javi, come speak that verse.
[Javi Chuckles ]
All right.
[Javi Imitating
Hip-hop Beat ]
All right.
Uh-huh.
[ Rapping ]
Why don't you go get us
some sodas or something.
And tell Conrad to get his ass
down here on his break.
Okay.
- Hey, man, what are you doin'?
- [ Laughing ]
[ Conversation, Faint ]
- You stupid fucker!
- [ Laughing ]
Oh, sweetie,
back that ass up.
I'd like to see how that thong looks
on my bedroom floor.
- Too bad you'll never know.
- Tracy?
Aw, shit. Fuck it.
Hey, Tracy, here's your Cokes.
I didn't pay for them anyway.
- Didn't have to with your fine ass.
- Fuck you!
[ Laughing ]
Have you seen Evie?
Nah, she went
to the candy store.
Want some?
- [ Gags ]
- Easy!
- What the fuck is that?
- Voodoo juice my friends made.
Don't be backwashing.
Wanna go find her?
Yeah.
You all right?
Tracy. Let's go.
Come on.
Evie?
Evie!
Hey. Want to suck
my cock, baby?
No!
Evie!
- Damn!
- How are you? [ Kisses ]
Javi spilled a Coke all over his pants
and he couldn't perform--
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Do you even know what time it is? Shit!
Hey.
Call me, baby.
[ Scoffs ]
Geez, Mom, I can't help it
if the movie ran late.
Bullshit, Tracy!
We checked the theater.
We got something to drink at Starbucks.
What's wrong with that?
-[ Melanie ] Where's the backpack?
- Oh, shit.
I got you a key chain.
Hey.
How was the movie?
- All right.
- Mom, I gotta talk to you.
- In private.
- Okay.
- Come in the kitchen. I'm making tea.
- I'll help you.
Should we talk about...
how you get stoned
every night with Rafa?
She knows I smoke pot, Tracy.
[ Scoffs ]
Look at your pupils.
You're so fuckin' busted.
- Fucking little--
- Ow!
-Jesus Christ, Tracy!
- Don't you ever touch me again!
Go ahead, hit me, Tracy.
You'll go to jail, you fucking slut!
Don't you fucking
call me a slut.
Mom, Mason just
called me a slut!
- Melanie!
- Stop! Stop it!
Wait, wait, wait!
Stop! Stop!
-Tracy, look at this shit!
-[ Melanie ] Birdie, she didn't mean it.
Mom, don't touch me!
Don't touch my hair!
- She's out of control.
- Have you had anything to eat today?
- Mom, stop with the food thing!
- Fuck it.
You don't want me to cook
for you anymore? Fine!
- Then don't eat my food.
- Fine!
- I hate your nasty store-brand food!
- Great!
Then I can stop doing 1 2 haircuts a day
trying to pay for all this shit!
You think I want to be here?
[ Gasps ]
[ Whispers ]
Fuck.
Damn it.
Goddamn...
1 .50-a-square-foot floor!
[ Brady ]
Mel. Mel.
[ Panting ]
I told you we needed a new floor.
Baby?
Mel.
- You all right?
- [ Laughing ] Yeah. I'm okay.
I'm okay.
- You're okay.
- I'm okay. I need to call Sue.
[ Tracy ]
Mom!
Uh, don't worry
about that, all right?
I'll take care of it.
Mom! What the--
Damn it, Tracy.
What is it?
I can't even sleep
in my own bed?
Tracy, we can all sleep in here
if we could just get this dog out.
- Wake up, girl. Come on.
- [ Whimpers ]
It's-- Oh,Jesus.
- Something peed in your bed.
- We'll change the sheets.
- Here, Mason, take her.
- Mom, you're dealing with this!
I'll take care of it.
You know what, Tracy?
You're gonna have to
lay off of her.
Don't you tell me what to do,
you fucking cokehead.
You're such a loser.
[ Sniffles ]
-[ Door Closes ]
- I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry.
Arms up.
I can't do this with her anymore.
I can't.
I'm horrible.
-[ Water Running ]
- Get in the shower, Mel.
[ Door Closes ]
This place is fucking with my head.
[ Helicopter Whirring ]
Yeah, I want--
I want to get loaded.
Go see Mario.
He'll read the big book
in that scratchy voice.
Okay. I know what to do.
- Evie, I have to ask you something.
- What?
What happened in the dressing room
with you and Javi?
Nothing, pendeja.
He's your guy.
[ Kisses ]
[ Snorting ]
- [ Chuckling ]
- Uh-oh.
[ Tracy ]
So what's with the spoons?
-Just go like this.
- It's really cold.
- You're gonna call Evie's mom.
- Right.
I'm just gonna talk to her
for a few minutes.
I mean, she's just a kid,
after all.
- [ Both Speaking In Code ]
- [ Cynthia ] Mason, come here a second.
Brooke does this every morning,
and she still has huge bags.
I wonder how much of this
you have to swallow for it to kill you.
This family needs some healing.
- Who bought you that wet suit?
- Fuck you.
- Your mother's phone's disconnected.
- Mel, she's not my mom.
She's my cousin.
My mom was a crack whore.
Okay. Everybody
just take a deep breath.
Evie, honey, do you have a friend
that you could stay with for a few days?
I think this family
needs some alone time.
I'm the one that's here every day
trying to make the situation better.
Ask Mel.
Look, Mom, there's a huge swell.
I-I gotta get poundin;
- That's okay, baby.Just go.
- [ Phone:Melody ]
- Phone!
-[ Cynthia ] Wait, wait, wait.
- Hold on, hold on.
-[ Evie ] Hello? Conrad.
- [ Both Screaming ]
- Hey, Spidey!
Evie, honey, let's talk about you
for just a minute, okay?
- I need to make sure--
- Are you a board-licensed therapist?
Okay, you bring the stuff,
and I'll give you a surprise.
- She's done a lot of great things.
- She's a psychic.
Cynthia, do you remember when
you tried to bring back Grandma...
and Hampton ended up
humping your leg? [ Barking ]
- Cynthia, I can handle this.
- You know, I should, um--
I should be getting back to work.
I could be selling houses.
1 0:30 at Nona's.
[ Kisses ]
Cynthia can handle it, Mom. Ooh!
Want me to model my new thong?
It's perfect for pooping on the go.
- What's that under your shirt?
- None of your business.
- What is that?
- Don't worry about it.
- Let me see that.
- No! What is it with you and poking me?
- I just want to see what you got there.
- Mom, stop!
What the hell is that?
- I'm talking to you.
- [ Whispers ] It's a belly button ring.
Speak up.
I can't hear you.
It's a belly button ring!
How else can I say it?
I don't speak no other languages!
Oh. And do you want
to know what that is?
That is a tongue ring.
- When did you do all this, baby?
- Oh, Mom!
Two thousand years ago! I'm a mummy!
I was born 2,000 years ago! Whoo!
Tracy, Tracy, Tracy.
I'm really starting to lose it.
Stop it, please.
No bra, no panties.
- Stop it.
- No bra, no panties.
- You have to take her for a while.
- No, I can't.
- I need you to take her for a while.
- I can't.
I've been on the phone trying
to get out of this thing. I can't.
- I need you to take her for a while.
- Are you hearing me here?
I can't. I will talk to her.
It'll be just fine.
All right?
Where is she?
Is she in the back?
Hey. How are you doin'?
Listen, we, uh--
we gotta talk about something.
Um, I gotta tell you right up front
that I can't, uh, take you this weekend.
I knew that you
wouldn't take me.
Tracy, uh...
look, baby...
you--you have got to
cut me some slack, okay?
I am trying to kick ass
at this newjob.
I am trying to get you and your mom
more money. That's all I'm--
-[ Phone Ringing ]
- Let me, um,just shut this thing off.
Uh...
what's the problem?
What's going on?
Can I help? Tracy.
You gotta talk to me.
Dad, do you even remember
what the last thing we did together was?
-[ Phone Buzzing ]
- Dad,just answer the fucking thing!
Look, this could be an emergency.
Let me take this. Yeah?
No, I can't. I'm with--
I'm with a client right now.
Look, Chris, I will call you
from the airport, okay?
- Fine.
-[ Closes Phone ]
Nice talking to you, Dad.
Baby, I'm not going
anywhere, okay?
You know, fuck this work shit, okay?
I'm calling him back right now and
telling him I'm not going to Houston.
Dad,just go, okay?
Really. You need this job.
Yeah, baby, I do need this job.
Nice car.
Yeah, it's just a silly business tool.
We're going surfing
in two weeks, right? San O's? Okay.
She needs help, Dad.
Okay. Okay.
What is the problem?
Can somebody please just tell me,
what is the problem?
In a nutshell.
Wha--
Mason, wait--
Hey.
Nice car.
[ Sighs ]
[ Car Door Closes,
Engine Starts ]
[ Speaking In Code ]
- Good morning, Mom!
-[ Brady ] Whoa, hey.
- Hi.
- Knocking's real good.
Uh, Mom, we have something
really important...
that we need to talk
to you about, okay?
Okay.
Um...
I think that I would
get along a lot better...
with everybody...
if Evie just lived with us.
Brooke will pay you to take me.
She won't be like
all the other freeloaders.
She was abused...
by her uncle when she was nine.
[ Evie ]
Mel.
He put things inside me...
and he pushed me into a fire.
Okay.
Mel, you could really help me
if I lived here.
You could maybe even save me.
Okay, I'll think about it.
You're so cool.
Bye, Mel.
Why did you put me on the spot
in front of that poor little girl?
I can't reject someone like that
to her face.
- I know, Mom.
-[ Evie ] Come on, Tracy.
Good-bye.
I love you.
[ Bell Ringing ]
Bye.
Yea! I got an "A."
I got a "C-plus." "Movin" up.
What'd you get?
Let's just say my mother isn't
gonna get a bumper sticker this year.
Ah, I want to bleed more!
Hit me!
Make an effort, bitch!
Tracy?
-[ Melanie ] Food's ready, ladies.
-Just a minute!
Tracy.
Get up, okay?
You can't go out like this.
Oh, shit.
[ Groans ]
Here.
[ Moans ]
- Her uncle got seven years.
-[ Birdie ] I mean, look at you.
You're stretched to the limit.
Shit, you're stretched
beyond the limit.
Kayla and I are sleeping in a tent.
She's been abused by everyone
who's supposed to take care of her.
- I have to help her.
- No, Mom, come on. You don't know that.
I mean,Jesus.
How do we look, darling?
[ Giggling ]
Guys, say hello to the butt.
- I wanna play! I wanna play!
- [ Evie ] Okay.
- What happened to your lip?
- Nothing, Mom. I just bit it.
Is that my belt, Evie?
Yeah.
Mason, do you have any film?
- You want to take pictures of us?
- No, Evie, I don't.
Okay, kids.
This is the day. You guys did
a great job. These all look really--
What?
Oh, my God.
Wait.
Today is the due date?
You guys could have called to
remind me that today was the due date.
- We left you messages.
- Not to mention a note on your locker.
Oh, our phone's been disconnected
just because we've been having...
family problems.
My grandmother,
she passed away.
Go to the counselor, Tracy.
She'll talk to your mom.
Now.
- [ Kids Laughing ]
-[ Teacher ] Knock it off,you guys.
Fuck!
[ Sniffs ]
So, um...
you just wanna go to the boardwalk
and sell some shit?
I can't. Um, I'm late
for my biology actually...
and we're doing a play...
and... I'm a mermaid.
I can't even remember
how to spell "photographer."
- Where are we going, Mel?
-[ Turn Signal Clicking ]
Brooke. Wow.
- I've been calling for two weeks.
- All right, sweetie.
Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
I just... didn't want you
to see me like this.
[ Mumbling ]
Mel, my ear--
What?
They cut off my ears.
Okay, girls. Please go out
to the car, okay? Please.
Please, go out to the car.
I had that little kind of
turkey neck thing,you know?
I mean, all of a sudden I had
a kid to support. I mean, fuck.
- Y-You had plastic surgery?
- Mmm.
- Why? You were so pretty.
- Evie knows what I'm talking about.
You know that little kind of flap thing
that was in the pictures?
Oh, my ears hurt so bad.
Look.
- Is this, like, a standard procedure?
- Yeah, I guess.
I mean, you know, they had to
tuck the skin somewhere, I guess.
It's just...
I didn't realize they'd have to
do the whole, you know...
fuckin' crop circle.
So everything's okay, then?
Yeah.
Oh, sorry.
- It's okay.
- Excuse me.
Oh, God, I'm a mess.
Oh, dear.
- Can I get you a beer?
- No, that's okay. We're gonna split.
So, Evie...
we'll bring your suitcase
over later, okay?
- So you're not gonna adopt me, Mel?
-[ Dishes Clattering ]
Evie, I mean...
Brooke's back, so--
[ Crying Continues ]
[ Boy ]
Hi.
[ Girl ]
Hey, Trace.
[ Chattering ]
Hey, girlies.
Astrid, Medina.
-[ Evie ] Hey, baby!
-[ Car Stereo:Loud Rap ]
Ladies!
Let's go, ladies!
Whoo!
-[ Rap Continues ]
-[ Evie ] Whoo!
[ Girls Screaming ]
[ Fades ]
[ Tracy's Voice ] Evie. Evie, that was
hilarious. Now come pick me up.
It's Tracy.
Ev-- Can you hear me?
[ Sighs ]
Mason, would you hurry it up?
-Just a minute!
- God, are you jacking off in there?
- Fuck off.
- Tracy, I'm with a client. Work mode.
Mom, I told you
that I was having a bad day.
I can't fucking wait
till you move to Dad's.
What the hell did you say?
Nothing. It's just something I heard
Mom and Dad talking about, okay?
Forget it.
[ Gasps, Exhales ]
- [ Panting ]
-[ Knocking On Door ]
Hang on a minute!
-[ Melanie ] Hey, Tracy.
- Okay. Hang on!
- You's nasty.
- Yvette.
- I heard that you got used.
- What? By who?
By Conrad, on the stairs
at Nona's party.
Shit never happened,
but believe whatever the fuck you want.
That's not what Evie said.
You fucking lying?
- You better not ever touch me again.
-[ Man ] Hey!
-[ Woman ] Stop!
- This shit ain't over.
Stop it!
Hey, come back here!
[ Woman ] You've made F's'
on your last three tests...
and you haven't turned in
any homework.
On that basis alone,
you're gonna fail.
You'll be held back
in seventh grade.
What?
- They can hold me back?
- Yes, they can hold you back.
Tracy, your name was brought up
in impact group today.
-[ Bell Ringing ]
- Evie Zamora turned in your fake I.D....
and then there's the matter
of cheating in your math class.
You were one
of my best students.
Your poem at the beginning of the year
was incredible.
I'm sorry.
Hey, Tracy.
Your mom sent me to pick you up.
What's going on? I'm supposed
to be studying at Yumi's house.
I don't think so.
Come on. Hop in.
You'll be okay.
Hey, Evie.
Brooke.
You healed up great.
Sit down.
- I have to go to the bathroom.
- Leave your purse.
Fine.
- Tracy.
- What the hell?
They found my stash,
and I had to tell them.
I love you, okay?
You're my girl.
Remember that.
I love you.
Come on. Let's go.
- Tracy.
- What?
None of that shit's mine.
[ Whispers ]
We found it.
What? Speak up, Mama,
'cause I can't hear you!
Do not talk to your mother
like that.
She said, we found it
stashed around your bedroom...
all your little hiding spots.
Jesus, Evie.
- I had to. You don't get it.
- Oh, no, I get it.
Who the fuck do you think you are,
going in my room?
You're lucky I got there
before the cops did, honey.
Hey, I'm just trying
to help you, sweetie.
How do you explain
$860 in your purse?
What do you expect me
to say, Mom?
We jacked it, okay?
It's not like your broke ass
ever has any money to give me.
Mom, when Brady went
to the halfway house...
what happened to
our phone, our cable?
You didn't even know how
to pay the bills.
It's no wonder Dad
didn't want to be with you!
You didn't even finish high school!
We don't have extra stuff, but we're
doing okay. You know we're doing okay.
You don't have to steal.
Mom, you knew what was going on!
You're not that dumb, are you?
I didn't know it went that far!
[ Sobs ]
Oh, God!
We'll be moving up to Ojai,
so you won't be seeing Evie again.
Ever.
You're really cruel, Tracy.
I mean, I'm sure you can be
a sweet kid when you want to...
but right now you're
a really bad influence.
I mean, you cheat,
you lie, you steal.
Oh, my God!
Are you kidding me?
Where do you think I learned
all this shit from?
Tracy was playing Barbies
before she met Evie.
Did she teach you how to beat
the crap out of her as well?
- I've seen the bruises.
- What the hell did you tell her, Evie?
Come here.
What about this?
- What the fuck? We were just goofing.
- Tracy didn't hit her.
- Yes, she did!
- I don't believe this! She hit me too!
- And look at this, Mel.
- Don't you dare! No! Please!
- Get your hands off her.
- See? She cuts.
[ Tracy Sobbing ]
It's none of your business,
you fucking Frankenstein!
Oh, no, this child is my business,
you little cunt.
That's enough.
You need to get out.
- Honey, come on.
- Get out!
Who would want to be
in this shit hole anyway?
It fucking stinks in here, Mel!
Oh, no, Mom!
Get off of me. I hate you!
- Stop!
-[ Door Closes ]
I love you and your brother
more than anything in the world...
and I'll die for you, but I won't
leave you alone right now.
Mason said you wanted me
to move in with Dad!
You don't want me!
I want your dad
to be in your life more.
I want you here with me.
You're my heart.
I'll make it right.
It can never be right.
Get off me. No.
Get off. Mom, please!
Don't hold me! Don't!
Stop!
Mom, don't!
[ Sobbing Continues ]
Don't! Please.
No. No.
No. God.
Stop.
Mom.
[ Sniffles ]
[ Crying ]
Don't.
Oh, God.
[ Screaming ]