[ Keys Clattering ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ Door Closes ]
[ Exhales ]
[ Australian Accent ]
This is our
introductory pamphlet.
Do you mind if I ask
how much more time you have?
Eighteen months
and six days.
Perfect.
Basically the program
works in three phases.
The first phase is to develop
personal thought processes
and moral filters.
Um, the second phase,
and this is important,
tests those moral filters
in real-life situations.
So you could find yourself,
you know, working off-site, uh,
in work programs,
and any money you make
gets put into a bank account...
which is available to you
when you're released.
You mean I get to earn
money outside?
Yeah.
Well, that would depend on,
um, the type of work,
I suppose.
You know, minimum wage.
How much is minimum wage?
Well, in Maryland
it's $7.15.
$7.15?
Could be a little less here.
Shit.
That ain't bad.
Yeah, well, we can cross
that bridge when we come to it.
Um, the third phase
is reentry into society,
where you work with
your mentor to make sure
that you don't end up back here.
You ain't
gotta worry about me
ending up back in here.
Well, I hope not.
Yeah, I paid my dues and
then some in this motherfucker.
Yeah, well, some people find
the transition a little more
difficult than they expected.
What type of jobs they got
for someone like me?
Truthfully,
I don't know, you know.
Um, custodial, maintenance?
Crafts labor mostly.
Factory stuff.
You new at this job?
Yeah, I'm new at this job.
What kind of job
you have before?
I worked for a church.
Like a preacher?
No, like a business manager.
[ Chuckles ]
A business manager.
I guess even church
got to have business, huh?
Yeah, they do.
Why you don't have
that job no more?
What, your church
go out of business?
I have this job now.
Do you like this job?
I think I will, yeah.
Mm-hmm.
You get to talk to people
like me, offer your charity.
- Makes you feel good, huh?
- I'm not offering you charity.
You have to work
really hard at this.
You can't watch TV,
you can't smoke, you've gotta
fully dedicate yourself--
'Cause we got other things for
you to be doing. You're gonna
be in class five days a week.
Oh, so then that translates
into, like, an early release?
What do you mean?
What do I mean?
I mean, what's in it for me?
People come here
all the time talking about
programs and shit.
I always wanna know
what's in it for me.
I'm out the door
in 18 months no matter what.
You know what I'm saying?
Well--
We can't speak
for the parole board,
but if you're successfully
participating in the program,
we're happy to send somebody
into the meeting
to vouch for your work.
So you ain't got shit
to bring to the table.
Can't watch TV,
classes five days a week,
and then you send somebody
to the parole board to say
I've been a good little boy?
That's a bunch of bullshit, man.
That's a waste of my time...
when I'm out
the fucking door already.
We're interested in rebuilding
your commitment to community.
What the fuck you know
about community, man?
Hey, look.
What you think
this is in here, man?
I've been
in the penitentiary system
my whole life.
I already know a thing
or two about community.
Tell me something I don't know.
What if you transferred
those skills...
to outside
the penitentiary?
Hmm?
[ Scoffs ]
You've got an opportunity here.
Shit.
I don't believe in Jesus
or none of that, man.
That's fine.
This is Jesus, ain't it?
That is Jesus.
You know,
the program seeks
to develop the whole person--
spiritually, intellectually,
emotionally, physically.
But the spiritual aspects
of the program are based on
the teachings of Jesus.
Like I said, man,
I don't believe
in none of that.
Well, like I said,
you don't have to.
You ain't trying
to sell me on Jesus Christ,
then why am I
looking at this white-ass
picture then, man?
Why don't you
come to the table
with some real-deal shit,
talk to me about
how I can get the fuck
out of here in six months,
and then maybe we have
a conversation
about your damn program.
You did a nice job.
Carried yourself
real well.
Thank you.
Hey, listen.
It's not our job
to sell them.
In fact, we try to make it
sound unattractive...
so that way you really
get the guys that are
willing to go for it.
[ Chuckles ]
Well, look, thanks
for letting me tag along.
No problem.
See you back at the office.
See you, Bob.
Cheers, mate.
[ Woman ]
Are you having any problems
with your vision?
[ Man ]
Um, no. Not really.
Have you had
any dryness in your eyes?
No. No.
Okay.
I'm just going to
put this up
against your face,
and now you tell me
which lens makes
the letters more clear.
Number one?
Or two?
Two.
Three or four?
Four.
Five?
Six?
They both look the same.
Seven?
Eight?
Eight.
Nine or ten?
There you go.
Thank you.
Have you been
to this office before?
Uh, no.
Okay, can I get
your full name
and address, please?
Martin Bonner.
Mm-hmm.
Two N's.
350 Capitol Hill Way.
Apartment 4.
Reno, Nevada.
89502.
[ Man ]
Okay. Great.
Thank you, Mr. Bonner.
We'll give you a call
when they're ready.
Should be about a week or two.
♪ [ Speakers: Orchestral ]
♪ [ Continues ]
[ Food Sizzling ]
♪ [ Ends ]
[ Woman ]
I was gonna call you right after
I put the baby down,
but he's been
acting up all night.
Really?
Put some whiskey on your thumb
and let him suck it.
He'll be out like a light.
[ Chuckles ]
I will not.
And we don't have any whiskey
in the house, thank you.
Shame on you, girl.
You know.
It worked for you
when you were a baby.
[ Chuckles ]
Hey, how was your day?
What'd you do?
What did I do?
Um, I unpacked,
and I went and bought
some household stuff
and made myself some dinner.
So you're keeping busy?
Oh, yeah.
Lots to do.
What about work?
Work? Still in training,
and, um, yeah,
you know, you'd think I was
joining the C.I.A. for the
wringer they put you through.
Oh.
[ Chuckles ]
Well, we miss you back here.
Ryan and I didn't do
Sunday brunch this week
for the first time.
I don't know. We just forgot.
You were the one
who always reminded everyone.
Oh.
Well, I'll see if I can get
some vacation time in
a couple of months, all right?
And I'll come and visit.
Okay. Hey,
do you wanna say hi to Andy?
No, you two can put
that holy terror to bed.
All right?
I'll call in a couple days.
[ Chuckles ]
Okay.
I love you, Dad.
Love you too, pumpkin.
Bye.
Okay, bye.
[ Line Ringing ]
[ Man ]
Hey, this is Ryan.
Leave a message.
[ Beeps ]
Hey, Ryan,
it's your father.
I just talked
to your sister,
and she said
that you are as elusive
with her as you are with me.
All right, so why don't you
take her out for lunch
or something, all right?
Or go and visit the baby,
okay?
And if you're busy painting,
paint me something
really big for my wall here.
I look like
a darn college student.
All right.
Call me if you've got
some free time, okay?
Otherwise I'll call you
in a couple days.
All right?
Love you, Son.
[ Man ]
30. Now 35? 35.
Sold, $30,
number 36.
Twenty-three
is a German inkwell.
How about $25
to go on the inkwell?
$25 to go. 25 to start it off?
$25 to go. 25 to start it off.
How about $10 to go?
$10 to start it off.
[ Shouts ]
[ Man ]
10. Now 15?
10 bidding.
15 on the inkwell?
[ Shouts ]
15. Now 20?
20. Now 25?
20 bidding. 25?
20 bid. 25?
20 is the bid.
25 where?
[ Shouts ]
25. Now 30.
25 bidding. 30.
25, 30. 25, 30.
25 is the bid.
30 where? 25, 30?
Sold.
$25, number 298.
We've got the four
etched Fostoria stems.
On the four etched
Fostoria stems,
how about $25 to go?
25 to start it off
for Fostoria.
$25 to go, 25 to start it off.
$25 to go.
How about $10 to go?
$10 to start.
Now 15.
[ Man #2 Shouts ]
10 is the bid. 15 where?
10 bidding. 15.
10 bidding. 15?
Sold. $10. Number?
- [ Man #2 ] 319.
- All right. On the lamp,
10 is the bid. 15 where?
10 bidding 15.
10 bidding 15?
10 is the bid.
15. Now 20.
15 bid. 20 where?
15, 20. 15, 20.
15 is the bid. 20 where?
15 bidding. 20?
15 bid. 20 where?
[ Woman ]
Yes!
Now 25.
25. 20 bidding. 25.
Now 30.
Yep!
25 bidding. 30?
Now 35. 35.
30 bidding. 35.
35. Now 40.
Yep!
35 bid. 40 where?
35, 40? 35, 40?
Sold.
$35, number 300.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Homer.
Carrie Dozier.
Born 1890.
Died 1970.
Age of 80.
[ Voice Fading ]
[ Shutter Clicks ]
[ Typing ]
[ Shivers ]
[ Horn Honks ]
[ Man On P.A. Speaking,
Indistinct ]
- I'm Martin Bonner.
- Travis Holloway.
Good to meet you, Travis.
Thanks for picking me up.
Oh, absolutely no problem.
Sorry about the cold.
Yeah, it's a real bummer.
I've got an extra jacket
in the back if you want it.
I'm fine, thanks.
Oh.
Okay. So where to?
I'd like to go to my bank.
Okay. What's your bank?
Bank of America.
Yeah, well, that's easy.
Okay. Put your seat belt on.
[ Engine Starts ]
I'm actually
not your mentor.
Um, I work for SBL.
I'm the volunteer
coordinator.
You short on volunteers?
Oh, no.
No, you've got a mentor.
His name's Steve Helms.
No, I know.
He came to visit.
Oh, yeah. Of course.
Anyway, he couldn't
be here today.
Where is he?
I don't know.
But he thought you were
getting out tomorrow.
So did I.
Where are you from?
Australia.
♪ [ Car Speakers:
Man Singing Aria ]
♪ [ Continues ]
Order what you want.
It's on me.
I ate.
They gave me breakfast.
Okay.
[ Woman ]
What can I get for you?
I'll just have a coffee.
Breakfast bagel.
Coffee, cream and sugar.
- You got it.
- Thank you.
You married?
No. Divorced.
Kids?
Yeah. Two.
Boy and girl, both grown up.
They live here?
No, they live in Maryland.
What part of Maryland?
Annapolis.
You got family
in Maryland?
No, I have a buddy
who lived in Baltimore.
You have family in Reno.
No.
Family anywhere?
I have a daughter
in Arizona.
That's not too far.
Yeah.
How old is she?
Twenty-four.
[ Plates Clatter ]
Thanks.
That's good coffee.
Yeah?
This is a cool little place.
Yeah. Yeah.
This is my breakfast place.
You know, it's funny.
I've never been to Reno,
but technically
I've lived here for 12 years.
I've never seen any of it.
So you didn't live in Reno?
No, I lived in Sacramento.
Oh.
Well, I've only been here
about a month myself,
and I will say
it's a place not without charm,
but I didn't think it could get
this cold on the desert.
- You just moved here?
- Yeah.
From where?
Maryland.
Welcome to the neighborhood.
[ Chuckles ]
Does this look okay?
Looks fine.
Here's my card.
Um, call me if you have
any problems with Mr. Helms...
or if you need to know
anything else.
Thanks.
Do you want me to hang around
until you get checked in?
No.
I'll be fine.
Good to meet you, Travis.
You too.
All right.
You take care.
Yeah. Thanks.
[ Keys Clink ]
♪ [ TV:
Instrumental Soundtrack ]
[ Man Speaking, Indistinct ]
[ TV: Channels Changing ]
[ TV Clicks Off ]
[ Bubbling ]
[ Horn Honks ]
[ Truck Horn Honks ]
[ Siren Wailing ]
[ Travis ]
This is it.
Nice room.
Very clean.
You can put that anywhere.
Oh. Yeah.
I have another
full box for you.
Oh, thank you.
It's really nice. Thanks.
Oh, you're welcome.
You're welcome.
They-- These are clean,
they're not ripped,
but they-- they might be
a little out of style.
What, are there
bell-bottoms in here?
[ Laughs ]
No, those I kept for me.
Are you making coffee?
Yeah, you want a cup?
You know what? We don't
have time. We're gonna be late.
You oughta shut that off,
grab a sweater,
and we gotta go.
Okay.
Now they're trying to
figure out what to do
with these trees--
whether to leave them there
and tunnel through them...
or to rearrange the trail.
Although we are not trees,
in our Gospel lesson
we find the story
of a man...
who couldn't tell
the difference
between the two--
between people and trees.
To heal this man, Jesus
spit on the man's eyes...
and laid his hands on him.
But the man opened his eyes
and could see men,
but they were blurry
and looked like trees
walking around.
And then Jesus
repeated the process,
and the man could see.
The striking detail in the story
is that the blind man's vision
was only partially restored.
How many people among us
still see persons as things?
We do not see them
as children of God.
We do not consider them
as persons of infinite worth.
[ Congregation ]
So that we may love you
with our whole being...
and love our neighbors
as ourselves...
through Jesus Christ,
our Lord,
who lives and reigns with you
in the unity
of the Holy Spirit,
one God, now and forever.
Amen.
♪ [ Cell Phone:
Ringtone Chiming ]
- Hello?
- [ Woman ]
Hi, Dad.
Hey, pumpkin.
How you doing?
Not much. Watching TV.
What are you doing?
I'm at the art gallery.
You are? That's nice.
Who are you with?
Nobody.
You went to the museum
by yourself?
Yeah.
Hey, you're not talking
in the gallery, are you?
Uh, no. I am outside.
Okay. Well,
I don't want to keep you.
Well, no, no, no, no.
No, talk to me.
What's-- Is everything okay?
Yeah. I'm just checking in.
Good.
I am still alive.
Okay, good.
Have you met
any nice women up there?
What do you mean?
What do you mean
what do I mean?
Women. To date.
To take to the museum.
[ Chuckles ]
I'm too old to date,
April.
No, you're not.
Hey, you should try signing up
for an online service.
Yeah, no,
I'm too busy for that.
Okay, well,
what if I signed you up?
Would you do it then?
Probably not.
That's not a "definitely not."
Well, it's a most likely
definitely not.
Okay, what about I do it,
and then we'll see?
Okay, you can do it,
but...
I will still probably
most likely
definitely not do it.
Okay, I already did it.
So I'm just looking for
belated permission.
That's my girl.
[ Chuckles ]
All right. So do I have
any hot dates yet?
Not yet,
but I will let you know.
All right. Well, weed out
everybody except the 28-year-old
supermodels, okay?
Gross, Dad.
[ Chuckles ]
Hey, I'm gonna
head back inside. Um--
I'll call you
in a couple days,
all right?
Okay. I'm gonna
e-mail you about this.
This is happening.
Okay, that's fine.
How's that brother of yours?
He's good.
All right.
Love you, pumpkin.
Okay, I love you too.
Bye, Dad.
Bye, sweetheart.
So, how have you been
making out on the bus, getting
around town? Is that okay?
Yeah, it's been no problem.
Well, I can drive you
anywhere that you ever
want to go, okay?
Thanks.
Like, especially--
Salad.
that job interview tomorrow.
All right? I'd be happy
to take you there.
You know, I worked it out
on the bus, and I think
it's gonna be fine.
Okay.
Well, you've got my number--
Angela and I.
Either of us would be happy
to take you anywhere.
Did you decorate
this place yourself,
Mrs. Helms?
Yes. Oh, please,
call me Angela.
You did a great job.
It's a good look for the room.
Oh, thank you. It's, um,
thrift shop, antiques.
I'm a bit of
a bargain hunter.
And lots of great stuff
comes through here.
- Are you from here?
- No. Actually, St. Louis.
Oh, I love St. Louis.
Mmm, I love St. Louis too.
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah, I got stuck there once
for two weeks.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
I was driving cross-country
with my girlfriend,
and we broke up in St. Louis,
and she left me there.
No.
Oh.
Yeah. I was stuck there
for two weeks,
but then I got a ride back
to New York.
But that
must have been terrible.
[ Steve ] Mm-hmm.
Well, I don't know.
I had a blast there.
And she broke down
in Utah, so--
[ Both Laughing ]
Well, actually,
I was pretty young
when I left St. Louis,
so I don't really know
too much about
the nightlife.
It's pretty serious.
It was back then.
Hmm.
Are you from Nevada?
No, I'm from North Carolina.
Hmm.
I thought there was
a little Southern in you.
Mm-hmm.
There's a lot of
Southern in here.
[ Both Chuckle ]
So why did you come here?
God.
I don't think we planned
on coming here. I think
it was a surprise, but,
you know,
we prayed on it and, uh,
asked the Lord
where we were needed,
and here we are.
But I was hoping
he'd pray for
a second choice.
[ Steve Chuckles ]
And you did. You did.
Yes, you did.
[ Angela Chuckles ]
So you were already together
when you came here?
- Mm-hmm. We met on
a mission trip in England.
- Oh, cool.
Yeah, actually,
Steve's fiancée
was my bunkmate.
- Really?
- [ Chuckling ]
Yeah.
She complained about him
every night,
and I eventually talked her
into breaking up with him,
which now sounds
a little self-serving,
but I actually thought
he was kind of a jerk.
Yeah, I was a jerk.
[ Chuckles ]
But it's a great story.
Yeah.
And, actually, he was the one
that got me really serious
about the mission.
Were you always serious?
About Christianity?
No. I was a punk kid,
and I think my-- my parents
were the only two atheists
in Asheville.
I didn't get serious
until I was 16.
Sixteen's pretty young.
I had a pretty
significant dream.
What happened in the dream?
No, you wouldn't believe me
if I told you.
He's embarrassed to say.
Well, no, no, no.
I just-- I don't want him
to think I'm crazy.
Oh, I think he's seen
crazier than you.
[ Steve ]
I don't know.
Must have been some dream.
It was.
[ Angela ]
Did you have
enough salad there, Travis?
Um--
Have some rolls.
Extra rolls.
Yeah. Maybe.
Thank you.
We've got a good dessert
coming up too.
♪ [ Radio: Country ]
♪ [ Man Singing, Indistinct ]
[ Bell Dings ]
So what brought you here?
Um, would you believe
my daughter signed me up?
[ Gasps ]
Mine too!
Oh, really?
Yeah!
[ Chuckles ]
How old is yours?
Twenty-eight.
Oh. Mine's 17,
so only one more year
before I'm free.
Oh.
You know, enjoy them
as long as you can, 'cause
you're gonna miss them.
Really.
Yeah.
Yeah, she signed me up
about three weeks ago,
and she only told me
this week.
[ Gasps ]
Oh, my God.
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah.
- That's funny.
- Yeah. Yeah.
Well-- Well, good for you
for coming out.
Oh, dear.
Have you
done this before?
No.
Well, dating, yes,
but this--
this speed thing, no.
You seem like a pro.
Thank you.
I guess.
I mean, that is
a compliment, right?
Oh, yeah.
Oh.
Oh-- Yeah.
So, um,
tell me something
unique about you, Martin.
Um--
I don't--
Come on.
Well,
I sang in a rock band
in the '60s.
Get out!
What were you called?
Kopyrite.
With a "K."
- Oh, that is really unique.
- Yeah?
Yeah.
What about you?
I was gonna say I can juggle.
Oh, really?
Knives?
No, uh, the balls.
- [ Clears Throat ]
- [ Chuckles ]
Excuse me. I--
[ Clears Throat ]
- I'm a little nervous.
- Oh, that's all right.
I was pretty apprehensive
about this too.
Really?
Yeah.
You know, just
this meeting new people--
it's tough.
I feel a little...
socially dysfunctional,
but I guess
maybe we all are
a little bit to be here.
Maybe we're just unlucky.
[ Bell Dings ]
Oh.
Okay.
It's good to meet you,
Cheryl.
Wait. It was nice to meet you.
Hey, thank you.
It's a pleasure. Bye.
Hi.
Hi, Sandra.
Are you having fun yet?
[ No Audible Dialogue ]
Hey, handsome.
You looking
to keep warm tonight?
Uh--
[ Chuckles ]
I could use someone
to keep me warm.
You might try
a couple more layers.
That could do the trick.
Come on. You're not
gonna leave me standing
around here, are you?
I don't know
if it's a good idea.
Why wouldn't it be a good idea?
I don't know. Uh--
All right. Let's get
out of the cold.
I don't have much cash on me.
Fifty dollars, plus the room
for anything you want.
I'm staying in a motel.
[ Siren Wailing In Distance ]
So you're looking at a bargain.
What's your name?
Lacy.
- All right, Lacy.
- Where's your car?
[ Chattering ]
[ Travis Grunting ]
Thanks.
[ Door Closes ]
- Thanks for meeting me.
- Not a problem.
I'm interested in hearing
how things are going
with the program.
Yeah?
And with you, in general.
I got a job.
Really?
What is it?
Parking lot attendant.
[ Chuckles ]
That's great.
Yeah, a lot of people
have trouble
with that first hurdle.
Things are tough,
especially now.
No, that is really good
that you got that.
Yeah. I mean,
it's something to do. Um--
It's somewhere to be
is more like it.
How are things going
with Steve Helms?
Fine.
Yeah?
I don't want to be rude,
but is there a reason that you
wanted to meet me and not him?
Well, I did call him.
We talked for a little bit.
He's a really nice guy.
He's just, uh,
very Christian.
Okay.
I mean, I believe in God.
I just feel like
I'm a fraud around him.
God?
No. Steve.
Oh, I see.
I don't mean that you're not
very Christian. I don't know
much about you at all.
I just felt
that it would be nice...
to talk to someone different
once in a while, you know.
Yeah, well,
that's understandable.
Are you?
Very Christian?
I've got a degree
in theology,
and I worked for the church
for many, many years.
Yeah, I should have known.
Yeah, you shouldn't be
intimidated by that.
Doesn't mean anything.
Well, I feel like
it should mean nothing
or everything,
and I can't get to
either place, you know.
I know that sounds very vague.
I just--
I'm trying to
restart my life,
and I feel like if I don't
get on the train at the get-go,
then I'm gonna miss it,
and I'm gonna
fuck everything up.
Sorry about my language.
I wouldn't worry about it.
Yeah.
I mean, I--
You know, I know where
you're coming from.
I'm in a similar
place myself.
Are you?
Yeah. I had
what you call a--
a crisis of faith...
a few years ago.
What happened?
I mean,
you don't have to answer that
if you don't want to.
[ Woman ]
More coffee?
Uh, I'm fine, thanks.
I'll have a little.
Thank you.
Thanks.
I'll tell you
if you tell me why
you were in prison.
Can't you just look that up?
Yeah, I can look it up.
I was in prison
for manslaughter.
Unintentional.
I killed a man drunk driving.
He was 26.
He had a wife, no kids.
He drove a Mazda 626.
[ Sighs ]
Well--
[ Clears Throat ]
I wish I could say
there was something
to start it,
but-- you know,
like if my son had been
in that car.
But I, um--
I woke up
one Sunday morning, and...
I didn't wanna go
to church anymore.
I felt
I'd sacrificed enough
of my life to God,
and I didn't wanna
do it anymore.
So I woke up selfish,
and it hasn't gone away.
So you quit the church?
No, I was fired
when I got divorced.
They fired you
for getting divorced?
[ Chuckles ] Yeah.
It wasn't funny then,
but it is now.
But you still wanted to work
for a Christian organization?
Frankly, Travis,
these are the only people
who would hire me.
Well, you could always be
a parking lot attendant.
[ Chuckles ]
That's not so funny,
you know.
I applied
for a manager's position
at Starbucks,
and I couldn't even get
an interview, so--
No, this is pretty much
all I'm qualified to do.
[ Martin ] Where are you off to?
[ Travis ]
Back to the bus, to the motel.
[ Martin ]
I'd give you a lift,
except I have to be somewhere.
No problem.
The bus is fine.
Okay.
Well, do you like soccer?
No. Why?
[ Whistle Blows ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Girl ]
No! No! The ball!
[ Girls Shouting ]
[ Whistle Blows ]
[ Cheering ]
[ Girl ]
Hey, ref.
Do that again.
You want me
to take a shot?
Yeah.
I'm gonna kick it
to your right.
Not bad.
You wanna take a shot?
Yeah, I don't think
I've ever kicked
a soccer ball.
Come on. Just pick your mark
and kick it.
[ Laughing ]
Um--
[ Chuckles ]
Close.
[ Girl ]
That guy has no aim.
That was a horrible shot.
Thank you.
[ Chuckles ]
Is it tough being away
from your kids?
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
You talk to 'em much?
Well, I don't get to talk
to my son very often,
but I talk to my daughter
as much as I can.
She's got a baby around,
so she's busy.
So you're a grandpa.
Yep.
And I don't look a day
over 40, right?
Why don't you get to talk
to your son much?
He's an artist,
and he runs a gallery,
and he's very busy.
And... I get the feeling
he just doesn't wanna talk
to me at the moment.
Oh.
That must be tough.
[ Travis ]
Thanks for the ride.
[ Martin ] Not a problem.
And thanks for showing me
around a bit.
Hey, anytime.
I'm, uh, thinking
of inviting my daughter up.
Oh, yeah?
That'll be nice.
Yeah. I think she might like
to see how I'm settling in.
Did she visit you much
when you were in the--
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
She did.
She, uh, you know--
She came by as much
as she could.
What's her name?
Diana.
Yeah.
That's a pretty name.
Well--
All right.
You take care, Travis.
I'll see you around.
♪ [ Rock ]
[ Martin ]
♪ Oh, Genevieve
[ Singing Along ]
♪ Sweet Genevieve
♪ Oh, Genevieve
♪ My Genevieve
♪ Don't you leave me
♪ Oh, don't leave me
♪ In misery
[ Chuckles ]
♪ Genevieve
♪ My Genevieve
♪ Baby, don't you leave me
♪ Oh, don't you leave me
♪ In misery
♪ Well, you've gone
♪ And left me in misery
♪ You've treated me
so horribly ♪
♪ You've treated me so bad
♪ You've treated me
so carelessly ♪
♪ You're the one and only girl
I've ever had ♪
Hey, punky, it's your father.
It's about 10:30 your time,
so you might already be in bed.
Um, I thought
I'd ring and let you know
that I went on those dates,
and they were terribly awkward.
You know, it's hard enough
to impress one woman a night,
let alone 10.
I didn't get any matches.
But, you know,
I only put one name down,
and I wasn't sure
who was who at the end, so, um--
Give me a call tomorrow, okay?
And I love you.
And you owe me big-time,
all right?
Bye.
[ Line Ringing ]
Hey, this is Ryan.
Leave a message.
[ Answering Machine Beeps ]
Hey, Ryan, it's your father.
Um, I just read about
your latest show online,
and it sounds to me
like it was a huge success.
"Toast of the art world,"
I think someone said.
Um, really proud of you,
and you better send me
some of your new work...
before it's too expensive
for me to afford, all right?
Give me a call when you can.
Bye.
Just put this
in your window.
Okay.
And pay
when you come out.
[ Computer Voice ]
Now serving H750...
at counter number 22.
[ Man ]
Okay, let's see here.
[ Paper Rustling ]
Mm-hmm. Well, you know,
I can tell you
right off the bat...
that you're gonna have
to retake the written
and the behind-the-wheel test...
before we can issue you
a driver's license.
Um, what I need to tell you
is that Nevada is
an illegal "per se" state.
And what that means is
that when you blew hot
at the scene of the accident,
the D.M.V. took immediate
administrative action,
completely separate
from any criminal penalties.
It's an automatic
three-year suspension,
and the clock doesn't run
while you're behind bars.
Okay, well, I'm really
just trying to figure out...
what I'm gonna need
for this to happen.
Not necessarily today,
but when the time comes.
Sure.
I perfectly understand.
What you do
is fill out this form...
and provide residency
and proof of identity.
Then we can issue you
an I.D. card...
that should be helpful
in the interim.
But, uh, what you're
gonna have to do...
is complete
a Substance Abuse
Traffic Offender Program.
It's fairly simple.
It's a computer-scored
questionnaire...
that assesses your lifestyle
and your drinking patterns.
Then you'll meet
with a counselor,
and they'll go over
your drive record here
with you...
and make
a recommendation of either
a basic 10-hour program...
or a weekend
48-hour program...
or a 50-hour
clinical program.
Uh, and they'll cost you
about $190.
Now, you have a right
to a second opinion
from a different counselor,
um, but that normally
goes about 120 bucks.
If you're recommended
for the basic 10-hour program,
uh, that's included
in that $190 assessment fee.
But if you are recommended
for the weekend
48-hour program...
or the 50-hour
clinical program,
that can cost you anywhere
from $350 to $750.
[ Bell Clanging ]
Now, as soon as you've
completed that program,
and we have confirmation
that you've been successful...
and you can show proof
of liability insurance,
then we can get you
behind the wheel
and get you tested.
So don't worry.
It's just like riding a bike.
And once you're successful
at the drive test,
all you have to do is pay
the $45 reinstatement fee...
and remember
to just smile pretty
for your photograph.
[ Man ]
When I really wanna worship,
I love to be in there.
Because these people
really get it.
And the beauty of this is
not just the men and women
who are being ministered to,
whose lives have been changed,
who are gonna get out of prisn
and get a mentor--
And the studies have shown tht
we have reduced the recidivism
rate to 8% when we do this.
Not only is that
a wonderful thing,
but the world sees something.
And what they see
is what John Calvin said--
that the church is making
the invisible kingdom visible.
And when they see these people
coming out of these communities,
getting transformed
and living for Christ,
that's when they see
the invisible kingdom
become visible.
Thank you
for being a part of it.
And those who are not,
I urge you to do so.
I think you'll find
great blessings in it,
as I have these past 30 years.
God bless you.
I wanna thank y'all for
giving me this opportunity...
and for letting me know
that even though
I've made mistakes in my life,
there was somebody out there
that cared.
You know, I also found
that my father Jesus Christ
also cares.
And he's really blessed me.
And I woke up this morning,
and I thanked him.
Because I got
an 11-year-old son,
and I made him some breakfast.
And that's something
I've been asking for
since the day he was born,
and I just thank him for that.
[ Woman ]
We've seen the wonderful
benefits of this program...
to our community
time and time again.
We will have an offering
for SBL if you'd like
to contribute financially,
and the volunteer coordinator,
Mr. Martin Bonner,
is here today.
If he'd stand up.
Martin will be over
in the fellowship hour...
if you'd like to sign up
to be one of the mentors.
Thanks, Martin.
And now if you'd all stand...
and please join in singing
"For All the Saints."
Hymn number 711.
[ Auctioneer ]
60, 65.
60 bid. 65 where?
[ Ringing ]
This is Martin Bonner.
Martin, it's Travis.
Hello, Travis.
Sorry to bother you at work.
No trouble.
So I just talked to
my daughter on the phone.
Really? How'd it go?
Good. Really good.
I mean, she cried, but I think
it was a good cry, you know?
Sure.
So anyway she's gonna
come out and see me.
She's gonna grab a bus
tomorrow and come out for the
day.
Great.
Yeah.
Uh--
I-- I talked about you
and what a help you've been,
and-and she really wants
to meet you.
She was hoping that you
would have lunch with us.
Really?
Yeah.
Tomorrow?
Well, don't you wanna
spend time with her alone?
Yeah, we will. It's just, uh--
She said she really
wanted to meet you,
and I thought that lunch
would be the only opportunity.
All right.
Great.
She gets in at noon.
And the station is
right next to a Carrows.
I was thinking
that maybe I could take
a bus over to your office,
and if you didn't mind too much,
you could drive me over there.
That'll be fine.
Great.
I really appreciate it.
Uh, anyway, I'm at work,
and I'm not supposed
to be making calls,
so I'll see you tomorrow
at 11:30?
Okay, Travis.
It'll be my treat,
all right?
Thanks.
No worries.
Bye-bye.
[ Customers Chattering ]
[ Woman ]
Hello. How many?
[ Woman #2 ] Two.
[ Woman #1 ]
Right this way, please.
Hi.
- Who's this?
- This is my friend Martin.
He works
for the program I'm in.
Hello.
Diana, yes?
Travis has told me
a lot about you.
Hi.
Um, are we all
eating together?
Yeah.
Oh.
Okay. We're gonna need
a bigger table then.
When did you start
wearing glasses?
Uh, 12th grade.
They look good.
Thanks.
Excuse me a second.
I need to make
a quick phone call.
Sure.
I'm sorry.
Give me a second.
I'll be right back.
Martin!
Wait a minute, man.
Where are you going?
What's going on here?
Nothing.
- You didn't tell her about me.
- I'm sorry, okay?
I didn't know that it was
gonna go down like this.
I don't-- I'm--
Just don't go, please.
No, I've got no business
being here at all.
Look, I haven't seen
the kid for 12 years.
I didn't know
if I could handle it alone.
It was a shitty thing to do.
I get it. I'm sorry.
You cannot go.
You have got to stay.
Here.
What is that?
I said it would be my shout,
so, you know, take it.
Please.
I have to get back
to the office.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
[ Engine Starts ]
Did your party
come or leave?
Um, I'm not sure.
Well, would you
like to order?
Could you give me
a few minutes and--
Sure.
Thanks.
Sorry about that.
It's fine.
I'm sorry
if you had to wait.
I'm sorry to be late.
It's fine.
Can we start again?
Can we hug?
Okay.
Are you crying?
No. Why?
You looked like you were crying.
Well, I'm not.
I haven't eaten at a place
like this in ages.
Me either.
Oh. Right.
How was the bus?
It was fine.
I took the Greyhound.
It was fun.
It felt like that
Simon & Garfunkel song.
- Which one?
- Are we ready over here?
Oh, I haven't even looked.
I can be ready.
You go first.
Okay.
Um, is it possible
to get a half portion
of the turkey melt...
and then a cup
of the vegetable soup?
Um, I'm sure they can do that.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
What kind of bread?
Sourdough.
Okay.
And for you?
Oh, and no mayo
if it comes with mayo.
Okay.
I'll have the Superbird.
Also with no mayo.
Uh, french fries
or onion rings?
And can I have
a glass of water also?
Sure. Can I take these?
Thank you.
[ Chuckles ]
One time when you and Astin
were having a sleepover,
you asked me if you could have
French toast for breakfast,
and I said, "Yeah,"
but I didn't know
how to make it.
So I went to Denny's,
and I-- I got some
when you went to bed,
and I came back and heated
it up the next morning.
What?
Yeah.
You said the food was bad
and that I was a bad cook,
but really it was
just a day old.
That's gross.
Are you and Astin
still best friends?
Oh, God. I mean,
she was my best friend
in middle school.
I--I have no idea
what she's doing now.
I don't even talk to her
on Facebook.
On Facebook?
On the Internet?
Mm-hmm.
What about Mark?
Do you still talk to him?
Mark who?
Uh, I don't know.
You had a boyfriend named Mark.
Oh, Mark.
I don't even remember
his last name,
and he wasn't my boyfriend.
He's-- I thought
he was a good kid.
Well, how are you?
I'm good.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Are you--
Are you working?
Yeah. I work at Best Buy.
But I'm going to school
for my master's
of library science.
So you're a librarian.
Well, studying
to be a librarian.
Hmm.
I didn't know you needed
a master's for that.
[ Chuckles ]
I mean, you always were good
at reading, I guess.
You read a lot
of   Baby-sitter's Clubooks.
Well, my-- my taste is
a little different now.
I remember you won
a lot of personal pan pizzas
for reading stuff at school.
I don't even like pizza.
Can I have
a sip of your water?
Sure.
You sure?
Go ahead.
Thanks.
[ Exhales ]
Are you married?
No.
That's why I'm getting
into the library business--
for the men.
[ Chuckles ]
You're funny.
This is...
very hard, you know.
[ Sighs ]
Yeah, I know.
I mean, I'm--
I'm trying to be positive.
I'm glad that you're out,
and, uh, I'm glad I came, but--
Yeah.
There's a reason
I didn't come visit you.
I know.
I don't--
I ju-- I think this
might be a mistake.
No. Wait. A mistake? Why?
You asked me about Astin
and some random boy...
before you even asked
how I was doing.
Well, wait a minute.
I'm trying here.
I think that I should go.
- No, no, no, no, Diana.
- Sorry about that.
Phone call
took a little longer
than I expected.
Where are the menus?
We ordered.
Oh, never mind.
I'll have a coffee.
What did you guys get?
Uh, turkey melt
and a soup.
Ah, that's a good one.
Superbird.
What's that,
a giant chicken?
It's a, uh,
turkey sandwich.
Ah, all right.
Well, um, this
is kind of funny.
Um, I mean, it seems
so silly now
that I see you,
but, um, I brought
a picture of you with me
in case I didn't recognize you.
But you look exactly
the same.
I don't really know
what I thought was gonna
happen in 12 years,
but I guess you don't
really change that much
when you're older.
[ Chuckles ]
I wish.
Which picture?
Oh.
Yeah, I don't remember
where this was taken.
Your mother took it though.
Yeah, I know.
The glory days.
Hmm.
Well, you could have chose
a worse picture.
You mean like...
this one?
- Let me look at it.
- [ Travis ] No, no.
No, come on.
Come on. Come on.
[ Chuckles ]
Very sharp.
Burn this one.
I don't have many pictures
of when I was a teenager.
How come?
I don't know.
We didn't own a camera.
Um, but there--
Someone must have brought it
around because there were a few.
Did you grow up
in Australia?
Yeah, yeah. In Perth.
Oh, really?
Yep.
I've always wanted
to go to Australia.
Me too.
Well, you should go.
Did you need
a menu, hon?
Uh, no, thank you.
Um, just a coffee.
[ Woman ]
Milk and sugar?
Yep.
[ Woman ] Um, your food
will be out in just a second.
Thanks.
Mm-hmm.
So this Kiwi walks into a bar
with a pig under his arm,
and the barman
looks at him and he says,
"Where'd you get it?"
And the pig says,
"I won him in a raffle."
Good one.
It's a bit lame though.
You can use it
if you want to.
[ Woman ]
Whenever you guys are ready.
Can I take these?
Yes.
Thank you.
- [ Travis ] No, no, no, no,
don't do that.
- Oh, it's fine.
Yeah, please let me get it.
Okay.
Let me give you some money
for my coffee.
No, no, no.
I've got it.
Okay. It's my treat
next time.
I mean,
the day after Christmas
I always work, you know,
because it's
the big sales and stuff.
Right.
If you need, like,
a DVD player, let me know.
Well, Diana,
it has been a pleasure
to meet you.
Nice to meet you too.
All right,
have a nice afternoon.
Have a good trip back.
Thanks.
Yeah, and I hope
to see you again soon.
- Okay.
- All right. Travis.
Could you come
by the office this afternoon
when Diana is on the road?
Sure.
I need you to do me a favor.
Okay.
Okay. Duty calls.
Bye.
He's nice.
Yeah.
[ Engine Starts ]
It's cool what those people
are doing for you.
Yeah, it's cool.
I have to look
at an apartment later.
Do you wanna come,
or should I do it tomorrow?
Actually, I-- I think
I'm gonna head back to the bus.
What?
I got my return ticket
for the 3:00.
I thought you were
gonna take the 6:00.
I thought I might,
but I didn't.
I just-- I--
I didn't know what to expect.
Can you change it?
I don't know.
Look, this was nice,
but let's just
take it slow, okay?
I mean, I know you
probably wanna make up
for lost time or whatever,
but I can't just
do it like that.
This is how I need to do it.
Okay.
Can I give you money
for the bus?
No, no, no, you keep it.
I'm-- I'm all right.
So--
Okay, well,
let me know when you
get home safe, okay?
Okay. I will.
So--
Bye.
So there's
a closet over here.
Yeah. Over here
is a bathroom.
Listen, I prob--
Forget it.
Well, thanks
for coming back.
Hello, Jeff.
Hey, Mr. Bonner.
Jeff, this is
Travis Holloway.
Travis.
Hi.
This is Jeff.
He's our video guy.
Hi.
So, are you guys all set?
Yep. Just give him
a quick rundown on what
you're gonna ask, that's all.
Sure.
Well, you'll sit here,
and I'll just ask you
about how things have
been going in the program.
It's for prospective
volunteers and donors,
so hopefully
you can keep it
positive but truthful.
And, um, just answer
with experiences
you've had...
now that you've
been released.
And you're
gonna be filming this?
Oh, yeah.
I'm not very comfortable
on camera.
[ Jeff ]
Oh, that's fine. That's fine.
You don't have to be Cary Grant.
Just answer
however you feel.
Okay.
All right, so--
If you can look at me
when you're speaking,
and, uh, whenever
you're ready,
if you could just
say your name
and spell it for me.
Okay. Look at you?
Right.
Travis Holloway.
T-R-A-V-I-S
H-O-L-L-O-W-A-Y.
So how has-- Or how do you think
has the program made you
a better person...
since you've
been released?
Well, I think it's made me
a better person because--
because it's shown me
what a better person
looks like, you know?
Giving me all these
positive role models...
and positive influences
in my life...
shows you that you can be
just like that if you choose to.
How has the program made you
a better husband...
or father?
Well, it's definitely
made me want to learn
how to become a father,
and I think
that will help me be
a better father in the long run.
[ Jeff ]
And cut.
Print.
That's a wrap.
Very good.
Thanks, Jeff.
No problem.
I'll cut these together
with the ones
from High Desert State...
and get you something
next week?
Sounds good.
Take care, Travis.
Thanks.
Now we're even.
That wasn't so bad.
Good.
Thanks also for
the whole paying thing.
Oh, yeah. That's fine.
I feel like
all I wanna give her is
advice or money to help her,
but I don't have
any of either.
She seems like she's doing
all right though, huh?
Yeah. Yeah, I think she is.
I was unemployed
for three years...
between my last job
and this one.
During
my daughter's wedding,
I was filing for bankruptcy,
and I couldn't afford to pay
for any of it.
[ Elevator Bell Dings ]
Hey, this is Ryan.
Leave a message.
[ Answering Machine Beeps ]
Hey, Ryan.
It's your father.
I'm looking
at this wonderful
painting you sent me,
um, hanging right
in the middle of my apartment.
You know, it means a lot
that you sent it to me,
um, and it's wonderful
to hear from you,
even though indirectly.
I wanna tell you
that I love you, Son,
and... that I'm
really proud of you.
Give me a call when you can,
all right?
And-- Otherwise,
I'll give you a call
in a couple days.
Okay?
[ Sighs ]
♪ [ Stereo: Pop ]
Here. Why don't
you try those on
and see how they fit.
Thanks.
[ Ball Bouncing ]
[ Chattering ]
♪ [ Rock ]
[ Martin ]
♪ Oh, Genevieve
♪ Sweet Genevieve
♪ My Genevieve
♪ Don't you leave me
♪ Oh, don't leave me
♪ In misery
♪ Genevieve
♪ My Genevieve
♪ Baby, don't you leave me
♪ Oh, don't you leave me
♪ In misery
♪ Well, you've gone
♪ And left me in misery
♪ You've treated me
so horribly ♪
♪ You've treated me so bad
♪ You've treated me
so carelessly ♪
♪ You're the one and only girl
I've ever had ♪
♪ [ Instrumental Solo ]
♪ You treated me so horribly
♪ You left me alone
♪ You left me, darling
♪ In your brew of misery
♪ Genevieve
♪ My Genevieve
♪ Baby, don't leave me
in misery ♪
♪ Oh, you've gone and left me
♪ [ Instrumental Solo ]
♪ [ Ends ]