1
00:01:48,500 --> 00:01:53,175
Now that the war is over,
may i call you 'father' again?

2
00:02:01,630 --> 00:02:03,921
Gentlemen If you please...

3
00:02:04,021 --> 00:02:06,656
...your attention for a moment?

4
00:02:06,830 --> 00:02:08,830
A toast, gentlemen

5
00:02:09,140 --> 00:02:10,800
To those of our comrades...

6
00:02:10,900 --> 00:02:13,450
...who are not here tonight...

7
00:02:13,590 --> 00:02:16,790
...those to whom peace
came sooner than to us...

8
00:02:16,890 --> 00:02:23,350
...and to the same comrades of the
French, Italian, English and Americans...

9
00:02:24,490 --> 00:02:28,400
...to the comrades-living
and dead, of all men

10
00:02:41,080 --> 00:02:44,380
Funny how every bottle
seemed like the last?

11
00:02:44,480 --> 00:02:47,370
Now there's a million ahead of us.

12
00:02:47,420 --> 00:02:48,180
I'm going to drink to the life

13
00:02:48,280 --> 00:02:49,930
I never had a chance to live

14
00:02:50,030 --> 00:02:52,030
Cradle to the frontline

15
00:02:52,270 --> 00:02:54,570
I'm going to spill champagne
from Hamburg to Munich...

16
00:02:54,670 --> 00:02:56,990
...fall in love with every girl I meet

17
00:02:57,090 --> 00:02:59,090
I'm going to live.

18
00:03:02,300 --> 00:03:03,460
I've often thought about that too

19
00:03:03,560 --> 00:03:05,560
My life, I mean.

20
00:03:06,330 --> 00:03:09,150
I wonder what it was like
I haven't the vaguest idea.

21
00:03:09,250 --> 00:03:12,480
But it must be something that's passed

22
00:03:12,900 --> 00:03:16,200
So I'll drink to what I
value most-the three of us.

23
00:03:16,300 --> 00:03:16,550
To us.

24
00:03:16,650 --> 00:03:20,260
Not from day to day now,
but from year to year

25
00:03:20,360 --> 00:03:22,750
Erich, Gottfried To us.

26
00:03:26,130 --> 00:03:27,650
Now yours Gottfried.

27
00:03:27,750 --> 00:03:31,320
You may think it's childish but here it is

28
00:03:32,300 --> 00:03:35,780
On every battlefield,
soldiers think of going home

29
00:03:35,880 --> 00:03:38,220
Bands are playing when they left

30
00:03:38,320 --> 00:03:40,970
Heads were high and hearts were proud

31
00:03:41,070 --> 00:03:44,140
But in four long years now
many heads have fallen...

32
00:03:44,240 --> 00:03:46,875
...and many hearts have stopped

33
00:03:47,780 --> 00:03:50,180
So I drink to those who
think of home tonight.

34
00:03:50,280 --> 00:03:54,130
I drink to the peace they
hope to find at home.

35
00:03:54,230 --> 00:03:57,460
Now that peace has come to them in war

36
00:03:59,080 --> 00:04:01,180
You're a miracle Gottfried

37
00:04:01,280 --> 00:04:03,745
An idealist, born of the war.

38
00:04:04,810 --> 00:04:06,330
At ease, gentlemen.

39
00:04:06,430 --> 00:04:07,370
Captain Koster

40
00:04:07,470 --> 00:04:11,060
Your plane is to be ready for
dismantling in the morning

41
00:04:11,160 --> 00:04:12,980
You mean, my plane is to be torn apart?

42
00:04:13,080 --> 00:04:14,120
In the morning.

43
00:04:14,220 --> 00:04:15,420
But if you're ready...

44
00:04:15,520 --> 00:04:17,645
My plane is always ready.

45
00:04:32,980 --> 00:04:34,320
Otto always said there
was one good thing...

46
00:04:34,420 --> 00:04:35,730
...about getting killed

47
00:04:35,830 --> 00:04:39,145
Wouldn't have to say goodbye to 'Baby.'

48
00:05:37,560 --> 00:05:39,260
That's what we fought for.

49
00:05:39,360 --> 00:05:41,030
That's what we come back to

50
00:05:41,130 --> 00:05:43,370
Violence and terror.

51
00:05:43,970 --> 00:05:47,370
Won't they ever stop...
- It's not our fight, come on.

52
00:05:47,470 --> 00:05:49,140
It's my fight.

53
00:05:49,240 --> 00:05:50,590
I can't keep turning my back on peace.

54
00:05:50,690 --> 00:05:51,590
Look Gottfried, we're eating.

55
00:05:51,690 --> 00:05:54,320
We got a place to sleep and a job.

56
00:05:54,420 --> 00:05:56,030
We're running a repair shop not a country.

57
00:05:56,130 --> 00:05:57,950
They're running the country

58
00:05:58,050 --> 00:06:01,120
Give a hoodlum a club
and he'll run anything.

59
00:06:01,220 --> 00:06:02,580
The others like you, Otto

60
00:06:02,680 --> 00:06:04,240
They close their doors and windows...

61
00:06:04,340 --> 00:06:06,910
...and keep whistling in the dark.
- And we have six bottles of rum...

62
00:06:07,010 --> 00:06:08,960
...and it's Erich's birthday

63
00:06:09,060 --> 00:06:11,060
Now come on.

64
00:06:17,780 --> 00:06:20,130
Temper, temper.
Remember the repair shop.

65
00:06:20,230 --> 00:06:22,230
Keep whistling.

66
00:06:27,730 --> 00:06:30,840
What are the new heroes of
the Fatherland doing tonight?

67
00:06:30,940 --> 00:06:32,080
Posioning the drinking water?

68
00:06:32,180 --> 00:06:34,070
It's none of your business,
we're running a garage...

69
00:06:34,170 --> 00:06:35,330
...we're going to be very rich

70
00:06:35,430 --> 00:06:37,000
Germany will need mechanics
in the years to come

71
00:06:37,100 --> 00:06:39,360
There'll be all sorts of things to repair

72
00:06:39,460 --> 00:06:44,985
Souls, consciences, broken hearts and...
- Shut up and come inside.

73
00:06:48,960 --> 00:06:51,940
Happy birthday.
From Gottfried and me.

74
00:06:52,040 --> 00:06:54,440
Six, I mean four bottles of Cuban rum...

75
00:06:54,540 --> 00:06:57,630
...and the two missing went for riot attacks.

76
00:06:57,730 --> 00:06:58,990
What are we waiting for?

77
00:06:59,090 --> 00:07:01,000
There won't be any customers at night.
Let's celebrate.

78
00:07:01,100 --> 00:07:01,870
Celebrate, that's the thing.

79
00:07:01,970 --> 00:07:04,320
Let's get out of this crazy town.

80
00:07:04,420 --> 00:07:04,730
Where to?

81
00:07:04,830 --> 00:07:06,580
Anywhere. South America,
San Francisco, Mars,

82
00:07:06,680 --> 00:07:08,060
I'll settle for a ride in the country.

83
00:07:08,160 --> 00:07:11,110
We'll take Baby-the terror of the roads.

84
00:07:11,210 --> 00:07:14,100
And the rum. Don't forget the rum.

85
00:07:40,510 --> 00:07:43,230
I think he wants to 'play' Otto.

86
00:08:42,030 --> 00:08:44,880
Am I mistaken gentlemen? or did
we pass somebody on the road?

87
00:08:44,980 --> 00:08:46,060
Well I heard a noise

88
00:08:46,160 --> 00:08:48,160
Don't forget the rum.

89
00:08:48,730 --> 00:08:50,130
What kind of junk is this?

90
00:08:50,230 --> 00:08:51,590
You say something?

91
00:08:51,690 --> 00:08:52,630
I asked what make your car is

92
00:08:52,730 --> 00:08:53,800
Why, it's a Mutt.

93
00:08:53,900 --> 00:08:55,340
Grandfather was an airplane...

94
00:08:55,440 --> 00:08:56,800
...and Grandma was an old radio...

95
00:08:56,900 --> 00:08:59,960
...and it's Papa was an alarm clock.

96
00:09:01,070 --> 00:09:03,070
Well my name is Breuer.

97
00:09:03,740 --> 00:09:04,900
I'm Lenz.

98
00:09:05,000 --> 00:09:06,580
This is Koster and Lohkamp.

99
00:09:06,680 --> 00:09:09,410
Otto, why don't you show
Mr. Breuer the car?

100
00:09:09,510 --> 00:09:11,510
It'll be a pleasure.

101
00:09:12,690 --> 00:09:13,890
You know...

102
00:09:13,990 --> 00:09:16,370
...you wiped me off the map.

103
00:09:23,510 --> 00:09:24,730
Beautiful evening, isn't it?

104
00:09:24,830 --> 00:09:26,830
Very.

105
00:09:28,800 --> 00:09:31,010
Unusually mild form March.

106
00:09:31,210 --> 00:09:32,370
Yes.

107
00:09:32,470 --> 00:09:34,470
Terribly mild.

108
00:09:44,210 --> 00:09:46,790
We didn't know there was anyone so, er...

109
00:09:46,890 --> 00:09:49,430
...in the car. We'd have let you win.

110
00:09:49,530 --> 00:09:50,610
Why should you?

111
00:09:50,710 --> 00:09:52,150
It wouldn't have been fair.

112
00:09:52,250 --> 00:09:54,250
We can do 95.

113
00:09:54,420 --> 00:09:56,590
95. Phew.

114
00:09:56,830 --> 00:09:58,380
You didn't know that naturally.

115
00:09:58,480 --> 00:10:00,650
I'm afraid your husband felt insulted.

116
00:10:00,750 --> 00:10:03,480
One ought to be able to lose sometimes.

117
00:10:03,580 --> 00:10:07,040
And Herr. Breuer isn't my husband,
he's just a friend

118
00:10:07,140 --> 00:10:08,550
Are you three brothers?

119
00:10:08,650 --> 00:10:11,280
No. Do we look alike?

120
00:10:11,280 --> 00:10:12,790
Not exactly.

121
00:10:12,890 --> 00:10:14,880
But yet you have the same look.

122
00:10:14,980 --> 00:10:15,920
Hungry

123
00:10:16,020 --> 00:10:18,350
No. Proud.

124
00:10:18,350 --> 00:10:20,070
I suppose you wouldn't
consider selling the car?

125
00:10:20,170 --> 00:10:23,655
I'd sooner consider selling my right arm.

126
00:10:27,170 --> 00:10:27,830
Koster.

127
00:10:27,930 --> 00:10:31,830
When you take a curve at high speed,
do you use the break?

128
00:10:31,930 --> 00:10:33,220
I just turn the wheel...

129
00:10:33,320 --> 00:10:35,320
...and hope

130
00:10:36,830 --> 00:10:39,090
You know, I drove a car in the war.

131
00:10:39,190 --> 00:10:40,760
A squad car in Berlin.

132
00:10:40,860 --> 00:10:42,860
Better than the front.

133
00:10:43,780 --> 00:10:45,770
Oh much better. And safer.

134
00:10:45,870 --> 00:10:47,490
Unlucky for the country.

135
00:10:47,590 --> 00:10:50,490
Somebody had to live to run Germany
with most of the men dead.

136
00:10:50,590 --> 00:10:51,800
What's that?

137
00:10:51,900 --> 00:10:52,770
Nothing, nothing.

138
00:10:52,870 --> 00:10:55,335
Just turn the wheel and hope.

139
00:10:56,530 --> 00:10:58,490
Patricia-that's an English name isn't it?

140
00:10:58,590 --> 00:11:01,190
It was my mother's name, she was English.
- And your father?

141
00:11:01,290 --> 00:11:01,910
German.

142
00:11:02,010 --> 00:11:04,790
He was killed fighting the English.

143
00:11:04,890 --> 00:11:07,100
My mother died soon after.

144
00:11:08,130 --> 00:11:10,360
Were you in the war?
- Only a year.

145
00:11:10,460 --> 00:11:13,240
He wasn't boiled very hard.
Just sort of dipped.

146
00:11:13,340 --> 00:11:16,820
We were babies then.
- I like that.

147
00:11:16,820 --> 00:11:18,510
Gives us something in common.

148
00:11:18,610 --> 00:11:21,380
We're neither dead nor alive.

149
00:11:21,380 --> 00:11:23,420
Don't say that.
- No?

150
00:11:23,600 --> 00:11:24,570
No.

151
00:11:24,670 --> 00:11:27,170
You and Erich, you're both alive.

152
00:11:27,270 --> 00:11:28,660
Remember that.

153
00:11:28,760 --> 00:11:31,055
Alright. We'll drink to it.

154
00:11:34,890 --> 00:11:38,390
You ought to join our
organisation. Make men out of you.

155
00:11:38,490 --> 00:11:41,290
Marching men together.
- Marching what together?

156
00:11:41,390 --> 00:11:44,360
You know too many people think they
have the right to opinion nowadays.

157
00:11:44,460 --> 00:11:47,210
What Germany needs is order. Discipline.

158
00:11:47,310 --> 00:11:48,420
Stop that.

159
00:11:48,520 --> 00:11:50,520
Oh, sit down, sit down.

160
00:11:50,590 --> 00:11:53,200
You shell shocked fellows give me
a pinge with your hysterics.

161
00:11:53,300 --> 00:11:55,300
Easy Gottfried.

162
00:11:58,290 --> 00:12:02,540
From now on, we'll drink
milk on Erich's birthday.

163
00:12:05,250 --> 00:12:08,350
So its your birthday? How old are you?

164
00:12:08,450 --> 00:12:10,170
Old enough.

165
00:12:10,270 --> 00:12:12,435
One of the nicer ages?

166
00:12:12,485 --> 00:12:14,250
Which is the nicest?

167
00:12:14,350 --> 00:12:15,020
Well...

168
00:12:15,120 --> 00:12:16,920
...your age I think

169
00:12:17,020 --> 00:12:20,170
Yes, just about your age.

170
00:12:29,190 --> 00:12:32,430
Think Herr. Breuer can drive alright?
- Oh, I think so.

171
00:12:32,530 --> 00:12:34,250
If you're not quite sure, one of us
could go with you, gladly.

172
00:12:34,350 --> 00:12:37,410
No it's alright. He drives
the same, drunk or sober.

173
00:12:37,510 --> 00:12:40,700
May I call in the morning to see
you got home alright?

174
00:12:40,800 --> 00:12:41,830
If you like.

175
00:12:41,930 --> 00:12:44,630
It's really our fault, you know
with all my birthday rum.

176
00:12:44,730 --> 00:12:46,730
2796

177
00:13:10,940 --> 00:13:14,085
I wonder what she sees in that swine.

178
00:13:14,160 --> 00:13:15,490
Wonderful girl huh?

179
00:13:15,590 --> 00:13:16,860
Yeah, she's alright.

180
00:13:16,960 --> 00:13:18,960
Alright?

181
00:13:19,100 --> 00:13:21,410
You know Erich, I think you must have
recieved a serious head wound...

182
00:13:21,510 --> 00:13:23,390
...that you never reported.

183
00:13:23,490 --> 00:13:26,360
She's such a tiny thing though.
Looks like she could be blown away.

184
00:13:26,460 --> 00:13:28,700
Must be nice to remember your birthday.

185
00:13:28,800 --> 00:13:30,520
When was yours Gottfried?

186
00:13:30,620 --> 00:13:31,640
March.

187
00:13:31,740 --> 00:13:34,205
Er, no. April, it used to be.

188
00:13:41,340 --> 00:13:43,220
You know Erich

189
00:13:43,320 --> 00:13:46,720
Something ought to be done about that girl

190
00:13:46,820 --> 00:13:48,470
What girl?

191
00:13:48,570 --> 00:13:50,990
What girl? The one with Breuer.
What's her name?

192
00:13:51,090 --> 00:13:51,940
Pat what?

193
00:13:52,040 --> 00:13:55,170
Ah well. How should I know?
Maybe she's only got one name.

194
00:13:55,270 --> 00:13:57,224
Well you wrote down her
address on a matchbox.

195
00:13:57,324 --> 00:13:57,710
I saw you.

196
00:13:57,810 --> 00:14:00,480
So do I. Matches were all used up.

197
00:14:00,580 --> 00:14:02,440
You mean, you threw it away?
- Yup.

198
00:14:02,540 --> 00:14:05,070
Do you realise what you threw away?

199
00:14:05,170 --> 00:14:10,050
And after Otto and I sat listening for an hour
to that Breuer so that you could move in.

200
00:14:10,150 --> 00:14:10,850
Maybe Otto knows it.

201
00:14:10,950 --> 00:14:14,220
No he doesn't. I mean er...
maybe he does.

202
00:14:14,320 --> 00:14:17,800
I should've known you wouldn't have
enough brains to appreciate her

203
00:14:17,900 --> 00:14:19,900
Did you see those eyes?

204
00:14:20,550 --> 00:14:20,890
Of course not.

205
00:14:20,990 --> 00:14:22,980
Because you were looking at yourself
through a glass of rum.

206
00:14:23,080 --> 00:14:24,680
Very high class rum too.

207
00:14:24,780 --> 00:14:26,330
And her hands.

208
00:14:26,430 --> 00:14:28,430
Long and slender.

209
00:14:28,720 --> 00:14:30,550
Like Romain salad.

210
00:14:30,650 --> 00:14:32,490
Otto and I appreciate such things.

211
00:14:32,590 --> 00:14:35,580
You should travel Erich,
you've never been anywhere.

212
00:14:35,680 --> 00:14:37,320
Germans don't understand love.

213
00:14:37,420 --> 00:14:40,740
I'm really a Latin,
that's what Pat's got.

214
00:14:40,840 --> 00:14:42,700
The soul of a South American.

215
00:14:42,800 --> 00:14:46,540
If you like South America so much,
why did you come back after 3 months?

216
00:14:46,640 --> 00:14:49,590
Because I've got the soul of a German.

217
00:14:49,690 --> 00:14:52,920
Think I'm going to get myself a drink.

218
00:14:59,180 --> 00:15:03,710
Hello?
- Er.. hello, this is that man.

219
00:15:04,010 --> 00:15:08,000
What man?
- the man you met the other night.

220
00:15:08,290 --> 00:15:11,683
I've met lots of men on lots of other nights.

221
00:15:11,783 --> 00:15:15,100
I don't exactly know
how to describe myself.

222
00:15:15,200 --> 00:15:20,430
I was one of the men that beat you.
- Really you must have the wrong woman.

223
00:15:20,530 --> 00:15:24,100
In our car I mean.
- Oh, of course...

224
00:15:24,780 --> 00:15:27,058
...you were the one who
was so upset about...

225
00:15:27,158 --> 00:15:28,350
...the state of the nation.

226
00:15:28,450 --> 00:15:31,250
No

227
00:15:31,530 --> 00:15:36,139
No? Well, you must be the one who sang
with Herr Breuer. 

228
00:15:36,239 --> 00:15:36,440
No,

229
00:15:36,540 --> 00:15:38,540
Was there another?

230
00:15:39,030 --> 00:15:41,460
Of course, I remember you.

231
00:15:41,980 --> 00:15:43,710
I was just wondering if
you got home alright.

232
00:15:43,810 --> 00:15:44,810
Did you?

233
00:15:44,910 --> 00:15:46,960
I'm quite sure I did.

234
00:15:47,580 --> 00:15:49,580
That's fine.

235
00:15:49,670 --> 00:15:52,490
Well, goodbye.

236
00:15:52,910 --> 00:15:55,720
Did you call me up just to say that?

237
00:15:55,820 --> 00:15:57,120
No,

238
00:15:57,220 --> 00:15:59,920
We just weren't very busy.

239
00:16:01,730 --> 00:16:06,235
Well, oddly enough, I'll be busy next
Tuesday evening.

240
00:16:06,450 --> 00:16:09,680
Well that is odd. Well goodbye.

241
00:16:10,570 --> 00:16:14,565
Till Tuesday evening then.
- Till Tuesday evening

242
00:16:34,380 --> 00:16:38,210
Fraulein Hollmann please,
she's expecting me.

243
00:16:38,310 --> 00:16:40,350
If you'll come this way.

244
00:16:51,700 --> 00:16:55,610
Whom shall I announce?
- Lohkamp, Erich Lohkamp.

245
00:17:00,400 --> 00:17:03,860
Well, do I have to wait till
the piano goes home?

246
00:17:03,960 --> 00:17:06,540
Ludwig always brings
people through this door.

247
00:17:06,640 --> 00:17:08,050
The piano is my problem child

248
00:17:08,150 --> 00:17:10,150
Either there is no entrance or no piano.

249
00:17:10,250 --> 00:17:12,070
You'll have to come in
through the bedroom.

250
00:17:12,170 --> 00:17:17,780
Oh no, I wouldn't think of doing that.
Not while, Ludwig's looking.

251
00:17:19,030 --> 00:17:22,600
Is there anything more?
- No Ludwig, thanks.

252
00:17:24,070 --> 00:17:28,170
He loves to think I still own the whole house
though I only rent this little bit of it.

253
00:17:28,270 --> 00:17:31,160
This was your house?
- Hm, long ago.

254
00:17:31,580 --> 00:17:33,550
I thought you told me you were poor.

255
00:17:33,650 --> 00:17:35,690
Does it look as if I am?

256
00:17:35,860 --> 00:17:37,900
Sit down.
- Thank you.

257
00:17:41,230 --> 00:17:45,990
No easy chair in the shops or the backseat
of limousines.

258
00:17:45,990 --> 00:17:47,990
Now that's gone.

259
00:17:48,970 --> 00:17:50,950
I sold it to Mr. Schultz.

260
00:17:51,050 --> 00:17:53,050
We bought a taxi.

261
00:17:56,380 --> 00:17:59,550
It's still mild out isn't it?

262
00:18:01,160 --> 00:18:03,300
You don't know how to
make conversation...

263
00:18:03,400 --> 00:18:05,910
I was just thinking something foolish.

264
00:18:06,010 --> 00:18:08,230
Thinking how nice it
would be to pick a time...

265
00:18:08,330 --> 00:18:09,330
...to be born.

266
00:18:09,430 --> 00:18:11,800
I'd pick an age of reaon and quiet.

267
00:18:11,900 --> 00:18:13,290
If there ever was one.

268
00:18:13,390 --> 00:18:14,640
What would you pick?

269
00:18:14,740 --> 00:18:16,740
I don't know...

270
00:18:17,930 --> 00:18:20,380
This minute is good enough for me.

271
00:18:20,480 --> 00:18:22,470
That's a lovely compliment.

272
00:18:22,570 --> 00:18:24,870
Or is it just something you
thought of to say?

273
00:18:24,970 --> 00:18:26,970
No, what I mean is,

274
00:18:27,970 --> 00:18:32,440
How would I know I'd get to meet you
in the 'Age of Reason'?

275
00:18:32,540 --> 00:18:34,540
Shall we go now?

276
00:18:34,580 --> 00:18:36,960
I've to be back here by ten.

277
00:18:39,730 --> 00:18:42,840
It's a kind of business affair.
I'm trying to get a job.

278
00:18:42,940 --> 00:18:44,430
This way, through the bedroom.

279
00:18:44,530 --> 00:18:46,910
You can just shut your eyes.

280
00:18:56,410 --> 00:18:57,700
Where shall we dine?

281
00:18:57,800 --> 00:19:01,285
Well, there's a tea room down the street.

282
00:19:02,620 --> 00:19:04,210
Perhaps a big hotel?

283
00:19:04,310 --> 00:19:05,500
Nonsense, where would you go?

284
00:19:05,600 --> 00:19:07,810
Oh, well that's a terrible place.
Alphons' bar.

285
00:19:07,910 --> 00:19:10,970
That's absolutely out.
- Alphons' bar?

286
00:19:11,080 --> 00:19:14,062
It's very rough. No place for a girl like you.

287
00:19:14,162 --> 00:19:17,540
Alphons' bar's exactly the
place for a girl like me.

288
00:19:17,640 --> 00:19:19,640
This way.

289
00:19:26,470 --> 00:19:29,502
It's wonderful, it even smells
the way I thought it would.

290
00:19:29,602 --> 00:19:30,880
This is our headquarters.

291
00:19:30,980 --> 00:19:34,040
And this is Alphons on his
way over. He's crazy about...

292
00:19:34,140 --> 00:19:35,140
...choir singing.

293
00:19:35,240 --> 00:19:37,020
Food Erich?
- The best you've got.

294
00:19:37,120 --> 00:19:38,730
Two dinners.

295
00:19:38,830 --> 00:19:41,430
Fraulein Hollmann, this is Alphons.

296
00:19:41,530 --> 00:19:44,340
Would you like something special
on the phonograph?

297
00:19:44,440 --> 00:19:45,900
I would.

298
00:19:46,000 --> 00:19:47,650
But I don't know whether you have it.

299
00:19:47,750 --> 00:19:50,800
You see I'm crazy about choir singing.

300
00:19:50,900 --> 00:19:51,740
Choir singing?

301
00:19:51,840 --> 00:19:54,985
Well we have the best. Wait a moment.

302
00:19:55,860 --> 00:19:56,980
We're in for it.

303
00:19:57,080 --> 00:20:01,330
He's got over 200 records
of assorted choir music.

304
00:20:05,710 --> 00:20:08,005
Martini and a rum, Alphons.

305
00:20:13,580 --> 00:20:16,040
You have the looks of one
who enjoys good singing.

306
00:20:16,140 --> 00:20:18,140
But only choirs.

307
00:20:18,720 --> 00:20:19,500
Wait a minute.

308
00:20:19,600 --> 00:20:20,680
Take that away.

309
00:20:20,780 --> 00:20:23,892
Sausage is for ordinary
people. I have something...

310
00:20:23,992 --> 00:20:26,050
...very special. Bring me some chops.

311
00:20:26,150 --> 00:20:30,860
A prized pig. Killed it myself.

312
00:20:31,050 --> 00:20:33,930
Thats the only way a man knows
what he is getting.

313
00:20:34,030 --> 00:20:36,330
I see you understand meat also

314
00:20:36,430 --> 00:20:39,065
How about the soldier's hearts?

315
00:20:41,770 --> 00:20:45,090
He's madly in love with you.
- And I with him.

316
00:20:45,190 --> 00:20:47,190
Alphons and I have a lot in common.

317
00:20:47,290 --> 00:20:48,760
Meat and music.

318
00:20:48,860 --> 00:20:50,950
It's not generally known but

319
00:20:51,050 --> 00:20:54,880
I sang in a choir once and
have lived like a pig...

320
00:20:54,980 --> 00:20:56,980
...for years.

321
00:21:03,580 --> 00:21:04,690
Always smiling.

322
00:21:04,790 --> 00:21:07,150
Does that mean you're always happy?

323
00:21:07,250 --> 00:21:09,560
Oh yes, I'm a very superficial
and frivolous person.

324
00:21:09,660 --> 00:21:11,870
You see when I got over...

325
00:21:12,300 --> 00:21:14,300
Got over what?

326
00:21:14,780 --> 00:21:16,260
What I meant was...

327
00:21:16,360 --> 00:21:20,080
...when I found out I was
going completely broke

328
00:21:20,180 --> 00:21:22,610
I decided to live as I liked...

329
00:21:22,710 --> 00:21:25,550
...even if, only for a little while.

330
00:21:25,650 --> 00:21:27,690
I wanted to be very gay.

331
00:21:28,280 --> 00:21:29,930
and I was.

332
00:21:30,030 --> 00:21:32,770
Do you think that sounds irresponsible?

333
00:21:32,870 --> 00:21:35,020
I think that sounds very brave.

334
00:21:35,120 --> 00:21:37,240
I was frightened enough sometimes.

335
00:21:37,340 --> 00:21:41,675
As if I'd taken somebody else's
seat at the theatre.

336
00:21:44,060 --> 00:21:46,740
Now it's all over and I've got to get to work.

337
00:21:46,840 --> 00:21:48,840
For Breuer?

338
00:21:49,770 --> 00:21:51,880
What made you think of him?

339
00:21:51,980 --> 00:21:53,630
Oh, I don't know...

340
00:21:53,730 --> 00:21:55,855
...suddenly felt unhappy.

341
00:21:56,240 --> 00:21:58,830
When do you start?
- In a week.

342
00:21:59,140 --> 00:22:02,410
Then I'd be too tired to go out
in the evenings.

343
00:22:02,510 --> 00:22:05,230
That doesn't leave us much time.

344
00:22:05,260 --> 00:22:07,100
Lost the address huh?

345
00:22:07,200 --> 00:22:10,685
The matches were gone so he
threw it away.

346
00:22:10,860 --> 00:22:13,523
He couldn't even remember her
name. Didn't think much...

347
00:22:13,623 --> 00:22:15,510
...of her either the first time he met her.

348
00:22:15,610 --> 00:22:19,430
I guess he just didn't have anything better
to do tonight.

349
00:22:19,530 --> 00:22:21,350
Seems a little embarrassed
about something.

350
00:22:21,450 --> 00:22:24,680
Pretty clumsy.
- I warned you about the riff raff here.

351
00:22:24,780 --> 00:22:27,180
Let's keep very quiet and
maybe they'll go away.

352
00:22:27,280 --> 00:22:31,170
Erich's pretty smart, maybe she's got
a lot of money.

353
00:22:31,270 --> 00:22:33,650
You know, some men can
do that sort of thing.

354
00:22:33,750 --> 00:22:35,010
But I couldn't.

355
00:22:35,110 --> 00:22:40,380
And they expect us to sit with them
as if nothing had happened.

356
00:22:55,610 --> 00:22:57,490
My watch says quarter to ten, is that right?

357
00:22:57,590 --> 00:23:01,560
There are no clocks in this cafe.
Thats why we come here.

358
00:23:01,660 --> 00:23:03,030
Koster.

359
00:23:03,130 --> 00:23:07,040
Tomorrow's the anniversery
of our first attack.

360
00:23:09,470 --> 00:23:12,320
Another one from the war.
it'll never stop.

361
00:23:12,420 --> 00:23:15,480
The dates of battle are our only calendar.

362
00:23:15,580 --> 00:23:18,000
Doesn't seem to matter
whether you win or not.

363
00:23:18,100 --> 00:23:20,700
The war's become a center
of everybody's life.

364
00:23:20,800 --> 00:23:23,670
A wheel that everything turns on.

365
00:23:30,870 --> 00:23:33,900
Sorry, I have to go.
- Gottfried.

366
00:23:42,060 --> 00:23:44,940
I worry about those two monkeys.

367
00:23:45,760 --> 00:23:48,430
You see we've been together so long

368
00:23:48,530 --> 00:23:51,980
You're very fond of them.
- That's why I worry.

369
00:23:52,080 --> 00:23:54,920
Lenz is fighting for a reason
in a mad house.

370
00:23:55,020 --> 00:23:58,165
Fighting when its so futile to fight.

371
00:23:58,400 --> 00:24:03,500
Tormented by his duty to us,
to what he calls his conscience.

372
00:24:06,130 --> 00:24:09,870
The war did such different things to people.

373
00:24:12,260 --> 00:24:14,260
Erich plays well.

374
00:24:14,270 --> 00:24:17,090
Sometimes he plays for pocket money.

375
00:24:17,190 --> 00:24:20,570
Erich's different from Lenz and me.

376
00:24:21,160 --> 00:24:24,510
Erich's still alive. He's got
something to live for.

377
00:24:24,610 --> 00:24:28,180
What worries me now is that he's drifting.

378
00:24:31,370 --> 00:24:33,370
We get along.

379
00:24:37,970 --> 00:24:41,310
There are times in life
when you want to be alone.

380
00:24:41,410 --> 00:24:43,960
I don't want to be alone tonight.

381
00:24:44,060 --> 00:24:46,060
Stay with us

382
00:24:46,970 --> 00:24:52,210
I mean decisions one has to
make when one's alone.

383
00:24:53,250 --> 00:24:56,440
There ought to be someone you
could ask what to do.

384
00:24:56,540 --> 00:24:58,540
Ask us.

385
00:25:00,070 --> 00:25:03,300
Its just one of those things
that began with the war.

386
00:25:03,400 --> 00:25:05,730
There wasn't so much to eat you know.

387
00:25:05,830 --> 00:25:09,020
And I grew too fast and ate too little.

388
00:25:09,120 --> 00:25:11,120
Well, I...

389
00:25:12,690 --> 00:25:16,610
Last year it caught up with me
and I took to bed.

390
00:25:16,710 --> 00:25:18,980
Were you alone a long while?

391
00:25:19,080 --> 00:25:20,870
A year.

392
00:25:20,970 --> 00:25:22,970
Then I

393
00:25:23,600 --> 00:25:25,700
I've got to go now.

394
00:25:29,990 --> 00:25:31,990
I'll take you home.

395
00:25:40,220 --> 00:25:44,160
Perhaps I should call a taxi.
- Oh no, let's walk, it isn't far.

396
00:25:44,260 --> 00:25:48,270
I wouldn't want you to be late
for your business appointment.

397
00:25:48,370 --> 00:25:53,560
I've heard that its good business to
keep business people waiting.

398
00:25:53,660 --> 00:25:56,840
What will you do after you take me home?

399
00:25:56,940 --> 00:26:00,130
I've got some friends on the other
end of town I promised to meet.

400
00:26:00,230 --> 00:26:03,030
And have you lots of other friends
besides Koster and Lenz?

401
00:26:03,130 --> 00:26:06,520
A few. Nice girls too some of them.

402
00:26:11,120 --> 00:26:13,760
I'm really sorry about
my business appointment.

403
00:26:13,860 --> 00:26:16,700
I'd like to see you don't drink
any more of those double rums.

404
00:26:16,800 --> 00:26:18,800
They never affect me.

405
00:26:19,140 --> 00:26:22,470
What I hope is you'll remember
it's only a business appointment.

406
00:26:22,570 --> 00:26:24,570
What?

407
00:26:26,050 --> 00:26:28,280
Why, you baby.

408
00:26:29,370 --> 00:26:32,260
Good heavens, what a baby you are.

409
00:26:33,500 --> 00:26:35,795
I'm acting like a half-wit.

410
00:26:35,860 --> 00:26:37,860
No you're not.

411
00:26:39,690 --> 00:26:43,550
That's my ear.
- The better to hear me with.

412
00:26:44,280 --> 00:26:46,660
Go home Erich and go to bed.

413
00:27:17,760 --> 00:27:19,760
2796 please.

414
00:27:35,810 --> 00:27:38,270
Hello.
- Hello there.

415
00:27:38,690 --> 00:27:41,750
Having your business interview?
- Yes.

416
00:27:41,770 --> 00:27:44,910
Are you still with your friends on
the other end of town?

417
00:27:45,010 --> 00:27:47,305
Oh yes, it's quite a crowd.

418
00:27:47,760 --> 00:27:51,590
Listen Pat, haven't you had any friends
by the name of Erich?

419
00:27:51,690 --> 00:27:53,690
Yes.

420
00:27:53,870 --> 00:27:56,060
Well then you ought to be
able to say my name.

421
00:27:56,160 --> 00:28:02,040
Go on, try it.
Say 'Erich is a low dog...'

422
00:28:02,520 --> 00:28:05,480
Erich is a baby and I like him that way.

423
00:28:05,580 --> 00:28:07,875
Only Erich drinks too much.

424
00:28:08,620 --> 00:28:13,690
Now I've got to hang up.
- Goodnight, sleep well.

425
00:28:16,950 --> 00:28:18,950
He has his nerve.

426
00:28:19,410 --> 00:28:22,670
He's very young.
- Your taste seems to be deteriorating.

427
00:28:22,770 --> 00:28:24,770
On the contrary,

428
00:28:25,400 --> 00:28:27,290
Let's talk about the phonograph shop.

429
00:28:27,390 --> 00:28:30,789
Might be fun if all I had to do
was sell records of choirs. 

430
00:28:30,889 --> 00:28:31,300
Choirs?

431
00:28:31,400 --> 00:28:32,960
What are you talking about?

432
00:28:33,060 --> 00:28:36,160
I don't want the job.
- Oh Pat, let me help you.

433
00:28:36,260 --> 00:28:39,667
Not by giving me a shop with
that ridiculous salary. 

434
00:28:39,767 --> 00:28:40,320
Why not?

435
00:28:40,420 --> 00:28:44,755
Because, I couldn't earn it.
Believe me, I couldn't.

436
00:28:45,000 --> 00:28:47,960
Well frankly, I didn't think
it mattered much to you.

437
00:28:48,060 --> 00:28:52,550
You told me once nothing did 'very much.'
- Once might be last year or last week,

438
00:28:52,650 --> 00:28:55,410
Or even today. But not now.

439
00:28:55,660 --> 00:28:58,680
Something to do with those choir records?

440
00:28:58,780 --> 00:29:00,840
Maybe.
- And that telephone call?

441
00:29:00,940 --> 00:29:02,410
Maybe.

442
00:29:02,510 --> 00:29:05,570
Pat, I tell you, I don't know
what to do with all my money.

443
00:29:05,670 --> 00:29:10,350
You'd be safe Pat.
Germany's a pretty rough sea right now.

444
00:29:10,450 --> 00:29:12,060
And you're drifting.

445
00:29:12,160 --> 00:29:16,170
Say that again, about my drifting.
- You've got no port.

446
00:29:16,270 --> 00:29:17,130
No destination.

447
00:29:17,230 --> 00:29:20,340
But I'm not alone anymore.
There are so many drifters.

448
00:29:20,440 --> 00:29:22,660
And we might all drift together.

449
00:29:22,760 --> 00:29:26,120
And someday we might even
find pleasant seas.

450
00:29:26,220 --> 00:29:30,980
May I drink to that please?
To nice weather for drifters.

451
00:29:56,620 --> 00:30:00,790
3 marks profit. Over and above
the water pump which died.

452
00:30:00,890 --> 00:30:05,880
Lost the license and cap. Drunks tip best,
old ladies don't tip at all.

453
00:30:05,980 --> 00:30:09,610
There's a moral there somewhere.
Whats the matter with you?

454
00:30:09,710 --> 00:30:10,860
I'm in a mess.

455
00:30:10,960 --> 00:30:13,270
I've completely ruined myself with
Pat. Thats what I've done.

456
00:30:13,370 --> 00:30:15,233
She's probably used to
millionaires and counts...

457
00:30:15,333 --> 00:30:16,220
...and the way they behave.

458
00:30:16,320 --> 00:30:18,240
I acted like a drunken sod.

459
00:30:18,340 --> 00:30:21,600
Well how do you think millionaires act?
Like millionaires?

460
00:30:21,700 --> 00:30:26,800
Its too bad though. I should've
stayed at Alphons to take care of you.

461
00:30:26,900 --> 00:30:28,330
It might've been better for all of us.

462
00:30:28,430 --> 00:30:31,405
What do you mean, another riot?
- No.

463
00:30:31,520 --> 00:30:35,100
But I think a couple of them
followed me home.

464
00:30:35,200 --> 00:30:38,900
Look, Gottfried. You know all about
such things. South America and all that.

465
00:30:39,000 --> 00:30:41,260
What does a fellow do? How
does he apologise?

466
00:30:41,360 --> 00:30:44,250
He doesn't.
- I acted like an idiot.

467
00:30:44,460 --> 00:30:47,370
Send flowers. They cover everything.

468
00:30:47,470 --> 00:30:49,470
Even graves.

469
00:30:49,820 --> 00:30:51,820
Now come on.
Go to work.

470
00:30:56,410 --> 00:31:01,170
Be careful with that radiator.
Don't take anybody uphill.

471
00:31:18,090 --> 00:31:20,130
I did it, blame me.
- What are you talking about?

472
00:31:20,230 --> 00:31:21,620
They followed him home last night.

473
00:31:21,720 --> 00:31:24,010
This is my contribution to the two of you.

474
00:31:24,110 --> 00:31:25,764
We share and share alike.

475
00:31:25,864 --> 00:31:28,880
This is what I give you
for what you give me.

476
00:31:28,980 --> 00:31:32,470
Oh shut up and get to work.

477
00:31:32,970 --> 00:31:36,630
I'm sorry, Otto, Erich.
- We can't blame you for...

478
00:31:36,730 --> 00:31:39,535
...everything that happens to us.

479
00:31:39,890 --> 00:31:42,525
Thats the worst of it. You can.

480
00:31:57,910 --> 00:32:01,700
Hello Gottfried.
Its nice to see you.

481
00:32:03,080 --> 00:32:05,570
We'll be moving again soon.

482
00:32:05,750 --> 00:32:10,340
They've found us. Somebody
was nearly killed yesterday.

483
00:32:11,890 --> 00:32:19,340
Something that you have to tell me?
- I.. its hard for me to say, Dr. Becker.

484
00:32:20,340 --> 00:32:22,550
I can't come here anymore.

485
00:32:22,830 --> 00:32:25,720
I can't work with you anymore.
- So?

486
00:32:26,010 --> 00:32:30,290
I've made up my mind. To withdraw.
- Too bad.

487
00:32:30,510 --> 00:32:32,510
May I know the reason?

488
00:32:32,580 --> 00:32:34,980
Perhaps you no longer
believe in what we do.

489
00:32:35,080 --> 00:32:37,120
There are things I'm expected to do.

490
00:32:37,220 --> 00:32:41,430
And I have no right to do.
I have my two comrades.

491
00:32:41,630 --> 00:32:44,960
We've lived and fought
together so many years.

492
00:32:45,060 --> 00:32:47,270
I can never let them down.

493
00:32:47,680 --> 00:32:51,170
I have no right to make them
fight or pay for...

494
00:32:51,270 --> 00:32:54,070
...something thats important to me.

495
00:32:54,170 --> 00:32:56,170
I understand.

496
00:32:56,520 --> 00:33:00,920
Its so easy to fight on the
wrong side and hurt everyone.

497
00:33:01,020 --> 00:33:05,900
But to fight on the right side
and hurt the few you love.

498
00:33:08,360 --> 00:33:14,685
Get drunk Gottfried. Get very drunk.
And love your comrades very much.

499
00:33:14,735 --> 00:33:18,270
Goodybe Dr. Becker
- Goodbye Gottfried.

500
00:33:25,640 --> 00:33:26,750
You see him?

501
00:33:26,850 --> 00:33:29,220
Yes and I've just put a knife
through my conscience.

502
00:33:29,320 --> 00:33:33,060
I promise you Gottfried its better this way.

503
00:33:43,210 --> 00:33:48,360
You see? We don't want a dead
hero, we want a living man.

504
00:33:48,510 --> 00:33:51,400
I wish we were somewhere on earth
the two could go together.

505
00:33:51,500 --> 00:33:53,500
Living and being a man.

506
00:33:56,770 --> 00:33:59,450
Even in the city I can smell of spring.

507
00:33:59,550 --> 00:34:02,525
Smell much better without the city.

508
00:34:03,970 --> 00:34:05,970
Cold?

509
00:34:06,120 --> 00:34:09,030
You dress too light.
- I don't like heavy things.

510
00:34:09,130 --> 00:34:11,410
It'll be nice when its really
warm in the summer.

511
00:34:11,510 --> 00:34:13,390
Cold makes you miserable.

512
00:34:13,490 --> 00:34:14,840
Maybe it'll warm you up to drive.

513
00:34:14,940 --> 00:34:16,940
I don't know how.

514
00:34:17,660 --> 00:34:20,160
If I did, I'd go about the
streets every evening.

515
00:34:20,260 --> 00:34:22,470
Half awake, half dreaming.

516
00:34:22,500 --> 00:34:25,220
Then I wouldn't need anybody else.

517
00:34:25,320 --> 00:34:28,210
You'd need someone.
In the evening.

518
00:34:28,430 --> 00:34:33,710
Yes, its odd.
When it turns dark, you need someone.

519
00:34:38,890 --> 00:34:42,450
Then I went around the world in freighters.
Especially South America.

520
00:34:42,550 --> 00:34:44,910
You've been to South America.
Tell me about it.

521
00:34:45,010 --> 00:34:50,080
There's Rio De Janeiro, Buenos Aires...
- Yes, I know. What are they like?

522
00:34:50,180 --> 00:34:52,330
You roll on down to Rio

523
00:34:52,550 --> 00:34:53,820
Its' wonderful.

524
00:34:53,920 --> 00:34:56,720
Then you roll down to Buenos Aires.

525
00:34:56,820 --> 00:35:01,410
They have monkeys. No, er.. coffee.
Monkeys and coffee.

526
00:35:01,460 --> 00:35:03,700
What were you doing in South America?

527
00:35:03,800 --> 00:35:05,380
I was a gaucho.

528
00:35:05,480 --> 00:35:08,280
I had some coffee plantations.
One in Rio and one...

529
00:35:08,380 --> 00:35:10,000
Now we've left Buenos Aires?

530
00:35:10,100 --> 00:35:11,310
Oh yes, we're in Rio now.

531
00:35:11,410 --> 00:35:15,350
And whats Rio like?
That is outside the coffee and monkeys.

532
00:35:15,450 --> 00:35:18,085
It's mostly monkeys and coffee.

533
00:35:21,500 --> 00:35:26,855
And crocodiles, and jaguars and orchids.
Blooming in the jungle.

534
00:35:27,000 --> 00:35:29,380
My, you tell it so wonderfully.
Now, I'll never have to go.

535
00:35:29,480 --> 00:35:31,830
You really should go.
- Can we come to?

536
00:35:31,930 --> 00:35:35,790
I've always wanted to get away myself.
But first school, you know then the war...

537
00:35:35,890 --> 00:35:37,890
Hello Pat.
- Hello.

538
00:35:38,500 --> 00:35:40,180
You want to hear what he told
me about New York.

539
00:35:40,280 --> 00:35:44,190
The people go around in solid
gold automobiles.

540
00:35:44,990 --> 00:35:49,278
Well am I only supposed to
talk about school rooms...

541
00:35:49,378 --> 00:35:52,013
...and shell holes and garages?

542
00:36:34,930 --> 00:36:36,930
Just in time. My vest.

543
00:36:37,610 --> 00:36:39,850
Get me a safety pin will you Gottfried.

544
00:36:39,950 --> 00:36:42,260
What do you want the pin for?
He's tied from the back.

545
00:36:42,360 --> 00:36:44,460
No we can do that with a piece of string.

546
00:36:44,560 --> 00:36:47,810
Piece of string? Won't that show?
- No, not if you don't take your coat off.

547
00:36:47,910 --> 00:36:52,650
That's very important. Remember that.
Never take your coat off in the opera.

548
00:36:52,750 --> 00:36:54,590
No matter how much you sweat.

549
00:36:54,690 --> 00:36:57,334
You can wipe around inside
it with a handkerchief.

550
00:36:57,434 --> 00:36:58,570
But never take it off.

551
00:36:58,670 --> 00:37:04,195
And don't pick your teeth with your thumb.
Use your little finger.

552
00:37:04,620 --> 00:37:07,130
That alright now?
- Yeah, much better.

553
00:37:07,230 --> 00:37:09,230
Here slip into my coat.

554
00:37:16,780 --> 00:37:19,790
There's a button missing.
- Oh yes, I forgot.

555
00:37:19,890 --> 00:37:23,630
Remimd me to tell you sometime
how I lost it.

556
00:37:24,700 --> 00:37:26,700
Here, try mine.

557
00:37:32,960 --> 00:37:36,270
Like a glove.
- Little tight under the arms.

558
00:37:36,370 --> 00:37:41,590
Can't even reach my pocket.
- That's going to save you a lot of money.

559
00:37:41,690 --> 00:37:43,053
Pants are a little tight too.

560
00:37:43,153 --> 00:37:45,540
You can't dance anyway,
they're alright to sit in.

561
00:37:45,640 --> 00:37:48,785
Or are they?
- Alright, if I sit still.

562
00:37:49,190 --> 00:37:53,880
I wish you two were coming along.
- We are. My coat and Otto's pants.

563
00:37:53,980 --> 00:37:56,190
And this will top you off.

564
00:37:58,030 --> 00:38:01,600
The darned thing won't open.
Anybody got a tire wrench?

565
00:38:01,700 --> 00:38:03,700
Bang it on something.

566
00:38:06,650 --> 00:38:09,170
Never mind, I'll carry it for effect.

567
00:38:09,270 --> 00:38:10,650
It'll open once it sees the other little hats.

568
00:38:10,750 --> 00:38:16,080
He'll be alright. If he does'n t fall apart.

569
00:38:17,220 --> 00:38:20,330
Well, Cinderella goes to the ball.

570
00:38:31,410 --> 00:38:33,320
Oh, its silly, come back here.

571
00:38:33,420 --> 00:38:37,250
I wouldn't trust myself besides that dress.

572
00:38:38,900 --> 00:38:41,570
I couldn't afford this dress.
It was my last extravagance.

573
00:38:41,670 --> 00:38:43,510
Did it make you happy?

574
00:38:43,610 --> 00:38:47,265
I don't know yet.
I've never worn it before.

575
00:38:54,320 --> 00:38:56,430
Why hello Pat. I was hoping to see you.

576
00:38:56,530 --> 00:38:59,080
H.. Hello, you remember Herr Lohkamp.

577
00:38:59,180 --> 00:39:01,870
Hm, oh yes of course,
hello.

578
00:39:02,730 --> 00:39:05,920
You simply must join us afterwards.
We're going to that new American place.

579
00:39:06,020 --> 00:39:07,020
The real thing.

580
00:39:07,120 --> 00:39:11,795
Bring your friend along. You'll love it.
Free champagne.

581
00:40:05,000 --> 00:40:06,850
Champagne for everybody.

582
00:40:06,950 --> 00:40:09,090
Mineral water for me please.

583
00:40:09,190 --> 00:40:12,165
Good boy Erich.
- Yes, very good boy.

584
00:40:12,680 --> 00:40:14,680
Will you dance?

585
00:40:27,920 --> 00:40:32,270
He's very fond of her.
Its been a lucky thing for her.

586
00:40:32,370 --> 00:40:36,261
These foreign aristocrats
haven't much chance...

587
00:40:36,361 --> 00:40:40,016
...these days without
someone to cope with.

588
00:40:43,130 --> 00:40:45,935
And she fell right off the horse.

589
00:40:48,900 --> 00:40:51,780
Think we should go home?
It's 2 o'clock.

590
00:40:51,880 --> 00:40:53,880
It's 2 o'clock?

591
00:40:54,180 --> 00:40:55,960
Let's move onto another place.

592
00:40:56,060 --> 00:40:57,680
Pat looks tired.

593
00:40:57,780 --> 00:41:01,370
Tired? No, no.
You don't know her as long as I have,

594
00:41:01,470 --> 00:41:04,190
She doesn't leave parties early.

595
00:41:06,000 --> 00:41:07,840
Shall we dance?

596
00:41:07,940 --> 00:41:09,940
I really am tired.

597
00:41:13,370 --> 00:41:15,835
You haven't danced all night.

598
00:41:17,770 --> 00:41:20,060
With me.

599
00:41:23,230 --> 00:41:25,050
I don't know anything about this dance.

600
00:41:25,150 --> 00:41:28,240
In the war, we all used to dance the waltz.
- Let's dance the waltz.

601
00:41:28,340 --> 00:41:31,790
I've forgotten all about it.

602
00:41:33,480 --> 00:41:35,520
We won't if you don't want to.

603
00:41:35,620 --> 00:41:37,290
At least we're not at the table.

604
00:41:37,390 --> 00:41:38,350
At least I'm near you.

605
00:41:38,450 --> 00:41:42,275
If you aren't going to
dance, come sit by me.

606
00:42:00,810 --> 00:42:05,825
I've just placed that coat,
my grandfather was buried in it.

607
00:42:15,980 --> 00:42:18,780
Let's go somewhere else.
To the other side, where we can fix it.

608
00:42:18,880 --> 00:42:20,880
It's no use Pat.

609
00:42:21,490 --> 00:42:26,410
I'm just not...
It can't be fixed, I'm sorry.

610
00:42:49,130 --> 00:42:51,130
Double rum Alphons.

611
00:42:52,370 --> 00:42:55,760
Hello Cinderella.
Got both your slippers on?

612
00:42:55,860 --> 00:42:57,860
What happened?
- Nothing.

613
00:42:58,240 --> 00:43:01,090
Sharp midnight I changed
back into a garage mechanic, thats all.

614
00:43:01,190 --> 00:43:03,825
Where's Pat?
- Where she belongs.

615
00:43:04,560 --> 00:43:06,300
Ah, she's a rich man's girl, I knew it.

616
00:43:06,400 --> 00:43:09,590
Let's forget about it.
- I won't have anything said against Pat.

617
00:43:09,690 --> 00:43:11,960
Well it's not her fault.
She's a rich man's girl.

618
00:43:12,060 --> 00:43:13,060
What can Erich do?

619
00:43:13,160 --> 00:43:15,550
He could go ahead and get drunk.

620
00:43:15,650 --> 00:43:17,775
Bring the bottle Alphons.

621
00:43:36,650 --> 00:43:38,650
Pat.

622
00:43:38,650 --> 00:43:42,190
What are you doing here?
- I think I've been asleep.

623
00:43:42,290 --> 00:43:44,925
How did you get here?
- I walked.

624
00:43:45,030 --> 00:43:47,750
I mean, why are you here at all?

625
00:43:54,680 --> 00:43:56,110
It's cold.

626
00:43:56,210 --> 00:43:58,210
You're shivering.

627
00:43:59,690 --> 00:44:03,990
Rum, cognac, whisky.
League of nations, darling.

628
00:44:04,600 --> 00:44:08,120
You got drunk because you couldn't dance
and you ran away and left me.

629
00:44:08,220 --> 00:44:11,570
I don't ever want you to
run away and leave me.

630
00:44:11,670 --> 00:44:13,670
I'm much warmer now.

631
00:44:14,070 --> 00:44:16,610
And this is a lovely time of day.

632
00:44:16,710 --> 00:44:18,380
It isn't day, it isn't night.

633
00:44:18,480 --> 00:44:20,605
It's the age of eternity.

634
00:44:20,850 --> 00:44:23,100
Let's stay right here forever.

635
00:44:23,200 --> 00:44:24,530
Between day and night?
- The world we were born into.

636
00:44:24,630 --> 00:44:26,630
Thats where we belong.

637
00:44:38,460 --> 00:44:40,530
You're cold Pat, let me take you home.

638
00:44:40,630 --> 00:44:45,580
Take me home? How?
I am home.

639
00:44:51,780 --> 00:44:54,042
What is it about love that makes a man...

640
00:44:54,142 --> 00:44:56,630
...swallow his food whole
instead of chewing it?

641
00:44:56,730 --> 00:45:02,030
It all belongs to you. I'm not
going to steal, I've already had my lunch.

642
00:45:02,130 --> 00:45:05,130
Whats going to happen with you and Pat?
- Why should anything happen?

643
00:45:05,230 --> 00:45:07,090
You're in love, why don't you get married?

644
00:45:07,190 --> 00:45:13,050
We're in love, isn't that enough?
- No, you're as fed up with drifting as I am.

645
00:45:13,150 --> 00:45:16,000
Somewhere there's a battle
going on and I'm not in it.

646
00:45:16,100 --> 00:45:19,450
Somewhere there's a home to be made
and love to be had.. 

647
00:45:19,550 --> 00:45:19,800
Well?

648
00:45:19,900 --> 00:45:22,540
Marry Pat.
- What can I offer a girl like Pat?

649
00:45:22,640 --> 00:45:24,550
Nothing now and nothing to look
forward to.

650
00:45:24,650 --> 00:45:26,920
Well marry her anyway, you'll at
least have that.

651
00:45:27,020 --> 00:45:29,315
I have nothing to give her.

652
00:45:30,610 --> 00:45:33,100
Now is the right time believe me.

653
00:45:33,200 --> 00:45:39,235
Sometimes it comes and goes so quickly
that you'd have lost it, forever.

654
00:45:41,900 --> 00:45:45,690
Well, whats wrong about Erich?
- Nothing is wrong about Erich.

655
00:45:45,790 --> 00:45:47,950
Well, he's alright.

656
00:45:48,950 --> 00:45:50,834
What are you playing with
the hammer? Schubert?

657
00:45:50,934 --> 00:45:51,460
No, Mendelson.

658
00:45:51,560 --> 00:45:53,560
I'm being whimsical.

659
00:45:54,230 --> 00:45:55,820
Let me give you Erich in a nutshell.

660
00:45:55,920 --> 00:46:00,370
He'd look cute in a nutshell,
but if you don't mind...

661
00:46:00,470 --> 00:46:02,250
Honesty?

662
00:46:02,350 --> 00:46:06,010
Take 10% of for South
America but that leaves 90%

663
00:46:06,110 --> 00:46:07,860
Spirit? All there is.

664
00:46:07,960 --> 00:46:10,085
Stick to your music Otto.

665
00:46:10,170 --> 00:46:11,900
You're telling me things I know already.

666
00:46:12,000 --> 00:46:16,010
Then, why don't you marry him?
- He hasn't asked me.

667
00:46:16,110 --> 00:46:18,110
He's scared.

668
00:46:18,420 --> 00:46:20,420
Why don't you ask him?

669
00:46:20,900 --> 00:46:26,490
Now lets have some Beethoven. No, I
imagine Wagner's easier with the hammer.

670
00:46:26,590 --> 00:46:30,050
Look, you love each other
you have everything to love for.

671
00:46:30,150 --> 00:46:33,440
There's hope in both of you, and
shelter for the future.

672
00:46:33,540 --> 00:46:35,540
It wouldn't work.

673
00:46:36,640 --> 00:46:37,940
It wouldn't be fair to him.

674
00:46:38,040 --> 00:46:42,600
Why not?
- I don't know.

675
00:46:42,600 --> 00:46:45,510
I guess I was born for irresponsibility.

676
00:46:45,610 --> 00:46:49,050
I guess I couldn't take anything seriously.

677
00:46:49,150 --> 00:46:51,790
You mustn't ever lie to me Pat.

678
00:46:53,360 --> 00:46:57,355
No I mustn't. So don't ask me
anymore questions.

679
00:46:58,870 --> 00:46:59,830
You're scared.

680
00:46:59,930 --> 00:47:01,748
Scared of having any joy in your life...

681
00:47:01,848 --> 00:47:04,040
...because it'll be all
the more harder to lose it.

682
00:47:04,140 --> 00:47:07,210
You're afraid.
- Yes, thats it, lets leave it at that.

683
00:47:07,310 --> 00:47:09,600
But now you're not being fair Pat.

684
00:47:09,700 --> 00:47:11,810
You've got to think of Erich now.

685
00:47:11,910 --> 00:47:16,590
You're being a coward, you're being selfish.
- Thats not true.

686
00:47:16,690 --> 00:47:18,690
Then what is true Pat?

687
00:47:20,790 --> 00:47:23,765
I told you once, I'd been very ill.

688
00:47:24,270 --> 00:47:26,450
Well I'm just patched up now.

689
00:47:26,550 --> 00:47:28,550
It'll come back.

690
00:47:29,650 --> 00:47:31,650
Your lungs?

691
00:47:35,240 --> 00:47:38,000
Don't let me marry him please.
- But you've got to.

692
00:47:38,100 --> 00:47:41,160
He'd want a happiness that would last.
A home, children...

693
00:47:41,260 --> 00:47:43,470
A future that doesn't exist from day to day.

694
00:47:43,570 --> 00:47:45,570
I'm no good.

695
00:47:45,910 --> 00:47:48,240
He has a right to more than me.
- Then, live Pat.

696
00:47:48,340 --> 00:47:51,850
Take that gamble. Stake your life on a love
like yours and Erich's.

697
00:47:51,950 --> 00:47:53,600
I'd have to tell him.

698
00:47:53,700 --> 00:47:58,720
No, thats a part of it.
Don't make him afraid, make him happy.

699
00:47:58,820 --> 00:48:01,680
Aim at the stars.

700
00:48:04,140 --> 00:48:07,455
I wonder if they mind we aimed at them.

701
00:49:44,150 --> 00:49:45,390
Wait a minute.

702
00:49:45,490 --> 00:49:48,380
I now pronounce you, man and wife.

703
00:49:57,980 --> 00:49:59,221
Do you believe in prayer?

704
00:49:59,321 --> 00:50:01,800
No, I believe in tomorrow
that will follow today.

705
00:50:01,900 --> 00:50:05,675
And that tomorrow will
find you even happier,

706
00:50:05,775 --> 00:50:07,775
both of you.

707
00:50:08,680 --> 00:50:13,185
She's too good for you, you know that.
- Much too good.

708
00:50:14,940 --> 00:50:17,360
He's too good for you, you know that.
- I know nothing of the kind.

709
00:50:17,460 --> 00:50:22,700
Everybody's too good for everybody else.
I can hardly wait to get drunk.

710
00:50:22,800 --> 00:50:24,341
Remember that happy life
you were going to...

711
00:50:24,441 --> 00:50:25,310
...come back to from the war?

712
00:50:25,410 --> 00:50:27,970
It's starting now.
- I'm sure of that, Otto.

713
00:50:28,070 --> 00:50:31,120
We'll see to it. All four of us will see to it.

714
00:50:31,220 --> 00:50:35,050
Alphons, it was the most
wonderful wedding ever.

715
00:50:35,150 --> 00:50:37,150
Thank you.

716
00:50:40,820 --> 00:50:42,860
Bring on the pork chops.

717
00:50:58,650 --> 00:51:03,390
What does the meter read?
- 318 Marks.

718
00:51:03,620 --> 00:51:07,030
You'll never be able to pay it.
- Don't worry, I know the driver.

719
00:51:07,130 --> 00:51:09,130
He's a husband of mine.

720
00:51:14,390 --> 00:51:16,390
Oh, Erich look the sea.

721
00:51:22,000 --> 00:51:23,503
Is that the hotel?

722
00:51:23,603 --> 00:51:27,780
No, it can't be, it looks
just like the postcard.

723
00:51:36,180 --> 00:51:40,460
You know who were now?
Herr and Frau Erich Lohkamp.

724
00:51:42,730 --> 00:51:46,790
He has a nice way of putting things.
For better or worse was one of his phrases.

725
00:51:46,890 --> 00:51:50,920
And what's this er.. and
sickness and in health,

726
00:51:51,020 --> 00:51:53,020
till death do us part.

727
00:51:55,010 --> 00:51:58,410
Now, there you see, you're bored.
- No, I'm not.

728
00:51:58,510 --> 00:51:59,700
You soon will be.

729
00:51:59,800 --> 00:52:03,790
What on earth are we going to talk about for
the rest of our lives? -You.

730
00:52:03,890 --> 00:52:06,540
12 minutes by the clock.
- Me then.

731
00:52:06,640 --> 00:52:09,955
Oh, we couldn't talk,
we'd have to sing.

732
00:52:10,110 --> 00:52:14,980
Books and music?
- I don't anything about books or music.

733
00:52:15,270 --> 00:52:19,110
I'll teach you, its high
time you went to school.

734
00:52:19,210 --> 00:52:20,510
I went to school.

735
00:52:20,610 --> 00:52:23,590
I was taught how to keep a
machine gun from jamming.

736
00:52:23,690 --> 00:52:26,330
Prove why its better to shoot a man
in the stomach than in the head.

737
00:52:26,430 --> 00:52:28,880
We'll have a garden full of flowers in the...

738
00:52:28,980 --> 00:52:32,635
I can show you the quickest way
to bury a...

739
00:52:35,020 --> 00:52:40,000
I can teach you to swim and drive a car,
and to climb mountains and play tennis.

740
00:52:40,100 --> 00:52:42,450
I didn't know I didn't till now.

741
00:52:42,550 --> 00:52:45,520
I thought I belonged to something
that was dead and gone.

742
00:52:45,620 --> 00:52:47,745
Now I realise I am alive.

743
00:52:48,010 --> 00:52:51,300
With you, I'm alive.
- We're alive darling.

744
00:52:51,400 --> 00:52:53,400
And I'm glad.

745
00:52:56,980 --> 00:53:00,125
Maybe I can't learn all those things.

746
00:53:00,150 --> 00:53:02,620
Maybe you're in love with just a fragment.

747
00:53:02,720 --> 00:53:05,310
And a lovely fragment if there ever was one.

748
00:53:05,410 --> 00:53:07,450
Oh, Erich I love you so.

749
00:53:11,860 --> 00:53:17,680
I've just been kissed.
Can you tell me which was is the ocean?

750
00:53:31,710 --> 00:53:39,430
19,20,21..
- What are you doing?

751
00:53:39,600 --> 00:53:41,780
Shh, listen, a cuckoo bird.

752
00:53:41,880 --> 00:53:43,160
That makes three of us.

753
00:53:43,260 --> 00:53:47,600
I'm counting, everytime he calls you have
that many number of years to live.

754
00:53:47,700 --> 00:53:50,327
There's a better one than
that. When a cuckoo calls...

755
00:53:50,427 --> 00:53:52,410
...rattle your money and then it multiplies.

756
00:53:52,510 --> 00:53:54,170
24..

757
00:53:54,270 --> 00:53:58,076
Only I haven't got any
money to rattle. So the...

758
00:53:58,176 --> 00:54:00,880
...cuckoo is making a fool of himself.

759
00:54:00,980 --> 00:54:03,250
Imagine, our silver wedding.

760
00:54:03,350 --> 00:54:06,470
Our handsome son has left college.
He refuses to go to war,

761
00:54:06,570 --> 00:54:09,020
and is thrown into jail for the rest of his life.

762
00:54:09,120 --> 00:54:12,640
26..
- Now we're together once more.

763
00:54:13,350 --> 00:54:16,270
A sweet, silver haired old couple.

764
00:54:17,450 --> 00:54:20,980
27..
- Now I'm hungry.

765
00:54:22,590 --> 00:54:26,840
We'll come back tomorrow and count
cuckoos all day.

766
00:54:27,620 --> 00:54:31,020
Here try this, best way to get sand off.

767
00:55:32,460 --> 00:55:35,960
Is she alright, is she better?
- Where was your wife being treated?

768
00:55:36,060 --> 00:55:37,960
Who was her doctor?
- Doctor?

769
00:55:38,060 --> 00:55:42,140
She must've had a doctor for this.
- I don't know.

770
00:55:43,860 --> 00:55:47,020
Jaffe? Prof. Phoenix Jaffe?

771
00:55:47,470 --> 00:55:49,330
You must get in touch with him
at once by the telephone.

772
00:55:49,430 --> 00:55:55,210
Yes but can't you tell me is she..
- She must start breathing at once.

773
00:55:56,600 --> 00:56:03,320
Dr. Jaffe's left? But I've got to get it in touch
with him, its a matter of life and death.

774
00:56:03,420 --> 00:56:06,990
Have him ring here as soon as he comes in.

775
00:56:29,140 --> 00:56:35,600
I'll find him and I'll ring you here again.
Don't worry Erich, I'll find him.

776
00:56:43,540 --> 00:56:47,620
Jaffe.
- I'll go, I'll have to talk to him anyway.

777
00:56:53,670 --> 00:56:56,135
Koster's gone to fetch Jaffe.

778
00:56:56,540 --> 00:56:58,540
You'll be alright soon.

779
00:57:08,390 --> 00:57:11,363
There's a friend of yours,
Lenz. They found him.

780
00:57:11,463 --> 00:57:14,940
Lenz told me Jaffe's instructions
very clear, in detail.

781
00:57:15,040 --> 00:57:17,320
Is he a doctor too?
- He was a soldier.

782
00:57:17,420 --> 00:57:21,666
He said Koster had already left
with Jaffe and they'd be...

783
00:57:21,766 --> 00:57:23,900
...here in 2 hours by automobile.

784
00:57:24,000 --> 00:57:28,180
Thats impossible. Its a long distance and
I know the roads.

785
00:57:28,280 --> 00:57:30,410
Full of dents and fog.

786
00:57:30,870 --> 00:57:37,160
It'll take at least 3 hours.
- If Koster's said 2 hours, it will be 2 hours.

787
00:57:40,590 --> 00:57:43,030
You're going very fast.
- Can you stop the haemorrhage?

788
00:57:43,130 --> 00:57:45,595
Yes, if we get there in time.

789
00:57:58,410 --> 00:58:00,410
Has it stopped yet?
- No.

790
00:58:01,300 --> 00:58:07,590
There'll be here in half an hour.
- An hour at least, maybe two in this fog.

791
00:58:19,860 --> 00:58:23,180
You're risking both our
lives. Is she your girl?

792
00:58:23,280 --> 00:58:25,060
No.

793
00:58:25,160 --> 00:58:27,160
You're crazy.

794
00:58:48,030 --> 00:58:50,750
They're coming, I can hear them.

795
00:58:50,890 --> 00:58:54,120
Impossible, it must be some other car.

796
00:59:01,480 --> 00:59:04,030
You can't fool me, thats Baby.

797
00:59:22,360 --> 00:59:23,360
How is she?

798
00:59:23,460 --> 00:59:26,130
I don't know, so much
has happened so quickly.

799
00:59:26,230 --> 00:59:29,690
She'll be alright now. Give me a cigarette.

800
00:59:29,790 --> 00:59:35,910
Nice of you to come up, Otto.
- Nice trip, not bad, only one patch of fog.

801
00:59:49,750 --> 00:59:51,426
She never told me, not a word.

802
00:59:51,526 --> 00:59:54,640
She never worried about
herself, only to make me happy.

803
00:59:54,740 --> 00:59:58,250
I thought nothing ever would
happen to a girl like that.

804
00:59:58,350 --> 01:00:01,835
Give me another cigarette. I forgot mine.

805
01:00:03,110 --> 01:00:05,930
She safe?
- Think I'd be standing here if she wasn't?

806
01:00:06,030 --> 01:00:08,610
I'm sorry, it was so quick.
- She's his wife.

807
01:00:08,710 --> 01:00:11,460
I hope you're less a fool than she is.
She's been one all her life.

808
01:00:11,560 --> 01:00:15,810
May I go in now?
- Only for a moment and no talking.

809
01:00:16,830 --> 01:00:18,980
Was it right to bring you?
- Yes.

810
01:00:19,080 --> 01:00:21,820
Serious?
- No more when she gets back to town.

811
01:00:21,920 --> 01:00:24,052
One thing is for sure, tell your friend.

812
01:00:24,152 --> 01:00:27,320
She has to go to a sanatorium
by mid-October at the latest.

813
01:00:27,420 --> 01:00:31,068
She'll go. When are
you going back to town?

814
01:00:31,168 --> 01:00:34,738
None of your business. I'm going by train.

815
01:00:36,480 --> 01:00:40,050
Everything's over now, Pat. Just be quiet.

816
01:00:44,810 --> 01:00:46,810
Erich.

817
01:00:47,140 --> 01:00:50,965
You mustn't be afraid.
- We'll never be afraid.

818
01:01:01,400 --> 01:01:03,690
You mustn't cry about us Pat.

819
01:01:03,790 --> 01:01:09,350
We're not unhappy. Soon you'll be well
and then we'll be happier.

820
01:01:11,290 --> 01:01:13,290
I love you

821
01:01:18,300 --> 01:01:20,935
Mid-October at the very latest.

822
01:01:30,370 --> 01:01:31,370
Well?

823
01:01:31,470 --> 01:01:34,650
If the right fron tire lasts,
we'll break even this week.

824
01:01:34,750 --> 01:01:39,170
Don't count on that tire.
It blew twice this morning.

825
01:01:39,340 --> 01:01:44,220
When Pat went walking, the sun came out.
- You know, I thought about that.

826
01:01:44,320 --> 01:01:46,540
I saw the sun come out
and I thought about Pat.

827
01:01:46,640 --> 01:01:51,485
It's a step forward you know,
when she can walk out alone.

828
01:01:51,500 --> 01:01:57,170
I'll drop you on the way to station.
You wait here till the delivery comes home.

829
01:01:57,270 --> 01:02:01,800
Well you can't keep moping about Pat.
Make her laugh, we'll pull through.

830
01:02:01,900 --> 01:02:05,555
Who knows, maybe Erich will get a fine job.

831
01:02:40,910 --> 01:02:43,690
What makes you think an
automobile can go through you?

832
01:02:43,790 --> 01:02:47,110
I represent Koster and Co. the best fastest
and cheapest repair shop in the city.

833
01:02:47,210 --> 01:02:48,630
You'll be very happy.

834
01:02:48,730 --> 01:02:50,150
Boy,

835
01:02:50,250 --> 01:02:53,020
I saw the whole thing, you're a...
- Nobody asked you.

836
01:02:53,120 --> 01:02:56,451
Here, call this number, tell him we have...

837
01:02:56,551 --> 01:03:00,590
...a repair job and tell him
to come as fast as he can.

838
01:03:00,690 --> 01:03:04,290
You'll have it as good as new in 2 days.
- It was good as new 5 minutes ago.

839
01:03:04,390 --> 01:03:06,490
Before you wrecked it.
- Iets not quibble.

840
01:03:06,590 --> 01:03:11,610
Materials and cost, labor and standard rate,
plus our profit of 200 Marks.

841
01:03:11,710 --> 01:03:13,100
Settle for a 100.

842
01:03:13,200 --> 01:03:17,140
Here's your claim check. Get your car
on Wednesday night at 6 o'clock.

843
01:03:17,240 --> 01:03:21,575
oh, by the way, you hurt?
- No, no, thank you asking.

844
01:03:32,310 --> 01:03:33,315
You, the owner of this car?

845
01:03:33,415 --> 01:03:35,240
No, I'm one of the men
whose going to repair it.

846
01:03:35,340 --> 01:03:38,570
Koster and company.
- Now, isnt that peculiar?

847
01:03:38,670 --> 01:03:44,240
I was just telling my partner, here's a car
that's just begging to be repaired by us.

848
01:03:44,340 --> 01:03:47,120
Sorry, you're already too late, I've already
got an order from the owner.

849
01:03:47,220 --> 01:03:49,070
Hand it over.
- Don't be silly.

850
01:03:49,170 --> 01:03:51,550
Hey, we've talked enough. Iets dump
this monkey down the sewer.

851
01:03:51,650 --> 01:03:56,240
Make it the sewer you live in.
- Well you asked for it..

852
01:04:28,630 --> 01:04:33,080
You certainly must give it to Erich.
He's a natural born fighter.

853
01:04:33,180 --> 01:04:35,730
How many were there Erich?
- 14.

854
01:04:36,460 --> 01:04:40,060
Yeah, by the time we arrived they were all
worn out from chasing your husband.

855
01:04:40,160 --> 01:04:43,390
My husband? I've never seen that face
before in all my life.

856
01:04:43,490 --> 01:04:47,482
There he was striking right
and left. He knocked out...

857
01:04:47,582 --> 01:04:49,590
...a little boy all by himself.

858
01:04:49,690 --> 01:04:53,848
Now, I'm beginning to
understand. He got the job...

859
01:04:53,948 --> 01:04:58,538
...first and you three
surrounded him and beat him up.

860
01:04:59,480 --> 01:05:01,830
Iets talk about you for a change.

861
01:05:01,930 --> 01:05:07,030
Where did you walk?
- Oh, I just walked and walked, thats all.

862
01:05:07,380 --> 01:05:10,990
Walking is a pretty big event for me,
it doesn't really matter where.

863
01:05:11,090 --> 01:05:17,270
Everything about you matters.
You two go on ahead and start on the car.

864
01:05:28,200 --> 01:05:30,200
Queen Solomon.

865
01:05:40,130 --> 01:05:42,132
And all that trouble just for a 100 Marks.

866
01:05:42,232 --> 01:05:44,380
Its the easiest money
that we've ever earned.

867
01:05:44,480 --> 01:05:46,050
Its been a slow summer.

868
01:05:46,150 --> 01:05:47,870
And what do I give?

869
01:05:47,970 --> 01:05:51,810
What can I ever give?
- Just being here, thats what.

870
01:05:51,910 --> 01:05:54,860
And don't talk about things not mattering.

871
01:05:54,960 --> 01:05:58,785
Where you walk, we three
walk beside you now.

872
01:06:35,880 --> 01:06:41,510
Winter is coming again, it is the
time for storm and tempest.

873
01:06:42,040 --> 01:06:46,060
It is the time and nature itself that
is all confusion.

874
01:06:46,160 --> 01:06:52,630
And given over to violence. And so too
are the people confused.

875
01:06:52,770 --> 01:06:58,260
Looking in all directions, and in vain.
For the peace and hope,

876
01:06:59,780 --> 01:07:03,690
which was to have been their's
at the end of the war.

877
01:07:03,790 --> 01:07:07,060
But there has been no end to the war.

878
01:07:07,380 --> 01:07:11,380
How can we look for peace?
And how can we hope?

879
01:07:11,550 --> 01:07:15,434
As long as we use violence and terror to...

880
01:07:15,534 --> 01:07:19,614
...supply what must come
from sanity and reason.

881
01:07:20,040 --> 01:07:26,210
There is and there will be,
a solution, a cure for all your ills.

882
01:08:32,140 --> 01:08:34,265
Winter is coming outside.

883
01:08:35,240 --> 01:08:39,660
No, not yet. You only think
that because of the wind.

884
01:08:40,440 --> 01:08:42,735
Its been windy so long now.

885
01:08:42,850 --> 01:08:46,845
Sometimes at night, I dream
of being blown away.

886
01:08:46,980 --> 01:08:49,720
When I think of my life as it was before,

887
01:08:49,820 --> 01:08:51,820
I thank God for you.

888
01:08:55,840 --> 01:08:57,880
It sounds lovely when you say that.

889
01:08:57,980 --> 01:09:03,520
Say it again.
- I thank God for you.

890
01:09:05,420 --> 01:09:08,100
From now on, I'm going to say that
every 10 seconds for the week.

891
01:09:08,200 --> 01:09:10,130
Say it when I'm asleep too.

892
01:09:10,230 --> 01:09:12,230
Then I won't dream.

893
01:09:19,480 --> 01:09:23,645
The phone for Herr Lohkamp.
- Oh, thank you, Erich.

894
01:09:31,140 --> 01:09:36,290
How can she stand the trip? What trip?
- The trip to the sanatorium.

895
01:09:36,390 --> 01:09:39,535
I told her a week ago,
she must leave.

896
01:09:40,040 --> 01:09:44,510
If you want to keep that girl
alive, you send her off today.

897
01:09:44,610 --> 01:09:46,610
And I mean, today.

898
01:09:47,330 --> 01:09:49,330
She'll go today.

899
01:09:49,750 --> 01:09:51,750
Goodbye Doctor.

900
01:09:56,820 --> 01:10:00,170
You should've told me Pat.
- No, I couldn't,

901
01:10:00,270 --> 01:10:03,690
We've been so happyand its
been such a short week with you.

902
01:10:03,790 --> 01:10:05,790
Such a long week away.

903
01:10:06,080 --> 01:10:08,545
We'll have other weeks later.

904
01:10:10,030 --> 01:10:12,155
You better start packing.

905
01:10:13,420 --> 01:10:16,830
We stole a week and they can't take it back.

906
01:10:16,930 --> 01:10:19,055
Its mine to keep forever.

907
01:10:20,360 --> 01:10:25,400
Why won't you please say it twice? Its
been at least 20 seconds.

908
01:10:25,500 --> 01:10:27,540
I thank God for you Pat.

909
01:10:30,360 --> 01:10:32,360
Thank God for you.

910
01:10:37,410 --> 01:10:42,340
Oh Tony, hello. Where's your sister?
- She isn't coming Pat.

911
01:10:43,360 --> 01:10:46,920
How do you know all these people?
- From 2 years ago,

912
01:10:47,020 --> 01:10:51,930
We're all at the same sanatorium. All the
birds migrate at this time of the year.

913
01:10:52,030 --> 01:10:54,030
They can't be so bad.

914
01:10:54,300 --> 01:10:58,460
And in spring you'll be home again,
all brown from the sun.

915
01:10:58,560 --> 01:11:01,360
Did you pack your silver dress? You are
magic when you wear that dress,

916
01:11:01,460 --> 01:11:05,930
Don't wear it for anyone else.
- i haven't got magic for anyone else.

917
01:11:06,030 --> 01:11:08,750
You're behaving beautifully Pat.

918
01:11:12,820 --> 01:11:15,115
Whats the good of anything?

919
01:11:17,830 --> 01:11:20,880
I've been so proud of you the whole day.

920
01:11:20,980 --> 01:11:25,130
Its only this bad the day you leave. Then
everything becomes alright again.

921
01:11:25,230 --> 01:11:30,840
I haven't been brave all day, you just didn't
notice it, thats all.

922
01:11:31,130 --> 01:11:36,910
So long as you don't give in, you're
bigger than what happens to you.

923
01:11:39,700 --> 01:11:42,165
Where are Otto and Gottfried?

924
01:11:45,120 --> 01:11:47,839
These are from Gottfried,
with regrets and love.

925
01:11:47,939 --> 01:11:49,620
They're lovely, give him mine.

926
01:11:49,720 --> 01:11:56,860
I hope he isn't in any trouble with all
this fighting in the streets and the crowds..

927
01:12:09,330 --> 01:12:12,900
Don't look now, either of you.
Turn around.

928
01:12:31,800 --> 01:12:34,860
What happened to Gottfried?
- Come on.

929
01:12:48,980 --> 01:12:52,720
He's in that warehouse.
We've got to get him.

930
01:13:23,970 --> 01:13:28,080
Gottfried. Its Otto, can you hear me?

931
01:13:30,370 --> 01:13:32,520
I took a long time.

932
01:13:33,930 --> 01:13:36,735
But I've finally made up my mind.

933
01:13:46,910 --> 01:13:48,910
Was he your comrade?

934
01:13:52,920 --> 01:13:54,920
He was mine too.

935
01:15:10,310 --> 01:15:14,430
Maybe we should've told the police.
- The police have nothing to do with this.

936
01:15:14,530 --> 01:15:17,940
They haven't lost Gottfried, we have.

937
01:15:23,650 --> 01:15:26,680
Dr. Ploughton asked me to pick you up,
if I found you.

938
01:15:26,780 --> 01:15:29,750
What news from the village?
- Christmas is coming.

939
01:15:29,850 --> 01:15:34,270
Christmas makes you think of home.
- Yes, yes it does.

940
01:15:34,380 --> 01:15:37,240
If you have no home,
you think of it anyway.

941
01:15:37,340 --> 01:15:39,780
Or the home that you might've had.

942
01:15:39,880 --> 01:15:44,250
To get on a plane there, to the next
village, to go somewhere.

943
01:15:44,350 --> 01:15:48,600
You have a husband, is he coming?
- We're very poor.

944
01:15:48,920 --> 01:15:51,390
You're poor?
- Very poor.

945
01:15:52,950 --> 01:15:57,510
You mustn't think of the cost of an
operation that may give you a new life.

946
01:15:57,610 --> 01:16:02,310
Perhaps it isn't my responsibility to
sign a new lease of life.

947
01:16:02,410 --> 01:16:03,980
What are you going to do to me?

948
01:16:04,080 --> 01:16:08,170
We often get splendid results with this
operation with cases of your kind.

949
01:16:08,270 --> 01:16:12,300
We take a little bit of bone from your
ribs and collapse your lung,

950
01:16:12,400 --> 01:16:16,690
There is no real danger after, except
that you must keep very still for 2 weeks.

951
01:16:16,790 --> 01:16:18,790
Very still.

952
01:16:27,840 --> 01:16:30,450
When do you operate?
- Right after Christmas.

953
01:16:30,550 --> 01:16:35,310
That means I'll be here for that long.
- Please don't talk that way.

954
01:16:35,410 --> 01:16:38,130
Forigve me, it's just Christmas.

955
01:16:53,350 --> 01:16:56,835
Koster been in this evening?
- No, not yet.

956
01:16:57,650 --> 01:17:00,760
He's a hard man to keep track of,
here taste this.

957
01:17:00,860 --> 01:17:04,157
He's out now, looking for
him. He's a crazy man.

958
01:17:04,257 --> 01:17:06,090
Thats a job for both of us.

959
01:17:06,190 --> 01:17:09,845
No, he's right. You've got Pat to think of.

960
01:17:10,550 --> 01:17:14,800
To think of?
You can't hold a thought in your arms.

961
01:17:14,840 --> 01:17:16,840
Play for us, Erich.

962
01:17:21,390 --> 01:17:28,955
Here's a present for you, came 3 days ago.
She told me to hide it, I put it in the icebox.

963
01:17:39,420 --> 01:17:42,565
Erich, you were going to play for us.

964
01:18:25,500 --> 01:18:27,500
Gottfried gone.

965
01:18:28,140 --> 01:18:30,350
Pat, a million miles away.

966
01:18:32,440 --> 01:18:34,480
I wish Koster were here.

967
01:21:17,290 --> 01:21:19,220
I still say it was a job for both of us.

968
01:21:19,320 --> 01:21:23,485
If you'd be standing beside me,
he'd have hit you.

969
01:21:23,720 --> 01:21:25,720
Go open your telegram.

970
01:21:28,870 --> 01:21:33,885
Anybody see you?
- He fired first anyway it was self-defence.

971
01:21:43,280 --> 01:21:46,350
How long since you heard from her?
- Less than a week, why?

972
01:21:46,450 --> 01:21:49,765
Better get her on the phone right away.

973
01:21:59,790 --> 01:22:04,110
I'm so glad you called.
No, I'm in my room.

974
01:22:15,380 --> 01:22:21,670
They want me to rest up. They want me to
have a little operation next week.

975
01:22:23,140 --> 01:22:25,140
Operation?

976
01:22:25,500 --> 01:22:31,170
What for? What kind?
- Seems like I don't need so many ribs.

977
01:22:31,900 --> 01:22:38,340
It isn't really dangerous, but I...
just wanted to hear your voice.

978
01:22:40,500 --> 01:22:42,660
Koster and I will leave tonight.

979
01:22:42,760 --> 01:22:43,940
In Baby.

980
01:22:44,040 --> 01:22:47,185
We'll be there before tomorrow night.

981
01:23:27,830 --> 01:23:30,125
We thought you'd be in bed.

982
01:23:33,400 --> 01:23:38,920
I'm grateful to Baby, I love her. I didn't think
I'd ever deserve it but I'm getting in here.

983
01:23:39,020 --> 01:23:44,217
Don't ever leave me. Tell me if
you're ever leaving me again.

984
01:23:44,317 --> 01:23:46,317
I'm never leaving you.

985
01:23:58,190 --> 01:24:00,190
I'm outta gas.

986
01:24:01,580 --> 01:24:06,340
Took your time in picking me up.
I was freezing to death.

987
01:24:09,490 --> 01:24:14,675
She behaving herself?
- In a way, too wild, too many cocktails.

988
01:24:15,280 --> 01:24:16,760
Cigarettes.
- Without nicotine.

989
01:24:16,860 --> 01:24:18,200
Coffee.
- Without caffine.

990
01:24:18,300 --> 01:24:20,300
Dancing.
- Without.. you.

991
01:24:21,120 --> 01:24:25,880
That must be terrible.
- Herr Lohkamp can I talk a minute?

992
01:24:29,070 --> 01:24:33,790
And how's Gottfried?
- He is.. he couldn't come.

993
01:24:38,080 --> 01:24:42,050
And Erich? He still love me?
- He loves you Pat.

994
01:24:43,600 --> 01:24:45,810
Yes, he loves me terribly.

995
01:24:49,400 --> 01:24:53,120
After the operation she'll have to lie
very still for a few weeks.

996
01:24:53,220 --> 01:24:55,940
Sudden movement may prove fatal.

997
01:24:56,490 --> 01:25:01,350
Things haven't gone so well, have they?
- It would be much worse staying in the city.

998
01:25:01,450 --> 01:25:05,020
I didn't realise it would be so expensive.

999
01:25:05,600 --> 01:25:07,980
We'll get the money somehow.

1000
01:25:16,370 --> 01:25:18,370
Is that the road home?

1001
01:25:19,990 --> 01:25:23,480
In May, you'll be going
home along that route.

1002
01:25:23,580 --> 01:25:25,060
In May.

1003
01:25:25,160 --> 01:25:30,030
This isn't what we're supposed to say
this first time together.

1004
01:25:30,130 --> 01:25:34,370
All this while, I'd figured out what I'd say
and you'd say, word to word.

1005
01:25:34,470 --> 01:25:36,470
Do you want to hear?

1006
01:25:36,610 --> 01:25:39,470
We'd be lying on this bed just like this.

1007
01:25:39,570 --> 01:25:43,318
I'd say 'Is that the road
home?' You'd say 'Yes,

1008
01:25:43,418 --> 01:25:44,950
its 600 kilometers.'

1009
01:25:45,050 --> 01:25:47,620
And I'd say that doesn't matter now.

1010
01:25:47,720 --> 01:25:51,545
We love each other beyond
time and place now.

1011
01:25:51,870 --> 01:25:54,090
You'd say, 'That's right.'

1012
01:25:55,000 --> 01:25:57,000
Then you'd kiss me.

1013
01:26:04,390 --> 01:26:09,670
You'd say,' Ought I to be in this room now?
'Are we breaking the rules?'

1014
01:26:09,770 --> 01:26:14,445
And I'd say,'Mustn't I start now?
By not breaking them?'

1015
01:26:15,880 --> 01:26:18,175
Because I can't let you go.

1016
01:26:20,090 --> 01:26:23,235
And suddenly it would all be so real.

1017
01:26:30,900 --> 01:26:32,900
He gave me an estimate.

1018
01:26:34,310 --> 01:26:40,090
Over a 1000 marks? What are we going to
do? We got to get it but how?

1019
01:26:40,690 --> 01:26:43,870
I can make the city by tomorrow.
- How are you going to raise the money?

1020
01:26:43,970 --> 01:26:45,550
I'll get it.

1021
01:26:45,650 --> 01:26:47,140
You forget all about it.

1022
01:26:47,240 --> 01:26:53,275
Forget about everything but Pat tonight.
- Don't do something crazy Otto.

1023
01:27:00,960 --> 01:27:02,960
The silver dress.

1024
01:27:08,350 --> 01:27:12,940
Service is right. They belonged to
a couple of waiters.

1025
01:27:13,100 --> 01:27:15,352
My wife gave me some
dancing lessons. May

1026
01:27:15,452 --> 01:27:17,030
I try them out on you, Ma'am?

1027
01:27:17,130 --> 01:27:22,995
I'd adore it. I adore your wife.
How did she ever happen to marry you?

1028
01:28:35,730 --> 01:28:37,730
May I go in now?
- Yes.

1029
01:28:41,740 --> 01:28:44,205
Herr Koster wants to see you.

1030
01:28:53,710 --> 01:28:56,460
Been here a long time?
- I've been and come back.

1031
01:28:56,560 --> 01:28:59,020
Just to see me?
- Just to see you.

1032
01:28:59,120 --> 01:29:01,240
I'm taking the train back to the
city this afternoon.

1033
01:29:01,340 --> 01:29:04,655
The train? Why didn't you come in Baby?

1034
01:29:05,530 --> 01:29:08,080
Um.. er.. the roads too rough.

1035
01:29:08,240 --> 01:29:10,800
You sold Baby.
- No, Pat. What made you...

1036
01:29:10,900 --> 01:29:13,365
You're not to lie to me Otto.

1037
01:29:15,570 --> 01:29:18,850
She was about to fall of anyway.
Nothing but an old wreck.

1038
01:29:18,950 --> 01:29:20,950
You sold Baby.

1039
01:29:22,010 --> 01:29:26,510
To buy me a sweepstake ticket.
- The important thing is how do you feel?

1040
01:29:26,610 --> 01:29:29,530
I feel alright.

1041
01:29:30,090 --> 01:29:33,650
I think they took my
backbone out by mistake.

1042
01:29:33,750 --> 01:29:36,555
You've got enough for two anyway.

1043
01:29:37,480 --> 01:29:40,030
Kept pretending I had a child.

1044
01:29:40,400 --> 01:29:44,395
Must be nice to leave a
part of yourself behind.

1045
01:29:50,060 --> 01:29:52,270
For a moment I'd be there.

1046
01:29:53,890 --> 01:29:55,870
I don't understand it Otto.

1047
01:29:55,970 --> 01:29:59,795
Why two people should
love like Erich and me,

1048
01:30:00,360 --> 01:30:02,360
and yet one die?

1049
01:30:08,660 --> 01:30:14,185
I've been lying here alone for so many
hours, I've figured it out.

1050
01:30:17,020 --> 01:30:19,660
If you asked yourselves,

1051
01:30:20,120 --> 01:30:23,220
Perhaps I might live a few months longer.

1052
01:30:23,320 --> 01:30:27,230
If you sold your repair shop,
a few more weeks.

1053
01:30:29,930 --> 01:30:33,340
Perhaps if you sold your fingers,
one by one.

1054
01:30:33,440 --> 01:30:37,500
The blood in your veins,
the marrow in your bones.

1055
01:30:37,600 --> 01:30:39,895
Perhaps even a year or two.

1056
01:30:41,850 --> 01:30:44,950
So that I could still breathe a little.

1057
01:30:45,050 --> 01:30:47,050
My heart still beat.

1058
01:30:47,890 --> 01:30:49,890
For what Otto?

1059
01:30:55,670 --> 01:30:57,670
A dead dragging weight.

1060
01:30:58,270 --> 01:31:03,200
So that I could look at Erich and
know I'd grown old and ugly.

1061
01:31:03,300 --> 01:31:05,680
We'll all grow old and ugly.

1062
01:31:10,790 --> 01:31:16,990
To me, the happiness I never would know.
To Erich, his life.

1063
01:31:17,200 --> 01:31:21,280
And what have I given to Gottfried?
- Gottfried...

1064
01:31:22,730 --> 01:31:24,730
He's dead isn't he?

1065
01:31:27,290 --> 01:31:30,730
How did he die?
- Bravely.

1066
01:31:47,260 --> 01:31:50,065
He did what he thought was right.

1067
01:31:50,640 --> 01:31:54,380
Thats honourable to die
bravely and proudly.

1068
01:32:05,710 --> 01:32:07,710
Well, I'll get my bag.

1069
01:32:28,180 --> 01:32:33,460
Iets not go back to the city, lets..
go to South America.

1070
01:32:43,710 --> 01:32:45,710
Can we start now?

1071
01:32:48,360 --> 01:32:50,740
Its the deck of a boat in the morning.

1072
01:32:50,840 --> 01:32:52,840
No no, its evening.

1073
01:32:55,350 --> 01:32:59,120
I'm making eyes at the native girls
and you're getting mad.

1074
01:32:59,220 --> 01:33:02,850
And I'll always be very
strong and never tired.

1075
01:33:02,950 --> 01:33:05,075
I'll never want to sleep.

1076
01:33:05,300 --> 01:33:07,800
Because life would be
too good to sleep away.

1077
01:33:07,900 --> 01:33:13,520
We'll travel up the Amazon,
at the end there'll be a mud village.

1078
01:33:14,450 --> 01:33:18,150
and a little thatched hut with our names
on them and we'll go in.

1079
01:33:18,250 --> 01:33:24,285
Once we're in, we'd just sit.
- And I'd look at you and you'd look at me.

1080
01:33:31,100 --> 01:33:34,075
I'll go see Otto off. I'll be back.

1081
01:33:35,750 --> 01:33:37,750
Erich.

1082
01:33:42,730 --> 01:33:45,980
Its been so much more than 10 seconds.

1083
01:33:50,480 --> 01:33:52,480
Thank God for you Pat.

1084
01:33:56,280 --> 01:33:58,280
It ticks too loud.

1085
01:34:17,490 --> 01:34:19,530
Its not ticking anymore.

1086
01:34:20,790 --> 01:34:22,790
Time is standing still.

1087
01:36:26,160 --> 01:36:28,965
Its right for me to die, darling.

1088
01:36:31,300 --> 01:36:37,920
It does hurt, but I'm so full of love.

1089
01:37:05,810 --> 01:37:08,700
South America is so very far away.

1090
01:37:09,650 --> 01:37:12,285
I wish they were going with us.

1091
01:37:18,030 --> 01:37:20,495
There's fighting in the city.

 