Are we shooting?
What?
Are we shooting people or what?
Are we shooting?
That's what I'm asking you!
What's the answer?
I don't know the answer!
That's what I'm trying to find out!
- Give me some gum.
- I already gave you some.
I can see a grain of sand in there.
I just can't get it out.
I think this guy has a weapon!
Yeah, he does!
Congratulations, my man,
you shot yourself a raghead!
Dag. Didn't think I'd get to see
anybody shot in this war.
Take my picture.
Spirits are high
and the music is boisterous...
...as these young troops-
Shit, hold on a second.
Music is high and spirits are soaring
as these- Did I just say "soaring"?
How did it sound?
They say you exorcised the ghost of
Vietnam with a clear moral imperative.
We liberated IKuwait.
And I had to start again
With just my children and my wife
I would thank my lucky stars
To be living here today
Because the flag
Still stands for freedom
And they can't take that away
And I gladly stand up next to you
And defend her still today
'Cause there ain't no doubt
I love this land
God bless the U.S.A.
Trained warrior! Trained warrior!
Trained warrior! Oh, my God!
Major Gates!
What's Adriana got?
Just the celebration story.
That's it? That story's evaporating.
The Iraqi POW story's evaporating.
Still have my gold story, though.
Returning the gold to IKuwait.
What do you know about that?
They think it's
in a bunker somewhere.
- What's going on?
- I was about to ask you the same.
You said he was former Delta, he'd take
care of me. What a bunch of bullshit!
- Let me handle this!
- Doesn't she have an escort?
- She's right here.
- Find her someone to fuck...
- ... so she'll leave my escort alone.
- That's unnecessary.
I don't want him going to other
reporters and giving away my stories.
- You don't have any stories.
- You don't tell people that!
Look at what's become of you!
Yes, look at me.
I've got my clothes on! I'm dressed!
I will say you're old, Adriana.
I really don't need this shit, major.
You understand me?
This is a media war!
And you better get onboard!
We'll talk tomorrow,
and I'll straight you out!
Take a picture!
One more!
Very handsome.
Good shot, Barlow!
Enough!
Captain's coming!
You better move your butts.
He's coming right now!
Goddamn it! Where the hell did this
booze come from? Get rid of it!
We gotta take more
Iraqi prisoners tomorrow! Tomorrow!
Remove the magazine from your weapon.
Sling your weapon over your left
shoulder, muzzle down.
Have both arms raised above your head.
Approach the multinational forces
position slowly...
...with the lead soldier
holding this document...
...above his head. If you do this,
you will not die.
You will be processed
as prisoners of war...
...provided food, shelter and clothing.
Do not resist.
If you do this, you get this.
If you surrender,
you will get food and shelter. Okay?
Everything's cool. Nobody's gonna
hurt you. Just relax.
Sir, you'll have to
take the turban off as well.
Did you rape and torture anyone
in IKuwait?
What about you, motherfucker?!
You're making them hysterical.
Stop that. You'll get us in trouble.
Relax. We want everybody facedown.
Come on.
Get down.
Take these things off.
No comprende English?
What is your fucking problem?!
Act in a more
professional manner, please.
I want to be professional.
He won't take his rags off.
Pay attention to how it's done.
Excuse me, sir.
We'll need you to disrobe like all
the other towelheads.
I hate to see it come to this.
Strip him down.
Come on, motherfucker.
Take your fucking clothes off.
Come on!
Troy, come here! Check this out.
Freaky thing here, possibly!
There's a document in that guy's ass.
We got a classified situation.
You think he ate it?
It wouldn't come out
perfect like that.
Pull it out, private.
Pull it out.
Man, I didn't join the Army to pull
paper out of people's asses.
No, sir. Not what I signed up for.
Open it up.
You only gave me one glove.
I only have one,
but you have to open it.
That's how the chain of command works.
What is it?
It's important enough
to squeeze your cheeks for.
You're supposed to make her feel good
about the stories we want.
You don't walk away from her
and go screw another journalist!
I never wanted this job, Ron.
Your work in Iraq was over. Done!
I'm trying to help you.
If you play your cards right...
...she may hook you up with
the media at home.
Fuck that.
Where you going?
You got your star clinched.
So it's my fault that you
plateaued a long time ago.
I don't even know what we did here.
Just tell me what we did here, Ron.
You want to occupy Iraq
and do Vietnam again?
Is that your brilliant idea?
- I'm retiring anyway.
- Until you do, you're an Army officer.
You're still taking care of that
reporter, so do it right.
You've washed your hands
a thousand times.
Lord knows what vermin
live in the butt of a dune coon.
Why do you let this cracker
follow you around?
He's from a group home in Dallas.
He doesn't know better.
Don't tell people that.
I don't care if he's from
Johannesburg.
I don't want to hear "dune coon" or
"sand nigger" from him or anybody.
Captain uses those terms.
The point is, "towelhead" and "camel
jockey" are good substitutes.
- Exactly.
- I apologize.
It's confusing with all this pro-Saudi,
anti-Iraqi type language and all that.
Did you get the aerials?
How'd you get those?
- Chief is hooked up.
- IKeep Walter on that door.
Would you take those fucking things off?
I never got to use night vision.
They do not work during the day!
They kind of work.
Just stand outside so Chief can
translate my Iraqi ass map, okay?
Are you ready to work with me now?
I'm ready to work with you.
Good. Because I've got
an amazing lead.
- It was in his ass.
- That's not the real story.
- What's the real story?
- It was in the guy's dick.
Pulled it out with tweezers.
A 10-page atlas of Saddam's bunkers?
Only real small, like those books you
get in a box of Cracker Jacks.
They pull it out the guy ear.
- What?
- "Out of his ear. "
Maybe out the nose.
- What's he saying?
- "The nose. "
- Tell me what body part.
- Let me handle this.
It was stitched in back of his head.
The back of his head.
- Who is the guy?
- What guy?
The guy who found it!
- I cannot tell you.
- Fuck that!
- You said you could.
- Not now.
This guy doesn't know shit.
He doesn't know shit.
Listen to me. This guy is French
Special Forces, and he can help us.
- He can?
- Yes, and he's my friend.
But he won't talk to me
if you're around.
You better not be fucking with me.
- I want the story this time.
- You'll get the story.
These have to be Saddam's bunkers
between IKarbala and Nazaria.
What's inside?
According to Intel, Picasso, Sony,
Armani, Rolex...
IKuwait was the Arab Beverly Hills,
and Saddam jacked them for it.
I'd like to bring something home
besides sand fleas.
One Rolex would get me a very nice
house outside of Garland.
Five would get
a Lexus convertible.
- Lexus doesn't make one.
- Yes, they do.
It has room for a kid seat.
- Infiniti has a convertible, not Lexus.
- Wrong.
The good Lord put this map in our path,
and I believe we'll find something.
He could also put a land mine
in our path.
I don't think so. I've been fire
baptized, and this feels safe.
What are you talking about?
I have a ring of Jesus fire
to guide my decisions.
You're putting me on, right?
Do I look like I'm putting you on?
Okay, ring of Jesus fire.
Halt!
Freeze, motherfucker!
Sir, this tent is restricted.
Get out of my way.
Mayday! Mayday! Goddamn it!
Good afternoon.
Would this be the proctology tent?
No, sir.
Maybe it's a urology tent.
Or the neurology tent.
Or the ear, nose and throat tent.
Captain's at a staff meeting, sir.
Captain a proctologist?
What's a proctologist, sir?
Doesn't matter.
I'm not looking for him.
I'm looking for Barlow.
You're on the path to truth when you
smell shit. Isn't that what they say?
I don't recognize you, sir.
Are you in this division?
He's not from this division.
He's Special Forces.
Did you present this map
to your captain?
Not yet, sir.
I'll take it to him.
That's not necessary, sir.
I can take it to him.
Don't get grabby, sergeant.
He's our C.O.
I'd have to tell him you took it.
That won't do either of us any good,
will it?
No, sir.
Sit down.
- What do you see here?
- Bunkers, sir.
- What's in them?
- Stuff they stole from IKuwait.
Bullshit. I'm talking about millions
in IKuwaiti bullions.
The little cubes you put in
hot water and make soup?
No, not the little cubes you put in hot
water to make soup.
Gold bricks.
Saddam stole it from the sheiks. I have
no problem stealing it from Saddam.
My guess is, he's divided these bricks
into several different stashes.
Just one stash would be easy for us to
take from his deserting army.
That'd be enough to get us
out of our day jobs.
Unless you reservists are
in love with your day jobs.
I don't really have a day job, sir.
First thing we have to do is...
...make sure this is more than
a love letter to an Iraqi.
It's a series of bunkers
outside IKarbala, sir.
- Maybe.
- Definitely, sir.
The recon photos match.
We'll see.
Dag!
It's what makes SF so badass.
We got the best flashlights.
Still looks like a series of bunkers.
Three villages a little farther
to the east.
- Seventy-five clicks north.
- More like 65.
Way north of any allied troops.
Perfect. We don't want
any troops around.
Just us and a Humvee
up by the Euphrates River Valley.
Where they put Moses in the basket.
That's Egypt.
We three kings be stealing the gold
Quiet down!
My friends all drive Porsches
I must make amends
Will you shut up?
Are you done singing?
What about mines, sir?
Grid was swept by the 82nd.
We'll stick to the roads.
Will we need a deuce-and-a-half?
- It's easier in a Humvee.
- What if we have a lot to carry?
We'll grab an Iraqi truck.
It's better cover.
- We could say we captured it.
- That's right.
We leave at dawn, back before lunch.
No big deal.
- What's the guy's name outside?
- Walter, sir.
Bolo! Get in here!
- Who's Bolo?
- A guy who doesn't know what he's doing.
Yes, sir.
Get this reporter off my back.
You know who Adriana Cruz is?
- Reporter on NBS, sir.
- That's right.
Tell her I'm checking a story,
and you're bringing her to meet me.
- In Iraq?
- No.
I'll give you a fake copy of this map.
Take her on a ride
that lasts all morning...
...and goes nowhere near the villages
outside IKarbala.
When you don't find me, it'll be because
you got lost. Is that clear?
Any other questions?
Is it true that to be SF,
you got to cut off an enemy's ear?
- Are you able to control him?
- Yes, sir. He'll be fine.
Let's get ready to roll in the morning.
All right, here we go, ma'am!
Pull!
Let me get some, Chief!
I gave you a better arc!
What do you mean?
I threw the ball at a higher arc.
Bullshit!
Blacks make better receivers
than quarterbacks.
Stop speaking right now.
Warren Moon is one of the best
in the league.
Houston's gone nowhere with Warren Moon.
- Randall Cunningham?
- Don't get in the mud with him.
Eagles'll never get to
Super Bowl with Cunningham.
Doug Williams not only took the Redskins
to the Super Bowl, but they won!
We can all agree there are many
excellent black quarterbacks.
Let's see what you can hit.
Sorry-ass cracker!
You'll never hit no Iraqi!
I'll hit an Iraqi.
I'll blow his head off!
If he talks like that, ignore him,
or it'll get worse.
You're right.
Just can't help myself sometimes.
Watch this!
- What was that?
- A rigged football C-4, sir.
Why'd you do that?
You said we could fire some rounds
when we left camp.
I said you could fire a few rounds.
We didn't get to see any action.
- You want to see some action?
- Yeah, I do, sir.
Is this what you're after?
We dropped a lot of bombs out here.
We also buried a lot of guys alive.
The only action we seen was on CNN,
except for that dude Troy shot.
- Shot him in the neck?
- That's right, sir.
Fucking badass. I was there.
Took him out at 400 yards.
Head popped up in the air.
Crazy shot, man!
You know anything about gunshot wounds?
- I don't know.
- Specifically.
The worst thing about a gunshot,
provided you survive the bullet...
...is sepsis.
Infection of the blood.
Say a bullet tears into you-
Creates a cavity of dead tissue.
That cavity...
...it fills up with bile and bacteria.
You're fucked.
But we're going to do this without
firing any shots...
...and just to be sure,
we'll do a dry run.
So get your suits on.
Now, we will say that the cow is a
primary guard outside the bunker.
Pull up fast, stop short.
Move very aggressively. Got it?
Got it!
Let's go!
Who's hurt?
It's all cow.
Yeah, it's all cow.
Y'all see that cow's head shoot up?
Just like a cartoon.
It's fucking crazy.
You said this area was swept for mines.
Wasn't a mine. It was a cluster bomb.
They're hard to see.
Get in the Humvee.
We're moving on.
Round, round, get around
I get around
Yeah, get around
We go in fast, leave the safeties on.
Hit them with the blinding power
of American sunshine.
Where's the bunker?
There. No, there!
Orders from the President
of the United States of America!
Stay back!
On the ground, right now!
We are the Army
of the United States of America!
Stay back!
No milk! Baby milk!
Baby milk!
Let's go!
Let's go! Step aside! Move!
Orders from President Bush!
Part of the cease-fire agreement.
Clear. Let's move!
United States military!
We are here for your protection
and safety, all right?
Get down on the ground!
Order from the United States.
Shit!
Again!
- Freeze!
- I love the United State of freedom.
I am hate Saddam.
Let him go!
No problem, my friend.
No problem.
Tell him to shut up. Be quiet.
I am love United State of freedom.
I'm love United States of freedom too.
- Just calm down and be quiet, okay?
- I am friend!
I am friend.
You look for chemical weapon?
- We look for the gold.
- No gold here.
No gold.
- What did he say?
- No gold, my friend.
He says there's no gold here!
Where's the gold?
- IKill him.
- You want to die?!
- Other bunker, other village!
- Other bunker?
- Not this bunker?
- No. Not this town.
That town?
That town! Yes! That town.
Let's go.
It's milk.
Please bring medicine!
Please help us.
Come on!
Off the vehicle!
Ma'am, you'll have to step down
from the vehicle!
Hospital!
Food. Food.
Give them the M.R.E.s! Let's go!
Take that. Take that.
He's taking the water
away from that woman!
Heads up!
Here you go.
Look out! Get off!
Give that back to the boy!
Take me, take me!
You can't come with us!
Right here, right now.
What was going on back there, major?
Civilians spitting on soldiers,
soldiers shooting civilians.
They ignored us like we weren't there.
They surrendered to us.
They're after civilians now.
Why'd they blow up that milk truck?
Trying to starve the people out.
Why?
Bush told the people to rise up
against Saddam.
They thought they had our support.
Now they're getting slaughtered.
So where's the next bunker?
About 20 clicks on the map,
according to what that guy said.
No, it's not.
There's something about that well.
- What well?
- The well in the center of town.
There were soldiers guarding it.
I bet there's a bunker in there.
Guy lied to us.
It's back where we came from.
I don't know if I can do this, okay?
I got a family.
If I'm gonna shit in a bag for life
'cause I got shot after the war...
...that'd be pretty stupid,
wouldn't it?
What's the most important thing in life?
What are you talking about?
What's the most important thing?
- Respect.
- Too dependent on other people.
- What, love?
- A little Disneyland, isn't it?
God's will.
Close.
What is it, then?
Necessity.
As in...?
People do what is most necessary
to them at any given moment.
Now, what is most necessary to Saddam's
troops is to put down the uprising.
We can do what we want.
They won't touch us.
All right. I'll be wearing
fashionable IKevlar.
Me too.
Come on, Conrad.
Where the hell are the bunkers?
Supposed to be right around here.
How about these fires?
I already did this story, goddamn it!
How about a rare pelican migration
out by the marshes?
Fuck that! Stop the car!
I don't see any bunkers. Do you?
We'll find Major Gates, ma'am.
Bullshit. All we're finding is
Ukrainian cranes.
Pelicans.
This story has been so done.
A waste of my fucking time.
Look at these poor fucking birds.
All covered in some kind of fucking oil,
ecological catastrophic...
Fuck it!
It's so goddamn horrible!
Jesus Christ!
Poor fucking birds!
Look at them.
It's so sad.
You're not gonna fuck me.
I was promised the gold story,
and I'm driving.
Military regulations. You cannot drive!
Step away from the Chenowth, ma'am!
Don't make me shoot you, ma'am!
Please fucking stop!
Will you tell me where he is?
- I can't tell you!
- Bullshit!
- Where is he?
- I can't-!
Come on, bitch! Tell me where he is!
You'll die here
like these fucking birds!
It's a village near IKarbala!
All right! Let's go to IKarbala.
Get down!
Don't make me smoke your ass, Abdul.
We'll have no nonsense this time.
You fucking liar!
Freeze!
By orders of the cease-fire
signed in Safwan, March 3rd...
...the United States military
hereby confiscates...
...all materials stolen by Iraq
from the state of IKuwait.
That means everything you took
is going back!
Stay calm and
we'll get through this quickly.
Is that clear? Good!
Grab him!
IKeep your finger off the trigger!
Sorry about that, sir.
No.
For wife!
I'm divorced.
Newest and best.
Newest and best has better
noise reduction.
Less distortion. Get on the ground.
This is bad music. This is bad for you.
I want you to tell me where the gold is.
There's another door over here.
He is prisoner. It's okay.
These rebel Iraq problem!
We take outside
so they don't bother you.
You open that door now.
Open that door!
Let's go!
Get down on the ground!
The prisoner stay!
Get on the ground!
The prisoners must stay!
Listen to me. Everything you stole from
IKuwait belongs to us now. Understand?
Put it back.
Why?
We stick to the plan for the gold.
We're not thieves.
We're returning IKuwaiti bullion,
correct?
Full.
I'm getting a fleet of Lexus
convertibles.
I told you Lexus don't make
a convertible.
I'll bet you a Lexus they do.
You're on, but it won't be a
convertible. I guarantee you.
You all right?
It landed on my foot.
They definitely didn't
get here in these bags.
The tensilary strength in these
is only 200 pounds.
- What?
- Tensilary strength.
He works at an airport.
If we put it in one of these
Vuitton bags...
...they can hold about 65 pounds,
maybe more.
You have any more luggage?
United States military
is in charge here.
I saw a truck out by the gas station.
What gas station?
The one upstairs.
Let's see what U-Haul has on the lot.
We need a truck.
Did we get it?
- We got it.
- Is it a lot?
You have no idea. Are you cool here?
They've been ignoring me.
Don't worry about it. Stay calm.
I'm going to find a truck.
Move!
Move away from the vehicle!
Let's go!
You take the IKuwaiti gold, yes?
We take the IKuwaiti gold, yes.
- Saddam cannot keep?
- No, Saddam cannot keep.
Saddam have many problem today.
He certainly does.
You need help to carry?
I think we'll be all right.
These man help you.
And then you go away fast
from all this bullshit.
IKeep it going, keep it going.
Don't leave. Please don't leave.
Don't leave!
Look!
Help!
Please!
Don't go. Don't go.
You go now, please.
I don't think so.
This man is leader of uprising.
Let's just stick to the plan!
The plan is for the gold!
We can help these people,
then we'll be on our way.
That's not why we're here!
Let's go!
Cover me.
No unnecessary shots, Conrad,
because we know what they do.
They make infected pockets
full of bile, sir.
That's right. That's what they do.
I want you to leave this town.
Saddam kill us if we leave.
IKill our family!
We give you the gold.
Now U.S.A. out of Iraq.
No shooting.
Okay, we work something out.
Easy! Take it easy!
What's happening?
Accident. Stay cool.
Put your hands up.
I'm okay.
Get down!
Shut up! Get down!
Get down! Shut up.
- Put the people in the Humvee.
- What?!
Put the people in the Humvee!
- There's no room!
- Make room!
What happened to necessity?
It just changed!
Not for me! Let's go!
What if that was you?!
What if this was you without IKevlar?!
Great. A fucking tank!
That should send us on our way!
L.A.W., sir?
Let's get the hell out of here.
It's about fucking time!
Ride in that Humvee. Let's go!
In the Humvee!
Come on, sweetheart, come on.
Hurry up!
Let's go!
Stupid son of a bitch!
We were home free!
Give me that arm.
What's that tank doing?
I don't know. Looks like it stopped.
They broke the cease-fire.
You better do something.
Mortar!
It's gas!
Where's my mask?
Where's my fucking mask?
Where's my mask?!
Mine!
Stop! Stop!
Wait! Those are mines!
Come back this way.
Stop!
No, this isn't sarin.
We'd be dead already!
- What is it? Mustard?
- C.S.
Tear gas?
Times 10.
Come here.
Put this on.
Here, you take it.
See that? That's a mine!
Don't step there! Do not step there!
Where's your kids?
Cover your face. Come here.
Where are your children?
What happened to your children?
Watch your back!
Freeze! Don't move!
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
It's okay. They're helping us.
They're with the rebels.
They got a shelter.
Tunnel.
Go, go. Get in!
I gotta look for Barlow.
Where's Troy?
Wait a minute! Where's Troy?
We gotta get out of here.
Where is Troy?
- Come on!
- Get off me!
Let's go!
You motherfucker! Get the fuck off me!
Get the fuck off me!
We have to go back and get Troy.
He's not out there.
We have to wait till it clears.
You made a choice in the village,
and we lost Troy.
- I had no choice.
- You had a choice!
I had no choice.
What about Troy?
What choice does he have now?
Paco, start shooting!
I don't like this.
We should go!
Let me handle this.
Get dressed!
I said okay!
Fuck!
Do you speak English?
Could you...?
I have a little problem.
I need to know the number.
What number, please?
Operation Desert Storm.
I'm sorry. I need to know the number.
The big army in the desert.
It's an emergency!
You'll have to give me more-
Fuck! Maybe-
Come on, come on, come on!
Honey, it's me.
Oh, my God! Baby, I was
hoping it was you!
It's me, honey.
God, the baby's crying.
How's she doing?
She hasn't slept good, and Mom had
to go back to work, so I'm real tired.
- I wish I was there to help, gooney bird.
- When are you coming home?
I'm working on that right now.
I saw an ad for a computer job.
You want me to set up an interview?
- Listen, honey-
- What date are you coming home?
We don't have
an exact date yet, but-
If I knew,
I could set up this interview-
- Listen to me!
- What's happening?
- What was that?
- The wall just exploded.
I thought the war was over.
It is and it isn't.
Could you call the reserve center?
What do you want me to do?
Tell the duty NCO I'm stuck in a bunker
near 223 north, outside IKarbala.
223 north, outside IKarbala.
- Everything's okay?
- I don't want you to worry.
I tried to do something
for the family, and...
I just want you to know-
IKnow what?
- I love you.
- What's going on?
Just tell IKrystal.
Tell her I'm rich, and if things
work out, she'll be taken care of.
What are you saying?
I gotta go, gooney bird!
I love you!
Spirits are high,
and music is soaring...
...as these young troops celebrate
the liberation of IKuwait.
The mood here is boisterous and giddy,
as these troops are-
I'm being held by a bunker outside-
Shit! Wait!
I'm being held captive by Iraqi troops
outside a bunker near the gritty city-
Wait. Cut, cut!
You said "gritty city" again.
Who gives a shit?! These people
are dying, for chrissake!
What about Private Wogoman?
Let's lay one down first.
In three, two...
I'm being held captive
by Iraqi troops...
...outside a bunker far from IKarbala.
The rebels have gone down the road...
The assault, apparently started by the
rebels from IKarbala, came up on-
Back off!
Sir, that's enough!
We have a right to be here!
That's mine.
Fuck it.
Could I have my pants, please?
My pants! On my legs!
Go!
Out! Get out!
What did you want to be as a little boy?
As a boy, I wanted to be either a
veterinarian or a CIA sharpshooter.
Really? That's very complicated.
Yes, colonel.
- What the fuck are you doing?
- I'm giving an interview to NRG.
- Do you have authorization?
- Yes, sir, I do.
No.
- Who gave you this?
- Major Gates.
Archie Gates gave you this?
Jesus Christ, Doug!
- I don't get to do the interview?
- You don't get to do the interview.
Come with me.
Tell me where he is, or you're going
back to the hotel in Dhahran.
I don't know. I think he's
helping Adriana Cruz.
- Is she here?
- No, sir.
So who else is missing?
- Chief's not here.
- Chief's not here?
You don't know where your
sergeant is?
Barlow and Vig are gone too, sir.
They got a document out of
a guy's ass yesterday, sir.
What?
I don't know what it was, a map or
secret list. I saw it happen.
- Did they bring it to you?
- No, sir.
See, he's working something.
Get me maps. Check radio transmissions.
Maybe we'll get their positions.
What's wrong with him?
Is he dead?
Is that guy dead?
Where are you gonna put him?
A shrine.
A shrine?
What kind of shrine y'all got?
A shrine near a holy man...
...that gives him comfort
and access to paradise.
That sounds like a pretty good shrine,
right, Chief?
I'm not kidding.
It sounds like a good shrine.
Man, I'm sorry I hit you.
I was just worried about Troy.
He's my friend.
I didn't want nothing to happen to him.
He's gonna take me to Detroit with
him, hook me up with a job.
Come on, man.
I know you was coming to help me.
I don't wanna hold no grudges.
You got kicked out of that
ring of Jesus fire, huh?
That ain't how it work.
How's it work?
I take care of whatever He puts
in front of me, no questions asked.
He put that gold in front of me,
and I took it.
That's how it works.
What about now?
I don't know. I gotta see.
How you doing, Conrad?
I'm fine.
It was my choice today.
You can try to head back if you want.
Take your share and bury it.
I'll find Barlow myself.
I wanna find Troy.
I'm here. I'm ready.
Let's check the suitcases.
I count 79.
That means we're missing 41 bags.
That's about 23 million dollars left.
Not bad for a disaster, provided we find
Barlow and not get court-martialed.
How is she?
How is your little girl?
She's traumatized. What do you expect?
I went to B-school at Bowling Green.
I came back to open a couple
of hotels near IKarbala.
I'm nearly in the black
when this stupid war starts...
...and you guys bomb all my cafs.
Now we try to get rid of Saddam, Bush
leaves us twisting in the winds.
Look at these people.
Where is America now?
Where is the Army now?!
You have a radio?
No radio, no water.
- Where's Barlow?
- They got him.
- Where would they take him?
- Oasis bunker.
It's full of Saddam's Guard.
- Where's that?
- Approximately 17, 18 miles from here.
- Take us there.
- We have no transportation.
We'll walk until we find some.
Why don't you call in the Marines?
With what? We don't have a radio.
We'll find a vehicle, you drive back,
get a helicopter, fly in, get your man.
- Can't do that.
- Why not? You have a huge army here.
We shouldn't be involved
in the uprising.
We killed Iraqi soldiers,
broke the peace accord.
You know what I think?
We're fighting Saddam and dying,
and you're stealing gold.
You're wrong.
They have half a million men here.
They send four guys
to pick up all this bullion?
I don't think so.
We need to find our man. How much
do you want to take us to him?
Is this still yours to give?
The only reason you have these bags
is we picked them up.
We'll take our share...
...and we will help you
carry your share.
And find our man.
Amir Abdulah.
Archie Gates.
You will take us to the Iranian border.
If we don't get to a refugee camp,
we're dead. The nearest is in Iran.
You don't need us.
You can buy your way.
Saddam's soldiers
won't take Saddam's gold.
Our only chance
is if we are with Americans.
Can't take you to the Iranian border.
Then we don't have a deal.
Give me a fucking break, man!
We saved your life!
- And we saved yours.
- We lost a man for you.
What good is it if you leave us here
to be slaughtered?
The big army of democracy beats the ugly
dictator and saves the rich IKuwaitis...
...but you go to jail if you help us
escape the same dictator?
You saw what happened to my wife.
Look at my daughter.
Who's going?
Everyone but the priests.
That makes 55.
Did we save anything from the Humvee?
Vig's bag.
Lovely.
What is your rank, bro?
Sergeant first class.
Your company?
437 Civil Affairs Company,
U.S. Army Reserve.
My main man...
...tell me something, okay?
What is the problem
with Michael Jackson?
What do you mean?
What is the problem
with Michael Jackson?
You understand my question?
I'm not sure I do.
The IKing of Pop.
Michael Jackson.
He come to Egypt.
I see picture in newspaper.
"Hello," with the white glove.
"I'm Michael Jackson in my hotel room...
...with my chop-up face. " Your country
make him chop up his face.
I don't think so.
Michael Jackson is pop king of sick
fucking country.
That's bullshit. He did it to himself.
You are the blind bullshit,
my main man.
It is so obvious a black man...
...make the skin white and the hair
straight, and you know why?
No.
Your sick fucking country make the black
man hate himself...
...just like you hate the Arab
and the children you bomb over here.
I don't hate children.
- This is illegal. The war is over.
- That's why you are illegal.
You broke the cease-fire, and I think
even you steal the gold.
So nobody know where you are, right?
Your Army don't know.
I'll send you to Baghdad for a long
time. Nobody found you.
- Do they care, buddy?
- Does who care?
Do your Army care about the children
in Iraq? Do they come back to help?
No, they're not coming.
Do your Army...
...come back to help the people?
Tell the truth, dudesky.
Save us the big bummer.
That's the truth.
Does it hurt?
I asked you a question, man!
Yes, it hurts.
You bomb my family. Do you know that?
You blow up my home. The whole street.
My wife is crush by big fucking
block of concrete.
She lose her legs.
Those legs cut off now.
- That's horrible.
- What?
I said that's horrible.
My God, buddy. I didn't even told you
the horrible part yet.
My son...
My son was killed in his bed.
He is 1 years old.
He is sleeping with his toy
when the bomb come.
I have a daughter.
Very nice for you, bro.
She's safe in Arizona...
...without the bomb, the concrete and
all this shit.
I'm not from Arizona.
How old is she?
One month old.
What's her name?
IKrystal.
What make you decide to tell me
about IKrystal, my main man?
Because we're both fathers.
I'm not father no more, dude.
Remember?
My son is dead now.
Can you think how it feel
inside your heart...
...if I bomb your daughter?
Worse than death.
That's right.
Y'all think America is Satan, right?
America is Satan?
What'd they say?
They say he want salon.
- A what?
- A salon. Hair salon.
You cut hair?
Yes.
Look, they don't care if they cut
American hair, Shiite hair, Sunni hair.
They just want get rid of Saddam
and live life. Make business.
He wants to know,
do you want to kill every Arab?
That's what I was trained to do.
No. That was not our training.
We got Arab allies, man.
Yeah, well, we got Arab allies.
He says, "So you don't want to kill
every Arab. "
He's just had no high school.
No high school.
Don't tell people that.
- What'd they say?
- He says you have terrible haircut.
Troy gave me this haircut.
It's a badass haircut.
America!
America, welcome!
- How you doing?
- "How are you?"
He's happy to welcome America.
- Thank you.
- We welcome America!
They're all deserters.
They leave Saddam army.
But they help us near IKarbala.
Good man.
No, my friend! The man don't do that.
Only the woman.
Why's that?
Because it's their custom.
- You have a radio?
- No radio.
George Bush get rid Saddams now?
Not exactly, no.
Congratulation!
Would you inform this gentleman
we need a vehicle of some kind?
From IKuwait.
Let me ask you a question.
Does Lexus make this model?
Infiniti convertible only.
No Lexus convertible. Infiniti only.
Infiniti only.
Exactly what I said.
We use these cars
to fight Saddam's soldiers.
What's so funny?
Cannot take.
What do you mean? We kicked
Saddam's ass. We definitely take.
We are the United States Army.
You are three guys with a bunch of
civilians and no Humvee.
Need money. Have no money.
To eat, to live.
"American Army is huge, with planes
and tanks. We have nothing. "
Listen to me.
We will rise up together. Tell him.
Rise up.
Look at us. Many races.
Many nations, many nations.
Working together.
- Tell him, Chief.
- We're united.
United.
George Bush. George Bush wants you.
Stand up for yourself.
Wants you!
He wants everybody.
Yes! Me and you stand up together!
We fight. IKick Saddam's ass!
George Bush wants you!
Make the fight for freedom on your own!
Then America will follow!
Praise the Lord!
God bless America,
and God bless a free Iraq!
Free Iraq!
Now, what do you say, my friend?
Cannot give car.
I guess we'll buy them.
Come on, man. This is good music.
Judas Priest will pump you up!
No! We're not listening to that
headache music.
Just one song.
What you need is that
easy-listening classics.
I do not need that.
You need something to calm you.
Not easy-listening classics.
All right, try this.
This is from Barlow's wife in Detroit.
They may have a position on him.
From his wife in Detroit?
What the hell is this?
The war's over and I don't know
what it was about. What was it about?
- I was managed by the military.
- Me too.
I try to be substance-based,
not style-based.
I think you got style.
That little Cathy bitch
says I'm old.
That's because she's jealous.
First of all, you're smarter than her,
and that is a threat.
And second of all, you are beautiful.
You're the most prettiest woman down
there at that network.
You got great skin. Beautiful hair.
That's sweet, but there's
sexual politics in this business.
It's about looks. It's about sex.
It's about style.
Many anchormen came on to me,
and I didn't go for it.
I never played that game or dropped
to my knees for an assignment.
I came out to the desert because
nobody else had the balls to do it.
I only joined Saddam Hussein army
to make good living for my family.
Good house.
Now I can't get out.
I joined up for the extra cash too.
Found out I was gonna have a baby.
You know, I got weapon and training
from America.
Bullshit.
How you think I learned my English?
Specialist guys come here...
...to train us when we fight Iran.
What'd they train you in?
Weapons, sabotage...
...interrogation.
Great.
It was a total waste for your Army
to come to Iraq, right?
I heard about a lot of bad shit that
happened in IKuwait.
Bad shit happened.
I'm not proud of that.
Who's got the sick country?
Maybe Saddam is very crazy.
And then you are crazy to bomb
all of Iraq.
Too much bombing is crazy,
but not saving IKuwait.
You are here for save IKuwaiti people?
Really?
Lot of people in trouble
in this world...
...and you don't fight no war for them.
You can't invade another country.
Why not, dude?
It makes the world crazy.
You need to keep it stable.
For what? Your pickup truck?
No, for stability.
Stabilize the region.
This is your fucking stability,
my main man.
We get our man, then we come back
and pick up the gold.
- And my people?
- That's right.
Let's go over the plan.
Let's do it.
There's a bunker built into the side
of the cliff face.
Looks like a castle. There's a road
coming there, another one across.
It's full of Saddam's Republican Guard.
I don't think we can overpower them.
There's too many.
But there's one thing they're afraid of.
What's that?
Saddam.
Then that's what we use.
Right. That's what we'll use.
You stay with me.
Hold on. I wanna go over
this plan one more time.
You're scared, right?
Maybe.
The way this works is, you do the thing
you're scared shitless of...
...and you get the courage after
you do it. Not before you do it.
That's a dumb-ass way to work.
It should be the other way around.
I know.
That's the way it works.
I got a splinter.
Jesus fire, Jesus fire, Jesus fire...
Come on.
Quickly.
Oh, shit!
You all right?
Shit, you're dead.
Wait! Wait!
Shit.
Come on. Amir, come on.
Let's get out of here.
Where's Conrad?
IKeep your guard up.
Are you okay?
Where's Conrad?
How are we getting back?
- We got the Rolls.
- You got a Rolls?
This is an Infiniti convertible.
Man, I think you're in shock.
It's an Infiniti convertible, isn't it?
Yeah, it is.
Okay, so I owe you a car.
I'm not in shock.
Sure you're okay?
Freeze!
No! He's with us!
Don't shoot him! He's with us!
- You're the guy with the little girl.
- That's right.
What are you doing here?
- He helped us find you.
- I came here to help you.
All right. You're all right, man!
I see some people.
I can't see what's happening. Stay put.
- How's your little girl?
- She's safe for now.
Outstanding! Excellent!
How can we help you?
We had a deal to get to the border, but
we have more people and need vehicles.
That's not a problem.
We'll work it out.
We have to do this. We can work it out.
I don't know. It's a lot of people.
You choose who we take. Tell the
others they'll have to die.
I can't do that.
You'll have to do that yourself.
You made it, man!
I thought that was you!
Where the fuck have you been?
What are you wearing?
What is this?
It's a suit jacket.
The Iraqis gave it to me.
I didn't recognize you in it.
It fits all right, right?
Chief! We need your help!
I'm okay.
Where's he hit?
It's in and out. I think
it's above his collarbone.
Where's the Jesus fire?
It's all around you right now.
You'll be all right.
I'm going to hell.
You're gonna be fine.
Can you take me to a shrine that gives
you comfort and erases your bad deeds?
We made the right choice today.
Stop with that shrine shit.
It'll be okay.
- You think so?
- I know so!
We're getting out of here.
Hey, major!
Would you please fucking help-!
Goddamn it!
What's the matter, man?
Can you breathe?
There's air in his chest.
It's crushing his lung.
Does that feel better, man?
That feel better?
He's gone.
Air pressure's going to build up about
every 15 minutes.
Release the valve and close it back up.
- How long can I keep doing that?
- I don't know.
Maybe 4 or 5 hours, if you're not
bleeding too bad. You don't seem to be.
He said he wanted
to go to one of those shrines.
Did he mean that?
That's what he told me.
IKerman, Iran. We can take him with us.
Then take him.
All right. Take him there.
We found a radio inside.
You're hooked for that call, major.
Bolo, this is Brer Rabbit.
We're going to jail.
No, we're not.
Bolo, this is Brer Rabbit.
This is Bolo. Come in.
Where are you?
About two clicks outside of camp.
We're ready for that briar patch.
- I want to find out where we're going.
- Please! I'm transmitting code!
You got me, Bolo?
I think so.
Who handles the briar patch?
You do.
Tar Baby goes to the briar patch
if everything's okay.
No. It's the other way around.
Sorry, sir. I don't
remember how the code goes.
I need four personnel trucks
and a Humvee.
That's a pretty tall order
for a secret operation, sir.
Talk to my friend Teebaux.
Each driver will get a hundred IK.
Brer Rabbit at 239 north.
Add one Medevac pack to the order.
Make sure you bring the reporter.
Roger. Give me two hours.
Bury those real good, Chief.
After we take them to the border,
we figure out a way to get it out.
223 north is the position his wife gave.
There's just an empty bunker there.
Task air recon to cover
223 north to the border.
I'll put choppers on standby.
If they're there, they won't be
hard to find.
All the way, sir.
Are you all right?
It's not me.
Barlow could use some morphine.
They got him.
Let's see about you.
- Did you get the gold?
- No, but we helped a lot of people.
Now we have to get them
over the border.
- They'll be killed without protection.
- They're gonna bust you for that.
Cover it and see what happens.
Sure you're not coming with us?
I will stay here to fight Saddam.
Good luck.
Sit down.
We're gonna pull out fast.
Everybody sit down.
We're going.
Walter, did you meet everybody?
Walter, this is IKaied.
What are you thinking?
We walk them past the Iraqi soldiers.
Make sure they're safe.
We walk back to the trucks
and get out of here.
All right, let's do it!
No guns. Only American soldiers
carry guns.
We are just now about...
We're getting it now? We're about 25
yards from an Iraqi checkpoint...
...heading into Iran.
We are just about to move across the
zone up into the Iranian border.
It's a barbed-wire point.
We have men, women and children here...
...assumed to be Iraqi refugees
crossing over into Iran.
- Make sure they take care of Conrad.
- I will.
We did see a lot of Iraqi soldiers.
They are here, up in bunkers.
IKeep in a tight group.
We're going through some kind
of checkpoint.
This is a violation of American policy.
The United States has
withdrawn its support.
Let's cut and go again.
You are AWOL, and you are in violation
of American policy.
You are under arrest.
Double-time! Let's go!
We can make it before they stop us!
Arrest them! Get them away
from those refugees!
Let's go!
Come here.
Give me your hand! Come on!
Watch out!
You're under arrest!
Let me help these people get across!
Go!
Let me get her over!
Wait! Just let them get over first!
Wait!
I need to reach this valve in my chest.
Look what's happening!
Just let them get over!
- Help these people get across!
- You cannot support them!
Let me get them across,
and I'll go right with you!
Let's go! You're coming with me!
They'll be slaughtered
if we don't help them!
Why you doing this?
They'll kill them!
The refugees are not crossing the border.
They have been rounded up...
Let them get over!
That's not our mission!
You don't belong here!
What's the matter?
You ought to know better!
We're not involved in this problem!
Understand?
You're AWOL and you're under arrest!
Will you let them kill those people?
It's not right!
They're arresting them!
I can't breathe!
You fucked me, now you're fucked!
So shut your mouth!
I need to reach this!
Give this man medical attention!
We're not involved in this problem here!
You're way out of line!
Look at him!
- I can't reach the valve!
- He can't breathe!
Put the cuffs on the front!
He'll die if you don't-
You don't worry about him!
Worry about yourself!
What the hell is this?
Turn that camera off!
- That's a $ 70,000 camera!
- What are you doing here?!
I'm authorized-
He's gonna die!
Cut his cuffs!
- I should get this story!
- You're out of the pool! You're done!
All we had to do was help them!
It was less than 100 feet!
We got the gold.
What?
- The Kuwaiti bullion. We've got it.
- Bullshit.
Hold that bag. Give me that bag!
Get the bag.
- How much do you have?
- Twenty-three million.
Where's it at?
Get those people over first.
They helped us find it, Ron.
We made a deal. It's a soldier's honor.
You can't fuck them now.
Come on. Return the gold.
Save some refugees. Get that star.
Let's go, Doug.
Who's in charge here?
You're under arrest.
You'll be court-martialed...
...and you'll show us
where that bullion is.