Declaration of Christmas Peace is an
essential part of Finnish Christmas.
The first Declaration of Christmas
Peace was issued in 1320...
It's really stupid and childish
of you to hide in the kitchen -
when I want to talk to you.
Hiding in the kitchen won't help.
If you have something to tell me,
you'd better tell it right now.
You're mad, paranoid mad. - There
is no such thing as paranoid mad.
It's paranoiac. And no, I'm not.
You invited your
Russian friends over? - Yes, yes.
Yes, yes, yes.
It didn't occur to you
that this is a Finnish Christmas?
This is not some Russian
Father Frost disco, damn it!
In Finland, we celebrate Christmas
with family. - I have no family here!
Whose baby is it then?
Tell me whose it is.
You're not going to say anything.
You just stare at me.
I could tell
by looking into your eyes.
I could tell already back then.
You're just poisoning yourself.
And me.
Fine. We'll drink vodka then.
At least put the ham on the table.
- It's in the fridge.
It has to be served warm. Fuck!
It's frozen, damn it!
The ham has to be roasted the night
before. It's the Finnish way!
It'll take at least five hours
before it's done.
Were you going to serve ham
with some whipped cream for dessert?
Put the ham in the oven; it won't
roast by itself in the sink.
Please, put the ham in the oven.
Thank you.
No use protesting.
This was your fault.
If I give you a task,
you have to perform it.
That's how we do it in Finland.
Now close the door
and switch the oven on.
Don't slam it!
Did you hurt yourself?
It's the water thing! Get up, okay.
Sit down.
Yeah, it's the baby's water.
We have to go right away.
I'll get your coat.
Put your coat on. Shit!
Let's go. The ham will be okay.
Hello.
Hi, it's Dad.
Hi, Daddy.
I just got back from Paris. Where
can we meet? - I'm in the hospital.
Are you okay?
- I'm fine, but Mom isn't.
What is it again?
- Come here if you want to know.
We have to go to Grandpa's grave and
visit Grandma in the nursing home.
You've never done anything for me,
so I don't care if you come or not.
Which hospital are you at?
- At the women's clinic.
I'm right next door.
I'll be there in a minute.
Damn it.
Shit, this is the North Pole.
Hold it back.
Press your chin to your chest.
- Good.
Push! It's coming.
Darling, please tell me. I can't
go on living if you don't tell me.
One more push.
- Push once more.
It's coming.
Was it Erkki? Tell me if it was him.
Tell me. Was it Erkki?
- Yes!
Get out! - I could tell it right
away. I could see it in your eyes.
At least tell me if it's
a boy or a girl. - It's a girl.
Out!
- I could tell right away.
Hi.
Tero. What's the situation?
Mom is dead.
You killed her.
Juha, hurry. There is a fight.
- I'll kill you.
Stop!
You'll have to live with it now!
You'll pay for it.
Are you alright?
- Yes, I'm fine.
Everything's okay.
Are you sure?
- Yes.
Is... Riitta Parviainen
somewhere here?
I'm Rauno Vajanne.
Follow me.
Hello.
It's Santa Claus.
- Okay, I'll open it.
Okay, Justus, go and see who it is.
Who is it?
- Good evening!
Please, come in.
Merry Christmas. It does, indeed,
look very Christmassy here.
Look at this big box, Justus.
I think it's for your mother.
- No, it's not.
So I shouldn't give it to her?
- No, because it's not for her.
But it says M...
No, it says J, U, S, T.
You're right. It's for Justus.
Santa's eyes are bad,
and Santa is tired.
Santa has a long night ahead of him.
Come and give Santa a hug before
you start opening the presents.
Merry Christmas, Justus.
Santa gives you a big hug.
Merry Christmas, dear child.
- Santa must be in a hurry.
No, I'm not in that big of a hurry.
Why don't we open this one.
It must be for you.
I'm sure Santa has a lot of children
to visit tonight. - Well, yes...
Justus, Merry Christmas.
Okay, time for Santa to go.
- Already?
Mom will see Santa off.
Erkki, you can't do something like
this. I can't take it anymore.
I'm sorry. I just had to see him.
Take good care of him.
Tell him that I loved him.
That I always loved him. Promise?
Of course.
I'm sorry about all this.
- So am I.
Well, that's how our life went.
Yeah, that's right.
Dear Justus -
I decided to write to you because
my illness has been getting worse.
I am afraid
I will not see you again.
Even though I have not been
the father I had hoped to be -
I want you to know
that you have been my everything.
I hope you will understand
my decision, whatever it will be.
Hi. - Hi.
I just had the baby. Imagine
becoming a father at this age.
Let's go and have a drink.
- Congratulations.
It's kind of a bad moment. I was in
the middle of something important.
C'mon, don't be such a bore.
You are born only once.
But you die a bit more often.
We'll die, that's for sure.
I wanted to have a drink with you.
Okay.
See you there. Bye.
Rauno, damn it.
What are you doing here?
- Hi!
I slipped and had my knee checked.
But everything is okay. - Good.
What's up with you?
- I just had a baby.
Today, on Christmas Eve?
- Yes. At this age.
Congratulations! That's incredible.
Life is full of surprises.
Can I buy you a drink somewhere?
Thanks, but I am not sure if I have
time. I have to meet someone.
Actually, I'm going to see Erkki.
Oh. I would get to see him too.
So you don't have
any Christmas plans then?
I'll give my Christmas gift
to Tero tomorrow.
I'm free to do anything today.
What the heck. We're both Christmas
widows. - If it's okay with you.
Of course. I'm just a bit puzzled
to see you here.
This is incredible.
- Let's go then, if you have time.
I have to drive my car home first.
We'll grab a bite, too...
Enter into the joy.
- Quite a mansion. This is nice.
This is okay, nothing special.
- Nice and cozy.
Feel free to look around.
You must be hungry.
- It smells really good.
There is gravy on the floor.
- What?
Yes, it's gravy, indeed.
It's my wife's water.
What?
- I'll clean it up later.
We'll close at six tonight.
Will there be anything else?
One more, please.
Hi.
Hi! And congratulations!
I can't believe this.
- I brought my girlfriend with me.
It's great to see you. It's been
a long time. - Great to see you.
We haven't met since your bachelor
party. - Let's not talk about it.
Can I get you something? We're
closing. - We'll all have vodka.
I'll have a beer as well.
- I'd like French red wine.
So, which one is it?
- A girl Jesus.
And everything is okay? - Yes.
How much does she weigh?
- The same as the ham.
I don't know her weight. Like all
babies, she's small and wrinkly.
Does she look like her father or
mother? - Like her mother, I hope.
How is your wife?
- She is fine.
I'm sure. Her life
revolves around the baby now.
It's been some time we last met.
- It's been almost a year.
Let's toast to a new life!
Congratulations, Matti!
- Thanks.
What could be more beautiful
than having a baby on Christmas Eve?
And it's incredible we met. - We
ran into each other at the hospital.
So you have been living abroad.
- Yes.
What brings you here?
- I have family obligations.
So you just arrived?
- Yes, I arrived today.
You have to see people at Christmas.
So, how is your son?
- He's doing alright.
He's been working
as an electrician in films.
And now he is a stagehand
at the National Theatre.
But he hasn't quite
found his place yet.
He's smart, though.
He's the little boy who hit me in
the balls with a badminton racket.
Yes, in a doubles match.
So, are you single?
- No. I have a French girlfriend.
I'm a bit of a traveling man. One
day I'm here and the next I'm there.
I have to decide whether I'll stay
there or if I'm going to come back.
Why? I understood
that you have a good career there.
I've got a lot of interesting work
there, but I miss Finland.
You managed to get out of here,
so stay there. - Yes, this is no...
Sorry, I have to take this.
It's a work call.
We have to go to another bar.
- Drink up, and we'll go.
Are there any bars open tonight?
- We'll find a place.
What is it with his son? - I don't
know. I thought Rauno was gay.
Well... He is.
You never know.
But that is what I have understood.
Not that it matters.
I wonder if this French girlfriend
is just a cover-up. - Well...
But he's a great guy anyway.
- That's right.
It's incredible that we're here
together on a night like this.
We're in the same spot as 30 years
ago. We have the same freedom.
I don't know about you, but
I can do anything I want tonight.
It's beautiful how
the age of a person...
Look, he's still got the same
enthusiasm. - No, but I mean...
We are going to hear
philosophizing and praise all night.
I haven't had a chance to speak
Finnish in a long time. - Now you do.
All the different ages are in us.
- Tell me about it.
They're present in us all the time.
It's fascinating. - It's true. You
carry them with you your whole life.
Guess where I bumped into you
the last time? - I have no idea.
You won't believe this.
I was in a book shop in Paris.
Your photo book was there. It'd been
translated into French. - Really?
Didn't you know? - Of course I did,
but it was amazing you found it.
I though it would end up
on a shelf at the Finnish embassy.
For some reason, they
translated the title as L'Intimité.
In their plainness
and expressiveness -
your photos are exceptional.
Who was the actress you worked with
in the film that was shown here?
The one where the woman's son
starts to threaten your character.
She had dark hair.
A beautiful woman. - Nathalie.
She's a fantastic actress, but
the film itself was nothing special.
It was an art house film.
- They played it here in the spring.
But the woman...
I wanted to ask you something
after reading your book.
The relationship you have
with the people you photograph...
I had no relationships, especially
not with the girl on the cover.
I wish I had.
I even asked her if we could.
You have photographed so much
suffering and misery, and war...
That's the point.
When your work
has been based on the shock effect -
you want to show things
in their nakedness.
They're nude photographs? - No,
the people's eyes are naked in them.
So they're portraits? - They
portray people in their daily lives.
I've made one series of nude
photographs. I'll show them to you.
I hope the nude photos are
not of you. - No, they're not.
The photos are of dead
and dying people.
Bruised people.
But that's Matti's everyday life.
- Sort of.
I would like to spend one day
in your shoes.
You're working on a project
that has to do with the police? - No.
I'm just interested in how people in
different professions see the world.
Why do you bother yourself with
that? Evil is contagious, you know.
Why touch all that? - I'm interested
in different perspectives.
My perspective is illusory.
I work with fiction.
That's what I mean.
I work with fiction as well.
But you see the reality as well.
You photograph the suffering.
That's what I mean. Is it worth it
to touch all evil in the world?
Even though we are taught that
we shouldn't look at everything -
I think we should
choose what we want to see.
Why should we deliberately poison
our souls and minds? - You're right.
I've had enough of all that.
I can't stand
the smell of dead bodies anymore.
So you're saying
that you're tired of your work.
What pills are you taking?
Remember that I'm a cop. If you have
stimulants, please share with us.
We'll empty our pockets for you.
- Pop anything you want.
That makes this Christmas perfect.
- Merry Christmas, Mr. Santa!
He seemed a bit lost.
Where are we going to find a bar
that's open? - And soon, I hope.
Matti, you know the bars.
Don't worry, young men.
We'll have hypothermia.
And with some more snow,
they'll never find us.
"Three mummies found in a park."
- You never whined about cold before.
Let's go and sing something.
- Let's run! Boys, let's run!
You can't be serious.
- Absolutely!
The lights are on.
This is a karaoke joint.
Are you sure you want to go in?
We're closed.
Sorry, but we're closed. - Please,
we've been walking all night.
You'll have to come back
after Christmas. - Please, wait.
I became a father today.
We'll drink a lot.
Alright then. Make sure
you drink your money's worth.
Merry Christmas!
You can sit wherever you like.
- Thanks.
There are not too many people here.
- We can sit anywhere we like.
One, two, one, two...
I would like to eat something.
- We'll get something.
You can also sing karaoke.
You can choose your own song.
I'll show you.
You can sing while you drink.
You know this one?
Te-pe-tee, te-pe-te-pe te-pe-tee
Spring is in full swing
I heard a little bird singing
Erkki, come!
We are two birds in the same tree
When we sing together
Everyone will hear the call of love
Te-pe-tee, te-pe-te-pe te-pe-tee
I built a nest
I want to share it with my dearest
This is a flamethrower.
It was worth waiting for.
We haven't toasted to
the new father yet, so here we go.
To the new father and to fatherhood.
- To all beautiful and lovely women.
All women are so beautiful
I could fuck them.
It's so surprising
to hear you say that.
Our Don Giovanni.
I've always been into
falling in love.
So you fall in love and... - At
the same time, I long for solitude.
When I'm abroad,
staying at a hotel -
I enjoy my freedom and
independence immensely.
There is no one
who will tell me what to do.
Then I see a person
who smiles at me -
and looks like she might like me.
And I see us living
a happy life together -
sharing moments and all that.
At night, I have these fantasies
about caring for someone.
I'll find a woman shivering
with cold. We're on an island.
The woman has been sailing
and has suffered a shipwreck.
I'll carry her in and heat the sauna
for her. I'll take her clothes off.
It's erotic and protective
at the same time.
The women must be in seventh heaven.
But I've never found
a woman on an island.
So what seems to be love is really
just a fleeting moment of passion.
It is an erotic fantasy -
as it always ends in love-making.
- You mean fucking.
But there is tenderness
and giving pleasure.
Do you give pleasure to the woman
or yourself? - To the woman.
It's part of male eroticism. Like
Alberoni says, a man is by the...
Sorry to interrupt,
but do you see a connection -
between the way
you act with women and your morals?
You said earlier
that one should have morals.
Or do you just act on your instinct?
- I act on my instinct.
So you're an animal. - Yes. What
is the world crying out for? Animal!
It cries out for something more.
- We should free the animal in us.
I wish I had understood earlier -
that instead of
focusing on yourself -
you could delve into
the other person.
I have never taken responsibility
for anything.
I always left
when I should have made a decision.
Do you feel a longing
for something you have lost?
I don't know.
I have always enjoyed long flights.
I often become emotional.
I feel like crying about my life
and the people I have lost.
I want to cry about the happiness
I have had in my life.
It's a happy cry.
What are you crying about?
Do you miss your children?
I have tried to learn to be selfish.
I have tried to tell myself -
that my children
are not an extension of my life.
They have their own lives. I don't
want them to be defined by me.
Of course I offer them security.
But I've been away from home a lot.
I have been reckless,
and I have felt guilty about it.
Especially after my divorce,
I worried about them.
How would they do
when I wasn't there -
to provide them with security.
But I've tried to learn selfishness.
- Why do you want to be selfish?
Would you do it for your children or
because it makes your work easier?
I believe
that if I can fulfill myself -
and become myself,
so to speak -
I will be a better person
with other people and my children.
You say you will be a better person
if you become whole and yourself.
How will it help your children -
if you're whole
on the other side of the world?
Sorry for being provocative. - It's
as if you are talking about my life.
My situation is different.
I haven't had children before today.
It has been
the biggest tragedy of my life.
That is why my first marriage
ended the way it did.
I'm happy that it ended because
it was really difficult in the end.
Are you crying? - It's just that it's
like you're talking about my life.
It's just that... I'm so fucking...
I talk about humanity
and about being a better person.
I talk about how, as an actor,
I should be a better person.
And the only thing
I have done in my life -
is leave my family.
Then you have to face
your nothingness.
The conflict is sometimes so...
- What is the big issue then?
I have abandoned my closest people.
I have escaped,
escaped and escaped...
Do you feel a need
to do something about it?
I don't know if I can. How do you
undo the past thirty years?
Do you keep in touch with your
ex-wife, the mother of your son?
I see her at Christmas.
I think you just touched
a sore spot there.
He was like that
when I met him in the hospital.
What is it?
- I don't know. He hasn't told me.
We should be able
to talk about things like these.
Just between us...
- Did I say something wrong again?
You must have touched a sore spot.
You showed the animal in you.
Shit, shit, shit.
These things are not easy.
And if you think about Rauno...
He's coming.
- I mean, you and your women...
Gypsies, wine and women! Like
Dmitri in The Brothers Karamazov.
C'mon, let's sing something.
I need some signs of life, you know.
- Patron!
Loneliness around me
Sometimes takes human form
I know what I want
I know how little I am capable of
Loneliness in my heart
Condenses into bitter drops
That is the cause
And consequence of loneliness
I'm stuck on you
I will always be
Say "leave"and I will go
Soon you will see
I didn't go anywhere
I wish I knew you better
Then I might learn to know myself
Even though I never left you
I will come again
I wish I knew you better
Then I might learn to know myself
Even though I never left you
I will come again
I don't envy those
Who were born to live a double life
Sometimes I feel
One life is hard enough
I wish I knew you better
Through our frozen fatherland
Even though I never left you
I will come again
Good job, Rauno!
Give it your all!
That was a great performance.
Good job! - Perfect!
Excellent.
- Sit down, will you.
Who's the next one on stage?
- We have to cool off.
Just get on stage.
I've got a song for you.
We agreed everybody would sing.
- In a minute.
We'll finish the cigars first.
I need another drink.
- Another round, please.
First sing, then drink.
- My throat feels coarse.
Somebody called you.
- I see.
It was Chérie.
Your darling called.
Did you answer?
- Yes.
Excuse me, I have to call...
- Don't go anywhere. Sit down.
Seemed like a nice person.
We said that you were on stage.
You didn't answer the phone?
- Yes, I did.
And?
- I said you were singing.
Your Chérie is....
- I have to call...
So this Chérie is a man.
Who called me?
- Chérie.
This is my agent's number.
- No one has an agent named Chérie.
What is his name? Jean-Pierre?
- No...
Why hide something like this
from your old friends? - Hide what?
Stop joking. Your boyfriend called.
- I don't have a boyfriend.
Who was it then?
- My agent.
Why does it say Chérie on that?
I won't let you wriggle out of this.
We'll talk about it
once and for all.
We're going to drink some more.
- I made it a triple.
The size of the glass
seems right to me. - Thank you.
A toast to Chérie!
- To Chérie.
You think I'm gay?
- We don't think anything.
So I'm gay because I'm an actor
and live in France?
There is nothing wrong
with being gay these days.
Why are you hiding
something like that?
Being gay must be so much easier.
- Could be.
Probably.
- Who knows.
It looks like it's Erkki's turn.
That's right.
- The stage is yours.
You didn't get offended, did you?
- It was tasteless.
It was completely harmless.
- Yeah, right.
Are you ready? Let's go.
I can say "thank you"
In ten languages
I can wish a happy new year
But I can't catch
The early morning shining star
Hi. It's Dad.
I'm at the Swengi karaoke club.
Please come here, so we can talk.
Love died in the stream of life
Save me if you can
Save me
I could walk
Till the end of the world
I could come back and take a breath
But after you are gone
There is nothing left for me
I don't understand the magic of life
Save me if you have time
Save me
That was a great performance, Erkki.
Very soulful.
You just told more about yourself -
than you have
during the whole night.
That's right.
You cover yourself so much.
With you two,
there is a good reason for it.
Why couldn't we have
more moments like that?
Why do we have to be so goddamn...
I told you
that the joke was tasteless.
Fucking tasteless.
Riitta just died.
And Tero beat me up at the hospital.
And you,
who I consider my friends...
Riitta is dead?
Should we follow him?
You have a problem?
- I hope not.
Everything is fine.
- Good.
Did you know?
- No.
I didn't know. I could tell
he wasn't himself when I met him.
Rauno the Ruin.
That's how I used to call him.
I was joking.
It was just a nickname.
In reality
Rauno was in ruins when we met.
Rauno the Ruin.
I was working as an on-call
mental health counselor.
It was a depressing job.
After work, at 5 a.m., I used to
have coffee at a night cafe.
They don't have places
like that anymore.
It was a place
where night and day met.
That's where we met.
Rauno was still in the party mood
after a long night.
I recognized Rauno
from television and films.
I thought I was
his last desperate attempt.
He walked me home and said he
would come for coffee the next day.
At the same time and place.
I was sure we would never see again.
The next morning Rauno sat there.
Sober.
I have to admit
he made an impression.
In a month, we were living together.
A year later, Tero was born.
Then everything was over.
I think he fell in love with me -
because he saw in me
a chance to change.
But when Tero was born, he didn't
have the strength to change anymore.
For a few of years, he tried to hang
onto the relationship. Then he left.
The divorce was
actually a relief for me -
but Tero is
a walking fatherlessness.
It hurts more than death.
It's normal to react that way
in a situation like this.
Saying that the joke was tasteless
was an excuse to tell us something.
Maybe it was good that he...
Okay, I'll leave.
- No, you won't.
I'm sorry about that.
I'm really sorry about that. - We'll
all feel bad if you leave now.
I will go to my lonely hotel room
and be sad.
Sit down and stop talking bullshit.
We don't want you to be alone
thinking about things like these.
I'm really sorry.
It's your big day and Christmas.
So much has happened in one day.
- You could have told us right away.
That is exactly what I mean.
If one could always tell...
what is on one's mind.
How did she die?
She committed suicide.
Took some pills.
You are not responsible for it.
- Yes, I am.
Riitta always had such a clear mind.
I don't understand how a person
like her can do something like that.
Tero blames me for it, and Riitta
left a note where she blames me.
How do you undo a thing like this?
- Give it some time.
When did it happen?
- Today.
Give yourself a couple of days
before thinking about it.
I have to leave for Paris tomorrow.
I don't have time to think about it.
I'll just try to breathe
a little bit.
But you know what, guys?
Now we'll start this evening
all over again.
We'll have drinks first.
- I'll sit here, and then you come.
Let's take a couple of steps back.
I wish I could rewind my life.
To avoid this happening again,
let's speak the truth from now on.
No... - We'll speak nothing
but the truth from now on.
Straight, honest talk.
- That's a great idea.
Things tend to build up.
You won't get a new round of drinks
before Matti has sung. Hurry up.
Here I go.
Sing something cheerful.
- Hurry up.
A happy song, please.
This is Matti's choice. - This is not
that happy, but it's from our youth.
Are you ready?
- Yeah, let's go.
One, two, three.
Your empty bed next to me
Reminds me of you
You are gone
And I will not have you
Next to me again
You went into another bed
And started everything
All over again
Even though you knew it would hurt
And destroy all we had
I don't know where to go
I don't know how to go on living
The day is windy
The ice just won't melt
But one day
I will be on my feet again
If I could just try again
And hold my head up high
This one was for the beautiful woman
who just walked in.
Thank you.
- Good job, Matti.
Great performance, Matti.
You got audience.
Would you like to sit with us?
Come and sit with us.
- We'll get you a drink.
Do you speak Finnish?
Please come and join us.
- What?
Come and sit with us. - If you like.
We'd love to have you at our table.
Would you like something to drink?
A glass of water? - No...
Red wine.
I'll get it.
Are you waiting for someone?
- Or...
You got married?
I hope this is okay. Here you are.
Thanks. Or....
Merry Christmas!
- It's nice that you came.
Yes... How nice... Christmas.
This is unbelievable. Where
did you come from? Who are you?
What are you doing here?
Why are you here?
Well...
- Maybe you asked too many questions.
How?
- Yes. I mean, how did you get here?
I walked. I mean...
- It's a beautiful thing you came.
Do you live around here?
Yes.
- Does your family know you are here?
I mean,
does somebody wonder where you are?
Excuse me.
- May I sit with you?
He's just unbelievable.
- Is everything alright?
May I take a photo of you?
I'm a photographer.
Is it okay if I take a picture?
They're laughing.
- They're laughing at me.
He is a professional photographer.
They think they're funny.
You have been photographed before,
haven't you?
Please put your hand on the table.
Yes, that's beautiful.
Thank you.
Please look that way.
Can I ask you one thing?
Smile, please.
Why don't you smile?
If you want,
I'll delete these pictures. - Well.
Thanks.
What an idiot.
That fucking whoremonger! Damn it!
What a charming woman!
- She looks really disturbed.
You think with your cock, or what?
- C'mon.
She could be a Russian whore.
She is crazy, that's for sure.
Not all Russian women are whores.
You should know.
What do you mean by that?
- Nothing.
What did you mean by that?
- I didn't mean anything.
When you said
she was a Russian whore...
Were you talking about my wife?
- No. I didn't mean anything.
Don't blame it on me.
You said it yourself.
You know this isn't that easy
for me. - C'mon. Calm down.
Why did you bring it up?
What's your motive? - That's unfair.
I don't understand you.
I think your behavior is outrageous.
Why can't I photograph this woman
if I find her beautiful?
C'mon.
Everyone can see what you are after.
Why are you so upset?
- I don't understand you.
It's just innocent fun. I wouldn't
exploit a woman like that.
How do you know where it will lead
to? How do you know what she wants?
How do you know you won't hurt her
or somebody else, maybe her husband?
If it leads to something,
I will let it happen.
I won't give a shit about criticism.
This is what I was
talking about earlier.
If I had given love and
looked at another human being -
instead of thinking about fame
and other fucking people -
I would have understood
other human beings better.
If I had loved
another human being.
I could love this person.
I love you, Matti.
You're my friend. - Don't touch me.
I don't understand your way of life.
How can you live like that?
That's quite a broad question. - You
talk from here and act from here.
How is my life any of your business?
Do you even know
how many children you have? - Two.
Are you sure?
- As sure as a man can be.
You call your fuck after nine months
and ask is she is okay? - No. No.
We better not say anything.
It's no use talking
when you are in a state like that.
You're not going anywhere.
Now we'll talk this over.
C'mon. - You always run
when you have to talk.
Let me go, you fucking cop.
- What?
A cop.
- Yes, that's my job.
Don't do this.
We're in no hurry.
- What did I say wrong?
You talk about morals,
but you have none in your life.
You never look back
at what you have done.
What kind of carcasses
have I left behind then? None.
You never looked back.
Why are you talking to me like this?
- I know something about your life.
We're friends, aren't we? Damn it.
- Think about it.
We shouldn't have to think
about that, butthead.
You see children in the yard again
Playing games under your window
You are standing by the window
You can't move
You fly back in years
Every day your memories catch you
Who is going to sing the swan song?
Your eyes reflect
Moments from birth to death
They make some believe in God
Others in the Devil or in anything
But they do not believe
In this world
You once found
The love of the half-century
It was easy to be happy
What do you do with your instincts
When the birds have flown
Out of the nest
Old photos are
The only things you have
You look at them
Over and over again
You might not need my pity
It won't numb your pain
That pain is writing this song
That pain will catch anyone
You see your mourning veil
You lifted your veil five years ago
The swan song made you cry then
It made you cry
You would like to be
like you were then
When you wore your white veil
Are you sick?
- Yes.
You're sick.
- Yeah.
You want me to give you a snow job?
Listen, boy. We promised
we would be honest with each other.
I want to tell you now
that I invited you here -
because I wanted to get so drunk
I could kill you.
I'm fucking going to kill you.
And you know why.
You know exactly
why I'm going to kill you.
What are you talking about?
- You fucking two-timer.
What?
- What have you done to my life?
What are you talking about?
- "What are you talking about?"
Do I have to fucking draw
a picture for you?
What's the matter?
- Do you remember last spring?
Put that away. - No, I won't.
Listen to me carefully.
Remember last spring when
we were at my summerhouse? - Yes.
Remember that I went to bed,
by myself?
After that, my wife got pregnant.
Do I have to count
the months for you?
The thought
hasn't even crossed you mind!
It's not true. - You want to ask
my wife? She told me today.
I could tell right away.
I knew it the next day.
I don't believe you. - You don't?
Do you want to go see the baby?
One thing is certain.
You will never see the baby.
I wouldn't kill you because you've
done something you shouldn't have.
I don't want you to come between
me and my child. She's my child.
I've dreamed of a family
all my life.
I will not let you ruin it.
You understand?
Tell me that you do. - I do.
Good. - I do.
That was my Christmas message.
Go ahead. I was going to do
the same anyway. - What's this?
You know what it is.
- To hell with it.
What's wrong with you?
What is it?
I have received radiotherapy
since spring.
Now it has been discontinued.
I am getting symptomatic treatment.
The radiotherapy
has been discontinued.
I'm dying.
Fuck... - I told you I was ill.
And now I am this far.
I'm sorry.
- You're my friend. I'm really sorry.
You have always been my friend.
I have admired your achievements.
I have envied you because
you always got all the girls.
But now I'm dying. I'm dying.
I got it.
I wouldn't have killed you.
- How could you have killed me?
You'd have been in deep shit and
your child wouldn't have had a...
You said it's your child and
that nobody could come between you.
Nobody will.
Take care of your child.
I will.
I didn't know
you had reached that point.
... Others in the Devil
Or in anything...
I think you just found
a new soulmate.
It's winter.
She needs someone to protect her.
You'll never learn.
I think you'll have a woman
at your deathbed caressing you.
I'll do my best to guarantee that.
Maybe we'll die tonight.
- Not tonight.
And you'll have a woman
by your side.
Yes, I have a woman.
- That's beautiful, too.
You are cold. You should go inside.
Let's not talk about this to anyone.
This will remain between you and me.
I'll go in. See you there.
How does the song end?
- I don't know. Ask him.
Oh, dear, how does the song end?
I'm going to be a father.
That's great.
Yeah, I know.
That's really great.
- It's great.
No more cigars.
That's great.
Matti, I don't want to
talk about it anymore.
Oh, it's you.
I thought...
- No...
I'm sorry.
- For what?
I'm behaving a bit... I haven't
drunk anything in two years.
How do you feel?
- At the moment I feel good.
I stopped taking
my medication today.
Really? I stopped taking mine.
Today. - Today?
Yes. What meds were you taking?
Certral. You know it?
- Yes.
For depression.
It was that bad? How long did you
take them? Where were you?
I ran away so that I could live
without the meds.
How are you feeling?
- Now? A bit strange.
Do you remember Papillon, the film?
A young prisoner comes in,
and an old prisoner asks him, -
"How do I look?"
The young one says,
"You look damn good."
I can say the same to you. How do I
look? By the way, what is your name?
Magdalena.
- How do I look?
You look fine.
- Thanks.
Why did you take photos of me?
- I am a photographer. Really.
This camera is a bit small.
I'm a photographer -
but I'm tired of carrying
all the equipment with me.
Take a photo of me.
I mean...
If there will be no tomorrow, I want
you to photograph me the way I am.
This is me.
You are beautiful.
I don't know
if these are going to be any good.
The medicine has ruined my eyes.
I can't see either.
- Why not?
I mean I can see.
But I only see... fire.
Fire?
- Fire.
Have you...
Have you ever...
Have you ever accidentally
killed your family?
What happened?
I was supposed to
put out the candle -
but I fell asleep.
They were sleeping.
I promised, but I forgot.
I can't see anything else.
Such a small baby.
You have to stay here.
You have to keep on living.
There are so many
beautiful things in life.
There are so many things
worth living for.
Why didn't you want to live anymore?
I have incurable cancer,
and I had decided to leave today.
I don't want my closest people
to see me swollen and bleeding.
Stay a little longer.
Don't go just yet.
We could suffer together, maybe.
Or I don't know...
Oh, you....
- I have to put my coat on.
The Three Wise Men;
Caspar, Melchior and Balthasar -
Baby Jesus, Magdalene and...
Ho, ho, ho!
Oh, my, if it isn't...
Who's been naughty; who's been nice?
We were a bit bad,
but now we're nice.
What about you?
- I've been exceptionally nice.
You've been having a porn Christmas.
- What?
What about you, Santa?
- I've been damn nice. Hold my cane.
That's it. - Through the nose
is the way Santa drinks.
Don't drink it all...
- Drink up!
May I sing?
- Yes, you have to.
Sing us a Christmas song.
- Merry Christmas!
Who did what in the sauna? What?
It must have been Eero
Who did the sauna stove
Who did what in the sauna? What?
Was it you? Or was it me?
Who was it? What?
Who? What? How?
What happened to Eero then?
I think he burned his balls real bad
Who? What? How?
What happened to Eero then?
Was it you? Or was it me?
Who was it? What?
Merry Christmas, everyone!
Who made noise in the sauna? What?
I think it was Erkki
Who screamed so bad
Who made noise in the sauna? What?
Was it you? Or was it me?
Who was it? What?
Great performance!
The sun is rising
There is dew on the grass
It is time to wake up
Get up and go
See my dearest friend
So beautiful is earth
So high is heaven
The birds sing
And the flowers bloom
The waters are shady
So shady
The sun is shining
The wind blows in the woods
It is time for laughter
And play and joy
With my dearest friend
So beautiful is earth
So high is heaven
The birds sing
And the flowers bloom
The waters are shady
So shady
Get up, Santa.
You'll freeze.
The sun is setting
The shadows are growing longer
Santa, we'll call you a cab.
It is time to part
And say goodbye
My dearest friend is gone
So beautiful is earth
So high is heaven
The birds sing
And the flowers bloom
The waters are shady
So shady
DIRECTED, PRODUCED
AND EDITED BY
WRITTEN BY
DIALOGUES
CINEMATOGRAPHY
SOUND DESIGN
Translated by Aretta Vahala
Proofread by Peter Sapiano