(EPISODE 1: THE RIDICULOUS GUYS)
What was that?
- Gosh.
- My back...
No, I was just about to see her face.
Yes, this is Ahn Min Hyuk of Ainsoft.
I warned you.
I told you to get rid of "Albertan Chronicles".
- Or else, you'd end up dead.
- Listen, jerk.
Do you know what time it is?
You should let me sleep for a threat to be effective.
I'd be more scared if I was actually awake.
This is so frustrating.
Don't be surprised at what happens from now.
You asked for it.
Ainsoft will go bankrupt. I'll make that happen.
Gosh, who is that?
(DISQUALIFIED)
I know. I know I didn't make it.
(RESUME, DO BONG SOON)
(COVER LETTER)
Not another cover letter.
My name is Do Bong Soon.
I live in Dobong-dong, Dobong-Gu. I'm Do Bong Soon.
As for me,
I'm very special.
Does that sound wrong?
(RECORDINGS OF SECRETS IN BONG SOON'S MATERNAL ANCESTRAL LINE)
I have a secret...
that makes me unique from others.
(BONG SOON'S FIRST BIRTHDAY, 1992)
I'm strong. And not just strong, I'm really strong.
The progenitor of this secret gene...
came down from my ancestor Park Gae Boon...
who attacked the enemy by throwing rocks...
during the Siege of Haengju.
This extraordinary power that's handed down...
in my maternal line has a veiled secret.
It was during 1862's rebellion of Jinju peasants and slaves.
An ancestor named Ga Wook Bang...
used her power on the side of the officials...
and hurt the innocent people.
When she looked only after her selfish desires,
she lost her power overnight.
In her last days, she suffered leprosy in solitary.
Ever since then, my ancestors realized that if the power...
was used for something immoral, they would have to pay the price.
However,
my mother Hwang Jin Yi completely ignored the jinx.
Her fanaticism led to a problem.
There wasn't a problem using her power to boost national prestige.
However...
Thank you.
Bring it. Give it to me. You, jump.
Kneel, you punk. I told you to kneel.
What?
It was true. If you used your powers...
for something unjust,
you have to pay the price.
A rising Greco-Roman wrestler Do Chil Goo...
and the now powerless weightlifter Hwang Jin Yi...
What happened to your face?
- I'm fine.
- Hey...
They ended up...
setting things on fire that day.
Hey, you jerk.
Push.
Your princess came out first out of your twins.
Is the boy not out yet?
Look. She has a fist.
My goodness.
That's how I was born.
(MY NAME IS...)
(STRONG GIRL BONG SOON)
There were many times I was frustrated...
while hiding my power.
I must ignore such dirty hands.
For 27 years, I had to fight with myself.
If I could help it, I tried to ignore it.
This station is Dobong. Dobong Station.
The doors are on your left.
I didn't want to become a spectacle.
I had to hide my power.
For intentional death or suicide, insurance payment could be delayed.
No, Sir. I'm not particularly talking about you.
I've tried all kinds of jobs after graduating high school.
Hello, handsome. You look so brave.
She's a girl.
I even tried farming.
After 10 years, only farmers will survive.
We'll run out of gas, and that will limit our movements.
At that point, we'll have to become self-sufficient.
Bong Soon, put your power to good use.
You should farm. Farm.
Do you know how great farmers are?
With Bong Gi going to medical school,
Uncle left the city to make money from farming.
Mom insisted on closing the walnut bakery and switching to farming.
She first sent me to Uncle's as an envoy.
Oh, dear!
Look at her, Grandma.
Our plan to return to farming has failed.
By the merest chance, I stumbled upon a job that was right for me.
In the real world, I have to conceal my power.
In this world, I was able to meet another side of me.
My dream is to develop a game in which the main character is...
based on myself.
Oh, yes!
That was easy.
The success of role playing games...
depend on the constant supply of contents the users can enjoy.
That's how "Albertan Chronicles" became successful.
It endlessly reveals the world the users can experience catharsis in.
There's no room for boredom.
The CEO of the company only goes to work twice a week.
For the remaining days, all he does is play.
What a life, don't you think?
I wish you the best of luck, my students.
Hey! Stop right there.
Hey!
You'd better stop there!
You will be dead when I catch you.
Darn it.
I need a personal bodyguard.
Recruit one immediately.
I had a feeling something was bound to happen...
and it did.
(BUD KINDERGARTEN)
What is wrong with my age?
Age is a number when in love.
Excuse me!
No one's here.
What kind of a jerk parks a truck like this?
Who would...
What do you want?
Is this your truck?
No. It's lunch time.
How can I pass through when you're blocking the road like this?
You old man. You can't pass through here.
How can you decide that for yourself?
This isn't your property.
Hey, just go back when I tell you nicely.
If you keep talking back to me, you might get good a beating.
What are you doing?
Goodness. My phone!
I gave you a chance to get out, old man.
You just blew your chance.
- I told you to leave.
- It hurts.
"It hurts"? So what?
Does it hurt?
What?
What are you going to do about it?
Hey, you. Get over here. Quickly.
Let's go. Hey, let's go.
Jerk.
Hello. I would like to file a report.
This is Dobong-dong...
- What are you doing? Give it back.
- Hold it.
Why do women take pictures of food?
My, my.
- Is this your boyfriend?
- Why are you looking...
through my phone? Give it back.
You must have lost your senses.
Who said you could call the cops? Do you want to die?
I see. Are you a law-abiding citizen or something?
Then I'm a law-abiding thug.
You started to beat up that poor old man.
Are you the old man?
Are you the one who got beaten up?
Gosh. He looks like a loser.
Go away.
Gosh.
My screen got cracked.
Hey. You have to pay for my phone.
Goodness.
I still have three years left on my contract.
It's been only three months.
I am asking you for the last time.
- Please pay for this.
- My goodness.
How can kids these days be so fearless?
Should I rip you into pieces like a rag and hang you on the clothesline?
Look how tiny you are.
- What is going on?
- You're such a small target.
I can finish you in a second.
- Don't hit me.
- What's the police doing?
- I'll kill you.
- Spare me.
This is why I don't like the police.
Don't hit me.
What are we going to do?
Your face is so small like a CD.
Lower your eyes.
Lower them. I told you to lower them.
Hello?
I am at a construction site for redevelopment in Dobong-dong.
I need some police officers and the police squad here.
There are a lot of people here.
A woman and an old man are being threatened by thugs.
Even if I can't use my strength again...
and the plague engulfs my body,
I can't let this man slide.
- What on earth is the police doing?
- Oh, wow.
- What happened?
- Boss. Boss!
She did it.
What was that?
Darn it.
What is happening?
- Boss, Boss!
- Hey, you.
You have to pay for my phone.
- Who on earth are you?
- Don't fight her.
You should know if you're a social person.
We save all the numbers on our cellphones.
- It will be so uncomfortable...
- Don't do it.
- If my phone stays as it is now.
- She's crazy.
You must be out of your mind.
Hey.
My hand... It got folded.
I'm sorry. Oh, my.
- What should I do?
- Don't fold it.
- I didn't mean this to happen.
- Don't do it!
My goodness. I'm sorry.
Sorry.
You shouldn't have tried to hit me.
Why you...
Come on. Pay for my phone.
Let go of my...
Who... Who is she?
I got you now.
What is this?
Sorry about that.
- No way.
- She's so cool.
Here. Over here.
- Get him out.
- Help.
- Help me out.
- Get him.
Help him out.
Should I call an ambulance?
No, a girl hit me.
She threw me.
- I'm serious.
- I got hit here.
That's not right.
(SERIOUS CRIMES UNIT THREE)
What do I do?
Gook Doo's going to think it's strange. What do I say?
What do I do...
Hello, Gook Doo.
My gosh, Gook Doo. It's been a while.
You're hard at work, aren't you?
What should I say?
What's wrong with her?
- I'm telling you the truth!
- I almost died.
Calm down and sit.
I'm not joking.
Do Bong Soon.
My gosh, it's her.
That... That's her.
- It was her.
- It's her.
Who did that to you again?
Detective, kids can't lie.
Why won't you believe...
- Name?
- What they say?
- Do...
- Do Bong Soon. Address?
1342, Dobong-dong, Dobong-Gu.
You're saying they took over the road...
and restricted traffic?
The driver Jeong Sun Ho asked them to clear the way,
but they declined and used force.
At the time, the witness Do Bong Soon...
who was trying to report the situation...
You got into a conflict while trying to report,
and Do Bong Soon hit Kim Gwang Bok's face.
His cheek sunk in,
and four of his teeth fell out, resulting in a serious injury.
She's not a joke. If she throws us, we'd fly.
Meanwhile, Hwang Hyun Dong who saw what happened to Kim...
came to resort the issue,
but ended up with five fractured fingers.
When Oh Jin Pyo and Yang Yong Chul came afterwards,
they were thrown 30m into the back of a truck full with sand.
They each received fractures on their neck and their legs.
Chan Young Nam who came to retaliate...
ran into Kim Gang Bok and fell.
Kim flew over 10m...
and hit a truck and fell to the ground.
Does this make sense to you?
Well, the thing is...
According to the current law, young children do not have legal force.
Also, their testimonies do not make any sense.
The problem is,
this is what the driver testified.
If this is true, section 750 of the Civil Act say...
that this is an intentional act of violence. You'll be punished.
If there isn't a testimony from the reporter...
Do you call that a report? It sounds like a martial arts novel.
Who's that?
Korean police are hopeless.
How dare you take your salary after writing such a report?
Who is he?
I reported the incident, and I'm a witness.
What is this? Really?
Guys, you shouldn't lie at the police station.
Do you really think she beat all these men?
- All by herself?
- Yes!
- I told you, it's true.
- Kids don't lie.
Did you watch "The Avengers" at daycare today?
What are your teachers teaching you?
They call it audio-visual education and just play movies.
Their daycare needs to go through a thorough investigation.
Did you report this case?
Yes. I reported it, and I'm also the witness.
However, my testimony is different from what the driver said.
He was a part of the incident. He's a victim.
He was probably not himself.
How was it like, you ask?
What should I say...
Should I say it was five minutes before the world turned into a mess?
A false testimony is not a punishable act,
but if the victim requests a civil suit, you'll be called to court.
Then it'll be seen as perjury and you'll be punished.
Then explain to me how those men got injured.
Look at me. Say it while looking at me.
Them?
I saw them fighting each other.
Be quiet!
- Sit back down.
- Sit down.
Sit down, sit down.
No.
That girl beat all of them on her own.
Kids.
Can you read this?
See?
There is no time for kids to learn Korean.
Why, do you ask? All they do is watch movies.
Education starts from daycare, but look where they're at.
A single girl beat seven men?
She doesn't even have a weapon. It doesn't make sense.
- Why doesn't it?
- No.
Hollywood is ruining too many of us.
Guys. What should I do for you?
Should I just throw you behind bars for self-inflicted injury?
- Why would you do that?
- She did beat us.
- Who beat you?
- Who beat us, then?
Who broke his leg?
Who fractured his neck?
Who did that?
Hey, just wrap it up.
If we report this, the higher-ups will fire me.
To be frank,
does it make sense...
for seven men to get broken bones by one girl?
- Hey.
- It's true.
Why are you making this ridiculous incident a case?
They hurt a driver, and tried to blame it on an innocent person.
We must perform an investigation. They even have criminal records.
- Sit down.
- That's not fair.
Sit down. Just sit down.
- You're the best.
- You're so awesome.
- You're awesome.
- You're the best.
Who did this to us, then?
- You're so awesome.
- You're the best.
Are you happy?
If you don't want to get involved with that kind of people,
find yourself a job instead of wasting time at home.
Sir.
What happened? Why are you at the station?
I've never seen such a thing in my life.
Excuse me.
Shouldn't you thank me?
Why did you lie to the police?
What is this?
I helped you from getting charged.
You won't thank me or apologize to me?
- What is this?
- Why did you bother?
If you're a man,
be like one.
Don't just watch while a woman takes charge.
You should be ashamed of yourself.
What's with her?
She's really strange.
She's so hot.
Pardon?
She was the most unique person I've ever seen.
How unique?
She was... Ms. Seo. I really liked your project.
Thank you, Sir. I'll work harder.
Please do. You can do it!
Well, I mean...
The encounter was more thrilling than any other computer game.
- Encounter with whom?
- With that girl.
(DOBONG WALNUT BAKERY)
Please enjoy.
- Goodbye.
- Thank you.
- Hello.
- Thank you for coming.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
Hello.
Did you sell a lot?
Is this all?
If I find any money on you, I will hit you for each bill I find.
There you go. You should've started with this.
Let's not be petty. Okay?
You are a man, aren't you?
- I will try.
- Give me a cup of coffee.
I'm back.
Why are you so late?
I had my reasons.
Reasons? What reasons? You don't have a job.
You went to the internet cafe, didn't you?
I am embarrassed to face Myung Soo's mother.
Goodness. What am I going to do with you?
I knew three million young adults were unemployed,
but I never guessed you would be one of them.
Hey, you should just get married.
Get a rich guy who is dumb enough to marry you. Got it?
Whatever.
Officer, take a look at this.
- Lieutenant In.
- Yes?
How do you and the Avengers lady know each other?
We went to the same elementary, middle, and high school.
That's right. You are from Dobong-dong.
Look at this. The witness from before...
I did a background check on him and he's the CEO of Ainsoft.
What kind of a company is Ainsoft?
You don't know about Ainsoft?
It's the company that created the game, "Albertan Chronicles".
Ahn Min Hyuk's a son of Ahn Chool Do, the chairman of Osung Group.
I knew it. He was too arrogant.
By the way, where are Kim Gwang Bok and Hwang Hyun Dong?
- Are they still in the hospital?
- Yes.
Hey, did you find out about her or not?
Well...
I am about to die.
You have to find her.
This is too embarrassing.
Boss. She was no joke.
She was the strongest person that I've ever gone up against.
- Shut it.
- Sorry, Sir.
Hey, what is her name?
- Do Bong Soon.
Do Bong Soon!
- Calm down.
- Do Bong Soon!
Look at the fractures.
I've been an orthopedist for 10 years.
- I haven't seen anything like this.
- The bones...
were bent all the way and returned to their places.
This has to be done by a person who possesses a mysterious ability.
Look at the arm. The bones were completely twisted.
In the medical community, some say...
we should research about the dynamics between...
the bones and the muscles under force.
This could be a revolutionary research. Revolution.
By the way, this patient lost four teeth from a single punch.
Professor Shin, how should we interpret this?
He was crying, saying it was a woman's doing.
Should we treat him with the Department of Psychiatry?
Psychiatry?
I will give Professor Kim a call.
Here it is.
(1997, DO BONG SOON AND DO BONG GI GET ABDUCTED.)
Mister. My brother is peeing.
Darn it. You will ruin the car seat.
- Please don't kill us.
- Shut it!
Bong Gi.
Don't cry.
You, two. You want to go back to your parents, right?
Then, be quiet. If you keep crying,
you will make me very angry.
Mister. My brother is crying. Please stop the car.
If you cry and pee again,
I'll kill you with my own hands.
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by VIU
Get back here!
Come here.
You little brats.
Run. Hurry.
Bong Soon.
You completely crushed them.
They started it.
Don't you dare tell Mom.
I wonder what will happen.
By the way, are you going to be okay tomorrow morning?
You remember the curse, right? The abduction didn't count...
because the kidnapper was a scumbag. But this time...
So were they. They were scumbags, too.
Get studying.
Goodness. I am so relieved.
What a relief.
I'm just fine!
All right. Yes!
Good morning, guys.
Good morning.
(RESUME)
(KEY SKILLS AND CREDENTIALS)
A taekwondo master with a 4th degree in judo and 5th degree in hapkido.
(AWARDS)
"Second place in the 2014 Pan Korean Jiu-jitsu Tournament".
"Worked in Squad Three of the security office at the Blue House".
That girl. Find out who she is.
The girl we saw at the police station.
Yes, her.
The girl you're thinking of right now. Got it?
I mean...
Article 60 of the Public Officials Act states that police officers...
must keep all sensitive information confidential even after tenure.
- I'm just...
- Please leave.
I absolutely cannot disclose anyone's personal information.
Apparently, personal information cannot be disclosed.
The police officer was unflinching.
What's his name?
- His name is In Gook Doo.
- In Gook Doo?
The door is open. Come in!
Hey, are you ready?
You heard about what I like, right?
Show me!
Hey, stop.
I said stop!
Who are you?
Wait! Gosh! No, please...
You have the right to remain silent,
and have the right to an attorney.
Hey, are you a cop?
You rat. Do you have a warrant?
I'll request a warrant within 24 hours of your arrest.
Since you might flee, I'll have to arrest you first.
- You punk. Are you a guy?
- Yes.
Do you know whom you're dealing with here?
Mister, do I have to know that?
Article 61 of the Public Officials Act clearly states...
that all officials cannot give or receive gifts, money...
or any other incentives...
in dealings with any persons in regards to their duties.
I've been taught that everyone is equal in the eyes of the law.
He just happens to be a congressman. Why is that my fault?
Lieutenant In, know your place.
If you keep this up, you might end up...
losing everything in one blow.
Bring it on, then!
My deepest apologies.
Yes, Sir!
What a lunatic!
The higher-ups are losing it right now.
Well, he's not all there.
He used to be known for being peculiar in the academy.
That's what I heard.
That punk. Let's suffocate him with car exhaust fumes.
Send him to the traffic team!
Well, that would attract too much attention.
Then demote him to your worst-performing team!
Lower your head. You're blocking my view.
All of them will die before they even get there.
Anyhow, we should try to tackle things step by step from now on.
Hello, I've been transferred to your team. I'm In Gook Doo.
You can't even get through to that lunatic. He gives me a headache.
It sounds like he's a true police officer.
What?
By the way, why do you need her number?
She's my type.
Oh, was it for your love life?
So to speak.
- How is Chairman Ahn doing?
- Great, thanks to you.
You've been helping my dad in many aspects all his life.
I must say,
I'm very proud of you for achieving this much without your dad's help.
But you know what? There's a limit to what you can achieve...
without utilizing his connections.
Shall I just do physical labour for the rest of my life?
The hourly wage for construction labour is high. It's nothing bad.
Bong Soon, stop eating. Let Bong Gi have some, too.
Also, I misused my strength...
and met with the worst mishap. Shouldn't you know better?
I ended up marrying this man.
What's up?
Gosh.
Hello?
Yes, this is Do Bong Soon. Who is this?
So you're not working at the moment, right?
In professional terms, I'm a job seeker.
I'm not bumming around.
Oh, I see.
Anyway, my boss saw you that day...
and was very impressed. That's why he made such a bold decision.
Gosh, how much more pathetic can he get?
- Pardon me?
- If he has something to say to me,
he can meet me himself. Why did he send you?
I mean, you look much older than him.
Well... You can think of this as a preliminary job interview.
I see. A preliminary job interview?
- Yes.
- Got it.
So you're asking me...
to work as a bodyguard for your boss or whoever that guy is, right?
Yes. We'll be sure to pay you a top-notch salary.
Sir, I've worked all kinds of jobs since graduating high school.
I can tell which companies are scams...
and which ones are about to go under or work me like a dog.
Also, I don't want a physical job.
I'd like a job where I can use my brain. That's my outlook on career.
I'm not sure why you're giving me this offer,
but I know exactly what I want to do...
and for which company I want to work.
If you don't mind, may I ask you what kind of job it is?
It's none of your business.
I'm so sorry to say no when you came all the way here.
Have a safe journey back.
60,000 dollars a year.
Plus incentives.
Mister, by any chance...
Is it actually for some sort of an adult entertainment establishment?
Why are you offering me such a hefty salary?
What do you even know about me?
- Does that guy like me?
- No, no.
Come to think of it, how did you get my number?
- Am I being stalked?
- Gosh, no.
- Also...
- That's not what it is.
I'm wondering why he's not hiring a male bodyguard.
Why does it have to be a girl? That's the weirdest part.
It is very strange indeed.
- Lend me your ear for a second.
- My ear?
- Why do you need my ear? My gosh.
- There are...
Gosh, that doesn't even make any sense.
What's the name of the company?
It's called Ainsoft.
Sorry? What did you say?
Have you heard of it? It's Ainsoft.
Ainsoft...
Mister.
When can I meet your boss?
- Thank you.
- Here you go.
I hope you enjoy it.
Thank you.
I already put sugar in it.
So we should...
call the district office and the city hall...
a dozen times a day to let them know we're against the redevelopment.
How about one of you just buzz your hair off?
- You should do it.
- Come on.
Protesting by buzzing your hair won't get through to them.
Just let the official correspondence pile up...
and go head-to-head with the person in charge.
But actually, I'm all for redevelopment.
Laundromat Alley is a terrifying place to be after 10pm.
You're right. Something has to be done about that place.
There are so many unsavoury hoodlums going about town these days.
Oh, my. Gook Doo's mom is here.
- Hello.
- Hello there.
Welcome.
Did you see her wave her hair like a young woman?
I'll take 4 egg tarts and 2 pecan pies, please.
"Two pecan pies, please."
By the way,
I enjoyed your novel,
"Furtive Hormones of the Night".
Oh, dear. Was it to your liking?
Yes, I finished it within a day.
I've never thumbed through a book...
so fast in my life. I couldn't stop.
That's right. I heard that Gook Doo ran into...
Bong Soon at the police station.
- Pardon?
- The police station?
There you go.
Bong Soon!
- Bong Soon.
- Let's eat.
Get over here.
- What's with you?
- You!
Why were you at the police station?
How did you know about that, Mom?
Gook Doo works at the police station. Of course I'd know.
You troublemaker, why would you go there?
It just happened that way.
Did you beat someone? Did you? Did you?
Listen, Mom. So you see...
Are you crazy? Didn't you hear about my mother?
She beat a man at the marketplace and suffered from diarrhea...
for a month and then got haemorrhoids. How about me?
Mom, I'm fine.
To be honest, I had a lot of similar incidents.
But I'm fine.
- What?
- Mom?
I must be a mutant.
Also, I got hired.
Now, I can let my talent shine.
Bong Soon, I'm hungry.
Oh, Bong Gi is here.
- What are you doing?
- Hey there.
- Are you all right?
- Gosh.
I got too excited for a second. I'm sorry.
Let's go inside.
Mom, taste it.
Of course.
- Thank you for the meal.
That looks good.
- It's delicious.
- It's good, right?
It's good.
- Hello.
- It's me.
Yes, I know.
I looked into the assault suspects at the redevelopment site.
They're rotten to the core. Don't travel late at night.
Also, carry around a taser.
There is a surplus, so I'll take you one after work.
- All right.
- I'm hanging up.
Gook Doo, I think I got a job.
See you.
What a jerk.
I know he's really rude,
but I still like him so much.
There she goes again.
Shouldn't we add some laver flakes?
Good idea.
Come in.
Hello.
Welcome.
The ceiling won't be collapsing, so take a seat.
All right.
- Did you bring your resume?
- Yes.
(RESUME)
Have you interviewed for our company before?
Yes, I have.
(QUALIFICATIONS)
What's this? You plan on getting hired with these qualifications?
You're brave.
I applied because it said gender, educational background, and age...
aren't primary factors here.
You're brave. That's for certain.
"Dobong-dong, Dobong-Gu, Do Bong Soon".
Did you move there to match your name with your address?
Then shouldn't everyone in every...
neighborhood share the same name?
I'm sorry. That was a very unfunny joke.
- It was very old-fashioned.
- Got it.
Why did you want to work here?
Because it's a good company.
- Welcome aboard.
- Thank you.
But you must be disappointed it's not the Strategy Department.
A bit.
There's something I'm curious about.
You seem perfectly healthy,
but why are you in need of a bodyguard?
I have enemies everywhere.
But don't be mistaken, I'm not a criminal.
Sure, of course. What is the company's incentives...
and pension policy?
It's commensurate with your performance.
We need to know how good you are.
Is there a company dining hall?
- Yes.
- Are there menstrual leaves?
Not at the moment.
That's a pretty poor standard.
The nature of a bodyguard's profession allows for no holidays.
Fine. Then are there stop motions?
What are "stop motions"?
Are you unfamiliar with the term?
Do you mean "stock options"?
Oh, yes. That.
We'll think about how to award stock options...
for your particular line of work.
How disappointing.
Then may I take a look at the contract?
- Let's arm wrestle.
- Excuse me?
I need to see how good you are.
This is your entrance assessment exam. Let's go.
Come on, then.
Arm wrestling?
Give it a shot.
You go.
My goodness.
You can add the other hand if you like.
This is ridiculous.
Don't get humiliated because you lost to a woman.
I'm kind of special.
I'd appreciate it if you don't tell anyone about this.
Mr. Gong, please bring in the contract.
Take a seat, please.
(EMPLOYMENT CONTRACT)
60,000 dollars?
- You can write your name down here.
- Okay.
(DO BONG SOON)
When is my first day?
Do you have strong legs as well, too?
Excuse me?
Mr. Gong, try chicken fighting.
With whom? With her, Sir?
- Yes.
- Goodness.
Come on, Sir. I'm an ex-marine.
That's not exactly a fair match.
Just try it.
Stop joking around around, Sir.
Mr. Gong, if you win,
I'll give you my car.
Contenders, please step in.
All right. Ready...
Hold on a moment. Can he put on a helmet?
- What did you say?
- You might hurt your head.
You should probably wear one.
A helmet?
Then let's order jjajangmyeon.
Three bowls of jjajangmyeon, please.
- Enjoy your meal.
- Excuse me. We need your helmet.
- Come again?
- Give me your helmet.
Please, I insist.
That's for the helmet and the meal.
- Thank you. Enjoy!
- Have a good one.
Don't push it, Sir.
Let's hurry before the noodles get soggy.
Hurry.
Gosh, I can't believe I'm really doing this.
This is a disgrace to my ancestors.
You're really going to give me the car, right?
It'll be yours right away.
On a count of three, get started.
Understood, Sir.
In 1, 2, 3...
- You're not dead, right?
- Are you all right?
Oh, thank the divine. You're alive.
- Excuse me...
- Are you all right?
- Come again?
- I'll speak casually now.
I can't be using honorific to my bodyguard.
Sure.
Carry on.
I want to know my exact responsibilities.
Your main responsibility?
It will be to protect me. You must make me unassailable.
I have a favor to ask.
- What is it?
- If by any chance...
I do a stellar job,
may I transfer to the Strategy Department?
I don't know.
I'm not sure about your abilities in that line of work.
The only proven ability I've been able to see...
is your strength.
Well, I'm just asking for a small chance.
Sure, then. I'll give it to you.
But for now, protect me well.
- Understand?
- Yes, Sir.
Tidy things up before you go.
- Report in by 6am tomorrow.
- Yes, Sir.
Since Mr. Gong is injured,
- you'll have to mind the office.
- All right.
- I'll get going.
- See you tomorrow.
Sure.
Gosh, how can he be so informal from the get-go?
I can't believe that jerk is the CEO. What a shame.
Gosh, but at least I got hired.
Fine. I'll give him a shot.
But he's such a jerk.
I'm going to let it slide because of the high salary.
I'll consider myself duly compensated...
for the informality.
It got all soggy.
Why did he make me do that?
"Bodyguard".
(BODYGUARD)
Come outside real quick. I'm out front.
Gook Doo.
Here.
Is this for me? I'll use it well. Thank you.
What do you mean? You shouldn't have to use it.
Don't ever put yourself in a position to need it.
This doesn't require a possession permit.
Don't expect a big voltage. It's meant for self-defence.
- Head back in now.
- You're leaving already?
It's late. Go inside.
Hey, Gook Doo. How is everything going with your girlfriend?
Hi, Hee Ji.
- Is practice over?
- Oh, it's her.
Did you eat? Go back inside.
See you.
Bye, Gook Doo.
Have a good night. Thanks for this.
We have a casualty.
Everyone, attention!
During last night's meeting,
a homicide occurred in our jurisdiction.
- What? A homicide, Sir?
- What was that?
- Where?
- Dobong-dong!
What on earth is going on?
Look at the blood.
- It's blood.
- How could this have happened?
- This area used to be safe.
- Tell me about it.
- Oh, no.
- Where are you going?
- How can this be?
- It happened there.
Hey. Oh, gosh.
Did... Did someone die?
- I said I'm surrounded by enemies.
- Gosh, you startled me.
What is that?
I'm not sure. What could it be?
Well, it's one reason why I hired you.
In the IT world, even the threats are digital.
Funny, right?
Recently, I've been getting stalked and blackmailed.
- By whom?
- If I knew, they'd be detained.
- Then report to the police.
- I don't trust the police.
I will catch them.
- Help me.
- What?
Didn't you say you like games? It'll be thrilling.
Why don't we try catching them like a game? It'll be fun.
You said you wanted to join the Strategy Department, so try it.
We must win.
Is this a joke, Sir?
Life is a game, and the biggest game is life.
There is nothing be serious about.
What do you think? Doesn't it sound like a plan?
If we catch them, you'll get your transfer.
Your career opportunities will be guaranteed.
What do you say? Are you in?
Last night, at a local Dobong-dong intersection,
- I'm in.
- A homicide incident occurred.
The victim is a young 31-year-old female.
An unfortunate detail is that her wedding was approaching...
in two months time.
Currently, there are no suspects and no surveillance footage available.
The lack of any reliable secondary footage...
is hindering police investigations.
The victim was an editor at a local library.
She was on her way home after working late...
(UNKNOWN CALLER)
Do not ignore this warning.
Wait and see what unfolds.
Synced & ripped by bozxphd
Subtitles by VIU
(STRONG GIRL BONG SOON)
Someone must be observing us from around here somewhere.
I can't be sure. There might be an explosive.
- You want me to die?
- Then should I die?
I wonder if there's a crazy, rich guy just for her.
Let's just sleep at my house.
- How do I look?
- It's so perfect.
You like that officer, don't you?
She was totally my type.
- He's gay.
- That's all right.
Nobody is perfect these days.
There was another victim.
Save me, please.
How dare you come in here?
The culprit has appeared. We need to lock the place down.
I heard the culprit's voice.
He appeared not long after I left the scene.
Call an ambulance, now!
He saw Bong Soon's face.
I might have super strength, but it's useless right now.
Bong Soon, stay with me tonight.
My friend Bong Soon is a helpless girl. Let's go.
Leave her be.