Nice and warm.
Watch your feet!
Twice.
Sleep well.
Pleasant dreams.
Eyes shut.
You'll get the white.
Not your turn!
Go to the sacristy tomorrow.
Ask them to say a mass.
- For whom?
- For my purposes.
But don't tell a soul. Don't tell Dad.
l'm to say, ''Here's a coin.''
l want a mass said
for Thérèse's special purposes.
- Not very serious!
- lt's a secret.
Go on.
Between a mean man and me.
Tell, or l'll pinch you.
lt's for a killer.
- Know him?
- No. lt's Pranzini.
That monster! He did 3 women in!
He's too proud to beg for forgiveness.
He cut a child's throat.
l'll save him before they cut his.
A mass for...
lmpossible!
l'm not asking him for much.
Just a little remorse. To console me.
What do l tell the priest?
Let me. lt's my business.
Go to sleep.
What are you doing?
Come see.
At the guillotine,
Pranzini pushed away the executioner.
''Leave me,'' he said.
He rejected the priest...
but kissed the crucifix.
He died at 5:02 this morning.
He kissed it!
He's saved!
l saved him! l won!
Oh, Terry, my pet...
What a gift you have!
l'm so thirsty.
Haven't had a drop all day.
My throat's on fire.
Slowly!
- Was that also for his sake?
- lt wasn't hard.
- l bet Mom's watching.
- She'll be glad.
Put it back.
l see my Pranzini in his cell.
Dawn. Door opens slowly.
''Come, sir. Time to lose your head!''
Hush, Terry!
l wish l'd been with him, held his hand.
Put it back.
Why shouldn't we read it?
Thank you, Jesus.
Anything wrong?
Not at all.
When Pauline and Marie
became Carmelites...
how did you feel?
- Want to know?
- Yes.
Giving 2 daughters away is an honor.
- And?
- Not really a pleasure.
But l'm proud of them.
Be proud of me, too.
l'm in love with Jesus, l'll marry him.
Bored with me here?
He chose me with his arms open.
Dreams.
He's courting me, what can l do?
l want to pray, save a lot of people for him.
So young, so fragile. You'll be turned down.
You know nothing.
But he knows. He'll teach me.
l knew you'd be sad.
You're my king, too. Nothing's changed.
We'll never be apart.
- What's with her?
- She has a cold.
- And Dad?
- So-so. Better.
- And you?
- Something is wrong, Terry.
l hardly sleep or eat. l'm not all there.
Don't worry, kid. We'll help you. Be patient.
l don't want to wait, or be unfaithful.
Honeybunch...
no one is asking you to do so.
And don't say ''l want.''
lf ever l was, l'd be disappointed.
Quit worrying. You'll never meet the boy
who could satisfy you.
He doesn't exist.
- Eat sweets, enjoy yourself.
- Have fun.
Go to Paris with Dad.
And risk a broken leg before l'm here?
l have a friend, can't say who...
who fears dying before knowing love.
That's Clothilde!
The way she looks at men!
l plucked it for you.
Last one from the garden.
Teresita,
l doubt you'll be joining us that soon.
My hands are tied. Men decide.
l know this town,
l don't need such a scandal...
about Thérèse entering Carmel.
Again people will say,
and l've heard them say it:
''ltchy Martin! He likes to travel.
''So he's getting rid of his daughters.''
That's horrible.
That's how it is. The world is vile.
l won't say yes for 3 years.
l'll die before.
You're too young to endure such hardships.
Carmel is tough.
You should know.
- l'll move mountains.
- The mother superior agrees.
Why push me? There's no fire.
Go see the bishop if you wish.
My answer, however, is no.
Definitely no.
End of discussion. l'm not mean...
but l'm responsible for the convent.
l must protect it.
Strange.
Both father and daughter in such a hurry.
l can sum it up in 2 words:
patience and hope.
Months go fast, days are like hours.
Why does Jesus make me
desire something...
and refuse it to me?
lt is to test you, to strengthen your calling.
Test me?
Why test me if l can't bear it?
l must tell you the truth.
On our way here, Thérèse told me...
that if you refuse, she will ask the pope.
We'll apply for the next pilgrimage to Rome.
Forget everybody around you.
Got it pat?
Yes. ''Your Holiness, l have a big favor.''
All l want is a yes. l hope he says it.
You are next. Don't speak to his Holiness.
He is ill.
l have a favor to ask you.
Please let me enter Carmel.
This very young girl wishes to enter Carmel.
lt is being taken care of.
You must obey your superiors, my child.
Say yes and everyone will agree!
You'll go, if heaven wishes.
Say yes, your Holiness!
Say yes!
Tell father that everyone...
thoroughly enjoyed his pear tarts.
The crust was crunchy. Just as l like it.
Lost your tongue?
My one visit a week, l save it for you,
and what do l get, a wall.
Quit sulking or l'll pull the curtain.
l warned you...
Stop!
lt's scary.
lf we weren't sisters,
we'd have to talk like this.
- Open.
- lf you smile.
Open or l'll go!
Blackmail doesn't work here!
The cardinal wrote to Mother Superior.
He entrusts her with the decision.
No explanation.
Now you tell me?
How wonderful!
l'm not going to cry, l promise!
lt's very cold, we have no heat.
We're fasting till Easter. You're growing up.
l suggested you join us in the spring.
Spring?
l want you to make it.
Let's place all the odds on your side.
ls that so! What does Marie think?
We're not keeping you out
of our husband's house.
But you could knock some more.
l have knocked, Pauline, l have.
Keep knocking. Suffering is the key.
Not love?
You're engaged.
Come on, wait a bit for the wedding.
You want it all at once.
- Yes! l must act quickly.
- Why?
Let's not talk about me.
Don't go catch cold now.
No chance.
You're adorable.
Go back to bed. l'm better.
lt's over.
Lord, your love is ferocious.
l'm frightened. Hold me.
What if l'm wrong?
Hold me tight!
l'll never be able to leave you.
Come back, Sebastian. l love you.
- For me?
- Yes.
- lt's too small.
- lt won't fit?
l can't.
lt doesn't fit?
l wanted to give you a present. But what?
So here's my pencil box.
Of course, Bernard's name is on it.
You'll think of me?
- You'll write?
- Yes.
What'll l do without you?
You'll come too.
Don't talk nonsense.
He'll come for you.
And Sebastian?
He'll love you more. He'll never betray you.
- And my jam?
- Let's see...
Push!
You'll have to bring it.
You desire?
His mercy.
The poverty of the Order
and company of the sisters.
Are you determined to persevere?
l wish and hope to do so...
with His mercy
and the prayers of the sisters.
l'm not worthy for you to come in.
But say a word and l'll be cured.
The body of Christ.
l too wanted to be a bride.
l'm happy for you.
Thanks for coming from so far.
Take on the slight burden of Jesus.
Those who follow the pure lamb...
will be part of his sparkling white escort.
My beloved speaks.
He says, ''Come, my beloved, come.''
Winter is over. The rain has stopped.
How l've longed for this day!
l'll give my life for you.
l'll be yours forever.
l am not perfect...
help me to do good, to help others...
to please you.
l wish l were already up there, to see you.
Jesus was greeted by the waiting crowd.
A woman there had been bleeding
for 1 2 years.
She'd spent all her money
but no doctor could cure her.
She touched Jesus' garments.
She stopped bleeding instantly.
Jesus said, ''Who touched me?''
Peter and his friends said:
You're in a crowd,
and you wonder who touched you?
Jesus said, ''Someone touched me.''
l felt a force leave me.
The woman threw herself at his feet
and told him publicly...
how touching him had cured her.
Jesus said:
''Your faith saved you. Go in peace.''
Lie on the floor outside the refectory.
Yes, Mother.
Passing by me...
he said it was time for me to be loved.
Washed me with perfumes...
gave me lace to wear.
He fed me the purest flour
and honey in abundance.
l became beautiful in his eyes.
He made me a powerful queen.
That was my husband.
My husband.
l hardly knew him. He sold wood.
His horse threw him one day.
Smashed his head.
l've had it on the sly for 50 years.
l've known many Mothers Superior...
never could confess it.
Take it.
Ask our Mother to keep it.
You're silent, you obey the rules.
That's good.
At my age, not talking all day...
is hard.
Now give me a kiss.
A real kiss.
The kind that warms you up.
Put it there.
We knew all about it.
Tell no one though.
We can't agree whether...
to let her keep it or not. What do you think?
She no longer wants it.
l like her.
A broken heart can make a good Carmelite.
She had some money.
She added butter to our bread.
You have little to say to your superior.
The words fail me.
They won't come to your lips?
Write them down.
Why not write down your feelings
and your memories here?
lt might be interesting. Do it for me.
Take this.
Bring it back when it is full.
Yes, Mother.
l'll call our Mother.
No... Your hand...
He is the Consoler...
always beside us, loving...
Not in a hurry!
Sheets, family, Mother Superior.
Us = servants.
We've been washing.
- The scissors.
- They're on the way.
They aren't here yet... Small scissors.
Give me roots or give me wings...
like you.
You didn't drink the hot milk.
Nor the potion.
Sorry, no.
You must!
Tomorrow l'll give you a rubdown.
l'd rather not. lt's not like we were at home.
Or what's the point?
True, you're no longer a kid sister...
but a sister like the others.
- l must get used to it.
- We're sisters even more.
Did l hurt you?
No.
l sleep, but not my heart.
l hear my beloved knock.
Open, my sister, my friend,
my dove, my perfection.
For my head is covered with dew,
my curls glisten from the night.
My beloved, come into your garden.
Take the fruit of your trees.
My beloved instructs my soul...
speaking to it in silence and in darkness.
He wasn't in the kitchen.
Normally he'd be making breakfast.
l went to his room.
He was on the floor by the bed.
He caught these today.
He fears you might need them.
Poor father.
He's my baby. l'm a mother to him.
ls he in pain?
He tries hard to talk with his eyes.
- ls he in pain?
- Being helpless hurts.
- He understands us?
- Just a bit.
lf l leave him, he moans like an animal...
until l come back.
He often does that.
l thought, he's ashamed.
But it's something else.
What?
Only he knows.
He'll be a sun in heaven.
Here's oil from the Holy Face.
He carries a gun.
lt's loaded.
- Quiet.
- Go on.
At any sound, he pulls it out.
Thinks l'm in danger.
So no one comes over. Not even Sebastian.
Everyone thinks...
it's your fault, you and your sisters.
Especially you, Thérèse.
- That you killed him.
- That's enough!
That you're selfish, useless and crazy.
Don't get all worked up.
That's the rumor.
l hate when you exaggerate.
We can't talk any longer.
Let's all kneel and pray for father.
Sundays are difficult.
All your things are still there.
Give me the handkerchief, l'll wash it.
Control yourself!
l won't tell a soul.
You're lucky to have such a family.
Speak.
May l keep my father's handkerchief?
lf you have nothing else from home...
l have a pencil box.
You'll return the handkerchief.
Yes, Mother.
Carmel cannot pay...
the property taxes.
- You want to talk?
- No, Mother.
l wanted to say, l had a dream.
You gave everyone a gift.
My turn came, there was nothing left.
And?
l'm ashamed. Can't tell you, Mother.
Speak properly, make complete sentences.
My turn came, there was nothing left.
Your hands were empty.
You smiled and said, ''l give you my heart.''
Such a gift is a godsend.
l wish to be a saint.
Pride.
No, l'll become a great saint in secret.
Only He will know.
No credit due to me, Mother.
Don't always say ''Mother.''
l'll not consider you a child.
You're strong.
l'll never fear to humiliate you.
As the last to enter,
you are everyone's servant.
That should make you happy.
He brought me to his wine cellar.
He poured his friendship in me.
Sustain me with flowers,
strengthen me with fruit.
l pine away for love.
He puts one hand on my head,
the other embraces me.
l'm allowed to talk to you.
About everything, with no witnesses.
Great!
l had to ask three times for it.
Thanks for trying.
My pleasure.
Your Mother?
Yet another wire. She won't come.
Oh? How's your eczema?
Worse.
And the rest?
My periods are gone, my tummy's a mess.
This isn't a sacrifice, it's a massacre!
My body's here, my mind's elsewhere.
Well!
Gift from the chemist!
Boil it 20 minutes,
then call Mother Superior.
l'm becoming stupid!
They tell me to stretch toward perfection.
The way l see it, l'm stretching thin.
That's my whole spiritual life.
We're so tiny.
We don't have great thoughts.
l try hard, but no one notices.
- He does.
- Oh, him...
Fondle him, that's how l snared him.
- l'm not his type.
- He fancies you!
He stands me up.
- Playing. He'll be back.
- l'll shut my door!
He'll crawl.
On his knees? That'll do him good!
- He'll beg you.
- Yes! Yes!
We're nuts!
Falling for a guy dead 2000 years.
lf he ever existed!
- He did.
- lt's all in the mind.
Know what l do in bed?
lt'll make you blind.
l'm ashamed.
You're cutting on his share.
l've put these all over.
And that will lure him?
l like him a bit rough. Or else...
lt's the devil!
As ugly as the seven sins!
- Cut your tongue?
- A scratch.
l'll tell the boss.
Don't. lt's nothing, really. Gone, see?
l'll report you right away. l love squealing.
Your tomcat is the talk of the town, Mother.
They say you woke your girls one night
to find him.
You had them catch birds...
and stew them so your pet could feast.
lt is true. l had that weakness.
l asked them to forgive me.
Step up.
Press your chest against the grating.
Where is your heart?
l had a lump under my jaw,
but now it's gone.
Here, l'm not a man, but a doctor.
Take off this sack.
Open the window.
Just a broken vessel in your throat.
Or perhaps in your nose.
- Eat well?
- Too well.
How so?
l'm always hungry.
lt often wakes me at night.
A touch of anemia.
Give her fats and red meat for a month.
Whatever it costs.
An odd thing occurred
at Mestivier's wedding.
Céline was about to dance
with the most handsome guy...
when suddenly her knees jammed,
as if paralyzed.
They had to help her sit.
He was so embarrassed, he vanished.
He's answered my prayers!
Céline can't dance with another.
He wants her all for himself.
- Want Céline here?
- Oh, ever so much!
All 4 of you? lt's an invasion!
They'll vote no.
l paved the way. Most will vote yes.
- Then, if l may...
- Speak.
l wish to leave!
Leave us?
l want to go to a Carmel far away,
across the world.
To hide, save from him.
l'd miss you. Especially your simplicity.
lt'll shine out of you some day.
l wish to see it.
l need strong, happy girls. Be careful.
l am.
You're burning.
Dear sis,
lf l told you my dream...
You were dying a martyr.
A man dragged you into the woods.
l saw you leave for martyrdom with glee,
l held my breath.
We saw a wisp of smoke rise to the sky.
A bird sang. We said, the sacrifice is over.
Thérèse is a martyr.
My heart beat wildly. And me?
Would l be parted from my sweet Thérèse?
That couldn't be!
Something made me hope to join you
in your happiness.
l was out in the country.
A young cobbler threw himself upon me.
He stuck his awl down my throat.
l was too happy to run away.
But he was too weak, and l didn't die.
He got angrier,
and ended up plucking my eyes out.
l collapsed, thinking, more, more...
l wanted more, but l still wasn't dying.
l envied your fate.
Having endured all these horrors....
l woke up, regretting it was only a dream.
l bathed him, shut his eyes. He's beautiful.
l, Sister Thérèse of the child Jesus
and the Holy Face...
solemnly declare...
to promise obedience...
chastity and poverty...
to God our Lord...
to the Holy Virgin of Mount Carmel...
and to you, Mother Superior...
and to those after you...
until death.
A riddle for a heathen.
T as in...Thérèse.
After our walk, during which Dad
always gave me a little gift...
l came home...
l did my homework,
and the rest of the time...
l hopped around in the garden,
near Father...
because dolls bored me.
And then, on winter evenings,
especially Sundays...
how nice it was, after our game...
She's quite a problem.
Help me. Hurry.
You do nothing for her.
l can't tell her l love her.
Careful, she's capable of anything.
Make her your best bride.
So what?
His left hand touches my head...
the other embraces me.
Downpour cannot extinguish love...
nor floods submerge it.
Only way to cure chilblains.
Christmas, our husband-child's birthday.
We'll embrace one another
and ask for forgiveness.
We must always love and help one another.
- You won't wear them?
- No.
Like little flowers.
But l like them.
l have two little candles,
two little messages.
Those messages are a secret, sister Lucy.
Thank you.
Sisters!
From the sea!
Are they real?
Yes, they're real!
One for each.
For Carmel.
A man's at the door!
With a heavy trunk.
Of course, show him in.
Put it there.
Who sent this?
l'm not to say.
Thank you.
My cousin Aimée is here.
Can l shake her hand?
Of course. Come here, sister Aimée.
She left me for you, see.
lt was quite a shock. We were engaged.
Quiet.
She sewed a medal of the Virgin
in my jacket.
Secretly. lt's still there.
l'll rip your tongue off!
You've been very kind.
Miss me?
Please leave me alone.
- Merry Christmas, ladies!
- Merry Christmas!
Long live the Republic!
Merry Christmas,
from a carpenter and his wife.
lt's real champagne, it's not cider.
Everyone's looking for you.
The party's not over.
Go away. This is my home.
l can't bear those crazy old hags.
They are treasures.
You and l are the only treasures.
Know what they call you? Little sister Amen.
l love you.
l'm your fountain of love, l'm your shadow.
A grain of sand casts no shadow.
Silly. lt's yes to him,
but without you, it's no.
That's my deal.
l came because it's heaven here.
Out there was so ugly.
But why are you in this hole?
lt's my niche.
Stupid bandages!
You two stay apart.
l wasted my time on you, sister Thérèse.
l opened the door to my beloved.
l turned around and he had vanished.
What despair! l fainted.
l looked but couldn't find him.
l called, he didn't answer.
l ran into the night watchmen.
They beat me, they wounded me.
They who guard the ramparts
took off my coat....
This will be my best picture.
lt'll go to all the Carmels.
No cause for such alarm.
Get the doctor, please!
l'll think about it.
Now! lt's serious.
Our doctor is gone till Sunday.
He has a replacement.
A beginner. Too young.
They say he is good.
l will not let in an unknown.
She's in danger!
Don't insist. That's disobedience. Go!
- l shall inform the Bishop.
- Watch your tone!
Get out! l'm sick of the Martin sisters.
Let election time come
so l'm no longer in charge.
You'll get my job, don't worry.
She's very ill.
She is not.
- The lung is gone.
- l don't believe you.
lt's tuberculosis.
You're wrong.
- Your doctor will confirm.
- He said no such thing.
To each his method. l prefer frankness.
Give her rubdowns.
- Fever cups, morphine shots.
- No way.
For the pain.
There's no need.
There is.
- She'll refuse them.
- l'll ask her.
We're on earth to suffer as our husband did.
He suffered only a day.
He's in agony till the world ends.
For you, for me, for all our crimes.
Suffering is hideous.
Not here.
They ought to burn this place down.
They probably will.
- How much?
- Nothing. As you know.
- l'll tell her parents.
- They're dead.
- You're dangerous.
- No, the salt of the earth.
Are you dressed?
l have a sheet to finish.
Go back to bed. You remain at the infirmary.
He's not sure what's wrong with you.
He'll wait for our doctor.
Shall l go on writing in the notebook?
The notebook? Yes, fill it up.
l don't even think.
lt's like fishing. l write whatever pops up.
- l look forward to reading it.
- Not what l'm writing now.
Why? ls it gloomy?
l see nothing after this life.
A wall rising to the stars.
Maybe he's mad at me?
He used to make me so happy!
You're just tired, pet. He's faithful.
l'd love a chocolate cake
with custard inside.
A bouché?
Even better. l think it's called an éclair.
Just one, if we can afford it.
She might be contagious.
Let her rest. No visitors.
Especially not sister Lucy.
Very well.
l see nothing after death.
A wall rising to the stars.
Maybe he's mad at me.
Please, if you meet my beloved...
tell him l'm ill with love.
Carry on. l still give the orders here.
What was for lunch?
Rice with herbs.
l love the wide-open spaces.
l love gigantic pine trees.
But is there pure love in my heart?
We look for Jesus.
We go to the hospital.
We wash the hands and feet of the sick.
Among them is a leper.
His hands are putrid stumps.
We wash them, too.
Then we drink the water
we used to wash them.
lt floods us so sweetly
that we sail on joy all the way home.
A scaly piece of skin
from the leper's sores...
slips into my mouth.
l don't spit it out. l swallow it.
l feel like l've taken communion.
l share with you.
You can't die or l'll leave.
Tear this up.
My beloved, you instruct me in silence...
and in darkness.
- Time out. May l talk to you?
- Of course.
You look well.
Thank you.
Maybe you're not as ill as they say.
l'd like something to remember you by.
Take a flower.
No, it'll wither and l'll be sad.
lt's all l have.
A hair?
A fingernail?
Will you forget l didn't like you?
l never thought that.
- Pray for me in heaven?
- lf l go there! l'm still strong!
l can't pray for you.
We all agree,
you deflect the prayers onto others.
You pass on all your gifts.
- So why make me any gifts?
- Right!
You don't have to struggle. lt's easy for you.
You think so?
l'd love to catch you in error. l can't.
l'm just a spiteful old goat.
l'll never change.
Don't worry.
At Carmel, the first 30 years are the hardest.
l see only a void.
lt's his doing.
He wants me to think heaven doesn't exist.
They warned me
he's even more handsome when he hides.
You must pull yourself out of this!
l'll think of you every day when l say mass.
You will never be alone.
Am l in error?
No. l promise you. l give you absolution.
l am not worthy for you
to come through my door.
Just say a word and l'll be cured.
Do all you can for your sister.
Miss services,
break silence when you have to.
You be the judge.
l'm sorry. l ruined it.
Drink a little.
My mouth isn't dry.
Still depriving yourself!
Whatever you need, you must ask.
Drink in obedience.
You may not find me...
You may not find me tomorrow.
No grief, no handkerchiefs.
He'll have come for me.
- His baby needs him.
- You're not a baby.
Yes, l am. Small enough to stay in his arms.
l'd cross mountains and plains
in search of my loves.
l'd go see the shoots in the valleys...
the budding vine,
the blooming pomegranate trees.
We're off limits.
l was thirsty.
Me, too.
- So hot!
- Record high.
ls sister Thérèse very ill?
Very.
Will she....
Unless there's a miracle, yes.
l dreamt that l escaped from here.
This is not a prison. The door is open.
l traded a violin for a train ticket to Paris.
l am a shepherd. You are my lamb.
l'll do all l can to keep you.
Expensive water from Lourdes.
lf you don't sleep, l won't!
l'm in pain!
Pray!
- l'm praying.
- What are saying to him?
- Nothing.
- And he?
- Pray louder. He's deaf.
When l say, ''lt hurts,'' you say, ''Good.''
No.
lt hurts.
lt hurts!
Good!
- lt hurts!
- Good!
- lt's stopped hurting.
- Good.
lt's stopped.
Can l see her? One second?
No longer.
Sleep.
Sleep, my little blue nestling.
You're going to sleep well.
And so will l, you know.
lt's going to be good.
l'm walking for someone.
Who?
Someone.
You won't say who?
No.
l want to sit there.
For sister Lucy.
lt's plain Lucy now.
Don't you ever stop?
No. We sell them.
l'd like to give you a proof of my love.
No one ever gave you that.
We'll miss you.
l'll send flowers.
She might jump away.
She'll hurt herself.
l'll let her go.
Back together, eh?
Poor thing, he's a bit lonely.
After her death,
Thérèse's notebook was published
and translated in several languages.
Her tomb is often visited.
ln 1925, she was declared a saint
and canonized.
English subtitles:
Henri Béhar - Matthew Pollack