I wonder what it's
like to be dead.
I hope it's peaceful.
Like you're floating.
I hope you don't keep thinking
about how you died.
And why.
Or... how it makes
no sense.
The thing about it is...
it's all so final.
Davey, come on,
we gotta go.
I can't find my flats.
Come on,
we're gonna be late.
- I can't find the right shoes.
- Borrow a pair of mine.
This kind, generous man.
This loving husband
and father...
who left us much too soon...
...would want us
to remember him
from every portrait
he created...
...every face
that he found fascinating.
Put some dirt on Daddy.
And we're going
to talk soon, okay?
Salad? It's very good.
Homemade.
Your aunt says it's
important to eat.
And what does she know?
She hasn't seen me
since I was five.
It's a nice picture of him,
don't you think?
Yeah.
I took it myself.
In June.
Right in front
of the store.
You think it's a good idea
to keep reading
about it?
What else am I
supposed to do?
I wonder if the cemetery
will get all muddy?
Like I have to put some kind of
tarp thing over the grave.
Or maybe it will be better
for the grass,
so it could
finally grow back.
- Why don't you just take a break?
- Come out to New Mexico.
I just hate to leave you
in this neighborhood, alone.
Okay, thank you.
We don't want you
to worry about money.
We're in a position to help.
I... I promise I'll pay it back.
So you just call
if you need anything.
Get away! Get out of here!
What are you
gonna do about it?
Do you hear me?!
Get away!
It's okay, they're gone.
Go to sleep.
How long will you be
in New Mexico?
Maybe like a week
or so.
Don't let her out at night...
Oh, and don't let her drink
out of the toilet bowl.
Don't worry, I'll take
good care of her.
I know.
Bye, Minka.
Look, a balloon!
Honey, get your head
back inside.
This is a moving car.
How could he of the world's largest
hot-air balloon festival.
Walter, watch the road.
I'd like to go up on one
of those balloons.
It's beautiful to watch, honey,
but only a fool
would actually go up in one.
Well, then I guess
I'm a fool.
If Davey's going, I'm going.
Nobody's going.
It's a moot point.
Walter, watch the road.
What's a moot?
It means it doesn't
matter, honey.
Because
it's not going to happen.
I'd like to go up...
Never come down.
Wow, it's really pretty here.
It's like
we're in another world.
Well you can see why Oppenheimer
chose Los Alamos
as the site for"Project Y."
What's "Project Y"?
It's a codename for
building the atomic bomb.
And Los Alamos
is the secret place
where the scientists worked
when they were developing it.
Bitsy works as a guide
at the museum.
She knows everything
about this place.
So, we're in a secret place,
where nobody can find us?
Well, it's not that much
of a secret anymore.
Wow, look at this house!
When we brought
this house,
we expected
to raise a family here.
- Didn't we, Walter?
- We did.
But... C'est la vie.
We're just so happy
you're here.
We want you to have
a wonderful time.
It's not like we're on vacation,
Aunt Bitsy.
I know that, Davey.
Jason...
You take care of a car,
it'll last for a long time.
Like this little beauty.
253,000 miles and
still going strong.
Oh!
Make sure you
wear that helmet.
And use plenty of sunscreen.
You're at 7,500 feet here.
Okay, Aunt Bitsy.
Be careful!
Ow!
Daddy?
Can you hear me?
Can you?
Hey!
You okay?
Who, me?
Yeah, you.
I thought you were in trouble,
the way you were calling out.
I'm fine.
What are you doing
down here?
Just thinking.
- Is there a law against that?
- No, no law against thinking.
Except, you're alone.
So, I'm alone.
You're alone too.
Yeah but, I mean, I've had
plenty of experience.
And who says I haven't?
You don't know
your ass from your armpit.
You mean elbow, don't you?
- Are you always so friendly?
- When I feel like it.
Ow.
You're thirsty...
You came into the canyon
with no water?
- I forgot it.
- Here.
Hey, easy, easy.
You'll get sick.
So, what's your name?
Uh, you can call me...
Wolf.
Is that a first name
or a last name?
Either.
Let's get going.
I gotta be somewhere
in an hour.
So, go.
You're going with me.
Guess again.
I'm not in the mood to be called up by
Search and Rescue later, ok?
I got other things to do.
Do you live around here?
Do you live around here, Wolf?
The more you talk the harder time you're going
to have climbing.
And next time,
bring some water
and a friend with you.
- It's safer that way.
- I don't have any friends here.
Well, maybe you should
make some.
So, uh...
So, what's your name?
You can call me...
Tiger.
Tiger... Is that a
first or a last?
Neither.
And over here are duplicates
of the first atomic bombs,
"Fat Man" and "Little Boy".
They were detonated over Japan,
in August, 1945.
Now, these are the only two
atomic weapons
ever used in warfare.
They represent
one of the greatest
scientific achievements
of all time.
And both bombs were designed,
fabricated, and assembled
right here in Los Alamos.
They killed a lot of people,
right?
Yes...
And in the next room...
How many people
did they kill?
It was something like 220,000.
Okay, thank you.
Sarah's dad got blown up
in a war
and now he has
a metal brain.
Uh, does anyone have
any questions?
Does Uncle Walter
make bombs?
Uncle Walter is involved
in Research and Design
for National Security.
Really?
I didn't know that.
Your Uncle Walter is a
group leader in W Division.
W?
But today's lab is equally
involved in health,
medicine, energy,
and environmental research.
- Mom?
- Excuse me a minute.
I'll take care of this.
Mom?
Mom!
The baby looked very much
like a mouse in every way.
He was only about
two inches high
and he had
a mouse's sharp nose...
I can't believe
you design weapons.
Yeah, it's my job, Davey.
It's your job?
That's it?
I do my best
to help protect us.
To keep us safe.
We all want to be safe,
don't we?
Don't we?
Safe?
Is that a joke?
Before he was many days old,
he was not only
looking like a mouse,
but acting like one too.
He was wearing a gray hat
and carrying a small case...
Just me!
Your mom loved cocoa
with marshmallows
when she was
a little girl.
She was afraid of the dark.
So I used to tell her
bedtime stories.
Sometimes, I would pretend
like she was my baby
instead of my sister.
Uhm, you know that
your mom is seriously stressed
and Walter and I don't think
she should leave
until she's feeling better.
We feel responsible for you.
Now, Jason is eager
to go to school,
so tomorrow I'm taking
him over to Aspen.
It's a very good
elementary school.
All of our schools
are very, very good.
And then I'm going
to take you over
and register
at the high school.
School?
No, I- uh, I'm not going
to school here.
Davey, please don't make this
harder than it has to be.
You've missed
a lot of school already,
and your mom
needs time to heal.
Well, how much time?
Well, as long as it takes.
How am I supposed
to go to school here,
if I don't know how
long I have to stay?
What does that have
to do with it?
Everything.
It's what we're doing...
Good night.
Okay, guys.
So today we're going
to talk about how this novel
changed our ideas on
traditional storytelling...
Now, what I want you to do
is think about the actions
of these characters
and ask yourself why.
Why they made
the decisions they made.
Come on in.
How are you doing?
What do we got?
We've got Davis Wexler...
- Everyone calls me Davey.
- Davey. Sure. Welcome.
So... Tony Morrison's Beloved.
That's what we're reading.
- Have you read it?
- No.
Alright, well we can get you
a copy after class.
Just do me a favor and take notes from someone who actually
knows what's going on in here.
I always know
what's going on.
But I think in this case
Davey should go with... Jane.
Jane, raise you hand for me.
- That would be Jane.
- Okay.
Alright, guys... Hi.
That's why my parents
named me Jane.
What do you mean?
You know, that whole
Davis and Davey thing.
I mean with a simple name like
Jane, nobody's ever confused.
I'm used to it.
...alright? We're going
to go over this next week.
So, where are you
from anyway?
Atlantic City.
Oh, that's in California,
right?
New Jersey.
Oh, New Jersey, uhm,
I guess I was thinking of,
uhm, Studio City.
That's near L.A.
Atlantic City...
That's where the Miss America
pageant started out, right?
Right.
You want some?
My father only drinks
the best vodka.
No...
I'm good.
Ignore them... They're"stomps" -
just slightly above Neanderthal.
So what division
is your dad in?
At the lab.
My dad?
Um...
He's uh, away...
In India right now.
Oh, my dad went to India...
Hey, Davey.
Ready to go?
Whenever you are.
- Bye, Daddy.
- Alright.
See you later, Mr. W.
Stay off the beach...
- And be home by ten.
- Don't worry, Daddy.
I mean, how can I not worry?
What happened?
Are you okay?
It's... it's probably
the altitude.
I mean,
you're new here.
Hey, where are you going?
Don't you have class?
Hey!
You new around here?
I bet you can't tell your ass
from your armpit.
- Hey.
It's the tiger.
In the flesh.
What were you doing
up there?
See those caves?
Tiwa people lived in them 800
years ago... my ancestors.
Your ancestors?
Yeah...
Now that part of my family
lives in a pueblo
thirty miles that way.
All I know about my family
is my great grandmother
lived in Atlantic City,
in a boarding house...
Like...
two thousand miles
that way.
I think you mean that way.
Right.
That way.
- We have a lot in common.
- I was thinking the same thing.
Get yourself a decent pair
of climbing shoes
and I'll take you up there.
Wait, to the caves?
You have a bright smile,
Tiger... But sad eyes.
You want to talk about it?
- No.
- Okay.
Maybe someday, but...
just not right now.
Yeah. Whenever.
What's wrong with Mom?
Oh, you know...
She's just got headaches.
Is she gonna die?
No, Jase.
She's not going to die.
How do you know?
Because I know.
What if she does?
Will we stay here with
Uncle Walter and Aunt Bitsy?
She's not going to die, Jason.
What if she does?
Then, yeah.
I guess we'd stay here.
See the Big Dipper?
I think so... I want to.
Everything's going
to be alright.
I promise... Okay?
It has to be.
This time you've bitten off
more than you can chew.
I can handle it.
You better, before it starts
to affect my work.
I don't have time for this.
Shhh! She's my sister, Walter.
This is important to me.
She needs more help
than you can give her.
Then I'll make sure
she gets it.
Yeah and your niece, oh man.
She's no piece of cake, either.
I know what I'm doing.
Well, I hope so, Bits.
I hope so.
The Society For the Preservation
Of Creative Anachronisms.
Uhm- I don't know what that is.
Oh, we celebrate
medieval life...
You know, jousting
matches and festivals.
Don't take this the wrong way
or anything,
but I'm not really
that into jousting.
You can- you can
give it a try.
- I'm really busy as it is.
- How so?
I have a lot of family
responsibilities.
Go on...
And she's volunteering
at the hospital with me.
Yeah! I'm volunteering
at the hospital.
I see.
I thought you were
the unusual type.
But I can see that
I was wrong.
I hate being around
sick people.
But, it's going to look so good
on my college application.
So it's worth it.
And if I don't
get into Harvard or Stanford,
my father is just
going to kill me.
He's head of T Division.
- T Division?
- Theoretical.
He's the one who thinks
brilliant thoughts.
You have a lot to learn about
Los Alamos, missy.
Guess so.
Oh,"103." That's you.
Good luck.
I've been waiting for you.
You've been waiting for me?
Any pretty girl.
I am just here
to refill your water.
Look at this.
My son brought it to me
from California.
- Silly, isn't it?
- Yeah.
Willie Ortiz.
Davey Wexler.
It's my first day
as a volunteer.
You like it?
- It's yours.
- No... I couldn't.
Besides, I don't think
we're allowed
to take things
from patients.
I'll tell you what.
I'm not going to be here
very long.
And when I'm gone,
I want you to have it.
Don't be sad.
I'll uh, I'll see you
next week, okay?
Next week.
Go do something
that will make you happy.
Watch me first.
Okay, now you try.
Use your legs for strength.
Next step.
Excellent.
You gotta
believe you can do it.
Don't be afraid.
Okay, take the next step.
I got you.
I knew you could do it.
See the black carving?
That's from their fires.
Over 800 years old.
Wow.
- A cave with a view.
- Yeah.
You can see why the
Tiwa people lived up here.
Pretty good vantage point, huh?
I wouldn't mind living here.
I'd bring my little brother.
And my cat.
My cat would love to
chase those.
When Winter comes, all the
lizards will disappear.
You won't see them again
until Spring.
Then they'll lay out
on the rocks,
soaking up all the sun.
Like me.
You disappear in Winter?
I might.
When I was young...
I used to climb here
all the time with my father.
I hope it never changes.
Everything changes.
Hey, Mom.
Mom.
You have to stop taking these.
Did you hear me?!
You need to stop taking these!
Yeah, I have to stop
taking them.
Can you please get up?
We need you.
I'm not the person
I was before.
Before Adam.
Good... That's great.
She'll never
get out of bed
if you keep
bringing food to her.
You know, you're turning
her into a zombie.
Who's a zombie?
No one.
Time to get this batch
in the oven, hmm?
Now, how long are we
going to bake them?
Eight minutes,
because of the high altitude.
And what are we going to set
our temperature at?
350.
Ugh, excellent.
I love making cookies.
You know, someday we
can open a cookie shack
in Atlantic City.
And we'll call it
"Jason's Cookies."
Will it be on the boardwalk?
Yes, it will be
on the boardwalk.
And in all the best hotels.
Or you can just open one
right here in Los Alamos.
There's no boardwalk
in Los Alamos.
You know you're sitting in the
same tub Oppenheimer used
when he live here?
- Oppenheimer?
- Wait...
As in the guy
who invented the bomb?
Yeah.
- He lived here?
- In this very house.
Uhm.
Hello?
Yeah.
Oh, hi Ted.
Tonight?
Really?
Oh, okay.
That's perfect!
Okay.
Okay, sweet!
Eight o clock.
Alright, see ya then.
Davey, this is so exciting!
Who is he?
Only the most popular
guy in school.
Okay, we have to think up
someone for you.
How about Ruben?
Ruben's perfect.
What if Ted thinks
I'm pathetic?
I don't know,
I'm just-
I'm not really that
experienced, you know?
Wait, do you
have a boyfriend?
I mean did you
have a boyfriend
before you moved out here?
No.
...but it does warm you up.
She can be an idiot.
But I love her like a sister.
She's wasted.
Well, yeah. That too.
Davey!
And so am I.
Whoa!
Oh, man.
Isn't Ted amazing?
Hey, I'm freezing.
Let's warm up in the car.
You don't have a car.
I do now.
I wish we had the keys
to the ignition.
I could use some heat in here.
Make your own, dude.
- Hi.
- Hey.
How are you doing?
Can we talk?
How about a walk
on the beach?
Yeah.
Let her out, let her out!
That's... really gross.
Well... I gotta go.
Tell Jane I'll uh,
see her around school.
I just drank a little too much.
I'm fine, that's all.
I just needed a little,
just to loosen up, you know?
Those boys...
I'm just so shy!
Shhhh.
I'm sorry.
Wait, guys, guys!
The famous physicist.
Shhhh!
We couldn't be more pleased
that you and Jane Albertson
are friends.
You know, her mother is in
my Thursday book group.
And her father, Bud Albertson,
is a world class physicist.
Isn't that right Walter?
You bet!
I hear Jane's no slouch either.
Oh yeah...
She's a straight A student.
Maybe some of that can
rub off on you.
Maybe...
Mom!
You're up.
I gotta get myself together.
Well let's start
with breakfast!
Tea and toast?
Sure.
Mom guess what?
so now I can read
Captain Underpants
all by myself.
I can't wait for you
to read that for me.
Honey, you don't want
to be late.
Don't want to miss the bus.
There you go.
Have a good day.
- I... I'll see you later?
- Okay.
Come... come in.
Meet my son.
Martin.
This is Davey.
Hello.
Hi.
Martin was a national
Merit Scholarship winner.
And he's runner-up to the
Westinghouse contest.
Come on, Dad.
He doesn't like to talk
about himself.
So I do it for him.
- Right Martin?
- Yeah.
He's going to be a
brilliant physicist.
He won a full scholarship
to Cal-Tech.
He's the first in the family
to go to college.
Come on, Dad.
Rest.
She should be on
the swim team.
She's got good shoulders.
Why didn't you say anything?
Why didn't you tell me
your father was sick?
I guess I'm just
a private person.
I am too.
You know when you told me
that I had sad eyes?
Yeah.
It's because my father died.
I'm sorry, Tiger.
Was he sick for a long time...
Like my dad?
No.
I-it happened suddenly.
Whatever happened...
It's tough either way.
Yeah.
Double fours...
1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8.
Ventnor...
We used to live there.
We still live there.
That would be Ned.
Hey, Ned.
Come on in,
everyone's ready.
Oh, okay.
Ned, this is Bitsy's sister,
Gwen Wexler.
Gwen, this is my colleague,
Ned Grodzinski.
Ned plays a piano
in our group.
Nice to meet you.
I've heard a lot about you.
Oh, okay.
Gwen, you're in for a treat.
Ned plays like an angel.
You guys,
keep the doors locked.
Oh, Gwen.
No place safer
than the hill. Don't worry.
We won't be long, okay?
Bye.
Twelve.
1,2,3,4,5,6,7,8,9,10,11,12.
Boardwalk.
I'll take it.
Okay, so I'm building a hotel
on Boardwalk
and another one
on Park Place.
And two houses...
Wait have you
been stealing the bank,
you little creep?
Yeah, you!
Come here!
Get back here!
- No. No!
- Come over here!
I'm going to get you!
- Please, stop!
- Never!
Stop. Stop. Stop.
Jason...
do you miss Daddy?
Come on, Jason.
I know you do.
Why won't you just say it?
I mean, why won't
you ever cry?
Crying's for babies.
Now let me up!
Not until you say
you miss Daddy.
No!
Jason, say that
you miss Daddy!
No, you say it!
Jase.
Don't you want to go
finish the game?
Finish it yourself!
It's easy to get lost
in Santa Fe,
so make sure you're back
at the car by four.
We will.
Look at those.
What do you think?
For my mom.
She'd like those.
Yeah, you should get those.
Alright.
We'll get these.
Here you go.
Thank you.
I'd like to get this.
I bet this is
for someone special.
Yeah... it is.
I have the feeling
he's a lucky guy.
Not really.
Oh, God,
it smells like plastic.
Come on, dance with me.
Oh, here they are.
Hey, guys!
Look what I got.
Great.
Wow, look at that.
Give me a kiss.
Merry Christmas, young lady.
We really love you.
Thanks.
Boy, you are cold.
- Let's go inside, okay?
- I know, I'm freezing. Okay.
This is for you, Daddy.
Happy Chanukah.
I wish you were here.
I miss you so much.
I thought you might need
a friend tonight, Tiger.
I know I do.
Hey, what are you doing?
Exactly what I feel like doing.
How's the swimming team
doing this year?
The swim team?
You're a swimmer,
aren't you?
Only in the ocean.
The ocean?
You should be on the team.
I can tell from your shoulders
you're strong.
That's what counts.
- Are you a swimmer?
- I never learned.
You can't swim?
In New Mexico,
there's not a lot of water.
- What is it?
- Don't be afraid.
For two years I've
been fighting this.
- I'm ready.
- Don't say that.
"Life is a good adventure."
Now, it's time for
my next adventure.
Not until you learn
how to swim.
I like a girl with
a sense of humor.
Isn't that the guy
from the hospital?
- Hey.
- Hey!
What are you doing here?
Hop in.
- Where are we going?
- It's a surprise.
- Uh, Jane, this is Wolf.
- Hey.
Wolf?
What kind of name is that?
Either a first or last name.
Your choice.
So, you're just going to
leave me here?
Martin Ortiz?
It's good to see you.
How's your papa?
I heard he was sick.
It's pretty rough.
I'm sorry to hear that.
He's a good man.
Very devoted to you.
He is...
This is my friend, Tiger.
- Nice to meet you, Tiger.
- Nice to meet you guys, too.
I'm glad you could make it
to the ceremony.
Come have some food.
Say hello to everyone.
Sure.
My relatives.
The making
of a relation ceremony.
Something we do
from time to time.
Martin Ortiz, my son.
Come.
This ceremony... ensures...
that no one...
is left to feel alone
in the universe.
It is vital,
as we are social beings,
who depend on one another.
A person is taken in
as a relative.
Relatives are as strong
as blood.
It must be.
Because the welfare...
of the group...
...sometimes hinges
on one individual.
If that person...
feels disconnected...
He or she may fail.
The medicine wheel...
represents your connection...
to the four directions...
and the hoop of life.
The feather represents
your life.
Because, like your hair...
it grows.
It represents your wisdom.
It represents
your connection...
to the past.
Thanks for
bringing me tonight.
Glad you were
with me, Tiger.
- I'm going to miss you.
- What do you mean?
I'm going away.
Now?
Soon.
When will you be back?
You're late.
You missed dinner.
Who was that
in the truck?
What truck?
The truck
you just got out of.
He's a friend of mine.
What friend?
You don't know him.
Well maybe I do.
His name is Martin Ortiz.
Ortiz?
Does he to the high school?
Not anymore.
- He's a dropout?
- I didn't say that.
Okay, why don't you
just tell me about him.
Instead of playing
twenty questions.
I'm not the one playing
You know, you can't just
accept rides
from boys, Davey.
He's not just some boy.
He goes to Cal-Tech.
He's just taking
some time off.
Cal-Tech.
It's an excellent school.
That still doesn't mean you
can get into a truck
with a boy
that we don't know.
Mom.
I'm sure that Bitsy
knows what's best
in this case, Davey.
Since when?
Since when does everyone here
know better than you?
You're turning into them.
Do you realize that?
Just afraid of everything.
You know a person
can get killed,
minding his own store.
Did you ever think about that?
You apologize to your mother
right now.
Walter, she didn't mean it.
Did you hear me?
Did you hear me?!
(GLASS SHATTERS)
Your children are totally
out of control, Gwen.
Oh, really?
Are they still my children?
Stop it, stop it,
stop it, all of you!
Anytime
you're feeling lonely
you're feeling blue
Hey.
You're late.
I thought you weren't
even coming.
Well here I am,
ready for the audition.
Have you been drinking?
No...
Okay just a teensy, weeny bit.
Just like a little.
I'm fine, Davey.
I'm fine.
You can't tryout drunk.
Well then
I'm not going to tryout,
because I'm sure as hell
not going up there sober.
Then don't tryout.
That was great, Joel.
Thank you so much
for coming.
That was fabulous.
Thanks again.
Jane Albertson?
Just tell her you
changed your mind.
Jane?
Here. I'm here.
Don't do this.
Uhm... I want to do
uh, "Anytime", right?
Yes, right.
You okay there?
Yeah, I'm good, I'm good.
Okay.
Ready?
Anytime I'm feeling lonely
Anytime I'm feeling blue
You could have had me...
for a friend...
and you chose her.
I hope you're happy
with your choice.
Thank you so much,
Jane, for coming. Thank you.
Yeah.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine.
I feel like I'm
going to throw up.
Davey Wexler?
Go for it, Davey.
I can't believe you
signed me up.
Davey Wexler.
Here.
- Hello.
- Hi.
Woo!
Go for it, Davey.
Shhh. Hush.
Anytime you're ready.
Anytime
you're feeling lonely
you're feeling blue
Anytime
you feel downhearted
That will prove
your love for me is true
That was really good.
I have the music right here.
So why don't I give it to you...
You rehearse it and
Monday we'll work it through.
Okay.
Thank you.
Okay, see you Monday.
Jane.
Jane, get up.
Come on.
Did I
make a fool of myself?
Yes, you did.
Come on.
Look, you need help.
There's nothing
wrong with me.
Look, I'm trying to
be your friend,
so don't play this game
with me.
- And what game is that?
- It's called denial.
You're a great one to
talk about denial.
You...
told me your father
is in India.
But that's not what your
aunt told my mother.
You really think
you're the only one
with all the problems?
If you think my life
is just so easy,
you're wrong.
Hey, it's a school night.
You should be studying.
I was watching that.
You know...
with a little effort you could
be getting all A's and B's.
You know,
you're really not
working up to your
full potential.
How do you know?
You don't know
anything about me.
Well I know that you have to
think about your future.
It's never too early
to have goals.
I have goals.
Well I hope they include
improving your grades.
It's what you learn that counts.
Not what kind of grades
you get.
Where did you learn that?
From my father.
Yeah I should have guessed.
You want to end up like him?
No education.
Running a sandwich shop?
It's a wasted life.
How dare you say that
my father had a wasted life.
You don't know anything.
He was a better man
than you.
A better man than you
could ever be.
If your father had been
a better man,
your mother wouldn't be
where she is now.
That's so not true.
That's another example
of a wasted life.
Pregnant in high school.
Destitude at thirty-three.
Shut up, asshole!
I hate you.
And...
"When the lizards run".
Does that mean something
to you?
Yeah... it does.
Mr. Ortiz...
Mr. Ortiz?
Last night...
His son was with him.
He asked me
to give you this.
Hey, Davey.
How are you doing?
Ready to go?
Whenever you are.
See you later, Mr. W.
Alright, stay off the beach.
Every time
we say goodbye
I wonder why a little
Daddy.
I need you.
Thanks, Ruben.
Break a leg, okay?
And next up is Davey Wexler,
singing "Anytime."
Change of plans.
Every time we say goodbye
I die a little
I wonder why a little
Why the gods above me
Who must be in the know
Think so little of me
They allow you to go
When you're near
There's such an air
of spring... about it
I can hear a Lark
somewhere
begin to sing...
about it
There's no love song finer
But how strange the change
From major to minor
Every time we say...
What the hell?
Daddy?
Daddy!
Help me.
Daddy! Daddy!
Oh, my god. Daddy!
Help me, Davey.
I'm trying.
Help! Somebody help!
Help!
Daddy!
Help! Help!
There was a robbery.
He was shot in the chest
three times for 67 dollars.
So that's how it was...
I tried to help but...
I couldn't.
I just wish I knew what to do.
Remember that you're alive.
He'd want you to live.
Your life...
All the past...
And all the future.
In the summer,
this was the home
of the Tiwa people.
Over 800 years ago.
In the winter they would
go down and live in the caves.
Wow.
You know a lot about this place,
don't you?
I had a good teacher.
It's been a long time since
we've done something,
just the two of us.
I know.
You know, up until now
I've uhm...
I've been afraid
to be alone with you.
Afraid of me?
I was afraid that you would want
to talk about Daddy.
And what happened
that night.
And I was afraid that it was
going to be too painful for me.
I did want to talk about it.
I know. I'm so sorry.
I'm ready
to talk now, okay?
I miss him.
I miss him so much.
I know, so do I.
What are we going
to do, Mom?
I'm going to figure that out.
It's a new recipe.
But I substituted olive oil
for canola,
because canola just
doesn't agree with Walter.
I gotta remember that.
Well, I have some news.
We want you to know,
we think Ned Grodzinski
is a wonderful man,
and we couldn't be
happier for you.
Wait, what?
He's asked your mother
to marry him.
Ned is a good man,
with a bright future.
But I said no.
You said no?
Come on, Bits,
it's way too soon.
He's a good friend,
but I'm not in love with him.
Love?
You're not a teenager
this time, Gwen.
Don't expect love
to feel the way it did
when you were seventeen.
Well, what I was going to say
is that it's time for us
to make a move.
What do y-
What kind of move?
It's time for us
to go home.
You can't!
I mean the children
are settled here.
And you guys
have been wonderful.
I wouldn't have
been able to manage
without you, but it's time
for us to go back home
and start our
new life as a family.
We can help you find
a place of your own
right here, in Los Alamos.
Try to understand.
You should be the one
to try to understand.
I don't know what your mother
is trying to prove.
I don't know why she feels
she has to do this.
What does that mean?
It means
"Life is a good adventure."
Sometimes it is,
and sometimes it isn't.
I admire your courage, Davey.
I really do.
Goodbye, Daddy.
that I'm not going to think
about you anymore.
This doesn't mean t
hat I'm not gonna...
give up that night.
Because that night happened
and there's nothing
I can do about it.
I love you.
I'll always love you.
Goodbye.
You okay?
Yeah.
This is for you.
What is it?
Open it.
A tiger's eye.
For my tiger.
Thank you.
Look.