Peace be upon you.
And upon you Peace.
Here.
Cheers.
Medications.
Two tablets in the morning,
two in the evening.
Yes...
They replaced that one.
Yes, I know. A generic.
Let's go.
Attention !
Important information !
Cigarettes are prohibited.
Music is prohibited.
Women must wear socks.
Attention !
Women must wear socks and gloves!
For those who speak Bambara...
No cigarettes.
No music.
For those who go to the market,
socks are required.
Understood ?
I just said it in Bambara.
- Roll up your pants.
- All my pants are like that.
Roll them up, it's the new law.
I said roll them up !
Peace be upon you.
What brings you here?
We have a new announcement.
And you just enter like that?
One does not enter the house of God
with shoes and weapons.
It's not right.
We can. We do jihad.
You do jihad? And you want to do it here?
In the house of God?
Here in Timbuktu, one dedicated to religion
does it with his head and not with weapons.
It is the hour of prayer, we want to pray peacefully.
Please get out.
Get away from my nets!
You hear me?
Guess what I'm thinking,
at this moment.
What ?
About your cattle.
About GPS, your favorite!
GPS...
- This is your answer?
- Yes.
Do you know something ?
If GPS has a calf
and if it's a bull,
I will give it to Issan.
He deserves all your flock.
All cattle?
Yes.
He deserves it, he's a good boy.
He will be happy just with the calf of GPS.
Don't you think?
He will.
Will you give him all the flock?
He deserves it, that boy!
I swear he deserves it.
Thank you.
I'll pay you later.
Thank you, see you.
Sister, you must wear these gloves!
Wear gloves to sell fish?
How will I water them with gloves?
Our parents raised us with honor.
Without gloves.
That's enough!
You want to cut hands?
Here are two! Cut them off!
We do no cut hands here !
For gloves, we need hands!
We do not fight with these people.
We're sick and tired!
They already forced us to wear veil.
How to work with gloves?
Calm down.
Not today, not tomorrow!
- In this case, we take you away.
- Take me.
What needs to happen will happen!
Give this to my mother.
Release the handbrake.
To the right.
Go ahead.
Look in front of you.
We start again.
Again!
Abdelkrim!
Can I tell you something ?
Yes, please.
You see ?
You do not know everything.
Only God Almighty knows everything in this life.
God be praised.
Did you drink ?
Yes, with mom.
Where were you this morning?
With the goats.
You watched the herd?
You're a good girl.
My little bird ...
Wait for me until I return.
I'll bring you gifts.
Look at me. Is it okay?
Watch over the herd.
See you later.
Daddy!
My bird ...
Daddy will make a trip and return.
Watch the house and wait.
Dad has left.
I told him
not to forget us.
You want to convince me to give up the jihad.
Me ?
Who am I to say, "Give up the jihad" ?
The jihad of others is not my business.
I do jihad for myself.
I swear, I do not have time for the jihad of others.
If I was not committed
to my moral improvement,
I would be the first among you.
I pray to Allah, the Almighty,
and hope he forgives me and forgive you.
Help us to turn away from the vanity and pride.
Stop what you are doing.
You damage Islam and Muslims.
You endanger the children
in front of their poor mothers.
You even hit
the mother of two children,
without an acceptable reason.
Before you
a woman came here to complain
that you forced her to wear gloves ...
like that ...
without explanation,
without demonstrating their utility,
as prescribed by Allah and His Prophet.
Remember the words of Allah Almighty:
"Forgive them.
"Involve them in decisions.
"Talk with them.
"Once you have decided,
put your trust in Allah,'
"Because He loves those who trust him."
Where is the mercy?
Where is forgiveness?
Where is the piety?
Where is the change, the change?
Where is God in all this?
These are the people that I do not like.
I do not like them.
But the driver is nice.
Who told you he was nice?
Peace be upon you !
How are you doing?
Good.
You always come when my husband is gone.
I am a married woman.
You go to see her every day after her husband leaves.
She is a married woman.
She must cover her head, it's indecent.
He tells you to cover your head.
If it displeases him, he should look away.
A man who harms a woman is ungodly.
She says ...
nobody invited you here.
And do not look at what you don't like to see.
If she needs something, she can ask me.
If you need something, you can ask him.
Have a good day!
We joined in 1990,
and we beat them in 2001, 2003 and 2005.
2005 ? I don't agree.
In 2005 they beat us.
Are you sure about that ?
Of course.
No, you need to review this.
In 2001 he already left.
Who says he left ?
Scumbags.
I respect Zidane, he is a great player.
But he doesn't have the record Messi has.
Messi scored three or four goals per match.
Comparing Barcelona with Real Madrid is pointless.
Never !
I'm not comparing,
I just set the record straight.
At that time, France was the only team
in the world, that defeated all its rivals.
And also won the World Cup.
No... let me tell you about France,
it's the only country so well known
that hasn't really ever won anything !
They paid money to Brazil in '98,
or sent them a ship loaded with rice because they are so poor.
And told them: go to bed and let us score three goals.
And so they won the World Cup !
Me... I need to leave.
I need to leave.
Stop, stop.
Satima is beautiful, she has a strong spirit.
Her husband is a good man.
What are you talking about,
a strong spirit, a good man?
One should be a good believer.
They are believers, and that's enough.
Omar, how bad is your Arabic !
Yes, I know.
I can speak Tamasheq and English.
It's a stormy day.
Yes... it makes us think of the past.
The neighbors left.
Everyone fled.
There's nobody left.
There is only us.
I rather stay here.
Where should we go?
Why should we always run?
Where to go with Toya
facing thirst and drought?
Still, we should be closer to others.
The neighbors will eventually return.
All this will stop one day.
These people scare me.
When you're not here, they come.
Here?
Inside the tent?
No.
I'd like you to support me.
To have patience.
If we stick together,
we will fight and we will make it out.
I know you're scared.
Me too, I'm afraid.
Admit that you miss your friends !
That is true.
Lift up the lamp, my brother.
To the right... to the right.
You need to look at me.
In the name of God, the merciful.
Peace be upon you brothers.
As you know,
the Prophet said:
Believers are parts of the same body...
... when one is hurt ...
... the others suffer too.
In the past,
I was doing music
I was a rapper.
In other words, I was a sinner.
But thanks to God ...
The problem is you lack of focus.
I don't feel any persuasion in what you say.
Are you convinced of what you say here?
- No.
- There you go, tell it to me straight.
It's not worth the pain of filming it.
Let me do it.
Brothers,
In the past I was doing rap.
Today, God be praised,
I am on the road of God.
The road of Jihad.
Do you see my eyes ? There's no movement,
no extraneous gestures.
I am convinced of what I say.
This is how you should say it.
Don't move like that or like this.
We're not doing rap, this is serious.
Come.
In this world,
everything perishes...
Stop. What is bothering you in this world ?
Firstly, the West...
The injustice ! You decry injustice.
Injustice... You've seen parents suffering,
You've seen the abuse.
It must stop today. You're done waiting.
In this world...
Where is this music coming from?
Abu Hassan sent us to find where it comes from.
Go there. We are searching here.
Let's go.
You're going that way, me this way, we meet in the square.
Ok.
Good evening, Abu Hassan.
Good evening.
I know where the music comes from.
I found where the music comes from.
There are praises to God and His prophet.
Should I hold them?
Pay attention to my nets!
GPS !
Daddy !
Issan returned crying without his stick.
Where?
What happened, my boy?
Where are the animals ?
Why are you crying?
GPS is dead.
what about GPS ?
Who killed her?
She was killed ...
by Amadou, the fisherman.
Get up.
Come.
Stop crying.
Tell me what happened.
I led the animals to the river,
to drink...
GPS escaped and went straight
into the nets of Amadou.
I went to get her,
but I arrived too late, he had killed her.
Don't cry, Issan.
Amadou killed GPS.
Why did he kill her?
To prevent the herd from drinking.
I do not understand.
You should go talk to him.
Go without your weapon.
That weapon, I've had it since you met me.
When I met you, you did not have Toya.
Weep not, it will not bring GPS back.
Do not cry.
We will have another cow
and we will call her GPS too.
Come what may.
But all this ...
should stop.
The humiliation should not continue.
What I don't say, you know.
Issan, why are you worried ?
I think of my father.
How was your father?
My father was big,
strong and kind.
A better stockbreeder than yours.
He knew more about the animals.
My father is also
big and strong,
and if he's still alive,
it's because he plays guitar and he sings.
He is not with the warriors.
Those who wage war die quickly.
If he is there or not,
I know he sings, but don't tell anyone.
I will not tell anyone.
Here...
...under Islam...
..it is forbidden...
Peace be upon you.
- Is this ball yours ?
- No, I swear!
It is forbidden...
... sitting...
...in the streets...
...and in front of houses...
...and doing idle things...
...to waste time...
...in the street.
Come on, baby.
The sin of adultery
and uncleanness.
Adultery...
...during the month of Ramadan...
...major sins...
The punishment is
death by stoning.
You played football; do you know it's prohibited ?
Did you know football is prohibited ?
Yes.
Since you knew that football is prohibited, you are sentenced to 20 lashes.
Because you knew that it's prohibited,
you will be punished with 20 lashes.
You bastard!
Amadou, is the water yours or your grandfather's ?
By what right?
Are you crazy or what?
What are you doing?
Peace be upon you, Abdelkrim.
Hello.
Peace be upon you also Abu Jaafar.
There was a murder here.
What ?
Your Arabic is incomprehensible.
Speak in English.
There was a murder here.
No, no, no... tell me in English!
Ok, sir.
I say that somebody killed somebody here.
What ?
Who killed who?
Somebody killed somebody here.
I will call you back.
Peace be upon you.
Your name?
Kidane.
Do you have a gun?
Your phone too.
Go up.
Mom, when will daddy return?
Soon.
Let's wait where there's network signal.
Call my wife, I want to let her know.
I do not understand!
Who speaks Tamasheq here? Please, help me!
Peace be upon you.
Please, call my wife.
Her name is Satima.
At 70 52 52 11.
I promised. They have no news.
70 52 52...
May God help you.
This is my land and this is my Timbuktu...
It's children are mourning and suffering
It's the land of love and warmth and dignity
So tell me, why are the children crying ?
Because of the injustice, violence, and fear of the future
Stop crying, my Timbuktu will always be here
Everything will go very fast.
You've got little time left.
You will be judged very quickly.
Sharia law will be applied.
The judge is a just man, he will apply the law of God.
You will have to obtain forgiveness
from the family of Amadou.
We will also settle the price of blood.
Do you have cattle?
Tell him I had eight cows.
GPS is dead.
I only have seven left.
He said he had eight cows but one was killed.
Regardless, he has to give at least forty.
You will be required to give forty cows.
You are a stockbreeder, you have cattle.
Forty cows?
Exactly.
I cannot stop fate.
My life is in the hands of God.
That is right.
Now, I would like...
to ask him a question.
No disrespect. I just want to know ...
Go on.
Tell him I want to know
if he has children.
God blessed him with two,
one is a boy of eight.
The Almighty has given me a single girl,
which is twelve
and she is called Toya.
She is everything to me.
She brings me milk to drink in the morning.
She brings the cattle back at dusk.
I have nothing in life
that is more precious than her.
God gave him a boy.
I have not had that chance,
He only gave me a girl.
But she fills my whole being.
I speak to you.
Tell me.
You look like someone I know.
Like who ?
Mohamed Ag Elgimit, of the tribe Kel Assouk,
of Lere.
I do not know him.
I come from the green country,
from Libya.
Libya?
It was here that my family lived until now.
What have you to do with these people?
A long history connects us.
They brought me here.
What is written will be done.
I am at peace with death.
We are all His children.
We must protect our children.
My daughter will not be protected.
That hurts my whole being.
Down in the grave without knowing what will happen to her.
Most of our relatives have already left.
But in all this,
since there is only one God,
I worship,
He will make justice.
No one escapes his fate.
Tell him that it's not death that scares me
but not being able to look back
and find her face.
Not seeing her before I die, it hurts.
Knowing that his daughter
will soon be an orphan
really makes me sad,
but do not translate that.
Understood.
Do you know that yesterday evening
you were caught in a room playing music ?
Yes.
Do you know it's prohibited ?
Since your parents were not present,
you will be convicted to forty lashes
for playing music,
and another forty for meeting by yourselves.
Look what I found.
Abdelkrim...
Everyone knows that you smoke.
There's no need to hide from me.
Who told you that I smoke ?
It was twelfth of January -
2010, six fifty three in the afternoon, exactly
the same time as Miami.
At six fifty three, time of Port-au-Prince, Haiti,
the Earth trembled,
and I found myself here,
at precisely nine fifty three.
Nine fifty three from Gonaives, Haiti, is that right ?
You've been there before
Take this, it's for you.
- It will bring you luck.
- Thank you.
Regardless the passage of time,
the trembling of the earth is my body,
I am the cracks !
Cracks everywhere from my head to my feet
From my head to my feet to my stomach to my arms to my ass.
On my face.
Regardless of weather...
I am cracked.
Me and Gonaives both,
filled with cracks.
Come baby, come.
- Do you speak French ?
- Yes.
Cover your face.
- What are you doing here ?
- Nothing.
Nothing ?
- I said what are you doing here ?
- I was talking on the phone.
With who ?
With my brother.
You lie.
I told you I was talking with my brother, you say I lie.
It's a lie, take her.
Don't touch me, don't touch me !
Abu Jaafar, speak please.
He says
he saw the girl in town,
she has a decent behavior and she's a beautiful girl
and he wants to marry her.
She says
that this way of doing things is not right.
Not with the tradition.
And the father was not there.
He said:
why?
He asks why.
Why?
Why should I give my daughter
to a stranger?
Who is he for me to give him my daughter?
He came
peacefully.
Your refusal obliges him
to use the force.
I'm not afraid of him.
I'm afraid of God.
He goes away now.
He will use force if necessary.
It's good.
Good, good.
Did you see that ?
- Is it good ?
- Yes, God bless you.
33...
34...
35...
36...
37...
38...
39...
40.
Hello.
No network...
Hello... hello...
Peace be upon you.
And upon you Peace.
Please ask the mother of Amadou if she forgives the killer or not.
I do not forgive. His death made me too ill.
Maybe tomorrow, but not today.
It felt too bad.
His blood is still warm.
She will not forgive, she is still in shock.
Ask him to raise his head.
Raise your head !
Satima.
I'm listening.
I am the driver of Abdelkrim.
I have a message from him.
There is nothing he can do.
It's over.
Tell him ...
the death of Amadou hurt me badly.
I did not want it.
As the sun rose this morning
and that I am still alive,
another day that God gave me,
what is going to happen,
I accept it.
Only one thing I will miss.
A face.
The face of my daughter,
that of my wife.
I ask God ...
If you have children,
it will help you
to understand my pain.
I do not fear the death you give me.
It has a place in me.
As you say, follow the law of Allah,
do it.
I'm ready.
You gave her daughter in marriage
to one of you,
without her consent or the presence of her guardian.
I had already asked
my brother here
to convey to you the case.
This action
was improvised during the night,
under the cover of darkness,
which is legally unacceptable.
Regarding her daughter
you have married her without her consent
to one of your young men ...
My sister,
what is the name the person who imposed the marriage?
His name is Abu Jaafar.
She says he is called Abu Jaafar.
That is why
I preferred to come myself
to explain the issue
this case,
and for you to clarify your position.
That's right.
We have married Fatima ...
Her name is Safia.
Safia, with Abu Jaafar.
It was a wedding ...
legal.
Based on Islamic law.
Regarding the absence of the guardian,
we are here
the guardians of any action
since we act in this territory.
We married Abu Jaafar
taking inspiration the words of the Prophet ...
"If anyone comes to you and you recognize his faith,
"Marry him."
Abu Jaafar is a pious young man,
a dove of the mosques, a fighter,
he is perfect.
On this basis, we have married them
and it's a perfect marriage.
The case was repeated
more than once in Timbuktu
this has troubled the people
and caused
many frustrations and anxieties.
We do not see
frustration or anything like that.
We apply the law of Allah
and the Sunnah of the Prophet, peace be upon him.
We have consulted
and acted
with full legality.
Mecca is in that direction.
I know.
My daughter and her mother are there.
Get me the motorcyclist !