Loving You a Thousand Times
Who is it?
Oh my, what brings you here?
I have something you need to hear.
For me?
Yes.
Why don't we go inside?
The weather is cold.
No.
Let's just talk out here.
Go Eun Nim and her husband said they'd divorce,
But she's come back.
Please stop it.
What?
No, what is that supposed to mean?
Go Eun Nim is a person who can't be in our family.
Why are you saying these things?
What in the world has our Eun Nim done wrong?
Yes. She's done something wrong.
Something that is so huge, I can't say it.
Then, I must know what it is so I can determine
whether they should be apart or together.
You really don't know anything.
Your daughter...
...was a surrogate mother.
S-Surrogate mother?
Are you meaning a person giving
birth to a child? Our Eun Nim?
Yes.
No, why are you telling lies that don't
even make sense right now?
As to whether it makes sense or not,
ask your daughter about it.
Right now, inside our house,
it's chaotic because of her.
That's why I came to find you.
No...
No, what are you talking about?
My father and grandmother don't know
about this, so they let her come back.
But, my mother couldn't say anything...
She's sick and lying down as a result.
Please detach Eun Nim and her husband.
No, what are you talking about, huh?
No, where did you get such slander?
Our Eun Nim did what?
Then, please do me this favor.
No, that...that...!
Honey, honey, are you all right?
Honey! Oh, god, this guy, really...!
I'm asking if you're all right, honey!
I'm all right, I'm all right.
Honey, don't believe her words.
I'll go over there and ask again. Huh?
Hey, look at me.
You won't stay still?
You. I told you to stop.
Why are you like this?
What? Why are you like this...?
You left my house  in chaos,
and yet you're asking why I'm like this?
Tell me again. Our Eun Nim did what?
Don't do this to me.
Call your daughter and ask her instead.
Hey. It was you who wanted a surrogate mother.
You used the surrogate mother to give yourself a child.
Then, how could you be like this and cause
disruption in our house, disruptively?
What did you say?
Do you think it's because I don't have
a mouth that I'm staying quiet?
You're in-laws. It's because
you're my daughter's friend.
Though I wanted to prattle,
I stayed quiet and endured it!
I can tell your mother you got a surrogate
mother to give birth to your child.
Should I just reveal that all to her?
Ahjumma...
Ahjumma, how did you...?
That's why, if you're scared of my mouth,
allow Eun Nim and her husband, Baek,
to live a steady life.
And don't spread rumors and lies about
Eun Nim being a surrogate mother.
Ahjumma.
But, our Yoo Bin came from her.
So, what now?
What?
You...What did you just say?
So, why are you making me say these things?
You can just be satisfied with what you already know!
Hey.
A-A-Are you crazy?
How can you say words with such absurdity?
No. The crazy one is Eun Nim.
Is getting back together with her husband not crazy?
You...Even if you hate Eun Nim to the extreme,
you shouldn't spit out nonsense!
Our Eun Nim bore a baby.
And not just any child, but yours?
I haven't seen Eun Nim pregnant.
Think about it well.
Why? Why would Eun Nim do something like that, why?
How would I know that?
Perhaps she did it because she was in need of money.
What?
Money?
I contacted the donor and paid the bill for dad's surgery.
No...! Where did you suddenly get
such a large sum of money?
That...
A senior of mine from college loaned me money.
My friend told me to pay him back some other time.
Mom, I have money aside from the surgery fee,
so use it to find a house.
After dad's out of the hospital, we can't not have a house.
Do me this favor, Ahjumma. Please have
Eun Nim and her husband divorce.
It must happen.
You must be so happy.
I'm talking about you and your husband going
to the States and living there together.
It really turned out great!
Yes, Dad?
For a moment, come by the house.
Dad, what's wrong with your voice?
Did something happen at home?
If I say to come now, just come.
You can come, right?
Yes, I understand.
Where did you just call?
To Eun Nim.
What are you going to say to her?
And she just recently got into that house, too.
Of course I have to ask her!
After hearing that, do you think I can just stay still?
I don't want to! You do the surgery!
Why are you doing this, seriously?
I can't do it, that's why I'm like this!
I don't want to! I'm telling you that I'm scared.
I'm sorry, unni.
Unni, I know that you're scared.
But, our dad, if not for you, will die.
Unni, unni!
I'm kneeling like this, please!
Please save our dad.
Mom, what's with her?
Tell her not to be like this...
Unni, if you save our dad,
I'll only live for you.
I'll do everything for your sake.
So, please, Unni...
You're not going to stop?
I don't want to. I'm never going to stop.
Please just stop, hurry!
He's going to China for a year?
Sunbae has a lot of work and seems to be really busy.
As for the money, for a year, I'll be helping him.
Then...
At the time, the surgery fee.
The surgery fee.
She did it for her father's surgery fee?
Oh my word...
What do we do?
You just came now?
For having something to do, you came early.
Yes.
I'll be going to my parents' house.
What, parents' house?
You, go and please don't ever come back.
I'll be going.
Just look at that girl! She's so rude.
Mother, just let her do what she pleases.
You have something to say to me, don't you?
W-What?
You told them about the surrogate mother situation?
Yes.
When you said you had something
you had to do earlier, that was it?
Now, everything will be cleaned up.
Since her father knows.
Do you think he'd leave this alone?
But still, how could you...?
Then, what was I to do? Should I have let those two be?
I can't do that. I'm doing this to have Yoo Bin in this house.
That may be true, but...
What would you like for dinner?
Should I make Gu Jeol Pan* that you like
so much, but haven't had in a while?
(*Pancake wrap dish with 8 sides)
Sure.
Mom!
What are you doing here?
Come see me.
But, dad said to come and see him.
First, come talk with me.
Y-You.
Four years earlier,
when you said you were going to China for a year.
Where were you, and what were you doing?
Why are you suddenly wondering?
Seeing that I know everything, tell me the truth.
Did you really, at that time,
give birth to a child? Huh?
Mom...
For your dad's surgery fees, and money for the house,
was that the money from giving birth to a child?
Mom, how did you...?
And that child is Yoo Bin? Huh?
Mom...
Aigoo! Why did you, why did you?
Aigoo! Why did you do it? Why?
Aigoo, what could we do now?
Aigoo, it'd be nice if I knew what to do!
Then, where were you during your pregnancy?
There.
In Paju.
What we supposed to do? What can we do?
You're saying that you were
in Paju during your pregnancy?
What are we going to do...?
It's difficult enough to have a baby.
How did you...
No, since you were all alone, how much
you would have suffered through.
When you're carrying a child,
there should be many things to eat.
Are you an orphan, huh?
You don't have a mom or dad?
Even if you wanted your dad to live that badly,
and even if you were single at the time,
how could you do this?
I don't know anymore.
I think I'm going crazy.
No. It's not a time to be crying right now.
Then, the reason to divorce
or not is all because of this?
It'd be nice to know what to do, it'd really be nice.
Then, your husband, Baek, knows about this?
Even though he knows,
your husband is still okay with it?
Then, it's fine. Huh? Then, it's fine.
Stop crying. Don't cry.
Do as I say. Listen to me.
First off, do what your husband wants to do.
Kang Ho wants to go to the States together.
Mom, I want that, too.
But, I'm scared.
Can l do that?
You have to go.
No matter what others say,
don't pay attention to it,
and go with your husband.
What do I do?
I haven't done a single thing for you.
Eun Nim, now, I can help you, so don't worry.
Just go straight to the States
with your husband. Okay?
Okay. Okay, it's okay, it's okay!
It's okay,
That's right, cry as loud as you want.
Our Eun Nim, it's okay. Cry a lot!
Go over there.
But, I have to see dad before I go.
Your dad?
Hey, your eyes are swollen from crying. You can't.
Listen to me well and go.
By any chance, did Dad want
to see me because of this?
Does dad know everything, too?
No, that's not it.
Your dad doesn't know a thing.
So, go and don't worry.
If he sees your face swollen, he'll be even more worried.
Are you like this because you don't
know your dad's personality?
Come back tomorrow.
Okay.
It'd be great if I knew what to do.
If only Nam Jung had done the surgery instead.
I feel like I'm going crazy. I want to die...
Later, when I die and meet Eun Nim's mom in heaven,
she can pull my hair out and I wouldn't
be able to say anything to her...
I don't have anything to say!
Why are you standing like that?
Why isn't Eun Nim coming? It's already past
the time she was supposed to come.
Don't call her.
Eun Nim isn't going to come.
I met her up in the front.
I told her to just go.
Why would you tell her to go?
I had intentionally called her here.
Why, what? What is it that you want to tell her?
Were you going to ask her about that thing earlier?
I just have to ask her!
Is it a must to really ask her?
That's right, that's right.
Eun Nim earned money by giving birth
to a kid. That's right.
What?
Are you being serious?
Seriously?
That's right!
How could a person do that?
Why would you think Eun Nim
would do something like that?
She did it to save you.
She did it to save you!
What does that mean?
When you were ill, where do you
think the money came from?
Then, that money...
Eun Nim did...!
That's not it.
Then, what you're saying is...!
That's right, you're right.
That money is that money.
Where in the world could you find a person
who'd lend you that much, isn't that right?
And we just believed in what she told us...
Honey, honey, come back to your senses! Honey.
We can't lose our senses, huh?
Then...Then that child is...
The child?
The child's probably doing well.
Honey. Eun Nim doesn't know that you know.
I said that you don't know.
You know what I'm trying to say, don't you?
So, you can never show it in front
of Eun Nim, you understand?
Eun Nim and husband Baek are back together again now.
Truthfully, if Eun Nim knows that you know,
you can imagine how uncomfortable her heart would be.
Then, that's the reason why Eun Nim was to get a divorce?
But, her husband understands it all.
He will forgive her.
But, her sister-in-law knows,
and her mother-in-law, as well.
Eun Nim must be going through
such a difficult time in that house.
Let's tell our Eun Nim to leave that house.
Did you not hear a single thing I just said?
Her husband understands, and they're going to live in the States.
So, that's why, honey, let's just keep
our mouths closed, and act like we don't know.
Do you understand, honey?
What am I to do about this?
Eun Nim!
But, how did Mom know?
Possibly...
Did that Ahjumma, because of money...?
It's me.
Where are you?
Are you at home?
I went out to my parents' for a little while,
but I'm on my way back.
Kang Ho, does your body feel better now?
Now, I'm strong.
Then, let's meet up before we go in.
Okay.
Then, I'll see you there.
So, you're taking your wife out to dinner?
Okay, I got it.
Buy her something delicious.
Okay.
Was that Kang Ho?
Him and his wife are going on a date.
A d-date?
What's with your facial expression?
It's been a long time for them.
The two of them can't go on dates or anything?
No, no.
When did I say that?
Before long, they're going to the United States.
It'd sure be nice if you could treat
them well before they leave.
Wh-wh-wh-what just happened?
She said she was going to her parents' house.
Is it that she went someplace else?
Well, that...
Mother, just wait a little.
Oh my.
Who is it?
What do you mean by who is it?
What was that? You startled me.
You didn't know your husband was coming.
What kind of thoughts were you having?
Nothing.
Don't think too much.
They say that thinking too much isn't a good thing.
Someone said that you need to let go of your thoughts
and materialism in order to lead a comfortable life.
That's why being simple is the best.
Look at you, making your own interpretation
of wise sayings again.
But, was there something going on
at your parents' house?
Your face looks swollen.
Did you cry?
What do you mean by crying? That's not it.
I'm starving.
What should we eat?
It's been a long time since we've eaten out, so let's eat something good.
What do you want to eat?
Think it over fast. I told you that I'm starving.
Jjajangmyun.
Jjajangmyun?
That's good.
Then, I should eat jjambbong
(spicy seafood noodles)
Let's get going.
What? Do you feel like eating this?
I should have ordered jjajangmyun, too.
Here.
Then, you eat this.
No, honey, you eat your jjajangmyun.
I, too...honestly, I think
I should've ordered the jjambbong.
Really?
It's always like that.
When you order jjajangmyun,
you want to eat jjambbong,
but when you order jjambbong,
you want to eat jjajangmyun.
It really is like that.
It's really good.
The jjajangmyun is good, too.
What is this? Getting it everywhere like a kid...
Here.
All done.
Today, I met with my brother,
and he said that we should hurry up
and go to the United States.
So, I told him that we're going to go next week.
Just thought you might want to know.
Next week?
- Meow!
Oh, cats!
- Cats!
- Meow!
Are you guys really going to be like this?
Like what, Auntie?
Hey, do I look like a joke to you? Why are you
suddenly separating now that I'm here?
Oh, seriously...!
No, why is there yelling again?
Unni, they're giving me so much stress, that
I don't think I can live anymore, seriously!
Hey, why is she like that again?
Well, we weren't doing anything.
We were just holding hands and
watching TV and Auntie came.
So we just separately when she got out.
You guys, why do you have to show off like that?
Mom, then, what do you want us to do?
When we're together, you say something.
When we're not, you still say something.
What do you want me to do?
Mother, I'm receiving too much stress.
Oh really, what am I supposed to do with her!
I've suggested joining a remarriage group,
and she says she'd rather die.
Yes, rather than marrying a divorced man or a single dad,
she says she'd rather die an old maid.
As she got older,
I never imagined she'd also get more troublesome.
Who would've thought?
Hey Mom. You should talk to PD Bong about Aunt.
What?
That's right, Mother-in-law.
Didn't Aunt say she was interested in him?
She told you that?
That she liked PD Bong?
Yes! That's why you should talk to him about it.
There's no harm in it anyway.
Mother-in-law, it's PD Bong!
What? Who?
Hello, hello, how are you?
Omo, the smell of liquor!
PD Bong, have you been drinking?
Yes, because I'm in such a good mood!
We've wrapped up filming!
So we went for a drink after that.
If that's so, shouldn't you have gone home?
What are you doing here?
That's true. Why exactly did I
come here?
No... I mean...
PD Bong, just now...
Didn't you say you came to discuss the script?
Is that so?
Well, let's continue the conversation in my room.
I don't think I said that...
- Come on, hurry, please go in!
- What? Why...
We'll talk in my room!
Mom! Mom!
Really, my mom sure can't read a situation...
In this kind of situation,
she should've sent PD Bong into Aunt's room!
Really, Mom has no clue at all!
No, I don't think that's it.
When...
Oh really, what's up with you?!
The children are in and all, really...
Well, you know me...
I act based on my self-confidence.
I have the confidence to believe in myself.
Is that something to be so proud of?
Would anyone call himself a fool?
What I mean is,
I'm the kind of person who doesn't
care at all what people think.
And so? What about it?
You know what I mean,
so please don't do this.
Mr. PD,
even if the actors aren't up to par,
you shouldn't torture the writer like this,
you really can't do this!
I'm really concentrating before the computer,
in order to write the scripts!
Why on earth are you doing this!
You're really no help at all!
Mother-in-law, here's a refreshing cup of water...
Has PD Bong fallen asleep like that?
Mom, what's PD Bong...
What's this?
Chul, isn't it amazing?
I've never seen someone fall asleep sitting up before!
Wow, it's really something.
Dear, you know,
with this kind of skill,
he could even appear on the Star King programme!
That's right! If he were to go, he'd surely win!
How could he sleep like that...
We're home!
Oh, Kang Ho,
did your date go well?
Yes.
Seeing you two get along well,
after such a long time,
makes me so happy I could fly!
Don't you think so?
Yes, Mother.
Auntie!
Yes, Yoo-bin.
Hey, kiddo!
Your auntie is your uncle's wife,
you know that?
Auntie, please make me chocolate cookies!
Oh dear, what to do?
If you eat cookies at night,
they'll rot your teeth.
I'll make you some tomorrow.
Yoo Bin, it's past your bedtime.
Let's go up to bathe and sleep.
All right, then after bathing with Auntie,
I want to shoot water guns with her!
Oh, look at you...
You like your Auntie so much?
Next time, Yoo-bin.
Tonight, go with your mother.
Let's go.
It's been a long time since we had some wine.
Why are you being so sensitive?
You're making things harder on Yoo Bin like this.
Just act like before,
as if nothing had happened,
wouldn't that be better?
Everyone knows, how can we act as if nothing happened?
We can't do that.
It won't be long before Kang Ho
and Sister-in-law move out.
Just bear with it until then.
It seemed just now like she was discouraging Yoo Bin,
so why are you acting like this?
I don't know, I guess we'll have to wait and see,
whether she'll leave so easily.
What do you mean by that?
What's wrong?
You're not feeling well?
I guess I ate lunch too quickly...
How could I not have known then...
Why? Why? Why?
How could I not know...
What are you doing?
Why are you being like this?
Oh God, Honey!
What are you doing this for?
You're really killing me!
I... Why do I live?
A person like me living,
can't even protect poor Eun Nim!
I'm so pathetic!
Why do I live, really?
What's wrong with you?
If you're really thinking of Eun Nim,
being considerate of her,
you should take care of yourself,
why are you drinking?
The daughter you love so much,
sold her body to save you.
How could you die?
You should live healthily for her!
Honey...
Only by living healthily,
can you protect Eun Nim!
Isn't that right?
So don't cry, don't cry...
Don't cry, Honey, don't cry...
Oh, you should've slept longer...
Aigoo, what's this..
I'll be off.
You really have to think of Eun Nim,
don't bother yourself with other thoughts.
If anything happens to you,
what would happen to your daughter?
You know very well.
Now isn't the time for me to be
scrubbing dishes like this.
That's right.
Can't let that woman keep ruining our Eun Nim's future.
Oh, really.
Hello?
It's me. You know who I am, right?
Yes. Is anything the matter?
Let's meet.
What's the matter?
I have nothing more to say to you.
But I have something to tell you.
I'm busy now.
I was your mother's friend before you married.
If an elder tells you to come out, you'll do so.
What did you want to tell me?
I heard Eun Nim and Kang Ho are going to the US?
Just let them go and live well.
Ahjumma.
It's something else if you don't know,
but since you know, how can you still say this?
That's right.
So she's even given birth to a child,
and hidden this fact and married someone.
It was undoubtedly wrong of her,
and I have nothing to say to that.
Even if Kang Ho weren't to accept it,
I'd have nothing to say.
But the fact is that he's accepted her.
Haven't I told you the identity
of the child sister-in-law gave birth to?
I was also forced under impossible circumstances
to tell you.
This is something that can't happen.
Why can't it happen?
Aren't you even afraid of god?
Of what punishment awaits you for this?
What god does is one thing,
why are you interfering in it?
What did you say?
What I mean is,
you can't do this.
Because you can't give birth,
Eun Nim gave you a child.
Shouldn't you be thankful to her?
Shouldn't you thank her and be grateful?
If you keep saying things like this,
it's you who'll get punished.
Whoever god helps in the end,
is not something that one can guess.
Isn't that so?
How incredibly thick-skinned.
I see why sister-in-law is also so thick-skinned.
What?
I've clearly told you before,
that the two would never do.
Be it for Yoo Bin,
or for our family,
I'll find away to break Kang Ho and Eun Nim apart!
Let go!
Please let Eun Nim off!
If you want me to go on my knees,
I'll kneel down and beg.
Why are you being like this?
I'm begging you,
if anything happens to Eun Nim,
my husband will die too.
Don't they say the wishes of a dying person will come true?
Even if it's for my sake,
aren't I your mother's friend?
There are things in this world that pass,
and things that will never do.
Even if the sky were to collapse,
Kang Ho and Eun Nim are not to be.
Eun Nim is a pitiful child.
Her mother died when she was young,
and so afraid was she that her father would follow,
she did that to save her father!
Didn't you also lose your father?
You should know her pain!
Please let our Eun Nim off this once.
Is she really Chung Ja's daughter?
She really doesn't seem like her daughter...
Yes?
Oh, are you packing your bags?
Yes.
Just pack simply, only the essentials.
I'll ask Driver Kim to send them ahead for you tomorrow.
If there's anything else you need,
you can just buy them there.
That could be fun too!
Yes, Grandmother.
But then, if you go to America,
won't it be uncomfortable not speaking the language?
Just learn some simple English here first before you go.
There'll be no problem when you're with Kang Ho,
but when Kang Ho goes to work,
won't you be bored alone?
Yes...
I'm learning little by little, now.
Hold on.
I know a really good English teacher.
Do you want me to ask him for a favor?
Oh no!
There aren't many days left anyway.
Oh yes, that's true.
Anyway over there,
there are many places teaching English to foreigners.
Since you're young,
you'll learn quickly once you get there!
Yes.
Yes, Dad?
Now?
Dad, why are we eating at such an expensive place?
For a father treating his daughter,
this much is all right.
Come, let's eat.
All right.
It's delicious.
Dad, you eat too.
Eat plenty.
You liked eating this when you were young,
but I couldn't afford to buy you more then.
If mother
and Nan Jung unni and Eun Jung had also
come that would've been nice.
Your mother and Nan Jung,
I can always treat them to a meal next time.
Go on, eat.
Oh Dad,
don't be speaking as if we'll never meet again!
Kang Ho has agreed that we'll be
coming back often to Korea.
And once we're settled in there,
we'll invite you and Mom over too.
All right,
thanks to my daughter,
I'll get to visit the US too.
Dad...
Why are you like this?
It's nothing, eat.
I'll just be going to the restroom a bit.
Yoo Bin! Yoo Bin!
Where's Yoo Bin?
He had a snack and is sleeping.
Would you like some coffee too?
I'm already feeling so bothered,
I'm not in the mood for coffee!
No matter what,
I'm starting to feel uneasy towards in-law Park,
and worrying that things might get worse.
I feel uneasy.
Looks like it's going to happen.
Brother and Sister-in-law's breakup.
I guess you're right.
In-law Park didn't know anything,
they must really be feeling the blow now.
Mother!
What?
Why do you keep thinking such thoughts?
Whether it was for you or for me,
did you forget the pains we went through then?
Forget? Who's forgotten?
I haven't forgotten a single thing!
I'm having such a headache over it!
I'm back.
Yes, good.
Is your father well?
Yes.
Since you're going to the US,
I'm sure he can't bear to let you go.
Yes, a little.
Yes, of course he would.
Even if you were to go back and forth often,
how could it be the same as if you were in Seoul?
So...
what did you and your father talk about?
Nothing much,
we just had lunch together
and I came home afterwards.
Ah, I see.
So, did you eat something nice?
Yes, Grandmother.
What is up with this?
What on earth is happening?
Didn't Eun Nim eat with her father?
Did you explain the situation clearly to the in-law?
Perhaps you were trying to be discreet,
and they didn't understand you?
No.
Then... what's going on?
I didn't talk about Yoo Bin with the in-law,
just about Sister-in-law's being a surrogate mother.
How thick-skinned!
How could he, knowing his daughter
had given birth to a child,
still marry her off as if she was a virgin,
pretending nothing had ever happened?
Even though Eun Nim's mom knows about Yoo Bin,
she even tried to put the blame on me.
What? Did she really?
How could there be someone so inhuman?
Becoming in-laws with such people
is so humiliating.
I'm back.
Came back with Sae Hun and Kang Ho.
Oh, yes.
Welcome home.
Then, I'll be on my way out.
Why, is something the matter?
No.
Sister-in-law, let me help.
Thank you.
Son, you've already told Driver Kim,
to send the luggage on ahead tomorrow, haven't you?
Yes, I have.
But do you have so little luggage?
No, it was I who told them to pack just the essentials.
Shopping for the rest when they get there,
will also be fun for them.
Oh, yes.
Those we haven't packed,
we'll just bring when we leave.
Oh, of course.
Honey, you sit too.
Here, these are the plane tickets.
Oh, they've arrived so fast?
I went to get them today.
Thanks, Hyung.
Aigoo.
Even though I knew you'd be leaving
now that I've seen the tickets
it does feel rather strange.
You've been living abroad since high school
spending each year in two parts of the world,
now that we've gotten closer
you're leaving again.
Then, Grandmother,
would you like to come and live with us?
What?
Don't say things you don't mean!
We'll come back really really often.
Of course, of course you must.
How much longer will I be able to live?
Oh my, Yeon Hee,
where have you been?
Do you know how worried I've been?
But then,
why did you sell the house?
Selling it while there's some of the deposit left,
isn't that better?
Mom, let's return to the countryside.
The countryside?
I can't live in the country anymore.
Is that so?
All right then.
Then you'll have to live alone
because I'm going down to the countryside.
If you do strange things again,
that will be the end of things between us,
please just keep that in mind.
Once I take this I'll have 3 points!
Aigoo! It was there!
Oh, what's this?
That's gone then!
Kang Ho finally failed!
Then Grandmother,
do you have it?
I don't,
don't you have it?
It's not me either...
It's right here with me!
What's this?
Aigoo!
This one's big...
Why aren't you two playing?
Quick, turn the cards!
Say, girl,
I'm so tired, I can't play anymore.
Yes, Grandmother,
I'm so tired too.
- Isn't that right!
- Yes...
So, my girl...
- This round doesn't count!
- Hey!
Hey, what's this!
How can you do this!
Kid, this one, 3 points,
it should me mine.
My girl, how can you live with such a husband?
Isn't that right!
He's making life difficult for me...
Isn't he!
Yes!
We can't play this anymore!
Yes, Grandmother.
I won 3000 won!
What are you doing today?
I'll pack up the rest of the luggage,
and go over to grandmother's place...
I don't know.
There's not many days left,
I'm getting anxious,
but I'm worried we'll leave something behind.
It's fine as long as you don't forget me.
Don't work yourself too hard.
A kiss!
I'll be off.
This is your last chance.
Sister-in-law, please, won't you leave?
Go somewhere where no one knows you,
you'll be saving my life.
Of course,
you'll miss your husband for a while,
it'll be hard on you for awhile.
But all that,
will go away with time
and everything will return to normal.
So, Sister-in-law...
I'm sorry.
I can't do that anymore.
Sister-in-law!
You're creating more difficulties for our family!
Why don't you know this!
Sister-in-law,
after I leave, I'll live quietly.
If you so wish it,
I won't return to Korea.
So, Sister-in-law,
please help me.
Are you really,
going to persist in doing this?
If it's about Yoo Bin,
Sister-in-law, you really have nothing to worry about.
You're Yoo Bin's mother.
I will always be Yoo Bin's auntie.
I've tried my best to the end,
to resolve this amicably,
but I guess,
that won't be possible.
In the future,
whatever end arises,
don't forget that it was all your fault.
Sister-in-law!
What are you planning to do?
Who knows?
Why would I be telling you, in any case?
You're leaving for work?
Yes.
Honey, don't worry too much.
Everything will be fine.
Aigoo, really.
This old man's forgotten his mobile phone again.
When will he stop forgetting things?
What are you doing here?
Mr. in-law, I've made things so clear,
how can you still let Sister-in-law go?
I'm sorry.
That matter...
doesn't seem to bother my son-in-law,
we shouldn't be impeding their future, should we?
I hadn't wanted to tell you this.
Our Yoo Bin...
Sister-in-law gave birth to him.
What?
What do you mean?
The child sister-in-law was a surrogate mother to,
is our Yoo Bin!
Sir,
so please stop sister-in-law.
The fortunes of an entire family
are tied to those of a single person.
Please, I'm begging you.
What, what's that girl doing here again?
Oh, really!
Honey, what was that girl saying?
Perhaps...
you were already in the know?
No, Honey,
what did that woman say?
Don't listen to her, she's wrong!
Why didn't you tell me?
Yoo Bin...
Yoo Bin is that child of Eun Nim's?
That child?
Honey...
Honey! Honey! What's wrong!
Honey!
Honey what's wrong, wake up!
Have you told the in-law about Yoo Bin?
It seems like acute liver cancer...
What punishment are you seeking?
Why are you doing this?
I'm afraid Yoo Bin will be taken away!
Afraid he'll abandon me for his real mother!
That's why I did what I did!
The one who made father-in-law collapse,
was it you, sister-in-law?
Were you planning to hide this truth to the end?
It seems tonight will be the last night.
If anything happens to my father,
I won't forgive you.
The lengths to which I went to save him!
I was only telling the truth!
What truth?
The truth that I gave birth to Yoo Bin.