Showtime
[Yam With Curry Sauce by Gary Chaw]
♫ Don't care about the depth ♫
♫  Without the baggage for an idol ♫
♫ Fun is the best kind of art ♫
♫ Absent any preconceived notions ♫
♫  Or any constraints ♫
♫ A pot of cooked curry sauce can also go with yams ♫
♫ Where did this world go wrong ♫
♫ This place and time suddenly got so out of control ♫
♫ If I could ring Da Vinci's cell phone ♫
♫ I would like to teach him how to invent ♫
♫ First put aside, huh, the IQ ♫
♫  And even better to empty what's inside the brain ♫
♫ Just follow your, huh, instinctive pulse ♫
♫ Don't pay attention, hey, whether it's right ♫
♫ Doesn't matter if it can be done ♫
♫ You will discover the Earth is no longer routine ♫
♫ Don't care about the depth ♫
♫  Without the baggage for an idol ♫
♫ Fun is the best kind of art ♫
♫ Absent any preconceived notions ♫
♫  Or any constraints ♫
♫ A pot of cooked curry sauce can also go with yams ♫
♫ Betrayal pairs with the fear of losing ♫
♫  Curry sauce goes with yams ♫
Look at the time stamp of the message.
2019? This is a message from the future.
We can join Team Shadow,
but first you have to answer one question.
Let me hear it.
Where is Coach Shen?
This is such an intimate picture!
Why would you rest on a woman's shoulder?
All these signs and clues,
I think, must have something to do with the delivery girl.
- Bring me the money!
- Don't move!
Listen clearly! The team does not belong to Feng Ying or Aster.
About Zhong Xiao Long and Wang Yong Ze,
you have already tried your best.
That's something a loser would say.
Give me a little more time. I will think of a way.
Xiao Long?
Why do you think my grandpa
urged you to join Team Hurricane?
- Just to have you sit on the bench?
- No!
But at least believe this.
Training is a daily routine for a cyclist.
You must not become lax. Follow me and bike for a bit.
Tonight, I will have you ride behind me.
I will help you block the wind.
Hello, Zhong Xiao Long?
Yes, it's me Ji Zi Qi.
Feng Ying came to find me.
Feng Ying went to find you?
No wait. Listen to me first. Even though he is a bit annoying and the way he talks can be blunt,
don't take it to heart.
Let me tell you. Even though I am an assistant, I am the one making the decisions here.
- Huh?
- Take it easy first.
What did you say?
Yong Ze and I have decided to join Team Shadow.
You guys decided to join Team Shadow?!
Okay. Bye bye.
Why didn't you tell me?
How did you make him change his mind?
- Me?
- That's right.
I didn't do anything.
Why would they decide to join Team Shadow if you didn't do anything?
They probably thought it through.
With a world class cyclist like me on the team,
to regain the glory that Team Shadow once had
has a high chance of happening.
Please. It's obvious that you're telling me bull crap.
Listen. As the saying goes,
"It's harder to be cold when you see each other face to face."
He was probably moved by my sincerity yesterday.
Also, there is another important point.
It must be my looks.
It's all right, not a big deal. It's not much. You don't have to thank me.
Yay! This is great!
Happy! Happy!
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Our [ Right ] Time! Team @ viki
Cool.
Brother Bao.
Are you sure you want these two with absolutely no talent?
To you, they are just bench warmers,
but to me, they deserve better.
Let's be clear.
Back then, it was Shen Qing who begged
Brother Bao to kindly take these two in.
And now we have to give you those two just because you asked?
What do think Team Hurricane is? A shelter?
That's right.
I wouldn't come and ask for them with nothing.
How much is the compensation fee to terminate their contracts?
Just tell me directly.
Going straight to the point. You're direct.
But I don't need money. I won't sell no matter what the amount is.
So what do you want?
It's simple.
You versus me, one on one.
If you win, then I will give you both of their contracts.
You can do whatever you want with them.
But if you lose,
I want Team Shadow to disband immediately.
And you, to return to the States.
Hey, you are going overboard.
Brother Bao this is a matter between us. It has nothing to do with Feng Ying.
How does it not concern Feng Ying? Today it is he who came to me for the contracts today.
What? Pride of Taiwan, are you afraid?
And I was wondering what it could be.
It turns out you merely want to race against me.
Sure, I accept.
- Hey, Feng Ying!
- I don't agree to it! I don't agree to it!
I don't agree to it! What kind of crappy place is this? So hard to find parking and I can't drive here.
I don't agree to it. I don't agree to it.
What were you guys saying just now?
You went to the wrong side!
Brother Bao said he wants to have a one on one race, and if Feng Ying loses, Team Shadow will have to disband.
You are taking too much a risk. I don't agree to this.
Don't you worry. I will definitely not lose.
As long as the green hills are around,  you can always find firewood to burn.
Speed up! Speed up!
Persevere!
Stop.
Don't stop your legs. Hands on the drops!
Hurry!
Feng Ying. They sent us the time and location.
I am adamant on my standpoint. I disagree with this.
Same here.
I know it doesn't feel good,
but we will use the fairest and most open method.
We will conduct an...
Internal vote within Team Shadow.
That's a great idea. Majority rules.
Vote?
Yes.
Please raise your hand if you don't think we should accept Brother Bao's challenge.
- I am against it.
- I also disagree.
There are so many cyclists. We can find other ones.
We don't have to risk it for those two.
Excuse me. May I interrupt?
To be honest, I don't agree either.
Because Brother Bao is best at riding on mountain road, so if he doesn't choose a course on the mountain...
No, he will most definitely choose a track in the mountain. It will be too unfair to you.
That's right. It's too risky.
If Team Shadow is racing just because of the two of us,
we will feel apologetic.
See?
The weather looks great today.
We have not done enough sprinting, so let me ask again.
Do you agree for me to accept Brother Bao's challenge?
- I agree!
Another vote from me. See?
All right. I will go to scout the location.
David, Ai Li, give Xiao Long and Yong Zhe an orientation.
- Okay.
Go to do some research on the history of Brother Bao.
You are better than Ji Zi Qi at grasping the key point.
Hey, I--
And you,
follow me.
What are you saying?  You should believe in democracy.
I am very capable too!
Hey!
You do care about Team Shadow, right?
You are not the kind who, in case you lose the competition and Team Shadow disbands,
can just go back to the States unbothered, right?
Even if I don't care about Team Shadow,
I would still care about my own reputation, okay?
Is the team yours or mine?
Yours.
When I first went to the States, I practiced in the mountainous area every day.
I have even won the title of King of the Mountains.
This is my advantage. Brother Bao doesn't know about it.
Team Shadow will most definitely not disband.
Please believe in your Chief, okay?
I believe, I believe. Chief,
go!
Go! Go! Go! Scout the location! Go!
I must figure out why
you care about Team Shadow so much.
Why is there white smoke coming out?
Why does it feel weird?
What are you doing?
What are you doing? What's going on?
Let's get off first to take a look.
It seems that the radiator might have broken. Or that all the engine oil has leaked?
This Han Sen! He doesn't regularly inspect the vehicle.
Wait here for a bit.
I will go to take a look up front about the road condition of the race course.
Hold up!
The car is like this already and you're still going to check on the road condition?
Don't you want to deal with this first?
Are you the assistant here or am I?
Call and ask for roadside assistance! Do I have to tell you what to do, Big Sister?
Fine, I got it!
Don't go too far.
What do you need from me?
I want to remind you that about this competition, you can't afford to lose.
I know.
If I win, no one will be able to take what belongs to you.
But if I lose,
you will probably feel troubled.
This is a newly developed drug that will enhance your explosiveness.
Rest early.
An athlete's sleep is very important, isn't it?
Did you take care of the things that I told you about?
Okay. If this is done well, then we are even.
I don't need drugs to win against Feng Ying.
Feng Ying!
Not answering?!
So there you are. Why didn't you answer?
Hey, look--
Hold tight!
Ji Zi Qi! Hold tight!
Hold on tight!
Almost there! Pull harder!
Hold tight!
Hold tight! Hold tight!
I am almost out of strength!
I won't let go!
Almost there! You can do it!
Pull harder! I will pull you up!
Don't let go!
It's fine now!
It was so scary.
I am still shaking...
Don't be scared. You're fine now.
Don't be scared.
- So scary...
- It's all good now.
It scared me.
What doesn't kill you makes you stronger.
Thank you.
Thank you, Chief.
Are you snoring?
Oh my god!
And he is always saying how handsome he is,
how awesome he is. That he is a Shadow.
But now, he is a Shadow pig! Sleeping like a pig.
I must to record this and save it!
This is too good.
Let's see if you dare to order me around in the future.
I know that you won't reply to my messages anymore,
But this is the only way to make me feel
like I can still talk to you.
Today, I finally mustered up the courage to message you.
How are you?
Do you miss me?
I know you will never reply,
but I want you to know that I will always love you.
Why would I dream about Ji Zi Qi?
This dream is so realistic.
Go, go, go!
Speed up! Go!
♫ Don't care about the depth ♫
♫  Without the baggage for an idol ♫
♫ Fun is the best kind of art ♫
♫ Absent any preconceived notions or any constraints ♫
Go, go, go!
We can do it!
Hands on drops!
♫ This place and time suddenly got so out of control ♫
♫ If I could ring Da Vinci's cell phone ♫
Yell it out!
♫ I would like to teach him how to invent ♫
♫ First put aside, huh, the IQ ♫
♫  And even better to empty what's inside the brain♫
♫ Just follow your, huh, instinctive pulse ♫
♫ Don't pay attention, hey, whether it's right ♫
♫ Doesn't matter if it can be done ♫
♫ You will discover the Earth is no longer routine ♫
♫ Don't care about the depth ♫
♫  Without the baggage for an idol ♫
♫ Fun is the best kind of art ♫
♫ Absent any preconceived notions ♫
♫  Or any constraints ♫
♫ A pot of cooked curry sauce can also go with yams ♫
Here, this is yours.
Thank you.
You're welcome. I'm here.
What are you going to do?
- You know.
- I don't know
- Can you be nicer?
3, 2, 1.
Hahaha....
You lie to me every time!
I don't lie. I'm very gentle.
Ouch, ouch! It hurts!
Xiao Long, Yong Ze, when you go home today, pack your things and move over here.
Before Tour de Taiwan race is over, everyone needs to be managed together.
I'm sorry, but what about my private life?
And my personal time?
We didn't bring you here to have a party, okay?
Living together is for easier management and standardized training.
And develop team spirit, understand?
That's right.
Right, Chief?
Fine, I will go easy on you this time.
Thank you.
You!
Huh?
Shadow, are you okay with the race tomorrow?
That Brother Bao is really strong.
Especially on mountain road, he just ride through it like no one else.
And he got the first place in Taiwan before.
He's like Nezha sitting on the Fire Wheels. (Zezha: Chinese mythological character)
Ready?
I heard Ji Zi Qi has a boyfriend.
What boyfriend? Who?
Stop talking nonsense.
The dream I had yesterday... I dreamt of her again.
In the dream, she sent me a text message.
And she had long hair.
You dreamt about Ji Zi Qi...
Why are you talking so loud?
They say dream is your subconscious,
a desire that is deep within you.
I think this dream is most likely telling you to pursue Ji Zi Qi.
Me? Pursuing Ji Zi Qi?
I think it's most likely that there is some problem with my brain.
Ji Zi Qi with long hair might look pretty good.
Look good? What good?
It's still two noses and one eye.
I really want to see what Ji Zi Qi looks like with two noses
and one eye.
Cut the crap.
Two noses, one eye.
Grab his hand.
Do you still remember the first time you fell asleep next to me?
I really want to know how are you doing now.
Do you still remember Onion? I went to see it today.
If possible, I really want to see you play with it again.
I know that you probably will never reply,
but I still want to say
I will always love you.
Do you know why this is?
Why does it say "read"?
"Read" indicates that the other person has seen it.
The other person has seen it?
Do you want to confirm one more time?
Are you sure the other person has seen it?
You must know why, right?
Miss, do you want to call your friend to confirm?
Call?
I really want to call him too.
So, you're sure he's seen it?
Yes, he must have seen it.
Then, if you have any more problem,
please let me know. I will go on and work.
He has seen it, he has seen it.
You have seen it.
You really replied to me.
I am sorry. Thank you.
Did you sleep well last night?
I slept very well.
He needed to practice, and pack for returning to the States.
How could he sleep well?
I know everyone calls you the glory of Taiwan.
Your popularity is more than what Ji Fong had.
But in the field of cycling, we only talk about skill, not popularity.
Let me tell you. Over confidence becomes arrogance. You will become a joke.
Whether it is confidence or arrogance,
you will find out after the race.
It was Shen Qing who begged me to kindly take in these two.
I thought people trained by a famous coach must have decent skills,
but they made me realized,
as expected, all legends are exaggerated.
Famous coach is really nothing more than words.
Brother Bao, even though I am a part of Team Hurricane now,
I won't let you insult Coach Shen.
Whom do you think you are talking to?
- Look who's talking, traitor.
- What did you just say?
I just called you a traitor. Don't you like it?
Say it again. What did you say?
- Say it again!
- Louder!
- Shadow!
- Hurricane!
That's enough.
Cut the bull crap and let's start the competition.
Not a problem. I can't wait to see your defeated look.
Are you ready?
Ready!
- Go!
- Go, go, go!
- Brother Bao, go!
- You can do it!
Go!
- Brother Bao, go!
- You can do it!
What's wrong? Your are the cyclist returning from abroad.
You can't bike without girls next to you now?
Catch up with me!
Catch up with me! Speed!
♫ The name you wrote disappears from my palm ♫
♫ I can't remember your smile ♫
♫ Don't care about the depth ♫
♫  Without the baggage for an idol ♫
♫ Fun is the best kind of art ♫
♫ Absent any preconceived notions ♫
♫  Or any constraints ♫
♫ A pot of cooked curry sauce can also go with yams ♫
Glory of Taiwan, is your specialty taking a fall?
I'll go on ahead.
That's strange. Didn't I inspect my wheels yesterday?
Why is there so much sand on the wheels?
Looking at the time, they should be at the last segment of the path.
Hey, hey!  Hey, hey.
Don't you think it's strange that they are not worried at all?
They are doing it on purpose. It's a strategy and they are purposely showing it in front of us.
But it's Chief who's competing and not us,
why would they show that in front of us?
You have a point.
Chief!
Brother Bao!
- Chief is back!
- Chief.
- How did that happen?
- Brother Bao!
- They are back!
- Chief!
- Brother Bao!
Let me help you! Are you okay?
Be careful! Jin Cheng!
- Let's help him to the pavilion.
- Hurry.
How did you get injured so badly?
Brother Bao, what happened?
Hey, come here!
- How is he?
- Be careful!
Hurry and help him in here!
Brother Bao, be careful!
How did you get injured this badly? What's the result?
What happened to the competition?
How did you get injured this badly? What happened?
It must be Brother Bao. Let me talk to him!
I am fine.
There's always a risk with mountain bike racing.
No one did anything. It's I who fell carelessly.
Let me treat your wound. I will get the First Aid kit.
Chief, is it because there was an issue with your bike?
That's right. We really waited for you for a long time.
I found that there was a lot of sand and small rocks stuck on my wheels.
That's why I keep saying that you must inspect your bike before a competition. Understand?
- Understood.
Bear with me.
Here I come.
- Is it okay?
- It's fine.
How did this happen?
Bear with me.
What now?
Are you here to laugh at me? Go on with your bike!
Go away!
How did the competition go? Who won?
You won, right? Brother Bao?
I said shut up!
Why was there sand?
Is it okay?
It's okay.
You seem pretty good at treating wounds. Have you learned it before?
My dad taught me.
- You dad taught you?
- Yes.
This competition ended because of me.
It counts as a loss for me.
Here are Zhong Xiao Long and Wang Yong Ze's contracts.
Let's go.
- Brother Bao.
Brother Bao...
Hello?
I lost the competition.
And I terminated the contract.
You rubbish.
Here, here.
Look here, everyone. More dishes!
Knock yourself out! We still have a lot!
- There is really a lot of food.
- Eat lots!
Yong Ze, the food at your restaurant is really good.
Right? So good.
This, this is our signature dish. You must try it!
It's really good!
Let's do it together. Let's have a toast today,
celebrating the official debut of Team Shadow. Let's drink up!
Cheers!
You love drinking so much. Are you trying to get drunk or are you trying to get Team Shadow drunk?
Brother Han Sen, it's such a joyous occasion today. Here, let me give you a toast.
Let's all drink together.
Let's drink up.
It's such a happy day today.
What are we toasting to here?
I know. For Chief,
to stay healthy and wish him all the best!
Wishing you good luck and prosperity.
I wish you boundless happiness and a long, long life.
Brother Han Sen is really good at spewing nonsense.
I have been wanting to ask this for a while.
Why did Chief go back to save Brother Bao?
Isn't it easier to just head to the finish line?
This is victory multiplied by four.
Wow, that's amazing, but it's too cruel.
I am confiscating this, not going to let you eat this.
That's okay.
I will just drink.
Drink more.
Delivery girl.
- What?
- You...
What?
Nice one.
To be honest, from the first moment I saw you, I already knew you were great.
That's enough. Let me tell you, to be honest,
I also knew from the second moment I saw you,
you're not that annoying. Not bad.
- Cheers?
- Okay! After this, the past is in the past.
We are finally free!
I am so touched.
We are really getting closer to the Tour de Taiwan race.
We have to work hard together.
Chief, congratulations! We, as Team Shadow,
are finally established.
Ai Li, let's cheers together.
I am a little tipsy.
Come on.
Cheers!
Don't drink it yourself. Let's do it together.
Come on, Team Shadow,
go, go, go!
Woah, he is drinking from an empty glass.
No, I drank some.
You drank from an empty glass!
No, it was full!
-  Three more as a punishment.
- No...
No, I can't drink that much.
Cheers!
How are you so good at drinking?
It's probably because I used to drink with my roommate.
Impressive, right?
Oh right. I didn't get a chance to ask because of the competition.
Your last name is Ji, and you are so interested in cycling.
And your dad taught you how to treat wound.
In the cycling field, there aren't a lot of people whose family name is Ji.
Your dad should be Ji Fong.
My dad is Ji Fong.
Isn't he good looking?
As expected.
Let me tell you.
My dad is so handsome.
My dad was the key member of Team Shadow.
He was carrying the weight of all the Taiwanese fans' expectation
and hope on his shoulder.
And also Coach Shen's dream.
My dad's only wish was to get the champion on the Tour de Taiwan race.
Carrying my grandpa's dream?
Why are you crying?
- I always want to cry when I get to this part.
- Drink up.
Alcoholic, have a drink.
Hey,
I want to ask you something.
Do you know where Coach Shen is?
Why is everyone asking me for my grandpa's whereabouts?
I want to know more than any of you.
Everyone thinks of him as an inspirational figure,
and respects him. But has any of you ever thought that
Team Shadow...
What about Team Shadow?
Drink up.
Cheers!
Think hard about
how we are going to bring these drunks back.
And tomorrow morning we will have to gather everyone to have our first training practice.
Let me tell you. I can't do it. Even though I am strong,
it's too heavy. I really can't do it.
I will rely on you.
You have so much left.
Drink up! Finish this.
Cheers! Team Shadow, go! Team Shadow is the best!
If Ji Zi Qi was the one who sent the message,
why does she seem so sad in the future?
I am still adjusting to the days without you by my side.
I really want to know how are you doing now.
♫ Don't care about the depth ♫
♫  Without the baggage for an idol ♫
♫ Fun is the best kind of art ♫
♫ Absent any preconceived notions ♫
♫  Or any constraints ♫
♫ A pot of cooked curry sauce can also go with yams ♫
[ YOU KNOW ]
[ SHADOW ]
[ 2018 ]
[ YOU KNOW ]
[ SHADOW ]
[ 2018 ]
[ YOU KNOW ]
[ SHADOW ]
[ 2018 ]
Everyone, wake up!
How much longer will it take?
Move faster!
Stop slacking.
How much longer will it take? Assemble in five minutes.
Hurry up!
Are you playing around?
Hurry, hurry!
It's...
Time!
- Report to Chief, everyone is here.
- Count off!
- One.
- Two.
- Three, uh....
Three.
Four.
Where's Han Sen?
Opportunities are reserved for the ones who are prepared.
What are you waiting for? Hurry and go!
Good morning.
I have a day off today. I am the assistant's assistant.
Hi.
Good morning.
That concludes Aster's marketing plan for CI108.
Our marketing plan for CI108 spans over 10 years,
which goes to show we attach great importance to influenza vaccination.
I believe in the following 10 years,
the efforts by Aster on CI108
will supersede everyone else in the industry.
This part does sound appealing,
but it seems that your company
did not include our opinion about commission in the report.
About this part, we did receive information about your requirements,
but with all due respect, after all, all the benefits come from the same source.
Compared to food safety, drug safety is even stricter,
and of greater importance.
If we only care about cutting price for competition,
we will just repeat the same mistakes in recent years on food safety.
I believe, for a big factory with hundred of years of history like yours,
profit is definitely not the first priority in your plan.
CEO, should we listen to the Chairman's advice and discount by 2%?
In order to obtain the distribution rights of CI108,
Aster spent about seven years.
I dare to say, I know better about CI108 than any of you here.
To be honest, I even regard CI108 as my personal research project.
I can sell it even with my eyes closed.
I believe what CEO said is true,
but the headquarters still some additional consideration.
Excuse me.
Hello? Please go on.
Okay.
Yes. I understand.
Our headquarters fully understand the intent of your company.
Therefore, we agree to giving Aster the distribution rights of CI108.
Happy to work with you.
Congratulations.
- Happy to work with you.
- Congratulations.
CEO, our company have been trying to get CI108 for years.
Even Chairman wasn't able to get the distribution rights,
today, CEO, you did it.
This is such a great achievement. The Chairman must be happy.
Yes.
Okay, I understand. I will arrange immediately.
CEO, the Chairman said
he wants to eat with you tomorrow night.
Someone must have told him about the result just now.
Is that right? The news spread so quickly.
Then I am going to head out first.
Right, CEO, congratulations.
[ Wei Wei: are you still in the meeting? You sacrificed so much for CI108. ]
Dad, your wish is finally starting to come true again.
your wish is finally starting to come true again.
Mom, today is the official first day of Team Shadow's re-establishment.
We finally took the first step.
- I won't disappoint you.
Go, go!
Anyone wants to eat?
I do!
What?
Give me a push.
And this.
Hey! Why are you so childish!
♫ The name you wrote disappears from my palm ♫
♫ I can't remember your smile ♫
♫ Don't care about the depth ♫
♫  Without the baggage for an idol ♫
♫ Fun is the best kind of art ♫
♫ Absent any preconceived notions ♫
♫  Or any constraints ♫
♫ A pot of cooked curry sauce can also go with yams ♫
Hey! Why are you so childish!
Not bad, huh? It was pretty good today.
We can enter Tour de Taiwan race now.
He is such a monster.
Look at Chief,
we ran on the beach today,
and then biked for more than 100 kilometers,
and he can still take his time to clean his bike.
I think this is really over the top. I can't believe this.
To be honest, this amount of training wasn't that much.
You haven't experienced the training that we had half a year before the competition when we were in the States.
That was truly hell.
Right, Ai Li?
Right.
David, how exactly was your training in the States?
You will know when you have off-site training anyway.
Right.
I know everyone worked hard,
but you guys are already half way in, if you want to drop out now...
No way!
Water.
Here.
It seems that you dad taught you a lot.
You know bikes pretty well.
Also, seeing how you biked today, you're not bad.
As expected, you do have some talent.
He is actually complimenting me?
Oh...
My dad really taught me a lot.
I really like cycling, so I studied on my own.
It's just that, no matter how much I study,
I can't match up with professional cyclists like you.
Of course, you can't match up with professional cyclists like us.
If you can, what does it make of us?
Let me tell you. If I am serious,
even you will be scared of me.
Hey! What are you doing?
For a bike that belongs to me, Shadow, do you think you can just touch it?
Let me tell you, it is gold-plated.
I must touch it.
Touch.
Yu Zhen, is it you?
- What are you doing?
- Thinking.
About what?
Thinking of you.
Do you want some water?
You know, an English study shows that
everyone who died on Earth had drunken water beforehand.
I even know, if you keep saying nonsense,
I will beat you to death.
Dying in your hands is my honor too.
Excuse me. Allow me to take the call first.
Hello?
Yes. What?
Shooting a commercial tomorrow?
But it's not on our schedule.
Let me tell you. For something of such a short notice, I will not agree to it.
Wasn't I cool?
As a world class manager, a case that I accept on your behalf must be a top case.
Put up a good show later. I will take care of everything else.
- Okay
- Got it.
Do your best!
Everyone, you are shooting a commercial soon!  So cool.
Do your best, everyone, do your best!
Do our best!
You usually don't look that special. After putting on clothes like these today,
you look pretty good.
Where is Feng Ying?
As a world class star athlete, of course the organizer prepared a...
VIP room?  So snotty.
Let me take a look.
Wow, for sure it isn't the same for the international level.
Brother Shadow, let me put some makeup on for you.
Take off your jacket.
Why do I have to take off my jacket to put on makeup?
To make your more comfortable.
Come on.
Let me take it off for you.
What have you been doing lately?
Biking.
Do you make a lot of money biking?
What's your zodiac sign?
What blood type?
You are so buff.
Let me find something.
Brother Shadow, do you have a girlfriend?
Do you have a girlfriend?
What do you think about a type like me?
I think we are done with makeup here, right?
- I haven't done your hair yet.
- Thanks, thanks.
Thank you.
Brother Shadow!
I think... I really should go to find my teammates.
I feel dizzy.
Are you okay?
Hey!
♫ The name you wrote disappears from my palm ♫
♫ I can't remember your smile ♫
♫ Don't care about the depth ♫
♫  Without the baggage for an idol ♫
♫ Fun is the best kind of art ♫
♫ Absent any preconceived notions ♫
♫  Or any constraints ♫
♫ A pot of cooked curry sauce can also go with yams ♫
Brother Shadow!
I feel dizzy.
Are you okay?
Hey!
If you are not a player,
you are just wasting your youth!
Ji Zi Qi!
Brother Shadow!
♫ Playing the F Chord, I refuse to be labeled ♫
♫ With PEAK in my left hand, and heart on the right , am I a freak ♫
♫ In this age, all of us want guarantee in our life  ♫
♫ Just being myself is more reassuring ♫
♫ It's okay without money but sad not to have dreams  ♫
Ready! One!
Two!
Three!
Four!
- Cut!
- Director...
Hold on a second. What I want is not looking cool.
I think we are lacking some...
dramatic impact. Do you understand? Dramatic impact.
Dance okay?  Dance, can you do it?
Dance. I want dancing!
Again!
It's all your fault!
If you guys make him unhappy,
then you are causing trouble for me! Do you understand?
Everyone, get out of the water!
Get out of the water!
Biceps, biceps. Triceps, triceps.
Shoulder, shoulder. Remember to use your abs.
Say it out loud!
Biceps, biceps.
- Triceps, triceps. Shoulder, shoulder.
- Cut!
Biceps... Triceps...
I still think we are lacking some...
aesthetics.
Pour water. Yes, pour water!
That's great. Pour water. Let's do it again.
Chief, the weather is so cold today, and they are going to pour water on us?
Director said to pour water.
- Water!
- You should go to talk to him.
Isn't this for charity?
Chief, I don't know what to say.
I'd rather go biking.
Hey, don't we practice cycling in the winter anyway? It's the same.
We are doing something for charity. Let's just endure for a bit.
Art, is what makes people lose so many brain cells.
If we have liquid, it should also mean that we need to have solid as well?
Right. Ice!
It's so touching.
- Ice?
It's a brilliant idea.
That's what I like.
I don't feel hot.
Isn't this too much?
Timing and Subtitles brought to you by The Our [ Right ] Time! Team @ viki
- Ji Zi Qi!
- Huh?
Let's have dinner together tonight.
Being your boss, I have the responsibility to understand my employees.
When you want to understand somebody, or something,
you can't just look at the surface.
You have to get near it,
get close to it.
Do you know what time it is right now?
Tada!
Sandwich, hot coffee.
Am I not thoughtful?
Don't be so early!
I said before that I will be responsible for my team's future.
Ji Zi Qi,
Be with me.
♫ Everything happens too fast ♫
♫ When you walk towards me ♫
♫ I guess I finally understand ♫
♫ that I exist for love ♫
♫ The name you wrote disappears from my palm ♫
♫ I can't remember your smile ♫
♫ Space and time warps ♫
♫ When the comet falls ♫
♫ I will wait even if memories fade with tears ♫
♫ I will wait ♫
♫ If I can still hold your hands and move on ♫
♫ I will never let go your hands ♫
♫ Crave your love in my heart ♫
♫ The name you wrote disappears from my palm ♫
♫ I can't remember your smile ♫
♫ Space and time warps ♫
♫ When the comet falls ♫
♫ I will wait even if memories fade with tears ♫
♫ I will wait ♫