My name is H.G. Wells.
My friend John is Jack the Ripper.
He's escaped from 1893
in my time machine,
and I am the only one who can catch him.
I know things about you
that you don't even know about yourself.
Like the fact that you
have a son. In Paris.
- Henry Ayers.
- Impossible.
You asked me if I believe in fate.
Oh, I believe very much so
that this moment was destined to happen.
I understand you went
to my childhood home.
We did overhear your
father talk about his work.
Project Utopia?
I don't know of any Project Utopia.
Griffin, your sister's here.
Brooke. What in the
hell are you doing here?
John escaped.
What happened? You were
supposed to keep him locked up.
I know you.
Good Lord. What are you looking at?
This is actual footage from World War I.
It's man versus machine.
It's not war. It's slaughter.
Why would John go to such a time?
What was so important in
Paris on March 30, 1918?
Could you open up that map again?
All we know so far
is that he landed at
Bois De Boulogne Park.
And he could have gone
anywhere from there.
Be impossible to find.
What was happening on that day?
It was toward the end of World War I.
The Germans had a new artillery weapon
called the Paris Gun.
They hid it in the countryside
and fired it into the city at random.
Despicable.
Innocent people struck
down at any moment.
You said John spent a year
in Paris at medical school?
Yes, but that was
years earlier, in 1890.
Did he have any friends or family there?
Not that I recall.
Except, no, there was a...
there was an English woman
who worked at the medical school.
Uh... Oh, what's her name?
Pauline. Pauline Ayers.
He boasted that they were lovers,
but then it ended when
he went back to London.
That's something.
What's this?
It's her genealogy.
Pauline was only in Paris a few years,
moved back to England,
worked at a hospital in Stockport,
died in 1914 of Spanish Flu.
Pauline had a son born in 1891.
Henry Ayers. Mother, Pauline.
Father...
John Stevenson.
Whoa.
Impossible. John never spoke of a son.
Maybe he didn't know.
But a-a woman would
tell a man such a thing.
So she had her reasons.
She easily could have kept it from him.
So how did he find out?
You can find anything
on the Internet today.
Henry Ayers.
He was a doctor in the
Royal Army Medical Corps,
9th Battalion.
He was stationed in Paris,
killed in action on...
March 30, 1918.
That's it, then.
John's gone back to Paris
to save his son's life.
Synced and corrected by Aaronnmb
www.addic7ed.com
I found some coats for Jane
and some currency for you to take.
Ah, excellent. Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- How's Griffin?
Oh, John did a number on him,
but he's with the doctor now.
He'll be fine.
Do you know where you're going, exactly?
Uh, Captain Henry Ayers was stationed
at the RAC field office in Paris.
He was part of the deployment from
Paris to Saint Quentin in the north.
At 11:00 a.m. March 30th,
the motorized transport
carrying Henry got underway.
Shortly after,
it was destroyed by German
artillery bombardment
just outside the city limits.
All men were lost.
John will try to stop Henry
from getting on that transport.
That's what we have to prevent.
You're gonna stop a
man from saving his son?
As cruel as it sounds,
if his son survives,
there's no foretelling
the damage it would cause.
H.G. is right.
The time ripples it could
cause would be devastating.
I will find him and bring him back.
John must pay for his
actions in this world,
and I will see to it.
Uh, Vanessa, did you discover
anything more about Project Utopia?
No, I've been through
my parents' papers,
the corporate archives.
There's no mention of it.
But I reached out to a
colleague of my father's.
I'm gonna go see him.
He was the head of
research in the early years,
so he may know something.
Do you think I could get
away with this in Paris?
Uh, you're not going.
Trust me, you'll want me there.
Je parle Français. I
spent a semester there.
I know the city inside-out.
But 1918 is a time of war.
Which is exactly why you need me.
No, it's too dangerous.
What kind of man would I be
if I put a woman in such peril?
This woman can handle herself.
She's proven it more than once.
I'm well aware, but at
the risk of sounding...
Like a sexist pig?
I've yet to oink, so I fail to
understand the "pig" reference,
but what I was going to say is
that as a man out of his time...
I went to the '80s.
That wasn't a problem.
I simply must say no. That's final.
Now, Martin, we can't risk
further destabilization
of the fourth dimension.
You'll sync the time
machine to John's first jump
and send me back in real time?
You got it.
John landed in Paris at 6:00 a.m.
Exactly 2 hours and 17
minutes have passed since then.
Therefore, I will arrive at 8:17
and have approximately
three hours to stop him.
Will that be enough time?
Henry's flat was just down the
street from the RAC hospital.
My hope is that he
didn't venture too far
in the hours before his deployment.
Jane.
Good luck.
I can't risk her life.
She will realize that.
Here, I was able to
track this down for you.
What is this for?
Protection.
It's a 1915 semiautomatic, fully loaded.
I am not comfortable taking a gun.
Violence is not the option.
Well, then, use this to prevent it.
Against all better judgment.
Wait.
When do you want me to send
the machine back for you?
12:00 noon. By then, I will
have accomplished my mission...
or failed miserably,
and all will be lost.
_
Londoner.
Is my accent that dreadful?
I was just down at the Army hospital,
and they said this is
where many of the doctors
come after their shifts.
Not for very much longer.
The Brits are moving north
to fight the Germans at Saint Quentin.
You don't happen to know a doctor
by the name of Henry Ayers, do you?
I'm an old friend.
I was hoping to bump into
him before he left Paris.
Henry Ayers, huh?
You're friends with that scoundrel?
So I take it he's a bit sinister, yeah?
Oh, I could tell you some stories.
Margot!
Henry, my love!
- How about one last drink for the road?
- Ohh!
Ohh!
Careful, he'll sucker you
into paying for the round.
I'm Margot, by the way.
I am this lucky bloke's fiancée.
Henry Ayers. Pleased to meet you.
John.
Well, don't be rude. You
don't recognize your friend?
It's quite all right.
I am cursed with a familiar face.
And I'm cursed to never forget them.
Are you sure we've met?
In all truth, no. No, we've not met.
But I've come to find you
because I used to know
your mother, Pauline Ayers.
I'll be damned.
He actually went to see his son.
You knew he'd go to 1918 Paris?
I knew he had a son in
Paris who dies in 1918.
I didn't think he'd actually go.
Why would John care about having a son?
He's a psychopathic narcissist.
Something was created in his image.
- His ego...
- Ow!
- ... must seek it out.
- Ow! That hurts.
You should have won the fight.
He had a knife. He didn't play fair.
What are you doing?
This treatment is more
effective on a fresh wound.
What treatment? Aah, Brooke, come on!
You... you could have numbed me.
I could have.
Dermis tissue.
Lab-grown from stem cells.
What the hell?
This is Dad's research.
A basic version of it, yes.
The injection activates
the transfer of genetic code
from the surrounding skin cells
to the undifferentiated tissue.
We could have used this in Iraq.
Well, pretty soon,
every soldier will be
carrying it in their pocket.
So if that's the basic version,
what else are you doing
with Dad's research?
Well, look at that.
Griffin's interested in
something other than himself.
No, I'm serious.
What's going on down here?
Would you like to meet
one of my patients?
Nick, this is my brother, Griffin.
You don't mind showing
off for him, do you?
Not at all.
Does that measure his grip strength?
Yep.
Whenever you're ready.
That's impossible.
I've developed an enhancement drug
from his own genetic makeup.
That number can't be right.
900 pounds means he has...
... The strength of six men.
And his heart isn't even up to 150.
- Thank you, Nick.
- Anytime, Brooke.
I'll be right back.
Is this even legal, what you're doing...
experimenting on humans?
Clinical trials. Completely
legal and contracted.
This better be on the
up-and-up, not like what Dad did.
This could be bad for us.
You mean bad for you and
your political career?
What's going on with Project Utopia?
Vanessa's looking into it.
So far, nothing.
Make sure it stays that way.
Are we doing the right thing here?
There's still time to stop it all.
If Vanessa finds out I'm involved...
I know you care about Vanessa.
You spent all this time
getting close to her.
It's only natural.
But her family destroyed ours.
We lost everything.
Don't forget that.
It's our turn now.
My mother moved back to Stockport
right before I was born.
Did you work with her at the hospital?
I was doing my residency then,
and Pauline was kind to me.
She spoke so highly of you.
I was at the hospital earlier
and saw your name on a chart.
Thought I'd look you up.
I'm so sorry to hear of her passing.
At least she was spared
the sight of this war.
She loved Paris.
It would have destroyed
her to see it this way.
Hmm. Yes.
And this is where she met your father.
She spoke about my father?
A bit, yes.
So you know he abandoned
her without a second thought.
She gave up on Paris
so my grandparents
could help her raise me.
Now here I am, defending it in war.
Yes, the number of men killed is...
unfathomable.
The past several months have
been... particularly bloody.
But still, the mind
finds ways through it.
It's a strange thing to
take a life, isn't it?
My calling is to save
lives, not take them.
Yes, but I imagine the...
lines are often blurred.
I can assure you they're not.
Well, it's impressive
to experience darkness
and not be consumed by it.
Well, we don't have much choice, do we?
We either reject the darkness
or we let it destroy us.
Another round?
Please.
- Two more, please.
- Make it three.
What do you say?
I thought you'd show
your face sooner or later.
So, Paris at war.
Quite a sight, eh?
It's an inconceivable tragedy.
Oh, lighten up.
Paris survives.
The world marches on.
We saw it ourselves.
And we saw the scars
that were left behind.
These conflicts happen again and again.
Each time, the killing
easier than before.
You're so dramatic.
War can never be truly stopped.
Once you unleash a
beast of this magnitude,
there's no way to call it off.
Perhaps one day, we shall
annihilate each other.
We'll call it "The War of the Worlds."
I see fatherhood hasn't granted you
a more benevolent view of humanity.
Hmm.
Yes, Henry.
I don't approve of the name,
but a decent lad, nonetheless.
Who'd have thought?
The conclusion is obvious.
Leave him alone.
Let him stay that way.
I'm doing a heroic thing here.
His death is tragic,
but the fact remains
you can't change history.
Is that a guideline, or will the
world fall apart in front of our eyes?
Quite possibly.
So I'm supposed to let my son die?
Is that it?
Unfortunately, yes.
Because that is how history records it.
Doesn't the Utopian philosophy
require us to use our
knowledge to save his life?
It's not our choice.
Saving Henry could
cost countless others.
Sounds like a grand adventure to me.
Is that why you're doing this?
Thrills?
Do you even care about Henry at all?
Maybe that's what I'm
trying to discover.
You're a complicated man, John.
I'll grant you that.
And I am sorry about your
son, but you can't interfere.
Another drink?
- Hey, there.
- How are you feeling?
All bandaged up and cleared for combat.
Thanks. Have you seen Vanessa?
Uh, she went to go speak with some guy
who used to work for her father.
About Project Utopia?
She's on her cell if you need her.
No, it-it can wait.
What's all this?
There were photographers and journalists
all over Paris during the war,
and these are from an archive
at the national museum.
Wow. Incredible.
How do you have access to this stuff?
My job gives me access.
What is it you do?
I'm an assistant curator
at the Space Museum,
Or I am until I get fired,
which could be any day now
if I keep calling in sick.
Ah.
So, um, what are you looking for?
I requested all the
images for March 30th
thinking maybe I could
give us some information
that would help us in 1918,
but all that is pointless,
given that I'm here and not in Paris.
Yeah.
Um, World War I was a dangerous time.
I wouldn't put a woman I cared
about in danger like that.
Am I the only one here that's
living in the 21st century?
No one wants to put
someone they love in danger.
I wouldn't say H.G. loves me.
Well, I've seen you two together.
If it's not love, it's
certainly getting there.
Uh, but I do feel for you.
Gonna be tough when he finally
takes his time machine and heads home.
Yeah.
I guess it will be.
It's time.
I don't want you to go.
I must.
But I'll be back soon.
Do you promise?
Yeah, good lad!
You'll never convince Henry
to dessert his comrades.
Then I'll have to use
other means to stop him.
Sorry to interrupt, gentlemen,
but I'm afraid I must take my leave.
When this is all over, I'll
look you up in Stockport.
We'll raise a glass to my mother.
I'd like that very much, Henry.
I'm sorry to see you go.
Say a prayer for peace.
Peace... and long life.
Well...
always a pleasure, H.G.
Stay seated, John.
I do believe this moment feels familiar.
Albeit reversed.
Aren't you worried people will see?
I will shoot you in
the leg and carry you
back to the time machine if I have to.
You have it all thought out, don't you?
I can't let you save your son, John.
And you can't stop me.
John!
Not in my café!
He's a bloody spy. I heard him talking.
He said the Germans
were up to something...
No, no, you've got this
wrong. I must stop this man.
Drop the gun before I kill you.
I'll go get help.
_
You have it wrong!
One more word, and you're dead.
- You must listen to me.
- You're not going anywhere.
I would explain everything,
but Henry's transport
is leaving in moments.
What does Henry have to do with this?
John has gone to pull him
off the Army transport.
- Why? Is he in danger?
- There's no time to explain.
You have to take my word for it.
_
Vanessa Anders all grown up.
My goodness.
I remember when you would
come visit your father at the lab.
I remember, too.
I loved those visits.
I think of your father often.
Your parents' death was such a tragedy.
So much important work left undone.
Well, that work is why
I'm here, Dr. Meyers.
I've recently come across
a project my father was working on...
Utopia.
Do you remember it?
Oh, Utopia. Um...
no, not sure that rings a bell.
It was 1980.
My father had just
patented his breakthrough.
You were his right-hand man.
You knew everything going on in the lab.
It was such a long time ago, Vanessa.
Sometimes, the past
should stay the past.
Dr. Meyers, please.
This is extremely important.
What can you tell me?
I-I just don't want you to be
disappointed in your father,
to think less of him.
Why would I think less of him?
David was a brilliant scientist,
but he was young, impatient.
Some of the medications he patented...
they saved the company
from financial ruin,
but he didn't do the original research.
Did he steal the research?
He never admitted it,
but I did suspect.
There was no name on the
files other than "Utopia."
And after your parents were killed,
the original hard copies vanished.
Well, there must be something left.
I still have everything
I brought from...
from the lab when I retired.
But such a long time ago, Vanessa.
It's... it's unlikely, I'm afraid,
that I have anything that can help you,
but, uh, I'll look.
- Thank you.
- All right.
Excuse me.
Excuse me. Henry Ayers?
Henry Ayers. That way? Thank you.
I'll get right to it.
Henry! Henry.
John. You shouldn't be here.
Listen to me. It's
vitally important we speak.
- I only need a moment.
- Pardon me, sir.
I don't think you understand.
I'm deploying to war.
One, sir.
I have urgent news from your father.
That's impossible.
My father doesn't even know I was born.
I swear on my life he does.
He sent me to find you.
You worked with my mother.
How do you know my father?
Just... come with me for a moment.
- I'll tell you everything.
- Allons-y!
All right, men, let's move out!
What's so important my father
couldn't say it to me himself?
Your transport is going to be ambushed.
You and your men will be dead
before you even make it to the front.
You're mad. Where did
you get this information?
I can't say,
but your father sent
me here to help you.
That is the most
unbelievable part of all.
My father is a vile prat
who only cares for himself.
Why would he help me?
Because you're nothing like him.
I should hope not.
Hey, you. Busy day?
More like one of those days
where nothing is going right.
Mm, how can I help?
You could keep doing what you're doing
for a few more seconds.
Oh, hold on.
Things might be getting a little better.
Okay.
Dr. Meyers.
Vanessa, my late wife always
told me I was a hoarder,
but sometimes, it does come in handy.
You found something.
Some old files that I
thought had been shredded,
but I haven't had a chance
to go through them yet.
I'll be right there.
- Who is Dr. Meyers?
- Cedric Meyers, a scientist.
I will explain everything
when I get back.
- All right.
- Just keep your fingers crossed.
Okay.
Hey.
Hey, so I have something on Utopia.
We need to find Cedric Meyers.
Help! Someone!
It's too late.
They're all gone.
I have to get back to my men.
You don't understand
what I mean by "gone."
Why are you doing this?
Clearly not for the gratitude.
You have kidnapped me against my will.
I saved you!
Your father saved you!
The man you judge,
the man the whole world has
put on trial in absentia!
The selfish, vile prat. The Ripper!
You know him so well,
yet beg to know why.
Why? Why?!
He's lived a dark and dishonorable life.
He's done despicable things.
But that does not preclude
the possibility of good, does it, hmm?
My boy. My boy.
Congratulations.
You are the proof...
the one good thing he might ever do.
The punctuation of a remarkable,
misunderstood life.
You're a madman.
I do... I do believe you're right.
Untie me.
At once.
Are you with the 9th battalion?
There's been an attack, sir.
German artillery hit the convoy
on the outskirts of the city.
There have been heavy losses.
Sir, do you know, was everyone
present and accounted for?
Yes.
P-Please, I...
I need a moment.
- Let's go and search the tents.
- Yes, sir.
You son of a bitch.
Most men respond favorably
when someone saves their life.
I was supposed to be on that truck.
How did you know?
Henry, there's so much
I want to tell you.
We'll leave this place,
and I'll explain everything.
I promise I will.
Take this second chance,
and go be with Margot.
Stay away from us.
Don't let me see your face again.
1918. I have to go back now.
This is Henry Ayers
on the same day he supposedly died
when his convoy was
attacked outside the city.
The records were wrong.
He was never on that truck.
He died at a café.
H.G.'s looking for
him in the wrong place.
We should be looking at Café L'Automne.
Here it is. March 30, 1918.
"An unidentified army medic," our Henry,
"died trying to rescue people
"after the café was
hit by the Paris Gun."
There's no address.
Poor guy.
Avoided the ambush, but
ended up dead, anyway.
Jane, I-I don't think you sh...
That photo.
That guy in the background...
can you enlarge it?
Those clothes.
It's H.G.
Print... print the article.
H.G. wanted you to stay here, stay safe.
He doesn't get to decide
what I can and can't do.
- But if you go back...
- Are you gonna send me back,
or are you gonna let him die?
Okay. Okay.
D-Do you even know where to find Wells?
Um, the truck just left,
so I'll look for him
at the deployment yard.
What if you don't find him in time?
We don't know when
that picture was taken.
I'll find him.
Vanessa?
I'm sorry. I thought
you were someone else.
Ohh.
No! No, please!
No!
No. No, what are you doing?
Dr. Meyers?
It's Vanessa.
Hello?
Dr. Meyers?
Cedric?
Dr. Meyers.
Oh, God.
911. What is your emergency?
Hello. I'm at 380 Oak Street.
My friend... I think
he had a heart attack.
- Stay on the line.
- Yes, I'll stay on the line.
Okay, ma'am, help is on the way.
Hello?
Someone there?
Anybody here?
Hello?
_
Couldn't resist Paris
in spring, either, I see.
- Let go of me.
- Lost track of H.G.?
Has he not given you the bad news?
What are you talking about?
I won.
The transport left without him.
I saved Henry's life.
Congratulations.
I hope that makes you very happy.
What's this you're holding?
That has nothing to do with you.
What is this?
Leave it alone, John. Please.
Henry dies at the café.
I didn't save him after all.
Wait. Wait!
There was an attack on our
convoy headed to Saint Quentin.
What did you know about it?
I-I knew nothing. How could I?
Do you know what the
punishment is for treason?
Margot!
Henry.
You came back!
John pulled me off the transport.
Everyone else is dead.
No!
Henry!
Margot.
H.G.!
Oh, God. Oh, God, H.G.
Please be okay.
I tried to stop it.
Please.
You need a doctor.
Jane, what are you doing here?
I'm getting you to the time machine.
- It's coming soon, okay?
- Okay.
Come on. We have to get you out of here.
- Henry.
- It's all right. I'm here.
She's going to be okay.
How did you know?
No, Henry, don't.
- There are still people trapped inside.
- Henry!
- Henry.
- Don't!
Henry!
- Help!
- Get away from there!
This is how Henry's supposed to die.
- Henry!
Henry!
No!
There was nothing you could do.
It was his day to die.
H.G.!
No!
H.G., wake up!
Can you help him?
Can you help him?! Please.
Please. Please.
Not a good sign.
- Help him.
- Why would I?
Because you're more than a murderer.
You're a doctor. You told me yourself.
Now, prove it.
Prove it.
His eyes are dilated.
Could have brain swelling or internal
bleeding. He needs a hospital.
- Help me get him to the time machine.
- I'm not going back!
Yes. You have to.
There's nothing left
for you here. Please.
Please.
Where's the time machine?
This way.
His blast injury resulted
in a mild hematoma,
which obstructed blood
flow to his heart.
He's on blood thinners
and meds for the pain.
All he needs to do now is rest.
Thank you for getting him home.
Vanessa Anders, I assume.
We finally meet.
- Where are you putting him?
- The basement for now.
I saved Wells.
Isn't that worth anything?
Doesn't erase what you've done...
or who you are.
I suppose not.
Well, it was nice to meet you.
I do hope to see you again.
Jane?
Where are we?
2017.
We did it.
And what of John?
Vanessa has him locked up.
And his son, Henry?
He died.
John didn't change anything.
He did help bring you back.
He's locked up?
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Easy.
We had to insert this tube in your arm.
Oh, this is a very
impressive anesthetic.
I feel very lightheaded.
Ooh.
And good.
Jane, I'm so sorry.
- It's okay.
- No, it's not. I...
I didn't wish to be an oinking pig.
A sexist oinking pig.
I'm sorry if my behavior offends you.
No. I'm sorry for being too pushy.
It's just I've grown very fond of you,
and the idea that you
could be hurt is unbearable.
That's exactly why I had to go back.
I had to help you.
I do believe fate has
brought us together.
You're hurt. You need to rest.
No, hurt is what I'll be
when I'm forced to say goodbye to you.
You're not going anywhere
right now but to sleep.
But one day,
I will go home,
and I'll be forced to live
a life without you in it.
I can't imagine a day without you in it.
Wells is back, and he
brought John with him.
Vanessa has him locked up tight.
Wells, John, and the time
machine all in one place.
Makes things easier.
You killed Cedric Meyers.
- He had a heart attack.
- Don't lie to me, Brooke.
Not now, not about this.
I did what I had to do
to keep your girlfriend
from finding out what you're up to.
Well, it didn't work.
Vanessa has Meyers' computer.
Then you better hope she
doesn't find anything,
or we're both screwed.
_
Synced and corrected by Aaronnmb
www.addic7ed.com