- Hey, Astor!
- Well, hello, Molly. Nice to seeyou.
J.J. Madeleine,
I'd likeyou to meetJack Dawson.
- How doyou do?
- Pleasure.
Hello,Jack.
Areyou ofthe Boston Dawsons?
No-- the Chippewa Falls Dawsons,
actually.
Oh,yes. Yes.
Hemusthave been nervous,
butheneverfaltered.
Theyassumed
he wasone ofthem--
Heir to a railroadfortune,
perhaps.
Newmoney, obviously,
butstilla memberofthe club.
Mother, ofcourse,
couldalways be countedupon.
Tell us ofthe accommodations
in steerage, Mr. Dawson.
I hearthey're quite good
on this ship.
The best I've seen, ma'am.
Hardly any rats.
( Laughter)
Mr. Dawson isjoining us
from the third class.
He was ofsome assistance
to myfiancee last night.
It turns out that Mr. Dawson
is quite a fine artist.
He was kind enough to show me
some of his worktoday.
Rose and I differ somewhat
in our definition offine art.
Not to impugn yourwork, sir.
( Clears Throat)
Ismay:
She may be mine on paper
but in the eyes ofGod,
she belongs to Thomas Andrews.
( Whispering):
Are these all for me?
Just start from the outside
and workyourway in.
He knows every rivet
in her, don'tyou, Thomas?
- Your ship is a wonder, truly.
- Thankyou, Rose.
- And how doyou takeyour caviar, sir?
- No caviarfor me, thanks.
Never did like it much.
And where, exactly,
doyou live, Mr. Dawson?
Well, right now, my address
is the R.M.S. Titanic.
Afterthat,
I'm on God's good humor.
And how is it
you have means to travel?
I work myway
from place to place--
You know,
tramp steamers and such.
But I won myticket
on Titanic here
at a lucky hand at poker.
A very lucky hand.
- All life is a game of luck.
- Mmm.
A real man makes
his own luck, Archie.
- Right, Dawson?
- Mmm.
And you find that sort of
rootless existence appealing, doyou?
Well,yes, ma'am, I do.
I mean, got everything I need
right here with me.
Got air in my lungs
and a few blank sheets of paper.
I mean, I love waking up in the morning
not knowing what's going to happen
orwho I'm going to meet,
where I'm going to wind up.
Just the other night, I was sleeping
under a bridge, and now here I am
on the grandest ship in the world
having champagne with you fine people.
- ( Laughter)
- I'll take some more ofthat.
I figure life's a gift,
and I don't intend on wasting it.
You never know what hand
you're going to get dealt next.
You learn to take life
as it comes atyou. Hereyou go, Cal.
To make each day count.
- Well said,Jack.
- Hear, hear!
To making it count.
- All: To making it count.
- Archie: Bravo.
( MollyLaughing)
Mr. Brown had no idea
I'd hidden the money in the stove.
( Laughter)
So he comes home drunk as a pig,
celebrating and he lights a fire.
( Laughter)
( Softly): Next it'll be
brandies in the smoking room.
Archie:
Well,join me in a brandy, gentlemen?
( MenAgree)
Now they retreat into a cloud ofsmoke
and congratulate each other
on being masters ofthe universe.
Ladies, thankyou for
the pleasure ofyour company.
Rose, may I escortyou
backto the cabin?
- No, I'll stay here.
- Hereyou go, Molly.
Archie:
Joining us, Dawson?
You don't want to stay out here
with the women, doyou?
No, thanks.
I've got to be heading back.
- Ah.
- Probably best.
It'll be all business
and politics, that sort ofthing--
Wouldn't interestyou.
But Dawson, good ofyou to come.
Jack, mustyou go?
Time for me to go row
with the other slaves.
Good night, Rose.
( Clock BeginsChiming)
( Sighs)
Soyou want to go
to a real party?
- ( Drums Pounding, Men Whooping)
- ( PlayingLively Tune)
Is okay I put my hand here? Okay.
- Talla frikkensvenska?
- What?
( Repeats Phrase)
I can't understand you.
( GlassShatters)
Hey! Bravo, bravo!
- Thankyou. Come on, guys.
- Let's go!
I'm going to dance
with her now, all right?
- Come on.
- What?
- Come with me.
- What?Jack--Jack, wait!
- ( BandPlayingAtFast Tempo)
- I can't do this.
We're going to have to
get a little bit closer.
Like this.
- ( PipesAndDrums PlayingDance Tune)
- You're still my best girl, Cora.
- I don't know the steps.
- Neither do l.
Just go with it.
Don't think.
- ( Laughing)
- Hey.
( RoseSquealing With Delight)
Wait,Jack,Jack!
Wait! Stop,Jack!
- Ba-ba-ba.
- ( Dancers Whooping)
- Rose: Wait!
- Hey! Hey!
( Whooping)
-Jack: Yeah!
-Jack, no!
Whaaa!
( Squeals, Giggling)
...jurisdiction ofthe Sherman Act
so my lawyers will argue.
That's what Rockefeller said, but
the Supreme Court is not swallowing it.
( MenShoutingAndCheering,
DrumsAndPipes Playing)
What? You think
a first-class girl can't drink?
- ( Squeals)
- Get out of here.
- You all right?
- ( Laughing)
- I'm fine.
- ( Growls)
Two out ofthree,
two out ofthree.
So...
you thinkyou're
big, tough men?
Let's seeyou do this.
Hold this for me,Jack.
Hold it up.
Ow!
( Laughing)
-Jesus, Mary andJoseph!
- You all right?
I haven't done that in years.
Go see Maggie, lads.
Give herthe holley! Let's go!
Musicians:
Ho!
Coffee, sir?
I had hoped you would
come to me last night.
I was tired.
Your exertions below decks
were no doubt exhausting.
I seeyou had that undertaker
ofa manservant follow me. How typical.
You will never behave like that
again, Rose. Doyou understand?
I'm not a foreman in one
ofyour mills thatyou can command.
I'm yourfiancee.
Myfiancee?
Myfiancee?!!
Yes,you are, and mywife!
Mywife in practice if notyet by law,
soyou will honor me.
You will honor me the way a wife
is required to honor a husband.
Because I will not be
made out a fool, Rose.
Is this in anyway unclear?
- No.
- Good.
Excuse me.
Miss Rose!
- We had a little... accident.
- That's all right, Miss Rose.
- That's all right.
- I'm sorry, Trudy.
Let me helpyou.
It's all right, miss.
- Tea, Trudy.
- Yes, ma'am.
You're not to see that boy again,
doyou understand me?
- Rose, I forbid it.
- Oh, stop it, Mother.
You'll giveyourself
a nosebleed.
This is not a game.
Our situation is precarious.
You know the money's gone.
Ofcourse I know it's gone.
You remind me every day.
Yourfather left us nothing but a legacy
of bad debts hidden by a good name.
That name is the only card
we have to play.
I don't understand you.
It is a fine match with Hockley.
- It will ensure our survival.
- How can you put this on my shoulders?
- Why areyou being so selfish?
- I'm being selfish?
Doyou want to see me
working as a seamstress?
Is that whatyou want?
To see ourfine things
sold at auction?
Our memories
scattered to the winds?
( Sighs)
It's so unfair.
Ofcourse it's unfair.
We're women.
Our choices are never easy.
Hmm?
Congregation:
" Protect them byThy guardian hand "
" From every peril
on the land. "
" O spirit,
whom the Father sent "
"To spread across
the firmament "
" O wind of heaven,
byThy might "
" Save all who dare
the eagle's flight "
"And keep them
byThywatchful... "
- Hello, Mr. Andrews.
- Hello,Jack.
- Sir.
- I need to talkto somebodyfor a sec.
You're not supposed
to be in here.
" ...fire and foe
Protect them... "
I wasjust here last night.
You don't remember me?
No, I'm afraid I don't.
Nowyou're going to have to turn around.
He'll tell you.
I just-- I just need--
Mr. Hockley
and Mrs. Dewitt Bukater
continue to be appreciative
ofyour assistance.
They asked me to, uh...
giveyou this in gratitude.
- I don't wantyour money. Please, l--
- And also to remind you...
thatyou hold
a third-class ticket
and thatyour presence here
is no longer appropriate.
Please, I just want
to speakto Rose for--
Gentlemen, will you please see that
Mr. Dawson gets to where he belongs
and that he stays there?
Yes, sir.
Come along,you.
" Oh, hear us
when we cryto Thee "
" Forthose in peril
on the sea. "
Ruth: And why doyou have
two steering wheels?
We really only use
this near shore.
Excuse me, sir. Another ice warning.
This one's from the Noordam.
Thankyou, Sparks.
Oh, not to worry.
Quite normal forthis time ofyear.
In fact, we're speeding up.
I'vejust ordered
the last boilers lit.
Man: Okay, son,
wind it up tight like I showed you.
Okay, now, let it go.
- Was good, wasn't it?
- Quite nice.
That's excellent, son.
Rose:
Mr. Andrews, forgive me...
I did the sum in my head
and with the number of lifeboats
times the capacityyou mentioned
forgive me, but it seems that there
are not enough for everyone aboard.
About half, actually.
Rose,you miss nothing, doyou?
ln fact, I put in these new type davits
which can take an extra row
of boats inside this one
but it was thought by some
that the deckwould looktoo cluttered
so I was overruled.
Waste ofdeck space as it is
on an unsinkable ship.
Sleep soundly,young Rose. I have built
you a good ship, strong and true.
She's all the lifeboatyou need.
Just keep heading aft.
The next stop will be the engine room.
Come on.
Jack, this is impossible.
I can't seeyou.
- I need to talktoyou.
- No,Jack, no.
Jack, I'm engaged.
I'm marrying Cal.
I love Cal.
Rose,you're no picnic.
All right,you're a spoiled
little brat, even
but underthatyou're the most
amazingly astounding
wonderful girl-- woman--
that I've ever known and...
-Jack, l...
- No, let me try and get this out.
You're,you're ama--
I'm not an idiot.
I know how the world works.
I've got ten bucks
in my pocket.
I have nothing to offeryou
and I know that.
I understand.
But I'm too involved now.
Youjump, I jump, remember?
I can't turn away
without knowingyou'll be all right.
That's all that I want.
Well, I'm fine.
I'll be fine, really.
Really?
I don't think so.
They've gotyou trapped, Rose
and you're going to die
ifyou don't breakfree--
Maybe not right away
becauseyou're strong, but
sooner or laterthat fire
that I love aboutyou, Rose...
that fire is going to burn out.
It's not up toyou
to save me,Jack.
You're right.
Onlyyou can do that.
I'm going back.
Leave me alone.
Countess: Tell Lucille about the
disasteryou had with the stationer's.
Well, ofcourse, the invitations
had to be sent back twice.
- Oh, my dear!
- And the dreadful bridesmaid's gowns--
Let me tell you what an odyssey
that has been.
Rose decided
she wanted lavender.
She knows I detest the color,
so she did it onlyto spite me.
Lucille:
lfonlyyou'd come to me sooner.
Ruth saw some of my designs
in "La Mode Illustree."
Theywere forTrousseau ofthe Duchess
of Malborough'syoungest daughter.
Theywere quite charming, but I think
you'll agree, my dear, that together
we've created something ofa phoenix
from the ashes.
( Women Laugh Politely)
Hello,Jack.
I changed my mind.
- They said you might be--
- Shh.
Give meyour hand.
Now closeyour eyes.
Go on.
Step up.
Now hold on to the railing.
- Keepyour eyes closed, don't peek.
- I'm not.
Step up onto the rail.
Hold on. Hold on.
Keepyour eyes closed.
- ( Giggles)
- Doyou trust me?
I trustyou.
All right, open your eyes.
I'm flying!Jack!
( Softly):
" Come,Josephine, myflying machine "
" Going up, she goes "
" Up, she goes... "
That was the last time Titanic
ever saw daylight.
So we're up to dusk
the night ofthe sinking.
- Six hours to go.
- Incredible.
There's Smith and he's standing there
and he's got the iceberg warning...
in his fucking hand-- excuse me--
his hand, and he's ordering more speed.
26years ofexperience
working against him.
He figures anything big enough
to sinkthe ship
they're going to see
in time to turn
but the ship's too big
with too small a rudder.
Doesn't cornerworth a damn.
Everything he knows is wrong.
( Laughing)
It's quite proper, I assureyou.
This is the sitting room.
- Will this light do?
- What?
Don't artists need good light?
( ln French Accent):
That is true
but I'm not used to working
in such horrible conditions.
Monet!
- Doyou know his work?
- Ofcourse.
Look at his use ofcolor here.
Isn't he great?
I know, it's extraordinary.
Cal insists on carting
this hideous thing everywhere.
Should we be expecting him
anytime soon?
Not as long as the cigars
and brandy hold out.
- That's nice.
- What is it, a sapphire?
A diamond,
a very rare diamond.
Jack, I wantyou to draw me like one
ofyour French girls... wearing this.
All right.
Wearing onlythis.
The last thing I need
is another picture of me
Iooking like a porcelain doll.
As a paying customer...
I expect to get what I want.
Over on the bed--
the couch.
Go... Iie down.
- Tell me when it looks right.
- Putyour arm backthe way it was.
Right.
Put that other arm up,
that hand right byyourface there.
Right.
Now, head down.
Eyes to me,
keep them on me.
And tryto stay still.
( Exhales)
So serious.
I believeyou are blushing,
Mr. Big Artiste.
I can't imagine
Monsieur Monet blushing.
He does landscapes.
Just relaxyourface.
- Sorry.
- No laughing.
( Exhales)
My heart was pounding
the whole time.
It was the most erotic moment
of my life.
Up until then, at least.
- So what happened next?
- You mean, did we do it?
Sorry, to disappointyou,
Mr. Bodine.
Jackwas very professional.
Thankyou.
( RoseLaughing)
Whatyou doing?
Will you put this back
in the safe for me?
Mm-hmm.
Would you excuse me?
- None ofthe stewards have seen her.
- This is absurd.
It's a ship, there's only
so many places she could be.
Lovejoy, find her.
- Clear.
- Yes.
I don't think I've ever seen
such a flat calm.
Like a mill pond.
Not a breath ofwind.
It will make the bergs
harderto see
with no breaking water
at the base.
Hmm.
Well, I'm off. Maintain speed
and heading, Mr. Lightoller.
Yes, sir.
It's getting cold.
You look nice.
- ( KnockAtDoor)
- Lovejoy: Miss Rose?
My drawings!
( DoorCloses)
Come on!
- No, wait, wait!
- Wait, wait, wait!
Go, go! Down, down!
Rose:
Quickly, quickly!
( Giggling)
Bye!
- Sorry!
- ( Giggling)
- It's all right!
- ( Laughing)
Prettytough for a valet,
this fellow.
- Seems more like a cop.
- I think he was.
-Jack: Oh, shit.
- ( RoseScreams)
No, over here!
Quick!
( BoilerBlasting)
- Now what?!
- What?!
Hold up! What'reyou two
doing down here?
You shouldn't be down here!
It could be dangerous!
Jack: Carry on! Don't mind us.
You're doing a greatjob!
Keep up the good work!
Ah, lookwhat
we have here, huh?
( Rose Clears Throat)
Thankyou.
- ( Honks Horn )
- Where to, miss?
To the stars.
You nervous?
No.
Putyour hands on me,Jack.
Crewman:
God, it's bloody cold.
You know, I can smell ice,
you know, when it's near.
- Bollocks.
- But I can, all right!
Murdoch: Did you everfind
those binoculars forthe lookouts?
Haven't seen them
since Southampton.
Well, I'll be on my rounds.
Cheerio.
You're trembling.
Don't worry.
I'll be all right.
- They ran down there.
- Right.
Lovejoy:
Anything missing?
I've got a better idea.
Gotcha!
( RoseLaughing)
( Laughing)
Did you see those guys' faces?
Did you see the...
When the ship docks...
I'm getting offwith you.
This is crazy.
I know.
It doesn't make any sense.
That's why I trust it.
( Quietly):
Oh,yes. Here, look at this.
Oh, look at that, would you?
- They're a bit warmerthan we are.
- Well, ifthat's what it takes
for us to get warmer I'd rather not,
if it's all the same toyou.
- Bugger me!
- ( Alarm Bell Clanging)
- ( PhoneRings)
- Pick up,you bastards!
( PhoneRinging)
- Is there anyone there?
- Yes, what doyou see?
- Iceberg! Right ahead!
- Thankyou.
Iceberg! Right ahead!
Hard to starboard!
Crewman:
- ( Ringing)
- Crewman: Turn, turn! Steady!
- ( Bell Clangs )
Full astern!
- Hard over.
- Helm's hard over, sir.
- ( Ringing)
- Go, lads! Go!
( Men Yelling OutOrders)
Shut all the dampers!
Shut them!
( DampersSlamming)
Hold it.
Hold it!
Now, engage
the reversing engine!
( EngineStops)
( EngineRestarts)
Why aren't theyturning?!
- Is it hard over?!
- Crewman: It is,yes, sir, hard over!
( Softly):
Come on, come on, come on.
Turn.
Yes.
It's going to hit!
Jesus Christ.
( Glass Tinkling)
- ( Softly):Jesus.
- Hard to port!
Crewman:
Hard to port!
( MenScreaming)
Get back!
( Screaming)
- ( Hissing)
- ( Screams)
- ( MetaIDoors Closing)
- Come on, let's go!
Get out the door!
They're closing the doors! Get out!
Get out! Get out! Get out!
Get out the door! Go on!
Go on! Come on, lads!
Go, lads, go!
Get out!
( Screams)
( DoorsSlamming)
( Softly): Oh, my God.
That was a close shave, weren't it?
Smell ice, can you?
Bleeding Christ.
Note the time
and enter it in the log.
What was that, Mr. Murdoch?
An iceberg, sir.
I put her hard to starboard
and ran the engines full astern
but it was too close.
I tried to port round it
but she hit and the...
- Close the watertight doors.
- Murdoch: The doors are closed, sir.
- All stop.
- Crewman: Aye, sir!
( Ringing)
Find the carpenter.
Get him to sound the ship.
Yes, sir!
Fabrizio:
Porca puttana!
Che cazzo e?
Come on, let's get the hell
out of here! Come on, hurry up.
Excuse me. Why have the engines stopped?
I felt a shudder.
I shouldn't worry, madam.
We've likelythrown a propeller blade.
That's the shudderyou felt.
May I bringyou anything?
No, thankyou.
Man:
Did you see anything?
I don't see anything now, doyou?
( Commotion)
Ifthis is the direction the rats
are going that's good enough for me.
Crewman: Please, sir, please.
Everything's under control.
- You there.
- Sir, there is no emergency.
- Yes, there is, I have been robbed.
- Get the master-at-arms.
- Now,you moron!
- Yes, sir.
( Men Laughing)
Hey,you're going to miss the fun.
Did you see what happened?
No, I missed it.
Apparently, it hit overthere.
Crewman: Boiler room six
is flooded eight feet above the plate.
And the mail hold is worse. She's
all buckled in in the forward hold.
- Can you shore up?
- Not unless the pumps get ahead.
Haveyou seen the damage
in the mail hold?
- No, she's already underwater.
- This is bad.
We should tell
Mother and Cal.
I thinkthey're very good, sir.
Don't touch anything.
I want the entire room photographed.
Rose:
Just keep holding my hand.
We've been looking
foryou, miss.
Rose ( Sighs):
Well, here we go.
Something serious has happened.
Yes, it has.
Indeed. Two things dearto me
have disappeared this evening.
Now that one is back I have a pretty
good idea where to find the other.
- Search him.
- Takeyour coat off, sir.
- Now what?
- Come on.
Cal, what areyou doing? We're in the
middle ofan emergency. What's going on?
- Is this it?
- That's it.
This is horseshit!
- Don'tyou believe it, Rose. Don't!
- He couldn't have.
Ofcourse he could.
It's easy enough for a professional.
But I was with him the whole time.
This is absurd.
Perhaps he did it whileyou were putting
your clothes back on, dear.
Real slick, Cal.
Rose, they put it in my pocket.
- Shut up.
- It isn't even your pocket, is it, son?
Property ofA. L. Ryerson.
- That was reported stolen today.
- I just borrowed it.
- I was going to return it.
- We have an honest thief here, do we?
You know I didn't do this, Rose.
You know it.
Don'tyou believe them, Rose.
You know I didn't do it.
- Come on, let's go.
- You know I didn't do it, Rose. Rose!
Come on, son.
There's a good lad.
- Come on.
- You know I didn't do it! You know me!
Ismay:
Most unfortunate, Captain.
Water... 1 4 feet above
the keel in ten minutes--
In the forepeak, in all three holds
and in the boiler room six.
- That's right, sir.
- When can we get underway, damn it?
That's five compartments.
She can stay afloat with the first
four compartments breached
but not five-- not five.
As she goes down bythe head
the water
will spill overthe tops of bulkheads
at E deckfrom one to the next.
Back and back.
There's no stopping it.
The pumps--
Ifwe opened the doors--
The pumps buyyou time,
but minutes only.
From this moment,
no matterwhat we do
Titanicwill founder.
But this ship can't sink.
She's made of iron, sir.
I assureyou, she can...
and she will.
It is a mathematical certainty.
How much time?
An hour. Two at most.
And how many aboard,
Mr. Murdoch?
2,200 souls on board, sir.
Well, I believeyou may get
your headlines, Mr. Ismay.
Oh, it is a little slut, isn't it? Will
you look at me when I'm talking toyou.
( KnockAtDoor)
- Mr. Hockley?
- Not now, we're busy.
Sir, I've been told to askyou to please
put on your lifebelts and come up to--
I said not now.
I'm sorryto inconvenienceyou,
Mr. Hockley, but it's Captain's orders.
Now, please, dress warmly.
It's quite cold out tonight.
Now, may I suggest
topcoats and hats.
- This is ridiculous.
- Not to worry, miss.
I am sure
it'sjust a precaution.
Everybody up!
Lifebelts on!
- ( MenScreaming Orders)
- What's heyelling about?
Everybody up!
Putyour lifebelts on!
- What's the ruckus?
-Just putyour lifebelts on!
Crewman:
C.QD.?
Sir?
That's right-- C.QD.
The distress call.
That's our position.
( Sighs)
Tell whoever responds
that we're going down bythe head.
We need immediate assistance.
Blimey.
Keep lowering!
( Crewman Yelling OutOrders)
Mr. Wilde! Mr. Wilde,
where are the passengers?
We moved them back inside.
It's too damn cold and noisyforthem.
You there!
(Blows Whistle)
Get down here and
help with these lines.
( Orchestra Playing
"Alexander's RagtimeBand")
( People Conversing)
Care for a drink, sir?
- Crewman: Please putyour lifebelts on.
- Hey, sonny, what's doing?
You got us all trussed up here
and now we're cooling our heels.
Sorry, ma'am.
Let me go and find out.
I don't think anybody knows
what the hell's going on around here.
It's the goddamned English
doing everything bythe book.
There's no need for language,
Mr. Hockley.
Go back and turn
the heaters on in our rooms.
I'd like a cup oftea
when I return.
Yes, ma'am.
Mr. Andrews.
I saw the iceberg
and I see it in your eyes.
Please tell me the truth.
The ship will sink.
- You're certain.
- Yes, in an hour or so....
all this will be
at the bottom ofthe Atlantic.
- What?
- Please, tell onlywhoyou must?
I don't want to
be responsible for a panic
and get to a boat quickly,
don't wait.
You rememberwhat I told you
about the boats?
Yes.
I understand.
Over here, sir.
Sir, they need you
up in the second-class purser's office.
- There's a big mob up there.
- Go on, I'll keep an eye on him.
Aye, right.
Sir! Carpathia says
they're making 1 7 knots.
Full steam forthem, sir.
She's the only one responding?
The only one close, sir.
She says they can be here in four hours.
Four hours?
Thankyou, Bride.
( Softly):
My God.
( Crewmen Yelling OutOrders)
Sir! We are swung out
and ready, sir.
Hadn't we better get the women
and children into the boat, sir?
- Yes, we do.
- Sir?
Women and children first. Yes.
Yes, sir.
Crewman ( Yelling): Ladies
and gentlemen,your attention please!
Step this way, please.
That's right.
Come towards me.
Thankyou. Good.
Forthe time being, I shall require
onlywomen and children.
Man:
Right here.
All right, boys,
like the captain said
nice and cheery
so there's no panic.
"Wedding Dance."
( Orchestra BeginsPlaying)
Lifebelts on!
Here, putyour lifebelts on.
Putyour lifebelts on.
Here, putyour lifebelt on.
Here, come on, here.
( Commotion)
Crewman: It isn't time
to go up to the boatsyet.
Please stay calm.
Look, please, make sure, everybody,
you've gotyour lifebelts on
and gentlemen, allow the women
and children through to the front.
- What are we doing, Mommy?
- We'rejust waiting, dear.
When they're finished putting
the first-class people in the boats...
they'll start with us and
we'll want to be all ready, won't we?
( MenArguing)
Go and get some help.
Lower away!
Left and right together!
Steady! Both sides together.
Steady! Steady!
Steady!
Stop! Stop!
- ( Screaming)
- Hold the left side! Right side only!
Right side only!
Hold the left side!
Right side down!
Lower awaytogether!
Steady, lads!
( Explosion)
( Passengers Gasp )
You know, I do believe
this ship may sink.
I've been asked to giveyou
this small token
ofour appreciation.
Compliments of
Mr. Caledon Hockley.
Come on, sister,you heard
the man-- into the boat.
Any room for a gentleman,
gentlemen?
Crewman:
Onlywomen at this time, sir.
Will the lifeboats be seated
according to class?
I hope they're
not too crowded.
Oh, Mother, shut up!
Don'tyou understand? The water is
freezing and there aren't enough boats.
Not enough by half. Halfthe people
on this ship are going to die.
Not the better half.
Come on, Ruth, get in the boat.
First-class seats are right up here.
You know, it's a pity
I didn't keep that drawing.
It'll be worth
a lot more by morning.
You unimaginable bastard.
Molly: Come on, Rose, darling.
There's plenty of room foryou.
Come on, Rose.
You're next, darling.
Come into the boat, Rose.
- Come.
- Rose, get into the boat.
Rose.
Good-bye, Mother.
Rose! Rose, come back here!
Where areyou going?
To him?
To be a whore to a gutter rat?
I'd rather be his whore
than yourwife.
No. No!
- I said no!
- ( Hawking)
Ruth:
Rose! Please stop!
Crewman:
And lower away!
- Rose!
- Man the tiller!
- No, wait!
- Lower away!
- Rose!
- Lowertogether!
Help!
Can anybody hear me?
( BangingPipe)
Hello, help me!
( Distantly):
Help me!
Can anybody hear me?
Somebody help me, please!
Rose:
Mr. Andrews?
- Steward, checkthe starboard corridor.
- Yes, Mr. Andrews.
Madam, please put on a lifebelt.
Get to the boat deck immediately.
Lucy, for God's sake,
put on your lifebelt.
- Set a good example.
- Yes, sir.
- Anyone in here?
- Mr. Andrews? Mr. Andrews, thank God.
Where would the master-at-arms
take someone under arrest?
What? You have to get
to a boat right away.
No! I'm doing this with orwithoutyour
help, sir, but without will take longer.
Take the elevatorto the bottom. Go
to the left down the crewman's passage.
Then go right and left again at the
stairs. You'll come to a long corridor.
- This could be bad.
- (WaterGurgling)
Oh, shit. Oh, shit!
( Struggling)
- Excuse me, thankyou.
- Crewman: The lifts are closed.
- Woman: I do not care...
- The lifts are--
I'm sorry, miss,
but the lifts are closed.
I'm through being polite, goddamn it!
Now take me down!
E deck.
Come on. Oh, come on.
( Yells)
( Screams)
- I'm going back up!
- No!
No, no!
Come back!
I'm going back up.
I'm going back up!
Crew passage.
( BreathingHard)
Jack?
Jack?!
-Jack?
- Rose!
Jack?!
Rose, I'm in here!
I'm in here.
-Jack?!
- I'm in here.
- Rose!
Jack!Jack! I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
- That guy Lovejoy put it in my pocket.
- I know, I know, I know, I know.
Listen, Rose,you're going to have
to find a spare key, all right?
Look in that cabinet
right there.
It's a little
silver one, Rose.
Silver.
- These are all brass ones!
- Check right here, Rose.
Rose...
how did you find out
I didn't do it?
I didn't.
I just realized I already knew.
- Keep looking.
- Oh.
No key. There's no key!
All right, Rose, listen. You're going
to have to go find some help.
It'll be all right.
I'll be right back.
I'lljust wait here.
Hello, is there anyone here?
Hello? ls there anybody
down here?
We need help! Hello!
Damn it.
Can anybody hear me?
Please, hello! Hello!
Oh, thank God.
Wait, please, I need your help.
There's a man back here and--
Wait!
Hello?
( LoudRumbling)
( RoseBreathingHard)
- Hello?
- Ah, miss,you shouldn't be here now.
- Please, I need your help.
- This way, quickly.
There is a man down here
and he is trapped. Please.
- There's no need to panic.
- No, I'm not panicking.
You're going the wrong way!
Let go of me, listen!
- To hell with you.
- Oh!
( Ship Creaking)
( Softly):
Oh, my God...
- ( Explosion)
- ( Crackling)
( Gasping)
( LoudRumbling)
-Jack!
- Rose!
- Will this work?
- I guess we'll find out.
Come on.
Wait, wait, wait, wait. Try a couple
of practice swings overthere.
All right.
Good, now tryto hit
the same mark again, Rose.
You can do it.
Okay, that's enough practice.
Come on, Rose,
you can do it. Listen.
Just hit it really hard
and reallyfast.
Wait, open your hands up
a little more.
- Like that?
- Right.
Listen, Rose, I trustyou.
Go!
-( Clang)
-( Gasps)
( ScreamingAndLaughing)
You did it!
Come on, let's go.
Oh, shit, this is cold.
Oh, shit!
Shit, shit.
- This is the way out.
- We have to find anotherway. Come on.
- Tiller: Pull.
- (Orchestra Playing)
Pull!
Putyour backs into it, pull!
( DistantShouting)
Pull!
Now, there's something
you don't see every day.
Pull!
( DistantExplosion)
( Shouting)
Crewman:
What's this luggage doing here?
- Get rid of it, we need the room.
- (Crewman Giving Orders)
( Crying)
Keep calm.
No!
-Lovejoy.
-She's not on the starboard side either.
We're running out oftime
and this strutting martinet
isn't letting
any men on at all.
There's one on the other side
letting men on.
Well, then, that's our play. We'll need
some insurance first. Come on.
- ( Pounding)
- This way.
- All the way down here.
- (Jack Yelling)
Steward:
Here! What doyou thinkyou're doing?
You'll have to payforthat,you know.
That's White Star Line property.
Both:
Shut up!
Will you hold the boat a moment?
I just have to run backto my room--
Sit down! She's the last.
All right to lower.
Mr. Lightoller, why are the boats
being launched halffull?
- Not now, Mr. Andrews.
- There, look, 20 or so
in a boat built for 65,
and I saw one boat with only 1 2-- 1 2!
Well, we weren't sure ofthe weight,
Mr. Andrews. These boats may buckle.
Rubbish! Theywere tested in Belfast
with the weight of70 men!
Now, fill these boats,
Mr. Lightoller, for God's sake, man!
Please, I need more women
and children, please.
Crewman: Get back in there.
This is not an exit.
Get back in there.
You can't keep us locked in here like
animals. The ship's bloody sinking!