Thirteen... fourteen...
Comin' to getcha!
Fifteen...
sixteen...
seventeen, eighteen,
nineteen, twenty.
Ready or not, here I come!
What do you
make of the news, uh,
55 cents a share they're gonna
report for the first quarter.
Sync by fant0m
www.addic7ed.com
American Policy Institute.
How may I help you?
One moment.
Well, five down.
What do lucky lepidoptera
larvae eat?
Oh... Lepidoptera larvae eat
clover, among other plants.
If they're lucky...
Four-leaf clover.
Uh-huh. Well...
No, uh-uh.
I need 19 letters.
Try the Gaelic.
Yeah. Which is?
I don't know. The only Gaelic
I know is Pog mo thoin.
What does that mean?
Uh, try Latin.
Uh, marsilea
quadrifolia.
Marsi... yes.
Mm-hmm. That'll work. There you go.
Why do I drive myself crazy?
Keep it.
Hi, David.
Uh, watch that number.
So, how are we feeling?
I'm-I'm fine.
Fine. You?
What day is today, Will?
Wednesday?
Yeah...
Yeah.
April 8.
My birthday.
Get cracking.
I'm taking you to lunch
in four hours.
Maggie, I really...
You forgot to
bring the donuts.
Shit.
Sorry.
Getting the donuts is
your most important job.
Good morning,
boys and girls.
Okay.
Last night's intakes.
We got satellite photos
of Grant's favorite
imaginary missile silos.
Well, now...
Better safe
than sorry.
The Iranians are not
currently our best friends.
Miles,
why don't you
take a look at our
brothers in Pakistan?
They've taken a sudden
interest in telemarketing.
Telemarketing?!
Yeah.
Run it through Hal.
Will...
want to take another run
at Yuri the missile salesman?
Not without more financials.
He's running everything
through the Caymans...
Well, seems CIA borrowed
his briefcase yesterday,
and it's just full
of bank statements.
And last,
but not least, Tanya,
as our newest member,
you, of course, get
the most difficult
and tedious
of the day's intake.
Thank you.
Read it and weep.
...weapons, organizational
structure...
This will take me...
the rest of my life.
Ugh! I...
I need your help.
Will's help.
I'm just pitching in.
Yeah. All right.
Lanarca,
Seville, Ajaccio
all have fountains
in their main public square,
but not Dubrovnik.
Uh, Dubrovnik and Lanarca
have university hospitals,
but not Seville
and Ajaccio.
I mean, what-what, what
the hell's the pattern?
This is the Malaysian cipher?
Yeah.
Maybe some kind
of syllae algorithm?
Yeah, yeah,
I tried that.
Even Hal
drew a blank.
They were all part
of the Roman Empire.
They all have Palearctic
Mediterranean rain forest
and are part
of the chapparal biome;
they're all
in countries that spend
less than five percent
of their GDP on the military,
but maybe we are asking
the wrong question.
You're looking at the past
and the present.
What about the future?
Itinerary possibly?
Let's go.
Up and out. Lunch.
Can I take a rain check?
I knew it.
I-I... I'm...
I have so much
work to do, I just...
Rain check then.
I'm not giving up.
What's with the broom?
Um...
Mitchell was sweeping up the
other night as I was leaving.
He brushed against my foot
w"by accident.
Let me guess.
Ten years bad luck?
Worse. Much worse.
Brings imprisonment or death.
The only way around it is
to spit on the broom,
so I bought it from him
and did what I had to do.
It's ridiculous, I know.
David, I, um...
I think I found a pattern
in the big ticket papers.
There might be others...
I'm not sure...
but it's not just
the repetition.
Three down.
Two chambers
of the legislative branch.
Bicameral. Simple enough.
Two across... Fillmore,
where the Warlocks,
later known
as the Grateful Dead,
played in San Francisco.
But also,
Millard Fillmore...
lard-ass, know-nothing
13th President.
The executive. Four down...
would-be alma mater
of felonious record-holding
wide receiver.
Answer: Marshall,
as in Randy Moss,
Marshall University
Thundering Herd.
But also, Thurgood
Marshall, judicial.
Five down.
What do lucky
lepidoptera larvae eat?
Answer: marsilea
quadrifolia.
Which is? Four-leaf clover.
Our three branches
of government are here...
legislative,
executive, judicial.
What or who does
that fourth leaf represent?
And what's
the message?
I've seen this before.
Crossword editors,
quirky sense of humor.
Probably some kind of inside
joke. No, no, no, no, no.
I've done my share
of crosswords, and I've never
seen anything
quite like this. I mean...
I can see why this
caught your eye.
Thanks, Will.
American Policy Institute.
How may I help you?
80 years of work
to build a business,
five hours of trading
to put it on life support.
All from a few
artfully chosen words.
It's a thing of beauty.
Something
in the crossword today.
I've never seen
anything like it.
Crossword?
Which paper?
All the indicators.
Someone either
didn't expect
the pattern to be caught,
or wasn't afraid if it was.
Anybody else see this?
Internally? No.
Good catch.
Why cereal for lunch?
Cornflakes,
specifically.
Every day.
Spangler's a man of habits.
Have you ever
talked to him?
I bumped into
him once, and, uh...
...said I'm sorry.
This is
inedible.
So, tell me something.
Why is Will Travers
so mopey?
He's not mopey.
He's, well, just introspective.
He walks around every day
looking like his
favorite cat just died.
Try wife and child.
Try 9/11.
Morning of, he was supposed
to meet his wife and daughter
at the top
of the World Trade Center.
A surprise
for his daughter's birthday.
He was late.
He was always late.
He was coming out of the subway
when the first plane hit
the tower.
And he's never been late
for anything since.
I'll have the same.
Uh, for both of them.
Happy birthday.
Thank you, David.
So,
uh, I want you to know
I'm almost done
with a first draft
on the Nigeria thing.
Good. How is it?
It's what you asked for.
We're dealing with the
hypotheticals of instability,
but I think
the more interesting story is
in the infant democracy.
What's the big
picture here?
You'll know soon enough.
And how's Miles doing
with North Korea?
You know what
the biggest joke is here?
It's my business,
our business,
to tell people
what to think.
And the truth is,
I have no idea
what to think anymore.
About what?
This.
What we do.
Happy birthday.
Road food!
Well!
You reading
minds these days?
Look, I don't blame you
for taking stock
and weighing your options.
With a workload
like yours...
No, it's not that.
I don't work too much.
It's just that
when I leave,
I can't talk to
anybody about it.
That's the hdest thing
in this job,
you know, keeping secrets.
What... What are your
birthday plans tonight?
Count the minutes
till it's over.
No. No, no, no.
Why don't you...
Why don't you come
and eat dinner with us?
No.
Huh? Why not?
Days like these I...
I used to spend
with Natalie
and Shauny.
I miss 'em too much.
I do, too.
But they're gone, Will.
They're gone,
and that's just something
both of us have to accept.
This goes with the book.
Don't open it
till you get home.
David.
David, your Norton? Uh, it's...
Are you crazy?
I can't keep this.
You're smiling.
I can hear you smiling, Will.
You're keeping it.
The bike, the note.
Why-Why now?
I'll tell you in the morning.
I'm catching the 5:51
out of Putnam Station.
Meet me at the Annex Bar.
I'll see you there.
Oh, wait. Wait. David...
Which was part
of a firecracker ceremony
that's intended
to scare off bad spirits.
They were very loud
and I enjoyed it very much.
Basically, I learned,
at a very young age, it's part
of your culture and heritage,
so it's very important.
Thomas K. Rhumor died
in his sleep
last night at the age of 64.
I'm writing.
I'm fine.
Rhumor was a self-made
billionaire whose philanthropy
focused here at home
on the needs
of the underprivileged.
And we go back now
to the breaking news story...
we just told you about.
Wow. you see this?
We're getting
the first pictures...
Damn shame.
...of a train crash
that's taken place
just outside of Putnam Station
on the Fairchester line.
Emergency crews are
on the scene.
Early reports indicate
multiple fatalities.
But what I admired most
about my friend was his loyalty.
We all slept a little
better knowing that someone
with his integrity
was in our lives.
He was a devoted
husband to Joan,
father-in-law to Will,
father to Anna, Kevin
and Natalie,
God rest her soul.
David was an affirming
flame, and we
should all feel
grateful for having known him.
Will...
I know. I know.
It's okay. It's okay.
I am so sorry, Will.
So am I.
You spoke
eloquently.
Thank you,
Ms. Young.
I'll catch up.
We have something pressing
to discuss, Will.
David's position
was far too integral
to leave open for
even a week or a month
good decorum
would demand.
So I'd like to put off this
conversation, but I can't.
People I answer to,
upstairs and elsewhere,
are, uh... eager
for resolution.
I'd like you to step
into his position.
Well, I'd say I'm better off
staying where I am,
but I don't know
if that's true anymore.
It might be best
for me to leave.
I expected that.
Well, take a couple of
days to think it over.
If your mind
doesn't change,
I'll accept that answer
and your resignation.
Knight to king's bishop three.
Who is this?
Let me talk to David.
Where's David?
Uh, no, uh...
There was an accident.
Are you Ed Bancroft?
My-My name is Will Travers.
I answered the phone
when you called David's office.
May I come inside
and speak to you for a moment?
David's been killed.
He died in a train accident
on his way to work.
Can I get you some tea?
No, thank you.
I'm addicted to Earl Grey.
Sit.
David said
you were very bright.
One of the best
in the building.
That true?
I keep up.
I'll never be a
legend like you.
What does the legend
say about me?
You were a genius
at cracking codes,
until the codes
cracked you like an egg.
Like an egg.
Not my metaphor.
David was the only one
who stayed in touch.
We played
our endless chess games.
Talked.
I really can't believe
he's dead.
He was very fond of you.
You never broke his heart
like that idiot son of his,
up in Vermont.
Evan's troubled.
He's a nut.
Ed... I need
to show you something.
Haveou...
you ever seeany?
Four crossword puzzles
shared across
several newspapers.
No.
This is new to me.
Sorry.
They showed up
the day before David died.
Coincidence?
It was nice
to meet you, Will.
I'm feeling very tired.
You can let yourself out.
Right.
Good night.
Sorry to wake you.
I didn't know where else to go.
I know how this is going to
sound, but all his rituals,
his rituals, how
superstitious he was...
Slow down.
His biggest phobia by far was 13.
I mean, he respected
and feared it,
he constantly
watched out for it.
He would
never get on a boat,
an elevator, train,
a boat, a taxi...
Will, can you
lower your voice?
...or train that started
or ended with 13,
was divisible by 13,
aggregated to 13...
Will... Will, your voice.
They haven't... they haven't
retrieved his car yet.
His car is still there
at the train depot
where he left it.
Where he supposedly left it.
Supposedly?
It was parked
in spot 13.
Well, maybe he didn't
see the number.
He saw it.
Well, maybe he just
needed to get to work,
he saw the train coming up,
and he took the only spot
that was there. No, no, no.
There's no way David Hadas would
have parked in that spot.
So if he didn't
park in the spot...
Then he didn't get on the train.
But his remains
were identified.
I know that.
So, how were they found there
in the wreckage?
I don't know.
I don't know. I don't know.
What happened was horrible,
but it happened.
He's gone.
He boarded the train,
and it crashed.
He died with 36 strangers.
Maybe there is no why.
There's always a why.
Will.
You just don't
understand it.
When's the last time
you had a good night's sleep?
You need to rest.
This is hard.
Yeah.
Mommy?
I'm-I'm sorry.
I'm-I'm so sorry.
I, uh...
Did you get any rest?
I'm sorry about last night.
Is your daughter,
is she...?
Uh, she-she's fine.
What's that?
My resignation.
Don't worry,
I won't be here, but your life
isn't going to change much.
You don't call working
for Grant Test a change?
You know they're gonna put him in
David's job the minute you turn it down.
And where are you going?
Away.
I'm going away.
You can't resign.
Why not?
Because I would have
to work for Grant.
Glory has its price.
I'm serious.
You can't quit. You do
not have that option.
Sure I do.
No, you don't.
It was my birthday
last week.
I had no idea.
Maggie reminded me.
Yeah, I forget stuff
all the time. So what?
Your own birthday?
We all get
a little preoccupied.
It goes without saying.
It is the nature
of the job.
Miles, this place is a tomb.
I'm really sorry
about David.
I... know what
he meant to you.
I know he brought
you here.
And I... I know he
took care of you.
But I really don't think
that he would want you to quit.
I'm not so sure about that.
I think that he would want
you to pick up the torch.
Go away.
Well, if nothing else,
stay for David.
What changed your mind?
You know what? I don't care.
Let's introduce
you upstairs.
The last time was
just plain embarrassing.
Well, you can't bring that kind
of stuff home with you.
Yeah, leave it
at work, please.
Oh, what, me?
All right, look,
I'm hanging up now.
Yes, I am.
Mr. Spangler got called
down to Washington.
He wants to meet you
tomorrow morning.
9:00 sharp.
Old one, please.
This is your new
security agreement.
You'll be cleared to
a higher level: G5.
Sign here, here...
...and here.
Anybody double-check
that Tom is actually dead?
He blew his
brains out.
I saw his body,
for God's sake.
Good.
We're back on track.
Sync by fant0m
www.addic7ed.com