"When I die, will I join those stars?"
"You want to be a star?"
"Yes! I mean, my family are up there."
"Right."
"I want to become a pretty star."
"if you want to become a star,
you must live first."
"What does it mean to live?"
"To live is to have hope."
"Hope?"
"You can't live without hope."
"What if I lose hope?"
"Hope is always there."
"You might just lose sight of it."
"Is this heaven?"
"This is..."
"I wanna die on Monday morn."
"Don't wanna think on Tuesday morn."
"Worst of all is Wednesday morn."
"Feeling alright on Thursday morn."
"Feeling hyped on Friday morn."
He's rapping about me.
"Happiest of all is Saturday morn."
"Then I come down on Sunday morn."
"But life ain't all that bad, is it though?"
Bullshit.
- Good morning!
'Morning.
Time for morning exercises!
Reach your arms out and up,
and stretch your back! Go!
1,2, 3,4!
- 5, 6, 7, 8!
- Arms and legs!
1,2, 3,4!
I had trouble finding a job,
so when this company accepted me, I was elated.
I can't hear you!
5, 6, 7, 8!
Stretch your arms.
I had hopes and dreams, and even ambition.
Like this. This!
Three! A 1,000 yen fine
for every 10 minutes late!
"Company Philosophy"
Three! A 1,000 yen fine
for every 10 minutes late!
Four! Taking leave is unnecessary!
It leads to laziness!
"Prize Money"
Best Salesman Award:
Igarashi!
Yes.
17 new contracts.
Congrats.
Thank you sir!
Applause!
Heading out!
Take care!
Sales is all about results.
I thought I knew that,
but the reality was way harsher.
Aoyama!
Yes.
Daito Advertising just made a complaint.
The logo font's wrong.
But Saito told me to use it...
It's your responsibility!
So you should've checked it!
Yes.
If you want a raise, meet your quota, jerkoff!
Look here.
I gave you the account despite
your sales record because I'm a nice guy.
But you shit on my kindness!
Are you fucking with me?!
N-No sir...
Just go! I said you'd be there in 30 minutes.
Don't you dare be late!
Yes.
I want to contribute to my company.
But lately, when my boss yells at me,
my mind goes blank.
Nakano Shinbashi intersection.
Of course, I pay for taxis myself.
Igarashi.
Yes.
Using your prize money to go on a date tonight?
But seriously, 17 contracts is brilliant.
Make it 20 next month.
Yes.
Bye.
- Goodbye sir!
- Bye.
Oh, Aoyama.
Yes.
I'll take the money
you lost us out of your salary.
Bye.
And compile this month's sales figures for me.
By tomorrow morning.
Yes.
Hang in there.
Goodbye sir!
I've worked over 150 hours overtime
for three months in a row.
But I don't get paid for it.
All I get is my basic salary.
What?
"Oh, Takashi! I finally caught you."
What is it? I'm still working.
"Really? This late?"
Come on, make it quick.
"Well, if there's anything
you want to eat, I'll send it."
Listen, I told you you don't have to anymore.
"It's not such a bother, is it?"
It is. Get the message already.
"Oh...Hey, when are you coming home next?"
Don't ask me that now. I can't say yet.
"I want to eat some nice Tokyo cakes."
Whatever! Gotta go, I'm busy.
"Whenever I call him lately,
he's so irritable."
Work must be stressing him out.
Humor him.
He was only ever able to open up to you.
But...he hasn't been home
for over a year and a half now.
He's busy. Takashi's doing his best.
He'll be fine.
You're right.
Yes, you're right.
"Division Chief Yamagami"
What do... people work for?
If we work just so we can live...
...can I really call this living?
"A train will soon pass through on Track 2."
"Please stand behind the yellow line."
My body feels as heavy as lead.
I want a break.
I want to sleep.
I'm...exhausted.
I hope tomorrow never comes.
Long time no see! It's me! Yamamoto!
From elementary!
Sorry, I...
What a blast from the past! I moved, remember?
I lost touch with everybody!
Wow, this is awesome, yeah?
Let's get a drink!
- Like sashimi?
- Yeah...
Then it's a deal! Talk about a coincidence.
Gotta thank the guy upstairs.
Welcome!
Sit down already.
Er, the bathroom...
Bathroom's out back.
- Beer okay?
- Yes...
- Two drafts.
- Sure. Two drafts.
Hi, it's Aoyama here.
"Oh, Takashi? It's been a while. What's up?"
Well, I know this is sudden,
but do you remember a Yamamoto?
"Yamamoto?"
Yeah. I think he was in our class.
"What year?"
He said he moved away.
"Oh, Kenichi Yamamoto? From Year 3."
Oh, Kenichi Yamamoto!
Yeah, I remember. Kind of quiet.
Hey, the head's gone!
Sorry. It was full.
Yeah? Okay, let's drink to our reunion.
Hey Chef. Sashimi, whale bacon, edamame,
- and fried chicken.
- OK.
Sound good?
How did you recognize me?
You look the same.
Really?
You wouldn't know.
I think you've changed though.
My Osaka accent?
Osaka makes people funny.
Aoyama, watch it. Don't go sayin' that.
Don't think all Osaka people are funny.
It raises expectations too high.
Sorry. It does?
Hey, I'm only funny if you're my straight man.
I can't just say something funny on cue.
That's torture. For real.
Chef! Sardine sashimi.
Hey, remember much about elementary school?
You were with us till Year 3, right?
- Your beers.
- Thanks.
Aoyama, what did you wanna be back then?
- A soccer player.
- Yeah? That's news to me.
Remember "Mura-sen"?
Our homeroom teacher. Black tracksuit.
- Man, that takes me back!
- Me too!
- Murata?
- Murakami.
Murakami! Yeah!
Work around here?
Other side of the station.
Here.
Wow, you're a salesman.
- Phone number?
- Quit grinnin'.
- I wasn't.
Wrong line! Say "You quit grinning"!
Don't leave me hangin'!
Work on your comebacks for next time.
Yeah. Tell me your number.
Yeah. Oh, tell me yours.
Um, 080...
Aoyama!
Huh? What the...
Aoyama, you're up?
Day off, right? We're heading out.
Haul ass, dude.
- Haul ass, dude.
- Um.
Hey. How'd you find my place?
You told me, at the pub.
I did? I don't remember.
You were drunk.
Not that drunk.
Anyway, why were you up that tree?
Didn't know which apartment.
I ain't a stalker!
Remember this? We used to do it in elementary.
Hey, don't do that!
Just get in!
Huh? Hey! Hey!
Stop, it's dangerous! I never did this!
We did! We did!
Yamamoto! It's dangerous! Stop!
This isn't the quiet Yamamoto I knew!
Am I being taken for a ride
by some crazy gay stalker?
This feels great!
No it doesn't! Stop!
Sorry! I can't!
Ow!
Man, that was close!
Idiot! You could've killed us!
What's funny about that?
Check out the sky, Aoyama.
I hadn't looked at the sky for a long time.
I was glad I hadn't died,
and that surprised me.
Had I just forgotten, like Yamamoto said?
We'll pay for it. I mean, he will.
I felt like I was in elementary,
playing with a friend.
Whoa! This one's awesome!
Check it out.
- See?
- No, no way.
It's way cool, man! It suits you.
It's a bit... flashy for sales work.
It's just right. It's an ice-breaker.
Huh? Hey! What are you doing?
Your hair looks better like this.
See? Soft and non-threatening.
His fashion sense and gestures...
Yamamoto, have you entered
the forbidden zone after all?
This is Tuesday. Tuesday red.
And, this is Wednesday...
Sir!
Oh, sorry!
We'll take 'em...all!
N-No no no!
Gotta be fresh and neat in sales.
You also gotta smile, and talk real slow.
But they'll think I'm making fun of them.
They won't. I guarantee it.
They'll think, "He's so comforting!"
Comforting?
Yeah. Like this!
Hey! Hey! What the hell?!
Don't scare me.
- Thank you sir.
- Thanks.
Thank you.
Hey.
How can you know so much about sales?
Oh. A while back,
I worked for a proper company.
A while back? And now?
- I'm a NEET.
- You don't work?
I kinda work part-time.
What about full-time?
I can get by without working full-time.
You know, I can't figure you out.
Good morning.
'Morning. You're early.
You're necktie's different.
Is it strange?
No, it suits you.
I'm glad. I need all the help I can get today.
Kotani Confectionery?
Yes.
Good luck. You've courted them for six months?
It'll be your biggest contract.
Yes. But it's small compared to yours.
Not at all.
It has plenty of potential for growth.
Yes.
Aoyama, you seem different lately.
You look fresher, and you laugh more now.
Oh. Someone made me open my eyes.
A girl?
No, a guy. But he's a bit weird.
If you need help, ask me.
Thank you. Actually, there is one thing.
How do you always win so many contracts?
Well...Maybe because I try
to stay focused at all times.
Stay focused?
How about you?
How are you going to go about it?
Oh, I...
Good question.
I want to provide comfort for my clients.
Good luck.
Yes.
Mr. Noda!
Sorry to bother you. I've brought
sample posters for your new campaign.
So many?
I haven't decided on your company yet.
I'm aware of that. I pleaded with
our designer to create four alternatives.
Let's talk about it over there.
You'd spare your time?!
Well, I felt like having a coffee anyway.
Thank you sir!
For real? Way to go! That's awesome!
Noda, the guy in charge,
said he sensed my passion and sincerity.
That's great.
Now he even tells me stuff.
His grandchild was born last month.
I hope your streak keeps going.
Yamamoto, thanks for everything.
Like what?
I won this contract because of you.
Hell no. It was your talent.
If you hadn't reached out to me then...
Anyway, you're amazing,
recognizing me after so long like that.
Excuse me.
Iwai! Thanks for your help.
"Yeah, about that.
I found Yamamoto's contact details.“
- I already...
- "Yamamoto's in New York now."
"He's a stage director. Amazing, huh?"
Huh? But he's back in Japan now, right?
"No, he isn't. Look him up on Facebook."
Okay. Thanks.
Aoyama? What's up?
"5hrs - New York - Hello!"
"Stage first day today!"
Where were you?
What's that?
What are you sulking for?
Wanna move?
My old classmate is in New York.
Wow.
Don't "wow" me. We weren't classmates.
Oh. You figured it out?
No, at first I thought we were,
but I was wrong.
When did you realize that?
Remember you mentioned your teacher?
Mura-sen?
Yeah. "Hey, he wasn't my teacher!"
Oh man! You knew all along!
Did I?
You wanted to scam me?
Act like a friend and sell me something?
Hell no!
Then why the act?
You were so into it, I couldn't!
- Is Yamamoto your real name?
- Yeah.
First name?
Jun.
Don't believe me? Check this out.
"Driver's License"
"Jun Yamamoto"
Sure enough. Even so...
I look different now, right?
I was working sales back then.
Oh.
It was a mistake at first,
but we're friends now.
Or you don't think of me as a friend
because I wasn't your classmate?
Okay, let's start over. I'm Jun Yamamoto.
I'm Takashi Aoyama.
No secrets between us now.
Can I ask you something?
Do you...like guys?
Hell no! That ain't my style.
Relax, Ta-ka-shi.
Let's drink to our truce.
After our talk, we made a rough draft.
With larger and more readable text.
- It's great.
- It is'?!
- Can you go brighter?
- We can!
Understood. Next time,
I'll bring a sample using the actual paper.
Please do.
Will it take long?
Excuse me.
We'd like three days...
- How about two?
- Sure! Two it is.
Hello, Aoyama here.
"Aoyama, come back!"
"Kotani made a complaint!"
Igarashi, what complaint?
The paper we used isn't the one
they asked for. Mr. Noda was furious.
Was the order correct?
It should've been. I checked it repeatedly.
Did the printers mess it up?
It's happened before. To me too.
No. The purchase order's incorrect.
How? How could I have got it wrong?
Aoyama, get a grip. Let's go see them.
Huh? But Igarashi, it's not your client.
I took their call. I know the situation best.
I'm sorry.
- We're deeply sorry!
I was going to give you the contract, Aoyama.
It's a shame.
- Mr. Noda...
- Aoyama!
I'll talk to Mr. Noda, so wait here.
- But it's my...
- Don't worry!
I'll fix this.
You angered the client, and screwed us.
Igarashi and I had to fix your mess.
What the hell are you trying to do?!
I'm truly sorry!
I thought you'd won a decent contract,
but you put us in the red!
You're just a... piece of...shit!
- Igarashi, come with me.
- Yes.
Yes sir.
I don't mind you fixing his mess,
but you've only made 85% of your monthly quota.
Sorry sir!
You're our ace. If you can't pull your weight,
I'll lose face big time.
Don't worry. I'll make up for it
before the deadline.
Really?
Yes sir.
You'd better.
Oh no!
I've got to take a client to dinner. Oh no...
Thanks to you, I'm late!
Goodbye sir!
Aoyama, that's enough for today. Go home.
But...
Do what your senior says.
Yes.
Igarashi?
I'm truly sorry. I'll go home now.
Bye now.
Goodbye.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
"Print Order Management System"
I'll take the first train tomorrow.
First I'll go and apologize to Mr. Noda again,
and to Igarashi too.
I've got to get some sleep. I want to sleep.
Sleep should make me feel better.
I want to sleep.
Calm down. Calm down.
It'll be okay. It'll be okay.
Okay.
Where are you going?
To Kotani, with a new...
Who said you could?
Kotani is in Igarashi's hands now.
What?
Don't "what" me. What did you expect?!
Give her the new contract. Now!
Yes.
- Get it done.
- Yes.
I'm sorry. I hope it goes well.
I'll do the rounds.
Didn't you hear me?!
Letting you go out is bad for the company.
Look.
They were all working happily,
till you sapped their motivation.
Right, Taguchi? Sorry pal.
Happy? Happy?
Apologize!
Apologize to everybody here!
I'm sorry.
No no no no. Huh? Hey you.
If you were really sorry,
you'd get down on your knees. It's courtesy!
Sir! That's...Aoyama has apologized enough.
Igarashi?
- Igarashi?
- Yes.
Never mind protecting him.
Go to Kotani and fix this retard's mess.
I'm sorry. I'm truly sorry.
What are you mumbling?
I'm sorry! I'm truly sorry!
Again.
Again!
I'm sorry! I'm truly sorry!
Again.
Wait right there.
Keep going!
I'm sorry! I'm truly sorry!
Aoyama...
Aoyama! The boss has gone.
You can lift your head now.
I'm truly sorry...
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
That ain't cool, Takashi.
Yamamoto?
You ain't answering my emails or phone calls.
That's cold, dude.
Sorry.
I'm so lonely I could cry. Let's go.
- I don't...
- Don't what?
Want to drink.
Huh? You shoulda said so.
- Today is...
- Yeah yeah, I know!
You can relax here without drinking.
Beer? I mean, coffee?
They got a helluva menu here.
The pasta looks great!
And the pizzas. Carbonara. Gorgon pasta.
Gorgon pizza, penne, and gnocchi too!
Hey Takashi. Which gorgon do you want?
Whatever.
Yeah? What's a "beef ajillo"?
Okay, french fries it is.
Maybe I will have a beer.
Go for it. I'm fine.
Why won't you drink?
I don't want to.
I feel like I don't deserve to.
How come?
- Scuse me! Two beers.
- Yes.
I said...
Hey Takashi. What happened, man?
Was that really your fault?
It was. My purchase order was wrong.
You checked it, right?
Yeah.
Before you sent it?
Would I be like this if I had?
I bet somebody changed it.
Who'd want to do that, and what for?
Hey Takashi.
Has anybody got ahead thanks to this?
No. My company's taken a big hit.
Who took your client?
She got in trouble for helping me.
Alright. My bad. I was jumping to conclusions.
It's okay. Thanks for worrying about me.
What's wrong?
Huh? Oh, I felt a chill.
A cold?
No, I'm fine.
Hey Takashi. You gettin' enough sleep?
Well, kind of...
What about food? Did you eat lunch?
Yeah, on the rooftop.
The rooftop? Why the rooftop?
Well...No reason.
Hey Takashi.
Maybe you should get a new job.
Think of the J-League. Lots of players
start playing great after a transfer.
Getting along with
the manager's a big part of it.
You probably wouldn't understand,
but full-time jobs are scarce these days.
What's the big deal?
Getting married and having kids
is easier with a full-time job.
Worry about gettin' a girl first.
Anyway, I can't quit my job so easily.
Then what'd be easier?
For you, compared to quittin' your job,
what'd be easier?
What would be easier?
If you had to choose
between quittin' your job or dyin',
what'd be easier?
Nobody wants to die.
- You do.
- I don't.
You do. You tried to on the day we met.
You nearly felt on the tracks.
I just...felt dizzy...
Hell no.
I saw you at the ticket gate,
and I followed you from there.
Why did you do that?
Because I knew somebody...
who looked like you did that day.
Heading out.
Take care.
Aoyama, you went back to your drab neckties.
I gradually returned
to my old unchanging existence.
From now on,
I won't let myself get carried away.
I'll be careful. Very careful.
I won't ever cause trouble for others.
If I do that, I'll definitely get weekends off.
Then I can keep on living.
I don't need dreams or hope.
Can you make the yellow and green stronger?
The client thought the colors
were weak last time.
Got it.
Is two days enough?
Sure.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
Aoyama here. I'm leaving the factory
and heading back now.
I'll make arrangements tomorrow.
What's going on with him?
That's not the Yamamoto I know.
Come to think of it,
I don't know anything about him.
"Nagareyama Cemetery"
Excuse me, do you stop on the way?
No, it's a cemetery shuttle bus.
The city buses are...
Okay, this'll do.
"Jun Yamamoto"
“Who's idol group Jumpzm's
No. 1? Jun Yamamoto..."
"Jun Yamamoto"
What the hell?
"Mii's Blog"
"Deathday"
What's this?
"Three years ago today, Jun died.
It hurts to think why he took his own life."
"Jun Yamamoto Funeral"
"Why suicide?"
"Early on August 6th,
Miyala Food Company employee
Jun Yamamoto, 20,
was found dead in front of his workplace..."
"...suicide, brought on by overwork
and power harassment..."
No way.
Was Yamamoto trying to prevent my suicide
by coming back as a ghost?
Good morning.
Huh?! How did you get in?
The emergency exit, from the rooftop...
Sorry, did I mess up again?
No, I'm reading your Kotani data.
Sorry I didn't ask.
Sorry. Let me help you!
I'm done.
Let me help!
I said I'm done!
The boss told you to stay out of it.
If he finds out, he'll be angry again.
By the way, he also told me
to delete your Kotani data.
Could you transfer it to this?
Sure.
Hey Takashi!
Come on, dude. Don't be so scared.
No...
Got time? Let's go get a drink.
S-Sorry! I'm busy today!
What? You mad I told you to quit?
N-No I'm not.
If I make him angry, will he curse me to death?
But if Yamamoto came back
from the dead to save me...
- Okay, let's go.
- Yeah?
Ghosts don't have legs.
Thanks!
He plays soccer, does the Kazu dance...
A ghost in a Hawaiian pineapple shirt?
That felt great. Woulda been better
if you'd joined in.
He's no ghost. But what about that blog?
Hey Takashi. Takashi?
Yeah, what?
Let's make dinner, at my place.
It'll be the last thing you do.
You won't be able to leave.
Was he on his way back to his grave?
A ghost riding a bus?
My cooking's so good...
Gotta take a whiz.
If he really is a ghost,
and he came back to help me,
maybe the only way to put him to rest
is for me to do my best.
Anyway, I'd better do some work now.
I don't know how much I can do,
but I'll start by doing what I can, diligently.
- Heading out.
- Take care.
Okay.
Igarashi, got a moment?
About the Kotani data...
Why?! I thought you gave me all of it.
I did.
- What is it?
- Nothing.
Come with me.
What is this?
I thought you could use some notes
on what I talked with Mr. Noda about.
Like the order process,
his product plans, that kind of thing.
I already know about all that! What is this?
His hobbies and his grandkids?
It's just small talk!
This is your idea of "comforting"?
I'm sorry.
Acting chummy isn't enough.
You think this is useful?!
I'm sorry.
There's no more data?
You can check if you...
Hey you.
I hear you bitched to Igarashi,
even after she saved you.
You said it was your client.
You'd sewn up the deal.
As if she stole it from you.
No, I never said that...
Maybe I misspoke. I'm truly grateful to her,
so I wanted to help...
Bullshit!
Get this straight. Kotani Confectionery
is Igarashi's client,
and she gets all the credit.
Your only contribution was
that initial piece of shit contract.
This all started with your fuck-up. Got that?!
You'd piss on your only ally to get ahead?!
No!
And she's a woman, you asshole!
Shit!
You're...
...trying to take credit for our hard work!
You fucking leech!
Enough! Go back to work!
Igarashi, I'm sorry.
I should have made myself clearer.
I'm truly grateful. You teach me,
and help me, but I always trouble you.
I'll make sure I won't ever again.
Igarashi? Igarashi!
Get lost, idiot.
"Yamamoto"
You look relaxed.
Yamamoto, I'm sorry.
What for?
You tried to help me, but...
Can I join you?
No. Don't come.
I'll see you again soon anyway.
What do you mean?
Jun Yamamoto died three years ago.
So I'll join you.
Let's go for a drink when I get there.
Face me.
Face me, dammit!
Hey Takashi. Who do you think we live for?
Who is Takashi Aoyama living for?
- Myself?
- Partly.
- Others too?
- Yeah.
Who?
Whoever it is you care about.
- But I don't have a girlfriend.
- I know.
I mean somebody else.
Your family! How are they doing?
Hey Takashi.
You think you can end it all by dying,
but that's agony.
Agony for the ones left behind.
But I've...always been a jerk to my parents.
What did you do?
I let the vegetables Mom sent me go bad,
took my anger out on her, and...
After I started high school,
my dad was laid off.
But he couldn't find another job, and so...
...we moved in with my grandmother.
I didn't want to live in the country...
I cursed out my dad a lot.
Yeah?
I said it was because he was useless.
The same things my boss said to me.
Awful, right?
So he probably won't mind losing a son like me.
Man, you are an ungrateful son.
I know that!
No you don't!
You've got to find out for sure
how they really feel about you.
If a family's son dies before his time,
and the parents aren't sad, I wanna meet 'em.
Let's get out of here.
Let's go.
How did you know I was here?
Yamamoto.
What the hell are you?
A ghost.
Really?
Keep it quiet! I don't wanna be exorcised.
I'm home.
Takashi?
Why are you here?
You said you wanted some nice Tokyo cakes.
Thank you.
Hey there.
I'm home.
I want to eat your grapes.
I'll pick some.
The pricey ones.
You'd better pay.
- Me? Pay?
- Of course.
You'd charge your son?
Want some wine? It's good.
It's tasty.
Not right now. I'm fine. Thanks.
Alright.
Can you stay?
Last train. Work tomorrow.
Have dinner. I'll drive you to the station.
Okay, I will.
Fancy anything?
Your houtou.
Wow! I'd better get started.
The cakes were lovely.
Look, I'm stuffed. I ate so much!
Hey... I'm sorry.
What for?
I've taken you two for granted till now.
Don't be silly.
I didn't think about how you felt.
I'm really sorry!
What if, hypothetically speaking,
what if I quit my job?
That'd be fine.
I mean, it's not the only company in the world.
You could come home.
You're young. You can afford to make mistakes.
Right, right.
Takashi.
In life, as long as you're alive,
you'll get by somehow.
He's right.
Listen, Takashi.
When we moved here,
your dad couldn't find a job at all, remember?
Our savings kept going down,
and your grandma needed care the most.
You know, it all made me feel so exhausted.
I said to your father,
"Let's all die together."
But I changed my mind.
No matter how we felt,
you had your whole life ahead of you.
I wanted to see
what kind of grownup you'd become.
Anyway, call your mom from time to time.
She actually holds back from calling you more.
Honey...
She thinks up dumb excuses,
just so she can hear your voice.
Stop it, honey. You're talkative today.
Sure. I'll call more.
Yamamoto...Maybe you're...
...not a ghost... but an angel?
"Mr. Yamamoto. Thank you for deciding."
"Many angels are waiting for you."
"From: Takashi Aoyama. Morning!
Sorry to be so early."
Sorry it's so early.
No problem. What's up?
I wanted to tell you something.
What?
Thank you, for everything!
Knock it off! It's embarrassing.
I'm really grateful to you,
for being my friend.
From the moment you met me,
you've done your best to help me.
Listen, I know I asked you to come, but...
...could you wait here?
Sure. What's up?
I'm gonna go and quit my job.
1,2, 3,4! 5, 6, 7, 8!
Nine! Obey your superior as your god!
Ten! Abandon your feelings!
Feelings only make you weak!
Good morning!
You're 15 minutes late.
A 2,000 yen fine, asswipe.
Sir.
As of today, I'm resigning from this job.
Hey jerkoff.
It's too damn early for your bullshit.
This is why young people
these days are so fucking useless! Am I right?
Can't do their job,
but they're full of themselves.
No guts either! Am I right?
You don't know shit about the real world!
If you can't handle this,
whatever you do, wherever, you're fucked!
You'll be a loser your whole life,
till you die!
I live for myself,
and the people who care about me.
Huh?! You're just giving up
and running away from everything!
Don't fuck with me. You're a fucking pussy.
Think you can find another job easily?
Think again, jackass.
I don't want to, easily.
What?
I accepted this job too easily.
I was desperate, and took it
without knowing what I wanted to do.
I caused trouble for everyone because of that.
I'm sorry.
You're sorry? Who said you could talk, asshole?
Our rules state you've got to give
a month's notice before you quit!
Didn't you know that either?
If you still want to quit,
you'll get a disciplinary dismissal.
That's fine with me.
What?!
Until three days ago,
I felt like jumping off the roof.
But even a guy like me
could turn my life around tomorrow.
Someone I care about taught me that.
Huh?!
Right now, I still don't know
what I want to do, and what I can do.
But from now on, I want to smile up
at the blue sky, and be true to myself.
Don't fuck with me, shithead.
This ain't a toothpaste commercial!
Want to smile up at the blue sky, retard?
You think you can make a living doing that?!
Sir. I have one last request.
People here work very hard.
I'd like you to recognize their efforts.
Please do it, sir.
Please do it!
Thank you, sir.
Fuck you.
If possible, please take some time off, sir.
Fuck off!
Shit!
Ow!
Shit! Ow!
Sir, are you alright?
Aoyama!
Igarashi?
Thank you for everything.
About...that purchase order...
The one you made.
I changed it.
If you'd won that big contract,
my quota would've increased!
I...couldn't have coped with that.
You...started to look happier,
and I felt like you'd improve.
That scared me, so my only choice
was to steal your data...
...or kill myself.
It was hard for me too. I wanted to run.
But this company is all I have.
No other place would hire me.
I'm...worn out.
I'm sorry.
Back then, I don't know why,
but I was jealous of you.
So...you don't have to quit!
No, I'm done. I depended on you too much.
I never knew that you felt that way.
Thank you for telling me the truth.
Igarashi, I still wish I was more like you.
Thank you for everything.
And, just like that, Yamamoto was gone.
"Twice-Cooked Pork"
"Yamamoto"
The number you have called
is no longer in service.
Please make sure...
Yamamoto, just who were you exactly?
Will I ever see you again?
"Mii's Blog"
"Hi there."
Hey, Yamamoto.
"Takashi Aoyama"
Whenever I was in trouble,
you were there to help me.
But...when...
...you were with me, how did you feel?
- Hello.
I'll go ahead!
Wait up!
Mii got in touch too last night.
She grew up here.
She told me that the principal
knew Yamamoto better than anyone.
Yes, very well. From the day he came here.
- Hello.
You grew up here too?
No, My father used to be the principal here.
So those boys were like younger brothers to me.
Those boys?
Your friend, and his twin brother Jun.
His real name is Yu Yamamoto.
Yu...Yamamoto?
Jun and Yu came when they were five.
Their parents died in a car accident.
They were identical in every way,
as if they were born from the same soul.
The same soul?
When they first came,
only Jun could get close to Yu.
Yu wouldn't open up to me, or anyone else.
Yamamoto wouldn't?
Right. But then one time,
Jun showed Yu this photo book.
And said this to him.
"These children lost their moms and dads too.
But they're smiling.
So you should smile with them."
Then Yu put on a smile so big,
I was blown away.
So Yamamoto got his smile from Jun.
He told me once.
"Reiko, our parents gave us names
meaning 'pure' and 'kind,'
so we'd grow up that way."
Those two little boys thought that
if they went to the heavenly islands
of beautiful Vanuatu,
their mom and dad would be
there to hug them again.
Yu would grow up to become a teacher,
and Jun a doctor,
and then they'd go.
That became their dream.
"Three!"
"Eight and?"
"Two!"
"Nine and?"
"One!"
"Okay, let's sing together."
"Add to make 10."
"One, one, one and nine"
They wanted to go to university
on scholarships.
But Jun's cold got worse on
the day of his exams.
He'd caught it while caring for the others.
The poor boy
couldn't keep living here to try again.
He could only stay until he turned 18.
"Hey!"
"You're back?"
"Today. You good?"
So Jun had to find a job.
But he was optimistic.
He said he'd work and study,
and get into med school, so he'd be okay.
He told me that with a smile.
But he didn't get in the next year either.
The company he worked for was
what they call a "sweatshop."
- Morning.
- You alright?
Yu worked his way through university,
then began volunteer work in Vanuatu.
So Yamamoto went there first?
Right.
They'd been inseparable,
but now they were going their own ways.
"I'll take this."
Hey Jun.
I'm goin' to Vanuatu again next month.
Oh.
Jun. How 'bout we go together?
My company's busy.
I can't be the only one
to take a long vacation.
Jun, Vanuatu really is an awesome place.
They got no orphanages. Know why?
They got orphaned kids, like us.
But you know, those kids are
raised like family by the other villagers.
So they don't need orphanages.
Ain't that amazin'?
Really. That's great.
Hey Jun.
Why don't you quit, or find another job?
Yu.
I've gotta become a doctor
before I can go to Vanuatu.
You know,
when our parents had that accident,
and were gettin' operated on,
you held my hand, and I thought,
I wanna become a doctor,
so I can save Mom and Dad.
Jun... You've felt that way...
...all this time? Why didn't you tell me?!
How could I?
You should smile with those kids.
I said that to you.
If you'd found out
I never got over our sadness,
you never woulda smiled again.
I'll go too one day.
Okay.
I'll be waitin'. So you better come.
Jun's name means "pure".
Maybe he was too pure and kind
for his own good.
Yamamoto's the same. He's pure and kind too.
Right.
So when Jun committed suicide,
Yu blamed himself...
Yu?
Yu...
Long time no see! It's me! Yamamoto!
Hey Takashi. Maybe you should get a new job.
Long time no see. It's me! Yamamoto!
Aoyama!
Takashi?
Hey Takashi! Hey Takashi!
Um...
Up until recently, I was thinking
of killing myself, just like Jun.
But Yamamoto saved me.
Even so...
he never said a thing to me.
About Jun, or how he felt.
Nothing. Not a single word.
Yu came here a couple of weeks ago.
To say he was going away.
Going away?
He hadn't been back here for such a long time.
It was the first time since Jun died.
Back then, he told me.
He said he'd made a friend,
who'd inspired him to start over.
Yu told me.
"Reiko, ever see a grown-up guy in a suit
swinging his briefcase and
skipping over a pedestrian crossing?"
He looked so happy when he smiled.
But...he said there was something
he forgot to say to you.
Oh?
"Tell him, 'thank you."'
Why?
I should be thanking him.
Thank you.
That boy...is waiting for you.
He told me,
"When he comes here, give him this."
Look on the back.
"My angels."
"Wanna come and smile with them?"
“Hey Yu.“
"What if someone loses hope?"
"Hope is always there."
"You might just lose sight of it."
"Is this heaven?"
"This is..."
"This is the entrance to heaven.
A heaven called hope."
Hey, Yamamoto. I believe you now.
In life, there's always pain.
But, somewhere, there's always hope.
If you lose hope, look for it.
If you can't find it, make it.
And if
you even lose hope in doing that,
just start over.
Hey Yamamoto. Isn't that the only way forward?
Isn't that how Yu Yamamoto
has always lived his life?
- "Okay, Jessica?"
- "10."
"10! Okay?"
"How much?"
"Me! Me! Me! Me!"
"Mariontin?"
"8."
"8. Okay."
"How much?"
"Me! Me! Me! Me!"
"Naomi?"
"7."
"7, okay."
"Everyone got it?"
"Hey Mr. Yu!"
"What's up?"
"I wanna be a teacher like you."
"You wanna be a teacher?"
"Okay! Excellent!"
"Swing me too!"
So these kids are your angels.
Yeah. They're my angels.
Takashi. Good to see ya.
Yeah.
"Who's he?"
"He's my good friend."
Hey Yamamoto.
This time, is there anything
I can do to help you here?
You gotta start as a volunteer.
"What's your name?"
Your name!
"My name is Takashi Aoyama.
From Japan. 24 years old!"
Oh man. You need a crash course.
Yeah. Please teach me.
Okay, let's get to work.
But what do I do?
Start with easy stuff.
"Hide and seek. Takashi's it. Everyone run!"
Run! That's your first job!
Hey Jun.
Life...ain't so bad after all, is it?
English subtitles by Don Brown