Who is it?
It's Ripley.
The door's open.
- Believe it or not.
- I've been waiting for you for 2 months.
How are you doing, man...
Mastertition?
You son of a bitch, my name is Pogosh.
When did you leave Hamburg?
This morning.
- How's your wife?
- What wife?
- When do you go back?
- Today.
Let's get on to a very serious matter.
I think this is serious.
I sold one painting,
I'm ready to sell another one.
- How much?
- That's $2000 for you.
I told you I have a good eye.
Take care of it.
A new one is hard to find.
Don't you think I know this?
Now this...
I think I can get even more for this one.
I can use 2 of these in 6 months.
In 6 months I can paint 5.
Try to sell 5.
Two.
Don't be too busy for a dead painter.
You'll wear that hat in Hamburg?
What's wrong with a cowboy in Hamburg?
It's December 6
in 1976
There's nothing to fear.
But fear itself.
I know less and less about...
who I am...
or who anybody else is.
Even this river...
This river reminds me of another river.
And... that river flows...
it flows to the sea...
where ever that river goes...
God knows...
that's where I want to be...
Ladies and gentlemen, we come to
the high spot of the auction.
A particularly fine, later Derwatt.
May we see the painting once more?
Thank you.
There are few Derwatts left on the
market; this may be your last chance.
Lot 132.
I have several written bids.
I'll start at... 17,500 marks.
17,500 marks.
30,000 Mark.
I wouldn't bid so high.
Why not?
I'm doubtful of it.
What's wrong with it?
I had that painting for three days.
Look at the colors.
The blue's not right...
compared with other Derwatts.
It'll be a sure-fire proposition
in America.
"proposition" in America.
In Texas they'll be grabbing for it.
In Texas.
Yes, in Texas.
54,000 DM
We are still bidding.
58,000
Are you still bidding?
60,000 Marks
62,000 Marks
Are you still bidding?
Sixty-two thousand marks, Mr. Winter.
- Satisfied?
- Yup.
- Congratulations, Mr. Winter.
- Thank you.
- How's Daniel?
- He's fine.
Are you taking the painting with you?
No, send it to New York.
I won't be back until after Christmas.
I'm going to the wilderness in Canada
No telephones, no anything.
This didn't reach our reserve price.
- Ciao.
- Mr. Winter, are you satisfied?
- As always.
Although Johnathan doesn't like the blues.
May I introduce...
Mr. Ripley, this is Mr. Winter.
Pleasure.
Mr. Zimmermann
Oh ya? I've heard of you.
Let's go out.
You'll miss your plane.
You mustn't take that seriously.
Mr. Zimmermann's...
under a lot of pressure.
He's a good picture-framer...
but no longer a competent restorer.
Reason?
He's ill.
A blood disease.
Little hope of recovery.
Hopeless.
Maybe.
The treatment's expensive, too.
His wife has to help support them.
You should be asleep.
Where were you?
- What woke you up?
- The noisy trucks.
We're staying home now.
Goodnight.
Sleep well.
May I leave the light on?
Stop this drama, Tom.
- I've been waiting for 2 hours.
- To breaking into my house?
I aught to blow you away.
Do you know...
I gotta tell you the truth.
The only reason that I don't
is because someone might hear me.
I sent you telegram, Tommy.
A telegram, huh?
Now get your ass inside, you hear!
Someone who would look absolutely
incapable of doing such a thing.
Listen.
I know rock musicians.
I know lawyers...
I know art dealers, pimps,
politicians.
But murder...
I don't want to be involved.
Period.
It's not that easy, Tom.
You owe me something.
Don't forget.
All right.
This is crazy man.
Sixty marks, wasn't it?
It's a bit more, I'm afraid.
Mother left it to me; my brother
has no eye for art.
It's another twenty marks.
It will go into my bag.
Eighty marks.
I'm very pleased with it.
You're a sly one.
I'll put it up in its old place.
Thank you very much.
- Goodbye
Eighty marks!
My German is terrible.
Make me a frame.
Frame?
You can speak in English.
That is good.
Well... I suggest...
This one. Yes?
Uh-huh.
Yes.
Compliments the picture.
How long is it going to take?
Two, three days, yes?
That's fast.
Gantner told me you were a good craftsman.
I admire that.
I've always wanted to be able to
make something with my hands.
But... well...
some people have it
and some people don't.
May I show you something?
You have to move it. See?
You like it?
Well, I give it to you.
Really?
Why?
You see the last time we met...
my behavior...
well I wasn't polite and...
I don't know...
Please...
forget it.
I don't like people who
buy paintings
as an investment.
Wow.
You count me out.
No...
I count you in.
I'll be back one of these days.
Not with the left hand! Daniel, no!
Jonathan.
...with the left hand!
You were dreaming.
I was shocked...
"I was shocked to hear that
your illness is worse.
"I was embarrassed to speak to you
about it.
"Let me know if money is a problem.
I'll be in New York for three weeks."
That's right, he's in Canada.
Don't let him down...
"What are friends for?
You must not give up. Yours. Allan."
Written at the airport.
"...your illness is worse."
Why didn't he speak before? Who told
him? I should be the first to know.
BACK SHORTLY
My most interesting patient...
but I've no time to see you now.
I just need a minute.
At my last examination,
were the results really unfavorable?
You saw the test reports...
and we discussed them.
There are no alarming developments.
- Do you feel worse?
- Not at all.
It's just that a friend of mine has
heard somewhere that I...
haven't much longer to live.
Where did this friend hear such
nonsense? Not from me.
Your condition remains unchanged.
It's rumor-mongering.
Marianne?
Your wife's gone to the post office.
You spoke to Allan Winter before
yesterday's auction, Herr Gantner.
- Did you talk about me?
- No. Why?
- You know about my illness.
- But I'd never discuss it.
Someone's been spreading an idiotic
story about me.
It can't have been done maliciously.
Mr. Zimmermann?
Good day Mr. Zimmermann.
My name is Raoul Duplat.
You don't know me.
Do you speak French?
No.
- English?
- Yes.
You don't know me
but I know you very well.
I want to talk with you about a business.
Are you an art dealer?
In a certain way.
Let's go.
I want to show you something.
We take the Metro.
I lived in Paris, briefly.
I need one person eliminated...
possibly two.
What?
Now my cards are on the table.
You must be joking.
Not at all.
Where did you get my name?
Never mind.
Are you interested in 250,000 Mark
for shooting one man, maybe two?
It's certainly easy.
I don't know where you might
have heard that I am a gun man.
You must take me for somebody else.
No Mr. Zimmermann.
Listen...
We know that you are not
going to live very much longer.
- You've got a wife...
- Who told you all that?
You've got a little boy...
Don't you like to leave them some money?
When you'll die?
This is nonsense.
In fact, it's not.
Maybe your doctor didn't tell you the truth.
But you know, the truth?
Listen...
I'm completely informed about my sickness.
I know I have a blood disease.
I'm sorry, Mr. Zimmermann...
you are not completely informed.
But at least it seems you know
what I'm talking about.
It's your own free choice.
But it's a lot of money.
You could stop working
and enjoy the rest of your life.
I'm not a killer, mister.
Good.
That's just what we need.
Someone who is not connected to us.
The man I want you to shoot,
Mr. Zimmermann,
is a criminal.
- Belongs to the mafia.
- I'll stop here.
You're out of your minds.
You think about it.
I'm staying all day,
at the Pacific Hotel.
You're out of breath...
you know you shouldn't
over-exert yourself.
So you noticed.
What?
You left your scarf and cap here.
I wanted to ask you to take
the next sample now.
I was just going home.
Please, I'd feel easier in my mind.
Herr Zimmermann,
I wanted to tell you earlier.
In your situation there is no certainty.
No doctor in the world...
could guarantee you five years,
one year, a month.
Where could he have heard?
The doctor says it's all nonsense.
He says I shouldn't worry;
my condition is unchanged.
It's only a rumor.
Gantner...
knows nothing about it,
or so he says.
Daniel, my son.
Will he remember me?
"My father had a moustache."
"We lived in a house near the harbor."
It's starting all over again.
The last time was three months ago.
Now it's starting again.
There is too much on my mind and...
there is nothing I can say...
there is nothing I can do.
Good morning Mr. Zimmermann,
I was expecting your call.
Don't say anything.
Listen, I have a proposition for you...
Come to Paris and see a doctor
to get a new opinion about your...
state of health.
I already made a date for you...
with a hemotologist.
There is no obligation for you.
Take the first flight tomorrow
morning at 7 o'clock.
That's why I sent you the money.
I was on my way to you.
How were the tests?
The results can't be ready yet.
We only sent the samples to
the laboratory this morning.
- Perhaps they're ready.
- Check with me in two days.
Two days.
You could telephone now.
It's pointless... there are no results yet.
Sometimes I can't make you out.
Anyway, the results will be
the same as the last.
What if they're worse?
Sometimes I think you'd like that.
I'm going to Paris.
Why?
A client has got me an appointment
at the American Hospital.
They have specialists.
- You're leaving tonight?
- Tomorrow morning.
Very early.
The flight is at 7:30.
All because of the telegram?
It worried me very much.
I'd like to know how things really are.
If I put it off, I'll never do it.
Suppose the telegram
wasn't from Allan?
Who else would have sent it?
Wake up, Mr. Zimmermann.
Excuse me, I'm late.
You had a good flight?
You feeling well?
I took the appointment for you
at 10 o'clock at the hospital.
You have no more time to loose.
Rodolphe studies medicine.
He will stay with you and help you.
If there should there be any problems.
We go to the American Hospital.
It's the best one in Paris.
World famous.
Good nurses got there...
should get them too.
I don't intend to die here.
I think it's normal to see another doctor...
in such a serious case.
Mommy, shall I answer it?
Ask who it is.
No, only my mother.
The doctor.
I'm coming.
She isn't here yet; she's just coming.
Idiot, you look in the side,
not the top.
Idiot yourself!
Daniel, be careful with those things.
Dr. Gabriel?
No, he isn't here today, he's in Paris.
I thought you knew about it.
Any message for him?
When was he first diagnosed?
1971. No... 1972.
And you've had regular treatments?
No.
Where are you from?
Hamburg.
Northern Germany.
Is the Reeperbahn still as exciting?
Are you Swiss?
I studied in Berne.
But you're Swiss, too.
From Zürichhegel.
Then you can stand a lot.
Because I'm afraid this is going
to be painful in any language.
Yes, I know.
Let's do it.
Have you thought about the other affair?
The proposition
I made in Hamburg?
Well, I did not change my mind.
I will tell you have left.
Now, we take you to your hotel.
I'm going to hang a sign up
What's it going to say, I'm still alive?
No.
Deliver me from evil.
You're right, I'm dead and doing very well.
Andrew Pogosh Jerimiah.
I am alive.
You changed the blue.
- What do you mean?
- The last painting I sold...
you changed the blue.
It's different than any of the others.
How could you tell?
Oh, I couldn't tell.
I got got a friend in Hamburg
who told me that.
Did you have any trouble selling it?
None at all.
So...
just means he has a better eye
than you have, that's all.
Not for very much longer, I'm afraid.
- Hello, Jonathan?
- Hello.
I've got the report from the hospital.
I told them to work it out
as soon as possible.
Already?
Yes.
A first summary.
Oh, God. What is it?
- Why don't you come to my apartment?
- Okay.
On the other side of the river.
If you look out of your window,
you can see it.
It's the modern building
on the left of the bridge.
The third floor.
I'm wearing a white...
- Can you hear me?
- Yes, I can see you.
All right Jonathan, see you later.
I read it Jonathan.
I'm deeply sorry.
You look pale.
You better take this.
It will calm you down.
- I am very calm.
- Take it.
This is the man.
His name is... Ingraham
An American Jew from New Jersey.
A killer.
You wouldn't guess it
just from the photograph.
Nobody could recognize
an ordinary looking man...
in a subway crowd.
- Just from a single photograph.
- Of course not.
Rodolphe is coming with you.
He will show him to you.
The best opportunity in Metro station...
where he changes from one line into another.
You go into the... and shoot like this.
And after the shot, don't run away.
Take it easy.
Just move like a normal passenger. Okay?
Have you hurt yourself?
Thank you.
What's wrong with you?
I'm confused.
Don't try to be a nice guy.
I want to go home.
Let me love you for your money.
I'm confused.
Close the doors,
don't come in through the windows.
A little older, a little more confused.
You better watch your step, cowboy.
Strange.
You say he was shot? Subway?
In Paris?
No, I didn't have anything to do with it
Mona!
Can you repeat that?
Yes.
I can't hear you.
Speak a little louder.
Make it plainer.
All right, I can hear you now.
Go ahead.
We saw you from the window.
- I thought you'd be back this morning.
- I took the first plane.
- Did you bring me anything?
- I'm sorry, I had no time.
- Have you been bleeding?
- Just a bit, nothing serious.
Paris.
What did the doctors say?
They can't say if it's worse until
they've seen my case notes.
Our doctor must send them.
Come here.
Bye.
It's not my frame, I hope?
It's been one of those days.
For you.
I'm sorry your frame is not ready. Yet.
- I wasn't here yesterday.
- That's all right.
- Cut your head?
- It all right.
I started to work on your frame.
- Let me see it.
- What.
The frame.
It's in my workshop.
In the back room.
I like this room.
It's got a good feel to it.
It's quiet and peaceful.
Just like you.
I envy you.
The smell of paint and wood.
Must be good to work here.
Then when you finish something,
you can see what you've done.
It's not that easy.
Not that safe and easy.
What do you make.
I make money.
And I travel a lot.
I'm bringing the Beatles back to Hamburg.
I don't believe you that.
- No rumour.
- This is no rumour.
Rumor.
There wasn't time to tell you
this morning.
The doctors in Paris advanced me
some money...
because I'll probably have to
go there again.
That must mean it's serious,
or they wouldn't give you money.
They're taking a risk and so am I.
And if it's successful?
If it's successful, then I can
live a few more years.
Hello?
I take the night train.
I arrive at tomorrow morning at 9:14
I have something very presentable for you.
Okay, see you at the station.
That was the Paris specialist.
He'll be here tomorrow on business
and he wants to see me.
He wants to continue the treatment.
I don't believe you.
What?
I simply don't believe you.
You went to Paris
for quite another reason.
What sort of reason?
How do I know?
You never tell me anything.
There's less than half
of what you promised me.
I told you that...
there might be a second case.
Count me out.
I already made a date for you
with a specialist in blood diseases.
- Where?
- Munich.
- When?
- Tomorrow.
On a Sunday?
Yes.
It's a private arraignment.
I want you to take back the train
to Hamburg in the afternoon.
There is a man in the train...
I suppose.
Exactly.
The first part went so well.
I will see the doctor in Munich.
I will be on the train.
But I will be sleeping on the train.
And enjoy the ride.
Did you read the papers?
Ya. Congratulations.
To you.
What do you mean?
It was your idea.
Shut up.
You are too sensitive, Tom.
You will do it again.
What?
The American in the train.
Belongs to the other organisation.
You... never told me about...
the second murder, Minot.
So what?
It will look like a revenge
for the murder in the Metro.
And that's what I want.
Doesn't make any sense.
And it won't work.
And it's much too dangerous in a train.
This man can't cope with it.
Now, you get a professional.
I trust him.
He won't ever do it.
Framed.
Your son?
Daniel.
Danny Dan.
Look what I found.
You turn it like...
Well...
- You like it?
- A hum.
I'm going to give it to you.
Why?
Because the last time I saw you,
your behavior was so disgusting...
You know what I mean?
- You restore old paintings?
- Yes.
Some workers at my house today...
badly damaged one of mine.
I'll be home all day tomorrow and a...
Maybe you can come by?
No.
Tomorrow I can't.
I don't live very far from here.
No, tomorrow I...
have to make a little trip.
I see.
We really must be going.
Have a nice trip.
Thank you a lot...
for your present, Mr. Ripley.
A present?
I gave him one when he brought
the engraving.
You seem to know him well.
It's December 6...
1976...
There is nothing to fear, but fear itself.
I know less and less all the time.
Who are you?
I don't know who anybody else is.
Get out.
I'll have it for you tomorrow morning.
7 o'clock in the taxi.
Train station.
I don't know the old one with the girl.
Don't worry about them.
You have the gun?
And the other thing?
Did I give you the tickets?
My wife will get the money
whatever happens to me.
She will Jonathan. For sure.
- Hello, a letter for Zimmermann.
- Thank you.
Hi, Jon.
close...
Now looks like we're going
to have to finish this.
Drink this.
All right!
A friend is in there.
He's sick... a friend of ours.
Knock 3 times if everything's okay.
No drinking water.
Tell me when he's back.
Where's the gun?
I don't know.
It's occupied.
It's busy.
Ticket, please.
Just a moment.
You put it in the blue jacket.
Watch that corridor.
Open the door.
Help me with this.
Tomorrow at your shop.
Move!
Move! Move!
This time I've brought you something.
What is that?
It's a gyroscope...
that's what it's called.
Your hand shook, but you threaded it.
Hello.
One minute, who are you?
I cannot talk now. Sorry.
I've had enough! Who was that?
Your specialist again?
I'd like to know the truth, for once.
Don't tell me tales about check-ups,
not on a Sunday.
I'm sure your sudden trips are part
of Gantner and Ripley's crooked deals.
What dirty work are you doing?
What are they paying you?
I've had enough of your
skulking, lying.
Please be quiet.
I feel so deserted by you, so betrayed.
The worst is that you're using
your illness to deceive me.
What do I care what you're up to
with your American friend?
Be glad you know nothing about this.
This is funny.
They calculated that between the first and
the second man, 4 minutes must have passed.
You throw a gangster out a train going
80 MPH and then you throw a second one...
how much time passes between the 2 events?
If the train doesn't change speed between?
Right? 4 minutes.
I guess you'll want some of the money.
Keep the other half.
I don't want it anyway.
No, that's not it.
Why were you on the train?
I wanted to prevent a second murder.
But you didn't mind the first.
You had a choice.
I didn't know how...
insane Minot's plan's going to become.
By the way.
You did the job on the train alone.
I don't want Minot to know.
that I was in.
You're alone.
You don't want anything?
I wouldn't know possibly
what I can win from you.
I would like to be your friend.
But friendship isn't possible.
That makes me feel...
very comfortable.
Why did you spread...
this rumor...
that I am...
with one foot in the grave?
You remember that day that
we were introduced at the auction?
And you said "Ya..."
I've heard of you.
"I've heard of you."
You said that in a very nasty way.
that was all?
Isn't that enough?
Hello?
97,000 marks! Where from?
The doctors in Paris and Munich
have made a bet.
A bet on my life.
Who do you think will win?
That's the stake.
You're mad.
I get nothing out of it.
Jonathan.
What's gone wrong, Jonathan?
What happened?
They bombed my flat in Paris.
Car blew up.
Did you tell anybody about me?
- What?
- Something wrong in the train?
Why are they after me?
How can they know about me?
I don't know.
Everything went fine.
We killed the man.
- And one of his bodyguards.
- What do you mean "we"?
Tom and me.
Tom?
Tom Ripley?
Yes.
Swine!
Tom... it's me.
I've got to see you.
I don't know what to do.
- Tom, he knows, he...
- Stay cool.
You know what I mean?
Because I'm coming right now to pick you up.
Did you hear me?
What you got there, man?
You take this...
What do you want me to do here?
Just stay in here.
From here, you can see anybody
that's approaching the house.
Take care of it. All right?
Because we know somebody's
going to show up. Right?
- Who?
- Who? What do I know?
You know, the mafia?
I'm on the roof with a gun.
But I don't want to use it
because of the neighbors.
Jonathan?
I brought you something
to keep you alive.
Like this... I'm not going to live
very much longer.
Give me a cigarette, please.
You must be freezing out there.
I'm thinking about you all the time.
I need...
Sweet Jesus, light of the world.
Huh. Ambulance.
What the hell is holding up Angie?
Just take it!
Come on!
Run!
You have to drive the second car.
What?
- Okay.
- Jonathan...
Move over.
It's automatic.
All you have to do is start it.
Put it in gear.
Step on the gas.
Steer.
It's going to be a long road, Jonathan.
We gotta make it.
Shit!
I've looked for you everywhere.
Let's go home.
We can discuss things.
In peace and quiet.
I've seen the doctor.
You were deceived in Paris.
Those medical reports were faked.
Let's go home.
You needn't explain now.
Mrs. Zimmermann...
It's all right.
you can settle your problems tomorrow.
And you have plenty of time.
We're in a lot of trouble.
Help us.
Baby you can drive my car...
Now, if you want to help your husband...
you better drive the car
and follow us in the ambulance.
Because we have something we have to finish.
I think he's too exhausted to do it.
Try to sleep a little.
Where's he going?
I think he wants to get to the sea.
Oh, Angie! Can't win them all, eh?
He'll never bring the Beetles
back to Hamburg.
Shouldn't I drive?
I'll make it to Hamburg.
Back to Daniel.
One day you'll have to explain
everything to him.
Marianne, it's getting so dark.
Jonathan.
Jonathan!
Oh well.
We made it anyway, Jonathan.
Be careful.
Pity the poor emigrant...
whose...