Well?
I am sending you the code.
Yes I see that, thank you.
- What about my account?
- Delivering.
I have just sent it,
you should have it.
Yes, thank you.
Are you sure that this is legal?
We are just running a test on our
security systems, Sir,
it is fine.
You have a sexy voice. Uhh, is
there anything else we can do for you?
- To you?
- We have all we need.
Ready.
Yo, guess who just made 50,000 today.
- What did you do to my drive, man?
- Man, shut up I didn't touch it.
This isn't cool.
Don't ever, ever touch my computer.
The diagnostics show no damage but we are
certain that it was an intentional breech.
Are you saying we were hacked?
It wasn't a denial of service level.
They definitely cracked our door.
OK. Open the "Black Eye" files.
I want every hacker in the country,
who could have done this,
interviewed, now.
Sir, that is close to a thousand names.
With the holiday weekend,
we are short staffed as it is.
Listen...
We are the ones who are supposed
to keep this from happening...
And it just happen to us.
Get it done.
Sir, it is the middle of the night and they
are scattered all over the whole country.
Fine, get local law enforcement help.
Somebody thinks they can screw with us.
I want to find out who.
Jim, I said no.
Lucy, you're killing me, alright?
- Get out of the car.
- What?
- Get out of the car, now!
- Don't touch me.
- No means no jerk-off.
- What are you doing?
- John, stop it!
- Oh, don't call me that.
I hate it when you call me that.
- Do you know this guy?
- Shut up, just shut your mouth. Right now!
Dad!
Stop it! I mean it!
Dad? You said your dad was dead.
What?
You told this jerk-off I was dead?
- You actually said that?
- I may have exaggerated a little bit.
And is this guy what, your boyfriend?
- No!
- Yes!
I don't know, okay?
I'm sorry.
We will see.
What are you doing here?
You don't answer your phone,
you don't return my calls.
That is because I am not
talking to you.
Why aren't you talking
to me this time, Lucy?
Why not?
What? You want a list?
How about stuff like this:
You spy on me!
Do I spy on you?
You come over here and
drag my boyfriend of the car...
- You said that he is not your boyfriend.
- He is not!
- But you said that I was...
- God! Just...
You are such an asshole.
OK.
I am sorry for pulling your
not boyfriend out of the car.
OK?
Let's just get in the car.
No!
- Won't both of you just go away?
- Talk to me, Lucy.
I am tired and I am going for bed.
Alone.
You are damn right alone.
Lucy, wait one minute.
I want to talk to you.
Just wait.
Dad.
When I want to talk to you,
IF I want to talk to you...
I'll call you.
Lucy!
Wait, Lucy! Lucy!
- Lucy McClane!
- It is not McClane, it is Gennero.
Chicks, right?
I'm gonna go.
I'll go.
John!
It is Sclavino.
This is McClane.
- What are you doing at Rutgers?
- How do you know where I am?
We had all the cars tracked
4 years ago, you remember.
I am looking exactly
at where you are.
So that's not something
that I would turn on.
Yes, we did that, John.
We turned them on.
Listen...
The feds have called in a favour.
They are doing a sweep.
They want us to pick up a
a computer hacker in Camden.
The last name is Farrell.
The first name is Matthew.
Camden?
What are you telling me for?
It's 3 in the morning.
I'm on my way home.
Send a jug-head from the Academy.
They will be happy to go pick this kid up.
I can't just send in uniform.
The feds demanded
a senior detective.
The kid is a high value subject.
I don't know.
Just pick him up.
Escort him to the
Hoover building in Washington.
They had some kind of
computer breech there this morning.
Right.
Give me the information.
Give me that name again
What is it?
You owe me one, Jack.
God damn it.
- Who is it?
- NYPD.
Open the door, please.
- Hi.
- NYPD?
Yeah.
I get it.
Don't worry, everyone gets lost
round here, glad to help
Kid, I'm not lost.
Are you Matt Farrell?
Matthew Farrell?
No...
Actually, he doesn't live here anymore.
Of course not.
Who are you?
My name is Daisy Duke.
I got a lot of shit for
when I was a kid.
Please, don't add to it.
Can I see some identification, please?
Yeah, sure.
Detective!
Yeah that looks real.
Where did you get that?
Toys R Us?
It looks great.
That...
That actually looks pretty good.
Farrell!
Soldier just pdld a new copy of the killzone.
Do you want to come to take a look?
No, thanks though man!
And good luck at the bad timing awards.
Open the door.
Shit!
Can I get you something?
Coffee, warrant?
- What's this about?
- I don't know.
Some kind of computer thing.
The DC Feds wanna talk to you.
So, let's go.
- Feds, huh?
- Yeah, the Feds.
I've been watched for four years.
Once you are on that goddamn
list, such a pain in the ass.
Do you play with dolls?
Uhh, could you please
not touch that.
- Is it like a G.I. Joe?
- No, it is not!
It is a limited edition of...
- Is that meant to come off?
- No, it is not.
But it is much more valuable broken.
So thanks for that.
Crazy glue, I'm sure it's
very important.
I have other cool shit in
here if you want to break that.
Let's go, OK? Come on!
I've got to power down my gear, ok?
More dolls.
You don't spend a whole load of
time with the girls, huh?
Hey! Are you really trying to escape?
Please! Don't shoot.
- Don't shoot.
- Get down!
Keep your head down.
Let's go, come on.
Stay down.
Come on.
- Is everything alright?
- Stay down.
Stay down.
- You stay with me.
- OK.
- Follow me.
Right.
That's gonna wake the neighbours.
Get down, get inside.
Get down!
They are back in the room!
Are you nuts?
- Get out of there right now!
- I am trying...
Now!
Go to the right.
Let's go!
Get back in there!
Get ready to run.
Ready?
What the hell was that?
What?
Did you do that?
No.
Shit.
I didn't do that.
- Let's go.
- Shit.
Stay close to me.
OK.
Let's go.
Come on, let's go damn it!
Let's go!
Watch it.
Just tone it down.
OK.
Let's go!
Stay close.
Stay with me.
- Stay with me.
- Right!
Let's go.
Stay close.
Get in the car.
- Go, go.
- Yes.
- Kid, can you reload a gun?
- What? Me?
- Can you reload a gun?
- Oh, yeah...
Look in the glove box and get a
magazine out right now!
Get your head down.
Is the circus in town?
- Did you see that?
- I saw it. I did it.
Camden Base 10077, come back.
Camden Base 10077.
Camden Base go ahead.
I need to speak with your chief,
this is a police emergency.
ASAP.
Standby.
This is chief detective Wiesman.
Chief Detective, this is Detective
John McClane of the NYPD.
Police Emergency.
I want to report a police
shooting in your jurisdiction.
Yes.
What's the status?
Hold the line.
Thomas.
We have a problem in New Jersey.
Farrell is still alive.
- So he got away?
- Yes.
I did send 5 of you, is that right?
I am sending the chopper, get airborne.
We will track him down.
Think you can handle that?
Oh my God!
- Just breathe.
- I am breathing, but...
- I can't stop shaking.
- It is the adrenaline.
You are just scared.
It will pass.
Of course I'm scared.
Weren't you scared, back there?
Yes.
I was scared.
Really?
This is you being scared?
I dunno, you seem really calm.
Have you done stuff like that before?
Stuff like what?
Like killing people.
Yes.
Not for a long time.
Who were those guys?
Why did they try to kill you?
Why did they blow up my apartment?
They were there to kill you.
Why would they want to kill me?
You tell me, kid.
You're the criminal.
We got 7 dead hackers so far,
none high on our list
Collect the hard drives
and start sweeping them..
Yes, Sir.
Trey...
Matthew Farrell,
Find him for me.
On it.
What's with all the guns?
Operational prudence.
Think of them as hardware
to your software.
Good morning D.C.
Well it' shaping up to be
another beautiful 4th of July weekend.
If you've got any big plans,
you better get started early.
Because it looks like the
traffic is hotting up.
So another golden oldie
for all the commuters out there.
What?
What are you doing?
What is that?
It is Credence.
- Credence?
- Credence.
Credence Clearwater Revival.
- Classic rock.
- I know who it is.
It is old rock,
that does not make it classic.
What sucked back then
still sucks now.
You don't like Credence?
It is like having a pine cone
shoved up my ass.
OK, really...
Wow, that's mature!
Come on man.
We are at a heading of 060.
Making another pass.
Listen up everyone.
Are we ready?
The transportation hubs
are prepped and set.
Begin stage 1.
When was the last time you tuned
in your radio to pop music?
Give me any decade.
Was it the seventies?
Did Michael Jackson still play?
Pearl Jam.
I'm going back about 10 years.
Ten years.
Twenty years. The Cure? Nothing?
It's called News Radio.
I'm trying to see if any of your
friends from Camden made the headlines.
Hold on.
- You listen to the news?
- Yeah, you have a problem with the news now?
Yes, I have a big God damned
problem with the news.
Are you ready for this?
The news is completely manipulated.
Everything that you hear
every single day...
Is designed by corporate media
to do one thing only.
Jesus!
To keep you living in fear.
- Oh fear?
- Total fear.
Fear so you will go out and
spend money on things.
Things you probably don't even need.
Things you should already be sick of.
So that their advertisers keep
buying adds on their stations.
And I tell one more thing.
Are you ready for this?
I can do this all day man.
I've got days of data at home.
I'll drop a bomb on you bigger...
- HEY!
- SHUT UP!
That's good, that's good,
be dismissive
You...
- Are you alright?
- No, I am not alright.
Stay in the car.
You will be alright.
Hey man! Hey.
How are you doing, you alright?
Just call 911, alright?
Jesus Christ.
All of the lights are green.
Let's go, right now.
- We gotta go?
- Let's go.
Get your bag hack boy.
Let's go.
- Jesus.
- Let's go.
I've never been in a crash.
Are you alright?
Well it is very exciting.
This way, here we go.
- Have you ever been in a car accident?
- Yes, I have been in a car accident.
What are we doing?
A little thing they invented back
in the 60s, it's called jogging.
Sir, Chicago is reporting a
system crash in their train network
Amtrak is flashing a level 1
crash of their system
F.A.A. Just issued a critical alert.
Their ATC Net just went down.
We are under attack.
OK.
Let's get them outside
for a little bit of fresh air.
That is the Anthrax Alarm.
Alright, everyone out, Now!
Now!
Taylor, move, go.
Move!
All personnel must evacuate
and proceed to the shelters immediately.
This is not a drill.
All personnel must evacuate
and proceed to the shelters immediately.
Take the team and go for
the fourth floor. Got it?
Masks on.
Make it happen, OK?
Research the data
from these crashes,
see if you can ID the
point of origin.
Begin Stage 2.
Hey what is going on?
What is happening?
They are already starting to panic.
Of course they are.
They think that someone
is taking their money.
All of those nickel
and dimes they saved.
Useful idiots,
as Lyman would say.
Prep the video package.
DC transportation system is crashing
And they just hit the
financial sector. Everything.
Call the Secretary of Trans, the
Treasury and the Director of F.C.C.
Let's go people!
Somebody, somewhere,
has left a digital fingerprint.
Find it!
Is Deputy Director Bowman in here?
- Not now it will have to wait.
- Not today waxworks.
This is Matthew Farrell.
I brought him here on direct
orders from Bowman.
So if you don't know what's going on,
go find me somebody who does.
I am Bowman.
The video package is
ready for upload.
Thanks.
Listen, John.
I thank for bringing Farrell,
but everything's changed this morning
We are neck deep in
damage control right now.
Excuse me, I'm sorry, Sir.
Do you have something to eat?
Any snacks around here?
I would love... I am
really low on blood sugar.
Sir?
No?
As if the crash of the traffic
system wasn't bad enough.
The Stock Market found itself
in a selling frenzy this afternoon.
The Federal Trade Commission believes this panic
might have triggered by computer malfunction.
What we thought to be related...
Oh man, that is all bad.
It's not as bad as it looks.
We run drills to prepare
for things like this.
- Are these your suspects?
- They were.
All seven were killed
in the last 24 hours.
Do you recognize any of them?
No.
Not one?
Sir.
You need to see something here.
My fellow Americans...
it is time...
to strike...
fear...
into...
the citizenry.
Ask not...
It's not an authorised broadcast.
What your country can do...
to avert this...
crisis.
The answer is...
nothing what so ever.
Our military...
strength...
is in...
this case...
useless.
Read my lips.
The...
great...
confident...
ruler...
of the American...
progress...
and...
growth...
has come to...
an end.
All...
the vital...
technology...
that...
this nation...
possesses.
All
communication...
Transportation,
Internet...
Connectivity.
Electrical power.
Critical...
utilities...
Their...
fate...
now rests...
in...
our...
hands.
We will not tire.
We will not falter.
And we will not fail.
I don't know how they
are getting in.
Thank you.
And a...
Happy...
Independence Day...
to everyone!
That was creepy.
I tried to find more Nixon.
Do you think they bought it?
Absolutely.
OK.
I want telecommunications, transports and...
Jesus Christ! It's a Fire Sale.
What?
It's a Fire Sale.
Hey, we don't know that yet.
It is a myth anyway.
It cannot be done.
Oh it's a myth?
Really?
Please tell me she's only here for show
and she's not actually in charge of anything.
- What is a Fire Sale?
- It is a three step...
It is a three step systematic attack
on the entire national infrastructure.
Ok Step 1: Take out all
the transportation
Step 2: The financial base and telecoms
Step 3: Get rid of all the utilities.
Gas, Water, Electricity, Nuclear...
Basically everything that is
controlled by a computer.
Which today, is almost everything.
So that's why they call it a Fire Sale
because everything must go.
Hey, listen, what's your name?
Farrell?
Keep your voice down OK?
Nobody here is talking about a Fire Sale.
Not unless you are telling me
you helped plan one.
No man, I'm just saying...
We appreciate the concern, we
know what we are doing, thank you.
What?
- What?
- Nothing, I said I understand.
Hey, they didn't send the
girl scouts to get this kid.
They sent professional guys,
full tactical gear,
they blew the whole joint up.
Now look, I don't know this kid...
And, frankly, I don't give a shit.
No of fence.
But somebody wants this kid dead.
And obviously, it's got something
to do with what's going on here.
Humler is taking over
the interrogations,
of the hackers that we are bringing in.
I will get you an escort over there.
Right? Molina, get this kid
to the front of the line.
- I want to know what he knows.
- Right.
If he knew about half of what I know,
his fuzzy little head would explode.
Special agent Johnson.
I will take you there.
- Agent Johnson?
- That's right.
Right this way.
- So is any of what you were saying possible?
- Possible?
OK look, I will tell you again.
If you take away any one thing, no problem,
but if you take it down all at once,
the system crashes, and...
Look around, man!
Come on, the government has got to have
dozens of departments dedicated to that shit.
It took FEMA 5 days to get
water to the superdome.
How long until we get to
the Dept. Of Homeland Security?
Lauflin, get on the police band and get
them to clear a route to the D.H.S.
DC Metro, this is the
F.B.I., requesting you to...
Farrell just resurfaced on the grid.
The feds are taking him to Homeland.
Good, close that loop now.
Isolate the frequency.
Locate the vehicles and get
me John McClane's file.
Brad, we just found Farrell.
Stand by for location.
I don't mean to harp guys but
but have just passed another
snack bar and I am starving.
- Shut up.
- I need to eat.
Shut up.
Shut up. You have 14 minutes
to tell me why you lied to me back there.
Did I lie to you?
What are you talking about?
The pictures on the wall.
You knew those guys, right?
- I, wha..., I...
- Kid, don't lie to me.
I am a cop, I can tell you
are lying. Who are they?
OK, OK, OK...
They were my competition.
Make the next right onto Concord.
They said they were a software firm
that had developed some kind of
a new algorithm
and they just wanted to see
if it could be cracked.
That's what I do,
I do math based security.
Here's the thing,
the thing that I've been thinking is
that if you can do something this massive
you need tons of start-up guys
to write the software
but only a few black hats
to actually implement that stuff
so then the start-up guys
who haven't really done anything
- like me...
- End up as pictures on a wall
I swear to God McClane
I had no idea I was gonna be
an accessory to Armageddon
Take the next left at Lexington.
And that's a sexy voice.
What is she taking us this way for?
Oh, my God!
Unit this is dispatch
clear a route for two F.B.I. Vehicles...
F.B.I. We have cleared a path.
- That's her!
- Her who?
What are you talking about?
It is them.
- Are you saying it's "them" them?
- I swear to you, I know her.
I would know her voice anywhere.
- Don't say anything.
- Keep you mouth shut for a minute.
Hey Metro,
how's your day going over there?
Gotta be crazy over there
with all these 5-87s, huh?
Yes, Sir, we had to
dispatch all units.
Yeah you had to dispatch all units,
for all the naked people walking around?
Cut the bullshit honey
and just put your boss on.
Lauflin, we are getting off this route
make a left here on 14th street..
- Officer McClane.
- That is Detective McClane, asshole.
Don't worry though, we will have
plenty of time to get to know each other...
When I come visit you in prison.
But, John, I already know
so much about you.
Your address in Brooklyn...
The payments on your mortgage,
how long you have been in the NYPD
and how is Holly?
That's sad, you are divorced.
Was that tough on little
Jack and Lucy?
After thirty years, I would have thought
you had a better pension plan.
Oh and it gets worse...
Your 401k no longer exists
Tell you what, let me
make it up to you.
Box them in at that intersection.
Shoot Mr Farrell in the head,
and drive away
by the time you get to
the end of the next block,
all your debts will
be wiped clean...
And your children
will be set for life.
That really is tempting,
especially that last part.
But I think I'll pass, jerk off.
John, you are a Timex
watch in a digital age.
You are gonna lose.
Yes, well the other thing that can happen,
it is that I can come and find you...
Kick your ass and throw you
out of your own party.
- What do you think about that dickhead?
- Hold your position.
He is not responding.
Down, get down!
Officers down at the corner
of Main with Constitution.
I repeat, officers down.
Come on, come on,
get out let's go!
God Damn it!
Stay down!
Get down, just hold on!
We have a squad car under fire
we need backup.
I Repeat, we need backup!
This is base, we are
sending backup.
Hang on, hang on.
Hang on.
Hold on.
- We lost...
- Stay with them.
OK take the tunnel, left left left!
Give me the schematics
of that tunnel.
The tunnel!
Open the gates on the
North side entrance.
Redirect traffic,
occupy all lanes.
- Open the other side.
- What?
Move!
Hang on to something!
Hey, don't get out of the car!
Hey!
Stop!
Run!
Oh God!
Don't ever hesitate
like that again.
Are you alright?
- Stay here, don't move.
- What?
You've been here before John.
Get over to the wall, Sir.
The feds called in a favour.
All you gotta do is pick
up a kid in Jersey...
Drive him down to DC.
How hard can that be, huh?
It can't be that hard now, can it?
No, gotta be a senior detective
think that a traffic jam
or throwing a car at me
will stop me, huh?
Red, get in there and get it done.
This is not a good idea!
- Don't touch me!
- Ok, ok, sorry, sorry...
Are you OK? Oh my God!
- Pretty lucky shot, huh?
- Oh yeah lucky!
Jesus, you just killed a
helicopter with a car.
I was out of bullets.
How you doin'?
I skinned my knee and my
asthma is acting up...
Whatever, yeah I'm fine.
Red, check in.
What about Farrell and McClane?
- They are both dead.
- Come back in.
OK we are moving on,
begin Stage 3.
I have just spoken to Emmerson.
The teams are arriving
at Woodlawn now.
Very good.
Mai, get ready for the downloads.
I.D, Sir.
Park behind the transpo
and we'll lead you in.
Man the gate, you come with me.
The anthrax alarms only went off
across five floors.
Below that you will
need clearance.
I don't know why you would
need to go down there
there is nothing down there but servers.
All clear. Rodriguez!
Incoming.
- The gate is secured.
- Copy.
OK, we are in.
Hey, this is absurd, man.
There is tough and there is stupid.
You've got to go to the
hospital, look at you.
I am not a doctor, but
you look like you are hurt.
- Yes, sexy, right?
- No.
Come on.
We don't need a doctor,
we need the cops.
He's in.
Get out of the way,
look out, please.
NYPD, alright, I got this kid.
Come on let's go.
NYPD
Sergeant?
Sergeant!
I need to speak with you.
The doctor is in the back.
I am NYPD,
I need to talk to you.
Just give me a minute.
Oh my God!
Let's get of here.
Perfect! Now the second sequence.
The server is ready.
We are go.
Launch the downloads.
Nothing is happening.
Be patient.
- I don't know, it's not responding.
- Wait for it.
See.
There you go.
Let me know when the
download reaches 20%.
OK.
- Excuse me!
- Thank you!
Holy Shit!
Kid? Kid? Hey!
- You got a phone in that bag?
- Yes.
Come on let's go.
And here you go, agent...
Tavarek. I guess that's you.
The download is at 20%.
Time to move. Let's keep them
chasing their tails.
Due to the recent activity...
law enforcement agencies are
being extremely cautious.
They are telling drivers to abandon
vehicles, until they are searched.
And as you can see...
K-9 units are checking each vehicle.
Now whether this is connected
to the anthrax reports earlier...
or if it is a new terrorist threat
we don't know that this stage.
FAA just grounded all flights.
- Good.
- Sir...
We have complete access
over system networks.
Phones, power grids,
water, nuclear...
- Hey, excuse me...
- Dan Parry, The NSA
Chuck Summer DHS Liaison.
The White House made the call.
Anything you need,
We are here to help.
Help? Wow. That's, that's great.
We are gonna need some
work space for our people.
What can you do for us?
Well as you can see, we
are using the space...
You guys can stand in the corner,
and liaise.
And if I need something...
I'll just wake you.
- Wait, no no. Don't call.
- What?
- What are you talking about?
- They probably cracked that hours ago
if you use it they might
be able to trace us here.
- Just put in your pocket.
- Sure?
Yes.
Or smash it, you didn't
have to smash it...
Excuse me, excuse me.
This is a police emergency.
He'll call you right back.
Here, wait in here.
- Do you have a signal?
- Yes.
Yes.
This is John McClane
for agent Bowman.
Sir, John McClane is on the line.
McClane, go.
We never made it to DHS
They came for the kid again.
All your men are down.
- And what about Farrell?
- Yeah he's here with me.
- Sir?
- Hang on, John.
Yeah I'll hold on.
Another day in paradise.
They just swamped everything,
the whole telecom system.
Phones, cellular, satellite...
They are blanketing every station.
- Can you put the news back on?
- This is the news.
It on every channel,
it's been like this for a few minutes now.
Oh my God!
Shit!
McClane!
Look out!
Bowman? Do you see that?
- McClane?
- Bowman?
It's a fake.
I see it.
Thank God!
- McClane?
- Bowman.
The satellite's down.
Get me a landline.
Wrote one little piece of code
and the world falls apart.
- This is virtual terrorism.
- What?
It's crazy, the first time that I
heard of a Fire Sale
I actually thought it would be cool,
if somebody did it.
Hit the "reset" button...
Melt the system, just for fun.
Hey, it is not a system.
It is a country. We are
talking about people.
A whole country, full of people.
Sitting at home, alone...
Scared to death in
their houses, alright.
So if you are done with
your little nostalgic moment...
Maybe you can think a little
and help me catch these guys.
Just help me.
Just put yourself in their shoes.
Come on.
If this were your Fire Sale,
what would be your next move?
OK, the point of a Fire Sale is that it
is mostly done by remote, right...
But not everything is run
completely on-line.
Major utilities aren't,
they are run in closed circuits...
You can breech the security
up to a certain point, but...
To shut it down you would have
to physically go there...
You know what, give me that guys PDA.
The phones don't work,
they are all dead.
No the phones are fine
it is the network that is dead.
I only need to reprogram it...
And link it into the old sat-come,
hackers surf them the whole time.
It is probably what these guys are
using to talk to each other.
How do you know all this stuff?
Dude, I don't know.
I couldn't explain it to you.
OK.
The national power grid,
gas and the electricity...
They are divided in to
three zones, right?
Eastern, Central and Western.
Each one with a primary hub.
Here it is.
- What is that, what am I looking at?
- That is the eastern hub.
Now, they take this out...
It wipes out all the power
for the entire eastern corridor.
But again they will have to
do it manually.
OK.
- Come on, let's go.
- What, to West Virgínia?
I honestly don't think I can handle
any more people trying to kill me.
- McClane, McClane?
- Oh you get used to it.
McClane. Oh, shit!
Sir, wireless networks are down
they are hitting the landlines too.
I don't care how,
you find me a line.
Come on, what you got?
We swept the whole building,
it seems clean. We can...
- sweep it again, but...
- Don't bother.
Don't bother.
It is fake. These guys planned this...
Alright get everybody back
inside the crisis centre, now.
Let's open it up!
Come on, get in.
The door is locked. Unless
you have an extra gun to unlock it.
Hey, don't do that.
You're gonna disable it... Shit.
Wow, crazy, did you see that?
Sorry about that man.
I didn't know it would come out so fast.
How did you do yours?
Are you alright? What,
did it hit you a little bit.
Sorry.
Please, don't touch those, OK?
I know what am doing.
I have done this before.
I mean, I have read about it.
Road Assist, we have detected
an airbag deployment.
Yes erm! Please, we hit a tree...
And my Dad is having
a heart attack...
I think he is gonna die.
You need to help us!
Hold while we contact
the Emergency Services.
No, no, no! He is dying!
Please, listen to me. I can get him
to the hospital, I can drive.
I am fine! But the key doesn't turn.
So you have to start the
car for us OK? Please, Dad...
Your name, please?
My name is...
Frank and my Dad's name is...
Dvorak Tsargentzki!
Please, just help us!
We need your help, please!
The Emergency Services are on their way.
No, no, no! Listen, ma'am.
- What is your name?
- Dolores.
Dolores? OK, Dolores...
I don't know if you have a Dad...
But I do...
And I want to be able
to say that a year from now, OK?
Because my Dad is my
hero and right now he is...
In my arms, dying and...
And his only hope is...
To get to a hospital right now!
We can't wait!
So, please!
Start the God damn car!
Thank you, Dolores.
Pass the P.D.A.
I gotta call the Warlock.
- The what?
- Warlock, he is a digital jedi.
Ma'am, you are not
authorised to be here.
F.B.I. We suspect there has
been a security breech.
You have landed without authorisation.
- That was pretty good back there, kid.
- Thanks.
- What's the matter, nothing to complain about?
- No, just...
- Then what? What's the matter?
- It's not funny, I'm not like you,
I can't do this shit.
- What does that mean? Like what?
- Like... heroic and everything.
I am not that guy.
- Nobody here is a hero, kid.
- You saved my life like 10 times,
in the last six hours.
I was doing my job, that's all.
Do you know what you get for being a hero?
Nothing! You get shot at.
A little pat on the back,
bla bla bla. That a boy!
You get divorced...
Your wife can't remember your last name,
kids don't want to talk to you...
You get to eat a lot
of meals by yourself.
Trust me kid, nobody
wants to be that guy.
- Then why you doing this?
- Because there is nobody else to do it right now.
Believe me if there was
somebody else to do it
I would let them do it.
But there's not, so we're doing it.
That's what makes you that guy.
The things flying now.
Contact Emerson, tell him that
we will be there soon.
What the hell are you doing?
This whole floor is restricted access.
You stay here.
- We are in.
- Good, shut it down.
I guess you were right, kid.
OK... that's awful.
We got company.
So how would they
shut down the power?
- What?
- Come on!
Central control room.
- Fourth floor, fourth floor!
- Come on!
Shit!
- Try to keep up!
- I am keeping up!
I am just trying to stop for
just two seconds to catch a breath.
- They have these things called Gymnasiums...
- Well yeah, it's not like...
Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
Intel is fairly certain that
the terrorists are mobile.
It is the only way to consistently
avoid signal triangulation.
Judging by the amount of
hardware they are running,
we are probably looking
for a large vehicle,
probably a semi-trailer rig.
Right.
Tell the guys at
Homeland Security...
That we need every agent, satellite and
functioning network they have got.
Now!
Playtime is over sweetheart
Don't! Take your hand off the gun.
Hands up. Stand up.
Go on, now!
Let's go, kid! You're up!
As fast as you can.
That's enough of this Kung-Fu shit
I've met some bitches in my day...
But you...
Still awake, huh?
- Just keep doing what you are doing.
- OK!
- How much time do you need?
- Not much.
Are you done?
No... no, not quite...
I am not exactly checking
my email here, you know.
I ran this hacking PN mode on their
PI, I am just booting their host...
- What?
- It means about 30 seconds, ok?
It is not the easiest
thing to do, when...
OK.
- Undo everything you just did, now!
- OK, OK...
I'm a righty, I'm a righty.
I need my other hand. I really do.
I'm a righty...
One last door to open.
Do you know what you are doing?
Do you realise what this'll do to the country?
Yes, I do. Now open the door.
Ok, good. Glad we are
on the same page.
How you doin'?
Hang on!
Let's just talk about
this for once...
How you doing? That's
not too tight is it?
Damn it!
Well, great!
McClane!
Shit!
McClane, get out of there!
Come on man, come on!
Come on, man!
Did you see that?
- So you stopped her, right?
- Yeah yeah yeah.
Actually having a gun pointed at
your head makes it harder to do.
- What?
- I think she left a surprise.
Can't you just turn it off?
Lock 'em out?
I'm not sure.
I might be able to slow
them down though.
Western and central hubs are
ours, we are just waiting on Mai.
Hang on, something's up.
All of the security is
reactivating.
I think somebody is in the
market for some cheap Viagra...
And your girlfriend is dead...
Why not check out our sexy
singles you can chat with.
It's an e-bomb.
Alright, wait wait wait, OK
- Mai, talk to me what's going on?
- Mai...
Oh, yeah, little Asian chick,
likes to kick people?
I don't think she will be talking
with anybody for a long time.
The last time that I saw her,
she was in the...
Bottom of an elevator shaft
with an SUV rammed up her ass.
What's the matter?
Cat got your tongue?
Listen, Jackass! Your
Fire Sale is over.
Pack up your little circus or
I will come and kick your ass.
You have idea who I am
and of what I am capable of.
When I'm finished here and
I promise it will be soon...
I will focus all my attention on you.
You wanna make things personal, fine!
Reroute every cubic foot of natural gas
in the pipelines to that station.
- Can you get Bowman on this thing?
- Sure...
- Can get anyone.
- Do it.
- Now?
- Yes, now.
Please, no!
- That is Thomas Gabriel.
- Shit!
- You know this guy?
- I worked with him.
He was D.O.D.s chief programmer
for infrastructure security.
After 9/11, he's the guy
that told joint chiefs...
That the system was vulnerable. He was pushing
for total overhaul, but they wouldn't listen.
- Gabriel is not exactly people friendly.
- You think so?
When he tried to go public, they
crucified him, destroyed his reputation,
after that he disappeared.
We got a pretty serious problem.
Hold on a minute, what?
I think we need to get out
of here, right now.
- They are sending the gas lines here.
- Gas? What gas?
Christ!
Oh, all of them!
See that? Those flashing arrows?
That is not good.
- All that's coming here?
- Yes, I think we gotta go.
Listen, I gotta go.
Just find Thomas Gabriel!
McClane? McClane?
Let's go, finish this up!
Right now, let's go!
Come on!
Get in there!
Let's go, come on,
we gotta get out of here.
Oh what is the point, oh man,
what is the point?
Hey, knock that off. This has something
to do with that code you wrote, now think.
- Come on, help us win.
- Win?!
When did we start winning, huh?
Look around, are you out of your mind?
We are not even close to winning.
We just got the shit kicked out of us!
You think I'm holding out on you,
something I'm not telling you
If I knew what they wanted,
I would tell you!
- I would happily tell you!
- Jesus!
Warlock, Warlock!
Ah great, there goes the cell phone.
- They knocked the satellites out now?
- No, the battery ran out.
- Listen we should go see him.
- Who?
The Warlock, it's not that far
away, it's in Baltimore.
- You want to go to the Warlocks house, now.
- Hey, this is me helping you.
Trust me. We gotta go see the Warlock
it is our only hope.
- How do you feel about flying?
- You mean like, with a pilot?
- Stick it in the round thing.
- What round thing?
Here, put these on.
Stick it in there, that'll work.
- You OK?
- Yeah, uhh, I am afraid of flying.
- Yeah I used to be terrified of flying.
- Really?
I took some lessons, you know,
face my fears, that kind of thing...
- Yeah, did it help?
- Not really.
That's it...
- Is it supposed to make that sound?
- Yes.
Maybe we should just drive,
it'll be fun like a road trip...
Take it easy, they say taking
off is the hardest part.
Really, I'd heard...
- I'll be honest, I missed some classes.
- Ha Ha, you did? Really?
You got your license, right?
To fly one of these things...
Hey hey.
There we go, we're up!
That's good, that's
pretty good.
Jesus! Look at that! This
whole area's blacked out.
How will we find Warlocks house?
It will probably be the only one
with the lights still on.
Power outage keeps spreading,
half the east coast has gone down.
Alright, put everything
on emergency generators.
How the hell are they
getting past us?
- OK, down there, I see it.
- Down there?
Left, left, down.
We gonna land there?
- Alright, hang on.
- Oh, Jesus!
The fence! The fence!
- The fence! The fence!
- I see it...
Watch...
- Oh, Jesus!
- Come on.
- Oh yeah, taking off is the hardest part.
- Let's go!
There's something you need to know
about Warlock, he hates cops...
He hates them, so let
me do all the talking.
Hey Mrs. Kludis.
Is Freddy home?
I am Matt Farrell and that is Billy.
We are friends from Space Camp.
We went to Space Camp with Freddy.
Freddy!
- Freddy?
- You got company.
Frederick, didn't you hear me?
- All Baltimore heard you, ma.
- Your friends are here.
Friends? But what the...
Ma, how many times, you don't
bring people down here?
I can't see too well, you have
lost so much weight!
No, dude I gained 30 lbs,
who is that?
You know what it doesn't matter?
What are you even doing here?
I am rocking 5 generators just
so I can stay online.
And since you are being hunted by
assassins, maybe this visit
isn't a productive or a healthy way
of spending my time.
- Hey, don't touch that alright?
- CB radio?
- A little low tech for you isn't it?
- Old? That my friend...
Is an end of the world
insurance system, OK.
When the last microchip is down
I will be able to...
Be in contact with the world,
be they zombies or not.
I'll tell you that right now.
- What did you bring your Dad here for?
- He is cool, he's into games.
- Nice poster.
- Oh, what are you, a fan of Fett?
- No, I was more of a Star Wars guy.
- Star Wars! Who is this man?
He is...
Dump-truck, I'm not his Dad,
I am a cop. How about that?
Ah, a cop, I'm sorry.
Thank you very much.
Why'd you bring a cop into
my Command Centre?
- Command Centre?! It is a basement.
- It is a Command Centre!
Don't help, McClane!
I can explain...
Tell us what you know about Thomas
Gabriel. That's why we came here.
Thomas Gabriel, that's cool,
I didn't know. I'm sorry.
Get out, I want you out of here,
man, right now!
Hey, calm down.
- Just calm down big boy.
- You calm down, it's my house!
You are going to tell me what I wanna know.
Or I'm gonna kill you in your own house.
4 years ago the D.O.D.
Recruits Thomas Gabriel...
To be a cyber spook for them, OK.
First day on the job he
goes and tells his bosses...
That the nations security infrastructure
is wide open to compromise.
And what did they say?
"We will take it under advisement."
But he doesn't ease up 'cos he is
committed, like you read about.
So he breaks into a meeting
of the Joint chiefs of Staff, OK?
Using just a laptop he
hacks into NORAD
and shuts down the
entire defence network
So they put a gun to his head
and forced him to stop the hack,
Thomas Gabriel is the guy who
shut down NORAD with a laptop,
just to prove a point,
you think I'm scared of you?
- Just tell us how to find the guy.
- I don't know how, he is a ghost.
He just fell off the grid.
- Another dead end, come on.
- Hold on wait, McClane,
Listen, Warlock, a couple of
weeks ago I wrote this...
I know dude, you wrote a
mutating algorithm security code
that's probably being used
by Thomas Gabriel right now.
No, we know that, yes.
- Can you tell us what he's using it for?
- I've been trying to figure that out..
Here, look...
The only security system in
the country, that I can find,
currently employing
that particular template,
is the Social Security
Administration, ok?
They don't even use it
in the main facility, look.
They use it in this building,
over here, in Woodlawn.
What the hell...
- I know, right?
- Right, what?
What the hell you guys talking about?
The power consumption is off the charts.
It's hot, on fire.
- The chilling towers?
- That's what I thought.
- Hello, what's a chilling tower?
- Jees, see what I've been dealing with?
Large server farms generate a
lot of heat, they need to be cooled.
Why there?
I don't know what is in that building but I
assure you it's not Social Security numbers.
I have a red flag over here,
someone's hacking into Woodlawn.
Tracking IP on the server now...
Frederick Kaludis.
- Let's take a look at him.
- Fat bastard!
McClane. Where is his daughter?
We just got a trace on her cell.
You're gonna love this.
Alright let's get
a better look at you.
Freddy, what the hell are you
doing, meddling in my network?
McClane? I thought
I'd killed you already.
I get that sometimes.
Do you think you can
track where he is?
Detective, covering the camera with
your hand, doesn't turn off the microphone.
I know that am not as smart as
you guys and this computer shit.
But hey, I'm still
alive aint I?
I mean you got to be running
outta bad guys by now, right?
Gabriel?
Honestly, you can tell me.
How's that work?
Is it some kind of service or something?
Some kind of 1-800 number, 1-800 henchmen?
I bet you are still
on hold waiting:
"Get another dead Asian hooker
bitch over here right away?"
But seriously, all that kicking
aside, that skinny ninja chick...
she was smoking hot.
Another one of those is gonna be
real hard to come by, right?
- You're very impressed with yourself, aren't you?
- I have my moments.
Yeah?
Is this one of them?
- Hello?
- Yes, Emergency Services calling.
- Oh, thank God.
- Can she hear me?
My name is Lucy Gennero, I have been
stuck for hours, been trying to call...
- My cell phone's not working...
- Can she hear this?
Lucy, hang up that phone.
Calm down miss.
We know exactly where you are.
- Everything will be alright.
- Lucy, hang up the phone!
Please, John, I am
trying to have a conversation.
We are a bit overloaded tonight,
as you may imagine,
but I assure you, we are
gonna get you out of there...
Even if I have to come down there
and get you myself.
Thank you.
In the meantime, Miss Gennero, is there
anybody we can contact for you?
Yes, my Dad.
His name is John McClane,
He's a New York City cop.
We'll find him, just hang in
there Miss and we will get to you.
Very soon.
Thank you.
Wow, that's a great girl you
got there, can't wait to meet her.
What's the matter,
cat got your tongue?
Come on John? Make a joke.
Say something funny.
Wait, where are you going?
Hey, hold up. Where are you going?
What are you gonna do?
What do you think I'm gonna do?
I'm gonna kill this guy
and get my daughter.
- But she can be...
- No, listen to me.
It's gonna get messy,
You should just stay here.
- I think I...
- Hey, I'm doing you a favour.
I wouldn't bet on me, alright?
I'll take it from here.
Thanks for the help.
I wouldn't bet on you either,
so I guess I'll give you a hand.
OK.
F.B.I. Ma'am,
Jersey Field Office.
Mind if I see your ID?
None at all.
My dad is a cop, force some habit.
Your father sounds like
a very smart man.
- Kid, can you get Bowman?
- Uhh, yeah.
It's completely dead.
Gabriel must have shut down
all of the satellite links. Shit!
I'm sorry about Lucy, man.
All of it...
It is my fault you got into this,
this wasn't your fight.
You have nothing to be sorry about.
Bastard!
This bitch is a handful.
Are you gonna be alright?
Behave or I will hurt you.
Oh yeah? Let's step outside,
just you and me.
We will see who hurts who!
You really are his daughter.
Tie her wrists.
Trey! Gabriel wants to see you.
- Is it that time already?
- Yes.
I'll be back in a second.
Don't kill me! Please!
We are showing a breach
in an external vent.
Go take a look.
Don't be long, we are
packing up soon.
Hey, McClane!
Do we have anything resembling
a plan or anything?
To find Lucy and kill everybody else.
I mean like a plan,
like a way to do that.
Come on.
OK, according to the layout, the chilling
towers are kept on the bottom level.
It should be locked.
OK, now it looks like we are
getting somewhere.
OK this looks like it controls the
cooling system for the mainframe, which...
Should be...
If I can just hack in...
And trip the alarm,
it might alert Bowman.
Someone set off the alarms.
Yes, thank you detective.
I can hear that.
Find a way to turn it off.
What you got?
We got a problem.
The alarms went off at Woodlawn.
It's got to be him.
And what's, Woodlawn?
It's N.S.A.
A secure facility outside of Baltimore.
It's a failsafe we built after 9/11...
To backup all financial information.
The moment the networks were hit
all the financial data...
It automatically began
downloading to those servers.
Banks, Wall Street,
Corporate Records...
Government funds, all of it.
Basically a backup for the
accumulated wealth of America.
All in one location?
- What could Gabriel do with it?
- If he could get in he might try...
A transfer of the data
to a portable hard drive,
then he can have access to
those accounts from anywhere.
Syphon of billions for himself.
We would have no way to trace it.
But knowing him,
he could erase it all
and send us all back to the stone age.
Why the hell wasn't I told about this?
Frankly...
- It's above your pay grade.
- My pay grade?
How did Gabriel find out about
this when I didn't even know?
He designed it.
It was his program.
He knew that hacking your system
last night would trigger the download.
That's brilliant!
You two, geniuses,
stay out of my way.
Let me see if I can
get a floor plan of this place.
Don't move!
You!
Get away from the bag! Now!
OK.
We've been waiting for you.
Yeah?
I've been waiting for you too.
McClane!
Kid?
Matt? Kid?
Emerson...
We seem to have a problem
in one of the cooling towers.
- Tower 7.
- Find out what's going on.
- I will see to it. OK.
Sir?
Get the HR team to stand by.
We need to get Woodlawn, now.
The roads out, completely blocked.
DC's in total gridlock.
Then get us some helicopters.
They have all been pulled by the
Pentagon, for search and rescue.
Molina, find me some God damned
helicopters immediately.
Look, the Pentagon has jets
flying cap over DC.
Have them send one over to Woodlawn
and keep on eye on things until we get there.
Let's go!
Where is my daughter?
Russo, check in.
I think Russo is on his way down
to meet your girlfriend, dickhead.
He's on the third floor, the kid...
Did you get all that?
That's right.
I am on the third floor,
but I'm coming to get ya.
Don't move, pal,
I will send a doctor.
Kill this guy and
I will give you Mai's cut.
OK.
My algorithm.
Please... God.
Oh Jesus, they are
going after the money.
You coming to get me, John?
Is that the plan?
Yep, that's my plan.
What makes you think I wont put a
bullet in your daughter's head, right now?
Because you are scared of me.
Is that right, you think
I am afraid of you?
Cos otherwise she would
be dead already.
You need a bargaining chip.
Stop there! Hands up!
If you kill me, you'll never get it open.
Move away. Move!
You know John, I feel like
we have gotten off on the wrong foot.
And 'cos of that you think
I'm the bad guy,
Nothing could be further from the
truth, I'm the good guy here.
I told them this could happen
if they didn't prepare.
Did I get a thank you?
No, I got crucified.
- But they wouldn't listen.
- You got their attention now, don't you?
That's right.
I am doing the country a favour.
Ha ha, by tearing it apart?
Better me than some outsider,
some religious nut job
bent on Armageddon.
Nobody wants to see that happen.
Everything I've broken, can be fixed.
If the country is willing to pay for it.
Ah bullshit!
It's always been about the money.
What, I shouldn't get
paid for my work?
I'm workin' my ass
off here, John.
Just sit tight asshole,
I got a cheque for ya.
I can't talk to this guy.
You talk to him, see if
you can get him to focus.
Dad?
Hi, baby.
Now there only 5 of them.
Hang on, Lucy, I'm coming.
Would somebody, please,
kill this son of a bitch.
We have a problem.
There actually no problem here
I just got off at the wrong floor.
This is a mess.
Wow, I'm truly impressed, man.
Hacking all the financial data
of the whole country would take weeks,
unless you eliminated the congestion.
That's what this Fire Sale
is about, isn't it?
- It's brilliant.
- Yes, it is.
- Please, be quiet.
- Asshole.
- Who are you?
- Matt Farrell.
Lucy McClane.
I thought your name was Gennero.
Lucy Gennero?
- Not today.
- Can you crack the code?
Maybe, if I had enough time.
That is encouraging.
We take them with us.
- Let's go.
Gabriel, the Pentagon just sent
an F-35 towards us.
Keep an eye on it.
Pulling the go codes now.
Might wanna start thinking what
you want on your headstone, asshole.
Damned, hamster.
There you go!
Be still, spider boy.
That's right!
Seriously, you probably shouldn't
antagonise them since they have all the guns.
Listen, will you just take a minute and
dig deep for a bigger set of balls...
Because you are going to need them
before we are through.
Wow, I know that tone.
It's just weird hearing it
from someone with hair.
Sir, E.T.A. 15 minutes.
Fix it.
Why? You are just going to kill me
if I fix it, I know that.
Shit!
I'm not gonna do it.
- No no no! Shit.
- Robertson is coming really fast.
- I'm sorry, what?
- Something is wrong.
Robertson is coming too fast.
It's not Robertson.
That would be my Dad.
Freddy!
This is John McClane.
Look, I know you can hear me.
This is your frequency, right?
666. Come on pick
up the mic, Freddy.
Nobody here by that name, sorry.
Hacker jerk off!
Warlock!
I need you to do whatever
it is that you do...
To patch me through
to the F.B.I.
To Deputy Director Bowman,
you hear me?
Are you serious, you want me
to intentionally open up a com-line...
to the head of the C.I.A.
Cyber division? I don't think so.
Freddy, God damn it!
They have my daughter!
I can do that, hold on.
Thank you.
This is central, we have a
patch for Director Bowman.
Sir, central is trying to reach you.
Go.
- Bowman, it's McClane.
- McClane.
Listen to me,
Gabriel is on the 695,
headed north, in a
haz-mat truck.
Wait, Gabriel has left Woodlawn?
We were heading there right now.
Bowman, he's got my daughter.
Listen, this haz-mat truck, it's a
government vehicle so it should be Lo-Jacked, right?
Track that down,
should take you right to him.
- Gimmie the tag number?
- Alright,
Here it comes.
Golf, Tango...
Five-Niner-Two, November.
I've got it.
McClane, where is Farrell?
He is with them.
Listen to me, I'm gonna
go in there and get Lucy out.
But if something happens to me...
you gotta send in the cavalry,
do you hear me?
I mean everybody, don't let that
maniac get my daughter, you hear me?
John, don't worry.
I want your word, Bowman.
Yeah, you have it.
Why not?
There's the F-35.
Did you get the go codes?
- Trey! Did you get the go codes?
- Yes, I got the go codes.
Can you connect me to the pilot?
Isolating his radio.
Sending him the go codes.
AV-81.
AV-81, this is Marine Airway. ATC.
Gofer, AV-81.
Confirmed terrorist vehicle has been
located in your sector. Big-Rig Truck.
- We are in pursuit of a Haz-mat vehicle.
- I'm hearing you, ATC.
You are authorised to engage and destroy.
Copy that,
AV-81 engaging.
What...
God damn it!
You're shooting the wrong guy!
I don't think Daddy's
coming, honey.
Hey! Jackass!
Is that it?
Is that your best shot?
Come on, get out. That way.
We are leaving in 3 minutes.
You have 1.
The rules didn't change man, you're
gonna kill me the minute I unlock it.
- Ah, shit!
- Matthew?
Matthew! I really need
you to pay attention.
The rules can always change.
- OK OK.
- I will shoot in her in 10 seconds.
- Wait, wait.
- Nine.
- I can't...
- Eight.
I can't...
Oh, God!
OK!
Ok, ok, ok!
Six.
OK, stop stop, I'm doing it.
I'm doing it. Oh, God!
The Feds are heading this way.
Get everything on the plane.
- Dad?
- Careful.
Don't worry baby,
Everything is going to be alright.
Daddy!
Hold this.
Jesus Christ!
You got her?
You sure?
Nice effort though.
Matthew?
Shit. OK.
I'm doing it, I know.
McClane...
Would you do me a favour?
I know the lights are
beginning to dim...
But if you can just hang
on for a second...
As soon as Matts finishes,
I'm gonna kill him and your daughter
And I would love for you
to see that.
God damn it. Mathew?
10 second, ok, 10 seconds
and you will have all your money.
You can just leave,
nobody has to get hurt, OK?
A few seconds.
Stay with me, McClane...
- Stay with me.
- Dad?
On your tombstone
it shall read:
"Always in the wrong place,
at the wrong time"
How about:
"Yippi-kai-ay, mother fu..."
Daddy?
- Are you OK?
- Yeah, I'm fine...
I knew you would come for me.
Of course I would come for you.
It's OK.
Freeze!
Hold up, Hold up!
He's OK.
Help Daddy up.
I think I'll just stay
here for a minute.
Daddy, you are out of your mind.
- What are you talking about?
- You shot yourself.
It seemed like a good idea at the time.
Don't tell these guys
that I did that, OK?
Is he OK?
Lift your arms up,
Now put them down, further.
He might die from shock
on the way to the hospital.
Alright.
I'll be right back.
- Hey.
- How does it feel to be shot?
Actually it feels great. He gave me...
What's it called? Morfon...? Morphine.
- Well, you got your merit badge now?
- Yeah... I don't know what that means.
- Plus, you know, chicks dig scars.
- Really?
- Not that one.
- What?
- Don't even think about it.
- How did you know what I was thinking?
What, did she say something to you?
I felt, we had a vibe...
Take it easy, it's just
the morphine kicking in.
Besides, after all we've been through,
I'd hate to have to
beat you to death.
That would suck.
- Good to go?
- Yeah, all set.
Take care of yourself
I'll see you in the hospital.
Hey. Thanks for saving
my daughter's life.
What was I gonna do?
That's what makes you "that" guy.
Yeah.
Did he say anything about me?
Jesus, Lucy!
What? I'm sorry,
I'm just asking.
I'm in enough pain already.
Hospital...