Tony Jaa
- Tom Yum Goong: Honor of the Beast -
...Then hunters came out from the shadows...
And the Guardians were
surrounded from all directions...
The Guardians can beat them
with their sword skill!
The Guardians lost their swords,
they must fight with their bare hands.
Dady, will they die?
No no no ... Don't worry,
the hunter's weapons were useless ...
Boom ... Kick ... Punch ... Hack...
What did the hunters attack, father?
I will tell you later.
But l'm going to be an Imperial Guardian!
I want to know!
It's time to sleep Kham, tomorrow,
Alright?
Bathe in the water, Kid.
Bathe, bathe, bathe...
Did you see? He plays with me!
Yes... He likes you
You play like an elephant!
Dad, look!
Be careful...
Dad, why is she touching him all the time?
Oh...When you grow up i'll tell you.
Come on, come on...
Go from the back, from the back...
Quickly...
Look out!
Run!
As a light of a soul has faded...
And it passes into the beyond...
The holy one... The holy one...
Please take care of the soul
of this innocent creature...
When i was in the army, I was
assigned to a base near the city.
They had Kid there,
he was in very poor condition.
They treat animals very badly in the city,
so I took him to our village.
Korn...
Look...
I brought you a mango.
Want it?
She is so lucky...
Whay can't it happen to me once?
I have no luck, I'll never find a decent man.
Don't worry, you're beautiful, you'll will find someone.
He looks nice but you don't know how he is really like.
I hope I'll meet someone at the festival,
or I'll end up depressed as this elephant!
It's hard to see him like this.
So sad...
I felt the same after your mother died.
So I know what it feels like.
There is no cure.
Other than time.
Sir!
Veterinary permit.
Good day.
Over there, come on...
Sergeant Gahb...
Please step inside for a short check,
come on...
This shall take a while,
you can come back in 15 minutes, ok?
Cheif Veterinary,
this is Sergeant Gahb.
Honored Sergeant Gahb.
We served in the army togeter,
give him speacial treatment.
Bell necklace...
Hello.
How much does it cost?
Very cheap, only 2 Baht.
Holiday spirit... For only 2 Baht...
Thank you.
Load the elephant, go on..
What? Wh... What is...
Your elephant is sick, see?
But don't warry, you'll get it back
from quarantine in a week, ok?
What's that?
Security!
Watch it...
Crooks!
Call the Police!
Police!
Come on!
Move aside!
Hey! Thieves!
Get out of may way!
Pull away!
Father!
Who did this?
Kham... They took him...
Hey!
Emotional Boy!
Get out of my house!
Guards!
Get him!
Don't stand there! Go!
Help! He hit me!
You emotionless lowlife!
- You know what I want!
- I do... I do..
- I'll kill you!
- No!
Your elephant, is in Sydney.
Hey! Let him go...
No! He'll kill me!
Come on!
This way!
While NGOs were gathering to protest
the transfer of Thai elephants to Sydney.
There's a report,
that the elephant was stolen.
Mr. Witia Tamarat...
The owner of a well known
Thai restaurant "Tom-Yum-Goong".
Has been killed.
The motive of the murder is believed
to be that Witia was involved...
with a Chinese mafia gang
and many illegal activities
that can lead to business conflit
with them.
For the missing elephant.
There is no report or information
from the authorities at the moment
if this connects to the mother case
the elephant belongs in Thailand!
The best way to enrich this elephant's
evironment is to put him with other elephants!
So the can live! With his family!
In his home!
We don't want the elephant in Australia,
The elephant belongs in Thailand!
Yeah! Send him home!
Send him home!
Reporters have asked the consulate for
more information about the incident.
We are very sorry for
the incident that happened today.
We also would like inform you that.
In Thailand we have a very strict law for the
protection and conservation of elephants.
At first we thought that... the...
Giving of the elephants to the zoo
is done by donation.
We later found out that there's
criminal activity behind the scenes.
And this is the main Asian market in Sydney.
Most of the people here are Asians.
You know? Chinese, Thai, Vietnam
Oh! And Laos!
So, Officer here needs to understand
Asian square, like me for instance.
It is how I do my job, it's important
to same as with people.
Oh, very good.
Yeh, these are fresh from today...
Oh, These look great
mmm....ripe!
Yeh, Thery in season...
Take and be healthy.
How much?
Oh..Gift!
Then I'll take some more!
Thanks alot! Thanks!
It's just the way we do things here.
Asians in foreign place need
to stick together, like fireman.
Why? Do you miss me?
Take it easy baby!
I'll give you a kiss first!
Ok?
I love you.
Bye.
Hey! Jusy in time!
It is my partner, Rick.
He's a young little bit hard up rook.
A little less hard-working
than I am.
Hey! That's enough!
Mark has to work right now.
You see, Public services is a part
of our job as police officers.
You know?
To serve and protect!
I'm a damn babysitter.
Sergeant Mark, there's a robbery
at Mini-Mart on Rogan street.
Why did you call police?
You are in toruble now!
Please...Please...I'm sorry.
Do you hear me?
I want to get out!
Apparently the robber is a teenager.
Only the shop owner and his
wife are in the shop...
Oy! Get that?
I want you to drop your weapon...
Mik, Mik! No no no...
Leave him to me.
Hey hey hey...
Take it easy...
Is that you?
Ichi's son?
What are you doing?
I'm robbing a store.
This gun can hurt someone,
put it down!
I need money.
Hey... I just came in...
Aim it back at them.
Ok, you give me some money then.
Here's a dollar!
- You son of a bitch!
- No, No!
Hey! Hey!
You have the right to remain silent...
He has been charged with Entry.
Anyway, enough fun for now, ok?
Bye.
Excuse me Mark! Mark!
Another question please!
Bye bye bye.
Go home! Straigt away!
How could you do that Sarge?
It's against procedure!
There's no use arresting a young junky minor.
- Yeah but we should go by the rules..
- Who the fuck is it?
I'll be right there.
Let's go!
Oh, I can hardly hear a thing ...
Why aren't you working?
When the hell are you
going to work this debt? Hu?
Witin Yahh...
Remember him?
Or you want to die like him?
I know i can pay...
You know you can pay?
How the hell are you going to pay?
Thai students only have 2 jobs here.
One, you can be a waitress.
Or you can be a call girl.
What can you do?
You've got 2 ways,
That's it.
As you saw in the presentation.
We are a step away from
dominating the market.
Thereby...
Increasing our profit by 200 percent.
With a rise in stock value 15 times fold.
Benefiting stock owners.
The agreement will allow us to use
eastern resources.
The important of which is life.
Life...That can be very tasty.
This tastes like rodents.
Stop! Stop for a moment and think.
This is a rotten deal!
True I am also a business man.
I make money.
Own property, sometimes I win and...
Wait I'm not done yet!
...Sometimes, lose.
But why do I do all that?
What is the purpose of this effort?
The answer is simple, I want a better life!
But...Better life is not just money.
It is a good society to live in.
A society which your company steps on!
They want to buy my health.
And want to buy my morals.
Buy law, nature, the air I breath.
All for some "Big money"!
I can make money in many ways.
By selling my children's future,
all I can do is...
Lose.
Bastard.
Ruining all I have built so hard.
An interesting fact is...
That our new friend...
Is a regular customer of ours!
See?
I think it's time we treat our
customers more personally.
Sorry, sorry.
Hey, good day mate!
Where is a pretty boy like you from?
Ok, next question.
Where we're go...
Europe, hu?
OK ride ahead.
Tom-Yum-Goog.
Yeah I know this place, great food,
beautiful girls, you like girls?
Did you get into this country legally or illegally?
You've got a passport?
Change of plan.
Hang on!
Come on!
Go!
Look at him, you're good for nothing!
Nothing!
Mark, we found Jimmy heading to Thai Town,
requesting backup immediately.
I'm on it.
(I'm falling asleep...)
Stop here!
Is that the best you can do?
I'm trying!
Now some action!
Shit! Come on Boy! Come one!
Get out of the car!
Come on! Get away from me!
If you come any closer he's dead!
Get away from me!
Hey! Jimmy!
Calm down!
Let's talk, ok?
I don't want to talk!
Just get away you...Hey!
Drop the hand and piss off!
You want me to shoot him?
I'll shoot the little bastard...
Do you want to piss off?
You want me to shoot him you wanker?
Hey! I'll shoot him...
- Ok ok!
- I'll go! I give up!
What the hell are you doing?
He's the one that was hit.
No, he wasn't.
Now go get him!
I said, go get him.
What am I charged for?
I will handle this.
Vincent didn't have to shoot him.
Don't you think he went too far?
Jimmy was no ordinary thief,
I know him well.
And this guy was no victim.
How do you know?
I don't.
I just have a hunch.
What were you doing there?
You understand!
Help me find my elephant!
Of course I'm Thai!
That's why I'm handsom!
Elephants in Sydney, are you sure?
Yes, yes, they brought him here.
- Big one?
- Yes
- Gray colored?
- Yes of course.
Animals... Animals...
Where can animals be?
Let's go to the station,
maybe I'll remember later.
Tom-Yum-Goong
OTOP (Thai export program)
Hey Mark!
How are you doing?
You're here? Oww...
How's work?
- I feel great at this new job.
- Yes, fancy Tom-Yum-Goong.
- I give out dinner invitations, have one.
- Oh, thank you very much.
Ahh, no Thai pride.
Even Tom-Yum-Goong is full of gangsters now,
it used to be a respectable place.
- It's him! It's him!
- Shut up!
Ok, great seeing you!
- Yes.
- We should meet soon.
- Let me out!
- I said shut up! Be quiet!
Hey hey, what's going on?
- It's him, he took him!
- No no no.
I remember him,
he was in the picture with the traders.
No we can't do that now,
you should press charges.
Let me out, I'll take a Taxi.
No, we'll go to the station first.
Stop!
Or I'll shoot!
You're going to see the secretary...
Johnny!
Where is my elephant?
He's asking for his elephant.
Johnny!
Feeling lucky?
Fellow, you don't know who you're
dealing with, they will kill you.
This is top quality.
Kill them.
Shit!
You think this is a game?
What are you doing? James? James!
Make sure he's dead.
The Thai government says that
it is trying to resolve the issue.
Of elephants wandering around
Bangkok streets.
Ordering the evacuation of the
pachyderms out of the capital.
What should I do with the two of you?
You've lost the suspect.
And managed to cause all that
racket on the road.
I'm taking you both off the case.
It's been assigned to someone else.
As of now,
the two of you can help inspector Vincent,
with security for the Secretary General's
meeting with Mr. Sim
- Aren't you being slightly...
- I'm not racking with you!
I patched you up with Mark hoping
you'd be able to keep him in line,
I didn't expect you to start
acting like him.
We've had a report from area 3.
About drugs and an Asian shoot-out.
Everybody split the scene.
There's evidence that needs
to be collected.
I don't understand why this
area is so buggered up.
The area that you Mark,
is so proud to protect.
Where is Jimmy's body?
Wow...
Any evidence?
Look. Don't take anything.
Peep show...
Usually there are prettier bodies.
Ok, thanks!
Alright...
I got it.
I know.
I'll leave now!
The hunters were many.
The battle was fierce.
But the power of the guardians...
Was never in numbers, but their heart.
Why steal the elephants, Dad?
Some people eat animals, Kham.
At the scene of the crime.
Police have found a passport
belonging to the suspect.
Who authorities believes was involved
in the drug deal in the warehouse.
The suspect was seen wearing a red scarf.
If anyone have seen this man,
please contact the police immediately.
Alright, ok, let me get back to
you on that.
Bye. Thank you.
Is life good?
Come in!
My medicine!
Go! Go!
Hit the alarm!
It's you?
What the hell are you involved in?
They made me do this or...