The Jaturuungkabart
Were sworn to protect
the mighty royal elephants.
Why?
Elephants are so big.
Who could hurt them?
The king sits on top of them.
So they must beware
of things from below.
Beware of what, Dad?
If they lost their swords,
they would use their bodies as weapons.
Throw, crush, grab, and break.
What do they need to be careful of?
I cannot tell you yet.
But I'm going to be a Jatuuruungkabart.
I have to know.
Not yet, Cam.
One day you will know.
Hello.
- Hello.
Splash him, son.
Splash him.
Come on, splash him.
Splash him all over, son.
Splash him, son.
Splash him.
How do you feel, Por Yai?
Por Yai, you’re so naughty!.
Dad, look at him.
How was it?
Was Por Yai up to his old tricks again?
Why did Por Yai do that to you?
Oh! Splash him, come on.
Dad. I'm here.
Father. Father. Father.
Where's Por Yai going?
Let him go, son.
Pull... Pull... Pull it tight... Lasso it.
Come on, pull. Pull it.
If I ever had the chance
to present Por Yai to the King...
...it would be biggest honor of my life.
At the very least, it would mean that
I upheld the name of the Jatuuruungkabart.
Kohrn...
I have something to show you.
Nice, nah?
I reckon this Songkran Water Festival
is going to be fun.
Mr. Suthep is taking care of everything.
He's throwing a huge party.
Well, his son's now a member
of government.
Hopefully, he can give us back
some of our profits.
Koi, I heard they are going to
check the elephants for royal status.
Aren't you going to take your elephants,
to see if they're in with a chance?
Say goodbye to Por Yai, Cam.
After Por Yai has been checked...
...We might not have the chance
to see him again.
This could be
a great opportunity for you.
There's no reason to worry.
Annual Songkran Water Festival
Mr. Koi,
...this way, please.
Hello.
Welcome.
Dad. They're here.
Hello, Mr. Koi.
- Please, come inside.
- Yes, sir.
Everything's ready.
Come in.
Go on, Kohrn.
Wait outside for awhile.
Your father should go in alone.
This is Supoj, a friend of mine.
Hello, sir.
He takes care of this place.
He will take care of everything for you.
Young man, would you like a bell
for your elephant?
Do you want a bell?
Do you want one?
It's for good luck.
Do you want one
for your elephant?
How much is this one?
That one is 40 Baht.
It's not expensive.
Buy a bell for your elephant
and get good luck.
Thank you, sir.
Let me take a look.
That's lovely.
Let's go.
BLIND BOXING
Thank you.
Come on.
Bring it here.
Wait! Wait!
Are you taking him away today?
Yes, today.
You can go back home and wait there.
I will let you know what happens later.
But...
Come on. Quickly.
Move it.
Come on.
Quickly.
Come on... Come on...
You can't take him.
Not yet.
I won't let you.
You can't.
You can't. You can't take him.
I said you can't take him.
Force it to go.
You old fart.
I told you.
Move it. Quickly.
Look! Elephants.
Didn't you see the truck?
Father...
What happened, Father?
- Father...
- Cam.
Check on Por Yai.
Move it.
I said move!
Oracle Ceremony - To Find Por Yai
Baby. We belong together
enjoying the forest with a joyful heart.
The waterfall pours down
as if heaven was before our eyes.
Birds coo like my loving words for you.
Who the hell are you?
Do you want my foot in your mouth?
Go on.
Get him.
Go get him.
My teeth!
Wait for me.
Where are Por Yai and Kohrn?
- Where are they?
- I don't know.
I don't know.
You don't know? You don't know?
Johnny.
Johnny took them.
They're in Sydney.
Where is he?
Father!
Shoot! Shoot him!
Enough.
You’re hurting me.
Come on. Quickly.
Move it.
Sydney 2 Weeks Later
While the NGO were gathering to protest
the transfer of Thai elephant to Sydney.
there’s a report
that the elephant was stolen.
and Mr. Wittaya Thammarrat.
the owner of the well-known
Thai restaurant Tom Yuum Goong Atop
has been killed.
The motive of murder
was believed that Wittaya was involved
with the Chinese mafia gang
and many illegal activities
that can leads to business conflicts
with them.
For the missing elephant.
there is no report or confirmation
from the authorities at the moment
if this connects to the murder case.
...belongs in Thailand.
The best way
to enrich this elephant’s environment
is to put it with other elephants.
so that he can live with his family.
in its home.
We don't want the elephant in Australia.
The elephant belongs in Thailand.
Yeah!
Send him home!
Reporters have asked the Thai consulate
for more information about the incident.
We are very sorry for the incident
that happened today.
We also would like to inform you
that Thailand do have a very strict law
for the protection and conservation
of elephants.
At first. We thought that the...
giving of elephants to the zoo
is done by donation for public use.
We later found out that there’s
criminal activities behind the scene.
And this is the main Asian market
in downtown Sydney.
Most of the people here
are Asian, you know?
Chinese, Thai, Vietnam.
Oh, oh, oh, oh!
And Laos.
So officer here
need to understand Asians way.
Like me, for instance.
This how I do my job.
It's important to stay in touch
with the people.
What beautiful mangoes.
Hello. How are you?
They look lovely.
How much?
Do you want some?
Take some.
Take them. It's no problem.
- How much?
- Forget it.
- Are you sure?
- Just take them.
Well, okay, then. Can I take two more?
Take them. Go on.
- Thank you very much.
- Not at all.
This just the way
we do things here.
Asian in the foreign place
needs to stick together.
Like firemen.
...I'll be there to chase.
Why? Do you miss me?
Whoa, Wwwwhoa, Wwwwhoa, Wwwwhoa,
Wwwwhoa, Wwwwhoa, Wwwwhoa.
Take it easy, baby.
I kiss you. I kiss you first.
Okay?
I love you.
Bye.
Hey! Just in time.
This is my new partner Rick.
He's a young
aristocratic kind of bloke.
A little less hard-working than I am.
Hey!
Lighten up, mate!
Let's not work right now.
Using public services
is part of our job as police officer.
You know?
To serve and protect.
You look like you're constipated
or something.
Sergeant Mark. there's a robbery
at mini-mart on Thurwood Street.
Why you call police?
What am I supposed to do?
Apparently, the robber is a teenager.
Only the shop owner and his wife
are in the shop.
All right, listen up!
I want you to drop your weapon...
Nick, Nick, Nick.
No, no, no, no.
Leave him to me.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Take it easy.
Take it easy, mister.
Okay? Okay?
Hey, Tuui.
You stupid prick.
What the hell do you think you’re doing?
How did you know, Sarge?
You idiot. With a face like that,
who wouldn't be able to spot you?
Put the damn gun down.
Put it down!
Stay away.
If you come any closer, I'll shoot.
Shoot me if you want,
but don't forget your mother.
When she gets here,
you're in deep shit.
Don't lie to me.
My mom isn't here.
She is. Look behind you!
Come on. Imbecile.
Look. They caught the guy.
He's so brave.
It's been just another day.
Anyway, enough fun for now, okay?
Bye.
Excuse me, Mark.
Mark, can I have another question, please?
Go on, run.
Don't be such a wimp.
You idiot.
How could you do that, Sarge?
It's against procedure.
It's no use arresting young junkie mind.
Yeah, but we should go by the rules.
Put a sock in it!
Don't you know?
Just forget it.
You idiot! Go! Go! Go!
Let's go!
Shit! When did that happen?
Why didn't anyone tell me?
Why aren't you working?!
Why in the hell
do you think your boyfriend's dead, huh?
Remember him?
Or do you wanna die like him?
I know I can pay.
You know you can pay?!
How in hell are you gonna pay?!
Huh?!
Thai student only allowed two jobs here.
One, you can be a waitress,
or you can be a call girl.
What can you do?! Huh?!
You got two weeks.
That's it!
News from Thailand.
Thai have expressed a concern
about the boycott from NGOs.
If the NGOs truly understood
the elephant situation here,
then they wouldn't be against us.
From all the exits to the meeting room,
guards have been placed
at every 10 meters.
Uncle, I have
arranged everything for you.
I've hired Sydney's top chef
to make abalone soup.
I made it for all of you.
I hope everyone will enjoy it.
Especially you, Uncle.
You should have more of it.
This is good for your health.
It will keep you strong.
With good health,
you’ll be able to look after
the family business forever.
Are you sure this is abalone?
It's bland, there's no aroma
and no sweetness.
It tastes like earthworms.
You know earthworms, right?
Slithering insects
which have 2 genders...
without being either.
So what about it, Rose?
If you can't even
provide proper food for me,
how do you expect to protect me?
For security,
it's better to let Cheng handle it.
I think this is better.
When your father was alive,
Cheng Was in charge.
What you do shows
no respect to our clients.
We are negotiating
with representatives of the government.
If we unite with them,
our business will grow rapidly.
Concentrate on the restaurant
I gave you.
That's enough responsibility
for you, Rose.
That stupid old man made me lose face
in front of everyone.
You don't need to be angry or impatient.
You already have this, don't you?
I think this new fate of mine
will finally rid me of that old man.
Sorry. Sorry.
Hey, g'day, mate.
Where's a pretty boy like you from?
Next question.
Where We go...
Oh, here, is it?
Okay, right ahead.
Tom Yuum Goong.
Yeah, I know this place.
Great food.
Beautiful girls, too.
You like girls?
Tell me something, did you
get in this country legally or illegally?
You know the big gates...
Have you got a passport?
Change of plan.
Hang on!
Come on!
Look at them!
They're good for nothing! Nothing!
Mark. We found Jimmy
heading to Thai town.
Requesting back-up immediately.
I'm on it.
A tricycle is faster than this.
Stop here!
- Is that the best you can do?
- I'm trying!
God, you drive like a pensioner.
Shit! Come on.
Come on, boy!
Come on!
Get out of the car!
Get out of the car now!
Come on.
Keep away from me!
You come any closer, he's dead.
You hear me?
Keep away from me!
Hey! Jimmy! Calm down.
Calm down, calm down.
Let's talk, okay?
I don't wanna talk!
Just get away!
You! Hey! Hey!
Can't you hear me?
Piss off!
You want me to shoot him?
I'll shoot the little bastard!
Hey, hey, hey!
- I'm gonna count to three.
- Stop!
One! One... piss off!
Do you want me to shoot him,
you wanker?
Hey! I'll shoot him!
Piss off! Eh!
Okay, okay!
Uncle! I give up!
What the hell you doing?
He was a hostage.
No. He wasn't.
Now go get him.
I said go get him.
I didn't do anything wrong.
I will handle this.
Vincent didn't have to shoot him.
Don't you think he went a bit too far?
Jimmy was no ordinary thief.
I know him well.
And this guy was not with him.
- How do you know?
- I don't.
I just have a hunch.
What are you doing here?
Oh! Are you Thai?
I'm speaking Thai.
Do you think I'm Burmese?
Did you come to Sydney
to break the law?
No, sir.
I've come here to find Por Yai
and my little brother.
- You’re looking for your relatives?
- Yes, sir.
- What do they look like?
- Like elephants.
Elephants?
Who's like an elephant in Thai town?
Come on. Let's talk about this
back at my office.
Mark!
Hello.
How's it going, Goong?
- Are your clients keeping you busy?
- Not really.
It's your fault.
You never visit my restaurant.
I'm really busy.
- There's a new promotion on.
- Yeah?
Special price at lunchtime.
- I'll go if I have time.
- Okay.
It's a Thai restaurant.
Tom Yuum Goong is Thai food.
So why did they hire
a Vietnamese guy like Johnny
to be the general manager?
- It's Johnny! Johnny!
- Shut up!
Okay. See you later.
See you.
- Work hard.
- You, too.
Follow them quickly.
Hurry up!
I said shut up! Be quiet!
- Don't start any trouble.
- Follow that car quickly!
Quiet down! Quiet down!
Those are the people
that took Por Yai and Kohrn.
Don't say that.
You can't accuse someone
without any evidence.
I have a photo, but it's in the taxi.
Don't waste my time.
We'll talk at the station.
Hey!
Let him go.
Hey! Hey!
Stop!
Or I'll shoot!
I've come to see the secretary.
- Sure you wanna...
- Johnny!
Where are my elephants?
He asking for his elephant.
Johnny!
Give me back my elephants.
We are both Thais. So I'll warn you.
Don't get involved with them.
This is top quality.
Kill him.
Shit!
You think this is a game?
What are you doing?
James.
James!
Make sure he's dead.
The Thai government says it is trying to
resolve the issue of elephants
wandering around on Bangkok Streets.
ordering recreation of the pachyderms
out of the capital.
What should I do with the two of you?
You lost a suspect and managed to
cause all that ruckus on the road.
I'm taking you both off the case.
It's being assigned to someone else.
As of now, the two of you
can help Inspector Vincent
With security for the Secretary-General's
meeting With Mr. Sim.
Aren't you being slightly...
I'm not arguing with you.
I paired you up with Mark
hoping you'd be able to keep him in line.
I didn't expect you
to start acting like him.
We've had a report from area 3.
About drugs in an Asian shoot-out.
Everyone's fled the scene.
There's evidence
that needs to be collected.
I don't understand
Why that area's so buggered up.
The area that you, Mark,
are so proud to protect.
Where is Jimmy's body?
Whoa.
And the evidence?
Look. Don't take anything.
I know.
You’re an ugly son of a bitch.
Okay, thanks.
A Thai man with a red scarf.
- What did we lose?
- A lot.
We’ve also lost our dealer..
Who will want to do business with us
after this mess?
Get the hell out of here.
- Do you want me to...
- Just get out.
All right.
I got it.
I know.
I will leave now!
Kings sit upon the elephants.
Vital areas are underneath.
Enemies aim for those areas.
Soldiers protect the 4 most vital areas
of the elephants.
One day you will know, Cam.
At the scene of the crime
police have found a passport
belonging to the suspect, who
the authorities believe he was involved
in the drug deal
at warehouse inn King Cross area.
The suspect was seen
wearing a red scarf.
If anyone has seen this man.
Please contact the police immediately.
Yes, yes.
All right, okay.
Let me get back to you on that.
Right. Thank you.
To our success!
All right!
My... my medicine.
Go! Go!
What are you doing?
Tui.
What the hell are you doing?
He forced me to do it, Sarge. I...
What? What the hell...
Rick!
What's up, senior constable?
You’re not familiar
with your new gun?
Take him.
He and this Thai boy
killed the Secretary-General.
Bring him back!
Over there.
You, go with him.
Come on.
Go right here.
Boss, he's gone.
We searched around.
One girl is missing.
Find her.
It disgusting.
People who buy pirated DVDs!
Don't do it again.
The assassination of the
Secretary-General of the police bureau
has shocked the city.
Police are now tracking down
Senior Sergeant Mark,
who is well-known in China town.
The coroner's reports indicate
that the fingerprints on the gun
belong to Senior Sergeant Mark.
Police assume that the motive
behind the killing
was a trade dispute.
Meanwhile, the Asia Channel
has recently broadcast a secret tape
that Senior Sergeant Mark
illegally released the Thai convict.
- Hello.
- Mark.
This is Goong.
Where are you?
I just watched the news,
and I'm worried about you.
Don't say anything.
Someone might be listening.
Can we meet?
Plas just called me.
She has evidence which can prove
that you’re innocent.
She won't see me unless I see you first.
No problem. Where?
Mark?
I'm sorry.
You!
Where's the camera?
No! Let me go!
Let me go!
I don't know, I don't know!
I don't know anything!
Please! Let me go!
Ever since Johnny came here...
it has been hell for everyone.
Everyone from the waitresses
to the manager.
I don't know what to do.
They built a secret entrance
at the back of the restaurant...
for their VIP clients.
Everyone wants to know...
what goes on up there.
Hey! No! Please!
I'm sorry! No!
Maybe the relative you are looking for
is up there.
Where's Johnny?
Hey!
Hey, you!
Where are my elephants?
What's he saying?
What you looking for? Huuh?
Looking for this?
Kohrn!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Don't touch me!
Let me go! Johnny!
- Hey, Johnny!
- Let me go!
Let her go, Johnny!
Kohrn!
Have you found your brother?
Shit! An elephant!
A real elephant!
How did you get here?
Kohrn!
Come, come.
Rose, the heir to the business
should be Sim's son.
But Chao is only thirteen.
He's still a child.
He doesn't yet have the ability
to run the family business.
Then the most suitable person
should be Kang.
He is the son of Third Aunt,
who is the younger sister
of both Sim and your father.
Um, that should be good.
Kang has just graduated
in Management from England.
He should be able to take good care
of the business.
Why don't any of you think
about how I feel?
I am also my father's child.
I have devoted everything to this family.
I would always help Uncle
when he was still alive.
Take a good look at yourself.
You’re neither a man nor a woman.
How do you expect us
to let you run the family business?
We wouldn't be able
to show our faces in public.
Kang! What's wrong with you?
Please don't scare me. Help! Help!
You! Why did you do this?
The most suitable person is dead...
What's wrong? Tell me, Chao!
...and the second is dying.
Is there anyone suitable left?
In that case, I accept the responsibility.
I promise you all...
I will make the family business
better than ever.
I won’t let you down.
I won’t let my father down.
And I hope for the utmost cooperation
from you all.
Authority says that this restaurant
has been the front of an illegal activity.
The owner has been accused for selling
and cooking endangered animals.
And the most shocking of all,
that there are young girls from Thailand
who have been sold as a prostitute.
I can't say much right now,
but our sources say that a number
of Thai police are involved in this.
A Thai man with a red scarf
pops up often in these reports.
At least we still have the girl.
As bait.
Johnny, you've been with me
ten years now.
Do you still not understand me?
What we are about to do
is of immense proportions.
But you can't even take care
a little operation like the restaurant.
How does make me look?
You let those high losers,
get on my nerves.
And you still have the guts to face me?
Get out of here.
Leave it to me.
I'll take care of everything.
You always seem to know what I want.
How can I ever pay you back?
Well, how about this?
To return your kind favor,
Let me get rid of those
who stuck their noses into our business.
My sweetheart.
It's no big deal.
Let my men handle it.
But what fun
is merely watching the prey,
when we can hunt it ourselves?
Be patient, Kohrn.
We'll find Por Yai together..
Hey, you know
Where Cam and Mark are?
We're looking for Cam and Mark.
Cam and Mark.
You know who they are?
- No.
- Come on, you must know.
- Where's Cam and Mark?
Where is Mark?
You better tell me now!
...share with you that...
Hey, Cam.
We can't stay here anymore.
I think we've disturbed you
enough, Father.
Thank you very much
for your gracious assistance.
Once you have stepped on fire,
no matter how far you run,
your feet Will still burn.
At least we won’t cause you
any problems.
I must go now, Father. Come on, Cam.
- What are you doing to do now?
- I must find Por Yai.
I think that transsexual
knows something.
I think we should
go back to the temple first.
Father!
Someone, help!
Get out quickly. Go on.
Cam!
You should take the elephant
back to Bangkok.
I have connections at the port.
It would be easy for you to go back.
What about you, Sarge?
Don't worry about me.
And I promise to bring our business empire
to new levels of greatness.
Especially now.
We have the full collaboration
of the government and police.
Since this is new beginning for us,
may I be the first one to announce
a slight change of name
of our business empire.
Where's my elephant?
Where is he?
So...
Who am I gonna shoot first, huh?
The elephant?
Or the monkey?
You... asshole.
You piece of shit!
Kohrn!
You’re scum!
Get on your feet!
Your mother's a dirty whore.
Get up. Get up!
Johnny. Put the gun down.
Put the gun down!
Johnny, put down the gun!
I came to settle the score!
You wanna catch me?
You know where to find me.
This majestic elephant...
...Will enhance your dominion.
All will bow to you...
...and the power which you hold.
Kohrn! Kohrn!
Stupid!
Watch out!
What you done!
Be careful my elephant!
Bring him down.
Get down! Move!
An elephant is most vulnerable
at its tendons.
If its tendons are severed, it will fall.
Wait.
Lower down, lower down, lower down.
Up, up!
Are you okay, Goong?
A good man is always a good man,
no matter where he is.
I have good news.
Your new partner.
Name?
Somsaka, sir.
- God, are you Thai?
- Aren't I speaking clear enough?
You sarcastic piece of shit!
Excuse me.
What about the reports of a Thai man
with a red scarf and a baby elephant?
Elephants have represented Thailand
for many years.
We respect them as if they were
our own brothers, our family.
Thai people don't appreciate it
if anyone tries to hurt an elephant.
Actually, Thai people like peace.
Peace! Peace, you know?
But we don't like it,
when people take liberties.