Here. Thank you.
Thank you.
- Here. Thank you. - Thank you.
Your mother was a volunteer teacher here.
Every single brick in this school was built because of her.
How long ago was this?
Probably the year before you were born.
The year before?
Principal, you must have gotten it wrong.
My parents were already married then.
Ji Fan.
Actually, your birth father...
was this volunteer teacher from the university.
He has a very lively personality.
Just like you.
I don't believe you.
When your mother was pregnant with you,
this university student got into an accident.
Because of you, your mother had no choice but to marry Director Ji.
Director Ji was really good to your mother.
He also treated you as his own son.
It was just that your mother  had found it hard to forget this volunteer teacher.
Soon after, she left home and came here.
Until she fell ill and passed away.
Ji Fan.
The reason why your father never told you this
was because he didn't want to destroy the image you had of your mother.
But this is really too unfair to him.
So,
I should tell the truth to you now.
Subtitles by team Single Princesses and Blind Dates at Viki
Miss, please sign here.
Shareholder Chen,
it has been a long time since we last met.
Moreover, the prizes are really good.
Have the gifts been prepared?
I have prepared them.
- You must host them well. - Yes.
There's nothing else.
- Go and get busy. - Yes.
May I know if you are...
Please queue up and register over there.
So many people have come today.
Not only would the shareholders be here today.
I heard that they mystery person who gave financial backing would be here too.
So the person who could fish out  several billion at one go would come too?
I am really anticipating this.
The person you are anticipating is here.
He's here.
Director Ji.
Everyone, excuse me.
Director Ji, can we talk about
your acquiring of RA Group shares.
Is it because of Xin Yue Company?
What is your real motive?
Can you say a few words for our TV viewers?
I am the reporter from Song Guan Evening News.
May I know what are your plans?
Everyone.
We will answer the questions at the press conference later.
Please excuse us now.
Stand back!
Every injustice has its perpetrator!
Everyone, stand back.
Don't come over!
Mister, don't be impulsive!
Stand back, or I'll kill him.
Don't be impulsive!
Every injustice has its perpetrator!
Mister!!
Don't be impulsive!
I'll kill him if you come over!
Mister, don't be impulsive!
Let's talk!
Let's discuss about this.
Don't hurt our Director.
Go!
Mister.
Hurry!
Go!
Put down your knife.
Go.
Listen to me...
You better not fool around!
How is uncle?
Uncle?
Yes. The guy who got attacked on TV.
You know Ji Peng Wei?
I don't care who Ji Peng Wei is.
Tell me how is Uncle Ji.
Looks like she doesn't know anything.
He had dragged him into the conference room on the 5th floor.
5th floor?
You never thought this day would come.
You acquired organisations  and made me suffer an injustice.
It is your fault that my wife left me
and my family have broken up!
Uncle Ji!
Stand right there!
How dare you bring the police here?
Get out. Otherwise, I'll kill him.
It's dangerous here. Get out.
It's alright.
- I'll talk to him. - Get out!
Please watch your own safety.
Uncle Ji.
Stand right there!
If you come over, I'll kill him.
I'll come in exchange for him.
You?
Who do you think you are?
Me? I am his daughter-in-law.
Tong Tong.
Get out of here.
It is dangerous here.
No.
I want to accompany you here.
I know!
Both of you have conspired to lie to me.
What daughter-in-law?
I heard you calling him "uncle".
What nonsense is this?
You can't come in here.
He is Mr. Ji's son.
Let him in.
Uncle Li, what is the situation now?
Miss Le is in there.
I did not lie.
Hasn't it always stumped you why
he acquired the entire organisation
because of a small company?
The reason is me.
I am the one who begged him to do that.
I...I don't believe you.
That is the truth!
Let him go. Take me instead.
That way, you can control his son.
Too late.
It is too late to say these things now.
I know that there are police outside.
As long as we do not sue you,
you would not be charged.
If I can't live,
you guys won't leave here alive either.
Don't!
Tong Tong, don't be afraid.
If he really wanted to kill someone,
he would have done that a long time ago.
You!
Do you think I really don't dare to?
Don't!
I believe that you dare to.
But you never thought of  the consequences of your actions.
I can't consider so much now.
You can choose to not think about it.
But have you considered your daughter?
This has nothing to do with my daughter.
Your daughter.
Her name is Fang Dan, right?
She is your precious daughter.
How...how did you know that?
Before I acquired the organisation,
I made a background check on all relevant personnel.
I know that
you dote on your daughter very much.
Your daughter is also very proud of you.
She thinks that you are a good father.
Have you considered that
when this matter is broadcasted on TV,
what will your daughter think of you?
I...
I believe that my daughter will understand.
Even if she understands,
would her classmates understand?
People in school  will point fingers at your daughter
saying that she is the daughter of a murderer.
Would you have known that?
I... then...
What should I do then?
Put down your knife.
Go out together with us.
I will make sure that the reverberations of this matter will be as little as possible.
Moreover, I won't sue you.
I definitely won't kick aside  all the old guards of this organisation.
I have already made adequate arrangements for you.
You...
Uncle Ji.
Will you really let me go?
I will ask for pardon from the police.
Fine. I...
I will believe you one more time.
I will go out with you.
Get up.
Uncle Ji.
Mr. Ji.
Mr. Policemen,
He has already surrendered.
He has surrendered.
Uncle Ji...
You are not allowed to hit him.
Who are you?
I'm his son.
Dad, are you alright?
I'm alright.
Ji Fan.
You finally call me "Dad".
I'm sorry...
We will be holding a press conference later.
All thanks to Miss Le.
Otherwise, things would have gotten ugly.
Not at all.
It was what I should have done.
Miss Le.
Were what you told that man the truth?
I...
What did she say?
She said...
she's my daughter-in-law.
I only said that in the heat of the moment...
I understand...
Looks like our Ji Fan doesn't have the luck.
Sorry. Let me take this call.
Tong Tong, where are you?
I have something on.
Later, I would like you to accompany me  to take a look at the grounds of the wedding party.
Tonight?
Yes.
Why? You have something on?
Didn't you always hoped to have an unforgettable wedding ceremony?
Fine then.
Wait for me at home then.
OK. See you later.
Tong Tong.
I have something on. I have to go first.
Mr. Ji.
These are the details of RA Group's shares.
Take a look.
Later, I will hand it over to Ji Fan.
Now, it is time for him to take over.
Tong Tong.
Are you willing to stay for me?
We have already gone too far.
It is no longer possible now. Sorry.
Subtitles by team Single Princesses and Blind Dates at Viki
Colleagues.
Since I took over as Vice-Chairman,
our company's sales has improved.
So,
with the approval of Chairman Fang,
to increase another position of Manager  in the wedding planning department.
Upon several recommendations,
we will now invite the new manager  to say a few words.
Hello everyone, my name is Ge Lan.
Thanks to Chairman Zhao,
I was invited to take on the position of manager of the wedding planning department.
Because of my wealth of experience in going for blind dates,
I believe I will be able to give everyone  many good ideas.
[Delete Chang Sheng?]
Forget it.
No harm leaving him in my phone contact list.
Manager Ke.
Help me interview for the new assistant.
I really don't know what this new generation that was born after 1990s, is thinking!
I'll be right there.
Did you bring your CV?
How old are you?
Which school did you graduate from?
Do you have any job experience?
What position did you take in your previous job?
Next.
How old are you?
35.
So old and still come for interview?
An old cucumber painted in green?
Pretending to be fresh?
It doesn't matter.
As long as I can work with the girl I like,
it doesn't matter what I work as.
That...
Any work experience?
Does being a boss count?
Probably.
What company did you start?
I know. An inn run by crooks.
Right?
No.
It was a bar whose business was doing well.
Later, because I fell in love with an employee,
but she didn't reciprocate my feelings.
And then?
Later, in order to assauge the pain,
I visited the four famous mountains in Buddhism.
Mt. Pu Tuo, Mt. Wu Tai,
Mt. Er Mei, and Mt. Jiu Hua.
And confess my past crime  of being flirtatious to old monks.
I did that till my intestines turned green.
Really.
Then I thought they might take me in as a disciple.
But they said that
it's not time for me to leave the mortal world for monkhood yet.
So I was allowed to come back to settle matters of the heart.
You beancurd brain!
Why didn't you ask me along?
I will definitely convince them  to make you a monk.
But I still haven't made my final wish come true.
This is a little embarrassing...
I shall do my own accompanying music.
What colour
What choice
Full of memories
Sadness or happiness
Don't cry.
How many girls  have you deceived with this trick?
Never before! This is the first time.
I do not know if it would work.
I am afraid that after I agree,
someone would still be flirting out there,
and mixing around with other women.
No. This time,  I have really turned over a new leaf.
If I really flirt around in the future,
you can use this
on me, once and for all.
Wouldn't you be a real monk then?
Can't bear to?
No salary, only tips.
Work 6 days, rest 1.
Security, bartending and assistant. You'll do it all.
Then.
Only salary, no tips.
Work 6 days, rest 1.
Cleaning, security,
customer service. All inclusive. Will you do it?
Boyfriend, Husband, Dog.
I'll do it all.
Dad. Your arms and legs are moving together.
Don't be nervous.
Why should I be nervous?
I'm not nervous...
You are perspiring all over.
No air-conditioning. Warm.
It's warm.
At this time, we should move forward.
Two steps. Come.
One. Two. OK.
I will then read the blessing.
And then I will ask
if there is anyone who has reason  why this wedding should not continue.
Otherwise, they should forever hold their peace.
After that, I will first ask the bride.
Le Tong Tong.
Do you take this man  to be your lawfully wedded husband,
in sickness and in health,
and for whatever reason,
you will always love him, cherish him,
respect him, accept him.
and be faithful to him
as long as you both shall live?
Tong Tong,
at this time, you should say
"I do."
I do.
Good.
During the official ceremony,
please be more focused.
Next, I will ask the bridegroom.
Fang Yan,
Do you take this woman  to be your lawfully wedded wife
in sickness or in health,
and for whatever reason,
you will love her, and cherish her,
respect her, accept her,
and be faithful to her
for as long as you both shall live?
I do.
Good. At this time,
you can put the ring on the bride.
In the name of the Father, and of the Son,  and of the Holy Spirit
I pronounce you, Husband and Wife.
What therefore God has joined together, let no man put asunder.
Le Tong Tong, Fang Yan,
I have great joy in witnessing as you pledge your love to one another in holy matrimony.
I hereby announce you, husband and wife.
At this time,
the bridegroom may kiss the bride.
Good...
This is the entire process.
I hope that during the official ceremony,
you won't be too nervous.
Be more relaxed, ok?
Sure. Thank you, Father.
You're welcome.
Tong Tong, it would be our wedding in a few days' time.
I am still busy with a few things on my side.
I can't accompany you.
I understand. Go get busy.
Uncle, Aunt.
I have something on. I'll leave first.
Let's go.
He's leaving just like that?
Your husband's career is too massive.
He's leaving us just like that?
He really is rather busy these days.
You must be more understanding.
Let me tell you.
Let Carry be your bridesmaid during the actual wedding ceremony.
I have been one three times already.
If I do this again,  I would really not be able to get married.
Are you that superstitious?
Oh yes. Has Carry's book signing tour ended?
SHe has just come back.
Let me tell you.
We have prepared a special surprise for you.
We intend to hold  a wild bachelorette party for you.
Ba Mei.
You said you intend to hold a WHAT?
Aunt, don't worry.
This wild party only has females.
No men allowed.
In that case.
Oh yes.
Don't let it get too wild either.
Mom!
(If) it's not wild...
how can it be called a wild party then?
Cheers!
Tong Tong.
Fang Yan just left you there to do his own stuff.
Aren't you angry?
Tell us the truth.
Do you still think of Ji Fan?
She's hesitating!
That means you are still thinking of him.
Ji Fan and I are very good friends.
But Fang Yan doesn't want me to meet up with him.
So petty?
Then after your wedding,
does it mean you can't have contact with any members of the opposite sex?
I don't wish for it to be this way either.
But...
Enough...
Let me announce some happy news to you.
Firstly,
Tong Tong is about to marry  the handsome guy, Fang Yan.
Also, Carry's nationwide book-signing tour is now complete.
I have good news for you too.
I have been accepted into the foreign university that I applied for.
Moreover,
it is a full scholarship!
Congratulations!
- Thank you! - I'm envious!
Wait.
I have good news too.
No. You already have a good husband. What other good news do you have?
I know.
Your husband has bought something nice for you?
No... I know!
You must have lost a pound or two?
Losing a pound or two isn't considered good news.
Sou Sou.
Ignore Ba Mei.
She is jealous that you got married before she did.
I...
OK.
Tell us your good news.
I'm pregnant.
Really?
Be careful...
Sit down.
Don't hurt the womb.
This...
I want to be the kid's god-mother.
No. Only those who are married can be a god-mother.
Who said so? That's unfair.
Who said single girls can't be god-mothers?
Carry, am I right?
I have no comment.
Even if I am unable to get married in the future,
it's alright with me.
What's wrong, Carry?
You're not happy?
No.
I just felt that everyone seems to have a good partner.
I am the only one who is single.
Who said so?
Sister Huang Ye too.
Please.
Don't bring me into this.
I willingly gave up.
She must be still thinking of  Li Xiao Yao.
Don't mention him.
I get angry when you mention him.
I have known him for so long.  Yet he is still so immature.
But his love for you  is very mature.
What is the use of that?
Love.
I don't even know where he is.
You can go after him.
Jia You!
Coming...
Stop pressing!
Where's Xiao Yao?
Xiao Yao? Xiao Yao has moved.  You know that.
He even changed his phone number.
That.
Perhaps he wants to start a new life.
Start a new life?
Can you please tell me where Xiao Yao is?
I'm sorry.
I really don't know where he's gone.
Looks like the two of us are really not fated.
I can see that Xiao Yao was serious about you.
But you kept making things difficult for him.
Ji Fan.
If you see Xiao Yao,
please tell him
that I came to look for him.
Thanks.
Carry, Carry, Carry.
This week's edition of "Fashion Magazine".
Take a look.
It's written pretty well.
Oh, especially page 100.
Photographer: Li Xiao Yao
That, um...
I'm here to apply to be an assistant.
Books say that
"When you're in a bad mood
eat a piece of chocolate".
Books also say that
"When you can't think of an idea
eat a piece of chocolate
and your thoughts will become clear".
Thank you.
No problem.
It's expired.
Just kidding.
Continue working. Continue working.
Don't holler in the office.
Carry. Carry.
Don't drink so much alcohol.
Alcohol is bad for the body.
It'll make you older more quickly.
I'm already 30. You're 20.
This is a fact.
If the attitude is young.
The person would also become young. Yeah!
My attitude is even older.
It's about 50 years old.
Why are you still here?
Did you do this?
It's not bad.
It's pretty late.
Have you eaten yet?
No.
Say, I deserve
to be praised, to be cherished.
Got it!
What's wrong...!
The utmost, memorable.
Last night...
I have already thrown away
the word "Love",
ten years ago.
Also, what happened last night
doesn't count as anything.
We really have nothing going on,
right?
Do you need me to say it twice?
I don't like flowers.
Useless actions.
Stop thinking of tricks
that appease little girls.
I won't fall for them.
33 presents.
This way
it doesn't matter it was birthdays before I met you
or after.
I would have celebrated for you.
I'm the older sister. He's the little brother.
Also
he's younger than me by a lot of years.
Why
didn't you tell him just now
that I was your boyfriend?
Can you not
always lose your temper like a kid?
It makes me very tired!
From today onwards,
I will use
the rest of my life
to prove my sincerity to you.
Please accept
my marriage proposal.
I always wished that
we would be together in the future.
But I was wrong.
Our relationship
was definitely a mistake.
No.
You're not wrong. I was wrong.
I was completely wrong about you.
Let's break up.
Carry, just hold on a little longer.
We'll be there soon. Hold it in!
Careful!
Are you an idiot?
Donating that much blood.
Do you think you're a "Blood Oxen"?
I'm fine.
My body is very healthy.
As long as you're fine,
no matter how big the sacrifice
it's definitely worth it.
What are you laughing at?
Seeing me sick, are you happy?
No, I...
Happy birthday to you!
Happy birthday to Carry!
One orange balloon
carrying your smile.
[It] found the sky that belongs to me.
Floating away, forgetting me.
Holding your right hand.
I'm not afraid of you flying over me.
One orange balloon.
Jumping around with you.
Fighting for a dream.
There's a lot of bumps along the way.
Not caring about the wind and rain.
Binding you and me.
Never landing.
Good, Very beautiful.
Here, another one.
Be more happy!
Okay, very good!
Here, take a look.
How do they look?
Not bad.
They're good.
Good right? Not bad.
Xiao Yao.
later.
Xiao Yao, come karaoke with me.
No, I asked first!
I said it first! I said it first!
Alright, alright. Don't argue.
We'll eat first, then go karoaking after.
Okay?
Li Xiao Yao.
You brat.
You just come and go.
You didn't even tell me
that you change your number.
Hey, who do you think you are?
Why are you so mean to our Xiao Yao?
Xiao Yao, she's your older sister right?
She isn't. She's...
" Air".
Do you know what "Air" is?
"Air" means "doesn't exist".
Also, you don't have to
acknowledge her existance.
But unfortunately,
if there's no air,
humans will suffocate.
Do you know what that is? It's...
I hate it
when I'm not by your side.
I already said you are my air.
Then what am I to you?
Do you really want to know the answer?
Yeah.
Alright.
I'll let you know
the answer right now.
Lonely memories.
Is that clear? But I know
everything has all passed the transit migration.
Not very clear.
If you do it again
I will...
Let's just say that everything has ended.
Why
does the sound of your voice...?
Is that clear enough?
Clear.
Not clear. Everything's messy.
I... I...
If there's another one then
I will...
You!  My world.
Hey, is there
something wrong with her brain?
Probably.
Who has a problem?
Don't spout nonsense!
Carry,
is there something wrong with your brain today?
Li Xiao Yao!
No problem (with her brain).
Do you know how old
the Earth that I'm laying on is?
46 billion years old right?
The Earth's age
is 46 billion years old.
And we have a difference of 10 years.
Does that count as a lot?
Yesterday's promise
has already left me.
There's only one person left
in the rain.
Why does my reliance...
¿But 5 yrs old and 15 yrs old
is a pretty large gap huh?
But if it was 85yrs old
and 75yrs old,
it should be about the same right?
Yeah, it's about the same.
This is something you said, okay?
Subtitles brought to you by team SPBD @ Viki
Tong Tong.
Why haven't you changed yet?
I'll change right away.
Do you still remember
the wedding schedule?
What's wrong? You don't look happy.
Nothing.
Are you nervous about
getting married?
Maybe.
What's there to be nervous about?
Cinderella
has become a princess.
You should feel
very happy.
But I think that
I'm more like Sleeping Beauty.
What's wrong with being
Cinderella?
The end is still
living happily ever after
with the prince.
Right?
Cinderella was abused by her step mother
and two sisters.
I wasn't.
I was just waiting quietly
for love to come.
Just like Sleeping Beauty.
Is it that
you're still waiting for someone else?
We are about to get married.
Why are you saying this?
Sorry.
I was just joking.
I hope you don't mind.
Okay. Hurry up and change.
I'll wait for you outside.
Why isn't the chairman here yet?
I already
talked to his secretary.
He should be here soon.
Has the security been arranged?
That... Remember.
Don't let the accident that happened last time
happen here.
The chairman is old.
He can't take any mishap.
Don't worry.
I've already made all the appropriate arrangements.
In a while,
when the chairman's car arrives
and the door opens,
there would be a bodyguard
rushing over there.
That is the best case scenario.
You,you,you...
Why are you here?
I'm here to work.
No, let me tell you.
We're here to welcome
an important guest today.
You can't park here.
The parking lot is over there on the left side.
Okay?
I'm really here to work.
We are not hiring today.
Take your helmet.
Hurry and leave. Wait...
I'm making a phone call.
Do you know him?
He's Tong Tong's boyfriend.