ALIENS IN THE ATTIC
Oh, my God, Stewart?
- What is it?
Tom's grades finally posted.
Look!
- Wonderful!
Not one A!
- No.
Or B!
- Hm..huh!
Not even in Health?
What the..?
- It was a D.
How are these changing?
Utter one word and you're dead.
Are you crazy?
Dad catches you, he's gonna kill you.
- Dad's not gonna catch me.
I don't get it!
What you see in that guy?
Bye, babe!
You mean other than the fact that...
..he's good-looking, sweet, sensitive,
romantic, funny...
..and ridiculously athletic?
Dad's coming and he is mad.
- And who?
Tom!
- Tom?
What?
If you're so smart enough to hack into
the school's website...
..then you're smart enough to pass maths.
Do you think Bethany got accepted to Michigan
by screwing around all the time?
Of course not.
She got in because she's perfect.
No, your sister worked her tail-off.
And that's excatly what I expect from you.
Yeah, you're right, Dad.
I don't deserve a family vacation.
I should stay home tomorrow.
Learn my lesson.
Oh, no, no!
I'm not taking that bait, kiddo.
This isn't you.
The bad attitude, the grades...
What is going on?
- Nothing.
I blame all this, for coming between this,
right here.
A good old fashioned, no tech...
..family togetherness is exactly
what we needed.
So, get some sleep.
We're hitting the road at sun up.
Oh, and you guys too.
Hannah!
Please next time, you ride the hump, okay?
I throw up in the hump,
remember?
..and that's the final report.
In other news, it looks like there will be more
than just fireworks in the sky tonight...
..as an unexcepted meteor shower
adds a little excitement..
..to our area this holiday.
Sound's exciting!
We're going in for a real show.
It would be beautiful, guys.
- Better wear your hats, tonight.
Hope, you don't want to get your
heads on fire.
Wow!
Your boy toy is a complete idiot.
Ricky is not a boy toy.
We're in a true loving relationship.
Okay, why don't we talk in a few years,
..when you have a clue
what's dating all about.
Like, Ricky has a clue?
One more word about Ricky,
And I swear to God, I'll kill you.
Okay, that is enough!
Knock it off, you guys!
We're almost there.
And there is the pool.
Bye.
Leave me, Uncle Nate.
Oh, ya, haha!
I got it, Tom.
Don't worry!
Nice, huh?
- Nice, nice! I got that.
Hope, there's a discount for booking us into the
most boring spot in the whole country?
Come on! We're almost stone's throw away
from world's top-notch fishing lakes.
Oh, We got a time machine...
So we can go back 5 years,
when they thought fishing was cool?
Hey, I bought us all whole new
side strap reels.
Anti-reverse technology.
Lame!
So lame!
Nice landing, Nate!
Told you, I could fish tail this thing.
Nice try, Nate!
But you just missed my kids.
But he did almost give your mother
a heart attack.
Again!
Nana!
- Hi, Mom.
Hi, hon.
- Nana!
Hey, sweetheart.
I got you a little treat.
- You did?
Yep, I did.
Here we go.
Thank you.
Oh, it's so good to see you.
Hey, we're here!
- I missed you.
Well, one of the Pearson brothers,
came to party.
Are those even legal here?
- No!
Come on, Stu!
Let's get him.
Nate, stop it! Hold on!.
- Get him! Get this bastard, Nate!
Take his shirt off.
- Mom?
Oh, Stu's crying for mommy-y-y!
Twins, in here.
- Hey, guys.
Put my bags on the bed.
- Sir! Yes, Sir!
Can I be the wise guy?
- No. Definitely not.
Don't provoke.
- Good.
Now, get these out of here.
Oh, wait a minute.
Why, you get the best room?
I was here first.
- I'm here now.
I'm older.
- But I'm bigger.
Did you grow up since Christmas?
- 2 inches, Coz!
I can tag a stop sign without even
having to jump.
And how's math fights?
- I don't do math fights anymore.
You tired of getting beat up?
Tom?
Get down here and help us unload.
Now!
Close the door on the way out.
Surprise, surprise, Princess!
- Ricky, what are you doing here?
I'm just stopping by to spend my afternoon.
Or may be the night!
What's that?
- What's what?
Ricky!
Hey, watch out for the car.
- I can't believe you're here.
Well, you're my girlfriend now.
So there's nothing,
I wouldn't do for you.
Give Papa some sugar.
Bethany!
Please, don't give Papa Sugar.
Mr. and Mrs. P!
- Ricky, wow!
- Hey, Ricky!
What a surprise.
I got you what a housewoman get.
Oh, that's so sweet.
Isn't he sweet?
Yes, they are beautiful.
- They are gorgeous.
Yeah, very patriotic too,
huh?
Let's stick these flags in some water
and see if they grow.
Yeah, we can do that.
Hey, do you want anything to eat
or drink?
Oh, that is so sweet of you!
I..And I really wish I could...
But my parents are in a lakehouse
in Oakstown and...
I got to get back before dark,
incase my car breaks down again.
Oh ho! Car trouble.
- Dad, why don't you look at it for Ricky?
I don't mind getting my hands dirty.
Try it again, Ricky.
That would be some obvious, Dad.
I gotta be honest with you,
auto mechanics isn't really my thing.
Now, if this was a spreadsheet or a ledger,
I would be all over it.
Tell you what, Ricky.
Why shouldn't you stay here, tonight?
And will take your car to the shop
in the morning?
Mr. P! That's really considerate of you.
- Well..
Really? He can stay, tonight?
- Yeah, in the den. On the couch.
Of course!
- Don't fool around.
Dad!
What a gaspipe!
I know!
Why can't they see that?
Oh, dude!
Parents are wired coupling.
Their brains are old.
Machines.
Fried from bad 80's music.
So, it's upto you, Thomas.
You got to defend your family honor.
Like a man.
I call it
'The Punisher'.
Your dad bought you this?
- Perks of divorce.
Never underestimate the power of
a grown man's guilt.
If we even mention mom,
he drives us straight to the mall.
This is all yours.
Don't be a...all your life.
I don't know, man.
Take a look at that guy.
Do you really want Ricky as your
brother-in-law?
Heck, no!
Then let's go trim the family tree.
It's much fun out here, Ricky?
Oh, yeah!
You know, it's just the beginning.
Wow, the sun off the water...
And this cotton..is so...
..restricting!
- I hate cotton.
Mind helping me with the lotion, babe?
I think, shooting my sister's boyfriend,
isn't the best idea.
This isn't about ideas,
this is about action.
Don't think.
Do!
I can't beleive, even,
I'm listening to you.
You're dressed like a shrub!
Now, spread on my chest.
- Target is on the move.
Hit it now, before he reaches second base.
No, I don't think...
Why did you that?
- Cover! You'll compromise our position.
Oh, my God!
She saw us.
What do we do?
Don't look.
Head down and lie hidden.
I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
- You shot my boyfriend.
Sorry, don't even touch that.
When, Tom?
When you're gonna grow up and stop
being an total embarrassment?
And that's why we use camouflage.
- Shut up, Jake.
I don't know, what were you thinking.
I really don't!
Yeah, I'll be alrite.
- A paintball gun?
Don't you know that it's a gateway gun?
Come on, what's next?
B..? Pellet? Stun?
What..
What I'm gonna do?
What do you think I should do?
I don't know, what to do!
Can't you keep him in his room
for rest of the week?
But, it wasn't even me.
- Okay, Okay.
Look! You boys are just lucky that
Ricky was't badly hurt.
It's okay, Mr. P.
I was little kid once too.
Oh, that's nice, Ricky.
Thank you.
He's a good guy.
He's a good type.
But, I'm not okay with this.
We are here to fish.
Not to hunt your sister's boyfriend, alrite!
You could have put his eye out,
would that have been funny?
I don't think so.
Let's start off with a clean slate.
Tomorrow, we fish.
7.a.m, sharp!
- 7?
You're kidding.
- Pass.
Nate?
- Yeah, Stu.
Don't you think that's a little too early?
How about this?
10.a.m on the boat.
No questions asked!
Way to crack it, Nate.
Way to crack it.
Oh, Stu?
Stu?
Baby, the TV's all haywired.
- Stu, TV's got haywired.
Mom! Mom! Stop it.
It's probably the dish.
Right after the storm, I will climb up
on the roof and fix it.
Hey, wait a sec, Mr. P.
Let me fix this, man.
That's the least,
I can do for your hospitality.
No Ricky, you're hurt.
- Oh, no, it's just a graze.
- No. No, honey!
He's fine!
Go ahead, Richard.
Show some muscle.
- Yes, indeed!
But I'll be needing a helping hand.
What do you say, brother?
Here's a chance to bury the old hatchet.
Make things alrite with Ricky,
or don't come off that roof.
L-l-ladies first.
Wow!
It's all a creep show.
Alrite.
Here we go.
Listen, about the paintball thing...
- Oh, hey!
Don't worry about it.
Firecracker!
Too slow.
You know, what?
Thanks to your little...
..sharp shooting stunt. I wrapped up
pretty points with your parents.
And your sister's just itching to be
my private nurse.
So thanks a ton, ace.
That was a textbook maneuver.
Come on, quit stalling.
Get your butt up there and
make me your Nana's hero.
But you told my Dad,
you would fix it.
Oh, I told your Dad a lot of things.
Like, my car broke down...
My parents are on a lakehouse...
I'm 18...
You're not a senior?
Not in high school.
Now, go.
Go.
Hello?
Dude, you made it too easy.
- It's not funny.
What the heck happened to the dish?
I can't do a week here,
without TV.
I can't do a week here.
Period.
Hello, humans!
Please tell me, you see that too.
Not sure want to, but yeah.
- We come from up...
Wow, wow!
Wow!
I handle human contact.
- Yes, Sir. Noted.
Yes, I understand.
Hello, humans!
No need to notification army.
We come in pieces!
In peace.
- What?
Say with me..'Peace-e-e'
- What are you talking about?
Stupid book!
Forget the book!
Attack the humans!
Attack!
With pleasure.
Humans!
Submit.
Hey, what is it, you girls took so long?
- No! No, lookout!
Ricky!
What's happening to him?
- Now the fun begins.
Testing, Testing!
Testing...
Testing.
Insignificant subjects!
We are the Zirconian species.
And we hereby claim your lushious planet
as our own.
What?
- What?
You have the choice of turning
into slaves or...
..instantaneous death.
Run?
- I'm good for run.
You have chosen instantaneous death.
The human corrupts are escaping.
- It's locked.
Not from me.
Which way?
Duck!
Unbelievable!
Razor, go.
- Yes, Sir!
Hey, can I play too?
- Hey, Han! Thank God.
Open!
Hurry!
Creepy-crawly!
- No, no, no..come back!
Come back!
Get down.
- Get down.
Hey, frog face.
What's up with all the noise?
Open the window.
Open it.
- You open it.
No, you open it.
Hurry!
- Get them.
Someone open it.
Come on, right there.
Hurry up!
Move, twins.
Everybody downstairs!
Now!
What?
- Just move.
Creepy-crawly!
Creepy...
- Go, go, go..go!
Down!
Move, move!
- Hurry up!
Grace Commander, be careful.
- What's wrong with this?
What's wrong with this?
Be careful.
- Fix it.
I will.
This is very, very...
You're a zombie?
- No.
You?
Prove it.
- What do you mean?
I mean, prove it.
- You wet the bed until you were 10.
A zombie wouldn't know it.
- Here, they come!
Look out!
- Ugly human.
Take the rope.
Tom, tie it off.
- I'm trying, push harder.
Oh, my God!
She scratched him with her claw.
Get off, sucker.
Wow, you cut off her nails.
We got to call 911.
I can't get a signal.
- Neither can I.
Mine's dead too.
These midget Martians must..us.
Never a good sign.
It's working.
There's no buttons.
What is this thing?
It's a rotary phone.
You see that?
What happened up there?
Was 'Get them' not clear enough?
Someone was obviously distracted.
I was following the plan.
You were playing with your little toy.
This is a deadly weapon.
- No.
It is!
- These are deadly weapons.
Listen all yourself!
This is why we lost success on
our mission previous.
Not looking to blame through,
but that was Razor's fault.
What? You with...
- If we loose success this time...
I loose my command.
Now, you going to learn to work together...
..or we'll together end up shovelling manure
back in Sector-7.
We won't let you down, Sir.
Let's go and slave some humans.
Oh, actually, about that...
I'm sure, enslaving is funny but...
But why the humans?
- What?
They don't seem that bad.
- Oh, poor kid!
Oh, they don't seem that bad?
Funny, that's what our engineer previous said.
Engineer previous?
Right before that creature that was
'not that bad'...
..ate him!
Humans are vicious.
Peace is not an option.
Sheriff, here.
There's an alien invasion in our rented house.
Knee-high beings, very violent!
Knee-high? What like..a hobbit?
- No. Real.
Look, I know it sounds crazy but
you gotta understand...
Okay, yeah, listen son!
You do know that making a forgery complaint
is a federal offense?
Is punishable...
- Hello?
Decent technique...
for a female.
How's that technique?
Hello?
We gotta tell our parents.
You think, he's still an alien zombie?
You are useless.
Why aren't my mind control plugs working?
You are the engineer,
figure it out.
Hurry up! Hurry up!
Fix it.
He's not talking to us, right?
- Fix it, you idiot.
I think, he's picking up their conversation...
..there, like a bluetooth.
Are you telling me that the plugs only
work on mature subjects?
Why did we not plan for this?
You have failed me.
Your incompetent piece of...
'Translation not available'
These humans will pay.
Did you hear that?
- Yeah, sounds like Ricky landed on space.
No, those things they shot at us.
They..they are mind control plugs.
They won't work on kids.
It's like you said,
we're wired different.
What...
What about Ricky?
They..him and he's Bethany's age.
Look, he lied.
The fool's in college.
So, if their plugs don't work on kids..
- That means we're safe!
It means we can fight.
- It means, they'll go after our parents.
They are walking targets.
- We gotta tell them. Now!
Wow! Wow! Wait!
Think.
If our parents even go near those things,
they'll  get zapped and are zombies.
Our own parents will attack us.
- We need the police.
And a hard-core firepower.
- Armed zombies, even better!
We are done.
- Game over.
Game over for the grown-ups.
But we can still fight back.
Do you expect to stop an alien invasion
on our own?
He's right.
We are the only option.
But we can't tell anyone.
No police, no parents,
no exceptions, go it?
Hannah?
They are up in the attic.
Right now! Little aliens!
They are loud, and scary,
and really mean.
Han, there's no such things as aliens.
- Yes, there is. I saw them.
They smashed the skylight and tried
to break the attic stairs.
Well, let's hope not,
for your sake.
We put a huge deposit on this place.
You boys, better keep it in one piece.
You heard her, Tom.
No more trouble.
It was just a video game.
We shouldn't have let her watch.
It was pretty creepy!
- Yeah! Yeah!
Tommy, I'm scared.
I don't like the mean aliens.
Don't worry, Hannah.
Just pretend it's a big game.
A game, we all gonna win.
Just think about how little they're.
Little and deadly.
- What we do now?
We figure out the weakness.
They flew here from other galaxy,
you really think they have a weakness?
First rule of the warrior code...
'All enemies have a weakness.'
Sparks!
Why isn't my locator map up and running?
I told you,
I need parts to repair it.
Aha, even on Earth,
the male is dominant.
Wait...
- But the female always wins.
What the...?
By thy rings of Zirkon.
Makes no sense.
- They were fighting...
Now their lips are hugging?
I would never...
- Never.
Never-r-r!
Oh, I'm sorry, can I get you anything?
Cold drinks or snacks?
Or would you rather help me
invade the planet?
Alrite, here comes my specialty.
I'm going up.
I'm coming with you.
- Tom, be careful.
Enemy...
..apprehended.
I'll interrogate here.
Disgusting.
- What? Seriously, what?
Locator activated, Sir.
- Excellent! Target the objective.
Zoom in!
Zoom-m-m!
Zoom!
Zoom, zoom...
- You don't have to keep saying zoom.
Zoom..eh...
..and rotate.
- They're after something in the house.
Keep rotating
- Good...
I'm going in for a look.
- Stop.
Rotate, rotate...
Ah...
the basement!
Tom, help me!
That must have hurt.
Basement.
We gotta get to the basement.
Ricky?
Hey guys, wait!
Have you guys seen Ricky?
Pretty sure he's still hanging around here,
somewhere.
Actually, Beth...
- He didn't leave, did he?
No! No!
He...
He told us,
he was heading back to the lake.
..to bronze up his rock-hard abs.
Hey, he wants you to meet him there.
Wait.
What you guys were talking on the roof?
Did he say anything about me?
- No. No! He...
He talked about his car and...
Pretty much his..his car.
But you should hit the lake, so...
- Yeah, the lake.
Over there.
- The lake's over there.
I'm telling you,
their map led down here.
You positive?
- Shh, you hear that?
Rice krispies!
What is that?
It's them.
Something down here is setting it off.
Well, whatever it is,
we can't let them get to it.
Everyone, gear up!
We move on my command.
- Wait, just hold on.
If we run up there with a bunch of random
gonna get creamed.
We can make something better.
- We are in the middle of a battle...
..and you wanna play science fair?
No way!
We're going back in, now!
Before our parents end up as alien zombies.
You're not thinking.
We need a plan.
I already have a great idea for a weapon.
Yeah?
Let's go.
Now!
Hannah, hand me that tape.
What's up, Nate?
- Hey, guys.
Who wants a treat?
Huh, that's a lot of tools to,
try to fix a TV.
They are passing through!
Warrior Code says
'Strike first'.
Art, cover me.
With the rake?
How do you feel now?
Suckers!
Mission accomplished.
Oh, Christ.
It's a...
What the...!
What's happening?
- Why are we floating?
They turned off the gravity,
like in Halo.
This isn't Xbox, Lee
It's real.
Like Wii!
Now, what we gonna do?
- I don't know.
Stay behind me.
Go! Go! Go!
- Go, it's not okay...
Hello, humans!
Enjoying the ride?
They have gravity boots.
- Why don't we have gravity boots?
Yeah, gravity boots...
The door!
Stop them.
Use your weapon, Tom.
Bring it to me, sack.
- Today!
A potato gun?
That's your big idea?
My plan is working.
- My plan. You mean, my plan.
Hurry, Tommy.
You okay?
- I'm fine.
The door?
- On it.
Jake, get the grenade.
Hurry!
Quick!
Toss it here.
What?
Sweet monkey.
You little...
Go. Stand back.
- Shoot them.
Shoot them.
- Go! Go!
Huh!
Alrite, tough guy.
What a gun fire.
Wow, that's the thing,
he used to control Ricky.
Wow!
Wow, Cool.
Let me see it.
Nice action on the toggles.
What are these..?
- Give it back.
Let me see.
I picked it up first.
Give it back.
- Lee!
Hey..hey guys, this is not a toy.
It's real.
Ricky?
- Yep.
Get him before somebody finds him.
I'll stand and alien watch.
s
I'm sure that will buff right out.
- Just a little.
Wonder, where he went?
- Oh, I'll find him.
Wow!
Cool, so these move him.
And these...
..rotate the arms.
Talk about the ultimate gameboy!
Do the big button, dude.
Wow-w-w!
What the...?
My Car-r-r!
That would be the on or off button.
Press again.
Who did this to my car?
- You did, you giant idiot.
Ricky!
Where have you been?
Oh, shut up, you little...
Bethany?
What?
Why are you hitting me?
- Why are you being just a jerk?
Huh?
- Revenge is so sweet.
I just spent the last hour walking
around the lake.
Where were you?
I thought so.
- No, I don't know.
Want me to bring him back?
Hey, what's the matter with you?
- You just...
Let him suffer.
Where's Ricky?
Taken prisoner by the aliens?
- No, worse...
..my sister.
Any action up here?
It's been quiet.
Too quiet.
Got it?
- Yes, Sir.
What are they doing in the vents?
Their map!
That's how they get to the basement.
What do we do?
Hope this works, Einstein.
I'm getting get to thank you for pulling me
back to safety back there.
Because I didn't need you to.
Oh, that doesn't make sense.
- I don't like you.
Cut the crap up.
- Okay.
I'm sweating?
It's hot.
Hotter...
- Run.
Run!
Fall back! Fall back!
Sounds like...
Nice job.
I think it's working.
Kids! Get down here,
right now.
Who turned on the heat?
I did.
We need that on.
Are you crazy? It's July!
- Yeah, but it's freezing here.
Oh, yeah, Arctic.
I think, Han is coming down with something.
Han, what's going on?
- We are fighting aliens.
I'm pretending it to pretend.
I mean,
I just pretend.
Okay, but I'm not pretending.
So...
..don't touch the thermostat.
Tom, I'm not playing around.
- Neither, am I.
Tom, I'm not kidding.
You wanna spend the rest of the week
in your room?
Why not just trust that there's a reason
on doing this?
A reason you're blasting the furnace
on summer vacation?
Yes!
A reason why you shot your sister's boyfriend?
- Yes!
A reason why you're taking back,
giving me attitude?
Failing your classes?
So that's, this is about?
I failed them on purpose.
Yeah, I changed my grades, okay?
I'm tired of getting picked on because
I'm a brainiac.
I was brainiac,
it worked for me.
I don't wanna be like you!
I wanna be cool.
Don't touch the thermostat.
Are you sure?
Really failed on purpose?
Nobody likes a mathlete.
Man, we can't fight these things with
our parents around.
We can't just get rid of them.
Maybe we can.
Here's what I want you to do.
Send it.
I hate it, when we fight.
I can't fight someone as cute as you.
Well, I'm glad we made up.
Well, it's not official to make-up
without a make-up kiss.
Are you serious?
My family is up there.
And your family is crazy about me.
And what about you?
- Well, you know I like you.
And we have all the summer ahead of us.
May be we don't need to go so fast.
What?
Is that a no?
Ricky!
Careful!
Don't break him.
Ricky!
- Let him have his shirt.
Still no sign of them.
Where are they?
- Two options!
We are dealing with a retreat...
..or a surprise attack.
Surprise attack!
Hey!
Where's Tom?
I thought he's gonna help you.
So did I.
- Bad news!
The leasing office called.
They need you to go back there before
they close for the holidays.
Really?
- Problem with the contract.
They insisted.
Ricky, are you okay?
Oh, umm, ahh...
Just allergies, Mr. P.
- Just allergies, Mr. P.
But they did say it's urgent.
Urgent?
Okay. I'll call and
I will resolve this out.
That's so weird.
Oh, this is weird, Stu.
I think the phone is dead.
They just cut off our power?
Oh, they're gonna hear about it from me.
Let's go!
And we're going down there, right now.
- Hey, guys...
We could use some more beers
and chips...
Why don't you run up the grocery store?
I'll fire up the grill.
And watch the kids?
- Okay, whatever.
No!
- No!
I mean, you all have to go.
They...
They said that all your names are on the list.
I'll look after the kids.
- I don't know if that's a good idea.
Well, I guess I could drive.
Okay, okay.
- Oh, and Mr. P...
..while you're out,
can you get me some adult diapers?
Mine are almost full...
That is a bad allergy.
Superabsorbent!
Look!
Alien death gas.
Don't breathe.
Put him on pause.
Happy 4th of July, space maggots.
Jake, there's smoke in the vents.
It's me.
We heard these things on the move,
I'm tracking them down
and heading them off.
Thanks.
- Parents?
Gone!
- Thanks.
Now, we can take it up to next.
This could get ugly.
Hannah!
Go hide.
Yes
- Me...
Not you.
Incoming!
- Move..move! Go!
Sayonara, suckers.
Oh...
- Crap.
Go! Keep moving.
- Keep moving.
Go! Go! Go!
Go back.
Go back!
We'll have to go back.
Now, I'm starting to see why
the last engineer...
I see, you booby trapped your room.
I got it, got it...
No, don't got it.
Genius human snare...
Oh, Wow!
I thought I was clumsy.
It's okay, don't worry.
- We come in peace...
It's okay,
I'll help you.
Don't worry.
It's okay.
Oh, you got to.
Don't move.
Okay?
- Thank you.
Tazer. Razor.
Sparks..!
Sparks...?
He's critical to the mission.
Nice sounds.
- It's music.
Music. I try?
- Sure.
That definitely slowed them down,
but those buggers adapt fast.
We need to pull up big guns.
Black cat whistler or Fire Dragon?
How about not burning down the house?
He's armed...
Enemy armed.
Hannah, step away from the alien.
No!
No. Leave him alone.
He is my friend.
He was just holding a raygun to your head.
It's my bubble blower.
He fixed it for me.
He is not like the others.
Look!
First sign of aggression,
I'm taking him down.
..with extreme prejudice.
- I don't have training for this.
No training...
- It's okay, Mr. Snugglelump.
Snugglelump?
- Yeah, that's what I named him.
My name is Sparks.
- He's not your pet, Hannah.
He's a freaking alien.
He's my alien.
Hi..
Oooh!
I mean..Oh!
Maybe she's right.
I mean, look at his belt...
It holds only tools.
It's okay, buddy.
We just want to talk to you.
Come on, Snuggs.
Back off.
Watch!
Awesome.
How does he do that?
What the heck was that?
Talking about feelings comes as a territory
when you have a girlfriend.
You know, there's no need to fall for that one.
Okay!
Okay, I get it.
I'm here to talk and
I'm yelling.
I'm sorry, it's...
amateurish to shout.
Look, I'm so..
so happy being your girlfriend.
But if you really care about me,
the way that I care about you.
Then it shouldn't be a problem to give
me the time that I need.
May be you should think about it.
I respect guys like that, okay?
Take all the time that you want.
I'll be here...
..ready to talk.
With you.
So, that's how it is?
I'm getting the silent treatment?
Well, who is in high school now?
Why are you trying to kill us?
What's the invasion plan?
What is your weakness?
- Water?
Earthworms?
- Women?
Are there more of you coming?
- We need the information.
Guys, don't be mean...
- Hannah, we have to interrogate him.
Do you want the world to end?
Do you?
No...
Wow-w-w!
House, here.
Mission objective, here.
What you're after isn't in the basement!
It's under the basement.
- Yes.
What are you trying to steal from
our planet?
This isn't from our planet.
Look at that thing, looks alien to me.
It must be from their planet.
Yeah!
Planet Fruit Cake.
Whatever it is, it's huge.
Almost done.
So that's what in the capsule.
Some kind of giant machine?
Oh, great!
A giant alien death machine.
No one said anything about death.
- Yeah, well, I doubt it's a photo-copier.
Come on.
We can't trust this four armed freak.
He's one of them.
- He's not.
This guy doesn't fit in with the others.
He is...
..different.
Great!
A geek alien.
Jake, he is not a geek.
It's better than a killer alien.
Buenas noches, wrinkles.
Oh, this is ridiculous.
Well, this sucks.
Modified!
- Wow!
Sweet.
Sweet..!
Sorry.
It's the Popo. Be cool.
- Be..cool?
Open up.
Oh, crap!
We forgot about Nana.
Hold on.
Hannah, quick.
Hide your alien.
- Open the door now.
Snuggs, get in.
Hold on a second.
- Children of my children...
..I request entry.
I have candy sweets.
Don't open.
That's not Nana.
Are you sure?
Yeah, I'm sure.
Surrender engineer Sparks, now.
Get out of my way, Earth children.
Move.
- Nana...
..don't make me hurt you.
Nana, I was...
Return him to me.
Tom, do something.
Oh, gross human.
Someone's gotta get the door.
- If they get the cops, it's too dangerous.
Nana, move.
- Leave my Nana alone.
Silence, little human.
Silence!
I got Nana's controller.
Free me!
Free me or face the consequences...
Oh, no!
- In here.
You will not catch me.
I have you.
Oh, you...
Shake all you want,
we own you.
The suitcase.
Go.
Ha, missed!
Stand still,
Earth maggot!
Got it.
- Don't let them take Mr. Snugglelump.
Art, quick.
Shoot them!
- Shoot the humans!
- Get down.
You lose.
- He's ours forever.
I'm sorry, Han.
I'm sorry they got him.
Sweet, huh?
- Very nice.
This is the Creek Landing
Sheriff's Department...
..open this door at once or
I'll begin enforceable entry.
In 10, 9...
- Okay.
You guys get rid of the cop,
I'm going after the aliens.
5, 4...
- We can't leave him up here.
..1.
Don't know how much, you kids,
know about penal codes.
But making phone calls with the intent
to annoy or harass...
..is a serious offense.
It's congruent to mischief and
it can mean 6 months in jail.
911 is for emergency calls only.
In any misuse of this system compromises
this county's only line of defense.
And that's me.
Around here, I'm the law.
Literally, I'm the only one.
My Deputy is on maternity leave.
Look, Sheriff.
We told you, we were sorry.
It won't happen again.
So, really...
You can leave now, we'll be good.
Oh, I can leave?
Okay, we got the whole problem solved.
Hey, what's in there?
- Don't worry about it.
Squadron, come in!
Come in!
Do you have Sparks?
- No.
Oh, is there any job,
you two don't screw up?
Come in!
I'm sorry, I apologize.
That was unthought for it.
You are still trapped in that box,
aren't you?
Yes, I'm.
Step aside, young man.
- No, no need for that.
It's just my sister's robot dog.
It's sound activated.
Right, Han?
- Right. It's not an alien.
You know what?
I'm gonna take a look inside that chest.
So please step aside.
It's the Popo.
Be cool.
One hour!
We were gone one hour.
What happened?
What this kids do?
Hi, I'm Nina Pearson.
Are you kids, okay?
Is everything, okay?
- No, ma'am.
I would say making a forgery call to 911
about an alien invasion...
..is most definitely not okay.
You called 911?
Come on, buddy.
I'm sure, you can let these kids off...
..with a warning.
Look at them.
One, I'm not your buddy.
Two, I have noticed that your vehicle
is missing a proper license plate.
Three, how about I write you a big ticket?
- How about you don't?
Nate, stop talking.
You people usually leave your kids
unsupervised like this?
No. No!
Not at all.
We had to go into town to the leasing office.
They...
They shut our power off.
Looks, alright to me.
Sheriff, I know this is something
hard to explain.
But honestly, there is nothing wrong here.
Hey, why don't you stay and see for yourself?
We're barbecuing.
Join us.
- Mom...
Thank you, ma'am, I would like to.
But I'm on duty.
Look, the kids made a big mistake.
And I assure you, Tom will be punished.
But my wife is right.
We got plenty of great food.
Why don't you stick around?
Look, I know you're on the job.
But there's no law against
home cooked meal.
We got lots of hot dogs,
..hamburgers, steaks...
You'll love it.
Okay.
I have to tell you this.
It has been a while.
Alrite, I'm successfully twisted.
- Great.
I guess, a hour off won't kill anyone.
Oh, no.
Gotcha.
- Hey!
What was that?
What was, what?
- No, I felt something.
Come on, everyone. Dinner.
- Everyone, dinner...
..inside.
- I got the dessert.
You're going down, punk.
- You're going down, punk.
I just said that.
- I just said that.
Stop that.
- Stop that.
You been punked!
Hey, yeah!
Ziraconia!
s
Okay. Hold on, Mom.
I didn't hear one word.
Now, what happened?
One moment,
I'm cleaning my dentures...
..and the next thing, you know,
I'm down here.
You know, your entitled to see a
few moments at your age.
I'm sorry, Sweety.
I forgot.
Did you want cheese in your burger?
No.
I wanna to find whoever invented love...
..and hack him into pulp with a machete.
Boy trouble.
- That makes two of us.
I don't know what to do about this,
Tom situation.
Be the guest.
Happy face.
Hey, Nate. Where's Jake?
- I've no idea.
Well, dinner is almost ready.
How about you track him down?
Jake's an adult.
If he wants to eat,
he'll come down and get it.
Aww, sorry.
- Stop or it'll will.
You said it.
- No, you're pushing me.
Oops!
Watch your head.
I tell you this,
there is nothing more American...
..than a solid chunk of meat
in your stomach.
I bought the pickles.
- Really?
Well, if you think these things will
get you out of that ticket...
..it's a no-go, mister.
My stomach!
I'm starving.
Any word from Jake?
- Still no signal.
Where is he?
Hey, boys!
You guys, not at the table.
Right, Nate?
- What, right?
They're playing with their phones.
- Oh, yeah, whatever, open up.
Can someone pass me the mustard.
Hey, Hannah!
Did you eat all the hot dogs?
No!
I mean, yes.
I tell ya, I usually eat only noodles
in my squad car.
Everyday, by myself.
Comfortable up there, earth boy?
- Hope so.
Enjoy some dirt in your face.
Attention, all.
Resistance is futile.
Give me, what I need.
- Oh, baby.
I knew you would come back.
Step aside, hormonal female.
Wait!
You're calling me, hormonal?
Back away.
You're irrelevant to my mission.
Irrelevant?
I don't care, how old you're.
But you can't talk to me like that.
What is going on?
- Teen drama. I..I think.
It is teen drama,
right, Ricky?
Snuggles.
Turn him off.
- It's not me.
Let's move. Bring Nana's.
Wow, wow, wow!
Freeze.
You kids are not excused.
Let them go.
We're playing a game, Uncle Stu...
I mean, Stu.
We're on vacation.
Am I aging backwards?
No, I don't think so.
You really want to deny me my time
with the kids?
Wow, guilt never gets old.
Well, go ahead.
I think, we ought to keep Mom
out of the Pinot Grigio.
You have lost.
And now the invasion shall begin.
Invasion?
I mean, there's more of you guys coming?
Many more!
And we'll crush you like bugs.
Not if we crush you first.
I will not be beaten by children.
Any more signs of resistance...
..and the one you call Jake will be eliminated.
I want Snugglelump back.
That's it!
Time to die!
Richard,
you remember Nana?
Game on.
- Game over.
Wow!
Wow, what was that move?
Double handed flip with a left-handed twist.
Nana, get up!
He's on the light.
Send Nana after him.
Nana!
Lee, flying is your specialty.
Take him out, Lee.
- I can't.
Art, hurry up!
Give it to me.
Ricky?
- What the...
Nana?
Yes, scream human,
for your species ends tonight.
What the heck was that thing?
Space alien.
Too much to explain.
We think, they're probaly here to destory
the world as we know it.
Come on, if we don't get down there,
we're gonna be in real trouble.
I would say that's the understatement
of the century.
Mom?
Are you okay?
What happened?
How do I..get...
Oh, I just need a glass of water.
Okay.
Somebody better start talking.
It looks like, you guys had a battle realm here.
- We did.
Nana versus Ricky.
- Not now, Hannah.
Dad, it's not what it look like.
- All of you, upstairs.
Now!
- Uncle Stu, it wasn't our fault.
Okay, unless you want to join them.
You better spill it.
What the heck happened in here?
I haven't got a clue is to what happened.
But my back hasn't felt this good in ages.
Mom? Mom?
Where you going?
Aliens.
- Mom?
Build a machine. Now.
- No.
I'm sorry, guys.
It's over.
Over?
It's not gonna be over.
Ricky is down in the basement with that...
..space rodent.
- You don't get it.
An entire fleet of those guys are
about to invade.
Well, man up and deal with it.
I have been...all day.
Well, if he's scared,
may be you guys can help me.
Not without Tom.
Why?
- Because he's our leader.
Come on.
It's not just Ricky,
Jake needs your help too.
And Snuggles.
- And like, everyone on earth.
Including our parents.
Alrite.
Let's go, save the planet.
And your dumb, old boyfriend.
You want monkey?
He's got luck.
I'm fine.
Stay close.
They could be anywhere.
It's Jake.
Those Zirconians!
They tied me up and
dragged Snuggles outside.
This vacation really sucks.
- You seen the machine?
Yeah, you were right.
It was sent here years ago.
Some idiot built this place,
back on top of it.
Guys, help me here with Ricky.
He's waking up.
- Where the heck am I?
Oh baby, I'm so glad,
you're okay.
Wow, don't touch me!
Stop.
- Okay, okay.
I know, it's been a really weird day,
but you have to let me explain.
Okay.
Explain to me why I keep blacking out.
Why I'm bleeding and...
..why your grandma did a fine ninja kick
on my face down the stairs.
Okay.
We are fighting, um, space aliens.
Yeah, yeah!
Okay, they're small but dangerous and
really scary.
Oh, no! Of course, I believe you.
Why wouldn't I be?
Bethany, why you wanna waste our time...
..playing hide and seek and kill the aliens...
..with your stupid brother and
your dumb little cousins?
Don't talk about my family like that.
Oh, you don't have to worry
about it anymore.
Because we're done.
I knew, I should have stayed home and
hooked up with Annie Filkins.
She's smoking hot and
she doesn't like talking about...
..feelings all the time.
I'm going straight to Annie's.
I'm really sorry.
Don't be.
You were right all along.
If it's any consolation...
..he's not going straight to Annie's.
Or anywhere for a while.
Wow!
Guys, enough of this sibling bonding.
We're in DEFCON 1, here.
Oh, my God.
They're forcing him to build it.
- Building, what?
How would they beat the world
with that thing?
I really don't want to find out.
We gotta stop them before
their fleet arrives.
Fleet?
- This is just the advance team.
We have to rescue Snugglelump.
Snuggle what?
- Lump.
The foreign fella.
He's on our side.
The other three,
not so much.
This is so not happening.
We got to get out there.
Let's move.
Not so fast.
I have a plan.
Look at me here.
Did Nana give anyone, mentos?
Why?
- Hand them over.
Alrite.
What? We're gonna throw candy at them?
- No.
My little science project.
Mentos bomb.
You're a genius.
We shouldn't do this.
Humans, friendly group...
Incoming!
In my eyes.
Let's get them!
Move!
Snuggles!
Traitor-r-r!
Leave me!
- Every men those mess with chicks gets...
He's out cold.
You?
- Get off my planet...
..you little green son of a...
How do you feel now?
- We did it.
Finally, we did.
How do we do..?
- Too bad...
..not sweet, so!
Not sweet!
Hey, humans...
- Guys, listen!
..machine..molecule expand...
machine make the Commander...
Who's little now,
Earth maggots?
Pretty cool, huh?
- We're gonna need a bigger potato.
It's over.
I win.
Where's he going?
- Anywhere he wants.
What do we do?
- What about my Mom and Dad?
Everyone, listen.
We don't have much time.
Sparks, can anything go on
in that machine?
Theoretically.
- Good.
Art, Lee!
I'm gonna need you to control it.
Bethany, I need you to keep the
other aliens on locked out.
Okay.
Jake, come on.
This battle is not over yet.
Awesome!
Here.
Wow, cool.
Super-sized.
You're one ugly alien.
He may be ugly but he's mine.
You don't know to quit, do you?
We need a clean shot at his neck.
I'm going up.
You broke my nail.
- I don't care.
Wow!
Oh, my God!
It's the beacons.
He's calling the invasion.
Holy Mother Mary!
- Look at this...
Oh, God! Bless America!
That's what I call a patriotic act.
Not bad.
- But it's nothing compared to this.
Wow! Wow!
Those are Category 3 pyrotechnics
you got there.
I suppose, it's another ticket.
Light them up.
Let's put that guy to shame.
I got it.
Tom! Tom, I found it.
Get him to turn around.
Hey, down here!
You prehistoric space scumb.
Nice one, Nate.
- That was awesome.
These things cost only $1.99,
can you believe it?
I don't think that's you, Nate.
- What is that?
It's them.
They all be coming soon.
Open your eyes, people.
There's only one answer.
Meteor shower!
- Oh, that's right! I heard...
Oh, yeah..yeah.
- Oh..sure.
That's all you got?
Oh, hey!
- Come on...
Tom!
Take the shot.
Shoot him.
His collar is still in the way.
Look out!
The ugly one got big.
Hurry.
Do it, Tom.
45 meters...
The angle is...,
resistance's all gone. Speed squared.
45 degrees.
What was that?
You messed with the wrong mathlete.
Yes.
- Get him away from him.
Commander?
- Wait a second.
...humans!
Is that all you have?
Looks good.
You see that?
- Sparks, reverse the machine.
Too easy.
Nothing's working.
- Give it to me.
Oh, Cruel!
- But effective.
It was awesome.
Reversed.
- Tommy, it's time.
You came back for me.
Let's get...
We can hug like this in Zirkon.
Bethany!
- Han, you okay?
Over here!
- Bethany!
Did you guys, seen it?
- Good job, Han.
Snuggs was great.
So were you guys.
- Tom, what about the others?
There's too many.
Retreat! Retreat!
The machine is destroyed.
We have been outsmarted by the humans.
The invasion has failed.
Retreat to Zirkon, right away.
Retreat! Retreat!
It's gone.
It's over.
It's all over!
We woned!
Thanks Snuggs...
..for everything.
You're alright for a space maggot.
I'm gonna miss you.
Miss him? He's staying here.
With us.
Please, don't go.
You can be a part of our family.
Han, I think he already got a family.
My family.
Goodbye, Hannah.
Hey!
Listen, about your grades...
- Dad, let me save your lecture.
You were right!
And I was wrong.
Turns out, there are advantages
to being smart.
I'm sorry.
I just, really great lecture planned.
Even rehearsed in front of the mirror.
Did you see the meteor shower?
- Yeah!
Yeah, it was life changing.
Nice catch, Nana.
- Hey!
I got one.
Oh, yeah! Oh, yeah!
Come on.
Annie.
- Ricky...
I thought, you were at your lake house?
- Well, vacation ended early.
This is it for you.
- You're so sweet...
Well, hey, you're my girlfriend now.
So there's nothing,
I wouldn't do for you.
Now, give pappa some su-u-u...
Ladies...
- It's the girl's night out.
But, hey, you should come.
If you like to dancing.
Dancing?
You ain't even seen dancing...
- Until you seen the Funky Ricky.
Wedgie time!
I think, he got kinda crazy.
Turn him off.
Ricky, you're acting really weird.
What are you talking about?
Okay, back on.
I'm so keeping this.
s