Stop. What the fudge?
You have your own fries.
-You'd let Howard.
-Shut up! Stop.
Howard? Who's Howard?
Oh, Howard?
She loves the Lexus-loving, grunge poser,
pathetic slave to juvenile delinquent Mitch
whose head I happened to splatter
at paintball last week.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
Oh, great. Thanks.
I'll be right there.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
-Mel!
-Jen?
Okay. I know.
Jen? Okay.
I know I left 10 minutes ago,
but there was nobody here.
It's dead, so can... Thanks.
Hey, you! Can you hear Mommy?
I love you. I love you.
Okay, my battery's going so...
Can you say bye?
Bye.
I'm sorry. What can I get you?
Yeah. The special. No mayo.
And if it's got no sugar, an ice tea.
-Okay.
-Excuse me. On second thought,
I'm gonna take the mayo.
And an ice tea, however the hell it comes.
Congratulations. Lucky number 7.
It's for when you pay.
Get down! Come on, get down!
Assist. Evac's running late.
This is the shooter, the customer.
We lost them both on the way.
We're gonna have to get going on this one.
There was another one that was
dead on the scene. A busboy.
-I guess he went straight to the locker.
-I was just there 20 minutes ago.
Come on, let's scrub in.
Well, I wish we had an affordable house.
Ours?
Find your perfect place.
It's easy at remax.com.
Nobody sells more real estate than RE/MAX.
My dad was a minister, as you know.
The question he always used to ask...
Hey, Jimmy, how are you doing, bud?
What will He have us do?
Bear witness. From our lips to His ear,
in the language of our inmost longings,
we humbly pray.
Hey, Jimmy, I'm Ron.
It's my job to talk to people
after upsetting experiences,
like accidents or crimes.
The doctor who examined you
thinks maybe we should
get to know each other.
Though I hear you're not saying much.
Will you talk to me?
Will you shake your head "yes" or "no"?
Will you write down your answers
if I ask you a few questions?
When you want to figure out how you feel
about what happened, will you see me?
You've got superficial trauma,
maybe a concussion when you fell.
You may sleep a few days straight,
have some blurs and blanks.
One thing's sure,
you are some kind of lucky.
Beyond lucky.
He's already gone. Let's call it.
No, no, wait. Maybe I can...
Shit, I nicked an artery.
Looks like a bone frag's hit the aorta.
I'm gonna have to clamp and start over here.
Bruce, there's nothing to clamp it to.
There never was.
Honey!
Oh, my God!
Don't cry, Mom. Don't cry.
I'm so sorry.
Thank you.
It's different odds down here.
No one wins them all.
You went the extra mile. And a half.
Gave it your best.
Right now, authorities still are
officially searching for motives.
Meanwhile, here at
Baird Community Hospital,
the gunman has been declared
dead on arrival.
One victim in critical condition
is set to be airlifted.
And the hospital says its emergency...
-Miss Davenport?
-I gave it already. My statement.
I'm not police. I'm with the
County Mental Health Department.
Are you a doctor?
No, but the hospital consults with us
in these cases.
So...
Well, I tried to call out,
-but the battery on my phone died.
-It's not your fault.
-It's normal to feel that way.
-No, I know that.
In the next few days and weeks,
you may experience a lot of new feelings,
including loss of sleep, even appetite.
There's a list.
Everyday life may feel different.
You might start to remember things
that you really don't want to, Carla.
I'm sorry. Can I call you Carla?
Wait now.
You got these printed out before?
In case something like that happens?
And then you give them out after?
Well, that's not important.
It's that if you need to talk, you can.
About how you're feeling.
To you?
Yes.
Excuse me, ma'am,
can we speak with you for a second?
You were at the scene, right?
-That's right. I was.
-Well, were you hurt at all, ma'am?
No. Not myself.
But you lost someone in your family,
someone that you know, right?
No, but...
-Excuse me. Thank you.
-Hold on. Thanks...
Belmont police continue to deflect
questions about their investigation,
while citizens struggle to reclaim
the notion of a town that was,
reconstruct a timeline of the actual moments
when life and death hung in the balance.
In the blink of an eye,
for ordinary townspeople...
-Hi.
-Oh, my God, Carla, you drove here?
I took a bus from the hospital.
From the hospital? Oh, my... We saw it.
Thank God you're okay.
You saw it?
Well, I guess I did.
I tried to call out.
We didn't know where to call.
I mean, I told Scott
to call the police, but he said no,
that it's best to wait for word
in these situations.
I can't help but think 5 minutes later
and my Scott would have been in there.
So, are you okay?
Yeah, I'm okay. I guess I feel a little bit...
Thank God is what. That's what I say.
You know, I saw those girls on TV,
and that one whose father died.
But you don't have scratch on you.
I mean, just... You know, thank God.
-What's wrong with you?
-Oh, he's been a little colicky.
Okay, well, I guess
I'll see you at the diner tomorrow.
Tomorrow? You know what?
Melda's won't be open tomorrow.
Oh, God, yeah. Jeez.
Whatever. Whatever.
Just call us any time, okay?
We'll take him any time. It's gonna be okay.
Thanks. Bye.
$12.95 is your change.
You're the 100th customer this month.
You get a free bike helmet.
Anne, honey,
what is it? What are you doing out here?
Let's just get you back inside.
We've got something to help you sleep.
Okay, baby. Let's just go inside.
Any luck reaching him on the cell phone?
Nothing.
If you don't mind, I just have
a few questions that I want to go over.
Are you sure your father didn't know
anyone else at the scene?
Mr. Hagen? Mr. Carline?
Not absolutely sure.
-But I don't know.
-And between you?
Any recent problems?
My dad took us in a year ago,
after my divorce.
No questions. So, no, no problems.
And you're not aware of any bad feelings
anywhere, business gone wrong?
-You need a hand with that?
-No, thanks.
My dad owns his own driving school.
One room, one car.
Paid a small business loan off
after my momma died.
Mom!
He owns this house free and clear.
He don't owe nobody.
So, no, I'm not aware of any bad feelings
or business deals. Thank you.
Not for several years anyway,
since he owed on that gambling marker.
Mommy, come here!
-Excuse me?
-We heard about that.
I have no idea what you're talking about.
Now if there is nothing else,
I have a babysitter waiting inside.
Miss Hammet, I know you want any word
on your father's whereabouts and condition.
Thanks for saying it, Detective. Excuse me.
I was at the diner this morning
before it all happened.
You were not. Why?
I got a coffee on the way to the hospital.
What?
And then on the way out...
I held the door open for
the guy who shot everybody.
How do you know it was him?
'Cause 20 minutes later they wheeled
everyone in, and he was there
and he had a big fucking hole in his head.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm fine. I mean,
it's not like I was still there
when it happened.
-Darling.
-Crazy, huh?
Do you want me to get you a drink?
Yeah. That'd be good.
Did the suit come back from the cleaners?
I'll bring it in.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
You know, Stu, you look at everything
that's happened here,
and it's hard not to speculate on the toll.
Had the gunman entered the scene
just 10 minutes later, during the height...
Do you think he's sleeping?
He was out like a light, last I looked.
Like the man said, keep him home, quiet.
He'll talk when he's ready.
Sweetie?
Oh, my God!
Jimmy, down!
Come on.
Big crowd.
Half didn't even know that Hagen guy.
Or Hank Carline.
At least I worked for him once.
Well, I cleaned the tables
when they came in.
They know me to see me, I guess.
So, when are you gonna let me
take you out for that beer at Closkey's?
Looks like you could do with one.
Oh, hey. Hey, it's no biggie.
No biggie. I'll see you around, Carla.
Who was my father?
An example of the kind of faith
that we need most.
When we are scared or tempted by doubts,
or guilt, or hatred.
So let the Lord lead us on
to fly high to the gates of heaven,
to let Him judge us, and my father,
who gave his life for mine
and Jimmy Jaspersen's.
My father who hid us
and held on to my hand, smiling.
He was my dad.
Wait.
Kneel with me, Lori.
Let's be as brave as our dads.
Let's pray to be strong enough to forgive.
I want to, Anne, but...
-Lori, honey.
-Your dad was so brave, too.
It's what he'd want. I know that.
God knows that.
Jimmy and I are witnesses.
Partners in prayer.
Witnesses to love
and bravery to be proud of.
We just wanted to say how sorry we are.
-Bob, too...
-Thank God one of us can testify.
Yeah!
The network subscriber
you are trying to reach
is either unavailable or out of range.
Please try again later.
2. Crap 2 right away.
New shooter.
Gentlemen.
-You okay?
-No.
My fucking head again. I can't see anything.
A migraine? I'll get you something. Okay?
I'm not proud. I'll try anything.
Just put this under your tongue.
It's a sublingual,
so it's gonna work pretty quick.
My miracle worker genius.
I haven't had one of these
for such a long time.
Feeling better? Is it working?
-Yeah.
-It is?
You're a magician.
You think so?
Nothing less. Ever.
Anne?
One sec, Mom.
-Hello.
-Hi, Ma.
Carly. That's you.
-Yeah.
-Well, my God.
-How's the knee, Ma?
-Good enough. If I take to my pills
and leave the weeds grow in the yard,
good enough.
Now are you keeping up with your classes
at the junior college?
-Ma, you know what happened?
-And your boyfriend? Steve, is it?
How's he? Any plans for you two?
-Everything's great, Ma.
-Well, that's wonderful for you, Carly.
Oh, there's your dad now.
He's wandering.
I guess the phone woke him up.
-I better go.
-Okay, you take care.
-Bye-bye.
-Bye.
I'm sorry.
Okay, I'm sorry, I'm sorry. Okay.
-What's wrong with him?
-I'm not sure. Let's try a bottle.
-Do you have a bottle?
-Okay.
Come on, little fellow. Up you go.
-This way.
-Okay.
You hungry? You hungry?
We have a hungry man here.
When did you last feed him?
Well, I tried off and on all night,
but he wouldn't take it.
He was crying so hard.
Anything different about the way
you prepared the formula?
No.
Well, I don't see the point
in running any tests
as long as he's alert
and he has a good appetite,
which he clearly does.
I think he'll be fine. Here.
That's great to hear.
I do think you should get yourself
a regular pediatrician, though, Carla.
And there are free clinics
if insurance is a problem.
I took that parenting course at the Y, and
he's never had one thing wrong before this.
Well, I understand,
but I think it's just for the best.
So, let's just see if we can keep to
a regular feeding schedule.
Okay. Will do.
See if you can't get
some more sleep yourself.
I wouldn't want those pretty eyes
getting red and tired-looking.
No.
Okay, well, thanks, Dr. Laraby.
He's not as nice you.
He acts like he never saw me, but nice.
-How are you feeling, Sam?
-Pecker won't stand up,
I got a tube in my nose,
and I'm too dry to spit. You?
-I think we'll both live.
-Yeah, but I'm looking forward to it.
You look like you could take it or leave it.
Mutual funds go down?
Tough match at the club?
Take it easy.
Keep eating your prunes, Sam.
Sam's a tough case.
He could go on for years,
he could drop dead on the sidewalk.
-Not if I can help it.
-I don't think that's our call.
Hey, what are they pushing
for migraines these days?
Molodil.
It's a sublingual.
It's the quickest vaso-constrictor out there.
It actually works like a charm.
Possible side effects are arrhythmia,
mild tightness.
-And to treat that? That's...
-Stantrocet, yeah.
Of course, you can end up
where you started,
which is with headache symptoms.
Stantrocet causes headaches,
Molodil cures it. It's a bi-polar scenario.
-Catch-22, huh?
-Yeah.
-How's Jo?
-She's good. I'll see you tomorrow.
Yeah.
Rumors swirling after she was spotted
in this hot, exclusive L.A. nightclub
talking to which hunky actor
rumored to be on again, off again
with his temperamental supermodel wife?
Mr. Fussy.
Hey.
Bruce, Sam's been in a coma
most of the night.
Okay, clear.
-Time?
-5 and a half minutes.
-Shit. I'm gonna do one more, okay?
-He's brain dead.
Clear.
Pulse.
He's breathing.
-Bruce...
-I just want to try one more thing.
I don't care if you try 10 more things.
He's brain dead, Bruce.
Come on, Dan.
Well, what the hell are we doing here!
Sorry, nurse.
Hey, Bruce, what's going on?
We're not playing God here.
You can't decide them all.
Man, I can't imagine what it's been like
for you, being at the diner.
Look, we're all stressed here.
But you've got to talk. All right?
I'm here for you.
I really don't want to bother anybody.
I just want to check with his students.
So, he left by 11:00?
You're sure?
Okay. Okay. Thank you so much. Thank you.
7!
Winner, yo!
First of all, I want to thank God
for keeping me safe
and guiding my hand to this wonderful
opportunity to provide for my loved ones.
Thank you, Big Guy!
Keep going, keep going!
Hey. How're you doing?
I'm fine.
So, I guess we're both fine and good.
And there's 2 kinds of people
in this world,
those who are and those who aren't
fine and good.
Sir. Coming out. 7 yo. Same shooter.
Just to say, hey, hey! Hey, now!
7!
Your father and I used to take you here.
It hasn't changed a bit.
Everything has.
Yeah. Too much has.
We're tested. That's all this is, Mama.
Don't doubt anything now. Just forgive.
I know you want to forgive,
but forgiveness is hard. First, there's hatred.
I'm sorry, baby, but there's a lot of it.
Doesn't it make you mad?
What happened, honey?
At all? I mean, don't you miss Dad?
I don't doubt anything now. I just be proud.
Do you think that you would talk
to that man from the hospital?
No. All these doubts and fears can fly away
just the way they came.
Don't look at them.
That's what they want, not what God wants.
Honey, we were glad when you wanted to
go to Sunday school with the other kids,
but it was fine with us
when you wanted to stop going, too.
I mean, you're upset, I know.
There's been so much stress.
Sweetheart.
Come on, Mama, right now.
-Honey, what is it?
-Pray with me. Right here, right now.
Stop it, Annie. Just stop it.
Please, kneel with me, so God knows
you don't have a doubt in your heart
-and you believe in what's true.
-Anne! Right now!
Please, kneel with me. Lori did.
For me. For all of us. For Dad.
Mr. Jaspersen?
How's Jimmy? I'd like to see him.
We're up for a new medical policy
at my shop.
Well, there'd be no records, I assure you.
Maybe no problem, too. I mean,
like you said, he could talk at any time.
Mr. Jaspersen, do you have reason to
believe that Jimmy isn't going to benefit...
-Did my wife tell you to come here?
-No.
I'm here because I'm concerned
for Jimmy, that's all.
You know, we're also concerned
about our other son, Michael.
He's still stuck at the V.A., like a vegetable.
I'm sure Jimmy misses him, too.
Just like you.
What happened to Jimmy,
you ever experience anything like that?
Let the man come and see him. That's all.
You think Jimmy's going to talk to him
when we can't even get in a word.
He's got enough to think of.
You know, I've got a month before we go
on the medical policy at the shop.
What do you think they're going to do
if they find out about
Jimmy's so-called pre-existing condition?
I'll tell you what they're going to do.
They're gonna let me go
rather than pay the doctor bills.
-It'll be my job.
-Your job? This is Jimmy's life.
Which won't be much
without clothes on his back or food...
It won't be much with either if you keep...
Lydia, will you give him time?
Give him time.
The means to my end
is more than met with my last bet.
Thank you for your love and support.
Sci-Fi Suite.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you, Pete.
That's not my name.
Pete got fired. I just started.
My tag isn't ready yet.
Okay, well,
thank you, not-Pete who got fired.
Dan. Sir?
Did you really win all that?
I heard 100K, guy in a bike shirt.
Then it must be me.
Can you believe it? A C-K.
You know what that means?
-No.
-Tomorrow... Adiós.
I pack it in. First thing.
'Cause that's my step-away point.
Always have a walking-away point.
-Doug. Dan.
-Dan. Dan.
Always have a walk-away point.
Okay, sir.
-I hope you enjoy your stay.
-You, too, Dan.
Dan from Morongo Casino.
All rightie.
-Hey, calling for help?
-Yeah.
Hey, Anne. You okay?
Me and Billy made first string.
There's going to be a party at Mitch's.
It's just a few people, if you want to go.
Thanks, though.
Fly bar's got to align perfectly.
That's the battle, right there.
Tighten the hex nut against the main shaft
without stripping it.
Millimeter tolerances.
You know what I mean, buddy?
A flying Swiss watch.
You and I and your brother Michael,
we all know damn well that
talking about it don't help.
I've got your back there. It's under control.
You say whatever,
and whenever you're ready.
Tell them I say fuck them.
Think they got all the goddamn answers.
Fuck them.
Come on. Fuck them. Give me one.
Come on. Fuck them.
It's all good. That's why we're here.
Chopper don't got to think about it.
Chopper don't got to talk about it.
Just got to fly.
Above it all. Just gotta fly.
Nothing new, Miss Hammet,
about where your father might be.
Something else did come up.
We got a partial fingerprint and some blood
off the gun.
Not the shooter. That's all we could tell.
-Could be your dad's.
-I don't understand.
Neither do we.
You said your father had a checkup?
Does this mean anything to you?
-Not a thing.
-It would really help if we could talk to him.
Now, we can get a warrant
for his recent credit card bank activity.
That can take a day.
We're just hoping that you can help us out
by providing the PIN numbers.
PIN... I don't have a PIN.
We all want to close the book on this,
for your father's own good.
If he's in any kind of trouble...
Thanks.
-Hey!
-Hey.
Captain.
Good. I need some presents
to bring back to my family.
You get commission, right?
-I do.
-Beth is about 5 or 6.
She's a real pistol, Beth. About yea high.
Her mother, she... She's about your height.
Bigger in the shoulders, but she's a woman.
She's got the... You know.
Small, medium or large.
That's what we got, sir.
Oh, so, you're a straight shooter.
I like you, captain. You call me Charlie,
though. Call me Charlie.
Hey, Charlie.
-Charlie C-K. You could say that.
-Charlie C-K.
I got the stuff, plus a buck to spare, man.
What the hell.
It's tragic to waste this magic.
"Give a dime," they say.
Charlie?
-Maybe we should...
-We'll split the winnings. What do you say?
Gotta always leave on an up note.
Anne. Hey, sit with?
-With you?
-Yeah.
We want you to know
how brave we think you are.
It was really my dad, I mean...
God gave me the strength to be brave
and to save our lives with his faith.
Well, she means if we pray,
then maybe we'll get over it, you know,
-quicker.
-Yeah, sure. Whatever works.
Never really a popular one.
She's always writing her poems and stories
and acting out her plays by herself
in her room.
Her dad was always her best friend.
Always laughing, just like kids.
And then Jimmy.
They rode the bus since second grade.
So now who is there?
Of course, I am concerned
about her not sleeping, barely eating.
It was her idea,
but maybe it's too soon
for her to be back at school.
No, no, it's not.
She needs to re-establish her basic trust
in her physical environment,
her relationships with the everyday.
She talks like a born-again, nonstop.
All faith and forgiveness.
People do turn to their faith
in order to get them through.
Anne?
Hasn't been to a church once
in half a dozen years.
It was God who made my dad brave.
He provided people with homes
for their families,
because that's what faith is,
and having it says that
what other people think doesn't matter.
And when we pray with our eyes closed,
it means that we are with God,
in that moment.
So will you do that with me now?
For my dad?
-Hi.
Jimmy's in his room. Maybe you could
wait here while I go get him.
-Okay. Good.
-Good.
Jimmy! Jimmy!
Wait! Jim!
Damn!
Hello?
Jimmy?
Is it that man Abler?
Okay, listen to me, Jimmy.
What do you think you're doing, Jimmy?
Come on. It's gonna be okay.
Jimmy.
Still, there's the 2 of us.
Come on.
Dr. Laraby, please.
Carla Davenport. Thanks much.
Hi, how are you?
No.
No, I guess not.
He's sleeping right now.
Yeah.
Well, I guess just to say thanks again,
Dr. Laraby,
and maybe even...
No, sure, I will call one of those clinics.
Thanks again.
Everybody's lucky every now and then.
Not in it for a win.
This is to keep it real.
Killer shot. Seal the deal.
2. Craps, 2. High and away.
No, no, no, the plumbing contractor's
supposed to start in April.
Right.
Then the chap's coming to do the floor.
And then the finished carpentry guy
is starting.
Then we're done. I mean, I can't believe it.
Geneen made a really good point.
She said, "Why sit on a plane for 15 hours
all the way to Europe,
"when you can go to Montreal?"
They loved it.
And there are great restaurants,
great hotels, so much less expensive
than Europe. Not touristy.
Your head again? Another migraine?
Yeah.
Why didn't you tell me?
You have enough to worry about.
This is the same as before.
It's a vaso-constrictor.
Here. Under your tongue.
I love when you play doctor with me.
Thank you.
Hey, Charlie!
How you doing? You good?
All's good, captain.
Take care now, all right?
Anne, this seems like such a phenomenon,
such an amazing and incredible outpouring
of love and support from your community.
Are these people friends, here,
gathered to honor your dad,
or is this part of a bigger movement
back toward belief in God?
I think it's both, you know?
I think no one should be alone
with their fears and doubts,
and we call out and our voice is heard.
And for that,
I give thanks to friends, neighbors,
and loved ones of Calmont.
Thanks, Lori.
Okay, guys, let us hold hands and pray.
To the Lord in the hour of my distress,
I call and He answers me.
"Oh, Lord, save my soul from lying lips,
from the tongue of the deceitful.
"What shall he pay you in return,
O treacherous tongue?
"The warrior's arrows sharpened
and coals red-hot blazing. "
Talk to the hotel. They'll take a marker.
Hey, where are you from?
Why? Are you my friend?
Sorry, not me.
And the ones that might be
willing to stake you,
they're not your friends either.
The figure's 30%,
depending upon your collateral.
And if you miss the payback,
you don't have nowhere to go.
-They'll find you.
-I just need 20 grand. That's...
You just tell them about it.
Here.
Good luck.
No, no, you keep it.
Hello? Hello?
Dad? Dad?
Hello?
Keys.
25 K. All right?
See you in a couple of days. All right?
Car comes back
when you pay your debt, Charlie.
Hi.
-God damn it.
-God, you feel so big. Come on.
-Fuck!
-No! No! Stay in!
-Fuck this.
-Steve, wait. Come on.
No, fuck this, man. It's fucking stupid.
Hey, excuse me, sir. For you?
Mai tai. For me.
And a sign from on high, as they say.
If you will or if you would.
If you can or if you could.
You shall if you should.
Feeling lucky, huh?
It's coming along. It's off and on.
Well...
I've been known to change
one into the other, sweetheart.
And that's a sure thing.
Hey. Hello, up there.
Anything working for you?
Stop, stop, stop. It's the feeling.
This is mine. See?
Well, he has some congestion,
which could be an allergy,
but he's also a little dehydrated.
So, he could just have a fluid imbalance
from missed feedings or something.
-Missed feedings?
-Everybody misses one. It's nothing.
I'm sure he's just had the runs
and your sitter hasn't told you or something.
He's behind on his electrolytes.
The sitter, yeah, because I know I feed him.
I always... All I do is feed him.
How did you go with the pediatrician?
Did you call the clinic?
Well, I called, yeah, but maybe
they called back, maybe they didn't.
-I mean, I had to take Davy out.
-It's okay, it's okay.
-He was crying...
-I'm sorry.
Listen, we'll just feed him up
till he's nice and sleepy
and we'll keep an eye on him
for the rest of the day.
I know it's frustrating not being able to
help him when he's like this,
but it's nothing life-threatening. Believe me.
-But will you be here?
-All day.
So, if you'll just wait in the waiting room.
Okay. I'll do that. Okay.
Dr. Laraby?
Don't you think
everything happens for a reason?
Like us. Here.
After what happened in the diner?
We all want to believe it.
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Do you think it has a personality?
Yeah. Of course. Why wouldn't it?
What kind does it have?
I mean,
what kind of people would live
in a house like this, anyway?
People like us.
Right. Intelligent.
Kind.
Wealthy.
With a great sense of humor.
-How are the headaches?
-They're okay.
I love the slope of the roof against that hill.
Don't you?
I was looking at the plans again today.
And I was thinking,
the sheer walls have to be
where they have to be,
but, in terms of the space inside,
we could actually go
with a second spare bedroom,
if we wanted to.
In case we decide to, you know...
What?
I love you is what.
Did you know that?
Calmont Internal.
Yes. Hello, hi. Dr. Laraby, please.
Dr. Laraby isn't on tonight.
Is this a patient or regarding one?
Ma'am? Hello?
No, please. Please.
Come on.
-Ed Sacks, you remember him?
-Yeah.
He had a sister-in-law that couldn't talk.
-Oh, God.
-You know what they did?
I can't listen to this.
You're just worried about the insurance.
-I'm not.
-Yes, you are.
-Lydia, it's not about that.
-What is it about then?
No, I'm asking you, what is it about?
Because if it's not that, I want to know.
Lydia, I've told you a million times,
and you just don't listen.
No! What is stopping you
from helping him? That's...
This is the last one I can bring you
on the house unless you play.
Okay.
Sir! Sir! If you're gonna play, please step up.
Otherwise, I'm gonna have to
ask you to take it back.
Hey, what the hell, man?
-Sorry. Sorry.
-What's the problem with this guy?
Excuse me, sir,
you're gonna have to come with me.
-Lydia...
-He needs help.
By telling him how fucked up he should be?
-Nobody is gonna tell him how...
-You're crazy.
You're crazy.
You're crazy! You're crazy!
Keep screaming like that,
pretty soon you're gonna start believing it.
Okay. Come on, let's go.
Can't even piss on his own.
They fucked Michael's head.
Michael was in a fucking war!
He'd be right here, right now,
at home with us if it wasn't for...
If it wasn't for what?
This is about Jimmy,
you self-righteous prick.
God, who is in all things,
let us fly free on the wings of angels,
to face fear,
avoid pride and temptation,
and be thankful for Thy gifts
above the sins of this earth.
Give us the strength
to give strength to others.
Stop!
In the name of Thy only son.
Good evening, sir.
Changing $20,000.
Okay, Steve.
From San Diego.
It's risk and reward.
What we're all headed toward.
Now or never.
All or nothing.
I got faith.
I got doubts.
Is it your call?
Mine?
Question is,
am I lucky?
14, sir.
-Hey. How are you?
-Hey.
Good. And you?
I'm good. Listen, I'm sorry.
I got a pedes case waiting.
I'm not gonna make it for lunch.
Do you want to
just grab something without me?
I didn't think you were going to make it.
I'm eating leftovers anyway.
-What leftovers?
-The soup from last night.
It's even better today. I've had some already.
-I didn't see you save any.
-Well, I'm not saving any for you.
Then I have to head out to the site.
I need to check some measurements.
Tell you what? Why don't you stay there?
Maybe I can get away.
You just said you couldn't, silly.
I'll only be half an hour.
That's all I have anyway.
Yeah, but why don't you wait?
Then maybe later we can both go out there.
Later? I'm late now if I want to
get any work done at all today.
I'll call you when I get back, okay? Bye.
Jo?
Listen, will you get the day nurse
to deal with her,
and get child services here right now?
Hey, Charlie.
Was just coming to see how you fared.
I was hoping you'd look like a winner.
Hey, Jimmy?
Jim?
Bob.
Have you seen Jimmy?
No.
Put it down right here.
Just so that I'm straight here,
so that nobody misunderstood anybody,
you lost 25 and change in a day?
Is that what happened?
Charlie, is that what happened?
So, empty your pockets for me, Charlie.
Charlie, you use that, okay? You call a cab.
You call someone from your family
to come get you.
Get down on your knees.
I want you to grab the crate.
You know, I hate this, Charlie.
I fucking hate it, but it's happening
because you're stupid.
Okay.
Please. Please, no. Please! Please don't!
God, please don't! Please! Please!
-Please!
-Pray!
Please!
Anne? Anne?
It's Jimmy's mom.
He's been gone since last night.
It's okay, I know where he is.
Miss Davenport,
we just have a few questions
before you can see Davy. Will that be okay?
Hold it!
Jo! Jo!
Kath? Kath.
God knows they were brave, Jimmy.
Dad smiled down on me
like he didn't have a care in the world.
God wants you to be brave.
And you can be, too.
God can help you see into the hearts
of everyone who fell, like I do.
-His witness, which you are, too.
-So, witness, but tell what you really saw.
-Tell it!
-Jimmy.
This is dangerous.
Whatever you two think that
you have to hide,
-it's not worth...
-Tell it!
Annie.
I saw Dad,
and he smiled down
and he told me not to be scared.
He was so brave. And then...
I was holding his hand,
and he was holding mine,
-and then his Coke spilled.
-No!
Then there was more shots,
-and the alarm went off.
-No! Remember it!
-You go on and I will.
-Jimmy. Please.
This is enough.
Tell it.
He did...
-He did...
-Nothing!
Please, no. Please! Please don't.
God! Please don't. Please.
Please.
Don't you say anything.
Ever.
Jimmy.
Give me the gun.
Okay? Just give me the gun.
Here we go.
I just sat there.
I just sat there while
that man shot Dad, and I...
I didn't do anything.
I didn't hold his hand.
I let go of his hand.
I let go of it. I couldn't help it, I...
He didn't die brave like I said at all.
He was just...
He was just scared, alone,
and I couldn't do anything, Mom.
I'm sorry.
No, it's okay.
I can't ever forgive that man for what he did.
I can't. Never.
Never again. It'll stop. Just give me this.
Jo, Jo. It's all right. It's all right. It's me.
Okay. You're okay. It's all right. It's me.
It's okay.
You're gonna be okay. I promise.
You're gonna be okay.
You okay?
You wanna talk?
Just wanna sit here for a while?
Subtitles: Arigon
In the ordinary world,
we trust in where things belong.
Everything has a place,
and believing in that makes us innocent.
And through the days under the same sky,
we hope, dream, and laugh.
We find and lose our way.
Endings are beginnings,
and moments, like pieces, fit together again.