The passenger list, sir.
Very good.
Who are the guys Edmond, Brooke soldier?
Three brothers, sir. All for Africa
broadcast on the same date.
My birthday, sir.
Is that so?
Unbelievable ...
Sir ...?
What is he doing here?
Go back to the coast.
Let this guy take apart the customs, of
Diemen, South African Boer.
Accompanied him here.
Tell him ...
Major Carlysle that he wants to talk.
Yes, sir.
This is, give me another.
- Yes sir.
Brooke! Where are you going to so many
hurry?
I asked one of the Boers
guide.
The Major wants to see him.
- Let me see.
We had to hang them all,
or not?
Instead of a safe haven ...
- Name?
Goddamn!
With me, Brooke.
The next.
Hey!
Mr. van Dijmen?
- Diemen.
van Diemen.
Hello sir of Dijmen,
what about U. ..
all the way to our remote
corner of the earth?
Curious.
Curious?
You must be very curious to
thousands of miles to travel ...
Sure I'm curious!
Very eager for news of finding out why
you two have crossed oceans ...
the British to help my farm
to burn.
Arjan van Diemen ...
And I thought the war was over.
Not for you, you murdering bastard, you
under arrest.
Give it away.
Give him his gun back!
NOW, YOU IDIOT!
Put your weapon away.
Do you know who this is?
- That's it, thank you Saunders!
Let me not to report lying!
Go back to the harbor, Brooke.
Give the soldiers a real hero's welcome.
- Yes sir.
My apologies for the unworthy reception,
Mr. van Diemen.
Saunders was with me in South Africa.
Apparently he forgot that the war
over. That you understand it?
So you really exist?
I led a cavalry section for
nearly two years searching for U.
Haunted by all you Transvaal
while you cause chaos.
And you, sir.
You could not even catch a poor farmer?
What's your plan here, van Diemen? You
very far from home. - You too.
No, this is my home now.
Home.
Brits seem to your home
Today half the globe to be.
Are U. .. planning to buy some land here?
Maybe ... You want to start again
farmers?
No, we did not have enough left you,
right?
Well, for what it's worth
Mr. van Diemen ...
I hope you find
you are looking for here.
Come here ...
What is this?
This is a piece of home.
What do you mean home?
The home of my grandfather.
Sometimes he cried so.
Looks like sand to me.
Red sand.
You're beautiful.
There are a lot nicer in this city.
Some officers are women ...
- No, no, I've seen many women.
Huahine and Tahiti ...
there could be a princess.
Hey hands off, well I can hear them running.
Belongs to the rank, Corporal Drake.
Watch out, Teddy.
Do not call me Teddy, you ...
There's a lantern in the stables!
I will get good cigars!
Well, well, well.
What have we here?
If the young Lucy is not.
And a damn wild.
What are you doing here?
Apart from the obvious?
I do not know you ...
You know him? - Never seen.
I wonder where his money
gets.
You were not interested in horses
do you?
He talks to you!
Do you think he speaks English?
You may not come here.
Army property.
I say we beat him.
And you undergo your punishment like a good
wanted.
Keep it up!
I will teach our women
fool around.
What did you say?
- Leave him alone you asshole!
You had to take your beating, boy.
Jesus, you fucking ...
You ... You've done it. You did
murdered.
You fucking killed him!
I'll get a doctor.
Get a doctor!
So you went into the shed and he was you
just like that?
Yes, sir.
- No response?
Well, we asked what he doing
was ...
We thought he on the horse
had foreseen. - And that was it?
Levin?
That was how it went.
Was that how it went?
Yes, that was how it went.
He came from the whaler
arrived yesterday. - Sergeant Leybourne!
I do not think he comes close, sir.
Let us take care of that.
He is seen along the coast.
I need 5 men and horses.
He is on foot, so we will
soon have overtaken him.
And dogs?
- No, not dogs!
This is not a blood sport and I do not want
there is one.
Local explorer who ...
- Mr Bryce, sir.
Yeah, Bryce. I want him here ready to
go within the hour.
We leave at dawn, care for it.
van Diemen.
You have not seen anything I assume?
We could use a good sleuth.
The reward is 100 sovereigns.
100 sovereigns alive, 25 dead.
That's a lot of money.
See that guy?
He has British officers slaughtered.
I want to rig not my area.
You do not worry about it
Sergeant-Major. You're not coming.
You and Levin are not corporal
condition for anything to hunt.
You two go back to the barracks.
I guess I am clear!
Yes, sir.
Yesterday when I arrived at the port have
I have not seen whaler.
They left without him during the
noon tide.
The captain wants to hang himself. Walked
screaming at everyone ...
if she had seen him.
I almost had him locked up.
Why was he so angry?
Well, he had lost his harpoenist.
Harpoon a good man
gold today.
These were all his possessions?
- Yes, and his equipment there.
That?
- Yes.
Okay, dismount. Sergeant Leybourne,
the horses ...
rest are required for
a few minutes.
Mr. Bryce? What is it?
- Maori.
Look. All the weight on the toes.
No heel print.
Weight's right ... according to the distance ...
about its length.
This is it.
If he continues to follow the coast, he
Dunny's Point reach, like a boat ...
and the sea on his way you know it.
Barker soldier!
- Sir!
Go back to the cliff and see if we are to ...
abutment to the flood arrives.
- Yes, Sir!
Mr. van Diemen, is there a problem?
It is not him.
No disrespect to Mr. Bryce, but
Our man is accustomed to wearing shoes.
This man, whoever he was ...
never wore shoes.
Major Respectfully, I do not think our
man just a sailor.
I think he gets home.
If we go, we have around
can we cut off before the flood.
Thank you, Barker.
Well. In the stirrups!
van Diemen!
Van Diemen!
Damn! Barker! Get his horse.
- Yes, Sir!
Bryce?
Mr. Bryce?
Your man left with no inventory, no?
- That's right.
You'd like Mr. van Diemen.
Raupo bread.
Maori corn bread ...
How would he get it?
Look at the size of this fire.
Whoever it was, he was in no hurry.
Mr. Bryce, You tell me now
We have all day to follow the wrong man?
Same build, same height,
Maori wrong.
We had to fuck dogs
entail.
We go back and start where
Mr. van Diemen disappeared.
And you know that you think can?
I now have two tracks to follow ...
instead of one.
- Then we better hurry, right?
You've fished, huh?
Head ... feet ...
So you knew I loved watching you ...
Good.
You have made shoes yourself, huh?
Smart guy.
The horses will not help us much
From now on, Major.
Okay, thank you Mr. Bryce.
Barker soldier! You bring the horses
back to the barracks in the morning.
Yes, sir.
Crowther, we love your horse for the
luggage.
Do not move unless I say so.
I said, do not move!
Stand still!
Stop!
Shut up!
Goddamn!
That's better, not true.
How much they pay for me?
How much?
100 sovereigns alive, 25 dead.
25?
Many people would be happy with 25.
Luckily I got you.
If I have to kill you, I will do that.
Anyway, anyone who
25 is satisfied ...
would probably be too stupid
to find me.
Yes, indeed.
That's 75 sovereigns difference
living and dead.
What about this, how much you give me
if I promise myself not to choke?
Walk it now.
What are you reading?
Hey, I asked you something.
That the wicked will perish.
"The enemies of the Lord disappear
the fat of lambs. "
"But the righteous shows mercy and
feeding. "
The 37th Psalm.
I have a lot of time in the
Mission school.
There I learned to read.
You're trained.
- Does it matter?
Maybe ...
- Why?
Because education is the difference between
civilized man and the wild.
There are no wanted here.
The missionaries taught us all
read. All.
My father was your Bible from cover to
cancel cover.
You can not know your enemy, he said,
until you know his god.
Has he found our god?
- Yes. He has met him.
In a sling.
So what is my life worth now?
125 sovereigns?
I am not a murderer.
You get a fair trial.
I get a fair execution.
What is that?
Let's see.
You can trust me.
Wife, daughters ... beautiful.
- Yes.
How old are they, your daughters?
- 8, 6 and the twins.
And where do they live? In the city?
No, they do not live.
They are buried somewhere in South Africa.
They say if children die, they remain
for all children.
You can not start and the story does not
finish.
That's not good.
That's not good for your soul.
Stop here.
Okay, let's continue.
It's just mango. That you can eat.
You did not know, huh?
Anyway, you're not educated.
You see this? Makamaka.
Just chew and your throws
your bowels for days out.
That I do not have to tell
do you?
"His blessing covers the earth
like a river ...
and like a flood the
dry land is drunk '
I would build a raft for us ...
"So his wrath inherit the nations, as
He finds water in brine. "
Stop.
Sit.
Do not move.
I'm not moving.
- Turn around.
Slowly!
Drop the gun.
Drop the gun!
No.
What?
LET FALL!
No!
I'll shoot you ...
You know ...
when I travel I always leave the room
free, in case accidents happen.
Before you've loaded, I have a ball
between your eyes.
You're lying.
Frankly, I'm not sure.
I am quite careless of the
last day.
Anyway ...
We will not know until you do
trigger.
I do not believe you.
- Also good.
And I'll pull the trigger.
- Good.
If you are right, I am dead, I
equal then you die.
Until you pull the trigger, we know that
not.
Drop it!
No!
You let it fall.
I let nothing fall!
I let nothing fall.
Well ...
We walk to the shore.
Keep your hands where I can see.
No!
I pull the trigger!
I take the gamble.
My legs are cold!
You'd have to stay where
dry.
You're the most annoying
I have ever known.
I'd have to murder
that reason alone!
I thought you were a murderer?
I am no different, I would have immediately
shot!
In that case, you would be dead.
That we do not know, do you?
I would like to swim.
- No!
They come apart along ...
- Stay there!
and then there are two.
- Both, two men.
Okay, which side?
- This way.
Is that your wife?
What language is this?
I told you, I'm from
South Africa.
You're one of the Farmers ...
Sounds like our bush language.
Farmer.
That means farmer.
You are the strangest I have ever farmer
encountered.
You fought against the British, right?
My grandfather led our people from the
British.
He was a great leader.
A warrior!
But he lost ...
just like you.
And that brought shame on our nation.
And we were "tangata hara" ...
sinners. Rebels.
I'm not lost.
Why are you here in my country?
Where is your farm, farmer?
You fought the British and you lost
Also, right?
You lost!
And that's not all it?
Where did you learn to sense?
Daarby.
What do you mean, Daarby?
My father's servant.
Old Hottentot.
Hottentot ...
Hottentot!
What is a Hottentot?
South African Bushman.
One Bushman, I've never seen.
You'll never see. They are
all gone. Almost.
Like me ...
As stupid as they are, they'll do
get.
And probably shoot.
If I were in your shoes ...
so what ...
I would worry more that they're
will find.
You can not forever escape.
One of us ZLA found. Pray that it
I'm not.
but I'm not the one on the
flight.
You are the one that flight.
And I think ...
I think you have your soul
left.
Now, pull it apart before I break your neck.
You know, if you sit long at sea
all men can shoot.
If someone comes along do not we throw him
on board at the next port.
With you, I think we are not to
next port waited.
Your wife ... how did she die?
Was she ill?
She was sick of you?
Sorry, I did not say.
Run.
What is this?
Biltong.
I'd rather die of hunger ...
Flat here ...
And here.
Blood.
Fighting, or ...
Which way?
Come on.
Would not it be easier to
wait until the water has dropped?
No. I take no risks with the rain.
Not in this fucking country.
It does not rain!
I'm a sailor! I can again
predicted using the water color.
I lied, okay? I lied!
You take me back
to be hung ...
for something I did not even have!
What would you do it? What?
Mr. Silently now huh?
If you say another word, I hang yourself
to that tree!
You lie too!
You're lying all by saying nothing. All
not what you say is a lie!
The hell are you talking about?
This is only the second question me
have asked.
And you will answer it!
But you just say that if you hang me
I say another word?
Your wife ...
She died in that war is not it?
That's none of your.
It is true huh?
- None of your business.
I just ask.
- Why ...
No ...
I ...
- She is not dead in that war.
But you said ...
- I do not know how she died, okay?
When that us Brits could not sporty
beat ...
Lord Kitchener sent his troops
our farms to burn.
He drove our women and children
cattle ...
to these camps with barbed wire.
I do not know how they died.
Disease, hunger ... There is no one
who can tell.
We both hate the British.
- I hate the British do not.
Yes.
- I hate the British are not!
I hated my god for a time.
I stood naked before him, I scolded him.
I was so angry.
I thought ...
I knew him.
Then I remembered.
God had not created the wild in me.
"Though he slay me,
I would not hope? "
"Nevertheless, my roads
Defend his face. "
I still think
You hate the British.
You think I'll release.
I do not know. - You think that if
You can make like you and me ...
I would release you.
I fought for something.
You are a criminal.
I am not a criminal.
You walk on my land!
My Tipunas have the mountains and rivers
a name.
It's my bloodline.
And I saved your life, thumbtack.
It's about respect.
I'll tell you what respect is.
During the war my men cut off the
index fingers ...
of the heroic British officers off.
Only the heroic. Those who
respect earned.
Do you understand?
That's what I did with people I
respected.
That leaves little hope for me, right?
Hope kills idiots like you every day.
Sergeant, Corporal Crowther send to
barracks for new supplies.
This takes a lot longer
than I had hoped.
Let Crowther see where you think we
Tonight will be because I do not know.
It will be a rough estimate Major.
- That I'm sure, Mr. Bryce.
Do you think he is, sir?
That van Diemen?
Without a doubt.
Are the stories they tell about him
where?
About the massacres of M.E.?
Let me say, without
we reward ...
it unlikely
have to execute.
I think that would have deserved
, sir.
Drake was a good man.
- Drake was a monkey dressed.
A disgrace to his uniform and rank.
Apologies, sir, but ...
He did not deserve to die
as he did.
No, you're right.
He did not.
You have not yet seen action, either
soldier?
No, sir.
Not as such. Not yet.
I hope there.
A warning.
Be sure that your kids if you
ask what you did ...
what you did to your country
defend ...
you can answer them with dignity
business.
What do you mean, sir?
If he survives, he will be honest
trial.
If he is guilty,
he will be hanged.
There will be an example.
Teairra Rua Maimo.
Rua Maimo path.
Spiritual guard.
He is known for its people
who are at risk to save.
What?
This. The Pakeha Townsend called the Gorge.
Let me see.
Listen, you can pull your gun and me
shoot.
Doubt it not.
I will shoot you.
The ball will cost you 75 sovereigns.
Nice.
North ...
South ...
East ...
Oops!
Come on.
Come come come.
I am not much for that idea.
I let you fall.
Let me fall.
- I drop down.
Let go! Let me fall!
I swear I'll shoot you!
You can try.
But to get to your weapon, you'll
rope with one hand to let go.
I'll break your bloody neck as you jump.
Or you can fall down with me.
And with the luggage, your gun and your
fat ass you can sink and drown!
I'll shoot you when you fall!
You might miss, and I could
drown.
Rua Maimo would have saved me.
But we will not know, right?
Until you let me fall.
Would you fight me? Come!
Arise!
I am innocent!
What is wrong with you using?
I'm just trying to uphold the law.
You're a liar!
This has nothing to do with the law!
It is money! You have sold your soul.
You know me to hang
for something I did not even have!
There were witnesses!
Soldiers!
And the woman!
She is a Pakeha woman. And I am a Maori.
They were soldiers who did!
And the soldiers who were my father
hung.
I had to watch.
Then they turned my head
and forced me ...
to see how the father
my friend hung up.
If you kill me, kill yourself. They
will find you.
No matter how long, how many years it takes.
Oh, what a couple of years worth.
What are a couple of years worth of a
condemned man?
Do it!
DO IT!
You can not kill.
You can not.
Everything good?
Pretty good, Mr. Bryce. Thank you
Damn Hori.
That's enough!
That's enough, Mr. Bryce. Unless you allow him
to the city to wear.
Sergeant, tie him up.
Grab the rope.
Mr. van Diemen, you have a clear
few tough days behind.
Yes, sir.
'm Not afraid.
The 100 sovereigns for U.
Commendable.
Come, get up.
Stand up, damn wild!
Arise, murdering bastard!
Major, with your consent. If you are
hands bound before him ...
he goes easier.
And faster.
Sergeant, do what Mr. van Diemen
suggests.
I did not expect to see you until I
back, Sergeant Major.
Crowther said Corporal Your orders
were ...
me to return soon
with new supplies.
I am sure that no corporal
said.
But now you're here, we need only
with it.
But remember well, Sergeant Major. This is
No retaliation.
Hard bastards, right?
My family ...
They fought wars in the country. 30
years ago.
Good fighters.
Smart as weasels.
If you do a wicked war dance
will do ...
their Haka ...
crying like a pack of wild dogs ...
then you know you are in trouble.
Furious.
And the women are worse.
- Excuse me.
I should know.
I am a married.
Some meat ...
Thank you.
You must have been a good soldier.
- I've never been a soldier.
Okay, if we rebel
The British stopped ...
but that was short.
And you fought for your country and
for your freedom.
That makes a man a soldier.
Fighting for my freedom?
Well, that's so or not?
I'll tell you what for
I fought freedom.
Late one morning ...
The day after New Year ...
I was driving out to my farm.
Then I saw Daarby for the last time.
He hung on the tree of the neighbor.
The British had him hanged?
- No ...
not the British.
My neighbor had him hanged.
To steal from a branch.
82 years old ...
No ancient Bushman would
steal from the whites.
My friend ...
hung on the tree.
He had him six months suspended ...
as an example.
Do you have avenged him?
No ...
I waged war ...
and fought for the rights of those
asshole do it again.
That's the freedom I fought for.
Without freedom we are nothing.
When she hung up my grandfather
he shouted at me.
You have to liberate us all
these Hara.
This shame.
I ran away.
That's different ...
You was just a boy.
Therefore, they've never hung.
I was not big enough.
The soldiers threw the bodies
Just a hole.
I could not decently buried.
So I ran away.
But I knew in my heart that I
to come back ...
and she was free.
So why did you come back?
Because you have family honor
violated when you ran away?
I had almost made it ...
It is just beyond that ridge.
But you stopped me one.
You stopped me one.
You and your Daarby.
Saunders, I think the prisoner
without your attention to.
The ropes were cut, see?
He has something to do with ropes ...
He has something with cords?
You knew?
You have to let him go!
It was hard enough to catch him ...
do you really think I had
I let go again?
Well, I'll tell you one thing ...
someone has to let him go.
And fast.
He also cut his bracelet.
What is he, Sergeant?
The Wild have been good between them,
but he's fine.
Mr. Bryce!
How long?
Two, maybe three hours.
But he is in bad shape.
He leaves a good trail
and will not get far.
van Diemen!
Mr. Bryce knows what he is talking about.
Excuse me gentlemen, but I
have a bone to pick.
Okay, here we leave the camp.
Mr. Carlysle.
I hope that this is important Saunders.
- I just wanted to ask Mr. ...
Now that the prisoner was armed, we can ...
- Armed?
How armed?
Did you not tell the sergeant Leybourne?
The prisoner has escaped
with Renwick's rifle.
Unfortunately, it seems that the
leukigheden of law ...
luxury that we no longer
can afford.
You have permission to shoot.
But, this is not a game.
There is no place for sports.
I care for a court-martial for everyone
who did not with the first shot kills.
Understood?
Mr. Bryce.
He could have gone both ways.
If we take the wrong ...
Mr. Bryce, tell me ...
- I love it!
Do that, and fast!
This is a holy place.
The house of Rua Maimo.
I came here with my grandfather when I was
was small.
I had to wait outside while he
Cave went ...
with our spiritual protectors
talk.
Now it's my turn.
Time to the mana of my ancestors
cash.
There is only one way out.
You know this area.
Bryce is our lost track, but not for
long.
We need to get you out of here.
Believe me, they'll shoot you now.
I'm still wondering why you
index fingers cut off by British soldiers.
God says it is a sin to someone
dead.
Unless your home and family protection.
The weather prevented good men
sinned.
Bryce is better than you thought!
There's enough coverage. If we split
we can around it.
They can not continue.
They have given us yet.
I can not run, I can not climb ...
There is no way around them. - You have to!
I can not run!
We may not have to run.
It's your life.
No! It is your life.
And I'm not a murderer.
We can fight.
Yes?
You have a thing for me.
lets big.
No.
- You should.
I do not.
You gotta help me on my journey to
Hawaiki.
What? - This is the
final resting place for our people.
Let them hang me!
I do not want to die like my forefathers,
hanging on a pole!
Without mana, without dignity.
Saunders, Bryce, take the right.
Sergeant, with me.
van Diemen?
Another trophy for justice
of his highness.
He had courage. He should get respect.
I do not know if Saunders same opinion,
van Diemen.
I have some left for him.
- Fuck off.
I'd rather have his head.
- Before you pay the price.
We must take the corpse.
Let him at least buried.
We can not leave here!
Sorry Mr. van Diemen, there is enough
this wasted time.
I ordered the sheets that you asked
did, sir.
It will be long before your wife
arrives.
He's alive!
Sergeant! Sergeant Leybourne!
I want a man in every port
on the ...
lookout for a Maori
without the right index finger.
Now damn it! I want him arrested
are alive and brought here.
van Diemen ...
Major ...
I heard you left.
- This country does not interest me anymore.
Australia.
There is a place called "Van Diemen's
Landing ".
That is to me.
Will you leave without your reward?
25 sovereigns.
It could have been four times.
He's alive, right?
As always should have been
for you ...
he shouted, not even when
You cut off his finger.
I assume that you have your reasons ...
I think I will never understand
they are.
It's a lot of money.
The blessing of the generals.
You were there or not ...?
Have you ordered?
Have you ordered my farm
to burn?
No, I did not.
Tell me ...
there was someone in the house?
When you burning?
No.
I can assure you.
Sir!
We are ready!
The captain wants to leave.
Major ...
van Diemen ...
You know that I sent messengers to every
Port've sent?
Each whaling station?
Ever seen that one?
Maybe you did a few weeks
given, perhaps a few days.
I really hope it was worth.
Do you know what life means a few days
for a condemned man?
Translator Unknown.
Control and various adjustments: Goffin