Previously on Stargate Atlantis.
They're not people.
They're machines.
They've even built themselves
a version of Atlantis.
The probes of your minds
uncovered the truth.
You only came to live there from
your original home, a planet called Earth.
Our intention is to destroy it.
They see humans as the favoured siblings
who receive all the parents' love.
They've been seeking revenge ever since.
Atlantis is under attack
from Replicators.
I'll be damned if I'm going to let a bunch of
replicators take our home away from us.
They emit a directional energy beam that
disrupts the connection between nanites.
So the Replicators literally
fall apart when you fire on 'em.
Well, we beat 'em this time,
maybe we scared them off.
Maybe.
Doctor Weir?
Doctor Keller. How is
my Head of Medicine?
Uh, Acting Head of Medicine, actually, and
that's kinda what I wanted to talk to you about.
What's up?
- I need to be replaced.
- Excuse me?
Look, after Carson
Someone had to step up and take over, and
I'm glad to help out, don't get me wrong. But.
I'm not qualified to run a
department of this size. You...
You need someone... better.
Everyone down there
says you're doing great.
Well, (a) I'm not sure that's true,
and (b) it's been pretty smooth sailing over
the last few weeks. I think I've been lucky.
Well, the IOA are reviewing
candidates but,
to be honest, they're not
that great at making quick decisions.
Yeah. So, a week?
Two weeks?
I just haven't been sleeping very well.
This whole being in control
thing kind of makes me anxious.
Carson felt the same way
his first few months.
I appreciate you trying to lie to me.
Look, I feel very comfortable with my life in
your hands; and at the end of the day.
That means you're
doin' a pretty good job.
Dealing with the pressure
it does get easier with time.
Right. Uh,
how much time, exactly?
Like, it'll get easier over the next
two weeks and then you'll replace me,
so I can go back
to being a regular doctor?
I'll keep you posted!
Thanks.
- Can I please have someone else do these?
- Performance evaluations?   - Yes.
No. Year-end employee
reviews are important.
They're how people
get promotions, and raises.
OK, look. Asking me to do performance evaluations
is ridiculous. I am the first person to admit.
I don't know who these
people are, nor do I care to.
Look, if you'd like, I could take
you down the hall to the labs and just
point at the people who annoy me more than
the rest, but that's about as useful as I get.
- All done.
- Oh, of course !
That was quick!
Hey, John, wait a minute. You've just given
everyone excellent and above averages.
- Ooh! Can I do that?
- No!
I know this is not the most
glamorous part of your job
but you are in
leadership positions and,
unfortunately, that comes
with administrative responsibilities.
Well, everybody who works for
me is excellent and above average.
You want me to lie? `Cause I don't
think leaders should lie, Elizabeth.
- Doctor Weir?
- Yes, Chuck?
The Apollo just came out of hyperspace.
They're ahead of schedule.
Probably just tryin' to show off you know,
bein' a new ship an' all.
Colonel Ellis, you've made excellent
time on your first voyage here.
- Thank you. I'm beaming down now.
- Very well. We'll meet ...
Set up in the Conference Room.
Doctor.
- Colonel. Welcome.
- Thank you.
Colonel Sheppard, Doctor McKay.
This is gonna make things easier.
I'll need to brief you all immediately.
- What's going on?
- Well, I'd prefer to talk in private.
Ever since the human-form
Replicators made a play for the city.
We've had the Daedalus make regular
reconnaissance fly-bys of their home planet.
- Yes, we know.
- Two months ago, it took these pictures.
I'm sorry, what am I supposed
to be looking at here?
- Nothing.
- Excuse me?
This image was taken about three
weeks ago in the very same location.
- They're building ships a lot of them.
- Why weren't we made aware of this?
I'm making you aware of it now.
Well, if they're coming for us, we should start making
preparations to bolster the shield. I mean, we should...
They're not gonna get here.
I'm here to inform you that in precisely
twelve hours, the Apollo in consort with your team.
Will launch a surgical strike
on the Replicator planet.
Stargate Atlantis - Saison 3 Episode 20
"First Strike"
(Season Final)
Synchronisation: Golgi, Malikay, Ricana.
Edition: Golgi, Linwelin, Malikay, Ricana.
Transcript : Callie Sullivan
Relecture: Golgi.
h
ht
htt
http
http:
http://
http://p
http://pr
http://pro
http://proj
http://proje
http://projet
http://projet-
http://projet-s
http://projet-sg
http://projet-sg.
http://projet-sg.n
http://projet-sg.ne
http://projet-sg.net
- So, uh, you're gonna blow up their ships.
- That's right.
- Just like that?
- Just like that.
How the hell do
you plan on doing that?
A set of Mark Nine tactical nukes
housed in a custom-made
weapons platform codenamed Horizon.
How many nukes do you have?
The Horizon carries six warheads
and four decoys.
I'm gonna need you to do a final
inspection before we head out.
- Whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa-whoa, wait. Six?
- That's right.
- That's not enough.   -  The Replicators are
self-replicating robots, which means that they can...
I'm aware of that, thank you, Doctor, but
they're not like the Milky Way Replicators.
Their ships aren't built from nano-cells.
They're constructed of real material
that can be destroyed.
Six will be more than enough for now.
"For now"? Look, isn't this a bit
like poking a sleeping dragon?
Why don't we just wait `til
Area 51 finishes the PWARWs?
- Which one's that, again?
- Planetary-Wide Anti-Replicator Weapons.
Look, the Asgard were capable of creating a satellite
that could wipe out an entire Replicator planet.
I mean, we've had some
trouble making one of our own but.
Look, would I prefer taking out
an entire planet at once? Absolutely.
But this image is giving
the IOA a lot of sleepless nights.
The Replicators know the location of Earth and,
with these new ships, have the means to get there.
We can't just sit on our hands while the guys
at Area 51 try to come up with a solution.
This mission's primary objective
is to eliminate key military targets.
We'll come back and finish once
the new weapon is up and running.
Doctor, I'm gonna need you to start
your inspections as soon as possible.
- Well, yes, sure. I just...
- Doctor McKay is ready to beam.
Well, he's not, actually...
OK.
We're finished here.
Thank you.
- Can you believe this?
- No.
It all seems too good to be true.
What?!
Well, if those nukes do
what Ellis says they do...
Since we won back the city, we haven't
heard so much as a peep from the Replicators.
Well, obviously
they haven't gone away.
No, but maybe they've decided that
we are more trouble than we're worth.
That the threat of our AR weapons
is enough to keep them at bay.
You don't build that many ships
to make a run at Atlantis.
They're headed for Earth.
Colonel.
- May I have a word?
- Sure.
- This mission is a mistake.
- It most certainly is not.
It is an ineffectual first strike. You've gotta
know how dangerous that could be for us.
All due respect, Doctor, it won't be ineffectual.
Besides, the IOA doesn't think we can wait.
I think we should stall them
try to open a round of negotiations.
They're not a race of people.
They're a weapon. Try to keep that in mind.
Weapon or not, they're sentient.
Negotiating with them could buy us
enough time to get the PWARW up and running.
Usually I'd be more than happy to go twelve
rounds here about who's right and who's wrong,
but it wouldn't matter.
I have my orders, and you don't have
the authority to tell me to stand down,
so, again, with all due respect, ma'am,
I have a mission to execute.
Well, the specs check out. We've loaded
the target information. They're ready.
Yeah. It's good to go.
This is a bad idea, isn't it?
We could tell them
they're not ready you know,
there's a fault with the guidance
system or something.
I thought about that. They're gonna have guys
here to contradict us pretty quickly.
Yep. But we're here alone. We could
make them not ready.
They're building an armada, Radek.
I saw them. They showed me the pictures.
I'd feel pretty stupid if we break this thing, only
to have the Replicators show up and destroy the city.
Yeah. Yeah,
that would be bad.
Tell the Colonel we're good to go.
- Hey.
- Colonel Ellis has asked me
to join the mission.   - I know.
I was gonna stay behind in a cloaked
Jumper after they launch the warheads;
do some battle damage assessment.
I know that too.
He told me that you called Woolsey and General O'Neill
and tried to get the whole thing called off.
- Yes, I did.
- They didn't bite.
They did not.
- Look, I know you think we're doing
the wrong thing here, but, uh...   - John...
Good luck.
Alright.
Horizon is online.
The warheads are armed and we
are ready for final sequencing
- as soon as we drop out of hyperspace.
- Start now.
- Open the bomb bay doors.
- We're still in hyperspace.
We're coming out of our jump
uncomfortably close to the planet.
I don't wanna waste
any time. Just get it done.
Well, you're the boss.
Ready to launch
on your command.
You're sure about this, right?
I mean, like, this is the right thing to do?
Not the best time for
that kind of talk, Doctor.
Right. Sorry.
Coming out of hyperspace in
five, four, three, two, one.
Launch the Horizon.
We have detonation confirmation
on all six warheads.
- Sheppard, you have a go for launch.
- Copy that.
- Clear. Jump away. - Very well. We'll
pick you up in an hour. Pull us out of here.
There is so much
radiation interference,
it's hard to get an accurate yield
calculation from the scan telemetry.
Please, there is more than enough data. It's not
like we're trying to take out a person here.
We're taking out massive chunks of a city.
Someone just please tell me
if we hit our targets or not.
If this data is right,
then all of your primaries and most of your
secondaries have been incinerated.
Excellent.
- Welcome back.
- Thanks.
- I hear congratulations are in order.
- Yeah, you heard right.
- How was the mission? Was it a success?
- We did get all the ships.
I wish I could've been there to see it.
Well, space battles are always a lot more
exciting on TV than they are in real life.
Doctor Weir? You're gonna wanna see this.
We've got a contact.
- Just came out of hyperspace.
- Is it broadcasting IFF?
- No, ma'am.
- Wraith?
Naah. It's very small. I doubt it.
- Raise the shield.   - It's taking up
a geosynchronous orbit above the city.
What is it?
Maybe we should have
the Apollo check it out.
Tell the Colonel he needs
to get back to his ship.
- Right ahead of us, sir.
- Shields?
Affirmative. Shields are up.
OK, I've got a visual. Looks
like a satellite of some sort.
- It's a Stargate!
- A Stargate?
That's right.
I thought you said
it was a satellite.
It's both. It's a satellite, but
in the middle there's a... Stargate.
- What could be the purpose of that?
- I've no idea.
- It just activated.
- The Gate?!
Get us away from it!
Sir, the satellite is turning again.
It's hitting the planet.
- It's a sustained beam.
- That is bad for a dozen different reasons.
It's protected by a shield.
Give me some options, McKay.
The shield's taking
its power from the beam.
Look, I registered a slight drop
in output when you fired on it.
Could I get a nuke past its shield?
No, probably not.
I'll get in the Chair and give it everything
we've got. Maybe that'll collapse the shield.
I said "slight" as
in point zero zero two. Look,
I doubt any amount of firepower is gonna
collapse it while that beam is active.
- Then what do we do?   - We stand down
and let me think, is what we do.
- Just give me five minutes to get my bearings.
I'll brief you.   - McKay, it's shooting at us.
Yes, and the shields are holding.
Look, we've got plenty
of time... just give me five minutes.
- What've you got?
- We're in trouble.
It took you five minutes to figure that out?
You're slippin', buddy.
Look, the satellite is basically
just a stripped-down ship.
There's a hyperdrive engine,
a shield, and navigational systems.
There's a small power source that was
designed to take it to its intended target
and power the shield
until the Gate can be dialled.
But once a wormhole has been established
to whoever's on the dialling side,
it fires a beam into their Stargate
and it comes out on our side,
allowing them to fire on us
and to power the satellite.
That's very clever.
Yes. As long as they can keep
the beam powered from home,
the weapon remains operational.
Oh, and one fun added side bonus is that because
their Stargate is in such close proximity to our planet,
- we can't dial our Stargate. We're stuck.
- Maybe that's a good thing.
The beam'll turn off at the end of
the Gate's thirty-eight minute cycle.
If we dial our Gate at that precise moment,
we can neutralise theirs.
What, and if it's not pulling power
from the beam any more,
then we can collapse
its shield and destroy it.
Sure. The problem is, I don't think it's gonna
shut down in thirty-eight minutes.
But I thought it was physically impossible for
an artificial wormhole to stay open any longer.
There is one exception to that rule.
The SGC has encountered attacks
of this kind on their own Stargate
and sadly we've discovered that
if you pump enough energy into it,
a Stargate can remain active indefinitely.
That would require an insane
amount of power, wouldn't it?
Like a black hole, or
an unlimited number of ZPMs.
- So we can assume the Replicators
are behind this. - Well, I hope so.
- You hope so? - Well, otherwise, we've
discovered yet another super-powerful enemy.
If it is a normal Stargate, can we
still contact the dialling planet?
Well, I'll need to boost the signal considerably
to get through the interference, but, uh, yes.
- See what you can do, please.
- Right.
- Why would you wanna contact them?
- To negotiate.
It's a waste of energy. We need to
figure out how to destroy it.
I'd love to go twelve rounds here
about who's right and who's wrong,
but at the end of the day I'm responsible
for the well-being of this city,
and you don't have the authority
to tell me to stand down.
So with all due respect,
I think I'll place my call.
Alright.
I think I've got it.
They're responding
to the transmission.
- Oberoth!
- Doctor Weir.
I must say I'm surprised
to see you.
Each of us exists within the collective
and can be replicated many times.
- You need to disable your weapon
immediately.   - That is not possible.
We had no choice but to attack you.
You're building warships.
- They need to be neutralised.
- And now, so do you.
That assault was just the tip of the spear.
We were hoping it would bring you to your senses.
If you don't stop this aggression,
we will be forced to launch an all-out attack.
Really? Why have you waited?
The annihilation of
your people is not our goal.
Ideally, we would like
a peace to exist between us,
but we will not stand idly by while you build ships
and weapons that can be used to destroy us.
Interesting. We feel
the same way about you.
Perhaps I should remind you every time we've
met in battle, our side has been clearly victorious.
Elizabeth. They're attempting to upload
a virus on the comm bandwidth.
- I've been able to stop it for now but I'm not...
- Shut it down.
- Well, that went well!
- Yeah. Always been one of my favourites.
What if the Gate doesn't shut down
at the end of its thirty-eight minute cycle?
Look, if they're able to maintain
the energy beam's intensity,
- which I'm sure they will...
- And how long `til our shield fails?
It's twenty-nine hours.
Well, it was worth a shot.
- Alright, we're gonna need another plan.
- Yeah, OK.
Look, stop dialling.
It's not working.
Sir.
You two give us a minute.
What can I do for you, John?
We need to head back
to the Replicator planet.
- We do, do we?   - Yeah. If this satellite
weapon is powered by its homeworld,
maybe we can neutralise
it at the source.
Well, the Apollo is in no condition
to get in a battle right now.
- That beam took a lot out of our shield.
- No, we've gotta do something.
- We did do something.   - I'm sorry, sir, but I can't
help but think that we're somehow responsible for this.
- Why, because Weir said so?
- No, sir.
John, listen to me.
I, uh,
I've been over your record.
I know you have your detractors but personally
I think you've done a hell of a job here.
- Thank you, sir.
- You should be running Atlantis, not Doctor Weir.
Then I'd be The Man, and who
would I have to rage against?
Listen. Because of us, Earth won't have
to deal with an armada of Replicator ships,
so whatever happens here,
we did the right thing today.
I'm sorry.
It's just...
they didn't even consult me.
I imagine they felt the need
for secrecy was great.
I have the highest level of
clearance humanly possible, Teyla. No.
Tthey're trying to undermine me.
Some of the military doesn't like
that a civilian, let alone a woman,
is in charge of this city.
Surely General O'Neill
doesn't feel that way.
And the IOA, they've backed you
several times. They believe in you.
Yes, when things are going well, but
as soon as we run into a major problem,
the military steps in
and assumes absolute control.
- Certainly you don't wish to coordinate military
attacks.   - No, and that's not what I'm saying. Look,
our current situation could have easily
been avoided. I told them as much,
but they put next to no weight behind my opinions
regarding the safety and protection of this city.
Yes, the IOA is happy
to have me as lead administrator,
but when it comes to the big decisions...
If we get out of this, I think
I may have to step down.
Give it some time. You need
to step back and...
We've got something.
We were throwing some ideas
back and forth... well,
he was throwing them forth
and I was throwing them back
and while he was droning on about some idea that
might have worked, it suddenly occurred to me:
this city has encountered problems
like this before, so I...
We don't need the history
of your idea, Doctor.
I'll let that be a surprise when I read
your autobiography. Just tell me the plan.
- We submerge it.
- I'm sorry?
-We submerge the city.   - I thought you said
we couldn't submerge the city.
That was two years ago before the Ancients came
and activated a number of new systems. See...
- The "how" is complicated, but I think it's possible.
Look, it's not a permanent solution... - but
- it'll buy us enough time
`til we come up with one.   - Exactly.
- How much time?
- Some. As much as a week.
I don't understand. Why?
Ah, you see, the history part
would have made that a lot clearer.
- Had you been a little more patient, I would
have painted you a picture of...   - McKay.
Ten thousand years ago when the Ancients
were under siege from the Wraith,
they sank the city in order to dissipate
the Wraiths' energy blasts in the water.
This way, the shield was able to hold far longer
than it ever could on the surface. So, now,
we submerge the city. The water attenuates the
satellite's beam intensity, buys us some more shield time.
We cannot predict how much
the Replicators' beam will be attenuated.
- It might not buy us any time at all.
- There's no way to know for sure, yes,
but it's not a reason not to try.
- Alright, get it done.
- Yeah, I don't think that's your call.
Worst case scenario?
We lose some power from the ZPM?
Oh, no – worst case scenario is that
we've both read the numbers wrong,
we use up a ton of power and
the city doesn't submerge at all.
Look, as much as I hate to say it,
Zelenka's not infallible.
Still, I agree. It's worth the risk.
Alright. The city has an automatic
submersion subroutine already in the system.
I'll need it to tweak it a bit to work with one ZPM
and disable some safety protocols. Give me an hour.
- It's been an hour.
- We're ready.
- No... you've got to do the, um...
- Oh, just, um...
- We are ready.
- Good.
Give me city-wide.
Attention all personnel. We are about
to attempt to submerge the city.
From what I understand,
it could get a little bumpy,
so this is your last chance to secure equipment
and get to the designated safe areas.
- We've come full circle, eh?
- Yeah. Feels that way.
OK. Take us down.
Aye, aye, Captain. Shall we?
That's it. We're down.
- The beam still looks pretty serious, Rodney.
- Yeah, I know. Just give me a second to...
- Crap!
- I told you.
- Thank you, Radek. Very helpful.
- What is it?
The beam is breaking through the water
much more efficiently than we thought.
- The water has no effect?   - It's having an effect
but just nowhere near what we wanted to. Look,
- that plan took us three hours to execute and
bought us an additional... ten hours.   - Nine.
Nine.
OK. What's the plan?
That was the plan.
I need to learn some science.
What for?
I'm not all that useful
in situations like these.
If we get into a fight, or we need to break out
of somewhere, you know, kill someone, I'm your man;
but a laser attacking the city's shield,
I don't know where to chip in.
Well, that's why we're a team,
like the Fantastic Four.
It's a comic book where superheroes
fight crime and stuff.
See, I'd be Mr Fantastic;
Ronon would be The Thing;
McKay would be the Human Torch...
you'd be the Invisible Woman.
I am not invisible.
- No. No, and McKay's not a human torch.
- Well, how come you get to be Mr Fantastic?
Because he was the leader and I'm the...
I'm just saying that they were a cool team and we're a
cool team and they use their strengths to, you know...
I'm gonna go check on McKay.
Shouldn't you guys be
bickering or something?
Ah, we've got nothing to bicker about.
He's run out of bad ideas... finally.
If we survive this,
I'm putting in for a transfer.
Oh, please. We both know that
you've done your best work under me.
- Under you?! I'm my own department head, you know.
- Please! We both know that department is a joke.
Why don't you two guys just
make out and get it over with, huh?
I mean, we have, what? Under one day to figure out
how not to get destroyed by this satellite thing,
and you guys are arguing
about who works for who.
Every possible scenario ends in failure.
There is nowhere on the face of
this planet that that thing cannot kill us.
- You don't think...?
- No.
Old girl too banged up?
No, the Replicators fixed all the damage we did
with the drones. We just don't have the power.
- Yeah, but ideally...
- it may be the only way.   - What?
The drilling platform. You guys
have it operational down there, right?
- Close enough, but we couldn't bring it with us.
- Bring it where?
- We don't need to. We just need a boost.
- You might be onto something here.
Hey! What's your idea?! Hey!
Well, luckily the
umbilical's already in place.
Yes, I know. Look, are you capable of
outputting the power we need or not?
We just started drilling into the crust.
I can get you nine
percent of the way there.
- There goes that plan.
- Can't the ZPM make up the difference?
Ah, no. The ZedPM's a little busy
powering the shield at max.
What if it didn't have to?
What if we could take the strain
off the shield momentarily?
Well, we'd need about a minute.
Why? What do you have in mind?
Lantea's moon has some
sizeable satellites itself.
Asteroid-like chunks we think are left over
from a second moon that no longer exists.
I'd like you to beam up Lorne and get a flight
of F-302s close enough to nudge one our way.
You wanna bring an asteroid
towards us? Is that wise?
Well, today it is.
Alright, guys. We need to get
close enough to clamp on to it.
Get enough of us drilled in, we can
fly it like a ship... a really slow ship.
It's probably gonna be a real pain
in the ass to steer, but a ship nonetheless.
OK, let's take this big gal for a stroll.
Flights Three and Four,
begin your burn. Full thrust.
Son of a bitch! We might be able to pull this off
after all! Flights One and Two, begin your burn.
It's working?
- It's slow going, but, uh, yes,
they're bringing it towards the planet.
They should be able to get
here before our cut-off time.
- So we can actually do this?
- I think so, yes.
OK, time to tell people.
Patch me into the PA, please.
May I have your attention? As you all know,
we have found ourselves in a spot of trouble.
The reality is that no matter where
we try to hide on this planet,
the Replicator satellite
will be able to track us.
Therefore, Doctor McKay and Colonel Sheppard
have come up with a rather ingenious way for us
to escape the satellite's range altogether.
In the next few hours, we will fire
the city's stardrive and head into space.
Atlantis is leaving this planet.
- May I come in?
- Of course.
- All non-essential personnel have
been beamed to the Apollo.   - Good. Good.
Has Doctor McKay located
your new home yet?
Yes. M12-578.
It's the closest
non-populated habitable planet
with a large ocean. He's a bit nervous
about trying to land on solid ground.
I can understand that.
- Listen, I know you don't like me very much...
- Colonel, that's nei...   - That's OK.
To be honest, I'm not that
crazy about you either.
OK!
But if I've crossed the line here
or there in regards to your command,
I apologise. I'm used to making the calls.
But I don't want you to think
I don't respect you. I do, Doctor.
Thank you. I appreciate that. I wish
the rest of the military felt the same way.
Well, I can't speak to that. I do know
General O'Neill is awfully fond of you.
I'd better be heading out.
- Good luck.
- Thanks. We're gonna need it.
Alright. Zelenka is doing a final
pass over all the coding we've done,
but so far it's looking good.
The underwater drilling platform's power output
has been dialled up as high as it'll go,
and the crew down there have
been beamed up to the Apollo.
We're gonna wreck
that thing, aren't we?
What, the drilling platform?
Oh, hell, yes! But
thirty percent of our total power requirements are
gonna be consumed in the first ten seconds of flight.
The station will provide us with that
power right up until we snap the umbilical,
at which point we switch
over to the ZPM. Now,
if we can interrupt the satellite's beam,
which is greatly taxing our power levels
we should be able to squeeze out just
enough power to actually do this thing.
- How's Lorne doin'?   - He's making good time.
He should be here in the next twenty minutes.
Well, I guess it's showtime.
- You sure you can do this?
- Fly the city?
What else could I possibly
be talking about?
I flew a V22 Osprey once.
Was it as big as a city?
Well, you had to use your hands and feet with that one.
This one, you just have to sit down and think... "Fly."
OK, why don't you just get in
the Chair and start your pre-flight?
Oh, I'm gonna head up
to the Control Room,
and Zelenka will monitor
output from the ZPM Room.
And, uh, good luck.
You too.
Doctor McKay,
can you read me?
Five by five.
Lorne, you in position?
We're getting close.
You about ready?
Zelenka, I need a Go or No Go.
We're Go. All non-essential systems
have been shut down. We're in the green.
- Are you ready, Sheppard?
- Ready as I'll ever be.
OK, Major, make sure she's
moving as slow as possible.
Are you sure we shouldn't
just lob this thing at the satellite?
No, they'd easily be able to navigate
back into position. This is still our best bet.
Copy that.
Package is away and on course.
We're heading back to the Apollo. Good luck.
OK, calculating travel time
based on current speed.
That's it. We're good.
Here goes nothing.
Asteroid is entering the beam.
We're on the surface.
Fire the stardrive.
We're not flying high enough.
It's stalling out!
It's not working.
What are you doing wrong?
Sure, blame me.
We don't have enough power.
- Oh, sure, blame me!   - It's not working.
What other reasons could there be?
I have no more power to give you!
- Shut it off.
- What?
- Lower the shield.   - We're about to go into space!
If you plan on breathing, we're gonna need the shield.
Turn it back on at eighteen thousand feet.
We just need the boost to get started, no?
That might work.
OK, I did it.
Give it all you've got.
That's it!
We're flying!
That's it. Time's up.
Raising the shield.
Taking us into hyperspace.
We did it!
McKay! Elizabeth!
I need a medical team to the
Control Room, stat! Multiple injuries!
- Keller, what happened?   - Apparently the beam
grazed the tower and blew out the...
Adams, that guy just has a cut. Tell him
to put pressure on it and move on.
There's a lot of people
worse off upstairs.
Elizabeth? Is she gonna be OK?
I don't know yet. She took quite a fall
and her pupils are sluggish.
I'm gonna have to get her
under a scanner. I'll know more in a bit.
Oh, God. Are you alright?
- Yeah, I've had worse.
- How come no-one's helping you?
I told them I didn't need any help.
Other people need more.
- I doubt that. Get this man to the Infirmary.
- Yes, sir.
- You guys alright?
- All things considered.
- What happened?   - The beam grazed the side
of the tower before the shield was completely closed.
- Damage?
- Minimal, I think.
Look, I was able to get the shield up
fairly quickly. It took the brunt of the blow.
Oh, what now?
What is happening?
- We just dropped out of hyperspace.
- Have we already reached M12-578?
No. There's no way. It should have taken
at least another few hours.
- The hyperdrive just shut down.
- Why?
- I don't know.
- Get it back up.
I just said I don't know what's wrong. I can't get
it back up if I don't know what happened.
- Where are we?
- In the middle of nowhere.
There's no planets,
no moons, no Stargates.
How much power do we have?
- This can't be right.
- How much?
At current consumption, we've got
twenty-four hours of power left.
After that, there's no shield.
- No shield, no atmosphere. No atmosphere,
we're...   - Can we use the Stargate?
In order to dial a Gate, it needs to
be calibrated to a specific location. We are lost.
Look, we dropped out of hyperspace
way too soon. I have no idea where we are.
* Rapidité *
TO BE CONTINUED
* Efficacité *
* Projet-SG *
http://projet-sg.net
www.tvsubtitles.net