Prof. Yoshiyama...
Here's the research data you asked for.
Thank you.
Don't forget the conference at 14:00.
Immersing yourself in
your own research is fine...
but don't be late this time.
TIME TRAVELLER
- The Girl Who Leapt Through Time -
Here's one from 1972.
Why do you collect coins
from so long ago?
I'm not sure myself.
"1972"
Original novel by Yasutaka Tsutsui
"The Girl Who Leapt Through Time"
"Shotoku Univ. Entrance Exam
Results for 2010"
No way!
Here it is.
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
"Department of Pharmacy"
Directed by Masaaki Taniguchi
Miracle happens!
Congratulations!
Congratulations on passing the exam.
Thanks.
We always celebrate here.
Yeah.
This boat feels smaller each time.
I wonder when we'll come next.
Mom...
What kind of person was Dad?
Why ask now?
I was just wondering.
I barely remember him
so I'm curious.
He's different.
He's back in Japan
shooting movies again.
He's in the mountains right now.
You keep in touch?
He emails me sometimes.
Why didn't you tell me?
You never asked.
That's why?
For you, ducky.
"Misonou High: Archery Club"
"Today is the seniors'
last day of practice"
I knew it.
Your form was cool though.
Shut up.
Just take them home
a little by little.
I'm glad you're here.
Thanks from me too.
Well, it's nice being
around young people.
You know that song?
Of course. Takuro Yoshida is my idol.
He's a strange kid.
- What's this song?
- "It was Spring"
Correct.
Our voices disappeared...
It was spring...
My throat hurts.
Too much singing.
You're such a big help.
Mom always says it's great
to have you around.
She says that?
She says that.
Is she still busy?
She's a workaholic.
I hope she doesn't get sick.
Thank you for helping.
See ya.
Goro!
Sorry to bother you.
You have something for me?
A photo of you.
Of me?
Remember my neighbor
Granny Fukamachi? It's from her.
She found it in her attic.
She doesn't know why it was there...
but wants you to have it.
Was this guy in our class though?
She grows them
in her greenhouse.
She knows you like lavender.
Saturday. Science lab.
Yoshiyama...
I have to go.
Sorry to keep you.
Sorry.
Yoshiyama.
Fukamachi...
Hello.
My name's Yoshiyama.
The daughter?
Yes.
She has no serious external injuries...
and they'll heal completely
in two weeks.
But she hit her head hard
and is still unconscious.
We don't know when
she'll come around.
Talk to her as much as you can.
I'll be back later.
Mom...
Wake up!
You haven't slept.
You should lie down.
No.
You have to stay strong for
your mom when she wakes up.
Today, let's travel back
in time to Mar. 3, 1974.
The Noshiro night bus accident.
The bus, full of passengers,
departed Shinjuku
on the night of Mar. 2.
It traveled northbound
on Route 4 until...
36 years ago
I was supposed to be on this bus.
It fell off a cliff killing
38 people onboard...
I was going on a ski trip.
But I forgot my bus ticket at home.
"A Night Bus Accident
Kills All Passengers"
A friend of mine...
died in this accident.
But...
I'm alive.
It was fate.
Fate is on your mom's side.
So she'll wake up.
I'm sure of it.
Thanks.
"Birth of Akari Hasegawa"
"Masamichi Hasegawa"
"I'll be filming in the
mountains for 4 months. "
"This is Akari. Mom had an accident...
and is in the hospital. "
"If... "
Mom...
It's...
my birthday today.
I'm 18.
Sort of...
sounds grown-up, huh?
Mom?
Mom!
Akari...
It's me.
I have to go.
No! Lie still.
What?
To see him.
Kazuo Fukamachi.
Kazuo Fukamachi?
The photo and key...
in my bag.
Bag?
The photo...
This?
I have to go.
No, Mom!
I'll go, okay?
I'll go.
Where is he?
Saturday, April 1972.
The junior high science lab.
1972?
The key to my desk...
There's a liquid...
It'll take you to the past.
Drink it and wish hard.
Tell him that...
Okay.
I'll go tell him.
So you have to...
Mom... Wake up!
"Showa Era 47"
That's 1972.
Saturday, April 1972.
Science lab.
What am I doing?
This is crazy.
Was it...
February 1974?.
Saturday, February 1974.
Science lab.
What the heck?
She came falling.
Out of thin air.
I'm sorry.
Who are you?.
I'm Ryota and
this is my apartment.
Remember yesterday?
Yesterday...
Kazuo Fukamachi?!
You're...
Not.
Is this the Setagaya
Jr. High science lab?
Shotoku University.
Oh, no!
I couldn't just leave you there.
So I brought you here.
What's today's date?
Sunday, Feb. 17, 1974.
1974...
February 1974.
April 1972.
I'm 2 years too late.
Your bag!
Where's Setagaya Jr. High?
Uh, the station's that way.
I'm completely lost.
Come with me.
"Setagaya Junior High School"
Excuse me... I'm looking for someone.
This guy.
That's Kazuko Yoshiyama
next to him, isn't it?
That's right.
But I'm looking for the guy.
I've never seen him.
Stop loafing around and go home.
Fresh off the grill.
Thank you.
It really is February 1974.
What's your name?
Akari Yoshiyama.
Your home?
Go home when you finish eating.
Your parents must be worried.
You ran away, right?
I...
came from 2010.
I came from the future
to meet someone.
You hit your head hard.
I'm serious. I appeared
out of nowhere, didn't I?
Yeah, but...
Okay, proof.
My wallet.
A 500-yen coin and...
What's this era?.
This is technology of 2010.
A small radio?
A mobile.
Mobile?
It's mainly a phone.
No signals, of course.
It's also...
a camera. Cool, huh?
A multiple communication device.
I use this in my SF movie.
You can transmit and record
messages from anywhere.
My invention, right in my hands...
It hit the spot.
So you believe me?
You're an SF geek, right?
Geek?.
You.
Ryota, let me stay with you.
"Ryota"?... No way.
I'll clean, wash, and cook.
I won't get in the way, so please.
Wait.
I have to do this.
Give a message to Kazuo...
and go back to my mom.
If I find him...
and give him the message.
she might wake up again.
So, please.
Help me find him.
I'm sorry.
Come in.
What are you doing?
See.
What's up?
You tell us.
Hello. - Hello.
She's cute.
Your type, huh?
No...
I'm his cousin Akari.
Yeah... my cousin.
She's here visiting colleges.
Great! Do you have a boyfriend?
He's Kadoi. I'm Natsuko.
We're in Ryota's movie.
We're just across the hall.
Come if you want.
Natsuko...
I think...
Here.
Natsuko Ichise.
"The actress most likely
to hold a grudge"
That's her.
He should be in high school.
Which one though...?
Is there a famous director
called Ryota Mizorogi?
I don't know about movies.
His address?
I don't know.
Using a red towel as a scarf.
What's that?
A hit song, "Kanda River".
Let's walk from the bathhouse.
I want a bath.
There isn't one.
No bath?
Then let's go to the bathhouse.
No bathing for another 2 days.
You don't bathe everyday?
That's a waste.
Plus, it's winter.
The season matters?
Use the communal sink.
In the hallway?
Forget it.
Sleep under the kotatsu.
It's heated.
Sorry.
"Setagaya Junior High School"
We're clear.
Class 3C...
Here it is.
Kazuko Yoshiyama...
Here.
Your mom?
Yeah.
Where's Kazuo Fukamachi?
He's not here.
Let me see.
Nope.
But look.
They're both wearing 3C class badges.
Weird...
He's not a ghost, is he?
I have an idea.
Let's go ask my mom.
Here's her address.
Hello.
Is anyone there?
Uncle Goro?
Uncle?
So you're Kazuko's cousin.
Yeah...
You're the big brother.
Yes...
You don't look alike.
You surprised me when
you called me "uncle. "
Sorry.
Kazuko always talks about you
so I feel like I know you.
She talks about me?!
It seems like nobody's
home right now.
They moved to Yokohama.
When?.
When she entered high school.
You didn't know?
We haven't been in touch.
Oh yeah...
Do you know him?.
Never seen him but
he's wearing our uniform.
Oh...
What's Kazuko's school and address?
I have them at home.
I'll be off work tonight
so call me.
Asakura Liquor Shop.
Dial "D-R-I-N-K-U-P."
See ya.
"Drink up"?
We have some time.
Can I take you somewhere?
"Moving Picture Club"
What is it?
A flying car of the future
in year 2011.
Start.
The Planet of Light.
The earth began spinning off its axis,
losing its field of gravity.
Fundamental changes occurred
in the earth's crust.
The artist, Hiro, painted a cherry tree
with 100 buds on the wall.
When these buds blossom,
help will arrive.
They waited, believing it was so.
And...
"Bathhouse"
I go this way.
I'll transform myself
into a girl of the 70s.
Feels wonderful...
Paradise...
Right there.
Feels great.
Hey.
It felt so good.
You took too long.
I'm all warmed up.
I'm cold.
How do I look?
Beautimus, don't you think?
Beautimus?
What language is that?
Beautimus.
It's totally 70s!
Just like that song.
What?
You were staring at me.
No, I wasn't.
Let's go. It's cold.
It's too hard to pick her out.
But she's here for sure.
Let's find her.
Your mom?
Excuse me...
I'm looking for someone.
A guy named Kazuo Fukamachi.
Kazuo Fukamachi?
Your classmate in junior high.
That's me?
You know him, right?
No. I'm sorry.
I don't remember taking this photo either.
But... you're in it with him.
Same class badge...
I'm sorry.
I'll come back tomorrow.
Maybe you'll remember something.
Goodbye.
Your mom doesn't even
know him. We're stumped.
He really might be a ghost.
Absolutely not.
She made the liquid to
come see him herself.
You're right.
Can we go visit someone?
Gotetsu... It's Ryota.
Oh, you were here.
Hi.
Does everybody do this?
Your girlfriend?
No. My cousin Akari.
Hello.
Akari... "Light"... Nice name.
Light is essential to good shots.
Please get dressed.
This is Gotetsu, the cameraman.
Gotetsu?
His nickname for staying up
five straight nights gambling.
Hey there.
Well drawn.
Good, huh?
You okay?
Don't you get it?
My dick won't get hard
with a drawing like this.
Make it hard.
It'll get hard.
Gimme a hard-on.
Shit! My camera!
Get a rag.
Wipe it.
Ryota...
Do you remember anything?
I'm sorry I can't help you.
Is there something between
me and him in the photo?
Rather a lot...
So, why a school in Yokohama?
I want to go into pharmacy studies,
and this school has
a strong science course.