Try pineapple.
I'll have some of that...
that turkey jerky,
that smoked turkey?
It's excellent,
and it's quite tender.
Wake up, Tommy.
Lemme get a shot, Connie.
Last call was 15 minutes ago.
Oh, come on.
Get one for him too. Whatever he wants.
I'm tryin' to get outta here.
Connie!
Bill, you want one?
Nah.
Oh, that's pretty.
Thank you.
Hey, what's your name again?
Mike. Right. I'm Tommy.
Hey. Buddy?
Buddy? New guy.
Back door.
Front door's closed.
Whoa. I'll take it.
Okay, Bill, we're closin' now!
Everybody went home, Bill.
Bye-bye!
Everybody went home.
Ahh.
Get me a three-quarter-inch
wrench, would you, Raymond?
Jesus Christ!
Your brother's here again.
You want me to go talk to him?
No, get me a cup of coffee.
Just don't look at him.
What is wrong with him? I don't know.
Let's just go.
He's been standin' out there
every day for a week almost.
Good. Let him. He'll get tired of it
eventually. Well, I'm tired of it.
Rob. I'm just gonna talk
to him, okay? Relax.
What the fuck, Tommy, huh?
What the fuck?
What do you want?
I just wanna know how it feels.
How what feels? How does
it feel to be a chump?
I don't know. You tell me.
Ah-ha-ha-ha-ha.
You're bein' an asshole. At
least I know I'm an asshole.
- Question is, do you know it? -Yeah, I
know you're an asshole. Everybody does.
No, no. Do you know you're an asshole?
That's the question.
I'm an asshole? Right!
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Hey, you're an even
bigger asshole than me,
and if you don't think you are,
you're a bigger asshole than that.
You know what I'm talkin' about, man.
Hey, don't...
Let go of my finger, man!
Ah!  Rob!
Stop! Stop! I'll break it off.
I don't wanna hurt you.
Get in the car. Rob.
Rob. Take it easy!
Take it easy, man!
I'm warning you, man.
Jesus Christ!
Calm down.
Go, go, go, go, go!
Hey, Johnny!
Johnny!
Yo. Come here for a second, will ya?
Hurry up.
What's up? Sit in here and keep
your foot on the gas pedal.
I wanna run upstairs and change my T-shirt.
This stallin' out?
Take me two seconds. Yeah.
Take your foot off the gas.
Let me listen for one second.
It's gonna stall out.
I need to listen to the engine.
I won't be able to start it.
Just for one second.
Will you trust me?
Take your foot off.
Come on.
That's a serious problem
you got there. Yeah.
All right.
Good luck.
But you can't leave it there.
You're blockin' my driveway.
All right, all right.
What'd you tell me
when you came in here?
- I know what I said.
- You made me promise to cut you off after one drink.
Okay? One drink.
I already served you two.
I didn't make you promise.
Jackie, what'd he say
when he came in here?
He said he promised one drink
and then he's outta here.
You weren't even here
when I came in, Jackie.
You say the same thing
every time you come in.
What the fuck you listen to her for?
She don't know. She was here.
Hey, show some respect.
Bill, back me up on this.
Back yourself up.
Come on.
Just give me one.
You're a weak man. That's why I drink it
straight. The ice cubes are too heavy.
Thank you.
Hold it. Ho, ho, ho, ho.
I'll tell you what.
I'll give you five bucks
if you don't drink the drink.
I'll do it. Don't get weird
on me, Victor, please.
I'm not gettin' weird on you. I'll give
you five bucks. See, you can't do it.
- Give him the drink, for Christ's sake.
- Hey, butt out!
What the fuck am I gonna
do with five bucks?
All right. I'll give you $10.
Ten dollars?
Yeah, if you don't drink the
drink and you walk outta here.
I've never been
so insulted in my life!
Big money. Do it!
Look at this.
Ten bucks.
Unbelievable.
Out, now. Yeah. You're leavin'.
Out. I'm leaving?
Go. Go ahead.
I'm a weak man, Vic!
You little chickenshit!
See, I knew he couldn't do it.
Can I help you? Yeah, I
was in here last week.
I left my number. Just wonderin'
if you found a mechanic yet.
No, not yet. Hey,
'cause I'm available.
I know you're probably still
lookin' at other possibilities,
but, uh, I could start anytime.
I remember you.
Where's your car?
My car? Yeah, when you drove
away from here last week,
your car stalled out
down the block.
It took you 25 minutes
to get it started.
Well, it's a piece of shit, but, uh,
I got it runnin' pretty good now.
So how come you're on foot?
Just felt like walkin'.
That's... That's...
That's my number.
If I'm not there, you can leave
a message with this guy Vic.
Thanks a lot.
Do you think I'm using you?
Oh, Theresa, please.
Do you?
No. I said
I was sorry.
How many times
do I have to say it?
Whose baby do you
think I'm carrying?
Tommy's, okay? Is that
what you want me to say?
Is that what you think I think? How many
times do we have to go through this?
Well, if that's what you
think... It's not what I think.
Look, I said I'm sorry.
He's drivin' me crazy.
Well, don't let him. Ignore him.
I know, I know.
That's what I do.
Yeah. You don't
even look at him.
It's like you're tryin'
to punish him or somethin'.
What do you think,
I'm playing games?
No, I don't think
you're playin' games,
but... you did go out
with him for eight years.
So what?
What do you mean,
"So what?"
What do you mean, what do I mean?
It's over. It's been over.
Yeah, well, you don't
have to be so fuckin' cold.
What do you want me to say,
I'm still in love with him?
Are you?
No.
You idiot.
Besides, if I wanted to be
with him, I would be with him.
And even if the baby was his,
I would still want you.
What?
Even if it was his baby?
- Meaning it could be.
- No, I was just saying that.
"I would still want you."
"Want." Not "love," want.
What do you want with me? Oh,
you are such an asshole.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
Yeah? Yeah? Well... Hey, hey, hey.
I'm in there.
Do me a favor and
tell me your name again.
Come on. I told you
twice already.
I know, I know. But,
you see, I wanna say...
It's Christine. It's not Christine,
but it sounds like Christine.
What's this?
Look into my...
Crystal! Crystal. Yeah.
Oh, my God.
I'm losin' my mind.
Ah.
That's a nice name.
Yeah, you said that
the first time.
- I did?
- Rum and coke.
Yeah, you did. Well, I'll say it again.
It's a nice name.
It's different. That's why I can't
remember it, 'cause it's unusual.
Yeah, yeah, it is.
- Hi.
- Is your last name "Meth"?
No, it's not "Meth."
No, I'm kiddin'.
What are you doin'?
What am I doin'?
My name is common, but
yours, I swear to God,
Who's watchin' Anna? I'm
never gonna forget it.
- Oh, who's that?
- Because now,
now I got it
"embezzled" in my head.
Yeah. All right. All right?
Now I'll tell you another reason.
Why?
Because it's a pretty name, and
you're pretty like your name.
Thank you.
You're killin' me.
Oh, stop.
You're makin' me blush. Pretty
name for a pretty girl.
Gimme a kiss.
Forget it.
-  You gamble?
- No, I don't.
Okay, good. I'm gonna make you a bet.
Connie!
Let me get two big
glasses of beer...
and a little shot glass of
beer here for Cleo... Crystal!
Not this stupid trick
again, Tommy.
What trick? Who do ya think you're
trickin' here, huh? It's not a trick.
Be quiet, Connie.
It's a trick.
It's a bet, all right?
It's a gentlemen's bet.
I bet you that I can drink
two big glasses of beer...
before you could drink
one little shot glass of beer.
But if I win,
I get to take you home.
If you win, you go home with me.
What kind of deal is that?
That don't make sense to me.
It's a good deal.
It's a good deal for me.
I gotta see this.
Come on.
You have to let me
finish one beer first.
You have to wait till I put my glass
down before... Let me get this straight.
You're gonna drink one
full glass of beer. Right.
When you put the glass down, I'm
gonna drink this little, Yeah.
Eensy-weensy
glass of beer.
And you're gonna drink another glass of
beer, and whoever finishes first wins?
But remember, you can't touch my
glass, and I can't touch yours.
Come on. Let's just do it already.
Wait. Hold it.
Connie, let me get
two shots of Wild Turkey.
- Do you want me to leave?
- Gotta warm up here.
- I'm watching this.
-  One for you, one for me.
Salute.
Salutey-booty.
- Whoo!
- Okay, here we go.
- Wait a minute.
- What?
- You have to wait till I put
my glass down. - Well, come on.
Hey, wait a second. No!
You can't touch my glass.
Why not? That's not fair.
No, that's the deal.
- You can't touch my glass. I win.
- That's good.
- That's not fair!
I know.
Yeah.
I'm glad we could talk. What trick? I
explained the rules fair and square. I win.
-  No. You said it was a gentlemen's...
- I'm not a gentleman.
Hey!
Hey, what...
I win, and you lose.
Yeah, that means
you go home with me.
We'll see about that. Think
you got it like that, huh?
Do me a favor? Yeah? Anything.
I'll be right back, okay?
Okay.
Don't, don't sit with anybody
and don't talk to anybody.
No. And don't dance with
anybody else, okay?
I don't wanna lose you.
You won't.
All right?
Okay.
Mmm.
Want another drink?
I don't think so.
No.
You wanna sit down?
Uh, yeah. Okay.
Okay. Oh! Ooh! Okay.
Jesus Christ! You all right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Sorry.
I'm so embarrassed. It's okay.
It's okay.
They're not paying attention.
Ahh!
You all right? Okay. Okay.
Be right back.
I'll be okay.
Take me home after this?
Take you home?
Take me home.
Okay.
Okay. Hurry.
Oh, I'm hot. Hey, man,
you doin' blow in there?
What you fuckin' talkin' about?
You are, right?
Fuck you! I don't give a shit,
but don't let Connie catch you.
She'll 86 your ass right outta here.
Great. Yeah.
Oh, God.
I don't even know anybody
who does it anymore.
That's why I was surprised
when you... What?
Uh, you got good shit or what?
No, I...
I-I used to, but, uh...
Why, you want some? This shit sucks.
Does it?
I wouldn't mind just doin'
just a little blast,
'cause, uh, I got
somethin' goin' right here.
Aw, why not?
Sure hope nobody
comes in that door.
Hey. Freddie, how ya doin'?
Hey, man.
You done or what?
Yeah, yeah.
Freddie!
Yeah.
Later.
Crystal?
Wanna wake up?
Yoo-hoo. Hey.
Come on. You wanna wake up? No.
Hmm?
Sorry.
Crystal, come on.
Come on.
Up-p-p-p-p.
Hey, what are you doin'?
Just gettin' her up. Just put her
back down and let her sleep.
Hey, hey, what are you doin'?
I need her car keys.
She can't drive, all right? She came
with me. She doesn't have a car.
I'll take her home. No, you're
not gonna take her home.
I think maybe you should
go home by yourself now.
No, she wants
to go home with me.
What's with everybody over here?
He's goin' through her bag.
Just... Connie, just... It's okay.
You wanna have a drink?
No, I don't want a drink.
Leave her alone!
Let her sleep, please!
What is wrong with you?
She's tryin' to sleep.
Tommy. What?
Leave her alone. Just relax. Sit down.
All right. You relax.
All right.
Nosy.
All right. Now you stay here, Anna.
Don't move.
Anna! Anna!
Get over here right now.
Get over here.
No, no!
I don't wanna go!
Oh, God! Please don't
do this to me, honey!
No, no! I don't wanna go.
I don't wanna go.
Oh, man.
All right. All right.
Wait a minute. Quiet.
Absolute... Hey.
Silence!
What do I wanna hear?
Uncle Al's song!
All right. You ready?
Let's hear the Uncle Al song.
Uncle Al loves you too,
and he loves your mothers.
Tommy!
Yeah.
Tommy.
- What's up, Raymond?
- You sleepin'?
Yeah.
What do you want?
Been tryin' to call you.
Did you hear about Uncle Al?
No. What?
He had a heart attack
in his ice cream truck.
I'll be right down.
I'll be right in. Just
make sure you lock up.
Tommy.
Matthew. Oh, man, I can't
believe your father.
Yeah.
I mean, I know.
How ya been?
Me? I'm, ya know... I'm okay.
You remember Samantha? Hey,
Samantha, how ya doin'?
Hey. Good.
You look... You look great.
Oh. Thanks.
So do you.
You got new hair?
I mean, not new, but, uh...
Yeah, it's smaller.
Yeah.
Hi, Tommy. Hey, Sandy.
Oh, your father.
God, I'm so sorry.
Hey.
Who's this?
George.
George. Yeah.
Haven't seen you since the wedding.
Yeah.
The wedding. Yeah. He wasn't
at our wedding, George.
Oh, your wedding.
Yeah. No, I, uh...
I, uh, don't know what happened.
Sorry.
It's all right.
Tony.
Tommy's here.
I got two eyes, Josie.
Hey, Dad.
Doesn't he look good?
I think he looks good.
He looks better now, that's for sure.
Oh, please.
For Christ's sake,
your brother is dead.
Couldn't we have one day without an
argument? Just one day, I'm asking you!
All right. Get off my back.
I'm not on your back!
I'm just asking... Ma! Get
off my back, will ya?
Please.
I'm goin' in.
She give you any money?
No, and I didn't ask.
Well, don't ask me either.
I'm not.
I can't keep giving you
handouts forever.
Did I ask you for anything?
I came here to see Uncle Al.
I didn't come here to get anything
from you. Don't yell at me.
I'm not yellin' at ya.
What do you... Okay, okay.
Okay.
Thanks.
Keep the pack. I got
a carton in the car.
Hey.
For weeks I said
he didn't look good.
Nobody listens to me.
I just don't understand why he carried
on the way that he did if he knew.
If he knew that... You know how many people
tried to change your father, Sandy?
It couldn't be done.
I couldn't change him. You couldn't change
him. Your mother couldn't change him.
My mother couldn't change him.
Nobody could change him.
Sandy, you want more coffee?
No, thanks, Aunt Josie.
I couldn't change him. Your
brother couldn't change him.
I was, uh... I was sorry
to hear about you.
About me? Yeah. Uh, Matt
said that you lost your job?
Oh, that.
Yeah. Well...
Whatever.
Yeah.
Well, you know, good
mechanic's not easy to find.
Shouldn't be too hard for you to get
picked up by another place, right?
Yeah. I haven't really been lookin'.
Just takin' it slow.
Ya know.
Good.
So... You know, if you're just lookin'
for a job just for the summer,
you should take over Al's truck.
Really? Yeah, Sandy said he
made out really good on that.
Uh...
Drivin' an ice cream truck. I don't really
see myself drivin' an ice cream truck.
Hey, Sandy.
How ya doin'?
- You saw him recently, huh?
- Your father?
Yeah, there was a poker game at
his house last Saturday night.
You see? I never
played poker with him.
He would never ask me. No, no, no.
I was just passing by.
The light was on,
so I, ya know, went in.
We should go downstairs soon.
Yeah, you're right.
You know what he said to me?
He told me to stay after the game
and have one last drink with him.
That's what he said. One last drink.
Really?
Did he say anything about me?
Well, yeah. I mean,
we talked for a while.
I mean, uh... I'll bet it
was hard for him, Matt,
because, uh, ya know, I mean, he
felt like he was a failure to you.
He made me feel like a
failure, you know? It's...
Like not even a fail... Like nothin'.
Like I was nothin'.
No, but you know why? Because he felt
bad about the kind of father he was.
So he had to make you feel bad. And then
that probably made him feel even worse.
That's why he hated me.  Come on.
He didn't hate you.
He didn't say he
hated you, Matthew.
H-How could
he hate you?
I mean, who knows? M-Maybe
he thought you hated him.
You think so?
No. Hey, come on.
Don't listen to me.
I'm just... Hey, deep down,
he knew how you felt.
Ya know? Just like, uh, you
know how he felt about you.
But along the way, things
got fucked-up, ya know?
But so what? I mean,
everybody's fucked-up.
Ya know? But nobody wants
anybody else to think they are,
but everybody knows
they are anyway, so...
The thing I'm tryin'
to say, Matthew, is that, uh,
I think, in his own way,
your father really loved you.
It's... It's
that simple.
Uh, we should really get
back downstairs. Yeah.
Fuck. I just did
your line, man.
I'm sorry. No, hey, man.
You deserve it.
It's all right.
Hey, Bill, did... Did
you ever kill anybody?
What kind of an asshole
question is that?
I mean in, uh, Korea.
What career?
- No.
-  Hey, Tommy.
We're gonna get some food. You wanna come?
No, I'm all right.
Listen, uh, Rob said if you come to the
station again he's gonna call the cops.
Did I come by today?
No, but...
you're comin' by
like every other day.
So what? Anyway, what
are you, his messenger?
Look, I'm just tellin' ya.
Now you're tellin' me.
You're gonna call the cops now?
Forget it.
Remember somethin'. You wouldn't be
workin' there if it wasn't for me.
Am I supposed to quit
because you got fired?
No, but you could take my side for once.
You're my fuckin' brother.
It was your own fault
you got fired.
Oh, really? Who told
him about the money?
Hey, he asked me. What was I
gonna do, tell him I took it?
No, but you could keep
your mouth shut.
Why are you pissed at me? Every
time I talk to you lately...
Then don't talk to me, okay?
That's simple.
If my best friend
stole my girlfriend...
and fucked her and knocked her up and...
fired me,
I don't know what
I would do, man.
Look, I asked ya. Now I'm
not gonna ask ya again.
Just move, all right?
What are you asking me?
- I said would you just...
- Hey, hey, hey, Matthew. Sit down.
- Just move, all right?
- Raymond, sit him down, will ya?
You big pussy. Hey! I said move!
You guys!
Hey!
- Not on that clean floor!
- Christ!
Come on! Oh, get
f... Get off him!
- Matthew, come on!
-  Get off me!
Matthew, go!
Go! Come on, man!
Now calm down!
Calm down, all right?
What is that guy doin'?
Just calm down.
Get him outta here! I asked him
about five times all fuckin' night!
Everything's all right. You
want a drink on the house?
If I were you, I'd shoot him.
Who?
Your ex-boss.
What's his name?
Rob?
Rob's his name?
What?
Rob?
He steals your girlfriend
and that's his name?
So where's the fuckin'
after-hours clubs around here?
Not here, man. Forget about it.
Oh, fuck!
Really? I really don't
feel like goin' home.
Well, don't you have to, like,
work in the morning or anything?
Oh, man! What do you do, anyway?
What do you do?
You're a mechanic?
Yeah.
Yeah, I been lookin' around, but if anybody
calls Rob for a reference, I'm screwed.
Is the guy a scumbag or what?
Oh, he's pissed off at me.
He's pissed off at me.
'Cause the kid's yours or what?
Well, she's got him thinkin'
otherwise, but... Nah.
I mean, yeah, but there's this
other thing that happened...
right before he let me go.
What?
I borrowed money from him,
and, uh, I was
gonna put it back...
You were gonna put it back?
- Well, he didn't know I took it.
- Hold on, man.
You took money from the station?
Yeah. I mean, it was a
Friday night, and, uh,
I mean, he wasn't there, and so
I just borrowed this money.
I was gonna put it back.
How much?
Fifteen hundred.
Fifteen hundred bucks?
Yeah. But I went
to Atlantic City...
that weekend, and then, I don't
know, I just lost it all.
The first time that ever happened to me.
Where am I goin'?
Uh, three more lights
and you can make a right.
How 'bout here?
Where? Here?
Yeah, man, I'm not
too far from...
Mind if I take another beer?
See ya.
Fuckin' loser.
How you feelin' today? I'm
okay, but I'm a little tired.
Hmm. Do you want
my pancakes?
Mm-mmm.
I'm feeling fat.
Oh, I-I like you fat.
I don't have to go today.
I can stay with you.
Oh, yeah?
You pitching today?
Yeah. Why? Well, maybe if you
don't go, your team will win.
- Ah! Ha-ha-ha!
- You said I was fat!
No, no. You said you were fat.
I said I liked you fat.
- I said I was feeling fat. - Don't start
with me, okay? I'm not in the mood.
I'm not in the mood today. Everything
I say is wrong. I'm not starting.
God, Mr. Sensitive.
Is that a crime?
No.
What are you doin'?
I like you like that.
Yeah? You're so fat.
Stop. What do you got
in there, a Buick?
What is it?
Uh!
Rob. Come over here, will ya?
We're ready for the cake.
Bring that camera. Get a
shot of this beautiful face.
Really close.
What are you doin',
you moron? Not me!
Sandy. It's her birthday.
She's 22 years old today.
Twenty-five, Dad.
Twenty-five.
What do you mean 25?
I'm only 42 years old.
Right!
Right, and your name
is Pinocchio.
Oh, really? My name is what?
Pinocchio.
Your nose is growing.
Is it?
Uh-huh.
Can you see it growing?
I see it.
Look at it closely.
Uh-huh. I'm looking.
Then come over here and maybe you'll
get something else that grows, baby!
You are sick!
You're a bad boy!
Don't be gross!
It's my birthday.
It was him.
It wasn't me.
Here comes the birthday cake.
Here comes the birthday cake!
Can you guys liven this up a little?
I wanna sell it to channel "J".
Oh, yeah? You want me
to whip it out?
Don't, Tommy, don't!
Sure. Just let me get out
the microscopic lens here.
Ooh! Ah-ooh!
Them's fightin' words.
Put up your dukes.
Raymond, attend me.
Yes.
Kick him in the nuts.
I'm gonna kick your ass!
Prepare to die.
Yeow!
Hi-hi-hi!
Oh!
Ha-ha!
Hey-ah!
Oh, he killed me!
He killed me!
Oh, my baby!
Oh, God! He needs mouth-to-mouth.
Oh, yes, I do.
Good idea. Mmm!
Wait.
More, more, more!
Oh, geez!
I thought it was you!
I... Oh...
Darling! Oh!
She was saving my life.
You don't understand.
And who's gonna save you from me?
I... He is.
Help me, please. He hasn't told you yet.
We're together now.
I thought she was you!
- He didn't know it was her.
- You're in big trouble.
Here.
Don't get mad. Okay?
Vic. I knew you were comin'.
Pitcher of beer, man.
Hey, Billy.
Come home.
Why? I don't wanna
live there anymore.
Are we gonna talk about this?
There's nothing to talk about.
I get no support from you!
Oh, no. Just a roof over your
head, clothes on your back.
Food on the table.
Oh, God, I hate you!
What?
Victor. You got my 10 bucks?
'Cause if you don't,
take a walk.
I got your 10 bucks.
Victor!
Gimme a Wild Turkey.
Hey, Tommy.
What?
Sorry about Al.
Yeah, me too.
Hey, Vic.
Give Tommy a beer.
Do I have to? You
buyin' me a beer?
Yeah, I'm buyin' you a beer.
Wait, wait. H-Hold it.
Not, not, not that swill.
If he's buyin', I'll take
a bottled beer. Imported.
What are you,
Mr. International?
Payback.
Still hurts.
Should've bent it back further.
Thank you.
See ya later.
Hey! What the fuck?
Didn't you see me there?
Sorry, man.
Hey, Tommy. What's up? Fuckin'
gave me a heart attack!
You all right?
Yeah.
Hmm. Got a new fuckin'
problem, that guy.
No, put the car in neutral
and turn it off.
I put the car in neutral
and turned it off.
If you'd done that, James, it
wouldn't have jumped fuckin' forward.
Can we get two Budweisers?
You 21?
I'm 22.
You got I.D.?
He's 22. Can't serve
him without I.D.
He shouldn't even
be in here without I.D.
Okay, uh... He's with me, all right?
He won't drink.
What's the problem?
Throw 'em both out.
Mr. Hyde!
So this is where you hide.
No, he's Dr. Jekyll today.
Look at him. Grungy.
I like it. James,
you're pushin' it, man.
What, uh... I didn't even recognize you
sittin' there. You stop takin' baths?
That's funny, man. Funny. Damn!
You know, it's bad enough...
we gotta be workin' on a Sunday, and
then we run into our fuckin' boss, huh?
Yeah, you look like you're
workin' your ass off.
Look. Gimme a shot of bourbon
with that beer. It's on him.
All right. Him too.
He's... He's 22.
Thank you. What, you
own this place too?
Nah, he just lives here.
I thought you were on vacation.
You're livin' here now, huh?
You don't like your new house?
No, I like my house fine.
How 'bout Marie?
How she like it?
Well... See? See? I
fuckin' told ya.
What? I told ya you weren't
gonna like it out here.
Six months, you and Marie be at each
other's throats. Now it's been what?
Half of that?
I fuckin' told ya.
You never said nothin' to me.
I shouldn't have had to tell ya.
Marie's a city girl. So are you.
No, I hate the fuckin' city.
Oh, right. And this is
so much better, huh?
Got yourself a little
lawn you can piss on.
So what?
This Wonder Bread town.
Everybody looks alike, run around
like they all happy and shit...
when they're really
fuckin' miserable.
Just look around ya.
It's bullshit.
- Hey, let me get a quarter. - Ja They
ain't got y no no stupid shit.ll right?
Hey, not for nothin', man,
but my taillight is cracked.
Aw, shit.
What happened?
James hit him in the ass. James?
I'm teachin' him how to drive stick.
You need more drivers.
Fuckin' guys!
This cover it?
It's my truck.
It's your truck?
Yeah.
You own that truck?
He owns like five trucks.
You own five trucks?
Yeah.
I could use some work, man.
I'm available.
I got a mechanic I use
already, man. I'm sorry.
No, I mean as a mover.
I'm stronger than I look, man.
I can do it.
Uh... Oh... Well, I got
a full crew. I mean, I...
Come on, man. Ya don't gotta be a fuckin'
genius to move furniture, do ya?
You gotta have a brain.
Come on.
Just wait a minute.
Just wait one second.
Christ! Bill,
just take it easy.
Slow down.
Slow down, all right?
Bill?
Bill. You gonna sleep
with your clothes on again?
Connie.
Where ya goin'?
You wanna go get some breakfast?
Don't you ever stop?
No.
I'll see you tomorrow, Tommy.
You'll be all right.
Get some sleep.
Connie.
What am I gonna do?
Yeah!
One. Come on.
Let's go.
Hey.
What's he doin'? Come on.
What are you doin'?
We don't want any.
Come on!
We don't want any! Hey!
Get away from the truck!
Back up, man. You come on.
Come on.
Hey, you fuck!
Get away from the truck!
Where's Uncle Al?
He... He's not here anymore.
When's he comin' back?
He's not. He died.
Died?
Who are you?
I'm Tommy.
Uncle Tommy?
Nah.
Just Tommy.
You want somethin'?
Hey.
Oh. Hey, Deb.
I need some gum.
Help yourself.
I heard you were doin' this
now, but I couldn't believe it.
I haven't seen you in how long?
This is how you treat me?
I'm mad at you.
What for?
What happened between you
and my Aunt Theresa?
Why don't you ask her, not me?
She's smart.
'Cause she hooked up with Rob?
He's smart too.
He doesn't cheat on her.
- How old are you now?
- Fourteen.
- You're only 14?
- Seventeen, stupid!
-  When you gonna be 18?
-  Why, you gonna ask me out?
I might.
I'm a free man now.
- You're an old man now. - Yeah?
You wanna get out here?
Stop! Stop the truck. What?
Oh.
Hey, Lisa, what do you want? Can I
have a banana cream pie, please?
Banana cream pie?
Uh, we don't have...
Uh, you like fudge bars?
Just give her a fudge bar.
It's dead up there.
You should turn here.
Forget this block.
Make a left up there.
That's how Al used to do it.
Stop. Don't.
It gives me a headache.
Stop, please.
Hey, this is your street.
Yeah, you can drop me off.
You're not gonna go all the way with me?
No, I can't.
I have to eat. You
should take a break too.
Nobody's gonna be out
again till 7:00 anyway.
I was gonna go home. How
late did my uncle stay out?
9:30, 10:00.
That late?
Man, you need training.
Nice.
Very nice.
Get in the house
and help your mother.
Hey, Jerry. You tryin' to
corrupt my daughter or what?
I'm sorry. I thought
she was allowed.
Aw, fuck it. You hungry?
You want something to eat?
Yeah.
This is excellent, Patty. Yeah,
this is good grub, Patty.
You wanna grab us
a couple more beers, please?
Thanks.
Hey, Slappy.
You all right over there? It's
good to see you again, Tommy.
Just because you don't go out
with my sister no more...
doesn't mean you can't
stop by once in a while.
No, I know. I will. I mean it.
I missed ya.
I missed you too.
The only reason I went out with Theresa to
begin with was so I could be close to you.
Oh, stop it.
It's true.
You know, uh, I used to have
a big crush on you.
Please.
Sorry, Jer.
That's all right. You two
wanna go upstairs? Go ahead.
Jerry!
What?
It was a joke. He made
a joke, so I made a joke.
Yeah, but his joke was funny.
The only reason I married Patty was
so I could get close to Theresa.
- That's sick!
-  What?
Aunt Theresa was only 14 when
you and Mom got married. So?
She didn't look 14.
Jerry!
What, not funny?
No.
Tommy, you want some more roast beef?
Debbie doesn't eat meat.
No?
She's a veggie.
I am not.
What do you mean you're not? I
never said I was vegetarian.
I just don't eat meat
every night. It's gross.
What about chicken? You know
what they do to chickens?
They keep 'em cramped together in little
cages and they peck each other's eyes out.
Hey. What did I say about talkin'
about that shit at the table?
- She asked me. - I don't
care what they do to 'em.
I don't wanna hear about it
while I'm eatin'.
- Tommy, would you have some more?
- No, really, I'm fine.
We should go.
Hey. You're gonna get me
in trouble again.
Thanks a lot for helpin' me.
Sure.
It was fun. You need
some help tomorrow?
You want to? Yeah,
if you want me to.
Yeah, why not? All right.
See ya tomorrow.
It was fun.
Yep.
Bye.
Don't he look like you?
He doesn't look like me.
He's got a mustache.
He's got tights on.
You could have a mustache.
We could get you... I ain't wearin'
no tights. No, thank you.
Anyhow, this is all fixed.
Are you jealous?
Jealous of this guy...
with the tights
and the mustache?
He looks like one
of the village people.
Hey, Stan, where's your glasses?
Billy, Stan got new glasses.
Show him your glasses.
He don't like 'em.
Get ready, Bill.
- You look like an idiot!
- Go fuck, Billy!
What'd you say that for? He looks
like Kissinger with the glasses.
I ain't wearin' 'em no more.
Now look what you did.
I'm gonna squint.
Ha! He's gonna squint.
You think he wants anything? I
don't think he's comin' back out.
Had a dream about you last night.
Really?
Yeah.
You're a jerk.
- What did I do?
- Tell him what you want, honey.
Hi. All right, big guy.
What do you want?
Blue cotton candy.
He loves that stuff.
Hey.
How ya doin'?
Hi.
-  What do you say?
- Thank you.
Okay, thanks. Oh. I'm so sorry.
Hold on. Oh, 75 cents.
Here you go.
Keep the change. Okay.
You know her?
Not really.
Do you?
Yeah, she's weird.
- Why?
- I don't know.
What's her name again?
How should I know?
- You just said you knew her.
- What, do you like her?
What do you care?
Watch it, watch it.
Look out, look out.
Honey, these will stay here.
Why did I even bring
all this stuff?
Here.
My ice cream really made a mess.
Yeah. Can I get a bite?
You already had one.
All right.
Let me sit down.
Can I get a bite of yours?
Why didn't you just get one?
I don't want one.
I just want a bite. You always take
the whole sandwich, so don't eat it.
Don't let him eat it.
Hey, you pig!
Come on.
I wasn't gonna.
You were too.
I'm not...
Too big? You want me
to put it back?
That is really
disgusting! Ugh!
You don't want it now? Not after
you had your whole mouth on it.
Oh, yeah. Throw it away.
It's putrid, disgusting.
Great.
What are you doin'?
Let me have a cigarette. You
gonna smoke in front of her?
You miss Brownie? That's
why I brought him. Mm-hmm.
- Thank you.
- Ruff! Ruff!
I wanna move to the city,
or else upstate. No.
Where's she gonna go
to school in the city?
Huh? You gonna follow her
to class every day?
Sit with her so some idiot doesn't blow
her head off? We'll figure it out.
I don't wanna move, Mom. We're just
talkin' about it, sweetie, all right?
No, we're not. We're
not talkin' about it?
No. We're not movin'.
Upstate?
I could commute two, three fuckin'
hours every day to go to work? No way.
You don't go to work every day.
You go to a bar every day.
I'm on vacation. Huh! Great.
Some vacation.
You ever heard of Disneyland?
Are we going to Disneyland?
No, no, no.
We're not.
Fuck! You shut up! Hey!
You don't tell me to shut up.
I tell you to shut up.
Hey! Mike! What? Yeah, hey.
Let's go inside, babe.
Come on. Let me know
when you wanna talk.
Anna, gimme a kiss.
Hi, Mom.
You're back.
How was the movie?
It was all right.
Is he staying?
No.
Connie. Can I
get a beer?
What are you looking at?
Are you looking at my tan line?
Hey, Bill.
Did you eat?
Did you see the Chinese I left for you?
The noodles? Yeah?
You see my tan?
I got a tan.
I do look tan, right?
Don't I? Yeah, you look...
Yeah, you look great.
I don't look tan.
What?
What? I saw you today with
somebody in your ice cream truck.
That's Debbie.
It's Theresa's niece.
Ooh. Nice.
How old is she?
There's nothin' goin' on, Conn.
I just asked how old she is.
She's 17. Why?
I mean, I'm...
I don't... I don't...
I don't come here, I mean, much.
I didn't.
You know, but...
You look like you do.
Excuse me, hon. You're
gonna have to leave.
You have no I.D.
and you're not 21.
I am too. I told you,
my purse was stolen.
She's... She's telling you
the truth. I swear it.
You're gonna have to leave too.
Why? Why? I-I'm 21. I
showed you my proof.
You lied about your friend here.
- I'm not lying.
- We're waitin' for my boyfriend.
He'll tell you how old I am.
Who's your boyfriend?
Tommy Basilio.
Tommy!
Eww! Don't lick it
so much.
You too, huh?
What?
-  Think I'm disgusting?
-  I didn't say that.
-  Is this good pot?
-  - Oh, like you would know the difference.
I don't. That's why I'm asking.
Mm-hmm.
It is good.
I get too stoned if it's good.
Oh, it's okay.
It's just nice. You're not
gonna get wasted or anything.
It won't get you too high...  But
you gotta inhale it, though.
- Or messed up.
- Oh, really.
- Well, she doesn't inhale her cigarettes.
- Get outta here.
You don't. He's right.
You don't.
So what?
That was really beautiful.
"That was really
beautiful."
Wow. I wasn't
laughin' at ya.
You were.
I guess I was, huh?
No, with total
respect and wonder.
Ooh.
Oh, that was very...
deep, heavy shit, Mike.
I'm serious.
I know.
- Yeah?
- Fuck you.
What?
I'm serious.
Me too. Yeah? About what?
About what? Yeah. What
are you serious about?
Anything at all.  What
are you talkin' about?
Anything. Would you give me something
that you're serious about?
Oh, that's good.
Anything that you're serious about.
What's the matter with you?
Leave him alone!
Just shut up.
I'm askin' him. Don't
tell me to shut up!
You should shut up! Why don't you shut up?
No, I'm sorry.
Kelly, I am so sorry
that I said shut up.
Seriously?
- She's good.
-  I know.
So that deserves somethin'.
Voilà!
Ahhh!
You?
Uh, I don't want any.
More for us. Uh, nah,
that's all right.
- Amazing.
- Well, I'm gonna go look around.
Hold on.
Do it. I don't care.
I don't want any.
Sure.
Might as well.
Come on. Dance with me.
It'll be fun.
Come on.
No, I don't wanna dance.
Oh!
Ooh!
Sorry.
Shut up. Shut up!
Oh! What? Everybody's gotta go.
Everybody's gotta go.
Now, now, now!
Out! Out! Out! Hey, don't push.
Come on.
Stop pushing us! Go on!
Thanks... for comin'.
Good-bye.
Marie?
Hi.
Yeah, I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
So sorry.
I know, I know. Me...
Would you get outta here!
Get! I forgot my keys.
Yeah. I know,
I just... I...
Shit!
Will you get out!
Go... what...
No, nobody.
Noth-Nothing.
Where's Kelly?
She went to the park.
I thought you were supposed to
stay over her house tonight.
I'm really stoned.
You want me to take you home?
No, I'm too stoned.
Hey, Deb.
What?
Are you stoned? Eee-ooh-ooh.
Shut up.
Whatever it takes.
Yes.
Will you just come home?
Please?
It's hot. Careful.
Is it instant?
Yeah.
No, thanks.
Ay-yi!
How ya feelin'?
Pretty beat.
You wanna lay down?
I'll fall asleep.
So what? You're supposed to
be at Kelly's house anyway.
If you fall asleep, I'll take
you home in the morning.
You sure? Yeah. Why don't you take the bed?
I'll sleep on the couch.
Do I have to go now? No,
we can go to bed later.
I mean...
You know what I mean.
Nine, 10 bottles of gin
So, tell me about Mike.
Mike?
That guy's some kind of a wacko.
Why?
I don't know. There's
somethin' wrong with that guy.
If I had a wife and kid, I
wouldn't be doin' what he's doin'.
What does he do?
Hangs out at the bar all the time.
He does shitty drugs.
That's what you do.
Yeah, but I'm not him.
So you think if you and Theresa were married
and the kid was yours, you'd be different?
Wait.
Where'd that come from?
You said it. I said if
I had a wife and kid.
I didn't say with who.
Well, what I meant about Mike was
what does he do for a living?
I don't know. He like
owns some trucks.
He's got a moving company. He's
not really a friend of mine.
Do you have any friends?
What do you mean,
do I have any friends?
- Yeah. - You used to hang
out with my dad a lot, huh?
Well, he kinda had his own crew.
- Your father knew some real sickos.
- Like himself.
Hey, Jerry's all right.
Saved my life once.
What, he was gonna kill you,
but he changed his mind?
No.
One time...
One time this guy
had me by the throat.
This big guy.
Where?
At the Trees.
I think I spilled my drink
on him or somethin'.
So Jerry picks up one of
those big glass ashtrays?
And he whacks it down
on the guy's head.
He scares me sometimes.
So you used to get
in a lot of fights?
Me? No.
I mean, my friends did
all the time, but, uh...
I was pretty useless when it came to
fights. They kept me around for laughs.
Yeah, I remember
when you used to be funny.
You remember
when I used to be funny?
Yeah, you and Rob would do The Wizard of
Oz for me when I was little, remember?
Yeah.
The Munchkin Song?
Do it.
Get outta here.
Come on. Please? No way.
Just a little bit?
Do the Cowardly Lion. No, forget it.
That's it. No more.
Oh! You used to be good
at imitations.
Yeah, I coulda been somebody.
Instead of an ice cream man, which
is what I am. Let's face it.
Who's that?
What?
Was that Jerry Lewis?
Jerry Lewis?
You thought that was
That's it.
You're goin' home.
Come on.
Where's your shoes?
Hey! What,
you wanna wrestle?
No.
Come on. I'll show you how.
I know how.
I'll whup your ass, Basilio.
Oh, you think so?
Oh, yeah.
Let's see.
Hey, you can't hit!
Why not?
Ow! Jesus!
Ow! Hey!
Ow! God!
Ow! I don't wanna
wrestle anymore.
Okay, okay.
What do you wanna do?
I don't know.
You wanna watch TV? No.
You want me to take you home?
No.
Is this good here? I'd drive
you further, but, uh...
No, this is fine.
All right.
I should go.
Maybe I'll see ya later?
Yeah, I don't know.
What's the matter? I don't know.
I kinda feel weird.
Don't you?
Why?
I mean, we just... We just
had some fun, that's all.
Yeah.
It's all right.
See ya, Tommy.
Bye.
Hey.
Don't forget your bag.
Thanks.
Oh, Christ!
- You seen Debbie? - Hey,
Jerry, what are you doin'?
Lookin' for Debbie. What
are you doin' around here?
- You're lookin' for Debbie?
- That's what I just said, Tommy.
She slept over a friend's house
last night, but she snuck out.
Girl's mother calls
about an hour ago...
saying her daughter got busted in the
park, and Debbie wasn't with her.
- No? - No! And I'm
fuckin' pissed!
You at the Trees last night?
Uh, last night? No.
I mean, uh, no.
Why? I thought maybe
they were barhoppin'.
- The girl got caught with a
phony I.D. on her. - Huh.
Well, what are you doin'
out so early, Tommy?
Just, uh, goin' to restock the truck. I gotta
get there early before there's a line.
Yeah. Uh, okay, Tommy. Lemme...
Lemme let you go, all right?
All right, Jer. Well, uh, let me
know if she's all right, all right?
Oh, yeah.
Fuck!
She's home.
Where was she?
I don't know yet. Will you let
me handle this? That's bullshit.
She's gotta learn.
Jerry, I am warning you.
Hey. I'm goin' upstairs to talk to her.
That's all, all right?
I'm just askin' you a question.
Where were you?
Fuckin' leave me alone!
What did you say to me?
Hey!
You slam this door
on me? Huh?
You don't ever slam
the door in my house!
Hello.
Hi, it's me.
- Theresa?
- No, Debbie.
Oh.
What's up?
My Dad threw a shit fit this morning.
Fuckin' wailed on me.
- He what?
- He went nuts...
'cause I wouldn't tell him
where I was last night.
Tommy?
Yeah, I'm here.
- Can I come over?
- Uh...
Well, where's, uh...
Where's Jerry?
He went out. I don't wanna
be here when he gets back.
Well, I was just about
to take the truck out.
- Can I come with you?
- Oh.
I don't... I don't think
that's such a good idea.
Why not?
It... It...
It's just not.
What do you think we should do?
What do you mean?
With my dad. Can you talk to
him, tell him I was with you?
Ooh.
I don't know, Deb.
You don't think
we should tell him?
I, uh...
I... I... I...
I can't think straight
right now.
Deb?
What?
You okay? Did, uh...
How bad did he...
did he...
Okay, Billy, easy does it.
Take a little sip. Drink this.
That's enough. Put it down.
Pass?
Relax. You better? I'm fine.
Billy, listen.
You don't look so hot.
Go upstairs and lay down.
Here, wipe his nose.
Come on, Stan.
Here, Bill. All right.
You all right, Billy?
How ya doin', Vic?
You work last night?
No, Connie did.
She workin' tonight?
She's supposed
to be here at 4:00.
Gimme another one, will ya?
While you're at it, give Billy one.
We almost had him there for a minute.
Yeah, we almost did have him. That's why
I don't want to give him another one.
Fuckin' guy don't stop.
Hey, Deb.
Oh, hey, Tommy.
This is my friend Puck.
Puck, Tommy.
Tommy man.
How ya doin'?
What's goin' on?
Do you remember me? I'm Kevin
Kelly's little brother.
Eddie. What do
they call you now?
Puck.
You play guitar?
Yeah, she's good.
Let's go.
See ya.
You movin' out?
Yep.
Hey, Tommy man. Can we get a
couple ice creams for the road?
We don't have time, Eddie.
Let's just go.
Look, would you just
wait a minute, please?
Where you movin' to?
I'm movin' in with my cousin Vickie
in the city for a while. All right?
- I can give you a ride. - And
what, sell ice creams on the way?
Really, dude, it's cool.
I don't mind takin' her.
Where's your cousin live?
263 East 10th Street.
What?
Hey, Deb.
Are you all right?
Can we go? We're goin'.
We're goin'.
Hey, Tommy,
I'll see you later, bro.
- Who else was here last night?
- I told ya, nobody.
This guy, uh...
Tommy, from the bar.
- What were you guys doin'?
- Hangin' out.
Ya know, can't I
have people over?
I thought you said
it was just you and him.
Ya know, I really don't
wanna talk about this anymore.
Do we have to?
I'm really glad you're home.
I really am.
Really.
So can we just...
Can we just stop, please?
You want some ice cream?
Go to second! Third base!
Third base!
Here you go. Who gets the change?
Me.
All right, Mommy.
Anyway, I come back outside.
The other girl left.
Debbie didn't want to go home,
so she ends up at my place.
- At your place?
- Yeah, which is not cool.
Hey.
Can I help ya?
Oh, this is Marie, my wife.
Oh, hi.
I'm Tommy.
Tommy. You're the Tommy
who was over last night.
Uh, yeah.
We were just, uh... The bar got kinda
crowded, so we were hangin' out.
Oh.
Hope that's okay.
Oh, yeah. Sure. You
got a nice place.
Thanks.
Uh, how much?
Uh, five.
So I guess I'm supposed to ask if there
was anyone else over there with you.
Like girls, maybe?
Uh... No. No. It was
just me and Mike.
Huh. That was
a joke, Tommy.
Oh.
Let's go. Yeah, there was about
five or six girls there.
Oh, really?
Yeah. Naked girls.
Naked girls? Sounds like fun.
Sorry I missed it.
Yep, me too.
See ya, man.
Oh, shit.
She was with you last night,
wasn't she? Fuck!
Hey, Jerry.
Jerry, take it easy.
- Wasn't she?
- Nothin' happened.
- I... Jerry!
- Hey! Hey!
- She's 17 years old!
-  Keep goin'! Hit it!
Jerry!
You fuck!
Jerry, come on, man!
-  I fuckin' trusted you!
-  Get off the field!
- Get off the field!
-  What happened last night, Michael?
Would you give me a fuckin' break?
What? What?
I wish you'd just tell me
the truth for once!
Ahhh!
Hey, hey...
Hey, fuck you!
Hey! Hey!
Jerry, ome on, man.
I'll fuckin' kill you!
Jerry! Come on, man.
Cut it out!
I swear to God,
nothin' happened.
You're fuckin' dead!
Listen to me.
Get the fuck outta here! Nothin' happened!
I swear to God!
Ow, Jerry!
You're fuckin' dead, Tommy!
- Come on, man!
- Motherfuck...
- Jerry! Get him away from me, will ya?
- You're fuckin' dead!
- Shut the fuck up!
- Nothin' happened!
You're fuckin' dead!
Come on, man.
Kiss your fuckin' truck
good-bye, Tommy.
Hey, Jerry, come on, man.
Jerry!
Oh, man! You like that, Tommy?
Huh?
That's my truck!
Hey, Jerry!
Come on, man! I'm sorry, all right?
I should've told ya, okay?
But, please... You like that, Tommy?
Huh? Huh?
She's 17 years old!
I... I swe... Ah!
Fuck you, Tommy.
You didn't try anything
with Debbie, did ya?
Oh, Tommy. She's like 17.
I know.
I know, Raymond, but I...
I swear to God,
nothin' happened.
She... You know, she ended up
stayin' over and, I don't know...
We... Nothin' happened. We just ended up
makin' out like a couple of high school kids.
She is a high school kid.
I know. I was there.
Hey.
Hi. I heard
you were here.
Who told you?
Your mother?
What happened?
I... I'll tell ya
some other time.
How you doin'?
I'm all right.
You look good.
You just missed the baby.
No, I saw the baby.
You did?
Yeah.
Isn't he beautiful?
He's so little.
He's a little old man.
Can't they take
some of the wrinkles out?
Cut it out. You gave birth to Mr.
Magoo.
No, he's... he's...
he's amazing.
What are you gonna name him?
Um, we didn't decide yet.
Um... I know
when we were goin' out...
I was a jerk a lot, and, uh,
I treated you like...
Like shit?
Yeah.
Yeah?
Well.
I'm sorry.
I was really fucked-up
back then.
Oh, and you've really straightened
yourself out now, right?
I would if I had a kid.
I mean, if we had a kid.
Tommy.
I would.
I mean, things...
It was just so much better
when we were together.
You just told me
how fucked-up you were.
I know, but now I'm even worse.
I don't know what I'm doin'.
I just, uh...
I just feel like...
I don't know what I feel.
I don't...
I don't feel anything.
Except lost.
Look, I was stupid to think that
I was gonna change you, right?
No, I know. I gotta do that
myself and all that shit, but...
if I had a reason...
Look, I don't care
if the baby's not mine.
I don't.
Tommy, stop.
I'm really tired.
Well, you mind if I just
sit here for a while?
Um, Rob is gonna be back
any minute, so...
Okay.
I'm sorry.
Yeah, I know.
What?
You're drinking
the whole bottle, Vic.
This is my last one.
Then I'm gonna go.
Oh, geez!
Thought you were Bill.
What happened to you? Yuck!
Nothin' happened to me.
Just gimme a Wild
Turkey and a beer.
Don't talk to me
that way, Tommy!
I'm sorry. Can I just get my
drink and a beer, please?
You know, your friend Jerry
was in here this afternoon...
askin' if I saw you
and his daughter last night.
Hope I didn't say
the wrong thing.
Oh, like what? "I think Tommy's
boppin' your daughter, Jer"?
I only told him what I saw. He
must've drew his own conclusions.
Looks like he drew a conclusion
on your head.
"Conclusion on your head."
Yeah, real funny, Connie.
Hey. You're sittin'
in Billy's seat.
What is this?
So what?
No respect.
Where is he, anyway?
- He's in the hospital. - He's in
the hospital? Wh-Wh-What happened?
He just stopped
breathing. Yeah.
Poof. Just like that.
Stopped.
It's true. Wasn't like he
had an attack or nothin'.
He just fell off the stool
like all the air went outta him.
Well...
Shouldn't... Shouldn't somebody
be with him? Yeah, I'm gonna go.
I'm gonna go in a few minutes.
Come on.
You've been sayin' that for an hour.
By the time you get there,
he'll be dead already.
Hey, I'll go when I feel
like it, all right?
When I'm ready, then I'll go.
He's gonna be all right.
Oh, come on. Don't talk
like an idiot, Stan.
Don't call me an idiot, Jackie!
Well, then don't talk like one.
Listen. He's gonna be fine.
They just have to clean out
his system is all.
What the hell are you talkin'
about, cleanin' out his system?
Why don't you just
shut up, Jackie?
Gimme a quarter, Conn,
for the box.
You're not gonna play
that song again.
Just be quiet.