When you get home,
take a clock out for practice...
and have your mother help
teach you how time works.
It's really hard!
It's super easy!
Yeah... sure.
Is the answer 12 o'clock?
- Number one?
- 7 o'clock.
- Number two.
- Number two...
- School starts at what time?
- 8:30!
- She got all that?
- Yeah.
She's good.
Wow, it's a lot.
How do I take all this?
Watch it!
Why are you so late?
I had a hair appointment
at 3 o'clock!
Hurry up and take your sister home.
Sis!
All done.
No, don't touch!
Mom, I got 100% on my homework.
Nice.
Mom!
0h Bin, let me take my coat off.
Jin, take Bin over there.
Set the table.
Jin!
- Yes?
- Come and get this.
Were you late picking up Bin today?
Yes.
Do I always have to tell you?
- Don't be late again.
- Okay.
Here's a bean.
What are you doing?
Eat your dinner.
Here, drink some water.
Jin, get the door.
- Mrs. Lee, can we talk for a second?
- Yes.
Go back in.
Let's go outside and talk.
Mom, what'd you talk about?
Never mind. Finish your dinner.
Did you finish your homework?
Not yet.
Mom...
I...
I... wet the bed.
It's okay.
Blow your nose.
We'll keep it between us. It's fine.
Go sleep on my side.
Let's try it. What's the first answer?
- Nine!
- Easy.
- Okay, what's next?
- One!
- Next?
- Seven!
- Now, add nine, one and seven.
- Seventeen!
Actually, we haven't learned how to
add up to the teens yet.
- We'll learn this soon. Know when?
- Nope!
Next lesson. We'll start on Monday.
It'll be super fun!
- I wish it was Monday now, Teacher!
- Yes, me too.
That's messed up!
Why do I always get stuck?
Be careful kid.
Mom, what's going on?
Come inside and help me clean up.
What about my school?
I told your teacher so it's all set.
Aren't you excited to visit your aunt?
It'll be fun.
Big Aunt
Jin...
Listen...
Stay here with Bin... for a second.
I... have to go find your aunt.
Okay?
Bin, stick to your sister.
Don't move.
Sis...
Come see our delicious fish for sale!
Best price in town. 5 dollars a box!
Bin!
I've been looking all
over for you!
Jin! I told you to watch your sister.
Stick to your sister, got it?
Keep an eye on her.
You're here!
Oh, how are you sister-in-law?
It's been a while.
Yeah... so what happened to your face?
You remember Jin?
- Jin, greet your Big Aunt.
- Oh! You've grown so much.
Do you remember me?
Girls, bow to your aunt.
We meet for the first time, right?
Here, you can hold her.
Let me see.
You're a little twig, huh?
Anyhow...
Have you heard from that bastard?
0kay, let's go.
Jin, hold your sister's hand.
Take this bag.
Here you go. Eat up.
Eat.
Go ahead. What's wrong?
It's not as good as your city food.
No, it looks delicious.
They're good eaters.
But they ate some junk food
on the bus.
Hurry up and eat.
They'll eat anything...
so it won't be too hard for you.
It will be fine.
What choice is there?
Mom, what are you doing?
Jin...
I have to tell you something.
You two...
have to stay here with
Big Aunt for a little bit.
I'm... going to go find your dad.
No way! I'm going with you.
This is for you and Bin.
Whenever you obey your aunt...
she'll give each of you a coin.
Put the coins in here,
and when it gets full, I'll be back.
0kay?
Take care of Bin for me.
I believe in you Jin.
Please take care of them.
Take care of yourself and
don't worry about them.
Thank you so much.
Let's go in.
Mom!
Where are you going?
Sis!
Oh, there she is!
Mom! Mom!
Mom!
Sis... let's go inside.
Here it is!
Get it! Get it!
Sis, let's play.
Go away.
Don't mess around.
Let's eat.
Give me your bowls.
Eat up.
You were hungry.
You know how to eat!
Why aren't you eating?
0kay, don't eat.
Bin, you eat.
Go ahead and starve yourself.
Go to your room.
Bin, wait outside.
Go outside!
- What? Peeing in bed at your age!
- Didn't do it.
Quiet! Your blanket is all wet.
You keep annoying me and I'll send
you to your grandparents' farm.
- Don't want to.
- Put your shoes on.
Auntie...
- I didn't pee in bed.
- Be quiet!
Here, go beg for salt
from the neighbors.
Big Aunt...
Get going!
Sis...
Hurry up and go get some salt.
Auntie!
I'll go instead.
Come with me.
You got work to do.
You two are a real pain.
Bin! Bin!
Bin!
Yeah!
Hey!
What are you doing here?
Let's go.
No way!
Oh, who are you? Her sister?
Yes.
- Let's go in and have some snacks.
- Go inside.
Kids, come here. Have some cookies.
You too, come here.
Come on, dig in.
Hyun, here.
Don't be shy. Eat.
- What's your name?
- Jin.
- And you?
- Bin.
This is the first time
I've seen you around.
- We came to visit our aunt.
- Oh, really?
- And where's your mom?
- She went to take care of business.
0h, really?
Hyun, share your stickers with friends.
- Like this?
- Right.
Want to give it to your friend?
Here you go, Bin.
Can you give one to Jin?
- We have to go now.
- Going already?
Bin!
Wait.
Don't forget to wear this.
- Thank you very much.
- You are welcome.
Good-bye. Come over anytime.
- Okay!
- See you soon!
Let's go in.
Sis! I found a tree.
- But it's dead.
- No, it's not.
0h yeah? Let's try planting it.
Hold it up high.
Here?
- Now, get me some rocks.
- Rocks? Here is one.
Look around for more.
I found one.
Just this one.
0h! It's standing!
We did it. That was hard.
Sis...
Mom comes back when our
piggy is full, right?
Sure.
It was that tall boy in the alley?
He's right over there.
Stand here and be quiet.
Hello?
- Yes?
- Can you come out here?
What's the matter?
Your son threw a rock and
hit my kid on the face.
- My son? He'd never.
- He did! Her older sister saw it.
- He'd never do that.
- Ask him! Girls, he's the one right?
Wait one second.
Minoo!
- They were just playing, so what?
- Just playing?
He drew blood!
That's not just playing.
Give me money for her medicine.
- What medicine money?
- Here, look at her bloody face.
What's the fuss? It's just a scratch.
You want me to do that to your boy?
You should apologize.
Minoo!
Don't play with these kids!
- Is that enough? What a weirdo!
- Who are you calling weirdo?
Why don't you raise your son better?
You're the weird one!
Let's go.
Jin and Bin...
Stop and listen.
I have to go take care of something.
Jin, take Bin home first, okay?
What about Bin's medicine?
What? She's fine.
It's just a scratch.
Just clean her up.
Go on home.
You'll get your allowance
after you clean up.
- Deal?
- Deal.
Here Bin, wipe the floor with this.
Wait, let me see.
Who painted your nails?
- Mom.
- Your mom?
What a thing to do to a child.
Go clean that room.
Wipe it clean.
Big Aunt, have you heard from Mom?
Not yet.
Don't just eat the soup,
eat some fishcakes.
- I'm eating fishcakes!
- Okay.
You were hungry.
Not much...
0ne... Two... Three...
Auntie!
What?
She took my card!
What? She took your card?
Hand it over.
Why are you teasing your
sister with this?
Come with me.
Stand here and lift your arms up.
Didn't I tell you to play nice?
You little brat.
Are you trying to make your sister cry?
Put your hands down.
Go out and play.
I said go play. Stop crying.
What's there to cry about?
Sis.
It's all fine. Stop crying.
You can go.
Let's go.
You don't want to go either?
Fine, stay with your sister.
Sis!
Get lost!
Are they in pain?
Why would it hurt?
They are dead already.
Hey Sis!
That boy gave me this.
- What's this?
- Grasshoppers.
It's yummy!
That's gross.
Here!
Try it.
You eat!
- Give me one.
- Me too.
Get away, it's mine!
- Let's share it.
- Wait!
- How much?
- Six dollars.
Thanks.
Let's go.
Why aren't you asking?
You're supposed to do it first!
What's going on? What?
- We want... some cake.
- What? Cake?
Ask your mom later.
I'm not made of money. Let's go!
- Hello!
- Oh, hey.
You two sit down here.
- It's been a while.
- Yeah, I need a drink.
- How's your health?
- You kidding? I'm sick all over.
- How's your business?
- It's finished.
- What?
- I closed it.
Auntie, I'm hungry.
Wait until we get home.
- Are they your grandkids?
- No way! Do I look that old?
They're my nieces.
I'm taking care of them for a bit.
- Should I get them something?
- No way! Why waste my money?
They'll eat at home.
Auntie!
Auntie, I'm hungry.
- I'm hungry.
- Shut up.
Here's rice!
Let's go eat.
Grasshopper, grasshopper...
where are you?
Here! Here! I see one.
Look, hold it like this.
I'm making money.
- Did you do mine?
- No not yet. Be careful.
Ready.
- Ready to eat?
- Nope.
- Sis...
- Yuck.
- Can I eat one?
- No way.
- Hi, I'm selling grasshoppers.
- Yeah? How much?
- Ten cents.
- Give me one. Here.
- Give me two.
- I'm first.
Cool. Let's go.
Let's go.
No way! I'm putting them in.
Hey little piggy, stay still.
One, two, three!
Grasshopper, grasshopper,
gr-gr-gr-gr-grass-hopper!
It will pop out when we fill it up.
Told you to be careful with it.
Lady! Lady!
We'll be late.
Hi there!
- Hey, what's up?
- Can I play with Hyun?
Be quiet.
He's over there.
You want to ask him?
It's yours.
Got one? Put it in the jar.
Thanks.
They are having fun...
before they die.
Mom!
Grasshopper, grasshopper,
gr-gr-gr-gr-grass-hopper!
- Grasshopper....
- Hey kids, where did you go?
- We went to catch grasshoppers.
- Oh, I see. You caught a lot.
- Want to come in for some cookies?
- No thanks, we have to go.
- Then next time. See you.
- Good-bye.
Let's go play.
0h, darn.
- What?
- I killed it.
- Grasshopper killer.
- Bin, you flip it.
- Look, use this to poke them.
- Yeah! Very funny.
- Then kill 'em with this.
- No way.
- Try it.
- It's almost done.
- Stop it!
- Hot, hot, hot.
- It's not hot.
Stop goofing around.
Almost but not yet.
Wow, it stinks!
It's burning...
But they are burnt.
It's fine. Hold this.
Hey! Hey! Hurry, hold this.
You want some grasshoppers?
- Okay, give me one.
- Me too.
Me too, here.
29... 30... 31...
You can see it using one eye.
But I have to hold it really high.
- Okay, here then.
- Oh, where is the hole?
It's right here. Look through it.
- Wow!
- It's exciting right?
How'd you mess up your dress like this?
Can't you play like a princess?
I have to wash my hands...
roll up my sleeves first.
Hello!
- Hello!
- Yeah, what?
Hi, is Minoo home?
Minoo's at school.
- What do you want?
- We were going to play...
Shouldn't you be in school, too?
Don't you go to school?
We're here visiting our aunt.
Well... Minoo has to study hard.
So don't bother him.
Go play on your own.
- You understand?
- Yes.
- Goodbye.
- Bye.
- We can cross.
- Not yet.
Come on!
Lady! Lady!
Hello there.
What's the matter?
- Our aunt's not home.
- Your aunt?
I'm hun... no, I want cookies!
0h sure, come on in.
Bin, drink some milk.
Hyun, you too.
- Who bought you that dress?
- My mom.
It's very pretty.
Mom's coming when our piggy is full.
Piggy?
Anyway, where is your aunt?
I don't know.
Should I call the police and check?
- No, thank you. It's fine.
- You're okay?
Thank you for the food.
- You're going home?
- Yes.
Bin, let's go.
Sis, let's go. All the grasshoppers
have gone home.
Hello, I got grasshoppers.
You sold us the burnt ones.
No way!
Wait! I'll give you a discount.
What do you think?
Get it cheap.
Okay, give me all
your stuff for 10 cents.
What's the matter, Sis?
I finished drawing.
Ask him.
Mister... can I make a call?
- What? Who do you want to call?
- Our mom...
- What's the number?
- 011-242-0945
That number is disconnected.
Here.
Come on, let's eat.
What's all this? Stop crying.
Bin, doesn't it look good?
Make your sister stop crying.
Why can't you two get along?
Make her feel better.
Let's just eat.
What a way to ruin the day.
Wipe your face.
Here. That's enough.
Piggy, I'll fix your eye.
Got it.
All better now.
Piggy, when is Mom coming?
- Lady! I want to buy a sweetbun.
- Oh, you came alone?
Yes.
Come here.
Here you go.
Wait for your change.
I only have one cent coins.
Here you go.
Give me your hand.
- Wow!
- Oh...
- Be careful.
- Yes.
Hey, Sis!
Where did you get that?
I bought it.
Where did you get the money?
From piggy... a coin... sweetbun...
I bought a bun with a big coin
and got many small ones.
- What?
- Look at this.
I got a lot of coins from one.
Let me!
Get all the big coins.
Mister!
Hello, kids.
Can I have small coins?
- Change to one cent coins please!
- Oh...
Hurray!
Hurry up and put them in!
Wow, we got a lot!
Hurry, hurry.
Wow, it's full!
Bin, here comes a bus!
- Mom didn't come.
- She'll be on the next one.
Sis...
Mom didn't come.
Don't worry. She'll come tomorrow.
Let's go.
Big Aunt...
We want to eat.
Auntie!
Auntie, we're hungry!
Here, go and get something.
Tastes good?
Good.
Bus is coming!
Getting on?
Here, you have the rest.
Bin...
Don't be sad...
Mom will be here soon.
A few days ago,
I got a letter from your mom.
But I didn't know how to tell you...
I was waiting for the right time.
What did she write?
Here, I'll read you the letter.
Dear Sister-in-law,
I hope you are well.
Things with Kang have not gone well.
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
Even if I return now,
I'm not capable of supporting my girls.
I know they are a burden and I can't
ask you to look after them longer.
Only option left is my parents' farm....
Liar! You just want to get rid of us.
No, why would I want to do that?
I tried my best to take care of you.
I'm sorry things didn't work out.
But you had fun here, didn't you?
Sis, what about Mom?
Mom's not coming, stupid.
They are your responsibility now.
Their mom asked me to bring them here.
What are you talking about?
They're not my kids!
- What? They are your grandkids.
- That bastard brother of yours!
Don't bad-mouth my brother.
What about your daughter?
- Shut up!
- They're yours now. I can't raise them.
- Got it?
- Do whatever you want!
You do whatever. I'm done.
I did all I can. You should thank me...
Kids, what are you doing?
- We came with our aunt.
- Oh, really?
- Come with me. It's cold.
- Hello, nice to meet you.
Follow me.
Sit there.
Girls! Come over here.
It's nice and warm.
Get warm. Put your hands up like this.
We got a good fire!
You are just like your mom.
- I'm not at all.
- Is that so?
Mom's a big liar.
Is that what you think?
But... you shouldn't say such things.
Thanks for helping me.
Jin come here.
Don't you want to say good-bye?
Come closer.
Hurry up.
While you are here, be good.
Listen to your grandma and grandpa.
Jin, take care of Bin.
Bin, listen to your sister.
Don't fight, okay?
If you wait just a little bit longer...
your mom will come for you.
She'll come for you, understand?
Big Aunt!
Go inside. Go in!
Sis...
I miss Mom.
And I miss Dad.
I miss... Big Aunt, too.
I miss them all.
Hey kids, come over here. Come here.
Come on over.
Here you go. Eat this.
You too. Come to your grandma.
Take this and eat.
Come on!
Don't be afraid of your grandmother.
Want some? Put this in your mouth.
Here.
How do I do this?
Here, do the rest.
Sis, look!
- Finish it for me.
- Here.
Where's my lunch?
What are you doing?
What's the matter with your belly?
The kids aren't even complaining.
You two are making me laugh.
What are you staring at?
Are you learning something?
Getting nice and big!
- Can I touch it?
- Of course, go ahead.
- You think she'll cut it?
- Yeah...
- Dumplings!
- It's too thick...
- Looks like a dumpling.
- Not ready yet...
Bin!
Grandma's calling us.
Straighten this for me. Pull it.
You can do that side. Good.
Leave it like that.
Grandma, what is this stuff?
They are "chee-ja."
Spread them out.
Grandma, can you eat this?
You can, it's herbal medicine.
Very good for you.
Turn it off!
Good.
Grandma!
You got me water?
Good job girls.
Sis!
Peep-peep-peep....
You can't smile and you can't move.
Where are you going? Come back!
Catch me if you can.
Now you have to freeze!
You can't smile...
Hey!
... and you can't move,
when I say "freeze"!
"Per..."
Wait, let me erase this.
Try writing "The person."
When is Mom coming?
Just study.
"The person..."
Until the mountains in the Als...
- "Alps."
... mountains, at nigh change...
- "night"
... change their colors to red,
Heiti and Peter
- "Heidi"
Heidi and Peter.... Herd.... their sheep...
and play.
Let's take the wood home.
Help your sister.
Grandma!
Sit down, sit.
Get warmed up.
You want some sweet potatoes?
0h, hot! Hot.
Here. Peel the skin and eat.
Isn't it cold today?
It's hot, hot.
Real hot!
Eat up girls...
Me too...
These are all done nicely.
- Hot, hot.
- Real hot.
Now, I can peel it.
- Grandma...
- What?
- Can you buy us some winter shoes?
- Oh... okay.
Sure thing...
0h, a rock... better take it off.
Grandma, you got a hole in your shoe!
- What?
- You got a hole in your shoe.
0h, this lil' thing.
Grandma!
- Grandma!
- What?
- You can buy new shoes.
- Girls, come over here.
Here's our piggy bank...
What are you doing with your toy?
- No, it's...
- Put that down.
Please buy yourself
new shoes with this.
0h... really?
Let me see.
Wow! It's so heavy.
You got a lot in here.
Thank you very much.
You have to wash.
Come here girls.
- Are your hands cold?
- Nope.
Mom's coming for sure.
I promise. Seal it. Super seal.
- Grandma! Grandpa wants his lunch.
- Coming right up.
- Bin!
- Sis!
Let's catch grasshoppers and grill!
I want to walk up
the side of a mountain,
I want to walk down
the other side of the mountain,
I want to swim in a river,
lie in the sun,
I want to try to be nice....
to everyone.