What is that?
Ming Dynasty the person with Sim Chung Su Jik Je Hak all at find untie example.
Exactly untie example what is it?
You say laugh pear. With Deok Gim. Take this untie example.
Over there the something I already have seen it is nothing.
But.
Those people go dark blue cliff valley find untie example.
Then what exactly is it?
Laugh pear is. Untie example.
she's the Haerye.
From the beginning. Is people.
Laugh pear. Laugh pear very dangerous.
Can come how much child?
They can get side village the child
all bring over will be good.
Right.
Yes, that's right. But I a bit nervous.
Isn't this the first time.
Towards other people teach us the word.
Yes.
I'm also
the first time teach older brother write characters the time.
I'm also nervous before.
Right.
Always have been like that.
My here kind nervous is regular.
Of course. Regular.
Cover go this.
Ga. Gia. Ge. Gye. Pitiful the me body.
Have became lone body one person.
- Go. Gyo. Gu. Giu
- understand. Understand.
You what is it now?
Suddenly eat very good.
Stomach suddenly be really frightened.
I'll go to express sympathy for a moment.
All of you first go on.
Ga. Gia. Ge. Gye. Pitiful the me body.
Have became lone body one person.
Go. Gyo. Gu. Giu.
Who are you?
Who exactly are you?
Like this pry into or spy on other people the family.
Is looking for some from capital came lady.
Lady.
Those give maltose the lady.
You know her live where is it?
Unclear.
That on the contrary not very clear.
Ga. Gia. Ge. Gye. Pitiful the me body.
Have became lone body one person.
Go. Gyo. Gu. Giu.
Have worked hard the me the that one half.
Bon Won say.
Palace maid is not want print word.
But want spread word.
Want mobilize the everything the trick go stop then can.
Must go skim over Badaojiang (district in Baishan city mountain, Jilin) mountain.
No. Nyo. Nu. Niu. Play.
Play
take advantage of young more play.
What is it song?
This.
This song is have position lady teach us.
You also must learn.
With only give me both bowl rice will be enough.
That lady. Have said what?
Teach all of you these.
Call us everywhere sing this song?
Only need to have bowl rice will be enough.
All of you just for one a bit to eat then sing this song.
You're not learn then can forget it.
Then leaving.
Teach you all this is song the lady.
At where?
You want to learn then from we this side learn.
Follow that Tang Shan (prefecture level city in Hebei) tree lane go go up.
At most side the that house.
Thank you.
Teach word the paper already prepared properly.
Have prepared twenty piece around you.
Want or not want again more prepare some.
Again more bring some.
Exactly how what is going on?
Still not hurry tell.
What happened?
How come you like this?
Your Majesty.
This girl ruin big issue.
You kill my.
What exactly is this?
Solemn if seems like being arrested.
Laugh pear with Deok Gim. Also in danger.
What?
After that.
Ming Dynasty the one woman
give me bring another one furnace.
Let me hear that fragrance.
What else?
My mental become absent-minded
seems like.
All give say out.
Is bewilder fragrant.
Bewilder fragrant what is it?
Is Ming Dynasty the factory guard extort a confession the time using the
-=factory guard : Ming Dynasty emperor the intelligence mechanism=-
People once hear this fragrance.
Then lost soul.
Ask what answer what?
So.
You already have said what?
Untie. Example.
You. You say untie example.
They is currently looking for.
Untie example came here.
Seems like.
Speak out laugh pear place the place.
They certainly have gone laugh pear place the place.
Laugh pear very dangerous.
Oppa!
How come come to why late?
Gyeon Jeok Hui.
We late have came one step.
I came to the time. Then already like this.
Save him.
Save him!
Exactly how what is going on?
Asking you exactly how what is going on?
That.
Suddenly heard scream sound over one look.
Have little fellow
be taken away at there family live the two lady.
See face.
Yes. Face in vain.
Also don't have a bit beard.
Size. Is so high.
Yes. Correct. Very high came here.
Split second.
Already get they be taken away.
Is Yun Pyeong.
-Ga. Gia. Ge. Gye.
Pitiful the me body
- they already said today also give maltose.
Today not only give maltose.
- Will also teach us write characters the
- have became lone body one person.
Really?
Right.
Is Yun Pyeong.
Is him be taken away within people.
Sir have said is with you hand over before hand the secret warrior.
Your target also untie example.
Peace official why want to find untie example?
Is Lee careful footprint sir the order.
Anyway two of us most wanted is the same the things.
Furthermore, good like us also don't have complete objective.
Press presently circumstances see seems like not necessary must fight support.
Bon Won.
Just now received Yun Pyeong the notify.
Yun Pyeong have been traced my wife stay somewhere temporarily the place?
But Sim Chung Su since appearing there.
What?
Sim Chung Su let within people escape go out.
Even with Yun Pyeong fighting.
Sim Chung Su.
This Sim Chung Su surely is have other premeditated.
From Yun Pyeong there have saved within people this fact.
Already enough proof he have other plan isn't it.
So. Press Geun Ji have said.
Start the time is Yun Pyeong appear.
After that have appeared Sim Chung Su.
With Yun Pyeong caused a struggle.
But at there that moment masked woman appear.
Geun Ji have been caught.
Yes. Press Geun Ji, is.
That masked woman.
Is right advisor sir faction came.
That's true.
She said have heard.
With her men say Manchurian language.
She don't know I can understand Manchurian language.
Investigate Lee careful footprint want use untie example do what?
She said right advisor sir.
Order said to find untie example.
See they not at identical moment appear.
Jeong Gi Jun. Sim Chung Su. Right advisor sir.
Good like them don't have jointly operation.
That's true.
But.
Their eye is better like is the same.
They at find untie example.
Each operation.
Press Your Majesty have said like that.
They are is not all each have plan to.
But.
I the plan have appeared changes.
How did matter always? Like this not pleased.
Bon Won.
Cannot let go don't care.
Sim Chung Su if first take action.
We also have to do have prepared.
If.
Sim Chung Su compared to us first find understand example.
He take this that will to where inside go?
Who can know?
Will go Your Majesty there.
Still is will go to Bon Won here come.
Furthermore.
If to Bon Won here have came also.
He'll surely not just for in vain the take it out
then come here.
Sim Chung Su why so do?
I'll have to first know reason.
You go to check a moment.
The palace what happened matter?
Yes.
What is the meaning of that?
All of you exactly.
How exactly is have gone to where now, then appear?
Aigoo. Listen to me. Listen to me.
I and exceed noticeable currently escort my wife came here.
But that half face suddenly appear
get these my wife all give kidnap leaving.
That's why I say?
By send away to serve a penal sentence the within people
why let you come escort?
But.
Eventually arrested within people the
not that put on or wear mask.
But one Ming Dynasty woman come over
have them give been taken away.
Just like this.
You this again is some what are you saying?
But.
Midway and have someone appear
get these my wife and give have kidnapped.
After that they. Really.
In other words. Chae Yun now.
One person very dangerous.
Hey.
You this head die hog.
Said that how does he can understand?
Now immediately.
Towards prosperous cliff valley dispatch troops.
That's why I say why must towards prosperous cliff valley dispatch troops?
What I mean is...
Why you nonsense so much?
Already said before appear at there some soldiers with within people dangerous.
That's right.
In other words, is currently escort my wife the time.
Pill. Pill.
This damn it.
Children.
Yesterday at here.
Give all of you send maltose
teach all of you singing.
Those eonni never seen.
Today also is saying want to our maltose.
Call us at under the tree waiting for her.
But never come.
Who all haven't come?
That. Have uncle is came.
Uncle.
What does he look like?
Face in vain. Furthermore, height high.
Sound.
Like ghost the same is frightening.
Read this word the child.
Will have very big reward.
Who all? Not to recognize.
I don't know.
I'm not sure,
Already said today also give maltose.
But uncle who are you?
All of you sing the that song.
Later. Do not again sing.
That song is die the time sing the song.
Yun Pyeong.
Because have something urgent I'll have to immediately see observe make.
You this fellow
thought is what place then dare rush and came in?
Isn't this not like you such a fellow
anyhow able to enter the place?
Hurry retire.
Is Eo Myeong.
Hurry give me one mate horse.
After that mobilize everything military strength.
All must carefully the investigating this nearby.
Immediately.
Issue I will be responsible for
spread.
Just have to let laugh pear take charge.
This is a dangerous the matter.
You have to protect her.
And complete this matter that day
you just with laugh pear to go far.
If this girl. Do that matter the time.
Will is in dangerous or death also.
Your Majesty. And older brother.
All of you cannot let time.
Wasted on looking for me the body.
It can't be.
Pill cannot.
Laugh pear. You awake.
Is it okay?
You is doing what?
Geun Ji.
I.
Is by Yun Pyeong that fellow captured.
Geun Ji with me is be separated try to escape the
don't know now how is it?
We. Later what will happen?
Isn't it not even task have not complete.
Just like this die.
Geun Ji with double take charge of fall forward.
Not sure how is it?
Older brother.
Packing luggage have gone never seen.
Never seen.
Those fellow seems like from we
packing luggage start tracking.
Gang Chae Yun.
Even see all never seen before.
My wife solemn if respect.
Still have not make charm.
So I only take return some sample.
Furthermore.
Within people although give children taught song.
But character still have not teach give them.
That's true.
Want must prepare give children teach word the plan also.
All regain.
Spread considered to be block lived for.
Lee the spread plan. First of all failed.
What did you say? Yun Pyeong taken away.
I until attain the time.
Yun Pyeong that person.
Already have pill with within people
all made leaving.
And already all confirmed properly
that nearby the child.
Whether or not have learn to read.
They are confirm character whether or not have by spread.
Everything is this lowly person mistakes
I should one step have not should leave.
Furthermore, feel dangerous the time
should be directly.
Notify pill then yes.
Is mine responsibility.
Jeong Gi Jun can grasp hold of my spread plan.
I should earlier discovered this point.
My spread plan as failed end.
Eventually will be I hand issued people
is in dangerous condition.
Lee.
Really cultivate raised a
great the my wife.
Holding spread character the person.
Since is not Grand Prince is not princess.
Furthermore, also not scholar.
Since is all not sure the my wife.
Really hard to imagine.
But.
Although like that
but still is smoothly the escape have left the Palace.
So all of you should be.
Hugging very big hope
want at eight provinces of Joseon.
Spread character.
But now.
That hope already everything disappeared.
Character absolutely. Will not spread go out.
Untie example. Where is it?
Don't know he why must looking like this?
Condition extremely urgent
simply unable to forecast before one's eyes.
But he actually stick to to stop character
exactly what to do then yes?
Sim Chung Su already start bill have worked.
It seems is the palace happen some condition.
Aigoo.
Recently why not bring guest come?
Imperial examination ended then few days.
Now is off season. Off season.
Don't the time.
Imperial examination next day
still know wondering come over many people.
Is that a fact?
I am a bit then area then can.
But this girl what is it? Are you feeling unwell?
No just because Gae Pa I disappeared.
You have never seen before Gae Pa me.
Gae Pa I. I do not know.
Ignorant.
Turkic ethnic group people will have what good the?
Want.
To Koryo Seonggyungwan, university dating back to Korean Goryeo dynasty, in Gaesong, North Korea wondering some
idle about the show then forget about it?
Yes. Hurry go on.
Even more bring some come over.
Gae Pa I.
Where did you go?
Melt village the person noisy very serious
already said uncle you are bad egg.
Have you eaten?
Then is at here wait there.
I'll go bring rice come over.
Why will reach here come?
Originally should plan to.
With you discuss that day the matter.
That matter feeling.
Do you mean what is the matter lazy?
Don't have received report.
Tell me in detail.
Your Majesty.
Let Palace within the secret everything all oneself stand come out.
What?
Palace within talking about
heaven and earth reign name 713-741 of Tang emperor Xuanzong [Tang2 Xuan2 zong1], a peak of Tang prosperity the identity also everything openly announce.
Those member just for change Royal Court inside the control.
Already finding ways.
Although Your Majesty already declaration.
But I am still unable to approve of.
That character will surely.
Let people reject Chinese character.
Correct. Correct. Correct.
Yes. Yes. We fully understand.
Because from the beginning seen character the time
we are also contrary correct.
Lee school texture.
Learn everything Chinese character
waste have spent how long a period of time?
One day. Still is. Ten day later.
Chinese character common few word
you don't tell me, don't know.
How can one day ten day then everything learn?
Yes. Is impossible matters.
But...
Your Majesty a wound made the character.
Even if come across most foolish the person.
With only ten day. All able to learn.
Chinese character is unable to self-study and finish parts.
But.
Use me this type of character.
Able to read go out everything Chinese character and voice his meaning.
We are according to palace hall gave the order
is currently do that work.
Like this still is believe
this character.
Is reject Chinese character.
What is the meaning of that?
Now, even Chief Scholar.
You always feel have I am secret.
To me
are you or not secret nothing good concerned with?
We at Koryo Seonggyungwan, university dating back to Korean Goryeo dynasty, in Gaesong, North Korea the time.
And joined this Jiphyeonjeon the several tens of years.
That mutual affection don't tell me, will disappear.
We age the same
everyone always joke with you look old the time.
I can always. Is standing at your side.
Say I am boy color.
Not at all is because of you is old color.
Now mention about this matter
is want with I cover close to the meaning.
How can?
How did I?
No understand Choe Man texture.
But.
Such a long period of time come
aren't you also have seen.
His Majesty's meaning
always already don't have bias before.
You so oppose.
No is also because of
understand His Majesty's nature isn't it.
Yes.
So.
Then even more want oppose then can.
I say you.
Since have already declare.
So Your Majesty now.
Will finding ways issue character.
But. I am still.
Unable to consent character.
Even if is understand.
His Majesty's close intention also.
We just arrived Jiphyeonjeon the time
Your Majesty said if it's like this.
In order to enough let His Majesty
able to make clearly the choice.
Support until the end.
Want with Your Majesty together fight.
I will surely do that.
Will according to His Majesty's come do.
Your Majest must release character the day hurry must go to.
But.
Stand came out secret one also don't have.
His Majesty's heart is really unable to understand.
Min party give contrary party.
How can let those treason the criminals
with us jointly sit scheme together big issue?
Is His Majesty that kind nature.
Benefit at most the no really is.
Sir Jo with me.
If not because that kind of nature.
Regarding deal with Your Majesty wife's father the Sir Jo.
With always recommend let peaceful Grand Prince the me.
Former kings death of king or emperor later.
Still will keep we these people.
Actually such.
That kind of His Majesty's heart.
Secret also should understand then is.
Is really very smart good someone to be afraid off.
Lee.
Then yes, that's right.
That declaration what do you mean?
If secret with grandee a hundred percent listen to information Your Majesty.
Secret Ji Seo.
Become one piece waste paper.
That's true.
Royal court have how much secret?
But don't have one people.
Get this news tell you.
Everyone. All at waver.
Yes.
Look at in the past the Your Majesty.
Very possibly everyone will believe
that condition is turn out to be true.
Will appear cease to be faithful.
With Sim Chung Su cease to be faithful move to other place.
Will also mutually related isn't it.
Eventually.
Organization will collapse.
Must.
Must first organization Sim Chung Su the activity.
Secret among.
Understand this place the don't have a few people.
Although. Presently still safe.
But Sim Chung Su know here the position isn't it.
Unable to confirm Sim Chung Su how would operation?
We must strike first.
Bon Won.
Regarding must prevent character the Bon Won the wishes.
All of us understand of course must provide assistance.
But.
Before that
must first save secret isn't it.
Now.
Compared with stop character
protect secret even more important.
I am also having similar thoughts.
Bon Won.
Really want to get secret give up.
This girl.
Is ignorant the
one arrive at Yeo Ryu Ji contemporaries.
But I'm actually know regarding secret
which is is beneficial.
Bon Won is.
Seen character then have changed.
Cannot forget give Bon Won the task what is it?
Violent death ; to die in a disaster the Teacher Sam Bong
with Teacher Sam Bong theory.
Teacher Sam Bong son.
And. Jeong Do Gwang seonbae.
Now, is still.
Even a presentable death anniversary also don't have.
How are you now?
Joseon hard army inside. Have notify.
Not yet.
Your Majesty.
Extremely worried laugh pear.
Now.
Regarding seek palace maid issued all energy.
Relax. Will found.
Your Majesty. Let me see me.
No also should have said Your Majesty worrying laugh pear.
And want to say what?
I want have an audience. I must certainly.
Have an audience with the Emperor seeing His Majesty.
Even if this girl.
Do those matters
will is in dangerous will die.
Don't care Your Majesty also good?
Older brother also good.
All of you cannot let time.
Wasted on looking for me the body.
Anyone death die
also cannot stop.
We go forward the pace.
And.
Want lost precious the person.
Double take charge of fall forward.
Gang Chae Yun have an audience.
How can? Come looking for me.
I will surely seek laugh pear.
And at be shaken is that so?
Don't be like that.
Is my mistake.
Causing pill sink into dangerous.
I will surely find back come.
Presently still do not know should be at where how about that seek?
But is as such wait here stay.
I can't.
Forgive I myself Your Majesty.
So this lowly person. Now. Plan to go find pill.
So Your Majesty. Ask you to go. You own road.
Absolutely must not waver.
Want go forward Your Majesty.
If here have pill. Will also such have said.
Mother. Mother.
You came already.
You have gone out.
Yeon Du. Yeon Du where is it?
Yeon Du so you at.
What is that?
Is want with friend
eating together.
That's true.
But. You why?
Looking for us family Yeon Du.
That. Gae Pa I.
Gae Pa I have have no news.
Secret and so on have being drive.
He even dare come.
Have came is still not directly being caught.
Yes.
We are also
if you know they are such fierce the person.
Then will surely have them all arrest.
Gae Pa I is not fierce the person.
How can not be? Shut your mouth.
Yes, that's right.
Gae Pa I is not that kind of person.
But.
Uncle see one see Gae Pa me.
Perhaps Yeon Du.
Know Gae Pa I where is it?
Want catch him.
No, it's not no, it's not.
Uncle want with he say something.
Yeon Du also.
Know laugh pear palace maid.
Laugh pear palace maid. Being arrested.
So uncle must certainly rescue.
Must find she.
Uncle with her.
Is from small together and grown up good partner.
Uncle the family member.
And palace maid the family member.
All have gone. Heaven the world.
So now only left uncle with palace maid.
Uncle must find palace maid then can.
Yeon Du.
Uncle feel that.
Palace maid have gone Gae Pa I the place.
Yeon Du really don't know Gae Pa I at what place?
If know then hurry please say it.
Hurry have they all be brought into in prison.
Wine lady.
We Yeon Du want to say.
You want to say what?
Just recently want to say what?
Then. Yes.
Gae Pa I if come contact. Then tell you.
Fine.
Must certainly tell me.
Yes.
Karl fee.
From rear.
Yeon Du. Dangerous.
It's dangerous.
Pill.
Tonight.
Prepare a moment with Lee careful footprint the meet with.
Lee careful footprint.
By monitor the possibility very big.
Want absolutely correct keep confidential.
Also cannot let Lee careful footprint.
Notify outside.
Biggest limitation the be careful.
Prepare meet with then can.
Yes. Comply with your order.
Come just in time.
Those by Royal Investigation Bureau expel the within people how is it?
I also actually have heard this matter.
Able to say the also General Tae.
Heard what according to real say will do?
Royal Investigation Bureau process the exactly have what wrong?
I must know then can.
In other words those my wife.
Let double take charge of fall forward the exceed noticeable Pak Po escort.
But suddenly meet by chance have reached mask male the attack.
Mask male.
Is that called Yun Pyeong or for what fellow?
So. After that.
Is currently being arrested.
This time actually have appeared one Ming Dynasty the woman.
But soon after to appear again one man.
That's why must towards prosperous cliff valley dispatch troops?
And one man. Have said is who?
This.
Because exceed noticeable shouting and screaming the never hear clearly.
And one man.
Could it or not be Sim Chung Su.
Sir.
Your Majesty So Jeong the time.
Remaining very little.
But have occured this type of big issue.
Very will possibly Bon Won with Your Majesty.
Already know.
Sir.
You once said by Your Majesty discovered is only one choice which is to die.
By Bon Won discovered.
Also only one choice which is to die.
Sir.
What is it?
Gyeon Jeok Hui the men bring over this thing.
Understand you go out.
Yes.
She how say? Exactly how kind?
She said Bon Won.
Will possibly sense to our movement.
What?
This is my Lee careful footprint whole life the biggest crisis?
Live to seventy.
That righteousness and be regarded as have gotten what?
Young the time doing what join that secret
to old already taste the greatest extent (lit?
) bitter fruit.
Bon Won.
What have said? Everything is correct.
What?
Prime minister chairman system.
Is just to even more beautiful Joseon.
Let Teacher Sam Bong so proposed the strategy.
Compared with get country relying on give to a king.
Must as well depend on leave to majority wise the scholar officials.
Possibly regarding commoners will have even more benefit.
So secret.
Actually want with this point service.
Although is Teacher Sam Bong with Lee fragrant far the fight.
But with only Joseon exists in.
Also king with court official between Yeong Mu stop the issue.
Yes. Bon Won.
You consideration too right.
But still...
This character.
Is Lee with me between.
Regarding each confident read the fight.
I cannot to look on helplessly look at.
Lee he as history for the stage.
Play this dangerous very much the game.
One getting into politics the person.
Even result also don't even know.
Oneself also cannot be in charge of.
Unexpectedly just want want with commoners experiment.
One at most.
Can only rule fifty year king.
But Bon Won.
Don't worry. I know you worrying what?
I have already want good enough.
Only a little bit late only.
You this is. What intention?
What did you say?
Yun Pyeong kidnap the my wife don't have take untie example.
By bewilder fragrant fascinate the my wife say don't have untie example.
I did not.
That's true.
Originally already don't have untie example.
Thst's not possible.
That my wife say Yu Hae example the place is prosperous cliff valley.
Unbelievable.
Prosperous cliff valley is me ask her laugh pear location the answer.
So.
In other words, similarly the issue.
Answer different the answer.
But.
Absolutely cannot is a lie.
By bewilder fragrant fascinate the person.
Is impossible telling lies.
So. This how exactly is?
Don't have untie example.
Untie example Jae Chang cliff valley.
Prosperous cliff Gok Yu So pear.
Is laugh pear take this untie example.
No, no, no.
Isn't it said originally already don't have untie example.
Don't tell me.
Should I also have like she the same the ability
should have will be better.
What?
You have said what is it ability?
Seems like see seen before once.
Then all all able to remember the appearance.
All all able to remember the ability.
Don't tell me. Laugh pear is. Untie example.
Sir.
Lord Seong Sueng have came.
Seong Sueng how can come?
Invite him please come in.
Aren't you as compile.
Is with Chinese toon seat of government ten feet along before came
-=Chinese toon seat of government ten feet : with other people father the address=-
That isn't it.
Have important matter.
So temporarily
steal have used father the taboo name with a sedan chair.
What?
Embezzle taboo name with a sedan chair.
Ask you to follow me father the a sedan chair.
Your Majesty want see you.
Your Majesty.
Yes. Extremely secret.
Where exactly are you going?
With Yeon Du go together to living mountain.
Even if is have found lit.
Spider's thread and horse track also good.
Chae Yun.
If you like this have an urge
even you also something happened what to do?
Then you ask me how to do?
Call I'm at here blind wait.
I can't do that.
Also don't even know pill In Jae what place
suffer how is it the matter?
Exceed noticeable.
I almost urgent have died.
Clear be woken up.
Pill. You think kill her.
That's right.
You. With Pak Po together.
Continue at wine curtain or screen there crouch
take a look Yeon Du whether or not have come back.
I want to go find bit trail.
I want go inside then can.
Stench beg.
Bastard something.
Do you know this is what place?
So beggar.
Even if have what injustice also cannot report?
Have fellow let all of the younger brother
everything friend be killed.
You this fellow.
Have them all have been killed.
Good. Where is it exactly?
Is prosperous cliff valley.
Prosperous cliff valley.
I seen before that fellow.
Go quickly. Hurry.
Understand understand.
I will upward noodle report.
You just hurry. So let's go.
I'm going to die.
Is wronged have died.
What's this?
Don't know still ask.
Then because of all of you they all have died.
I won't let you off.
I will take revenge.
Listen properly have said detailed bit.
You have seen.
And also you so know the the everything.
Please.
Beg you to tell me.
Your Majesty.
Right Deputy Prime Minister Lee careful footprint sir arrive.
Aigoo. Right advisor sir.
Come. Please sit.
Comply with your order. Your Majesty.
Your Majesty.
You why at here very late at night
call this small official come here meet together?
Right advisor sir.
To my Chi Se what's your impression?
What?
You why next ask?
Such to take sth for granted the matter.
Really it could even be said is Jeon Mu people from ancient times later Mu Lai Ja.
This disc land never had living peace and prosperity.
This all is.
Your Majesty your Gyeong Eun
land under heaven all the people all very clearly.
This but not only is. I, own power.
Is with comply with my meaning.
To bend to a task and spare no effort ; striving to the utmost the
royal court chancellors the contribution.
Right advisor sir also. All this while.
Have suffered many hardship.
Your Majesty.
You can such empathize this small official.
Really Your grace is bountiful, Your Majesty.
You are secret.
Very sorry.
With lost already Geun Ji.
Fear is.
Gang Chae Yun be taken away.
I am secret the matter.
It is also possible exposed.
Then I.
Already get victory or defeat bet at today the matters.
welcome back.
I want to see Bon Won. All get one sound.
I'm asking whether or not you secret.
Your Majesty. What do you mean?
Your servant how can is?
Is my, when saying laugh. What are you afraid of?
Your Majesty. Your servant.
Really by you be really frightened.
Right advisor sir. In case.
I was saying in case.
Right advisor sir if is secret.
Achieve prime minister chairman system the Dae Ho opportunity
why will missed?
I'm only saying laugh.
Why such shock right advisor sir?
And what I've said also never wrong?
Secret the biggest target is
achieve prime minister chairman system.
They why will reject this matter?
I was saying if right advisor is.
Secret.
Your Majesty seems like.
Want with your servant play one outing play.
So.
Your servant just take it that
oneself is secret.
Come answer you.
Should be very interesting.
You explain about.
Just like Your Majesty have said the same.
We secret.
Is Mister Sam Bong the secret organization.
Eye is achieve prime minister chairman system.
But.
Why at able to achieve
like this important target before?
Why suddenly? Reject.
This is because.
His internal people thoughts no unify.
So.
Your servant not very satisfied this strategic decision.
Have what will compared to?
Prime minister chairman system
achieve more important.
I'm really not knowing what to do?
Secret internal. Appear difference.
Right advisor sir still have this kind the literary or artistic talent.
Is similiar to so matter.
Your Majesty can one's heart's content laugh heartily.
Your servant also. Extremely happy.
Right advisor sir. All say until here.
I again asking you one thing.
I, already with secret explain
let them to clear place come.
With I, discuss a dispute this matter.
But right advisor. Why no surrender?
Yes, that's right.
Is possibly trust the issue.
Exactly should should not.
Believe in Your Majesty.
Shu (11th earthly branch: 7-9 pm, 9th solar month, year of the Dog) 3-5am quiet society period.
Mister Sam Bong pass away later.
By divide as contrary party already.
Have several years.
Such a long period of time the memory.
One night between how can forget?
Your servant.
Is secret
want say this.
Still a bit uneasy.
I.
At place where the emperor listened to lectures Jang Ga is saying before?
Wide flat isn't it by secret so kill.
Admit secret the lawful status.
I even want to how say then will be let them believe in?
Yes.
Your Majesty indeed is do your best?
But.
You actually unable comfort people's feeling abyss the fear.
I, cannot comfort this kind of fear.
Cannot continue let them believe.
Oneself create how is it?
Oneself create.
Your Majesty. Your servant stupid.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Really headache.
Right advisor sir.
We wills say until here inside.
Right advisor what have said?
Seems like true.
I will mistake believe right advisor.
Is secret.
Is that a fact?
Come. Have a drink.
Put down knife.
Please come in.
You still have the face to come see me.
You this fellow. How can betrayed secret?
Betrayed secret is. Bon Won you.
What?
I loyalty the is not secret.
Is not authority. Not you.
Only prime minister chairman system the righteousness.
Now clearly.
So...
Tyrant if it is the worst the person.
Outstanding the monarch can only be regarded as second bad the person.
Any Myeong Gun also cannot replace system.
Rule class do not need one Myeong Gun.
And need prime minister chairman system this kind of system.
Scholar officials need authority.
System the perfect.
Just for properly take care of commoners.
Don't want taboo against using the personal names of emperors or one's elders.
Not you let I have become secret.
I'm at after that day.
I'll get life. Life. Family the fate.
All be handed over to you.
You is mine Master Zhu (another name for Zhu Xi )
Is mine Confucius.
But.
This kind of you why must do like this?
This cover word extremely scary.
You still not clearly.
You also unclear. This matter.
This later.
At here later how are you going to do it?
You think do your best come stop word the disseminate isn't it?
At here later.
Prime minister chairman system.
Commoners want what course to follow?
What do you want?
I know untie example at where?
Now Bon Won except for this cover word will not want any problem.
You get this untie example come stop word the disseminate.
Also...
Really. Chat very happily.
I'm also because have right advisor sir at extremely interesting.
But. Night already close.
Your Majesty also should. Rest.
Good. Is should like this.
Right advisor sir. First get up.
Good. Your Majesty.
Get Jeong Gi Jun hand over.
If it's like this.
Then don't need to worry about me don't believe you.
Furthermore.
As secret branch the leader.
You can in the palace court.
Develop prime minister chairman system.
You take this untie example go stop word the disseminate.
I. At here later.
Guide secret.
Continue go Mister Sam Bong the road.
-=Next Episode Preview=-
Go investigate Jik Je Hak.
Sim Chung Su at what place?
I am. Joseon the scholar. This is mine road.
What exactly is happening?
Hurry hide.
Bon Won. Bon Won.
Laugh pear.
Every sky already want to live very trusted Bok.
Particularly with Gang Chae Yun together.