[ Woman Moaning ]
[ Moaning Continues ]
[ Woman On TV,
Indistinct ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Panting ]
[ Grunts ] That
was pretty good, right?
Yeah.
You know, I get this really
stupid employee discount
at that restaurant.
If we walked over there,
they'd pretty much give me
an entrée for free.
But that's not
really my style,
you know?
Or we could head back
to my place.
My shift doesn't start until
4:00 tomorrow. We could rent
a movie or something.
Like I said,
I get paid by the mile.
[ Sighs ]
Sounds like that's
a pretty dangerous job.
A lot more dangerous things
if you made a list.
You got a list?
No. [ Laughs ]
No, I don't have a list.
You sure you're not hungry?
Do you wanna
watch TV?
Got to make it to Reno
in the morning.
Oh, yeah. Of course.
Hey, um, listen.
I really appreciate
the motel room.
It's not really my style
to let the female pay.
And I-I don't want you to think
that I just used you
or-or anything.
- I don't.
- Oh, okay.
That's good.
Um, you want my e-mail?
Take it easy.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Engine Revving ]
[ Beeping ]
[ Boy Laughing ]
[ Door Squeaking ]
[ Keys Dropped On Counter ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Breathing Heavily ]
[ Phone Rings ]
[ Answering Machine Beeps ]
Diane, it's Jenny Bell again--
Len's fiancée.
Will you please call me back?
I really need to talk
to you today.
Diane, call me.
[ Beeps ]
[ Knocking ]
[ Sighs ]
Saw your rig.
Ladies night.
Well, I guess
you'll be getting
some discounted drinks then.
Just got paid.
You're going with me.
[ Grunts ]
I can't, Runner.
I just got back.
You know it's a dream
of every man in California...
have an opportunity
to get drunk with you.
I'm not sure that's
a compliment, Runner.
Well, it ain't an insult.
Come on.
[ Sighs ]
It's that
country-western crap?
Seventies night.
Seventies night
at the V.F.W.?
[ Gasps ]
Let me get
my lipstick.
¶ [ Disco ]
[ Man Laughing ]
[ Glass Hits Table ]
You just gonna
sit there all night?
You gonna let me
sit here all night?
¶ [ Funky Soul ]
[ Female Back-up Singers ]
¶ We found the spark ¶
[ Female Singer ]
¶ Oh, baby, you're glowing ¶
¶ Started a fire ¶
¶ Oh, baby, you're burning ¶
¶ Looks like we made
a soul connection ¶
¶ We found a soul connection ¶
¶ To find out ¶
¶ Find out ¶
¶ That what we have
is real ¶
¶ Have is real ¶
¶ We had to find out ¶
¶ Find out ¶
¶ That what we have
is real ¶
¶ To find out ¶
¶ Find out ¶
¶ That what we have
is real ¶
¶ [ Ends ]
This is fucking great.
That's-That's
a pretty drink.
[ Laughs ]
I'm going to the bathroom.
[ Chuckles ]
¶ [ Country Western ]
[ Door Opens ]
Hey there.
Do-- [ Chuckles ]
Do you know me?
No, I don't you.
Maybe I could though
if I tried real hard.
Yeah. Um--
[ Chuckles ]
Well, I'm Rick.
I'm Runner's
brother-in-law.
[ Mumbling ]
Oh. Rick.
Yeah, he's mentioned you.
Oh, good.
Hey. Excuse me.
Hey.
Excuse me.
Yeah, he's married.
Yeah, but we're not
fucking each other.
So excuse me.
I'd like to avoid
a bladder infection.
Oh, well, did you ever
hear of that term,
"playing with fire"?
Yeah. I think you're
doing it right now.
No. You are.
Move it, shithead.
Don't be
a home wrecker now.
A good one.
Hey, Rick,
how's it going?
Well, not as good as you.
Go home, Rick.
You're a lucky guy, Runner.
You're a real fucking
lucky guy.
¶ [ Radio: Christian Rock ]
What the fuck do you
have this thing set for?
What?
That's Christian rock.
You caught me listening
to Christian rock?
Yeah.
It's soft rock.
Have you ever
heard of F.M.?
- There's a difference.
- Oh, my God.
What is this? This is reggae.
- ¶ [ Reggae ]
- Just don't go poking
and banging at it like that.
Basic radio,
for Christ's sake.
Don't punch it.
[ Laughing ]
Keep hitting the bottle.
[ Chuckling ]
¶ [ Reggae Continues ]
What?
[ Tires Squeal ]
Jesus!
[ Groans ]
¶ [ Continues ]
Okay.
Oh, my wife's
gonna kill me.
She's gonna have
to stand in line.
Ow! Ow.
Slide over.
Ow.
God.
Where you going?
I'm suffering here.
Goddamn.
You're really a bleeder.
Kind of like what
you're doing though.
Shut up. [ Laughing ]
Oh, wait, wait.
Here. Here.
¶ [ Continues ]
Hold it down.
Are those--
Shove 'em up in there.
I'm not putting tampons
in my nose.
Yeah, that or bleed to that.
No, I'm not gonna--
I'm not gonna do it.
Oh, yeah.
[ Chuckling ]
[ Muttering ]
Oh!
[ Both Laughing ]
Ah, I wanna live.
[ Chuckling ]
Oh, God.
You're lucky
I didn't bring the ones
with the applicator in it.
[ Laughs ]
Shit.
Just sit back now.
You're gonna be fine.
Oh, I swear to God.
[ Engine Starts ]
[ Tires Squeal ]
[ Brakes Squeak ]
[ Engine Off ]
[ Grunts ]
Oh, Jesus Christ.
- [ Door Closes ]
- [ Groans ]
Ooh, you really
did it this time.
[ Grunts ]
This is the last time
we're going out.
[ Groans ]
Tonight was
a wake-up call.
You lead
a lonely life.
Ow!
Shut up, Runner.
You did that on purpose.
Yeah, you think?
Ow!
[ Groans ]
God, you're
a heavy sack of shit.
Why don't you settle down?
Why don't you--
Why don't you find Jesus?
What do you know
about Jesus?
[ Runner ]
Nothing.
Then why do you suggest
that I find him?
I don't know.
I heard he makes
people happy.
- Shut up.
- Oh! [ Laughs ]
[ Laughing ]
Oh, you are dead weight.
Okay.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Chuckles, Groans ]
Shh. You're gonna
get me in trouble.
Shh. Shh. Shh.
[ Exhales ]
[ Both Laughing ]
[ Panting ]
- Diane?
- Yeah.
[ Panting Continues ]
You're so pretty.
Thank you, I think.
Oh, idiot.
[ Chuckles ]
Yeah. Nice, sis.
I told you, Molly.
Shut up, Rick.
Hey.
[ Engine Running ]
[ Engine Stops ]
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
[ Keys Jingling ]
[ Footsteps Approaching ]
- Diane! Hey!
- [ Grunts ]
What the hell
are you doing?
Who the hell are you?
You know who I am.
I'm Jenny Bell.
I've been calling you
and writing you.
Well, Jenny Bell,
I don't check my messages
all that often.
Diane, listen,
Len's got an infection.
All right?
And he's in the hospital
for a few days.
And I have to leave
tomorrow night to go
to my mother's funeral.
So you can see I have
somewhat of a dilemma.
Well, Len and I
have an agreement.
Yeah, well, it was Len's idea.
Don't you have
some neighbors or
some friends or something?
I guess not.
All right, Diane, listen,
you don't owe me anything,
all right?
But I can't work
and take care of Len...
and go to my dead mother's
send-off and watch your
fucking kid right now.
Yeah, well, I'm
on the road all the time.
It's three weeks.
Three weeks?
Yeah.
Peter, come on
over here.
No. Mm-mmm.
Peter, come over here.
No, Jenny.
No.
Peter, come on.
Jenny.
Fuck you.
Peter, come on.
Listen, we talked
about this.
Peter.
Peter, listen to me.
[ Grunts ]
Listen to me, all right?
It's just for a little while
until your dad's feeling better.
All right? Listen.
He loves you, and he needs you
to do this for him.
Can you do this for him?
All right?
Say "okay."
Come on.
Thanks a lot, Diane.
I'm gonna call you
in a few days, all right?
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
[ Engine Starts ]
You're gonna
stand there all night?
Go on.
So you can crash
right there, all right?
I'm gonna get this whole
mix-up resolved tomorrow.
All right? I'm gonna
go see Leonard in L.A.
Runner will watch you.
He's my friend.
He'll probably be
pretty hungover though.
Yeah.
[ Foot Tapping ]
So I just got
the one-bedroom house.
Just a one-bedroom.
[ Exhales ]
Don't like to talk, huh?
I don't like
to talk to bitches.
Fair enough.
Ooh.
You ever had
a breakfast
burrito before?
Not bad
for a dollar, twenty-nine.
Come here nearly
every day before work.
What do you do?
You ever heard of
a jack-of-all-trades?
Well, that's me.
Actually,
I'm more of a--
more of a six
of diamonds-of-all-trades.
You see those guys
right over there?
I work with them
sometimes.
[ Speaking Spanish ]
Aren't they illegal immigrants?
Well, I guess
it depends on who you ask.
Yeah. Sure.
It's good. Take a big bite.
It's full of eggs.
You're gonna like it.
So your dad's got
the big "C," huh?
Sorry to hear about that.
Yeah, well,
it's just in his colon.
No big deal.
He'll get better.
Yeah. Sure he will.
You'll go back
to your old school
and your pals,
and your mom
can get back
to her regular life.
I hate my school,
and I don't have any pals.
You got to have
a best friend.
Me and my dad
are best friends.
Well, I guess you're
the sort of guy...
who's choosy about
who he's buddies with.
I can relate to that.
I'm a bit of a-- a bit
of a lone wolf myself.
You're gonna use
your hot sauce?
[ Woman On P.A.,
Indistinct ]
Excuse me. I'm looking
for Leonard Bonner's room,
please.
It's Room 608,
and it's right
down the hall.
Thanks.
You got it?
Got it.
You got the I.V.,
sweetie?
I got it, baby.
[ Len Groaning ]
Damn it.
All right, we'll
clean that up later.
[ Sighs ]
- [ Grunts ]
- [ Jenny ]
Does it hurt?
No. I'm all right.
Just a little sore.
Okay.
[ Monitor Beeping ]
Hey, baby.
Yeah?
Can you get me
some water?
[ Door Opens ]
Three weeks.
Don't you have a home?
Me or him?
[ Fingers Snapping ]
- Where you going?
- Oklahoma City.
Get up.
You're going with me.
Where's
Oklahoma City?
Take a guess.
I'm not going.
I can take care of myself.
Dude, I'm trying to pay
my bills here, all right?
I don't have time
to play nice right now.
Well, then, why don't you
ask me and not just tell me?
All right, listen,
do you wanna go?
I don't know.
Do you want me to go?
Why don't you tell me
if you wanna go?
You tell me first.
Why don't you tell me first?
'Cause I was the one
who asked first.
So?
So that's
how it works.
Dude, man,
I got to get on the road.
This is too much for me.
If you ask me
and act like you
want me to go,
then I'll go.
All right, man,
do you wanna go?
Do you wanna go with me?
Do you wanna go
to Oklahoma City with me?
Please.
I'll think about it.
[ Exhales ]
¶ [ Country Western ]
¶ Everybody calls me the girl
in the little pink Mack ¶
¶ The bumpers are chrome
and so are the wheels
and the stack ¶
¶ It's got polka dot curtains
hanging in a sleeper of pink ¶
¶ Ha-ha, this Mack's a dandy ¶
¶ Some kind of truck
they think ¶
¶ In my truck-drivin' boots
I stand about 5 foot 3 ¶
¶ But don't let
the size fool you
Man, I can take care of me ¶
¶ When you see a flash of pink
go flyin' by ¶
¶ The next thing you know
there's a taillight
in your eye ¶
¶ Everybody wonders who'd drive
such a rig like that ¶
¶ All the truckers would ask
"Who's the gal in the little
pink Mack" ¶
- [ Radio Off ]
- Big country, huh?
Stay in the truck.
What's up?
Just about everything,
darlin'.
Hey, you see
a little kid around?
Hey, you see a little shit
of an 11-year-old boy
roaming around here?
Hey! You seen
an 11-year-old kid
running around here?
He might be
over there.
[ Panting ]
Shit.
Hey!
Oh, shit.
Goddamn it.
You little goddamn shit.
What the hell
are you doing out here?
I was just looking around.
Do you understand
what this fucking place is?
It's people coming
in and out of here
from God knows where.
They'd like nothing better than
to get their grimy little hands
on your pretty little face.
You're crazy.
Damn it. I told you
to stay in that truck.
Listen, I'm sorry
I smacked you, all right?
But I don't wanna
be reading about you in
the newspaper tomorrow morning.
Okay?
Let's go.
I don't feel like it yet.
Listen to me.
I wanna make
the New Mexico line
by nightfall, all right?
I want my on-time bonus.
So? My ass hurts now,
and I just feel
like sitting.
You got two minutes.
You give Len
this much trouble?
I don't make trouble.
People make trouble for me.
[ Scoffs ]
Ever get into fights?
Kids picking on me,
calling me names.
I don't care.
You ever win?
Well, I just freeze up.
Whatever.
I'll go back there soon,
and you won't have
to worry about anything.
I'm not worried
about anything.
It seems weird
for a woman
to be driving a truck.
Yeah, well,
what should I be doing?
I don't know.
Something else.
Yeah, well,
I like being my own boss.
I own that truck.
I paid it off this year.
It's a hell of a lot better
than being a nurse
or a waitress or something.
Wiping tables
or wiping asses.
Just seems
pretty lonely
and boring.
Yeah.
Not everyone's cut out
like everyone else.
Come on.
New Mexico's calling.
Wait up.
Why are you
walking so fast?
[ Mocking ]
"I wanna get
my on-time bonus."
Give it a rest, kid.
[ Sets Brake ]
Why are we stopping?
Get some sleep.
- Where?
- Back there in the bunk.
Where else?
Okay, I am not sleeping
back there. No way.
I wanna stay at a hotel.
Oh, damn it.
There are only a couple
of reasons to get a hotel room
when you're out on the road,
and this ain't one of 'em.
Get your ass back there.
[ Sighs ]
[ Blows Lips ]
Shouldn't you brush
your teeth or something?
I don't have
a toothbrush.
Yeah? Well, what have
you been using then?
- My finger.
- Yeah? How's that?
[ Scoffs ]
That's disgusting.
You're gonna catch
something like that.
Well, give me some money,
and I'll go across
the street.
I saw a store.
[ Bag Unzips ]
[ Objects Hit Counter ]
[ Sighs ]
Hey! That's my shit.
That's personal.
Not anymore.
Hey, dude! Dude!
Listen to me.
You can't go out there
by yourself, dude.
It's dark out there.
[ Boy Speaking,
Indistinct ]
Hey, faggot.
Go buy me something.
[ Door Bell Rings ]
Do you think
he'll buy you something?
Hey, homo,
what did you get us?
Nothing, dickhead.
What'd you just say?
[ Grunts ]
Shit, man, what
did you do that for?
I wasn't-- I was trying--
Hey, come back here!
Dude, I wasn't
trying to do that.
[ Grunts ]
Hey! Hey!
Who did that? Who?
Some boys across the street.
[ Door Opens, Closes ]
[ Horn Honking ]
[ Speaking,
Indistinct ]
Hey!
Wha--
You fucking better watch
who you fuck with!
All right? You got it!
[ Door Bell Rings ]
Fuck was that?
Whoa.
And a pack of generics.
[ Panting ]
[ Panting Continues ]
I'll get dressed.
Ow.
[ Monitor Beeps ]
[ Grunts ]
I know
it hurts, son.
You could hold
his hand.
Sorry.
Here you go.
You drink coffee?
Yeah. Why not?
Thanks.
I like a lot of cream.
Can we stop
and see some stuff
along the way?
We already lost
half a day.
Right.
That's a good stick
you got there.
Thanks.
Oh, no, you didn't.
Get back here. Hey!
Hey, Diane!
[ Laughs ]
Just hang tight,
all right?
Hey.
Okay, we're
all set, honey.
Great.
I just can't give you
your on-time pay.
Jonnie, I always
deliver early.
I know.
My boss just won't let me--
Jon, that's
a bunch of bullshit.
Is that your kid, hon?
Yeah, it's my kid.
But I'm gonna be rid of him
in less than a month.
All right?
He lives with his dad.
Does he go to school?
No, he don't go to school.
Yeah, Di,
but federal law and all.
Jon, I need new tires.
Look, it's been
a little light here.
I'll-I'll call you
when we get
something in.
Right.
All right, let's go.
And I'll be rid of you
in a month too. Bitch.
I didn't mean that.
[ Door Opens ]
You didn't say one word
since Texas.
You think it's easy being stuck
in a cab with an 11-year-old
who doesn't say anything?
Well, it ain't easy, all right?
It'll drive a person crazy.
Dude, and that's what
you're doing right now, man.
Living with you
will drive me crazy.
[ Objects Clattering ]
Listen, you have no idea
what my life was like
before you got here.
And you walked through this
door and expect everybody
to roll right over for you.
Well, I didn't ask
for your dad to get cancer,
and I didn't ask
for you to show up either.
Well, then why
did you have me then?
- I didn't wanna have you,
goddamn it.
- [ Objects Hits Window ]
[ Object Hits Counter ]
I didn't mean that.
I wanna see my dad,
and I'm gonna
tell him everything.
Everything!
Hey.
Hey! Hey!
I got a name, bitch!
You stop calling me that.
I am not a bitch.
Look, I knew what you were--
just a lot lizard tramping
around in dirty truck stops.
That's not
was I was, dude.
You little shit.
That's not what I was.
Goddamn you.
[ Quietly ]
That's not what I was.
[ Water Starts Running ]
[ Water Stops ]
Dad!
[ Len ]
Oh!
[ Speaking, Indistinct ]
I missed you.
Wow. I missed you.
How you been?
All right?
Dad, I'm gonna
get some ice cream.
Hey, get some
whip cream on mine.
Okay. I'll get some too.
[ Sighs ]
You know,
after you took off,
I-I planned on
how it was gonna be
when I saw you again.
[ Laughs ]
Well, 10 years later,
this ain't it.
You look fine.
You dating anybody?
Dating?
Yeah?
You ever think
about marrying again?
To who?
Not me, I guess.
I'm not very good
future husband material
these days.
Yeah, well, you'll be
making Jenny miserable
soon enough.
So did he turn out at all
like you thought he would?
He looks like you,
doesn't he?
He did when he came out,
so I figured he'd stay that way.
What the hell are you
trying to pull, Leonard?
Listen, Di, I--
[ Chuckles ]
I had no choice.
All right? I--
I couldn't find anybody
to take him.
Well, when is Jenny coming back?
She's staying with her dad
a little bit longer.
I can't keep asking her
to watch after him
all the time anyway.
I mean,
she's got to work too.
I need your help.
I'm-- I'm talking
about a month maybe.
I'm on the road
two weeks at a time,
sometimes more, Len.
[ Exhales ]
I'll pay you.
Fuck you.
Goddamn it.
You always knew just
what to say to make me
wanna break your neck.
We made this arrangement
10 years ago.
Yeah, we did.
I know.
Ten years ago,
and that's that.
So shut the hell up,
'cause you're gonna
be just fine.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
[ Sighs ]
They're all
white trash out here.
Yeah, but they're
California white trash,
and they all got suntans.
Listen, I got
to make that run, but
I won't be back too late.
I'm trusting you now,
right?
[ Bell Ringing ]
Runner will
check in on you.
I'll be fine.
[ Exhales ]
[ Engine Starts ]
Hey.
Oh, hey, Runner.
What are you doing?
I thought I'd finally build
that gate for your mom...
so she can lock up her stuff
when she's doing long trips.
Wanna help me?
Oh, I'm not great
at stuff like that.
Ah, everybody's good
at stuff like this.
It's easy.
And it makes you feel good
even if you do it half assed.
[ Sighs ]
Here. Hang on to this.
[ Groans ]
I'm good.
Trust me.
You're gonna love this.
It's lots of fun.
I don't wanna
mess it up. Here.
Making mistakes
is the only way you learn.
And trust me.
I learn like four
or five things every day.
All right.
Grab a bunch,
slap it on the edge,
just like you're
putting icing on a cake.
Your mom is gonna
be real surprised
when she gets back from Phoenix.
She's been doing a lot
of short hauls lately,
hasn't she?
I guess.
Perfect.
All right.
Grab one of these.
[ Grunts ]
Try to set it down nice.
A little more that way.
Like that?
Uh-- Good.
You know...
when I was a kid,
my folks got divorced.
I tell ya,
the best day of my life
was when my dad left.
Now he had
the meanest left hook.
Never could see it coming.
Think that's why I did
so good in the army.
Diane said you got shot.
Yeah. And it hurt
like a son of a bitch.
Still does sometimes.
So what are you,
in grade six now?
Yeah.
You into that new school?
Well, there's
this kid I like.
I might try out for baseball
even though I suck.
Yeah?
Baseball's good, sure.
Oh, yeah, your dad
used to play, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, your mom told me.
She used to go watch him.
Your mom's pretty good
with a glove. Should ask her.
Probably give you
a few pointers.
Yeah, maybe.
[ Diane's Voice ]
All right, man, you just
gotta lean into it, okay?
Really, really lean into it.
[ Peter ]
All right.
Whoa!
What was that?
Oh, my God. I thought it
was gonna get me.
You just gotta keep
your eye on it.
All right, I'll be easy
on you this time.
[ Sighs ]
Whoa! Are you
trying to kill me?
I didn't say walk into it.
Let's do it again.
I'm afraid of you.
What's there to be
afraid of? Come on.
Just don't get crazy
with that thing.
Ohh! Ohh!
I didn't mean that.
Goddamn it!
Dude! Dude!
Dude, that is not cool.
I got to go.
Yeah.
But listen.
You have to take a swing at that
thing if you wanna get anywhere.
I just wanna hit it.
That's all I wanna do.
You can hit a home run.
No, I can't.
I know what I can do
and what I can't.
Why, because
somebody tells you so?
No, because I know so.
And you think you're so tough.
Trying to tell everyone
what to think.
But you're the one who's
always scared of stuff.
You're the scaredest
person I know.
[ Horse Whinnies,
Nickers ]
[ Sighs ]
Hey.
[ Diane ] Nice gate
you got going here.
Well, it's a start.
You know, I was thinking
maybe you and me and Peter,
we could all do something
together, you know?
Go dirt biking or something.
I don't think that's
such a good idea.
Yeah. Pretty dangerous.
Yeah.
What's he doing right now?
Watching TV.
Seems to be taking to it
out here a little bit.
Yeah, well, he'll be back
in L.A. soon enough.
Yeah.
You know, I lived
in this house six years?
Yep.
- I'm gonna own it someday.
- That's right.
- You agree too much.
- Am I agreeing?
Mm-hmm.
Well, sure,
I'm agreeable.
Stop looking at me, man.
You want something
from the store?
Nah.
I'll get on that gate.
I'll finish it soon.
[ Dog Barking In Distance ]
[ TV Playing, Indistinct ]
Come on. Get up now.
Turn off the TV.
Why?
- [ TV Turned Off ]
- Go brush your teeth.
- What are you doing?
- I'm trying to be nice here.
[ Sighs ]
Okay.
[ Spits ]
This is my blanket.
Here.
It's your dad's.
It's pretty raggedy, but, uh,
you can have it to sleep with.
I don't sleep
with stuffed animals.
It's a clown actually.
But I-- I gotcha.
Okay.
Good night, then.
- Diane?
- Yeah?
Dad said that when he was
on the road with his team...
he stopped off in Needles,
California, and saw you
at a truck stop.
Yeah, well, flat broke.
[ Chuckles ]
You know how that can be.
He said you were the most
beautiful girl he ever saw.
He said that, huh?
I was 18.
All 18-year-olds
are beautiful.
He said you didn't
leave because of me.
But I know you did.
It wasn't you particularly
that made me leave.
It's just that your dad's
a man, and a man's man
to a fault.
And a man like that expects
a woman to do a whole bunch of
things I wasn't prepared to do.
Like what?
Like staying
around the house...
and being like a--
like a woman
everybody's used to.
What's wrong with
staying around the house?
Some people like
staying around the house
and some people don't.
Doesn't make you
a bad person, right?
Does Jenny stay
around the house?
No.
- See?
- But she wants to.
Me and your dad were
staying in this bungalow
we rented in Hollywood.
It was a pretty nice place,
you know?
I'm getting
kinda tired, kid.
Okay.
I don't know.
You know, I've been
thinking about it and...
being in that house holding you
or feeding you a bottle
or something,
and it was like
I was half there.
You know?
It was like I had this body,
but it wasn't mine,
and I just moved it
around or something.
And then one day
you were both asleep
and I just...
took the money I was saving
and I just left.
Did you love me?
It's getting pretty late.
I got an early start
in the morning.
You comfortable?
Yeah.
Good.
Well, good night.
Good night.
[ Sighs ]
[ Chattering ]
When are you moving
back with your dad?
I don't know.
Probably about
a couple of months maybe.
Do you like
staying at your mom's?
Not really.
But she's not around
that much.
What does she do?
Well, she drives a big rig,
which is a truck,
and she goes all over,
um, the states, you know.
And, uh, right now,
she's actually going
on a trip to San Diego.
She is?
Yeah.
What are you doing
after school?
All right, do you know
what a whippet is?
[ Hissing ]
Okay, okay, okay.
First time, keep it easy.
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughing Continues ]
What the hell
are you doing?
Oh, shit.
You, who the hell
are you? Out!
Get the hell out. Out.
Ah, fuck this.
But this is my house too.
The hell it is. Jesus.
- You're bullshit.
- You're bullshit, all right?
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
You see what
happened to me?
[ Spraying ]
Oh, shit!
Oh, you little fucker!
You get--
[ Peter ] Oh, fuck!
Ohh!
Yes, you better run!
Oh, shit! Run! Run!
You little bastard.
Well, at least
he's got a friend.
Yeah, I don't know.
He wanted to stay over there
tonight, but I didn't think
it was such a good idea.
Well, don't let it bother you.
Kids do shit like that
all the time.
Hell, I did it.
Look how I turned out.
Inspire me, why don't you?
Shit. What do you know
about raising kids?
You're barren or sterile
or shooting blanks
or whatever.
You know, sometimes I think
you'd just best be served
by just...
closing your mouth
every once in a while,
just walk away once in a while.
You gotta wife
to talk to like that.
I'm ain't your wife.
Yeah, but you and me
are friends.
I won't let my other pals
talk to me like that.
Don't think it's
a little strange you and me
going out all the time?
It's not all the time.
We're neighbors,
for Christ's sake.
It's important for people to
have other interests, you know?
Friends and such.
I'm your only friend,
Runner.
I got friends, Diane.
I got pals I served with.
Well, the guys
on line down at the V.A.
don't count, dude.
Oh, wow, you really--
[ Chuckles ]
That don't make me
feel too good.
Just keep on drinking that
creamy drink there, Runner.
Well, it happens to be
in a to-go cup,
and I'm to-goin'.
Come on. Runner!
Hey!
What are you littering for?
Give a hoot, man.
You just can't--
You don't see it.
See what?
Forget it.
Where are you going?
You know, I don't care if you
just see me as some jerk who
follows you around like a dog.
What do I care?
But damn it, I'm crazy
about you, Diane.
Well, I'm crazy
about you too, Runner.
You know that.
But I'm not gonna let you
get in my underpants.
Yeah, why not me?
Why every other dumb Joe Blow?
It's not every other
dumb Joe Blow.
We've been hanging
around for four years.
We've been going out.
We've been palling around.
And I-- You--
You can be really
nasty sometimes.
But I've never
thought about a woman
the way I think about you.
Well, go ahead.
I'm waiting for the commentary.
Hell, Runner,
I'm not gonna say anything.
I better go.
[ TV: Indistinct ]
¶ [ Man Whistling ]
¶ I got a secret ¶
¶ I shouldn't tell ¶
¶ And I'm gonna
go to heaven in a ¶
¶ In a split-pea shell ¶
¶ Lordie me ¶
¶ Didn't we shake sugaree ¶
¶ Everything I have ¶
¶ Down in pawn ¶
¶ You know I pawned my watch ¶
¶ I pawned my chain, yeah ¶
¶ And I'd of sold myself ¶
¶ But I felt ashamed ¶
¶ Lordie me ¶
¶ Didn't we shake up sugaree ¶
¶ Everything I have ¶
¶ Down in pawn ¶
[ Cheering, Applauding ]
[ Boy ]
Okay, let's do it!
Yes, get a hit!
Hey, you made it.
Yeah.
[ Cheering, Applauding ]
[ Woman ]
Let's go! Let's go! Yeah!
[ Man ]
Okay. Come on, Robert!
What the hell you doing
drinking at a kids' game?
I'm not drinking per se.
I'm just celebrating life.
Anyhow, it's in a bag.
Peter, let's go!
You can do it!
Okay, let's a hit!
Come on, Peter!
[ Woman ]
Let's go, Cal!
That's good pitching!
Home run!
[ Umpire ]
Strike one.
He needs to choke up a little.
He'll be all right.
[ Man ] Watch it, Peter.
[ Boy ]
Come on! Come on, Peter!
Let's go!
Strike two!
[ Cheering, Applauding ]
All right, last one.
Come on, dude.
[ Diane ]
Go, little man!
Whoo!
[ Boy #1 ] Come on, Pete!
[ Boy #2 ]
Come on, Peter!
[ Boy #3 ]
Let's go, Peter!
[ Boy #4 ] Come on, Pete.
[ Man ]
It's all you, Peter.
Yeah! Go!
[ Man ]
Go! Go! Go!
[ Diane ]
That's it! Go!
Shit!
[ Umpire ]
That's an out!
Game's over.
What the hell's
he doing?
Hey!
Over here!
Did you see me?
I hit it.
Yeah.
I saw it.
Kept your eye on the ball.
[ Runner ]
Hey, come on.
Don't be talkin' like that.
[ Phone Rings ]
All right, put the porno on
and, uh, I'll grab some plates.
[ Rings ]
Which one you
putting in first?
Hello?
[ Sighs ]
Nice.
This is Diane.
'Cause if it's a scary movie
I gotta have a blanket.
It's gotta
cover my feet.
Yeah.
And it has to wrap underneath.
It has to be like a taco.
I have to be wrapped.
I see.
A burrito.
[ Door Closes ]
Hey.
Now listen.
If my mom was alive or I knew
where my dad was,
I would-- I would try to
fix things up with them, but--
I've been talking to Jenny,
and she's gonna take him, Di.
But I don't want you to talk
to him about it just yet, okay?
I'll-- Just let him be.
Does she really want him?
Wants him enough, I guess.
You sent him
out to me on purpose.
You've known for a long time
how sick you were.
You know, I wish we could've
seen eye to eye on some things,
Diane.
That would have been
cool with me.
I just-- I just never
knew where I stood.
You know, like I was right there
with you or making love to you,
but you were always
somewhere else.
I could never get a foothold.
There I was.
You pulled up in that
big bus with your team,
you stepped off.
I thought I'd never seen
a better looking man
in all my life.
Seemed like you came
down from heaven or on
a white horse or something.
You had your hair slicked back,
cut over your left eye.
I would've gone just about
anywhere with you at that
moment, and I guess I did.
You did.
That's-- That's very true.
[ Whispering ]
I like that mouth.
Your dad wants you
to come in now.
Your dad wants you,
okay?
Peter, go on.
We'll be right here
when you get back.
Come on now. Go.
Well, I guess you can tell
by looking at me I'm not
in the best shape of my life.
You look all right.
You win your game?
Come on.
Come sit next to me.
I got some things that
I wanted to talk to you about.
How's your throwing?
Bad.
Yeah, well,
I wasn't so good
at throwing either.
Or batting, for that matter.
You like your mom?
No.
You love her though, right?
I don't know.
[ Sighs ]
Now I gotta tell you this,
sweetheart.
I'm not so sure that
I'm gonna be seeing you
around again before too long.
Now me and you,
we've been together
since you were a baby, right?
That's a long time. That's a--
That's a real long time.
You know, when you first
came out of your mom, well...
it was the happiest day
of my life.
Now here, here. Stop-- Stop
playing with your fingers for
a second and look at me, okay?
No.
Now listen to me good, okay?
[ Sniffles ]
I want you to try and be
a good man, if you can.
And I don't mean giving quarters
to homeless people or whatever.
I'm-- I'm talking about...
treating people right,
you know?
Or... I don't know,
standing up for people
that need you.
Even if you're--
Even if you're scared.
All right, do you know
what I'm saying?
No.
You do those things.
Maybe if all goes well,
I'll be sure to see you
before too long, all right?
Okay, now, go get Jenny,
'cause she needs to make
some calls.
No!
Go on.
Go-- Go get Jenny.
No, Daddy!
[ Sobbing ]
[ Woman ]
¶ Wilderness song ¶
¶ Kids and a clown ¶
¶ Lanky boys with ¶
¶ Big mouths ¶
¶ My staircase ¶
¶ A vow leans against my cloud ¶
¶ And all your wanderin' ¶
¶ Wanderin' about ¶
¶ Well, it tells me ¶
¶ I should have bones
to pick with you ¶
¶ And I should feel
the need to kill ¶
¶ Against you
Yes ¶
¶ I should have bones
to pick with you ¶
¶ I don't have no ¶
¶ I don't have no bones ¶
¶ Mmm, grubby hands ¶
¶ My itchy finger ¶
¶ And the tonal tunes and ¶
¶ And their tidy singers
What ¶
¶ Oh, I should have bones
to pick ¶
¶ Oh, I don't have no ¶
¶ I don't have no bones ¶
¶ [ Strumming ]
[ Diane ]
But that run is mine, Frank.
I am dependable.
Listen,
my kid's dad just died.
¶ [ Continues ]
Yeah, sure,
that would be fun.
No, a drink would be great.
Thank you.
Okay.
¶ [ Continues ]
You sound like
a real rock star in there.
[ Dog Barking In Distance ]
Listen, I'm gonna need you
to go stay with Jenny another
weekend in, uh, L.A., okay?
Next weekend.
I'm gonna go do Reno.
¶ [ Continues ]
[ Crowd Cheering, Applauding ]
Out!
Peter!
[ Man ] Who's up? Who do we got?
[ Man #2 ]
Let's go! Next batter!
[ Crowd Applauding ]
Hey!
Hi.
That was great.
Thanks.
Hey, Peter.
How are you?
Hi, Jenny.
I thought you weren't
coming until tomorrow.
Where's Runner?
Bringing the truck around.
Listen, Peter, I've gotta
work tomorrow afternoon,
so I was thinking we just
drive back to L.A. tonight.
Well, me and the team
are gonna go get some pizza.
I got a call a few hours ago
to make another run after Reno.
Where?
Boston.
Where's Boston.
It's gonna be
a couple extra days,
so maybe you wanna stay
out there with Jenny
a little while longer, okay?
How long?
A few days.
Just an extra few days.
And then we'll see.
Okay?
See what?
Hey.
It's just a few days.
A few days, okay?
Listen to me.
You can go back
and be with your friends,
all right?
You can stay
in your old house.
You can have
a better life.
You can be with people
who love you.
See, I am who I am,
all right?
This is who I am.
I'm always gonna be
like this.
Like what?
Like this.
Jenny is a really
nice woman.
I don't want a nice woman.
[ Engine Starts ]
I'll be back in a week or so.
Just play it by ear
or something.
Okay, Diane.
He's a good boy.
I know.
How you doing, Jenny?
[ Sighs ]
To tell you the truth,
I'm pretty fucking sad.
I'll bring him by
in the morning.
He'll be fine.
Good night, Diane.
Yeah.
You did good tonight.
[ Sighs ]
I could have been
a good dad, maybe.
Maybe still could.
What?
Nothing.
[ Sighs ]
You look
real pretty tonight.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Thanks.
I like your legs.
Never get to
see 'em much.
Actually I don't think
I ever seen 'em.
Yeah?
My legs?
Yeah.
What else do you
like about me?
I like your knees.
My knees are a part of my legs,
the part that makes them bend.
Well, can't it just be me
saying something?
Just say something else then.
You already got
my legs covered.
What would you say
if I leaned in a little
right now?
I guess I'd tell you
when you got here.
Not sure if I like it.
No?
Maybe a little closer.
Can't quite get the full bouquet
of the whiskey.
[ Chuckles ]
No.
Diane, I'm sorry.
No, it's not you.
I just don't want to
live like that anymore.
Like what?
Kinda half-assed, you know?
Not thinking things through.
I mean, you got Molly,
she's okay, but damned
if you're ever gonna leave her.
I don't know what I'm doing.
But whatever it is
maybe I've gotta think
about my future more...
than just what city
I'm running a load of
two-by-fours to, you know?
You know what I mean,
Runner?
Not all the way.
But, yeah, I gotcha.
I can support you
on that.
You better go.
He's gonna be home soon.
You gonna say something?
Uh...
Ah, hell, Diane, you got
the most beautiful tits
I ever laid hands on.
Well, if nothing else, you--
you're a true gentleman.
[ Engine Starts ]
Stay out of trouble.
[ Clanging ]
Hey!
What are you guys doing?
How was the game?
Get out of here.
[ Clears Throat ]
Mmm. Wow. Okay.
Here you go.
What, are you
looking at something?
[ Chuckles ]
What are you looking at?
Are you fucking
looking at something?
Nothing.
I got my kid coming home.
Mmm.
Look at me.
No, look.
I said I got my kid
coming home.
If you get
out of here right now,
I won't call the cops.
Okay.
You fucker!
Bitch!
Get up!
Come on!
Ahh! Ahh!
Look at me! Huh?
Look at me!
I'm looking at you!
I'm fucking
looking at you!
Ow! Fuck! Ahh!
Goddamn it!
No! No!
See, I have a son, all right?
I don't want him coming in
on this, all right?
Listen, my truck's
parked outside.
All right?
Take me outside. In the truck.
In the truck. In the truck.
Oh, God!
My son! No!
Goddamn it!
Get the fuck off her!
Jesus! That is not
what I am!
That is not what I am!
Diane!
Diane.
This is my house.
Get out of my house!
[ Panting ]
Peter.
Those guys that were
just here-- [ Sobbing ]
[ Cigarette Lighter
Clicks Open ]
[ Clicks Closed ]
[ Cars Passing By On Freeway
In Distance ]
[ Whispering ]
The freeway's really loud.
Sometimes
it puts me to sleep
like waves at a beach.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I'm okay.
Are you?
Yeah.
Do you want me
to go with Jenny?
Do you wanna
go with Jenny?
[ Sighs ]
That's not what I asked you.
No, I don't want you
to go with Jenny.
Do you want me
to stay with you?
Will you say it?
I want you
to stay with me.
What can I call you then?
Anything you want.
Okay.
¶ [ Guitar ]
¶ [ Music Fades Out ]
¶ [ Slow Country Guitar ]
¶ [ Continues ]
¶ [ Fades Out ]