He said I had a new mother...
and that I should forget.
He wouldn't even let me talk
about my mother.
It was like she'd never existed.
[Sobbing]
- Need help here.
- I think we should stop.
No. I want you to hear this.
My father was afraid of love.
He couldn't give it, and
he couldn't receive it either.
- Maybe that's worse.
- Morrie, we should stop.
Not letting
ourselves be loved...
because we're too afraid of giving
ourselves to someone we might lose.
[Gasping]
[Gasping Continues]
- Um... Connie! Connie!
- [Hissing]
Ahh. Connie! Connie!
[Bell Ringing]
You're okay. Okay.
- [Groaning]
- That's it. Okay, breathe.
Good. Good.
Okay. You're okay.
[Morrie Sighing]
[Pager Beeping]
[Sighs]
[Phone Rings]
Where the hell are you?
You're supposed to be
in New York for the play-offs.
Yeah, I'll be there
tonight, Walter.
Oh, it's only the play-offs.
Hey, what is this number?
How many jobs have you got?
It's got nothing
to do with work. I just...
- I thought that the column came first.
- This is personal, okay?
I just need
a little bit of time...
You have time
for everybody but me.
- I got plenty of guys here
dyin' to write a column.
- What is that supposed to mean?
- You think Detroit
can't live without you?
- Why don't you find out.
You know that comp time you've got
built up? I suggest that you take it.
- You do whatever the hell you want to.
- Well, fine, I will.
Fine!
[Toilet Flushing]
[Connie]
Here we go.
We'll soon have you
back in your chair.
Okay, I'm just gonna
get your feet clear.
One. Okay, you're all set.
Connie. Connie,
show me how to do that?
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay. Come on over here.
Okay, now bend down.
- Slide your arms under his
like you're lifting a log.
- Okay.
- Okay, now he can't
help you at all, honey.
- Like this?
- Yeah, it has to be all you.
- All right.
- Now lift. Okay.
- [Morrie Groaning]
- Sorry. I'll get it.
- Okay, let him move.
Okay, okay, good.
All right, I got ya.
- I got ya. Okay.
- [Groaning Continues]
- Okay.
- You got him.
[Groans, Sighs]
- Sorry. You all right?
- Oh, yeah.
Sorry. I'll get better at it.
[Morrie Mutters]
Don't look so sad
because I'm gonna die, Mitch.
Everybody's gonna die.
Even you.
But most people don't believe it.
They should have a bird
on their shoulder.
That's what the Buddhists do.
Just imagine a little bird
on your shoulder...
and every day you say, "Is this the day
I'm gonna die, little bird?
" Huh? Am I ready? Am I leading
the life I want to lead?
Am I the person that I want to be?"
If we accept the fact
that we can die at any time,
we'd lead our lives differently.
So every day you say,
"Is this the day?"
- Hmm?
- One sec. One sec.
Okay, go ahead.
[Morrie On Tape] If you did
have a bird on your shoulder...
you wouldn't put off the things
closest to your heart.
[Mitch Narrating] I didn't need
the recorder to hear his voice anymore.
It was always in my mind now.
I thought ofhis helpless weight
in my arms as I lifted him... -
that frail, failing body...
and the voice, the spirit inside...
at its ruthless mercy.
- [Muttering]
- And time whooshing past...
like thejet stream
outside my window.
And notjust for Morrie.
I'd taken Morrie's advice.
I'd put a bird on my shoulder.
O-Oh, yeah. Come on in, baby.
Let's hear it back.
- Oh, hey, Mitch Man, I didn't see you.
- Hey.
- So, what do you think?
- Oh, I couldn't hear it. I was outside.
No, no, no. I mean, about her
going solo. No more backup.
- She didn't tell you we're
gonna lay down some tracks?
- Get outta here.
Oh, yeah, man. She's got the voice.
I mean, all she needs is the "want to. "
Very nice, baby.
Let's hear playback.
- Hi.
** Where is that worn-out wish **
** That I threw aside **
**After **
- This sounds great.
- ** What **
**My lover needs ****
Can we go someplace after this?
I really need to talk to you.
Mitch, we broke up.
Don't do this, please.
- Good night, guys.
- I think it's great,
you goin' out on your own.
Well, I'm singing.
That's enough for me.
- Uh, so I've been
seeing a lot of Morrie.
- How's he doin'?
He's amazing. When I'm with him,
I don't want to be anywhere else.
I don't even take my cell phone
with me anymore.
- That is amazing.
- Uh, he's made me think
about a lot of things.
- [People Laughing]
- And, uh...
Well, he always asks about you.
He really wants to meet you.
Will-Will you come with me
to see him next Tuesday?
- Mitch, how can you do this?
- I want you to get
to know him the way I do.
How can you just... blow in and
expect me to come back into your life...
- as though nothing's happened?
- Something has happened.
Look, Janine, I have
something to say to you...
and I really can't do it here.
W-Will you come home
with me? Please?
I can't. I'm sorry.
- Janine, come on. Please.
- Morrie sounds wonderful.
He's done something for you.
I can see that.
And I wish I could've met him.
But it's just too late.
- Janine? Janine, please.
Can we just talk for once?
- [Engine Starts]
A few months ago, Shawn Daley,
18, a hot college prospect,
had a brilliant future.
Cut to last night: Sports car,
drinking, drugs, tree.
- Well, you know the story.
- If they cancel my scholarship,
it's like my life is over.
- I'm dead.
- Yeah, right, Shawn.
You're 18, in perfect health.
You maybe blow a scholarship,
and you think you're dead?
You got your whole life left
to screw up in, you stupid idiot.
On his way home from yet another night
of toasting his success...
Shawn crashed his new GTO "jockmobile"
into an innocent tree.
Shawn, who managed
to squeak past his SATs...
had no such luck
with his drug and alcohol tests.
With no daily deadlines, noJanine,
I had lots of time on my hands.
I thought of Morrie counting his
breaths, what time meant to him.
[Morrie] Work, money, ambition.
We bury ourselves in these things.
But we never stand back and say,
"Is this what I want?"
[Mitch]
Unless somebody teaches us to.
[Morrie]
We all need teachers, Mitch.
- Why'd you become a teacher?
- I needed a job.
Lots of jobs pay better than teacher.
You could've been a doctor or a lawyer.
I hate the sight of blood.
And I hate lawyers.
[Laughs] So what made you
become a teacher?
[Coughs] Well, you think there's only
one reason why we do things?
[Coughs]
In a way, because of my father.
- Your father?
- Yeah. It's...
- Is this him?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Well, he doesn't seem like the kind
of guy who would encourage you.
He didn't. He tried
to get me started in his trade.
- What did he do?
- Sewed fur coats together,
when he could find work.
There was this... factory.
It was a sweatshop.
Third Street and Avenue B.
- Still remember the address?
- I will never forget that place.
It was the only work he knew,
and he hated it.
- But he wanted you to work in it?
- What could he do?
Hunger allows no choice.
[Workers Shouting
In Foreign Language]
I'd hear him complain to my stepmother.
How he was cursed at, belittled.
Always pushed to do more, and
denied the money he had coming.
That was my father's world.
It was going to be my world too...
- except I found out something that day.
- [Gasping]
- [Mitch] That you'd
do anything but that.
- Something else.
It's when I learned
I had asthma.
- [Laughing]
- 'Course, they thought
I was just a crybaby...
- that I was scared.
- [Gasping Continues]
They were right about my being scared,
but there was something else.
I made a vow that I would
never do work that used people...
that hurt them
and degraded them.
I was never gonna make money
off the sweat and pain of others.
- Tsk. So, in a way,
you owe your father.
- Yeah.
My-My-My stepmother, Eva...
- uh, she was just the opposite.
- Loz der moyekh trakhtn.
Everything I love about
education I learned from her.
The father of our country is?
- [Slurping]
- [Young Morrie] Washington?
It's what I call
the tension of opposites.
- [Mitch] The tension of...
- [Morrie] Opposites.
Life pulling you back
and forth like a rubber band.
Pull you one way, you think
that's what you want to do.
Pull you another way, you think
that's what you have to do.
- Sounds like a wrestling match.
- You could describe life that way.
- So, who wins?
- Love. Love always wins.
You don't believe that?
I don't know. Maybe I don't. I mean,
have you looked at the news lately?
Love's not exactly racking up
the gold medals out there.
Maybe the game isn't over yet.
- What are we... We're through?
- Coach, can I talk to you
for a second as a friend?
That's the way we always talk.
Now, why did you stop the tape?
Well, because this is, uh...
Uh, I need a little help here.
Um, I bought a ring forJanine...
an engagement ring.
Congratulations! Does this mean
I finally get to meet her? [Coughs]
Well, um... Look, I'm ready
to make the plunge.
I really am. I'm talkin' marriage,
family, the whole nine...
Everything I've been putting off
up to this point, basically. But, um...
Okay, I take her way too much
for granted. I always have. I know that.
And, believe me, I know what a selfish
jerk I can be, especially with my time.
But, um... You know,
it's just what you said.
It's about this fear that I have about
not just giving love but receiving it.
And, uh... And of being part of something
that isn't just all about me. And, uh...
You know, uh, living
for somebody else and, uh...
- uh, learning to give and, uh...
- She didn't like the ring?
Oh, I never even
got to give it to her.
- But you love each other?
- Yes, we do, a lot.
Uh-huh.
So, if love always wins, what the heck
is the matter with us? [Chuckles]
I could use a little...
little wisdom here.
Maybe my wisdom
isn't what you need.
Start that thing again.
This is our last thesis together.
We got to get it right.
We don't have a lot of time.
[Coughs]
[Morrie On Tape]
We think we don't deserve love.
That if we let it come in,
we'll become soft.
[Mitch] He had answers
for all the big, important things.
- [Morrie Continues On Tape]
- Why not me?
Love is the only rational act.
Said it right.
Let it come in.
- [Tape Recorder Clicks Off]
- [Sighs]
[Beeps]
Okay, I'll be right down.
Thanks, Lloyd. I'll just
be a couple of minutes.
[Mitch] I hate sports metaphors.
I never use 'em.
But this was a real Hail Mary.
A last-second desperation play.
I wrote a letter toJanine.
Everything I'd never said to her.
Including the part
where I begged her to marry me.
****[Mitch Playing Jazz On Piano]
My Hail Mary hadn't worked.
As Tuesday neared, I had plenty of time
to think what a stupid idea it was.
[Phone Ringing]
[Answering Machine Clicking]
- [Beeps]
- Mitch. Walter. Call me, please.
I've got a temper, so do you.
It goes with the job. Just...
I'm tryin' to tell you that I'm...
****[Resumes]
I asked for an "aisle. "
You're gonna find me an "aisle. "
- Is that too much to ask?
- What the hell happened
to the air conditioning?
It's not the airline's fault, sir.
Just wait your turn.
Hey, back off, pal! Huh?
I got a big, big problem here.
[Woman On P.A.]
Please consult a ticket representative...
What are you going to do?
[Clicks Heels]
If this is a no,
why didn't you just call me?
Because I don't know
what the answer is.
Whatever Morrie did that
made you write that letter...
I want to see for myself.
Food man's back!
- Hey, how's he doing today?
- Not so good.
- You can put the food
in the kitchen and...
- I'll see you later.
- I'll go get 'em.
- Uh, Connie? Connie?
- I'd like you to meetJanine.
- Oh, hi. I'm sorry.
So many people come through that door,
sometimes I forget my manners.
- Very nice to meet you.
- Hi.
All right. Let's see. Can you take
some of this off this table, please?
- Uh-huh.
- You can just put it right up there.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
It's gonna be fine.
The two people I love the most...
are finally
gonna meet each other.
[Wheelchair Clattering]
[Connie]
All right. Here we go.
- Oh, there's my buddy.
- Hey, Coach. How ya doin' today?
All right
[Laughs]
- [Kissing]
- What'd ya bring today?
- I have some grape leaves.
I got some pasta salad.
- Oh, boy. Uh-huh.
- Nice warm pita bread.
- Oh, you always bring the right things.
- Oh!
- Oh, uh, I brought something
else with me today, Coach.
Morrie...
- this is Janine.
- Yeah, Janine.
Can I tell ya somethin'?
You're as lovely as your name.
Thank you.
[Both Laughing]
[Slurping]
- [Slurping]
- [Clears Throat] Morrie...
- Huh?
- TellJanine the story you
told me... about the ocean?
- The ocean? Oh, the little wave?
- Yeah.
Yeah, it's a sweet little story.
See, there's this little wave.
And he's out there bobbing up and down
and havin'a grand old time.
You know, just enjoying
the sunshine and the wind...
Right. Until he see...
Until he sees the other waves.
Yeah. He sees the other waves crashing
into the shore, so he gets scared.
- And another wave sees him and...
- He's like, "Oh, my God."
- Look at what's gonna happen to me.
- Does he do this to you?
- I'm tryin' to tell a story here.
- Sorry.
And another wave says to him,
"Why do you look so sad?"
And the little waves says,
" Because we're gonna crash.
All us waves are gonna be nothin:
Don't ya understand?"
And the other wave says,
"You don't understand.
You're not a wave.
You're part of the ocean."
Part... of the ocean.
[Coughs]
- Oh, that's a beautiful story
- [Gasps] Thank you.
Okay.
No. I got ya.
- [Morrie Gasping]
- [Oxygen Tank Hissing]
Okay. There you go.
[Steady Breathing]
- Okay.
- Okay?
Thank you.
My helper, that one.
Mitch tells me you're a wonderful
singer, a professional, huh?
Well, I mostly sing backup.
- Backup?
- Uh-huh.
Yeah, background, you know?
The humming and the oohing that
makes the singer sound good.
But she's not really gonna
do that anymore.
- Oh, you don't like
the humming and oohing?
- No, it's just that she's gonna be...
- the one out front now.
- I like singing, any kind.
Yeah, but let somebody else
back her up.
I don't feel like
I have to be number one.
- What's wrong with being number two?
- [Laughs]
Would you sing for me?
You know what, Coach?
Everybody asks her that.
I'll tell ya what, she's recording now.
I'll bring ya a tape next time.
Wouldn't that be nice?
Would you excuse us for a few minutes?
Exc... Me?
Yeah, just go make some phone calls
or something like that, would ya?
- Sure.
- Bye.
[No Audible Dialogue]
- Hey.
- Oh, hi.
No, no. Please don't get up.
You look exhausted.
[Sighs]
So, is it...
It's really bad?
Yeah, it's getting to his lungs.
Couple of times there, I thought
we were really gonna lose him.
It's a damned shame.
He's such a sweet man.
****[Janine Singing]
** That's everything **
** The very thought of you **
**And I forget to do **
* The little ordinary things *
** That everyone ought to do **
**I see your face in every flower **
** Your eyes in stars above **
**It's just the thought of you **
* The very thought of you *
- **My love ****
- [Laughs]
I told you there'd be tears.
[Chuckles]
Mitch doesn't believe in tears.
I'll get to him someday.
[Chuckles]
[Mitch] You ever gonna tell me
what you talked about?
He told me how much
he loved dancing.
That's all?
No.
Hmm, mostly he let me talk.
[Chuckles]
So many times
I've heard you sing.
Never like that.
Um...
The letter I wrote, I guess
it wasn't the best way...
The ring that you
gave me was beautiful.
[Scoffs]
But you gave it back to me.
Well, when you
give it to me again...
I'd like for you
to do it in person.
- Okay.
- Mmm.
[Sobbing]
[Mitch] I talk to Charlotte
almost daily now.
She told me about the bad times that
I rarely saw on our Tuesdays together.
[Sighs]
Now I was afraid that
each Tuesday would be our last.
[Thunderclap]
He hasn't been able to eat solid food
for some time now, Mitch.
I'm sorry, Charlotte.
I just want to bring
him something, you know?
- [Coughing]
- Boy, maybe I shouldn't
stay today, huh?
Oh, don't be silly. He's been
asking for you all morning.
"Where's Mitch?
It's Tuesday. "
You bring him a great deal, Mitch.
You bring him so much.
****[Soprano Singing Opera]
****[Continues]
- Hiya, Coach.
- Hiya, buddy.
[Chuckles]
How ya doin'?
Ever see such rain?
Oh! I was thinking
about the kids...
trying to move their stuff
into the dorms out of the cars.
- It must be gettin' all wet.
- Nah.
These days some people hire
people to do that for 'em.
- Oh?
- They go off and have
a latte somewhere.
- So, how ya feelin', Coach?
- Oh...
I passed a landmark.
Remember what I said about someday
somebody havin' to wipe my ass?
- I'm there.
- You're not gonna expect
me to do that, are you?
Why not?
You might be good at it.
You know, the culture teaches us
to be ashamed of that. See, I don't...
- W-W-W-W-Wait. You always...
- [Indistinct]
- Wait. You always
start before I'm ready.
- Huh?
- You always start before
I'm ready. Wait. Okay.
- Oh.
- Oh, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. You okay?
- [Groans]
Coach, maybe we shouldn't
work today, huh?
You look like you
should be in bed to me.
If you're in bed, you're dead.
That's my latest aphorism.
We're gonna work, and
the subject is dependency.
- Go.
- I'm dependent on others...
for just about
everything, you know...
eating, urinating,
blowing my nose.
The culture says
I should be ashamed of that.
- Since when have you ever
done what the culture says?
- Oh, since never.
There is nothing innately
shameful about being dependent.
- [Groans]
- What's the matter?
My feet. There's some
salve over there.
They're... They're useless,
you know, but they hurt. I-I...
When we're infants,
we need others to survive.
When we're dying,
But here's the secret. In between,
we need others even more.
We must love
one another or die.
- Oh, quoting Auden, huh?
- No. I'm quoting you.
- Oh.
- I do that a lot these days.
Once you learn how to die,
you learn how to live.
Yeah, but do you believe that?
Does it apply to you?
I don't know.
If you listen to that little bird
on your shoulder, you'll believe.
It's not that easy, Coach.
Out in the world it's kind of hard...
- it's kind of hard to get
in touch with your inner bird.
- [Chuckles]
Ever tried being spiritual
in a locker room full of naked jocks?
You hate that word,
don't you? "Spiritual."
You think it's just
touchy-feely stuff, huh?
Well, I guess
I just don't understand it.
We must love
one another or die!
It's a very simple
lesson, Mitch.
Good student like you shouldn't
have any trouble with it.
What are you thinking about?
I was thinking about regrets.
- What do you have to regret?
- [Laughs] So much.
Pride, vanity,
hardness of heart.
When were you
ever hard-hearted?
I had a strange dream.
I saw my father...
under a tree...
He was reading
his paper, as usual.
You know how my father died?
- I think he was scared to death.
- How?
Well, it was after
I was grown up.
One night he was walking and reading
his paper, like he always did.
Some muggers
pulled a gun on him.
He threw his wallet down and ran.
Now, he had seen
terrible things in his life.
Why was he
so scared that night?
He ran until his heart gave out.
I got a call from the police.
Come down to the morgue...
and identify him.
I looked at my father.
I didn't even cry.
I've got tears
for everything nowadays.
But I couldn't cry for him.
I couldn't forgive him.
Not then.
- But you did.
- Yes, too late.
First, I had to understand
and forgive myself.
All those years that
I shut my heart to him.
Why couldn't I stop
and see what was in his?
[Sighs]
God, that poor man...
was scared most of his life.
I was selfish. I thought of nothing
but how I needed him.
Oh, God, the waste of it all!
I... Forgive everybody everything!
Now! Don't wait!
Not everybody has
the time that I'm getting.
[Labored Breathing]
I won't die like he did.
[Laughs]
I'll be surrounded by love...
of my family, my friends.
At peace.
Yes, the tension of opposites.
We learn from what hurts us...
as much as what
loves us, you know?
****[Opera]
****[Continues]
- [Grunts]
- Okay.
- You all right. Okay?
- Yeah.
****[Continues]
- I've never seen your bedroom before.
- I hope you never see it again.
- When you're in bed, you're dead.
- Yeah, well...
sometimes a bed's
just for sleepin', okay?
- [Aldo] Let's roll over, Morrie.
- There ya go.
- How's the congestion today, huh?
- [Groans]
Let's see what
we can knock loose, huh?
Ooh.! Ooh-ooh-ooh, ooh.!
What are you doin'? What are you doin'?
[Groans]
Well, he's got all this
poison in his lungs.
And this keeps it
from solidifyin'.
Feel it in there, Morrie, huh?
Do ya feel it loosenin'?
- Feel something loosening.
- [Pounding Continues]
Maybe it's my ribs.
[Groans]
- [Connie] Mitch, telephone.
- Saved by the bell, huh?
[Groaning]
- Hello.
- Hey, buddy. It's Walter.
Finally got ya on the phone.
- Yeah. Sorry. I should've called.
- Yeah. Look, uh...
Janine told me about, you know,
your friend back there, uh...
Should've said something.
Um, anyway,
I'll make this short.
I was wrong, and I'm sorry.
Just, uh, tell me
how far I have to crawl.
- Oh, no, no, no. We were both wrong.
- [Flesh Smacking, Groaning]
- I'm sorry too.
- So, uh, will I see you in the office?
- [Woman] I got that paper.
- I just can't stop things
here, Mitch. I-I gotta know.
[Flesh Smacking, Morrie Groaning]
Yeah. I'll see ya
in the office, Walter.
- Good.
- [Groans]
[Groans]
[Groaning, Slapping Continue]
Show me how to do this?
- Okay with you, Morrie?
- Yeah.
[Aldo]
Okay, it has to be hard.
It's the only way to break up
all that wicked congestion
so his body can eliminate it.
- Okay. [Clears Throat]
- All right.
- No. A little harder than that.
- Harder than that?
- Yeah. There. Under the shoulder
- Okay.
- [Morrie Grunting]
- That's it. Little bit harder.
Good. Knock the poison loose.
Knock it loose.
Oh, you... You wanted to hit me.
[Groans]
- This is for that " B" you gave
me sophomore year, Morrie.
- [Laughing]
When did I ever...
give you... a " B"?
[Together]
Six, seven, eight, nine...
[Mitch] The large lessons
oflife... We're sometimes...
given the opportunity
to learn them.
But how do we know we're
gonna be able to keep them?
I know I will, Mr. Albom.
I've had real excellent counseling,
and I've learned from my mistakes.
It's like I had
my whole life given back to me.
- When they dropped the drug charges?
- Yes, sir.
- And let me keep my scholarship...
- [Man Whistles]
[Coach Shouting] Hey, Daley!
We need you down here!
How can we ever be sure
we've learned anything, though?
Well, like I said, I learned my lesson.
I'm never gonna forget.
- [Coach] Hey, Shawn,
we need you down here now.!
- I gotta go, sir.
Thanks for your time.
Hey, Shawn.
Hope you're right, man.
[Players]... nine, ten, eleven,
twelve, thirteen...
- [Mitch]
I was glad to be writing again...
- [Chuckling]
Even if it meant Walter
screaming about deadlines.
He screamed louder when I asked
for two weeks off to go to the islands.
I got one.
We made the best of it.
We called Morrie.
He cried, of course...
which I took as a sign
that things were still normal.
When we got home, I got
another day off from Walter, Tuesday.
I told him I was gonna need
all my Tuesdays for awhile.
[Clears Throat]
So, I'm typing up the thesis.
What there is of it, anyway.
- Thought you might want
to read it over.
- Okay.
- 'Course we're not finished yet.
- No.
So I had a thought.
It was kind of weird.
- Wait-Wait, I don't think
the tape is rolling.
- Oh.
Okay, so, weird thought.
- Uh-huh.
- Uh, if somebody could
wave a magic wand...
and give you one day...
24 hours of perfect health...
- how would you spend it?
- That's a weird thought?
That's a good thought.
[Laughs] Oh... [Inhales]
Twenty-four hours?
- Care to share it with the world?
- Well...
I'd have a lovely breakfast:
Sweet rolls and tea.
Then a good swim.
I'd ask my friends for lunch,
a great lunch. You know, but...
A salad or something simple.
And then we'd take
a walk in a park...
with trees,
so we could watch the birds.
And we'd talk about how much
we meant to each other.
And for dinner, I'd take 'em
to a place that had great pasta.
Oh, boy.
And a little duck. Yeah, I love duck.
Do you like duck?
- Yeah.
And then I would dance.
Oh, I'd dance
with my lovely partners...
till I was exhausted.
Then go home,
and I'd have a great sleep.
That's it?
That's your perfect day, huh?
- Uh...
- Sounds pretty simple.
Oh, yeah.
What about Charlotte and your sons?
You didn't mention them.
Well, I don't
have to mention them.
I mean, if they weren't there, how
could it be a perfect day? [Chuckles]
Oh, I-I picked
the spot to be buried.
It's on a hill under a tree.
It's got a pond.
Great place to think.
[Chuckles] You plannin' on doin'
a lot of thinkin' there?
I plan on being dead there.
Will you come and visit,
tell me your problems?
Won't be quite the same,
not hearing you talk.
Well, I'll tell you what...
when I'm dead,
you talk, I'll listen.
What if, uh, you know,
after you're, uh...
What if all this was just...
What if...
What if all this was
just wasted on me?
Well, you think
that could happen?
Well, out in the world...
you know, outside this room...
things aren't so clear.
Your wisdom and your aphorisms...
"Once you learn how to die,
you learn how to live."
What if you can't learn that?
What if you just want to run like hell
when you see death coming?
What if, uh, we're like
your father, you know?
What if we can't learn it
because we're not really like you?
- Yeah, but you are like me.
Everybody is.
- Nobody's like you.
And if it took your death
to teach me these things,
then I'd rather not learn 'em.
All the things you said, I'd give
'em back in one minute. [Sniffles]
- If this wasn't happening to you...
- It's happening.
- It's-It's going to happen.
- Yeah, well, I don't want it to happen.
I don't want you to die.
That poem you're always quoting,
"We have to love one another or die"?
We die anyway, don't we?
We learn to love somebody
and they die, or-or we die or it dies.
What's the point? Wha... What do we
learn really from all that suffering?
Hold.
[Sniffles]
I'm sorry.
I just can't accept it.
I don't want you to die.
I guess I flunked
the course, huh?
Death ends a life,
not a relationship.
Poor Mitch, you still don't know
how to say good-bye, do you?
Look at me.
[Sighs]
Don't you understand?
You touched me.
What if you hadn't
come back to see me? Huh?
This is the way
we say good-bye.
- Love you.
- [Shudders] I love you too, Coach.
I know. You wanna
know something else?
You always will.
[Sniffling]
I'm gonna come back
next Tuesday, okay?
- Yeah.
- I'm gonna bring, Janine
with me, okay, next Tuesday.
- Yeah.
- [Weeping]
Of course, next Tuesday.
We're Tuesday people.
[Mitch Weeping]
[Mitch] Morrie died
on a Saturday morning.
- [Phone Ringing]
- We got the call that afternoon.
Hello? Oh.
He had died peacefully and simply,
with all his family around him.
****[Continues]
Just the way he wanted it.
Charlotte kept it small,
just family and friends...
- [Rabbi Reading In Hebrew]
- all the ones he would've taken
dancing on his perfect day.
[Rabbi Continues]
- [Rabbi] Amen.
- Of course, there was poetry.
"When he shall die take him
and cut him out in little stars.
"And he will make
the face ofheaven so fine...
"that all the world will be
in love with night...
and worship not the garish sun. "
[Mitch]
When I'm dead, you talk. I'll listen.
It wasn't that hard
to hear his voice.
It was Tuesday.
Have you ever had
a special teacher?
One who taught you things you may not
understand, but who never gives up?
Who knows the really tough
lessons take a lifetime to learn?
The last class of my old professor's
life took place once a week on Tuesdays.
The subject was
the meaning oflife.
The teaching goes on.