I love you so much I can't let you go
And sometimes I believe you love me.
But somewhere between your heart and mine
There's a door without any key
Somewhere between your heart and mine
There's a window that I can't see through
There's a wall so high it reaches the sky
Somewhere between me and you
Somewhere between your heart and mine
There's love I can't understand
It's there for a while that fades like a smile
And I am left in the middle again
Somewhere between your heart and mine
There's a window that I can't see through
There's a wall so high it reaches the sky
Somewhere between me and you
Somewhere between your heart and mine
There's a window that I can't see through
There's a wall so high it reaches the sky
Somewhere between me and you
Somewhere between me and you....