That shit!
- Hello!
- So, did you ask 'em?
- Yep. They said fine.
Oh, good!
Sure it's okay with your mom,
though, right?
Yeah, she doesn't care.
She's working.
Isn't she coming up this weekend?
I don'tknow.
So, ah, come on, how cute is he?
Spitit out.
- Oh, he's kind of gorgeous.
- Yeah?
He's sort of like a cousin, butnot
really. He wants to be a forestranger.
Oh, good! Well, then after dinner
we could set a fire in your room,
and he can come and rescue us.
You should've seen the look
on her face.
I never laughed so hard, I swear to God.
I just can'tbelieve you mightmiss it.
Oh.
Hi, Gulliver.
How you doin', boy?
Hey, Pilgrim.
Come here.
Hey, babe.
You're such a beautiful boy.
What are you thinkin', huh?
What are you thinkin', boy?
You wanna go for a ride?
Let's go for a ride.
Come on. Come on, boy. Come on.
- Hello?
- It's me.
- Hi.
- So what train are you taking?
- Um, I should be in by 2:00.
Okay.
You wantme to pick you up?
No, I can take a cab.
Grace go riding?
Mm-hmm. What do you want to do
about dinner?
- I hadn't thought.
- I can ask to try thatplace
Emily says...
- Oh, hang on.
- They're here, so...
l, I'll let you go. We'll figure it out
when you gethere, okay?
Yeah, okay. Okay. Bye.
Hello?
Please! Oh, God, please!
Oh, wait. Have you seen that
stupid cereal commercial? It's like...
-And where are the paintings? It's about
her work, and we can't even see it.
-But we're trying to...
We can change the colour of the deck,
and we can move it up so then
you can see the paintings...
We need to see the paintings.
She's an artist.
- Have you checked on her going rate?
- Gottschalk.
Yes. The legal department's
on thatrightnow.
- David!
- Did you speak to Felton?
Yes, we're suing.
Well, is that absolutely necessary?
lt'll justmake it a bigger story.
- Am I on the speaker?
- David, he signed an agreement
thathe wouldn't talk to the press...
and now he's libelled me
by saying I faked the figures.
- You're not going soft on me, are you?
- Well, nothing like a good public feud.
Exactly!
- You know thatkid Adam?
- Yeah.
- Mm-mmm, he's very cute!
- l, I think you'd make a good couple,
Grace.
- I don't think so.
- Oh, I do!
- You think he's cute?
- Eww! Are you serious?
- I think he's cute.
- Oh, I think he's lucky
thathe lives next door to you.
- I think, I think l...
- What do you think?
I think you have a crush on him.
All right, let's take a shortcut.
Let's take a shortcut.
- You know, we can't even read it.
- Friday is confirmed.
- Right, okay.
No, no, no, no, no, no.
We have to reshoot this.
- I said it
- I said that
- It's "that." It's "that."
- I said it
- I swear to God, it's "that."
- lt, it, it, it!
- It's "that."
- All right, fine.
Let's start again. Ready?
- All right, fine, fine, fine.
All right.
I methim at a party
And he told me how to drive
He said he'd like to do itbackwards
I said it
It
- Come on.
- Judith.
I said it
lt!
Come on!
Gulliver. Gulliver, up!
Up, Gulliver! Whoa!
- Judith!
- Hey! No! No, no, no!
Grace, look out!
- Pilgrim! Judith, Judith!
- Grace!
Hello!
No!
Gulliver!
Gulliver, stop!
Hold it, Gulliver!
Gulliver! Come on!
Robert.
Judith's dead.
And what about Grace?
- She's in pretty bad shape.
- It's a multiple trauma.
- Where is she?
- She's still in the O.R.
- O.R.? What for?
- l-lt's just... It's...
It's a mid-shaft, tib-fib fracture
with a vascular compromise, meaning
the blood supply to the lower leg...
They think they have to take part
of the leg off.
Which leg?
T-The rightleg.
Oh, Jesus.
Okay.
Just take it easy.
This is gonna be tough on both of us.
So let's notmake it any harder
than ithas to be.
Judith.
- Thatbag's almost empty.
- Oh, they'll be in to change it.
If you leave it up to these people...
Excuse me.
- My daughter needs a new I.V.
- Yes, I know. We have her down.
Well, I'd like it
taken care of now, please.
You have to stay on top
of these people constantly.
I'm sorry.
- Thank you.
We really should lether get some rest,
and I do have to change the bandage.
You can come back in a couple of hours
and see how she's doing.
Mrs MacLean? Mrs MacLean,
you have a call on line two.
You can take itright there.
- Hello?
- Annie, it's Liz. How's Grace?
Her leg was very damaged,
and they had to remove it.
Oh, God. Annie, I'm so sorry.
Listen, l, I know
that you're being hit with a lotnow...
and it's hard to think
about anything else,
butl have to talk to you aboutPilgrim.
Hello?
Yeah, I'm here.
I've never seen an animal
with these injuries still breathing.
I'd like your permission
to puthim down.
- It's, it's really the best thing...
- Uh, l... Y... Uh...
You mean shoothim?
- Annie.
- Well, um...
Um, look, Liz.
The doctor's here rightnow...
and l, I can'tmake this decision
on my own.
- Annie, I understand that,
butl have to know...
- Uh, just do what you can.
- Okay?
- Annie, no matter whatl do,
this horse will never be the same.
Well, look, l, l, l, I just don'tknow.
It's Grace's horse, so when she...
- It's notright to make it suffer.
- I cannot deal with this now, Liz.
l-lf you need a yes or a no,
then don't do it.
Okay? Just, just, just, j-just do
what you can for him, okay?
Right.
Animal should be put down.
Anybody can see that.
What did he say?
Nothing.
He's just going off duty.
Well! That's importantinformation, huh?
Christ.
Doctors, huh?
I'm gonna get to know all
the nurses' names.
It's, it's good to know their names.
- I'll go get some of her things.
- I'll go.
No! I'll go.
You stay, in case she wakes up.
You guys go on ahead.
I'll be up by Christmas.
Oh, I meant to tell you. I got
those tickets for the Knicks game.
Good.
- Wanna come, Annie?
- No. Why don't you go with a friend,
Grace?
Yeah.
Wanna eat something else, honey?
We can order out something else.
No, I'm justnot thathungry.
That's all.
Well, you should try to eat anyway.
It's the only way you're gonna...
I said I wasn'thungry.
- Wanna watch some television?
- I think she should finish first.
- Maybe.
I just... l... I can't.
- Here.
- I'm sorry.
No, Dad! I gotit. Gotit.
Sorry.
- You've got to stop doing that.
- What?
Helping her all the time.
Running to her every time she trips,
anticipating her.
You know, Annie,
this didn't justhappen to you.
Hi, Grace.
I don't care whathe told you.
The man's a liar.
He's a actor, for God's sake.
He'd do anything to get a cover.
Gracie, whathappened?
It doesn'tmatter.
I just...
I don't wanna come back.
That's all.
Well, what are you gonna do? I mean,
you have to go to school, sweetheart.
I said no!
I don't want to come back.
That's it. I wanna go home.
Grace, listen to me. Hmm?
Your leg is justhealing, and you have
to give the rest of you time as well.
Is that your version of a pep talk?
Well, you're not staying home all day,
feeling sorry for yourself.
You're gonna get up,
and you're gonna figure this out.
Fine.
It's still early.
What's your next class?
Gym.
Appears to be an excellent jump.
Head and hands, eyes, perfect.
Pilgrim moves with absolute confidence
at the command of Miss MacLean.
- Whatis it, sweetheart?
- I wanna see Pilgrim.
- Hello.
- Hi.
It's so good to see you.
How are you doing?
- She's doing just great.
Aren't you, kiddo?
- I'm fine.
Watch your step.
Mind how you go.
It's muddy back there.
Back there?
W-Well, what do you, what do you mean?
Why isn'the in the barn
with the other horses?
Well, Grace, you see...
Pilgrim justisn't the same horse
thathe used to be.
As a matter of fact, maybe now's
not the best time for you to see him.
I really wanna see him.
Can you open it, please?
Hey!
Hello, beautiful boy.
- No! No!
- Grace.
- Oh, God, no, no, please.
- No, Grace.
- No, no, no, no. Leave me alone!
Here. Grace. Grace!
Mr MacLean, I'm so sorry.
- Dad, why didn't you tell me?
- I'm so sorry.
You should've told her, Annie.
This animal is beyond help.
Annie, can I have your permission now
to puthim down?
No.
And getme every publication on riding,
racing, breeding.
Everything.
Medical publications as well.
Veterinarian journals. And tell them
it's me, and I wantitnow.
- Hold on, hold on. Gottschalk.
- I'll call him back.
- He says he's on his way
to the airport, he really needs...
- Lucy, I'll call him back.
I'll call him back.
Just getme whatl want.
"A million years before man...
"they grazed the vast
and empty plains...
"living by voices
only they could hear.
"They first came to know man
as the hunted knows the hunter...
"for long before he used horses
for his labours...
"he killed them for meat.
"The alliance with man
would forever be fragile...
"for the fear he'd struck
into their hearts...
"was too deep to be dislodged.
"Since thatNeolithic moment...
"when a horse was firsthaltered...
"there were those among men
who understood this.
"They could see
into the creature's soul...
"and soothe the wounds
they found there.
"The secrets uttered softly
into troubled ears.
These men were known
as the Whisperers."
It's perfectly shot,
perfectly cropped...
perfectly laid out,
and I am so bloody bored.
Start again.
Thank you.
Would you excuse me for a moment?
Yes.
- Hello?
- Yeah, this is Tom Booker.
I got a message you called.
Oh, hello, Mr Booker.
It's Annie MacLean from Cover.
You know, the magazine.
Um, well, thank you
for returning my call.
- Is there something
I can do for you, ma'am?
- Yes, yes.
I read this article about what you do
for people with horse problems.
Well, truth is, I help horses
with people problems.
Well, whichever way
you want to putit.
Uh, this article said that you were,
you were a, a horse whisperer.
Oh, they said that, huh?
A whisperer. Hmm.
And I was hoping that you'd come
to New York...
and take a look atmy daughter's horse
and possibly do some...
Ma'am, I'm sorry, butl'm,
I'm afraid you've misunderstood
whatever itis you read.
Because that's not exactly whatl do.
I mostly conduct clinics, you see, and...
Well, could you come to New York
just for the day?
- It's only a few hours by plane.
- And I'm not doin' them now.
I'm on my way to Montana where I have
a ranch to take care of.
Well, I'd pay your fare, of course.
Uh, first class.
Ma'am, first class to Montana
is a waste of good money.
Well, if you could just give me a time
when you'd be available.
Say, am l, am I being too polite here
when I say "no" in Nevada?
Does thatmean "yes" where you are?
Look, I'm really sorry for your
situation, but there's nothing I can do.
You just called the wrong person is all.
I'm sure there's some fine horse doctors
back east.
No, butl don't want a horse doctor.
- I want, I want you.
- So l, I hope everything goes okay
with you and your horse.
- Well, but you see, it's notmy horse.
- So, so, goodbye now.
Grace?
Grace, it's Mom.
Are you all right?
- I've decided aboutPilgrim.
- Oh.
I think we should puthim down.
It's not fair to lethim suffer.
- Well, I think that's a very...
- Maybe they should putme down, too.
- What?
- I'm notmuch use anymore.
You're getting a fax.
- You're up late.
- Is it?
- How was the dinner?
- Is Grace asleep?
- Yeah, I think so.
- Nothing we haven'theard before.
Justlouder this time. That's all.
- So why'd you go?
- Well, one of us had to.
They're still our friends, Annie.
Listen, I had a thought.
What do you think
we go someplace warm, the three of us?
Bermuda or the Bahamas or...
What?
Mmm, nothing.
No, I just don'tknow if Bermuda
would be such a good idea.
- Grace would have to wear
summer dresses or shorts.
- Oh, yeah, of course, of course.
Whatis it?
I want to take Pilgrim out to see this
horse guy. Drive him out to Montana.
- No, I'm serious.
- Now, wait a minute.
- I thought you said you didn'tlike
the way he sounded on the phone.
- Well, I didn't.
- I want to take Grace with me.
- You're kidding!
Liz'll find me a trailer.
We can stay atmotels along the way.
- What, you made arrangements already?
- No, I just checked out a few things.
You know.
- Wait a minute. Drive a crazed horse
all the way to Montana with...
- Oh, he's not crazed, Robert.
- Don't exaggerate.
- No, I can't justpack up and leave.
- Well, I'm not asking you to.
I'll do it.
- By yourself? How?
- You can't take care of Pilgrim.
- He'll be sedated.
- I do know a thing or two abouthorses.
- What about the magazine?
I'm in charge.
I can oversee things from Montana.
- I can take my fax, my computer.
- Oh, you're in charge.
Well, what about Grace? The doctor says
she needs stability and security.
Well, I can't say he's being
all that effective with her.
- Are you a psychiatrist?
He says it takes time.
- Well, I don't care whathe says!
I cannot sithere and pretend
everything's gonna be all right.
- I am notpretending. I am trusting.
- We have to do something, Robert.
- Other people know more
about this than we do.
- We are losing... We are losing her!
I don't care what the doctors say.
They don'tknow her.
I don't care
if this doesn't sound rational.
Nobody is suggesting anything better!
l, I can't explain it, Robert.
I justhave this feeling.
I justknow it's the right thing.
Why, Annie?
I justknow it.
Does this, uh, cowboy vet
know that you're coming?
Yeah.
Whatif Grace doesn't wanna go?
She will if you think she should.
- And you think it's best
if I don't come.
- No, that's not whatl said.
Daddy?
I don't wanna go.
Straightback. Come on.
A little closer. A little more.
Watch it. Getbehind him.
Hold it! Getback! Hold it.
- Watch it!
- There he goes, Eddie!
- Why don't you getinside and...
- Lady, we're doing the best we can!
- It's the only way to load
this kind of horse.
- Keep trying.
- Maybe we should give him
another sedative.
- We did.
Get the gate! Get the gate!
Let's get out of here!
Hold that door!
You got a gun, justin case?
Of course not.
That's probably best.
You may want to shoot yourself
halfway to Ohio.
Grace, are you hungry?
Do you want to stop for lunch?
I don't care.
I want to find a place before
it gets dark. What do you think?
- Grace?
- Doesn'tmatter.
Okay, Lucy, look.
This is whatl'll do.
I'll get to the nextmotel,
see if they have a fax and then...
Oh, wait, hang on. Uh...
I gotta go, okay? Later.
Grace, do you want
to put your music on up here?
Grace.
Do you want to put your music on
up here?
And when you purchase
your Eureka World Deluxe Vac...
Here the agricultural markets
and farm news headlines continue to...
Insecticide for small grains.
Important to always read
and follow label instructions...
This here man was rejuvenated
in the grace of the Lord.
He was washed.
Mmm, Grace, look at this.
Do you wanna see that?
- I don't care.
- "I don't care."
Oh, it'll be fun. You haven't seen
any of the sights yet. It's history.
When I was 13, I used to love
doing things like this.
Oh, you were never 13, Mom.
Oh.
Greatidea, Mom. Now what?
- How long is this gonna go on?
- What?
You know whatl mean.
Do you want us to go back home?
Is that what you want?
What are you asking me for?
You didn't ask me if I wanted to come
in the firstplace.
Now I get to decide? Sorry.
Do you know who I'm doing this for?
I'm doing this for you.
Bullshit! It's all about you, about
you deciding, about you being right!
-lt's like we work for you or somethin'!
-I don'tbelieve this!
- How come Daddy didn't come, huh?
- What do you mean?
You know everything.
You figure it out.
- Your father had to work.
- Yeah, right!
- Would you please stop acting like
you know what you're talking about?
- You are amazing, you know?
I mean, you actlike I don't even live
in thathouse anymore.
What, you think
I don'tknow what's going on?
You think I'm still five years old!
- When you actlike this, you are.
- How long are we gonna be away, huh?
- I don'tknow. I don'tknow.
- Yeah, well, whatif this guy
can't do anything, huh?
I don'tknow!
I don'thave all the answers.
No, you just actlike you do.
- You okay, ma'am?
- Yeah, I'm, I'm fine.
That young lady's gettin'
a little worried.
Oh, sorry. Sorry.
- Good night, ma'am.
- Good night.
You buckled up?
- Are you cold?
- A little.
You may have seen
the Kennel Club champion being rewarded
with a box of chocolates the other day.
Veterinarians and humane...
Butl can't get you out of my mind
Everybody...
Winter weather got you down?
Wilson Travel is offering charter
packages to sunny Orlando, Florida.
Well, looks like lots of precipitation,
as we mentioned, overnight.
GreatFalls, an inch and a half.
Plus, itlooks like
about another half an inch.
He had an epiphany. Paul had
been transformed by the grace of God...
so he was a new creation in Christ.
Is there a man who is completely...
Hop on down to the Northern Plains
John Deere. We'll be glad to see you.
Gee, this place looks like fun.
- Don't they believe in signs
around here?
- What would they say?
- "Ten miles to Big Rock,
twenty miles to Bigger Rock"?
- No.
- Great trip, Mom.
I'm having so much fun.
- I think I should turn here.
Oh, yeah, those rocks over there,
much more interesting.
Can we take a look atBronty's foal
when we're done here, Dad?
Sure, as long as she don'tmind.
There's this kid at school says
we should have imprint-trained him.
Says if you do it soon as they're born,
makes 'em real easy to handle later on.
That's what some folks say.
There's this thing on the TV
about a guy who does it with geese.
He has this aeroplane,
and these baby geese all grow up
thinking it's their mom.
And he flies it, and they just follow.
You hear about that, Uncle T?
Yeah. Heard aboutit.
Well, what do you think
about all that stuff?
Well, I'll tell ya, Joey,
itmightbe all right for geese to
grow up thinkin' they're aeroplanes...
buthorses, as far as I can tell,
can't fly.
We expecting company?
- You know who itis?
- Nope.
- Mr Booker?
- Yeah?
Tom Booker?
Annie MacLean from New York.
We talked on the phone.
I had a little bit of a hard time
finding the place. There are no signs.
Oh, there are plenty of signs,
justnotmany of them printed.
Why do I get the impression
that you're justnot driving through?
I want you to take a look atmy horse.
Now, it won't take long.
And if you still feel the same way,
then I'm sure I can find...
You thinkin' aboutpersonally
driving me back east?
Oh, no, no, no. No, I broughthim along,
and my daughter, too.
We're at, we're at the Lazy J Motel.
- You hauled him all the way outhere?
- Well, yeah.
I had a trailer. It's notlike
I made him run alongside the car.
- By yourself?
- Mm-hmm.
Well, ma'am, I appreciate the pains
that you've obviously gone through...
Look, please don't do
the "Shucks, ma'am" thing again.
I have just driven a few thousand miles
for a few minutes of your time.
I have broughthim
all the way outhere.
Just take a look athim.
If you still feel the same way...
I will be on the road by morning, and
you'll never hear from me again, okay?
Deal?
We're at the Lazy J Motel.
Whenever you're free.
You don'thave to call.
Jesus!
- No, this is what you call the boonies.
- Mom, the door.
No. No, notreally.
No services,
and there's one doctor in town.
Butl managed to find a therapist
for Grace.
I had to drive, like, two hours.
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
Did they get the colour corrections?
- Yeah?
- Uh, I'm Tom Booker.
Is your mother around?
She's on the phone.
She'll be right out.
- Could l...
- Mom, there's a cowboy here.
This is not Gottschalk's business.
Why is he interfering with this?
I told him I'd take care of it.
No. I told him I'd take care of it,
and I will take care of it.
I justhave to getmyself settled here.
Well, um, putitin a memo,
and I'll sign it.
- This your first time in Montana?
- Oh, no! Really?
Uh, it's completely ridiculous.
It's completely ridiculous.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah,
yeah, yeah. I can imagine.
I can imagine. They are?
Then why did you go to meethim,
alone, secretly?
- All dressed up?
- That's, that's funny.
No, really?
I can'tbelieve that.
- Is she gonna be long?
- Probably. She's on the phone
23 hours a day.
- What does she do?
- She's an editor.
An editor? Ah, ah, yeah.
Justin case she hasn't told you,
which she probably hasn't...
I don't wanna be a part of this,
okay?
Mm-hmm. Thank you.
Hi. Sorry about that.
Grace, this is Mr Booker.
Did you look atPilgrim yet?
I was gonna take thatlook now.
Would you like me to come with you?
I have to run over to the office
and give Mr Peterson a cheque.
- Doesn'tmatter.
- Grace?
Do you wanna come with us,
take a look atPilgrim?
- Probably best she stay behind anyway.
- Okay.
- Howdy, Lester.
- Howdy.
- Goin' to see thathorse?
- Yeah, I thoughtl might.
Well, I hope you gotinsurance.
That dirty son of a bitch.
Well, you're the closest
anyone's ever gotten.
I have to be honest with you.
I still feel you've made
a long trip for nothin'.
Butbefore I even think aboutit...
I need to know somethin' rightnow.
And it's a question for Grace.
You see, when I work with a horse,
it's no good justme doin' it.
- The owner's gotta be involved, too.
- Well, that'll be a little complicated.
You can make it as complicated
or as easy as you like.
But she's the one that's gonna
be ridin' him. Am I right?
Hey? Right?
Now, here's the deal.
I don'tknow thatl can do anything.
Butl'm prepared to give it a go,
if you'll help.
- Oh, you have a problem with that?
- Isn'tit, like, obvious?
Not to me.
Either you want to or you don't.
- Look, I'll talk to...
- Excuse me. With all due respect,
this is her decision, not yours.
Now, I don't wanna waste
anybody's time here, mostly mine.
Well, nothin' else to do around here.
That's not good enough.
I can'thelp you.
What do I have to do?
I said, what do I have to do?
Well, what does she want?
- Does she want you to take care
of her horse?
- Somethin' like that.
- And they're stayin' in a motel?
- The Lazy J.
Can I have some butter please?
- Not exactly a tourist stop.
- Well, well, what about the girl?
Doesn't she go to school?
- I don'tknow.
- You know, I just think she's got
a lot of nerve showin' up here.
Draggin' that, you know, poor animal
and that child all the way...
Honey, don't eat with your fingers.
Frank, don't you think
she's got a lot of nerve?
Well, hell, I don'tknow. According
to Tom, she's a pretty determined woman.
She must've thoughtit was worth it.
Yeah. Well, I guess they'll want
feedin', bein' outhere all day long.
- I don't think they'll expect that.
- What, they gonna drive 40 miles into
town every time they want a hamburger?
- Mixed salad.
- What?
Well, I believe women from New York
eatmixed salads.
- Ain't thatright, Tom?
- I believe so.
Well, that's just what we need!
A vegetarian from New York
on our cattle ranch.
A Great Traveller, interested,
notmerely a good one...
is a kind of introspective.
As she covers the ground outwardly...
so she advances towards fresh
interpretations of herself, inwardly.
And this is the quality
which lends Frea Starks' books...
the memorable poetic density
which is their special cachet.
Moreover, itis this quality
which makes them as fresh and strike...
You're at a good place to quit.
Oh, I gothim movin' out a bit.
That's aboutit.
It's still a long ways away
from gettin' a leg over him.
Well, we're movin' along.
What's he doing?
Is this some kind
of physical therapy?
Hello? Hello?
What? No, you're breaking up.
Hold on. Hold on.
Don't start a fight with him.
Joey, give me your rope.
Just to pull him back.
We'll never gethim outta there.
Letme go in after him.
Mr Booker, I'm really not comfortable
with you taking these kind of risks.
- Oh, God!
- Hey, hey! Pilgrim!
Lethim go!
Lethim go.
Does thathurt you?
Only when I kick somebody.
Don't you go to school?
Taking a break.
Don't you?
School term's out early for us
so we can work the ranch.
Look athim outin the pasture.
He must've been a big,
beautiful-lookin' horse.
How was he to ride?
Excuse me.
I've got chores to look after.
Are we in the way?
Should we leave?
I guess we'll go then.
From now on,
leave your phone somewhere else.
Miss MacLean, would you and
your daughter like to stay for dinner?
Joe, take off your hat at the table.
I don't want to say it again.
Uh, dear Lord...
we are humbly thankful
for these gifts...
for the blessings on our home,
our family and our guests.
And bless those that aren't
as fortunate.
Bless all God's creatures. Amen.
- Amen.
- Like some roastbeef?
- Looks great. Thanks.
Thank you.
- Want some milk?
- Yeah. Thanks.
OI' Hank got us
a couple more men...
to move the cattle.
And whatkind of cattle
do you raise, Mr Booker?
Well, we run a mixed herd,
butmostly Black Baldies.
And, uh, what're, what're those?
- Black Angus Herefords
instead of straightHerefords.
- Oh, Black Angus.
- There you go.
- Of course.
And, uh, what's,
what's the difference?
- Well, they suit the weather better.
- And their utters are black
instead of pink.
They don't getburnt
with the sun bouncin' off the snow.
- They make good mothers.
- Our daddy raised straightHerefords.
You know, that's interesting. Um...
I've always wondered every time l,
you know, when I go into a restaurant...
what's the difference between a regular
steak and a Black Angus steak?
I can never taste the difference,
butl could swear that one
was more tender than the other.
I didn'tknow there was
thatmuch difference between the cows.
Of course, I've never been on
a cow farm before.
Seems to me that the bulls
have the best of the time.
Justlaying around the fields,
waiting for somebody to come along
and ask them to do their work.
So on balance,
I reckon I'd choose being a cow.
Yeah.
- Hey, young man.
- You getback up to bed!
So how's the Lazy "J"
holding up for you?
Oh, it's fine.
I still can't get used to how dark
it gets around here, though.
Every time I leave the ranch,
I hold my breath
until I can see the motel.
Well, by golly,
that's a lot of drive time.
You know, Tom, while you're working
on thathorse of theirs...
Annie and Grace should move
into the old creek house.
Nobody's usin' it. It's silly for her
to be driving back and forth...
when she, she don'tknow her way around
that well.
Well, that's very kind of you,
butreally we're fine where we are.
Oh, hell, look,
I know the Lazy "J."
Whole place is as good
as falling down around your ears.
Frank, they're already
all settled in.
And anyway, I'm sure
they want their privacy.
Well, it's got doors, Diane,
and private as can be.
Tom?
I don'thave a problem with it.
I think it's up to Annie.
Well, it'd be great for when my dad
comes to visit.
Where is your dad, honey?
He's athome, working.
You know, um... I don'tknow, um...
Is it worth it, really? I mean,
how long do you think you'll carry on
working with Pilgrim?
That depends on Pilgrim.
I know. Me, too.
When are you comin' to visit?
Yeah, well, there'll be plenty of room
'cause we're moving down to the ranch.
Yeah, yeah. They've got this really cute
little house down by the creek.
It's really pretty.
Okay. Okay.
I love you, too.
Ho-Hold on.
Dad wants to talk to you.
Hi.
- Well, she sounds like
she's doing all right. How is she?
- Yeah.
You know, I think she seems
to be getting more comfortable
on the ranch...
which is, which is the only reason
I said yes to this move.
Well, thatmakes sense.
So, how are you doing out there
in Marlboro country?
- Is the magazine complaining at all?
- Yeah, butnothing I can'thandle.
Lucy says she thinks Gottschalk's
plotting. But what else is new, hmm?
So when are you coming home?
You know, I asked him thatmyself
tonight, and he doesn'tknow.
Hmm. I miss you, Annie.
Yeah, I know.
We miss you, too.
- Good night.
- 'Night.
Did you ask him to come visit?
You already did.
Do you wantme to help you pack?
- Hi.
- Howdy.
What's he doing?
He's tryin' go gethim
to hook on.
How's it going?
Get over there!
Ha! Come on!
Hey, you over there!
Wanna make yourself useful?
- Hey, Hank.
- Yeah?
I think you got a volunteer here.
You wanna take care of her?
Where's Grace? Grace?
- You okay?
- Yeah.
- Cocktail hour yet?
- What?
I said, is it cocktail hour yet?
Come here a second.
You handled thatpretty well.
I think it's time you started earning
your keep around here.
So when we're not working,
you're not doing your therapy...
I'd like you to help out
with the horses, you know,
rubbin' them, cleanin' the stalls.
Think you can handle that?
- That's not a question, is it?
- Nope.
Okay.
Hey, cowboy.
When I was out walkin'
one morning for pleasure
Spied a cowpuncher
come a-lopin' along
His hat was throwed back
and his spurs was a-jinglin'
And as he approached
he was singin' this song
Hey, you little ones.
How are you?
He was only 18, he had a flat
on his little pickup, and...
You know you're not allowed
to go swimming in the river.
And Marie here made the bestpie.
Cherry pie. Go get some.
As luck would have it, he didn'thave
all the lug nuts off...
but the jack slipped and fell
right on thatrock he calls a head.
Is he okay?
Well, itrearranged his scalp
about 12 inches...
Buthe always dreamed of having a place
where he could raise horses...
and have a whole separate life.
My grandson Joe is named for him.
And somebody told him
about a place called Stockett.
He got on his horse
and he rode over there...
and he got off, and he walked
as far as he could one way.
And then he turned around, and he walked
as far as he could to the other.
And then he decided that
that's where he was going to settle.
And that's where we raised
Frank and Tommy.
- Where do you call home?
- She's from New York, Mom.
Um...
Well, I was born in London,
butl'm from all over really.
My father was a diplomat,
and so we moved constantly.
Oh, my.
That sounds very important.
No.
No, he was, he was a wonderful man.
He died when I was 12, but we,
we lived all over the world.
We... It's, it's not the same as,
as knowing a place like this.
Well, sometimes people carry it
more on the inside...
than the outside.
If ithadn'thave been
for them troublesome doggies...
I suppose I could gather up
some of these cups and plates.
- You guys done with these?
- Yeah?
You better give me thatrecipe.
It was really...
I know, I know.
Be glad to tell her anything.
This family has quite a history.
Yeah, it's a story, all right.
- I love how she calls him Tommy.
- Yeah, always did.
I think she always favoured him.
She loves tellin' this story about...
when he was two years old,
he ran off...
and they found him sleepin'
in the barn...
between two gianthooves
of a Percheron stallion.
He said thathorse was protectin' him,
and nobody could convince him otherwise.
Why do you always wear thathat?
'Cause it fits my head.
- Wanna try it on?
- Come on!
What do you wantme to do?
Huh? What?
What do you call that?
Okay, one more time.
You gonna, you gonna sit on me? Here.
So you can watch this 'cause I don't
wanna do this too many times, okay?
Put your finger up. Okay?
Okay? Loop's knotted, right?
Looks like the only way to getit off
is to break the touch, right?
Now watch.
You watchin'?
Watch careful.
- Again! Again!
- Again! Again! One more time.
Oh, no, no. I don't fall
for that one twice.
Now, you guys get on in
before your mother calls you.
- Here.
- So...
Thank you.
- What?
- Do you ever sit still
for just a minute?
Well, you sit still too long
in New York and you getrenovated.
Why is it, Mr Booker,
that sometimes I get the feeling
that you're laughing atme?
I don'tknow. Why?
No. You're supposed to say
you're notlaughing atme.
Oh, I see. You take care of both sides
of the conversation, do you?
It's a man's world, Mr Booker.
Most women have to.
You can call me Tom.
Maybe I am laughin' a little bit.
I figure since you're here, itmight
be nice to relax into the place a bit.
Yeah.
Well, it's beautiful country.
And I could see having
some kind of a...
you know, vacation place, retreat.
Butl don'tknow how you do it
full-time.
Don't you miss
the rest of the world?
What's there to miss?
Well, if you've never lived
in a city with...
with museums and theatre and...
and restaurants and music...
uh, well, I can't explain.
Well, does Chicago count?
- You lived in Chicago?
- That's where I metmy wife.
You, you were, you were married
to a woman in Chicago?
Yeah, really. A woman.
No, I'm sorry. I didn't, I didn't...
No, I'm so...
I was studying engineering...
and she was studying music,
the cello.
And I once heard her play
a Dvorak concerto...
and I thoughtit was
the mostbeautiful piece of music
I'd ever heard in my life.
So, just who's laughin' at who here?
Jogger, huh?
I don't jog, Mr Booker. I run.
Well, that's lucky for you.
Grizzlies around here
mostly go for joggers.
You sleepin' okay in thathouse?
Well, I don't sleep well anywhere,
but the house is fine, yeah.
Oop. I have a way with animals.
That's all right.
He's just young.
Here, hold out your hand
just a little lower. That's it.
So he can get the smell of you.
He's beautiful.
- Now, how come you don'tride anymore?
- Hmm?
Grace told me you used to ride
when she was younger.
- She did?
- Yep.
Uh, I don'tknow.
Uh, no time, I guess.
I thoughtit was supposed to be spring.
Enjoy the day.
You, too.