Subtitles by DramaFever
[Episode 12]
What is this?
Why is it beating so fast?
Is something wrong with my heart?
What... where did she go?
Why is Seung Hyun sleeping over there?
Where did No Ra go?
[Cha Hyun Suk]
Hey.
Ha No Ra, where are you?
Home.
Hey! If you were leaving,
you should've told me.
Sorry. You were asleep, so...
You went alone when it's still dark out.
You should be more careful...
Anyways, you couldn't sleep so you left?
Huh? It was just so hot.
Saunas are supposed to be hot.
Can you take care of Seung Hyun?
Don't worry about that.
Just get more sleep.
Oh, make sure to tell your husband
why you stayed out last night.
I'll take care of it.
Why is it so uncomfortable?
I guess she didn't feel comfortable
staying out overnight.
Since she took off like a bullet.
Who were you talking to
so early in the morning?
My friend.
Cha Hyun Suk?
Professor, thank you.
I'll definitely pay you for the repairs
next month when I get paid.
Instead of paying for the repairs,
run errands for me.
What?
You can just run an errand for me later.
Oh, like yesterday?
Yes.
Anyways Professor,
you like No Ra, don't you?
Nope.
Park Seung Hyun.
I just think that you two
look good together.
Hey kid, No Ra and I are just friends.
Just friends.
You want to quit our club?
I think it'll be hard to do club work
while working part-time.
I already miss so many meetings.
It wasn't easy getting in, you should
keep at it even if it's just a hobby.
I wanted to,
but I think that was also a dream.
Reality is getting in the way.
There is a right time for everything.
As for dancing, I'll be content
with just watching from now on.
But if the club needs help,
send out an SOS whenever.
Except for when I have to work,
I'll help with everything.
I'm really going to send out an SOS.
When we need manual labor help
and stuff, I'm going to contact you.
Of course, Senior.
Once a junior, forever a junior.
Why am I like this?
Gosh, why did he have to startle me
by sleeping so close?
Producer Cha also knew that
Ha No Ra is your wife, right?
One thing I know for sure
is that he doesn't know about you at all.
When anxious, being direct is the best.
Hello, Professor Cha.
Our committee has decided to accept
Professor Kim Woo Chul's decision not to
consult for the "You and Now" project.
Of course it has.
Why is he acting so cold?
They way he's looking at me is not
as someone who's interested in me.
Why does it feel
like it's a look of hatred?
Kim Woo Chul and Ha No Ra...
If my intentions are exposed,
it won't be fun anymore.
- Legally...
- Find the answer.
Since you're smart.
Okay, I will find out
what the intention was.
Since I'm a smart woman.
Ha No Ra and Cha Hyun Suk
are high school friends.
Cha Hyun Suk used to like Ha No Ra.
And Ha No Ra's husband is Kim Woo Chul.
Cha Hyun Suk really dislikes
Ha No Ra's husband.
Why? Because he still likes Ha No Ra?
That's not it.
He showed interest in me.
Then why?
The fountain pen?
Kim Yi Jin, you're dating someone
in secret, right?
You should date properly,
before it's too late.
Will "W" turn into a heart?
Oh, Mother! Father!
Cha Hyun Suk knew all along?
You have something to say?
You told me to find out
what your intention was.
I came for a confirmation.
A confirmation?
Cha Hyun Suk, are you interested in me?
I was, a lot.
"I was..."
Were you interested in me as a woman?
I never said
I was interested in you as a woman.
I never said I gave you a ride because
I wanted to be with you, or liked you.
I said let's go ride a bicycle.
I never said let's ride it together.
Is my intention clear to you now?
If you can answer one more thing.
Why did you pretend you weren't friends
with Ha No Ra
when in fact you two are friends?
As expected, my hypothesis is correct.
Was that you warning
Professor Kim Woo Chul?
If Professor Kim didn't say anything,
then I also don't have anything to say.
But there's one thing you got wrong.
As for Professor Kim Woo Chul and I...
We are not having an affair
like you think we are.
What's your definition of an affair?
Professor Kim Woo Chul and his wife,
they are not a married couple.
In a practical sense, they are divorced.
What do you mean...
Oh, I knew Ha No Ra
wouldn't have told you anything.
That's probably why
you put yourself forward like that.
I asked what do you mean?
A few years ago,
they agreed to get divorced.
They even got their agreement notarized,
those two.
Divorce? Notarized?
If you can't believe me,
then ask Ha No Ra about it.
She probably has the notarized agreement.
One thing is clear.
I met Professor Kim Woo Chul who was
in essence already divorced.
And the reason why that agreement
hasn't been fulfilled yet
is because Ha No Ra
is having a hard time letting go.
That's also the explanation behind
her going to college in secret.
Would a sane person work at a college
if his ex-wife was going to that school?
Kim Woo Chul had no idea Ha No Ra
was even going to college.
So don't go around
misunderstanding things.
And make sure
no unfounded rumors get spread.
This is the final audition list
for each character.
Can you confirm with them that they will
be participating in the next audition?
Okay, I will.
Before you do that, let's eat.
You must be hungry.
What would you like?
Whatever you like, Sang Ye.
You always tell me to choose what I want.
Do you like spicy rice cakes?
Of course.
I used to live in a spicy rice cake place.
Senior likes spicy rice cakes too.
Were you two regulars at
a spicy rice cake place in high school?
Do you by chance know that
spicy rice cake place too?
Senior still hasn't told you?
That place is run by Yang Dong Chul who
went to Haekwang High School with you.
Yang Dong Chul?
It's a store run by Dong Chul?
Oh my.
Grandma's Flower Spicy Rice Cakes
is the name of the place.
Another regular who inherited the recipe?
Enjoy.
Ha No Ra!
Dong Chul!
You're finally here, huh?
What do you mean by "finally here"?
Aren't you here because Cha
told you about this place?
No.
How exactly did this come about?
Oh my! What is this?
What is that sign?
Yang Dong Chul, why are you here?
Why didn't you say anything
when we met at Haekwang High School?
Just come in for now. Come on in.
Back then, Yoon Young fainted
after No Ra's grandma's burial.
Do you remember that's why
I cleaned up Grandma's store?
Yeah.
I sent you the store deposit and
Grandma's bank account, right?
Yes, but that's not important.
How is that you're running the store now
with the exact same recipe?
It's because of Hyun Suk.
- Cha Hyun Suk?
When I went to organize everything,
Hyun Suk came along with me to the store.
Did you get everything that
Ra Yoon Young wrote down on the list?
Yeah, I did.
I guess we won't be able to eat
Grandma's Flower Spicy Rice Cake anymore.
Mister Bae from the real estate office
said this is a good location.
He wants to run it.
What good would it do?
It wouldn't taste the same.
Hey, hey, hey! It's the seasoning.
There was a reason for that unique taste.
What is this, anyways?
Dried radish.
If you stir-fry this and make a stock,
it will taste savory and delicious.
I didn't know it back then.
But Cha had taken ownership of the
store and let Mister Bae run it.
Hyun Suk took ownership
of my grandma's store?
Why would he do that?
He said he'd yearn for it forever
if he didn't.
But why are you running it now?
I never succeeded with my acting.
I got caught up in a pyramid scheme,
and ended up with a large debt.
I was going to set up a stationery store
by the school, so I came to this area.
And I saw this store,
Grandma's Flower Spicy Rice Cake.
The building was getting old,
and they were going to close down.
So, the secret recipe was passed on to me.
I became friends with Hyun Suk after that.
Hyun Suk was the one to keep
my grandma's store alive all this time?
Professor Kim Woo Chul and his wife,
they are not a married couple.
In a practical sense, they are divorced.
She couldn't even tell him
she's terminally ill, or going to college.
She's 38 years old, and he makes
her work a part-time job.
Why is she living with someone like that?
Because he's her universe.
It would make Min Soo's dad uncomfortable.
We agreed to pretend
not to know each other at school.
A few years ago,
they agreed to get a divorce.
They even got their agreement notarized,
those two.
Ha No Ra.
You idiot. You idiot.
You lived your life like that?
Why didn't Cha Hyun Suk
say anything earlier?
Hey, Yang Dong Chul! You too!
I told you.
Hyun Suk told me not to say anything.
It's fine. At least I know now.
Thank you.
Both you and Hyun Suk.
Hyun Suk must have been
really close to your grandma.
I guess so.
I couldn't even do what he did.
[Ha No Ra]
Where's No Ra?
Senior, by chance...
Was I not supposed to tell her
where the spicy rice cake store is?
What do you mean?
We were deciding where to eat.
And she asked about the spicy rice cake
store, so I told her where it is.
She left and hasn't been back.
Oh yeah?
- You did good.
- What?
She needs the good memories.
Sometimes, memories can give you strength.
Senior, what do you mean by that?
I want No Ra to remember
just how much she was once loved.
Oh, Dong Chul. Is No Ra still there?
What is she doing?
She's crying.
She heard the story about the store,
and now she's crying.
Just let her cry.
Close the store, and let her cry in peace.
I'll cover the sales for today.
You want me to close the store
and let her cry?
You'll cover the sales?
Hey! Are you Ha No Ra's husband?
Are you her dad?
I'm her older brother, you punk.
That's right. I'm not joking.
Don't talk to her. Let her be.
What is it now, and why are you acting
like her older brother this time?
I'm feeling heartbroken, that's why.
Is Professor Kim Woo Chul refusing
to break up with Kim Yi Jin?
That's not what's important.
As for No Ra's relationship with
Kim Woo Chul...
I couldn't fix it to begin with.
What do you mean by that?
The thing with the universe is...
it's not something we can live without.
I didn't think of that.
Can you live without the universe?
We can't even live without the Earth.
Are you saying that Kim Woo Chul
is Ha No Ra's universe?
If I had known earlier...
I wouldn't have been so mean, taunting,
or ask so many questions.
I wouldn't have gotten angry.
I wouldn't have done anything.
I should have just been good to her.
Like an older brother.
I should have been good to her
like an old friend.
She has no one to turn to or lean on.
I should have become someone
she could depend on.
What should I say when I see him?
Thank you...
Thank you doesn't really cover it.
- You're here?
- You're back?
Sorry I'm late.
Sorry I'm late, Sang Ye.
While you were playing hooky,
I did all your work, Ha No Ra.
Sorry.
I wasn't in my right mind.
- By the way, Hyun Suk...
- Hold on.
Sang Ye, did you pick some actors
for the roles of Dae Chul and Su Jin?
Yes, I picked a few people for now.
Then the only urgent thing left
is the meeting to come up with a title.
A meeting? I'll prepare some tea.
Forget about tea.
Go get the car ready.
- Sang Ye, you get the equipment.
- Okay.
Are you going somewhere?
We're having the meeting outdoors today.
I'll get ready and come down.
We have meetings outdoors?
Sometimes he likes to do them outside.
Whenever he feels tired,
there's a place he likes to go.
Oh.
Where is it?
What kind of meeting can we do
at a campground?
We're too busy to go too far.
He really is quite odd.
Your Senior over there.
I really can't keep up with him.
Ha No Ra, Shin Sang Ye.
You two are talking instead of moving.
Ha No Ra, you haven't read my script yet
have you?
Read this.
Sang Ye, you go over the audition lines.
Okay.
Here.
But who will do the cooking?
Who else? I'll have to do it.
Because you played hooky before,
you couldn't read it back then.
You need to read it quickly now.
You have to read it in order for us
to have our meeting.
Okay, here.
Report back to me when you're done.
All right.
Is this okay?
When Senior wants to do
a meeting outdoors
it's best to do what he tells you to do.
Oh...
Right... he's always had those dimples.
Let's eat!
Wow! Budae stew!
When did you prepare all this?
This is nothing.
I've lived alone for many years.
Sit down. Let's eat.
I'm so curious.
Try it.
It's amazing, isn't it?
I think you're better than me.
Hey, that's not true.
I know your cooking skills.
You're right. I don't cook that often.
But there's nothing I can't make.
Right, Sang Ye?
Of course. It's only because you don't.
Why did you go so overboard today?
I told you. It's for our meeting
to come up with a title.
Eat lots, and come up with many ideas.
I'm not too confident about ideas,
but I will eat lots of food.
I can't recall how long it's been since
someone's prepared a meal for me.
Here, here. Eat lots of meat too. Okay?
This is really good!
But why are you
changing the title anyways?
Hey, it's a rule that we do not talk
about work while eating.
We will have our meeting after eating
and cleaning everything up.
Our minds will be clearer.
Senior, what should our bet be
for who has to do the dishes?
Bet for the dishes?
Wow! I got it. I got it!
I got it again.
You're just on fire today.
Senior, you're really bad at this.
Oh yeah!
Oh yeah, Godori!
Have you been playing Go-Stop
all the time?
Yeah, I guess my past skills
are still there.
You have to win three out of five games.
It's not over yet.
Hey! The winner gets to shuffle the cards.
In my neighborhood, the loser
gets to shuffle the cards.
Oh! What is that?
What? What is it?
Oh, it was just a lamb.
Let's go again.
Oh yeah! You're all dead.
You're in trouble.
Go on, Cha Hyun Suk. I'll do it.
I lost.
You did the cooking and
now the dishes, too?
I'm your employee, at that.
It's just wouldn't be right.
Come on.
Then you can rinse the dishes.
We can do it together.
Here.
Should we do that? Okay.
Thanks.
For what? Your grandma's store?
I didn't realize how close you were
to my grandma.
I received a lot of free meals
from your grandma.
Still...
I don't know how I can pay you back.
Why don't you say,
"thank you, Oppa"?
What? "Oppa"?
I am taller than you.
Does being taller than me
make you my older brother?
I'm not just taller.
I'm a bigger person than you.
I have a bigger heart than you.
My birthday is probably earlier
than yours.
That's right. I am your Oppa.
Why do you suddenly want to be my Oppa?
You don't have an Oppa,
and I don't have a little sister.
I'm just saying you can think of me
as an older brother.
All right... Oppa.
Satisfied?
That's not bad.
Take a digestive before sleeping.
You went overboard with the food earlier.
Thanks.
I never have anything to say to him
but "thanks".
Okay, sleep well.
Thanks.
Yes, Yi Jin.
What are you doing?
I'm at the K Society meeting.
It's my turn this quarter.
Oh...
So, what is going on with our problem?
Why didn't you contact me again?
Like I told you, I'm looking at various
methods of figuring out the issue.
These various methods that you're
looking at...
when, where, and how
will I hear about them from you?
More important than anything,
these methods to resolve the issue
have to appeal to both my household
and Woocheon University at the same time.
You do know this, don't you?
Have you always been
this kind of woman, Yi Jin?
This kind of woman...
"This kind of woman"?
What do you mean by that?
You never used to inquire
about details like this.
You're not acting in a manner
that allows me to leave you be.
I need to go now, so I'll call you later.
Wait...
- Nice to see you all.
- Hello.
Why didn't Professor Kim Yi Jin come?
I'm not sure.
I guess she's busy with school work.
Professor Kim Woo Chul,
it's been a long time.
You were often too busy writing
your papers to come out.
I almost didn't make it this month either.
He's working on the manuscript revision
for Acta Psychologica.
But I dragged him here.
Acta Psychologica,
that famous international journal?
My manuscript has been accepted already.
I'm sure it's very difficult to get
your paper published in that journal.
Because it's difficult, it's more
meaningful to challenge it every year.
Did Professor Lindemann recommend you?
No, not at all.
If he comes to the conference in
Seoul this month, I'll give him an update.
Either way, this guy Kim Woo Chul...
In Germany, he was more diligent
than the Germans.
He's diligent to a fault.
What are you saying?
If you didn't go to Woocheon University
you could've ended up
at Jahcheon University.
What? Jahcheon University?
Over there. You see Doctor Ja?
Doctor Ja's father in law is a psychology
professor at Jahcheon University.
Apparently, his health is failing.
And he's about to retire
and emigrate to New Zealand.
And they will have
a faculty position open?
Officially, not yet.
But he'll make the decision soon.
Such a shame, Kim Woo Chul.
Jahcheon University.
Jahcheon University, huh.
It's somewhere around here.
I don't see it. Maybe it's gone now?
It was on the foodie blog a few days ago.
This is the Myungjin building,
and this is the convenience store. So...
Most college students these days
also work part-time.
There are students who work more.
She works at a convenience store?
What did you say?
- Come this way.
- Why? Why, why?
I'm sorry, Hye Mi.
I forgot about something urgent.
What?
Let's go for dessert next time. Sorry.
I have to go.
What...
Hey, Kim Min Soo! Hey! Hey!
Why are you home at this hour again?
Shouldn't you be at a library?
I need to talk to you.
You haven't heard me properly.
- When you become an adult legally...
- Did you know Mom's been working?
Oh, that. That's nothing.
She's just doing easy work
at her friend's office.
She's working at a convenience store too.
At a convenience store?
You two can do whatever you want
about the divorce.
But you should pay for Mom's tuition.
She couldn't go to college before
because of you!
Where... where is that convenience store?
Auntie, how many leftover
triangle kimbaps do we have?
Three.
I left them under the cash register.
You should take them home.
Okay.
I got free lunch for tomorrow.
What did you just say?
How dare you tell her to take home
some leftover triangle kimbap.
"Auntie"? Who are you calling "Auntie"?
Min Soo's Dad!
Who are you again?
Me? I'm her husband.
Who do you think she is for you
to treat her so poorly?
What are you doing?
Come out right now.
Why is Kim Woo Chul's wife here
being mistreated?
You're Professor Kim Woo Chul's wife!
Yeah, right...
A professor's wife.
What did you just say?
Would a professor's wife care so much
about an hourly wage and leftover kimbaps?
I'm sure her husband
doesn't make good money.
What?
You rotten bastard!
Here. I'm sure you can buy 20 of those
with this money.
Who do you think you are,
getting me fired?
I said I'll give you the money.
Look at that person.
He doesn't believe that you're a wife
of a professor.
You doing this makes me look bad.
I am not a wife of a professor.
I am not Kim Woo Chul's wife.
We agreed to get divorced, Min Soo's Dad.
It hasn't been legally finalized.
What?
Until it's finalized legally...
Yes, you're my responsibility.
I'm not a kid.
And between adults, why would one
be someone else's responsibility?
If you take your responsibility further,
you'll end up killing someone.
What?
I am now my own responsibility.
How can you make a living
working at a convenience store?
Oh, by chance, did Producer Cha say
he'll pay for your living?
If you're considering divorce because
you think you can trust Producer Cha
that really is a huge miscalculation
on your part.
You really are too much.
Were you always this difficult
to get through to?
What?
Forget it. You should leave.
Just get in the car. Let's talk at home.
That woman...
Guess who.
Why were you so late?
Hey you!
- Ha No Ra!
- Please, just...
It was Hyun Suk...
It was definitely Cha Hyun Suk.
Who is it, at this hour?
It's me, No Ra.
No Ra?
Is something going on?
I have something to ask you.
Oh, why don't you come in?
No. I can ask from here.
Did you by chance...
You remember the Massa Maren show?
Did you see Min Soo's dad?
Did you?
He wasn't alone...
He was with someone else.
Did you see that?
You did, didn't you?
Yes... I did.
So you did.
That's why you acted that way.
Towards me...
No Ra, the thing is...
You must have found it pretty amusing.
Seeing me running away after
seeing my husband with another woman.
What?
Why didn't you tell me earlier
that you knew about it?
Why do you have to embarrass me like this?
So, this is why you were suddenly
being a good friend to me.
You disliked me so much before.
You felt sorry for me.
Come in. Let's talk inside.
Forget it!
Ha No Ra... No Ra!
That's not why!
No Ra... Ha No Ra!
No Ra.
No Ra!
Don't you understand?
I helped you because I felt sorry for you.
Because you felt sorry for me?
In other words, it was pity.
If I didn't think you were dying,
I never would have put on a show.
You're damaging my belongings!
You can bill me for the damage!
I want you to quit your job here
and work in my office.
I need help with my project,
so come and help me out.
Let's work together.
Yi Jin, let's take my car.
Wait...
Am I supposed to drag you with me
when your husband is there?
You'd want to go with your husband,
not me.
I must have looked...
so stupid.
Senior, I have coffee.
Why is he coming down so late today?
[Ha No Ra]
Why are you calling so early today?
I won't be able to go in anymore, Sang Ye.
I'm sorry I couldn't give you
notice earlier.
Why can't you come?
Are you saying you're quitting?
Ha No Ra?
Is she quitting?
What happened?
Why is she acting this way?
Who am I that she'd care so much
and quit this job?
If she doesn't work, what will she do?
[Ha No Ra]
[Cha Hyun Suk]
[Part-time Job World]
I'm the one who told you about this path.
Ha No Ra, are you seriously
going to be this way?
You just got used to the office work.
How can you quit like this?
You know why I'm doing this.
What's the big deal?
There are all sorts of things
happening in the world.
Would you have said anything
if it were you?
I said nothing because I'm your friend.
Seeing you avoid me out of embarrassment
like this is actually hurtful to me.
I'm just uncomfortable about it.
Find someone to replace me.
We have auditions this evening.
Who can we find to replace you?
You have to do it.
Hello?
Ha No Ra? It's Kim Yi Jin.
Ah... yes.
I wanted to tell you about the part-time
job I told you about last time.
Hold on one moment.
I have to go meet someone.
Yes, please continue.
I'll be waiting.
Come to the office!
What am I going to do with you?
Kim Min Soo, why are you acting this way?
I said I'll tell you later.
When will that be? How long should I
wait around not knowing anything?
We were fine going to the dessert cafe,
and suddenly you ran off.
You've been weird lately.
Even when we're together,
you're not really here.
I need to know what it is
in order to help or be patient.
It's nothing.
If it's nothing, why won't you tell me?
It has nothing to do with you,
and it's my problem.
Once time passes
and I organize my thoughts
I'll tell you everything then. Okay?
What am I to you?
If we're a couple, shouldn't we share
everything and do it all together?
- What is it?
- It's not your problem!
Hye Mi... I didn't mean that.
Hey, young couple.
Young lady with the denim dress.
When a man has a problem,
they recede into a cave.
They need time to think alone.
If you leave him alone,
he'll come out on his own eventually.
Don't try to know too much, and just wait.
And you in the white sweater.
Your girlfriend is asking you to
acknowledge her loneliness and hardship.
If a man doesn't say anything,
women will imagine the very worst.
If you ignore your girlfriend just because
you're having a hard time
of course she'll feel hurt.
These are the ways in which men and women
differ from one another.
It's very hard.
You heard him, right?
Don't fall into your own thoughts
and lose me on the way.
My friend is in charge of a gallery.
Next month, they are planning
a large scale exhibition.
It's a project assistant job
that should last about a month.
Why are you helping me get a job?
Well, that's because...
You do work part-time jobs.
Why do you work part-time jobs, anyways?
Do you plan to continue working?
Are you doing it for independence?
Kim Yi Jin.
You're going through a tough time,
aren't you?
Pardon?
You don't need to do this.
What kind of person I am,
why I'm working jobs...
Or why I'm attending college...
None of that is important.
What do you mean...
Kim Woo Chul.
You can have him.
What?
I know why you are doing this.
I know who you are, too.
We run into each other often,
even in restrooms.
Yes.
[Cousin]
You must be close to your cousin.
Oh, okay. I'll call you again.
Ha No Ra, why are you working
in Producer Cha's office?
Because I need money.
Then are you open to working
another part-time job?
As long as the time
doesn't conflict with my jobs now.
Then I'll find out the specifics on time
and contact you again.
Okay.
[Cousin 010-275-017]
[Min Soo's Dad 010-275-017]
- Thank you.
- No problem.
Hye Mi, Hye Mi! Help me out.
Hurry, hurry!
What exactly are you talking about?
Your cousin's phone number and
Kim Woo Chul's number are the same.
Also... why do you keep asking me
so many questions?
Haven't you heard from Kim Woo Chul?
We've decided to go to court.
You've decided to go to court?
When?
He told me he needs to submit
a family information certificate
by the end of July.
So, we've pushed it till then.
A family information certificate?
I was told there's a personnel committee
meeting for new professors.
Personnel committee meeting?
"You can have him"?
She said "you can have him".
This is so absurd!
She doesn't need him, and I can have him.
Kim Woo Chul...
He said she came to college for him.
Oh, gosh!
Yes, Professor Lindemann.
I'll make a reservation at the hotel.
I'm eager to meet you, as well.
I heard that there is no
personnel committee meeting.
What?
I just met Kim Yi Jin before coming here.
Didn't she call you?
You met who?
Your woman...
Professor Kim Yi Jin.
I don't even want to know why you
lied and pushed back the divorce date.
But, I do know that you don't need
a family information certificate.
So, let's go to the courthouse now.
No, no. Wait.
I told Kim Yi Jin everything.
I told her that we're getting a divorce.
How could you...
Let's come back to the context of the
words that are coming out of your mouth.
The reason I used the the personnel
committee meeting as an excuse was
I determined that you needed time
to make the right decision.
Give it a rest now, would you!
Please!
You have narcissistic
personality disorder.
What?
I learned about it psychology class.
You think everything revolves around you.
You rationalize to make things about you,
and alter situations.
Stop that, please!
Min Soo's Dad, please...
Don't push this any further.
I even met up with Professor Kim Yi Jin!
What...
She met Kim Yi Jin?
How did she know?
I took her because Kim Yi Jin
is your woman!
So you need to hurry up
and deal with Kim Yi Jin.
Otherwise, I'll shred you to pieces.
I told you to never
show your face here again.
Why do you say one thing and do another?
What are you doing!
Didn't you say you'll protect
No Ra's family?
And then you tell No Ra about Kim Yi Jin?
What are you...
At the show, it wasn't No Ra
who saw us, right?
You saw us and told her, right?
Cha Hyun Suk, without you, Ha No Ra is not
someone who can behave that way!
How did you coach her, exactly, that she
gave me the divorce papers unprompted?
- Divorce papers?
- Yes.
How did you encourage her?
You probably told her about Kim Yi Jin,
and told her to get a divorce.
No Ra asked for a divorce?
Is that what you're saying?
When? When?
No Ra has decided
to get divorced for real?
What is this?
He didn't know?
Cha Hyun Suk, that punk.
Does this mean
his intentions were sincere?
He genuinely tried to bring
No Ra and me back together?
He has that much affection for her?
[Cha Hyun Suk]
Can't you please pick up? It's urgent.
Please.
[Cha Hyun Suk]
Yes.
You really aren't coming?
It's chaos here with Sang Ye by herself.
I told you I wasn't coming.
I'm really asking you for a favor.
Can you help me out?
Yes, it's straight ahead on that street.
Hey, Ha No Ra, didn't you
say you were my friend?
Didn't you thank me for coming
back to you as a friend?
Even if I faked it?
Goodness, I can breathe now.
- Thank you for coming.
- What should I do?
Put the audition list and the evaluation
form in the file rack.
And the actors auditioning for Jung Hye
and Ji Woo's roles will be here soon.
The scripts are over there, so can you
guide them when they get here?
Okay.
Suddenly one day...
The feeling of not being able to hear the
sound of breathing that was always there.
Do you know what that's like?
When my child fell asleep...
that breathing sound.
Can you go again?
Suddenly one day...
The feeling of not being able to hear the
sound of breathing that was always there.
- Hong So Ra.
- Yes.
You can go in now.
My goodness.
Ha No Ra's body must ache all over.
No, not really.
Good job.
What the...
You worked hard, and you did a good job.
You did very well.
I didn't do much.
Finish up here and come outside.
It wasn't a big deal,
but he says I did well?
It's all right. Why are you coming?
I'm also on my way somewhere.
Then go ahead.
I was going to take the bus too.
Cha Hyun Suk, I came today
because you were in a pinch.
I won't be coming tomorrow, or after.
I've already got another part-time job.
Come on, I heard from Seung Hyun
that you haven't yet.
When?
I got an interview somewhere.
Do you dislike working with me that much?
Stop.
Ha No Ra, do you think
I'm that good of a person?
Don't you remember when we first met?
I'm not that generous of a person.
I don't help people out
just because I'm sympathetic. Ever.
Even when I met you again, and when
I thought you were terminally ill...
Even when I knew your married life
was miserable...
I never pitied you. Not even once.
I'd rather not talk about those things.
You're a very important person to me.
That's why I was good to you.
Because I like you.
I did everything because I wanted to.
All on my own...
I got bothered, I got upset.
And I fretted over it all on my own,
like how I did in the past.
What are you trying to say?
Here.
What is it?
Open it when you get home.
Make sure you open it alone.
What is it though?
Proof that I didn't pity you.
Proof that you're quite the woman.
My precious memories.
Hey, I seriously wanted
to keep this to myself.
But because you're whining so much,
I'm revealing it to you.
So from now on, you can live your life
remembering who you once were.
What exactly is this?
Come ask me how you became
that kind of person to me.
I'll answer you then.
What could this be?
Oh, these are the songs I used to like.
At first, I was happy being your friend.
But that's not the case anymore.
Ha No Ra, I like you.
Ha No Ra.
I like you.
Subtitles by DramaFever