These violent delights
have violent ends...
And in their triumph die...
...like fire and powder,
Which, as they kiss...
...consume.
Gran?
Edward, don't!
She will see you.
Okay.
Grandma, I would like
you to meet...
Happy birthday, Bella.
Happy birthday, Bells.
I thought we agreed,
no presents.
Well, the one from me is not
wrapped. So, it doesn't count.
It's actually great.
Thanks, Dad.
Uh, goes with this one
from your mom.
We coordinated.
Well, she coordinated me.
It's to put your pictures in,
from senior year.
Senior year.
How'd you get so old so fast?
I didn't.
It's not that old.
I don't know.
Is that a grey hair?
No! No way!
Happy Birthday.
It's really funny.
Another missing hiker brings
the total to three presumed dead.
The Rangers are searching
for the killer animal...
Oh, it's Bella.
Bella!
- Hey.
Today is the big day, Bella.
Uh, R and J essay due?
Oh, yeah!
"Wherefore art thou, Bella?"
I wanna take a picture of you guys.
My Mom...
...wants me to put together, like
a scrapbook full of memories.
Oh, of course, yeah.
-I take them, I'm not in them.
No, no, no, come here.
You'll photoshop my nose
if it looks big, right?
Don't worry, I'm in the picture.
No one will be looking at you guys.
It's good.
Oh, good.
Cullen's here.
Yay.
Well, catch you later.
Happy birthday.
Don't remind me.
Bella, your birth is definitely
something to celebrate.
But my aging is not.
- Your aging?
I think 18 is a little young
to start worring about that.
It's one year older than you.
No, it isn't.
I'm a hundred and nine.
Wow! Maybe I should'nt be
dating such an old man.
It's gross!
I should be thoroughly repulsed.
We have to go to class.
Okay.
Wait a second.
Someone wants you.
Bella!
- Jacob!
- I'll leave you to talk.
Hello, biceps! You know, anabolic
steroids are really bad for you.
Well, I'm just filling out, Bella.
You know, wouldn't seem so drastic
if we hung out more.
We should switch schools.
Then you can come hang out
with the pale faces.
I'm alright.
I prefer the Res school's exclusivity.
They let any old rift raft into this place.
I see.
Why are you slumming it?
I was just buying a part for the Rabbit.
You should really come, take a ride,
when it's done.
Is it fast?
Uhm..it's decent.
Okay.
- Okay, good.
Hey, happy birthday.
Your Dad told my Dad.
So...
Yeah, of course, he did.
I saw this the other day and
thought of you.
It catches bad dreams.
Thats kind of perfect.
Thank you.
No problem.
See you soon. Bye.
- Yeah, see you later.
So, how come Jacob Black gets to
give you a gift and I don't?
Because I have nothing
to give back to you.
Bella, you give me everything
just by breathing.
See? Thank you.
That's all I want.
Bella!
Happy Birthday!
Shhh!
Alice, I thought I told you,
no presents.
I've already seen you open it
and guess what? You love it!
You're gonna wear it tonight,
our place.
Come on, please?
It will be fun.
Okay. Alright.
Great! Okay, I'll see you at 7:00.
Jasper...
...no fair with the mood control
thing.
Sorry, Bella.
Happy...
Never mind.
You can't trust vampires.
Trust me!
O, my love!
My wife!
Death that hath sucked
the honey of thy breath.
Hath had no power yet
upon thy beauty.
Thou art not conquered.
Beauty's ensign yet is crimson in thy lips
and in thy cheeks.
And death's pale flag
is not advanced there.
I hate being celebrated.
There are worse tragedies.
Hm, look at Romeo.
He kills his true love
out of sheer stupidity.
Yeah.
Though I do envy him,
one thing.
Juliet. She's like perfect.
If you like that obviously beautiful sort of thing.
No, not the girl, dear.
The suicide.
It's nearly impossible for
some people.
For humans,
a little poison...
...a dagger to the heart...
So many different options.
Why would you say that?
Because I had to considered it once.
I didn't know,
if I'd get to you in time.
I had to come up with
some kind of plan.
And what was the plan?
Uh, go to Italy,
...provoke the Volturi.
The what?
The Volturi.
Now, who would like to repeat
the last few lines...
of iambic pentameter just to show,
they were paying attention?
Mr. Cullen.
Oh, yes, Mr. Birdy. Uhm.
O, here.
Will I set up my everlasting rest,
And shake the yoke of inauspicious stars
from this world-wearied flesh.
Eyes, look your last!
Arms, take your last embrace!
And lips, O you,
the doors of breath,
...seal with a righteous kiss.
A dateless bargain to engrossing death!
Eyes on the screen, people.
Thus with a kiss I die.
The Volturi are a very old,
very powerful family.
I guess, the closest thing to royalty
my world has.
Is that Carlisle?
Yeah. He lived with them
for a few decades.
Described them as
very refined.
No respect for human life,
of course, but...
...respect for the arts
and sciences at least.
And the law...
...above all, the law.
Vampires have laws?
Not very many.
And only one thats
regularly enforced.
What is it?
That we keep the existence
of our kind a secret.
We don't make spectacles
of ourselves.
And we don't kill conspicuously.
Unless, of course,
you want to die.
We have to stop talking
about that.
I can't even think...
...about someone hurting you.
Bella, the only thing that
can hurt me is you.
And I don't have anything else
to be afraid of.
That's not true.
Victoria?
She will come for me one day.
Alice will see
what she decides and...
...we will be ready.
- I can protect you.
If you change me.
Bella, you already do protect me.
You're my only reason
to stay alive,
...if that's what I am.
But it's my job to protect you.
From everyone...
...except my sister.
It's time!
It's time! It's time! It's time!
Sorry about all this.
We tried to rein Alice in.
Like it's even possible.
Happy big Birthday, Bella!
Thanks.
I found it in your bag...
Do you mind?
Dating an older woman?
Hot!
What?
You first Rosalie.
It's a necklace. Alice picked it out.
Thanks.
Show me the love.
This one's from Emmett.
Already installed it in your truck.
Finally, a decent sound system
for that piece of cr...
Hey, don't... don't hate the truck.
Open Esme and Carlisle's.
Just a little something
to brighten your day.
We think, you're looking
kind of pale lately.
Ow.
Paper cut.
Jas... Jas!... shh, shh.
It's okay.
It's just a little...blood.
Get Jasper out of here.
I'm sor...
I'm sorry, I can't.
I'll have to stitch this up
in my office.
Check on Jasper. I'm sure
he's very upset with himself.
And I doubt he'll listen to anyone
but you right now.
Edward.
I never wanted to have a party.
It's not your fault.
Jasper hasn't been away from human blood
as long as the rest of us.
How do you do it?
Years and years of practice.
Did you ever think of...
...just doing it the easier way?
No. I knew who I
wanted to be.
I wanted to help people.
Brings me happiness.
Even if I'm damned about this.
Damned?
Like... like hell?
Carlisle, you can't be damned.
You couldn't, it's impossible.
Thank you, Bella.
You always been very
gracious about us.
So, that's it?
That's why he won't change me?
Imagine the situation in reverse.
If you believed as Edward does
...could you take away his soul?
You can't protect me.
From everything.
At some point,
something's gonna separate us.
It's gonna be an accident,
....or illness,
...or old age.
As long as I'm human.
And the only solution
is to change me.
That's not a solution,
it's a tragedy.
You're not gonna want me
when I look like a grandmother.
Bella, do you not understand
my feelings for you? No?
Carlisle told me how you
feel about your soul.
I don't believe that.
So don't worry about mine.
You should go inside.
It's still my birthday.
Can I ask one thing?
Kiss me?
I love you.
Hey.
Come for a walk with me.
We got to leave Forks.
Why?
Carlisle's supposed to be
ten years older than he looks.
People are starting to notice.
Okay,I..
I gotta think of something
to say to Charlie.
When you say "we"...
I mean to my family and myself.
Edward, what happened with Jasper,
...it's nothing.
- You're right.
It was nothing.
Nothing the way
I always expected.
And nothing compared to
what could have happened.
You just don't belong
to my world, Bella.
I belong with you.
No, you don't.
I'm coming.
Bella...
I don't want you to come.
You don't want me?
No.
This changes things...a lot.
But if it's not
too much to ask...
...can you at least
promise me something?
Don't do anything reckless.
For Charlie's sake.
And I'll promise something
to you in return.
This is the last time
you'll ever see me.
I won't come back.
And you can go on
with your life...
...without any interference from me.
It will be like I never existed,
I promise.
If this is about my soul, take it.
I don't want it without you.
It's not about your soul.
You're just not good for me.
I'm not good enough for you?
I'm just sorry,
I let this go on for so long.
Please...
...don't.
Goodbye.
Edward?
Edward!
Edward.
I'll try to call Cullens place again.
The Cullens left town, Charlie.
Good riddance!
Where did they go?
We'll find her, Charlie.
Thanks, Harry.
Charlie!
She's alright.
I got her.
Thank you, Sam.
October.
November.
Alice... ...you've disappeared.
Like everything else.
But who else can I talk to?
I'm lost.
December.
When you left...
and he left...
You took everything with you.
But the absence of him
is everywhere I look...
It's like a huge hole has been
punched through my chest.
But in a way I'm glad.
The pain is my only reminder that
he was real...
...that you all were.
"Undelivered Mail Returned to Sender"
Alright, that's it.
What?
You're going to Jacksonville
...to live with your mother.
I'm not leaving Forks.
Bells, he's not coming back.
I know.
It's just not normal,
this behavior.
Quite frankly, it's scaring
the hell outta me and your Mother.
Baby, I... I don't want you to leave.
Go to Jacksonville,
...make some new friends.
I like my old friends.
Well, you never see them anymore.
I do, yeah.
I'm gonna go shopping tomorrow,
with Jessica.
You hate shopping.
I need a girl's night out.
Alright.
Girl's night.
Shopping.
I like it, go.
Buy some good stuff.
Hi, Jessica, it's Bella.
Oh, yeah, Bella Swan.
I don't know, why you wanna sit through
all those zombies eating people,
...and no hot guys kissing anybody.
It's gross.
Like why there are
so many zombie movies anyway?.
Is it supposed to like
draw a parallel about leprosy?
My cousin had leprosy,
it's not funny, you know?
And like is it supposed to be
a metaphor for consumerism?
Cause don't be so pleased with your own
like, self-reverential cleverness, you know?
Like, some girls like to shop.
Not all girls, apparently.
Although I was surprised you
even called at all, you know?
Like, your depression thing.
I get it. I'm totally totally worried.
After a while, it's like,
she's still bumming?
And I'm going through
stuff too, you know?
Like Mike deciding
he wanted to "just be friends" !
It's hard, you know?
What's up, guys?
Where you going?
Keep walking.
This is dangerous.
Dude, come on.
Come here for a sec!
I think, I know those guys.
We got beer! We got bikes!
Well, they seem great.
Can we go?
I just need to see something.
Hey, girlie!
Alright, Alright!
We got a taker.
Turn around.
Shut up! Shut up!
Sorry, I thought
you were somebody else.
That's cool! I'll be whomever
you want to be, honey.
So, what do you say?
You promised me nothing reckless.
You promised, it would as
if you never existed.
You lied.
Say some'n, babe?
You know what? Never mind.
Stop.
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Hey, um, what the hell is wrong with you?
-Just curious.
I thought that I saw something.
You're insane, actually.
Or suicidal.
That homeboy
could have been a psycho.
I was about to end up in a FBI interview
room,like some lame TV show.
That was such a rush!
-Awesome!
So, you're an adrenaline junky now?
That's cool!
You can go bungee jumping.
You don't get on the back of some
random loser's motorcycle!
Crazy!
Alice, I saw him.
Maybe I'm crazy now,
but I guess that's okay.
If a rush of danger is what it takes
to see him, then that's what I'll find.
Bella!
Where the hell have you been, looker?
I... brought you something.
- Okay.
It's a little crazy.
Wow, scrap metal!
You shouldn't have.
I saved it from the junkyard.
I think, they'll probably cost
more to fix than they're worth..
But then I thought that if I had a
mechanic friend to help me out,
Ah! Me, being the mechanic-type friend?
- That's right.
Since when are you into motorcycles?
Since now.
I get it if you think that this
is really stupid and reckless.
Yeah, it's completely
stupid and reckless.
When do we start?
Now!
Please.
- Alright.
Oh, hey, be careful. These things
are actually really...heavy. So,
Jake, you're like buff. How that can happen?
You're like 16, I don't get it.
Age is just a number, baby.
What, you're like 40, now?
Feels like that sometimes.
That song was good.
You don't like it?
I don't really like music anymore
...kind of.
- Okay.
No more music.
I was thinking,if we're gonna do this
everyday, and hopefully we will,
We have to, like, fit some
homework in there somewhere.
I don't want Billy thinking that
I'm a bad influence on you.
You influence me?
Please.
Are you...?
I'm older than you.
So that makes me the influencer
and you the influence.
No, no, no. My size and knowledge base
actually makes me older than you.
Because of your gentle paleness
and lack of know-how.
I convinced you to build
two-wheeled death machines with me.
Don't you think that makes
you funny, young and naive?
Okay.
So, where do we stand?
I'm thirty five...
...and you might be like 32.
Come on.
Yo, Jake, you in there?
- No, it's okay.
It's... It's just my boys.
Hey, Jake...
Hey. Guys, this is Bella.
Bella, that's Quil and Embry.
I'm Quil Ateara.
So the bike building story is true.
Oh, yeah, yeah!
I taught him everything he knows.
What about the part
where you're his girlfriend?
Uh, we're friends, you know?
Hmm. Burn!
Actually, I remember, I said
she's a girl and a friend.
Embry, do you remember him
making that distinction?
Nope!
So you guys have girlfriends.
It's awesome.
Yeah, right.
Quil's actually taken his cousin to prom.
Yeah, that's still a riot.
You want funny, Black?
I'll give you funny.
Jesus!
I got five bucks on Quil.
You're on.
Dear Alice, I wish,
I had your real address.
I wish, I could tell you
about Jake.
He makes me feel better..
I mean,
he makes me feel alive.
The hole in my chest...
...while when I'm with Jake,
It's like, it almost healed.
For a while.
Quil keeps asking to come over.
I think he likes you
a little too much.
Oh, I'm really not into
the whole cougar thing, you know?
What's up with you and age?
I mean, how old was that
Cullen guy anyway?
But even Jake can't keep
the dreams away.
Hey, Bella!  Shh, Shh, Shh,
you're alright. You're okay.
I thought this thing was
starting to work,
...but I guess not.
Can I ask you something?
Hanging out with Jacob...
...that seems to take your mind
off things for a bit, doesn't it?
You know, sometimes you gotta
learn to love what's good for you.
You know, what I mean?
Of course, what do I know?
I'm just a terminal bachelor.
Famous ladies man.
Okay...
Go to bed.
I love you.
If I told you, I couldn't fix these
bikes, what would you have said?
Are you doubting your mad skills?
No.
No, definitely not.
I mean, they'll run fine.
It's just, uh...
May be if I was smarter I would've
dragged out the rebuild a bit.
If you told me, you couldn't fix these
bikes. I would say that that's...
...really too bad but were gonna
find something else to do.
Is that Sam Uley?
Yeah, and his cult.
Oh, my God!
Did you see that?
They're not really fighting, Bella.
They're cliff diving.
Scary as hell,
but a total rush
Rush?
Most of us jump from lower down.
We'll leave the showing off
to Sam and his disciples.
Is some kind of beef
with them or something?
Oh, no.
They just think they run this place.
Embry used to call them hall
monitors on steroids.
Now, look at him.
- That's Embry?
Yeah.
- What happened to him?
He missed some school...
...and all of a sudden started following
Sam around like a little puppy.
Same thing with Paul and Jared.
Sam keeps giving me this look, like
he's been waiting for me or something.
It's kinda starting to freak me out.
Well, you should just avoid him.
I'll try.
Okay.
You look scared.
- I'm not.
Alright!
Brake.
Clutch. Good.
Gas.
Ready?
Now slowly... release the clutch.
Bella
Stop.
You alright?
I'm gonna go again.
Hit the brake!
I wanna go again.
Are you trying to get yourself killed?
I'll try again.
- No, forget it.
No more bikes.
Man, your head.
Oh, my God, I'm sorry.
You're apologizing for bleeding?
Yeah, I guess, I am.
Well, it's just blood, Bella.
No big deal.
What are you staring at?
You're sort of beautiful.
How hard did you hit your head?
I dont know.
Let's go.
I did see something.
- Totally, baby, I believe you.
No, he doesn't.
He's just trying to get lucky.
It was jet black and huge.
On all fours, it was still taller
than a person.
A bear, maybe?
Or an alien.
You're lucky that you didn't get probed.
Oh, yeah.
- Well, I saw it.
You're not the only one.
My Dad's been getting
reports at the station.
Like five hikers been killed by some bear.
But they can't find the bear.
Last time you clowns
doubt my girlfriend.
So, I mean...
Bella is back!
Yeah, I guess so.
Huh, that's cool...
Welcome.
So listen, not now that...
You know, you're talking and...
...eating again, you know?
You gotta get that protein in there.
I was just wondering,
if you wanted to go see a movie with me.
Yeah, sure.
Yeah, I do.
Cool, um, let me see...We could check out
"Love Spelled Backwards Is Love".
Yeah, it's a dumb title,
...but, um, it's a romantic comedy.
I mean, it's supposed to be.
No. No romance.
How about "Face Punch"?
You heard of that?
Well, it's an action movie.
- Yeah, it's perfect.
With guns... adrenaline...
...it's my thing
Okay.
We should get a bunch of people to go.
Do you guys wanna go see...
..."Face Punch"?
- "Face Punch"? Yeah!
Mike, hey, we were supposed
to watch that?
Remember the trailer's like punch faces...
- Yeah?
Movie night with Bella!
So, "Face Punch", huh?
You like action movies?
Not really.
I heard it sucks. Bad.
Hey, are you even old enough
to see this movie?
I mean, you know, without adult supervision?
- Right, yeah.
Well, she's buying my ticket for me.
- She's buying it, okay.
Jessica bailed
...and Angela's got the stomach flu,
so Eric's taking care of her.
So, it's just us three.
- Great.
Great.
- Yeah.
Put the gun down.
Put your gun down or I'm gonna
blow your freaking head off.
Put both of your guns down or I'm gonna
blow both of your freaking heads off.
Alright, let's do this!
Okay, I think I'm gonna throw up!
Jesus!
- What a marshmallow!
You should hold out for someone
with a stronger stomach.
Someone who laughs at the gore
that makes weaker men vomit.
Yeah, I'll keep my eye open for that.
I feel bad. He probably has
that flu that's going around.
What? I can't hold your hand?
- No, of course, you can.
I just think it means
something really different to you.
Okay, tell me something.
You like me, right?
And you think, I'm sorta beautiful?
Jake, please...
don't do this.
Why?
Because you are about
to ruin everything.
And I need you.
Well, I've got loads of time.
I'm not gonna give up.
I don't want you to.
- But...
It's just because I don't want you
to go anywhere.
It's... it's really selfish.
You know, I'm not like a car
that you can fix up.
I'm never gonna run right.
So I should be fair to you.
It's because of him, right?
Look, I know what he did to you.
But, Bella, I would never,
ever do that.
I won't ever hurt you.
I promise.
I won't let you down.
You can count on me.
Well...
I need to go home.
I'm... I was feeling sick
before the movie, okay?
What is your problem?
Right now?
You are my problem.
Feeling sick?
Maybe you need to go to the hospital.
Do you want me
to put you in the hospital?
Jake... Jake, the movie's over.
What are you doing?
Jake, you're really hot.
Like, you feel like you have a fever.
Are you okay?
I don't know what's happening.
I gotta go.
That dude is weird.
Jake, Uh, your Dad says you have mono.
He won't let me visit but...
would you call me?
Hey, uh, it's me again. I just...I'm sorry
about what I said at the movie theatre.
I just wanted to hear your voice.
So, no pressure.
Jacob, please call me.
Okay, we should be
back around three.
Look, I don't have to go fishing today.
- Yes, you do.
Yeah, you do. Go.
What are you talking about?
Just be careful.
- I always am.
Those bears won't get
the drop on me, Bella.
My kung foo is strong.
Jake!
You cut your hair off?
And got a tattoo?
Bella...
I thought you were too sick
to come outside.
Or pick up the phone
when I'd call.
Go away.
- What?
What happened to you?
What's wrong?
Hey, what happened?
Did Sam get to you?
Is that what's happening?
Sam's trying to help me,
don't blame him.
But if you want somebody to blame,
How about those
filthy bloodsuckers, you love?
The Cullens.
I don't know what are you talking about.
- You know exactly what I'm talking about.
You been lying to everyone.
Charlie...
But you can't lie to me.
Not anymore, Bella.
- Come on! Jacob!
Look, Bella...
We can't be friends anymore.
Jake, I know that I have
been hurting you.
It's... it's killing me.
It kills me.
If you, may be,
give me like some time.
Don't!
It's not you.
It's not you, it's me, right?
Really?
It's true!
It is me.
I'm not... good.
I used to be... a good kid.
Not anymore.
This doesn't even matter, alright?
This is over.
You can't break up with me.
I mean...
I mean, you're my best friend.
You promised me.
I know. I promised that
I would'nt hurt you, Bella.
And this is me keeping
that promise, Bella.
Go home.
And don't come back.
Or you're gonna get hurt.
Alice...
Things are...
Things are bad again.
Without Jake, I just...
I can't stand it.
I don't see Edward anymore.
Now it really feels like
he never existed.
I will find a place
where I can see him again.
- Bella.
- Laurent.
I didn't expect to find you here.
I went to visit the Cullens, but...
their house is empty.
I'm surprised they left you behind.
Weren't you sort of a, um,
...a pet of theirs?
Yeah. You could say that.
Do they Cullens visit often?
Lie.
Yeah, absolutely, all the time.
- Lie better.
I'll tell them that you stopped by.
I probably shouldn't tell...
...Edward.
Because he's pretty protective.
- But he's far away, isn't he?
Why are you here?
I came as a favor to Victoria.
Victoria?
She asked me to see if you were still
under the protection of the Cullens.
Victoria feels it's only fair
to kill Edward's mate...
...given he killed hers.
An eye for an eye.
Threaten him.
- Edward would know who did it!
And he'd come after you.
I don't think he will.
After all, how much could
you mean to him...
...if he left you here unprotected?
Victoria won't be happy
about my killing you.
But I can't help myself.
You're so mouthwatering.
- Please, don't!
I mean, you've helped us.
- Shhhh!
Don't be afraid.
I'm doing you a kindness.
Victoria plans on killing you
slowly, painfully,
...where as I'll make it quick.
I promise.
You will feel nothing.
Edward...
Edward, I love you.
I don't believe it.
Dad, I saw them!
What's the matter?
- In the woods. They are not bears!
What you mean in the woods? Bells, what
the hell were you doing out in the woods?
They are wolves.
I mean, they're like huge wolves!
Are you sure about that, Bella?
- Yeah, I just saw them.
They were after... something.
Wolves? You saw 'em?
Alright. Well, Harry,
feel like going hunting?
Get some of your guys together?
Sure, yeah. I'll...
I'll just...
I know that those wolves
will be dead.
And Laurent would have told her
I'm unprotected.
Victoria.
I should go to the station.
Yeah, you should...
You should go.
You can just stay in the house?
Bella!
Oh, you scared me.
What the hell are you doing?
- Back up. I'm coming up.
Hey.
Look, look, I'm sorry.
For what?
- I wish I could explain,
...but I literally... can't!
Have you ever had a secret
you couldn't tell anyone?
One that wasn't yours to share.
Well, that's what
it's like for me. Or worse.
You have no idea,
how tight I'm bound.
I hate this.
I hate what they have
done to you.
I mean, the killer part is
you already know!
Bella, do you remember,
when walked on the beach in La Push?
The sto...
The story...
The story about the cold ones.
I guees, I understand why that's
the only part you remember.
There must gotta be something
You can do...
No.
I'm in it for life.
May be we should just
get out of here for a while.
We'll just leave.
Just you and me.
You can do that?
I'll do it for you.
It's not something
I can just run away from, Bella.
But I would run away with you.
If I could.
I gotta go.
They'll certainly wonder where I am.
Come here.
Please...
Try to remember.
It would be so much easier
if you knew...
I'll try, but...
Jake.
Jake, what are you doing?
Wait, Jake.
Jake.
Edward, I'm scared.
You should be.
Really it's just like an old story...
That we're not supposed to
say anything about...
Did you know, the Quileute are
supposed to be descendants from wolves?
Bella.
I need to see him.
He's not in.
I'm sorry, I really need to see him.
- Bella?
What did you do?
Okay, what did you do?
Hey! What did you do to him?
- Easy!
He didn't want this!
- What did we do?
What did he do? What did he tell you?
- Both of you calm...
Nothing! He told me nothing,
because he's scared of you!
Too late, now.
- Bella, get back.
Paul, calm down now.
Bella!
Run!
Jake, run!
Take Bella back to Emily's place.
Guess the wolf's out of the bag.
Alice, is it possible that everything is true?
Fairy tales and
horror stories?
Is it possible that there isn't anything
sane and normal at all?
Hey, I think, we should go back
and see if Jacob's okay..
I hope Paul sink some teeth into him.
Serves him right.
No way. Jake's a natural.
You see him phase on the fly?
I gott a five that says,
Paul doesn't touch him.
Come on in, Bella.
We won't bite.
Speak for yourself.
Oh, hey, about Emily...
Sam's fiance,
...don't stare.
It bugs Sam.
Why would I stare?
You guys hungry?
Like I have to ask...
Who's this?
Bella Swan.
Who else?
So, youre the vampire girl.
So, you're the wolf girl.
Guess so.
Well, I'm engaged to one.
Save some for your brothers.
And the ladies first.
Muffin?
- Sure. Thanks.
Leave it up to Jake to find
a way around Sam's gag order.
He didn't say anything to me.
- That's a wolf thing.
Alpha's orders get obeyed
whether we want to or not.
Oh, and check it out!
We can hear each other's thoughts.
Will you just shut up?
These are trade secrets.
Damn it!
This chick runs with vampires.
Can't really run with vampires.
Because they're fast.
Yeah? Oh, we are faster.
Freaked out yet?
You're not the first monsters I've met.
Jake's right.
You're good with weird.
Sorry.
So you're a werewolf?
Yeah, last time I checked.
A few lucky members of the
tribe have the gene.
If a bloodsucker moves into town,
then the fever sets in.
Mono?
Yeah, I wish.
Well, can't you find a way to stop?
I mean it's wrong.
It's not a life-style choice, Bella.
I was born this way,
I can't help it.
You are such a hypocrite.
What, I'm not the
right kind of monster for you?
It's not what you are.
It's what you do.
They never hurt anybody.
You killed people, Jake.
Bella, we're not killing anyone.
Then, who is?
We're trying to protect
you people from them.
The only thing we do kill.
Vampiers.
Jake, you can't...
- Don't worry,
...we can't touch your little
precious Cullens.
Unless they violate the Treaty.
It's not what I'm saying.
You can't kill vampires, though.
They will kill you.
- Really? We took out
...that leech with the dreads easy enough.
Laurent?
And his redhead girlfriend is next.
Vic... Victoria is here?
- Was.
We chased her all the way to the
Canadian border the other night.
But she keeps coming back.
We don't know what she's after.
- I do.
Me.
Don't worry,
we've got this place covered.
She wont get near you or Charlie.
But you gotta be careful.
She's fast, you don't know,
how fast she is.
You know, your lack of confidence
in us is a little insulting.
Alright, I better go.
And you gotta go.
- Yeah.
I got a vampire to kill.
Alice, I'm alright.
Until I'm alone.
And lately,
that's all the time.
Jacob's gone,
he's hunting for Victoria.
And Charlie is hunting Jacob.
And you're gone.
And so is Edward.
And I just have nothing now.
You got something, Harry?
Nope, nothing.
But I realize where I have to go,
What I have to do
to see him again.
Don't do this.
You wanted me to be human.
Watch me.
Please? For me?
You won't stay with me
any other way.
Bella. Please.
Breathe.
Come on, Bella.
Bella?
Bella, can you hear me?
Jake.
What the hell were you thinking, huh?
- I just needed to see something.
Take her home.
I'm gonna go help over at Harry's place.
What happened at Harry's?
Harry Clearwater
had a heart attack.
Charlie and my Dad are at Harry's place
with his family.
Is he okay?
- He's gone.
Come on, I'll give you something dry
and drive you home.
Hundred and eight degrees over here.
God! My hands are freezing.
It must be nice, never getting cold.
Its a wolf thing.
- It's not.
Its a Jacob thing.
Youre just warm.
You're like, your own sun.
This is better.
Now that you know about me.
But...?
You saw what happened to Emily.
Sam got angry, lost it for a split second...
...Em was standing too close.
He will never be able
to take that back.
What if I get mad at you?
Sometimes...
I feel like, I'm gonna disappear.
You know you don't need me,
to tell you something like this.
But I always will.
You're not gonna loose yourself.
I won't let that happen.
How?
I'll tell you all the time.
How special you are.
Thank you...
...for everything.
Wait!
There's a vampire.
- How do you know?
I can smell it.
I'm getting you out.
That's Carlisle's car!
Theyre here.
Bella, it's a trick. Stop!
You gotta come with me.
They won't hurt me.
If a Cullen is back here,
this is their territory.
The treaty says we can only
defend in our own lands.
I can't protect you here.
- Okay, it's okay. You don't have to.
Youre about to cross a line.
Then don't draw one. Please?
Alice?!
Oh my God!
Bella?
- What are you...?
I'm sorry, I just...
I can't believe you're here. Is...is..
Would you like to explain to me
how you're alive?
What?
- I saw a vision of you.
You jumped off a cliff. Why in the hell
would you try and kill yourself?
I mean, what about Charlie? What about...?
- I didn't try to kill myself.
I was cliff jumping.
Recreationally!
It was fun.
I have never met anyone more prone
to life-threatening idiocy.
Did you... did you tell him?
- No.
He only calls once in a few months.
He said he wants to be alone.
Bella, what is that
God awful wet dog smell?
That's probably me
Or... it's Jacob.
- Jacob who?
Jacob's kind of a werewolf. Ugh! Bella!
Werewolves are not good company to keep!
Speak for yourself.
I had to see if you were safe.
I thought you couldn't protect me here.
Guess, I don't care.
Well, I'm not gonna hurt her.
No, you're just a harmless Cullen.
We're talking about the other
bloodsucker who tried to kill Bella
...because of you.
- Victoria?
Yeah, Victoria has been around.
I didn't see her. I didn't see you
get pulled out of the water either.
I can't see past you
and your pack of mutts!
Don't get me upset.
- Hey, stop!
Things are gonna get very ugly!
- Stop! Stop! Stop!
I will give you a minute.
You're going anywhere,
you're gonna come back, right?
As soon as you put the dog out.
Is he...?
Are there others? How many Cullens are here
and how long are they staying?
No. It's just Alice.
And she can stay
as long as she like.
Are the rest coming back?
No.
Not that I know of.
Anything else?
That's it.
Well, if that's all, then you better go
run back to Sam.
I have done it again.
I keep breaking my promise.
We don't have to do this to each other.
Yes, we do.
Bella...
"Que Quowle"
(Stay with me, forever)
Swan Residence.
He's not here right now.
He's arranging a funeral.
Who is that? What?
- Always in the way.
Who was that?
- Bella, step back.
Jake, who was that?
- Stop.
Bella, it's Edward.
He thinks you are dead.
Rosalie told him,
why I came here.
Why didn't you let me speak to him?
He didn't ask for you.
- I don't care!
Bella, he's going to the Volturi.
He wants to die too.
He left you, Bella.
He didn't want you anymore, remember?
But I'm not gonna let him
kill himself out of guilt.
What about your Dad?
- I'm eighteen,
I'm legally free to go.
And I left a note.
Please, Bella.
Just... stay here.
Not for Charlie.
For me...
I have to go.
I'm begging you.
Please.
Goodbye, Jacob.
Okay.
So you made up your minds?
I'm afraid your particular gifts...
...are too valuable
to destroy.
But if you're unhappy
with your lot,
...join us.
We would be delighted
to utilize your skills.
Won't you consider
staying with us?
You know what will happen anyway.
Not without cause.
Such a waste.
I'm guessing you didn't rent this car?
I figured, you wouldn't be
opposed to grand theft auto.
Not today.
What? What are you seeing?
- They refused him.
So...?
- He's gonna make a scene.
Show himself to the humans.
- No! When?
He's gonna wait until noon,
when the sun's at it's highest.
Alice, you gotta hurry up.
- There's Volterra.
Why are they all in red?
- Saint Marcos Day festival.
They're commemorating the expulsion
of vampires from the city.
It's the perfect setting.
The Volturi will never let him
get far enough to reveal himself
We have 5 minutes.
- I know. Bella? Just breathe.
Alice!?
Bella, you're the only one
he can't see coming.
If I go, he will read my thoughts,
he'll think I'm lying and rush into it.
Where do I go?
- He'll be under the clock tower. Go!
No!
Heaven.
You have to move!
Open your eyes, look at me.
I'm alive.
You have to move!
Bella?
You're here.
- Yeah.
You're alive!
Yes.
I needed to make you see me once.
You had to know that I was alive.
You didn't have to feel guilty or anything.
I can let you go now.
Never like that again.
I just couldn't live in a world
where you don't exist.
But you said...
- I lied.
I had to lie
and you believe me so easily
Because it doesn't make sense
for you to love me.
I'm nothing... human.
Nothing.
Bella, you're everything to me.
Everything.
I won't be needing your services
after all, gentlemen.
Aro wants to speak with you again.
No rules were broken.
- Nonetheless, we should take this
...conversation to a more
appropriate venue.
Fine.
Bella, why don't you go enjoy
the rest of the festival?
The girl comes with us.
- No. You can go to hell.
Come on, guys.
It's a festival.
We wouldn't want to make a scene.
We wouldnt.
Enough!
Jane.
Aro send me to see
what's taking so long.
Just do as she says.
Go ahead.
Are you scared?
Are you?
No.
Hmmh.
"Buon pomeriggio!"
(Good afternoon!)
Is she human?
- Yes.
Does she know?
Then why would...
She wants to be...
And so she will be.
- Or dessert!
Sister, sent you out to get one
and you bring back two.
And a half.
Such a clever girl.
What a happy surprise!
Bella is alive after all.
Isn't that wonderful?
I love a happy ending.
They are so rare.
"La Tua Cantante"
(Your Singer)
Your blood appeals to you
so much...
...it makes me thirsty.
How can you stand
to be so close to her?
It's not without difficulty.
- Yes, I can see that.
Aro can read every thought
I ever had.
With one touch.
And now you know everything.
So, get on with it.
You're quite a soul reader
yourself, Edward.
Though you can't read Bella's thoughts.
Fascinating!
I would love to see if you are an
exception to my gifts, as well.
Would you do me the honor?
Interesting.
I see nothing.
I wonder if...
Let's see if she is immune
to all our powers.
Shall we, Jane?
No!
- Pain.
Stop!
Don't. Please stop!
Stop! Stop hurting him!
Please, please!
Jane?
Master?
Go ahead, my dear.
This may hurt just a little.
Remarkable!
She confounds us all.
So, what we do with you now?
You already know
what you're going to do, Aro.
She knows too much,
she's a liability.
That's true.
Felix.
Please! No, no!
Please! Please!
Kill me... kill me.
Not him.
How extraordinary.
You would give up your life
for someone like us.
A vampire.
A soulless monster.
Just get away from him!
You don't know a thing about his soul.
"Forse n del vostro l'uno l'altro"
(Maybe yours is one or the other)
This is a sadness.
If only it be your intention
to give her immortality.
Wait!
Bella will be one of us.
I've seen it.
I'll change her myself.
Mesmerizing!
To see, what you have seen.
Before it is happened.
Your gifts will make for
an intriguing
...immortal.
Isabella.
Go now.
Make your preparations.
Let us be done with this.
Heidi will arrive, any moment.
Thank you for your visit.
- We'll return the favor.
I would advise that you follow through on your
promise soon. We do not offer second chances.
Goodbye, my young friends.
Nice fishing, Heidi.
Yes, they do look rather juicy.
Save some for me.
This way, please.
Stay together.
Stop! Stop!
You're here.
You can sleep.
I'll still be here
when you wake up.
Bella, the only reason
I left
...was because I thought
I was protecting you.
I needed you to have a chance...
...at a normal, happy life.
It was so easy for you to leave.
Leaving you was the hardest thing
I've done in a 100 years.
I swear...
I will never fail you again.
I'm so sorry.
Charlie's coming.
- Hey!
You okay?
Fine.
Dad, you don't have to worry.
Yeah, last time you said that you took off.
I didn't see you for three days.
I'm really sorry, Dad.
Bella, do not ever do that
to me again.
Ever.
And you're grounded...
...for the rest of your life.
Okay.
I'm not technically breaking
any of his rules.
He did say, I couldn't take a step
inside through the door.
I came in through the window.
He's not going to forgive me easily.
I know.
Can you?
I hope you can because...
I honestly don't know
how to live without you.
Come here.
Once Alice changes me,
...you can't get rid of me.
She won't need to change you.
There are always ways to keep
the Volturi in the dark.
No.
You all know what I want.
And I know,
how much I'm asking for.
The only thing I can think of...
for it to be fair is to just vote.
You don't know what you just...
- Shut up!
Alice?
I already consider you my sister.
'Yes'!
- Thank you.
I vote, 'yes'.
It would be nice to not wanna
kill you all the time.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry, both of you,
for the way I've acted.
And I'm really grateful that you were brave
enough to go and save my brother.
But this isn't a life
I would have chosen for myself.
And I wish that there had been
someone to vote 'no' for me.
So... 'no'.
I vote hell yeah!
We can pick a fight with
these Volturi's some other way.
I already consider you,
a part of the family.
'Yes'.
Why are you doing this to me?
You know what this means.
- You've chosen not to live without her,
...which leaves me no choice.
I won't lose my son.
I'll wait until after graduation...
...to make it easier on Charlie.
I want you to be the one
to do it.
He wants to talk to me.
See, you're still alive for now.
He thinks, it's me keeping you away.
You stay the hell out of my head.
Jacob, I know you have
something to say to me.
But I wanna say something to you first.
If that's alright?
Thank you.
Thank you for keeping
Bella alive when I didnt.
No, you didn't.
And it wasn't for your benefit,
trust me.
I'm still grateful.
But I'm here now.
And I'm not gonna leave her side
till she orders me away.
We'll see.
Hey, my turn to talk.
I'm here to remind you about
a key point in the Treaty.
I haven't forgotten.
What key point?
If any of them bites a human,
the truce is over.
But if I choose it,
it has nothing to do with you.
No... No, I won't let you.
You're not gonna be
one of them, Bella.
It's not up to you.
You know what we'll do to you.
I won't have choice.
- Bella, please come.
Wait.
Is he gonna hurt me?
Read his mind.
Jake...
I love you.
So, please...
Don't make me choose.
Because it'll be him.
It's always been him.
Bella.
Goodbye, Jacob.
- No, you don't speak for her!
Bella, get out of here.
Stop!
You can't hurt each other
without hurting me.
Jake...
He's right.
You shouldn't become
what I am.
I can't do this alone.
Then please just wait.
Just give me... five years.
It's too long.
Then, three?
You're so stubborn.
What are you waiting for?
I have one condition...
...if you want me
to do it myself.
What's the condition?
And then, forever.
That's what I'm asking.
Marry me, Bella.
subtitle by sanggers
(tweaked silentfox's sub)