Mr. Andrus, I have
something for you.
Cablegram, Mr. Andrus.
Thank you.
Want a sleeping pill?
I suppose.
1 1/2 grain or 3 grain?
Tina, who's on duty tonight?
Dr. "Coldeyes."
You going to see him?
No, Tina, I'm going
out by the lilacs
to play shuffleboard
with myself.
Well, you don't have
to be so darn rude.
"...laterally.
"Multiple fractures
of the nasal bones,
"compound fracture
of the right mandible.
Manic depressive..."
Psychosis, compulsive violence,
delusional episodes,
alcoholism, acute and chronic.
Well, you're in a good mood.
Am I?
No.
But you're covering well.
What's bothering you?
The cable that you
received this morning?
So, you finally opened it?
You don't miss much
around here, do you?
What did it say?
Guess you can't afford
to miss much, can you?
Oh, from Rome.
"Everybody is here.
Why aren't you?
"And why do I waste my time
looking for an actor
"to play 4 great scenes
which you, repeat, you,
"could steal with
your eyes shut. Stop.
"Besides, I miss you. Stop.
It's been too long. Stop.
"Have rich part for you. Stop.
"$5,000 for 2 weeks' work. Stop.
"Jet to Rome pronto.
Don't just stand there.
Get going. Kruger."
How many pictures did
you two make together?
7.
And when was the last?
About 6 years ago.
Well, what ended it?
Hate.
Well, that's a long association
to be based on hate.
And love.
Mixed together with
lots of ice and an onion.
The Kruger way.
First word in 6 years.
I've been sick, crazy...
Perhaps you feel it's an act
of kindness on his part,
and you resent it.
Tell me, from what you
know of Mr. Kruger...
Would you say
he was the kind of man
given to acts of kindness?
Kruger?
He wouldn't give you the...
You don't believe
that pitch, do you?
Doesn't matter
whether I believe it.
Do you believe it?
Are you ready to go?
You tell me.
We believe that you've been well
for the last 3 months.
Why are you keeping it
such a secret?
There's a difference
between being well
and being ready to go out.
Now, in our opinion,
you are ready.
What makes you so sure?
I didn't say I was sure.
I said it was our opinion.
Suppose you're wrong?
I hope we're not.
Tell me, doctor,
if I do come back,
will my next cure take
longer or shorter or what?
We never promise a cure.
Pan-American world airways
announces the departure
of flight 14 to Rome.
Passengers will board
the aircraft at gate 24.
All aboard, please.
Hello, Jack.
Oh, hello.
Hello, Lou.
I said, hello, Lou.
I heard what you said, Jack.
I hated you
when you were a star.
You were arrogant
and irresponsible.
The most difficult client
I ever had.
Now that you're nothing,
I still hate you,
only now I can tell you.
That face from the dead.
This way, signor Andrus.
Mr. Andrus?
I'm Ravenski.
How do you do?
Publicity.
Mr. Kruger's expecting you.
Thank you.
I am sure it is him!
And I thought he died years ago!
Quiet! Silenzio!
Start the wind machine.
Turn on the paddle wheel.
Roll 'em!
Action!
Ta-ke me ho-me.
Later.
First we must talk.
I have a-nother li-fe.
A hus-band...
A fami-ly...
And a pro-ud na-me.
There's only one name for you.
On the streets of my village,
they call them--
I kill you!
I hate you!
I hate--
Cut!
Halt!
Print!
Oh--oh, no, signorina!
Signorina Barzelli,
per favore, no, no!
What is she doing?
That's good.
All right, come on, Barzelli.
Come on. Get up.
Get her out quick.
Here, quick, the towels now.
Barzelli, carissima,
you were superb.
A Lily! Get going.
Oh, and, Janet--
any word for me?
I've just the word.
"Nauseating."
Any more constructive
suggestions, Mr. Kruger?
Yeah.
Pretend you're a man.
When you kiss Barzelli,
try not to kiss her
like she was your mother
or your sister
or your gym teacher.
What other good takes
have we here?
Still giving
your leading man hell.
Still making out with
your leading lady?
You dog!
You stupid, stubborn,
no-good bum, you--
ha ha ha!
Oh, Jack!
Ha ha ha!
This is my friend Andrus.
Mr. Andrus, how are you?
He's the only actor
I ever made a friend of.
The only one who ever
told me the truth.
Well, what are you waiting for?
Come on! Next set-up!
Matching over-the-shoulder.
What did you think of it?
The scene?
Mm-hmm.
Terribly original.
Terribly or terribly terribly?
Terribly terribly.
Mmm.
You mean Barzelli?
Well, we don't use her voice,
just her chassis.
Here, we dub all the dialogue.
Well, tell me, son,
how does it feel to be crazy?
Oh, I was afraid
you'd never get out.
Oh, wait. You haven't
got a script, have you?
Janet, give Mr. Andrus a script.
There you are.
Thank you. I--
look, don't expect too much.
I--I haven't read
a word of dialogue
in over 4 years.
Oh, Jack, 4 days
after you're buried,
you'll be better actor
than this little creep.
Jack, drive your Maserati
down to the excelsior.
Clean up, and I'll get you
a suite as fast as I can.
My Maserati?
My suite?
Well, you're in a triple-a
picture, triple-a treatment.
You know, you've got
to make these people
feel you're important,
otherwise, they'll
walk all over you.
Say, how's Clara these days?
Fine. Dying to see you.
Oh, Carlotta's in town.
What a car.
Carlotta's in town.
You just said that.
Is she here by coincidence?
Who, Carlotta?
There is no coincidence.
There never was.
Mr. Kruger?
The cameraman is ready--
come on! Come on, will you?
We're losing the sun.
Buona sera, signore.
Buona sera.
Hello, George.
Hey, George, a taxi, huh?
Say, Brad?
Oh, Mr. Kruger.
Still in Rome?
Mm-hmm.
Well, how long does it take you
to write a feature story?
Oh, it'll be in the issue
coming out tomorrow.
Why don't you pick up
a copy at the newsstand?
You're on the cover.
With my story about
Barzelli and Davie drew?
No.
Why not?
It was a lie.
I don't lie to the press.
I never have.
You lie to yourself,
Mr. Kruger. That's worse.
Mr. Kruger,
you are behind schedule.
I need 2 weeks to finish
shooting this picture.
And I need time to dub.
Every word of every actor.
May I remind you, Mr. Kruger...
You have 2 weeks
to complete this film,
including the dubbing.
After that... Here...
Page 62 of our contract.
I control the dubbing.
You?
Me.
Can I get you something,
signor Kruger?
No!
Scusi, eh?
Scusi.
I've seen movies you've dubbed,
signor Junkman.
You've had your actors
mouthing their words
like mother guppies
gobbling their young.
You give me 2 extra weeks,
and I'll give you
a Maurice Kruger picture.
Don't you want
the best movie you can get?
No.
Don't you have any pride
in what pictures
you put your name on?
No.
The films I produce make money.
And you know why?
Because I'm
an international peddler.
On this film,
I will make 472,000.
Not lira, dollars.
Even if this film never
shows in one single theater.
Provided, please,
that it does not cost me
one lira more than
our contract says.
So, dear friend,
you get no extra weeks.
You get no extra days.
You get not one minute.
You left the set at 7:20.
Where have you been?
With Barzelli?
In her apartment,
or did Tucino lend you
one of his handy hideaways?
You and the tramps
you use for stars.
"Maurice Kruger,
the great lover."
You don't care what they are...
Old or young, thin or fat,
as long as you get your
grubby hands on them.
If you made a movie in
the--in the upper Amazon,
you'd have to make out
with the pygmy queen!
You and that big bounce...
If I ever catch the two of you
together, I'll--
don't forget!
I've got all the proof
from all the other times!
In a box at the California bank!
I could have nailed you for
adultery 10 million times!
And next time I will.
You're not going to get
away with anything!
'Cause I'm going to take you
for every dime you've got!
Every dime, Clara?
You're slipping.
Used to be every dollar.
Now where do you
think you're going?
Down the hall to see Jack.
Jack!
Bringing Jack Andrus
here behind my back!
To feed your ego,
you fly over an actor
you can't even use.
Now, Clara,
I photographed a lot worse.
It's only a little part,
so shut up.
Handing out $5,000 to a man
who wouldn't even look at
you for the past 7 years.
And who could blame him
after what you did to him?
You and Carlotta!
6 years.
Thank you, Clara.
For what?
Well, you've done it again.
You've given me an idea.
The fix I'm in, only Jack
could save my neck.
Save you? From what?
Oh, he'll scream at first.
The way he looked at that camera
today was just pure lust.
But I can handle him.
Always have.
I did have a part for you.
4 scenes you could steal
with your eyes shut.
That's why when you came on
my set this afternoon...
I saw you...
Through the eye of a camera.
Killed me.
Well, it... It looks
like you're stuck
for one round-trip plane fare.
If I could only
dream up something.
Something to keep you with me.
I'll take the first jet.
I'll have the Porter
make your reservations.
If you need any dough--
I don't.
Didn't they say it was
ok for you to drink?
Here you are, Jack.
You and I made some good ones.
Yes, and a couple of great ones.
Looked like there
was a federal law
prohibiting us from
doing anything wrong.
Yeah, it seemed like our
luck would never run out.
Only it wasn't luck.
We had the secret. We told
each other the truth.
Jack...
Now, you could take my cast
into the dubbing room,
just the same as I would,
and you could give this movie
the real Kruger sound.
Let me be absolutely
sure I understand.
On this picture of yours,
are you proposing that
I supervise the dubbing?
That's right, Jack.
That way we could
be together again.
When your cable came,
I couldn't believe it.
You were giving me a new start.
A chance to live again.
When I walked on your set
today, I was home.
Home.
But you flew me 3,000 miles
just to put me on.
Why?
Why'd you ever send that cable?
Well, just because
your doctor wrote
and asked me to give you
a job, any kind of a job.
I don't want your charity!
If I'm through as an actor,
I'm through!
And to hell with you and
the whole murderous business!
And then what?
You stupid, stubborn,
washed-up ham!
Without me, you're a nothing!
Just a nothing!
Go on!
Go back to your crazy
house and stay there!
What the hell
do I want with this?
That's all that's left of you.
Ungrateful pup!
Operator?
Operator, I'd like to put
in a long-distance call.
F-Fairfield, Connecticut.
The Ridgewood retreat.
I-I'd like to speak to Dr.--
Never mind.
Oh, Jack?
You're not going to leave
without saying good-bye to me?
You'd never forgive yourself.
Now, there's plenty
of time for the plane.
Let me buy you a drink.
No, thanks.
A coffee, then.
A farewell Espresso.
Now, you can't deny me that.
In Rome, they dub every
word of every picture.
Dubbing makes or breaks you.
So? You always dub
your own pictures.
I can't.
I'm trapped by a fine
Italian contract.
Now, if you don't
do this for me,
Tucino will.
That's doom.
I need you, Jack.
I need you.
Ha! I knew it!
I knew I could count on you.
And you can count on me.
On every picture
I make from now on,
it's the two of us together.
You'll be my right hand.
Now, you take tomorrow off.
Do some shopping,
take in the sights,
do anything you want,
but meet me at the studio
tomorrow at 6:00.
Oh, I've got a surprise for you.
You're back in
the picture business, son.
Ha ha ha!
Jack...
You're not doing this for me
just because you're sentimental?
Just because I sang you
a chorus of auld lang syne?
I'm helping you
because you "need" me.
What's the money?
Well, what I offered
you in the wire.
The agreed price of $5,000.
Tucino won't pay that
for a dubbing job.
Well, then, I will.
I'll pay it out
of my own pocket.
Now, I won't let you
do this for nothing.
I know you won't.
Because it is
out of your own pocket,
because you are in a mess,
I don't want $5,000.
Oh, please--
I want 10,000.
♪ Should auld
acquaintance be forgot ♪
♪ And never brought to mind ♪
♪ Should auld
acquaintance be forgot ♪
♪ For the days
of auld lang syne ♪
♪ For auld lang syne,
my boy... ♪
♪ For the sake...
...Poor player
that struts and frets
his hour upon the stage...
Turn that off and get out.
I want to get some sleep.
Tucino, you
international peddler!
Take a good look
at a movie that was made
just because we couldn't
sleep until we made it!
You can't
be a star in a cemetery.
Oh, stop pitching!
Can't you get it through
your head I'm one girl
who doesn't want to be a star?
Because he was
a drunk, you're a drunk.
Because he loved women,
you're a tramp.
But you forget one thing.
He did it with style.
I said, turn it off!
I don't want to hear it!
I hate him!
Make up your mind.
You hate him, and you
build this shrine to him?
He died over 10 years ago,
and you've been holding your
own private wake ever since.
Well, let me tell you something.
The acting isn't good enough.
It's a cheap performance
of a bit player.
Shh!
...Until you can pull
yourself out of this tomb!
Until you can see people
as they really are!
Until you can do this
to your father's picture!
...Poor player that struts...
And laugh! The way
he would have laughed!
That's not a god talking,
Georgia! That's only a man!
Oh!
You!
Miss Morrison?
It's all right, miss curry.
Kruger...
You're great.
I was great.
Ha ha ha!
Why'd you do it, Georgia?
You know why?
Because I--I was afraid I'd...
Oh, Jack, when I
think of all the years
we've thrown away.
Maurice, it's getting late.
Such a waste.
And for what?
Maurice, we've got a lot
of work to do tonight.
Oh, yes, yes, Clara.
I'll have to be up
until 3:00 rewriting.
Not again!
Georgia, come here.
Trying to give tomorrow's
scenes some life.
For once, Mr. Kruger,
just for once,
can't you leave a scene alone
until you see us play it?
Before you rewrite it into hash?
Nauseating little creep!
He's crazier loose than
you ever were locked up.
Oh, uh, Jack...
Take the sound of this movie
into the dubbing room tomorrow.
The real Kruger sound.
Mr. Andrus,
we'll run the rough cut
of all Mr. Kruger's shots
so far at 9:30 A.M.
We'll run it at 10:30, Janet.
But, Mr. Andrus--
10:30.
That's too bad.
Why?
Because I'd
make you a good wife.
Well, right now,
I don't need a wife,
I need a star.
It's cold now
sitting on the ground.
All right, let's go
in by the fire, shall we?
Hey, I thought
everybody had gone.
Everybody has.
How'd you like it?
Loved it. I thought
I was great.
What did you think of it?
I hate films.
Why?
Oh, when I have 2 hours,
I like to spend them my own way.
Not up there with them.
Why are you here with "them"?
A friend brought me.
He wanted to see your film.
He had to leave.
Why'd you stay?
You made me want to.
No, not me.
That was John Andrus.
Not a bad actor when he
had the right director
and a part--
what's the matter with your eye?
It's nothing.
Oh, do you have a car?
Yes.
I'd like a ride back to Rome.
Ok.
What's your name?
Veronica.
Veronica what?
Veronica
what's-the-difference.
Idiots. They never
look at anything.
Jack!
You just said that.
They told me you look marvelous,
darling, and you do.
You look so healthy.
You look so rich.
I am.
Married at the moment?
Not exactly.
But he's naming an oil tanker
after me. 60,000 tons.
How's buster?
Poisoned.
Buster was bound to be
poisoned sooner or later.
I suppose.
I still have the house
on the hill, Jack.
I've told you how you
look to me, darling.
How do I look to you?
Carlotta!
Did you get my message?
The operator didn't
quite understand it,
but you will.
Carlotta!
Suite 160.
How do you do?
You didn't answer her question.
How did she look to you?
Beautiful.
Who's buster?
A dog.
What kind of a dog?
Doberman.
She made him sleep
in her bedroom.
So?
Only he didn't sleep.
He growled, and he snapped.
So?
So that's why
somebody poisoned him.
Oh.
Was it hard to divorce her?
She found ways to make it easy.
It was damn hard.
It was about 3:30
in the morning...
Pouring rain.
I was drunk...
What are they screaming about?
Oh. Ha ha!
About how much
they love each other.
Very Roman.
So, 3:30 in the morning...
Rain...
Oh, I drove down the hill
from Carlotta's house.
When I got to the last curve,
I must have been
doing a good 90.
How much in kilometers?
Oh, about 140.
Uh... 144.
When I hit that wall.
Maybe it happened
because I was drunk,
maybe I meant to kill myself.
I still don't know which.
Well, I've been
divorced for 3 years.
I hadn't seen her
in 8--8 months.
She'd been in Europe,
I stayed in Hollywood,
watching myself crack up,
and then, that afternoon,
I saw Carlotta
driving down Wilshire.
She--she was wearing
that green chiffon scarf.
We--we always had
a thing about green.
Would you like
another Espresso--
she pulled up at the curb.
She said, "call me,
or just drop by
any hour of the 24."
She drove away.
I tried getting drunk.
Tried calling
the right phone numbers.
There I was...
3:00 in the morning...
Driving up the hill
to her house.
It used to be our house.
I used the gold key
she'd given me
our first Christmas.
The house was dark.
There was only
a light on in her room.
The door to her room was open.
I'm glad you weren't killed.
I'm glad you're here.
Hey, what's this?
Eh, this is interesting. Look.
What do you make of this?
Why haven't they got any faces?
He waits for a client
and then draws the face in.
Huh?
He wants to draw my portrait.
Sure. Sure.
Quanto? Quanto?
6,000 lira.
Cheap enough.
Let's go.
Listen, who knows? You might
be hanging in the Louvre.
Maybe. Ha ha!
Smile pretty.
That's it.
Bene!
Do you know what time it is?
Uh-huh.
So do I.
Hey, when will I see you again?
Will I see you again?
I'll phone.
Oh.
I'll drive you home.
No.
Oh, you have to get
to the studio early.
I'll take a taxi.
Uh-huh.
I said--
I know.
"I'll take a taxi."
Good night, Veronica.
Good night.
Yes?
Yes, Carlotta.
Yes, I found it when I came in.
Look, Carlotta,
you're the one person
I--I don't want to see.
At least that proves
you've been thinking of me.
And I of you.
Every night for
the last 4 years.
I know we can't make up
for 4 years in one night,
but we might try.
Oh, poor Clara.
Janet, I want to run
the whole thing over again.
Contessa,
it's important. Immediately.
Joe, when you get
to the end of this reel,
start at the beginning again.
She's so out of
place here in Rome.
What other angles have we got?
You know Mr. Kruger doesn't
go in for protection shots.
All day long,
he's at the studio,
and at night, he--
all that rehearsing with
Barzelli and all that.
Janet, how long have
you worked with Kruger?
12 years.
Janet, for 12 years,
you've lived vicariously
as "poor Clara,"
"poor Gail," "poor Madeline,"
and the other 2 "poors"
he was married to before that.
And after 12 years,
you still don't know whether
you love him or you hate him.
Mr. Andrus, you shut up!
Why don't we both shut up?
We found him last night
floating in the lake
with a knife in his back.
A family...
A husband...
A proud name.
No, Liz, no,
that's not quite it.
Oh, it sure isn't.
I'm lousy today.
No, no, no.
Say, Liz?
Yeah?
What do you love
most in the world?
Um, food.
You remember
that ice cream parlor,
wheelwright's, on sunset strip?
Those huge
luscious banana splits
a dollar a throw?
Worth every penny.
Well, next time you dub,
you think to yourself,
"we will have
10,000 banana splits.
Huge... Luscious...
Banana splits."
Got it.
Go ahead. Try again.
Ha ha ha! Do we?
You still have not understood.
I have another life.
A family...
A husband...
And a proud name.
Liz, we'll call you tomorrow.
Whoo! I know. Don't
call us, we'll call you.
Arrivederci.
Ready, Davie?
Let's try one.
Say, Davie...
Why'd you run away
in the middle of shooting
your last 2 pictures?
I, quote, cost
the studio millions.
Good.
But that's not why you ran away.
I saw your first movie.
It's beautiful.
You broke their hearts.
Look, is this my
10,000 banana splits?
One trick to set Liz right,
another to straighten
out Davie Drew.
Playing it friendly,
the big brother bit?
Well... I guess that
was the idea, Davie.
No dice.
I'll tell you why you ran away.
You were scared gutless.
You woke up one morning,
and they told you
you were a star.
You didn't believe them.
You knew you were
the same frightened little kid
you were when you went to sleep,
so you ran.
And you've been
running ever since.
You were dead in Hollywood
at the age of 22.
No studio would hire you,
and that's what
you wanted, wasn't it?
You stupid little creep.
You think you
discovered suicide?
I pulled all your idiot
tricks and plenty more.
Only you still have a chance.
Nobody put a gun to your head
and said you had to be an actor.
You wanted it.
Now do your job.
Oh, my job?
Certainly, Mr. Andrus.
And congratulations on
the brilliant performance.
But you wasted your time.
To Kruger, I'm just
90 feet of film a minute.
He hired me for nothing,
he treats me like nothing,
and nothing's what he gets.
You're Kruger's stooge...
And you get... Nothing.
We'll, uh...
We'll get whatever we can.
The best thing you can
get is to get packed.
Mr. Kruger gave you this job out
of the goodness of his heart.
You'd be saving him money if
you took your pay and got out.
Roll it.
Scusi.
Someday, you won't be able
to keep that hand from shaking.
What'll you do then,
go back to the asylum?
Signor Andrus, telephone.
Oh, thank you.
Yes?
Oh, Veronica.
The girl who
left me her picture,
but not her address
or her phone number
or her last name.
Tonight? I have
to come back here.
Work after dinner.
Tomorrow, more work.
Oh, not tomorrow night.
And not Sunday
while only thieves
and policemen work.
You'll pick me up?
At my house.
Well, Trestevari,
piazza Santa Maria, 24.
9:00.
Ok?
I'll be the girl
with the black eye.
Hey, why don't you
stop going around
with guys who
give you black eyes?
Janet, I'll be here for 2 weeks.
I have a job. Roll it.
There!
You and your friend Brad Byrd!
You had him all wrapped up!
I suppose you'll tell me
you haven't seen it!
No, I haven't.
Liar!
With your sense of humor,
you'll probably
find this amusing.
Listen to this.
"Prototype of the obsolete
Hollywood talent,
"now flourishing in Rome
is Maurice Kruger.
Once imitated by all, now
only Kruger imitates Kruger."
I'm not through
this garbage yet, Clara.
What does a $200-a-week
hack like Brad Byrd know?
One year I'm a genius,
the next year, I'm--
all right, then,
read it for yourself
and see what Brad Byrd knows!
"Like the bourbon kings,
"Kruger learns nothing,
forgets nothing.
"The set at Cinecitta
"is a museum
of directorial clichés,
"including the ritual courtship
"of the leading lady.
Current is pneumatic
Sicilian Barzelli--"
there! For
the whole world to see!
You don't even
bother to hide it!
Why should I?
Who in his right mind would
expect me to settle for you,
a worn-out, dried-up,
whining, meddling old hag?
My lawful wedded nightmare,
frustrated and stupid,
sticking your fat nose
into everything!
Day and night!
Every minute.
Clara?
Open the door.
Please, Clara.
Clara?
Clara...
Don't swallow all
those sleeping pills.
The doctor will
just have to come up
and pump out your stomach again.
You know how sick that makes me.
Clara?
I--I look at this film
I'm shooting...
I like it.
What if I'm wrong?
It's another calamity?
Where do I go from here?
Took me 2 years to get
this job, and that was a fluke.
How can a man go wrong
and not know why?
What's happened to me?
Jack looked at my picture.
He hated every foot of it.
I could tell.
What does he know?
What did he ever know?
He's a Jonah and a jinx.
Get rid of him once and for all.
Is it ego?
Self-indulgence?
Or...
Am I just plain afraid?
Oh, my poor...
I've seen the film
you're shooting,
and it's beautiful.
It's beautiful.
Going to meet me tonight?
After your party?
A Roman party?
I'll try to leave early.
I'm happy with you.
And damn lucky.
You're part of my life
I thought I'd lost forever.
Try not to be too late.
When you were a star...
There in Hollywood...
Before Carlotta...
Did you have a lot of girls?
Girls like me?
Not as many as I should have.
Certainly not as many
as they said I had.
What were you like then?
Lonely.
So famous and alone?
Everybody's alone.
Actors more so.
Then why would anyone
want to be an actor?
That's a good question.
Why?
To hide from the world.
Everybody likes to hide
once in a while.
Sure they do. Look
at any movie theater.
What's the audience doing there?
Hiding in the dark,
trading their problems
for mine on the screen.
Actors... What a job.
You know, I used to get up
at 6:00 in the morning,
rush through my breakfast,
jump in my car,
race down to the studio,
get into wardrobe, makeup,
get up on that stage, and
then at 9:00 in the morning
invent the telephone,
win the west, sway juries,
make love to the most
beautiful women in the world
hour after hour after hour.
I thought I had it made,
then, zoom...
I was a star.
Big business.
Hide from the world.
They were ramming it
right up my gut.
Lawyers, agents,
managers, partners.
All grabbing,
carving up my whole life.
One day, I looked at them all,
and I asked myself,
"who are these guys?"
"What are they doing here?
What do they want from me?"
Then, the second question
you ask is...
Who you really are.
Well, are you the face
on the billboard
smeared with lipstick kisses
from shrieking high school kids?
The face that barflies
all want to take a poke at
to see if you're as tough as
the roles you play in movies?
Is that you?
Or are you the face
you see in the mirror?
The face of the guy you've
been hiding all your life.
So, I started running,
living in a crowd,
balling it, lots of laughs,
lots of kicks,
through it all, Carlotta.
I kept running
faster and faster,
and suddenly...
Dead ahead of me...
There was a wall.
Is there an answer?
Does any actor find it?
Some do.
Eh, that I don't have
to worry about anymore.
That's for the Davie Drews.
What will you do from now on?
Finish this job for Kruger.
And then?
Live the future
one day at a time.
See what happens.
"Vin Nobile."
From Siena.
You like it?
Very much.
And I like you very much.
I like girls with black eyes...
Soft mouth...
I'm going to kill you, Andrus.
All right, you scared me.
Now, put it away.
Where is she?
Where is who?
Don't kid me.
I didn't come here
to have anyone kid me.
What kind of a kick are you on,
weed, goofballs, bennies?
How many girls have you brought
to hotel rooms like this?
With her, you must
have made history,
because she couldn't
wait to rush home
to tell me she
was through with me!
What did you do, get her drunk?
How many rotten, filthy lies
did you tell her?
Say, Jack?
Come on, get dressed.
I hate being late.
Oh, wait till you hear my
anniversary toast to Clara.
It's a Lily.
What would you do?
About what?
We're working out
the inner action
how you take a knife
away from a killer.
Well, if the man with
a knife isn't a man,
just a yellow-bellied
little creep?
Well, you look him in the eye,
you walk up to him,
and still looking him
in the eye,
you grab him by his limp wrist.
Don't fight my fights.
I was just going
to break his nose--
in how many pieces?
The little creep.
Oh, my god.
I've never begged before.
I'm begging now.
Give her back to me.
What does she mean to you?
Handy tramp?
Two weeks of company
in another town?
Studio's crawling
with girls like that.
So's the via veneto.
You could pick and choose.
Can't you?
No.
All the stories about me
over here and in Hollywood...
All of the filth...
Most of it's... True.
Till Veronica.
Look, Davie, you didn't
discover first love.
You're not the first one
to foul it up.
I can't live without her.
Anybody can live
without anybody.
I can't.
Is he gone?
Yes.
You're wasting your time
working with that creep.
Just keep him in his place.
Where is that?
At the toe of a boot.
Kick him.
Keep on kicking him.
That's the only way
I kept him in his place.
You didn't keep him.
The girl kept him here.
Hell of a girl.
You know, for a man
who's lived with Carlotta,
how can you be so dumb?
Don't you ever learn?
All women are just pure monster.
Go on. Get dressed.
Creep.
Jack...
Have you ever seen
a billion dollars breathe?
He operates Japanese tankers
with Greek crews
under the flag of Liberia.
Why don't you give up
all this movie nonsense
once and for all?
And do what?
Enjoy yourself
traveling with me.
Under the flag of Liberia?
He's so busy with
his business, darling.
He takes up
so little of my time.
He enjoys watching
other men want me.
Leave it to me.
You need never have
another worry in this world.
Come on! Come on!
Everybody, here!
Come on in!
Quiet!
Quiet, everybody!
Is it ready?
A beautiful--
quiet. Mr. Kruger's going
to make his speech now,
so you go ahead and
get it ready, please.
Friends...
In this day and age...
When cynicism rules...
I plead guilty
to being sentimental.
Is it sentimental to Cherish
wedding anniversaries?
Well, then, I plead guilty.
To enjoy the company of friends?
Guilty.
To propose a toast
to Clara, my wife?
Guilty.
To Clara...
On this, our eighth
wedding anniversary.
A tribute from a pen
mightier than my own.
"You are my true
and honorable wife...
"As dear to me
as are the drops of blood
"that visit my sad heart.
"The hand
that hath made you fair
hath made you good."
Then tell that hand
to stop working under the table!
Hmm?
Makin' out with that big bounce
right under my nose.
Cut it out.
Or I'll walk right out on you!
Now!
And then who'll wipe
your nose and dry your tears
when those lousy reviews
come out?
As for you, drop dead!
Aah!
No! No, please!
No! No! No!
What are you thinking now?
Let's get to the car.
I want to go home.
If that's what you want.
It's not what I want.
When you leave Rome,
take me with you.
Let me go with you, please.
Wherever you go.
Don't let it end for us.
Ever.
All right.
We leave in about 10 days.
You think that'll
make Davie disappear?
Or Carlotta?
Davie?
How long have you known?
Since this evening.
Is he the first man
you ever loved?
Yes.
Must have been
a tough guy to love.
Are you still in love with him?
You didn't answer my question.
I would if I knew the answer.
You'll never find it
by running away.
Are you telling me
to go back to Davie?
I didn't say that.
But you won't take me with you.
I didn't say that, either.
What was the name of that wine?
Vin Nobile.
Veronica...
Come here.
There. Don't cry.
Good evening, Mr. Andrus.
402.
Yes, Mr. Andrus.
Thank you.
Up, please.
Come down later. I'll call you.
Look, Carlotta--
oh. Yes, Ravenski.
What?! Heart attack?
Oh, my god.
Uh--well--how--how
do I get there?
Well, wait a minute.
Wait a minute. Yes? Yes?
Unh...
Get them out of here, please.
Get 'em outta here.
Please.
Unh... It hurts.
It's a harpoon.
We can take you
to the hospital soon.
It had to happen now.
Couldn't wait
another few lousy days.
If I don't finish the picture,
I don't collect my last check.
Without it...
What will happen to Clara?
We haven't enough
to pay the hotel bill.
Kruger's last picture...
Unfinished...
Botched by
an international peddler.
It'll be finished.
Oh, sure, by Tucino.
He'll hire any no-talent hack
who'll finish under budget.
Not by Tucino.
Well then, by who?
By me. The Kruger way.
What do you think I was doing
on our last 7 pictures,
walking in my sleep?
I'll take care of Tucino.
You take care of Kruger.
You know, I've
been faking so long...
I don't think I can feel
what's real anymore.
If I can...
It's what I feel for you, Jack.
Don't die with a lie.
You never felt
for anybody but Kruger.
Now that's the way to talk.
You know, as soon
as you start to die,
everybody's so polite
it's nauseating.
Jack...
Jack, I've got to tell you.
Carlotta...
She wasn't worth it.
It was all over town.
Everybody was talking.
How she was prowling.
So...
I took her to lunch at Romanov's
to read her the riot act,
and I said to her,
"now, Carlotta... You don't
do this thing to Jack.
You're to cut it out
right now."
Carlotta said,
"I'm not cutting it out,
"so why don't you jump
in the pool, Kruger.
The water's warm."
I let her drive me out
to a motel in the valley.
I never could turn down anything
that was handed me on a platter.
How do you know?
You never tried.
Thank you, Jack.
Jack?
Mr. Andrus?
Where's Jack?
Here I am.
Ok.
Call Clara. Ask her
to come to the hospital.
Tell her I'm on my knees.
You'll never be on your knees.
Heh. I know.
Tell her just the same.
Let's go.
Direct my picture, you?
Me.
You're insane!
Matto!
Traveler's checks.
All I have, my last cent.
If I finish one minute
behind schedule,
one penny over budget...
Cash 'em in.
The money's yours.
No word from the police.
He was seen coming out
of the excelsior
last night,
but since then, nothing.
And the airlines?
Nor the buses or the trains.
There's a body in the morgue
about Davie's age,
but it's been there 2 weeks.
I've covered everything
from the dog races
to the Vatican library.
Carlo, dismiss the company.
Si. Until when?
Until we find him--
if we find him.
Take his stand-in,
shoot the rest of the film
of the back of his neck.
I couldn't do that
to Kruger's picture.
Tomorrow morning
at 9:00 precisely,
somebody shoots my picture.
If not you, somebody.
Tucino!
David Drew?
Ah, David Drew,
actor, Americano.
Davie.
Davie!
Hey, what is this?
What about the press release?
We'll figure it out.
Come on up.
We've got to find out a way
to keep Kruger from hearing.
402, please.
Yes, Mr. Andrus.
Well, it's about time.
Where the hell have you been?
What time is it, anyway?
Where were you?
Right here waiting for you.
You know how many people
we've had hunting for you,
combing this town?
What for? Why?
Grab a shower and let's move.
We've got 40 minutes.
Here, you might as well shave
while you're at it.
40 minutes for what?
Mr. Kruger had a heart attack.
Mr. Andrus will finish
directing the picture.
You?
Me.
Hello.
Pronto.
Do you know how?
Well, we'll find out.
Hello.
Look, can I have some breakfast?
Some orange juice and coffee.
Cinecitta studios, please.
So I started thinking.
Congratulations.
It finally hit me.
One more runaway,
and I'd be finished.
Not just in movies.
I'm not talking about that.
Me, I'd be finished--
what's left of me.
That's why I went to your place.
But I didn't expect to wait
all day and all night.
What did you expect?
The answer neatly wrapped?
The riddle of life
and love revealed
in one painless session?
I asked myself who,
of everybody around,
fouled--fouled up
his life the most?
So you came to my place.
I said to myself,
"he's not completely stupid.
Must have taught him something."
Did it?
Not much.
Oh.
I did learn some.
Like what?
Shuffleboard,
the most comfortable
position on a couch,
a few 12-letter words
like "transference,"
"sublimation,"
the look on the face of somebody
who's taken the first step.
Why'd you bring me here?
You've got just 3 minutes
with her.
Why?
Well, for one thing, you can't
entirely dislike a man
who's tried to kill you.
For another thing,
now you've got
just 2 1/2 minutes.
Cut!
And print.
Janet!
Well, did you--
did you call the hospital?
Mr. Kruger's on the danger list.
No visitors.
Are--are you sure
about that take?
Oh, it couldn't be better.
Oh, Carlo!
Carlo!
Davie, would you mind
holding the chips
a little higher?
Mr. Andrus.
Mr. Andrus!
Let's try to play this scene
entirely different.
Play it calm and cool.
Oh, Mario, listen.
I think we can get
a kind of effect
by dimming down the lights
so at the end he's in
complete silhouette.
Mr. Andrus.
She says that Mr. Kruger
promised to rewrite the scene.
Mr. Andrus, she does not
understand English.
Not even one word.
Now you get dressed.
Quiet!
Silenzio!
Mario.
Mario!
Yes, Mr. Andrus.
Oh, Mario, this setup I picked
is terribly original.
Can you do something better?
I have worked for many
American directors.
No one ever asked me
for a suggestion.
Suggestion? I'm
begging you for help.
Ah, well, in this case...
Hands a little higher.
How's that?
Julio, ok?
He say he can see the shoulder.
Oh, very important.
You must keep your shoulders
back at all times.
Well, get to the hospital?
Yes. They wouldn't
let me speak to him.
No phone calls, no visitors.
Mr. Kruger's had
a restless evening.
Mmm, thank you.
Now, then, hands in position.
Shoulders back.
Ah, mama, Mia.
Reaching for the jewelry.
Put the jewelry in the dish.
Now reach in
for the poison ring.
Shoulders back.
She says can't you use
somebody else's hands?
Absolutely not.
Now bring out the ring.
Open the ring.
Reach for the poison.
Now pour in the poison.
Shoulders back!
Reach for the ring.
Open the ring.
Reach for the poison.
Pour in the poison.
Stop.
Turn it backwards.
Hey, Davie.
Yeah?
Stop. Forward.
Now look, see.
See, when she glances
over to you,
she smiles at you.
Yeah, yeah.
What about after that?
Supposing I walk around
in front of her,
pick up the parasol.
Very good.
That's it!
Barzelli, you're wonderful.
Davie, you're right.
That was the way to play it.
Mario, get me some lighting.
We've gotta get this today.
Mario, this has got
to be a Lily,
your masterpiece.
Now how long is it gonna
take you to light it?
Well, an hour, maybe less.
Do the best you can.
Mr. Andrus, excuse me.
This is the way I lined up
the list of the retakes.
Will you check it, please?
So, Jack, how do you do it?
You shoot all day.
You cut and dub all night.
When do you sleep?
While I eat.
Look, reverse 4 and 9,
ah, 4 and 9.
How the hell did
Lou Jordan get on this set?
The voice of the vulture
is heard in the land.
True blue Lou.
So it begins, huh?
They sniff the scent of gold,
the new Davie Drew.
Didn't take them long.
Long?
In 10 minutes, everybody
on the via veneto'll know.
In an hour, it'll be
all over Hollywood.
Mr. Andrus, telephone.
Not now, Janet.
Look, Mario--
it's the hospital.
Uh, hospital?
Oh, Clara, uh--
of course.
I'll be right over.
How is he?
Is he--
Clara?
Carlo!
Mr. Andrus.
I'll be back before
they light up.
Jack, got a minute?
I'm in a hurry.
Too much of a hurry
to make a lot of money?
Lou, some other time.
I'm rushing to the hospital.
Well, I'll walk you to the door.
How long before
you finish this job?
It's already finished
except for 2 days of retakes.
Good. You're available.
I can close the deal now.
You know how much finishing
this picture means to Davie.
Yesterday he was poison.
Today we can pick and choose.
We?
Yeah.
Didn't you know?
Davie made it clear.
On his next picture, you direct.
I've got just the package.
Davie, the number
one best seller,
you.
What about Kruger?
What about him?
You look tired, son.
Oh, I suppose I am.
Maurice, you--
you look great.
You had me so worried,
I was crazy.
They wouldn't let me see you
or even talk to you
on the phone.
Finished under, hmm?
Oh, 2 days ahead of schedule.
When can you run the film?
It's great.
It's just the way you
wanted it, the Kruger way.
Well, then you're
all wrapped up.
Company dismissed?
Not quite.
Why not?
You're not gonna believe this.
I persuaded Tucino to give us
2 extra days for retakes.
Oh, you should have
heard him scream.
Retakes?
On my picture?
Well, what are you
waiting for, Maurice?
You dirty, lying, ungrateful,
double-crossing crook!
You, that he dragged
out of a Broadway gutter
and saved from the nut house,
trying to steal his picture!
Shut up.
What, do you think we're stupid
and we don't know
what's going on?
Janet told us every sneaky,
slippery trick you pulled.
I tried to reach you
every day this week.
Retakes, you call them!
Ha, throwing out
Kruger's best work!
The scenes he wrote
with his blood.
Knifing him in the back
on his deathbed.
Maurice, you can't believe that.
So you finally did it,
didn't you?
It took you 7 years,
but you finally got even
with him for Carlotta!
Shut up, Clara.
Maurice, I want to talk
to you alone.
Never! Never again!
From now on, whoever talks
to Kruger talks to me first.
Maurice, for god's sake--
get off my set
and stay off.
You're washed up.
Maurice, I...
Tried to help,
not steal your picture. I--
Maurice, this may be
the last chance I have
to talk with you.
That's true!
The last chance anyone has
to talk with you.
Don't you see what she's
trying to do to you?
You dirty, lying thief!
Clara!
Take a look at
tomorrow's trade papers.
They've already got the story--
how I had to close
down my picture
and throw you out.
It was too much for you.
You couldn't do the job.
Because you were drunk
and unreliable!
Because you're still
nuts and always will be!
Go back! Go back
to your crazy house!
That's where you belong,
in a nut house!
Well, that is the end
of Mr. Jack Andrus.
Just one moment.
Mr. Andrus.
Mr. Andrus, there's
a telephone call
from the Cinecitta studios.
They say it's very important.
Mr. Andrus.
Tucino's hysterical, Carlotta.
He wants Jack to come back
and finish shooting the picture
the way Jack wants to shoot it,
but I guess the Krugers
pushed the button.
I see.
Look, Carlotta, I know
how you feel about the guy,
but for once in your life,
try and behave yourself,
will you, huh?
Come in...
Jack.
♪ Don't blame me
♪ for falling in love
♪ with you
♪ I'm under your spell
♪ but how can I help it?
♪ Don't blame me
♪ I can't help it
♪ if that doggone moon
♪ above
♪ makes me need
♪ someone like you
♪ to love
♪ blame your kiss
♪ and blame all your charms ♪
♪ That melt in my arms
♪ but don't blame me
Jack!
Racing down your hill!
Seeing that wall dead ahead!
Jack, Jack, we're in Rome!
Not the house on the hill!
Jack!
Aah!
Did I aim at that wall
and try to kill myself,
or was I just too drunk
to miss it?
3 years I've seen that wall.
I still don't know.
Aah!
Jack, Jack!
What a wall!
Aah!
Well, now we know.
Porter.
Alitalia, flight 288.
Where the hell have you been?
They've been calling you
every 2 minutes.
Where's Veronica?
At the plane on the runway.
Lou Jordan says
you turned me down.
You won't direct
my next picture.
Why?
Tell me why.
Here is your ticket,
Mr. Andrus.
Don't you like working with me?
Very much,
and we'll do it again.
But why not now?
I need you.
Don't you ever say that again.
The plane is waiting for you.
You don't need me.
You don't need anybody.
Get that through your head.
I thought I needed Kruger
and I could never work
without him,
but I could, I did.
I thought I needed Carlotta,
that she spoiled
all women for me,
that I couldn't live
without her,
but I could, I did.
I came here
looking for the past.
I found it,
and that hell with it.
I know I'm not off my rocker,
but I've gotta go
back home to prove it.
Now I've gotta prove
that the job we did together
was no flash in the pan.
Look, you know when we're
gonna work together?
When it's right for both of us.
Mr. Andrus, please,
we've got our flight orders.
Veronica.
Cheer up, Davie.
This has gotta last
me a lifetime.
Mr. Andrus, we must take off
or we'll lose our clearance.
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY
U.S. DEPARTMENT OF EDUCATION
AND TURNER ENTERTAINMENT GROUP
CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY
THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING
INSTITUTE, INC.