I asked my grandfather or
substance makes us sneeze
and he said, "Yes, but that you also see a sunset.
'
There was not a day that Grandpa
told me nothing would remember.
That day I woke up and I remembered
the days of the La Paloma.
So I called him later.
I had that many days
to give names.
It happened so much.
On that one day.
Forget the misery.
Forget the depression.
Visit the La Paloma,
Soue Philly's first movie theater
since before the crash.
Completely renovated.
New seats, carpets and
room attendants.
With air conditioning.
25 cents for a whole
day, up to 18 hours.
Special midnight show,
just tonight.
I was almost a teenager.
Now I'm almost middle-aged.
The day of the La Paloma was
Saturday, August 26, 1933.
Remembering dates me
by my grandfather.
There is no milk.
I took a lot from him.
Only his bad habits, "said Mamma.
But he did not.
In those days nobody had.
Not difficult ...
Gennaro is up?
- It was a depression.
Tell him I want to see him.
There is no milk.
- Here.
Grandpa and asking for you.
The refrigerator ran over.
You had them yesterday
but empty?
Drink your milk.
And not so frightened. Chew.
Why do you sweep the dust
under my bed ever end?
Go to your grandpa and give no criticism.
I'm in transition.
She is always in a transition,
but not change it.
Want to see your dime?
- I saw it yesterday.
And then?
I've seen it every day
since the crash.
I think you get it today.
You think all of two weeks.
Sunday was almost there, huh?
Have you already forgotten?
That priest Edmund me the last
rites administered to?
I gotta go.
- Where are you going?
I know until I get there.
Make no mistake, today
is going to happen.
So ... So think of today.
Prove it.
How do I prove that?
- Easy.
Just give me the penny.
If I now give you the penny,
what should I leave
you if I really go?
Then I can leave nothing behind.
You said it's mine when you die.
If you're going to die today,
give it to me today.
I'm not sure if today.
You know until you give me.
What are you talking to?
Mom, if Grandpa dies
today, he ...
God forbid.
How can you say that?
He said it.
Well, if he dies, someone
let me search.
Dad, why do you talk about
such things with the boy?
Who else can I talk about dying?
When I think about it now, I realize
that you must be stupid
to agree that you will get
one penny when he dies.
I was then sure that I've
never given quarter,
because Grandpa would
never leave us.
Are we going to do something?
- I'll take mom to the clinic.
Her teeth look like, because
"r gums festers.
Jeez.
She'll look like a potato.
A fake smile is too expensive.
Look away right now?
- Afternoon.
We have the whole morning.
- Are we going to church?
A wedding?
- Funeral.
Soon we have one.
Grandpa says it is today.
Did you get the penny?
- Would I go to church?
Are we playing field?
- It's too hot.
If I could only go to the movies.
- The church is cool.
This seems like a marriage.
Ma said the niece of our
neighbor has a funeral.
Thank you.
- Over here.
See?
Life on the streets
of Philly Soue
was actually just a movie.
This was a double movie,
burial and marriage.
Before I saw him, I heard
the announcer in mind.
"Forget the misery, forget
the depression.
Visit the La Paloma. '
Who would need it?
It took place before my
eyes a real movie.
Excuse me, but you got
the wrong church.
My neighbor, Victor Sculucci,
married here today.
On the side, please.
Let the family to grieve
in all intimacy.
Daddy, there's a coffin.
What is this a joke?
Get that thing out of there.
This must be a mistake.
Make sure they remove them.
That's bad luck.
How could you call my daughter
at my happiest days?
It must be a mistake.
We booked the church and priest
Rubolina for 10 hours, today.
We. We are saddled with Edmund.
The evil eye.
I am a widow before I'm married.
Where is my Victor?
- What respect for the dead.
Get that fucking thing
out of there.
What is going on here?
Victor, it's a sign. You die.
I? You also still married.
Coffins bring misfortune.
It is not my coffin.
- Ok.
You can remove them
here more quickly.
Let's put them in the alley.
Forget the misery.
Forget the depression.
Visit the La Paloma.
Soue Philly's first movie theater
since before the crash.
Completely renovated.
New seats, carpets and
room attendants.
25 cents for a whole
day, up to 18 hours.
Special midnight show,
just tonight.
H, Gennar.
- Hi, Uncle Joe.
How does Grandpa?
- The road to the fucking beast.
H, you want a banana?
If you buy a horse.
Come here, drink some.
Stupid macaronivreter.
What time does it open?
- 12 hours.
Afternoon?
- Afternoon.
It must have been
the cold water,
but I had an idea or a dream,
I would go home and grandfather
would walk around there
and dad would give me two coins.
But everything was
the same course.
If only I had more in him.
I always walked around,
wasted time.
I wish I 's had taken
time to say:
"I love you, Grandpa.
"Because ...
I really did.
What no?
No, I have no money.
It's crisis, though.
- Where to get a quarter?
I had to go buy bread
and milk on credit.
That is so gnant
I asked the lady of
the assistance
if we get some more, so
we can get by one week.
She looked at me strangely and said that "Ms.
Spirito,
Many use their money to gamble,
to take the train to go to the coast or to the movies.
'
She said the council is considering
giving us even less.
I said, 'That's great.
Less money, we can starve all the same.
'
She laughed.
She's not a bad woman.
- Can I sell something?
Charm not.
Do we have old newspapers?
- I sold them.
Could I find a job?
How much would you get
so much for wax?
I thought you were asleep.
If a mouse in a meelbak.
- Grandpa?
What now?
How can I tell you what
I did with the penny,
if you do not live like
me publishing it?
Then I do not care what
you do with your money.
I think it's not fair, Grandpa.
- What?
You have to die so I can
go to the movies.
Who said I must be dying?
Nobody said that.
Nobody even thought that.
Even to a large opening to
go, I do not want to die?
What is it?
Are you afraid that
if I am dead,
you will have nobody to get
knots out of your laces?
If I die today, you go to
the movies, you hear me?
Whatever happens.
That's an order.
My father died.
- I heard that.
I was 2 years, 4 months,
1 week, 3 days,
6 hours, 12 minutes
and 7 seconds old.
Ma helped me to calculate that.
Please, do not do it
again when I'm dead.
Does it hurt?
- What?
Die. Some suffering.
Old people, I think.
You will suffer?
I suffered enough, I might
die without suffering.
If you are not suffering, you
can still go to heaven?
If there is a heaven,
I go there.
How would it be there?
It is exactly as you
were proposing.
Until now, nobody knows
more than that.
I can not imagine.
Well, tonight I'll send
you a postcard.
I just got an idea
of ​​what it is.
Well, God bless you.
- It's beautiful.
Rest assured that
you will like it.
You see my house?
The house that God built for me.
Is it finished?
You can not call home,
rather it is a palace.
Of what is it made?
It is made of gold.
Of stone.
When you are born, God begins
to build a house for you.
And whenever there is a good
deed, he put a stone at.
If you do something bad,
he takes a stone.
So in my life as I did
more good than bad,
I think maybe my house
is almost ready.
It's ready.
Now I see it very well.
Do not worry, it's nice there.
I'm not worried. I think you do.
Would you push me sometimes in
my grave for a measly quarter?
I did not mean.
Honestly, Grandpa.
I swear.
- Okay, I know.
While you're there,
scratching it 's.
I'm going to earn a penny.
Grandpa knew that if I am not giving
up something in my head.
And he was right.
But there was no one who knew
less than I earn money.
You took the heart that
I gave you ...
and broke in two.
Now someone did the
same with you.
Is not that a hoot?
Well, you're the little prick
who got the reward he deserved.
Heart Breaker with
the broken heart,
you got what you deserved.
You got your salary.
You took the heart
that I gave you
and broke in two.
Now we did the same with you.
Is not that a hoot?
You're the setter who got
the reward he deserved.
Heart Breaker with ...
Hello, Auntie. Go to your mom?
Are you here to sing for money?
Indeed.
- He 's begging.
Not true, I have to entertain.
That is begging.
You make your mother's
name to shame.
I reveals' r name.
There was never a beggar
in our family.
What you got?
- 3 cents.
Enter.
- No.
- I need to earn a penny.
Come on.
- Give.
Maybe God forgives you when
I do a candle burning.
Another one.
God bless you.
You become so big.
How is your mother?
- Same.
I'll take your grandfather tonight after
Mass homemade macaroni salad.
Grandpa said that during a depression
the strong lose their jobs.
The others lose their minds.
On the day of the La Paloma,
I noticed that it was true.
Today no credit.
- I want a job.
I want no credit, but a job.
You know, there are men
who want to arrest,
because you're better off
in prison than in a loft.
There are kids your age
who put on the street by their
own mother and father.
I work all day for two coins.
Until a quarter to six.
In my time working
up until closing.
When do you close?
- Forget it. Fuck off.
Redeem him.
I have not the soap.
- It's my assistance check.
Do you suffer from the heat?
- Cash in him.
Do you hear it.
This certificate plus ten cents
entitles you to a bar of soap
with a picture of a movie star on.
This is not assistance check.
It is my assistance check.
- I would pay you out Saturday.
Redeem him, please.
- It's not a support check.
My children staring through
the window of hunger.
Jeez, she now gives
me a rotgevoel
because my children can eat.
How do I redeem a
ertificate for soap
If I can not even give credit?
Maybe ...
Maybe we can arrange something.
Send your man over here.
He went for a walk.
- If he comes back.
He left four days ago.
Want a job? Bring 'r home.
So they do not go hiking.
- Can they pay me?
I'll pay you.
- A penny?
Five cents.
- Ten cents.
Where do you live?
They stare out the window.
- Yes, but what street?
H, let her go.
Let her go.
She must go home.
And one night ...
she will wake up crying because
she stole some potatoes.
This morning there was a fat
lady in a red dress inside
and stole a bag of rice.
I let her alone.
I can not stand that
fat ladies hungry.
Hold it, stupid ragamuffin.
It could be worse, Mr..
Zavattoni.
Let me see.
Keep your head a little higher.
Good.
Your daughter believes
it was the heat,
but you and I know better.
- Help me get up.
Why?
I do not like lying on the ground.
Who knows what the
cats did here.
You had to be hospitalized.
Let me sit in my office.
Keep a seat.
I'm not finished.
Deep breathe, not talk.
- Since when are you
complaining about?
Deep breath. Still 's.
Here he is, now no
longer needed.
Grandfather.
Now it was almost there.
Help me in my office.
Let him sit.
We bring him upstairs to bed.
I'm not going to bed.
- You're so stubborn
like a mule.
I'm not going to bed.
- Just a donkey.
Do not listen. Ok.
Ok, sit.
- I will die out,
where God can see me.
Shut me about the hospital.
I arrived on the same
boat as your uncle.
Do not start over.
- He worked for ...
You think I'm crazy?
Grab my hat.
You know what I saw
when I was lying?
You know what I saw?
I saw the sky.
Really?
I was no more than
a half block away.
You know how it looked?
It looked ... exactly like ...
The new ... La Paloma.
Do you hear him laugh?
In his condition.
How can a man obey me?
Maybe he listens to you
He just ignores me.
What do you mean by
"in his condition?
It is all in order?
- Keep it out in bed.
Is that all?
- That's it.
Will you pay them, to
tell him to stop bed?
Can you give him any medicine?
If you give him a drug,
I make sure he takes.
Maybe it takes something out.
- It will not.
Maybe ...
it takes something out.
You should especially ensure
that he stays in bed.
The pills should be, because
he refuses syrup.
I do not know.
He says he saw the sky.
I was just a joke, but I
think he'm really saw.
I do not understand
why he has not.
Make sure your mother
will find it.
Shall I try s?
- I can manage.
There.
- Do you have many people visit?
There many people died.
Suppose I have a quarter to six to
wear your bag wherever you go.
I get 20 cents?
- I wear my bag myself.
In this heat?
I just need 20 cents.
With such a face, so stubborn,
you have nothing.
Anyway, honest. Come on.
- Do not.
What is that?
- H, boy, are you crazy?
There are people here.
- My grandson is so rich
he throws away money.
That boy's got a doctor.
I'm so sorry.
- What?
I can not pay sidekick.
My patients gain nothing.
Well ...
I can give you ten cents, if you
want to do some dirty work.
I want to do anything.
- Do not say that.
To anyone for any amount
whatsoever.
Tell me what to do.
My burner is full of ash.
You know where I live?
Where is your office?
Climb by my window, in order
not to disturb my wife.
Put newspapers in the baskets
for you the axle does.
Put them under the window, I will put
them in the garbage Wednesday.
Got it?
You want your money.
Here it is.
Some boys were Dr.
Bruna no. They found him funny.
Until that day I did not
know what that meant.
Ms. Bruna?
Dr. Bruna gave me 10 cents
for the ashes to clean.
Who are you?
- Gennaro.
That's a strong name.
Is that your first name?
Yes. My family name is Spirito.
- Spirit.
Do you speak any Italian?
- With Grandpa when he's drunk.
You're a ghost.
Well ...
I must hurry. Go on up.
The dust creeps into your nose.
If you muzzle, your
black handkerchief.
Previously he hired older
boys in his chores.
I'm old enough. I'm twelve.
Twelve is old enough?
- Listen ...
I must really hurry.
If you do not mind ...
You will not get blisters?
- I have strong hands.
Strong, yes, but not beautiful.
I am a boy.
- Did you see Dr. Bruna's hands?
He has the best hands
in the world.
Yes, he's a good doctor.
Those beautiful hands
never touched me.
Not once.
Nowhere.
If you get pneumonia, he did.
I start now, I need
the money on time.
From six hours is
more expensive.
He touched me was not as
bad as the reason why.
He did not confess anything.
Such disease.
And after the job I need
another ten cents.
With the money I have 15 cents.
- Do you 10 cents?
I have over 10 cents,
on my desk.
Want it?
- What should I do?
Go away.
Get out of here, please.
No, I have to clean up the ashes.
He has already paid me.
Do not go. Go upstairs, please.
Jeez, Tullio, you make me angry.
Did you play all programs with girls?
- They are too bossy.
No, I mean play.
Have you's done?
Do not just watch?
- No, just watch.
Why do you think about it now?
- I will not.
Would you do it for 10 cents?
What?
- You know.
Would they give you 10 cents?
It is a sin, paid or not.
- Who knows?
Saturday I will go to confession.
- Let her confession.
Then do not you do more.
Gosh, I do not even
know what to do.
You want me to go, huh?
- Do you?
A lady?
How old?
- A lady, so old.
A mother?
- She has no children.
Her husband did not hurt his hands.
Shut up about it.
She has tested just how
much money I wanted.
If I could go, we will
share the money?
Share?
With 5 cents, I can do nothing.
I share the sin, including
the money.
What did you do that?
- Something from last summer.
I want to share.
- Gennaro, wait.
Come on.
- But we ...
Call her.
- We're clearing the first axis.
I did not ...
- When she hears noise,
she comes.
You want the hair that
God sees sin.
I'm sorry I let you come.
Did come?
Turn on the light, wall
underneath the stairs.
Go along.
- Damn.
I did not tell the grandfather,
by his weak heart.
But my mother was gone.
He did not utter a sound.
He gave me a safe feeling.
He said it was not my fault.
That he kept repeating.
Did you hear what
I told grandpa?
Really, Mom, I just wanted
to clean up the ashes.
No, that's not true.
Go back to sleep.
I tell you ok grandpa are.
Did my grandfather
sneakers again?
What's wrong, Mom?
He sits all day every
morning in the Sun
You'd think his face would
get some color.
In the shadow you see his face
paler than yesterday.
As if the sun went by
without him noticing.
What kind of world is it if not what
color you get from the sun?
Ma?
I have insurance classification
last month.
What does this mean?
That I do not penny
more to give.
I do not want.
- Yes it is.
For once you are wrong.
- I'm not mistaken.
You want to film, anyway.
It does not mean we are poor
and crazy women scare you.
You have something in your head
and you notice that others
do not have a breakdown.
You only think, 'I want, I will.
'
And you do not realize is
that nobody can give you.
Give me a towel.
Do you cry when you're mad?
- You should cry.
Why, you do not want a dime?
Why not?
Because you do not get it?
I can cry my whole life.
I never heard you talk.
Now I believe you are sitting
in the transition.
Come here, scamp.
You know what I'm saying?
I say I'm not a penny. Get it?
I can not give. But you want it.
Who says?
- Your mom says.
Why you are so smart.
- Come on.
And I'm not smart.
Your father never said I was smart.
Otherwise, he said that,
for he never missed anything.
Will you give me a
glass of water?
After we buried him, I sat
here crying for weeks.
I did not utter a sound.
But I sat here crying like
a deaf mute girl.
No sound.
They said: 'You should care for your child, you put over it.
'
I said, "I can not help it.
I want my husband.
I want him to come through the door and ...
"You know.
I always had a dream.
He saw me sitting there, in
black, crying like a fool,
and he said, "Why are you crying?
I'm not dead.
It was a joke.
I was in Atlantic City. '
And we laughed and laughed and ...
God ...
I wish that dream was real.
God, that I wanted so badly.
Little by little she
helped me on top
and I saw that it does not
feel like the impossible.
But when I finally said, 'OK,
it's impossible "...
You know what happened?
I never had that
beautiful dream.
And from that day,
God how I beg before
I go to sleep,
I can not dream of him.
If you give me 's would not
interrupt you for flies,
you would know that I no
longer need the penny.
I only need 10 cents.
Then you have 15 cents.
Go buy me a can of tomatoes.
I know you've hidden some
money somewhere.
It would be in summer school,
because then children make
their parents crazy.
What am I?
I get even more glass of water?
Someone to talk to?
- Okay, Dad, you slept.
Watch out.
This may be the last glass
of water that brings me.
Bring him and talk to him.
- It's five hours.
I still earn 10 cents.
- Use your grandfather talk
be nice, and I'll give
you ten cents.
Promised.
- Yeah, right.
Look at me.
I once broke a promise?
Well, that all mothers do.
Come on, come on.
It's coming.
Put it down there.
Come talk to me?
- Until I aanheb my sneakers.
Your mother said you had
to do with me talking
not until you're wearing sneakers.
- Your ears miss nothing, huh?
I know one thing.
If I have five minutes to die,
you would not get your quarter.
- Why not?
Because ...
you want to do me a favor.
Who says?
- Do you?
What?
I mean, sure, but what then?
I've been here one whole
day to think ...
Especially since this
is my last day.
I need someone for a favor.
Not your mother, who would
drop dead of shock.
I must therefore ask you.
- Well, ask me.
Take care, it is not easy.
You must ask me first.
- That's the hardest.
Ok, come here. Sit down here.
When I was a young
man, 17 years old,
I came here with my wife.
I know.
- She was my wife.
She was a girl I
met on the boat.
I always call her my wife, even
though we were not married.
And then?
- Well ...
In my hometown, Abruzzi,
The men had a saying.
And that means ...
"If a man is virgin on
his wedding night,
he remains a virgin throughout his life.
'
Can men than virgin?
Will you ever interrupt me?
- Continue.
So ...
as my wedding night approached,
played again by saying
that my head.
I could not touch
your grandmother,
because I wish they were immaculate
as they walked to the altar.
But I was still a virgin.
I had to do something.
I started looking around for the
good of your grandma, and ...
I found a girl ... Guendolina.
Guendolina was much
older than I,
but very frail.
As slender as a doll
in a shop window.
Anyway ...
I will keep the story short.
I told her I was engaged.
I let her believe that ...
if they treated me well, you
know, I 'r would marry.
She gave herself to me.
Do you understand?
When I married your grandmother.
That was bad of me.
It is the only sin I
have ever committed,
I could not forget.
Have you ever confessed?
- What could I confess?
I committed the sin
against Guendolina.
A priest forgive me.
That's his job.
But Guendolina ...
I am playing with the idea that
she has never forgiven me.
Have you ever asked her that?
That's what you do for
me before I die.
That's the favor I ask.
- I?
She lives in ...
Norwood Street, 6 ... 4 ... 3.
With her two sons.
- Maybe they moved.
She is not moved.
I have often thought to
go himself, but ...
it never happened.
And now I can not remember.
You must do it for me.
Well? Do not do it?
- Absolutely not.
Please, Gennaro.
Do not let me die with
this on my soul.
Look, it's simple.
You just go to her and says:
"I'm Gaetano's grandson.
He sent me to say that he regrets what he did.
'
She remembers you down anymore.
She remembers me, believe me.
After what happened to her, by me.
- What happened?
You're too young.
Where you going?
I'm not going to her.
- Come on. Gennaro, come on.
Tell me what happened.
Ok, come here.
A few years after
this happened ...
Guendolina had handled
her disappointment
and married.
It is obvious that her
future husband ...
thought he was married
with a clean girl.
But ...
on the wedding night he
discovered the truth.
Who told him?
Nobody should tell
a man something.
He hit her. Very.
He hit all her front teeth.
She never got a false tooth.
- Then she looks like a potato.
Ok, now go. It is getting late.
I'm Gaetano's grandson and I
must say that he repents.
From what he did.
- From what he did.
Would you forgive him?
Wait, wait.
You're right.
I have to walk.
- I did not say.
No, I have.
Until Norwood Street?
That you never get.
I'll lean on you, to your door.
I'm not going inside.
- Up to the door.
Forget it, Grandpa.
Sit down to catch his breath.
I'm going down.
Maybe God still places
a stone on my house.
What, Dad?
Stop singing that song.
What song? I do not sing.
- La Golondrina.
I know La Golondrinaniet agree.
My heart does pain.
That was the secret that
Grandpa carried.
It was already after 5 hours,
the La Paloma had to wait.
There was almost nothing.
I just had to say he was sorry.
Guendolina live here?
But for a reason.
To her neighbors life miserable.
I hope you have a good reason.
My grandfather sent me.
- It's good.
If your grandfather is the pope.
I want to speak Guendolina.
I have something for her.
- What? I will give her.
I have to do, it's a message.
My mother is the supper.
Briefly. Then grandpa die happy.
We could always get along well.
He ran inside.
Sit down. Give Mom her food.
What do you want?
Who are you?
- I'm Gaetano's grandson.
I had to say he was sorry.
Would you forgive him?
Come here.
Gaetano's grandson.
Eat.
He will carry me.
- I?
Gaetano Zavattoni's grandson.
I gotta go. It's late. Please?
Put it half full.
If you have more brags,
I spit it out.
What did you tell me?
Is sorry. Would you forgive him?
It is almost six hours,
the price rises.
I still have 10 cents to fetch
and say you liked it.
Did he say what he did?
Will you ever do that too.
Boys are born ... to destroy.
Let him go, mom.
You did too much.
But not enough.
Boys are born unclean.
- I do not know.
You are unclean.
- Mom, stop it.
Louis, lure not fight off.
Give Gaetano's grandson
a plate and some food.
No, I do not have time.
Say that you forgive him, yes
or no, before it's too late.
Is he dead?
- For me, I mean.
Kiss me.
Then I'll forgive him.
Give me ten cents.
- Where did you go?
I can not say.
Ok, it's between
you and Grandpa.
Here's your ten cents.
She has forgiven you, Grandpa.
I heard only the announcer:
"Forget the depression.
Soue Philly's new cinema.
New seats, carpets. '
I ran as fast as I could go.
Nothing could stop me.
That was it.
Philadelphia's newest cinema
After what had happened,
I had no sense anymore.
Ma was probably right.
If I did not get my way,
anyone in the tree.
But that place was something
I did not come loose.
I went back and stared at it.
But now it seemed so far away.
Grandfather.
Grandpa?
For my grandpa
Grandfather.
Are you there?
What do you do when our
heart is breaking?
I do not know.
- The doctor wants a blanket
for your grandfather. Bring him.
Is grandpa ok?
Yet you went to La Paloma?
- The price was increased.
50 cents.
I only have a quarter.
Well, if there is
a midnight show,
you will certainly get.
I looked at the stuff
in your room.
And what did you steal?
I love you, Grandpa.
Get that blanket away.
I sweat out of me.
you can never do what
the doctor says?
I do not even listen
to my real doctor.
He is here simply because
the other his wife ...
Where's your mom?
- In the parlor, to cry.
Ask her if she can stop
crying long enough
coffee for me to continue.
He is one of the guys ...
who saw the woman hanging there.
He found her.
He is so scared.
He does not know how
scared he is.
Someday he a lamb hanging in
the window of the butcher
and vomiting.
The onlookers will say:
"What's that guy? He left. '
Dad?
Want coffee?
Are you sure? Ok.
If he wants coffee,
he can go to bed.
No bed.
- You can not lie.
Please, no.
- What if it rains?
Then we need umbrellas on him.
Joe, are you there?
- Yeah, Dad, here I am. What?
I want to apologize
for what I did
that your wife was
such a curmudgeon.
Nice of you, on your deathbed.
- Sorry. Come, give me a kiss.
Put him up.
Where is the nurse?
- No ambulance.
The doctor knows best.
- Send him away.
Send him away.
- Get out of here.
My father gets what he wants.
Leave him alone.
We will take turns to sit
with him to talk to him.
Place a large coffee.
Get seats to sit on.
Go home, you. And ...
Tell your cousins ​​to their
father and I stay here,
they do not have to wait.
Want a piece?
- No, thanks.
When I think back, I could
hardly understand
how one could have fun,
dancing, laughing,
while the world was so poor and my
grandfather was sick at home.
I was that day as adults.
Everyone does his best.
The beauty of life is
that it continues.
Our Father which art in heaven.
Hallowed be thy name.
Thy will be done ...
No, Your kingdom come.
Thy will be done on
earth as in heaven.
Grandpa?
She promised that she would
not let me close my eyes.
You see, you can not trust them
once they reach adulthood.
Would you stay here, Gennaro?
Keep my eyes closed.
You promise?
Okay, Grandpa.
As I close, save me.
- Ok.
But lettuce is not too hard, because ...
I'm not that strong.
Grandpa?
- What now?
Only people to die?
Dogs and cats die too.
I do not mean.
Lamps die.
- I mean other things.
The things inside us.
You mean the feelings we have?
Yes, they die too.
- No, just people dying.
Jeez, you ask me a question
because you know the answer
and then you give me the answer,
as if it was I who asked
the question.
I'm sorry.
The things we die too.
How do you know?
You think all I say is
true because I die?
No, I knew it before.
Please, let me die crying.
Can I sleep here tonight,
besides you?
Are you afraid that you
do not get dime?
I did not need, Grandpa.
What did you say?
Really, I do not need it.
- Why?
Why did not you need?
- I do not want the movie.
You no longer require,
that is something else.
- What 's the difference?
It is an enormous difference.
Your belly needs.
Your heart desires.
That's the difference.
What's wrong with you?
You stand under the same
cloud as everyone else?
You're twelve years old.
You can also run faster
than any cloud.
I did when I was your age.
I wanted to come here, that I wanted
more than anything else.
Everyone said, 'No, I can not.
It is impossible. '
But here I am.
In what kind of world
I live today?
Someone should just say something
is impossible ...
and then nobody wants it yet.
As if ...
longing for something
impossible ...
impossible.
Why do you talk with
your eyes closed?
I had to promise you.
You must promise me one thing.
Will you do that?
- Why not.
Wish.
What do I desire?
Open your eyes, Grandpa.
I'll hit hard.
Grandpa?
What is it?
Dad?
- What did he mean?
I promised him something,
but I do not know what.
Come on.
Pa.
You must not stay, Gennaro.
You do not need such images
in your head prints.
Just go to my house.
Thank you, Grandpa.
You know how it looks above?
It looks like La Paloma.