And you instigated the murder
of former Prime Minister Kang Seok Hyeon
On those charges
I am reporting against you.
What kind of situation is this?
Aigoo...
Oh my!
Admit your crimes now.
You instigated the murder of the Prime Minister
and you gave the order to abduct the child.
What are you talking about now?
It's true that I met Doctor Im,
but I went that night
because I was feeling ill.
The doctor's office was closed. My primary-care physician is a
quack, so I saw Eun Gang's primary-care doctor for a short time.
How does that turn into
instigation of murder?
Wait a minute.
It isn't true he ordered
the child's kidnapping,
because the child Il Joo brought
isn't Shin Eun Soo's child.
What is this nonsense going on?
Is that true?
Quiet, please.
Quiet or whatever!
Hey, did you have our father killed?
Come here!
Honey. Please stop.
Order! Order!
The court is adjourned. Clear the court!
Hey, you punk! What kind of son
goes around finding evidence his father is an
instigator of murder? Don't you have a conscience?
No, I take after my
father, so I don't. Why?
You taught me since I was a kid.
The weak fall prey to the strong,
and the world is a jungle.
Don't have sympathy for the weak.
Don't even shed a tear.
You beat that into me.
Yes, you bastard. I'm still your father!
I suffered through everything and came this
far in order to pass everything down to you.
How can you do that to me?
Are you crying, father?
A man can become weak after all.
I think your innocence was proven.
I think it'll be hard to put
Kwon Soo Myeong behind bars.
That guy... I expected him to be shameless,
but I didn't know it would be that bad.
We can't put him behind bars with
just Kim Gyeong Min's testimony?
Not to that extent.
Because he's denying even knowing about it.
Along with stealing Prime Minister Kang's
slush funds and laundering the money,
that's hard to pin on him unless Moon Seon
Ho makes a declaration of conscience.
The most important thing is to investigate the
Prime Minister's murder. We have to reveal it.
You heard it.
He won't even admit that he
met the attending physician.
Before we catch Im Dong
Jun, it'll be difficult.
Il Joo even sacrificed herself to do that.
You try.
- No, I don't want to.- Why?
That doll looks impossible to grasp.
What if I really want it no matter what?
You can just keep trying
until you run out of coins.
And what if I still don't get it?
Then, it can't be helped.
We can't break the machine
just to get a doll.
I'm afraid I'll want to do that.
What?
What are you saying...
should we try once more?
Are you done?
Let me see.
Go to the karaoke room, take sticker
photos, go to the amusement park.
Oh, this is the same. Pitch
a tent and camp out.
This one, too. Backpacking
trip around the world.
Oh... Yeah!
To be honest, I've never done
these with any of my friends.
Me neither.
As you know, I'm everyone's enemy at school for
living in the same house as Jin Hyeong Woo.
So what I'm saying is, I like that
you're here because you're my friend.
Wow. But doing all this
will take about ten years.
Everything written down here,
we're going to try everything.
Yes. Let's do it.
How about this? Bungee jump?
No, let me think about that.
My heart... bounce...
- No...- Bounce
Il Joo.
I told you to come to the house,
why did you want to meet here?
Because of Mi Rae, it's still
awkward to see Il Do and Il Ran.
I talked to the family members already.
Don't worry.
I'll go before I turn myself
into the police tomorrow.
Now, I just want to meet you alone.
Why did you do it?
You didn't have to do that.
My Mi Rae is also certain
that you didn't do it.
I felt like I wouldn't feel comfortable.
As my father said,
I don't want to live my entire
life carrying embarrassment.
Now that I think about it, Eun Soo, I must
have been messed up since I was little.
If there was something I wanted, I had to
have it even if I broke something else.
Mom tried her best to raise me.
It must have been because
I grew up so lonely.
I understand it all now, Il Joo.
Someday,
after I pay for my crimes,
will we be able to go back to the
dreaming mind like in high school?
We can go to karaoke rooms together,
pitch a tent, and camp out.
And we go on a backpacking
trip around the world.
I'm sorry, Eun Soo.
I have no friend other than you,
but I am so sorry toward you.
Why did we live like this?
Look here, Prosecutor Jeong, wasn't it
decided I'd be indicted but not detained?
But why do you keep calling me here
and being bothersome? I'm a busy man.
You must have heard from
your Chief Prosecutor.
What Jin Hyeong Woo said was true.
You stole Prime Minister Kang's money, fabricated
the evidence, and laid the blame on Shin Eun Soo.
Do you have evidence that I did that?
Jin Hyeong Woo could have that money, too.
This young guy has no manners.
Can you make your way in
career if you act this way?
Prosecutor Jeong, let's keep it simple.
Don't try so hard without any
evidence, and go easy at the trial.
Do you think I studied my ♪ss off
to make these kinds of deals?
He doesn't seem to
understand what I'm saying.
Do you have any evidence that I did that?
Prosecutor, someone is here to see you.
Who might you be?
I am the evidence.
I am the launderer for
Kwon Soo Myeong's money.
From nine years ago until now.
And framing Shin Eun Soo, I
did that on his instructions.
You must be crazy. Pull yourself together.
If you do this, do you think you
won't be punished under the law?
If I was afraid of that,
would I have come here?
Let's die together, Kwon Soo Myeong.
Why did he report you?
There's even word that you instigated the murder of
former Prime Minister Kang Seok Hyeon. Is it true?
Everyone step back!
President Kwon, just say one word?
- President!- President,
please say something.
- Please say something!- President!
President!
President Kwon Soo Myeong of Taepyeong
Daily News was charged today.
President Kwon was arrested on a charge of smuggling
astronomical amounts of money out of country
and making a false accusation
of instigating murder
against the late Kang Seok
Hyeon's widow, Shin Eun Soo.
The person who revealed President
Kwon Soo Myeong's criminal activities
was revealed to be someone named Moon
Seon Ho, who laundered his money.
Moon Seon Ho is being imprisoned
along with President Kwon—
Who is Moon Seon Ho?
More important, what happened to the
instigation of Father's murder?
Be quiet so we can hear.
The former Prime Minister's family insist President
Kwon was the one who instigated his murder,
but the Prosecutors have revealed that
that they have no evidence of this.
The key point is whether they can catch
the former Prime Minister Kang Seok Hyeon's primary
physician, Im Dong Joon, who fled to Singapore.
I understand what you said now.
I'm sorry.
Now I'm going to leave that path.
I'll take a few years.
I'll be back, Father.
For all this time, I've
been sorry and thankful.
I'm going.
Where are you going now?
Hey, where do you think you're
setting foot? Get out immediately!
You don't really want to
turn yourself in, do you?
Why?
How could we be on such different pages?
How could you betray me?
Don't you know that your
father killed mine?
- What's that? - Oh, that psycho. Hey!
- Shut up. - Oh, my, what?
It should've been enough that I
protected you from my father.
I would take over Father's position,
and we could live happily forever.
That was the plan.
The Il Joo I've seen till now; glance,
expression, words, actions.
All of them told me that!
I already sent the divorce
papers to the attorney.
Please take care of it with the attorney.
Divorce? You want to divorce again?!
Did I kill your father?! How? How?!
How?! How could you abandon me?! How?!?!
How could you abandon me?!?!?!!??!
LET GO!
IL JOO! IL JOO! LET GO!
LET GO! TAKE YOUR HANDS OFF!!
LET GO!! LET GO!!!!!!!
I'm talking about Mi Rae's dad. I didn't expect him to
voluntarily step forward even allowing himself to be charged.
I felt like I should at least say something, so I
went to visit him in prison, but he won't see me.
But right now... what is this feeling?
He went to jail, which he had tried to avoid even
by changing his identity and losing his arm.
He struggled a lot because of
his unfortunate childhood.
His life was put up as collateral to Kwon
Soo Myeong, so he was controlled by him.
I can't help but think his life
must have been exhausting, too.
I'm foolish, to think this, am I not?
No.
This is how you originally looked.
Innocent and nice.
He would've liked you before too.
That's why he returned and
became a witness for you.
Hey, hey, look here.
You think this is fit for a person to eat?
If you aren't satisfied with it,
you'd better buy your own food.
There is not much difference between this and
that. That's not fit for a person to eat either.
I've never seen such small
and tough meat in my life.
Is this some kind of hotel?
You're in prison.
You rascal... do you know who I am?
I am the boss at the greatest media company,
who holds and controls Korea under his thumb.
But you're in prison now.
Ah, whatever. If you're not going to
eat it, give it back. I'll take it.
It's fine!
What are you doing, not using the
perfect lawyer's reception room?
I am sorry about that. Because of the public
opinion, we can't use the lawyer's reception room.
Anyhow, these people don't leave
anything that helps me alone.
Anyway, when can I get out of here?
I'm dying here! Get me out of here!
The lawyer group is working
on the upper authorities.
And our side of the assemblymen
is covering the petition as well.
Please endure until the trial.
You'll be released on probation.
That's a given!
No matter how I think about it,
the trial date is too far away.
How can I stay here until then?
Do whatever you can to move the date up.
I'll do what I can.
Why doesn't Moo Hyeok visit me, his
father, even once while I am in jail?
Can I ask why you changed your mind?
Like you said, I'm only trying to repay
that woman back for seven years ago.
Is the egg hitting the boulder going well?
Thanks to you I was halfway successful.
But in order to have him get all of his
due, there's someone we need to find.
Are you talking about that
primary-care physician?
He ran away to Singapore.
When I looked into you, you
also emigrated to Singapore.
Could you tell me about that country?
You seem to know a lot about
the dark side of its routes.
Since it isn't anyone else, but in order to
catch Kwon Soo Myeong, I'll give you a tip.
I hate him quite a lot too.
How much guts the primary-care physician
has, he must not use his true identity.
Seven years ago, I also got a new identity as
Brian Moon through a Chinese gang organization.
In that area, everything has to
go through that organization.
We might just be able to
locate him through them.
Where is that?
I still heave a sigh of relief.
Stop making me so upset.
I'm sorry, Mom.
In any case, I saw it all over the TV news,
that old president getting taken away.
Anyhow, the person who helped you...
what's he called? Moon... Seon... Ho?
Aigoo, thanks to him. I felt as if my
life had been shortened by ten years.
But who is he that he would
do such a grateful deed?
Mom!
Mi Rae!
Mom, aren't I doing well?
Good job, my puppy!
Now you can speak well.
And she is so strong.
Mi Rae, are you exercising
a lot with the nurse?
Is that why you're strong?
I worked hard.
Sure, sure.
I told Moo Hyeok to come, why are you here?
That rascal doesn't listen
to a word his father says...
President,
Did something happen?
Actually, Executive Director showed symptoms
of mental illness and set fire to the house.
The fire spread quite far, and the house
is almost completely burned down.
What? That crazy punk.
So? Is he alive?
What about my safe?
Look here, Kwon Moo Hyeok, did you
commit arson? Do you admit it?
Our Il Joo...
Where is my Il Joo?
Please tell her to come here.
My Il Joo...
Eun Gang,
are you looking at me from up there?
What state is this to be in?
I wanted to contact you
before I came in here,
but I couldn't bear to face you.
I thought you'd come here once though.
Is it bearable?
- It's not too difficult?- It's a little
hard physically, but my mind is at peace.
Thanks for being courageous.
And ultimately it was that courage that
allowed your heart to be at peace.
All my shame isn't gone.
I'm still really sorry towards you.
Sixteen years ago, stealing that document
and putting it in Eun Soo's bag,
I sincerely apologize for that.
That's what started this whole tragedy.
It caused your father to die, and
it split up you and Eun Soo.
But towards you who
continued to love Eun Soo,
I felt so much resentment and hate.
That shame won't disappear no
matter how much time passes.
I'm really sorry.
The same goes for me.
Because of my desire for vengeance,
I used you for 15 years.
Don't feel guilty.
I feel a little better since you say that.
Since the law convicts you
of the crime you committed,
when you finish serving your sentence,
you'll probably be able to feel free.
But I'm not sure about me.
Actually, I want to go in there, too.
What are you talking about?
With the mind of hating someone,
using them and betraying them.
I killed them a hundred times in my heart.
The life I've lived until now was all fake.
For me, being here on the outside
is more suffering than being in jail.
Eun Soo will melt away
that suffering.
Eun Soo will have a harder time than me.
Eun Soo and I
can't become happy this way.
The trial of President Kwon Soo
Myeong is taking place here today.
President Kwon, who is on a charge
of smuggling ₩1 trillion abroad,
including the late Prime Minister
Kang Seok Hyeon's slush fund,
and President Kwon's oldest son Kwon Joon Hyeok, who
helped steal the late Prime Minister Kang's slush fund,
and came from America,
will stand trial together.
Also, the second son, Kwon Moo Hyeok has been
arrested on a charge of instigating the murder.
The three of them seem to be
going to trial side by side.
Defendant Kwon Joon Hyeok,
do you admit your guilt?
Yes, I acknowledge it.
Defendant Kwon Moo Hyeok,
do you admit your guilt?
Where is my Il Joo?
Please put me in the same cell as Il Joo.
Please, Your Honor.
I want to be with Il Joo.
Defendant Kwon Soo Myeong,
do you admit your guilt?
I'm sick so I don't have
the strength to respond.
How could he say that?
Your Honor!
We have to restart the trial
for President Kwon Soo Myeong.
Who heedlessly comes into my
courtroom and makes such noise?
Bailiffs, remove him.
Wait just a moment!
Please see this person
before having your say.
Who is that?
I arrested Dr. Im Dong Joon, who murdered the late Prime Minister
Kang Seok Hyeong, in the south Pacific and brought him here.
I did cause the pacemaker to malfunction.
The one who gave me ₩20 billion and ordered
me to do it was President Kwon Soo Myeong.
Hey, Doctor Im, how could you do that?
How could you do that to our father?
Quiet! Quiet!
In that moment, strangely
I didn't feel enraged.
Everything was over, but it
didn't seem like the end.
I felt like I had lost
my way in a heavy fog.
While living, is it possible
not to hate anyone?
Can the world be changed with good?
The war between good and evil occurring
in my mind several dozen times a day
will never find a victor.
Flowers bloom, the sun
gives warmth, leaves fade.
Even though the heavy snow
buries my past sins in my mind,
my life won't change.
In the brief moment of less than half
of my lifetime, too much has happened.
Even while I try to organize
my thoughts, I can't.
Where am I headed?
Will I be able to find myself?
Inmates Entrance
I said I wouldn't see you, why do
you keep coming and bothering me?
I thought I should see you once.
Thank you.
I think I'll be able to tell Mi
Rae that you were a good person
as I did before.
Don't say things like that.
You know.
I approached you from the beginning
on Kwon Soo Myeong's orders.
I ran away abroad with ₩2 billion, abandoning
you in the last month of your pregnancy.
Even when I returned, it was
me who put you into the trap.
I'm not a good person at all.
Still, in the end, you
stood on the good side.
It was because Kwon Soo Myeong tried
to kill me, it wasn't because of you.
Listen well,
I'm someone who's been erased forever.
Don't talk about me to Mi
Rae and don't come here.
When my sentence is over, I'm
going back to the south Pacific.
There are many more women
better than you there.
Jin Hyeong Woo is a decent man.
Live well at least starting now.
Sentencing for Prime Minister Kang Seok Hyeon's Murderers: Im Dong Joon Gets Life, Kwon
Soo Myeong 15 Years, Kwon Joon Hyeok 2 Years, Kwon Moo Hyeok 3 Years in Mental Hospital
And the wind is blowing.
I still haven't decided where to go.
I should now go to the person
I'm supposed to go to.
But I have too many fearful
burdens in my heart.
Go inside.
Hyeong Woo.
I can't go back to the way I felt before.
I don't think we'll be able
to walk this path again.
So much has happened during this time.
In a furious storm,
we didn't have room to
look back in our minds.
When everything was over, I thought
I could be happy with you.
But what went wrong?
It might not even be love.
Well...
Love?
Something different from that
is weighing down on me.
Could it be you felt indebted to me for
letting go of my hand 16 years ago?
That isn't it.
Lovers who meet in the midst of war,
have an intense feeling
of love for each other.
However, they say that those lovers
part ways when the war is over.
Because they weren't able
to experience normal love.
I wonder if that was the same for us?
I've come back to my position now.
So you don't have to feel indebted anymore.
You fully did everything
you could to protect me.
So go and find your happiness now.
I'll be going.
Three years later
Hey, Soo Ri!
If you go around hugging boys already, it
will be trouble. Looks aren't everything!
What's wrong with that? It's
all part of growing up.
You never know, we may end up as in-laws.
Hey! Quit that ridiculous talk!
Soo Ri, Soo Ri, My Soo Ri, there'll
be more than 100 men in your life,
but do you want to set your life already at the age
of three? Yoon Ho is absolutely a "no-touch," got it?
After a kid grows up, you can tell how he looks, but with the
theory of the good-looking parents bearing a good-looking son,
it'll be hard to find looks
like my Yoon Ho. Right?
Hey. Beauty can be upgraded
by a few alterations.
What use is a handsome husband? Do
you live by eating a handsome face?
That's how you think. Soo Ri
might have other thoughts.
- Hey!- Right?
We have more calls to acquire the business.
The franchise fee is less
than other franchises.
Rumors seem to say the
training is run properly, too.
President... If there's a
store left over, can I...
You can't.
He's worked hard all this time,
how about giving him a chance?
He might just have a knack for business.
That would be leaving a
fish market to a cat.
You're too much!
This manly Kang Il Do has worked without being paid or
complaining under the renewing-myself project for three years.
Is it... that I've been exploited?
Do you recall emptying my Il
Ran's safe three years ago?
The wedding jewelry I had
given her was in there, too.
If you were to count that, you wouldn't be able to
repay that even if you worked for free forever.
Truthfully, being born as the first-born in
this family, I haven't been given a cent,
don't you feel sorry for me?
Feel sorry for you? In a house
where you don't pay rent,
you eat three meals a day,
what should I feel sorry for?
Just look at the Chairwoman.
Chairwoman Shin Eun Soo
Because we got more donors, we are planning to expand
our support to more senior centers and orphanages.
Please increase the staff, too.
How about welfare centers? Isn't there any
problem for the budget bill submitted last time?
No. There isn't any problem with the budget
because sufficient funds have been secured.
Hello, everybody!
Il Ran!
What's going on? After moving out, did your affection
for me cool off? How can you not even visit once?
I thought you'd be busy raising Soo Ri.
She's growing up on her own. The
house feels completely empty.
Are you seeing anyone?
Oh my, when would she find time
to date when she's this busy?
Hey! I'm not talking about a man right now.
Is there another woman you're seeing that
you're keeping your distance from me?
Mom!
Oh, Mi Rae! Are you already
coming back from piano lessons?
I practiced since early this morning.
You worked even though it's Sunday?
I have a lot of work these days.
Mom, hurry, hurry! I'll show you
what I learned on the piano today!
To take everything you got in the will
and turn it over to the foundation,
three years ago or ten years ago,
why are we still living like this?
Aigoo. I feel upset.
If even one-tenth of that money was left over,
you could have at least bought Mi Rae a piano.
I save money in installment savings.
I'm going to buy Mi Rae a
piano with the money I earn.
President, it's going to be lunchtime
soon and I'm so busy. Why are we here?
Because there's something to
take care of, just follow me.
Good grief.
You've deposited faithfully every
month for three years now.
It matures next month, are you going
to withdraw the funds at that time?
What is this? You dragged me here in
the morning to brag about your money?
Someone's been working like a dog for three
years and hasn't even touched money.
Why would you tie it up for three years?
A man should know how to spend.
I think I'm going to have
to tie it up even more.
This account owner doesn't appear
to have his act together yet.
Then do I redeposit it
under Kang Il Do's name?
President, is this really mine? Really?
It was obvious if I gave it to you as salary,
you would have squandered it the very next day.
So I carefully saved it up for you.
You've gone through much hardship working
at the restaurant all this time.
President!
Wait, why are you hugging me?
- Then let's work hard for
just seven more years.- What?
We have to fulfill the ten
years from your father's will.
I'll give this to you at that time.
President, I mean, In-law Ma,
- Moo Hyeok, when did you get
out?- It's been a few days.
Hey, kid! Then you should have come
to see your father, I've been dying.
What were you doing that
you're just coming now?
You're sentenced to 15 years but in just three you got out on
suspension of execution of sentence. What are you whining about?
You're feigning illness, aren't you?
No, I'm not. There isn't
anything that doesn't hurt.
The Prime Minister was released on
sick bail and went around freely.
But, they don't let me out of
here, it's just like jail.
I should have gone to a
mental hospital like you.
You deliberately acted insane
to avoid jail, didn't you?
You're the one who said I was insane.
But, Father. Do you know
anything about Il Joo?
Hey, you. Even now, you
think of that backstabber?
Yes. I think of her every day.
Your own children are of no use.
Joon Hyeok went to the States
as soon as he got out of jail.
The company went bankrupt, and there's
no word from the grandchildren.
You're the only one here.
What have I done so wrong in my
past life to turn out like this?
It wasn't your past life,
you did a lot in this one.
You crazy punk.
Is this Kang Yoo Gyeong's teacher
certification with the ink not dried yet?
How is your work?
Why do you bother asking?
The third level of the internet reporter is always
called "Reggie."(Reggie = report + garbage in Korean)
Still, this Kwon Ah Reum will
receive the Pulitzer Prize someday.
I know you were avoiding Beom Soo so
carefully, but do you know how he's doing?
Last time, Beom Soo failed his bar exam.
Really?
You guys, why are you talking
about me behind my back?
You cut off a friend who's preparing
for an exam and don't cheer him on,
you have no loyalty.
What are you doing here?
What? What? You're always popping
up, can't I do the same?
I called him here. After hearing that I
could finally contact you, Beom Soo...
I gotta go.
Hey, where are you running off to?
Sit down.
You better take responsibility
for me not passing my exam.
It's because you were disturbing me.
Hey, that isn't a fact. When,
where, how and why would I?
This is the first time I've
seen you in three years.
I don't know. In any case,
it was because of you.
Who said you could disappear
after a teary phone call?
From now on, let's eat a meal
and go drinking. You're buying.
Hey, you know who I am.
Because of my grandfather...
What do the grown-ups have to do with us?
It's busy enough just trying to eat and live.
I'm hungry, hurry up and buy me dinner.
Hurry up and collect all this.
Fine.
Why don't you stop in?
No, I have some things to take care of
at the foundation. Send my regards.
What brings you here without calling?
I was passing by and stopped in.
Myeong Joo, have you been well?
Myeong Joo, your present.
Thank you.
Of course.
Isn't it difficult to run this?
What would be difficult about it?
The foundation gives us plenty of
money and the volunteers help a lot.
The welfare children's lives
have become brighter.
But I still feel bad when I see you.
You were an assemblywoman. Don't you have
any thought of getting back into politics?
Not at all.
I think this works suits me best.
I think Father and Mother
would be pleased, too.
It's all thanks to you. Because you
gave me a chance to reflect on myself.
Director!
- There's been an accident.- Accident?
One of members in this center
escaped, but he's mentally disturbed.
It appears he was in an accident. I
was notified by the police station.
The volunteers are supposed to come.
I'll go.
Hong Myeong Ho, tell the truth.
Are you going to keep lying?
Hello.
Yes, who are you?
I'm Hong Myeong Ho's guardian.
What happened?
He's here on suspicion of obscenity.
What? No, no.
This person took my wallet.
Give me my wallet. My wallet.
What are you talking about?
You touched my girlfriend.
That's right, this pervert touched my butt.
So we'll have to receive a settlement.
Hey? No, no, I didn't!
Hyung! Did you come?
You're dead. You're dead.
I think it will be resolved.
I'll bring him back.
- How did it turn out?- They're
expert defrauders at doing this.
They have quite a number
of previous convictions.
- I took care of it neatly
by law, so you can take him.
I don't know this lady. I want
to go with Hyung Hyeong Woo.
How am I your hyung?
You're much older than me.
Hey, that's why you are my hyung. Let's go.
I'll take him to the welfare center.
- Have you been well?- Yeah.
- You look good as well.-
Because my mind is at peace.
I heard that you were
staying in our home town.
I had nowhere else to go.
Let's go.
I'll get going.
Law OfficeAttorney Jin Hyeong Woo
Hyung!
What happened to bring you down to the countryside you
don't like because you're afraid you'll get rusty?
I came down here after
taking a preservative.
How long are you going to keep
doing work that doesn't pay?
Make your big comeback soon.
Then are you doing work that pays?
That's what I mean. We need to
be a set of two to have synergy.
Ahh. That ₩300 billion! Instead of giving all to the
government, we should have saved some part for us.
It's not your bones getting
rusty, you're itchy all over.
Actually, there's this amazing woman.
She's a junior of mine
and she's the real deal.
She's really interested in you, do
you want to go on a blind date?
Ajusshi Kku, I'm going out
for a competition now.
What competition?
I'll let you know if I win a gold trophy.
Look forward to seeing it.
Are you listening to me?
She's total, total, totally a killer.
Hey, kid. If she's such a great catch, then you
date her. Why are you introducing her to me?
Her standards are a little high, you see.
Just meet her once! Hyung!
I came.
Who are you?
Who are you, Hyung?
What are you doing?
I have good judgment.
Just looking at you, I can
tell you're just like me.
You came from the mental hospital
way over there, didn't you?
Get out of my way.
I know right away when I see it.
I planted it so that when it blooms, it will be a
pink heart in the shape that you like so much.
You look forward to it, right?
Mom! Mom!
Catch your breath! What is it?
I won first prize in the
storybook drawing contest!
Really? My daughter is really amazing.
- What did you draw that you won such
a big prize? - Do you want to see?
Wow. You drew it really well.
A long time ago, there was a
pretty fairy named Kku Ee.
But Kku Ee wronged the jade emperor
and as her punishment, she became a bird.
Kku Ee was crying on a large tree branch.
But one rainy night,
the Kku Ee bird fell from
the branch and got hurt.
Then the Kku Ee bird was saved
by a young girl and boy.
On that tree, there was a legend.
The young girl and boy like each other,
and if their hearts don't
change in ten years,
the two people will get
together and Kku Ee bird
becomes a fairy according to this legend.
However, when ten years passed,
at the last moment the two people broke up.
And because of that, Kku Ee bird is still
crying because she can't become a fairy again.
I'm sorry, I'm a little late, ain't I?
Not at all. Please have a seat.
You're Assemblyman Kim Yeong Deok's aide.
You're a lawyer too?
You've done a lot for your young age.
But it's nothing compared to you.
In my world, you're legendary.
Your praise is excessive.
You are the one who put media
king Kwon Soo Myeong in jail.
I heard from senior Jong Yeol that
you give free legal service here.
Are you going to follow in your father's
footsteps and run for the assembly?
If not, there's no reason for
you to be working without pay.
If you get elected, I'd
like to become your aide.
If possible, I'd like to
be your aide forever.
Mom, I threw it all the way over there.
Ah, you're not supposed to be
playing in a place like this.
Let's meet at Kku Ee's
tree tomorrow morning.
I'm sorry, my child is still young.
Not at all. It's okay.
Where did you hear this story?
Umm, before Ajusshi Kku told me a story about a bird
who became a fairy and a story about the Kku Ee tree.
And I changed it a little bit. Why?
Nothing. You drew it very
well and wrote it well.
Mom, but is there really such
a thing as a Kku Ee tree?
I really want to see it.
Whoa, is that the Kku Ee tree?
Ajusshi Kku!
- Mi Rae!- Mom, it's Ajusshi Kku!
Oh, Mom! Someone wrote my, your
and Ajusshi Kku's names here!
Wow, that's so neat? Who did that?
Kku Moo, Kku Soo, Kku Ee
Ajusshi Kku, push me!
There.