Where did you find that trash?
Tell me! Tell me!
That's filth.
What a way to begin.
You're just like your father.
Tits! That's all he ever cared about.
You think he was a hero, right?
I can tell you
a couple of things about him.
I'll kill you if I find trash like this in the house again.
Get the trash can.
I'll burn all this.
Don't stay there, stupid!
Come on!
Bastard, you must have taught
this to your kid
so he could grow up to be like you.
You're a pig.
I'm sure there's more trash
around here.
Don't be stupid
and get the trash can. Hurry up!
THE NIGHT HAS 1000 SCREAMS
I knew something was wrong
when I arrived.
It was all very calm.
Oh, my God.
Have you seen this?
- What is it?
- An arm.
Oh, my God.
- Are you all right?
- Yes, I'm fine.
There should be a boy,
little Timmy.
- What's in there?
- This is his room.
Oh, my.
Whoever did this,
is completely crazy.
It's terrible.
I've never seen so much blood.
There must be something here.
That's Mrs. Weldon.
I knew it. I knew something bad
had happened. Oh, my God.
Please, go with her.
Don't worry, I'm fine.
Don't move.
- It was a big man, very big.
- Oh, Timmy.
Very big-
Calm down, Timmy.
Where is his father?
He passed away in Europe.
In the Air Force.
But he has an aunt
who lives nearby.
I'll call her. I'll go get her.
This is terrible.
40 YEARS LATER
Mom.
Mom, where are you?
Mom, come back!
Will you take long?
Otherwise, I'll move.
Just a minute, miss.
Fine.
I'm sorry, gentlemen.
I'm sure the Dean
will see you soon.
Don't worry,
we're used to this.
Did you know the girl?
Well, I don't really remember.
This university is big.
It's very hard
to remember all the students.
Yes, Dean?
Are those gentlemen still there?
- Yes, sir.
- Very well. I'll be right out.
Fine.
You must be Bracken.
- Lieutenant Bracken.
- Yes, nice to meet you.
Sergeant Holden.
- How are you, Sergeant?
- How are you?
Come in, please.
Grace, don't send in
any call, please.
Come in.
What terrible business.
Have you heard the latest news?
There's a water bed in the gym.
What do you think?
Have you ever laid
on a water bed?
The most wonderful feeling
in the world
is smoking a joint
and at the same time
doing it on a water bed.
Watch out. He's there.
You'll see.
Professor Brown.
Excuse me, sir,
can I ask you a question?
Where are the pectorals?
My classmates say
mine are very funny.
I assure you
there's nothing wrong with yours.
Yes, but where are they?
Here, right here.
We'll be discreet.
What's happened
is an unfortunate incident...
What a terrible thing,
that murder.
The police are inside.
They think it's someone
from the university.
I won't ask you
how you got that information.
What makes you think that?
Well, the lieutenant says
it looks like an inside job.
Poor Willard.
He found the body.
But they haven't found
the head yet.
I wonder what the murderer
did with it.
- You know? I...
- Will they take long?
I don't know, Professor.
They've been there long.
I don't think they'll take much longer.
But if you prefer
to come back later...
Find Professor Brown, Grace.
He must be in the professor lounge.
He's right here, Dean.
Shall I send him in?
Great. Yes, send him in.
According to our latest data,
there's over 2,000.
I'm glad you came, Arthur.
Let me introduce you
to Lt. Bracken and Sgt. Holden.
Nice to meet you.
I'd like you to show them around.
When's your next class?
Precisely tomorrow.
Tomorrow. Excellent.
They want to ask you
about that girl, Virginia Palmer.
She was in your class,
if I remember correctly.
Professor Brown is in charge
of our Anatomy Department.
Please, show them
everything they want to see.
Don't hesitate to come see me again
if you need anything else.
Now...
I beg you to be discreet.
Imagine what it'd be for the university
if this was in the newspapers.
Don't worry.
It wouldn't help us, either.
We'll be discreet.
Fine. I trust you will,
for everyone's sake.
Our version will be that
what happened...
was an unfortunate accident.
I hope people will believe it.
These things
always end up being known,
but, anyway, what's important now
is to buy some time.
I think I've talked too much.
I've got work to do.
I don't think I'll be much help.
I don't remember the girl much.
I've had a lot of students this term.
Come on, Arthur.
You only have one department,
I've got all campus to deal with.
I'm sure you'll do it
better than I would.
Gentlemen, excuse me.
I'm really sorry.
Professor Brown
will show you around.
Thank you, sir.
You've been a great help.
I'm glad. Please,
keep me up to date.
Of course. Don't worry.
So you didn't know the girl well?
- You got a light?
- No, I don't.
Do you know
what kind of girl she was?
Was she chasing boys?
She was very attractive,
but I don't remember
if she had a boyfriend.
This is my class. Come in.
Here we study Comparative Anatomy
to use it in Anthropology
and similar courses.
One of the students
brought it as a gift.
I don't know where he got it.
It's the skull of a 16-year-old girl.
I'd like to talk to that boy.
What's his name?
It was a long time ago.
You don't think
one of our boys killed her?
Our job is like identifying
clothes without tags.
We have to check everything.
That girl,
did she have friends in class?
Yes, she was very popular.
If you come to my office, I'll give you
some names that might help you.
Thank you very much, Professor.
We have to start somewhere.
We don't even have the forensic report.
Fine.
Willard.
When do you expect
to finish your work on campus?
I don't know.
One or two weeks.
But don't worry,
it won't cost you more.
It's the agreement I made
with your secretary.
- Everything's included.
- Yes, I know.
But the sooner you finish,
the sooner you can work somewhere else.
And I guess
that's what's best for you.
Yes. I'll finish
as soon as possible.
Okay.
How about a swim
in the pool by ourselves?
- Hi.
- Hi. How are you?
Are you leaving? So soon?
Yes, I have to study.
That Brown is terrible.
There he is.
What a weird guy.
Always by himself.
How sexy.
- See you.
- Bye.
Kendall?
Have you seen Kendall?
Yes, he's over there.
Thank you.
By the way,
are you free this afternoon?
That's what I was saying,
you're not free.
Kendall, I finally found you.
This is for you.
What is it?
What do I know?
I just know it's urgent.
Where have you been?
I looked for you
all over campus.
I was here before,
and you weren't here.
Alister, when did you get this?
About half an hour ago.
Half an hour?
That's weird.
Tell me. My lips are sealed.
- Yes, I know.
- See you.
Leave him.
Don't move.
Stop or I'll blow your brains.
I don't envy your job.
Nobody realizes
how terrible it is.
Thank you for coming
so quickly, Professor.
Hank, get me that.
I need your help.
I don't have
the forensic report yet,
and I need to know now
if this, this slaughter,
has been done with that saw.
Wait, don't touch it.
You could smudge the fingerprints.
I'm sorry, I didn't know.
I'm not a pathologist, but...
I could almost guarantee
that it was done with that.
Or with something very similar.
Okay, Professor.
We'll be in touch. You can go now.
Thank you.
Lieutenant, do those boys know
I want to see them?
Yes, they do.
Fine, let's go see the Dean.
What's up?
Nothing. I don't know,
I felt something.
This case is driving me crazy.
Me too.
I have the strange feeling
somebody is watching me.
I think it would be convenient
to have undercover agents here.
I'll tell the Dean
when we talk to him.
- Women, right?
- Yes, of course.
It's all the killer wants.
See you.
One moment, kid. You too.
The Lieutenant asked you to go
to the Dean's office in half an hour.
Okay. I'll make sure
he comes with me.
Don't worry, we'll be there.
I hope so, for your sake.
And don't say a word about this.
Yes, okay.
Yes, man. We know.
We're absolutely sure
that person is on campus.
You won't suspect
my students or my professors?
It could be anyone.
Do you want to cooperate or not?
You want to have
two policewomen here to spy on us.
That's asking too much.
There have been two murders.
And that maniac will kill again.
I assure you
it's the only way to catch him.
Yes. Okay.
Of course. I understand.
When do you want to start?
I will let you know.
Now I would like to ask
your secretary some questions.
And those two boys.
Hey, you don't need to say
you didn't find me the first time
you went to the library.
You know the police.
Do you think I'm stupid?
But, hey, where were you?
If you want to know, with Alice.
Do you know her?
The blonde one?
Don't tell me. Her too?
Sure, and without problems.
What a guy.
You have to give me your recipe.
If you behave.
Let's see,
if I understood correctly,
you found on your desk
a letter addressed to Kendall
that said "Urgent".
Yes. And I gave it
to the Dean right away.
Right, sir?
What did you do?
I'm sorry, but is this
really necessary, Lieutenant?
We could ask the parents
of the murdered girls, don't you think?
Yes, I understand.
It's natural.
You see,
I told Grace, my secretary,
to send the letter
to Kendall urgently.
Urgently? Why?
I don't allow my office
to be used as a post office.
Students know that and keep bothering
Grace with their foolishness.
Love letters and things like that.
Despite that,
when I found the letter on my desk,
l supposed
what the envelope said was truth.
"Very urgent".
I'm sorry, sir.
I never thought Jenny would use
your office for something like that.
You're wrong, boy.
It wasn't her.
That note was sent by the killer
to keep you away from the pool.
Why did you go?
I really don't know.
A hunch.
Something strange.
Something I couldn't explain,
Lieutenant.
Okay.
And you, do you know something?
Me? Not a word, I swear.
It's fine.
But don't say anything
about this conversation.
Understood?
Understood.
When you feel better, call me.
There's somebody
I'd like you to talk to.
- Okay.
- I have no more questions. Do you?
One, two, three, four.
And one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
One, two, three, four,
One, two, three.
Okay.
- I'll go out a moment.
- Okay.
What's up?
You scared me to death.
- You were so sudden.
- Come. I want to tell you something.
Come in.
Hello, doctor.
How many times have I told you
not to call me that?
I'm a psychologist,
not a doctor in medicine.
Is this the boy?
Hey, I don't need a shrink.
Come here.
I'm not a shrink, young man.
And I'm sure
you don't need me.
Don't worry.
What the doctor wants is information.
About what?
My name is Jennings.
I'm a psychologist, as you've heard.
My job is to make
a detailed psychological profile
of the possible murderer.
In many cases, the profile
is all we have to start with.
But I don't know anything.
Or do I?
Exactly. Maybe you know
the murderer and don't know it.
Now, if the Lieutenant is so kind
to go back to his job,
we'll try to figure it out.
Okay.
I'll see you later.
Bye.
Have a seat.
Is it dangerous?
Very much.
Better. I'm sick of getting bored
in this damn office.
I supposed so.
You find an active girl,
put her to fill out paperwork,
and six months later,
she'll volunteer for anything.
Dr. Jennings is done with me.
Well, it wasn't so serious, was it?
Hey, aren't you Mary Riggs?
Herself.
Mary Riggs, Kendall James.
Pleased to meet you.
I've watched almost all your games.
But why is
a tennis champion here?
Simple,
this is my home.
Do you mean you work here?
Of course.
She's the lady I told you about.
She'll work undercover
in campus.
She'll be the new tennis instructor.
That's great.
I really appreciate you trusting me
like this, Lieutenant.
And you too, of course.
Kendall, all you have to do
is keep your eyes open
and be always near Miss Riggs
in case she needs help.
- Okay?
- Okay.
He's a good boy
and he's had a rough time.
We've talked seriously
and I think we can trust him.
I think that's fine.
But why did you tell him about me?
We're at a dead end.
And I don't have anyone
to go there with you.
I trust him.
I'd put my life in his hands.
And mine, too, of course.
I don't know why you complain.
You'll be playing tennis all clay.
You'll play tennis
until you're bored.
- And we'll be watching...
- I need to talk to the Lieutenant now.
I'm really sorry,
but it's not possible.
It's orders, you'll understand.
- I can't...
- I've been calling all morning.
Let her.
What's up?
I was waiting for you, Lieutenant.
Do you have a minute?
Who are you? It's okay.
Sylvia Costa, Boston Globe.
What's going on
at the university?
What's going
I don't know
what could be going on.
There are rumors,
strange things are happening.
It seems there's a maniac.
Or something like that.
Madam, rumors like that
spread every day at the university.
Yes, but this time it seems it's true.
There's even rumors
about a murdered girl.
The imagination
of the students is wild.
I'm sorry, but I'm very busy now.
Would you excuse me?
But...
Why don't you talk to Miss Riggs?
She's the one up-to-date
on those things.
40-15.
Game for Miss Riggs.
Very well, Miss Riggs.
You've been great. Great.
Thank you.
There's tea at the professor's lounge.
I'm sure you need it.
Yes, but I'd like a shower first.
That girl made me sweat.
Please, Miss Riggs.
Don't be modest.
I'm sure with your lessons,
our tennis team will improve greatly.
Tell me, does anyone suspect?
Does anyone know why I'm here?
Nobody except those
who the Lieutenant told.
Fine, then you're the only one.
I'd like to talk to you
some other time. Could I?
Yes, of course.
But what about the other woman?
I don't see her anywhere.
Well, you'll see,
I came alone.
These jobs are for volunteers.
You are brave, Miss Riggs.
I just hope you can do your job
efficiently, but discreetly.
This is very important.
By the way, where's Willard?
We had to set him free.
We don't have evidence yet.
Please, I'm sorry to interrupt.
Could I talk to you for a moment?
I'm afraid I can't right now, Miss.
I'm busy. I'm sorry.
It's very important.
What is this about?
It's about what's been going on lately.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Tell me what's been going on.
- Do you know?
- I don't know anything at all.
Nothing strange
is going on here, right, dear?
Excuse us, we're in a hurry.
Who's over there?
Oh. It's you. You scared me.
What's this?
What are you doing?
No!
- The key, where's the damn key?
- We don't have a key.
I'll go through the window
and open the door.
Come.
Hurry up.
No.
Find help, quickly.
Use the phone there.
If the door is closed,
knock it down.
Damn bastard.
- What's happened?
- That bastard cut a girl's arms.
We haven't been able
to catch him.
Calm down.
This time, we'll get him.
Sergeant, make sure every inch
of the building is searched.
- I will, sir.
- Every inch, is it clear?
Don't worry.
Doctor, how's the girl?
It's hard to tell. She's still alive,
but she's lost a lot of blood.
It's very serious.
I don't think she'll survive.
God.
That bastard
must be laughing at us.
What's happened?
Where did you come from?
What?
Are you deaf? I asked you
where are you coming from.
Upstairs, the library.
Fine.
We'll talk later.
Kendall.
Dean,
something terrible happened.
Listen, kid,
I'm sending patrols everywhere,
but it's not enough.
I want you to keep
your eyes and ears open.
I need your help.
And I especially want you
to closely watch Miss Riggs.
I shouldn't ask you this,
but I can't afford having
this crazy bastard run away again.
Go now.
Randall, I want you
to investigate the whole staff.
Thoroughly.
Use the whole department
if you have to.
Very well, Lieutenant.
I imagined you'd like that.
Try to do it the best you can.
I don't think
he'll take long to kill again.
Shut up. Don't you see?
You'll wake up all campus.
And you were afraid
we'd get caught?
What a story.
Oh, Kendall.
Does every woman
always have to end up crying?
Come on, leave me alone.
You're all the same. When you get
what you want, you ditch us.
What are you doing?
Are you leaving now?
Kendall.
- Miss Riggs.
- It's you.
- You scared me to death.
What's happened here?
I don't know. I thought I saw
somebody running in the garden.
I went out to see who it was.
Then he attacked me.
And there he is.
But it's my kung-fu instructor.
What are you doing here?
Well, I was doing footing,
and all of a sudden, I was attacked.
But I see it was nothing.
Good night.
- Bye.
What are you doing here so late?
Lieutenant asked me to watch you.
I saw you go out,
but when I went down you were gone.
So I got my bike.
Next time, forget the bike.
It sounds just like a saw.
Since you are okay, I'll leave. Bye.
No way, Kendall. No.
Let me get my gun
and I'm leaving with you.
Okay.
Hop up.
Hold on.
Well, thank you.
For saving my life tonight.
See you tomorrow, okay?
Mary.
One drink?
Some other time.
Thank you.
Casanova.
You?
Willard.
Who put on that music?
It's unbearable.
They must be testing it.
I thought that was your job.
No, Miss.
I only take care of the garden.
The loudspeakers
are controlled from the Dean's office.
Kendall, call and ask
if there's somebody testing them.
There's a phone in the lockers
if Willard can get the key.
It's forbidden to use that phone.
I'll take responsibility.
Wait here.
How do you stop that?
I don't know.
That damn music
is driving me crazy.
Is there any way
to turn that music off?
I'll try. Come with me.
Let's go.
And that key?
Don't touch it.
It could be evidence.
If something's happened, I mean.
Kendall?
Kendall!
Kendall, where are you?
What's happened?
Another one. In there.
It's Suzy Billing.
Yes.
While we were distracted
with that music,
that bastard was killing her!
Animal!
He cut her in half
while she was still alive.
Do you imagine
how much she must have suffered?
Sergeant,
we're running out of time.
I know, Lieutenant, I know.
I'm doing my best.
But if I go too fast,
I could miss something important.
I need more time.
That's what we don't have,
Sergeant.
Make an effort, don't sleep,
but give me something.
Lieutenant, I'm doing my best,
but I'd like some help.
I can't be up all night.
My eyes are so tired
I can't read anything.
I think I can get you some help.
Do you remember Kendall?
That kid could be useful.
Are you kidding?
We can't use a suspect for this.
Don't be foolish.
That kid knows people well.
He's been five years in university
and he could detect any abnormality
sooner than any of us.
Yes, Lieutenant, I know.
But the rules...
The rules can go to hell.
We need to find the killer.
That's what the rules say.
So in half an hour,
Kendall will be there.
Don't worry, Mom.
I'll fix it.
Professor. Professor Brown.
Professor.
Do you mind if I go with you?
I'm a little jumpy
after what's happened.
In broad daylight, I don't think
there's much to be afraid of.
I'm going to the Horton building.
ls it convenient for you?
Yes, sure.
I'm sorry.
You must think I'm foolish.
- But after what I saw...
- No, not at all.
I'm too used to seeing dead bodies,
I might be desensitized.
Contrary to the Dean,
you look like a sensitive man.
I think you are not familiar with campus politics.
Why do you say that?
To survive in a campus like this,
you have to be very tough.
I wouldn't put obstacles
in the Dean's way.
I'm sure I wouldn't do well.
It looks like
you have experience.
Bitter experience.
I call it as I see it.
- Tell me more.
- There's nothing more, Miss Riggs.
I don't like people who try
to meddle in other people's lives.
I just want to know
where I am, Professor.
Especially if there's
a maniac going around.
- It's me.
- I'm sorry.
Sorry. I'm a little jumpy,
that's all. Where have you been?
Lieutenant asked me
to help Sgt. Holden to check the files.
Wow, the Lieutenant
is pretty unorthodox.
Well.
Do you know
where I can find the Dean?
He won't be back
until this afternoon.
He goes to Arlington
every first of the month.
You'll find him in his residence
around 7:00.
At 7:00?
Okay, I'll see him then.
As you wish.
- See you soon. Bye.
- Yes. Bye.
Hello.
Where do we start today?
Our police apprentice.
I hope you still like this job
after ten hours looking at papers.
You don't smoke, do you?
No. Why, does it bother you?
Yes, I can't stand smoke,
especially down here.
Well, you know how it goes.
Read carefully every report
and take down any notes
about any university member.
Okay?
That's your desk.
Okay.
Well, Miss Riggs,
what a surprise.
Excuse me,
I don't want to bother you.
Come in, please.
I just wanted to ask you
some questions.
Perfect. If you insist in staying here,
we'll just have to get comfortable.
It's ridiculous, don't you think?
This way.
Would you like something to drink?
I was making tea,
but maybe you'd like coffee.
Yes, coffee, please.
Your apartment is beautiful.
Thank you. You're kind.
I don't hear that often.
This is too big just for me.
Make yourself comfortable, dear.
One moment, please.
Miss Riggs,
how do you like your coffee?
With milk and sugar?
Milk and no sugar.
Maybe some saccharine.
I see you watch your diet.
I didn't think you'd have to,
playing tennis.
I'll put in a little.
One moment.
Here I am, dear.
I'm sorry I took so long.
Here's your coffee.
I don't know if you'll like it.
It's instant.
Thank you.
I put in some saccharine,
as you asked.
It tastes great. It's fabulous.
You're too kind,
but I'm glad you like it.
Now, Miss Riggs, tell me,
what did you want to talk about?
Professor Brown.
Yes. Do you know if he has problems,
something he wants to hide?
I hate asking questions like this.
But it's absolutely necessary.
Would you like some more coffee?
Yes.
It was very good.
I think that if we don't find
something soon,
each member of the campus
will be investigated.
Frankly, I wouldn't like
to see the university
full of officers
looking for bodies everywhere.
It would be pretty annoying.
Sergeant,
this seems important.
He's changed his name.
It's not much,
but we should look into it.
I'll check out the files in Arlington.
I hope there's someone there,
it's a little late.
Arlington?
Sergeant Holden
from Boston.
I want an expansion
on report number 672947HF.
It's urgent.
Yes, I'll hold.
You'd better keep working.
This will take some time.
I'm talking to an old man
who sounds like he's about to die.
I'm listening. Tell me.
Yes.
Are you sure?
Could you telex that to me right now?
To our central office.
It's really urgent.
Yes, I understand.
That's it. Thank you.
What did he say?
We got it. I'm sure
the Dean is the killer.
Apparently, his mother
was dismembered when he was little.
That must have made him
lose his mind.
I imagined it had to be
something like this.
Mary. She said she'd go see
the Dean at 7:00.
God. Why didn't you say so?
Let's go.
No, you stay here
and call Lieutenant immediately.
What am I saying?
No, there's no time to spare.
We'll use the radio in the car.
Let's go.
I hope we make it in time.
Sorry. The water was cold
and I had to heat it up again.
- Thank you.
- Your coffee.
We were talking
about Professor Brown.
He's a homosexual.
I found out by chance a few years ago.
But so far, he hasn't broken
any rules.
And, therefore, it's his business.
Don't you think, dear?
Brown was very worried
I found out his secret,
and he tried to destroy me.
But I'm stronger than him.
I don't feel well.
I feel something strange.
You're feeling the effect
of the drug I gave you.
You can see and hear
everything I tell you, right?
But you can't move, right?
Lieutenant.
- Lieutenant.
- What's up?
An urgent telex for you.
It's about the university murders.
It looks like they've found the killer.
Tell Roger to get my car. Fast.
Nobody will ever find her. Ever.
Sergeant.
One moment.
You go from behind the building.
Let's go.
That way.
Kendall, stay here
and don't move.
Lieutenant,
you can't do this to me now.
Okay, but go behind.
If somebody yells "floor",
I want you kissing it like a soldier.
Yes, sir.
Move.
Still.
Mary.
What's wrong with you?
Mary, what did he do to you?
The Dean isn't here.
We've got to find him.
He can't be far.
Kendall, stay with her.
I'll ask for an ambulance
in the radio.
Come on, Mary.
Mary.
Mary, please.
You have to stand up.
Move. Stand up.
Please. Come on, up.
Let's go.
It's all over. Please.
Come on. I'll help you.
Come on.
Very well, Mary.
You have to walk now.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
Now you have to walk a little.
That's right. Very well.
Come on.
- Are you okay, kid?
- Yes. Yes.
- You were lucky.
- I can see that.
How's Mary?
She'll be fine soon.
She's been drugged.
Get something to cover him.
Sergeant,
let's search everything.
- Hey, look at this.
- Let's see.
It's awful, isn't it?
I wouldn't say so.
It's not so bad.
I never thought the Dean
would collect things like this.
Kendall, as you see,
you learn something new every clay.
Let's go, fast.
And the Lieutenant?
He left with Miss Riggs.
Fine, you can go.
How are you?
I'm fine.
Still want to be a police officer?
- Are you kidding?
- Come on, I'll buy you some coffee.
You can rest assured,
you've helped avenge them.
- Let's go.
- One moment.