Under the sign of Capricorn
Translation: palanca (CST) - Portuguese Portugal
In 1770 the master
Cook discovered Australia.
60 years later, Sydney,
capital of New South Wales,
... emerged over 4 million
km2 of land unknown.
The colony exported raw materials.
A material matter
primitive: prison.
Many convicted unjustly.
But settlers would
a large area.
In 1831 the Crown of England
had sent a governor...
... to govern the colony.
So begins our story.
Present arms!
As a representative of his majesty,
... the King Guillermo,
... acted fast for your interest...
... for the welfare...
... and progress of their community.
I know little of you e. ..
... you little about me.
Many do not have good
background.
I have the honor of
I turn to Charles Adare?
- Yes, who are you?
-Potter, Cedric Potter.
I am the director of the Bank
New South Wales
They told us to come
with the entourage of the governor.
Will be grateful to the
we can for you.
Whatever.
- Strange place for business.
- None.
Possibly unconventional,
but act quickly.
No doubt.
I had customers walking in January
in June and drinking champagne.
- You will see amazing changes.
- Insurance.
Give me some time before
to talk business.
See you tomorrow.
-You will be in the governor's house?
- Yes
-It 's cousin of his excellence?
An interesting relationship.
- I hope to see again.
-Tomorrow at 11?
Magnificent.
Is ending.
Should I meet with him.
Gentlemen, I have
more than they say.
Only that they appreciate
its receipt.
Viva the governor!
- Were not very effusive.
- Is the climate.
Wellington said that no matter
the shouting before the battles.
We do not know what to expect.
here.
WELCOME
-Have commercial experience?
- None.
I am the lowest of three
children of a noble Irish...
... of little fortune.
Should learn to shoot and ride.
But I am short
I hate the sight and horses.
- Poor thing.
- Poor.
Between!
Mr. Flusky want to see.
To wait a few minutes.
I am the cousin of the governor.
Flusky, is a curious name.
Reminds something.
Who is Flusky?
One of our
prominent citizens.
Has great properties.
Has invested
very profitable.
A financial genius. The best
mare of the territory is his.
Works like a slave,
with hardness.
Where to hear that name?
What is the secret
to become rich?
Working very much, Mr. Adare.
Ask the others,
the Flusky.
How it started?
Long story.
We are not accustomed to speak of
past...
... of notable citizens.
An ex-con.
An emancipated?
Yes, an emancipated.
Condemned him for stealing
a bank or murder?
Do not speak of
affairs in Sydney.
The past of a man
it is something.
Here only to the
present and future.
That does not learn
Ireland.
When it stumbles in the past.
May submit to him?
- If you want to.
- I will be cautious.
Among Mr. Flusky!
Come here.
Presenting the Charles Adare.
Cousin of the governor.
- Came to Sydney to fortune.
-Yes?
Very pleased.
I told you that is not
fortune as fleas in a blanket.
Yeah, I said.
I never saw a flea.
Are difficult to capture?
It depends on how fast it is.
In my country the flea
are famous for their agility.
-What is your country?
- Ireland, the west of Ireland.
Ireland.
-As it is called?
- Adare.
Maybe.
So either make a fortune.
It is not the only one.
With that account to start?
With nothing to Impress
Mr Potter.
Of the Adare Killale?
My father is Lord Killale.
You know?
give me time to think...
... and help you.
-If you come tomorrow...
The take-.
If you come with me
right you a few things.
No long thing.
Draw something from the box.
See us another day, Mr. Potter.
Mr. Adare...
... is a strange man.
It was nice.
I will give you a hint.
-If you invite to come to your home will not.
-why?
A gentleman of his position
must be alert.
Anytime.
Wants
repeat what you said?
Do you not understand.
'If the old Flusky
calls to your home, not go. "
He said that?
-Not paying attention.
-pay attention to me.
Bring the horse.
Want to make money?
There is a part of land
which is sold in thousand pounds.
I want you to buy.
I wanted to buy
many things,
... but no money.
Potter you will
Short-term loan.
I will buy you this land
by more than paid for it.
I want to give
of this money?
-Is it worth it.
-why?
Very simple.
bought all the land
the crown that allows the law.
-This is a particular business.
-Not bad.
I'm still surprised.
that gives me
this business?
You may have my
reasons and can not.
This is the office of
records.
I do some things.
Come and submit your offer.
Gain time.
Here, off
as always.
I have to pastures
your new sheep.
Do not worry.
-And my secretary?
-He got one.
Read and write.
Says he is a gentleman.
-What is your conviction?
Five-years.
give a look.
Winter!
Open your mouth.
Very thin arms.
Know-how accounts?
-Yes, sir.
Therefore, here.
-Do you not understand.
It is the fool or?
-was a fraud?
-No.
-A confusion of skirts.
-It is not that.
His father did not want
in casássemoss.
Enough! In my house there
this class of problems.
-What is your name?
-Winter.
If I accept, comply.
I give you my word.
The word of the young
is not here.
If you do not comply,
return to prison.
-Accepted.
-Good luck.
If well, treat well.
But if not...
-See this?
-Yes.
Your provisional.
If we put your name,
will be condemned.
send it to me the house.
Workers who sent fathoms
I serve.
A thief of horses
and the other a murderer.
I do not want to be the next target.
I do not want murderers in my house.
meets the ballots.
Send to collect.
If you say...
-Not like the cuatreros.
-No.
-Neither the murderers.
His scripture.
Learly, the lady is waiting.
-What do you think?
-temperamental?
The hell of it.
Flusky!
It is a human head?
Reduced.
This traffic,
although it is prohibited.
I pay for it.
His murderer.
Mr. Flusky,...
Come to my house tomorrow.
Any driver knows where it is.
Dinner at 18:30.
Thank you for your kindness,
but hurry things.
What do you mean?
I do not want to cause you problems.
why not?
I have not had time to get situated.
If you need money,
I have one hundred pounds.
This option will.
Talk tomorrow
better the business.
-Mr. Adare?
-Yes.
His excellence sends you greetings.
Want to talk to you.
It will be a pleasure.
-Where is your excellence?
-Here, sir.
-Who is it?
-Charles.
Between!
and if the desire is to serve
a drink.
Thank you.
Where were we, Max?
Excuse me, Charles.
-Sure.
-His Excellency drew his attention...
-About?
Not said.
Yes, you say that the surroundings
the port is a muck.
I do not like the barrels
old, car wheels,...
... rotten cabbages,
and the cats killed.
That take all or
Ripped out his skin.
The attention it devotes to
health conditions of the port...
... leaves much to be desired.
Yes, that's what
have to say. Type.
Name-your attention...
-Not so loud.
I have to speak with Mr. Adare.
Do not go.
The entreteve?
Yes, very much.
-It was the bank?
-Yes.
What you think of your projects?
No big deal.
Charles, I hope
made a great effort.
Where's the soap?
I already have.
I was talking
with one of the magnates.
Will meet here.
Who is it?
-Flusky.
-You know, Banks?
Yes, I know.
-Something that you disapprove?
-No, it is very honored.
Only a few problems with Mr. Correct.
Who is Correct?
The supervisor-general.
-Sure.
Everyone has problems with it,
but not say anything to the contrary.
Receive the Flusky Box
government or socially?
No.
Mr. Potter, director of the bank,
says it is an emancipated.
-A convicted.
-It is not.
Watch out, Charles.
Keep in mind...
... that is my cousin.
I hope you have not seen
talking to him.
Tomorrow I shall dine at home.
What Flusky done?
It was nice, we talk about
the land of the crown.
I condemned it at the.
I have no idea.
I said that is
incorreto ask it here.
Max!
With the greatest respect,...
... Mr. Adare is right.
It is customary that when
completed his sentence,...
... do not talk about its history...
... if not breaking the law.
Flusky.
I heard it in some part.
The same I said.
It is equal.
Today
is a very rich man.
Flusky, something about a woman.
Can not be the same.
Give me those towels, Max
Thank you.
Come with me to take
some notes as I seen.
See you at dinner.
Do not go to the house subject.
Must be alert.
Could I commit
and not draw anything.
Absolutely nothing.
It is an order.
I hope we can
eat in kitchen.
No, go back to Sydney.
-So far?
-If you do not mind.
I do not like this place.
Why?
Looks nice.
His appearance is less.
There is something strange,
understand?
Afraid not.
Rights to him that I do not like.
I am not not a moment.
-What time should I come back?
At-ten.
Minyago Yugilla.
-What?
-why cry?
Charge that it
the ladies rim well.
So have something than talk.
-The ladies?
-There.
Winter, dined
with different people,...
... everything is in order.
entrusting a good wine,
the best.
deal with everything.
I do not understand it.
I ask you to you...
ask me, not the lady.
I run the house.
Pack with you.
What happened?
He said that I condemned
by abduction.
Certainly.
Let the fight and the store.
You open the door
and serve the port.
gives them their ballots for
provisional freedom.
the return to the
and send us more.
Me take care of them.
good night.
I have not bothered.
Seeking entry.
good night.
the grid but not touched,
so I gave back.
It is strange.
Delighted to see you.
Pass the restaurant,
if not download it.
I see that prepare a
big party tonight.
-Winter.
Say, sir.
Lady Flusky, should realize.
good night.
I present to you Reverend Smiley...
... and to Mr. Riggs, local engineer.
My wife regrets very...
... could not come.
Is not good e. ..
... Ms. Riggs is with her.
My wife also feels.
Like these parties.
Come on, please.
It is a serious illness?
No, sir.
My wife is not strong,
but recovers easily.
Thank you, Mr. Flusky,...
... their gift of the font.
The Lord bless the donor.
-Like to Sydney, Mr. Adare?
-Yes, very.
In particular, the goose,
zarigüeya and wild duck.
With that not disregard the ants,
... the laurels, cockatoo,...
... iguanas and kangaroos.
Do not mention it,
unless the life of society.
There is?
-Not much.
Beautiful city, but
with little social life.
I do not care, but
heavy for women.
-The Governor will receive a lot?
-I it is said.
Do not forget our names.
Riggs.
-Mrs Riggs is all a lady.
-Do not doubt it.
A refined woman who lives
the time here too.
-I would like to know.
-Good.
The refinement is important,
but a load.
Yes, you see.
No, thanks.
My dear sir,
How are you?
You may not feel Wilkins.
A terrible headache.
I have left it alone but
had to know your guest.
There is an epidemic among
the ladies of the city.
It is difficult...
Mr. Adare, the largest Wilkins.
-The commander of the prison.
-Good to know you.
How is the governor
after his trip to England?
-His health is excellent.
Me alegro.
Do not remember me.
I was assistant when he belonged
the staff of Wellington.
I hope that it will
inspect the prison.
It is a disgrace to the colony.
Do not stay there or a pig.
-Believes in pigs?
-No word.
This is something Irish.
-Pardon, you are Irish.
-Yes.
-And the governor also.
A great race.
Men wonderful.
Great gentlemen,
brave soldiers.
I hope you talk to
Sir Richard's arrest.
It is a scandal.
My prime concern
the scandals.
Will have their sympathy.
Flusky, sorry.
My wife had some commitments.
Mr. Adare, I guess.
I am Dr. Macallister.
Very pleased.
I feel the delay, but
My wife could not come.
A last-minute compromise.
Do not worry, I understand it.
Mr. Correct, tax general.
Mr. Adare.
-Both taste.
-How are you?
I talked to his father
on one occasion.
Do not remember me.
-Milly!
-He was right?
None of these vipers.
-Where?
Upstairs-see.
-Do not let down.
-According.
They should start to dinner.
Bring up your cups,
dinner is served.
Can dinner, Mr. Adare.
follow me, gentlemen.
What about our patients?
-I hope you sleep better.
-Very well.
My wife presented his apologies.
Seems to be the focus of the evening.
See their names on the cards.
Do not we have to
sit as separate.
Come, please.
-Benzo the table?
-Yes.
Yes, please.
Kind Lord.
It makes you the thanks for
the gifts we receive.
Makes nourished by them
encontremo us stronger...
... and able to meet
with the duties worthy...
... of his divine will.
Amen
Highest Wilkins,
suit you forgive me.
I was just A. ..
Please, feel you.
I hope not too late to get
take a glass of wine with Argentina.
My wife, gentlemen.
Lady Henrietta Flusky.
Sit down.
Please, feel.
-I do not recall his name.
-Adare.
... forgive me
... for being so silly,
know us?
I think so, although
I was a boy then.
Where we saw?
Adare.
You must be the young Charles.
Strange coincidence.
Yes, I'm Charles.
Yes, remember it.
Adare was the only
that did not fit.
His sister took him one day.
And you no longer lame
my favorite horse.
Sam has never forgiven the.
I serve it with wine?
No, thanks.
Married me with Sam Flusky.
But that was long after.
How is your sister Diana?
Do not write that much.
You are very good. married up.
-With the French?
-Yes.
It is natural.
Only two people know
these things in the world.
A man and woman.
Nobody knows nothing of
Sam or me, except...
... unless...
I am not very good.
I can assist in your arm?
Excuse me, gentlemen.
was a pleasure to see.
Sam, do not you move,
follows with his guests.
This will then.
Sam.
Stay, and Mr. Adare
I are old friends.
Friends of truth.
Thanks, was very nice.
Here I am railing.
Solid handrail.
-Mr. Adare!
-What?
Come soon, please.
Go!
-You have a gun?
-Yes.
Bring, fast.
The bed.
Where is it?
Then, in bed. Do not move.
Will no longer troubled her.
Thanks, I have troubled you.
I am very grateful to you,
very nice.
good night.
-I understand that there are rats.
-Yes, the color pink.
Each has their tastes.
The color is less.
Thus there are rats
in New South Wales
I was young...
... but my aunts did it.
When taking the tea
always said.
Yes?
Was the topic of conversation
long.
I am not surprised.
I was a lad of-court.
-Consider it fun.
I started with very little boy.
I was many years with Consity,
as outside the family.
Ireland take be.
Taught her to ride.
If the visa had mounted
in a horse.
Had a great value.
Jumped a fence as the other side
was the kingdom of heaven.
So was this girl.
And so is...
... but tonight
not the show.
No.
Never dare
you make the cut.
Although he was an angel.
Understand it.
She took the devil in the body.
And believe me too.
Had to arise
and arose.
-You bored?
-No, follow.
His family was determined
to punish me and punish me.
Not enter into details,
... but was lucky to
escape the gallows.
mandrels for me here is 7 years.
He will say that everything is over with this,
but no.
Was sold as
and followed me up here.
-What did you do then?
-Wait.
Open and eyes from
I came to this land.
Do not delay to make a fortune.
Wished only for her.
So had suffered.
Things have not went well.
Kept in a separate
abyss despite the years.
We had that talk of
although in empenhássemos.
As the Bible says,...
... a great chasm...
... what was there.
I had my work.
But she...
Look...
... I missed of the class.
That was what happened.
Never the mencionávamos.
But we can not stop thinking.
We do not care.
What could I do?
why not to send to England?
In England?
You know why I invited you tonight?
No, and I knew.
Believed that all the drafts
colony wanted to know...
... the governor's cousin.
Perhaps better than
have not been.
I thought it would consolation...
... even if met with
poor imitation of its class.
I want those gentlemen.
Gentlemen...
Can I buy them,
spare me money for it.
So I gave the one hundred pounds.
No, this is different.
I distinguish a true gentleman.
Tonight it went
the bad business.
No, it is different, you assure.
It was not her fault
that were not women.
This as the Henrietta
is due and thank you.
No, our agreement follows on foot.
I am not convinced
that agreement. Is it legal?
Absolutely.
Nothing prevents you from selling
their land when it.
-This is the letter of the law.
-And in the spirit?
It is not my subject.
Milly!
Let go Milly.
Milly is very good.
I do not know what would have done without it.
Henrietta knows the deal.
We have to get
this in some way.
We?
I know that I am not responsible, but...
... was a friend of my sister.
Appreciate it.
- I think I will mind.
-I believe.
You can that there is some hope.
Allow me to come
see it on occasion?
Maybe it can interest in
that bunch of new.
Or dresses. Women
like a lot.
We could go to Sydney.
If you speak to those times,
this could help.
You never know.
Yes, really appreciate it.
Do not forget that we are
the same people.
As I told you it was very friendly
on my sister.
Milly, why so long?
The other day I gave orders concrete.
I told you it was not the house
this man.
Now I know that I disobeyed.
Was in a meeting
with the worst of the colony.
It was Mr. Correct.
Where will Mr. Correct
it is something.
Undoubtedly has something
to do today.
What do you mean?
What bothers me coming.
Have you bother?
-Yes, very.
Mr. Correct is my legal adviser.
Come to resolve
a complicated issue...
... and out for you.
Is that your signature?
Yes, Richard is my signature.
Do not call me Richard.
you would be when I talk.
-All right, Mr. Do not change.
me change?
bought land from the government...
... without a penny?
I know, sir.
On behalf of all the devils!
Suppose we have this land.
What you do with them?
-Possibly create sheep.
Create-sheep!
Black sheep.
These lands are in the
the city center.
This exchange the picture.
will graze the sidewalks?
It would be shocking.
If msiturou with
inadequate people.
Correct says Mr. Flusky
demand not violate the law.
More worth it!
Charles...
... is the son of my Aunt Carrie.
It forgive
some foolishness.
But do not sujará
the governor's house.
If I let it break the contract
forget what happened.
If not, wash your hands and go.
If it was not the son of his aunt
that would authorize the sale.
I suppose.
Put the usual
and will.
-Where to live?
-I do not know.
Insurance that Mr Flusky
I welcome the Minyago Yugilla.
-Where?
-Minyago Yugilla.
A luxurious mansion.
The name means:
why cry?
Or why make a mountain
of a grain of sand?
-It is the home of Flusky.
-I.
Mr. Correct me
tell your friend about Flusky.
Grape seed that is not escaped
with Henrietta.
It was a boy of blocks.
There is something worse.
It is quiet, but killed his
brother in cold blood, in Dermot.
If they had done justice
it would have hanged.
The juror said
homicide by recklessness.
Sentenced to 7 years.
This is his friend
has a reputation as a belligerent.
Not-so?
Thus, it is.
Charles does not know this country.
Think.
Re, think
in my position.
Has nothing to do
with its position.
Now reconsidered.
good morning.
you see was a puff of smoke
Irish air.
I am grateful
for that and other things.
I also I am grateful.
It is a pleasure gathering darkness
across the world.
I have said many things.
-It was kind to me at dinner.
-Nonsense.
I remember a little of everything.
-I was right.
-I.
I was completely drunk.
Nobody had told me
this in my life.
It is a shame.
Yes, but nobody did.
Not even Sam?
Does not understand the situation
between Sam and me.
Passed
many things...
... and most of which do not speak.
My weakness has become
part of it.
needs help.
It is too late.
Those 7 years.
I thought after suffering
could be happy.
Not so.
We lost.
-I not worth anything.
-Do not talk like that.
I hoped that everything changed.
Including myself lived the basis
the willingness and I am exhausted.
that is tormenting?
I ridicule
on the night of the party.
I do not recall whether it was dressed.
It was a nightmare.
-I was wearing?
-Yes, more or less.
It is the first time
I see that smile.
-It is very nice.
-No, you are good.
Obtained as M
a dog bum.
I got to make housing
and food and will.
The Irish must cause
better impression in the colony.
We?
It does not matter.
Has a good effect on me.
I always chin
of boredom...
... and now boiling enthusiasm.
We have many things to do.
Navigate the bay.
Mount you. Sam says
which is good horsewoman.
Must be a beautiful horse.
It is useless, I can not.
Learn to take home.
What do the ladies?
-Must have the food.
Milly-dealing that.
Must be punctual,
stay stylish.
Fill the morning with your clothes
or what form the love of home.
Charles, Milly takes care of everything.
I'm finished.
I tried everything by Sam,
but it was useless.
I see myself as I am.
-Right?
-Of course.
Do not look in the mirror?
I have, I am disposing
makes them years.
What to see?
If you see what I...
... will see a very beautiful woman.
What do you think?
I'll get you a mirror,
will be your conscience.
If you look it
every day and say...
... sister Henrietta.
Come on someone?
The mirror will,...
... yes, the riding itself
for departing from the shadows...
... and again to be
sovereign of his kingdom.
I felt that someone
pisava on my tomb.
Milly-is.
-I believe it and fall.
It is a wonderful woman.
Want to much Sam
and is good with me.
His appearance is normal, but
looked at me in a way...
... that would have scared the devil.
What is that funny?
You said things that have made him laugh.
it has smiled.
-Who is that?
-What?
It is the image of Lady Henrietta or not?
looks like it.
-I am proud.
-Charles.
why not?
A respectful tribute
its reincarnation.
We were very respectful.
My intention was not another.
why would I observe?
Because it is a great lady.
promised to be a lady
of your home.
The first work of art
that is done and beautiful.
-Stressed me.
-Yes, but not finished.
We have done more to start.
Now the keys.
are with Milly.
Milly, who think he is?
The keys must have the
the lady of the house.
What to go tinkle. This
give you confidence. Okay.
What is the first battle?
The kitchen.
Milly would be furious
if the kitchen.
It is angry.
You who must give
all orders.
Do not forget.
Okay, let music.
Who gives the orders in
Flusky's house, home of Flusky?
What I would do without you?
Must do without me,
going to the kitchen.
Come with me.
-You are a gentleman.
-Yes.
A gentleman must be discreet.
So do not bring to a woman.
Always the same song.
Bottles and more bottles,
has no remedy.
It is a liar, Susan,
not rub the saucepan.
Of course the esfreguei,
and pans too.
Not discussed.
Which of you is the cook?
What happens to these people?
Speak as Parakeets and
suddenly become silent.
Some are ignorant,
I take care of them.
No, from now on
ask me anything.
However, many left
things to their charge.
Come here every morning.
No, you all to my room
the morning for instructions.
I would like to see the wardrobe of lingerie.
Give me the keys?
Are we.
Yes, give me the keys.
Will be difficult days,
but will continue.
It is useless, you assure.
Better to leave,
is finished.
Do not talk like that.
has interest.
You saw her more than me.
Do not want to talk to her?
Not discouraged,
is recovering.
Tonight does not appear.
Other times it locked and
well spent whole weeks.
Tonight is different.
Almost is itself
and we must do something.
It is pointless and not fun.
I do not know what happened in the kitchen,
but Milly has a fault.
Do not know what Milly
have to bear.
That would
does not speak well of her.
-It is not my thing.
-It is not her thing.
Henrietta and I will help.
Do what you want.
Henrietta!
-No answer.
-I said.
-Not even you.
-I do not dismay.
Henrietta, I am climbing.
Henrietta!
Henrietta.
I do not want to see you again.
get outta here
I could not do what I said.
Go back to Ireland and
say die.
Do not say that.
Go back to Ireland...
... and I leave this wonderful place.
-In this beautiful room.
-No I do it.
You have to get up.
What? The one important...
... if you are standing or head.
-This is better.
-It is not better.
Yes that is much better.
You are standing.
Must always stand.
-Do not ever leave.
-You do honor to you.
Yes it does, or will.
I have never done anything serious
but now I'm doing.
Have courage.
Courage was his birthday,
but lost.
Charles, I am not brave.
I have a disease.
As I can,
but it is a misunderstanding.
What can not it.
Absolutely.
You know what happened in the kitchen?
I lose all control
Milly is right.
It would be the ruin of this house
before a week.
I would prepare a dinner.
But I can not do anything.
Do not remember anything.
You have to remember.
Not remember the wind
that blows from the Atlantic?
Fill your eyes the grass
green, the people born in?
The grass remains on the hill.
Not feel the earth tremble
under the hooves of your horse?
Sleep and dream of it.
Milly the call, the
help you sleep.
Ride tomorrow
to the bay.
A sea is like another.
This will bring you memories.
It is very good to me.
I honor him for Ireland.
Between!
It is you.
help to lie.
-You have not done?
-What do you mean?
Insolent.
I can not avoid it,
I have to say it.
Mr. Flusky, his wife has a problem
without putting in my work.
I have nothing against it,
but not my goal in kitchen.
What to do in other
is not my account,...
... but should open their eyes.
-Pardon, did not know...
-Stay.
has said he owed.
I do not want interference.
-Do not hold it all.
-What is this?
Those who put these ideas to
should leave him.
Who wants to take hat
that light.
One moment!
I believe you should hear something.
Beginning to understand
what is here.
-Last night.
-Yes, last night.
I could say some things
about last night.
Might say, intriguing.
Speak clear.
You know what happened
last night with his wife.
The kitchen and was met
something of a calculated and brutal abruptness.
Last night I saw this man
in your room.
The camera
and she almost naked.
This is rude, to the rest.
-What you said in the kitchen?
What-if.
Already told Mr Flusky,
have the right to ask me.
You do not!
Who believed, is not it?
Pardon is not as stated.
I was there e. ..
Yes, of course it was there.
Came calm and played
some bottles on the table.
Your Lordship knows where appropriate,
to talk about sensitivity.
Mr. Adare, you are
a gentleman was not so.
Damn gentleman,
go away.
You too.
Of course you will of this house.
If you accept these things as I do.
my work
-Let it go.
-We can not do without it.
Everything will improve.
Not good.
All the gossip was
to cover their withdrawal.
Do you believe?
Absolutely.
Do not think...
I do not know what to think.
What do you mean?
It is their word against that of Milly.
-Accept my.
-Why is a gentleman?
Winter also is.
It seems that unite all
against the upstart.
The garbage, the world's contempt.
Against Sam Flusky first.
The boy in court.
The ex-convict.
My wife... is a lady.
The ladies and gentlemen
see things your way.
Can that Milly and I
see differently.
He said I gave him hope.
-Did they despised?
-Not yet.
I listen to myself and not
this gossipy.
Milly here many years.
If you a slander of the Milly,
can give us a hand.
-I understood you wrong.
-So.
Goodbye, Mr. Flusky.
Prayer.
Pray to the Lord
open your eyes.
Goodbye.
-What do I do with the breakfast?
-What do you think?
Milly was instructed that
and the ladies of the kitchen.
I ask the lady Henrietta?
Never gets up before noon.
As a rule these mad?
-If you charge it.
I-I can.
Milly was where?
it was.
-why?
What do I know?
Can not be. Should not go.
Come back.
It is stubborn as a mule.
Sam, this is terrible.
There must be a reason.
How are you?
I very well, thank you.
The post of governor's house.
There is no quote or invoice.
It is a wonderful morning.
-What happened?
Milly-is gone.
It is a wonderful morning.
It is perfect.
What will I do without it?
-Mr Adare says everything.
-We will see.
Will speak
with them yourself.
Who gives the orders
this house?
I will send the
all to Sydney.
Sam,...
... I will.
Well-Henrietta.
-Will be silent!
So he said, is my good heart
who sent it.
It is the truth.
If a woman do if your heart,
it throws the ruin.
Where the guard?
Search genever?
Not to care.
Not enough on top.
The baby that arrives.
Not disapproved.
-See what I have done?
-Yes.
You know what?
As of today do not
You 'il take anyone in this house.
-Understand?
-Yes.
yes, my lady.
Yes, my lady.
If you want to stay here
may do so.
There are 3 things I dislike.
The noise, fights and robberies.
If any commit any
these three things...
... back to the prison.
Yes, my lady.
What is your name?
Susan, the soft.
that soft?
Why am.
Smooth as butter,
as they say.
-Call him Susan.
-Yes, my lady.
Who is the cook?
Often-I.
-It 's a liar.
-I am the chef, she a killer.
-Silence!
-Marta, knows casserole?
-No, my lady.
The three will make the breakfast.
Coffee, toast, eggs and bacon.
3 cafes in the morning match.
Each prepare a breakfast.
What you do best
will be the chef.
Yes, my lady.
Well, no noise, no fights.
To work.
leave me alone.
-No, I do.
-Charles...
-I have news.
On behalf of your
Governor excellence,...
... Flusky Mr. Sam and his wife,
lady Henrietta Flusky,...
... are invited to the prom
of the Irish...
... in the palace of government
on 24 January.
-I do not like these games.
-It is not.
I got the invitation in the mail.
Do not understand. Never in
had invited the governor.
Do not invite an ex-convict.
My cousin is always
what you want.
It is a family inheritance.
Have to go.
You heard what
my husband said.
I agree with him.
I want it
Henrietta. They see...
Could this new dance
French dance. Meet the waltz?
It is seductive and a respectable time.
Do not say nonsense.
For years already danced in Ireland.
-Once you know dance.
-Do both.
-There.
-No.
What I heard, no?
No woman in fashion
says no.
What would the governor
is rejecting the call?
You have to show them to all...
... which is a real lady.
I have that dress.
-I find something.
-Of course it is.
Fixed then.
No, do not talk anymore.
It is his return to society.
Will the sound of trumpeter
and violins.
Do not be coward.
Okay.
Would you, Sam?
I do not dance, and much suo.
Take Mr. Adare.
No one can compare it
in one hundred miles around.
I will be proud of you.
Is the end of everything.
Be... keys.
guard that ask
when needed.
No, I want you to have.
Hanging at the waist, as Milly.
So do not lose
and enjoy it.
Buy a beautiful dress.
Today I will go to Sydney.
Monitor or better
Henrietta and I will.
You are right.
I only buy chairs and harness.
So the shoemaker shoes.
I just write my sister,
or put a few lyrics?
No, make on my behalf.
I write.
How do I start?
As you said in my
letter that is 15 years...
No, put: Diana, mi...
... dear friend.
I hope you can
call though.
certain that his brother
you said something to me.
From my story.
But it has said,
because they do not know,...
... how grateful we are.
The happier we feel
with your company.
I believe
because I know.
Your company.
I appreciate it very much...
... and should feel proud of him.
Your stay means...
... more than I can express.
Someday you will
New South Wales
Then you tell it.
Must not do
Governor expected.
-How do I look, Sam?
-Very well.
Well? The lakes are well.
The twilight of
the pyramids are right.
The Taj Mahal is well.
Sam, you say something more original.
I think that was a jewel not bad.
I think so, Sam?
It is a suggestion,
a necklace of rubies.
With that outfit?
They seem
a Christmas tree?
You are right.
Do not go with this dress
and I have rubies.
said it was a suggestion.
Be perfect.
Will make us ugly.
-Goodbye, Sam.
-Walking.
Very beautiful, I
to recognize.
They make a cute couple,
This blood.
I collect my chest.
Tomorrow beginning at
home of Mr. Correct.
Admitted to me today,
therefore come too late.
Can I sleep in my
old room?
Will get a car
my chest early.
Yes
It allows me to bring
something hot as before?
Do cold in this house tonight.
Should not expose themselves to a cold.
Not enough care of himself.
You will, though
be distracted these days.
That is well, it was wonderful.
As if it had produced
something new in your life.
The dance of the governor.
Not just the miracles.
All the talk of your town
dress and how beautiful it is.
If instructed him, Mr. Adare himself.
Not a minute left or
the home of the seamstress.
Everyone says that you
Adare is a lady...
... because it is strange that a man
deals with things of women.
Although it has nothing to bad.
Are noble.
They have our standards.
They leaflet for everything.
Here I am chatting.
Is loneliness.
It is fair that you have fun
since you do not lose your head.
I should not ask me about it.
Not ceased to
is doubtful.
It is no longer the
court that his wife.
You are a man
that respect.
So you respect everybody.
Or almost all.
But it is wonderful that
lady has ido...
... in a car in the dark.
Surrounded by lights and music.
There is a new style of dance.
Man and woman dancing
embraced by pall.
Call waltz.
I do not believe that the dance party.
No woman
leave a decent
strange embrace it
with everyone watching.
Although...
Mr.... Flusky, I am worried.
I hope you do not
case that Mr. Adare...
... were in
quarter of the lady.
She had no guilt.
not
was responsible for his actions at that time.
was dressed in half and gave
not account for anything .
Made me fear what
took to open the door.
I could have mistaken me.
I wish I had wrong.
Sorry, is not on the list.
should be an official
jurisdiction.
The right to the governor.
Sorry, sir.
The Honorable Charles Adare
and lady...
This is not my letter.
must satisfy
the card itself.
-Allows me?
-Yes, major.
But lack of practice.
Had not seen in my life.
-It is a great lady.
-Here it comes.
-Who is it?
A wife of Flusky.
-Who?
-It is very beautiful.
A large Irish lady.
Who is that
delicious creature?
Who refers?
Who knows. Do not get
eyes from above.
That, sir?
I do not know.
Ask.
Can you talk a moment?
Yes, what happens?
produced by a
embarrassment.
You can see this invitation?
It is intolerable.
His Excellency stressed
they do not invite him.
Of course I said.
Where is this person?
good night.
-What party so beautiful!
-Do you that?
Why are you here?
Nothing yet.
I dance a little.
Was not invited.
Banks, which is forgotten
I Irish.
He has nothing to do.
I personally
deleted his name from the list.
-why?
-You know.
Disobeyed my orders.
Vai in bad company and
is not better than them.
Devi lheenviar Ireland
is weeks.
Richard, with respect to their dependents,
Plenty...
gossip.
As both,
but not to listen.
go away.
I have just arrived.
If you do not leave before
of two minutes...
Sir, lady Henrietta Flusky.
Charming.
Hatty consists.
Go,...
... met his father.
We saw
because prior to remember.
Yes we saw.
But the master of his majesty
give little attention...
... the girls with delantalitos.
I imagine with a smock.
I am confused,
remember it perfectly.
it has more in our horses
that in me.
Mount the horse now?
-My days went from amazon.
-No way.
We will give a tour one day.
Dinner?
I love, but Mr. Adare...
Lady Henrietta, I am sorry.
received urgent orders.
I have to obey the next.
You have to monitor the house.
Sir Richard, I...
I received the instructions
for its excellence in person.
-We gotta go.
-Charles.
No, sir.
The minutes are
of vital importance.
-after all...
-It is important to me.
spent the two minutes.
-I have no remedy to obey.
-We see another...
There is no other in any position
like mine.
I would urge you to be fired
of their excellence.
What should I do?
What I say and dinner.
Mr. Adare, if there
served in the army...
... know that if they
contradictory orders,...
... will meet later.
Ordering him to stay.
Give me the honor?
Charles is the son of a
my sister, Carrie.
Highest Wilkins, I'm Mrs Riggs,
Remember me?
Certainly, may I?
Thank you.
Sam, who changed opinion.
Magnificent.
allow me.
-It 's my friend.
Everything went well.
Be proud, it was
for dinner with the governor.
-Take a cup and you explain.
-Where?
Dining with the governor.
Would not there is
obtained a triumph.
Not the damage.
Damage it?
I believe, not worth for my wife
when you poke the nobility.
Do not be ridiculous.
Has not dressed for the prom.
Put it into a compromise.
Be reasonable.
I take your hands off.
I do not know
nothing more from you.
prior to ten years now
had me all the broken bones.
Great.
why not mount now?
A husband likes the horses?
-Yes, of course we like.
Sam.
What surprised me this.
Sir Richard, I present to you
to my husband.
Talking of horses.
You said...
I grew up in a
stable. I have heard.
Sir Richard bought the Rocks to the Pride
Dad died when we take the court.
-Remember the Rocks Pride?
-Yes.
I left him lame and Dad thought
that would have to kill him.
Sam the healed.
It was more, brush him.
Gave him to eat,
... cleaned him because pesebre
was a boy in court.
-married with one created.
-I see.
There should be between
many gentlemen.
It is a party beneficiente.
My money is as true
like the others.
With the greetings of Sam Flusky.
This pay for dinner for my wife.
I imagine that his cousin
Nor have paid.
We also invite.
Do not have a penny
that it has given me.
Here is your part.
I do not know what is being proposed.
But I have very good memory
for this class of incidents.
What drove him to do that?
Insisted that outside
and damaged everything.
-You are jealous.
-Don 't know what.
You know which is lower
and is felt to you.
Are you top of their brightness, their world.
You are crazy, go back to Ireland.
suffered much.
I have done so much damage you...
I love to...
and I marry him.
By not giving him children.
I was a burden for him as
to repeat these in this country.
How will not hate me?
Their debt is liquidated.
Now it should not.
This is not to pay a debt.
Sam is part of me and
I him forever.
This makes the learning
much when I was a girl.
It was well and nothing could change it.
Together cavalgávamos
for miles.
For hours.
Sam five steps backwards.
In respectful silence
as a good place.
I shudder to content
because I knew what love was.
My father does not worry
tardança on our return.
Sam knew it was trust.
Would return unharmed.
Sit on the grass.
Facing the bay,
looking the ocean calm,...
... deep and quiet...
... as their love for me.
I knew because of his love
had spoken to me of him.
With soft and sweet
Irish voices.
We never said anything.
One day we went to Dublin
the exhibition of livestock.
Sam subjects my horse
a store front.
When grabbed the stirrup
so I put up...
... said with his voice rough,...
... 'I condemn this. "
I said: 'Sam baby,...
... I will save. "
That night grabbed the jewels
that was prepared...
... to the dance of the viceroy
and ride for hours...
... in the rain until druggist.
We found a fisherman who
led us to Scotland by the channel.
A thief of horses in
sold two animals...
... with those that did
the route.
A pastor in the united
in marriage.
I was exhausted.
We take our first
breakfast in an inn.
Sam looked to the front of me.
Was also tired.
But Sam has always
something to do.
Was cleaning and pressing the
gun that had brought it.
ria as hum
in a low voice.
Then came Dermot,
my brother.
It was a great rider,
its only good quality.
Carrying a pistol in his hand.
With the death in the eyes said...
... who married them?
Not enjoy it '.
Pointed his gun at me.
Sam stood up for a jump.
Covered me with his body.
Grabbed the gun on the table
and shot against my brother.
Shot under the arm of Sam.
There was an expression
of amazement on his face.
Dermot dropped.
The gun he shot to fall.
They found the bullet in
March of the window.
This saved the power of Sam...
... as found guilty.
Did not know that he is accused.
I was so sick that
I am not acquainted with anything.
My family will not let me talk
with anyone.
They wanted to avoid the scandal.
Delirei for weeks.
Once I knew what he did for me.
Was arrested on a ship
of prisoners,...
... across the world.
I wrote...
... 'if something is worth what
there was among us,...
... not say anything.
Do for me, my love. "
I. ..
... could not talk after that.
Had to meet him.
I did what was
in my hand.
Follow it up here and talk to
him through the bars of prison.
How you lived these years?
What matters?
I thought it was a consolation
to know that he was here.
Wanted to offer a home...
when to leave...
to compensate for the suffering.
I thought we could redo
our life in this country.
But...
... I was surrounded by terrible things.
That hut...
... in the port.
Full of moisture
and insect repellent.
Those women drunk.
Boys looking at
refuse to eat something.
That misery.
Once again,...
Sam tried... I forget
when his sentence expired.
There is nothing.
It was part of me.
Still would
falling below...
... how far could not
reach below.
Where to now nothing could hurt me.
No man deserves
such sacrifice.
Believes that he understands
you have done?
No, still have to live your life.
Is inconsistent with this.
When Sam came in tonight
hall, paid as it could be.
Not understand.
This could not do it
the governor's house.
You may be alone.
Out!
Sam, makes a mistake.
-I heard?
-Yes, I heard you!
You heard what he said.
Not worth the sacrifice
it has done.
Please.
Tomorrow-speak.
Non-pass another night here.
-Please, Sam.
-Outside of this house!
-Don 't understand.
-Out!
I listen well, back tomorrow
and if you...
Sam, like going back to Sydney?
Re walking, whatever.
vai grab your horse.
Prevent it, not let him.
Mount does not know if killing.
Dane-up him.
-Don 't understand.
What happened?
Never been so.
Appeared in a crazy dance.
Now again it seems.
-What is it?
-You know.
Your caballerete too.
This does not make me.
It is a...
... shameless.
Go see the mare.
Do not let me near.
tired out.
Can not raise.
with a broken foot.
Damn the time
who came to this house.
Where you going?
Neither I nor my mind.
Almost kill me.
Kill the horse.
Do not know what it means to him.
A gentleman, a bloody murderer.
Not yet?
lost another job?
The first is the first.
need someone.
It's terrible suffering
by others.
I refer to Mr. Adare.
The had warned.
Where is it?
Lady Henrietta did not see
also to Mr. Adare.
Wait until you see.
Milly will be
despite everything?
Can I see Mr. Adare?
Do hours of hope.
We have specific orders
not between you, lady Henrietta.
I knew it would something.
How could I bring to
this irresponsible idiot?
Do not understand.
Charles, sorry, I
to comply with my duty.
Here is the general tax.
You must declare
on the aggression of Flusky.
The suit does not make him talk.
His life in danger.
I do not think it protects the woman.
If you die, for nothing
serve this.
Be equal at all.
Charles has nothing to fun.
I agree.
Should begin now,
lost much blood.
It is important to rest.
You should go.
I believed that was what
gave the orders.
Where is the general tax?
You are here, come,
do what we say.
How are you?
you ask the doctor.
For my part tell you something,
... Charles is to recover the
exclude from that territory.
If you die, hang your husband.
I will in my colony to
Flusky as a wild beast.
Return to the penitentiary.
This is impossible.
It is not impossible.
Only one release emancipated
remains good.
was an accident.
There was no fault of anyone.
Last night I learned how
was Mr. Flusky.
He knows by his violence.
Escaped the gallows by miracle.
No, make mistakes.
It is a former prison.
This is his second offense.
This is not exact.
You should never condemn.
For all the Saints!
Killed his brother.
No,...
... was I who killed him.
it gives an account of the case?
Yes, I give.
Sam found guilty.
Promised to never
nobody would know.
Perhaps forgive me...
... when you know you did.
If this is true, I
to comply with my duty.
I am an old soldier of
one religion, the duty.
The general tax the
as will comply.
Yes, its excellence is right.
If ratify his confession
the crime, the more certain...
... it has to return
Ireland to be judged.
It is the truth and I must say
Sam and I shirk, We A. ..
Rented a cart for
I bring.
I no longer see the Charles.
Believe they can die.
If you survive, to expel
and forward to Ireland.
Gives the impression that
prefer to live.
I saw the governor.
It was the general tax.
As is known, correct?
Yes, correct.
No one believed
word of what he said.
It was a nightmare.
Will send to Ireland.
They said I killed Dermot.
I know, Sam.
I know I have broken my oath,
but had to do it.
It was the only way.
my god.
take me with you.
With which Ireland.
There the linked too.
It was neat
between you and the governor.
The Honorable Charles
Adare leaves the house...
... and the noble lady will later.
What do I do?
Taking care of the house while
fun in Dublin?
They keep
lit the fire until...
... your friend is tired of you
and return it?
Is wrong.
If you think so, see me.
Go for what?
To return to be created?
Swap it for what?
after that I made there,
want all the leaves.
Well I will not.
Shame of years that you paid for.
was so silly
to tell you.
Now you pay, not me.
I got it done for you.
Had imprisoned him.
Hang it by cheat.
saw the other night.
It is very serious.
Go with this if you like.
go.
Sam does not know what to say.
You are wrong.
Do not take seriously.
I would.
is saying without thinking.
Looks sick,
should drink.
I did not know what was left.
I taão little.
-A lucky.
-Sorry.
Forgive.
Too hot.
we have a storm.
The doctor says he is better.
Insect-bad...
-Yes, I am better.
Leaving the next week.
What do we do with you?
What rights to his father
and aunt Carrie?
I have to send him over there.
Sure.
I think we can take so
I can not tolerate scandals.
It is very bad.
You can go back and lady Henrietta
in the same vessel.
What do you mean?
-Left to Ireland?
-There is no other remedy.
It does not matter,
Correct and is mine.
What is more
that grape seed without this?
Comply with its duty,
how even more.
-For more unpleasant it is.
-What to say?
What will do with it?
confessed the crime by
which condemned the Flusky.
According to her killed her
brother Dermot.
Confessed.
I missed that you have made.
feeling well?
asks the doctor.
returned to their old habits.
I will dispense.
I am glad you are better.
Good night, Doctor.
The doctor is gone.
Then leave the dinner.
What say?
Can I sit?
I could not believe the
bad as it is.
Some said they see strange things.
As horrible as before.
You know, delira.
Recipes you more
somniferous of the strong.
5 drops every 4 hours.
Said that more
I had no more to ask when
be able to travel.
-He said that?
-Very little. Not responding.
Knows more than he says.
You are always with the governor.
Adare said it is better.
Get me a weight from above.
The Lord follows mysterious ways
for his miracles.
All ends well.
When you went,
you will live in peace.
I never had peace.
I will with it.
Will?
We need the state
where you are.
But the house,
which will make it?
Sell everything.
Sank forever.
Here is someone you,
there is not anyone.
I know all this.
I do not care.
She has friends there.
Will do that by
daughter of an earl.
Leave it to the noble and
with Adare. She will feel good.
Should not go, Mr. Flusky.
Do not go.
Stay with me, take care of you.
Work you to death.
Do not go.
In taking a decision...
... never go back.
Milly!
I will.
May not rise, Mr. Flusky.
Is not likely that
see. Close the windows.
Instructed me to look after it,
leave me.
Do what I said.
Hatty.
Sam, come on.
away from me, I tell you.
Does that go.
Please make it go.
Then in bed.
Where is there.
Always the same, looking at me.
Nothing.
be calm.
You have to kill you, Sam.
Not to see?
Charles saw her.
Shot and the mouse was gone.
Nothing.
I told him to please him.
They are visions.
Nothing, assure you that.
See.
You can see it yourself.
Nothing.
Was dreaming.
The wind...
moved and the lights...
moved up the shadows.
Do not see what you doing?
Must be strong.
If you continue,
be crazy.
Come on, lady Henrietta.
Not discouraged.
I brought you something to drink.
Logo throws and sleeps.
Drink up.
Sam!
Calm down, you will awaken
the whole house.
Flusky not want to see that.
-Sam!
-Shut up!
-What is the scandal?
-Sam!
-Do you not see how you behave?
It has nothing to fear.
-What happens?
-Shut up.
-Want to kill me.
-What are you saying?
Do not know what it says.
tried to give me the drug
this whole cup.
-I.
-Look what you have done.
Look in the basket.
It was this that plot.
Work for me until death.
Okay, even death.
You drove me to do so.
How would let go?
If you believe that it would leave
that is sacrificed...
I know how are these aristocrats.
Do not understand.
-Hatty not believe that...
-Of course not.
why did it?
Believed to my friend.
I am not your friend.
Sink to you and
was falling to yourself.
It easier to drink.
Do not understand.
You are in love with my husband?
Do not say that.
The Lord does not forgive
by saying something.
All this time...
... trying to kill me.
Treated to kill you.
When I felt hopeless...
... I brought you a drink.
Each night more.
-You asked.
-Yes, ask her.
I wanted to convert
as I convert...
... to my husband that I hated.
Today we wanted to finish once.
Do not mind.
You are crazy.
It is the drink.
The doctor said
would therefore be the end.
The Lord punished him.
Simply, viper.
I saw that this was done.
I know it, Sam.
I know...
... that kind of love drives
to do terrible things.
I do not understand that kind of love.
When you and I talk about
love do differently.
You know.
In spite of that we
happened, you know.
that wanted to kill me?
Believes that love a killer?
With a married.
No, Mr. Flusky am not enough
for you. I know.
Only serve to work
as employed.
-Take care of this drunk.
-Shut up!
Sam, let it
will not hurt us.
-Let me your covers?
-No.
It is a little late.
Yes, believed it would be better
come the night.
The governor wants to avoid
the scandal if possible.
What do you want?
Take-statement.
-Come to my office.
No, you give legal form
below.
Know without doubt that his wife is
confessed to having killed his brother.
We need
confirm the statement.
This will shorten the procedure.
Avoid delays.
And can be excused.
I help them to
Hang my wife.
Hurry to save them work.
Do not dare to
say that.
In short, can not
you do anything without my explanation.
In a sense, it is.
The law differently.
Leave this house now.
Okay.
I must notify you that it delivered
mittimus...
... against you by intent
the murder of Charles Adare.
If you persist in your attitude, if
give way to that commandment.
It was an accident.
I must remind you that
an ex-convict...
... and we are in
New South Wales
It is his second offense.
You know what?
Yes, I know.
committed an act of violence.
You can not hang more.
Do not believe that.
We will not do so, return to activities
I was familiar with.
Is it easy to get used to
to work again...
... in jail for inmates.
I shot against Adare.
What he said?
It was an accident.
I explained him the situation.
I was generous with you.
Offered him the opportunity to not
be a real ex-convict.
It would be a huge difference.
I will give you time to
tomorrow to reflect.
What happens, Sam?
-What?
-Correct and his assistant.
What do you want?
Nothing.
I do not humor
listen to them.
-told them walk.
-You can not do anything.
confessed.
-Yes, confessed.
-What you want?
I declare.
Was prepared to
risking his life for me.
-What else could we do?
-Sacrifice.
Sacrifice.
Are we sacrificing
always the one by the other.
This must have an end.
The law says that there was a death.
Have you paid for it.
that following the chase?
Not dare to touch him.
Nobody can do you harm.
I saved you.
Always be together.
Do not say anything.
Tomorrow we talk about this.
-Sam.
-No more talk tonight.
Platoon, turn around.
Ready to mount, assemble.
Above you,
Look behind you.
The head high, not
won us yet.
Ready? That between now.
Winter, ask the car.
I go to Sydney.
What is talk that way?
Are you treated as a
ex-convict and are not entitled.
Mr. Correct gave
an opportunity.
You just have to say a word.
I talked to him this morning,
never say that.
be where you are.
Sir Richard, I'm desperate.
What you do?
confessed that killed the Dermot
to show that never...
... should you order.
He said as such as
Mr. Adare injured.
Do not count it?
Mr. Adare is hurt.
We will give your version.
It is not necessary at this time.
Listened to those created
discussion and shot.
I saw her husband a
hours before all this.
Was capable of something.
This is intolerable.
What is here, for
what is raised?
-Hatty, told me that he had been.
-Charles.
And that is sick.
What is this a confession?
I am not sick.
How are you?
that come from?
imprisoned for Sam again.
Do not understand.
What happened?
Is quieting their
nerves in prison.
Should be the last
to regret it.
You helped me.
more than anyone knows.
help me now.
What to leave Sam in freedom.
tell them what happened.
Have to leave you free.
return it to me Charles.
They say they tried to kill him.
they explain it was an accident.
Best is between 4 walls.
Best to you, to
me and lady Henrietta.
-The murderer.
-No, Sir Richard.
Mr. Adare-know...
Lady Henrietta, you know what happened.
I know what happened.
Have something to say?
If so, say it and
just go to the order.
Accompanied the lady Henrietta
your house after the dance.
Flusky came to little time.
I was furious.
You know, Richard, you saw.
No matter the reasons,
but I played for his home.
Grabbed his horse to return.
It was very dark.
In a shock to some high
that had not seen...
... and just in a gutter.
I was hurt and
horse broke a leg.
I came back and told Flusky.
was seeking a gun.
Went out and killed the animal.
When I returned...
... wanted to grab the gun.
Was double barrel.
I did it meanly e. ..
... received a shot in the shoulder.
That is all.
Lady Henrietta said
that discussed.
This was said?
Flusky was not very happy by
have lost their favorite horse.
Do not remember discussing.
I warn you I do not believe it.
This will be my statement.
Give me your word of
honor, as gentleman,...
... that was all that happened?
Word of honor.
Correct, you leave in freedom.
But excellence...
... is not so easy.
-Not yet started.
-Do what you say.
Lady Henrietta, I
which could for you.
Have the goodness to leave.
I have no time to
talk ladies.
I mind me, sir,
... and I am very grateful.
Goodbye, Sam.
Mr. Adare, is very
what you need.
Goodbye, for now.
Be the first immigrant to
returns to the homeland without fortune.
Be the fool of Dublin.
-Bye, Hatty.
-Bye, Charles.
I forget.
I can never forget it.
-Sorry to go.
-I do feel that.
This place is not bad.
There is a great future.
It is a great country.
-that part?
-So.
Is not large enough.
Goodbye and good luck.