7
00:04:41,147 --> 00:04:43,445
Anda, perro. ¡Quítese!

13
00:05:56,089 --> 00:05:58,557
Buenas tardes.

15
00:06:54,013 --> 00:06:56,982
Why are you afraid of me?

16
00:06:57,083 --> 00:07:00,814
I love you. I love you.

17
00:07:00,920 --> 00:07:03,980
You came to life for me.

18
00:07:04,090 --> 00:07:06,285
Don't you know me?

19
00:07:06,392 --> 00:07:08,292
Buenas noches, doctor.

20
00:07:08,394 --> 00:07:11,158
- Ah. Buenas noches, señor Geoffrey.
- Buenas noches.

21
00:07:11,264 --> 00:07:13,164
Just in time. Exactamente.

22
00:07:13,266 --> 00:07:15,257
The inglés is always by the clock.

23
00:07:16,302 --> 00:07:19,271
You go to the Red Cross, I think.

25
00:07:21,741 --> 00:07:25,177
Mm-mmm. It's good.

26
00:07:25,278 --> 00:07:27,940
Very good.

27
00:07:30,249 --> 00:07:33,412
But, no, there is something wrong.

28
00:07:34,520 --> 00:07:38,012
I know, señor.
You have no socks.

29
00:07:42,862 --> 00:07:46,525
Quite. No socks.

30
00:07:46,632 --> 00:07:51,569
With that espléndida vestimenta,
there must be socks.

31
00:07:51,671 --> 00:07:55,801
- You want I should bring you?
- No. Gracias. Not necessary.

32
00:07:56,909 --> 00:07:59,935
By the way, señor Bustamante,
did you find any letters -

33
00:08:00,046 --> 00:08:02,537
can'tas - any letters addressed to me?

34
00:08:02,648 --> 00:08:06,015
No. No, señor.
lfind no letters for you.

35
00:08:08,554 --> 00:08:11,614
What letters have you lost?

36
00:08:11,724 --> 00:08:13,749
From my wife.

38
00:08:17,163 --> 00:08:20,462
You have heard from her then.
What does she say?

39
00:08:20,566 --> 00:08:22,727
Is she coming back to Mexico?

40
00:08:22,835 --> 00:08:26,134
No. I don't think so.

41
00:08:26,239 --> 00:08:28,605
I'm sorry to see you apart.

42
00:08:28,708 --> 00:08:32,576
I have always great admiration
for señora Yvonne.

43
00:08:32,678 --> 00:08:34,509
I think she comes back.

44
00:08:34,614 --> 00:08:37,412
She writes to you,
then she will come back.

45
00:08:44,724 --> 00:08:47,693
I also received a letter
from her lawyer.

46
00:08:48,895 --> 00:08:50,863
It seems we're divorced now.

47
00:08:50,963 --> 00:08:54,126
Uy, amigo.

48
00:08:54,233 --> 00:08:57,259
Is this true?
Yes.

49
00:09:01,107 --> 00:09:03,007
It's true.

51
00:09:08,581 --> 00:09:11,049
I promise to come back.

52
00:09:11,150 --> 00:09:13,710
No!
You won't come back.

53
00:09:13,819 --> 00:09:17,846
You hate me. You despise me.
No. No.

54
00:09:17,957 --> 00:09:20,448
Liar! Hypocrite!

56
00:09:29,135 --> 00:09:32,070
Las Manos de Orlac.
The Hands of Orlac, no?

57
00:09:32,171 --> 00:09:34,071
It's a good story.

58
00:09:34,173 --> 00:09:38,007
A man is a pianist,
but loses his hands under a train.

59
00:09:38,110 --> 00:09:42,012
Is given him another,
but they are the hands of a killer.

60
00:09:42,114 --> 00:09:45,015
Uh, these hands murder people.

61
00:09:45,117 --> 00:09:49,781
But his heart does not,
and he's very, very sorry.

62
00:09:49,889 --> 00:09:53,985
Some things you can't apologize for.

63
00:09:54,093 --> 00:09:57,221
The fate of all the world is changed, I think.

65
00:10:00,066 --> 00:10:03,661
Only in Mexico
is death an occasion for laughter.

66
00:10:03,769 --> 00:10:08,866
On Day of the Dead,
when their spirits come back to us...

67
00:10:08,975 --> 00:10:13,105
the road from heaven
must be made - made easy...

68
00:10:13,212 --> 00:10:15,180
and not slippery with tears.

72
00:10:46,212 --> 00:10:50,478
Sorry, old girl.
They won't let you into this occasion.

73
00:10:50,583 --> 00:10:53,381
Your gowrs cut far too low.

74
00:10:58,224 --> 00:11:00,317
Good evening, sir.
How are you?

75
00:11:00,426 --> 00:11:03,088
How are you?
You know the doctor.

76
00:11:05,798 --> 00:11:07,698
Poquito de brandy.

77
00:11:07,800 --> 00:11:09,825
Poquito de anís.

78
00:11:09,935 --> 00:11:12,233
Poquito de tequila.

79
00:11:13,773 --> 00:11:15,832
Mmm. Poquito de whiskey.

80
00:11:15,941 --> 00:11:17,841
Poquito de mezcal.

81
00:11:17,943 --> 00:11:20,878
Oh, no, no. No mescal.
Never touch mescal.

82
00:11:21,914 --> 00:11:24,075
I'd go thirsty
before drinking mescal.

83
00:11:24,183 --> 00:11:27,846
Is loco.
Mescal is just the tequila of the poor.

84
00:11:27,953 --> 00:11:29,887
Mescal is for the damned.

85
00:11:29,989 --> 00:11:33,789
Oh, good Christ.
Last blast of diplomacy coming up.

86
00:11:35,261 --> 00:11:37,661
Buenas noches, señor Firmin.
Buenas noches.

87
00:11:37,763 --> 00:11:43,292
I wish to introduce to you
Herr Krausberg, German attaché.

88
00:11:43,402 --> 00:11:46,565
Herr Krausberg, Mr. Firmin.

89
00:11:46,672 --> 00:11:49,641
Former British Consul to Cuernavaca.

90
00:11:49,742 --> 00:11:51,937
It's a great pleasure for me
to meet you, Mr. Firmin.

91
00:11:52,044 --> 00:11:54,638
Same, I'm sure.
Un cocktail de champagne.

92
00:11:54,747 --> 00:11:59,116
I hope your next, uh, post
will be as beautiful as Cuernavaca.

93
00:11:59,218 --> 00:12:02,619
Nothing next. I've retired.
Oh, have you really?

94
00:12:02,722 --> 00:12:06,681
"Cut is the branch that might have grown
full straight," or something like that.

95
00:12:06,792 --> 00:12:09,784
I'm going to stay on here in Mexico.

96
00:12:09,895 --> 00:12:12,728
Oh, how fortunate for me.

97
00:12:12,832 --> 00:12:15,198
I hope to have a friendship with you...

98
00:12:15,301 --> 00:12:19,101
as close, as cordial, as the friendship
between our two nations.

99
00:12:19,205 --> 00:12:23,301
Actually, Herr Krausberg,
you may be able to do me a great service.

100
00:12:23,409 --> 00:12:25,843
I would be very happy to help
in whatever way I can.

101
00:12:25,945 --> 00:12:27,845
It's to do with my brother-
half brother.

102
00:12:27,947 --> 00:12:29,915
- Do you understand "half brother"?
- Mm-hmm.

103
00:12:30,015 --> 00:12:33,348
F-Father remarried
an American Southern beauty.

104
00:12:33,452 --> 00:12:36,819
Hugh. Uh, newspaperman.
Freelance sort of stuff.

105
00:12:36,922 --> 00:12:40,187
He's chasing some rumor down
right now.

106
00:12:40,292 --> 00:12:44,092
But you may be able to shed some light.
Most gladly, if I can.

107
00:12:44,196 --> 00:12:48,030
Is Germany financing a Nazi movement
here in Mexico?

108
00:12:49,535 --> 00:12:53,562
Of course not. Your brother, Mr. Firmin -
Half. Half.

109
00:12:53,672 --> 00:12:55,936
Half. Sorry. Your half brother...

110
00:12:56,041 --> 00:12:58,908
obviously suffers
from an overactive imagination.

111
00:12:59,011 --> 00:13:01,571
Called the sinarquistas,
if I'm not mistaken.

112
00:13:01,680 --> 00:13:05,207
Nonsense. It's just a rumor, as you said.

113
00:13:05,317 --> 00:13:09,151
In any case,
we are allies now, aren't we?

114
00:13:10,189 --> 00:13:14,751
Since that marvelous agreement between
your prime minister and our führer.

115
00:13:14,860 --> 00:13:17,988
So, let's drink together, shall we?

116
00:13:18,097 --> 00:13:21,498
To, uh -To the understanding of our nations.

117
00:13:21,600 --> 00:13:26,094
It is a union I'm, uh, convinced...

118
00:13:26,205 --> 00:13:28,969
that will assure peace
for many, many years to come.

119
00:13:29,074 --> 00:13:31,042
Prost, Herr Firmin.

120
00:13:32,845 --> 00:13:35,507
Yes, quite.
The Munich Pact and all that.

121
00:13:35,614 --> 00:13:38,981
Peace in our timel
But let's not be too hasty.

122
00:13:39,084 --> 00:13:44,613
Let's hedge our bets, what?
After all, the Mexican railroad has.

123
00:13:44,723 --> 00:13:47,157
They don't mean to be taken by surprise.

124
00:13:47,259 --> 00:13:52,128
Just take a look at their newest timetable -
at the fine print.

125
00:13:52,231 --> 00:13:56,725
Corpses must be transported by express.

126
00:13:56,836 --> 00:13:59,168
Each of these express corpses...

127
00:13:59,271 --> 00:14:03,605
must be accompanied
by a first-class passenger.

128
00:14:03,709 --> 00:14:08,510
Now, let's suppose, uh, the treaty fails
and it's bloody Armageddon.

129
00:14:08,614 --> 00:14:10,275
Just think of it.
You -You

130
00:14:10,382 --> 00:14:12,213
Railways stand to make a fortune.

131
00:14:12,318 --> 00:14:14,479
You're right. You're right.
But just think of it.

132
00:14:14,587 --> 00:14:18,455
All of those bloody corpses,
each holding a first-class ticket.

133
00:14:18,557 --> 00:14:20,252
Absolutely.

134
00:14:20,359 --> 00:14:23,294
One Day of the Dead won't be enough.

135
00:14:23,395 --> 00:14:26,762
Month. Decade.

136
00:14:26,866 --> 00:14:29,664
Age of the Dead, more like it!

137
00:14:29,768 --> 00:14:33,101
The whole world
will learn to laugh...

138
00:14:33,205 --> 00:14:36,299
at the sight of stinking cadavers.

139
00:14:36,408 --> 00:14:39,809
Oh, ha, ha.
Bloody ha, ha, ha!

140
00:14:39,912 --> 00:14:41,812
Oh, good God.

141
00:14:41,914 --> 00:14:45,816
Express trains will be booked up
years in advance.

142
00:14:45,918 --> 00:14:50,787
Corpses hand in hand
with bloody first-class ticket holders...

143
00:14:50,890 --> 00:14:55,054
standing in lines for miles
waiting for transport.

144
00:14:55,160 --> 00:14:57,060
Aha. Yes.

145
00:14:59,365 --> 00:15:02,391
Ladies and gentlemen of the Red Cross...

146
00:15:02,501 --> 00:15:05,299
you have your bloody work
cut out for you.

147
00:15:05,404 --> 00:15:08,498
Arranging storage of, uh -
Amigo. Señor.

148
00:15:08,607 --> 00:15:11,838
Storage for this bumper crop
of dancing carcasses.

149
00:15:11,944 --> 00:15:15,175
Señor Geoffrey.
Build special depots.

150
00:15:15,281 --> 00:15:17,875
Uh, stack them in layers.

151
00:15:17,983 --> 00:15:20,213
Or squeeze - squeeze them in upright.

152
00:15:20,319 --> 00:15:22,844
No, better still - cut them in pieces.

153
00:15:22,955 --> 00:15:26,891
Chop them up
and stash them in sacks.

154
00:15:26,992 --> 00:15:29,825
And paint red crosses on them.
Come, señor.

155
00:15:31,697 --> 00:15:35,656
Come, amigo.
Throw away your mind.

156
00:15:35,768 --> 00:15:40,467
It is sad to spend your life
in such continual tragedies.

157
00:15:40,572 --> 00:15:46,408
Ah, it's not in the times, of course,
but in the heart.

158
00:15:46,512 --> 00:15:50,380
No se puede vivir sin amar.

159
00:15:50,482 --> 00:15:53,815
Uh. No se puede vivir sin amar.

160
00:15:54,853 --> 00:15:59,654
Hmm. I woke up one morning,
she was gone.

161
00:16:01,126 --> 00:16:05,324
Nothing. Just a bloody note.

162
00:16:05,431 --> 00:16:07,558
I need her.

163
00:16:07,666 --> 00:16:10,794
Come. I know what you must do.

164
00:16:10,903 --> 00:16:13,804
Come with me.
It is not far. Come.

169
00:17:24,376 --> 00:17:27,243
She is the Virgin of Soledad.

170
00:17:28,614 --> 00:17:31,105
La santa patrona...

171
00:17:31,216 --> 00:17:34,379
for those who have nobody with...

172
00:17:35,687 --> 00:17:38,884
and those what are lost...

173
00:17:40,559 --> 00:17:42,993
and mariners at sea.

174
00:17:45,764 --> 00:17:47,732
You must ask...

175
00:17:49,034 --> 00:17:51,002
for your esposa again.

176
00:17:53,505 --> 00:17:55,996
Ask her.

177
00:17:56,108 --> 00:17:58,474
I can't.

178
00:18:00,479 --> 00:18:06,076
It's like asking my fairy godmother
for three wishes.

179
00:18:09,855 --> 00:18:14,315
You must forgive my compañero.

180
00:18:15,627 --> 00:18:18,687
He's too borracho to pray.

181
00:18:21,700 --> 00:18:26,865
No se puede vivir sin amar, Madrecita.

182
00:18:28,173 --> 00:18:30,141
And he -

183
00:18:31,543 --> 00:18:35,070
He - He has lost his esposa.

184
00:18:36,115 --> 00:18:38,709
And he ask for your help.

185
00:18:41,186 --> 00:18:43,086
Please.

186
00:18:46,158 --> 00:18:48,251
Pray to the Virgin.

187
00:18:59,872 --> 00:19:02,500
I'm dying without you.

188
00:19:05,244 --> 00:19:07,576
Come back to me, Yvonne.

189
00:19:42,915 --> 00:19:44,974
Are you listening, Fernando?

190
00:19:45,083 --> 00:19:47,608
Si es absolutamente necesario.

191
00:19:47,719 --> 00:19:51,450
Pay close attention.
A lesson. A parable.

192
00:19:51,557 --> 00:19:55,118
I'm telling you about responsibility,
Fernando.

193
00:19:55,227 --> 00:19:57,889
Si es absolutamente necesario.

194
00:19:57,996 --> 00:20:03,161
This ship was a thoroughgoing lie...

195
00:20:03,268 --> 00:20:06,294
and I was the commanding officer.

196
00:20:07,806 --> 00:20:12,641
This ship - the S.S. Samaritan...

197
00:20:12,744 --> 00:20:14,644
it was called...

198
00:20:14,746 --> 00:20:20,446
Iooked from the outside
like a harmless, fat old lady-

199
00:20:21,753 --> 00:20:25,382
a laden freighter
lying heavy on the sea.

200
00:20:26,425 --> 00:20:28,950
Are you listening, Fernando?

204
00:21:07,866 --> 00:21:10,664
...sink anything the Germans
might send our way!

205
00:21:10,769 --> 00:21:14,364
It was 1917, spring.

206
00:21:16,408 --> 00:21:20,845
We sight a periscope sighting us.

208
00:21:30,122 --> 00:21:32,249
Are you listening, Fernando?

209
00:21:35,260 --> 00:21:37,251
They prepare to board us.

210
00:21:38,363 --> 00:21:40,888
Then the big surprise.

211
00:21:43,869 --> 00:21:45,700
Are you listening, Fernando?

212
00:21:50,108 --> 00:21:52,008
Oh.

213
00:21:53,045 --> 00:21:55,479
We drop our disguise.

214
00:21:55,580 --> 00:21:58,378
The predator suddenly becomes the prey.

215
00:22:08,126 --> 00:22:10,890
I got a medal for capturing that sub.

216
00:22:12,497 --> 00:22:16,024
But first I had to be tried
at a court-martial.

217
00:22:16,134 --> 00:22:19,331
The mystery
of the missing German officers.

218
00:22:19,438 --> 00:22:21,406
You see...

219
00:22:21,506 --> 00:22:25,567
the remains of seven men...

220
00:22:25,677 --> 00:22:27,941
were found in the furnace ashes.

221
00:22:30,082 --> 00:22:32,050
Rather gruesome, hmm?

222
00:22:38,690 --> 00:22:41,124
It just isn't done, Fernando.

223
00:22:41,226 --> 00:22:45,424
People just don't go around
putting other people into furnaces.

224
00:22:52,204 --> 00:22:54,866
Hmm. Yvonne.

225
00:22:56,808 --> 00:22:58,867
I'm back.

226
00:22:59,911 --> 00:23:02,607
Is it really you?
Of course it's me.

227
00:23:02,714 --> 00:23:04,477
Can't be.

228
00:23:06,885 --> 00:23:11,379
I wrote you I was coming.
Didrt you get my letters?

229
00:23:13,058 --> 00:23:15,959
I wasrt even sure you were still here.
I had to call the Foreign Office.

230
00:23:16,061 --> 00:23:18,928
I am always more or less here.

231
00:23:19,030 --> 00:23:23,023
Uh, I did go away, uh, once,
just last week.

232
00:23:23,135 --> 00:23:25,660
To a bullfight, in Tomalin.

233
00:23:25,771 --> 00:23:27,671
Wound up in El Farolito.

234
00:23:27,773 --> 00:23:30,173
But just for drinks, mind you.

235
00:23:31,710 --> 00:23:34,201
How did you get here?

236
00:23:34,312 --> 00:23:38,908
I came by, uh, boat from New York.

237
00:23:39,017 --> 00:23:43,215
I caught a plane from Veracruz.
I see.

238
00:23:43,321 --> 00:23:45,516
You must be exhausted.

239
00:23:47,159 --> 00:23:52,187
Not really. I had a million hours
of sleep on the boat.

240
00:23:52,297 --> 00:23:55,494
The worst part
was the ride from the airfield.

241
00:23:55,600 --> 00:23:57,500
A bus.

242
00:24:10,115 --> 00:24:14,415
It's the shakes that make this life
insupportable.

243
00:24:15,454 --> 00:24:19,151
But they subside, if handled properly...

244
00:24:19,257 --> 00:24:24,126
with the necessary swigs,
the therapeutic touch.

245
00:24:25,931 --> 00:24:30,766
Have a drink with me.
No, you have one. I'll cheer.

246
00:24:52,224 --> 00:24:55,955
Calle Nicaragua 52.
Sí, señora.

248
00:25:23,688 --> 00:25:26,851
How, unless you drink as I do...

249
00:25:26,958 --> 00:25:30,257
can you hope to understand the beauty
of an old Indian woman...

250
00:25:30,362 --> 00:25:32,353
playing dominoes with a chicken?

251
00:25:55,086 --> 00:25:57,577
Well, the taxis seem
to have all disappeared.

252
00:25:57,689 --> 00:26:00,556
- Shall we walk?
- Why? What's happened to the car?

253
00:26:02,761 --> 00:26:04,729
You haven't smashed it up again,
have you?

254
00:26:04,829 --> 00:26:08,822
Well, as a matter of fact,
I lost it.

255
00:26:08,934 --> 00:26:10,834
- You lost it?
- Mmm.

256
00:26:10,936 --> 00:26:13,996
Look here, dash it all,
you must be terribly tired, Yvonne.

257
00:26:14,105 --> 00:26:16,130
Let's not walk.
Let's sit and wait for a taxi.

258
00:26:16,241 --> 00:26:18,835
No, not at all. I would think
that you're the one who's tired.

259
00:26:18,944 --> 00:26:22,345
Oh, no, no. Fine here.

260
00:26:23,782 --> 00:26:28,651
Glad to get some circulation
going in the old legs.

261
00:26:30,522 --> 00:26:33,923
Did they tell you, the Foreign Office,
that I'd resigned?

262
00:26:34,025 --> 00:26:36,357
What happened?

263
00:26:36,461 --> 00:26:38,361
Just fed up.

264
00:26:41,366 --> 00:26:44,927
Geoffrey, why didn't you
answer my letters?

265
00:26:45,036 --> 00:26:47,596
Shakes, you know.
Bit unsteady with a pen.

266
00:26:49,040 --> 00:26:51,975
You might have hired him.

267
00:26:52,077 --> 00:26:53,977
Dear Yvonne...

268
00:26:54,079 --> 00:26:58,175
I'm taking the easy, only way out -
Semicolon.

269
00:26:58,283 --> 00:26:59,978
Good-bye - Full stop.

270
00:27:00,085 --> 00:27:03,418
Change of paragraph.
Change of chapter.

271
00:27:06,458 --> 00:27:09,018
Change of world.

274
00:27:16,801 --> 00:27:19,235
 How sweetly blooms the graves 

275
00:27:19,337 --> 00:27:23,330
 With fragrant flowers

276
00:27:23,441 --> 00:27:27,275
 Just once a year
the dead live for the day 

277
00:27:27,379 --> 00:27:30,780
Do you remember that Strauss song,
Geoffrey, called "All Soul's Day"?

278
00:27:33,318 --> 00:27:38,415
 Return to me, my love
that I may hold you  

279
00:27:39,457 --> 00:27:42,949
 As once in May 

280
00:27:43,061 --> 00:27:46,827
 As once in May 

281
00:27:49,601 --> 00:27:53,970
What have you been doing for the past year
besides getting a divorce?

282
00:27:56,107 --> 00:27:58,735
Mostly I was in New York.

283
00:27:58,843 --> 00:28:01,403
I got a part in a revival
of The Italian Straw Hat.

284
00:28:01,513 --> 00:28:05,973
Remember-
the play I was in when we met?

285
00:28:06,084 --> 00:28:08,348
I was the ingenue then.

286
00:28:08,453 --> 00:28:10,683
Afraid those days are gone.

287
00:28:10,789 --> 00:28:15,089
This time, I only had a character part.
We closed last week.

288
00:28:15,193 --> 00:28:17,093
I see.

290
00:28:25,437 --> 00:28:28,235
Look, his eyes are closed.
The horse knows his way home.

291
00:28:43,488 --> 00:28:46,184
Gracias.
Gracias, gracias.

292
00:28:49,461 --> 00:28:52,624
Oh, hello, hello!
Look who comes here!

293
00:28:52,731 --> 00:28:55,461
My little Oedipuss.

294
00:28:55,567 --> 00:28:57,467
Hello!

295
00:28:58,703 --> 00:29:02,161
Oh, there you are.

296
00:29:02,273 --> 00:29:05,470
Do you think he's forgotten me?
No, he's not forgotten you.

297
00:29:06,945 --> 00:29:10,972
I never believed it - that cats are not
attached to people but to places.

298
00:29:12,016 --> 00:29:13,984
I've missed you, Oedipuss.

299
00:29:14,085 --> 00:29:16,053
He's missed you too.

300
00:29:18,056 --> 00:29:20,286
ISeñora, qué gusto!

301
00:29:20,391 --> 00:29:22,723
Oh!
Buenos días.

302
00:29:22,827 --> 00:29:25,887
Buenos días, Concepta.
Cómo la he extrañado.

303
00:29:25,997 --> 00:29:28,363
Oh, I've missed you too, Concepta.

304
00:29:37,075 --> 00:29:40,340
What happened to my beautiful garden,
my camellias?

305
00:29:40,445 --> 00:29:42,504
It became a bit of a jungle, I'm afraid.

306
00:29:42,614 --> 00:29:45,082
But look here,
just suppose for argument's sake...

307
00:29:45,183 --> 00:29:47,981
that you, uh, abandoned a besieged town...

308
00:29:48,086 --> 00:29:51,852
and somehow or other,
not long afterwards, you come back.

309
00:29:51,956 --> 00:29:56,586
You can't well expect to invite yourself
into the same green graces...

310
00:29:56,694 --> 00:29:59,993
quite the same, uh, oh...

311
00:30:00,098 --> 00:30:03,067
dear old welcome here and there,
can you, hmm?

312
00:30:08,273 --> 00:30:11,140
Have you come back,
or are you just visiting?

313
00:30:11,242 --> 00:30:13,210
I'm here, aren't I?

314
00:30:17,782 --> 00:30:19,716
Hugh! Come out here!

315
00:30:19,818 --> 00:30:22,719
You'll never guess who's just popped in.

316
00:30:22,821 --> 00:30:26,416
Is Hugh here?
Oh. Didrt I tell you?

317
00:30:26,524 --> 00:30:28,424
Oh, he's been back some time.

318
00:30:28,526 --> 00:30:30,687
He came straight
from the Spanish Civil War.

319
00:30:30,795 --> 00:30:32,888
Been playing Florence Nightingale for me.

320
00:30:32,997 --> 00:30:35,124
Hugh. Where are you?

321
00:30:35,233 --> 00:30:39,465
He was quite disappointed when he got back
and, uh, discovered you'd flown the coop.

322
00:30:39,571 --> 00:30:42,404
I do believe he's missed you
full as much as I.

323
00:30:42,507 --> 00:30:46,273
Hugh. Where are you?
Where can the young pup be?

324
00:30:46,377 --> 00:30:50,609
Hugh! An emissary calls.

325
00:30:50,715 --> 00:30:53,912
The Consul of Cuckold's Haven.

326
00:30:54,018 --> 00:30:57,579
Come and give the wife
a"welcome back" kiss.

327
00:30:59,490 --> 00:31:02,926
Oh, I forgot. He's in Mexico City.
Be back some time today.

328
00:31:03,027 --> 00:31:06,793
He'd gotten a wind of some,
uh, rumor, and he -

329
00:31:06,898 --> 00:31:10,095
he chased off
like a hound after a hare.

330
00:31:19,911 --> 00:31:23,711
Geoffrey. Just tell me.
I can go.

331
00:31:23,815 --> 00:31:29,151
This is Hugh's home cure for alcoholism.

332
00:31:29,254 --> 00:31:31,154
Strychnine.

333
00:31:31,256 --> 00:31:34,089
He bribes Concepta to poison me.

334
00:31:34,192 --> 00:31:36,319
Veneno.
Señora, eso no es verdad.

335
00:31:37,795 --> 00:31:39,763
It's dreadful.
It is.

336
00:31:41,165 --> 00:31:45,124
Uh, would you like a whiskey?

337
00:31:46,404 --> 00:31:48,372
I haven't had breakfast yet.

338
00:31:57,815 --> 00:31:59,783
Geoffrey?

339
00:32:01,686 --> 00:32:05,383
Geoffrey. Take it.
What?

340
00:32:05,490 --> 00:32:07,583
For God's sake, drink it.
I'm not expecting miracles.

341
00:32:07,692 --> 00:32:12,994
No, no, no, no. I'll stick to the old,
uh, medicine, thank you.

343
00:32:25,777 --> 00:32:29,440
- Have you really resigned?
- Absolutely.

344
00:32:29,547 --> 00:32:31,515
No more diplomacy for me.

345
00:32:33,418 --> 00:32:36,216
Well, then there's nothing really
holding you here anymore.

346
00:32:36,321 --> 00:32:38,289
Magic.

347
00:32:39,390 --> 00:32:43,349
"He on whose heart
the dust of Mexico has lain...

348
00:32:43,461 --> 00:32:46,157
will find no peace
in any other land."

349
00:32:46,264 --> 00:32:48,698
But nothing's really holding you.

350
00:32:48,800 --> 00:32:51,564
There's nothing more real than magic.

351
00:32:53,905 --> 00:32:56,635
All right, Geoffrey, we can
talk about it when you're rested.

352
00:32:56,741 --> 00:32:58,641
When I'm sober, you mean.

353
00:32:58,743 --> 00:33:02,270
Surely you know by this time that I can't
get drunk, however much I drink...

354
00:33:02,380 --> 00:33:05,781
and that I'm only drunk in the conventional,
incoherent staggering sense...

355
00:33:05,883 --> 00:33:08,249
when I haven't had a drink.

356
00:33:08,353 --> 00:33:13,017
Surely you appreciate the, mmm -
the fine balance I must strike...

357
00:33:13,124 --> 00:33:18,426
between the, uh, shakes of too little
and, uh, the abyss of too much.

358
00:33:20,865 --> 00:33:24,392
- I do appreciate it.
- Yes. Quite. Well.

359
00:33:26,938 --> 00:33:28,906
Well, I'd like to have a bath.

360
00:33:31,075 --> 00:33:33,270
Have your drink.

361
00:34:39,410 --> 00:34:41,310
Ah.

362
00:34:49,587 --> 00:34:51,487
Concepta!

363
00:34:52,590 --> 00:34:54,785
- Señor.
- Tequila, por favor.

364
00:34:54,892 --> 00:34:56,792
- No hay nada que tomar.
- Nothing?

365
00:34:56,894 --> 00:34:59,385
- Nada.

366
00:36:16,707 --> 00:36:20,768
- Ah, good morning, Quincey.
- What's good about it?

367
00:36:20,878 --> 00:36:23,073
I have just been
inspecting my paradise.

368
00:36:23,181 --> 00:36:27,413
I half expected to see Adam
come riding out of it on a tiger.

369
00:36:27,518 --> 00:36:30,282
- On a what?
- On a tiger.

370
00:36:30,388 --> 00:36:34,586
I would imagine -
lots of tigers and pink elephants too.

371
00:36:34,692 --> 00:36:37,684
- About your cat, Firmin -
- I've been giving a lot of thought to Eden.

372
00:36:37,795 --> 00:36:40,787
Finding a path back to our origins.

373
00:36:40,898 --> 00:36:46,393
Perhaps I'll go and live among the Indians,
like William Blackstone...

374
00:36:47,605 --> 00:36:50,233
stripped of useless trappings.

375
00:36:50,341 --> 00:36:54,937
Unaccommodated man - the thing itself.
You know about Blackstone?

376
00:36:55,046 --> 00:36:58,812
My wife and I are kept awake half the night
with its infernal howling.

377
00:36:58,916 --> 00:37:02,317
- Or don't you hear it?
- Blackstone's a character I've always admired.

378
00:37:02,420 --> 00:37:06,015
He lived peacefully
among the Indians, in, uh -

379
00:37:06,123 --> 00:37:08,956
somewhere in what is now Massachusetts.

380
00:37:09,060 --> 00:37:11,620
But the-the Puritans found him...

381
00:37:11,729 --> 00:37:15,165
and tried to-to coax him back
to a respectable life.

382
00:37:15,266 --> 00:37:18,633
If you don't do something
about your cat, I will.

383
00:37:18,736 --> 00:37:23,230
But Blackstone didn't like the Puritans.
Oh, no. No, he didn't.

384
00:37:23,341 --> 00:37:26,139
He'd have none of them.

385
00:37:26,244 --> 00:37:30,044
So he went further
into the wilderness...

386
00:37:30,147 --> 00:37:32,741
never to be heard from again.

387
00:37:32,850 --> 00:37:36,217
I'll strangle that damn cat
with my bare hands.

388
00:37:40,291 --> 00:37:44,421
Don't worry, Quincey.
Oedipuss only howled for Yvonne.

389
00:37:44,528 --> 00:37:46,496
And she's come back.

390
00:37:56,040 --> 00:37:58,736
- Knock, knock.
- Who's there?

391
00:37:58,843 --> 00:38:01,835
- Cat.
- Cat who?

392
00:38:01,946 --> 00:38:04,210
Cat-astrophe.

393
00:38:04,315 --> 00:38:06,215
Catastrophe who?

394
00:38:06,317 --> 00:38:10,845
Oh, uh, cat-astrophysicist?

395
00:38:17,328 --> 00:38:20,525
- Have a bite of breakfast?
- I already partook.

396
00:38:26,103 --> 00:38:28,196
- You look weary.
- No, I'm fine.

397
00:38:30,274 --> 00:38:31,969
Hah.

398
00:38:32,076 --> 00:38:34,442
You've always done that -

399
00:38:34,545 --> 00:38:39,005
always carefully cradled
your lemon wedges.

400
00:38:39,116 --> 00:38:41,016
So meticulous.

401
00:39:01,072 --> 00:39:02,972
Oh.

403
00:39:09,547 --> 00:39:13,039
Do you remember the names of the months,
the Mayan months?

404
00:39:14,885 --> 00:39:17,251
- Pop.
- Mm-hmm. Uo.

405
00:39:18,389 --> 00:39:22,325
- Zotz.
- Uh, Tzed. Xal.

406
00:39:22,426 --> 00:39:24,417
Yaxkin.

407
00:39:24,528 --> 00:39:26,758
Mac. Isn't there one called Mac?

408
00:39:26,864 --> 00:39:29,560
There's Yax and Zac.

409
00:39:29,667 --> 00:39:31,760
"In receipt of yours, dated Zac the first"?

411
00:39:35,005 --> 00:39:39,738
My favorite was always uayeb-

412
00:39:39,844 --> 00:39:44,781
the poor little month
that only had five days.

413
00:39:55,326 --> 00:39:58,591
I've wanted you back so badly.

414
00:40:05,069 --> 00:40:08,266
I'll do anything.
I'll stop drinking.

415
00:40:08,372 --> 00:40:10,897
I'll do anything for you.

416
00:40:12,610 --> 00:40:15,477
It's us. It's - It's us again.

417
00:40:29,293 --> 00:40:32,126
Oh, Geoffrey!

418
00:40:48,679 --> 00:40:51,011
I'm sorry.

419
00:40:51,115 --> 00:40:53,106
It isn't any good, I'm afraid.

420
00:40:58,823 --> 00:41:00,723
Stay.

423
00:41:54,845 --> 00:41:57,279
Where are you, old man?

424
00:42:10,427 --> 00:42:12,088
Hello, Hugh.

425
00:42:12,196 --> 00:42:14,426
Yvonne.

428
00:42:24,942 --> 00:42:28,105
Well, how absolutely...
something or other.

429
00:42:33,017 --> 00:42:34,985
Geoffrey told me you were here.

430
00:42:39,323 --> 00:42:41,223
Did he?

431
00:42:41,325 --> 00:42:43,020
He did.

432
00:42:48,332 --> 00:42:50,800
You look awfully well.

433
00:42:50,901 --> 00:42:53,335
You too. Quite a get-up.

434
00:42:53,437 --> 00:42:56,873
- Like the Ringo Kid.
- With a touch of Savile Row.

435
00:42:56,974 --> 00:42:58,965
- I thought you were in Spain.
- I was.

436
00:42:59,076 --> 00:43:02,068
- What happened?
- What?

437
00:43:03,547 --> 00:43:06,277
Why did you leave?
The war's not over yet, is it?

438
00:43:06,383 --> 00:43:09,910
Why, I was sort of wounded.

439
00:43:10,020 --> 00:43:11,248
Hugh.

440
00:43:11,355 --> 00:43:16,224
On the way to watch the battle for Madrid.
Fell out of an ambulance.

441
00:43:16,327 --> 00:43:19,421
Seven cases ofbeer and six journalists
fell on top of me.

443
00:43:25,402 --> 00:43:27,495
Ah, it's a lost cause by now anyway.

444
00:43:27,605 --> 00:43:30,506
Franco has all the soldiers
and the tanks and the aeroplanes...

445
00:43:30,608 --> 00:43:32,701
and all the Loyalists seem to have
are good songs.

446
00:43:33,777 --> 00:43:36,837
  Sólo es nuestro deseo  

447
00:43:36,947 --> 00:43:40,576
  Rumbala, rumbala, rumbala   

448
00:43:40,684 --> 00:43:43,380
- When did you get here?
- Just this morning.

449
00:43:47,057 --> 00:43:48,957
Well, where is he -

450
00:43:50,194 --> 00:43:51,889
our monarch?

451
00:43:53,130 --> 00:43:56,930
He's gone out.
For a bottle, I believe.

452
00:43:59,370 --> 00:44:01,304
You just... appeared?

453
00:44:02,473 --> 00:44:05,203
- What?
- No warning.

454
00:44:05,309 --> 00:44:07,277
No, I wrote.

455
00:44:09,446 --> 00:44:11,346
Still I -

456
00:44:11,448 --> 00:44:15,111
I think I...
caught him by surprise.

458
00:44:20,791 --> 00:44:24,921
- How did he react?
- Glad to see me, I think.

459
00:44:25,029 --> 00:44:27,020
I'm sure he was.

460
00:44:30,434 --> 00:44:32,834
- How do you find him?
- His drinking, you mean?

461
00:44:32,936 --> 00:44:37,430
- Well, yes, his drinking.
- Half the time, I can't tell when he's tight.

462
00:44:37,541 --> 00:44:40,510
He has the constitution
of a bull, you know.

463
00:44:40,611 --> 00:44:42,602
He's gone down, I think.

464
00:44:42,713 --> 00:44:47,150
Well, now you've come back like this...

465
00:44:49,920 --> 00:44:51,751
perhaps he'll stop.

466
00:44:54,758 --> 00:44:56,658
Yeah.

469
00:45:12,810 --> 00:45:15,244
Look here, is everything all right?

470
00:45:15,345 --> 00:45:18,405
I say.
I say, what's the matter here?

471
00:45:21,018 --> 00:45:23,009
Nothing. Absolutely all right.

472
00:45:23,120 --> 00:45:25,611
All right? But you were lying down
in the middle of the road.

473
00:45:25,723 --> 00:45:29,090
All right just the same.
Thank you very much.

474
00:45:29,193 --> 00:45:32,185
My dear fellow, you were lying right down here.
I might have run you over.

475
00:45:32,296 --> 00:45:34,457
- Are you sure there's nothing wrong?
- No.

476
00:45:34,565 --> 00:45:37,159
What? Are you sure you're all right?

477
00:45:38,335 --> 00:45:40,235
Oh.

478
00:45:43,373 --> 00:45:46,809
- Havert I seen you somewhere before?
- Oxford?

479
00:45:46,910 --> 00:45:49,572
- No. Cambridge.
- You're wearing an Oxford tie.

480
00:45:49,680 --> 00:45:53,377
Oh, the tie. That belongs to my cousin.
We're headed for Guatemala.

481
00:45:53,484 --> 00:45:56,885
We're making a little tour of the temples,
don't you know?

482
00:45:56,987 --> 00:45:59,353
- Splendid country, isn't it?
- Splendid.

483
00:45:59,456 --> 00:46:03,256
Look, are you absolutely sure
there are no bones broken?

484
00:46:03,360 --> 00:46:05,658
No, no bones broken -

485
00:46:05,763 --> 00:46:08,288
Oh, my dear fellow.
My dear fellow. Here.

486
00:46:09,800 --> 00:46:13,930
Now, listen.
We are staying at the Bella Vista.

487
00:46:14,037 --> 00:46:18,098
Why don't we pop back to the hotel,
and you can have a little bit of a lie-down?

488
00:46:18,208 --> 00:46:20,267
- No, fine, thank you.
- No?

489
00:46:20,377 --> 00:46:23,710
Well, I always keep something
in the car for emergencies.

490
00:46:26,216 --> 00:46:29,014
Irish. Burke's Irish.

491
00:46:33,123 --> 00:46:35,284
Mmm. Thanks a million.

492
00:46:35,392 --> 00:46:39,123
- No, no. Carry on, my dear fellow. Carry on.
- Ah. Mmm.

494
00:46:44,601 --> 00:46:47,434
Awfully decent of you, old chap.

495
00:46:48,539 --> 00:46:50,837
I say. I know where I last saw you.

496
00:46:50,941 --> 00:46:53,432
You were that chap
who made that speech last night.

497
00:46:53,544 --> 00:46:56,069
- Is that right, old man?
- Quite right.

498
00:46:56,180 --> 00:46:59,013
Didrt really get through to me completely,
but you sounded jolly good.

499
00:46:59,116 --> 00:47:03,212
Look, if you're absolutely sure that you're
feeling all right, I'd better be pushing off.

500
00:47:03,320 --> 00:47:06,187
- Top hole.
- Don't go falling into roads anymore, will you?

501
00:47:06,290 --> 00:47:09,259
- You might get run over or run in. Ha, ha.

502
00:47:09,359 --> 00:47:11,657
- Bloody awful road, isn't it?
- Dreadful. Dreadful.

503
00:47:11,762 --> 00:47:14,754
Yes, yes. The weather's splendid.
Cheerio.

505
00:47:23,273 --> 00:47:25,833
Let me know if you're ever
in any kind of jam.

506
00:47:25,943 --> 00:47:28,571
- Tallyho!
- Tallyho!

508
00:47:49,733 --> 00:47:53,635
Hey, Hugh!
You old snake in the grass.

509
00:47:53,737 --> 00:47:57,537
- Hello, Geoff, old man.
- Quite a surprise, huh, Yvonne appearing like this?

510
00:47:57,641 --> 00:47:59,541
Calls for a celebration.

511
00:47:59,643 --> 00:48:03,670
God, I forgot. I haven't got a drop in the house.
What kind of a host does that make me?

512
00:48:03,780 --> 00:48:06,681
I just popped out for the champagne,
bumped into an old college chum.

513
00:48:06,783 --> 00:48:09,479
Maudlin man.
Sit down, you two.

514
00:48:09,586 --> 00:48:12,419
Did you tell Hugh
about your return to the stage?

515
00:48:12,522 --> 00:48:14,717
She's made a comeback.
Great success.

516
00:48:14,825 --> 00:48:17,123
Hugh's looking well, isn't he? Huh?

517
00:48:17,227 --> 00:48:19,855
Mexico agrees with him.
Brown as a berry.

518
00:48:19,963 --> 00:48:22,830
Why, he's been taking
splendid care of me.

519
00:48:22,933 --> 00:48:25,493
And I do believe
results are beginning to show.

520
00:48:25,602 --> 00:48:27,661
I feel strong as a horse.
Strong as a horse.

521
00:48:27,771 --> 00:48:31,400
All due to Hugh's wonder drug.
Kill or cure.

522
00:48:31,508 --> 00:48:34,909
Oh, we could all have a strychnine.

523
00:48:35,012 --> 00:48:37,947
Excuse me, will you?
Uh, I'll, um -

524
00:48:38,048 --> 00:48:40,175
Amuse yourselves
for a few moments.

525
00:48:40,284 --> 00:48:42,718
I'll, uh, tidy up a bit.

526
00:48:42,819 --> 00:48:44,753
Aah.

528
00:48:49,426 --> 00:48:51,326
Yvonne, forgive my asking like this...

529
00:48:51,428 --> 00:48:55,592
but, uh, have you...
really come back to him?

530
00:48:56,867 --> 00:48:58,835
Or what?

531
00:49:00,270 --> 00:49:04,172
I mean, I'd just... like to know
precisely what the situation is.

532
00:49:07,678 --> 00:49:10,704
- So would I.
- You don't know?

533
00:49:16,620 --> 00:49:19,282
Yes. I've come back to him.

534
00:49:22,292 --> 00:49:24,192
All right?

535
00:49:25,662 --> 00:49:27,630
All right?

537
00:49:40,344 --> 00:49:43,313
- Right here, old man.
- Oh, Geoffrey.

538
00:49:43,413 --> 00:49:46,678
Upsy-daisy. There we go.

539
00:49:46,783 --> 00:49:49,809
Can't stop bouncing about.

540
00:49:57,494 --> 00:50:00,861
- I wonder what this is like.
- Geoffrey!

541
00:50:00,964 --> 00:50:03,558
Not bad. Not bad.
Slightly under proof.

542
00:50:03,667 --> 00:50:05,567
A little like Pernod.

543
00:50:05,669 --> 00:50:08,695
Still, it keeps
the galloping cockroaches at bay.

544
00:50:08,805 --> 00:50:11,103
- Oh. Oh!

545
00:50:11,208 --> 00:50:13,176
Into the shower.

548
00:50:25,722 --> 00:50:29,988
Little cockroach on the wall...

549
00:50:30,093 --> 00:50:32,687
ain't you got no one at all?

550
00:50:38,101 --> 00:50:40,069
Ah. Allow me.

551
00:50:42,773 --> 00:50:45,105
Ooh. Oh!

553
00:50:51,948 --> 00:50:54,815
- Feeling better?
- New man. Revived.

554
00:50:54,918 --> 00:50:58,319
No past, only future.

555
00:50:58,422 --> 00:51:00,390
Now be still.

557
00:51:06,563 --> 00:51:10,897
Oh, hey. No, listen.
We ought to go to the fiesta.

558
00:51:13,270 --> 00:51:17,434
- What, now?
- Yes, it will be all, all gone tomorrow.

559
00:51:17,541 --> 00:51:21,375
I mean, we ought to,
unless, of course, you're too fagged.

560
00:51:21,478 --> 00:51:23,207
No, I'm fine.

561
00:51:23,313 --> 00:51:26,180
Now hold still.
I'm doing your neck.

562
00:51:26,283 --> 00:51:31,220
"Don't be careful,"
as the Mexicans say.

563
00:51:34,925 --> 00:51:36,825
- I'll be back in a moment.

564
00:51:36,927 --> 00:51:39,122
- Mm-hmm.

565
00:51:41,431 --> 00:51:44,400
- All right.

566
00:51:45,969 --> 00:51:47,937
She looks well.

567
00:51:49,439 --> 00:51:53,808
- Doesrt she, huh?
- Yes. She does.

568
00:51:53,910 --> 00:51:55,810
Mmm. Looks well.

569
00:51:55,912 --> 00:51:57,812
I think-

570
00:51:57,914 --> 00:52:03,284
I think I will only drink beer
today on our outing.

571
00:52:03,386 --> 00:52:05,911
Chin. Chin.

572
00:52:06,022 --> 00:52:08,752
There's nothing like...

573
00:52:08,859 --> 00:52:10,759
beer-

574
00:52:10,861 --> 00:52:13,261
beer to straighten one out.

575
00:52:13,363 --> 00:52:15,058
- You know?
- Mm-hmm.

576
00:52:15,165 --> 00:52:17,065
- And then -
- Uh-huh, uh-huh.

577
00:52:17,167 --> 00:52:21,729
Then go back to the strychnine.

578
00:52:23,106 --> 00:52:26,007
Strychnine. Who knows?

579
00:52:26,109 --> 00:52:28,669
- Uh-huh.

580
00:52:28,778 --> 00:52:31,076
Who knows?
I may actually-

581
00:52:32,115 --> 00:52:35,209
I may get off it completely.

582
00:52:35,318 --> 00:52:38,947
- Well, you ought to try.
- Yes.

583
00:52:39,055 --> 00:52:42,218
- Yes, yes. Yes, yes, yes.
- All right?

584
00:52:42,325 --> 00:52:44,225
Yes, yes, yes.

585
00:52:49,399 --> 00:52:52,266
Look, Geoff, shouldn't I -

586
00:52:52,369 --> 00:52:54,633
Shouldrt I leave?

587
00:52:54,738 --> 00:52:56,706
- Leave?
- Yes.

588
00:52:56,806 --> 00:52:58,797
Immediately,
rather than hang around.

589
00:52:58,909 --> 00:53:01,275
Whatever for?

590
00:53:01,378 --> 00:53:04,313
Well, I thought
it might make things easier.

591
00:53:04,414 --> 00:53:07,212
M-Make what eas-easier?

592
00:53:08,251 --> 00:53:12,153
For the two of you. Here.

593
00:53:12,255 --> 00:53:14,689
- For the two of us?
- Yes.

594
00:53:14,791 --> 00:53:18,522
I mean, now that Yvonne's back,
you'll be very well looked after.

595
00:53:20,130 --> 00:53:22,758
- What are you afraid of?
- Nothing.

596
00:53:24,167 --> 00:53:28,831
Yvonne's wiles
or your own baser instincts?

597
00:53:28,939 --> 00:53:31,305
For Christ's sake,
should I go or not?

598
00:53:31,408 --> 00:53:34,741
Wouldrt it look rather odd,
you just shooting off?

599
00:53:37,981 --> 00:53:40,677
Stay, Hugh.

600
00:53:40,784 --> 00:53:44,083
Hmm. Of course. You must stay.

601
00:53:57,634 --> 00:53:59,534
Ready.

602
00:54:00,770 --> 00:54:03,967
You look very... very.

603
00:54:04,074 --> 00:54:06,065
Thank you.

604
00:54:10,647 --> 00:54:13,241
Mmm. Here.

605
00:54:39,542 --> 00:54:43,410
No se puede vivir sin amar.

606
00:54:43,513 --> 00:54:45,504
What?

607
00:54:45,615 --> 00:54:47,947
"One cannot live without lovel '

608
00:54:51,655 --> 00:54:56,115
It really is an extraordinarily nice day
for a trip.

609
00:54:56,226 --> 00:54:59,855
We should, uh, carry on to Tomalin
after the fiesta.

610
00:55:01,031 --> 00:55:03,158
No car.

611
00:55:03,266 --> 00:55:06,292
Where's your sense of adventure?
We can take the bus.

612
00:55:06,403 --> 00:55:10,430
Get there in time for the charreada.
IOlé! and all that.

613
00:55:10,540 --> 00:55:13,839
- Are we up to that?
- "Up to that?"

614
00:55:13,943 --> 00:55:15,843
"Up to that?" What a question.

615
00:55:26,022 --> 00:55:27,956
Oh, they look so serene.

616
00:55:28,058 --> 00:55:31,186
Our ever-present guardian angels.

617
00:55:32,228 --> 00:55:34,753
Popocatepetl and his sleeping lady.

618
00:55:34,864 --> 00:55:37,765
- We should pay them a visit.
- That's the spirit.

619
00:55:37,867 --> 00:55:40,961
After the bulls,
we'll pop up old Popo...

620
00:55:41,071 --> 00:55:43,539
and look into the hot heart
of the volcano.

621
00:55:43,640 --> 00:55:45,870
- One step at a time, old man.

622
00:55:47,877 --> 00:55:51,313
Doctor Vigil!

623
00:55:51,414 --> 00:55:54,781
- Buenos días.
- Buenos días.

624
00:55:54,884 --> 00:55:57,819
I am glad, after last night,
you are among the living.

625
00:55:59,255 --> 00:56:01,223
- Buenos días, doctor.
- Buenos días.

626
00:56:08,031 --> 00:56:10,499
Hello, Doctor.

627
00:56:12,135 --> 00:56:14,035
Nice to see you again.

628
00:56:14,137 --> 00:56:17,538
- Since when you are here?
- I came this morning.

629
00:56:17,640 --> 00:56:19,540
Miraculous.

630
00:56:19,642 --> 00:56:23,009
Truly it is a miracle.

631
00:56:23,113 --> 00:56:27,607
In the night, we pray to the Virgin
for those who have nobody them with.

632
00:56:27,717 --> 00:56:30,550
The consul and me,
we pray for your return...

633
00:56:30,653 --> 00:56:33,247
and now you are here.

634
00:56:33,356 --> 00:56:35,324
Is it not wonderful?

635
00:56:38,294 --> 00:56:40,922
Geoffrey? Did you?

636
00:56:41,030 --> 00:56:43,999
I might point out, amigo,
Yvonne left New York over a week ago.

637
00:56:44,100 --> 00:56:46,534
It seems your miracle is after the fact.

638
00:56:46,636 --> 00:56:51,835
Ah, but the Virgin, she knew you were
going to pray before ever you prayed.

639
00:56:51,941 --> 00:56:53,909
Is still more miracle.

640
00:56:54,010 --> 00:56:58,242
The good doctor makes logic and faith
lie down together like the lion and the lamb.

641
00:56:58,348 --> 00:57:01,215
Doctor, what would you prescribe
for a chronic case...

642
00:57:01,317 --> 00:57:04,809
of uncontrollable, all-possessing
and inescapable delirium tremens?

643
00:57:04,921 --> 00:57:08,254
More alcohol is best,
in a quantity moderated.

644
00:57:08,358 --> 00:57:11,088
- Precisely. You hear that, you two?
- Uh, I heard " moderatedl '

645
00:57:11,194 --> 00:57:15,221
Doctor, would you care to join me
in a little moderation?

646
00:57:15,331 --> 00:57:19,199
I cannot. I must see to a child coming.

647
00:57:19,302 --> 00:57:22,897
- So I leave the family to be together.

648
00:57:23,006 --> 00:57:26,100
Señora Firmin, truly you are a miracle.

649
00:57:26,209 --> 00:57:28,109
Thank you, Doctor.

650
00:57:28,211 --> 00:57:31,908
Buenos días.
It's a lovely day.

651
00:57:32,015 --> 00:57:33,983
We shall have thunder.

652
00:57:35,018 --> 00:57:36,986
- Adiós.
- Adiós.

653
00:57:52,902 --> 00:57:55,928
- Did you?
- What?

654
00:57:56,039 --> 00:57:58,064
Go to the shrine.

655
00:57:58,174 --> 00:58:00,574
I'm sure I couldn't tell you honestly.

656
00:58:00,677 --> 00:58:03,874
Uh, the events of last night
are somewhat, uh, dim.

657
00:58:06,182 --> 00:58:08,082
Ah.

658
00:58:11,421 --> 00:58:14,618
"Plingen, plangen, auf gefangen...

659
00:58:14,724 --> 00:58:18,387
swingen, swangen at my s-sidel '

660
00:58:18,495 --> 00:58:22,591
Uh - " Swootle, pootle...

661
00:58:22,699 --> 00:58:24,599
"off to Bootle.

662
00:58:24,701 --> 00:58:26,635
Nemesis: a pleasant ride!"

663
00:58:26,736 --> 00:58:28,966
I arrived in heaven!

674
00:59:18,121 --> 00:59:20,885
Doña Inés.

679
00:59:59,762 --> 01:00:02,993
That's the way to contend
with the grim reaper.

680
01:00:03,099 --> 01:00:05,499
Offer him a drink and a dance!

681
01:00:10,974 --> 01:00:13,169
Will you two talk to me
after I've gone?

682
01:00:13,276 --> 01:00:17,645
Offer me bread and sugar skulls to help me
on my journey into the next world?

683
01:00:17,747 --> 01:00:20,648
Oh, absolutely, old man.
Once a year.

684
01:00:21,918 --> 01:00:24,682
You should write something
about the Day of the Dead.

685
01:00:24,787 --> 01:00:26,687
- It's been done.
- Oh.

686
01:00:26,789 --> 01:00:30,384
Give it a -
Give it a Marxist interpretation.

687
01:00:30,493 --> 01:00:34,122
Matter of fact, I've about decided
to trade in the old typewriter...

688
01:00:34,230 --> 01:00:36,926
for a musket.

689
01:00:37,033 --> 01:00:38,933
I might -

690
01:00:39,035 --> 01:00:42,436
I just might go back to England,
enlist in the R.A.F.

691
01:00:43,706 --> 01:00:45,674
This next war will be fought in the air.

692
01:00:45,775 --> 01:00:48,710
The next war?
Just the same old one.

693
01:00:48,811 --> 01:00:50,711
Oh, no, no, Geoff.

694
01:00:50,813 --> 01:00:54,647
This time, it won't be for territories
or possessions, but for our very souls.

695
01:00:54,751 --> 01:00:57,447
Our souls? Ah, good.

696
01:00:57,553 --> 01:01:00,181
So we still have them, do we?
I thought, uh -

697
01:01:00,289 --> 01:01:04,020
But no, I mustrt judge others
as I judge myself.

698
01:01:04,127 --> 01:01:06,391
You have a soul, Geoff.
You have a great soul.

699
01:01:06,496 --> 01:01:10,626
I must have mislaid it then.
Perhaps you'll help me to find it, my dear.

700
01:01:11,901 --> 01:01:15,803
- Well, shall we brave the rides?
- The infernal machine?

701
01:01:15,905 --> 01:01:18,635
Not me. You two go on. I'll catch up.

702
01:01:18,741 --> 01:01:21,608
- Shall we go back?
- No, no. Go on. Enjoy yourselves.

703
01:01:21,711 --> 01:01:25,112
I'll fortify myself for the bus ride.
Hair of the dog, you know.

704
01:01:25,214 --> 01:01:28,274
Go on. I'll - I'll, uh, catch up.

705
01:01:30,286 --> 01:01:33,722
I think perhaps you've
come back just in time.

706
01:01:33,823 --> 01:01:36,257
I would've come back sooner.

707
01:01:36,359 --> 01:01:38,259
Why didn't you?

708
01:01:38,361 --> 01:01:42,730
Well, I wasrt sure he wanted me to.
He never answered my letters.

709
01:01:42,832 --> 01:01:44,800
I don't think he ever read them.

710
01:01:44,901 --> 01:01:47,802
- What?
- Your letters.

711
01:01:47,904 --> 01:01:50,771
He carries them around
stuffed inside his shirt...

712
01:01:50,873 --> 01:01:52,932
but I don't think he ever opened them.

714
01:01:56,145 --> 01:01:58,238
I cannot find them at all.

715
01:01:58,347 --> 01:02:00,713
Think of places you can go.

716
01:02:00,817 --> 01:02:05,015
Think in your mind the cantinas
where you go all the time.

717
01:02:05,121 --> 01:02:07,988
- Think.
- Bustamante's.

718
01:02:08,091 --> 01:02:10,992
Hmm. Sí. El Sol de la Noche.

719
01:02:11,094 --> 01:02:12,994
They're not there.

720
01:02:13,096 --> 01:02:16,588
El Popo? No. El Petate? No.

721
01:02:17,633 --> 01:02:20,761
Uh, Todos Contentos y Yo También?

722
01:02:20,870 --> 01:02:22,997
No.

723
01:02:23,106 --> 01:02:25,939
- El Farolito.
- No.

724
01:02:26,042 --> 01:02:29,068
Señor Cónsul, you never been there.

725
01:02:29,178 --> 01:02:32,944
- Yes, once.
- Oh, you makir a joke on me.

726
01:02:33,049 --> 01:02:35,677
Gentlemens never go to El Farolito.

727
01:02:35,785 --> 01:02:38,777
Es horrible. Es muy malo.

728
01:02:38,888 --> 01:02:41,789
Men balls turn blue...

729
01:02:41,891 --> 01:02:44,860
and then they go sick,
and then they go crazy and they die.

730
01:02:44,961 --> 01:02:48,692
Ha! If anybody be there,
I break the glass here.

731
01:02:49,732 --> 01:02:53,759
Believe me, doña Gregoria,
I am as chaste as a new-frocked priest.

732
01:02:55,605 --> 01:02:57,573
There's no need to break my glass.

733
01:02:57,673 --> 01:03:00,141
Only fill it again on your own,
doña Gregoria.

734
01:03:00,243 --> 01:03:02,939
Ay, señor Cónsul. Hmm.

735
01:03:03,045 --> 01:03:05,343
After a while, I began to wonder.

736
01:03:06,482 --> 01:03:09,747
If a man can hold his liquor as well as Geoff,
why shouldn't he drink?

737
01:03:09,852 --> 01:03:12,343
Somehow, Hugh,
that is not very consoling.

738
01:03:12,455 --> 01:03:15,686
I'm simply at a loss
as to how to help him.

739
01:03:15,792 --> 01:03:19,193
Perhaps we should get away from here,
away from Cuernavaca.

740
01:03:20,229 --> 01:03:23,756
- Find a farm somewhere.
- A farm?

741
01:03:23,866 --> 01:03:28,166
A real farm, with a red barn and silos
and pigs and chickens.

742
01:03:28,271 --> 01:03:30,739
What, no guinea fowl?
No peacocks?

743
01:03:32,575 --> 01:03:36,341
- Is it so fantastic?
- Perhaps not.

744
01:03:36,445 --> 01:03:38,606
We have money. Enough.

745
01:03:38,714 --> 01:03:42,172
I'm sorry.

746
01:03:42,285 --> 01:03:44,412
It's just the notion of Geoff
among the alfalfa...

747
01:03:44,520 --> 01:03:47,819
in bib overalls and a straw hat,
soberly hoeing.

748
01:03:47,924 --> 01:03:51,451
Well, it wouldn't have to be
as soberly as all that.

749
01:03:51,561 --> 01:03:53,529
What if he hates farms?

750
01:03:53,629 --> 01:03:56,496
Maybe the mere sight of a cow
makes him seasick.

751
01:03:56,599 --> 01:04:00,695
Well, maybe it's ridiculous, but at least
it's better than sitting here doing nothing.

753
01:04:02,805 --> 01:04:05,330
No. Gracias. No. No.

754
01:04:05,441 --> 01:04:07,909
No!

755
01:04:10,713 --> 01:04:13,079
- No, gracias.
- Let me pass.

756
01:04:13,182 --> 01:04:15,309
- No, gracias.
- No, gracias.

758
01:04:18,855 --> 01:04:20,755
Here's to your love.

759
01:04:22,058 --> 01:04:24,492
- Well -
- I hope that she come back to you soon.

760
01:04:24,594 --> 01:04:26,926
In fact, she has.

761
01:04:29,165 --> 01:04:31,929
So it is. One day,
maybe she come back to you.

762
01:04:32,034 --> 01:04:35,162
She has.
This morning, on the bus.

763
01:04:35,271 --> 01:04:38,672
Señor Cónsul, if you had esposa...

764
01:04:38,774 --> 01:04:41,368
you would lose everything
in that love.

765
01:04:41,477 --> 01:04:43,445
Oh.

766
01:04:44,847 --> 01:04:47,714
Because is beautiful to have love.

767
01:04:48,751 --> 01:04:51,879
But your mind is "occupated"
on one thing.

768
01:04:51,988 --> 01:04:55,890
So you will never lose your mind.

770
01:05:03,933 --> 01:05:06,128
I hope your wife come back soon.

771
01:05:06,235 --> 01:05:10,331
She's there, right now. Out there.

772
01:05:12,275 --> 01:05:15,142
You can ever think of it.

773
01:05:15,244 --> 01:05:18,008
Ay, señor Cónsul.
¿No quiere otra?

774
01:05:19,048 --> 01:05:22,540
- No, a bottle of Habanero, por favor.
- Ay.

775
01:05:22,652 --> 01:05:24,620
Cómo no, señor Cónsul.

776
01:05:24,720 --> 01:05:26,620
Ahora se la traigo.

777
01:05:31,160 --> 01:05:33,628
Ah, you know, señor Cónsul...

778
01:05:35,765 --> 01:05:39,792
I think you going to see
your esposa very soon.

779
01:05:40,836 --> 01:05:43,396
I can see you together...

780
01:05:43,506 --> 01:05:46,703
laughing in a very nice place.

781
01:05:46,809 --> 01:05:50,006
In the place you used to laugh.

782
01:05:50,112 --> 01:05:52,012
Huh?

783
01:05:53,616 --> 01:05:55,846
Ay, gracias, señor Cónsul.

784
01:05:59,555 --> 01:06:03,491
- Adiós.
- Adiós, doña Gregoria.

788
01:06:17,373 --> 01:06:19,273
Uno

794
01:06:59,248 --> 01:07:02,740
Here we go.

801
01:07:22,972 --> 01:07:27,204
Ride 'em, cowboy!


803
01:07:31,147 --> 01:07:33,843
Go on, my beauty!

804
01:07:33,949 --> 01:07:35,814
For your life!

808
01:07:53,102 --> 01:07:56,094
M-My heels kicked at heaven!

809
01:07:56,205 --> 01:07:58,435
Oh! IGracias!

810
01:07:58,541 --> 01:08:00,873
Gracias. Gracias.

811
01:08:00,976 --> 01:08:02,876
Gracias. Gracias.

812
01:08:02,978 --> 01:08:06,812
Gracias. Gracias. Gracias. Gracias.

813
01:08:06,916 --> 01:08:11,216
Gracias. Gracias.
Gracias. Gracias.

814
01:08:11,320 --> 01:08:14,414
- Let's forget the charreada, Geoff.
- Absolutely not.

815
01:08:14,523 --> 01:08:17,151
Forward to the arena!

817
01:08:38,481 --> 01:08:41,041
It's like riding over the moon.

818
01:08:45,354 --> 01:08:50,519
I thought divorcées didn't wear
their wedding rings.

819
01:08:50,626 --> 01:08:53,060
- They don't.
- Well then?

820
01:08:54,263 --> 01:08:56,231
I couldn't get the ring off.

821
01:08:58,934 --> 01:09:02,995
He's a bloody sinarquista.
Look at that badge on his lapel.

822
01:09:03,105 --> 01:09:05,869
They're the ones
I've been writing about.

823
01:09:05,975 --> 01:09:08,136
The ones getting money
from the Nazis.

824
01:09:28,597 --> 01:09:31,361
Stop. Stop the bus. Alto.

826
01:09:45,014 --> 01:09:47,107
- Prohibido.
- The hell it is.

828
01:09:54,590 --> 01:09:56,490
Good Christ.

829
01:09:56,592 --> 01:09:58,583
Geoffrey, it's the flute player.

830
01:09:58,694 --> 01:10:00,719
- A doctor in Tomalin?
- Sí.

831
01:10:00,829 --> 01:10:03,662
- Go on, Geoff. Let's get him on the bus.
- Stop. Prohibido. Don't touch.

832
01:10:03,766 --> 01:10:07,327
No, señor. We go to jail.
No mi camión.

833
01:10:07,436 --> 01:10:09,927
It is the law.
You will be made accomplices.

834
01:10:10,039 --> 01:10:12,132
Let it go, Hugh.
Here come the local authorities.

836
01:10:14,710 --> 01:10:16,803
Well, we have to help him.

837
01:10:16,912 --> 01:10:18,812
It's too late.

838
01:10:21,784 --> 01:10:23,684
What you doing?

839
01:10:27,156 --> 01:10:30,990
- You murder?
- No, of course not.

840
01:10:31,093 --> 01:10:33,721
- You know who murder?
- No!

841
01:10:33,829 --> 01:10:36,263
He's dead, Hugh. Let it go.

842
01:10:44,640 --> 01:10:46,767
IVámonos!

843
01:10:59,922 --> 01:11:01,890
He was thrown from the horse.

844
01:11:02,925 --> 01:11:05,723
Come from the market.
Mucho dinero.

845
01:11:10,833 --> 01:11:12,960
Could've gotten yourself shot.

847
01:12:02,418 --> 01:12:04,318
IOlé!

848
01:12:06,422 --> 01:12:08,322
IOlé!

850
01:12:28,110 --> 01:12:30,010
Gracias.

851
01:12:32,748 --> 01:12:34,648
Buenas tardes.

852
01:12:34,750 --> 01:12:36,980
Perhaps you'd like to start
little " hin fishl '

853
01:12:37,086 --> 01:12:39,884
- "Hin fish?"
- Nice "hin fish."

854
01:12:39,988 --> 01:12:42,513
- Gin fizz.

855
01:12:42,624 --> 01:12:45,320
Tequila, por favor.

856
01:12:45,427 --> 01:12:47,622
Uh, sí. " Hin fishl '

857
01:12:47,730 --> 01:12:49,664
Uh, "hin fish" for the lady.

858
01:12:49,765 --> 01:12:52,029
- Tequila doble, por favor.
- Ydos tequilas doble.

859
01:12:52,134 --> 01:12:54,534
You like eggs, señora?

860
01:12:54,636 --> 01:12:58,003
Stepped-on eggs? Divorced eggs?
Poxy eggs on toast?

861
01:12:59,708 --> 01:13:01,608
Uh, no "poxy" eggs for me.

862
01:13:01,710 --> 01:13:04,702
What's this?
"Spectral chicken of the house"?

863
01:13:04,813 --> 01:13:07,338
- Pollo de la casa.
- Ah.

864
01:13:07,449 --> 01:13:10,850
- Shall we try the spectral chicken?
- Uh, sounds heavenly.

865
01:13:10,953 --> 01:13:13,615
Pollo para todos, por favor.

866
01:13:13,722 --> 01:13:16,555
- Muchas gracias.

867
01:13:16,658 --> 01:13:18,717
Ah, the cocktails have arrived.

868
01:13:20,229 --> 01:13:22,129
Gracias.

870
01:13:29,238 --> 01:13:31,138
- IOlé!
- Sí.

871
01:13:32,641 --> 01:13:36,202
Muchas gracias, señor.
Gracias, señor.

872
01:13:36,311 --> 01:13:40,577
- Oh.
- Muchas gracias. ¿Permiso?

873
01:13:40,682 --> 01:13:42,650
- Sí, señor.
- Gracias.

876
01:14:03,071 --> 01:14:07,030
  Madrid, you wondrous city  

877
01:14:07,142 --> 01:14:10,805
  Madrid, you wondrous city  

878
01:14:10,913 --> 01:14:14,679
  Madrid, you wondrous city  

879
01:14:14,783 --> 01:14:17,149
-   Mamita mía  

880
01:14:17,252 --> 01:14:19,914
  We wanted to take you  

881
01:14:20,022 --> 01:14:23,583
  They wanted  

882
01:14:23,692 --> 01:14:26,627
  To take you  

883
01:14:30,866 --> 01:14:33,858
  But your courageous children  

884
01:14:33,969 --> 01:14:38,338
  But your courageous children  

885
01:14:38,440 --> 01:14:42,706
  But your courageous children  

886
01:14:42,811 --> 01:14:47,248
  Mamita mía
Did not disgrace you  

887
01:14:47,349 --> 01:14:51,445
  Did not  

888
01:14:51,553 --> 01:14:54,021
  Disgrace you  

889
01:14:58,293 --> 01:15:01,820
  And all your tears of sorrow  

890
01:15:01,930 --> 01:15:05,923
-   And all your tears of sorrow  

891
01:15:06,034 --> 01:15:10,232
  And all your tears of sorrow  

892
01:15:10,339 --> 01:15:15,470
  Mamita mía
We shall avenge them  

893
01:15:15,577 --> 01:15:19,775
  We shall  

894
01:15:19,882 --> 01:15:24,080
  Avenge them   

895
01:15:28,290 --> 01:15:33,193
- Gracias, señor.
- Good. Very good.

896
01:15:33,295 --> 01:15:35,195
Gracias, señor.

897
01:15:41,336 --> 01:15:44,134
Had an English friend fighting in Spain.

898
01:15:44,239 --> 01:15:46,833
He was there from the start.

899
01:15:46,942 --> 01:15:49,103
During the Battle of Madrid...

900
01:15:49,211 --> 01:15:52,772
he lay holed up with a machine gun
in the library of University City...

901
01:15:52,881 --> 01:15:55,315
reading Carlyle between attacks.

902
01:15:57,719 --> 01:16:00,187
He was a Communist.

903
01:16:00,289 --> 01:16:02,587
Approximately the best man I ever met.

904
01:16:04,993 --> 01:16:08,087
Had a taste for Vin Rosé d'Anjou...

905
01:16:09,264 --> 01:16:11,164
and a dog named Harpo.

906
01:16:12,467 --> 01:16:15,766
You wouldn't expect a Communist
to have a dog named Harpo.

907
01:16:15,871 --> 01:16:18,237
Or would one?

908
01:16:18,340 --> 01:16:21,070
He'd been reported dead
twice before...

909
01:16:21,176 --> 01:16:23,644
and both times
he showed up again at the front.

910
01:16:24,746 --> 01:16:27,237
So when he was listed
as a casualty the third time...

911
01:16:27,349 --> 01:16:30,113
no one took any notice...

912
01:16:30,218 --> 01:16:32,186
expecting him
to turn up again any day...

913
01:16:32,287 --> 01:16:34,255
hale as ever.

914
01:16:36,725 --> 01:16:39,091
He didn't.

915
01:16:41,196 --> 01:16:44,165
Cervantes! ¡Otros tequila, por favor!

916
01:16:44,266 --> 01:16:46,166
A bottle!

917
01:16:48,270 --> 01:16:51,000
When I think of the men I knew there -

918
01:16:51,106 --> 01:16:53,336
the ones who stayed and died -

919
01:16:54,443 --> 01:16:56,502
Christ, I feel like a deserter.

920
01:16:56,612 --> 01:16:58,546
I should never have left.

921
01:16:58,647 --> 01:17:01,115
You said yourself it was a lost cause.

922
01:17:01,216 --> 01:17:03,878
My conscience says that's no excuse.

923
01:17:03,986 --> 01:17:07,285
What do you know
about conscience and about guilt?

924
01:17:07,389 --> 01:17:09,914
Remember who you're talking to.

925
01:17:10,025 --> 01:17:11,993
Master of the S.S. Samaritan...

926
01:17:12,094 --> 01:17:15,291
whose hands - these very hands -
los manos to Firmin -

927
01:17:15,397 --> 01:17:18,855
flung seven German officers
into her fiery furnace.

928
01:17:18,967 --> 01:17:22,801
- You did not.
- One after the other, kicking and squealing.

929
01:17:22,904 --> 01:17:25,668
The tale gets taller
each time he tells it.

930
01:17:25,774 --> 01:17:27,901
Geoffrey, you know very well you didn't.

931
01:17:28,010 --> 01:17:30,274
The British Navy doesn't
give medals to murderers.

932
01:17:31,313 --> 01:17:33,577
Well, I might have done it.

933
01:17:33,682 --> 01:17:36,480
I was the commanding officer responsible.

934
01:17:37,519 --> 01:17:39,612
You can't apologize for some things.

935
01:17:39,721 --> 01:17:41,712
The past fills up quicker than we know.

936
01:17:41,823 --> 01:17:45,623
"Firmin innocent.
Bears guilt of world on shouldersl '

937
01:17:47,763 --> 01:17:51,096
Bears your guilt as well, doesn't he?

938
01:17:53,168 --> 01:17:55,068
He invited...

939
01:17:55,170 --> 01:17:57,661
the heart full of dust...

940
01:17:57,773 --> 01:17:59,673
that he got.

941
01:17:59,775 --> 01:18:01,675
Cervantes! Tequila!

946
01:19:03,405 --> 01:19:05,305
¡Olé!

947
01:19:08,643 --> 01:19:11,806
He's quite good actually.
I say, well done!

948
01:19:13,515 --> 01:19:16,040
¡Olé!

949
01:19:16,151 --> 01:19:18,051
IOlé!

950
01:19:20,522 --> 01:19:23,184
¡Olé! ¡Olé!

951
01:19:23,291 --> 01:19:25,759
It was always one of his dreams -
to be a matador.

952
01:19:25,861 --> 01:19:29,422
He practices veronicas
in front of a mirror.

954
01:19:32,167 --> 01:19:35,193
IOlé!

955
01:19:36,538 --> 01:19:38,438
¡Olé!

958
01:19:47,015 --> 01:19:48,915
IOlé!

959
01:19:50,819 --> 01:19:52,753
¡Olé!

960
01:19:58,026 --> 01:20:00,893
IOlé! Bravo, Hugh!

961
01:20:07,202 --> 01:20:11,866
IToreador! ¡Toreador! ¡Toreador! ¡Toreador!

967
01:20:29,090 --> 01:20:32,059

969
01:20:42,504 --> 01:20:45,405
- Geoffrey, listen. Look at me.
- What?

970
01:20:45,507 --> 01:20:48,943
- There's nothing holding us here any longer.
- No, there's nothing holding us.

971
01:20:49,044 --> 01:20:52,309
- Let's go away together.
- No.

972
01:20:52,414 --> 01:20:54,382
It's not too late.

973
01:20:54,482 --> 01:20:57,110
- We can -We can start again.
- Start again?

974
01:20:57,219 --> 01:21:00,450
Yes, in another place.
A new place will give us a better chance.

975
01:21:00,555 --> 01:21:04,423
Why not?
Why not, for sweetJesus' sake? Let's go.

976
01:21:04,526 --> 01:21:07,086
Oh, I love you.
I want our marriage back.

977
01:21:07,195 --> 01:21:09,789
So do I. So do I.

978
01:21:09,898 --> 01:21:12,696
- I've fallen down somewhat.
- Never mind.

979
01:21:12,801 --> 01:21:15,827
- We could go north, to Maine or Canada.
- Yes! Yes. Anywhere.

980
01:21:15,937 --> 01:21:18,303
Find a cabin slap-bang on the sea.

981
01:21:18,406 --> 01:21:22,240
Cliffs beaten by the surf.
Um, a small pier in a cove.

982
01:21:22,344 --> 01:21:25,142
- We could. We really could.
We could live on very little.
- Yes. We could.

983
01:21:25,247 --> 01:21:27,215
Draw our own water.
Chop our own wood.

984
01:21:27,315 --> 01:21:29,840
- After all, I'm still as strong as a horse.
- Yes.

985
01:21:29,951 --> 01:21:32,351
- What's all this?
- We're leaving.

986
01:21:32,454 --> 01:21:36,254
Headed north, where there's snow
and the year's divided into seasons.

987
01:21:36,358 --> 01:21:38,451
A farm with a red barn?

988
01:21:38,560 --> 01:21:40,460
No, no.

989
01:21:40,562 --> 01:21:44,999
Escape into the wilderness
like good old William Blackstone.

990
01:21:45,100 --> 01:21:48,627
Get to know the trappers
and the fishermen -

991
01:21:48,737 --> 01:21:51,001
the last free men on Earth.

992
01:21:51,106 --> 01:21:54,303
Nothing but tall pines.
No phones, no electricity.

993
01:21:54,409 --> 01:21:57,401
Quite a life. Tranquil isolation.

994
01:21:57,512 --> 01:21:59,878
Quite.

995
01:21:59,981 --> 01:22:03,109
Stuck between the forest and the sea...

996
01:22:03,218 --> 01:22:06,187
where there's all the time there is.

997
01:22:06,288 --> 01:22:08,256
Yvonne'll make pottery.

998
01:22:08,356 --> 01:22:10,688
I'll write my memoirs.

1000
01:22:12,994 --> 01:22:15,224
Go further north each winter.

1001
01:22:15,330 --> 01:22:19,096
Strike for the Pole.
Wear bearskins. Chew seal blubber.

1002
01:22:20,335 --> 01:22:22,599
Build igloos.
Live among the Eskimo.

1003
01:22:22,704 --> 01:22:26,834
Uh, uh, when-
when Brother Hugh comes on a visit...

1004
01:22:26,942 --> 01:22:30,036
fresh from his heroics
in, uh, Spain or wherever...

1005
01:22:30,145 --> 01:22:33,080
I'll show proper Eskimo hospitality
and give him my wife...

1006
01:22:33,181 --> 01:22:37,015
to bed down with
during the cold northern night.

1007
01:22:38,853 --> 01:22:41,720
Geoff, what possesses you?

1008
01:22:46,161 --> 01:22:48,186
Sobriety, I'm afraid.

1009
01:22:48,296 --> 01:22:50,264
Too much moderation.

1010
01:22:52,801 --> 01:22:55,429
I need drink desperately.
Get my balance back.

1014
01:23:08,416 --> 01:23:11,351
What an uncommon time
they must have had of it...

1015
01:23:13,188 --> 01:23:15,213
paddling palms,
playing bubbies and titties...

1016
01:23:15,323 --> 01:23:17,814
while I was having bouts
with rats and roaches.

1017
01:23:21,229 --> 01:23:24,221
"It isn't too late,"she said.

1018
01:23:24,332 --> 01:23:27,631
Why isn't it too late?
Why isn't it? Did I say so? No.

1019
01:23:27,736 --> 01:23:31,263
No, I thought it was -
it was all legally settled.

1020
01:23:31,373 --> 01:23:35,173
It's only she that insists
it isn't too late...

1021
01:23:35,276 --> 01:23:40,077
because she can't get
the bloody ring off.

1022
01:23:41,349 --> 01:23:44,250
Geoffrey. Geoffrey, I've come...

1023
01:23:46,354 --> 01:23:48,481
cr- crawling back.

1024
01:23:51,326 --> 01:23:54,090
What m-more can I do?

1025
01:23:54,195 --> 01:23:58,154
Let me be your wife.

1026
01:23:58,266 --> 01:24:01,667
When has she ever been a wife to me?

1027
01:24:01,770 --> 01:24:04,034
Where are the children
I might have had...

1028
01:24:04,139 --> 01:24:06,004
- that drowned to the rattling-

1029
01:24:06,107 --> 01:24:09,167
of a thousand douche bags?

1030
01:24:10,378 --> 01:24:14,280
Hugh, on the threshold of paradise...

1031
01:24:14,382 --> 01:24:19,012
puffing over her gills like a codfish,
veins like a racehorse...

1032
01:24:19,120 --> 01:24:23,557
prime as a goat, hot as a monkey,
salt as a wolf in pride.

1033
01:24:23,658 --> 01:24:28,686
Let them wallow here in their bliss
with my blessing.

1034
01:24:30,465 --> 01:24:32,695
Hell's...

1035
01:24:32,801 --> 01:24:35,269
my preference.

1036
01:24:37,105 --> 01:24:39,699
I choose hell.

1038
01:24:41,810 --> 01:24:47,544
Hell is my natural habitat.

1040
01:25:04,599 --> 01:25:06,726
Let him go, Yvonne.

1041
01:25:06,835 --> 01:25:09,998
- There's nothing one can do when he's like this.
- Something will happen to him.

1042
01:25:10,105 --> 01:25:12,869
He'll drink himself sober
and come dragging home in the morning.

1043
01:25:12,974 --> 01:25:15,636
- Hugh, we were wrong, not Geoffrey.
- And we'll never make up for it.

1044
01:25:15,743 --> 01:25:18,735
He won't let us.
He doesn't want your help.

1045
01:25:18,847 --> 01:25:21,111
I want his.

1049
01:25:32,961 --> 01:25:34,929
IHola! Bus!

1050
01:25:40,635 --> 01:25:42,535
Geoffrey!

1057
01:26:42,797 --> 01:26:44,992
Mezcal.

1061
01:26:54,943 --> 01:26:57,070
Mezcal, por favor.

1063
01:27:02,217 --> 01:27:04,185
Ay, el inglés.

1064
01:27:20,501 --> 01:27:23,493
I know who you are. Sí.

1065
01:27:23,605 --> 01:27:28,008
My England man! IMi amigo!

1066
01:27:28,109 --> 01:27:31,101
My friend. Old time, old time.

1067
01:27:31,212 --> 01:27:33,112
Oh, nice to see you.

1068
01:27:33,214 --> 01:27:36,672
You were very borracho. Whole time
you were drunk. I buy you to drink.

1069
01:27:36,784 --> 01:27:39,719
What do you want?
I pay for you and for me.

1070
01:27:39,821 --> 01:27:42,381
Cuatro mezcal, por favor.

1071
01:27:42,490 --> 01:27:44,390
Anís, para mí.

1072
01:27:44,492 --> 01:27:47,359
You buy, then I'll buy, then you.

1073
01:27:47,462 --> 01:27:50,761
What do you want, my England man?

1074
01:27:50,865 --> 01:27:54,062
I give you the beautiful girl?

1075
01:27:54,168 --> 01:27:56,159
- No, gracias.
- You always "no, gracias."

1076
01:27:56,271 --> 01:27:58,239
No good, "no, gracias."

1077
01:27:58,339 --> 01:28:01,399
I give you the most beautiful girl,
and you say "no, gracias"?

1078
01:28:01,509 --> 01:28:04,103
No, you can't.

1079
01:28:04,212 --> 01:28:06,112
Everywhere.

1080
01:28:06,214 --> 01:28:10,412
You want, uh, a little girl? Petra.

1081
01:28:13,688 --> 01:28:16,350
I give you a little girl.

1082
01:28:16,457 --> 01:28:19,449
You want the big girl? Sofia.

1083
01:28:19,560 --> 01:28:22,222
I give you Sofia.
Big girl. You can do it.

1084
01:28:24,032 --> 01:28:26,057
You want a boy?

1085
01:28:26,167 --> 01:28:28,761
I guarantee all clean.

1086
01:28:28,870 --> 01:28:32,670
What do you want?
I make a special price for my friend.

1087
01:28:32,774 --> 01:28:34,742
- How 'bout it?
- How about what?

1088
01:28:34,842 --> 01:28:36,810
- The works.
- What works?

1089
01:28:36,911 --> 01:28:41,109
The works -
God, nooky, moola, cornolir.

1090
01:28:41,215 --> 01:28:45,083
It's all covered in the Old and New Testimony,
as wrote by Mozart.

1091
01:28:45,186 --> 01:28:48,952
What one don't say, the other do.
I say burn all books but them.

1092
01:28:49,057 --> 01:28:51,150
Am I right, or am I wrong?

1093
01:28:51,259 --> 01:28:53,659
You're absolutely right, my friend.

1094
01:28:53,761 --> 01:28:57,356
This man es asshole americano.
No good for me or for you.

1095
01:28:57,465 --> 01:29:00,901
I no like americanos.
No friend to nobody.

1096
01:29:01,002 --> 01:29:04,267
Is asshole man. Get outta here!

1103
01:29:55,156 --> 01:29:57,920
Hey, I have something for you, señor.

1105
01:30:03,064 --> 01:30:07,626
Oh, my wife is picking up eggs
to be hatched.

1106
01:30:07,735 --> 01:30:10,727
She takes a baby,
puts it into the chicken run...

1107
01:30:10,838 --> 01:30:14,604
and this cock comes out
and pecks out the baby's eye.

1108
01:30:14,709 --> 01:30:18,736
She wants to kill him.
I said, " No, you cannot kill this cockl '

1109
01:30:18,846 --> 01:30:22,043
This is un bruto.
A very powerful cock.

1110
01:30:22,150 --> 01:30:24,118
You know what he did?

1111
01:30:24,218 --> 01:30:27,915
He won seven straight fights.
Can you imagine that?

1112
01:30:28,022 --> 01:30:31,583
Seven straight fights.
Is it a miracle or not?

1113
01:30:31,692 --> 01:30:34,183
Ah, here you are, señor.

1114
01:30:34,295 --> 01:30:36,593
Look. Do you recognize them?

1115
01:30:47,308 --> 01:30:49,674
Wait, hombre.
I send you puta o putas.

1116
01:30:49,777 --> 01:30:52,245
Bonita muchacha
por mi amigo inglés.

1117
01:31:02,323 --> 01:31:04,223
Hola, tía.

1118
01:31:09,864 --> 01:31:11,729
Where is su señora?

1119
01:31:14,235 --> 01:31:17,261
He's also a drunkard.

1121
01:31:50,505 --> 01:31:52,973
My heart has the taste of ashes...

1122
01:31:53,074 --> 01:31:56,066
and my throat is tight
and weary with weeping.

1123
01:31:56,177 --> 01:31:59,203
Geoffrey, why don't you answer me?

1124
01:31:59,313 --> 01:32:03,147
If you no longer love me and do not
want me to come back to you...

1125
01:32:03,251 --> 01:32:05,879
will you not write and tell me so?

1126
01:32:05,987 --> 01:32:08,956
It is your silence that frightens me.

1128
01:32:13,561 --> 01:32:15,859
What has happened to our hearts?

1129
01:32:15,963 --> 01:32:18,523
Don't we owe it to ourselves...

1130
01:32:18,633 --> 01:32:22,000
to that self we created apart from us...

1131
01:32:22,103 --> 01:32:25,038
to try again?

1132
01:32:25,139 --> 01:32:27,505
I am sorry.

1133
01:32:27,608 --> 01:32:29,701
I am so sorry.

1134
01:32:31,479 --> 01:32:33,379
Not enough.

1135
01:32:35,082 --> 01:32:36,982
Never enough.

1136
01:32:39,120 --> 01:32:41,088
It's not possible.

1137
01:32:44,959 --> 01:32:48,360
Not... in this world.

1139
01:33:08,082 --> 01:33:10,050
Bueno. Estoy bien.

1140
01:33:46,954 --> 01:33:49,752
- ¿Sí?
- Ah. No.

1149
01:35:53,581 --> 01:35:55,640
I'm looking for a tall man.

1150
01:35:55,750 --> 01:35:58,878
Englishman. White clothes.
Uh, has he been here?

1151
01:35:58,986 --> 01:36:02,615
- No hablo inglés, señor.
- ¿Buscan al borracho inglés?

1152
01:36:02,723 --> 01:36:05,317
- Sí. Sí.
- No sé.

1153
01:36:05,426 --> 01:36:08,020
- What?
- No sé.

1154
01:36:08,129 --> 01:36:10,393
- Let's go, Yvonne.
- No!

1155
01:36:11,932 --> 01:36:13,832
Oh, all right.

1156
01:36:13,934 --> 01:36:15,834
Wa

1158
01:36:52,540 --> 01:36:54,508
¿Inglés?

1161
01:37:11,058 --> 01:37:14,186
Oh, Geoffrey, Geoffrey, Geoffrey!

1162
01:37:15,996 --> 01:37:18,396
Oh, Geoffrey!

1164
01:37:20,701 --> 01:37:22,601
Geoffrey!

1166
01:38:02,409 --> 01:38:04,309
You pay.

1167
01:38:05,446 --> 01:38:07,914
- I paid the girl.
- You pay me also.

1168
01:38:12,686 --> 01:38:15,621
- Pay more.
- No.

1169
01:38:19,860 --> 01:38:22,727
Okay, my England man.
No worry for you.

1170
01:38:22,830 --> 01:38:24,855
María, she very clean.

1171
01:38:24,965 --> 01:38:28,833
If you need doctor,
I send all my amigos to this man.

1172
01:38:28,936 --> 01:38:31,632
Good man doctor. Here. Come on.

1173
01:38:31,739 --> 01:38:34,503
Here. Here.
Here you are. Take a look.

1177
01:38:57,665 --> 01:38:59,997
- Ah, my friend.
- Mezcal.

1178
01:39:00,100 --> 01:39:03,968
My friend, my friend, old time.
Sure, sure.

1179
01:39:04,071 --> 01:39:06,369
Mozart was the man
who wrote the Bible.

1180
01:39:06,473 --> 01:39:09,965
This man is nothing for you.
Oh, this man is son of a bitch.

1181
01:39:10,077 --> 01:39:12,671
You England man.
I don't care for son of a bitch American.

1182
01:39:12,780 --> 01:39:14,748
They no good for you or for me.

1183
01:39:14,848 --> 01:39:18,306
My Mexican -
My Mexican friend, old time, eh?

1184
01:39:18,419 --> 01:39:22,287
You gotta study deep down to know
that Mozart wrote the Old Testimony.

1185
01:39:22,389 --> 01:39:25,722
That's my religion
spoke in a few words.

1186
01:39:25,826 --> 01:39:28,192
Mozart was a lawyer.
Stick by that, you'll be all right.

1187
01:39:28,295 --> 01:39:31,594
Oh, American no good.
I no like americanos.

1188
01:39:31,699 --> 01:39:33,826
I happen to be an American...

1189
01:39:33,934 --> 01:39:38,371
and I'm getting extremely bored
by your insults.

1191
01:40:22,750 --> 01:40:24,718
¿Qué está haciendo?

1192
01:40:26,020 --> 01:40:27,988
What are you doing?

1193
01:40:29,323 --> 01:40:31,985
Nothing.

1194
01:40:33,560 --> 01:40:38,361
I... heard tell that the world
goes 'round...

1195
01:40:39,500 --> 01:40:42,298
so I'm going to wait here...

1196
01:40:43,504 --> 01:40:46,064
for my house to go by.

1197
01:40:47,274 --> 01:40:53,213
Then I'm gonna go inside...
and lock the door.

1198
01:40:55,349 --> 01:40:57,943
You want to steal mi caballo, huh?

1199
01:40:59,286 --> 01:41:01,777
No.

1200
01:41:01,889 --> 01:41:05,290
No, amigo mío.

1201
01:41:05,392 --> 01:41:07,292
Just looking.

1202
01:41:08,829 --> 01:41:11,024
Por favor. Mmm?

1204
01:41:16,336 --> 01:41:19,271
- ¿ Ya pagó por la bebida?
- No. Todavía no.

1205
01:41:19,373 --> 01:41:22,069
ÉI no ha pagado lo suficiente
por la muchacha.

1206
01:41:22,176 --> 01:41:26,670
Hmm. They say there is trouble
about you no pay.

1207
01:41:26,780 --> 01:41:29,578
You no pay for a drink.

1208
01:41:29,683 --> 01:41:31,947
You no have money, eh?

1209
01:41:32,052 --> 01:41:33,952
Sí. Gracias.

1210
01:41:34,054 --> 01:41:36,420
- I have money.
- No.

1211
01:41:36,523 --> 01:41:40,425
You no have money,
and now you steal mi caballo, eh?

1212
01:41:40,527 --> 01:41:43,553
- Decidedly not.

1213
01:41:43,664 --> 01:41:47,430
No, I was merely admiring it.

1214
01:41:47,534 --> 01:41:50,469
Looking at your horse. Admiring.

1215
01:41:50,571 --> 01:41:55,270
For why you look at mi caballo?
Huh? For why?

1216
01:41:55,375 --> 01:41:57,605
I think you steal.

1217
01:41:57,711 --> 01:42:01,112
To run away for to not pay money.

1218
01:42:01,215 --> 01:42:05,015
No, l-I already paid the girl.
I paid your friend.

1219
01:42:05,119 --> 01:42:07,053
You don't pay enough!

1220
01:42:07,154 --> 01:42:09,952
I think you pay... more.

1221
01:42:11,225 --> 01:42:13,250
Certainly. Certainly.

1222
01:42:13,360 --> 01:42:15,328
Ah.

1223
01:42:17,965 --> 01:42:19,956
¿Cómo te llamas?

1224
01:42:20,067 --> 01:42:22,194
This man is chief of municipality.

1225
01:42:22,302 --> 01:42:24,202
He want to know your name.

1226
01:42:24,304 --> 01:42:26,431
Sí, sí, sí.

1227
01:42:26,540 --> 01:42:30,567
We want to know your names.

1228
01:42:31,745 --> 01:42:34,145
- Trotsky.
- Al Capone.

1229
01:42:35,249 --> 01:42:38,616
Uh, my name is Blackstone.

1230
01:42:38,719 --> 01:42:40,619
William Blackstone.

1231
01:42:40,721 --> 01:42:42,621
You cabrón Juden.

1232
01:42:44,057 --> 01:42:45,957
No, no, no. Blackstone.

1233
01:42:46,059 --> 01:42:50,018
Jews are very seldom, uh,
very, uh, borrach-borracho?

1234
01:42:50,130 --> 01:42:52,064
So -

1235
01:42:52,166 --> 01:42:54,066
Where you come from?

1236
01:42:54,168 --> 01:42:57,228
From Russia, eh?
What for you do?

1237
01:42:57,337 --> 01:42:59,771
Uh, I'm -
I'm, uh -

1238
01:42:59,873 --> 01:43:02,307
a frontiersman.

1239
01:43:02,409 --> 01:43:05,344
This man is chief of gardens.

1240
01:43:05,445 --> 01:43:07,436
Jefe de jardineros.

1241
01:43:07,548 --> 01:43:10,483
I am chief too.
Chief of stockyard.

1243
01:43:12,586 --> 01:43:14,918
you are chief of borrachos.

1245
01:43:18,091 --> 01:43:20,616
For why you wear black glasses?

1246
01:43:20,727 --> 01:43:23,093
For why you make disguise?

1247
01:43:23,197 --> 01:43:27,759
I think he's, uh, maybe a spy then.

1248
01:43:27,868 --> 01:43:32,202
- And we shoot the spies in Mexico, huh?

1249
01:43:32,306 --> 01:43:34,274
You a Russian spy?

1250
01:43:34,374 --> 01:43:37,309
No comprendo.

1251
01:43:37,411 --> 01:43:40,312
William Blackstone, frontiersman.

1254
01:43:59,399 --> 01:44:02,197
Cuatro mezcal, por favor.

1255
01:44:13,180 --> 01:44:16,240
Go. Go. Vete rápido.

1256
01:44:16,350 --> 01:44:19,012
Estos hombres
no son amigos de México.

1257
01:44:19,119 --> 01:44:21,849
Son malos. Vámonos.

1258
01:44:21,955 --> 01:44:23,855
Go.

1259
01:44:23,957 --> 01:44:25,891
Gracias, señora.

1260
01:44:31,131 --> 01:44:33,861
- ¿Cómo estás?

1262
01:44:46,580 --> 01:44:49,515
Where is your passport, eh?
Mmm.

1263
01:44:52,486 --> 01:44:55,046
What for you lie?

1264
01:44:55,155 --> 01:44:57,589
Your name no is Black.

1265
01:44:57,691 --> 01:45:00,216
Hmm. Cabrón.

1266
01:45:01,261 --> 01:45:05,197
You Bolshevik prick?
Anticristo Jew?

1267
01:45:05,299 --> 01:45:08,462
¿Cómo chingado te llamas?

1268
01:45:08,568 --> 01:45:10,593
Blackstone.

1269
01:45:10,704 --> 01:45:14,663
It say here your name is Firmin.

1270
01:45:14,775 --> 01:45:18,575
I don't give a damn
what it says anywhere.

1271
01:45:18,679 --> 01:45:21,773
My name is Blackstone.

1272
01:45:21,882 --> 01:45:24,282
Where your papers?

1273
01:45:24,384 --> 01:45:27,785
For why you have no papers, eh?

1274
01:45:32,626 --> 01:45:34,890
Give me those letters.

1275
01:45:34,995 --> 01:45:37,759
You pox coxes!

1276
01:45:37,864 --> 01:45:40,526
You cox coxes!

1277
01:45:40,634 --> 01:45:43,296
You murdered that Indian.

1278
01:45:43,403 --> 01:45:46,736
Tried to pretend
that it was an accident.

1279
01:45:46,840 --> 01:45:49,308
You stole his money.

1280
01:45:49,409 --> 01:45:51,377
You stole his horse!

1281
01:45:54,181 --> 01:45:57,776
Give me... my letters!

1282
01:45:57,884 --> 01:45:59,977
What letters, cabrón?

1283
01:46:00,087 --> 01:46:03,181
Your name is Black,
and you have no letters!

1285
01:46:09,596 --> 01:46:13,726
Give me my letters.

1286
01:46:13,834 --> 01:46:17,531
I blow you wide open from your knees...

1287
01:46:17,637 --> 01:46:20,572
you chingado Jew!

1288
01:46:25,645 --> 01:46:27,840
You swines.

1289
01:46:27,948 --> 01:46:30,576
You murderers!

1290
01:46:30,684 --> 01:46:32,982
Give me my letters!

1291
01:46:35,789 --> 01:46:38,189
Trash!

1292
01:46:38,291 --> 01:46:42,751
Only the poor, the people
you wipe your feet on -

1293
01:46:44,398 --> 01:46:47,492
old men carrying their fathers...

1294
01:46:47,601 --> 01:46:49,796
philosophers weeping in the dust -

1295
01:46:49,903 --> 01:46:51,871
will be saved!

1296
01:46:53,507 --> 01:46:55,702
The beggars and the accursed!

1297
01:46:55,809 --> 01:47:01,076
I blow you wide open from your knees,
you chingado Jew!

1298
01:47:01,181 --> 01:47:05,049
Stop walking in your sleep.

1299
01:47:05,152 --> 01:47:08,519
Stop sleeping with my wife.

1303
01:47:17,097 --> 01:47:21,033
- Geoffrey!

1305
01:47:50,630 --> 01:47:52,689
What a...

1306
01:47:52,799 --> 01:47:56,667
dingy way to die.
