Hi, everybody.
This is your cousin Brucie. Whoa!
Our summer romances are in full bloom,
and everybody's in love!
So cousins, here's a great song
from the Four Seasons.
That was the summer of 1963...
when everybody called me ""Baby""
and it didn't occur to me to mind.
That was before
President Kennedy was shot...
before the Beatles came...
when I couldn't wait
to join the Peace Corps...
and I thought I'd never
find a guy as great as my dad.
That was the summer
we went to Kellerman's.
Ping-Pong in the west arcade,
softball in the east diamond.
All you Sandy Koufaxes,
get out there!
Complimentary dance lessons
in the gazebo.
Oh, my God.
Look at that!
Mom, I should've brought the coral
shoes. You said I was taking too much.
Well, sweetheart,
you brought ten pairs.
But the coral shoes
matched that dress.
This is not a tragedy.
A tragedy is three men trapped in a mine
or police dogs used in Birmingham.
Monks burning themselves
in protest.
Butt out, Baby.
Okay, we got horseshoes
on the south lawn in 15 minutes!
We've got splish-splash
the water class down by the lake.
We have the still life art class.
We got volleyball and croquet.
And for you older folks,
we got sacks!
Doc!
Max!
Doc, after all these years
I finally got you up on my mountain.
How's the blood pressure?
I want you girls to know...
if it were not for this man,
I'd be standing here dead.
- Billy, get the bags.
- Right away, Doc.
I kept the best cabin
for you and your beautiful girls.
Hey, thanks a lot.
You want a job here?
There's a merengue class in
the gazebo in the next few minutes.
The greatest teacher.
Used to be a Rockette.
It's his first real vacation
in six years, Max. Take it easy.
Three weeks here,
it'll feel like a year.
One, two, three, four! Stomp
those grapes and stomp some more!
One, two, three, four!
Listen to the music!
Sorry.
Move your caboose
and shake it loose!
One, two, three, four!
Start the train!
Come on, men!
Follow me into a round robin!
Ladies, the inner circle!
Come on, ladies!
God wouldn't have given you maracas
if he didn't want you to shake them!
Okay now, ladies,
when I say ""stop""...
you're gonna find
the man of your dreams.
Stop!
Remember, he's the boss on
the dance floor, if nowhere else.
Mom, Dad, I'm going up
to the main house to look around.
There are two kinds of help here.
You waiters are
all college guys...
and I went to Harvard
and Yale to hire you.
And why did I do that? Why?
I shouldn't have to remind you.
This is a family place.
That means you keep your fingers out
of the water, hair out of the soup...
and show the goddamn
daughters a good time.
All the daughters.
Even the dogs.
Schlepp 'em out to the terrace,
show 'em the stars.
- Romance 'em any way you want.
- Got that, guys?
Hey, hold it!
Hold it.
Well, if it isn't
the entertainment staff.
Listen, wise ass,
you got your own rules.
Dance with the daughters.
Teach 'em the mambo...
the cha-cha,
anything they pay for.
That's it.
That's where it ends.
No funny business, no conversations,
and keep you hands off!
It's the same at all these places. Some
ass in the woods, but no conversation.
Watch it, Rodriguez.
Can you keep that straight, Johnny?
What you can't lay your hands on?
Just put your pickle on everybody's
plate, and leave the hard stuff to me.
Sit down and I'll
get you some wine.
Thank you, Max.
This is Dr. and Mrs. Houseman.
Baby, Lisa, this is your waiter,
Robbie Gould.
Yale medical school.
These people are my special guests.
Give them anything they want.
- Enjoy.
- Thanks, Max.
Look at all this leftover food. Are
there still starving children in Europe?
- Try Southeast Asia, Ma.
- Right.
Robbie, Baby wants to send
her leftover pot roast...
to Southeast Asia,
so anything you don't finish, wrap up.
Max, our Baby's gonna
change the world.
- And what are you gonna do, Missy?
- Lisa's gonna decorate it.
She already does.
Doc, I want you to meet someone.
My grandson Neil.
Goes to the Cornell School
of Hotel Management.
Baby's starting
Mount Holyoke in the fall.
Oh, great.
Are you going to major in English?
No. Economics of
underdeveloped countries.
- I'm going into the Peace Corps.
- After the final show...
I'm going to Mississippi with
a couple of busboys, freedom ride.
This is our own Tito Suarez.
Mambo!
Yeah! Come on!
Who's that?
Oh, them.
They're the dance people.
They're here to keep
the guests happy.
They shouldn't show off with each other.
That's not gonna sell lessons.
- Hi, kids. Having fun?
- Yeah.
Actually, I've gotta excuse myself.
I'm in charge of the games tonight.
Would you like to help me
get things started?
Sure she would.
This'll only hurt for a minute.
You've got Blue Cross, right?
Was that good for you?
And for being such a good sport,
here you go!
I finally met a girl
exactly like my mother.
Dresses like her, acts like her.
So I brought her home.
My father doesn't like her!
Go figure.
- Hi.
- How'd you get here?
- I was taking a walk.
- Go back.
Let me help you.
What's up there?
No guests allowed.
House rules.
Why don't you go back to the playhouse?
I saw you dancing with little boss man.
Can you keep a secret?
Your parents would kill you.
Max would kill me.
Where'd they learn to do that?
Where?
I don't know. Kids are doing it
in their basements back home.
Wanna try it?
Come on, Baby.
Can you imagine dancing like this
on the main floor...
home of the family fox-trot?
Max would close
the place down first.
That's my cousin, Johnny Castle.
He got me the job here.
- They look great together.
- Yeah.
You'd think they were
a couple, wouldn't you?
- Aren't they?
- No, not since we were kids.
Do you love me?
Yo, cousin, what's she doing here?
She came with me.
She's with me.
I carried a watermelon.
I carried a watermelon?
Bend your knees. Down.
Watch. Watch my eyes.
Good.
That's better.
Good. Now roll this way.
Now watch.
Look.
Love man!
Ladies, join our hair-raising
wig show.
Try your Sandra Dee,
Jackie Kennedy...
or Elizabeth Taylor-Cleopatra wig.
- I'll knock with three.
- Look at that cute fella.
Look at these hands.
They're golden hands.
My God, it's Cleopatra!
I feel like such an ""asp"".
You look ten years younger.
At 10:.15, by the pool,
we have calisthenics.
Then on the west porch, we have
a symposium by Rabbi Maurice Sherman...
on the psychology
of insult comedians.
So I say, ""Ask not what your waiter
can do for you...
but what you can do
for your waiter.""
If tips keep up, I'll have enough
for my Alfa Romeo.
That's my favorite car.
Ladies, you look very lovely.
Baby, would you cover for me tonight?
Tell Mom and Dad I went to lie down.
Where are you going?
To the golf course. There's
a pretty view from the first tee.
Good. Thanks.
So you were really a Rockette?
I think you're a wonderful dancer.
Yeah? Well, my mother kicked me out
when I was 16.
I've been dancing ever since. It's the
only thing I ever wanted to do anyway.
I envy you.
- Aren't you dancing, Doc?
- We're waiting for a waltz.
Hi, Max. Aren't my dance lessons
starting to pay off?
You look great, Vivian!
Terrific!
That's Vivian Pressman,
one of the bungalow bunnies.
That's what we call the women
who stay here all week.
The husbands only come up
on weekends.
Moe Pressman's a big card player.
He'll join our game.
- Moe coming up on Friday?
- Friday.
He's away a lot. I know.
It's a hardship.
Where's Penny?
Everybody's been asking for her.
What do you mean, where's Penny?
She's taking a break.
As long as it's not
an all-night break.
Come on, doll. Let's take a walk.
I love to watch your hair
blowing in the breeze.
Maybe my parents
are looking for me.
Baby, don't worry.
If they think you're with me, they'll be
the happiest parents at Kellerman's.
I have to say it.
- I'm known as the catch of the county.
- I'm sure you are.
Last week I took a girl away
from Jamie, the lifeguard.
And he said to her,
""What does he have that I don't have?""
And she said, ""Two hotels.""
Robbie.
I don't hear an apology.
Go back to Mommy and Daddy and listen.
Maybe you'll hear one in your dreams.
I'm sorry you had
to see that, Baby.
Sometimes in this world...
you see things
you don't wanna see.
You hungry?
Come on.
So, Baby, what do you want?
You can have anything you want.
A brownie, some milk...
Ieftover rice pudding,
beets...
cabbage roll...
fruit salad, sweet gherkins?
Neil, look, I'm sorry.
I better go check on Lisa.
Yeah.
- Why's she here?
- In case Neil comes back.
Penny just doesn't think.
She wouldn't do anything
stupid, would she?
So, what's wrong?
What's the matter with her?
- She's knocked up, Baby.
- Billy!
- What's he gonna do about it?
- ""What's he gonna do about it?""
It's mine, right?
- Right away you think it's mine.
- But I thought...
It's okay. Johnny's here.
I'm never gonna let anything
happen to you.
We got to go.
Just hold on. Just hold on.
Good girl. Good girl.
What do you think you're doing?
You're in trouble, you talk to me.
I'll take care of it.
You should've come to me
in the first place.
Forget it, Johnny. I'm not taking
what's left of your salary.
- Penny, that's my business.
- Besides, it wouldn't be enough.
Oh, God, it's hopeless!
Don't say that.
There's gotta be a way
to work it out.
Baby? Is that your name?
You know what, Baby?
You don't know shit
about my problems.
I told her.
Jesus! She's gonna tell her management
boyfriend and then we'll all get fired.
Why not skywrite it? ""Penny got
knocked up by Robbie, the creep.""
- Look--
- No, Baby.
One of the counselors
knows a doctor, a real M.D....
just traveling through New Paltz
one day next week.
We can get an appointment,
but it costs $250.
But if it's Robbie, there's no problem.
I know he has the money.
- I'm sure if you tell him--
- He knows.
Go back to your playpen, Baby.
- Why should you tell me what's right?
- You can't just leave her.
I didn't blow a summer hauling bagels
just to bail out some chick...
who probably slept
with every guy here.
A little precision, please.
Some people count
and some people don't.
Read it.
I think you'll enjoy it. But return it.
I have notes in there.
You make me sick.
Stay away from me.
Stay away from my sister
or I'll have you fired.
What am I doing wrong?
You're lining it up
a little wrong, Marge.
If your mother ever leaves me,
it'll be for Arnold Palmer.
- Daddy, someone's in trouble.
- Besides your mother?
You're overcorrecting, Marge.
You always told me if someone
was in trouble, I should help.
Could you lend me $250?
Are you all right?
Are you in trouble?
No, it's not me.
Could you loan it to me?
That's a lot of money.
What's it for?
Baby, stand up straight.
I can't tell you.
It's hard for me to say that to you,
but I can't.
You always said you could
tell me anything.
I can't tell you this.
It's not illegal, is it?
No, Daddy.
That was a stupid thing to ask.
Forgive me.
I'll have it for you before dinner.
- Is everything all right?
- Fine.
Thanks, Daddy.
Here's the money.
- You mean Robbie?
- No. You were right about him?
- Then where'd you get it?
- You said you needed it.
- Is this kid for real?
- Takes a real saint to ask Daddy.
Thanks, Baby, but I can't use it.
What? What's the matter with you?
You should take the money.
I can only get her an appointment
for Thursday.
They do their act
at the Sheldrake Thursday.
If they cancel, they lose this
season's salary and next year's gig.
What's the Sheldrake?
It's another hotel
where they do their mambo act.
Can't someone else fill in?
No, ""Miss Fix-it.""
Somebody else can't.
Maria has to work all day.
She can't learn the routines.
And Janet has to fill in for Penny.
Everybody works here.
You wanna do it?
Take time out from ""Simon Says""?
It's not a bad idea.
It was a 5oke.
- She can move.
- It's the dumbest idea I ever heard of.
- I can't even do the merengue.
- See?
You're a strong partner.
You can lead anybody.
She can't even do the merengue.
She cannot do it.
- No!
- Oh, sorry. Sorry.
You don't step on the one.
You gotta start on the two.
Find the two. Understand?
-I never did any of these dances before.
-It's one, two, three, four.
When the music starts, you don't
dance until the two. Got it?
Relax, relax.
Breathe.
Frame.
Nope.
Again.
Ow.
Two, three, four.
Don't lean back. Lifting up.
Shoulders down.
Again. Concentrate. And...
Don't put your heel down.
- Don't put your heel down.
- I didn't--
Stay on the toe.
Just listen to me.
The steps aren't enough.
Feel the music.
It's not on the one.
It's not the mambo.
It's a feeling, a heartbeat.
Don't try so hard.
Close your eyes.
Two, three, four.
Breathe.
Head up.
Lock your frame. Lock it.
Look, spaghetti arm.
This is my dance space.
This is your dance space.
I don't go into yours. You don't
go into mine. You gotta hold the frame.
Again.
Frame.
Back. Easy.
And turn, turn. Down.
And lift. You'll learn that later.
And come on.
Down. Twist.
And the bow.
- Sorry. Sorry.
- You trying to kill me?
You gotta concentrate!
Is that your idea of fun?
As a matter of fact it is.
We do the show in two days, you won't
show me lifts, I'm not sure of turns.
I'm doing all this to save your ass,
but I'd rather drop you on it!
Let's leave.
Shit!
I locked the keys in the car!
You're getting wet, right?
- You're wild.
- What?
You're wild!
Now, the most important thing
to remember in lifts is balance.
Whoa! Whoa!
I got it now.
So where'd you learn
to be a dancer?
Well, this guy came into
this luncheonette one day and...
we were all sitting around
doing nothing.
And he said that Arthur Murray
was giving a test for instructors.
So, if you passed...
they teach you different dances, show
you how to break them down, teach them.
What?
Good.
Don't look down.
Look here. Good.
And...
Now, bend your knees
and go up. Go, go.
Good try. Now, you'll hurt me
if you don't trust me, all right?
Now, go, go. Go.
Good. Now, I'm gonna go up.
You know, the best place
to practice lifts is in the water.
Just bend your knees.
And... go.
Good.
Good. Good.
Now hold the position. Hold it.
Good. Don't break! Don't break!
Let's do it again.
All right. One, two, three.
Oh, sorry.
Good. Keep-- No, don't.
It's not too bad.
- One more time.
- Okay. Over my head. Go.
I can't believe it's tonight.
Sheldrake's 20 minutes away.
We'll change in the car.
Mrs. Schumacher.
Hey, wait, we'll help you.
Such junk. Such junk.
Benny Bernstein's Dancing School,
that's where I went.
George Burns was a teacher.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
I'll just keep my shoulders down,
my head up...
my frame locked,
stay on my toes...
What if I forget the steps?
Pull up, watch the frame.
And remember, let him lead you.
I'm afraid I'm gonna forget to spike,
get dizzy and fall on my face.
No. Don't look at my feet,
keep my head up, my eyes open...
tension in my arms, my frame locked,
seat pulled up...
Thanks, Baby.
I just want you to know
that I don't sleep around...
whatever Robbie might have told you.
And I thought that he loved me.
I thought it was something special.
Anyway, I just wanted you
to know that.
So, how does it look?
I'm scared.
I'm so scared, Baby.
Don't worry.
You'll be fine.
Bingo! Bingo! Bingo! That's right.
It's Thursday night at Kellerman's.
That's bingo night.
- Hey, how about a dance later?
- Could be. Who knows?
- Lisa, you have to do something for me.
- I don't have to.
Just tell Mom and Dad I have a headache
and I'm in bed, okay?
Bye.
The Sheldrake Hotel is proud to present
Johnny Castle and partner...
in ""Mambo Magic.""
Relax.
Now spot a lead.
Wrong way!
Over here.
Ready for the lift?
Come on.
Keep going. Keep going.
...because wherever you are now,
I want you to look at the sky.
Look at those stars.
What a show. Here are The Drifters.
You did good. You worked hard.
I saw that old couple from Kellerman's
and I thought that was it.
Me too. Me too.
You know, by the second turn
you really had it.
- But I didn't do the lift.
- You did real good.
Thanks.
Johnny!
Come on. It's Penny.
- She wouldn't go until you returned.
- Did you call an ambulance?
She said the hospital would call
the police. She made me promise.
He didn't use no ether, nothing.
- I thought you said he was a real M.D.?
- He had a dirty knife and a table.
I could hear her screaming
in the hallway.
I swear to God,
I tried to get in.
It's all right. Johnny's here.
What? What is it, Baby?
- Is it Lisa?
- No.
Excuse me. Excuse me!
Everybody clear out, please.
Yes, I know that hurts.
We're gonna take care of that.
- Who's responsible for this girl?
- I am.
Please, is she--
Doc, thanks a lot.
I don't know how to thank you.
- Was that what my money paid for?
- I'm sorry. I never meant to lie.
You're not the person I thought
you were. I'm not sure who you are.
I don't want you to have anything
to do with those people.
Nothing! You're to have nothing
to do with them ever again!
I won't tell your mother about this.
Right now I'm going to bed.
And take that stuff off your face
before your mother sees you!
Is everything all right, Jake?
It's all right, Marjorie.
Go back to sleep.
Can I come in?
I got a-- I guess it's not a great room.
You probably got a great room.
No. It's a great room!
Leave it on.
I'm sorry about the way
my father treated you.
No. Your father was great.
He was great.
The way he took care of Penny.
I mean the way he was with you.
It's really me it has to do with.
Johnny, I came here
because my father--
No. The way he saved her--
I could never do anything like that.
That was something. People treat me
like I'm nothing because I am nothing.
That's not true!
You're everything!
You don't understand the way it is
for somebody like me.
Last month I'm eating candy
to stay alive.
This month, women are stuffing
diamonds in my pockets.
I'm balancing on shit
and I can be down there again.
No, it's not the way it is!
It doesn't have to be that way!
I've never known anyone like you.
You think you can make the world better.
Somebody's lost, you find them.
Somebody's bleeding--
I go get my daddy.
That's really brave, like you said.
That took a lot of guts
to go to him!
You are not scared of anything.
I'm scared of everything!
I'm scared of what I saw.
I'm scared of what I did,
who I am.
I'm scared of walking out of here and
never feeling for the rest of my life...
the way I feel
when I'm with you!
Dance with me.
What, here?
Here.
Singers, dancers, actors,
this is your lucky day!
Auditions for the annual Kellerman
end-of-the-season talent show...
beginning in the playhouse.
- Everyone gonna be in the show?
- We're leaving tomorrow.
Miss the weekend traffic.
But we're paid up 'til Sunday.
- And miss the show?
- I said we're leaving tomorrow.
- I was going to sing in the show.
- It's the big event.
People bring their own arrangements.
You don't want to miss it.
Baby, I need you for props.
Why would you want to leave early?
It was just an idea.
We can stay if you want to.
- So, what were you planning to sing?
- ""l Feel Pretty.""
Or ""What Do the Simple Folk Do?""
Or ""l Feel Pretty.""
What do you think, Daddy?
You look much better.
You just missed your father.
He's such a wonderful man.
I'm sorry. I didn't realize--
You couldn't have. It's okay.
- So, how you doin'?
- I'm okay.
Dr. Houseman says
I'm going to be fine.
- I can still have children.
- Oh, Penny, that's really great.
So, how did it go last night?
Good.
Fine. I didn't do the lifts,
but it was good.
Well, I guess I gonna go.
See ya.
- So, he says you're going to be fine?
- What are you doing?
- I'll tell Max your grandmother died.
- How many times have you told me...
never get mixed-up with them?
I know what I'm doing.
You listen to me.
You've got to stop it now.
Look, I gotta run.
I got a lesson with the Kramers.
They'll kill each other
if I'm not there.
Well, sure. You've gotta go.
I'll see ya.
It's rainy day game time.
Pin the tail on the guest.
Win ten boxes of Kleenex
or a billy goat!
God, I am so sick of this rain.
Remind me not to take my honeymoon
at Niagara Falls.
So, you go to Acapulco.
It'll be fine.
Where is my beige
iridescent lipstick?
I know I put it in this drawer.
Baby, where are you going
in this weather?
Uh, they're having charades
in the west lobby.
Quite the little joiner,
aren't we?
- Have you had many women?
- What?
Baby, come on.
Tell me. I want to know.
You gotta understand
what it's like.
You come from the streets
and suddenly you're up here.
Women are throwing themselves
at you and they smell so good.
They really take care
of themselves.
I never knew women
could be like that.
They're so goddamn rich you think
they must know about everything.
They're slippin' their room keys
in my hand two and three times a day--
different women--
so, I think I'm scorin' big, right?
You think, ""They wouldn't be doing this
if they didn't care about me, right?""
That's all right. I understand.
You were just using them, that's all.
No, that's not it.
That's the thing.
It wasn't like that.
They were using me.
What's your real name, Baby?
Frances, for the first woman
in the Cabinet.
Frances.
That's a real grownup name.
I've decided to go
all the way with Robbie.
No, not with someone like him.
Do you think if we came back for a
ten-year anniversary, it would be free?
It's just wrong this way.
It should be with someone--
With someone that
you sort of love.
Come on.
You don't care about me.
You wouldn't care if I humped
the entire army...
as long as we were on the right side
of the Ho Chi Minh Trail.
What you care about is that
you're not Daddy's girl anymore.
He listens when I talk now.
You hate that.
Two, three, cha-cha-cha.
My frame.
Where's my pleasing arc?
Spaghetti arms! Would you
give me some tension, please?
You're invading my dance space.
This is my dance space.
That's yours. Let's cha-cha.
Don't look down.
Look right here.
- How you call your lover boy?
- Come here, lover boy.
- And if he doesn't answer?
- Oh, lover boy.
- And if still doesn't answer?
- I simply say...
Baby
O-Oh, baby
My sweet baby
You're the one
Takin' dance lessons?
I could teach ya, kid.
My grandfather put me in charge
of the final show.
I want to talk to you
about the last dance.
I'd like to shake things up a bit.
You know, move with the times.
I've got a lot of ideas.
I've been working
with the staff kids...
on a cross between a Cuban rhythm
and soul dancing.
Whoa, boy.
Way over your head here.
You always do the mambo, huh?
Why not dance this year's
final dance...
to the pachenga?
Right.
Well, you're free to do the same,
tired number as last year if you want...
but next year we'll find
another dance person...
- who'll only be too happy--
- Sure, Neil. No problem.
We'll end the season
with the pachenga.
Great idea.
Sometimes he's hard to talk to,
but the ladies seem to like him.
See that he gives you the full half-hour
you're paying him for, kid.
That little wimp. He wouldn't know a
new idea if it hit him in the pachenga.
I could have told him
some new ideas.
Why did you let him
talk to you that way?
- What, fight the boss man?
- You tell him your ideas.
- He's a person like everyone else.
- Look, I know these people.
They are rich and they're mean.
They won't listen to me.
Why not fight harder?
Make them listen.
Because I need this goddamned job
lined up for next summer.
My dad calls me today.
""Good news,"" he says. ""Uncle Paul
can finally get you in the union.""
What union?
The House Painters and Plasterers
Local Number 179 at your service.
I've been thinking a lot
about the Domino Theory.
Now, when Viet Nam falls,
is China Next?
I don't think they saw us.
Fight harder, huh?
I don't see you fightin' so hard,
tellin' Daddy I'm your guy.
I will. With my father,
it's complicated.
- I will tell him.
- I don't believe you, Baby.
I don't think...
that you ever had
any intention of telling him.
Ever.
Well, Cousin, it's almost over.
Labor Day weekend is here.
Soon it's back to the old books and
back to work. What a terrible thought!
Have you seen Johnny?
I'm sorry.
Looks like I picked
the wrong sister.
That's okay, Baby.
I went slummin' too.
Hit me.
Get out of here.
You're not worth it.
Win big, Moe.
As always.
This is our last night together, lover.
I've got something worked out for us.
Excuse me, sir.
The pirate number's next.
Oh, thanks.
Hey, kid.
I've been playing cards all weekend
and I've got an all-night game tonight.
Why don't you give my wife
some extra dance lessons?
I'm sorry, Mr. Pressman...
but I'm booked up for
the whole weekend with the show.
I won't have time
for anything else.
I don't think it'd be fair
to take the money.
I've decided tonight's the night
with Robbie.
He doesn't even know yet.
It's me.
Holy shit!
You wanna hear somethin' crazy?
Last night l--
I dreamt we were walking along
and we met your father.
He said, ""Come on,""
and he put his arm around me.
Just like he did with Robbie.
You know how you feel when you see a
patient and you think he's all right...
then you look at the X rays
and it's nothing like you thought?
What happened?
It's exactly what it's like when you
find out one of your staff's a thief.
Moe Pressman's wallet was stolen
when he was playing pinochle last night.
It was in his jacket hanging
on the back of his chair.
He had it at 1:30 and when he
checked again at quarter of 4::00...
it was missing.
Vivian thinks she remembers
this dance kid Johnny...
walking by.
So we ask him,
""You have an alibi for last night?""
He says he was alone
in his room reading.
There are no books
in Johnny's room!
There's been a mistake.
I know Johnny didn't do it.
There's been similar thefts at the
Sheldrake. It's happened here before.
- Three other wallets.
- I know he didn't do it.
Stay out of it, Baby.
Wait. Don't put those
tables together. Come on.
Daddy, I need your help.
I know Johnny didn't take Moe's wallet.
- Oh? How do you know?
- I can't tell you.
- Just please trust me, Daddy.
- I'm sorry, Baby. I can't.
This Danish is pure protein.
Maybe Johnny didn't do it.
Anyone could've taken it.
Maybe it was, uh--
It could've been that little,
old couple, the Schumachers.
- I saw her with a couple of wallets.
- Sylvia and Sidney?
Baby, you don't go around
accusing innocent people.
I even saw them at the Sheldrake. You
said something was stolen from there.
I got an eyewitness
and the kid has no alibi.
Come on, Neil. You'll learn
what it's like to fire an employee.
Wait a minute. I know Johnny
didn't take the wallet.
I know because he was
in his room all night.
And the reason I know
is because I was with him.
I told you I was
telling the truth.
I'm sorry I lied to you.
But you lied too.
You told me everyone was alike
and deserved a fair break.
But you meant everyone
who is like you.
You told me you wanted me to change
the world, to make it better.
But you meant by becoming
a lawyer or an economist...
and marrying someone
from Harvard.
I'm not proud of myself.
But I'm in this family too. You can't
keep giving me the silent treatment.
There are a lot of things about me
that aren't what you thought.
But if you love me, you have to love
all the things about me.
And I love you.
I'm sorry I let you down.
I'm so sorry, Daddy.
But you let me down too.
I have been lookin'
for you all over.
They found the Schumachers.
Fingerprinted their water glasses.
Found out they were wanted
in Arizona and in Florida...
and they made a fortune
here this summer.
So then it's all right.
I knew it would work out.
- I knew they'd have to apologize.
- I'm out, Baby.
They fired you anyway
because of me.
And if I leave quietly,
I'll get my summer bonus.
So I did it for nothing.
I hurt my family, you lost your job
anyway-- I did it for nothing!
No, not for nothing.
Nobody has ever done anything
like that for me before.
You were right. You can't win
no matter what you do.
Listen to me. I don't want
to hear that from you. You can.
I used to think so.
Dr. Houseman, can l, uh--
Look, I'm going anyway and I know
what you must be thinking.
You don't know
anything at all about me.
I know you want Baby
to be like you.
The kind of person
people look up to.
Baby is like that.
If you could just see--
Don't you tell me what to see.
I see someone in front of me
who got his partner in trouble...
and sent her off
to some butcher...
while he moved on to an innocent,
young girl like my daughter.
Yeah, I guess that's
what you would see.
I can't imagine being here
without you even one day.
Just think, you have more time
for horseshoes and croquet.
Maybe they'll saw you
in seven pieces now.
I guess we surprised everybody.
I guess we did.
Hardly would be sorry.
Neither will l.
I'll see ya.
I'll do your hair.
It could look pretty if--
You're prettier your way.
This way.
Kellermans, we come together
Singing all as one
We have shared another season's
Talent, play and fun
Summer days will soon be over
Soon the autumn starts
And tonight the memories whisper
Softly in our hearts
Join hands and hearts and voices
Voices, hearts and hands
At Kellerman's
the friendships last
Long as the mountain stands
Daytime, nighttime, any hour
Weather rain or shine
Games and lectures
Jokes and music
Happily combine
Good luck in medical school, son.
And I wanted to thank you for your
help with the Penny situation.
- I guess we've all gotten into messes.
- What?
I thought Baby told you.
Look, I'm not sure.
Penny said so, but you know with girls
like that. They're liable to pin it...
on any guy around.
- What's the hot tip for the day?
- Finished.
You and me, Tito.
We've seen it all, eh?
Bubbah and Zeda serving the first
pasteurized milk to the boarders.
Through the war years
when we didn't have any meat.
Through the Depression
when we didn't have anything.
Lots of changes, though, Max.
It's not the changes
so much this time.
It's that it all seems
to be ending.
You think kids want to come with their
parents and take fox-trot lessons?
Trips to Europe,
that's what the kids want.
Twenty-two countries
in three days.
It feels like
it's all slipping away.
But the heartbeats of vacation
There no cares are seen
So let's join in
just one last chorus
Visitors, staff and guests
What we've shared
won't be forgotten
Old friends are the best
Nobody puts Baby in the corner.
Come on.
Sorry about
the disruption, folks...
but I always do
the last dance of the season.
This year somebody told me not to.
So I'm gonna do my kind of dancin'
with a great partner...
who's not only
a terrific dancer...
but somebody who's taught me
that there are people...
willing to stand up for other people
no matter what it costs them.
Somebody who's taught me...
about the kind of person
I want to be.
Miss Frances Houseman.
Sit down, Jake.
I think she gets this from me.
Do you have sheet music
on this stuff?
I know you weren't the one
who got Penny in trouble.
When I'm wrong, I say I'm wrong.
You looked wonderful out there.
Now l
Had the time of my life
No, I never felt
this way before
Yes, I swear
It's so true
And I owe it all to you