In 1933 "Aliat HaNo'ar" was
established to save children
from the danger of extermination
at the hands of the Nazis.
During and after the war its
representatives continued to gather
children from their hiding places
and brought the survivors to Israel
where they built their homes.
Scores of youth villages were
set up for this purpose and they
absorbed 300 thousand
children and adolescents.
The movie "Under The Domim Tree"
is dedicated to this
marvelous organization.
Gila Almagor, Yakov Agmon
& Eitan Evan Present:
UNDER THE DOMIM TREE
Based on the book by
Gila Almagor
Kaipo Cohen as Aviya
Julian Mer
Riki Blich - Orli Perl
Aya Stiftel - Ohad Knoller
Jenya Katsen
Guest appearances:
Gila Almagor, Alex Peleg,
Ohad Shachar
Written by Gila Almagor and
Eyal Sher
Additional writing
Eli Cohen
Make-up
France Hyman
Costume designer
Rona Doron
Casting
Gila Almagor
Production designer
Eytan Levi
Music: Beni Nagari
performed by:
Raanana Symphonette Orchestra
Sound
Israel David
Editor
Dani Shik
Directer of photography
David Gurfinkel
Produced by
Gila Almagor & Eitan Evan
Directed by
Eli Cohen
Oudim State Boarding School
Winter, 1953
Misha?
Misha Alboim?
Over here!
They've found him.
We should have
taken care of him.
"There" we always took care of him.
Now the two of us are all alone.
Two of us are not all alone.
We should've gone with him.
Don't even think that way.
We couldn't have done anything.
Nothing at all.
Summer, 1953
My dear Aviya,
I'm going to Germany.
To see about our reparations.
Maybe things will finally work
out for us with this money.
I went to see your mother.
She's still
in the psychiatric ward.
It seems that she'll be there
for a long time.
Enclosed are two photographs
of your father.
I have a better
one somewhere.
If I find it,
I'll send it to you.
Take care.
Aunt Alice
Oudim
Money can't pay back
the murder of millions.
It's not about the Holocaust
I'm talking about my family..
Calm down.
- Isn't it enough that they
killed your parents?
Shut up!
It's not about the money.
It's a matter of principle.
Money for blood.
No reparations.
And that's final.
But it's money, Yurek.
Money.
I deserve that money.
It won't bring your Parents
back to life. -No.
But at least I'd have
something for my future.
We're not talking about you.
We're talking about our country.
Quite please.
Where are your manners?
You're in the dining hall.
I'm sorry, Rachel. They've
been arguing since yesterday.
There's no argument.
We all agree, except Sara B.
Zevik, I can hear you even when
you don't shout. Sit down.
But I'm the monitor.
The committee has to discuss
this before the children...
Rachel, they are old enough...
- Later
I want to introduce to you
a new girl who's joining us.
This is Miriam Segal.
- Mira.
Excuse me?
- Mira. My name is Mira.
This is Mira. I'm sure
you'll help her fit in,
and make her feel
at home.
Good luck, Mira. -I'm Ariel.
Let me introduce you?
Ayala, Aviya, Daniel.
She'll be in your room.
Pass me a knife. -Tell her
she can take off the hat.
Zevik, the tea's not hot.
- That's what there is.
Don't I eat get any fish?
Vegetarian table.
- I don't eat grass.
look what she's eating.
Miss Sarah B is on a diet.
She's not like the other
fat girls in the group!
No, Miss Sarrah B is special,
she's from Warsaw.
Stop Shouting.
You're making me death.
You look like your
from the ghetto.
Yurek's little servant.
Did you hear that, Yurek?
I'm from the ghetto.
Always on Yurek's back.
- leave him alone Sarah.
The bed unfolds like this.
In the morning, you fold it
back under the other bed.
Every morning. Why can't it
stay out like the rest?
I'm not a sucker.
- Who said you were?
Every year we draw lots
for the shelves and the beds.
Who was here before me?
Dita. Her mother married
an American millionaire
and took her to America.
- Yeah, sure.
This is your shelf.
Put your things here.
Where's your suitcase?
- This is the all I have.
When your shoes are dirty,
you leave them outside.
What a figure Sarah.
Congratulations.
It's "Bez" in Poland now.
- No, it's not.
What month is this?
No, in Polish.
June. "Czerwiec".
- Yes, "Bez" in June.
The leaves are
already dropping,
and when you walk on them
they make a sound like:
crik, crik, crik.
No, it sounds like:
Chak, chak, chak.
Leaves fall, girls.
They fall.
And you step
on them.
Fall. Drop.
What's the difference?
"Bez" is in October,
In the autumn.
And the snow is up to here.
And when you walk on it,
there's no sound at all.
I have soap in my eyes.
Isn't there a laundry
in this institution?
There is, but we wash
our underwear ourselves.
It's personal.
It's your own.
I don't care about the
Poles or the Fascists.
Yurek, why do you get so
angry when we talk about it?
Say your sorry or
I'll kill you. -Kiss my ass.
Stop it.
Yurek, what about?
- They're going crazy again.
Yurek.
- Run, run.
What are you staring at?
Get inside.
Why are you all standing
there like that? It's late.
Tell them to stop?
Don't you dare open it?
Nobody raises their voice
or their hand to me.
Go stop them now.
- They'll stop by themselves.
I've been telling you for months
that they must be separated.
If you don't do it, I will.
- Not now.
You don't learn from your
mistakes. Need I remind you?
of Misha? -Are you saying
Misha was my fault?
I'm not saying that?
But you don't want it
to happen again, do you?
Everyone here thinks
he's an expert.
It's the first time they're
like that since Misha drowned.
I thought they were cured.
Will they be like animals
all their lives?
If you want to talk, go outside.
I want to sleep.
Look at them now.
Acting as if they're normal.
Shut up? Pain in the neck.
- I knew mental cases like them.
Shut up.
- Hey, what's going on here?
It's because of yesterday's
discussion.
Things I want to forget
keep creeping into my head.
You're not the only one, chavy.
I think... -You think?
I think...
We have the right and the
obligation to talk about it.
What do you say, girls?
I wasn't "there".
I have no right to judge.
I think we should take
as much money as we can.
Shut up. You're both sabras.
(Native born Israeli)
Don't yell like that.
I say we should take
as much as we can.
I need the money
for my future.
All you think about
is money.
No blood money.
End of discussion.
In the end, everyone will
take the money.
Do you want to bet?
I'm ready to bet with anyone.
Sarah, what do you mean by
"my" money, "my" future?
We all have the same future.
Building the Kibbutz together.
Do you think I want to spend
my life in this group?
I've had enough
all these years.
I want to wake up alone.
Go to sleep alone.
Without 4 other girls.
I've had enough of all
this "togetherness".
I want to go study.
Succeed. Alone.
Did you hear that Yurek?
I've decided to break up
with Sarah B.
Then I'll break up with Ayala.
- But she's not your girlfriend.
If she were,
I'd break up with her.
What do you think of Ayala?
For me or for you?
What do you say?
For you, for you.
Woman give me a headache.
I give up.
Are your hands clean?
This is for you.
Very funny.
He's mad because
I tell him what I think.
You can't take it when
someone disagrees with you.
It's tough for you to digest.
- Digest. What Hebrew?
We should all learn from Sarah B.
- I digest, you digest.
Laugh. Even my Hebrew's
better than yours.
Right Yurek?
Aviya, come here for a minute.
Who me?
- He's talking to you, isn't he?
What's your answer?
- To what? -My letter.
What letter?
- The one I just gave you.
You gave me a ball of paper.
- Did you throw it away?
Read it.
So?
- What?
What did you want?
I liked what
you said today:
"I wasn't there.
I have no right to judge".
Is that why you called me?
- No.
I like how you speak.
Short. Staccato.
What?
- Staccato, "ta, ta, ta, ta."
Is that good or bad?
- Typical Sabra.
What?
Well.
- Wait a minute.
What, do Sabras shake hands?
Here comes Vim.
- Hi Vim.
Oudim Family,
let's welcome our friends
returning from Holland,
led by our dear
Vim Van Fliman.
To them, he's a hero
of the Dutch underground.
To us, he's a simple gardener
and leader of our Dutch group.
O.K. One moment, please.
This is really wonderful.
I. O.K. Now I'll speak
in Dutch,
because I can't find
the words in Hebrew.
I was visiting her majesty
Queen Juliana,
with my Jewish children
that I hid during the war.
Enough. I'm O.K. now.
I have a surprise.
The sack, please.
This sack has gifts from
my friends in the Resistance,
for all the school.
But I need "volunteers".
Who wants?
- Me! Me! Me!
For Vim's
a jolly good fellow.
Yes. That will do.
What happened?
- It's your fault.
"Unfold the bed,
fold the bed".
Everything's falling apart
and it's not my fault.
You're wasting your time.
It'll just break again.
How long has this
envelope been here?
You know that you're in charge
of the mail this week?
Why are you making such
a big deal?
Since you arrived, there's
been nothing but problems.
Go cry under your stupid tree.
For me, you don't exist.
And if you call me a bitch again,
I'll smack you both.
You understand Polish?
- "You understand Polish?"
Vim?
- Yes.
Why did you take the tractor?
We're planting.
- Are you crazy?
Planting Tulips in the summer.
It's too hot.
We're planting Tulips
to the north.
You're wasting your time.
Poor children.
There's not even a
drop of water here.
I read in book.
Once, many Tulips
in Israel.
Soon, this place
very beautiful.
What's this?
"Nabatean Farming".
The Nabateans lived here
over 2,000 years ago.
The Nabateans
know the secrets.
Soon, will be miracle here.
What are you doing with
the stones? You're nuts.
The Nabateans...
We shape the stone
to catch water.
And who told you, you could
take the tractor?
It's O.K.
- No. It's not O.K. at all.
I'll talk to Rachel
about this.
"Home sweet home we go".
Can I come with you?
- Not this time Yurek.
We have a wonderful house
with a tile roof.
You stick your head
out the window and plums
fall into your mouth.
I'm not sure you'll get along
very well with my mother.
You can gossip in Polish?
I forgot that horrible
language.
This time I have to go alone.
I'll take the photo out
like this?
What?
What is it?
- Untie it.
Your hair. Untie it.
Tie it up.
You mean braid it?
You "braid" hair.
Are you sure
you don't want to come?
My Dad would be happy.
- And his wife?
I'm going to see him,
not her.
I like it here when
everyone's gone.
At last, I get some privacy.
What, do Sabras
shake hands?
Last one to the gate,
washes the floor.
Is he coming?
He said he would come today?
Mama,
I brought you flowers.
I grew them myself.
- Henya, you have a visitor.
Don't talk to her like that,
she's not a little girl.
Do you want to go out
for some fresh air?
You're not dressed warmly
enough. You'll catch a cold.
I'm O.K.
It's very warm today.
Yes, warm.
Who gave you that photo?
- Aunt Alice.
She sent it to me
before she left.
She went to Germany?
To get our money
from the Germans.
There's no reason to go there.
They're all dead. I saw.
They're all dead,
in the woods of Narosdj.
Is this my father? -My father,
my brother, my husband,
they're all dead. I saw.
- Mama, you weren't there.
You came to Israel
before the war.
Don't tell me where I was.
You fool. You know nothing.
Isn't this from "there?"
- What is that?
Is the doctor blind?
Shut the windows, I don't
want the neighbors to hear.
They don't need to know
what's going on in my house.
Tell me about him, mama.
I have to know.
It says here "Kaybeach".
Who's "Kaybeach?"
From Haifa.
- I want the nurse.
I'll call her in a minute.
You have to tell me. Please?
I need to know.
Who's Kaybeach?
Tell me something, Mama.
I have to know.
We're alone again, Yurek.
Just the two of us.
That's not enough for you.
You want to be all alone.
"Alone" means you and me.
What do you see in her?
Is it her braid?
I can make one too.
You mean "braid" one, Sarah.
You braid hair.
Stop, Sarah.
It's over between us.
What we had
can never be over.
It's forever.
Then promise me
we'll stay friends?
No matter what.
Always.
Did you hear?
They found Yola's father.
He's alive in Poland.
- What? -Yes.
Avi, why are you
back so soon?
Didn't you go visit
your mother?
Did you hear?
- Yes. -It's unbelievable.
They called me into
the office.
I saw Rutka, the nurse,
sitting with Rachel and Ariel.
Then, Rachel hugged me and said:
Yola, it's a miracle.
You are not an orphan anymore.
They found your father.
He's alive in Warsaw,
in Poland.
We've heard that story,
it's getting boring.
You should be ashamed.
My father's alive.
Can you believe it?
He's alive.
It's amazing.
My father is alive.
He had these big "Lappas".
- What?
Lappas.
Big hands.
That used to wrap up
my little hands.
Soon, Yola. Soon you'll
be holding his "Lappas".
I'd give anything to see
my father just once.
Do you remember him?
He died before I was born.
Maybe it's better that way.
To be an orphan from the start.
Sometimes, memories can kill.
So, how's Yola?
- So how's Sarah B.
You didn't go see
your mother, did you?
Leave me alone. I have enough
problems. -What do you mean?
You and Sarah B.
I saw you together, as if...
As if what?
It's over between
me and Sarah.
It's final.
I missed you.
Yurek. Avi.
Wait a minute?
Can I come with you?
It was just by chance, right?
What happened to Yola,
It couldn't happen to
someone else, could it?
Am I right?
It's a miracle.
What's this?
- To Yola.
It's for me.
- Yola, when you're in Poland,
try to find this man for me.
- Janek Tilas.
- He's my father.
- Thank you and come
back soon. Menachem Tilas.
"Mailbox For Letters To Poland"
Where's Yola? She received
a package from Poland.
A package arrived?
What a tiny dress. Doesn't he
know how old you are?
He probably remembers you
when you were little.
No. This dress
isn't for me.
When I was small,
I had a doll this size.
It's for my doll.
I'm sure he just wanted
to make me laugh.
O.K. girls, let's get Yola
ready for her trip to Poland.
We'll embroider her shirt.
- No, two.
One for the trip and one
to celebrate the Sabbath.
Shoulders, 87.
Boobs.
79. You got bigger.
Waist.
Tushie.
A package arrived from Poland?
- Not now. Later.
Try this on.
- It's so beautiful.
Try it on.
- I can't.
My aunt says that
it's forbidden.
You only buy new things
for a baby after he's born.
Let's see how you'll look
when you meet him.
Let's pretend you just
got off the plane.
Wearing Israeli clothes
in Poland. Can you imagine?
In Warsaw, with the
clothes we made.
Yola.
Only 60 more hours.
Lod - Zurich,
Zurich - Paris,
Paris - Vienna,
Paris - Vienna, yes.
Vienna - Warsaw.
- Vienna - Warsaw.
Miss Yola Mintz.
Not Yola, Yolanda,
Yolanda Mintz.
If he hears Yola,
he won't know it's me.
People only call me
Yola here.
Miss Yolanda Mintz.
Wait. I forgot.
How do you say:
"How are you?"
And "Where have you been
all these years?"
Right.
And
"I love you Papa?"
Come on, let's pack.
First the winter clothes.
We'll put that in last.
And last but not least,
Rutka's coat.
Wait, we forgot something.
Bon voyage, Lalka.
Not so much water.
Just a little.
Vim, are you sure
it'll work?
Look.
A plant needs three things:
For the body
for the heart,
and for the head.
Water,
for the body.
Love for the heart.
And the Nabateans
for the head.
But, it's a secret.
Yola, Rutka wants
to see you.
Don't dance with anyone else.
I'll be back.
Whoever is not
in this group,
please leave now.
Your counselors
are waiting for you.
My dear children.
I have no words
of comfort.
We all shared
in Yola's joy,
and now we share
her grief.
I know that it's difficult.
- Where's Yola now?
In her room.
She's been taken care of.
I have a lot of letters
for Poland.
What shall I do with them?
I'll take care of it, Yola.
- No, I will.
We must end this.
Come with me, Yola.
Wash her face.
Lie her down in her room.
And close the shutters.
Yola, go rest.
It's heavy.
Damn. I can't stop myself
from crying.
I'm O.K. now.
Yola wants to return
the clothes you gave her.
There's no hurry.
- It can wait.
Go rest, Rutka.
Yes Rutka. I'm O.K.
Here's your coat.
I just want to unpack
the suitcase.
Why is Chavy crying?
Is she sick?
Don't just stand there,
help her.
Look at what my aunt
sent me.
For my trip to Poland.
I didn't even try them on.
My aunt sent me
long underwear.
She's completely crazy.
She wants me to travel
like this?
I ask you. To Poland.
Do you travel to Poland
like this?
Dressed like this?
Do you travel to Poland
like this?
Miss Yolanda Mintz.
Do you travel to Poland
like this? Like this?
My father will run away
if he sees me like this.
What hysteria.
You would think.
She thought he was dead,
didn't she?
Well now she's sure.
- Shut up. You monster.
You're better off.
- Shut your mouth.
One day you might go
to Poland,
and you'll be able
to visit his grave.
Get out.
You filthy.
Stop.
Stop it immediately.
Wash your face.
Take your things
and go to your room.
Look at what those
animals did to me.
I could kill them
one by one.
What did I say that was
so terrible?
At least she knows for sure
that he's dead.
Think about it.
All those thoughts.
Alive. Dead.
Now she knows that he's dead,
and she can visit his grave.
Who else here has a grave
that they can visit?
The most important thing
is a grave with a headstone.
Do you hear me?
I'm talking to you.
Is there anyone up there?
I can hardly see.
I'm up here.
I'll be down in a minute.
"Kaybeach, Haifa"
Are you running away?
I'm not going anywhere,
and you didn't see me.
Cause if you leave,
I'm taking your bed.
Where are you going in Haifa?
Uptown or downtown?
I don't know.
I don't know the city.
I'm going to visit someone
that I don't know.
Stick with me. I know Haifa
like the back of my hand.
Do you know someone
named "Kaybeach?"
Kaybeach,
Kaybeach.
You can't live
with a name like that.
Kaybeach is the area
of cemeteries.
That's where I'm going.
Who are you looking for,
my dear?
Your brother?
Your father?
- My father.
Was he in this regiment?
He died before I was born.
This is the military cemetery.
The older graves
are over there.
"Max Alexandrovitch"
Papa.
I brought you this flower.
It's from Holland.
Vim gave it to me.
He's our gardener
at the boarding school.
I work with him.
Mama's very sick.
That's why I'm at the
boarding school.
Watch over her, Papa.
And watch over me too.
I need someone
to watch over me.
Yurek.
I did it. It's unbelievable.
I found him.
I found my father.
What's wrong?
Was Ariel looking for me?
This day is the most...
The most...
I think...
- Listen,
I have to do
what I think is right.
We have to take care of the
problem once and for all.
Don't worry. I won't let
them be separated.
We'll come visit you.
You'll come visit us.
Zevik, Hadassim Boarding School
is a great place.
It's a lot like our "Oudim".
Yurek.
Come on.
We'll come visit you
in a week or so.
Have a safe trip.
- Don't worry.
So long, Zevik.
Guys, gather around.
I owe you an explanation.
Zevik is on his way to Hadassim...
He's going to Hadassim...
Take the dogs away.
Naomi. Listen to me.
They're search dogs.
Calm down.
They're here for the search.
This is all your fault.
We'll find them.
Do they have family.
or friends? Anyone?
No. But they can live
like this for months.
Like this? Outside?
They lived 2 years
in a forest "there".
They were like animals
when they were found.
Not "Like animals".
They were animals.
Don't ask me.
I don't have any answers.
But all these years that
you've been together.
We don't talk about
what happened "there".
I didn't tell them anything
about me either.
What does anyone know
about anyone else.
Even best friends don't know
anything about each other.
But that can drive one crazy.
- So you go crazy.
But for how long?
Maybe for good.
Maybe for life.
Remember last winter
when we searched for Misha?
We passed right through here.
I'm not going back there.
You're wasting your time.
They'll come back.
What's your problem?
Do your feet hurt?
Why are you making
such a big deal?
If you were missing,
it wouldn't be such
a big deal at all.
Somebody should look down.
In the water.
Please eat.
We must continue searching.
It sticks in my throat.
I have a bad feeling.
You always think the worst.
Stop it.
I'm afraid to think
what could've happened.
What could've happened?
There they are.
I told you they'd be back.
Either we stay together
or we die.
You'll stay together,
of course.
You'll stay together.
Let them breathe.
Come see.
The stupid psychologist
is leaving.
Are you happy now?
Stop, Yoram.
Enough, Yoram. Yurek.
Stop, Yoram!
Yurek, turn of the water.
Stop the water.
Save it for the tulips.
Daniel.
Don't walk on Tulips.
What's going on now, Vim?
Why did you take
all the hoses?
Couldn't you have left
me even one?
Why are you making holes?
Are you crazy?
Look.
The water drips. Drip-drop.
- Drip-drop?
Drip, drip, drip.
Drip-drop.
And who'll pay
for new hoses?
Maybe your Nabateans?
My invention.
Congratulations, Vim.
This is an agricultural
revolution in Israel.
You should patent it.
- Maybe.
Hi, Yorem Klein.
- How do you like "Yoram"?
"Uri"?
- What's wrong with "Yurek"?
I want to change my name.
- Why is a name so important?
I don't understand.
- You can't understand.
Your life's another story.
- Do I even have a story?
I have a great life.
I'm on vacation here.
We shouldn't argue so much.
Maybe we should go out
and have some fun.
And what about Zevik?
- Zevik's my problem.
He's not your problem.
Zevik's your problem.
I'm your problem.
Everyone's your problem.
- Don't be so dramatic.
You have no problems.
You have a wonderful house,
you stick your head out
and plums fall into your mouth.
You know what?
Let's go have some fun?
Let's go visit my mother.
Aviya, where are you
taking me?
You said we were going
to visit your mother.
Mama?
This is Yurek.
Mama, can you hear me?
I found him.
His name was on the tombstone.
I'll take you there.
We'll go together.
Just get out of here,
and everything will be fine.
There's nothing left "there".
- Mama, you weren't there.
She wasn't there.
It's all in her head.
Speak to her in Polish.
Mama, he is from "there".
He speaks Polish.
Where do you live?
- Same place as Aviya.
How's your father? -My father?
I don't have one. -Your mother?
How's your mother?
- Mrs. Alexandrovitch?
What did she say?
She told me about the house,
where you stick
your head out the window,
and plums fall into your mouth.
Some people want to forget
where they've been,
and others want to remember
where they've never been.
How do you pronounce
the letter "R"?
Mine sounds so foreign.
"Yurrrek".
But I like your rolling "R".
I want to pronounce it
like you.
They say...
- Yurrrek's Aviya's Boyfrrriend.
No. "Ruthi runs
by the Ararat River".
No. RRRuthi rrruns.
Come see.
Rruthi rrruns.
You have visitors.
Don't tease me.
Nobody came.
Who's here?
Nobody.
Tell me! Who is it?
- Some people.
What do they look like?
- I don't know. People.
A man and a woman.
They're short.
Wait! What should I tell them?
She's crazy.
My mistake.
They went on a trip and
they'll be back late tonight.
We should've called first.
I have to go. Leave whatever
you brought for her here.
That's her shelf.
What do you mean?
We don't have anything.
Why do you care
so much about her?
Why don't you air out
her smelly sheets?
That's exactly
what I'm doing.
You're terrible, Ayala.
- She won't notice.
It looks better like that
than it usually does.
What's with you?
Why are you doing
this to her?
I owe it to her, OK?
Ayala! Stop it!
- Can I come in?
She hasn't returned yet?
It'll be morning soon.
We'll have to start
a new search.
No, she'll be back.
After Zevik and Yurek,
I just don't know anymore.
They always come back.
Except Misha.
- Misha.
Right, Misha.
Get it into your head.
It wasn't your fault.
I can't believe we're
waiting up for her.
I'm afraid something happened.
I'm awake.
Why are you all
awake so early?
We never went to sleep.
We were waiting up for you.
- Who made my bed?
Mira, are you OK?
Let us help you.
- Are you OK?
I'm taking off your
dirty socks, OK?
I brought you some food.
Eat.
It's good.
You must eat.
Those people.
They're horrible.
They found me in Naples.
In Italy.
We arrived there by ship
from Poland. -I told you.
I don't remember anything.
Except that I was in
an orphanage. -Which one?
It was called "Dom Jetzka".
- That means "Children's house"
They're all called that.
We were in
"Dom Jetzka Jerusalem"
One day, they brought
us to Israel.
The boat was filled
with children.
Girls?
- Come in, Ariel.
Mira, we were worried.
Are you O.K.? -She is fine.
Sit. She's telling everything.
Go on.
Those people
found me on the boat.
They said they we're
my parents.
They bought me a big doll.
We lived in Afula.
Everything seemed fine,
but I always knew
Something wasn't right.
Then she got sick,
and he lost his job.
And he started to...
my back is covered with
scars from his beatings.
I couldn't stand it anymore,
so, I ran away.
I never want to see them again.
I could kill them.
What's wrong with her?
What's going on?
Mira, what happened?
- Its them. Those people.
Miriam, wait.
Sir, the office is over there.
No need for police.
Miriam Segal is my daughter.
This is my wife,
Miriam's mother.
We want to see her.
She doesn't want to see them.
This is a scandal.
Let us see our daughter.
Please. Go to the office.
They'll help you.
What are you? Fascists?
Stealing peoples daughters.
She doesn't want to see you.
Please?
- He has a bad heart
because of the Germans.
We only want
to see our daughter!
Stop them.
- Please?
Is this how you
steal children?
You should be ashamed.
I'll see you in jail.
Miriam?
- Come home with us?
Please?
You just wait.
This is just the beginning.
Can the court decide
whether they're her parents?
We all dream that someday
someone will come.
A father, a mother, someone.
From "there". And she.
I don't remember anything,
but I know they're not my parents.
Then what do they want?
I bet it has something
to do with the reparations.
If she can't remember, maybe
they really are her parents.
Mira.
Calm down.
You have an excellent lawyer.
Everything will be fine.
You'll see.
Good luck.
- Good luck, Mira.
It'll be alright.
- Good luck.
Stop!
Tell Moussa to stop!
Mira?
- Stay there. I'm OK.
I must have eaten something.
Sit up front. OK, Moussa?
- No problem.
Get in, my child.
Sit.
Good morning.
Let's go.
Take the hat off, Mira.
But I like it.
You have nothing to hide.
You're so pretty.
You have lovely eyes.
"DISTRICT COURT
OF TEL AVIV"
I'm sorry, but you can't
come inside.
Good luck, Ofra.
We're counting on you.
Mira, remember what we said?
- Stay calm
and don't get upset.
- Let's go in.
All rise.
Approach the bench, please.
I suggest that you try
to find a way,
to avoid this hearing.
There's no room for compromise.
She must return to her parents.
- They're not my parents.
Your Honor, I'm sorry
for the Segal's
and the girl they lost
in the war.
But they can't just replace
her with another girl.
Before hearing the testimony,
I recommend that Mr. Segal
take a blood test.
What?
- Although the blood test...
No test!
No blood!
Don't you believe
Jews here?
They already
experimented on us.
Isn't that enough?
Wasn't Auschwitz enough?
- Me too. This is from Hitler.
All we want is our daughter.
Mira, daring.
Come with us.
How can you concentrate
on trigonometry now?
Yes. They had a daughter?
She was four or five years old.
Today she must be big.
Then you can identify the girl?
Mr. Rosenberg,
do you recognize the girl?
That's the girl.
It was years ago,
mistakes have been made.
Maybe.
So here and there
new families were created.
Nobody gets hurt.
But in this case,
I'm not mistaken.
But Mira's teacher testified
that she noticed signs of violence,
and suspected that Mira
has been beaten.
I knew that the family.
had survived the Holocaust.
That there was tension
in the home.
Fears and rage.
Maybe they did hit
the child from time to time.
Then they did beat her?
- Your Honor, this is irrelevant.
The issue is not whether
they're ideal parents,
but rather whether they're
her parents or not.
And I state that they are.
I want you to wear this.
It'll look very nice on you.
Tell her to wear it.
It's brand new.
I've never worn it.
Quiet please.
- I told the judge
that it was important
for you to be with Mira.
You're everything she has.
He's agreed to let you
sit inside,
but you must all
behave yourselves.
Ladies and gentlemen.
I've heard the testimony.
The time has come
for my ruling.
Mira, Mira.
Don't worry.
My child,
you claim that these
are not your parents.
Then who are your parents?
Try to remember.
Your mother?
Your father?
A sister?
A brother?
Nothing.
I don't remember anything.
Try to remember something,
someone?
Your Honor, the situation
is very clear.
The girl has no evidence
to refuse the claims
made by her parents.
She must go home with them.
for everyone's good.
These people claim that
they're your parents,
and that they love you.
If they're mistaken,
I need to know
how they are mistaken.
Make an effort.
This is very important.
Give me a sign?
Anything?
Otherwise, you'll have to
go home with them.
I think they were taller.
My mother was taller.
Am I tall or short?
When my children were little,
I seemed very big to them.
When you were little,
you looked at your mother
from down here.
Mira, you have two people
here who want your happiness.
After all you and
they have suffered,
why don't you just go with them?
- I'd rather die.
Mira, think for a moment.
Miss...
We must move on.
Blue... -I have no choice
but to rule that the girl...
I remember the color blue.
I can't hear you, my child. Speak up.
- I remember the color blue.
When I looked up at her, from here,
I saw blue.
She had blue eyes.
Very blue.
Not like mine.
They were blue.
She had dark eyelashes,
like butterflies...
I can see her face.
I see my mother's face.
Her teeth stuck out a bit,
like mine...
My brother had the same teeth.
My brother, Antek.
His name was Antek.
Antek Rozner.
My mother is Ella Rozner.
My father is Menachem Rozner.
My name is Miriam Rozner.
And we lived in
Lubartovska St. in Lublin.
My name is not Segal.
They're the Segal's.
I want to be who I really am.
I want my name back.
How could I have
forgotten them?
forgotten you, Mama?
And Papa?
And Antek?
How could I have
forgotten my mother?
Don't leave me. I wanted so
much to remember you,
and I couldn't.
Please don't leave me.
I wanted so to remember.
Mira Rozner!
"An old straw hat,
and a wrinkled shirt,
"Not fancy you must say, "But
we don't mind, for all day long,
"we laugh and sing away,
ha-ha!"
We're going there
the minute we arrive.
Where?
I can't wait.
Stop!
What is it, Vim?
Come and see.
Avi?
We can't go there now.
It's occupied.
The Domim tree is occupied.
UNDER THE DOMIM TREE
Translated by:
Jerry Hyman & Madeleine Ali
Subtitling:
Elrom Studios