Subtitles by DramaFever
[Love 'til the End of Summer]
[Final Episode]
You must rely on yourselves
to draw a perfect piece of art.
Sir, do you have any tips for this?
Follow your heart.
That's why...
You must find what
you believe to be most beautiful
and then use art to show everybody
the world you see through your eyes.
Sir, where does
your creative inspiration come from?
That stretch of camphor trees.
Xiao Si.
In the past, I always read about
the confines of prison.
After coming here, I've found
it's actually not that cramped.
The sky is vast.
I can still see the white clouds
floating freely by.
But, I just can't see you.
Do you know?
Whenever I think back on
those days when
- Let's go!
- we biked around Qianchuan...
the countless times we jumped over
the school fence to go out to play
the artistic drawings you had
strewn all over the art studio
the yawns I made when
you started jigsaw puzzles at home...
When I think of these...
I feel so sad.
Xiao Si, there is so much
I want to say to you
but I can no longer
find a chance to tell you.
Within these four walls
I often watch the sun set
in the evening by myself.
The inmates have their own community.
They exercise together and eat together.
However, I'm more used to being alone.
Oftentimes, I tell myself I'm not sad.
But when I see autumn drawing to an end
I still feel faint twinges in my heart.
Do you think there will be a day
when a miracle suddenly happens?
The clock has been turned back
or perhaps, we receive
a different fate from the start?
We would once again...
lie on the yard together.
Let the grass tickle our necks
and the scent of the green grass
lightly lure us to sleep.
Let the summer sun
shine on the eyelids
covering our bloodshot eyes.
Do you think there will be such a day?
[Shanghai Detention Center]
It's been three years, Zhi Ang.
We will finally see each other again.
Hello, CEO Wu?
I'm sorry. I have something
very important to do today.
How about another day?
All right, bye.
Xiao Si, has my makeup melted?
No.
Do I look beautiful today?
Yes. This is the fifth time
you've asked today.
Beautiful, beautiful!
No, I have to touch up my makeup.
Does it look all right?
What do I do? I'm so nervous.
Lu Zhi Ang has refused our visits
throughout these three years.
Would he have fallen in love
with someone else?
No. Don't worry.
When he comes out,
I'm going to act perfectly
so he'll see I have improved.
Stop being so nervous.
You're making me nervous too.
How come he's not out yet?
Lu Zhi Ang, you bastard!
Why wouldn't you let me see you?
Why did you make me wait so long for you?
Do you think my youth has preservatives?
I'm about to expire!
Hug me tighter!
You're out.
I've waited a long time.
How come you've lost weight?
Did you not have enough to eat in there?
What's with the "ahs" and "ohs"?
Are you speaking in Morse code?
Can't you speak properly?
All right, all right.
I know you two have a lot to talk about.
Seeing as I'll be spending my life
with this person in the future
and I'll have him to myself
for much longer than you will
I'll give you two one more day.
24 hours. 86,400 seconds.
I'll let you tell each other everything
you couldn't say over these years.
All right?
Thank you.
I remember Qianchuan also had
many walkways like this.
They were lined with
camphor trees on both sides.
The leaves would sway with the wind,
swishing and rustling.
It was like the whole city was singing.
Yes.
How long has it been since we've biked?
Four or five years?
I remember we often raced back then.
We'd bike from home to school.
The loser had to draw
five drawings of a bust sculpture.
Maybe the creation of my art books
is thanks in large part to you
for beating me so many times.
You've been winning all this time.
Do you want to bike again?
If we could turn around
and sail back up the river of time
would everything be different?
Fu Xiao Si, have you ever thought about
how we'll be 10 years later?
10 years later?
That's too far in the future.
I've never thought about it.
I think you will have become
a real artist in 10 years.
You'll have numerous best-selling works
and a bunch of women pursuing you.
That sounds...
more like your dream future.
Do you know what my biggest dream is?
Your biggest dream?
How many dreams do you have?
I have many; big and small ones.
But there's only one that is the biggest.
Let me hear it.
Come here.
I'm not telling you.
Lu Zhi Ang!
You...
Xiao Si, my biggest dream is
to stay by your side
and be your guardian forever.
Fu Xiao Si.
Is my life over?
Don't say such things.
It's just getting started.
But the way I am now...
I have nothing left.
Don't you still have me?
I'll be your guardian.
Okay, I'm going to speed up. Sit tight.
We always fantasize about
going back in our lives
and returning to some point in our past
to change something
so that everything would
turn out differently.
However, life isn't
a cassette tape full of songs
which can be rewound to
the beginning at any time.
Real life doesn't have
a fast-forward, rewind, or pause button.
What has already happened
will not change.
The fortunate thing is
the future that has yet to happen
is full of unlimited possibilities.
We're here.
Lu Zhi Ang.
Do you still remember three years ago...
you gave me a cherry blossom necklace?
You might not know this.
Actually...
That necklace...
also comes in a matching set.
Yan Mo.
All this time, I haven't been
caring enough about you.
In the beginning,
I felt you were unreasonable.
I thought you weren't soft and gentle.
I thought you spent too much money
and was too mischievous.
But...
over these years...
Every time I thought back on it,
I felt like a jerk.
Do you want to say something?
I want to say...
Would you scorn this Lu Zhi Ang
who was always mean to you in the past
who now has nothing
who can only peel crayfish for you
and make sweet and sour spareribs?
Will you marry this jerk?
Lu Zhi Ang.
Three years was too long.
I really missed you.
In the future...
Don't make me wait anymore.
It's too big.
Is everything ready?
But... it feels a bit weird.
How so?
I'm not sure.
I just feel like I have
a lump in my throat.
You're about to leave your home.
You must hate to leave.
Yan Mo, I will take responsibility.
Mo Mo? Mo Mo?
Have you gone to bed yet?
Not yet!
I can't talk. My dad is here. Bye.
- Yan Da Zhuang.
- Mo Mo.
- So--
- Tomorrow--
Yan Da Zhuang, why are you
standing at the door? Come in.
To be honest, I've never been
so nervous before in my whole life.
Yes.
I managed to come this far
with Lu Zhi Ang.
I almost can't believe it.
I can't believe it either.
How come the little girl who was
acting spoiled by my feet just yesterday
is already getting married tomorrow?
How come you've grown up so quickly?
In the future, if you get hungry,
then come home for dinner.
Yes, dinner.
Mo Mo, why don't I
braid your hair for you?
I want it Athena-style.
Okay, I'll braid them any style you want.
Dad.
Do you still remember
the first time you braided my hair?
At the time, you nearly
scolded me to death.
That was the first in my life
I felt so useless.
Almost done, Mo Mo.
Just bear with me a little longer.
Okay, almost done.
That hurt! You yanked on my hair!
I'm sorry, Mo Mo.
I'll do it over--
Look, you moved and it fell apart.
Mo Mo, don't move around, okay?
Bear with me.
Do you know you looked like you were
about to chew me up and spit me out?
If I didn't have such high demands of you
would you have learned to perfect
your skills to such a masterly level?
So, going by what you say,
I should be thanking you?
Of course.
Listen up.
This is the only thing your hands are
good at. You're bad at everything else.
It's because of your handiwork that
I was often criticized by
teachers in kindergarten.
Are you done yet?
Daddy, the teacher gave us homework
to fold a paper frog.
A frog?
Daddy's the best at folding frogs.
All right, let's fold one together.
All right. Little frog, done!
Isn't Daddy amazing?
Daddy, how come the frog
isn't jumping? Is it dead?
It's not dead.
I'll think of a way to
make it jump. Watch.
Isn't it jumping now?
All right, Athena.
Have a look.
Let me see.
Not bad.
Your skills haven't slipped.
How did I make you so pretty?
It's just a bit of a shame.
I have to unravel the braids soon.
It's not a shame.
This is my...
last time braiding your hair for you.
Dad.
Go to sleep soon.
You have to be
the most beautiful bride tomorrow.
I'm going now.
Oh, right.
That is for you.
But open it after the wedding, okay?
Okay.
I also have something for you. Hold on.
This is for you.
Wait until after the wedding
to open it, too.
Okay.
I'm going now.
Go to sleep.
Goodnight, Dad.
Daddy, I won't call you
Yan Da Zhuang today.
I usually only say, "Yan Da Zhuang,
my card has hit the limit."
"Yan Da Zhuang, I bought another bag."
"Yan Da Zhuang,
Yan Da Zhuang, Yan Da Zhuang!"
It's been hard on you all these years
to have such an unruly daughter.
Now that I'm about to
be married, I realized
I seldom stopped to see
how you were doing.
This is what I feel most guilty about.
Daddy, when I was young,
I was always opposed to
you finding a stepmother for me.
You've held yourself back
for my sake.
You've done so much for me.
Now, I finally understand a little bit.
I know that finding someone you could
spend the rest of your life with
is a very blessed thing.
That's why I hope you can find
that someone too.
Stop worrying about what I think.
Live your life for yourself.
My one and only beloved baby.
I still remember you cried
the whole night on your sixth birthday.
Every time I recall that,
I feel my cheeks burning.
In the past 27 years
I hope you can forgive me for
any negligence in caring for you.
This is my first time being a father.
Even though I want to say
I don't feel sad at all
I can't manage to say the words.
Seeing how beautiful you look
in a wedding dress
I feel as if I am about to lose you.
Yan Mo, since the moment you were born
I have been preparing for this day.
Even so, I feel as if it is all
happening too soon.
However, I am proud of you.
You will inevitably need to
live your own life.
I believe my daughter
will be able to be happy.
Last of all, having you was
the greatest accomplishment of my life.
Mo Mo!
Mo Mo, Daddy's back--
Mo Mo.
Mo Mo?
Daddy.
Were you waiting for me?
I'm sorry. I was just too busy today.
I'm back late.
Happy birthday, baby.
Look at the birthday present
I have for you.
Is it a pink princess dress?
Yan Da Zhuang, why are you
being sentimental all of a sudden?
How annoying.
Are you asleep?
What is it?
You have to get up early tomorrow.
Go to sleep.
This is my last night being single.
Aren't you going to chat with me?
What do you want to talk about?
Oh, right. I have something fun.
Do you still remember?
There was a period when I was really
into astronomy so you gave this to me.
I remember your childhood dream
wasn't to be an artist.
I wanted to be
an aerospace engineer like my dad.
However, my mom
quickly killed that notion.
It seems neither of us
accomplished our initial dreams.
But, we've both become better people.
People are weird.
When we're young, we want to grow up
but when we're grown up,
we miss our childhood days.
It's all in the past. We can't go back.
We can't go back to the past
but the future is still up in the air.
I invited Li Xia to tomorrow's wedding.
I don't believe this is how
the two of you will end.
Do you think she will come tomorrow?
Li Xia, this world is too big.
It's so big that my voice can turn hoarse
from shouting in this sea of people
and I still won't receive
a reply from you.
But sometimes, I think that
in some corner of the world, you must
also be doing the same thing I am
and looking up at the same starry sky.
I haven't bothered you again
all these years
but I have left
an empty space in my heart
and I am waiting for us to
one day meet in due course.
[Groom: Lu Zhi Ang
Bride: Yan Mo]
Are you nervous?
I'm not nervous.
As if!
Are you nervous too?
Why would I be nervous?
You're the one getting married, not me.
Maybe she will come.
I think they should have two kids.
Two would be nice.
A boy and a girl to make a perfect pair.
That's what I think too.
Great minds think alike.
Yu Jian, what's the status with
you and Qing Tian?
He's pursued you for so long now.
We tried but it still didn't work out.
You'd just rather be alone than
put up with anyone.
- Look up there.
- Jun Bao.
What is 34 plus 27?
88.
It's obvious it was the gym teacher
who taught you mathematics.
Aren't these our seniors?
I still remember that tennis match.
What was it you said back then?
If you lost, you'd eat what?
What were you going to eat?
I'm now a role model for others.
That was the greatest embarrassment
of my life.
What high places
are you working in nowadays?
I'm not fit for high places
but I won't settle for less.
Mr. Lu Zhi Ang,
there's a package for you.
Thank you.
Zhi Ang, time is a mighty author.
It can pen a perfect ending.
Congratulations and best wishes
to you and Yan Mo.
Greetings from afar, Cheng Qi Qi.
May the groom please enter.
May the bride please enter.
Groom and bride, please face each other.
Mr. Lu Zhi Ang, please make a vow
in front of all present.
Do you take Ms. Yan Mo to be your wife?
I do.
Ms. Yan Mo, please make a vow
in front of all present.
Do you take Mr. Lu Zhi Ang
to be your husband?
I do.
Groom and bride, please exchange rings.
Give me a second.
I want the bouquet! Toss it to me!
I want to get married!
What's the delay? I want to get married.
It's my big day today.
Why do you look so miserable?
Come catch the bouquet.
I'll pass.
Okay, three, two, one!
Fu Xiao Si...
Everybody, come take pictures!
- Time for pictures!
- Pictures!
One.
Two.
Three!
There will inevitably be someone
to take our place
to carry the torch of youthfulness
in their time of youth.
There will inevitably come a day
when the Qianchuan we know
will be buried beneath layers by time
turning into something different
from our memories.
All stories eventually come to an end.
All that is left is
a continuous line of camphor trees.
When the annual wet monsoon
sweeps past these treetops
they silently deliver
those secrets held in our hearts.
Those boys taught me about maturity.
[Love 'til the End of Summer]
Those girls taught me about love.
Subtitles by DramaFever