I love you,
and I have a condom.
- Matt, I shouldn't be here.
- Come on, Anna.
- No. No.
- Come on, it'll be fun.
I really shouldn't be here.
Anna. Come on.
I'm at a party,
but all I want to do is get home.
Hey, where you going? Anna?
Don't go home.
And then I hear my mother's bell.
I go to find her.
When she got sick,
we moved her into the boathouse.
It's where she wanted to be.
She's alone.
She's not supposed to be alone.
Anna.
I run up to the house to find my dad.
There's something wrong.
It doesn't feel safe.
There's something evil in the house.
One way or another,
these dreams seem to be
about trying to get out of the woods
and back home.
Yeah.
And when I get there, it's like
Mom's trying to tell me something.
But I can't understand what it is,
what she's trying to say.
Well, we've talked about
the little redheaded girl,
but now there's a new detail,
the watering can.
Why do you think you were holding it?
I don't know.
I really don't remember.
Maybe you were trying
to put out the fire.
When my mom first got sick,
she said that she'd always be there.
Could be a stray cat,
or just the sound of the wind,
but it would always be her.
She'd always protect us, you know.
But...
But the night of the fire,
I couldn't protect her.
Smart girl.
If I'm so smart, why can't I remember
what happened that night?
Okay. Here's what I think.
We survive by remembering,
but sometimes we survive by forgetting.
You lost your mother in a tragic fire.
Your life was changed forever by,
what, a broken fuel valve?
Maybe it's not
such a bad thing to forget.
- But what about the dream?
- It's a dream.
You'll figure it out, or you won't.
That's how it all works.
It's a process, Anna.
What's it been? Ten months?
And you're almost finished.
But you're not gonna get there
in a place like this.
- Do you think I'm ready to leave?
- What else do you want from me?
Go home. Kiss a boy, get into trouble.
Finish what you started.
Hi.
One minute.
Pretty little Anna.
Going home, sweet home.
I'll be lonely.
I really gotta go.
There was so much blood,
wasn't there, Anna?
Do you really think they fixed you?
Come on, honey.
Let the girl pack her things.
What have we told you about
wandering in here all the time?
They couldn't fix me.
Who will I tell my stories to?
I've got a surprise for you.
- Look in the glove compartment.
- Tell me it's a cheeseburger.
Not quite.
- You finished it.
- Yeah. Look inside.
- Thank you, Dad.
- You're very welcome.
Is it any good?
Well, I don't know,
but I'm sure you'll tell me.
I know something that's good.
Oh, awesome. Thank you.
Yeah, Rachel made them.
She was gonna come today,
but I told her I wanted you all to myself.
She's been great, Anna.
Really, she has been.
I don't know what I would've...
- Dad. You got me to yourself.
- ... done without her.
Alex?
Anna. You're back.
You're early. I'd hug you, but I...
Welcome home.
You look great. You look so skinny.
I think I could use some time
at that place.
My first order of business
is fattening her up.
I've already started with him.
Yeah, she's been cooking all day.
- Making... Oh, what are you making?
- Beef Stroganoff. Your favorite.
So, you have a house
full of women now, Mr. Writer.
- Did your dad tell you my idea?
- No.
About the party.
We thought we could throw you
a "Welcome Home, Anna" bash.
Yeah, okay. Maybe.
Well, everybody's
been asking about you.
- We've got all summer. There's no rush.
- No.
Okay, I'm gonna go down to the water.
I blew it.
Anna.
Just like it never happened, huh?
Alex. Oh, I missed you so much.
So, what do you think?
You know, he had them
working weekends
so it'd be finished
by the time you got back.
Welcome to your new ward.
Better food, crazier people.
- When did she move in?
- Guess.
First, she was helping
with the accident inquiry,
and then she was helping
with the funeral.
Now, she's helping him cope.
Three times a night.
Whatever.
Hey, thanks a lot, by the way.
For what?
- Deserting me.
- Alex!
You know, I was stuck here
with those two
while you went off
searching for your inner psycho.
Alex, you don't know
what it was like in there.
She was my mother, too.
You know, you could've at least
written me back.
What are you talking about?
The playlists I made you,
the letters I wrote.
I didn't get anything, Alex. I swear.
Maybe Dr. Silberling
didn't want me to see them.
No, it wasn't Dr. Silberling.
Oh, he's such an asshole!
I mean, how could you
not send my letters?
Those were my letters, Dad.
What? Were you too afraid I'd tell her
about your new little girlfriend?
Was that it?
T alk about all the dirty little secrets?
And it was a mistake for you
to move her in here,
and our whole stupid town
just loves talking about it.
You disgust me.
- Alex, where are you going?
- As if anybody cares.
You caught me.
Come here. You can hug me now.
I'm clean.
Listen, Anna, I know the rules state
that you're supposed to hate
Dad's new girlfriend,
but I'm really hoping that
we can be more original than that
and make this work.
- Sure.
- Yeah.
- Something's different.
- Oh, yeah, we painted.
I really love all the wallpaper
in the house,
but the kitchen just needed
some brightening up.
There used to be something here.
- Did there?
- Yeah, a chalkboard?
Oh, yeah, the chalkboard.
It must be up in the attic
with all the other old stuff.
I think I figured
we didn't need one anymore.
So, what do you think?
Do you wanna help set the table?
No, I'm okay.
I'm not really hungry anyway.
Alex?
What are you doing?
So, was that you or Nursie
in the throes of ecstasy?
- I don't know.
- Okay.
You drunk?
Well, I went to a party
and drinks were served.
- Where did you find that?
- Upstairs.
What the hell are you doing with it?
- I don't know. It was in the attic and...
- Okay. Well, that's where it should stay.
- I hate that bell.
- Why?
It reminds me of Mom.
We needed it, Alex.
That's how she'd call for help
after she got sick.
Anna, wake up. Rachel bought the bell.
What are you saying?
She went into a goddamn pet store,
bought a bell,
came home,
and tied it around Mom's wrist.
And do you know why?
So that she could hear Mom coming
while she was busy riding Dad.
- You're making that up.
- Okay. Why would I do that?
To get back at Dad.
Trust me, Anna,
I'm way past getting back at Dad.
You know, I might be drunk,
but at least I know what the truth is.
Oh, here comes the burrito.
Maybe try a sledgehammer next time.
- Sorry.
- Looks good to me.
Great, actually.
Just what our little kitchen needed.
Isn't it, though?
- I'm out of here.
- Cool.
You know, Anna, I remember when
I first came here to look after your mom.
I showed up at the house,
and Alex was doing
her bitchy teenager thing,
disrespecting your father.
But you were different.
Quiet, you know? Polite.
A proper little lady.
I remember thinking,
"Still waters run deep in this one.
She's the strong one. "
When I was your age,
I had to deal with some rough things,
like you, and I learned to be strong.
To be a girl nobody fucked with.
I am so glad to have you back.
I hope it works out so you can stay.
Thanks. I intend to.
Did you see her face?
It was like
you totally jacked her Barbie kitchen.
I was swinging the hammer
with my eyes closed.
That is so awesome.
It's our chalkboard. It should be there.
Remember Mom
would leave messages on it?
Soccer practices.
Oh, but her handwriting was so bad.
Pinkie pact?
Am I, like, really pale?
Yeah, you're pretty much,
like, see-through.
Well, hopefully your future husband
won't notice.
No, you are not leaving me here.
- What are sisters for?
- Alex, don't you dare!
- Hey, Matt.
- Hey.
- So how you been?
- Yeah. Okay.
You know, I really wanted to visit you
up there, but they wouldn't let me.
Well, you should've slit your wrists, too.
We could've been roommates.
She's back.
- So, listen, that night at the beach...
- No, no. Listen...
I was nervous, okay?
So I drank a bunch,
and no one has ever accused me
of being smart,
so I was dumb and drunk.
But I was worried about you.
I even went looking for you.
What do you mean?
I followed you home that night, Anna.
I was here. I saw everything.
Running a little late, aren't you, Matt?
- Thanks. That's all we need.
- Okay.
- I'll just... I'll see you around.
- Bye.
Why don't you bring these supplies
up to the generator room?
And then come up.
Your father's starved.
- Your agent called today.
- Really?
Yeah. I didn't know
he rents a house up here.
Yeah, the last five years.
He likes to pretend to fish.
I think he has the editor of
The Book Review as a houseguest.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
So, I invited them for dinner
on Friday night.
- Really?
- Along with a few other people.
- Well, why not?
- Well...
We never have anyone to the house.
It'll be fun.
Please.
- Okay.
Murderer!
Anna?
What are you doing down here?
Hey. Are you okay?
It was Mom.
- What?
- I saw Mom!
What are you talking about?
Anna?
Anna!
She's been trying to tell me something.
- What?
- The fire wasn't an accident.
It was her.
Rachel just happened to
have the night off.
Yeah, right.
- Alex...
- No, it all makes sense now.
She left Mom,
parked her car down the street,
put on those little white shoes,
and walked back down
to the boathouse.
- Maybe we're jumping to conclusions.
- Excuse me,
I'm not the one that
saw our dead mother
point the finger
at Dad's creepy girlfriend.
Yeah, I think it was just a dream.
Anna, you were wide awake. I saw you.
Well, maybe it was all in my head.
Maybe so.
But it doesn't change
what both of us know.
That tap didn't leak. Rachel turned it on.
She killed Mom,
and she's not gonna get away with it.
Hello? Hello in there?
- Did she hear us?
- I don't know.
Listen, I'm going into town
to do some shopping for this party.
Would you like to come?
Have some retail therapy,
maybe grab lunch?
I'm totally hung over
and I'm expecting a headache later.
- But Anna wants to come.
- What? No.
What about Matt?
You could see him, talk to him.
I thought you said he came back
to the house that night.
- How about it, Anna?
- Come on.
You can go, and I can stay here
and dig through her stuff. Go on.
- You know, we can do it another time.
- No.
I'll be down in a minute.
I'm just gonna find
something cute to wear.
You little suck-up.
Your dad hates it when I drive fast.
- Our little secret, okay?
- Our little secret.
What happened to my mom's car?
Well, we discussed it,
and we just felt like
the family needed something more fun.
My one good piece of jewelry.
Where'd you get it?
Oh, there.
Someone gave them to me ages ago.
A boyfriend?
An old patient, actually.
Really? Sounds like a nice job.
I wiped old people's asses
for a living, Anna.
And let me assure you, they were
not all beautiful like your mom.
No, I mostly had to do things
that decrepit old ladies
with lots of money were either too
ashamed or weak to do for themselves.
Wanna know how I got through it?
It's terrible,
but no matter how condescending
they were,
how badly they treated me,
how badly they smelled,
I always told myself,
"They'll be dead very, very soon. "
You know, Anna, we all have things
in our past that we're ashamed of.
I think sometimes
it's best to just let it go.
Anna?
Anna, are you all right?
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
We have some shopping to do, right?
Beautiful marbling.
How long has it been aged?
- We sell everything fresh.
- Never mind.
- I'm gonna go grab the milk.
- Great, thanks.
- Matt.
- Anna. Hey.
What are you doing here?
Listen, I think... I think I know what
you were trying to tell me yesterday.
The fire wasn't an accident, was it?
- What did you see?
- Matt?
Those berries aren't getting any fresher.
Yeah, yeah. Okay, I'm coming.
- Will you help us, please?
- Yeah, okay. Just not here.
Okay, then can we meet tonight?
Matt!
- Yeah. 11:00. At the rock.
- Okay.
- Couldn't find the milk?
- Yeah.
- We should go.
- Okay.
Oh, and, Matt, you won't need to
make deliveries to the house anymore.
That's gonna be my job from now on.
- Have fun?
- Oh, yeah.
Been telling each other
all our secrets, right, Anna?
Yeah. Thanks for lunch.
- Was everything okay?
- I lost her for a little bit.
I mean, I just hope
this wasn't all too soon.
Alex?
Jesus, you scared me.
I thought you were her.
- Did you talk to Matt?
- Yeah, we're meeting him tonight.
Cool. Look at this.
God, when are they bringing
in the stripper pole?
I know, she's like a crack whore
without the dignity.
P.S., look at this.
Come on. Look what I found.
- Meet Mr. Chubby.
- Oh, that's disgusting.
No, I'm not touching that.
Okay, that's enough
to tranquilize a horse.
Or you and me.
- Come on, let's go.
- Wait.
Party's over, Rach.
Come on, let's go. We're gonna be late.
Matt?
This doesn't feel right.
What if something's happened?
It's okay, Anna.
We'll find him tomorrow.
Yeah.
I'm gonna go to bed.
No, please stay with me till I fall asleep.
If I had 10 bucks
for every time I heard that.
Thank you.
No funny stuff.
Anna, hey. Hey, don't be afraid.
I just didn't want to
wake your parents up.
Matt. Where were you?
We waited for you at the rock,
just like you said.
Yeah, I know, I...
What happened? You're soaked.
You know, I fell and hurt my back
or something.
Well, here, come sit down.
I'm sorry it's so late, but... It's just...
I think you need to know the truth
about what I saw that night.
Tell me.
You're shivering.
I can't feel anything.
- I'm scared, Anna.
- Don't be.
Matt, what happened to your back?
Your mother tried to warn me, Anna,
but I didn't listen.
Hold me. Anna.
Anna.
Please, hold me. Anna, please.
Anna? Hi, I'm Sheriff Emery.
I don't know if you remember me.
Listen, we're gonna do
a thorough investigation,
but he must have hit a patch of timber,
fell out of the boat and broke his back.
Were you supposed to meet him?
Listen, we all know
what you're going through.
Anything you need, anything at all,
you come see me.
You understand?
I'm deeply sorry.
It's just terrible.
I'm gonna make breakfast.
You should eat something.
- Coffee?
- Yeah.
- Dad, wait.
- What?
Matt wasn't just in the water last night.
He was coming to see me.
Anna, what happened to Matt
is not your fault.
Dad, that's not what she's trying to say.
One of you come help me.
- Dad.
- I'll go.
- What?
- I saw Matt in town yesterday.
He told me he saw what happened
the night of the fire.
Rachel overheard us.
She didn't want me
to talk to him anymore.
She didn't want him
to come here ever again.
Anna, why would Rachel
say something like that?
It's just...
What?
Is everything all right out there?
- We'll be right in.
- Okay.
Sweetheart, I know
this is difficult for you.
It's been hard for all of us,
but, please, don't do this.
Okay? Just don't do this.
- Come on, have some breakfast.
- I'll be there in a minute.
You okay?
No, I'm not okay.
I'm not crazy, Alex.
Matt was here, and I thought
that I was dreaming, but I wasn't.
- Anna, do you wanna sit...
- And he said
that Mom was trying to warn him.
- Okay, how can that be?
- And he was holding me.
- Anna, listen.
- Look!
Oh, my God.
- Okay, now I'm afraid.
- I'm not crazy.
They're not gonna send me back there.
No, I'm not afraid for you.
I'm afraid for us.
Anna, we're the last ones
standing between Rachel
and what she really wants.
Come on. Look,
last time I checked, you didn't become
some psycho serial killer overnight,
so we need to find out exactly
who Miss Rachel Summers really is.
Yes, hi, I'm trying to
get some information
about someone we hired
through your agency.
Her name's Summers.
Rachel Summers.
Hello, I'd like to get a reference
on one of your nurses, please.
I believe she was on your staff
at the hospital
between July and December of 2005.
Hi, I'm running a background check
on someone who worked for you
several years ago.
Summers. S-U-M-M...
Yeah, as in "mother. "
E- R-S, as in "Satan. "
What? No, that's impossible.
No, no, no, that's fine.
Okay, thanks very much. Bye.
We've got her.
Anna. Come in.
You know,
you have beautifully shaped lips.
You just don't know
what to do with them.
Men will go on about a woman's eyes,
but that's bullshit.
What they really want is
a girl with a pretty mouth.
There.
You seem very interested in these.
Would you like to wear them tonight?
- No, I don't think so.
- Oh, come on. It'll be fun.
There.
What's your real name, Rachel?
What did you say?
The State Nursing Association
has no record of a Rachel Summers.
Your social security number's
for someone named Rachel Summers,
but she's a school teacher
from New Orleans.
She died five years ago.
So, who are you, really?
You know what, Anna?
I don't think this is going to work out.
Where do you think you're going?
To talk to my father.
Well, there's really no need.
We've already discussed it
with Dr. Silberling.
- Discussed what?
- Well, your behavior.
Anna, he's very concerned.
He's beginning to think that
it was a mistake letting you out.
You won't take this away from me.
I won't allow it.
Now, get out. I have guests coming.
I can't believe she sold you out to Dad.
Maybe she can threaten you,
but what can they do to me?
- I'm gonna talk to Dad.
- No.
All she's gonna do is convince him
that we're lying
and that it's my fault, okay?
We just have to get through tonight,
and then tomorrow we go to the police
and tell them what's going on.
You're only gonna make it worse for me.
Fine. But this is gonna
take a lot of alcohol.
Hey. Look at you.
- What?
- You look terrific.
Thanks.
Well, I guess
you've grown up on me, haven't you?
Hey, if it's any consolation,
this is all pretty weird for me, too.
Book launch parties.
Might as well give everyone
a green light
to come into your house and judge you.
Can I ask you a favor?
Would you give Rachel a hand tonight?
The truth is, I don't think
she feels good enough for all of this,
and people here are judging her, too.
Sure.
What?
I just wanted to know
if you needed any help.
Really?
Sure. Open the oven.
Okay.
The key to a good roast is to
let it sit 10 minutes before carving.
It lets the blood flow back in.
Back to the fray.
Take out the garbage, will you?
You're next.
No. No. What did you do?
What did you do?
What are you trying to do to me?
What happened?
You leave her alone.
Just go to bed.
No, no. Listen, I'll be in New York
tomorrow and we can sort this all out.
Sorry about this. Travel safe.
Dad? Can I talk to you?
Tonight. There's a reason for
what happened.
It's Rachel.
She's not who you think she is.
Enough, Anna.
- What has she done this time?
- She's lied to you.
- About what?
- About everything. About her name.
Do you even know where she's from?
I'm not gonna dignify that
with an answer.
No, of course you're not, because
you only see what you wanna see.
All she is trying to do
is make this family work.
She's not trying to make it work.
- She wants you for herself.
- That is ridiculous.
God, if Mom could see you now,
siding with that bitch
who's trying to tear us apart!
Rachel isn't the one
who's tearing us apart.
Look, maybe we should talk
to Dr. Silberling about this.
Right, because I'm the one who's crazy.
- I didn't say that. You know I did...
- Dad.
You're not wearing your ring.
Are you gonna marry her?
- Tell me!
- Yes, Anna.
We're getting married
sometime this fall.
We talked about going away,
but I wanna have the wedding here,
for all of us.
I'm not ashamed, Anna.
I'm not ashamed to be happy again.
Bye, Daddy.
We shouldn't be late for Matt's service.
Wear something decent.
I wanna look like a family.
"In the Lord, I take refuge.
"How can you say to me,
'Flee like a bird to the mountains.
"'See how the wicked string their bows,
fit their arrows to the strings
"'to shoot from the shadows?
"'When foundations are being
destroyed, what can the upright do?'
"The Lord is in his holy temple.
The Lord's throne is in heaven.
"God's eyes keep careful watch. "
"The Lord is my light and my salvation.
Whom do I fear?
"The Lord is my life's refuge.
Of whom am I afraid?
"When evildoers come at me
to devour my flesh,
"these my enemies and foes
themselves stumble and fall. "
This is from April 11, 1996.
"Police have recovered the bodies
of three children
"from a shallow grave in the woods
less than 50 yards
"from the residence of prominent
physician Dr. Harrison Wright.
"Forensics reveal the children
were heavily sedated
"before being stabbed repeatedly.
"Police have issued a warrant
for the arrest of Mildred Kemp, age 19,
"who had been employed as the
Wright children's nanny since August. "
- Mildred Kemp?
- Holy shit. Listen to this.
"According to sources
close to the family,
"Kemp had became romantically
obsessed with Dr. Wright
"since his wife's death
in a car accident last February.
"Despite police efforts,
Kemp remains at large. "
Wait, what...
Look. Look what she's wearing.
The pearls.
Rachel said they were a gift
from an old patient.
She put them around my neck.
Like... Like she was proud of them.
Yeah, well, lucky for us,
now we have proof.
Yeah, if we can get our hands on them.
Don't worry about that.
This ends tonight.
Shit.
Hey, look.
- Alex, where are you going?
- Just go downstairs and get her keys.
- What are you gonna do?
- Just get her keys.
What are you looking for, Anna?
Is it these? Are you looking for these?
You should take them.
Please. They mean nothing to me.
We know, Rachel.
We know everything.
You caught me.
Here.
Alex!
Anna.
I don't want to hurt you.
This isn't how I wanted it.
You can make this easy.
- Anna.
- Alex.
- What happened?
- She drugged me. She drugged me.
Anna? Open the door.
Anna, listen to me.
- You have to get that necklace.
- I did. I got it.
Anna! Open this goddamn door!
You gotta go to Emery, okay?
- No. No.
- Yes. He'll believe you.
- Anna!
- I can't leave you here.
Pinkie pact.
Anna!
- Okay.
I love you.
I'll come back for you, okay? I promise.
Anna!
So, you're alleging that
Miss Summers is actually a woman
- named Mildred Kemp?
- Yes.
And she was the one responsible
for the fire?
That's right. It wasn't an accident.
She murdered our mother,
and now she's after us.
- Listen, I know how this sounds, but...
- No. Mildred Kemp. I remember her.
Out west in Woolridge County,
years ago, wife died,
man hired some nanny
who killed all the children.
That's right, but they never caught her.
Okay, listen, Mrs. Wright
had a pearl necklace, three strands.
There are pictures of it
on the Internet if you wanna see.
And?
Rachel is Mildred Kemp.
Okay? She's trying to kill us
and marry our father,
just like she did to them.
Listen, I want you to sit tight.
Jerry is right outside that door.
I'm gonna pull up Miss Summers
on the system.
No, there's no time for that.
You have to go to my house.
Alex is still there, and I'm afraid
something's gonna happen to her.
Nothing's gonna happen
to anybody, Anna. You wait here.
Mom?
Don't be afraid. I'm a nurse.
No! No! Don't believe her! No! No!
Please! Don't believe her!
No! She's lying!
Don't believe her, please!
No! No! Don't believe her! No! She...
There we go. Thank you.
I remember her.
It was out west in Woolridge County,
years ago, wife died,
man hired some nanny
who killed all the children.
Rachel is Mildred Kemp.
"Police have issued a warrant
for the arrest of Mildred Kemp, age 19,
"who had been employed as the
Wright children's nanny since August. "
"Forensics reveal the children
were heavily sedated
"before being stabbed repeatedly.
"Despite police efforts,
Kemp remains at large. "
You' re gonna sleep now.
You know, Anna, I'm never
gonna have children of my own.
I can't.
Did I ever tell you that?
It's never stopped me from imagining
what it'd be like to have a daughter.
But now you've taken that
away from me.
Careful.
You don't want to hurt yourself.
Anna?
We tried everything, Anna.
This was the only way.
What did you do?
I had to, Anna. Didn't I?
Didn't I have to?
It's okay. It's okay.
I'm here. I'm always here.
Look at me. Look at me.
Be brave, okay? Okay.
Oh, my God. Are you all right?
It's Rachel, Dad. Rachel started the fire.
- What are you talking about?
- She killed Mom.
Dad, I know you never listen to me,
but you have to believe us!
She waited until you were out of town,
and she drugged me,
and she drugged Alex.
- What?
- She was gonna kill us.
Alex had to do it, Dad. She saved us.
- Alex?
- Alex, tell him.
Anna, what are you saying?
He can't see it, Anna. He never will.
Anna, you know what happened
to your sister.
- Tell him, Alex.
- Don't believe him.
- She died.
- No, don't believe him.
In the fire.
- It was a year ago.
- No! He's lying!
Alex is dead!
What have you done?
Alex?
Anna?
Anna, what do you mean
the fire wasn't an accident?
What happened that night?
Tell me what happened that night!
Get away from me. Get away from me.
Get away from me!
Hello? Dad?
The guys, they want to
come back to our house.
It's not our house anymore.
What are you doing?
They can burn in hell.
Anna. Anna!
Anna, what's wrong?
- Alex?
- Coming, Mom.
Alex!
I mean, how could you
not send my letters?
Those were my letters, Dad.
What? Were you too afraid I'd tell
her about your new little girlfriend?
Was that it?
Talk about all the dirty little secrets?
Anna?
Listen, I'm going into town.
You wanna come?
I followed you home that night, Anna.
I saw everything.
Don't let go. Anna, hold me.
You know, Anna, I'm never
gonna have children of my own.
I can't.
It's never stopped me from imagining
what it'd be like to have a daughter.
But now you've taken that
away from me.
I'm sorry, Mr. Ivers.
I noticed the name
on Miss Summer's passport
doesn't match the name
on her driver's license.
She changed her name three years ago.
Had a boyfriend used to beat her up.
Her real name is Rachel Worshinsky.
Your daughter got it
in her mind somehow
that your fiance
was a woman named Mildred Kemp.
Why would she make all this up?
Hello, Anna.
Are you okay?
I did exactly what you asked.
Did what, Anna?
I finished what I started.
Welcome home.