THE BEST OF YOUTH
Act Two
And he spends the whole time
juggling.
Standing on his head,
like this.
TURIN
SUMMER OF 1982
And his feet against the wall.
Then he stops and goes:
It's great.
Then when I meet him
I say "Hi, Mimmo."
And he hands me his foot.
-And I go...
-Look, balloons!
I'll get you one.
-What color do you want?
-Blue.
Sure, that's your color.
-One blue balloon.
-Sure.
Well?
Are you happy
school's over?
No? But you're on vacation.
Beach or mountains this year?
When will Mommy come back?
I don't know.
You know that.
Monica says
that means that Mommy's dead.
What nonsense!
Don't listen to her.
That's absurd.
If she's dead, tell me.
Of course I'd tell you.
Why'd you let it go?
This way, if you lied,
it'll go to Mommy.
Forgive the delay.
In a few minutes
we'll be arriving
at Porta Nuova Station
in Turin.
Sorry for the inconvenience.
In Lebanon
the Israelis surrounded
the Palestinian neighborhoods
in Beirut.
Arafat requested...
Barbara Mellecca.
In the Falklands...
the British are 4 kilometers
from Port Stanley.
Roberta de Angelis.
Paola Riviello.
"United States of America.
Celia Bobak."
Stock market fluctuations
around 3 percent.
The public deficit
has carried over.
To reduce the deficit
the government proposes
budget cutbacks
and new taxes.
Selection round
for the 1982 World Cup.
In the game against Poland
a zero-zero tie
is no disappointment.
Patrizio Peci declares
in the Moro case...
-Who is it?
-Sorry, it's me, your neighbor.
I need to ask a favor.
One moment.
Sorry, I thought
the Randis were home.
No, they're away for two weeks.
I'm a guest.
Are you a teacher as well?
Yes, I'm here for an exam.
I'm from Udine.
My husband didn't buy milk
and we have a baby.
Do you have any?
No, I'm sorry.
-I didn't have time to shop.
-That's okay.
He can go and buy some,
it's his fault.
He should have remembered.
-Welcome anyway.
-Thanks.
Sara, go put on your shoes!
Her name's Sara, too?
Do you have a daughter
with that name?
No, my sister does.
Her name's Sara as well.
Is she a pain like mine?
No... yes.
No.
"It was the voice of Silver.
It took only a few words
to convince me
that I wouldn't leave
for all the gold in the world.
I stayed there,
trembling,
listening, terrified..."
She showed up this morning,
around seven o'clock,
but there was nobody here.
I always arrive first.
It was out of nowhere.
Who told her I worked here?
Well? Aren't you going
to ask me anything? How was she?
I don't want to know.
At first I didn't recognize her,
she has dark hair now...
I don't want to talk about it.
She wants to see Sara.
Just from a distance.
She won't speak to her.
She just wants to see her.
-Got a smoke?
-You smoke now?
No. What did you tell her?
Nothing. You know it's no use
arguing with Guilia.
She came, told me where
and left.
No greeting,
no "How are you?
You're a carpenter now?"
Nothing.
When do we meet?
The day after tomorrow,
during the match.
-Which match?
-Nicola, the World Cup!
Italy's in the final!
...Zoff. Carl Heinz,
Forster, Breitner...
They're watching the match.
Look, hyenas.
Hyenas.
Hyaena ridens.
-Laughing hyenas.
-They're funny.
-To show their teeth.
-A moose!
I saw lots of them
on that trip to Norway.
Look, a wild boar!
It's not a boar,
it's a warthog.
Breitner shoots from close up...
Breitner, three to one.
38th minute.
Three to one.
Breitner scores.
"His name was Fritz.
He was obedient and easy going.
He lived in Stupinigi for 25 years
and on November 4th, 1846...
He killed his trainer."
Jesus, Fritz.
Causio replaces AItobelli.
Clearly a substitution
designed to
waste time
and break the other team's rhythm.
One minute of play
left in the World Cup...
These are all birds.
A falcon,
good hunters...
a bird of prey.
And chickens...
-Looks like a henhouse.
-A pelican.
Look, a moose, with horns.
And that's a giraffe.
My favorite animal.
Why is it your favorite?
Because it uses its long neck
to eat the leaves off trees
and gaze at the sky.
I like animals
that gaze at the sky.
What's that?
-A manatee.
-It looks like a seal.
It looks like a seal,
but it's called
-a manatee.
-How do you know so much?
Because I read the signs.
Daddy, we won.
Yeah, we won.
FALL OF 1983
Good God, it's freezing!
And they say
it's sunny in Rome!
Where's the sun?
It's been days!
You don't have a motorcycle,
do you?
I don't like noise
in the patio.
The kitchen.
This is the living room.
Lots of light.
The furniture is new.
Look, over there...
the bedroom.
Perfect.
The TV is new,
the owners bought it.
Look, the movers,
poor lads,
they did four floors on foot
so I gave them
20,000 lira as a tip.
-Here.
-No, it's okay.
-At the end of the week.
-Fine.
Oh, the flowers!
The owner loves them.
They need watering
every day.
Unless it rains, of course.
-All right?
-Yeah.
If it's a bother,
I can do it.
No, it's no bother.
I'll do it.
Right, if you need anything
you can call me
or my husband.
We're downstairs.
All right, great.
Have a nice day.
I'll leave the keys here.
-Goodbye.
-Bye.
Everything okay,
princess?
Give me your heart,
I want my love to explode...
I've dug a hole...
-A more sexual vitality.
-We are Mediterranean...
Latin, which means,
hot-blooded...
There's just one problem.
The new Secret Service
will handle it.
Please.
Over here.
Hi.
Tomorrow we start
the night shift.
Two weeks,
then three days off.
Then we get the day shift.
That's the boss's office.
Watch out.
And that's yours.
This is the coffee machine.
And your desk.
Those are the guys
we're looking for.
Pretty much all of them.
The Reds and the blacks.
The ones we think
are in town.
What if we find this one?
What do we do?
It depends what she does.
If she reaches in her pocket,
we shoot.
I'd shoot even if she doesn't.
Just in case.
To make sure.
Dad, it's sticky!
Add flour and spread it.
...her daughter,
who had heard shots,
and a few neighbors.
The judge was still breathing
but died on the way
to the hospital.
There are bubbles forming.
A reader called "La Stampa"
saying that the Red Brigades
had ordered him
to call the paper.
The Red Brigades sent another
letter claiming responsibility
to "ll corriere della Sera"
in Rome.
Judge Caccia was handling
several terrorism cases,
as well as cases related
to drug runners and the mafia.
The D.A. in Turin...
Good morning.
Can I take this?
Is that you, Nicola?
The girl from Stromboli!
"The girl from Stromboli"
has a name.
Oh, right.
Don't tell me.
In the meantime
give me your ID
and I'll fill out a card.
I left it at home.
Marcella.
No, Mirella.
Oh, right.
Mirella, sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'll put it in my name.
Bring it back in two weeks.
-What if I steal it?
-I'll track you down.
Where do I live?
What's my last name?
I found you once,
I can do it again.
All right.
Are you here because of
that advice I gave you?
It was good advice.
It's a beautiful place.
It's lunchtime. You want to share
a sandwich and an apple?
I remember that day perfectly.
I've dreamt of you often.
Then I told my boyfriend
and he got all jealous.
I don't know why, he didn't
even know if you were real.
-Men are silly.
-That's true.
What about now?
If you tell him you saw me,
he'll kill you.
Yeah, he's the type.
Actually, I left him.
You want some?
You still take pictures?
Every once and a while.
You remember what you told me?
To look for the mystery?
I really liked that.
I've tried, to no avail.
I just can't capture
the person inside.
It's what you said.
Did I? I can't remember.
-You can't remember?
-No.
That's insane!
I had a nervous breakdown that day,
-and you can't remember.
-Apple.
Fine, I forgive you.
Only because you're handsome.
Don't forget the book.
Two weeks!
-Giovanna, hi.
-Hi.
Come in.
In there,
because back here...
How did you know where I live?
It was on the list
of new agents.
You didn't even give us
the address.
Have a seat.
I didn't know you were in Rome.
I got transferred
recently.
I'm living with Mom.
You've got so much space.
How is she?
How do you think?
You want something to drink?
Why didn't you tell us?
I found out by chance.
-You're like a stranger!
-I'll make coffee.
-I'm talking.
-No, you're blabbering
like a big sister.
You like playing Mother Superior,
but I have one of those.
Who you totally ignore.
What the hell do you know?
You're a judge,
you pass verdict!
This isn't a courtroom!
What did we do to you
to deserve this?
Giovanna, wait.
Giovanna!
Listen.
-Hi.
What's your name?
Matteo.
Matteo. Nice name.
Very pretty.
-And what's your name?
-Lolita.
-Where are you from?
-Venezuela.
What's the matter?
Are you sad?
What are you looking at?
-Your necklace.
-My necklace?
You like it?
Here.
For your girl.
I just don't feel up to it.
Maybe...
Maybe not.
The others are more decisive.
I'm so afraid.
Maybe I should...
I might not be ready for this.
I don't know...
Don't be afraid.
You'll be fine, you'll see.
Hello?
-Hello?
-Francesca.
-Listen to me.
-Okay.
I need to see you right away.
In two hours,
at the Forum gardens.
-Yes.
-You got it?
Sara has grown.
I would have brought a photo,
but I left in a hurry.
I was so nervous.
Nicola said he took her
to the movies last week
and right in the middle
of the theater
she asked him
what menstruation was.
-What did he do?
-He explained it to her.
With everyone listening.
That's Nicola,
he can't tell the difference.
Young, old, crazy, sane,
he doesn't care.
Listen.
Tell Carlo to request a transfer,
to get out of Rome.
Actually, out of Italy.
As soon as possible.
Go where?
-How?
-Anywhere.
He's in danger.
Do you understand?
But we have small children.
The house, his job...
Besides, you know Carlo.
He won't leave.
-I have to go.
-No, wait, Giulia.
Wait, you listen to me.
I'll try to talk to Carlo,
to convince him,
but he'll say no.
He was a friend of yours before.
Save him.
Tell him they can't!
-I can't. Let me go.
-No, I won't.
Say he has no schedule,
that he's never alone...
Say he's too risky a target.
You have to save him, Giulia.
Swear that you will.
Do you trust me?
Yes. I do.
All right.
I'll try.
Nicola's coming to Rome
for Christmas, right?
Yeah, I think so.
At New Year's.
-For a few days.
-I want to see Sara.
-Just once.
-I dont know how...
Take her to the Coliseum.
I'll call you to say when.
Okay.
Don't tell anyone.
All right.
So what do you do?
-I'm an engineer.
-Well, well, an engineer!
Every mother's dream.
Maybe that's why I did it.
So you build dams,
bridges, buildings...
Yeah, I work abroad a lot.
I have to travel often.
-Don't you like traveling?
-No.
-What would you like to do?
-I don't know.
Maybe what you do.
-Be around books.
-Quit and come join me.
-You like chestnuts?
-A lot.
Give me some.
-How much?
-3,000.
That's robbery!
Go pick them yourself!
Rome!
-Here.
-Thanks.
You want to go somewhere?
Where?
Put two fingers in front,
raise the palm of your hand
and do like I do.
Balance it and if you're
right-handed, left foot forward.
-It looks easy.
-Sure.
-My turn.
-Yeah.
You have to use your fingers.
-You can't otherwise.
-I have my own way.
All right.
-It won't go straight like that.
-Wait.
Watch and learn.
Too soft!
Shut up!
Goal! Goal!
The word is "strike."
"Strike" !
-Get in.
-Thanks.
-You're soaked.
-That's okay.
-I have to make a call.
-Okay.
You're soaked.
I have to go.
I have to take a flight
in the morning.
-There's trouble at the site.
-How long?
Just a week.
I'll be back the 7th.
What are you doing the 7th?
Picking you up.
What time?
When the library closes.
Okay?
I found this under your seat.
I got it the other day
and I couldn't find it.
I don't know how it got there.
Is it for your girl?
It's for you.
Then put it on me.
Relax, I'll do the shift.
-Day and night?
-Yeah.
Day and night.
You're a pal.
Just as well this isn't the highway.
This car barely runs.
-When will you get a new one?
-A new one?
It runs great.
Dad, it's junk.
-It sucks.
-What do you mean?
This car runs great!
You should buy a new one.
My daughter's
turned into a consumer!
Are we poor?
Why, you need anything?
Too bad we missed Christmas.
The gifts are at Christmas,
not New Year's.
Who says?
We do gift's at New Year's.
Who'll be there?
Grandma, Aunt Giovanna...
-Francesca?
-Francesca, Carlo, the kids...
They had another baby.
Yeah? What's its name?
Asdrubale
-Teofrasto Calimaco.
-Calimaco?
-No, Nabucodonosor.
-Dad!
Don't pull my leg.
-Michele.
-Michele?
"The trip started
on the right foot.
The Spaniard
was an excellent ship,
behaving well
even in the middle of the ocean.
The crew were all
magnificent sailors.
The captain knew his job
to perfection
and everything seemed
to be going smoothly.
Until one night,
as he headed for his cabin,
Jim wanted an apple
and went looking in the barrel
where they kept the fruit."
-They'll never get to sleep.
-Who cares?
They're having fun
with their cousin from Turin.
-Maybe you are.
-Why?
-Because you have a girl.
-So?
We're just better,
that's all.
-Come on!
-It's true.
If you'd had a boy,
you'd be much wilder.
-Really?
-But she's settled you down.
-She's raising you well.
-Oh, right.
Grey hairs, eh?
Come on, just a couple.
The 40-year-old charm.
Hey, 37, not 40.
The successful older man.
Put your finger.
How do you manage with 3?
-Me with one...
-I'm exhausted.
But I like it.
Carlo has bodyguards?
What for?
In these times...
Nicola.
Nothing.
Michele's awake.
Open the door for Carlo.
Why the bodyguards?
"It is the winter
of our discontent."
"The bookkeeper
went up the stairs..."
"...where the guard
was waiting..."
"It's the mad doctor!"
-How are you?
-Fine, you?
My dream is a post
somewhere like
Denmark, Sweden, Holland...
Countries with shop windows.
The citizen walks by them
and looks inside.
My dream is to have
transparent banks,
a transparent stock market.
Politics, the economy...
Everything transparent.
So handsome...
I think he's asleep.
Maybe.
Not quite yet.
There.
-What's going on tonight?
-There's news.
I'm here, Sara...
New voives, strange faces...
-Here, I'm an expert.
-No, he's asleep.
He's asleep?
-Here.
-Careful...
Over here.
You see?
Watch the duck.
-Francesca?
-Asleep.
She's exhausted.
This time of year...
You were saying...
Transparency, right?
Nice idea,
but is it possible?
The others do it.
Why not us?
No, I mean Italians.
Do we like transparent things?
I think you're naive.
Ready for bed?
-To your crib.
-So I think...
Come on.
-Here we are.
-Don't whisper.
That wakes them.
Babies like sleeping
around noise.
Silence scares them.
There.
Don't worry,
he'll wake up in half an hour.
Gorgeous.
Beautiful boy.
What looks!
Bravo!
You're still great with kids.
-What about with women?
-The same.
-Seeing anyone?
-Nothing serious.
Nothing serious?
How many?
What an interrogation!
You're jealous.
Well, I'd better
come out with it.
I married your sister
just to be close to you.
I'll tell you something.
You have all the symptoms
of a real faggot.
-Why, don't you?
-Of course.
Listen...
Who do you go out with?
Nurses? Anesthesiologists?
What do you care?
-Where do you see them?
-Away from work.
-What does Sara say?
-She doesn't know.
And with so many,
you haven't found one that...?
Yes, I have.
But then things cooled off,
and nothing.
You didn't answer me before.
Why the bodyguards?
Have you talked to Francesca?
No, why?
You want some whisky?
Well, what?
I've been threatened.
That's why I have bodyguards.
Why did they threaten you?
It's not just judges,
politicians and cops anymore.
The other day a friend of mine
from university was shot.
They say:
"Hurt one, enlighten 100."
They want to educate us.
They just want to scare us.
And you need a bodyguard
just to go to the bathroom?
You see any options?
What about a transfer abroad?
I was offered a post
in New York.
Well?
Drink your whisky.
It tastes like malt.
Why don't you accept it?
Because that would mean
that they win.
How did you find out
you're in danger?
Giulia saw Francesca
recently.
Giulia came out of hiding.
She says she wants to see Sara.
DECEMBER 31ST, 1983
There's room.
-Take Francesca, I'll follow.
-Let's park.
Yeah, he works with me,
but only since a week ago.
Six months ago, in his bar
they arrested a guy just like him
with a bag of cocaine.
He'd brought it from home.
That doesn't concern me.
If they're wearing a jacket,
I let them in.
I don't care about the rest.
Just no short sleeves.
-He'd been arrested three times.
-So?
I don't ask for their records.
I respect the dignity
of my employees. I'm a democrat.
What about you?
Azim Mohammed.
Nothing.
It's late,
I'd like to go home for dinner.
-It's New Year's.
-What do I care?
-Somebody's looking for you.
-Who?
Mirella.
-Why did you lie to me?
-What are you doing here?
I want you to answer me.
Why didn't you say
your name was Matteo?
How did you find out?
The kid who checks ID
at the bowling alley.
He says you go a lot.
He said you were a cop.
I'm an investigator.
But everyone else
investigates me.
My sister, you...
Everyone sticks their noses
in my life.
What do you want?
Just to see you.
I thought we got along.
-So what?
-Nothing.
-Just that...
-What?
What?
-I have work to do.
-Why do you do this?
I'm on duty,
I haven't got time.
I don't understand.
I'm going crazy.
Why did you say all that stuff
in Sicely?
"What's your name?"
"Nicola."
-Why?
-We can talk if you want.
But not here or now.
Relax, I'm leaving.
-I won't bother you again.
-Good.
You like books because you can
close them whenever you want.
But in real life
it's not up to you.
You're wrong.
It's always been up to me.
It was up to me
to stop seeing you.
That's not a choice.
Don't you see?
I'm a scumbag. A loser.
You got it?
Will you leave now?
I don't think you are.
What the hell
do you want from me?
-Nicola...
-Matteo, my name is Matteo!
Go on, scram.
Go away.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we're playing
Merchant at the Fair.
-No, please!
-Yes, yes.
Come on, it's fun!
Don't be snobbish,
Merchant at the Fair.
-Who gets to be the Merchant?
-You do it.
Someone impartial,
like a judge.
-No, no.
-A judge, a judge!
It has to be a man.
I'm not a merchant.
Carlo would be better.
-Come on, Carlo!
-I'm not a merchant either.
But I'm the most entertaining.
Hand out the chips.
Read it
and if you agree,
sign it.
You wait, my partner
will take you downstairs.
Wait, we haven't finished.
Sit down.
Sit down!
How much is he paying you
to go to jail for him?
-What are you saying?
-How much?
-That's a serious accusation.
-Shut up,
-you piece of shit.
-I won't!
I want to see a lawyer!
Is he your supplier?
Is he?
Isn't he?
Where do you get money for this?
From him?
Tell me!
Is that it?
Is it?
Who the hell are you?
Jesus!
You can't screw me over.
You can't interrogate someone
like this.
-I want a lawyer.
-You'll remember tonight forever!
Lawyer my ass!
You won't get away with this.
You're in trouble.
I have a friend at City Hall.
He'll transfer you both...
I don't care.
I'll kick your ass!
-You don't know me!
-Calm down!
You can't do this to me.
What the fuck are you doing?
Are you crazy?
Get out of here.
You'll get me in trouble.
You got that?
He has nothing to do with it.
Everyone ante up 500.
It's almost midnight!
Come on!
I have a huge...
a huge stack of cards...
that even Agnelli would envy,
for the paltry sum of
-1 ,500 lira.
-1 ,600!
1 ,600 going once,
says the doctor, 1 ,600...
-2,000.
-Adriana, 2,000.
-2,500.
-2,500, little Sara.
-2,800.
-2,800, says Orlandino.
Who'll give you the money?
Me?
-Daddy will.
-Mommy will.
He's taken the cards
from Mr. Agnelli.
"On such a windy, rainy night...
who would call at such an hour?"
-Who could it be?
-Who?
Happy New Year, Mom.
I knew you'd come!
Come in, come in.
Merry Christmas!
-How are you?
-Fine, you?
Happy New Year.
-Hi.
-Welcome.
Hi, Carlo.
Wrong place.
This is no gambling den.
Little sister.
"The bedouin" and "the warrior."
Don't touch it,
it's your change.
-Where are the other two?
-Asleep.
What?
Take off you jacket.
-Sara!
-Hi!
-You remember me?
-You're the crazy driver.
And right here for
the crazy driver,
we have a nice little spot.
For the kind gentleman.
Two cards for you, sir.
Right, here I have a huge stack
of cards...
He lifted his finger.
-Orlandino said...
-6,500!
-6,500... Orlandino!
-7,000.
Don't go too high,
Sara won't have enough.
I'll finance Sara.
I can lend you
up to a million.
Okay, but I don't like these
under the counter loans.
-No loans allowed.
-10,000!
No, that's insider trading!
-8,300.
Orlandino, that amount
is worthy of Uncle Scrooge.
10,000 clears the field.
10,000 going once, going twice,
10,000 three times...
The card is...
The grape.
Who has the grape?
-Not me.
-Frances...
-He's asleep.
-And the others?
Sleeping as well.
Sara, you want to go to bed?
No, I'm a grown-up,
I want to win!
All right, all right.
I remind you
there's a grape out there.
And what would any Christmas be
without... the weaning child.
-Here.
-It was the last one.
Mom, I have to call the office.
Go in my room.
-How many left?
-Nine cards.
Hold on, one moment.
Everyone concentrate.
It's an animal.
-Carlo.
-No, but it starts with...
-You go on.
-Start with the first syllable.
-I'll be right back.
-Horse.
-No, it jumps.
-A goat.
-Everything okay?
-Yeah.
You still have my notes?
Yes, ten, ten, ten!
-You were so smart!
-So smart...
-What should I do with this?
-Here, I'll put it in a drawer.
No, not in a drawer.
There are kids around.
I'll put it somewhere.
I'll leave you to make your call.
Listen, Mom...
I don't know if I can stay.
I have work...
That's all right.
Just coming was already a gift.
Shall I close it?
Yes, thanks.
We have here an animal.
And I'm very sorry,
so very sorry,
because Adriana
has the zebra.
I'm not home,
please leave a message or...
Hey, I'm hungry.
I'm going for something to eat.
Who'll watch your cards?
Go around
or you'll wake the kids.
Okay.
We have an animal...
that lives in water,
in water, lakes...
It's the swan.
The swan, the swan.
Hold on, Sara.
-Sara, the swan.
-No, dammit!
Relax, you're still in.
Two, two, two, one...
What, are you leaving?
-It's an emergency.
-Yeah, right.
You want some turron?
-Something sweet.
-No!
At least say goodbye to Mom.
-I don't have time.
-Come on, it's time.
-No. Are you staying in Rome?
-Yeah, a couple days.
-See you.
-Yeah. Call me.
You promise?
-Yeah.
-You sure?
What?
First prize is the cat!
You win! Very good!
What do you say?
Long live the Fair!
Long live the Fair,
Long live the Fair, Sara!
I'm not home.
Leave a message or call 70 22 54
during office hours.
Matteo?
Could you give me the phone number
for Police Headquarters in Rome?
Let's see what's
going on elsewhere.
We're getting ready
for the toast.
Three lovely ladies
are approaching.
That's it.
Happy New Year!
Congratulations!
Happy New Year, everyone.
Happy New Year.
Congratulations!
This morning,
in the middle of all the chaos,
the ambulance, the police...
A girl appeared,
a very pretty girl.
Brunette, dark eyes...
-I can't remember the eyes.
-It doesn't matter.
I'm only saying because
I'd never seen girls around.
Your brother never brought
women home.
I would always joke, I'd say:
"Such a good-looking man
with no lady friends?"
Go on, please.
So this girl suddenly appears
and she asked about
your brother.
I hardly had time to tell her
what had happened.
She didn't say a word.
She just ran off.
-Maybe you know her.
-No, I don't.
Such a good person!
Such a nice man!
-Thank you.
-I'm sorry.
Listen,
this might sound like
a crazy thing to say,
but I don't think your brother
jumped on his own.
-Someone...
-Don't be absurd!
-I'm sorry.
-Please, take her away.
Officer, take her away.
I'm sorry, Doctor.
We need to identify the body.
-Is your brother coming?
-No, I will.
-Are you sure?
-I'll go.
You stay with Mom.
-Okay.
-Please, stay with her.
Okay.
Mom, we have to go.
All these books...
Get some bags.
We'll take some books with us.
We can't take them now, Mom.
Maybe tomorrow.
I'll take care of it.
Just a few.
Mom!
Please! Calm down!
Calm down!
Mom!
That's enough.
Stop it.
Mom, calm down!
I should have noticed.
I didn't realize.
Maybe I did see it coming,
but...
I'm eating with Guilia.
I could have stopped it.
At the door.
He turned and looked at me.
And I...
closed the door
and nothing,
I erased it.
Now there's nothing.
The staircase of his building,
the sawdust on the ground,
the books, the lady downstairs...
I should have stopped them.
I loved them both,
but...
I wasn't able to
enclose them
with my love.
It was my idea of freedom.
I thought everyone had the right
to live as they pleased.
But what freedom is there
in death?
What happened?
Did it really happen?
Because I...
I don't believe it.
I know it's real
when I look at Mom.
Just as well you're here.
Not for long.
I requested a transfer to Sicily.
I leave in a month.
Sicily?
They need people.
No one wants to go.
You know, I still have
a postcard of yours from 1966
in Cape North.
It was written in Norwegian,
I think.
And below the translation reads:
"Everything that exists
is beautiful."
With three exclamation points.
Do you still believe that?
Not in exclamation points
anymore.
Listen, Giovanna.
Giulia's in Rome.
I'll be seeing her tomorrow.
She wants to see Sara.
She wants Francesca to take her.
But I decided to go myself.
-I won't listen to this.
-I'll say it again.
-Giulia wants to see Sara.
-Would you shut up?
Not this time!
Tomorrow morning.
-At the Coliseum at ten.
-What do you want me to do?
You think it's easy for me?
To ask you to catch her
and lock her up?
What do you think
I should do?
Wait until someone gets killed?
Wait till she gets killed?
Come on, let's go!
Dr. Carati? Excuse me.
Giorgia wants to talk to you.
No, tell her I can't.
Francesca.
All right, bring her out.
I'll wait here.
How should I tell her?
How?
Go on.
Be strong.
Giorgia,
I have something to tell you.
Something bad
has happened.
I had Giulia sent to prison.
I'd thought that...
I think that
it's
the best for her,
especially for her.
This was
her choice, and I think...
it's for the best.
There's something else
I wanted to tell you.
Matteo...
Matteo!
"I wander along the tracks
of the eternal void,
fleeing from this fateful day
leaving behind the hordes of care
that torment me.
And as I contemplate peace,
the warrior spirit
that roars within me sleeps."
Shall I comment?
The sonnet "At dusk"
is an inspirational work
by Ugo Foscolo, containing
the wonderful onomatopoeia:
"The warrior spirit
that roars within me."
The onomatopoeia is contained
in the Italian "r" and "th" :
"The warrior spirit
that roars within me."
You can practically hear
the roaring soul of the poet.
Sit down, Berardi.
Sit down.
Adriana?
How are the kids doing
in French?
Fine.
-Your wife has been informed.
-We're not married.
She refuses to see you.
Say that her daughter's here.
Tell her I'm not leaving
until I see her.
All right.
Where's Sara?
Outside with Giovanna.
I'll bring her in.
First I need to talk to you.
I won't leave you alone.
-You're in here, but...
-I can't hear you.
You remember right before
Sara was born?
The way we argued?
We'd say:
"It's just a piece of paper."
Well, I think
it's more than that.
Giulia,
I want you to be my wife.
You hear me?
I want to marry you.
Giulia, please.
Marry me.
I'm proposing.
Giulia!
Giulia, please!
Now you listen to me.
Don't come here anymore.
Don't bring Sara.
Don't write...
Just leave me alone.
-Wait, I'll bring in Sara!
-I can't see her.
-Of course you can!
-I don't want to!
She wants to see you!
She can't remember your face.
She was four years old!
You have to see her!
Please, Giulia!
Please, please!
-I can't...
-Yes, you can.
You can, you can.
Come on, Giulia.
We'll wait a second.
She can't see you crying.
All right?
Thank you.
Sara!
Sara, honey, look at me.
How you've grown, Sara!
Look at me, sweetie.
-Weren't you blond?
-I can be blond again.
SPOLETO
MAXIMUM SECURITY PRISON
Monfalco! You've got mail!
SPRING OF 1992
Monfalco, you've got mail.
My love,
I'm sending you something
only you can read.
Ma'am!
Return to sender.
Come on, Sara!
Come on, Sara, let's go!
Ready!
Go.
Come on, Sara!
You see this medal?
It's from a swimming
competition in 1964.
This way you have
at least one.
Are you kidding me?
I want my own.
I should have won.
I always beat her in practice.
Go on, eat.
I'm going to Milan tomorrow.
-Can you stay at Alessia's?
-To do what?
To serve as an expert.
A suicide attempt
in a prison.
-I've been named a judge.
-Who is it?
The manager of a public company.
The defense requested
his release.
-They say he's going crazy inside.
-They steal and then they complain.
How do you know?
He's where he belongs.
He should have been more careful.
-Why do you say that?
-People get into trouble
and then we pay for it.
Why don't you ask me
what I'm thinking?
Because I know.
I know when you think
of your mom.
Others without kids
can do whatever they want.
Not her.
I think your mom
knows that.
That's why she feels guilty.
She should.
She deserves it.
-She didn't kill anyone.
-Because you stopped her.
She won't see me.
She can't.
All right,
what do I care?
But what about you?
You write her
and she doesn't answer.
You visit her and she won't see you.
You piss me off
more than she does.
-What should I do?
-Find someone else.
My friends are crazy about you.
Alessia, for example.
Don't you like her?
-What are you talking about?
-You have gotten older.
I have?
You've got a belly.
You should be careful.
Are you still in love with her?
I don't know.
I think you are.
I read your last letter...
-You what?
-By accident.
It was on the table.
It's obvious
you still think about her.
-I don't want you to.
-If you don't mind,
I'd like to handle
my own affairs, all right?
Fine, sorry.
Did we just have a fight?
No, we didn't.
You and I never fight.
No? Why's that?
Because I love you too much.
You don't tell me very often.
There's a lot
I don't tell you.
For example?
I've decided to move to Rome.
With Francesca and Carlo.
I want to study Restoration.
You'd have to check
with them first.
It's already done.
Would it upset you
if I leave?
I know, but I'm leaving anyway.
Idiot.
Tell me one thing.
You can't speak,
or you won't?
I was summoned by the court.
Your lawyer approved.
Do you agree
with this decision?
Say yes or no.
I know you have a daughter.
So do I.
With kids, the shame of
being in prison is unbearable.
But our kids are much stronger
than we are, much more alive.
They have too much to discover
to be torn apart
by what their fathers do.
Or mothers.
Are you here to decide
if I'm nuts?
Let's just say your lawyer
wouldn't mind at all.
My wife and daughter
don't know the truth.
Until yesterday,
I didn't either.
You didn't know
you'd committed a crime?
You work in a hospital,
right?
There must be companies there
paying commissions.
Normally five or ten percent.
Is it possible
you never noticed?
Or it occured to you,
but you looked the other way,
like millions of Italians.
Then one day a judge appears.
And says the commissions
aren't commissions anymore.
Now they're called bribes.
And that financing political
parties is illegal.
That I'm a thief.
Now that's news!
Prison isn't just for
poor people stealing apples
anymore.
Now there's real justice.
They forget that
they were lining up to pay.
Buying favors,
pulling strings, eliminating
competition.
Now they want to change
the world.
Believe me, doctor.
Nothing has changed.
It's all a lie.
They only lock up
idiots like me
who get caught.
But the others,
and there are plenty...
keep doing the same:
stealing comfortably.
It's Italy.
I didn't make it.
And neither did you.
It's the Italy our fathers created,
believe me.
No, not my father.
Believe me.
Your father was a good person.
And you like being one, too,
right?
-Have you got a catalogue?
-Sure.
Here.
Thank you.
-Are the photos for sale?
-Yes, most of them.
-"Most"?
-Well...
The one from the billboard isn't.
Where was this?
What was he doing?
Have you asked?
No, the person who took it
wasn't there.
Here's the name.
It's a woman.
Look... Mirella Uta.
Maybe it was for her.
What was?
The eyes.
Maybe it was for her.
Who could she be?
Who knows when she met Matteo.
How does she know him?
Why do you ask?
She probably passed him
on the street.
You're wrong.
They talked.
If you like the book
you can keep it.
But I want you
to go and meet her.
Who?
Her, Mirella.
I want you to talk to her.
How will I find her?
What for?
-Because I said so.
-You're not my boss.
I do what I think is right,
and this isn't.
Are you offended?
Do you do as I say?
Have I asked you to leave?
How many times have I told you
to move in
with EIda and Gina?
Do you listen to me?
-I'm better here.
-No, you're not.
You think you are,
but you're not.
To know for sure you have
to try living on the outside.
We're releasing everyone,
and you insist on staying.
You're not nice anymore.
You've changed.
You're not even good.
You were, but not anymore.
You were nice, but not anymore.
And they complain
that people don't pay taxes!
They've already paid too much,
way too much!
Excuse me!
-The station chief?
-In back on the right.
-Thanks.
-You're welcome.
Where were you going?
To find who took the photo.
What for?
To talk to her.
I worked it out
with the police.
We can go.
We can go, can't we?
But I won't take you back
to the clinic.
-No, Nicola, I can't.
-Yes, you can.
-No, no, no...
You're already out.
You have Marcello's jacket on.
Marcello's wondering:
"Where's my jacket?"
You took the tramway,
all by yourself.
You're already out.
I won't take you back.
That's the house.
Are the others awake?
I think so.
A bus will be coming by
to take them to work.
You think I can do it?
You already have,
don't you see?
Then thank you.
Don't thank me.
Matteo's the one who convinced you
to leave the clinic.
This is a gift from him.
-Come and visit me.
-Of course I will.
I'll come and visit
every once and a while.
Come on, smile!
This is a big day.
Aren't you happy?
Go on.
-Come with me.
-No, I won't.
Get your bag, ring the bell
and they'll open the door.
-Here, you keep it.
-No, I gave it to you.
On the last page
they list the title
of each photo.
Matteo's is number seven.
-Hi, Giampiero.
-Hi, Giorgia.
Sev...
en.
MATTEO WHEN HE WAS NICOLA
Of course, but...
isn't there a way
to locate her?
I see.
Thanks anyway.
Goodbye.
I talked to the agency, but
she doesn't live in Milan
anymore.
She moved to Palermo
to cover the massacre.
What are you talking about?
They've killed Judge Falcone.
PALERMO
MAY 25TH, 1992
Your honor!
-Where are you going?
-To see Doctor Carati.
Not today.
You'll have to leave.
-I'm her brother, Nicola Carati.
-Can't you see what's going on?
Please go away.
There's Rosaria,
Vito Schifano's widow.
Rosaria wants...
She wants to talk as well.
She approaches the Cardinal.
Quiet everyone!
Tell everyone that the Lord
will punish them.
-Well...
-He'll punish them.
They'll burn in hell,
or even worse!
-Let's hope they convert.
-Come here.
You said it yourself.
-You tell them!
-You just did.
-If they convert...
-There is hope.
-They'll be forgiven.
-No...
The crowd has noticed
the coffins being brought out.
They gather around...
The moment has arrived
to pay homage.
Homage to Giovanni Falcone,
Francesca Morvillo,
Antonio Montinaro,
Vito Schifano,
Rocco di Cillo.
"Life is worth a button,"
said Giovanni Falcone.
I'm a Sicilian, a real Sicilian.
It's not necessary, thanks.
Wait here.
Hi!
I knew you were here,
but things have been a mess.
I saw you this morning.
I couldn't get close.
I'm tired.
We're all tired.
We don't even know
where to start.
I feel like hiding my head
like an ostrich.
You're no ostrich.
Why are you in Palermo?
I have to see someone.
Are you free for lunch?
I can't even have you over
to my place.
We have half an hour,
we have to stay here.
How's Mom?
And Francesca?
I haven't been to Rome
in ages.
And Sara?
Sara has turned into
a beautiful girl.
She always was.
How's your lovelife?
And yours?
I'm the judge here.
I ask the questions.
Hello?
Thanks for calling.
Yeah, fine.
Tomorrow, yes.
Where?
All right. Good night.
It's not what you think.
We educate our children
to respect others.
We instill a sense of duty.
We instill a sense of justice.
We instill morality.
We teach them not to beg for
what is ours by right.
We instill resistence
to the mafia.
We must never forget
Giovanni Falcone.
all those killed by the mafia.
We must always
remember them
as our own family.
We must love each other
like brothers.
We must defend our love
by example.
Sorry to keep you waiting,
but I have to develop them
this afternoon.
We'll talk later.
Aren't you bored?
Thank you.
The photo you saw
was taken here.
Right here.
It was very different.
There were orange tablecloths.
Had you known him long?
Five minutes.
He said his name was Nicola.
Later, in Rome...
I don't know why,
but he never told me his real name.
I found out for myself.
I found out that last day.
When...
The next night I left.
I went home.
I wanted to come back
to the island
to find some silence.
So you saw him again in Rome?
A few hours before...
I'm sorry.
I can't.
Neither can I.
I still can't talk to anyone
about it.
I'm sorry.
I have to leave soon.
How can you live on an island
with your job?
I don't work much.
Enough to get by.
Whenever necessary.
When there's important stuff,
like today.
Are you going back to Turin?
Yes, tonight.
Back to my daughter.
You have a daughter?
Her name is Sara.
She's 18 years old.
Next year
she'll study Restoration.
-She's all grown up.
-Yeah, she is.
Have you got kids?
One.
He's seven and a half.
He starts third grade
in September.
His name is Andrea.
And he's as handsome as Matteo.
-Morning!
-Good morning.
-Can I help you?
-No, it's okay, sir.
-Sir?
-Nicola!
Mom, you look like
a poor old lady!
I am a poor old lady!
Why's it so dark?
-I don't like the light.
-It's like a dungeon in here.
-Or a funeral parlor.
-I can't be bothered to open them.
-Without Giovanna...
-I'll do it.
-Let there be light!
-Don't make such a fuss.
Come on, look what
a nice day it is.
-No, please...
-Look at that sun!
I have something to tell you.
It's wonderful news.
It's about Matteo.
One of those unpredictable things
he used to do.
In Palermo I met a woman,
Mirella.
She had an relationship
with Matteo.
-A relationship?
-Yeah, they were in love.
Mirella had a child
after Matteo had already died.
His name is Andrea.
And I think he'd like to meet
his grandmother.
A boy?
Yes, Mom. A boy.
The train to Naples
leaves in an hour.
We can catch the ferry to Sicily
from there.
Wait a second.
What's wrong, Mom?
You want a glass of water?
I...
I can't.
I'm not ready.
What do you mean?
-How do you know it's true?
-It's true, Mom.
I saw him.
Why didn't she say anything
after all this time?
Why didn't she write?
We think bad news is normal,
but good news is hard to believe.
Come on, Mom!
-Let's go.
-I can't.
Come on, Mom.
Sara wants to move in with
Carlo and Francesca.
I know,
we talked about it.
So I'm the last one
to hear about it. Great.
-Do you mind?
-No, of course not.
On the contrary.
I understand.
Sara needs a home
with a mother in it.
And Francesca
is a great mother.
Thanks, sweetie.
Why?
For never being jealous
of your siblings.
Not my siblings.
But there is someone...
-Who?
-Your students.
-You're jealous of my kids?
-Yeah, of your kids.
You took them to museums,
you brought them home,
corrected their homework...
You loved them more than us.
I had to replace their families.
At home their parents
never talked to them.
So you talked to them.
I talked to them.
And I should have
talked more to you.
Mom, that's enough.
Mom, don't look at me like that.
Don't speak Milanese,
you're awful at it.
How did you adapt to Rome?
I loved it from the start.
That decrepit air...
Rancid, stuffy...
All those cynical people,
so rude...
It's just full of irony.
-You know how I met your dad?
-No.
In the market.
Back then he used to sell
vegetables, produce...
He'd bring them from Naples,
one of his businesses.
There he was,
at the orange stand,
with a sign:
"Spanish oranges."
And I said:
"Are they really Spanish?"
And he said: "Ma'am,
can't you hear the castanets?"
-And what did you do?
-Nothing, I...
I bought the oranges
and married him.
Andrea, they're here.
Hello.
Hello...?
Hello, Grandma.
-Hello.
-Hi, uncle!
Your grandma said "hello."
Stop crying.
I think they're getting along.
I wanted to say...
Thank you.
-What for?
-For letting us come.
-It's normal.
-You could have said no.
Oh, come on!
-Where's your school?
-There.
-That's the high school?
-No, it's in Lipari.
-Where's Lipari?
-There. But it has no volcano.
-Are you afraid of the volcano?
-No.
-What are you afraid of?
-Nothing.
How lucky!
I'm afraid of lots of things.
For example,
I was afraid to come here.
-You're afraid of the sea?
-Yes.
-You can't swim?
-That might be it.
It's easy, I'll teach you.
"I speak of the faith
that had never left him,
not even when he was
on the verge of desperation.
The faith that comes
from experience.
He continued on,
as if telling himself
about his own bravery
and talent.
Everything seemed so clear..."
Keep reading!
"So clear that in his mind
his tone of voice never changed."
They're photos...
photos of Matteo.
I couldn't look at them again.
I've tried many times.
My hands shake.
You keep them.
Andrea will be curious
to see what his father looked like
as a boy.
Can we look at them together?
-Goodbye.
-Thanks for everything.
-Bye.
See you soon, eh?
Let's go, Mom.
I'll miss your eyes.
No crying, eh?
Don't make me nervous
or I'll smack you one.
Why don't you stay?
-What?
-There's plenty of room.
I'd really like that.
And so would Andrea,
right?
Yeah, Grandma, stay!
Stay, you heard them.
-I have to clothes.
-You have lots of stuff.
Have Francesca send
anything else you need.
-You think?
-Sure.
Mom, can't you hear
the castanets?
Can't you hear them?
You know which is the gas?
The one on the right!
Relax, Mom.
I've got it covered.
There's lots of hats.
What do I do with them?
I'll keep them.
I didn't put in
the flower dress.
No, hold on. She wants it.
I'll get it for you.
-Here.
-Thanks.
Hi, Grandma.
Great. I'm learning Roman.
Yeah, and how are you?
Good. Grandma,
about the flower dress...
Are you sure you need it?
It's in fashion again.
But on you it would
look ordinary, right.
You're awful!
Why do you want to look older
than you really are?
-That's enough.
-Not if I wear it.
-Francesca agrees.
-It looks great on her.
-Go on, tell Grandma.
-No, really.
You remember that photo
with Dad in Capri?
Are you ready?
Are you sure
it looks good on me?
Yeah, you look great.
Though with heels who knows...
I can't stand up in heels.
Hurry up, the kids
are getting out of school.
-Can I drive?
-You'd better not.
-Come on, let me!
-No, please.
Thank you.
I like this place.
It's falling apart.
Too much work.
-But it's pretty.
-You have to take care of yourself.
I'll talk to the owner.
Yeah, talk to the owner.
-When's the break over?
-Professor!
Slavery doesn't exist!
-Since Lincoln!
-You hear?
What hard workers!
"Parrari picca,
travagghiari assai."
-Less talking and more working.
-Got it?
You're bringing him up right,
Professor!
TUSCANY, VAL D'ORCIA
SPRING OF 1995
Here we are.
Well?
A minute of silence
before this poetry, eh?
What? Don't look at me
like that,
it's one of the most beautiful
places in the world.
-The view is amazing.
-Just as well, because...
-Is this it?
-It's made of clay.
-It's in ruins!
-Come on, boys.
Use your imagination!
Men of little faith,
with no imagination. This way.
Well?
Two, three brilliant solutions.
-Brilliant?
Look at these cracks!
Bigger than my hand!
-It needs to be rebuilt.
-The foundation is cracked!
Yeah, but I called you,
Micavi Construction.
But if we rebuild over clay...
Here, a beam.
Red ceramic tiles,
like the square in Siena.
You been there?
All you do is complain?
What are you complaining about?
You make a fortune!
-Now you're the owner!
-All I have is debts.
No, the owners always complain.
That's enough of that!
The windows are okay
where they are.
I'd use aluminum...
-Not aluminum!
-Aluminum!
-You'll kill him!
Look at the kitchen.
It's amazing.
Francesca wants a big kitchen.
Look at that chimney.
It's magnificent.
Here's the bathroom...
And the kids' bedroom...
Every room has
its own bathroom.
Every room.
Here's another office...
Or whatever.
Let's see what
you come up with.
And here's the problem:
these basins.
I don't know if I should keep them.
What do you think?
That doesn't matter.
The problem is
you need a layer of aeration...
The floors, original handmade
fired clay.
You know what that costs?
I want original handmade
fired clay.
Micavi.
It's an official request.
Micavi Construction,
can it be done?
Look at that.
Goddamn it!
Can it be done?
Well, it depends.
If you ask me with the respect
I'm due,
maybe we can oblige.
Where's that wood!
I'm starving!
Coming, one second!
You sound like a boss!
You know there's a boy
chasing after Sara?
Yeah, Francesca told me.
-What's he like?
-He comes over every day.
-Every day?
-Every day.
He picks her up,
takes her to school...
-Brings her home at night...
-At least he brings her home.
-He brings her home.
-Thank God.
What's he like?
Is he a good kid?
Yeah, like us at his age.
That's comforting, thank you.
-You'll soon be a granddad.
-Hey, watch it!
-Grandpa, where are you?
-Don't provoke me!
-Come on, we're hungry.
-We need to start a fire.
Carlo, grab a newspaper.
-We'll make a fire.
-My newspapers?
-Your newspapers.
-Go find one.
Hello?
Giulia, where are you?
No, she's at school.
She'll be back later.
Hello?
-Can I park it here a minute?
-Just a minute.
Thanks, I'll be right back.
Hi.
-Shall I call her?
-No.
-Won't you come over?
-No, I'm leaving.
Who's that?
Mimmo, her boyfriend.
-I have to go.
-Wait a second.
-Don't tell her you saw me.
-Why?
-Please.
-I'll give you a ride.
No, stay here.
I can take you.
Stay here.
You mustn't inhibit his gestures.
It would be like saying
they're senseless.
They might make sense to him,
you understand?
Yes. It seems impossible to me.
Nothing's impossible.
Yeah, but I don't know
what to do.
Try to find the sense in them.
Nothing more.
It's like deciphering
hieroglyphics.
But in the end we managed
to decipher them, right?
We'll have the usual meeting.
-Call the others.
-We'll meet you inside.
No, let's do it out here,
under that tree.
Bien, my dear children,
see if you can guess
this animal.
Now my assistent,
Giacomo,
will do his mime for us.
Please.
Very particular.
This is a very difficult animal,
and Giacomo displays
his great gift for mime.
-A lizard!
-No, but close.
It's an animal that slithers...
that slithers...
-A worm!
-Not a worm.
-It slithers, but not a worm.
-A snail!
Not a snail.
It's not poisonous.
And let's say it's...
It's very smooth.
-A caterpillar!
-No, it's smooth, so it's a...
-A snake!
-Good, a snake!
Giacomo did a marvelous job.
After huge success in Monaco,
Paris and London
our very own Giacomo
will now perform his last mime!
This is a very difficult animal.
-A hare!
-Not a hare.
Nicola, shall I leave
your mail in your office?
No, I'll read it here.
The mail has arrived.
-A fox!
-No.
No certificate...
A postcard from Giorgia.
A mouse!
A letter...
But there's a mistake.
This letter is for
Doctor Nicola Carati.
-Who's that?
-You!
-Me?
-Yeah, you!
You're right!
Jesus, I always forget!
-You read it, Giacomo.
-He doesn't know how!
-Sure he does, you'll see.
-I know how to read!
He knows how, too.
No, I'll open it, because
the glue
is particular.
There.
You read it.
So everyone can hear.
Silence!
An important letter!
"Dear Nicola:
I would have preferred
not to write
this letter.
You mother
has passed away.
She didn't suffer,
she went in her sleep
very quietly.
I write you
now
because
she made me promise
that when
she was gone
I wouldn't
bother
anyone.
A kiss.
See you soon.
Mirella."
Good, Giacomo.
You read great.
Very good.
Is there sea where my dad
is buried?
No, not closeby.
You should bring him.
Near the sea.
You're right.
I'll bring him.
I promise.
What was he like?
Him?
He was like Achilles.
You know who Achilles was?
Your grandma must have told you.
He was brave and sad like him.
He hoped the gods
would take him away early.
You know how the gods are.
The best people,
the ones they love most,
are sent to Earth
and later taken away.
But they leave a mark
so that we don't forget them.
You're that mark.
This morning, looking at the atlas,
you looked just like him.
We did the same thing, long ago.
We looked at an atlas,
because we wanted
to take a trip.
We had to go somewhere far away,
where there was only sea.
That place was called
Cape North.
Where's that?
There.
And did you go?
I tried, but didn't make it
all the way.
Your dad wanted to go,
but in the end
he lost interest.
The gods were calling him.
Yeah, the gods
were calling him.
-Why don't you stay longer?
-I have to leave today.
Tomorrow the kids
have a test.
-I don't want to go back.
-Then stay.
I'll take you to France,
to Greece,
to Africa,
wherever you want.
Go on, choose.
Will it be another 3 years?
No, of course not.
It's great to see you,
Andrea...
SPRING OF 2000
It's definitely beautiful.
Beautiful?
It's sublime!
A paradise.
We told him when we saw it.
I told him right away:
" Buy this house."
-He didn't want to.
-And we insisted.
-So we said: " Buy it."
-And convinced him.
Look at that orchard!
It's new!
-He even put in palm trees.
-In front?
They're small, but...
You made a nice little sum
on this project, eh?
Money off my friends?
You never make money
off of friends.
-No, in spirit.
-In spirit, right.
In the spirit of giving
without receiving.
But they're driving me crazy.
Your sister is worse
than he is.
Watch what you say
about my sister.
I'll come after you.
She wants the roof tiles darker
so the match the...
-She has her reasons, right?
-Fine, but...
Your car can barely make it...
It's getting old.
Like us.
Carlo!
-Francesca!
-Is anyone home?
Observe, please...
observe the arch.
-Wonderful.
-This...
-The orchard.
-My favorite place.
Very Japanese...
Sara!
-Your daughter's getting married?
-Yeah.
Are you happy?
-So tell me.
Did he ask your permission?
He did.
With lots of respect.
He's a good kid.
Good.
He needs a haircut.
You're right.
Look at this opening!
It's magnificent.
A great work
by a great artist.
You're like Brunelleschi,
Leon Battista Alberti!
Some day this will all be yours.
Thanks.
Let's go for a swim.
-A swim?
-You bring a suit?
-You seen my gut?
-Give me a one-piece.
All I have is a thong, but...
We're glad you could make it.
So are we.
It's amazing here.
That's why I invited you.
-Is everything okay?
-Yes.
-And you?
-Fine, fine.
Are you glad your daughter's
getting married?
Very much.
-Are you happy?
-Yes.
Everything's okay?
-Good.
I'm going to talk to your son.
-I'll leave you two.
-See you later?
-Bye.
Well?
-How are you?
-Fine.
Good answer. Concise,
brief.
Growing a beard?
Or have you just not shaven?
How do I look?
What matters
is what the girl you like
thinks of it.
That I don't know.
Then ask her.
What's she like?
Pretty?
-Very.
-Have you told her?
-It's not easy.
-I know.
But tell her anyway.
First tell her she's pretty,
then tell her so are you.
-What does that mean?
-You're handsome.
The question is whether you look
better with or without the beard.
Is she funny?
I don't think so.
-Forget plan A. Plan B.
-Jump her bones?
How could I tell my nephew
to do such a thing?
What's her name?
-Ermione.
-Ermione?
Jump her bones.
Get out of here!
I couldn't.
I know you couldn't.
-Let go.
-No, I won't!
The happy couple.
-Such beautiful curls!
-Leave him alone, Dad.
Fine, I won't touch.
I need to talk to you.
Come on.
What is it?
Sara, my love:
I'm working in Florence,
at the library.
The other day I saw a newspaper
from 1966
and I found a photo.
I thought you might want
to see what your mom and dad
looked like as kids.
You were born of the love
between two happy people,
and all the sadness
that came after
had nothing to do with you.
I'm trying to start over,
far away from everyone.
I know my presence bothers you,
and I hate to bother anyone.
It came a few days ago.
That's you and Mom, right?
In Florence, in 1966.
What do I do?
It depends how strong you are.
-Are you happy?
-Of course!
Then it's time to be generous.
Goodbye!
IN MEMORY OF THE AID
GIVEN TO FLORENCE
BY YOUTHS FROM ITALY
AND ABRO AD
AFTER THE FLOODS IN 1966
Mom!
Giulia!
Sara.
Mom!
Mom, have you got a bed?
Yeah, mine,
but it's small.
We'll squeeze in.
I'd rather sleep here.
I don't feel like driving.
-Hello.
-Yes?
-Can you take our picture?
-Sure.
Here goes.
Move your heads closer.
Say "cheese."
-There.
-Thanks.
-You're welcome.
-Arigato.
"Arigato."
Let's go do a little shopping.
For my new house.
Where can we go...?
There's lots of stuff here.
This could be for bread,
but it's too sad for me.
These would be okay
for plate settings.
I don't know.
For pots...
Something brighter,
that stands out.
What's that?
A cast to make hats.
-Can we have a look?
-Sure.
Thank you.
It's the famous
"Maestro di Santo Spirito."
Two brothers painted it,
Domenico del Mazziere's sons,
Agnolo and Donnino.
But I like Donnino
much better,
I think he painted the baby.
Look at it.
It's beautiful.
"ll Maestro de la Conversazzione
di Santo Spirito."
And this is one of
Maso di Banco's greatest works.
My favorite.
All these virgins with babies...
Why do you like them so much?
You're pregnant!
Nobody knows yet.
How can I help?
There is one thing you can do.
-What?
-Play for me.
-Where? How?
-There's an organ.
I haven't played in ages.
I can't.
Besides, we'd have
to ask for permission.
Fine, forget it.
I ask only one thing of you,
and you can't because
we have to ask permission?
You wanted to change
the world and now you need
permission to play?
Right.
Let's go.
One more?
No. I'm dead.
I'll abstain.
Give me a hand,
I need a crane.
-Slowly...
-Easy.
-What are we doing?
Careful.
This way,
the exit's over here.
However...
you
should get one thing
straight in your mind.
-Should I?
-Go ahead.
I will.
Stop thinking of your brother
Matteo as an obstacle.
If you continue to think of him
as an obstacle
you'll end up hating him.
Are you drunk?
Yes. Good night.
However...
However.
-It's okay.
-There was a thigh there.
You made a mess.
Sure you won't come
to the wedding?
No, I'll come visit
when the baby's born.
You promise?
Good.
Do you always wear those?
The sunglasses?
You look better without.
-Bye.
-Bye, sweetie.
-Good morning.
-Morning.
-Hi.
Hi.
You want some coffee?
Yes, thank you.
-Have you had breakfast?
-Yes. Some milk?
Yes, thank you.
Did you sleep
in your clothes?
No, I didn't sleep.
Are you worried
about something?
Sara?
No, not at all.
That time, on the boat,
I wanted to kiss you.
Me, too.
NORWAY
SPRING OF 2003
Dear uncle...
or should I call you Dad?
Anyway...
Dear Nicola:
We finally made it.
Sometimes I think I recognize
the places described to me
when I was a kid.
Maybe it's just a fantasy.
It's nice doing things
with the people you love,
even though Ermione
is very stubborn
and always changing her mind.
Are they all like that?
Why not?
Where are you going?
Go on!
Come on, please!
Come here!
I convinced Ermione to take a flight
with me to Cape North.
She's terrified,
but it'll save us three days.
I see the midnight sun
fall to the horizon,
but then it stops
and never reaches the sea.
I remember my father,
my mother and you,
how you always say
that everything is beautiful.
I think you're right.
Everything is really beautiful.