greetings from cudencuden. Shout out to my cuz in Jamaica Queens.
Subtitle by
Aldi Arman
With all things in this world, we must make a decision
For example, when there's no more love
You can either forget about her
Or let her forget bout you
I specializes in capturing demons
One day, Master told me to catch a spirit in the mountain
By then I understood.
It wasn't about my kungfu skills
But it was about my mind
Killing is not where the spirit's most dangerous
It's that they make you
Lose control
I am "Tiểu Thiến" >.<, and you're?
"Yến Xích Hà"
What is this, it's so good?
Candy
I want to eat it forever
I didn't buy that much
Then I'll fall in love with whoever buys me them
Human and spirits cannot be together?
Then just kill me
Kill!
From here on out
I won't be in pain anymore
Because
You won't remember me
"Yến Xích Hà",
Attack her fatal point!
Cut off my hand!
Seal it with the enchanted weapon
Hurry!
Wait till the day I break the seal..
That will be your funeral day!
Losing one arm is nothing
But I've lost 3 of my brothers
"Yến Xích Hà"
You don't deserve to be a Spirit Master
I've think it through,
Human and spirits can't coexist
So I repressed our memories
To make her forget about our love
To make her forget about me forever
But I couldn't have known that
When that young man entered "Black Mountain"
The story between me and her then continues
translated by cudencuden via viet sub from Blue Magic | bluemagic1407@hotmail.com
Eh, young blood! What you doing? Stealing water?
No, ... I'm not
Get him
Bring these stuff back too
Chief, these things are strange. \nWhat are they for?
You brought so many equipments here
Must be to steal our water
Cut off his hands!
Right!
This isn't "Black Mountain" village,\nBut "Black/Evil Mind" village
Unlawful, barbaric people
I'm an official of the government
Chief!
Make way
Chief, He's..
What's matter with you?
He's
What's your name?
I'm "Ninh Thái Thần"
"Ninh Thái Thần"
Our village is well known in the South
for these clay pots
They haven't been used much
because there isn't much water
Can't even raise livestocks
We need to find a water source
Right,
We wrote letters to the mayor
Asking for help
You're really our savior for coming here
Don't say that
I'm just a small official for the govt.
You guys call just call me "Ninh Thái Thần"
You're an official, we have to call you "Sir"
Right, right, "Sir" Ninh
What is this that I see hanging everywhere?
Of course, "charms" are for warding off evil
Get lost!
We hang them to pray for rain
It's to pray for rain
Everyone come here
Come greet "Sir" Ninh
"Sir" Ninh is our savior
I promise everyone
I will find a water source
If not I won't go back down
Good!
Order
Sir, the people are really grateful to you
Although, there's one thing I'd like to ask of you
Please say it
One, alone, cannot go find a water source
I need strong helpers
to go up the mountain
What? Up the mountain?
Is something wrong?
If you just go up the mountain, everything'd be fine
"Sir" Ninh, it's fine.
- It's alright, go back
"Sir" Ninh, please wait
I am "Thiết Nha"
I want to go up with you
Good. The more the merrier
Why do they have chains around their feet?
They all are prisoners
The Chief allowed them to do some good
Sir...Ninh
When I was little, my father and brother
Used to take me up the mountain all the time
on this road
If you don't leave markings
You'd get lost easily
Wait for me a little bit
Without you as a guide I'd be lost
Don't worry
With me here, everything's fine
Go
Careful, don't fall
My leg.
- At this rate,
We will all be handicapped before finding water
It's just a small injury, stop whining
When are we gonna get there
They'd walk more comfortable
If we lose the chains
Can't
They only committed small crimes and shouldn't be punished like this
What small crimes?
They're all murderers
Killed people?
If we aren't facing the death penalty
Whose dumb enough to go up here?
Lets go
It's alright, just be a little more careful
Not with these guys but what's up there
What's up there?
Nothing, just be a little more careful
Be careful
"Sir" Ninh, look
Dig a little deeper
Deeper
On the way here, it's nothing but dry/dead plants
But here's the vegetation is flourished
Might have water here
I think a water source might be found
That's excellent
You help me watch them
Don't worry
Don't be wasting time
Here's candy for you
"Sir" Ninh
God, why's it like this?
Not sure
Let's go back. Can't stay when it's dark like this
You crazy? It's a long way back
Any place we can stay temporarily?
There's a shrine up ahead
Let's pack up and go.
Hurry!
Don't be scared
There's water?
There's water in here
There's water
It's really water
Give me a hand
This is water
Drinkable?
What are you doing?
Finding out how deep it is
This might be the water source we're looking for
Good!
You guys achievement today is not that bad
Where's everyone?
I'll go look for them
Don't let them escape
What are you afraid of? Am I really ugly?
What are you doing miss?
Doing what all you mean likes to do
Miss, please, don't
Our elder used to teach us to "welcome guests enthusiastically"
You don't like it?
No, I've never tried before
I know
You haven't tried.
It doesn't mean you don't want it
You will like it
Miss ! Please don't!
You're so bad
I'm so sorry!
What is that?
What's what
It's jade charm for protection
Take it off so I can see it
Take it off
Here you go
Doesn't matter if you keep feeding
I'll beat it out of you guys
Hey
You scared me to death
You risked your live\nJust to get the charm back?
Are you sad? A gift from your lover?
My mom left me this
Hey, look at me
If you won't look at me\nThat means you're mad
I don't dare think that
Sir Ninh, we're in trouble
We were killed by demons
"Thiết Nha"
A killer! Run miss
Run!
We're fight again another time
His skills are not bad
Who'll see who's better
Can't go there, go here
Why're we back where we start?
What?
That bearded guy is here
You follow me
He will come back
Sit down
"Black Mountain" is really full of evil/strangeness/mystery
We're gonna spend the night here
Why not find something to do?
Doing what
Strange
Not even a tiny scent
What scent?
"He's a good person"
Oh yeah
Miss
What's it?
That killer is still around
Be real careful
Stay here longer,
It's safer here
Are you really scared of dying?
What's your name?
"Ninh Thái Thần"
I'm "Tiểu Thiến"
I have something for you
What is it?
Sugar candy, it's good
You like it?
It's all yours
Don't know when I have a chance
To treat you to candy again
Running all night is really tiring
Wake me in the morning
God's Vision!
Look
"Yến Xích Hà", Man got his path, spirits got theirs
Why do you keep following me?
With I'm here, lets see if you can kill
Stop dreaming
When I get out...
If you get out, you demon!
What are you doing scaring me from behind?
Can't believe you going back to "Lan Nhược Tự" by yourself
Aren't you scared?
What did you throw into the water earlier?
It's a torpedo/bomb
Torpedo/bomb?
Don't touch it
It'll blow
Thats amazing
If I'm right
This water will flow to the right place
Then "Black Mountain" village will have water
"Ninh Thái Thần" don't move\nStay quiet
Just pretend you don't hear and see anything
Why?
If you want to get out alive then listen to me
I don't know why us two get along so well?
Of course, cause we both don't like...
that "Tiểu Thiến"!
No wonder "Lady Elder"
say good things about her everyday
Already has a catch
so early in the day
"Tiểu Thiến", If this keeps up, how are we gonna survive?
You guys are late
He's mine
Why's there still breathing sound?
Wanna take my meal?\nKnow your place
What's so funny? The one "Lady Elder" hates most is you
Over 10 days and still no good food for "Elder Lady"
Let me teach you in place of her
Why are you still here? Get gone!
Go find good food for her
"Ninh", Run
They will kill you
Tricked us?
"Tiểu Thiến"
"Tiểu Thiến", "Tiểu Thiến"
Why did you come?
Go
Let me go!
I don't care who you are\nOr whether you die or not
But you cannot stay in "Black Mountain"
If they feast on you\nThey'll become stronger
My life'll become harder
Let me go...
Stay still if you don't wanna die
Where's he?
Who?
His name's "Ninh Thái Thần"
He got eaten by you
Don't you remember??
Then why did you save me?
I will kill you,
If you keep hurting people
I know you're a great Spirit Master
and won't let me go easily
I won't forget that you saved me today
I'm grateful and in your debt
You should forget
Don't move
You won't kill me
Want me to kill you this instance??
Right now, you're in more danger than me
What?
I won't kill you either
Bearded guy
Feel comfortable?
You only tie one of his leg up?
Don't you think he looks adorable tied like this?
Lets go
Sorry
Before I said that you're afraid to die
Really?
In reality, you're not afraid at all
If not you wouldn't come back to save me
Honestly, I am scared
Then why did you come back?
What will you do now?
I'm going back down
Down the mountain
Do you still have sugar candy?
Yes
"Tiểu Thiến", Come with me
Now that I've found the water source
I can take you sightseeing
- You want me to come along?
- Yes
It's a big world out there.
A lot bigger compared to "Black Mountain"
And it have many more delicious type of candy
And many other amazing things
Come with me?
"Tiểu Thiến"
"I'm hungry"
Bring that young man back
What is it?
It's getting dark
Follow me
Why are you walking so fast?
"Tiểu Thiến"
"I'm hungry"
"Hurry and bring the young man back"
Don't run so fast
Hold on to me tight
"Where are you going?"
"Tiểu Thiến"... "I'm hungry!"
"Tiểu Thiến", What makes you run so fast?
- It's only strong winds. - Don't ask!
"I'm hungry"
"Bring him back to me"
"Come back"
What are you doing?
I
I wanna give you a piece of candy
To trick me to follow you?
- "Tiểu Thiến". - Is that what you think of me?
It ain't like that
Go just go
But we made an agreement
You need to leave
- Shortie. - Whose your shortie?
Why did you change so quickly?
I like it!
- Go way. - I won't!
Go go go!
"I won't"
"Tiểu Thiến, why won't you come back?"
"Tiểu Thiến"
"You won't obey Lady Elder words?"
Chief, Sir Ninh is back
I told you "Sir" Ninh has 9 lives
"Sir" Ninh
Sir
Thank you, "Black Mountain" village now has water
Really?
Chief
Everyone can celebrate \nBut don't waste too much water
Don't waste the water!
Besides
Those that came with me are now missing
They were all facing the death penalty anyway!
Greatness comes with great sacrifices
Let's not talk about those things
Chief... Chief
"Thiết Nha"
"Thiết Nha", are you okay?
Chief, him and the "demon"
What "dees"?
Look at you, so dirty\nGo take a bath!
"Black Mountain" village now has water. Let's shower
Yes, shower. - Him and "dee.."
Demon!
Sir, you are right
We should be grateful\nWe can't be wasting water
We're just gonna party till dawn (lol)
Splash him!
Speak
Why did you let him go?
"Lady Elder"
I will find better food for you
You love him?
I just can't see myself hurting him
"Lady Elder" you once said "The difference between us and humans is"
"that spirits can do whatever they like"
I said that?
I did say that
But in this place, you can only listen
To what I say, Not actually do it
Here at "Lan Nhược Tự"
There's only one boss
That person is me
You all will never be reincarnated
So just focus on serving your master, ME!
Subtitle by
Aldi Arman
Come on
Savior, Drink one with me
I drank so much already
Oh yeah, this is my niece
Sit down
Greets "Sir" Ninh,
offer him a drink
- "Sir" Ninh, please drink one.
- Oh, I cannot drink anymore
I'll drink first
She can drink!
Sir Ninh, this is really good
No, let me do it
You guys take your time
Make sure you service him good
"Sir" Ninh, what are you looking at?
Nothing
Eat something
You know what my fav thing to eat?
Sugar candy
Okay, I'll go buy it
No
I'll go myself
I'll go
Where're you going?
Restroom
You gonna find candy in the restroom?
"Tiểu Thiến"
Stop right there
You misunderstood me
I'm the good guy
I saw you killed people at "Nhược Lan" Shrine
The ones I killed
They weren't people
You're a brutal murderer, you're the one not human
I know my appearance can mislead people
Listen to me, I'm a Spirit Master
Things I killed are all demons
Lies!
Why would I trick you?
You're saying "Tiểu Thiến" is a demon too?
Yes, she is a demon
She is not
She is
No
Yes
Let me down and I'll show you my "Demon Mirror"
Take it out
Why are you like that?
I'll help you get it
You know how to use it?
You just tricking me to untie you
You just don't want to face the truth
What you're doing
Just untie me, don't chop down the tree
That's enough, you can't even hold a sword right
Where're you going?
You tricked me to save you
Let me borrow your power from heavens and earth!
Didn't work, again
Why don't you have a look
Lan Nhược Tự is just a thousand years old spirit
You lucky you didn't die and could escape
Down the mountain is that way
Hey, where you going?
I don't believe in your trickery
I'll go find "Tiểu Thiến" myself
Are you crazy? I just said she's a demon
Don't tell me you like her
None of your beeswax
It is my business
You must forget about her
I cannot do it
You must turn back now, else it'd too late
Which way is to "Lan Nhược Tự"?
"Blinded by demons"
Okay! You wanna die I'll let you
"Lan Nhược Tự" is that way. Go ahead!
Have a safe trip, to your afterlife!
"Tiểu Thiến"
"Thiến"
Ninh
I'm a demon
I know
Want it?
I'll get you out of "Black Mountain"
- I have no strength.
- I'll carry you
"Tiểu Thiến", why's your entire body so cold?
I'm under "Lady Elder" spell.\nDon't look back
If you look back we will never make it out
Just let me down and run
I'd rather die here
Oh no
I'm under a spell
"Lâm - Binh - Đấu - Giả"
"Tĩnh"
With this tide
"Yến Xích Hà", you can't make it to land
Lets rest here for the night, we'll head out in the morning
Don't worry, they won't find out that you're a demon
It's so messy here, bare with me
I'll find a better place tomorrow
I'll be warmer when the fire's lit
Feel any better?
Let me find something for the cold
Is it better like this?
How's this? Any better?
"Ninh Thái Thần"
You really want to take me with you?
You're not afraid that I'm a demon?
"I'm scared of poverty yet I'm still poor"
"I'm scared of boredom, still I'm bored"
That's just fate
Things we don't like still comes to us
But I'm still worry
You'll be like the others and eat human flesh
They don't eat human flesh
But didn't your friends
Killed and ate those "Black Mountain" villagers at "Lan Nhược Tự?
They don't want to eat human flesh
They just want your "Soul / Chi"
I know those guys are innocent
If they weren't lustful
Then they won't emit a scent
"Lady Elder" won't be able to smell them
And we wouldn't have caught them
I don't have the scent that you talked about?
You're good person
We don't have a choice
That year, "Lady Elder" got sealed by a Spirit Master. Her "Chi" was damaged
"Lady Elder" put all of us under a spell
She made us gather "Chi" for her. So she can break the seal
We'll be punished if we disobey
Even death
Don't be afraid, I'll get you out of here
From now on, you don't need to worry anymore
"Tiểu Thiến", are you okay?
Were you hurt badly?
I'll go find a doctor, and medicine
It's Lady Elder's magic. It's no use
You can take my "Chi"
It'll help you recover
Take it
Are you any better now?
If you need any more, I still have enough
Take it
Why are you smiling?
I can smell it
What?
Right now you have that "scent"
What scent?
That's really it
The heaven is earth, the dimension is flipped
You demon you, that's the reason why
I'll break your spell
So dizzy
That little demon, think you can trap me?
You're up
I'll go fix something to eat
"Ninh""
It's nothing
"Nhiếp Tiểu Thiến"
I'll let you taste this barrel of dog's blood
You'll turn into your true form fo sho
"Tiểu Thiến"
You really scared of me?
I won't swallow you
You're not human
Lady Elder
Please spare me
You think that I'll hurt you?
The plead you said earlier
Really is what I have in mind
Even though
You took off without even saying goodbye
But I'm not as evil as you think
This time I'm here to
say goodbye to you
These past years, you mesmerize so many men
Now, you actually found one that mesmerizes you
I admire it
I'm honestly happy for you
But you have to remember 1 thing
Your fox's spirit is still at "Lan Nhược Tự"
You can't go anywhere without it
Warrior
You're still alive, that's great
Where is "Tiểu Thiến"
She's...
Ran away
Got away?
Eating that much by yourself?
I'm starving
Why's there 2 pairs of chopsticks
Trying to fool me, you're with her aren't you?
What did you two do?
We..
You sex seeking fiend!
There's demon's scent
Who's there besides "Tiểu Thiến"?
Nobody
I won't let you hurt "Tiểu Thiến"
"Thụ Yêu"?
Return to your "Black Mountain", You can't stay here
Don't you worry about it
You don't have a choice, lets go!
I say there's no need
"Ninh Thái Thần"
What "Ninh", lets go
Splashing dog's blood, what's the use?
It'll hurt more if you struggle, lets go
"Hạ Tuyết Phong Lôi", what're you up to?
I'm about to..
Running away demon?
retrieve
"Yến Xích Hà",
Just look at yourself
You call yourself a Spirit Master
But can't see what's right and wrong
Hanging around these demons everyday
You're something else
So what? Wanna keep fighting?
Think you can beat me?
I can't beat you?
Playing me?
Why are you really here?
I'm here to teach you a lesson
What so good about you?
After I retrieve the demon, \nI'll deal with you
You guys...look
I still beat you with my one arm only
If you wanna kill just kill
"Hạ Băng", retrieve the demon!
Demon...
"Tiểu Thiến"! I've come to save you
De..mon
Chief, it's a monster
It's alright, I'm here, don't worry
Your hand
"Hạ Băng", they're under the demon's spell
Everybody calms down
Chief, gather everyone here.\nWe've got a solution
Chief, what happened?
Are we gonna turn into monsters?
Think of something
Chief
Everyone quiet
I've something to discuss
This thing is grown from our body
The more we panic the faster it'll grow
Thus we must remain calm
You, how come you're okay?
How can I avoid it
There's two needle pine under here
Aching like crazy
Everyone calms down!
This isn't the antidote
But it'll temporarily stop the growing
Not letting them spread anymore
Everyone's water is poisoned
Infected with a thousand years old Demon's blood
Once the demon is eliminated, your symptoms would disappear
But who would get rid of her?
My brother, "Ha Tuyết Phong Lôi"
The best Spirit Master
"Hạ Tuyết Phong Lôi"
I'll pay the debt between you and me
How can you pay?
Cut off one of my hands, two hands if it's not enough
I know you want to go up "Black Mountain"\nI'll clear the way for you
I don't mind death because of you
Just look at yourself
Pleading and begging, just because of one demon
"Yến Xích Hà", you still won't change if you die
I haven't changed?
Don't I always keep watch over "Black Mountain"
You just keeping watch over her!
"Yến Xích Hà"
Who are you?
What is there between you and me?
I'm human, you're a demon
We got nothing between us two
You don't know him?
He turned into his pathetic self because of you
Now you say you don't know him?
I'll let you know
He's your lover
Are you finished?
That's impossible
You, you bastard is just
Taking nonsense
Tricking me
I'll bite you to death
Let me out
I'll bite you to pieces
What are you looking at?
After I'm done with him, I'll get you
Hear that? Demons will always be demons
I know you already know this.
No love, no mind, no heart no trust
That will never change
Just like you, selling out your comrades, disrespecting our Masters
"Despised by humans, hated by demons"
"Yến Xích Hà"
What've you got in the end?
Honestly, I was gonna use your blood to wash my sword
Then use it to capture "Thụ Yêu"
But now I've changed my mind
A useless person like you, even demons despise you
Killing you just make my sword dirty
You really like her huh?
I'll let you watch her...
Burn to ashes
I wanna eat it forever
Brother, let me go too
- No.
- I can help you
Help me collect body right??
Honestly, there won't be bodies to collect
After I destroy "Lan Nhược Tự",
I'll die with "Thụ Yêu"
That's the best ending
When I joined I've already said
"Shed blood but don't shed tears"
Spirit Masters cannot be too emotional
If not mistakes would be made
Like "Yến Xích Hà",
You just hurt yourself in the end
I understand, brother
"Tiểu Thiến"
"Thiết Nha", Is "Thiến" in there?
There's no "Thiến" here, only demons..get lost!
Go!
-"Tiểu Thiến"! - Go away!
Let...let me go
Don't copy what I say
I'm here to look for "Tiểu Thiến"
Keep dreaming!
You know she's a demon and still save her?
I don't care . I must save her
You can't go
Sorry
"Tiểu Thiến"
Let me down first
"Tiểu Thiến"...
"Ninh"
I must get you out
What are you doing?
You make one wrong move,
"Tiểu Thiến" will burn to a crisp
Let me down first
No, you will capture "Tiểu Thiến"
I can't free you
Idiot! You don't understand this trap
Can't be wasting time, If all the coins fall
"Tiểu Thiến" will be destroyed
Let me down
Hurry
Quickly
"Tiểu Thiến"
Why must you and my brother fight?
Why don't you guys use your skills to fight "Thụ Yêu"?
If "Thụ Yêu" is not destroyed, catastrophe will come
This village won't have a tomorrow
I can let this demon live
"Yến Xích Hà",
will you save the innocent villagers?
Must get to "Lan Nhược Tự" before dark\nHurry!
You're really going up the mountain?
You need to know clearly that "Lan Nhược Tự"
Has thousand years old "Thụ Yêu"
2 deadly poison "Snake Demon"
And many other demons
Don't say any more, I'm really scared
But because "Tiểu Thiến" is still there
I have to get it
"Ninh"
Don't worry about me
As long as we have your "Spirit"
You can escape "Thụ Yêu",
she won't be able to control you any more
I'll die with no regrets
Thinking back when I got sealed
The last I saw...is you!
Today, now that I'm free
First thing I saw...
Is you again!
I didn't think time flies that fast
The thing is...
You're now old
Not as old as your thousands year demon!
You forgot my name is "Mộc Cơ" ?
I've always wishes that
I can rip your heart and drink your blood
I can't believe you're that good to me
Taking yourself here
I really want to see how you die!
So stank! What is it?
My virgin urine
You still "got" it?
Still a virgin after these years, Tastes good right?
Brother
That's why I adore you so much
Bringing both your old and new love
You traitor will never escape "Lan Nhược Tự"!
"Ninh Thái Thần", go open the water pond
You'll find "Tiểu Thiến" spirit
Heaven's eyes
"Lâm Binh Đấu Giả! Trận Liệt Tại Tiền!" (magic chant)
"Ninh Thái Thần", quickly
Hurry! I can't hold any more
Hurry up!
So cold@
Are you heartbroken "Yến Xích Hà"?
"Tiểu Thiến" is a part of me
If I die, she'll die with me!
How do you open this magic staff?
"Lâm Trận Đấu Binh" (magic chant)
"Liệt Trận Tại Tiền" (magic chant) ... Open
Aren't you guys suppose to quick?
"Tiểu Thiến"
Lâm Binh Đấu Giả
Trận Liệt Tại Tiền (magic chant)
Break!
You demon!
"Yến Xích Hà"!
"Tiểu Thiến"
You are "Tiểu Thiến"?
Come here, come with me
Sugar candy
I'll take you out of here
You're heartbroken right?
I despise you Old Demon!
Calling me old?
Better than someone who can't turn old!
You really want to leave?
I'll let your man see you off, alright?
I want his own hands to kill his woman!
You demon
"Tiểu Thiến"
"Lâm Binh Đấu Giả" (magic chant)
"Trận Liệt Tại Tiền" (magic chant)
"Thần Binh"
"Yến Xích Hà"
It's candy
Then go head and kill me
You demon,
You and I will die together
"Yến Xích Hà"
Sorry
I let you remember me
If you can choose again
Would you still make me forget about you?
I understand
Hurry and get out!
"Lan Nhược Tự" is created with "Thụ Yêu" magic
When "Thụ Yêu" is destroy, it'll crumble
"Ninh Thái Thần"
Take "Tiểu Thiến" out of "Lan Nhược Tự"
Lets go
"Tiểu Thiến", come on
Brother
If not we won't make it, hurry
"Ninh"
I won't go
"Yến Xích Hà" is right
We cannot be together
But I've found your fox spirit
Even if I leave here
I'm still a demon
Let me and my spirit die here at "Lan Nhược Tự."
Who knows, may be fate will bring us together again one day
By then
May be I'm not a demon any more
Free it
Then I won't go, I'll stay\nWe'll die together
You have to go,
"Lan Nhược Tự" is about to be destroyed
I can't let go
I can't
You want to sacrifice because of me?
I know that
"Tiểu Thiến"!
What is this? It's tasty
Sugar candy
Then I'll fall in love with whoever treats me them
Human and spirit cannot live together
You must snap out of it
It's all "a moon's reflection, illusions and smokes"
"Tiểu Thiến"
Saviors, on behalf of "Black Mountain" villagers
Thank you so much
Our..our "tree"\nWould it grow back?
Peep it and see
Right, our village haven't got this many trees in a long time
Savior, please stop why when you're free
"Ninh Thái Thần"
Subtitle by
Aldi Arman