Dino, next time tell me
when you borrow a car.
Ah damned, forgot.
- Do you have one with more leg room?
- Well, if you push the chair back...
...the leg room will improve...
- Signore Kelder, you look great.
- Dino.
I'm sure you drive the women wild.
Dino, it's going well here. Thanks.
Listen...
...this is your seventh,
eighth time here.
- Have you ever been in love?
- Definitely.
- Madly.
- Not with a car.
That's cruel. What you say is so cruel,
because you've broken her heart.
She sees you here every week
and every week you let her down.
Look, this car is crying
and who has to comfort her? Me.
Forget this car. OK?
You're not good enough for her.
What the hell are you doing?
Hey, show-off...
OK, I'll just do it.
Come on.
You take care of it.
Dino Valentino,
we're not in Italy, you know.
But he signed. I knew it!
Are you so eager to take risks?
When someone is determined,
there are no risks.
Life has to be exciting, Carlo.
When you wound the pride
of a guy like that, he'll buy.
Take risks, you mean.
- Hey, Carlo, you can trust me.
- Just don't exaggerate. Capiche.
Take it easy with those chocolates.
Good evening, princess.
Have you seen a life buoy
around here?
Because when I look into your eyes,
I'm drowning.
Help...
That seat is occupied.
Well, then I just liberated it.
It's for you.
The meeting for failed machos
is down the hall. Good luck.
You know quite well
you're going home with me.
- Yes, in your dreams.
- I only dream of you, bella.
That's all you've got?
- I've heard better pick-up lines.
- Is that right?
Hey, where are you going?
DJ!
Happy birthday to you
happy birthday to you...
Congratulations.
Hip hip hurray!
Stop it.
- It tickles.
- You changed your tune, right?
How would you like looking like a fool
like that?
I was just a bit of fun.
It was a surprise.
What do you mean 'surprise'?
It's not even my birthday.
We've been together
for exactly one year today.
Really? Today?
Today...
To another year.
To all the years that follow it.
The two of us forever.
Oh, that's so sweet.
A cow.
Cow?
I love it.
Thank you.
It's beautiful, David.
How much do I owe you?
Twenty.
There you go. Keep the change.
Thanks a lot.
The pasta, olives...
...and the melanzane alla parmigiana.
Don't forget the peppers.
- Goodbye.
- Thanks, Salvatore.
Have a good trip.
EXPECTED
LANDED
Mom!
Farid.
- How was your flight?
- Very good, mom.
Sweetheart?
No mirrors in Italy?
There's hair underneath your lip.
That's the fashion in Rome.
What kind of fashion is that in Rome?
Let's go.
Hey, Farid!
- Hey, Mounir! Everything all right?
- Sure. Relaxing, hanging out.
That's important too.
What?
Tell them.
I can't.
- You've been lying to them for a year.
- I can't tell mom and dad.
What if they show up at work?
They wanted an Italian, OK?
Moroccan, Italian, what's the difference?
Only this much.
You know that I have no choice.
If it weren't for Monique...
- If I hadn't met Monique...
- If, if, if.
Does she love you?
- Of course.
- Then she won't care.
She won't. Honestly.
From the best trattoria in Rome.
Look...
- Thank you, sweetheart.
- Pasta...
- Olives...
- Thank you, sweetheart.
And a small bonus...
Why?
You shouldn't have.
Of course he should have.
My son, Farid.
I missed you.
- Everything all right?
- I slept badly, but it's not too bad.
- How come?
- Oh, nothing.
What's that?
- It's the fashion in Italy.
- Fashion.
- Look, this one is for mom.
- It's beautiful.
- This one for Aziza.
- Thank you.
- And this one is for Ghalia.
Sears?
- And I brought this one for my nephew.
- Wow, Pirlo's shirt!
- That's enough.
- But it's not sweet.
- Like it?
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
Farid really made it
in that faraway Italy.
Well, I worked hard for it.
And I was a little lucky.
Look, Karim was lucky with Ghalia.
Lucky? Sure. But they don't
want to give me a job.
'Sorry, we already have a Moroccan.'
- There we go again.
Try harder.
They don't just hand it to you.
What do you know about it?
Easy. You're only interested
in big talk and soccer.
I was already promoted at your age.
Yes, to manager assembly belt.
Don't be cheeky.
Calm down, all of you.
Farid has a good job.
You have a good wife
and a beautiful son.
But you, son? Isn't it about time
you brought a woman home?
She's right.
Will you stay a bachelor forever?
It's about time.
Of course.
She's in Italy. In Rome.
I knew it.
I just had that feeling.
She works for a famous designer
of wedding dresses. Her name's Monique.
Bring her along some day,
so we can meet her.
Yes, bring her along.
Yeah.
Sweety, hope're having fun in Italy.
Miss you. X
Miss you too. Sleep well. X
Sleep well, son.
Sleep well, mom.
When someone is determined,
there are no risks.
Things always go smoothly for me.
Gorgeous.
What is this?
You like surprises, don't you?
Yes.
I've got one for you.
Dear Dino...
I've never been as happy
as I was this past year.
I love you.
I love your...
...tenderness.
I love your craziness.
But I mostly love your honesty.
So, honey...
...I'd like to ask you something.
Esther?
WILL YOU MARRY ME?
What's your answer?
And you said 'yes'?
Yeah.
So this is the moment of truth, isn't it?
- The moment of your coming out.
- What should I say?
That your name is Farid Ben Saoud.
That you used to be a taxi driver.
That you're descended from Moroccans.
Moroccans are very honest and loyal,
you know.
Right. And you're the perfect example.
Sorry.
Listen, if she really loves you...
...she'll understand that you pretended.
She's the one, Dave.
I'm nothing without her.
That's why.
What are you thinking about?
Nothing.
That's so cute.
You Italians have a big mouth,
but without clothes...
- No.
- Yes.
That's got nothing to do with it.
Monique...
I love you.
It's just that...
I...
- I...
- I know who your are.
Do you?
Yes, you're the love of my life.
It's such a shame that my mom
never got to know you.
Sweetie, I know you have to get used
to the idea. It's a big step for me too.
- Is it?
- Of course.
Monique...
'You are my love.'
And then?
'You are my truth.'
Beautifully put.
Are you Italian?
Me too. For how long
have you been in the Netherlands?
Things always go smoothly for me.
Smoothly?
But for how long have you
been living in the Netherlands?
In the Netherlands?
How...
Good morning...
Certainly, yes...
Let's go.
- What?
- He's staring at your boobs.
- What's wrong?
- Well...
- ...those Italians!
- Huh?
Sweetie, let's go to Italy next week.
- Why?
- You want to tell your parents too, right?
- My parents?
- Yes!
No, I have a better idea.
Ask them to come here.
Then I can introduce them to my dad.
Your dad? My dad?
That's a lot of dads at once.
Have you picked a date yet?
How about August 12?
That's when your mom and I
got married.
Beautiful summer day,
reception in an orchard...
- ...sultry summer evening.
- That's not possible, dad.
I phoned city hall. Because he has
a foreign passport, we need at least...
- ...six months to get all the right papers.
- Foreign passport?
What's today?
February 14 is a possibility then.
My parents' wedding day.
- In winter?
- That's excellent.
Fire baskets, lights everywhere.
- You guys in a reindeer sled.
- Dad!
- That's my father all over, right?
- Yeah.
What the heck is this?
Did you glue that picture on yourself?
Maserati believed this
when they hired you? It looks crappy.
You can't take this to city hall.
What?
No way. Absolutely not.
No fucking way.
I'm a painter, not a passport forger.
- Leave Nienke out of it. OK?
- Why not do it together?
- A romantic project.
- Oh, shut up.
- Come on. It's for a good cause.
- No way.
Jesus, man.
- Some friend you are.
- At least I'm honest.
Grazie, honest friend.
You were going to tell her,
weren't you?
Honey, honey...
How nice that you were able
to come so quickly.
Give your brother a kiss.
The doctor.
Hello. He's out of danger.
Thank you.
We performed an angioplasty.
He needs regular check-ups
and a lot of rest.
OK?
I told your husband before:
Less fat, less sugar.
But he doesn't listen. He's stubborn.
- Has my dad been here before?
- He came here a month ago.
His chest hurt.
- You can go and see him. Good luck.
- Thank you.
My son, Farid.
Dear wife, your cooking's too good.
I just ate too much.
Stop it.
The doctor told me everything.
Mom, this isn't the right time.
Come on.
So when should I yell?
When he's dead?
If we lie to each other in this family,
where does that leave us?
He lied because he didn't
want to worry you.
Not worry?
It's my job to worry.
Do you hear me?
That's my responsibility.
Calm down, mom.
Karim, go and calm down your mother.
Ghalia.
- I've blown it with her, haven't I?
- No, dad. You didn't.
Listen...
It's nearly Ramadan.
You're not allowed to observe Ramadan.
For your health. The doctor...
That's why I want you to replace me
during Ramadan.
- Me?
- Yes.
Dad...
You know that I haven't been
observing it for years.
Ask Karim or Aziza.
Aziza?
When Aziza wants to eat...
...she closes the curtains.
Listen, Farid...
The only thing I have left...
...is the Ramadan.
Of course, dad.
I'll do the Ramadan for you.
Thank you, my son.
- Are you really going to do it?
- Of course. I promised dad.
- You won't last longer than a day.
- Of course I will.
No eating and drinking before sunset?
And no lying?
That's not allowed either.
- What?
- Sex.
- Just thinking about it is forbidden.
- Not at night, though.
You're not married are you?
Then it's not allowed, anyway.
Especially not during Ramadan.
Can't I just a bit?
You know, a bit...
Thoughts have to be pure.
Oh, come on!
Dino, do you know
why I'm always benched?
Yes, naturally.
The secret weapon.
Every team has one.
You're ours, Nourdin.
Last week I could have made
the difference against Nissan.
If I'd have been allowed to play,
I'd have scored.
Tactical error!
I'll talk to Karel about it.
Hey, Nourdin.
Will you be able to play soccer?
I mean, tomorrow the Ramadan starts.
How do you know?
General education.
Isn't it tough?
Well, I think Ramadan is a nice month.
A month of contemplation,
discipline, purification...
...getting in touch with yourself,
your family, your Maker.
Yeah, man, it's a nice month.
But...
...now, during summer...
...long days.
No eating, no drinking.
Not even when it's 35 degrees.
And no water either,
if that's what you think.
Yeah, man.
Ramadan during summer
is sheer hell.
Dino, want to become a Muslim?
And 'hell', come on...
Restraint during the day
and gluttony at night.
Not to mention the Döner kebab.
- Dude, Döner is Turkish.
- I'm talking about the women.
Moroccan women have
the most beautiful black hair.
Get out. I have work to do.
Pray at 3.17 AM, at 5.43 AM...
...at 1.47 p. m...
How?
Which freak made up this schedule?
Hello.
- Am I interrupting?
- You? Never!
I figured I'd surprise my fiancé,
because he loves that.
How nice!
- Busy?
- Mwah.
Look at that: The lovebirds.
- Hi, honey.
- Hi, dad.
How do you say that in Italian, Dino?
- Coffee?
- Yes.
- How are you?
- Fine. And you?
Come on, man.
I even had passport photos taken.
David, look.
I don't have time for this.
I have to finish this by tomorrow.
Jesus, man!
No, sorry, Farid.
Dammit.
- Dino, what's wrong?
- I have to go for a pee.
Well... watching your weight?
Sorry.
I'll think about it.
You're probably wondering
why I wanted to see you.
- I'm leaving at the end of the year.
- Where to?
To Las Vegas.
They want me to replace Celine Dion
during her pregnancy.
I'm retiring.
I want the best person to succeed me.
As manager?
- Exactly.
- Where do you want me to sign?
It's not that simple.
The head office in Modena is strict.
They decide.
I recommended both of you.
You both have qualities.
Lammers, you're good with numbers.
Dino, you're Italian.
To show what you're capable of:
Qatar wants twenty Quattroportes.
Twenty!
They're coming here next week.
That's your chance.
So, gentlemen...
...get to work.
Deal.
Dino!
Can I talk to you?
Fight for it, Dino,
so I know you really deserve Monique.
Really deserve!
Things always go smoothly for me.
Right. Of course.
Come on, Dino! Come on!
Let me play!
Come on, Dino.
The secret weapon.
Dino.
Dino, are you OK?
Have a drink.
- Has the sun set yet?
- The sun?
I'm leaving.
Do you realize we have to let
Nourdin play now?
- Can I?
- No.
- Go.
I expect at least two goals from you.
- Hey, Dino!
- Fuck off.
- Are you OK?
- Yeah.
Honey?
Merda, merda, merda
means 'luck.'
Then the Italians say:
Merda, merda, merda.
Just like the English say: Break a leg.
Germans say: Hals und Beinbruch.
- Those Germans with their macho cars...
- Honey?
- Are you OK?
- Fine.
- You're perspiring. Are you ill?
- No, I'm fine.
I talked to city hall.
We have an appointment tomorrow
for the marriage license.
I can't tomorrow.
I have two appointments
and a video call.
I have to phone someone back.
A customer's coming by.
- Tomorrow's no good.
- That's the only opportunity.
- But...
- Or have you changed your mind?
- Oh, honey. Tomorrow, OK?
- Tomorrow.
Dad...
David, please. Help me.
They didn't even want to look
at my paintings.
- Who?
- That fucking jury.
- I'm just not talented.
- Come on. You're super-talented.
You really helped me out.
True. He really helped me.
With what?
Playing mysterious games
while I'm in trouble!
Thanks a lot!
Couple of failed Picassos.
Oh, right.
We've got something for you.
What?
No!
Yes.
- That's me!
- We hope so.
This is great! Fantastic!
- OK, your passports.
- There you go.
That looks fine.
There you go.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
That's me.
- Born in Rome.
- Rome, yes, Italy.
You see a lot of passports each day.
Look at...
- Yes.
- Nice.
Sorry, he has ADHD.
1.85 meter.
1.85, right.
1.85.
About.
OK. There you go.
- Is fine?
- Yes, it is.
Then you just need to sign.
- Madam over here and sir over there.
- Thank you.
- Well...
- Well.
Dino...
...Valentino.
Here you go.
Honey, amore, hold on.
I have to tell you something.
I was thinking...
It might be nice not to have sex
before we get married.
It's tradition.
- Tradition, Italy, calzone.
- Huh?
I know it's difficult,
but it brings us together.
It will make us stronger.
Contemplation, discipline,
in touch with yourself.
It's so pure.
Just as pure as my love for you.
More importantly:
The reward is the wedding night.
- I'm really looking forward to it.
- This makes no sense.
It's...
Yes, but... we can...
Can't we try something else?
And now I'm going to unhook your bra.
With your teeth?
No, in my mind.
Hey...
- You have to focus.
- I am.
Wait a minute.
I'm kissing your earlobe.
- What?
- Feel it?
- No, honey, I had an itch.
- Stop this nonsense.
- Nonsense?
- You're too tense.
- I'm not tense at all. Come here.
- Monique, wait. I...
- I really want you.
- Monique, sorry, OK?
- Hey!
I'm trying to spice up our sex life
and you...
You want me to jump your bones
like a wild guy.
Yes, Dino.
That's what I want.
How hard can that be?
I want you to touch me.
Make love to me. Penetrate me!
Louder, so the neighbors
can enjoy it too.
The neighbors?
What's going on with you?
I... I want...
It's not allowed. I mean...
It's very tense at work
and that competition with Lammers.
Bullshit. You're talking about traditions,
you're busy.
Why don't you want to make love to me?
Be honest.
- If you don't want to be with me anymore...
- That's not it.
All I want is to be with you.
You're gorgeous.
So show it, Dino. Do something.
I do...
What are you doing?
I'm penetrating you in my mind.
Princess.
I love you.
Isn't that the most important thing?
- Stop it with your 'princess'.
- Please...
You're everything to me.
Where are you going?
- I'm going home.
- I...
I phoned my parents!
They're coming.
Monique, this is my dad.
- Salvatore.
- Hello, Monique.
I'm Salvatore.
It's so nice to meet you.
- Sorry, in English.
- Pardon?
- No Dutch.
- Why not?
You're from Italy.
Monique, this is my papa.
Papa is the Pope.
You have to say pápá.
Sorry, you say Farid,
but it's Dino.
Maybe that's not a good idea.
My father doesn't sing.
- Italians have to be a bit...
- You're exaggerating.
I'm not exaggerating. Again.
I'm not tense at all.
It just has to go well.
- Tell Monique...
- OK, there she is.
Could you please bring your wife along?
Some appetizers.
Thank you.
Monica...
Cheers.
To the future and to our family.
- Monique, please don't encourage him.
- Just let him.
Can't you make him stop?
- Stop.
- I'm working on it.
This isn't a pizzeria.
- Pizzeria?
- Mom, please...
Are you crazy?
You and your ridiculous snob joint!
Stop it!
Let me explain. Hold on.
- This isn't how I pictured this dinner.
- Me neither! But they're villagers.
They're in the big city.
What do they know?
They're tired from that delayed flight.
And what was up with my dad?
- He'd been drinking.
- Are you blaming your parents?
- Not really. But my dad...
- Never mind, Dino.
I want to be alone tonight.
- Monica, I'm coming with you.
- No.
- I'm not letting you go on your own.
- Leave me be.
- Leave you be? Can't I come with you?
- No.
Bella, listen...
Just tell her.
No, that isn't an option.
Thanks.
You need to tell her.
Don't procrastinate.
How? She wants some time to think.
Then take her abroad
and tell her there.
Yes. Faraway from everything.
No woman will refuse that offer.
Honestly.
- Hello?
- Cara, it's me.
No, Dino, honestly... Go away.
- But I have a surprise.
- I've had enough of your surprises.
But this is a very special surprise.
Let's do it completely differently.
Just the way we always do it.
The two of us.
Away with that whole fuss.
Ticket to Las Vegas.
We'll get married there.
What do you think? Tomorrow.
I'll pick you up at five.
Please give me one more chance.
Las Vegas?
Good morning.
- Hey, asshole, what are you doing?
- Isn't vaffanculo Italian?
Since when do Italians
observe Ramadan?
Never heard of Italian Muslims?
I'm sure you have a damn good reason
for this, Farid Ben Saoud.
Fuck. You... you...
- Explain.
- What do you mean?
Why are you doing do this?
Would I have been hired here
as a Moroccan?
They were looking for
an Italian salesman.
OK. Let me tell Karel and Monique.
Don't say anything.
- When were you planning on doing that?
- I'm waiting for the right moment.
Jesus Christ, Dino.
- Farid.
- It's all I ask.
I don't see any reason why I
shouldn't go up there to tell him.
- Why?
- I have to think of myself.
Don't you get that?
I'll withdraw from the race. OK?
Deal?
You're kidding.
Well...
He's my favorite uncle, Vincenzo.
He's very ill, so I have to travel
back and forth.
But that's temporary.
- But giving up? Really? You?
- But I...
- I won't make a good manager.
- Bullshit!
You underestimate yourself.
You've got style. Customers love you.
Still, I won't do it.
The best choices are you and Lammers.
- So Lammers.
- No way! Don't abandon me now.
- Didn't Lammers tell you?
- No.
Those Qatarians are coming at five
and you'll be there. Or no wedding.
- What?
- Basta. Understand?
- Hey, sweetie.
- Honey.
Good thing you're calling.
Should I bring a warm sweater?
Monique, your dad needs me
for a huge deal.
- I won't be able to make five o'clock.
- What?
Take a cab to the airport
and I'll meet you at check-in.
I'll come as soon as I'm done here.
OK?
- Fine.
- Ciao, baby.
Bye.
Good morning!
- Hi, I'm Lammers.
- Hello.
Have a seat, ladies.
I'm sure you'll like this car.
Have a seat.
400HP. Leather interior.
Sir, this car is fit for a king.
- Enjoy your meal.
- It's not what you think.
Listen, I'm ill. Back pain. Medication.
Then you're allowed to eat. Honestly.
Listen, I badly need your help.
See you.
The Prince of Qatar.
He's coming too.
- Why?
- Why, why? Lammers...
It's a huge deal. Come on.
Twenty cars like that.
So the meeting has moved
to the Krasnapolsky hotel.
And Karel is leaving it up to us
as a kind of ultimate test.
What do you mean by 'us'?
We. I'm coming with you
if you need me.
- I don't need you.
- In case you can't handle it on your own.
- Of course I can.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
- OK.
- Ciao.
- Good luck.
- Aren't those Qatarians here yet?
- No.
- Where's Lammers?
- Don't know.
Very professional.
- I'll call him.
Yes, Lammers. Karel and I
are wondering what's keeping you.
- In a traffic jam? Come on!
- Come on!
You should have left sooner. Hurry!
Not very professional. Be on time
when you want to achieve something.
Dino, you and I will take care of it.
What's he saying?
That shipment to Qatar
will be very expensive.
So why don't we order those cars
closer to home?
What?
Did he understand us?
- Where are you?
- Come on, Dino.
Almost on my way.
See you at the gate.
Now boarding for the flight to Las Vegas.
Listen, Ghalia, I'm busy.
You can't come now. It's important.
Dammit, that asshole!
Is he consulting Modena all the time?
It failed! Get out of here!
- What's he saying?
- Don't you know what 'decision' means?
Fine.
What's twenty cars, after all?
Hand me those contracts.
Can you take care of it?
Go in peace.
Farid Ben Saoud!
What are you doing? Come on!
Asshole!
He's not Italian, he's Moroccan. OK?
I should have told you before. Sorry.
He's marrying your daughter.
A Moroccan!
All along he's been...
Are they the real ones?
Hello?
It's me. I'm on my way.
You sound stressed out.
No stress. I'm always tense
when I go on vacation. Nourdin!
Hold on. My dad's calling.
Don't hang up!
- What happened to your eye?
- I fell.
- You fell?
- No, I didn't fall.
- I'm not going to drive.
- Drive, drive, drive.
- In an M6?
- You've got your license, right?
Technically speaking, no.
- Dino, what's happening?
- I was talking to Nourdin.
- I really can't drive.
- Get in the car!
- I won't.
- Dammit, sit. Please.
We're leaving now.
Start!
We're coming.
- I'm hanging up. My dad's calling.
- Don't! I need to hear your voice.
We'll do crazy things in Las Vegas.
Step on it! Drive!
I'm talking to Nourdin.
The Grand Canyon?
That's high, right?
Good luck, Dino.
Hold on, babe.
Thanks. You've been a terrific help.
Farid. Nice to meet you.
I'm back.
We can go to Disney World too.
Have you ever been. It's terrific.
Or we can go to New Zealand.
New Zealand.
- Hey, buddy, wait your turn, OK?
- But my wife has already checked in.
What the fuck?
No, I wasn't talking to you.
Yes, I'm coming.
This gentleman was first.
Passport, please.
Thank you, madam.
Are you still there? Hello?
Hello?
Sir?
- Where are you going?
- Las Vegas.
- That flight is boarding now.
- Can't you make an exception?
My wife's checked in already.
We're getting married in Las Vegas.
- In Las Vegas?
- Yes.
How...
...do you say cara in Arabic?
Habibi.
You should have called me that
from the start.
Monique...
Hi, you've reached Monique's
answering machine.
Farid?
What happened?
What's wrong?
Where's dad?
Farid.
I'm so happy
you did the Ramadan for me.
It did me a lot of good.
I even gained a kilo.
- That makes me happy.
- Thank you.
But it didn't do you a lot of good, I see.
Come with me.
And then there's no way back.
They love you, but...
They love the other one more.
That Italian.
Dino Valentino.
Listen, Farid.
Never forget where you come from...
...or who you really are.
Yeah.
I'm proud of you.
Whoever you are.
You've never said that before.
Why would I bother you with that?
You know it, don't you?
- Can you say it again?
- Should I repeat it ten times?
Or has all that lying made you deaf?
Please...
I love you, son.
Just one more thing...
Don't tell me you're not only a liar...
...but a coward as well.
In order to make up with Monique...
...you'll have to find some way to do it.
Be a man.
Come.
Come on.
I sometimes wondered
when he was going to pop the question.
Six months ago he suddenly
showed up with this ring.
Thierry said: Let's take the leap.
Are you sure his name is Thierry?
Do you have proof?
Excuse me?
Oh, nothing. Sorry.
Is this the right place
for a wedding dress?
Sorry, I'll be right back.
Kind of remarkable that a man...
- ...is coming to look for a wedding dress.
- Yeah.
But my fiancée is remarkable.
She deserves the best there is.
When are you getting married?
I don't know yet.
- Isn't it handier if she picks one out?
- She doesn't know yet either.
- Oh, forced marriage.
- No.
No.
I...
I haven't been entirely honest to her.
I lied a bit to her and I...
- Lied a bit?
- No, I lied a lot.
- I was an ass.
- An ass?
Yes.
- I was an idiot.
- An idiot?
I...
I didn't know who I was anymore.
- Well, maybe it's better if I...
- No, stay.
He's leaving now.
Monique, please, I...
I know it's all my fault,
but I did it for you.
The way you smile and look at me...
How you poke me awake
when I'm snoring again...
How you plan
a weekend away together...
How you scare me jumping off a roof...
How you can pick things up
with your toes...
I was a stupid liar.
Stupid to think
it would be all right again.
I regret it.
It hurts so much.
Every day, every minute.
I do believe him.
I want you to leave.
I want you to leave now.
Could you hold this up?
Monique, I'm sorry.
Farid!
Do you, Monique Louwman...
...take Farid Ben Saoud to your
lawful wedded husband?
- How do you answer?
- Yes!
Do you, Farid Ben Saoud...
...take Monique Louwman
to your lawful wedded wife?
- How do you answer?
- Also yes!
I declare you husband and wife.
You first.