- Taking them?
- No
Dr. Gachet's place?
He won't arrive until
the 7 o'clock train
Know a cheap boarding house?
Ravoux's. That's the only one
You needed the next stop,
Ravoux's is closer to Auvers
- Glass of wine?
- I don't drink
Wait!
Don't go like that.
No suitcase?
I'll store all this
and go with you.
- You're no talker.
- I am...
- What are you doing in Auvers?
- Nothing
That's restful
You're in Auvers for the air.
I'm the railroad company
agent in Chaponval
Whole family's on the railroad.
Trains put me to sleep as a baby
Dad was a stationmaster
I couldn't pass...
...the test.
There's Ravoux's. If there's a room
she'll take you. But it's simple.
I'm not picky
Buddy here needs a place
3.50 francs room and board,
drinks extra.
- I don't drink
- He lives off his rotgut.
Want to see the room?
Bread and wine...
Here you are. Clean.
Fresh sheets once a week,
you make your own bed
A big cloest for your stuff
A view of the sea?
Lean out, you see the beach
Pretty port
Auvers-sur-Oise
is a charming town
Vessenots Street
There's Dr. Gachet
Tightwad took a cab!
"A handsom went
trotting along...
"Hippety-hop..."
- Taking it?
- It's fine...
- Going to Gachet's?
- Yes, where is it?
Vessenots Street,
And the bags?
I'll send for them tomorrow.
Still the right hand...
Change your pedal...hold it...
There! Then it shifts...
Right hand...
There...
Let up on it...softly...
Very good, Marguerite.
You have talent
Too bad you stopped
I stopped when mother died.
I'll start again
I hope so
Play "Lakme" for me
I can't play "Lakme"
Play "Lakme" Marugerite
You won't play it?
It makes me cry
I had a monkey named Lakme
And?
It's gone?
Dad put it in a zoo,
said it was too dirty
- Let the teacher play it
- No
Odd, to love a monkey
- It's not for tonight
- No, tomorrow
- They stink
- I bathed her every morning
Like a baby
Let's go on
We'll do staccatos
You're a bit late
I took the 3 o'clock train
I mean late in the season
The lilac's going to leaf
Come in
Sit down
I expected you in my
office...in Paris
I don't see patients here
I've a note from my brother
I'm not set up here
We'll manage...
...with what's at hand
Undress
My drawers too?
Keep them on
Need a napkin, Dad?
Smells good...Stew?
- It's not for tonight
- No, tomorrow
Lie on the couch
Sit on the table
Stare at me
Describe your fits
Go on
They vary
Recall the strongest?
The last one
How long ago?
Nearly 3 months
Time of day?
At night. 2 or 3 a.m.
I'd just fallen asleep
How long before?
Half and hour
I woke with a raging headache
Where?
There.
I'd never felt such pain
It lasted at least 20 minutes
A cold compress helped a bit
Did it return?
Not entirely
Bearable. And now?
I have a steady dull cahe
Now and then it vanishes, for a while
No pain...behind the eye?
Back of the neck?
Always on the side...
- ...you showed me?
- Yes, there
I have others, like everyone
but they're different
How do you know?
Who's that guy?
I'm not kept informed
A painter, I think
That so?
Here for rest and treatment
Can't he rest here?
We have room
Must I spell it out?
Great engraving. First printing
See how the blacks stand out?
Superb!
And the central figure, remove
it and it's a routine picture
I needn't tell you that
It's by Meryon
I'd like to have treated him
He was really sick
- Dad, I took some of your books
- My son, Paul, "Coco" to us
Do I...inform your brother?
- What do I owe you?
- I'll settle it with him
He's not here. How much?
7 francs all right?
- Need lodgings?
- It's done
Where, if I may ask?
The cafe near the station
Ravoux's, It's simple.
How much?
3.50 francs
I understand
Let's eat
Your sister's late, as usual
He's odd
I showed him my Renoir
What's for dinner?
Rabbit
- Where's the wine from?
- Duval's
It's not the greatest
I was saying
he ignored my Renoir
A doctor shouldn't always
discuss painting
He should think of other things
What?
You haven't eaten?
- I can serve you some soup
- I'd like that
Dinner here's at 7 o'clock
Sit on the other side,
it's quieter
- You still here?
- I haven't budged
I don't drink
Your napkin ring
It's the prettiest
You don't dose it?
People think that means pouring
wine in the soup and stirring
No, you save
just a bit of broth
...add a good spoonful of wine
That's how I do it
It's called dosing in my Mom's
town, spiking in my Dad's
Yet they're only 20 miles apart
Dad calls a funnel a "fontel"
In Mom's town it's a "tunner"
Where's your Mom from?
She's dead and buried
Life's funny
My brother's...
...first post was at Penglon,
near the grave site...
The big curve before the river.
There's a railroad crossing
The Clermont express roars by.
Every year...
...it runs over someone
No, don't
- I thought you were asleep
- No, I needed some air
What'll I do with this?
You'll see
God any soup?
Here's some
It's easier to wash at
the pump in the yard
Did you hear me?.
I heard you
- I'm Adeline. I'm 13
- I'm Vincent
What're you writing?
To my brother
You write often?
May I read it?
Too bad...
My grandson...
...wants to chat
My grandson
wants to talk to you
I'd like you to do my portrait
- What?
- I want you to paint me
Go home, grandpa
Come have a drink
- Your health
- And yours
To health and wealth
Wealth
Here he comes...
What's up?
What?
My portrait
Like it? The blue?
Want your portrait in blue?
Smile
Life isn't so bad, there's
even room for the village idiot.
I'll cost you 2 sous
I got no money
Take it and scram
Scram!
...Cezanne can't stand me.
Called us "Gauguin and Van Gag"
- Among aritists, that's mild
- I don't call him "seize- anes"
"16 asses"
I never thought of that
That's my house
Cezanne throws a lot away,
like all great painters. Do you?
Never
My family does it for me
My Guillaumin
but I've no frame for it
- You don't paint nudes, right?
- I can't afford models
A little Seurat
How'd you get it? He doesn't let
sketches out of his studio
It's a copy I made
In scret. I'm proud of it
- The scret or the work?
- Both
The hanged man's house
It's called that...
...but no one hanged there.
It had to do with the owner's name
He's improved since then
I'll show you...
...the finest..
That's really painting!
And how! Cezanne was about
to scrape it. I stopped him
I never scrape
Only once, "Christ in the
Garden of Olives"
That so?
- My daughter, Marguerite
- Nice flowers in your room...
- What?
- The painting
I want one of yours soon
Well, they're cheap
Mrs. Chevalier!
My Paris friend let me down
tonight. Come to my room?
You get what I mean?
- What's this dirt?
- It's a spot
I can see that!
It's rust
Don't worry, you can't see it
I can. A new dress!
Lovely old lace
from Aunt Francia
Hand-me-downs
You're pretty as a princess
If only
your Mom were here
She's not!
Want some tea?
I don't like it
We never see you
It's so long since you came
2 days ago
Seems like ages to me
You're so hesitant
I've watched you.
You hesitate over the simplest things
In fact, you do as you please
How do you want me?
Like that. Play
I've a headache
Want some quinine?
Bring Mr. Van Gogh
some quinine
All right. Let's go on
Don't feel like painting?
No, I don't
Yet I was told..
Who told you?
I'm not a machine
Sorry
I mean it.
Your simpering bores me. Play
At least you don't
pull faces like a virtuoso
Maybe bacause you're not one
You mean I play badly?
That's not for me to say
My sister Mina plays well.
Or so I thought at home
Is she pretty?
What do you care? Feminine rivalry
"She's prettier than me?"
You're cranky with everyone
Must be a strain
No, I'm happy as a lark.
Now play
Hold that pose
- You smiling?
- Yes
Not too much
Why are you here?
Simplicity is so difficult
We'll lunch outside
...in 15 minutes
Never changes!
At home, my mother and sister
always interrupted my work
To eat their lousy Dutch chow
Mother yelled "It's cold" or
"It'll burn!" My sister came...
...never looked at my work
- Women only care about material things.
- Don't be unfair
My late wife valued
painters' work
She adored Cezanne
It hurt her that
I was just an amateur
The "chow" here's not bad.
Mrs. Chevalier's quite the cook...
...except for my mother
It's ready
Marguerite's posing
Mr. Van Gogh's painting
Eating's more important
than painting
You can live without painting
but without food...you die
If I had a cook, I'd let her cook
I'd rather listen to you
So you say, but it's not true
When the food's ready
you chomp at the bit
Lunch is served!
Come anyway
Coming
Each year he takes Coco
and me to the company fair
The railroad band
plays classics
It's a bit boring
Last year there were ballet
stars from the Opera
They danced to Grieg's
"Solveig's Song"
- You like Grieg?
- Don't know him
My life's silly. I've the
right to read, Dad's liberal
Using what I learn is
another matter
A girl's called a tomboy on
her looks, not how she feels
We have to hide our
feelings. Men are lucky
They aren't restricted
We spend
all those days shut in...
...wanting to live. All we
can do is...
Is...?
Embroider
Painting's my embroidery
Go on, make fun!
Idle rich girls are the worst
At least working girls work
You've lived in England
Seen those suffragettes
protest?
I don't like those
marching women
I don't like to bite or being bitten
I wage my revolt in private
Much good it does me!
I'm tired of playing
Take the pose!
No more piano!
- Take the post
- Then it's no pose
Want to know what I think?
I don't care
I love grouchy painters!
My dress isn't like that
You made it leaden. The train
drags and my hands are claws!
It's all nonsense
The colors are like puke! And
your landscapes! You serious?
Is this a pictorial
disagreement?
Pose and shut up. Models have no say
in how pictures are exucted
The very word!
You're a pest! Our guest
kindly offered to paint you...
- I'm not talking to you!
- Enough!
Sure, treat me like your dog!
Hotblooded, like her mother
MY late wife treated our
painter friends better
This generation is hopeless
Admirable! That's the word!
The muted mauve, the rhythem,
background, hands, the swirling skirt...
It weighs a ton!
...like a wave, Vincent..
may I call you Vincent?
Painting is making a great
leap with you
How can we keep up with you?
Good news. I went by the gallery
and invited your brother
The whole family's
coming Sunday
I met your sister-in-law
Johanna
Theo's a lucky dog
Admirable woman!
Such a gentle look
yet strong, almost violent
In a positive sense,
of course
I venture to think
their marriage troubles you
You fear it may affect
your close realtions...
...with your brother
so fruitful for your work
...will strengthen your ties
Or in fact, restore them in
a calmer, more ample situation
I truly feel this
It's what I wish for
the three of you
I don't like mauve.
I wasn't wearing mauve
Neither was the wall
You paint me from behind
Never look at me head-on
Why not from the front?
Don't I inspire you?
I'm no goddess, but am I that
purple lump on a purple ground?
Look who's here!
We meet again
We met in Arles
I'm glad to see you
Stop, that's mine!
Yours? Impossible
It is. I just paid her for it
All the more reason..
She forgot her belt
It's a small world. When I heard
I thought, "it must be him"
How's your illness?
It's OK, Cathy
- I'm glad
- It's OK
How we talked!
I love talking to you
You bored here?
I can come and see you
It's better in the country
Am I still so stingy?
Give me another, that one's...
It's wet. Want your shirt?
There...
Leave the bottle
It's Tockay
But warm
I put it in the spring
but the heat...
Here
What've you been up to?
A 5-year Legion hitch
4 really
I was discharged
I tried to enlist
in the Legion
You wouldn't have lasted
a week
- You like bang-bangs
- I like weapons. You scared?
Gives me a laugh
Best thing for blowing
your brains out
For cowards
It depends...
My captain...
...Captain Longot...
...surrounded by Germans,
with the dead around him...
...knowing what they'd do to
him, he didn't hesitate!
What's going on?
You scared me.
Takes guts!
Coming?
Big-hearted
Most whores rush the client
I'm no whore
Three lays at my age,
the monster's tired
How old are you?
- Guess
- 40-45
You burned yourself out
And how!
You put it all into your work
left nothing for the rest
The rest counts most!
You a philosopher, too?
Not at all, but...
I've my way of talking
- And Sonia, in Arles?
- You liked Sonia, eh?
- Well?
- She went like that, phtt!
- You mean..?
- She's dead
I love being naked
in the country
Especially in summer, the rain's
warm, I roll in the grass
It's terrific!
The leaves stick to the skin
I didn't want to tell you
in Arles...
What?
Spit it out!
But that night when you...
I god a bad name!
But I know how you really are
And last year, remember?
When you scared me so?
I should't have let you go like
that. I wonder how you got home.
I do, too.
You were alone
I remember nothing
You could've let me know.
I thought you'd died
We do nothing
for fear of scandal
We're cowards,
it makes me sore!
That's how the worst things
happen, which you regret forever
But you can't always face up
to trouble
I'm not the remorseful type, but
when I think of it...I'm ashamed
Never mind, it's over now
Were you on something?
I said it's over
Hey, I can't see a thing!
I just went...
Aren't you ever happy
with a man?
Why not?
My husband...
- Your husband?
- Yeah, I was married
It was fine, now it's over
I can't do it with the guy
I live with
You're the only one
I'd like to
All men want that. They all
want that with whores
But women hate that,
they hate men
You never liked men?
I don't give a shit
That's the way I live
You can't always live
that way
I can
Well, what's it to me?
At least you're genuine
Looking for someone?
No, thanks
How did you find this place?
Everyone knows it
Men do. But women?
Depends which ones
How can they manage?
All those costumes!
And they take them off
with such ease..
You think I'm silly,
like all women
I don't know you
You probably don't
get to talk much
True. Dad says I'm introverted.
I don't speak for hours
There are no trains at night
It's a local line
I often hear the last train,
but not the first
When I sleep poorly,
I rise late
In Arles
I lived by the station
I love trains, like a kid
You're still a kid
in many ways
Lots of trains went through
Arles
Shall we sit or stand?
You'd rather lie down!
It's not that time
I have to get my gear
I have to go too
Won't you join us for lunch?
Friends are coming..
Sorry, I can't
I have a family lunch
It was a last minute idea
A pity, I would have loved to
I'll play you something
You have a lovely voice
That's going too far
You should visit me more
often. We could sing that
I can't read music
- I never studied it
- You sing wonderfully
My dad wouldn't let me.
And I work in the bar
- You have some free time
- See, they want me!
I've made a spot
'Bye!
Hurry! What are you doing?
You've got work to do!
I know
Chaponval!
Next stop, Auvers!
All aboard!
Here he is
- How are you?
- I wanted to rent a carriage
- You've got no money...
- It's not far..
Give him to me
I'll carry him
Chocolate!
Here they come!
My daughter, Marguerite
My son, Paul
He got little
or no care there.
The doctor at St. Remy
worte me that he got..
...no specific therapy,
nor regular supervision
I can't believe...
...he had epileptic fits
That word is used
to cover up ignorance
Your brother was...
...exhausted, overworked.
He works too much
Still now. It was drink, too.
Absinthe
And bad food
That's all it takes with
over-sensitive people like him
His pulse is good,
as are his circulation...
...blood pressure, and arteries
He's tough and in good shape
But any over-excitement
becomes an attack...
I'd say of hysteria
It's not confined to women
He is too concentrated,
monomaniacal...
The seating layout!
It's on the sideboard
You crazy?
It was harmless...
Well, lovebirds?
She connived to serve here today
Keeps tabs on you
You painted the pest?
Yes, why?
She's cute, but a bit vulgar
She's an innkeeper's daughter
Not your class
You're mean!
It's the champagne
To little Vincent!
I like him very much
And to the complete
recovery of big Vincent
Vincent the great
- Let's be serious...
- Homeopathy's not a serious topic
Homeopathy has one great virtue
It put an end to...
...the barbaric practice
of draining
That sounds good. But I read and
unconvincing homeopathic treatise
It listed 350 types
of headaches
I only know of one
There's a remedy for the fear
of being cuckolded!
- Charlatanism!
- A very widespread fear!
Come on, that doesn't exist
In allopathy, we did little
to cure patients
I soon realized...
...and I wasn't alone...
...that we hadn't learned
enough to heal...
- ...the sick
- Has that changed?
I've changed
The are of 1870 did it
I saw real suffering
Not just the usual
hypochondriacs
Men who'd been butchered
We had to do something
We couldn't handle
these men in real pain..
...with the usual phony
palliatives
Someone in pain is alone
Good intentions won't help
Sorry, madame,
we're boring you...
Not at all.
I'm never bored with painters
Painters?
I'm not much of one...
Theo must become a painter.
I insist. We're all talented...
Why else did I marry him?
He'll paint.
We got our talent from Mother
We shouldn't have
become art dearlers
You're right, but for yourself
For a somple man like me...
Not so simple, Mr. Van Gogh
You've carved a name in the art
market, almost cornered it
There's Durand-Ruel
- You have more taste and courage
- But less money
- You sponsor Impressionists..
- Except his brother
You've championed
Monet and Renoir
- Others will follow
- I can't wait! Right, Theo?
Enough laces. OK?
Not too tight?
Not too tight...Wait..
Don't move
One, two..
"My name's Toulouse-Lautrec,
I'm a handsome wreck,
"I get my inspiration,
In places of damnation
"Although I'm short of leg,
all the ladies beg
"So hide your wives from
the meanie
"They all want to taste my
wienie!"
In front of my kids!
I'm choking!
Once more?
Shall I do a number?
"After he entered a
monastery...
"...the King of Beggars..
"It's not really Quasimodo,
but it's quasi him!"
Dad, do the camel!
"The little mountain dwarfs...
"Do all the dirty work,
while the shepherds sleep...
"from the witch
they save the sheep..."
The Auvers ballet
I'd have liked a poem
There are lovely ones
I don't know any
Then a song. Jo, sing us
"Cherryblossom Time"
Everyone knows that song!
Don't insist, Theo
- You, Madame
- I don't dare
Please do
You can't turn us down..
A little song
I'll need the first note
We'll accompany you
"When we'll sing
of cherryblossom time...
"all the nightingales
and blackbirds
"will come out to rejoice...
"Lasses will have
ribbons in their hair..
"and lovers unshine
in their hearts
"When we'll sing
of cherryblossom time..
"But who of us can match
the blackbird's song?"
What about my poem?
I don't know any
It can't be
Is that true, doctor?
No, she just won't recite
one...Search your memory
I can't remember any
Let's go for...
...a walk by the river
Why not..
But the train's at 5:50
You've time
It'll do us good
You'll see, it's a
lovely spot
That's why
so many painters come
Jo has a fine face
My brother's lucky
So paint her
She scares me
Meet my fiancee.
She's fallen for him
Idle girls fall easily
If Vincent was a chic painter
Gachet would...
Let's get back to homeopathy
It's all contradictions
You can interpret it
any way you want
Like your brother's fine
works
People reject them today..
..as an outrageous,
clumsy mess
Soon those same
"learned" people..
..will claim they're sublime
But they are now!
I hope you're right
Sorry...
Shall we dance?
He's so clumsy
You wonder if he
really does those things
His many weaknesses
add up to strength
So do ours
How can you stand him?
You don't dance?
My father disapproves.
I practice secretly
Don't kiss a girl's hand!
He's a bumpkin
We sorely missed you
for lunch
Still want me to sing?
A friend, Mrs. de Marigny
You've been hiding her?
I don't recruit for anyone!
I didn't mean that...
Are you a lady killeR?
As with Lakme?
Good idea
Sing Lakme.
The pianist will accompany you
Our friend has a lovely voice
Accompany her?
Absolutely
That was wonderful
Remarkable voice
It's hard to find a woman
at least for me
For everyone
You're a wild man
I'm shy
especially with women
Meaning?
I don't dare
But I can also be bold
Really?
You never paint water?
No, I don't like to
It's too fluid
the reflections are tricky
It's one thing,
then another...
Cezanne can't paint the sea
It looks like cardboard,
but people dote on it
In a short time, the gentlest
of men has become..
..irritable and bitter
There are constant fights
Within a year...
Sorry to tell you...
My husband isn't
the Theo I once knew
He's more like you
They way he says you are
You don't love him?
Are you mad?
I love him more than ever
To see him like this...
He tries to be cynical..
He forces himself..
He's sick, that must be it
Something's going on.
But he won't tell me
He always was fragile. But,
unlike me, never complains
I can feel it...
He's still considerate, but...
You'd better..
I feel like a stranger
He rejects me
As for our child..He's
worried...
...by the tiniest bruise...
But he's also distant
At times wholly absent
What's wrong?
Is it another woman?
Not his style
Don't say that
He told me of your sprees,
the three of you
Ages ago!
I was forewarned
All that's past
Theo's faithful as can be
I'm sure of it
You don't see him that much
One's faithful or not
I don't agree
But he feeds the whole family!
You, the baby, our mother...
...one sister, and me.
That's a lot of worries
Not you, Vincent. You work
If you say so..
I do
But he's wearing himself out.
I tell you, it can't go on
Things must change
Listen to me
I don't want my brother's
death on my conscience
He can't die for my smudges
that'll never be worth a cent
No, I say that things
will change
I must do something. Theo, you and
the baby can't go on this way
What can you do?
What's he doing?
Don't worry
He did it on the ferry
with Mom
- Can he swim?
- He did it through our youth
There..
Pretty good
He'd really upset Mom
Come along...You'll catch
cold..How smart of you!
Very clever!
I'll get in first
My hat
We spent a nice day, right
kids?
Come back,
I'll paint the baby
You'll be a monster
Come visit
- Come to Paris soon
- On a Sunday
- Where is he?
- Gone. He always does that
We can't abandon him
Who said we will?
We never discuss things
Don't bother to ask!
Now I've got to go refill it!
You could say thanks
He gets on my nerves!
Now you water the wine!
- So, who taught me?
- Shut up!
You did!
Hear how she talks to me?
So much laundry!
I told my hudband
we need bigger vats!
He never listens!
I'm sick of it!
That's too much..Shit!
It's musty in here
I thought it might storm
Not a breath of air
Is the baby restless?
No, he didn't get much
champagne
You're being so nice.
Can't you always be this way?
It won't last
You haven't had a real talk
with your brother for a year
All last year..
Never
You were around
Yes, I was
But I was selfish
I thought only of us
That's all I ever do
When Vincent starts to paint,
I sell other painters.
That's what destroys him
You can't deny it
...his life's a disater
You're part of it
Your life's a disaster, too
You don't love me?
Of course I do
If you don't udnerstand
that...
I can't explain
You sling a lot of mud at me
Why?
I don't know
Let go of me
Some water? It's cool
Can I take it?
How will you paint?
Wait!
The milk's boiling...
You leaving?
I've got things to do. Be
back later
You won't eat with us?
I lost
Six and one, seven
Almost eight
There..No, a nine
A nine would be nice
Fice and four is nine!
Your turn
Call it
- What number?
- One!
Will you draw
the sand-merchant for him?
Mr. Van Gogh will draw you
the sand- merchant
Come beside me
Go on
Well?
It's nice
Thanks, Mr. Van Gogh
Look!
See the nice sand-merchant?
You're not kind
- What's it for?
- What?
Kiindness
To get on witih people...
To live happily, have friends
Some more?
Bread and butter?
I never eat in the morning
I was looking at this...
She's like my mom in her
youth, You did it?
No, Gilbert did
That's not like your other work
More like paper for books
Mom used to say one loves
only one person in life
It's true. Mom loved Dad, Dad
only loved her, Coco loves Dad.
- And you?
- I don't know yet
And you?
You love no one
Strange, my fire's lit
Who lit it?
Did you?
So do it everyday,
and bring me breakfast
I'm not Gilbert!
Don't joke. He had a fever
last night
How do you know?
Snopping again?
I never get to see you
I should've brought my
embroidery
Garlic sausage. What a treat!
Want some?
I needed a pick-me-up
I enjoy a rest. Mountain
guides eat slowly, in silence
You don't need a rest
You haven't started work
I'm all done
So paint me...
I Dad knew, he'd kill me
Him? No chance
You think everything's funny
No, I don't
You've got strength
Who, me? A real strongman
Your arms aren't very
muscular
A woman's shouldn't be
Well, a little shape...
Only Dad exercises in
our family
Glass of wine? C'mon
Coming?
Good wine from
my brother's vineyard
We'll soon see
If we don't drink too much!
It's nice here
You want another?
Seen my daugher?
Ah, doctor..
I see it's real party...
Sort of..
Can I have a shot?
Well, 'bye