Stop! Stop!
Customs, go!
- Let me through.
- No.
- Let me through!
Go!
Eugenio, Eugenio.
At your service, madam.
Did my son say where he was
going? Did someone 'phone him?
- Yes, Mr. Olivieri.
- Who's that?
- I don't know, but he often 'phones.
- What's his first name?
Calm down, it's not
the first time he's been late.
- Such terrible things happen!
- What are you thinking of!
Bianca, if you want we can go to the
police station, to the hospitals.
- It's never happened before!
- It's happening today.
Have you discovered anything
about the girl in the photo?
No. A certain Mr. Olivieri called
him. And how do we find him?
How come you don't know your
sors friends?
- They're probably university friends.
- I see, I'll go to the police station.
- I'll come with you. - No, I'll call
you later after speaking to the inspector.
Don't you feel well?
Do you want me to call someone?
He isn't in hospital,
that's good news, isn't it?
Don't worry, the inspector
thinks the same as me.
Anyway he'll send someone
to the house. Yes, two officers.
No, it's just a formality.
So you can explain things better
and give them all the names.
The girl.
The inspector was asking me
if Claudio had had
any disappointments.
Yes, if he's argued
with that girl.
No, inspector,
I said so too,
my son wouldn't do anything
stupid for some disappointment.
We've never met the young lady
personally, but it's just the same.
I'll just pop into the office and
then I'll come straight home, okay.
- Thank you for your kindness.
- Not at all.
I'm happy to have been of help
to a friend of the Honourable Valeri.
Guard!
You usually wait a day or two,
he could have left Rome.
My son would have let us know.
Has he had any quarrels
with his father?
My husband told the inspector,
nothing's happened.
- Whose letters are these?
- They're from school mates, friends.
I don't understand why
you're examining these papers.
Claudio must have had
an accident.
- Does your son do any deals?
- What nonsense!
- He's just a lad, he's in the first
year of university. - Thank you, madam.
You, come here.
- Where were you when you heard
the shots? - In the factory.
- Who was with you?
- The others.
- What time was it?
- About 5 o'clock.
- I've just come from the Valmauro's.
- Later.
That youngster, Claudio Valmauro...
Iook what I've found.
Play something more pathetic,
Marina needs some atmosphere.
Guys, let's telephone Claudio,
otherwise we'll be ruined.
- Fools!
- Why, isn't it true?
How funny you are!
- But really, why hasn't he come?
- He'll have found some blonde.
Worse for him if he doesn't come.
I don't care.
- What's the matter? - If you
want me to console you, I'm here.
- Here he is, calm down.
- He's playing the existentialist!
Claudio!
Your mother's been bombarding me with
'phone calls since this morning!
She started at 8.
- What did she say? - Your parents
went to the police station.
Where were you last night?
What's that face for?
- Can we go outside a moment?
- You want me to leave everyone like this?
Guys, make yourselves
at home.
- What's the matter?
- Nothing.
- Let's go.
- This way.
Marina Locatelli, on the third floor.
- Is she at home?
- Yes, she's having a party.
I'll go with you.
They're all excuses,
what do you suppose has happened?
I'm getting really angry!
Please, do me the favour
of not involving me in this.
When your mother phoned
I told her, what a voice she had!
Do you think I'm wrong? Say so!
You say you come to see me, and
instead you're playing around.
You're looking bad,
and you're drunk as well.
- Stop it, Marina.
- You stop it! I'm fed up!
I don't care if you've got others
girls! Do what you want!
But without a lot of drama
or pathetic scenes.
- You should say things to my face.
- Please, Marina!
There isn't anyone else.
No one.
I didn't think I cared
so much about you.
I didn't betray you, I'd have told you.
But there's one thing you don't know.
- Just one. - One? I don't know anything
about you, not even if you care about me.
It's the first time
you've ever told me.
I must go away. It'd be nice
to go away together.
To see far away places,
leave when and if you want
and return when you like.
Life would be great like that.
It's the only way to be happy.
You need money, lots and immediately.
Because I want to live life
while I'm young. At 20!
Not when I'm old.
- Do you understand?
- What are you saying?
What's the matter with you?
Have you argued with your parents?
It happens, you'll make it up.
They give you everything you want.
Do you think my father gives me
the money I've got?
I earn it myself!
It's not difficult, you know.
I was "doing well".
Very well!
Another few months and I'd have
asked you to come with me.
I want to save myself anyway, you see?
I don't feel guilty!
Nobody has the right to
take my freedom away!
Should I give myself up?
Spend years in prison.
Why give everything up?
I'd never be resigned to it.
It drives me mad just
thinking about it.
Give up my youth!
I've done everything to enjoy it!
I still think I've
got this right.
Even now that I've killed a man!
Yes, Marina, I've killed a man.
Are you mad?
What are you talking about?
Let's go away, maybe we'll never
see each other again.
Claudio!
I'm sorry. Do me a favour,
let's get away from here.
You won't be compromised.
You know nothing, understand?
You don't know anything.
It's not true, Claudio.
It's not possible.
It's true, Marina. I shouldn't
have told you anything.
But I needed to tell someone.
I don't feel any remorse, you know?
It's as if it hadrt happened to me.
If only I didn't feel so ill!
It happened when I fell.
What's the matter,
what's happened to me?
- How do you feel?
- I don't know, I feel ill.
Tell me how you feel.
It could be serious,
an internal wound.
Claudio.
Let's go to the doctor.
What does it matter now?
I'll take you to my doctor,
don't be afraid.
- Where are you going? - Dr. Bonanni.
- Go to the emergency ward.
Wait a minute, I'll be right back.
- Can I help? - Dr. Bonanni,
he should be on the emergency ward.
- Who are you?
- Tell him its Miss Marina.
Tell Dr. Bonanni that
Miss Marina is waiting to see him.
- He'll be right here.
- Thank you.
It's him.
- Madam, your son has come home.
- Where is he? - In his room.
How is he?
Claudio! He's come back!
- Please, Bianca,
let me. - No, me!
Calm down, this is something
I must deal with.
Good evening, inspector.
My sors come home. I'm sorry
to have inconvenienced you.
I must ask your son to come
with us to the police station.
To the police station?
Call a doctor, quick!
"Commendatore",
what's the doctor's number?
It's unbelievable,
you bring up a son day by day,
he's close to you,
and suddenly you find yourself
face to face with a stranger, a rogue!
Giulio!
What have they done to you?
Claudio, what have they done to you?
If only one of our children,
listening to our three stories,
feels healed
of the morbid fascination
which cultivates within him
too many false images,
if anyone, perceiving the unveiled
face of egoism,
feels faith in human solidarity
reviving within him,
our work
won't have been in vain.