Keto!
Keto! Where are you?
Got a cigarette, bro?
Where is she now?
I'm done for.
Keto!
Where the fuck is she?
Fuck it!
Keto!
Dima, take me for a spin.
Get out of here.
C'mon, take me for a ride.
If you fuck with me,
I'll screw your mother.
- Understand?
- Okay.
What the...?
Son of a bitch!
- Did you see who that was?
- No.
Damn it!
- Are you stupid?
- I swear to you, I saw nothing.
Didn't I tell you
not to go there?
What were you looking for?
Are you gonna answer
today or what?
It's always either school
or soccer.
There's a limit to how much
I can take, Mr. Shlomi.
Give me a break.
I've got hungry clients
and only two scooters,
what do you mean
give me a break?
Why haven't
the orders left yet?
They're going out,
stop yelling already.
Haim, I need to work.
I swear, I was on my way
to the address.
Did you lock it?
Sure.
Don't you know me, Haim?
I can work on the counter.
- I need the money.
- $0 do I.
Fuck you, you're all trouble.
You're breaking my heart.
Easy now!
Go home. I've got no wheels
for you. We'll see later.
Why are you still here?
C'mon, let's go.
What do you mean let's go!
No one is giving rides here.
Calm down, I'll walk.
Don't tell me to calm down,
I'll fuck you in the ass, come here!
If you come here again,
I'll take your eye out.
Who needs your fucking place?
Pay me what you owe me and you
won't see me again, you fat fuck.
Pay for the scooter first.
I'll give you money for a tombstone.
If it wasn't for your father,
you'd be dead now.
- Don't talk about my father, asshole.
- I'll say What I Want.
What's so funny, you fuck?
Beat it!
- Get out of here, you fat bastard.
- Asshole motherfucker!
You too? Come here!
Where are you going? C'mon.
Come back here!
- Adiel, goal.
- He's alone again?
You call yourself a goalie?
Don't let him through.
Guard him, guard him.
Look at him go.
Watch him go past all of you.
What a goal.
He got it in
right between your legs.
- Start playing.
- It's over, we Won.
Wasn't there an extension?
We said one extension.
Me and Adiel gotta go.
- You're going, Adiel?
- Yeah, I gotta go.
Meir, you owe me a game.
Next time whoever plays against Adiel
gets three points in advance.
- Naomi, are you going home?
- Yes, are you coming?
Do you mind taking Yonatan?
- Okay. C'mon.
- Thanks.
Here.
Did you see
how pissed off he was?
It's cause you always win.
He's just a shitty player.
He thinks he's Rolandinio.
How can he talk that way
because of soccer?
You do, you always win.
You should play on a real team.
You're talking nonsense.
C'mon, Meir, let's go.
I'm hungry.
Listen. bro.
I'm dead tired.
- Say...
- What?
What's with Naomi?
I think she likes you.
She wants you
to make her feel good.
Check it out.
Wow, just like Africa.
One love, one heart,
Let's get together...
What? What's the matter?
What's so funny?
Africa?
You were born right here.
Beautiful.
I like that song.
How about it, Eva?
Does your brother play Well?
Let's go to sleep.
- Give me a piggyback ride.
- C'mon, piggyback.
Good night.
Check this out.
You think it's a pizza?
I swear it is.
God sent it.
How long has this been here?
I don't know.
- I don't care, I'm hungry.
- Me too.
You thought I Wouldn't find you,
you bastards?
- Pizza, eh? You Want pizza. Here!
- We didn't do it.
- Then who did? Tell me.
- We found the scooter here.
Who dared to steal the scooter?
Who?
Talk, you fuck!
Tell me who took it, talk!
- Leave him alone.
- Fuck off!
- You son of a bitch.
- Let him go, Shlomi!
We found the bike, enough!
Move.
Are you okay?
C'mon, get up.
C'mon, let's go.
- Wait. Let him apologize.
- Are you crazy?
- What did you say?
- Nothing, nothing.
- Apologize.
- I'll kill you, I swear.
Can't you see they're stoned?
Enough already!
Take your friend
before things get out of hand.
- We're not thieves, you hear me?
- But you're a fucking nigger.
Enough already.
Move.
Son of a bitch!
- You think it's in good condition?
- I think so.
Take it to Haim
tomorrow morning.
I'm so tired.
I work the morning shift
tomorrow.
- Did you work the evening shift today?
- Yeah.
I love when you play that song.
It's so beautiful.
- It's always the same song.
- So what?
It's beautiful.
By the way,
Where were you today?
Sophi called.
Sophi called? Yes.
I'll talk to her.
She shouldn't have called.
Thank God she did.
You have to stop cutting school
and start studying.
You want to be like your father?
I won't be like him.
So stop cutting school
and start studying.
I'll be okay. I'm saving money.
I'll go to Germany.
Uncle Jenia
will arrange everything.
Why are you laughing?
Germany...
you're such a boy, Dima.
Hello.
What took you so long
to get here?
Smart ass.
Hi.
- How are things?
- Okay.
Thank God.
I'm so tired.
Does Daddy get a kiss?
Vlada, stop it, the boy's here.
Boy, why aren't you asleep?
Go to sleep.
You go to sleep.
Look at yourself.
Just like your papa.
Don't dare talk about my father,
you idiot.
Please, not in front of the kids.
Don't make noise,
Eva is asleep.
"Eva is asleep."
You only care
about these lazy bums.
- You don't give a damn about me.
- Don't talk to her that way.
See? That's your upbringing.
Is that any way to talk to a father?
What are you talking about?
Have you found a job yet?
A job?
Do you really give a damn
- if I find a job or not?
- Vlada...
Why don't you teach me
how to live?
stand up when you talk
to your father.
- Stop it. Please, Eva is asleep.
- Don't touch me.
- Calm down.
- Is this how you brought him up?
Is this any way to talk
to a father?
You're all against me.
What are you looking at?
Vlada, please,
this isn't necessary.
He's sitting there, staring at me.
Dima, where are you going?
He's a lazy bum.
- Dima, stop.
- How can you?
What are you whispering
out there?
Dima, please,
go to sophi tomorrow.
- Please, for me...
- How can you? How?
Dima, don't stay out late.
Let him go--
stinking piece of shit.
Go to your Germany already.
- Go to your Germany.
- I'll go to my Germany.
And what will you do here?
You'll crawl on your knees
begging me to take you
to Germany.
Dimwit.
- Did you run away from them?
- No, I Went for the hills.
- Then I saw it.
- What did you see?
It's 9:00 already.
You have to go to sleep, c'mon.
No, tell me what you saw.
I'll tell you tomorrow. It's late.
Mom will be mad.
Mom doesn't care.
All she does is sleep.
Okay, but promise,
not a word to anyone.
I promise.
Don't just promise, swear to God.
No, it's not allowed
to swear to God.
So swear on my life.
I swear on your life.
Go on, tell me.
You know the antenna?
That new tower in the fields,
- the one you can see from the pitch.
- The blue one?
It's not an antenna.
- What is it?
- It's a rocket.
No way, in the fields.
There are no guards.
I know. I wondered
Why there were no guards.
But I noticed the tennis court guard
keeping an eye on it.
Besides, this way it doesn't
arouse suspicion.
- So?
- I climbed the tower
- Do you know how high it is?
- What did you see?
There was a rocket inside,
a huge silver rocket.
I was blinded by it.
Really? Swear.
- I swear.
- Whose rocket is it?
It's our rocket, Israel's.
I think it can reach outer space.
Outer space.
Who's gonna fly it?
Who's gonna be the pilot?
What do you mean, who?
Little Yonatan ran to the garden...
C'mon, let's go.
Mom will be worried.
Besides,
you have to go to sleep.
- Are you all set?
- Yes.
Adiel, will you take me
to the rocket?
Sure I will.
Good night.
Adiso, bring me
a glass of water.
Here.
Is Yonatan asleep?
Yes.
I'll be back soon.
Where are you going?
That woman called again.
I've had enough.
You have to study.
Look at your brother Joseph.
Why can't you be more like him?
I'm not going back
to the Yeshiva boarding school.
So study, don't bum around.
Okay, Mom, I'm going out.
Don't be late.
You're taking Yonatan to school.
I'm going
to the doctor in the morning.
Okay, good night.
Good night.
Last card.
- I won this time.
- Well done, Sivan...
I think she's cheating.
Me?
No way.
- One more game.
- Okay.
And you, how are you?
She's all right.
- Can't Mom answer?
- Stop it, both of you.
- Itzik, Why don't you come back home?
- No Way.
I'm all right.
Don't Worry about me.
- How's school, Sivan?
- Okay.
- All of a sudden, you're interested.
- Enough, Shlomi.
Sivan, sweetheart, go to bed.
ltzik will come to say good night.
- You'll come?
- Sure I will.
Go on.
Good night, sweetheart.
Good night.
Aren't you going to say
goodnight to Daddy, Sivan?
Come here, sweetie.
Good night.
Since when is he her father?
Since you stopped being
her brother.
- You better watch it!
- ltzik, enough, please.
She's only got one father.
What's the story?
And you stand by
and say nothing?
And you come here
and pretend you care?
- Stop it, both of you.
- It's my house, you little punk.
- Itzik, please, enough.
- Get out of here.
Take it.
How's soccer?
Will you try to get
into Hapoel team this year?
Maybe. I don't know.
Why don't you tell him to stop
and go to school.
- He only has soccer on his mind.
- Cut it out, Mom. Enough.
- He stopped going to school?
- He goes and does nothing.
You want me to learn bullshit?
Why? It's not a trade?
Now you're on my case too?
Let's see you
when I make the pros.
Pros!
You've raised the new Pele.
Maradona.
Okay, get off my back.
What about you?
Where did you disappear
for two weeks without a word?
When are you coming
back home?
It'll be okay.
Go say goodnight to Sivan.
She really misses you.
- What's up?
- Come here for a second.
Wow! Someone
got a hell of a beating.
Meir, you abandoned
your friend?
No way,
that prick really fucked me up.
Why don't you go in?
The Russian bastard won't let us in.
Who did you call a bastard?
I'll be damned if I let you in now.
Yehuda, that's not nice.
He won't let us in.
He's a piece of shit.
Now, you won't get in
even with your mother.
Don't talk about my mother,
understand?
Shut up, Yehuda.
What's wrong with you?
Calm down. Here.
Some friends you've got.
Forget him. He's all fucked up.
Are the girls inside?
Ages ago.
she asked about you.
Can we go in?
Without Yehuda.
And don't make a racket.
You kept me waiting forever.
C'mon, what's with you?
- Do you love me?
- sure I do.
- What do you think this is?
- What do you want from me?
If my clad finds out about this,
he'll murder me.
- Do you love me?
- That has nothing to do with it.
Sure it does. If you were
really in love, you'd...
- Cut it out, Adi.
- But you promised.
We've been together
for four months already.
- It has nothing to do with it.
- sure it does.
Look at Jacob and Edna.
Jacob and Edna?
What did Jacob tell you?
Tell Jacob not to blab so much.
Okay, forget Jacob.
What about Sarit and that guy?
Sarit?
You want me to sleep around
like she does?
Go to her, go ahead.
What's gotten into you today?
Will you come tomorrow?
I'll see if my dad lets me.
You're such a little girl.
We're going to the Chika Club.
My dad doesn't like me
going out on Sabbath eve.
But everyone's coming.
Well?
We'll see.
Haim!
It doesn't look too good.
Give me the key.
Who took it?
I thought it was the Ethiopians,
but I'm not sure now.
- What do you want, eh?
- What are you doing?
You want to make amends,
you assfucker.
- Are you nuts?
- Now you need me, right?
- Get off me!
- You threaten me?
You owe me a month's salary,
you prick!
I'll fuck you and your brother,
you fucking smalltime punk.
- Why are you hitting him?
- Mind your own business, Drora.
Shame on you!
You'd better watch out!
Are you crazy? Get off him!
Esther!
Esther,
your brother's gone berserk.
Haim, what are you doing?
Haim, leave him alone.
What are you doing, Haim?
Leave him alone.
What are you doing?
Son of a bitch.
Look What he did to the bike.
Let me through.
He's only a boy.
Are you crazy?
- I'll smash your face in.
- Motherfucker.
Watch your mouth.
Get into the store I said, get in!
Haim, get into the store!
Son of a bitch.
Are you crazy? Beating a kid!
You want to get arrested again?
- Get into the store already.
- Okay.
Bring me a glass of water.
Are you religious?
No.
So why the yarmulke?
No special reason.
You put it on your head
for no reason?
I went to a religious school
before I came here.
- So you believe in God.
- Yes. I mean...
I'm a Rastafarian, it's the same God
but like... a little different.
How can I explain it to you...
It's complicated, eh?
Not at all. Rasta is for peace,
love, that kind of stuff.
So you're not Jewish.
I'm as Jewish as you are.
I'm not Jewish.
Is your mother Jewish?
- Yes.
- So you're Jewish.
There is no God.
Come in.
Okay. I wanted to speak
to you because...
You're aware of the situation.
Both of you don't come
to school regularly--
- I was here this week.
- Dima, don't interrupt me.
I don't think you're aware
of the gravity of the situation.
This is your last chance
and it's an understatement.
So I've asked Mann--
who knows you-- to help.
- I have a comment.
- Yes, Dima.
I'd like the protocol to show
that I don't play soccer.
Okay, we heard you.
Now you listen to me
for a change, both of you.
From now on
you're my responsibility.
You come to school every clay
and report to me.
At the end of the day you come back,
so I can see your pretty faces.
In the afternoon you go to
the community center for practice.
If you cut school or miss practice
once, you're finished.
- If you check the protocol--
- Dima!
There is no protocol.
There are two paths,
one leads to Matan;
the other one, out.
Don't worry.
We'll find something for you.
Adiel.
What do you want,
I'm on your team already.
On my team?
You haven't shown up
for practice for two weeks.
They don't pass me the ball.
If they don't pass it, come to me.
It's no reason not to come.
What have you decided?
Will you forget everything?
It's up to you.
I want you to know
that I don't play soccer.
Very good.
- See you on the court at 3:00.
- But it's Friday.
Don't worry. You'll get
to the synagogue on time.
Go on, out.
Dima, wait here for a minute.
Adiel, Adiel.
- How's your mom?
- Okay.
- Did it Work out with the doctor?
- Yes, I think so.
Adiel, you know
you can always talk to me.
Go to class.
You promised
not to talk to my mom.
I didn't see you all week.
Your mom said that you started
playing the piano again. Is that true?
I don't know
What you're talking about.
We talked about you performing
at the Memorial Day ceremony.
What?
What did you talk about?
I won't play.
It made her very happy.
She said you play
"Friendship" beautifully.
I promised her that you
would play it at the ceremony.
How could you have said that?
Can I go?
I told Orna you'd come
to rehearsals on Sunday.
Dima...
you're an intelligent boy.
It's your last chance. It would be
hard to convince the principal
- if this doesn't work out.
- It won't!
Hi, Dima, what's up?
Did you bring me some?
Forgot to do your homework?
What's up?
I looked for you this morning.
- They said you're--
- What?
- You're being kicked out of school"
- So?
- I thought--
- That I don't want the money?
No, that you weren't up to it.
Listen, they're not kicking me out
and I'm up to it. Give me my money!
But I don't have it on me.
Wait. Dima,
What are you doing? Wait!
- You said 51.
- shut up!
You think I'm playing games?
I'm not.
I'll slice open the next one
who fucks with me.
I'm not your friend.
Fuck.
Dima, wait a minute, Dima.
- Did you bring me any?
- What?
You know.
- C'mon.
- Where's the money?
- Is that all?
- I'll sort you out, you know.
Matan, how come there's
practice on Friday?
Got a problem with it,
Eldad?
If you do, you can go home
for Kiddush.
You all know Adiel.
And this is Dima.
Guys, we've finalized the terms
for the Independence Day tournament.
It's been decided that the team
waiting for us at the finals is
Hapoel Be'er Sheva youth,
coached by Jackie Dekel.
Enough.
I spoke to Jackie personally
and he promised to be there
and keep his eyes wide open.
So, that's why you brought
these two?
Shlomi...
You speak when I ask you to,
is that clear?
As the captain of the team...
on behalf of everyone, I say
that we don't need the Ethiopian.
He hasn't practiced for ages...
Adiel, sit down.
I've got news for you, captain.
His name is Adiel,
and he'd better not only adjust,
but become a part of the team.
Is that clear?
10 laps to warm up.
Go on, beat it!
Why 10? Damn...
Adiel, pass the ball,
don't do it alone!
It's okay, nothing happened.
Get, up! Continue.
Hey, what is this?
Why am I here?
You?
You're in charge
of team administration.
You bring water,
clean the locker room,
take care of the balls, nets.
You do everything I don't want to.
No problem, Dima.
One phone call to Sophi,
then your mother and it's all over.
Just give me a reason.
What's wrong with you, Matan?
I'm getting drinks, it's hot.
With plenty of ice, Dima.
Listen good.
Adiel better be here on Sunday
or I'm canceling the tournament.
Do you understand me?
I'll forfeit our spot.
Am I responsible
for the Ethiopian?
Shlomi, if you continue this,
you're off the team too.
He'd better show up for practice
on Sunday. Understand?
Okay, pay attention.
I managed to set up a practice game
on Sunday with Brom
from the job placement league.
Get a good rest on Saturday
'cause from now on there's
no fooling around. Any questions?
- Have a good Sabbath.
Does it hurt?
I saw What they did to you.
They didn't do anything.
Blind is he who chooses
not to see.
- Are you going to the synagogue?
- No.
- The Yarmulke is back...
- What do you Want from me?
I don't want anything.
You shouldn't let those jerks
get away with it.
We Rastas believe
that only serenity brings peace.
Doesn't Rasta tell you to fuck
whoever wants to fuck you first?
Whoever wants to make you his slave
isn't worth playing soccer for?
Who's a slave?
Don't think I don't see you
selling ecstasy and stuff on Fridays.
Hey, better watch
what you're saying!
You think they took you
because of your pretty face?
These people just use you
and throw you away.
And you sell ecstasy
because of my pretty face?
Just a slave.
How long do we have
to Wait for you?
Nobody asked you to wait.
The way you look,
I shouldn't have waited.
shut your mouth.
Who told you to come anyway?
Enough! Are you changing here
or at Chika's?
- We're not changing at the club.
- Hurry up.
- Why are you so uptight?
- Let's sit down.
Wow, Dima.
See that blonde?
I'd screw her.
Forget it.
I'd fuck her...
real good.
Everything"; cool...
Talk to me
before I go to the Forum.
Chill out.
Careful the vodka
doesn't go to your head.
Relax, everything will be okay.
Great music.
You have to drink that?
It's nothing. Why ruin things?
Can't you enjoy yourself without it?
You're like all the stoners here.
Anyone who heard you
would think you're a saint.
What did you say?
You have a problem?
I don't have a problem.
I'm having a good time.
Everybody enjoys Watching you
dance that Way.
What?
You never complained before.
Why should I? You look good.
Everyone likes to watch bitches, no?
Get away from me.
Is everything okay?
I told you my boyfriend is here.
This is your boyfriend?
This is your boyfriend.
- You can come along if you want.
- No, it's okay.
Get your hands off her.
What did you say?
Don't mess with me, understand?
I'll cut your balls off.
Outside.
Beat it!
Get the hell out of here!
son of a bitch, Why are you pushing?
Fuck you.
Beat it before I call the cops.
Get back inside.
Girls, how old are you anyway?
Beat it, go home.
Happy how?
You little shit.
Let's settle this now, c'mon.
Get out of here, you midget!
Are you coming? Beat it...
shut your mouth.
I'll fuck you.
- Just you Wait, you Russian cunt.
- Did you fall, sweetheart?
C'mon, get up...
Who's a bastard?
Who did you call a bastard?
Get out of here, you prick.
- You didn't have to do that.
- You'd have kicked ass yourself, eh?
- How old are you? Why?
- Leave them alone.
Go on, take them home,
take them home, Adiel.
Why? I would have shown her
a white dick made in Russia.
- Cut it out.
- Why not?
And you. Superman.
Next time I see you get into a fight
I'll kill you.
You'll ruin my business.
Get inside the club.
Let's go.
Look how big they are,
We're dead.
Look at their goalie, bro.
What is that thing? Scary!
Forget the goalie,
look at the size of that one.
Enough,
What are you, children?
That looks like a goalie to you?
That fatso,
I can circle him 10 times
before he knows what hit him.
Don't worry,
everything will be okay.
Avi, get the ball.
Relax, they're only kids.
Move in!
What's wrong with you,
don't you have a yellow card?!
Never mind, never mind.
Relax, Shlomi, relax.
Move in.
Aren't you ashamed of yourself?
They're half your size.
They're kids.
Do you want to kill them?
I spoke to the referee
and told them to calm down,
but that's no excuse
for what happened.
What's Wrong with you?
It gets a little physical, so you break?
- What about Eldad?
- What about him?
If you had defended your goalie,
he wouldn't have gotten hurt.
Disgrace, that's what it is.
It's a massacre, that's what it is.
At this rate there won't be a team.
Scared about getting hurt,
Ashkenazi?
Continue this way and you Won't
be playing in the finals.
If we continue this way,
nobody will be playing in the finals.
We'll end up in the hospital.
Avi, you're out.
Adiel, you're in.
Why me?
They didn't pass me the ball.
Avi, one more word...
I swear, just one more word!
Adiel, I want everybody
to help on defense.
- Nobody waits for the ball.
- What?
- What about Eldad?
Eldad?
Are you kidding?
He busted my shoulder.
Okay, that's enough.
Dima, put the cigarette out.
- Dima, you're in the goal.
- What?!
- Eldad, give him the vest and gloves.
- What's that?
You heard me.
C'mon, we're out of time.
He doesn't know how to play.
The last time I checked,
I was the coach here.
Eldad,
What are you Waiting for?
Dima, don't let the ball in.
I'm not playing.
He never even practiced with us.
Dima.
You know how to fight?
- I know.
- Good.
So do whatever you can to keep them
from scoring a goal.
No problem, boss.
Pass it to Adiel! To Adiel!
Very good, Dima.
Kobi . . .
Yes, yes. Exactly.
Shlomi! Pass it to Adiel!
Shlomi, I said pass it to Adiel!
I'll take you out.
- I'm warning you, Shlomi.
- Okay, I heard you!
Behind you!
Referee!
Adiel, get your foot in, that's it!
Kobi, get inside.
Wide, wide, Adiel!
Great! Great!
Way to go. Yes!
What's wrong with you?
Start defending.
Who can beat us now? Who?
Bring the juniors, bring Juventus,
we'll fuck them all.
What a goalie.
Did you see Matan fight
that goalie?
- That was far out.
- Where's that Russian?
- So long.
- Bye, Adiel.
Adiel!
Wait a second,
I'll be right back.
- Going home?
- Yes.
- Did you ever try out for Hapoel?
- No.
- Why not?
- No reason.
Don't you want to be
a soccer player?
No. I don't know.
I think you should go.
- Don't you enjoy playing?
- I like it. That's not it.
It's everything around it,
I don't know.
When you turn pro, it gets tough
and you stop enjoying it.
Didn't you enjoy today?
I did, but...
I don't know.
Cut the crap.
It's a shame to miss out.
There's lots of money in soccer.
I'll see. Maybe.
Matan thinks so too.
You know, we didn't take your bike.
We only found the pizza.
I know.
Sometimes I lose it.
- Are you coming tomorrow?
- Yeah.
- I'll see you.
- Bye.
Police!
Idiot.
What are you doing here?
Dimon, what are these clothes?
You play soccer?
I didn't know.
You're so dirty.
- You're a goalie.
- Cool uniform.
- Beautiful, Dimon.
- What do you want?
Oh! He isn't friendly today.
Dima, why don't you invite us in?
We can have coffee
with your mom and dad
and talk politics.
Ah!
Can't you say anything else,
asshole?
I'll kill you!
Relax. Okay.
Both of you relax.
You have no idea
what's going on?
- None?
I decided to come to you
for the money
and save you the trip.
- I'll be right back.
- Go on.
Vladik, stop it.
Everything will be all right.
You hear me?
Nothing will be all right.
I don't believe it anymore.
Stop it, you can't give up.
You'll see, everything will work out.
That's why I work all those shifts.
But I'm not working.
I can't live here.
Maybe if I went to Germany,
to Yivgeni, I'd make it there...
Forget Germany already.
Your family is here.
Who needs you there?
Dima, is everything all right?
- I have to go.
- Where are you going?
I'll be right back.
Sophi called.
Why?
I was in school today.
I know you were.
She wanted to invite me
to the ceremony.
Dima, is it true?
Did you agree?
Can Eva come too?
What will you play?
I don't know.
"Friendship," maybe.
Thank you, Dima.
Everything will be okay.
Excellent.
Well done.
Now we can talk.
Nice one.
Here, buy your mother
something nice.
Do you still have
my mobile phone?
No. Keep it.
There's a party.
A rave
on Independence Day eve,
I'll need you to pick up
a delivery in the afternoon.
We'll be able to sell
the stuff easily
at the party.
- Can I Work at the party too?
- Why?
Pressed for money?
- Are you paying as usual?
- Of course.
- I'll be there.
- Let's go.
A party, a delivery.
Someone around here
needs money.
When's the delivery?
At noon as usual.
We're leaving for the rave
at 10:00.
Okay? A kickass party.
Is that all this asshole knows
how to do,
repeat everything you say
like a jerk?
Dima, this time you're wrong.
You're wrong.
Go home now,
before I release the bulldog.
- Did you play yesterday?
- Yeah, with the team.
Really?
You're back on the team?
You won?
How many goals?
It was a tie, but we played
against the big guys.
- Did you score a goal?
- Yeah, three.
And we have a new goalkeeper.
You know Dima, the Russian
who lives in the nearby block.
He's not scared of anything.
He's crazy.
- Wow, three goals?
- Yes.
You should've seen them.
They were so fat they could hardly run.
Wednesday we're playing in
the Independence Day tournament
against Nitzanei Gimel.
If we beat them,
we'll play against Hapoel
Be'er Sheva Juniors in a stadium.
Really? The Hapoel stadium?
Yeah, I'll tell Mom to take you.
Will you play for Hapoel?
Maybe.
shlomi says I have a chance.
They'll also be coming from
the Netanya soccer boarding school.
The boarding school again?
Don't jinx it. It's the best
soccer school in the country.
They'll only take me
if I'm good enough.
But you're good, you're the best.
Even Meir says so.
You'll leave us again?
Forget it, I don't stand a chance.
Don't even think about it.
Here. Put it in your bag.
What are you worried about?
Besides, I like Hapoel better.
Okay?
Go on, eat.
Is this what I pay you for, Eyal?
You let some kid
make fun of you...
I'm talking about 7,000 NIS
in damages. Go see for yourself.
He's a piece of shit...
Who says he did it?
- Then who did?
- Plenty of people choked on your shit.
Cool him down
before I do.
- 7.000?
- 7,000. Check out the mess he's made.
Independence Day is in two clays.
What will I do?
How much
do you pay these guys?
51 NIS per hour plus tips.
He'll be here Wednesday.
He's yours until he pays up.
7,000 at 51 NIS per hour.
7,000? Come on...
What's the deal, Eyal?
Be honest with me, bro...
Is it because
he's his brother?
- Fuck you, if you dare touch him...
- Go get the jeep.
Go on.
He'll be here Wednesday.
- Haim beat him up in front of everyone.
- What?
What did you just say, ltzik?
I'm bending over
backwards for you.
You know what would happen
if it were someone else.
He'd better be there.
Let's go.
Go on, Adiel, go on.
Cut, Kobi. cut!
Adiel, look at the line, Adiel.
Take it.
Never mind. Very good.
Come here, everybody.
Tomorrow is Memorial Day.
There's no practice.
Wednesday, Independence Day,
you get to the game on your own.
The first game is at 9 p.m.
I'll let you know
Who's playing tomorrow.
You're starting to look like a team
and that's good.
Don't let it get to your head.
Don't worry, Matan,
everything will be okay.
We'll screw those wimps.
Do I look worried to you?
Go on, go home.
Adiel! Dima!
Come on.
So you're playing
against the juniors tomorrow?
We'll kick their ass.
They don't stand a chance.
What about you, nigger?
What do you play?
Why talk that way?
Striker.
- Is he any good?
- You better believe it.
He's Zidane.
Nice one.
What about the Russian?
The Russian is chilling out.
You look like it.
Say, how's my brother?
A real pro, right?
Your brother's fucking excellent.
He's a captain.
Right, he's got potential.
Well, he's an Adani,
not just anybody.
Look at the nigger suck on that,
as if it was a pussy.
Hey, relax, Kunta Kinte,
pass the joint.
He's got potential.
- Bye ltzik. Bye.
- Bye Shlomi. Bye Avi.
Shlomi, wait a minute.
Why didn't you tell me
about Haim?
- What are you talking about?
- Don't fuck with me!
- Why didn't you say anything?
- Get your hands off me.
The motherfucker hit me.
- What were you thinking?
- It's Haim. And Haim means Eyal.
If you have trouble with him come
to me. You don't just pay him a visit.
- I'd have killed the motherfucker.
- Shut up!
What's happening, ltzik?
Problems?
Everything's cool.
- He wants to see you Wednesday morning.
- I've got a game.
I don't think you get it. Tomorrow's
Memorial Day. There's no business.
But Wednesday morning,
you've got a shift.
- I've got a game, don't you get it?
- I don't give a fuck!
I'm not going.
What do you mean, not going?
ltzik, get into the car.
Remember what I said.
Next time, come to me.
Go home! Go on!
Damn it, ltzik, c'mon...
Think about your brother
next time.
Think about your mother next time,
assfucker.
You prick. Fuck!
Such a beautiful boy
Went to the angels
Up in heaven
And in the silence
His mother's cry was heard
Our hearts stopped beating
Wings...
Yes.
Where are you?
I'll be right over.
Is everything okay?
Where's Dad?
If you don't come, I won't play.
They say time heals all wounds...
Here you are. Orna is looking for you.
Where did you disappear to?
Have you spoken to your mom?
- Dim.
- What do you want?
She said she'll try to come.
I asked Orna to call you last,
right after the principal, okay?
I asked everyone to come
half an hour earlier to help.
He was with Matan.
I'm glad somebody
bothered to tell me.
Dima is here.
Everything worked out.
This is no way
to conduct a ceremony.
How was I supposed to know
Where you are?
I'm here now.
$0 what's the problem?
You should do something
about your attitude.
Orna, it was my mistake.
I didn't tell you.
Einav! What are you doing
with the wreath? Put it back.
Who does she think she is?
Never mind.
Everything will be all right.
- He didn't come to any rehearsal.
- Some things are more important
- than a ceremony.
- More important?
That's just the attitude
that makes him behave this way.
These things will bring him
closer to his heritage.
Yes, but Dima has to do it
at his own pace...
On Memorial Day?
While the sirens were sounded?
Next to the names of the 31
fallen soldiers from this school?
Disgrace.
Where do you think you're going?
Don't you have to get on stage?
I'm going.
Take an example from your goalie,
and he wasn't even born here.
Report to me at the end of the clay.
Go back now.
Before we begin our
Independence Day celebrations,
I ask that we all remember
the people that have allowed us
to be a free nation in this country,
celebrating Independence Day.
I'd like to invite one
of our students to the stage
to play the song of friendship
for us,
a song loved by one of our greatest
Prime Ministers,
a man who symbolized
the immortal lyric:
"The Beautiful
of Mind and Body,"
Mr. Yitzhak Rabin,
of blessed memory.
Coming up to the stage is Dima,
a new immigrant from the former USSR
who symbolizes the revival
of the Jewish nation in this country.
Dima, please.
You're through here!
Don't ever bother to come back!
My manager said, either you order
something or he calls security.
Tell your manager to come out
and say it himself.
Hi. Look who's here?
Rolandinio, no less.
What's wrong with you?
You didn't come today.
We had a ceremony.
What happened?
We had a game today.
I didn't forget, bro, I didn't think
anything would happen today.
Forget it,
he's got White friends now.
Was I talking to you?
Is that what you think of me, Meir?
I haven't seen you since Friday.
You disappeared then too.
Lay off already!
Meir, you know the score. I gotta play,
otherwise they'll kick me out.
I think you care more about
your white mates than your friends.
Is that so, Meir?
You're not coming
to my game tomorrow?
Cool, I get it.
Let him go. Fuck him.
Did you see the Jacuzzi
they have over there?
That's no Jacuzzi.
It's a therapeutic tub for injuries.
Forget that, did you see
the senior"; locker room?
Has anybody seen Matan?
I saw him talking
to Jackie Dekel outside.
Hey, anyone have a shin guard?
You lost it again.
What's with you, Berger?
- Adiel, you happen to have one?
- No, bro.
Take it from somebody
who's not playing.
Take one from Assaf.
He only plays if the whole team
is injured, including Matan.
Anybody would think you've been
playing since Adiel came back.
We're a team. No one plays alone,
have you forgotten?
Maybe you'll be the goalie, Assaf?
Hey, Shlomi, who's the goalie?
- How should I know?
- Eldad.
I told Matan I'm still in pain,
but he told me to come anyway.
He really went berserk
on Memorial Day.
No matter what you say, that Russian
asshole really knows how to play.
Who are you calling an asshole?
Dima!
The pianist.
Did you come to play for us?
Did you talk to Matan?
- What have I got to say to him.
- He'll let you play?
- I'm part of the team, aren't I?
- So you spoke to him.
Who spoke to whom?
- What are you doing here?
- Matan,
- Eldad is still hurt.
- Was I talking to you?
- What are you doing here?
- There's a game, isn't there?
Why are you all
giving me puppy eyes?
Go on, go Warm up.
Get dressed.
Shlomi. Shlomi, come here.
Listen, I just spoke
to Jackie Dekel.
He's got his eye on you.
- Take us to the finals.
- Don't worry, Matan,
- I don't miss opportunities.
- Go already!
Hello.
I'll be there.
I said I'll be there.
I'll be outside at 2:00.
Nag.
That was my mom.
she said she might come.
I think she'd better come,
for our sake.
Shlomi, what did I tell you?
- You're coming with me right now.
- Forget it.
Fuck you.
I said something, didn't I?
I'm not going.
What'll you do to me, eh?
C'mon already!
Haim's Waiting for you.
Beat it.
- Move before I...
- Before what?
- Let him go.
- Matan, it has nothing to do with you.
How's that?
He's the captain.
- Leave.
- shlomi, for the last time,
- come with me.
- I'm not going.
Now beat it!
Remember this, Shlomi.
I tried.
It's out of my hands now.
- Don't come to me when Haim...
- Haim, what?
What will he do?
Go on, get lost.
Go.
Sit in the stands and watch
your brother make a life for himself.
Go.
Well, go on.
Warm up.
Shlomi, Shlomi!
Remember this.
Avivim!
We're going to toss for it.
Ball or side?
Side.
You win. You start.
Good luck. Good luck.
Get down.
It's nothing.
Nothing happened, Ref.
Meir, I swear,
nothing happened.
Get out, I said, get out.
They wouldn't have
scored a goal!
Meir!
Substitution.
Quiet down.
Calm down.
Preserve your energy.
Okay, you played well,
you proved who you are,
you proved you're a team.
Very nice.
The final is in three hours.
It's going to be
a whole different game.
The deputy mayor will be here,
the seniors will be here.
I don't doubt that you can
beat the juniors, no doubt.
Enough.
Go say hello
to your friends,
family and drink
plenty of water.
Where are you going, Dima?
Don't worry, I'll be back.
Don't forget, eh?
Is that what you think?
The referee blows the whistle
at 4:00.
- Oh God, Yonatan isn't with you?
- What happened?
I don't know where he is.
What do you mean?
We went to buy
something to eat.
Your mom came back
and we couldn't find him.
- How come?
- He wasn't there.
What's the matter with you?
Answer me!
I have no idea.
I turned around and he was gone.
- I thought he was with you.
- Where were you?
At the falafel stand.
Can't you even watch him!?
We'll go home and look for him.
Are you playing?
Soon. In the finals.
Know somebody named Adani?
Matan!
Dimon.
See those white stairs?
So?
Go up to the second floor,
you'll see a door on the right.
There's a small bag on the floor.
Take it.
- Is that all?
- No, that's not all.
You take it,
but you don't come back here.
You go to Tanya.
Behave yourself
and she'll blow you.
- Real class.
- Asshole.
Where do you find them?
Until you grow up.
I have to hang outwith idiots.
I'll get to Tanya. And?
Tanya will explain everything.
There's no time. Go.
Don't forget.
I have to be back
at 3:30.
Don't worry, Maradona.
Yonatan!
I'm over here.
I didn't want you to win.
I didn't want you to go
to boarding school.
Don't worry, I'm not going.
Where's the rocket?
There's no rocket, you made it up.
There was one, I swear to God,
I think the army took it.
You're not allowed to swear to God,
He'll punish you.
Where's your yarmulke?
Did it fall off?
You bastard,
I'll fuck you, you bastard!
Have you seen Keto?
Have you seen her?
You lost your sister again?
Give me a cigarette.
Go home, you crazy fuck.
Mamuka loses everybody.
Keto! Keto!
Bastard, I'll fuck the shit
out of you, just wait.
Keto!
Stop!
- Give me the bag. You're under arrest.
- Look at this, Tzachi.
Look at this.
What's your name, kid?
- What's your name?
- Answer him.
Dima!