April the 10th, 1671.
Monsieurle Prince de Condé...
His Majesty gives me reason to believe
that he would graciously accept an...
invitation to vislt you at Chantilly.
The visit will last three days.
The king instructs me to say that
he wants no fuss.
Merely the simple pleasures
of life in the country.
I not her words, if you value His
Majesty´s favor,you will set no limlt...
to the extravagance and
ingenulty of festivities.
I´ll present my self before hand
to approve the arrangements.
Marquis de Lauzun...
in the service of His Majesty
Louis the 14th,of France.
My dear Master Steward,
Monsieur Vatel.
Good new sand bad news.
His Majesty arrives
on Thursday.
I can´t emphasize enough
the importance ofhis visit.
A dropped wine glassor
an uncomfortable cushion...
would spell disaster
to ourentire province.
The good news is that we may
go to war with Holland.
On that table.
-Good morning, Monsieur.
-Good morning.
The Princess has placed her
apartments at the Queen's disposal...
Naturally I should place mine
at the disposal of His Majesty.
From the King antechamber
we pass through the music room...
and next to the apartments
of the Queen.
Her Majesty's bedroom...
Drawing-room, and a further bedroom
for Her Majesty's lady-in-waiting.
Lady-in-waiting,
Madame de Montausier.
Anne de Montausier.
Her Majesty will be
comfortable and convenient.
The King won't be going to her bed,
he did his duty two days ago.
Remarkably well informed.
The Queen always goes to confession
the following morning.
-When was it?
-Monday.
-Monday?
-Remarkably well informed.
This room is to serve as
the Council Chamber...
and the King's bedroom...
A second bedroom so here.
And this of course...
we´ve allocated to the
Duchess de La Vallière.
Who I believe is close
to His Majesty.
No.
This room is for
Marquis de Montespan.
It 's hard to keep up when
you live in the country.
And La Valliere?
Anywhere. In the attic.
I prefer Monsieur Le Prince
if my rooms were north-facing.
-I don't like the sun coming in.
-Your rooms, Lauzun?
I myself will have only one room for
those 3 days. As will the Princess.
Every corner and cupboard
is spoken for.
And to accommodate the court
we had to use every farm house...
from miles around.
My room...
No. I won't have you
disturbed, Vatel.
You haven't slept
for aweek as it is.
Have that cleaned.
The first day,
the glory of the sun...
the bounty of Nature.
Trees, birds, butterflies...
fruits and flowers.
The second day, on the lake.
Fireworks.
The sun banishes the night.
The lamps are on their way
from Paris now.
For Friday, the fish banquet will be
presented in asea of ice.
Neptune's tribute to Helios,
the Sun God.
-The King will catch a cold.
-No, my Prince...
the braziers will be lit
one hour before the banquet.
And the ice will melt.
I have forbid it to melt,
my Prince.
Well, our fate is in your hands.
There is always a reason
behind a royal visit.
And the reason for this one
is William of 0range...
king of Holland, who wants war.
And if he gets it,Louie is going
to meet the best general in France...
that many people think
is none other...
than the Prince de Condé,
even withgout.
Compared to this visit
from the king...
war with the Dutch
will seem like a picnic.
-Thank you!
-How can I help you?
Excuse me, sir, but we will only talk
to the top. Nobody else.
I regret it. His Majesty
is busy at this moment.
His host, the Prince of Condé,
like wise.
Not them...
The man in charge.
The master of pleasure
and festivities. Vatel.
Vatel!
That 's slightly more difficult!
I'll see what I can do.
Please, follow.
Good morning!
-How many geese?
-6O, Monsieur.
Monsieur Vatel...
-You're trespassing here, Alcalet.
-All of us are owned money.
We've come to tell you.
From this moment nothing on credit.
Not asingle cabbage leaf or cracked
coffee cup, or table napkin. Nothing.
-Until our bills are paid.
-Exactly!
We mean to get paid.
Come.
We have business to run and
families to provide for.
When we will get
what we are owned?
What you are owned now is the truth.
We cannot honor our debts.
Not for the months
or the years gone by.
Much less this festivities.
We cannot pay you asingle ''sou''
nor will we ever.
You have only one chance
of getting your money.
By giving me everything
I asked for. Instantly.
And of the very best quality.
And then more of the same.
This visit is a reconciliation.
If the King is pleased
by the festivities...
then the royal coffers will open.
The Prince is bankrupt.
It 's up to you.
If we do give you more credit, how do
we know we'll get our money back?
The Prince said so.
My master is a man of honor.
On that I stake my life.
You will be paid.
Good.
Excellent.
Good morning...
Monsieur Vatel.
Are you going down, Madame?
I'm going up.
Where is Montausier?
Explain to her the Queen does not
wait on the lady-in-waiting.
Forgive me, Madame.
Please. Let me.
Allow me.
I hope your birds
will be happy with us.
Madame!
Here we are.
Put him with the fruits.
Monsieur, the King's brother
wants him for his page.
He chose me!
Get him dressed
and put him to work.
And what would you have me tell
His Highness, the King's brother?
Tell him I don't get my boys
from his boudoir...
and he won't get his
from my kitchen.
Yes... indeed I will.
I need another two of this.
The same size, if possible.
It 's not very wise upsetting
the King's brother, you know.
It could make things go bad for us,
if he chooses.
I'm asteward, not a pimple.
Monsieur Vatel!
The Princess has been bitten
by a monkey!
Master Steward, you filled my garden
with savage beasts!
I've been badly bitten.
Where were you?
Busy, Your Highness.
We had some unwelcome visitor.
-Beggars?
-No, no. Creditors!
Creditors?
Dr. Bourdelot!
I've been badly bitten
on the arm.
Oh, no!
-What 's your name?
-François Vatel, Madame.
Monsieur Vatel.
You were at Vaux-le-Vicomte
ten years ago.
Yes, Madame.
I was steward to Nicolas Fouquet.
His Majesty's Minister of Finance.
You mean, His Majesty's prisoner
for life in the fortress of Pignerol.
-That is so?
-Six thousand guests...
to meet the King.
Diamonds and saddle horses given
away as prizes in childish games.
That was overdoing it,
don't you think?
It showed how much
Fouquet had been stealing.
Gourville, why has the King
really come here?
It's revenge. The King will
never forget that Condé...
fought against him
in the civil war.
That was a long time ago.
The King was a child.
If there's awar with the Dutch...
the King will need Condé.
-Yes, but he is...
-Sick of war?
So he is. But he is equally sick
of being in debt.
I'm passing red hot stones.
Condé!
Majesty?
What exactly do you need
to borrow so much money for?
The better to serve France,
Your Majesty.
Well, Colbert, where are
our envoys from Holland?
-Aren't they here yet?
-Not yet, Your Majesty.
Peace with the Dutch
is good for nothing.
Except tulips.
How many tulips
do we have at Versailles?
-Two million, Sir.
-My gardener hates flowers!
He would love awar
with the Dutch.
Indeed, sir.
But would Your Majesty
please recall...
that you have offered your daughter
in marriage to William of Orange.
An invasion would not look well
in the eve of a betrothal.
My daughter can't even
talk yet, Colbert.
4 days ride from Paris, we have a
country of republicans, protestants...
and printers of
seditious pamphlets.
No King is safe
from free-thinkers...
especially if they are
as rich as the Dutch.
We have no better soldier
than Condé.
And if there is war,
we'll need him.
He's expensive.
But if there is peace...
What do I say in the meantime?
Why say anything?
Your Majesty was invited here
to enjoy yourself.
Not for business...
Your Highness?
Are the musicians ready?
Yes, my Prince. The King didn't utter
asingle word to me during Council.
-Kept muttering to Lauzun.
-Which one is the King?
You killed my only son.
You bastard!
He died working in
the machines at Versailles.
So the King
could have fountains!
-Take you hands of me!
-Have you no control of your people?
His Majesty wants her flogged,
and at once.
See to it, Master Steward.
I'm not your master
of flogging mad women.
A hundred lashes.
You know what 's at stake.
Don't weaken!
Murderer! Assassin!
My son! My son!
Monsieur Vatel!
I'm short of a page
at my household in Saint Cloud.
And you have a boy
who might do, apparently.
Send him to my apartment
and I'll have a look at him.
Come, Lauzun,
we have been promised music.
Music is my weakness.
The mad woman has been
flogged, Your Majesty.
I ask your pardon.
Mad woman?
Don't concern yourself, Prince.
I recall no mad woman.
There's no sign of them.
-How long are they going to be?
-You can't hurry a King.
Well, one can't
slow down the sunset.
-Madame...
-Monsieur Le Marquis?
The King sends you
his compliments...
and he begs the favor of taking
a cup of chocolate with you...
in your room, at midnight.
With me?
May I offer you
my congratulations?
Although, as you can imagine...
this came as a great blow to me.
After tonight I cannot
hope for deliverance...
from the pain
of my own desires.
May I suggest...
my rooms at ten?
Alas, Monsieur...
ten o'clock I have
an even more attractive offer.
Her Majesty has asked me
to delouse her Spaniel.
Madame.
Monsieur Vatel.
He is coming!
Thank God!
Go, go!
Table one!
With your King, eat, drink...
and enjoy yourselves!
Your hat!
Go, go, go!
The King's gout is bad.
Tell Dr. Bourdelot.
Madame de Courbé needs
a new napkin. Come on.
Marquis de Effiat wants his dishes
without coriander.
Isn't it to your taste,
Your Majesty?
Change Montespan
for Montausier.
You look pale, Prince.
Are you ill?
Your Majesty
is gracious to inquire.
Yes, indeed.
I see we share the same taste.
Taste?
In women.
There is a lady who has been
rejecting my advances...
in away which
I find quite stimulating.
Her world is about to change.
The King has asked for her tonight.
I suggest we mark the event.
I want you to make
a masterpiece.
Spun sugar, almond paste,
fruit and flowers.
-I'll leave it to you.
-I'm not a pâtissier, Marquis.
I will be too busy.
Ask someone else, Marquis.
Fruit and flowers
in the color of flesh and blood.
Flesh and blood.
I will send my valet
in the morning.
Young Sire,
I ask you to behave yourself.
-Don't you know who I am?
-I do not have the honor.
I am the Vicomte d'Amboise...
and when I grow up I will be
the Duc de LaTremoille.
In that case it 's not too soon to learn
to behave like the Duc de LaTremoille.
In truth, the Duc de La Tremoille
behaves like a pig.
I thank you, Madame.
The poorest of poor of Chantilly
picked those flowers...
just for a few ''sous''...
to make the trees pretty for
His Majesty. And did so on credit.
But the poor are happy
to be the King's creditors.
-It 's an honor they never dreamed of.
-Of course.
Both my parents were so honored,
they died of it.
The Prince's birds.
Oh, God! I can't believe this!
-Where are my birds?
-By order of the Vicomte I let them go!
What Vicomte?
The Vicomte d'Amboise, Doctor,
and his sister. They ordered me.
But they are children!
They are little children!
-But he is still a Vicomte, doctor!
-These were the birds of the Prince.
What am I going to do?
I mean, it is a disaster.
I specifically ordered those thrushes
and larks for the Prince's gout!
His gout is giving him agony today.
What am I going to do?
Use something else.
Use something else?
Use something else...
The heart torn
from the living bird...
is the only treatment for gout.
Everyone knows that.
-Why not chickens?
-Chickens!
He's a Prince! Chicken's hearts
wouldn't even cure a peasant.
Monsieur Vatel!
Are you trying to ruin me?
-Your Highness?
-First that mad woman.
Now the Marquis de Lauzun
tells me you've been insolent.
-Insolent?
-You refused to be of service to him.
I refused to be his pâtissier.
What is the matter with you?
Lauzun has the King's ear. For
the next few days do what he asks.
Bravo!
Gourville, have they put you
to spy on me?
If they had, you would be
in the Bastille by now.
You despise them, don't you?
They don't leave me
much alternative.
Tell me, Gourville,
who is Anne de Montausier?
-Why?
-How many times have l...
bitten my tongue? And now I snap at
the only one who is human to me.
Well, she is new at Court.
She still got a heart...
or so they say.
Good.
Yes, but it better be perfect.
Colbert is not in our camp.
He is hostile to our Prince
getting influence at court.
Good night, my Queen.
Your Majesty...
Madame de Montausier.
I'm concerned about the fish.
I have sent to Dieppe
for an extra cartload...
in case there are storms
off Les Havres.
You are my general.
The battle plan is yours to decide.
-What else?
-Nothing. Unless it rains.
The carving stewards
will have to sleep in the stable.
But they are German.
-The lanterns arrive in the morning.
-Very good. Well, I leave it to you.
Go to bed, my friend.
Vatel...
You did well.
Goodnight,Madame.
Can you tell me
where Vatel is?
You sent for me,
Monsieur Vatel?
Food for cattle.
Now we can feed cattle
through the Winter...
instead of having
to slaughter them every year.
How many varieties
of pears are there?
There are 5OO different
kinds of pear.
This is the best one.
Its name is?
-Bon Chrétien d'hiver.
-And...
-It was known to the Romans.
-Good.
When I'm rich,
I'd like a garden like yours.
I hope so, Colin.
I hope so.
Bravo, Colin.
You made a good choice.
The King will be pleased.
Colin...
don't leave the kitchen
without my order. Colin?
They were badly packed...
and the roads were bad.
Monsieur Vatel.
I am the valet
of the Marquis de Lauzun.
-My commiseration.
-Thank you.
Good.
Now a real flower.
Give me the blue one.
Harmony and contrast.
All beauty comes
from those two things.
You see, Colin? A few objects
are beautiful or ugly in themselves.
To know that is the beginning
of being an artist.
Here. Huh?
Now I will show you
a real masterpiece.
-For your mistress.
-Just a moment.
It 's from the Marquis de Lauzun.
Send it back.
She doesn't want it.
Will you keep me with you
when you are a Duchess?
Let 's wait and see
if I am to be a Duchess...
or just a night 's divertissement to keep
Madame de Montespan on her toes.
Or on her knees.
Louder!
-I'm in love!
-With a fish?
Monsieur Le Marquis?
-What?
-She refused it, Monsieur Le Marquis.
That 's rather beautiful.
Send it to...
the Duchess of Longueville.
With the note?
Of course.
There's far too much waste
in this country.
Madame.
There still won't be enough meat.
Not with the extra guests.
Monsieur,
I'm worried about the meat.
We have scarcely enough.
Monsieur Vatel!
The King's brother,
he is playing with the whale.
The monster must not get away!
Kill with my heart!
It is they your hand
should strike.
Strike now!
Your men are so careless.
They've quite spoiled our pleasure.
My men had orders
to wait for me.
The whale was intended
for the King's pleasure.
The King!
That 's ashame.
We, Bourbons, are unpredictable
when deprived of our...
pleasure.
You are astubborn man,
Master Steward. Admirable.
Horse racing!
Get that carcass
out of the water.
For your mistress.
Must be from the King.
There is a note.
It 's all right, Louise.
It 's all right.
It 's sugar.
Madame,you were kind to
one who turned a side kindness.
Such gift as I have,
Iemploy for your forgiveness.
François Vatel.
Master Steward,
do you promise us sport?
Yes, Princess, there will be sport.
-I smell blood.
-I promise you blood!
Montausier's stock is rising.
She spent the night
in His Majesty's bed.
Does everybody know
who sleeps with the King?
Every footman knows. Sometimes you
can be quite ridiculous, my dear Vatel.
You find the day more exciting
than the night, Madame?
You sent back
my gift and my note.
You think the King
intends to keep you?
Perhaps not, Lauzun.
But from the King's bed
to yours is a long fall.
And I'm not contemplating it
in this life.
François!
They are waiting for the sauces!
Pick this up.
Someone help him.
Go on.
Monsieur Vatel, the pie!
There's really not enough meat.
We are two tables short.
They gave us the wrong numbers.
Give me that!
-Bring me some mushrooms.
-Edouard! Mushrooms!
Condé has won 4O,OOO pistols
from the King.
Colbert must be furious.
By losing a little
you might have won more.
By winning a little
you might lose everything.
Is the Prince
losing its Chateau?
Not if he plays his cards wrong.
Your Majesty.
Madame de Montausier.
Condé's demands are excessive.
-Outrageous!
-You mean, he knows his price.
Of course, if there were
to be awar...
As yet there is no war.
My envoys from Holland...
may well bring terms we can accept.
I would prefer that.
It is not rational for
two rich countries to make war.
My dear Colbert, our destinies
are not ruled by reason.
Lust for power, like any lust,
is seated at least according to...
the latest medical knowledge,
in the liver.
Although, personally...
it hasn't been my experience.
Madame?
Madame!
Madame, please.
Are you ill, Madame?
I just needed to escape
from them for a moment.
If you make an infusion of this,
it will restore you.
I wanted the wind
to stop blowing.
I made it stop.
Oh, I thought it was God.
Then perhaps God provided me.
Is it so important?
It is no small thing
to please a King, Madame.
To please a King
is easily done...
and of no importance.
But as asteward
I have it in my power to...
to save the house
of the Prince of Condé.
What power do you have?
To create.
To astonish.
The visit of His Majesty
is the supreme test.
If I please him, his benevolence will
restore my master to his position...
in the destiny of France.
So the destiny of France
is in your hands, Monsieur.
That will be a great surprise
to the King's minister Colbert.
I must go back.
Laurent!
What kind of meat is this?
Unicorn. Laurent!
Hurry up!
For God's sake!
There's no news
about the lanterns.
More than half the eggs are addle.
We can't make the custard.
Watch.
Come.
The sugar will come out
like bitten egg whites.
-Don't forget the apricots.
-No, Monsieur.
Lanterns, lanterns...
Lanterns...
If they ask you what it is, tell them
it 's an old recipe from Chantilly.
Don't cut any more melons.
Who is it?
Don't be afraid.
Come on.
My mistress...
she asked me to stay
until I've seen you read it.
This is so pretty!
What astrange idea.
A custom from lndia.
Your kindness to me shows
a nobler heart thananyat court.
Where they know only
hunter and prey.
Use your powers
to protect yourself.
Beware Lauzun. A.
Please, thank your mistress.
I stink from head to toe.
This is good.
I don't know it.
It 's made from walnuts.
What did you want?
Monsieur sent me,
the King's brother.
It 's not an easy embassy.
Your name is in everybody's lips, you
know. This banquet will be decisive.
Your geniuses...
Get to the point.
Monsieur wants you
for his friend.
He admires, well... to speak quite
frankly, everything about you.
So, what he wants
from you is...
everything.
-Do I hear you right?
-What do you hear?
That monsieur has sent you
to ask me to join a long line...
of stable boys and Princes
whom he has honored so... intimately.
Yes, your hearing is very good.
Tell Monsieur...
and I quote Descartes
whom I once knew...
''There is no soul so weak
that it cannot...
acquire an absolute power
over the passions.''
Monsieur is not a Cartesian,
as far as is known.
He only wants a few moments
of your time.
Then I send him a message
which reveals more of me...
than he would ever see
if I were to submit. Tell him...
that both of us live
with a terrible thing.
The desire for the absolute.
The sublime. The perfect.
That 's why he flits
from person to person...
and that 's why
I give myself to no one.
And the Prince?
How long do you think it will take
before this reaches the Prince?
Not long, if you hurry.
My dear Vatel.
We all go round together
like a celestial machine.
The Sun King is at the center.
Condé is one of his planets
and I am Condé's moon.
Do you think there's a place
to stand when we are free?
Naturally I will speak to Condé.
Not to do so would be...
self-important.
Bourdelot!
Why have you got
Madame de Montausier's birds?
I got them from
Madame de Montausier.
-I'm saving them for the banquet.
-For the banquet?
No. In case the Prince
requires them for his gout.
But why?
The Princess has asked La Montausier
to sacrifice her canaries.
She refused.
So, the Princess
told Her Majesty...
and she commanded La Montausier
to give them to me. Her Majesty.
But canaries...
are so small.
I don't think that their hearts will be
enough to ease the Prince's pain.
See, all this rich food
is very bad for his gout.
I can't serve him omelet to celebrate
the visit of the King of France!
It 's not your fault. I just wish
I had some better birds, that 's all.
I have my parrots.
But surely, Vatel,
you will not sacrifice...
If the Prince's pain
gets too great to bear...
send to me for my parrots.
Tell the Princess
the canaries are too small.
Demaury!
Return those birds to
Madame de Montausier's room.
Condé is lucky. This banquet
would shame a Roman emperor.
Who is this Vatel?
Where does he come from?
Nowhere.
The slums of Paris.
He was apprentice to Eberhardt 's,
I believe.
Eberhardt 's? Fromlle Saint-Louis?
My mother swore by Eberhardt 's.
So did your father. Although I don't
think he went there for the pastries.
Vatel, I was just telling
the Duchess here...
It 's quite true.
No one knows more about the brothels
of thelle-Saint Louis...
than the Marquis de Lauzun.
I think he's just insulted you,
but it 's hard to tell.
That 's a rare gift.
If you punish him for it...
I'll tell everyone
your favorite perversion.
Fetch Bourdelot.
From lndia?
How beautiful! lngenious!
I have learned something today.
Which is rare.
-You sent for me, Vatel?
-I need something.
-Are you in pain?
-No.
I'm in the grip of some anxiety.
Anxiety? I've got nothing
for anxiety. I'm a doctor!
Vatel!
Go!
And now for you! One, two, three.
And more, and more!
I am the steward of the fish.
They tell me these carps
are called Love-Carps.
Gourville gave me your message.
You understand me like none
of my friends understand me.
I hope you find your perfection.
I know I'm looking
in the wrong place.
But when I despair...
I shall remember there was a man
who looked into my soul.
Sport! I demand!
There shall be a race!
-Between Efriat...
-Yes!
...and Carl.
-In!
Efriat, now!
Master Vatel,
the horses are ready.
Come on.
What awonderful spectacle!
Condé, who is responsible
for these marvels?
My steward, Your Majesty.
And what is his name?
François Vatel.
Bring me this Vatel.
I would like
to congratulate him.
16,OOO pounds of
flares and rockets...
gone up in smoke
to kill a groom.
Sir, the King wishes
to speak with you.
Not now, please.
Does he think all this
happens by itself?
I want everything cleaned up
by dawn. Understand?
-Is it Friday already?
-Yes, nearly.
I must send Demaury to look out
for the fish. The roads are bad.
-Demaury, Jean-Marie is dead.
-I know.
-You must tell his family.
-I sent a messenger to tell them.
Monsieur, the Queen is asking
for crystallized fruits.
Well, get on!
Lauzun!
Withered away, Lauzun?
The King has called for Vatel.
He's refused to come.
Claims he is too busy. Monsieur.
Lauzun?
I'll pass his message
onto the King.
Monsieur.
Halt!
-What is your business?
-King's business.
Envoys from Holland.
Let me go! Let me pass!
The black Queen loses, Colbert.
Let me try to help.
Your Majesty, my hand
needs all the help it can get.
If Colbert loses, he won't be able
to pay our workmen at Versailles.
-Monsieur, are you all right?
-How many workers do we have?
3O thousand, Your Majesty.
Well, Monsieur, don't deal him
the black Queen.
How many orange trees
do we have, Colbert?
-One thousand, Your Majesty.
-And one hundred in silver cups.
Versailles is
my favorite mistress.
That 's why she costs you
so much.
What are you staking, Prince?
Ten ''louie''.
Ten ''louie''?
How many fountains
do we have, Colbert?
One and a half thousand,
Your Majesty. Forfeit.
For Versailles, if I lose.
For something of yours,
if I win.
A glove perhaps, mon frére.
But one glove is no good
to anybody. Now...
What?
Well, Prince?
I have nothing do add to the glory
of Versailles, Your Majesty.
But that 's not true.
You have something
rarer than diamonds.
You have
the Master of Pleasures.
Majesty?
Vatel is worthy of a larger stage. And
Versailles could use a man of his gifts.
You are asking me to stake
my Master Steward on a card game?
Do you have any objections?
Look what you might win!
We take the bet.
Are we playing or not?
Very well.
Then we'll play.
Your Majesty, the envoys
from Holland are arrived.
Then they come in
an interesting moment.
This is true.
Well...
it 's between you two.
Prince.
Black Queen.
Bad luck.
The envoys.
If His Majesty comes out smiling,
it will be peace with Holland.
No, if he returns smiling,
it will be war.
War?
What do you think, Monsieur?
Certainly one or the other.
Also if he returns frowning.
Your Majesty...
Condé...
what are your opinions of war?
I have seen too much
of destruction, Your Majesty.
William of Orange
has declined the offer...
of the daughter of
the Duchess of La Valliière.
Gallantly telling us that
his family only marries...
the legitimate daughters
of kings.
-Not their bastards.
-I see.
Furthermore, the ruler of
the flat earth has minted coins...
with the image of the sun.
That is impertinent.
He has commissioned an oil painting
of one of my flagships sinking.
With your permission...
I will drown him in
one of his dikes, Majesty.
You do not have
the command yet, Prince.
It is between you and Turenne.
-Turenne.
-Oh, I'm sure all will be all right.
After all, you have the King
under your roof.
And Vatel to perform
his miracles.
The King is pleased with you.
Generals have been chosen
for worse reasons.
Tomorrow will be decisive.
No, no.
Just leave me this one.
The Prince is grateful
and would like to see you.
-Her Majesty?
-Asleep, Madame.
They were brought back.
Orders of Monsieur Vatel.
Would you like me
to undress you, Madame?
No.
Fortune seems to be with us.
A war with Holland.
Turenne is scheming to get Colbert 's
backing. The King favors me I think.
He will make an announcement
at the banquet tomorrow.
-Everything must be perfect.
-Everything will be perfect, my Prince.
We've always understood
each other.
You are a great man, Vatel.
You will end up as aVicomte.
-You have heard.
-Heard?
The King wants you
at Versailles.
Versailles?
I'm a cook, not a courtier.
The King wishes to honor you.
Go.
I am sorry. I can't.
I cannot leave my people.
We have a present for you.
From the Marquis de Lauzun.
This will teach you
not to step above your station.
In the name of the King,
let him go.
What do you want, Messieurs?
Preparation!
And plunge!
Excellent. Edouard... calf.
Louis. Back.
John! Wrist.
Bravo. Excellent.
And now... Open...
Tell Lauzun enough!
His Highness, the King's brother,
presents his compliments, Mons. Vatel.
He requests us to escort you
to your apartments.
It won't be necessary.
I wanted to thank you.
If the King knew
you were here...
The King is busy with
Madame de Montespan.
No one has seen me.
So you are coming
to Versailles, Monsieur.
Or haven't you heard?
My Prince will never allow it.
One of my people
was killed today.
Who was it?
His name was
Jean-Marie Benoud.
28 years old,
from the village of St. Crose.
His father is a miller there.
His mother died of
asweating sickness two years ago.
He had two brothers.
One a priest.
He came here as astable boy...
he was senior groom
for three years.
Three years.
-You knew him well.
-No. Not particularly.
He was one of my people.
He was fortunate in that.
Why did you save
my birds, Monsieur?
Because they were too small
to do any good, Madame.
And because...
because...
because they were yours.
Madame!
-Anne!
-His Majesty!
Go.
He asked for me.
He wants me.
It 's the King!
I'm a fool.
Yesterday you were a fool.
Stay here.
You think I can do that? You have
lived among the farmers too long.
Condé gave you away
at the card table.
To please the King he gave you away
like a hound from his kennels.
The King has retired.
Alone.
-We searched high and low.
-I was...
I know where you were.
But I would never betray you.
Now I told the King that you were
probably consoling a dear friend...
the Duc de Longueville.
The way his wife puts herself about
is disgraceful.
Don't you think?
You are a true friend.
Well, you will need a friend now,
won't you?
Would you do me the honor
of sharing a cup of chocolate...
with me...
even at this late hour?
I think you'll find the King a less
democratic man than myself.
And it would be tragic,
would it not...
if Vatel were to be sent back
to his former master...
a prisoner of Pignerole?
-My lord! ls there any news?
-News?
From the money.
The money from the King.
Money?
Yes, for sure.
The news is very good.
The King is well pleased with us.
-My God. Where is Vatel?
-I'm looking for him myself.
-Is everything all right?
-Oh, yes. Indeed.
-Is that all?
-Yes, sir.
Have you seen other fish carts
on the road?
No, sir. There are storms
all along the coast.
Few boats put to sea at all
and they came back empty.
Empty!
-Come back tomorrow to be paid.
-Thank you, Monsieur Vatel.
MydearPrince.
Todaythisbanquet willbe mylast.
But It willbe magnificent.
The broth will be made
from garlic and leeks.
Demaury, remember to blanch the green
vegetables before you sauté them...
or they will collapse
while waiting for the King.
The lobsters will be grilled.
They must be cut in half,
when they are still alive.
Be sure the knife
is big and sharp.
Don't worry.
Everything will be perfect.
Monsieur Vatel,
a lady dropped her fan.
Not now, Thibault.
Not now.
Monsieur Vatel.
From His Majesty.
It 's your commission
for Versailles.
The King commands that you
leave for the court tomorrow.
There will be awagon
for your personal baggage.
Do you have a horse?
He'll await your answer.
Monsieur!
Are you there?
Bravo!
It 's your turn.
Monsieur! Wonderful news!
The fish carts! They are arriving.
Poor little things.
Like prisoners.
Madame...
What is it?
Vatel...
This is for you.
I am sorry.
Madame,you were right.
I was not the master
of these festivities...
but their slave.
When you read this...
Is hall have left this world
with only one regret.
That I cannot be with you.
In the last three days
I have come to understand...
that I treasure freedom
above all.
Between Condé and Versailles
the pass is narrow...
and I have takenlt.
May you find a better road.
Your home is, I think,
in the south.
If so, remember that
there is a place...
not faraway, in Vaucluse...
where they plant cherry trees
among the vines.
The taste of the cherries...
comes through in the wine.
The fish banquet was
a tremendous success...
even though the sauce lacked
perhaps that touch of perfection.
But that was over looked...
in the excitement of
declaring waron the Dutch...
and of Condé receiving
his command.
0f course no one dared
to tell the kingthe truth.
And soon the word went round...
Vatel killed him self
because of the fish.
Which flattered His Majesty...
and pleased his courtiers.
Anne de Montausierleft Chantilly
quietly by a side gate...
and never returned to court.