I can't do it.
No, you can.
The question is will you?
This is no great illusion
when I'm with you
I'm looking for a ghost
or invisible reasons
to fall out of love and run
screaming from our home
'cause we live
in a house of mirrors
we see our fears
and everything's our songs
faces and
second-hand clothes
but more and more
we're suffering
not nobody,
not a thousand beers
will keep us
from feeling so all alone
but you are what you love
and not what loves you back
that's why I'm here
on your doorstep
pleading for you
to take me back
Is that a good one?
What the hell was that?
Flock of these.
Very funny.
You are what you love
Look at that guy.
Slut Speedo.
Cold water makes them
shrivel up.
How would you know?
We're really going to do this?
You can wuss up
but I'll be 20 bucks richer.
You're just gonna take it off
right here,
with everyone looking?
That was the idea.
Yeah.
I can't do it.
Yeah, you can.
The question is will you?
Oh, no.
You think because your eyes are
closed no one can see you?
Screw you.
Get in.
I can't swim!
- Yes, you can.
- No, I can't.
I don't like waves.
I hate waves.
And you just remembered this?
Oh, no.
You're naked!
I know!
We just came over to tell you
you have the best ass
on this beach.
What means this?
You French?
We are Romania.
No English.
Nice.
- Wanna go for a walk?
- Mm-mm.
Mm-mm.
She can use her tongue,
though, right?
Mm-mm.
- Where you going? Come on.
I'm doing it.
Look, mom.
You didn't want to stay
and see what your special
prize was going to be?
You mean my really special
gang rape?
Oh...
hey, what's the matter with you?
How about "I'm sorry,"
"excuse me" or something?
You can use your tongue.
Can't you?
Sorry.
You're selling ice cream.
Yeah, amazing powers
of observation.
Can I have one?
Which one?
What's good?
Uh, they're all shit.
Recycled industrial waste.
The red, white, and blue,
please.
That camera yours?
No.
You don't have to be
such a dick.
She's just trying to be nice.
Let's go.
Thank you.
Your mouth is so blue.
I think someone hurt him.
That makes it okay for him
to be an asshole?
Oh, come on.
You liked him, too.
Hey.
Lilly.
Jesus Christ.
Hey, what time is it?
Uh, I don't know.
Maybe, like, 6:00?
Shit.
I hope Norma's still
with a patient.
Good luck. I'm going to take
my award-winning ass home.
Okay.
Please don't do that.
Return my bike.
Lillian, where have you been?
I told you this morning,
brighten beach.
You took it all the way
to Rockaway?
All the way to Rockaway.
Okay, if you knew you were
going to be this late,
you could've had
the courtesy to call.
My phone died.
Joy would like to spend some
time with her family, too.
Well, dad's still in the office.
That is beside the point.
You need to eat something
besides noodles.
I don't like fish.
It's disgusting.
- It's your dinner.
- My disgusting dinner.
You know what?
That's enough.
- Joy?
- Yeah.
Why don't you go home
to your family,
and the girls will clean up.
Lillian, please go tell
your father
that we are going to be late
for the concert.
He can't still be
with a patient.
You stay there
and eat some protein.
And take your shoes off.
You're tracking sand
all over the house.
Did you tell him?
He was with someone.
What is wrong with you?
Edward, please go get changed.
We're going to be late.
It starts at 8:00.
Okay, I'm going.
Uh...
Sorry, I'm...
Edward, come on.
We're going to be late.
Coming.
Al Franken.
Al Franken is a God damn comic.
He's good, but what's the
name of that show he was on?
And she's the best civil rights
attorney in New York.
What is she going to do, go to
Wisconsin and work for some guy
who's on comedy central?
NBC. SNL is on NBC.
Jon Stewart's on comedy central.
Thank you so much for that critically
important piece of information.
Hey, get your ta-tas
all sun burnt at the beach?
Ta-tas. Really?
That's cute.
You told him?
No. You know you're
an asshole, right?
How about we change the subject?
Sure, we could talk
about politics again.
Well, we could talk about
your two favorite subjects...
television and body parts.
- Asshole.
- That's a body part.
He's 16.
What's your excuse?
Karl, come on.
So how's that tour-guide
thing going?
My boss is a perv,
and I have to wear a uniform.
Well you have a straight shot
into the masonic lodges
of the United States.
That's true political power.
So when do you head out
for school?
Oh, that's right. Yale.
Whiffenpoofs.
An Ivy-covered thing...
lay off her, dad.
Orientation is the first week
in September.
They're not telling you you have
to change your orientation.
I said stop it.
She doesn't come from a family
where you have to train
for dinner.
What's the point of dinner then?
Okay, great,
you guys enjoy your meal.
Let's go.
You just walked in
on your father
boning some random patient,
and you don't know
what you're upset for?
Does your mom know?
- Are you going to tell her?
- Are you crazy?
Everybody okay out here?
Dad, go away.
Your parents screw around.
I think they just talk
about it a lot.
I can't believe that you were
talking about sex.
Well, apparently in my house
you don't really talk about it.
You just do it.
We're the last ones.
On earth?
At Erasmus,
at St. Anne's.
That's basically the same thing.
We're going to fucking college,
and we're still virgins.
We've got to get over this hump.
You didn't say that.
Persons of the male gender
are required.
Out the windows
to your right and left
are the air ducts
to the Holland tunnel,
and if you smell
roasting coffee,
that's because general foods
built their coffee
processing plant
in Hoboken in 1846.
There are some people who say
you can still smell the coffee
from the other side of the river
even though the plant closed
in 1992.
You're probably ready for an
iced coffee right about now.
This is the end of our tour.
Gratuities are appreciated.
Please be careful getting
of the boat,
and enjoy the rest of your visit
to the big apple.
- Hey, girl.
- Hi.
Norma? Don't you ever
have to call home?
Only when I need bail money.
Uh...
- shit, I forgot to tell you what happened last night.
So I... God, I went out to
dinner with Danny and Kate.
This, like, obscure Italian
place in the village,
and the waiter
turned out to be him.
Who's that?
Um, the ice-cream guy
on the beach.
His name's David,
David Avery.
You just ran into him?
Not exactly.
What do you mean?
He had a book of matches
from Grotta Azzurra next to his
camera at the beach that day.
I can't believe you dragged
your parents to a restaurant
because you saw
a book of matches.
Okay, you don't have to make
me feel bad about it.
I'm not. I'm just...
it's like...
Didn't you have something
you wanted to tell me?
Uh, Fitzsimmons.
He came on to you again?
No, he... he just wants me
to give a tour
to a boat load of FBI agents.
Danny's going to love that.
I'm starving.
Do you want to split a burger?
Who said you could come in?
Mom's crying.
She's actually crying?
Where's dad?
I don't know.
- Where is she?
- In her room.
What happened?
Did they have a fight?
No, they were just
standing there.
And mom went to her bedroom.
What are you going to do?
Nothing.
It's none of our business.
I'm scared.
What are you scared of?
I don't know.
I'm just scared.
Come on.
I'll paint your nails.
- Red?
- Yeah.
- Really?
- Sure.
I feel like walking
do you feel like coming?
I feel like talking
'cause it's been a long time
now your hair is long
and you look so thin
you're always so pale
but something has changed
you're almost a man
Hungry?
- You made that?
- Maybe.
No one buys ice creams
on Tuesdays.
What are you doing?
No one takes boat tours
on Tuesdays.
What?
Are you the one who says
how many rivets there are
in the George Washington bridge?
Yeah.
What's your name?
Lilly.
I'm David.
I'm going to grab a shirt.
You ever been to the cyclone?
Yeah.
You wanna go?
Got my bike.
Come back for it.
I don't think I should.
Sure. Suit yourself.
682 rugby.
It still hurts
It hurts
la la la la
That's all I got.
It's not very good.
It's kind of shitty...
will you stop it?
I think it's great.
Why do you do that?
You're good.
I called him at the restaurant.
He wasn't there.
He's never anywhere
when you want to reach him.
I know you think I'm an idiot.
You barely know the guy.
I know.
So how come Norma
hasn't called you yet?
She's m.I.A.
Hasn't left her room in a week,
but I better go check
the battlefield
in case there are casualties.
Keep the faith.
Call me tomorrow.
Okay.
People have affairs.
This is the 21st century.
It's not the fucking
end of the world.
Lillian, I would appreciate it
if you wouldn't speak to me
that way.
Mom, there is
a whole family here.
He said he was sorry.
I heard him.
She's probably just
some random person.
He only did it to get
your attention.
This doesn't concern you.
It doesn't concern me?
He's my father.
I want him to stay.
Well, we all know
how you feel about him.
I can't believe
you just said that.
You're a God damn shrink.
You know what, Lillian?
If you can't find a way
to control yourself,
I'm going to have to ask you
to leave the room.
Thank God,
I can't control myself.
You live in a porno movie.
It's a photographer's studio.
Frank Mayo.
You heard of him?
Lets me sleep here in exchange for
kinda acting like a security guard.
- Weird place to sleep.
- Oh, I'm up there.
Want a beer?
Think they did, like, a lipstick
commercial here today, so...
He's got a dark room, too.
He doesn't use it anymore,
so kind of teaching myself
to print.
All the good stuff
was shot on film.
Where's your family?
Now? Eastern parkway.
I grew up on Staten island,
though.
I moved there from Tennessee
when I was five.
Staten island?
Yeah.
People actually live there.
Moved out, though,
when I was in high school.
How come?
It was just safer
for everyone that way.
You think your mom's trouble.
These all yours?
Yeah.
You really want to do this.
I don't want to do anything
except get out of here.
Where you want to go?
Rome, Paris,
I don't know.
Why?
Smell it.
Breathe it.
Tired of seeing it
in photographs.
Sylvia Plath.
Do you know this?
Would you read it to me?
"Daddy,
"you do not do, you do not do
"any more, black shoe
"in which I have lived
like a foot
"for thirty years
"poor and white
barely daring to breathe
or achoo"
I think you better get home.
You told Gerry you were going
to see her on Friday.
So.
Are you?
It was weird.
We met at the restaurant,
and then we just walked around.
And it was pretty obvious
that I was down to hook up,
and he didn't even touch me.
Maybe I should've come on
to him?
I mean, aren't guys
supposed to like it
when you make the first move?
I even wore my purple sweater
that's so low cut
my tits practically
hang out of it.
Shit.
Maybe that was too much.
- Oh, my God.
- What?
There he is.
I told him I was meeting you
here for open mic.
- What do I do?
- Nothing.
What do you mean nothing?
The song is about him.
It's fine.
Hey, you remember my friend
Lilly Berger?
David Avery.
I'm so happy you're here.
All right, okay.
I'm going to...
I'm going to go set up.
I'm really nervous.
So don't laugh at me.
I'm going to trip.
If you wanna find yourself
by traveling out west
Or if you wanna find somebody
else that's better, go ahead
Go ahead
If you wanna buy a band new
fancy automobile
Or if you wanna build
a place
Down in east Hampton,
go ahead
Go ahead
Be my guest
If you wanna have your cake
and eat it, too
Or if you wanna have
other people
Watch you while you eat it
Go ahead
If you wanna hold on
To the first girl
that you meet
Or if you wanna settle down
And plant roses at my feet
Go ahead
I wish you would
Just go ahead
- You're really good.
- Thanks.
This is a great jacket.
It's my dad's.
I gotta go.
What was that?
I mean, count on me to
find someone certifiable.
I can't imagine your dad
in that jacket.
I actually just can't
imagine him without a tie.
Have you seen him?
He uses the office, but she
won't let him come upstairs.
Well, maybe she's right,
you know?
You should be able
to trust the people
that mean something to you.
What?
Nothing.
Well, do you wanna
get something to eat?
Think I'm gonna go home.
Well, I can't sleep.
The guys who went on before me
said that there's a producer
in the audience
and that they're meeting up
with him at Wally's,
so I think I might
just go meet up with them.
Okay, wish me luck.
Luck.
Ow.
Sorry.
That was hard.
Good job, Lil.
Sit down?
No, thanks.
Hot as shit in that uniform.
I'm fine.
Yeah?
All right.
That trip was worth two tours.
You want more like that?
Specials?
Hmm?
Night cruises are triple time.
I take classes.
You're a real pistol.
Mm.
Won't bite ya.
I'm late.
All right.
Some other time then.
Yeah.
You know what you should do.
You should call the ACLU.
She wasn't exactly molested.
Well, verbally she was molested.
What?
That's disgusting.
It's gluten-free.
You know, I'd rather not have
a lecture about my intestines.
I would just like
some normal bread.
Such a pain in the ass.
I mean,
what is wrong with white?
Come to my house.
Everything's white.
Anyway, this is
kind of a big deal,
because you do
have an obligation
to the women who are gonna
work for this guy in the future
to make it clear that
what he said was inappropriate.
It's not okay.
It was more how he said it
than what he said.
No, I know exactly
what you're saying.
Can we please just have,
like, a little bit of privacy?
Little bit.
Just think about it, Lilly.
Were you scared?
Yeah.
But it must feel kinda good
to have a guy want your body.
Mm, no.
He makin' a house call?
What are you doing here?
I just came to watch your
parents scream at each other.
You just turn up
whenever you want to?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm out of here.
I just feel like
I don't understand you.
I believe you want me to tell
you things you already know.
Where can we go?
Wait.
I've got something.
It's all right.
I'm scared.
You haven't done it before?
Do you want it to be me?
Yeah, but I'm really scared.
Okay.
He's got you
where he wants you
And he'll have you
when he wants to
But you'll want him too
Yeah you'll want him too
He's got you
where he wants you
And he'll have you
when he wants to
But you'll want him too
You're going to be
very late for work.
She didn't come home
until 2:00 last night.
How do you know?
You were sleeping.
She woke me.
She took a shower.
I was hot.
Would you like to tell me
where you were so late?
Gerry's.
I don't know how late
they let her stay out,
but in this house,
your curfew is midnight.
Is that understood?
I'm going to college.
There is no curfew.
You're not there yet.
Can I play at Jackie's
after my swimming lesson?
You're like a stalker.
What do you want?
I'm gonna be late.
Listen, Lil,
this thing that happened
between your mother and I,
it's not your problem.
- It's not?
- No.
You just walk away
and leave me to deal with her
and then say
it's not my problem.
I'm sorry.
This is all bullshit.
I'm supposed to be
leaving for college,
not dealing with you guys.
Just have dinner with me.
Are you kidding?
No.
Okay. All righty.
Now, ladies and gentlemen,
can we have
a little attention please?
Can we have your attention?
Uh, we're about to commence
the cooking ritual,
as they used to say in the
international workers of the world,
by any means necessary.
And so I think
we need a sacrifice.
So is there a virgin here?
Oh, my God.
You know, there are some people
who are virgins
who don't want to be
perceived as virgins,
and there are some people who...
time to cook the hamburgers.
Time to cook
the hamburgers. Yes.
Yes. Okay.
You actually like him,
don't you?
We should just swap families.
Any time.
No one laughs at my house.
No one shuts up here.
I talked to David yesterday.
You did?
I mean, if you can call it that.
He's not much of a talker.
He called you?
No, I called him
to invite him to this,
but he said he couldn't come.
You think I shouldn't
have called?
I don't know.
What are you doing?
This is my room.
Excuse me.
The last time I checked,
I still paid the mortgage
on this house.
So I don't get any privacy?
Your sisters
are already up and out.
- Let's get going.
- Thank God for small things.
I sure hope
the inside of your head
doesn't look like this room.
Can you just leave that?
Come on.
Get going.
- Lilly.
- I'm in the shower!
Do you have my
cream rinse in there?
- No!
- Are you sure?
I can't find it.
Yeah, it's not in here.
Your father called.
He wants you to let him know
if you're going
to have dinner with him.
Okay!
I'm going downstairs.
I have a patient.
We have 15 minutes.
I'm lost in the light
I pray for the night
Take me to take you too
After so many words
Still nothing's heard
Don't know what we should do
So someone could see me now
Let them see you
Was my greatest thrill
When we just stood still
Let me hold your hand
till I had my fill
Even countin' sheep
Don't help me sleep
I just toss and turn
right there beside you
So if someone could
help me now
-  They'd help you too
- How'd you find this?
My cousins used to live here.
They'd help you too
See you through
All the hard things
We've all got to do
'Cause this life is long
And so you wouldn't be wrong
Bein' free with me
On my own
And I held my own
Still I rattled your bones
I said some awful things
and I take them back
If we would try again
Just remember when
Before we were lovers
I swear we were friends
So if someone
could see me now
Let them see you
See you through
All the hard things
We've all got to do
'Cause this life is long
So you wouldn't be wrong
Bein' free with me
On my own
Really like that one.
That one?
That one's my mom.
Sometimes I wish
she would just die.
Your mom?
Why?
She makes you very miserable.
I'm afraid of dying.
I'm afraid of not doing anything
while I'm still here.
I don't think there's
much chance of that.
What time is it?
9:30.
I told my mom I'd call
if I wasn't back my ten.
Where's your phone?
Aw, come on, don't go.
It's in the kitchen.
Well, mine's dead.
- Mom?
- Oh, thank God.
- Where are you?
- At a friend's.
Gerry's been trying to find you.
...Subway...
...emergency.
Her father died...
when are you coming home?
Right now.
What is it?
- Hey...
- don't.
I have to go.
What...
what's goin' on?
- Gerry's father died.
- Whoa, whoa. Let me go...
no.
I'm so sorry.
I don't feel anything.
You know, I know that...
that my life has
changed forever,
and all I want to do
is go to sleep.
Because I'm the same,
but I'll never be the same,
you know?
Like he'll never
slap me on the butt again.
He'll never see me graduate,
and he won't...
see me get married,
and he'll never know my kids.
I want my daddy.
How is she?
Okay.
How are you?
I'm fine.
You can't let this happen, mom.
You've got to let him come back.
I was very sorry to hear
about Gerry's father.
Yeah.
I'll go to the funeral
with you, if you like.
There isn't gonna be a funeral.
Just a memorial service.
Then they'll scatter his ashes.
That's how they do it.
Did mom talk to you
about coming back?
Yeah.
Are you?
I don't know.
You could just die,
and none of this would matter.
Just talk to her.
Explain it.
- Say you're sorry.
- I have.
She won't let you.
Try and understand it
from her side.
- Is that what you're doing?
- Yeah.
That's exactly what I'm doing.
Now...
I love you, but I gotta go.
Okay?
God, I can't go back in there
and look at all that food again.
It's like we're having a party,
and he's just late.
God, I gotta get out of here.
I want to go to work,
but Kate won't let me.
You should take a few days.
It's really weird.
All I can think about is David.
I keep imagining
that he's gonna walk
through the door.
Hello?
Oh, David?
Yes, hold on a second.
It's for you.
David Applebee or something.
Tell him I'm not here.
Why?
You are here.
Just tell him.
You're weird.
She's actually not here.
Can I take a message?
Okay.
Did you get my message?
- No.
- I talked to your sister.
- She didn't tell me.
- She said she'd write it down.
I've been trying to get ahold of
you for, like, three days now.
- I was with Gerry.
- How is she?
Okay.
I have a trip in 15 minutes.
All right.
I'll come back after work.
No, I'm gonna see Gerry
after work.
Okay.
I'll come with you.
No.
You should go this afternoon
if you're not working.
There's a lot of people
at night.
So, is that what you want?
For me to see her alone?
Yeah.
All right. I'll let you know
how that goes.
Hey.
Sorry about your father.
Well, thank...
thanks for... for coming.
Do you want anything
to eat or...
no, I'm f...
fine.
Wanna get out of here?
Yeah. Yeah.
Everything tastes...
sort of smells in here.
It's for the blind.
He used to take me
when I was a kid.
I mean, my...
my dad.
He was always so quiet.
It's like now.
Even he was quiet here.
Once I came by myself
on my bike.
And it started to rain.
I was like, uh...
Seven-years-old,
terrified, soaking wet.
And I, um...
I looked up and he was there.
I didn't tell anyone
where I was going, you know?
He just...
he knew.
I'm sorry.
Could you please hold me?
Could you hold me?
That was dad.
Would you make love to me?
And I'm asking you...
you don't need to feel
responsible or anything.
You know, I just, um...
I just feel like you understand.
Please.
All right, folks.
We all know Danny was
a man of, for the people.
He was also a sexy
son of a bitch.
I can't listen to this.
And he loved his Kate.
Anybody who spent
five minutes with him
could see that.
He came over yesterday.
David?
I did it, Lilly.
Okay, so you're thinking
about my father...
that this is crazy.
But it...
it just felt right.
You know, I needed to do it.
I understand.
You know, underneath
all that tough guy stuff,
he's really... he's...
he's so gentle and...
I'm glad it was him.
So...
I don't feel
any different, you know?
I mean, I...
I'm not sore.
I didn't bleed.
My mom always said I, uh...
I lost it to a swing
when I was four.
So...
Don't worry.
I'm okay.
If
you want
to fly
I love you.
Love you.
Just let go
of your mind
Can I have the brown?
Jackie's sleeping over.
Who said you could use that?
It's just an eraser.
It was on your dresser.
What's the big deal?
Stay out of my room
and away from my things!
Don't be sad
be glad
you'll find your way
and when
you reach
your love
David. Too busy
to answer my phone.
Or just relax
and drift away
and if you find
Hey.
I'll take that drink.
Um...
you want, like, a...
a drink?
Oh, shit.
I haven't got any ice.
- It's fine.
- Okay.
Okay.
Ooh, I need a haircut.
Oh.
Oh, boy.
Okay.
I really like you.
You're smart.
I wanna give you
a chance to walk away.
I don't want to hurt you.
I'm a big girl.
All right.
Let's have some fun.
Come on.
Hey, you on the pill?
- You on the pill?
- No.
- No?
Okay.
Stay right here.
I gotta get some protection.
Okay?
Hey!
Where you goin'?
Come in.
You okay?
Why'd you do it?
Do what?
Gerry.
Don't tell me what happened
didn't mean anything.
Yeah, it meant something.
You asked me to go see her.
I didn't ask you
to sleep with her.
No. She did.
So you did.
Is that what you think happened?
I don't have to think
it happened.
She told me it did.
She said that?
I just fucked fizsimmons.
Dad's back. He brought
his clothes and stuff.
He got you that?
- You had one.
- We did not.
Dad said
they were too dangerous.
Apparently, guilt will
corrupt people's principles.
You're cooking?
Hi.
That's it?
Hi?
You're just back?
No one talks about it?
You haven't given us a chance
to say anything yet, Lilly.
Here's your chance.
Your father and I decided
that it would be better
for everybody if he...
if he came back home.
Why?
What are we?
The wallpaper?
We're just supposed
to sit back and watch
while you move in and move out
and move in and move out again
like it makes
no difference to us?
This is what you wanted.
I don't understand
what's different
I've been asking you
to come back for weeks.
And now, suddenly,
you just do it.
This time, I asked him.
Are you crazy?
Do you want him to leave again?
What am I gonna do
when you leave?
- Transfer.
- Yeah, right.
Well, these could
be cute, right?
Mmm.
You didn't buy anything.
Saving all your money
for those designer drugs?
And I can't believe you're
gonna be in fucking old haven.
Like, what are you
gonna do there?
It's so boring.
Do you think I should call him?
No.
No, I don't think
you should call him.
I'm so tired
of hearing about him.
You're making
a fool of yourself.
Leave the guy alone.
If he wants to see you,
he'll call you.
Okay.
I'm sorry.
I'm gonna go home.
Great.
No one's stopping you.
Lilly!
I gotta talk to you.
Lil!
Lil, would you talk to me?
What the fuck?
Lil!
Lilly!
You gotta straighten
this out, Lil.
- Me?
- I didn't sleep with her!
- She told me!
- You fucking better ask her again.
I don't have to.
She's not a liar, David.
- I want you to tell Gerry.
- Tell Gerry what?
- How this all started!
- I don't know how it started.
I wasn't there.
- I thought you cared about her.
- I do.
Then tell her why
I came to the house that day.
Tell her how it happened!
We already know what happened.
I didn't call him.
He called me.
We're hanging out on Sunday.
What for?
What do you mean,
"what for?"
He wants to take a walk
in the gardens,
where we went before.
Okay.
Well, thanks for making me
act like a person.
I like yours better.
Go away.
It's me.
He's leaving.
Where's he going?
Paris.
Tomorrow at four.
That's it?
That's all he said?
Isn't that enough?
I think I should
go say good-bye.
David?
Why didn't you tell me?
You're really somethin' else.
- Why now?
- I'm gonna go do my work.
I can't deal with this anymore.
I really want you to stay.
- Then tell Gerry the truth.
- I can't!
Do you know
how hurt she would be?
What kind of friend
would I be then?
I don't know. What kind
of friend are you now?
I didn't sleep with Fitzsimmons.
I'm trying to tell you
the truth.
You hurt me.
So you had
to hurt me back, right?
You know, you really
are fully of shit.
You keep this up,
and there won't be anyone left
to play with, you understand?
I gotta go.
What was that?
He just kissed you!
I've been seeing him.
Since when?
All summer.
Until your dad died.
Wow.
What happened when my dad died?
I stopped seeing him.
He started seeing you.
You told him to see me?
Yeah, but I didn't ask him
to sleep with you.
Oh, my God.
You're such a conceited bitch!
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Oh, my God!
I just wanted
to make you feel better.
You liked him so much.
So you decided
to play God, right?
To throw him at me
like some sort of booby prize?
Because my father dropped dead
on a subway?
God, you're sick!
I was just trying
to do something good!
Yeah, like, sure,
you actually believed that!
- I'm so sorry.
- So am I!
I'm so sorry.
What are you doin' in here?
Nothing.
I had sex with someone.
You tryin' to shock me?
I don't know.
You all right?
It was with someone
Gerry really liked.
And she's upset?
She'll never talk to me again.
Well...
People aren't perfect, kiddo.
They make mistakes.
Sometimes, it's harder
to forgive yourself
than to get
somebody else to do it.
But...
People will surprise you.
Well, thank you for tellin' me.
I didn't know I could.
I'm here to turn this in
and pick up my last check.
There you go.
I didn't expect to, uh...
Give a shit.
Get out of here.
I guess I never really thought
this day would come.
It's your turn, babe.
At least, I gave you
some stellar examples
of how not to do it.
Okay. Let's go.
I think this is for you.
You were there, weren't you,
when he took that?
Yes.
I got it in the mail yesterday,
so I guess that was his...
his way of making sure
that you'd see it.
No.
It was his way of making sure
that we'd see each other.
I'm so sorry, Ger.
What are you doin'?
You don't know how sorry I am.
Okay, I bet.
You...
what are you doin'?
This guy was smiling.
Happy.
You need to put your clothes on.
Because this is crazy.
Yeah? You have
to forgive me.
I can't lose you.
Um, okay.
I, um...
I didn't do it.
I didn't do what?
I didn't sleep with him.
Um...
I asked...
I begged...
and uh, he kissed me on the head
and told me that he was in love
with someone else.
I'm really sorry.
I'm... I'm so sorry.
I'm... I'm never gonna
lie to you again,
I... I swear.
I was just...
I was really confused.
- Angry?
- Yeah.
At Danny, you know, for just...
fucking dying.
Ooh. Love you.
Me too.
I'm gonna visit you
a lot, a lot, a lot!
- Uh-oh. Oh, my God!
- Uh-oh.
- Oh, my God!
What's goin' on here?
What's happening?
Lilly's naked.
Shut up.
If you want to find yourself
By travelin' out west
Or if you wanna
find somebody else
That's better go ahead
Go ahead
If you wanna buy
a brand new fancy automobile
Or if you wanna
build a place
Up in cold water canyon
Go ahead
I wish you would
If you wanna have
your cake and eat it too
And if you wanna
have other people
Watch you while you eat it
Go ahead
Be my guest
If you want
Better things
I want you to have them
If you
Want better things
Then I want you
To have them
Go ahead
I wish you would
la la la la
I fell asleep
in my parents' room
I awoke to the cable news
There was a fire
at Brooklyn school
I melted down like Fukushima
Don't you wanna know
How I'm feelin'
I just want to talk to you
'Cause it burns
It still burns
It burns
It still hurts
la la la la
Ooh
Hold up I'm comin'
In the glow
of the rising sun
I found my calling
In the lows and the feeling
Of when you're gone
It burns
It still burns
It still hurts
la la la la
I can't do it.
No, you can.
The question is will you.