WHEN the lights go out
According  true events
For what was wrong
Our old house?
Where do you want me to start?
- I loved it.
Right. You could stay there.
- Very funny ...
Can you let some music, please?
- I say, no problem.
How are workers paid?
- 20 pounds.
Naughty boys.
Will appear when Brian and Rita?
Probably when all done.
Typical Brian.
- Typical Rita.
I do not like.
You do not know how good.
What this glupaèa doing here?
- Who?
I know from school.
Smells like mokraæu.
Sally!
Then hang out with
staraèkom people in the home.
Hello!
Hello.
Sally!
The cavalry has arrived!
- Is there a problem.
Do not panic, Len.
I have a job for you.
Oh shit, did we
so much missed.
I have a housewarming gift.
- What, now I will dobiæu free.
There is no place for the weak.
The first three are yours.
The first three?
There is a bathroom, baby.
Come on, smiling happily and look.
We go to the bedroom?
- Bezobraznièe!
Do you think it would be better?
Raèunaj on me at all times.
Forest Kastlfild. I was there.
Yeah, and?
It's really mysterious.
Turn.
- Come on!
For what so namrgoðeno face?
I do not take part in your
gentle talks.
Did you hear that?
Come on, come here. Come.
- To take pictures.
Come on, girls.
The show.
Beautiful, beautiful girl.
Way to go, you see?
God, nazdraviæete and you two?
For a new house!
- For a new house. Cheers!
Cheers!
Mehuriæi we have entered into the nose.
Yes, it is. Show
I love her. Great!
What's the matter, honey?
I thought you were happy.
- I'm more than happy, Len.
It's sick, is not it?
- I think it's really nice.
Become a slut?
- What do you say, I like the clothes.
It was supposed to be a model.
It's nice. Again. One more time ...
ptièica, come on!
Dad?
Yes, dear?
Have you moved my clothes?
You're kidding, right?
Fix it before you see your mother.
inflation rate of 17%, the largest
in the last 34 years ...
Avocado?
What?
Avocado. That would be nice, would not it?
What do you think of the green, baby?
Then you have no feeling for style, Len.
Or, more importantly, money.
Cheer up, honey.
What is it?
I do not like this house, it scares me.
- Is it?
The lamp rocked by itself.
Have you left a window open?
- Konjiæ dispersed.
Is not it made of?
Itself.
Do not believe me, do not you?
- It's time for school.
And so there was a decline
Catholic Church in England.
The monasteries were closed by the will of the king?
Sir!
- Mr. Pryce!
- Sir!
Sally?
Yes, sir?
She drew you, sir.
See, once
he blushed.
Well girls, that's enough. Hall,
Bring us to see. Come on.
This is really good.
I even said, and great.
If this is art for EAS.
And my hair is drawn're wrong.
It's a little polished.
Okay, now can anyone tell me
says who closed the monasteries?
Sir!
- Lucy!
Henry VIII, Sir.
- That's right, girl.
And how many women have?
I do not want to stay here alone, Mom.
We will not be long.
Just to spend a few shillings.
- Someone has here.
Stop it, honey. Now you're great
girl. Thus the act.
If I'm a big girl now
why can not I do that emerging?
Because you're still young.
I can not win, right?
- Do not ...
Hi, honey.
- See you later!
Then go.
Still it's your turn, right?
Here you are. To put the planted,
we have to be civilized, is not it?
Is conciliation goes according to plan?
- Yes.
He just got into his Sali
head, we are not alone in the house.
What do you mean?
Conviction that we have a spirit.
It's still pretty childish.
Rita?
I think I saw something.
Do not mention it, otherwise there
veèito hear that.
Ladies ...
To join you.
Cheers, darling!
Cheers!
Bravo for  Limmie & The Family Cookin ...
their 'A Walkin' Miracle. '
I hope you that you
liked their hit ...
Jimmy Osmond  climbed
to tenth place ...
Sue and Sani with his hit
'Doctors orders' ...
climbed to ninth place.
It is our Sally!
Hi, love ...
She was soaking wet, jadnièak!
What are you doing out here, honey?
Come on.
Mom, I saw him.
See, when a toy falls down stairs
does not mean that we have a spirit.
It's late. We're all tired.
Go to bed!
I believe you.
She's just angry.
- Really?
Next time will go with you.
Another damn power cuts.
It was supposed to inform us.
Others still have light.
Do you have sveæe?
- I do not know where they are.
God, what is that?
Come on, EIK guess.
Hello, Miss ...
What are you doing up there, hell?
You little naughty!
That's the spirit!
- Yes, hell!
God!
I'm not going to stay here.
I'm going to see if I was okay.
Bring a flashlight!
Rita, behind you!
What is going on here?
Welcome home. What happened?
Listen, this is not the first
time to play stupid joke.
No, this was different.
- How?
Simply different.
And then what happened to the lights?
- Power key was turned off.
A sound?
These children are recorded.
What about slavininom?
- Only needs to be replaced.
A grandfather clock?
- I fell.
Or was pushed.
I do not know ...
Look, it is obvious. It
does not want to stay here.
It's just her way of protest ...
- You think so.
Do not believe me, do not you?
- Not at all.
Where's Mom?
She's tired, it's still in bed.
Odneæu her tea.
I do not want to be disturbed.
You do not want more strife?
What are you doing? Let me go!
All ulepilo!
What is it?
Nothing, sir.
Then continue with it.
Look what I found in the library.
So, all spirits cool room ...
throwing things on and off the lights.
You know what I mean?
- What?
I believe that everything happens for a
normal explanation.
Yeah, you got spirit at home.
I think Len was not wrong.
You blame the kids?
- And before we had all kinds of jokes.
These are not two babies Èamps
Zens and exit the bar.
Maybe not everything you think.
Better let these things
stay where they are.
I saw you, you were
saw her, she was seen.
This is not a child's imagination
performed jokes.
How do you know she was lying.
- But I know what I saw.
If you had a child might understand it.
Sorry, I should not have said that.
It's okay.
I just want us all to be happy.
I know.
Shit.
You stupid cow!
You're like everyone else, do not.
Do not go.
- Today you hurt me.
I'm sorry.
Really do you like g. Pryce?
- Mind your own business ...
Yes.
- He was really nice, right?
He's like John Denver.
- Not!
You filled my senses, as in the night ...
Stop it!
And I like it.
- Leave it.
Maybe it's better that we go inside.
No more!
All right. You want to raise
doll in the air?
You little bitch, if it's my jacket?
Just to get my hands on.
If you, Sally, then ...
Shit!
Open the door!
Hall, open the door!
Something is in there!
Get out!
Sally, I'm warning you!
Open the door!
Dad, what is it?
- You little ...
bitch!
I'm sorry, honey.
I'm sorry.
What are you gonna do now?
- We're leaving.
Really?
What else would I need to do?
- Where to go?
We are already hard to find this house.
Then he would return to the wait
Subsidies to the end of the list.
But when they were told of the spirit?
You would not believe us.
What about the father of Clifton?
We were in the church!
He slammed the door in our face.
You need to know that you are always welcome.
I'm not going to be driven away. And full stop!
Who are you?
friends ...
Get out of here!
What do you want?
Avocado? Is not it green?
That's what I wanted.
If you can not afford
then you can not afford.
It is this lack of logic when ...
they imagine something in my head.
I hear that you have the spirit?
Yeah, and?
've Apologized a newspaper?
Just me more journalists missing!
For you, I could not find a couple of them.
My buddy works for 'Express'.
If you want, I can call him.
Do you get asked if I want to press?
Sorry, but this case may
help us to move.
What if they think that's the trick?
It will not. In addition, they get paid well ...
if you like the story.
Cancel them.
It's too late for that.
So here I was attacked.
But what, Mr. Maynard?
As a kind of presence.
Presence?
Yes, as a creepy priviðenje.
Have you seen him?
Do not ...
Were you touched?
No, but ...
Listen, I was scared, g. Smith.
I can not believe it.
I think there's nothing you can
be imteresantno our readers.
Everyone loves stories about ghosts.
But for this you need a ghost.
What do you think, Mr.. Smith?
- I'm a journalist.
I do not see anything specific
I would have to write.
If you look around a little ...
- I'll take a look.
Bravo, a wise head.
Shut up.
Ozbilno, g. Maynard, I
really busy man ...
Poltergeist haunts
Local family ...
Look at my hair.
The picture is terrible, is not it?
I'm not even mention.
It's not fair, honey, I do not think so.
No, not so.
Can we look?
Mom does not like people
come to our house.
My dad said to make up ...
No, it's true!
And how I pay the newspaper?
Leave her alone, tired.
- Want to be a good soul!
Two Iunatic!
Hair all these people?
Idiots.
What is going on here?
Sightseeing of the house, ma'am.
It costs a pound, but it's worth it.
Get out! This is my fucking house.
This is my daughters room. It
there was not much happening.
I'll be right now.
What are you doing this, Len?
- A little I earn.
Get rid of them!
- Want a new kitchen, or not?
Now!
Are we next?
- No, the show is over. Go!
Dad!
What?
- Can I get a ten pence, please?
Go on, get out!
Hunks.
Pound?
Jenny.
I thought you wanted to paste
wallpaper, not that you take them.
I did not do.
Shit.
Where did you get it?
I stole from the store.
It has a terrible taste.
Thief. Give it to me.
It looks like honey.
And it tastes Dubreta.
Shut up! Izbaciæe us out.
To whom it belonged to, please tell me?
- No one.
Then get out of here.
I'm drunk.
- I am.
Have you ever been drunk?
Yes, sometimes I steal from my mom a little sherry.
Are you coming to my birthday?
Of course! If you ask me.
- Of course.
Whether it was you in the hall?
You're really pretty.
Stop.
Stop it!
Get away from me!
What are you laughing?
What do you think?
- What?
It ...
I do not know.
The girl, perhaps a boy.
Yes, some of the city below. -What do you think?
I'll tell you what I think.
What?
Evil.
Where were you last night?
- With Luka.
Right. I am pleased to
You found a friend.
Lively companion.
I do not know what you're talking about.
Then suddenly appears
bodiless hand on the door
and then his wife
begun to preobraæuje.
Do not talk!
Yes, actually it's not bad.
Can be used.
What about your family?
Then God said good night.
I'm sure she's happy, you have ...
such a nasty guy
like you, is not it?
Who are you?
Friend.
Well, my friend, it might be
time to hurry home.
I just wanted to suggest to you.
- Really?
You shit, you fucking moron!
- Len, stop!
Stop ...
What do you imagine this? Damn idiot.
Maybe he was right.
And you tell me that?
I'm telling you, you should go home.
We had a row.
So what? Go home and make it up to her.
I do not know how to do that.
- You are married. That is enough.
Bastard!
I guess I'm not that bad.
Do not you ...
You've been drinking.
Not so much to realize.
Look what he's done.
It seems he wants us to break up.
Then do a good job, right?
Only if we allow him to.
Hi, you must be Sally?
Come in, my dear.
Did I arrived first?
Lucy did not tell you, honey?
Today you will be just the two of you.
Happy birthday.
What is it? Do you like it?
If not, you can not return it.
I love it.
On the nose.
Where is your father?
He went to a hooker. Mom tells all ...
to work night shift.
Sally, baby, come here.
Sit down, honey.
Can you do me a favor?
Making sure that Lucy
does not go into your house.
All right.
Promise?
- I promise.
Thank you, honey.
Is it because of the spirit?
Yeah, about that.
Sally, come here!
Go, baby.
Let's act a group Sweet.
I'll be the drummer. You
You'll be Brian Connolly.
Right.
Why are crying?
Are your parents home, my dear?
No.
I do not mind them saèekam?
- What is it?
You have an evil spirit in the house,
and I can not get him to leave.
If you want to do it
let go, of course.
Tell parents to
call me, will you?
Right.
Stop it, Len.
Stop it!
Len!
Yes, dear?
What's the matter, honey?
What is going on?
Who is this spirit and what the hell he wants?
- Let go of me. I'm tired.
You know more than you
tell me, Miss!
Getting dressed up! You're coming with me to the father Clifton.
- I'm not going to go anywhere.
Get out of bed!
- Let go of me!
Little bitch!
Slow down, please! Come on.
For you I'll take care of it later.
A four-hour morning
honey, he's sleeping now.
I do not care.
Am I to go down?
Yeah, sure, you go.
I've got the whole damn community
to help? Jesus Christ!
Jenny, you say
to the spirit of a young girl?
Why did not because of this
came to see me earlier?
I thought that you would chase me.
What do you want me to do?
- To free us from it, Father.
From what you told me,
It requires an exorcism.
Exorcism?
This is a very serious undertaking.
I need my license bishops.
God. And what do we do now?
I want to talk to you.
I'm sorry.
It's okay.
Last night I was
too hard on you.
Do you forgive me?
Yes.
Maybe he'll go away by itself.
Who knows, maybe it's already gone.
And here we come ... Nirsbi monastery.
Who will go first? - Oliver,
course. - Come on, guys!
And this is the dining room. What's that?
Where are the monks ruèavali, sir.
Very good, Lucy.
They had two meals a day flying
and one in the winter.
And what they ate, sir?
Only the necessary supplies.
Vegetables, meat, bread.
I have kept bees for honey. In
that time sugar was not invented.
What do you have?
- Mustard.
What is your problem?
- I love it.
Lesbians!
Come on.
I'm going to pee.
- OK.
Try not ukvasiš panties.
- Good.
Sally?
Sally!
Mr. Pryce!
What is it?
- I'm not allowed to come in.
Why?
- For the Spirit, sir.
I guess you do not believe in that nonsense, is not it?
Come on.
It is true, sir.
She told me.
He wakes up at night and play with her.
And that is why it is
always tired, sir.
I think you look
too much tv, miss.
We do not have television, sir.
How do you feel, Sally?
Hello, sir.
- Are you sure?
Lucy will take care of you, and
your mom gets home. Right?
She should not be here.
Okay, but should remain this way.
See you later.
You do not have to stay if you do not.
No, it's okay.
Where's the bathroom?
- On the floor.
You have no control?
I had earlier and I wear diapers.
- I am, too.
But not in ten years.
Again dark.
- I have to go.
All right.
Is that you, Sally?
What?
It's nothing.
Lucy?
Sally!
Lucy!
Sally! Please!
- I try to open it!
Sally!
What happened?
Lucy, come back!
Hi, Sally.
You know why I'm here, is not it?
You did not listen to what
I told you recently?
And you promised me, right!
It'll be good, right?
- I had to take her to the hospital!
Can I see it?
- You can not!
And the more you will not continue unless the VIDAS
If you do not want to have to deal with me.
Got it?
- Yes.
I thought I was just fine. Because
You were her only friend.
What is going on?
Your damn daughter, it is
going on! I asked her to ...
Lucy does not bring into the house.
I promised.
I had to take Lucy to the hospital.
I had no idea what was going on!
Now you know!
Mom, I'm not. I did not want ...
Fucking little bitch!
I'm sorry!
- How could you do that!
Bitch!
Do something to her.
Do not!
Do not! Stop it!
Please do!
Please!
Jenny? My God!
Come on! Hurry up!
Sally.
Is it ringing?
- Yes.
I gotta go.
It can wait five minutes.
Sit down.
I want to talk about.
Lucy had mentioned something about you and ...
spirit.
All have a tremendous fear of it,
as for the awful things, but
I think it's just lonely.
'It'?
- Yes.
The town hall
There is even her picture.
Not as bad as it looks, honey.
What is it?
Oh, my God!
What happened?
Come on! Try it!
Let me feel your sorrow weeping.
Honey?
Honey!
Sally?
Sally!
Sally, my dear, is prehladiæeš.
There, he found me.
Something we took.
Sally, come in, please.
There was lonely.
Odvešæu you here.
Odvešæu you both here.
Do not go near her, she's a witch.
Because of her, Lucy is not in school.
Certainly zaèarala, and
She will pee in death.
Give this a chance, honey.
At least no ghosts.
- But I'm not moving in here.
Shall we then stay there and suffer?
What else can we do?
- I'm worried about Sally.
And I am.
Just not enough to
gave up their dream home.
Bastard. It is always a
else's fault, right?
Probably my fault
I took you there.
But it's not my fault
our spirits fly in the house!
Why do not you take responsibility, Len!
- That's what I'm trying, that's why I brought you here!
Then look at all this!
Lord!
It was not easy to catch you, Mr. Maynard.
Who are you?
Your daughters teacher.
She asked me to find out
something about her spirit.
Really?
What I found ...
was the daughter of the local landowners.
Your spirit, that is, she went to a
Castlefield forest where
is lost and gone.
Sledeæeg morning she was found.
Hanged and half-dead ...
iseèenim with language.
She was thirteen. Just
as your daughter.
And now it is in our house?
From what I was told Sally that.
And then what?
Then what?
Maybe we should move?
That's what I wanted!
What prevents you?
- My wife!
I'm sure they watched
that differently if
She apologized to you
what I am to you.
It is now our already Lien thing.
After all, why do you
interested in this?
Concerns of teachers for their pupils.
I need to look at their problems.
Sally is a very special girl.
I see.
So that's the question, is not it?
What's this?
It would not be the first time that the teacher ...
Students attacked the beautiful, is not it?
Read it. In that case,
tomorrow be a little more reasonable.
What do you see?
What is the decision, Father?
He believes that there is insufficient
arguments for doing so.
So, that's it?
- I'm afraid so.
And what, if I move?
It will not be the end of the world, is not it?
Feel free to scroll. The Church can
be a great comfort in these ...
You have to do something.
And lose the priesthood?
I'd like that, would not you?
I found some things of the spirit ...
and tried to talk to your father.
Come, come.
You'll be all right?
See you tomorrow.
I'm sorry that you were killed.
But it is time to leave me in peace.
Lucy!
Come on!
The thing that belonged
deceased would be very useful.
This is our home.
We need your help.
I already gave the answer to your wife.
He wants another answer.
It's not possible. Lost
I would priesthood.
Anyway, it would be lost,
when this is released.
Who is this picture?
- It does not matter.
Yes, the world is a little less,
But what to do?
Blackmail is a serious
violation, g. Maynard.
Yeah, fuck rooms Pets and assistants!
- Even as a Catholic priest!
What is she doing in this picture?
At this ... She Klee.
Yes, Klee.
Please talk with us.
Do we understand?
And why you will not talk to us?
Are you dumb?
Will you go to Veena light?
You've got some unfinished business here?
With who?
Len?
Jenny?
Sally?
Oh, baby!
Is she in danger?
From who?
Tell me!
No!
Sally!
Get away from her! Get away from her!
Sally immediately take away.
- Come on, baby!
Come on, hurry up!
- Come with me.
I'm sorry.
I Razoèarao you.
Simply, they are too much for us.
'They'?
There is more than one ghost in this house.
I felt sympathetic presence.
And no one who is evil.
Yes.
And this is the presence of well-intentioned
a young girl who was raised ...
Poltergeist majority of these activities,
with the intent to scare and drive away.
Not to hurt you, but to protect you.
What others like?
It was not the first.
There were others before her.
Peasant women.
All have been done respectively
silent, just like her.
Iseèeni their tongues.
But she was educated.
Before he died,
managed to write
description of his attackers.
And who was that?
It was a monk from the monastery Nirsbi,
who prayed over nevinošæu
young girls.
He could have cost the church
nezapamæene shame.
Because the cards for him and hanged
I secretly buried.
Thank you for apologized.
Now I'm talking to.
What is it?
I think it's better to go home now.
I thought you'd help us out?
I did my part, right? So ...
What will you say when Rita
know that you are a coward?
You are a very ruthless
man, Len Maynard.
Under no circumstances does not
hesitate to answer.
Otherwise, we'll be in trouble.
Then points.
All holy saints of God ...
Answer!
Pray for us.
From all evil, deliver us, O Lord.
Of all the sins of sudden
and unexpected death.
Deliver us.
Hear our prayers for help.
Carry terror, Lord,
beasts that destroy thy vineyard.
Look at the Cross of the Lord. Run,
enemy force.
Here is terribly cold.
I bind them and cast into the abyss ...
Damn ...
Come on, after you.
- Go!
This is your fucking house!
- Get up!
He went there.
No matter what you say.
Your place is empty.
Go and stay in a snake pit.
Shit!
Go down and crawling with them.
I will not wait you here
all night, cowards?
Go away, I order you!
Blood of martyrs commanded you!
Continue.
Go on!
Nereðuju all you servants of the faith is Christian.
Exalted Christ commanded you!
- Exalted Christ commanded you!
Thank you, Father.
And no offense.
Negative!
If any of this occurs,
I will personally give you tearing their skin.
I'm sure that later
enjoy your images.
Give me some.
You're still here, are not you?
Mom!
Dad!
Sally!
Honey!
My God!
- Sally!
Sally!
Oslobodiæu, baby!
God!
Mom!
Dad!
Help!
Help me!
Mom!
Sally!
My God! Sally, are you okay?
Let's go!
Come on, sweetheart.
Get out of here.
Quickly!
.: Translation - intoxic:.
Maynard-wraiths are considered ...
one of the most brutal
approximation in history.
MS. Maynard still lives in the house.
Sally is still afraid to go to
enter into its former spavaæu room.
This film is devoted to Irene Holden.
.: Translation - intoxic:.