SEA OF VIOLETS
- My father wanted a boy.
- Because a girl is a disgrace worse than death.
- My mother was 15.
- She gave birth with a knife to her the throat
- A cry prolonged indefinitely.
- Then... silence.
- I was born, dirty and red
like a just-made quince paste.
- I was born, a girl
and you did not kill my mother.
- Resigned,
I am. I'm Angela.
- Angela, wait!
- Tommaso, it's not right!
- You run fast!
- Angela, walk!
- go on, go on!
Come on! What It takes to make this load?
- Rosario!
hold better that rope.
- Hold tight.
- Take the one stored.
- But it was for Palermo.
- We take that one and that's enough.
- The Baron expects the tuff
And we will bring it.
- Come with me!
- You are always the last!
- What do you want??
- Angela, do you smoke?!
- Where have you been??
- Did you hear me?
Where have you been this time, eh?
- Collecting Burarran!
- At this time of the night?!
- You hurt me!
- Was it good the cigarette you've been smoking?
- If you born man,
you could also smoke,
- but your mother made you a girl!
Am I right?!
- Am I right or not?!
- Come on! You must understand!
- Do you understand? UNDERSTAND?
- Father!
- Come on, put you down!
- Then I have to give you, eh?
Don't you understand? - No, no!
- "Voscenza benedica"
- Here he is.
- You did a a serious damage
- I know.
- I swear it will not happen again.
- I don't care what you swear.
- I care that I lost my things
- And now you you have to repay.
- But i have nothing.
- Only today's salary.
- And for you it's enough?
- today, do a long turn when you come home
- And say to your wife
to leave the door open.
- I will find for you
a way to pay your debt.
- What is happened?
- My husband think to do all alone to correct her,
- with his hands.
- Ahi!
- He doesn't have to know that i came here.
- Full, she is.
I feel them walking under the skin.
- Are you sure?
They are doing like ants.
- I wanna feel them too.
- Stop, shut up!
- Our father, save the souls of penitents,
press the neck of the unbelievers
and save from the fear this your
poor sick daughter.
- Our father, save the souls of penitents,
press the neck of the unbelievers
and save from the fear this your
poor sick daughter.
dryed the tongue, full of worms the teeth,
flabby flesh, every hair is a snake.
eyes burned, poison in her bones.
We are already sitting on your vault.
- I wash you with this water, pure like Maria.
- Purifies the body and my soul.
- I wash my hands like Pilate,
to the jew people you gave him.
- Careful! that you hurt him!
- You'll see how he runs away,
Nicolino is like an eel.
- What did i tell you?
- What do you feel?
- Nothing, What should i feel?
- The worms.
- The old woman told me I'm full.
- The worms? And where do you have them?
Here, here, here!
- Ah!
- What have you done? - No, nothing.
- Come on, show me.
- Leave me!
- What are you doing?
- I took the prize that I won
- The Burarran and "la gira"
must be cut to the roots
- Because inside you feel the ground.
We eat them every night.
- All nights?
- The Curator (her father) eats "grass" every night?
- Him, when he find boiled "grass",
he is happy.
- He drinks wine together, he faint on bed
and he leaves us in peace.
- You see?
With you everything seem easy.
- Sara, come, soon!
The Piedmonteses take your father!
- Father! Father!
- Back!
- Sara!
- Stop!
- Father!
- Sara!
- Sara! I'm here, Sara!
- Sara, I'm here! Sara!
- Stop!
- Sara!
- Leave me!
- You want to grow old
sitting there, Angela?
- Think for yourself, Nicolino.
- Sara will be back.
- How much tuff is left? - Few.
- Few months of work, not more.
- And in "Scalo Cavallo"?
- Nothing.
- Also there only dust is coming out.
- What do you say?
- I say that the Baron expect another reply
- These are the facts
- We look for the "Facts".
- Sara!
- Angela!
- It seems yesterday we were children.
- I'm happy you are back.
- How are you?
- I'm fine.
- How long will you remain on the island?
- It depends by the Baron.
- And how long will the Baron remain?
- You seem our "Madonnuzza" in procession!
- How nice to see this house open again.
- I remembered it bigger.
- I passed here along every day
since you went away.
- Nice, right?
- It will suit you.
- But this is for Ladies.
- And the others?
- Ventura work in the quarry,
Nicolino at the port, when he finds.
- And Tommaso?
- He is becoming rich.
- rich? How?
- With boats. He has three.
- Sara! Come, the Baroness awaits.
- Coming!
- What does she wants from you?
- That i comb her hair.
- She says that how i do it, nobody does.
- Why? you're so good?
- The Baroness say so.
- Then?
- When? Soon it's time for dinner
- Then tomorrow
I'll take you to visit the island.
- Maybe you think it's smaller too!
- What do you do, you don't come?
- See you tomorrow.
- What will i do when you leave?
- Why should i go away Baroness?
- Becasue soon you will be engaged
- and then you will marry.
- I can't continue to comb you the same?
- And if He will be jealous
and he will keep you locked up?
- This means that i will look for
a not jealous husband.
- Impossible!
- You are toomuch beautiful.
- This island is not little, it's mine!
- Why don't you comb my hair
instead of laughing?
- You are beautiful.
- Like the Baroness? - More.
- In the city they all comb hair so.
- How is the city?
- Big. There's a lot of people.
- So much that you can't
even imagine.
- And do you remember the Burraran?
- Yes.
- Do you still eat it?
- And when my father will changer?
- And yours?
- He never came back.
- From Where?
- From Trentino, from the war.
- They say he is missing,
but I don't believe them.
- Take me to the "tonnara" (*tuna-fishing place).
- Do you want to see Tommaso?
- Tommaso!
- What do you do, you don't come?
- I have to go home.
- Why are you in the dark?
- What he did?
- Things aren't going well at the quarry.
- Not well?
- Tuff begins to finish.
- It's not good.
- Is it your fault?
- Is it you to ruin it?
- Take care of the fire and shut up.
- I love you.
- I told you to shut up.
- I don't want a life like this.
- And what life do you want?
- I don't know.
- but not so, when everything
is always the same.
- We are the same too.
- You were wrong,
There's nothing up there.
- Simply clean the first lay.
There's a fortune here.
- What do you say? If you talk about a plant
that can grow up there, it's probably.
- But there's no tuff.
- But was it needed to call them
from the Continent (Italia)
two stupid like those?
- He trust them, the Baron.
- What do you wanna do?
- I know it's there.
- I trust you.
- Is it of the Baroness too?
- She promised me one equal
when i will marry.
- I do it.
- And when you will marry?
- When someone will "ask" me
to my mother.
- I "ask" you.
- You laugh!
- And what should i do?
- You are here!
I looked for you everywhere.
- They needed help
and they asked to my mother.
- Why?
- The storm last night
ruined all the nets.
- For long?
- Until i finish.
- They are Tommaso's?
- They are everybody's.
- If you want, You can remain and help us.
- What do you want?
- Nica, is her name.
- I give her to you.
- Why?
- Because you are alike.
She was alone and angry like you.
- Then i hugged her
and she started to laugh.
- Dogs don't laugh.
- You see, Was i right?
- Why? - Look with your eyes.
- You were right.
- This is an important day, Ventura.
- Important for the land
and important for you.
- Why don't you stop, Angela?
You oppress me.
- If i stop,
then you won't look for me anymore.
- You are stubborn.
- You are beautiful this way.
- I did it for you.
- Don't start again.
- I can't stop,
I love you toomuch.
- I love you too,
but not like you.
- There's only one way to love.
- Come!
- And now?
- Don't be shocked.
- We are two women, it's a sin.
- What's a sin?
- A thing we don't have to do.
- Ave Maria,
gratia plena, Dominus tecum,
benedicta tu in mulieribus et
benedictus fructus ventris tui, lesus.
Sancta Maria, materDei,
ora pro nobis...
...peccatoribus,
nunc et in hora mortis nostrae. Amen.
- Sancta Maria, materDei,
ora pro nobis peccatoribus.
Santa Maria, materDei,
ora pro nobis...
- Sara! I'm here! Sara!
- What are you doing?
- I'm counting the days you didn't come.
- Lucia!
- Angela, comes down!
Agnese you too, come down!
- Come, drink,
- Today is your party.
- You become engaged with Ventura.
- Ventura? - Eh!
- By the end of the year you will get married.
- Drink!
- No, I don't marry him.
- You do what i say.
- Drink!
- It has been - diffult to find you.
- I've been always here.
- Did you talk with your father?
- Yes.
- You say only "yes"?
- What should i say?
- My father leave us
the farm of Cala Torta.
- There are two rooms
to accomodate, but...
- It was only a snake.
- You killed it for nothing.
- Aren't you able to say "thank you"?
- By may I will accomodate those rooms.
- Do you wanna come to see it?
- I know Cala Torta.
- I say for the house.
- It's better if you make me a surprise.
- This is the way to enter in the house of god?
Like dogs are chasing you?
- You wanted to see me.
- I wanted to congratulate.
- What wishes?
- Aren't you engaged? - Ah.
- Come on, sit down.
- Look, Angela,
- Now you will have new duties
and we must think about it.
- What are these duties?
- Ventura is honest,
- God-fearing,
but you have to look your behavior,
- You don't have to kiss.
And you don't have to desire each other!
- I can assure you, I...
- Then, when you will marry...
- But you have to arrive "pure"
to that day.
- But i don't want Ventura!
- What does it mean?
- That i don't Marry him, Father Pantaleo!
- This is a mess, Angela!
- He's a good boy,
you must love and must marry him!
- I can't, Father!
- You have to force yourself!
- In this way your father decided
and you have to obey him.
- It's written in the commandments too.
- Commandments are for those able to read.
- And what i'm doing here?
I'm here to proclaim the words of God.
- I wanna read on my own,
these words of God.
- Teach me to read! When I will learn...
- You are possessed
- You come to talk in the
House of god in this way!
- You give us obedience,
to your father, understand?
- And you must marry Ventura!
Obedience and respect.
- And me? Who respect me?
- I thought you don't come anymore.
- You seem your father
when you have a so bad face.
- Where have you been?
- What's up, did i offend you?
- Tell me something, I was joking.
- My father "made me" engaged.
- Who?
- With Ventura.
- Sooner or later it had to happen.
- I want YOU!
- You want the moon.
- Is this the moon?
- If i can't marry you,
- I won't marry anybody.
- Come in.
I need to talk with you.
- If you don't come in,
you will spend the whole night here out.
- I won't marry Ventura!
- Really?
- Really.
- I don't want him.
- And who do you want? Let's see.
- Sara.
- Angela won't marry anymore.
- She doesn't want Ventura.
- No, no! Help!
- WALK!
- Walk!
- Help me, leave me!
- Go on! Move!
- No, no!
- Please!
- Brava, pray the Lord!
- Mather! Mather, He kills me!
- Mother He kills me!
- Shut up!
- Salvatore! What do you do?
- Go away!
- Come, come! go on!
- No! Aiuto!
- Walk! go on!
- Stop it I told you!
- Let's see if you will understand this time!
- You must understand!
- Help me!, Help me!
- Will you stop?
- No...
- Freak of nature!
- No!
- No, please! Please, no!
- No, please! No, Please, no!
Don Salvatore...
- Don Salvatore!
- I thought that tomorrow, after mass,
- Ventura and Angela could meet to talk.
- Angela isn't fine. - Matter?
- Nothing, some flu.
- Ventura did something wrong?
- Tell me, i will break him, that miserable!
- Ventura is a good boy.
We only need to wait.
- It's better if Angela doesn't go out,
for now.
- Angela!
- Sara! I'm here! Sara!
- Sara, I'm here! Sara!
- Sara! Sara!
Angela!
- What did you think?
Smells of roses?
- He keeps me like an animal.
- Stand up!
- I can't.
- Do it for your mother.
- And what she does for me?
- Why she doesn't come?
- If she comes here, your father will kill her.
- Leave me!
- What did you think?
Smells of roses?
- He keeps me like an animal.
- Stand up!
- I can't.
- Do it for your mother.
- And what does she do for me?
- Why doesn't she come?
- If she comes here, your father will kill her.
- Leave me!
- You don't have to touch this.
- What is it?
- The baby.
- They killed him.
- Who did it?
- And I was with him.
- When did it happen?
- When they forced you to the convent?
- I kept him anyway.
- He has to stay here.
- You don't have to touch him.
- I'll go to talk to her.
- You don't have to come here anymore.
- If you continue to come,
I'll use the dogs and they'll tear you to pieces.
- I want to know where Angela is?
- She left.
- Where did she go?
- You have to forget this street and this house.
- Angela won't be back anymore.
- At least tell me where she is!
- You must tell me, if she is dead.
- Why don't you ask Angela,
you sent her to me.
- You are so powerful,
I ask you for only one thing.
- Have I ever asked you for anything? Nothing!
Only this once.
- I don't want to know why,
I only want to know if she is dead.
- You must tell me if she is dead.
- With Palm Sunday we start to celebrate
the Holy Week,
where we recall,
the last days of life on earth
of Our Lord Jesus Christ,
the tremendous suffering,
the unfair proceedings,
the ascent to Calvary, death,
the grave and ultimately his resurrection.
A week that therefore, gives us hope,
as well as the certainty of
the resurrection of Christ.
A resurrection,
that places Christ at the center
of his victory over sin and death,
and gives us the hope of
liberation from sin.
- Can I talk to you?
- I can't stand it anymore!
- how long does it have to last?
Until she understands that she must
obey me.
- Please, Salvatore!
- I implore you Salvatore, get her out!
Before she dies.
- Nobody likes to die, even your daughter.
- Come to bed.
- I don't believe she will surrender.
- So it will last forever.
- Why doesn't she come anymore?
- I don't hear her voice.
- You have to forget Sara.
- Why doesn't she look for me anymore?
- She is not like you.
- What do you mean?
- She has been "promised" to Tommaso,
- Giovanni's son, that...
- I know who he is!
- When will they marry?
- Soon. In June.
- What does it mean?
- Where's the dinner?
Answer me!
- Get her out from there!
- Who are you to tell me what I
should or should not to do?
I'm your mother.
- I know that you never wanted her.
- And you are right.
- But I have only Angela,
she has to get out from there NOW!
- Listen...
- Don't use that tone with me
or I'll also put you down there.
and you will both die.
- You always protected her.
That is why she is what she is.
- I would be happier if she was a bitch
than a half man.
- For me she is already dead.
- You are right, I did make a mistake.
- But we can still do ... the right thing.
- Let's "make" her a man, as you wanted her.
- What are you saying?
- The Priest is indebted to us.
- Be silent, it is an old story!
- Before Our Lord, today is a historic day.
- I told you to keep quiet!
- Sit down, and I'll bring you some food.
- I know what we can say to the Priest.
- I don't need of your advice.
- Good Mother...
- But what are you speaking about?
- The Priest seems like a person
who is willing to play along?
- But how could I be wrong
between a boy and a girl, Donna Lucia?
- It's true, you know the difference very well.
You're an expert.
- But because some of your "experience"
comes also from our family,
- you could repay us.
- You are crazy.
- Why?
- Didn't you "practice", with my sister Agnese?
- Crazy and possessed.
- The "little baby", inside the glass jar,
- He looks like a lizard.
- But perhaps it really is a lizard.
- So, Angela can also be a man.
- I made a mistake, and you missed
my mistake.
- I'm dirty.
- You've  become like a little bird!
- What're you doing?
- I'll take you out.
- No, I won't marry Ventura, I won't
marry anybody.
- It doesn't matter, Angela,
it's all over.
- You father wanted a son
and now you will be a man. - Eh?
- It's easy, Angela.
- Just change one letter in the file,
at the end of the name.
and say that the Priest was wrong,
and so was I.
- You had a very absentminded mother.
Come, let's go.
- Hold on to me, Angela. Come.
- Here, Do you see the steps? Here.
- Careful, there's too much light,
Angela.
- Close your eyes,
You can hang on to me. - Mom...
- Here, you're out. Now we'll close this.
- I thought a lot about it.
- I can't go to the quarry forever .
- You will be a man and you take my place.
- And how can I do it?
- Don't you have men's thoughts?
- I'm a woman.
- It's the only thing
you can do to save yourself.
- You will be a man or you'll go back
to where you were.
- Everybody knows me in town.
- In town, they do what I want.
- If tomorrow I start to bark
because I've become a dog,
- I make them say "Woof, woof."
- So, you will be the Curator at once.
- They won't even have time to think
that they have to call you "My lord,
welcom, I'm your servant".
- Leave me for some hours.
Sara!
- Sara!
- Angela!
- You are healed, then?
- E Sara?
On the continent with the baroness,
for the documents.
- When will she be back?
- I don't know, they are time consuming things.
- Tell her that I will wait for her
at the Madonna of the Quarry.
- She is thinner.
Welcome.
Come on, come on!
- Don't stop.
Keep your head up and look ahead.
- What are you doing, why are you trembling?
You are a man.
They are like you.
- Come! Come here!
Listen to me.
This is my son: Angelo.
From today, he'll work here with me.
He has followed me for years.
I've told him everything about the quarry.
He has learned everything that he needs
to know.
He works here with me.
I've told him everything about the quarry.
This is my son.
Starting from today, what Angelo tells you,
it's like my own words.
Work well. Come on.
Angela...
Angela!
- Please don't say anything.
- But why is it so?
- So I could always be with you.
- I can I wear these dresses for my
whole life, if we stay together.
- All your life.
- We can't stay together, not
even for one minute.
- A lot of things have changed.
- Has the heart beat changed?
- Changed? I don't believe
that it doesn't beat like mine anymore.
- I don't believe it...
- I will marry Sara.
- Are you a man?
- So go down to the Madonna in my place.
- It takes strength. Get up!
Come on!
Get up!
- Do you really want to marry Angelo?
- Yes.
- But..How can you do it?
- You say this because you are afraid
of the Priest, the Baron?
- I really love him.
- I can't forget that Angelo isn't
what he seems.
- You have to tell me.
- I don't believe what the Priest says
like everybody else in town.
- I want to hear it from you. Is it true?
- No, no, look into my eyes and tell me
that Angelo is a man like me.
- He is a man.
He is a man, Tommaso.
They made a mistake when he was born.
- And do you love him?
Do you love him so much that you'll marry him?
- Dogs!
- I still don't believe it's true.
- What are you doing?
- I am a man.
- I know it's not true.
- Are you Angelo Vicari?
- Yes.
- I have this letter for you.
- Who's Angelo Vicari?
- It's me.
- Come with me.
Stand in front of me.
- Yours, it's a very special case.
- I know, but...
- Shut up! In the army you talk
only if you are questioned.
- I'm sorry.
- Undress yourself.
- I wanted to tell you one thing before...
- No no, Vicari.
Here you have to learn
to obey and that's all.
- Come on, undress.
- What should I take off?
Everything.
I said ALL.
- What's that on your face? Have you been hurt?
- No.
I wanted to tell you.
- And I knew it.
The Baron thought about everything.
Only that I wanted to see it with
my own eyes.
- And now?
- Get dressed.
- for the country you are a man,
But you are not suitable to serve in the army.
- Tonight you can send Ventura to the tavern.
- No tavern. We pay the men here,
at the end of the day.
- What do you say, Don Angelo?
What's this novelty?
- If it's because of Ventura that you're ...
- It has nothing to do with Ventura.
- Leave us alone, Vincenzo.
What the hell is this?
- If I have to take your place,
I want to do it my way.
- About these things it is neither his way
nor mine.
- It's the Baron that decides.
- It's true,
but all the salary the Baron give us,
I want to give it all.
What do we gain
with this beautiful thought?
- If the men are happier, they work better
and the Baron too is happier.
- The only happiness that interests me
is my own.
Remember that, if you want to
make your own way.
- Bless you.
- You think I'm a thief 'cause you
don't want me to manage the salaries.
- If I thought you were a thief,
I'd have already kicked you out.
Things have to change here.
- More than this?
- More than this, Ventura.
- And how should I call you?
Angelo o Angela?
- Curator, for everybody here
I'm only the Curator,
for you and for the others.
- Sorry.
- But what did you expect?
- That to erase everybody's mind
only needed trousers
or a backpack tucked into his pants?
- Don Salvatore, I take you as my son.
- What should I do with him?
- In the town the people say you need help.
- If I need help I'll call you.
- Don Salvatore, I no longer live.
- I have four daughters, give a
job to Nicolino.
- By Madonna, make a miracle!
- Let me go.
- Implore Him!
- Let me go, Filippo!
- Don Salvatore, Nicolino is strong as
a mule. Let's try him at least.
- Are you thirsting to give orders,
"Curator"?
- What do you want?
- Go away!
- Why don't you tell me that you are
the boss?
- Go away! Leave me!
- Tell me now that you are a man!
- Tell me now!      No! No!
- Tell me! Tell me now!
- Tell me now!
- What are you doing?
You are only a beast.
I'm not killing you only because
you're your father's son.
But tomorrow you have to leave the island.
Understand?! - Yes.
Go away!
Go home.
"The little baby under the parasol,
imitated Mama. "
"All the pizzas and sandwiches
flew from his hands."
"But sin does not rain here
and he just follows her. "
"If only there was a parasol
to take me from here to there."
- Again.
- Do you want a baby?
- What're you saying?
- Tell me, would you like it or not?
- And you?
- When I see pregnant women,
waddling like ducks,
... I miss it.
- Me too.
- What the fuck are you saying?
- You tell me
You are a man? So do your manly duties
in bed, like everybody else.
And right here, with my wife at home?
- I could only ask you.
- Why? Because I'm more stupid?
- You made me a fool of me in the past.
Do you think you can keep doing it?
- Who is it, Tommaso?
- It's Angelo. We are talking
about a shipment.
Just coming.
I don't know if you think you can make a
fool of me before God or the whole town,
but if you were a real man,
I would've whipped you dead
for what you are asking me to do.
- And if Sara were to ask you?
- It's always YOU.
- If she will ask you?
- It's the same thing. It's alway crazy!
- They deserved it.
- What are you saying?
- They were two demons.
- Shut up! D'you want the Baron to hear you?
- Two devils! And they are dead.
Now everybody knows who they were.
- You don't have to stay here if it hurts you.
- Women's odours that your father
took to bed.
That hurt me.
- Now, they know it, now everybody knows it!
- Vincenzo!
- Go home.
- Donna Lucia...
Come with me, please.
- They found a boy with a rifle.
- Where?
- At the "Monte Farro".
- Nicolino... - He had this with him
and he wouldn't tell us anything.
- It wasn't me.
- Go out!.
- What did you do?
Why did you have the rifle?
- I wanted to scare him.
My father wanted to kill himself.
It's his fault.
- And I found him with her.
- Where?
- They were near the well.
Your aunt had the skirt up
and the veil was on the ground.
Your father was on top.
Madonnina mia, are you sure
you want to know it? - How did they fall?
Your father saw me and he looked at me
with his eyes full of fire.
He got up up and I....
raised my rifle by accident...
He thought I would shoot him.
So he walked backwards into the well...
- And Agnese?
- She lowered her skirt,
made the sign of the cross
and threw herself.
- Is this the truth, Nicolino?
- It's the truth.
It's the truth, you must believe me.
It's the truth.
- I like the sound of your heart beat,
they seem like the drums at
the feast of Madonna.
- Tonight I don't feel any beat.
My father is dead and I feel no pain.
- It's because he hurt you.
It needs time..
- How much time do we have?
- Do you hear it?
- I'll go.
- Who is it?
- I am Tommaso.
- I'll do it.
But I'll do it for her.
- Don't you want to be in a bed?
- Do it soon.
- Go!
- Are you scared?
- No.
- What did you do? - It's not my fault.
The rope, it's old!
The rope?
- You have to stay silent, beast!
- You're like your father today.
- I want to see you happy.
- I am already happy.
- I can't do it.
It's not true.
it's not true, I know it's not true.
- What are you thinking, looking at me
with those eyes?
This dress is tight
Each day I'm growing more fat.
- I should change this dress.
- Do you feel sorry when they look at
me with this belly?
- A bit.
- Sorry for the delay.
- That's nothing, it's just a few minutes.
The Baron?
- The Baron had to go to "Cala Rossa".
He will be back late, not before dinner.
- Are you disappointed?
- For the quarry men,
What I have to ask
is really important for them.
- You really care about them, right?
- I care for what is good for you too.
- So, you can also talk to me then.
- Or you think that the quarries
aren't things for women?
- Sit down.
- No.
- A lot of things have changed for the quarry men
since the time you managed it.
They say you defended them like a lion.
- The counts are better,
but we need new ropes. - Mh-mh.
I'm worried about the shipments,
we loose too many in this way.
- It's a good argument.
- It's a persuasive argument.
- Look at me.
- Do you want drink a little?
- No. What is it?
- It's absinthe.
They drink it in France.
They use it...
to tame the girls.
- I'm not a girl.
And even if I were, I wouldn't need to be tamed.
Baroness...
- Don't you sleep?
- I was worried.
- Where have you been?
- To the Tavern.
The Baron promised me
the ropes I had asked for.
I paid for everybody's drink.
- Your father would be happy
that you paid for the quarry men.
- Come here - I will help you.
- No, it doesn't matter.
Come on...
Come closer, because it doesn't reach.
But they are so long!
It's less than a month since you cut them.
I missed you.
Did you put scent on like a girl
to go to the Tavern?
- Eh?
- What are you saying?
- Have you been with a woman?
Yes or no?
- Stop it, Sara.
- Dressing like a man you're now
becoming like them. Right Angela?
It seems I have it too.
- Ah yes? And where do you have it?
Here, and here?
- Ei!
- Here, here, here...
Sara...
- Sara, what're you doing?
- It hurts, it hurts.
Angela! Angela!
Signora Maria!
Signora Maria! Signora Maria!
She is ill.
- It's rust blood.
- The child still isn't near,
I can't do anything.
Angela!
Tommaso, open!
Tommaso!
- What do you still want from me?
- I need you, come.
- I have to go.
- At least the baby is...
- Can I see her?
Can I see her?
- Do you want to hold him?
"Give them eternal rest, Lord,
and may the perpetual light shine. "
"Rest in peace."