Sync by = B---k =
02h12,36min. 855MB.
Ugliness in a woman
es! a mortal sin
you are beautiful
qubn that you are looking for beauty
you are ugly,
Oehe qubn you are looking for ugliness.
- The door!
The al'gent!
- Veiled! Oest
all that I have saved.
It blows.
- Or were you?
I got worried sick.
I told you that you emmeniez too.
Because of you,
I spent three nights in jail.
- Greece é your absence,
I worked as ever.
- You gave me the address for the
leg.
- Uavidité, dear Violette
dest your vice, not mine.
Without me, you'd Paris é, é
starve
like the others!
The bells are ringing.
- Beef, you can be?
- It's expensive.
- For advance.
I can pourtoi much, you know.
Cris
ll suffocating.
- You killed,
dest what you want?
Had washed my hair for you.
Here, feel.
When I left you,
it will be too late.
You die.
Do me a favor,
plutét read my manuscript.
I need to know what you think.
So?
Not like you?
- Y has only
Celebrity for your friends.
You never talk to me, ever.
Fécrivais If I talk to you.
From my love Poui ' YOU.
- Write.
From the time that I tell you.
- I can not.
Take me in your arms.
Touch Me!
- You will not again!
- Close your eyes, imagine
I'm someone else.
- You are mad, get treatment!
- You are a monster!
A manipulator!
Veiled what you are.
Who had the idea to me
pass for his wife?
Who pushed me éjouer
lesjeunes married?
I'm trapped.
- We came to eat.
I could think that this war would last?
She sobs.
Tell me what you have read.
Your opinion is important to me.
- I'll tell you nothing!
You are like my mother.
EgoTste, perverse.
- And you, a horrible female.
Conformist and stupid.
Between us,
it will never happen.
Ga Put yourself in the head.
The door slams.
- I can kill me, you know.
- Take this notebook.
Go fuck you cool
under an apple tree.
You spit on paper what
makes you so unbearable.
Everyone will be better.
My mother never gave me the hand.
She helped me e up,
é down sidewalks,
pinging my clothes
Has the 0U Vemmanchure is perceptible.
- "Listen to me
Try to understand..."
- This humbled me
I rejected the hand.
- "I was a maid."
- It pingait me and raised me
like a chicken
qubn removed by a wing
I became soft
I rfavangais more.
My mother saw my tears.
"You wanna run over .7.
"You cry .7."
It was that mécrasait e e.
- My poor child...
I have one thing to say é.
Now you more E. continue.
- Maurice!
You're leaving?
As ga, without telling me?
- I gotta find money to live.
- Let.
I will return é Paris.
- I'll try to extract sub é NRF
in exchange for my manuscript.
You have not found bad?
Go see my rich friends.
They will not let me.
- You told me that you hated.
- What do you tell?
- It will hurt you!
- You wander,
I did not kill anyone.
- And the young Jewish girl é station?
You knew well.
She gave you money?
- Stop harassing me!
In a week, I returned.
I can not do without you.
- You lie!
You do not come back.
You abandon me, too.
She screams.
Classical.
Sonnefle.
- Who isthe?
-'s Friend Maurice.
- One second.
My son wants to see you.
I open.
Enter.
Do not move, I'll be back.
Tenez.
- Simone de Beauvoir, who is it?
- This is a friend of my son.
- A woman write such a big book?
You read it?
- A story of three e household?
No, thank you.
- A woman between two men?
- A woman between a man and a woman.
Ah, veiled my son.
- You are the friend of Maurice?
- This is me.
- It is stuck in Germany, near Hamburg.
A certificate of pregnancy
would return.
I found a doctor.
Qa will not be a problem.
- What was he doing leg-bottom?
He is committed
as a volunteer worker.
Qa went wrong for him.
- Poorly shot, ga mean?
- I do not judge é.
This is my friend.
- It is not.
Find another pigeon.
- You sign his death.
- You're kidding.
Lt is still out.
There will survive without me.
Classical.
The bells.
A knock.
Who is it?
- This is me.
- I'm coming.
- You're lying in the middle of
Paprés afternoon?
Qu'es't's going yet?
It fattendait yesterday é lunch.
Oest thou hast written ga,
The Asphyxiation?
- Key not re ga!
- This is gay, as the title.
- Well, the beef cheek.
Make it boil.
Oest for Michel.
, Thou shalt the cloth.
- You think your e brother now?
I want eggs well.
Ah you see.
Tell him dest me.
- You can not get a real job?
The war is over.
You still live like a thief.
- Do Enjoy as other, right?
For once I get the money.
- Patou?
Ah bah, say so...
You deprive yourself of anything.
All the money you win,
you can not let something
more suitable?
- I have other projects.
'F Ca;
A knock.
- Yes?
- Miss Debaralle?
- This is me. Do not move.
Veiled.
- Thank you. The account is.
- Debaralle, any idea?
- This is business.
This is the name of my father.
- Will not that
é goes ga you the head, Debaralle.
Debaralle, then ga...
If farréte police?
Tell them that your name Debaralle.
Qa would file the e Valenciennes.
She laughed.
Musiquejazz.
Miss?
Oh, no.
Hello, ma'am.
Dear madam?
I read The Guest, thank
you for having dared.
Here, I put my life in leg-.
- I'm in a hurry, maisje will read.
I promise.
- I sold everything.
- You promised me!
- Go see Marcel.
- Marcel.
- Ah!
- Coffee and sugar.
- Forget the Halles
reopened this morning.
1 kg of bacon.
From farted head of...
- I take everything. How?
- 2 O00.
- You are not going to
with the back of the spoon.
1500.
- Yeah, dest good.
Whistles and shouts.
Come!
- My Money! I lost my money.
Music intriguing.
- Hello, Violet.
- Hello, ma'am.
- You allow me
é call you Violet?
Enter.
First I have to e> <CUser.
I had taken you for a bourgeois
whose childhood was bored.
I was wrong.
You have written a beautiful book.
Almighty.
Intrepid.
Oest what counts.
You write long?
- No.
Well, not much, some items.
This is Maurice who pushed me.
- The Maurice Book?
- Yes, Maurice Sachs.
- Ah, Maurice Sachs...
"am.
- The beginning, but he left
Germany.
- I know.
You have him?
- No, and I do not expect.
- Maurice Sachs is the opposite of you.
This cache.
Especially behind the words.
Finally, he gave you the impetus
and taste Fécriture.
The pages devoted to it
I like less.
It would be better to remove them.
Keep them for another book may be.
I intend to give your manuscript
é Albert Camus.
The edge e its collection the NRF.
Make cuts quickly.
You should work some passages.
Your father, for example.
Nothing is known of him.
A fantéme.
This is his léoheté
which has made you a bétarde.
Probe.
I need the script in a week,
10 days at the latest.
We'll see you then.
Bravo, Violet.
We will work well together.
- No!
Make ga e me!
Bastard!
No, no!
No!
She screams.
Bell rings.
Go see!
A knock.
- My mother is?
- Be nice to her.
- Simone de Beauvoir
liked my book!
I'll be published.
- I leave Paris. Ernest sold.
He bought a farm in Charente.
Without consulting me.
- I told you!
Should not marry.
- Do not push it!
Oest Deje hard enough as ga.
- Oh, no.
Pardon me.
Sorry.
I beg your pardon.
Pardon me.
Come live with me.
Leave him, he deserves you not.
- And your brother?
- It is in both gone.
I'll let you live.
- 0U And we dwell?
In your hole é rats?
- I'll find more.
Oest finished the black market.
I take my life in hand.
Everything will change now.
- You réves, Violet.
Nothing changejamais. Classic
Musique.
- You deserve more.
II said this softly.
Tuck, calm down.
This pity
humiliated me for my mother
I promise you think.
I wanted hard, decisive.
Why he complained .7.
For years, I dragged a shot!
She wanted to throw at him.
But it em'uit.
II left shelter in his house
the well groomed park.
Knocking.
- It happened to you, muchAnd.
Thank you, Ms. Moustier.
At your service, Ms. Leduc.
Classical Music.
Conversation distant.
Laughter.
- Ah, Violet.
- Tomorrow.
- Tomorrow, Nathalie.
- Hello.
- Sorry, I'm busy.
- I finished.
- You are fast, ie well.
- Hold.
Foie gras.
Camembert, it is é heart.
And farted in the head veiled.
- From the black market?
- I did, dest completed.
- I'll pay you,
there is no reason.
- No, nothing.
For you, dest gift.
- Thank you.
I leave you, I am not alone.
A very fast.
- A very fast.
- Hello.
You know?
Maurice.
- What, Maurice?
He died in Germany.
It was removed shot in the head.
Drama Music.
- I year -
"My friend is dead ."
I repeated Yai
told '
"Death."
Jbssayais dkavoir word.
A syllable,
it is not long e crossing.
Pronounce it as you like IE.
Sonnefle.
- Yes.?
- Hello, I have an appointment with Mr.
Albert Camus.
- Who should I tell?
- Violet'te Leduc.
Just for signing.
- You're ahead.
- Yes, a little.
- Follow me.
Sweet Music.
- Why I am not a
published in the White collection?
This coverage is grim, confess.
- This is a widely
é cheapest rate.
Here is the list desjournalistes.
Mr. Camus happen in an instant.
Finally, dest what he said.
- Maisje do not know any.
What does one write
someone we do not know é?
"tribute Pauteur".
- Tribute of the author?
Oest not a homage to
send the text e critic.
- You will receive your copies by mail.
The door slams.
A bell rings.
- Note that I am Oreve.
- I have something for you.
- The Asphyxiation.
- Qa fate next week.
- At Gallimard, just ga.
Collection Hope, I do not know.
- This is a new collection.
Created by Albert Camus.
Great dissemination.
- Albert Camus, bah say so!
I'm happy for you, Violet.
You who thought never happen.
- You'll read it, right?
And we'll meet again?
Tell me we'll meet again, Hermine.
We stayed far too long.
You?
Tell me.
- Not much.
Always the same.
A lot of work.
And always the pupils.
I do not complain.
There ales holiday.
- And the other?
42a Go.
- Your hands.
They have changed.
- This is the dishes.
Should quej'y go.
- Always é St-Lazare?
- Do not insist.
- I want to see you again.
- You're hurting me, lick me.
- You still want me?
Music Ambiance.
- Tell me about your abortion.
- Nothing é SAY above.
You know as well as me.
- You were é how?
-5 Months and a half.
I almost died.
The baby
d0 be eradicated piece by piece.
It was him or me.
My husband wanted to keep.
- You were married?
- Not long.
Before, I lived with a woman.
Ga But did not work either.
I thought the wife Pardoise erase status
,
make me identical to the other.
- The child you regret?
- Oh... Not.
It would have looked like me.
It would have suffered, I
would have killed him.
My mother did not kill me, I have enough
criticized.
- Marriage is a sham, Violet.
For women, early Fesclavage.
You understood before others.
No freedom for them
without economic freedom.
But it is still far away.
- My 1st love story,
détait board.
Her name was Isabelle.
Qa lasted one school year.
It has been discovered,
my mother has separated us.
I have never seen.
Guess I'll pass.
In the street, in the subway...
- Will tell all ga.
- I can not.
- If I will be, your e CETES.
Will go further.
Tell all.
Your trafficking, and especially your love
, Pavortement.
You will thus help é many women.
- Hi, Castor.
- Ah, Genet, you get e pic.
Here
Dontje Leduc told you about.
Jean Genet.
- You are the greatest.
- No kidding.
Castor told me good your book.
- I do not happen to you calf.
- Well, no false modesty.
You dined with Sartre?
- Yes, as usual was too drunk.
He wanted to go to bed.
I, dest 0U time I wake up.
Scotch!
- No, dest for me.
Sir, 3 scotches.
Excuse me.
- Yes?
- I am looking for a novel.
Asphyxia.
- What author.?
- Some Leduc, I think.
Leduc.
Oest out Gallimard.
Hope Collection.
- Ever heard.
- I did the book, it is nowhere.
You find normal ga?
- This is often the authors
smaller.
The publisher has made a small run.
I command you?
- No, thank you, I'm passing.
What do you mean by
"small print"?
Pardon?
- Be specific.
What sub do you mean?
Qa does not deserve the same
treatment as the others?
No, but say it!
There for Julien Green, here!
- Calm down, you are not
in your normal state.
- Not in my normal state?
Qu'es't-so you say
ga?
I understood your petitjeu.
You think I'm Violette Leduc!
I'm not Leduc.
This is a very oHere friend.
Violette Leduc friends it!
And talent!
Fortunately she friends to say!
The door slams.
She cries.
I no longer want to live.
- I know you, you will live.
I will watch.
- I talked é everyone around me.
Everyone seeks
and can not find it.
- Jappellerai Gaston Gallimard
tomorrow, I promise.
- Ga But what change?
And what I'm living now?
To me,
everything has always been harder.
Since small, everything is hard.
Qa does not stop,
ga will never stop.
- Think Fécriture é, é
Deje what she gave you.
It will give you that
the company has denied.
(; Asked time.
Continue, work.
- If seulementje could hold your hand.
- I want you.
I'm going to hang up.
- I love you.
The bells are ringing.
- What are You?
- This is because I am ugly
that you do not like me?
- For me, there are few physical.
- Mine displeases you.
Admit it.
- I have a lot of work.
We'll talk another time.
- How can you love me?
I am a good person.
I can be very nice.
- Stop whining.
- What am I going to live now?
've Spent all my money.
- Give you at work.
- Write your obsessions.
Solutions come.
- Write for whom?
I'm interested.
- To default é do it for me.
The Asphyxia is a first book,
there will be others.
Give yourself that chance.
Qa just now.
Out!
- Non.
- If you have e time to lose.
The door closes.
- She mbrdonne dliter my shoes,
running over pebbles, nails,
glass!! thorns es
know I do.
She did not need my barefoot
on! e glass are thorns,
nails, I understand.
I cry because I understand.
Music Drama
have dreamed that you loved me, madame
I knew I dreamed
while you loved me.
My place is in myself.
The rest is vanity.
Arrive, loneliness.
Arrive with your long hair
defeated on your face.
Start snoring
organs of my desert.
My heart, madame,
dest my cross of honor
conceive How-
I greet you another Fagon 7
I travel,
I'm a glacier that moves.
Petit art.
A knock.
- I bother?
Here is someone who loved your
asphyxia.
- You found it?
It does not interest anyone.
He really liked me.
- The kind of book that you tear the heart.
- (,. Has nice dest
- writers like Jacques.
It is crazy enough to collect manuscripts.
- Jacques Guérin, enchanted.
- The name of my... I've
been to my misfortune -
- Do you like women, you
husband Bride.? - Not just.
You cigarettes
=.? = I e sec.
Thanks.
- You work,
we do not want to bother you.
- Calva.
Calva, ie everything I.
- Viewing.
- It is not sofllera.
- He is the husband?
- This is it. Feel free.
- Gringalet.
Shrimp.
- What are you doing in life?
He works in perfumes.
He is great, he can answer only.
- Perfumes d'Orsay, ie me.
- You're rich, then?
- Yes.
And Betard like you.
- Rich Betard.
- It is?
- My father has never acknowledged me.
It is not about my marital status.
Spent my childhood with my brother
hidden.
My mother passed
see us from time to time.
- She lived 0U?
- Elsewhere with him.
- He?
- My father. He married the
ratifying indefinitely.
He would not leave his wife.
You see, I am rich.
And I Betard.
- Oh!
It is three, I feel less alone.
- In my case,
I do not know if I'm right.
I have neither father nor mother.
Your Asphyxiation.
Cocteau loved.
Have you heard?
It Femmene dinner somewhere?
- At this hour?
I'm not ready.
But go you.
- No, we dine here.
You got what it takes?
- I'll see.
- You will come é campaign.
My house is open.
I want you to feel you you.
- Weekends are e Luzarches
Topper.
Skits were written,
is made idiots.
Jacques would we play in cinematography.
You'd the mother in my film?
- The mother, why the mother?
Have potatoes.
That's all.
Oest finished abundance.
So?
You're swollen.
He laughed.
She knows?
Go to the end.
Thou give him.
This is a smart woman.
- It let me down.
- No, I think not.
She needs you.
Sartre was infatuated with me. She
you.
Oest in balance.
Do you need money? I have.
Here.
Not bother you.
I'll give it back, I promise.
- You can type Guérin.
He likes you.
- How?
- Stop, you're in love with Simone.
It is not for you.
Either.
I'll let you read
bientét something.
A piece. Good.
You inspire me, you know.
I dedicate thee.
Good, thank you.
Oest my mother will be happy.
- And cruel love I accuse changed
constantly Famertume sweetness of life.
- Petrarch.
- I had no family,
I found a sister.
- Why not give me
your BMO 1st pages?
May be I could ask é
Gallimard advance.
- It's too tet.
I want to go after one.
What you read in one sitting.
- You are stubborn.
You want to tell me what it is?
- No.
- At least ga ale deserves to be frank.
- And you?
You never talk about yourself.
- I'm in my test
on the status of women.
I launched e Faveuglette.
I realize the mountain
é which I tackled.
Had a meeting with Sartre
type has yet told me:
. "Think ga
because you're a woman".
Would not argue it
ga as he thought because he was a man.
I checked everywhere and all the time
a man is right in his
and the woman is in the wrong.
I do not know how my
book will be welcomed,
but it supports 0U ga hurts.
I'm used é take hits.
- You've found a title?
- I'm not sure yet, but...
The second Sex can be.
And you?
- I, I know.
Lfiffamée...
Music Drama.
- Violet, Violet!
You're an awful actress
dubbed a troublemaker.
Is taken!
- No, not again, I'm tired!
- If you continue,
I replace you.
- And you hurt me, look!
- You had E. walk straight.
- I told you that I
pasjouer a mother!
- Do not take the pram!
- If, in fact!
I am grotesque.
Jacques, take my defense.
He persecutes me.
He became nasty.
Tell him he is evil.
- Genet, you are bad.
Cree and laughter.
- Oh!
Violette.
- I can not be a mother.
Even laugh, I told you so.
- I understand, Violet.
- No, not you understand.
You are not a woman.
You do not know what
dest to get pregnant.
- You take all tragic,
dest a game.
- A game?
To, ie a game?
Me, I felt abused.
Used worse than ga, humiliated.
I thought you were less
superficial, Jacques.
- I'm really sorry.
Everything hurts you.
We wanted to have fun.
A treat yourself.
- To make me happy?
She laughed.
But just ga?
But what you know my pleasure?
You know what would make me
fun, now?
You know what I would most want?
- Violet'te, ie ridiculous.
Like men, you know.
- Men, women...
It is not question of ga.
Me, I see the child serious
in you.
- Oh, stop!
Violet, do not we leave
on a misunderstanding.
Let me make a move.
I offer a deluxe edition
for your next book.
A limited print on beautiful paper.
Did the same thing for
John and his Miracle of the Rose.
Pauvert ga is very good,
is not it, John?
OR in your book Are You?
- I'm almost done.
- Perfect. For this publication,
I will give you 100,000 francs.
For you, obviously.
The rest is my office.
Please.
- Simone de Beauvoir will not like ga.
- You're not obliged to tell him.
- I'll think.
- Very well, very well.
Good road and e bientét.
- You've fared well, say so.
To The Miracle of the Rose,
I had only 70,000.
You're not close to see, your
100000.
This is a cheapskate.
She laughed.
- Jacques Guérin
This is a perfume, right?
- And a big collector.
I am wary of collectors.
- Why?
-They collect dead things.
These things are dead you know.
The words are alive.
They live, they act.
The cult objects is morbid, right?
- He still saved
manuscripts Proust.
- Hello, Mr. Meyer.
- Ms. Beauvoir.
- I leave you the keys.
Perfect, Ms. Beauvoir.
- Thank you very much.
- Bon voyage.
- Hello.
- At'tendez!
Hold.
- You've finally finished.
I read on the plane.
- Guerin wants to publish a deluxe edition.
- Really?
- Yes, against money.
100,000 francs.
- You aurezjamais
so far ahead of Gallimard.
This is welcome, right?
- Bient6t I can pay my rent more.
- The book is web.
Do not make this head.
I'm not dead.
- You come back when?
- A Paéroport Bourget please.
- If the plane crashed before reaching
é New York?
Music Drama.
- Guerin is very busy.
This is bientét season roses.
A knock.
- Yes, come.
- Guerin, Miss Leduc.
- Ah, Violet.
What a nice surprise!
- How are you?
- Well, thank you.
- And your book?
- (; Ay is finished dest
- you are happy.
- Yes, I'm glad.
- And Simone de Beauvoir.
- I am from him.?.? Give.
- What can I do for you.
- I just look 100000 francs.
If you have not changed your mind
,
course.
- Oh, not at all, not at all.
You prefer a check or tickets?
- Tickets.
It is soft, your carpet.
This is a true?
- A real what?
- Panthére.
- It's beautiful, is not it?
Oest a gift from my mother.
- I thought é what you told me.
We behaved like idiots.
- Never mind.
- If you want to recount.
- It's not worth it.
I trust you.
Sweet Music.
Moaning.
- Veiled.
Oest no more complicated than ga.
Veiled...
You coal?
- Just right.
In ascend tomorrow.
- Leave it to the men.
I ascend you with mine.
- Forward.
- Go to pleasure.
- Goodbye.
- Well things é your lady.
And the girl.
- I will not fail.
- Leave it to the men.
Talk.
If you let them...
By the way, your book...
- What, my book?
- The Asphyxia. . Thank you.
Oest not true what you say.
Qa made me a monster.
- You think so?
- The lady on the wall, ie it?
- Yes, it dest.
As if you did not know.
- You're not gonna start
with your silliness.
A shame your mother.
- Should you always belittle any re ga.
- The waters are on the landing?
- Yes.
Te not forget the paper.
Hey!
- Oh, sorry you me, Violet.
You still living in the Middle Ages.
- Do not worry ga, va.
Thank you.
- Eggs,
I sell the poulterer.
They are good, you'll see.
I was wanting more.
Maisje can not invent dozens.
I also chickens.
Eggs, I put
é lid near the stove.
You would see ga
when they break their shells
with their little bee...
Qa makes me want to cry.
Ernest said that this
maternal estl'instincl.
He is still good, Ernest.
- But...
Violet, what you got?
- I do not know, but turns ga.
Happened to me,
the other day in the street.
Dest You think serious?
- Fool.
You should be happy.
- Glad?
- It's back ege.
Finally.
Something evil is good.
You'll be able to enjoy.
- Enjoy. Enjoy what?
- Take someone.
- I would have otherwise
am that I am.
- What is quite missing?
Be wife.
And you will find.
Be wife, dammit.
Oest not rocket science.
Look at your mother.
OR you?
- Mme de Beauvoir returned?
- Still no.
- We opened the window.
- This is the maid.
- Are you sure?
- It is not returned.
- You address.
She followed his mail.
- No.
- Qa is three months she left.
She returned when?
- I know more than you.
- You know no more?
You are hiding something.
- This is not bientét finished!
Ms. Beauvoir, it is not.
It is not!
Sonnefle.
- What dest?
- Mme de Beauvoir?
- No, no one.
- I come in?
Let me in!
- You are crazy! Classical Music.
- Do not forget that these women haTssent.
They haTssent their condition.
Importantly,
they hate themselves.
Unable to love,
they are incapable of loving.
There are more than erotic ritual.
- I do not understand.
Their hatred of Madame,
dest their hatred of themselves?
- Obviously.
If you'll take your seats.
It is a rite that must reach
sublime tragedy.
We are in Racine, hear well.
These women do not reach their goals é
but destroy themselves.
Watch this glove.
This is not any glove.
This is a rubber glove.
This glove must be
in the heart of your concerns.
As you, I will not tell you
it should represent.
- An erotic object.
- It's true.
In a gesture you make him leave
dishwater.
To become skin gently fantasy.
Think about it, an important dest.
Is taken.
- If you did not like The Hungry,
have the courage to tell me.
- Ah, Violet.
Going to call you.
- A good time!
OR were you?
- Au> <USA.
For a lecture
é Chicago and California.
I went there two days.
- You lie!
- Dest What the fuck?
Finally, Simone.
- A little silence.
Please.
- I did not explain myself well é.
- You've met someone?
- Yes, an American.
Qa you going?
- Like it?
- Qa does not concern you.
I read The Hungry.
Oest what you wrote
more beautiful.
I did not expect so much love e.
This is not so easy for me.
Dest Sartre found a great book.
Gaston Gallimard will
you sign the contract.
We go out together.
The Second Sex and The Hungry.
White collection.
Qa you going?
- If only I could HATR you.
- He has What? We hear you.
- What do you want?
Nobody runs me the red carpet.
What do you think happens!
- What you can be melodramatic.
- Genet, I read your piéce,
dest shit!
Is asked to be e Racine Rimbaud?
Is asked to be e Rimbaud Racine?
- Miss Leduc, please.
- Last door left é.
Down the hall.
- Thank you.
It strikes.
- Yes?
This is me.
- I'm not presentable.
I mfinquiéte, I have no news.
You do not answer,
what's happening?
- I did not do my household.
I do not do mine
all lesjours either.
It is good to you.
- Bient6tje will not
have enough to put coal.
- You work?
- You think I'm ridiculous?
- From collecting pictures of me?
- Frankly, yes.
Maisje'm not here to talk about ga.
- Thank you.
Bravo, what hay!
- We're talking about you.
- I am taken aback by some.
Communists, for example.
Camus, quefestime,
saying queje ridicules mell.
A guy told me that I was humbled to be
a woman
I humbled and men...
ll take time.
- A glass of wine?
This is the 0th I have.
- I never refuse good wine.
-Here dest of the ordinary.
- I'm not here to talk about The Hungry.
You know what I think
failure of a book.
I do not Pattribue the
fact that you describe
your love for me.
Ga Get out of the head.
The book is web.
It is good.
He will live.
I came to talk about your future.
I hope that you get to work.
- I no longer believe.
- OR in the project which had been spoken
Are You?
This 1st sexual experience.
With this pupil when you
were young boarder.
- Isabelle?
- Yes.
- (,. Has nfintéressera person
these sexcapades girls
I might as well make the sidewalk.
But with my head, nobody wants me.
Who would..? pay more
I am an old
neurotic calibrated wasted.
- No.
- Si ..
40s.
Nothing before me
=... = Person...
Alone Forever Alone
have no money.
No love life, nothing.
- Gallimard is prét é
pay you an amount every month
I do not know how...
But
enough to live and write in peace.
Provided to get to work.
- Are you kidding?
- This is the Rele an editor
to get money
Greece é
mediocre writers who sell
to redistribute to sell less talented.
- Or not.
- Let's talk about your project.
- There was this 1st experience
board.
There is also Jacques, my husband.
Uavortement while ga.
- I even had a title.
- A good time.
- Ravages.
- (; Was like you.
- This is a real havoc,
that I lived.
- Nothing demolition
- more reason to make a
something constructive
I will leave some time traveling.
- Find your American?
- No, we broke up.
I'm in Norway.
- With who?
- Sartre.
- Take me.
Do not leave me alone.
- Why do vousjamais leaving from?
You do not like to travel?
- Was not taught me
we did not have the means.
- This is a matter of curiosity.
Qa would do you good.
I wait your BMO 1st pages
do not disappoint me.
Classical.
A knock.
- Mail.
- "Miss, revising accounting NRF
" é Yoccasion the end of Yannée.
"I am pleased to announce
" we pay you.
"A monthly payment of 25,000 francs."
- The
octopus in my belly trembled
Isabelle drank in her right breast,
left breast
I drank with it
I was breastfeeding
darkness of his mouth when séloignait
I drove hand
jusquéux raves tears of joy.
Moaning
I dug into his neck with my teeth
,
faspirais night under the collar her dress
roots of a tree rustled
I hold, fétoufie Yarbre
I the greenhouse fétoufie!'re voice.
I hold, I remove the light.
The storm broke.
Make it come.
It lends me his shoulder.
Or she borrows mine.
Do I have her face near mine
! must share it with Yinnocence
mysterious Music.
She left me a world
0d I had not lived
= = to get into a world
m 'I do not still living.
She gave me a legon humility.
I... Veffrayais
I'm flesh and blood
I'm alive
I'm not an idol
"Dear Simone de Beauvoir.
" Ravages advance.
"I left Isabelle
" and here I am with Jacques,
my husband.
"J {es write for love
"to find them,
not lose ."
"And I see the chasm widen
"between life and I méne
férotisme of livre that I write ."
This is bientét Roussillon?
- This is far behind
little lady.
One approach Vaison.
- I told you I was going down
é Roussillon.
What's village, there?
I'm lost.
0U We here?
- Falcon, Falcon you are e.
-There is a Hetel?
- A é Hetel Falcon? Ah ga, no.
- 0U And then I find a room?
It is that this house?
- The owner died
children no longer come.
- It feels good here.
Oest what this mountain?
- This is the Mont Ventoux
that protects us all.
Sweet Music.
- This was the 1st time that I entered
fintimité
dune lingerie man.
My hand touched a pile of tenderness
as in the womb of a woman.
On him I was looking for, I tétonnais
I thought
I touched the wrinkled skin,
brittle as eyelid.
H skzffrit.
J choked on my".
This is 1st time
no price i will not be 9a,
told my mother.
Moaning.
- Simone.
Return é reason.
- Violet'te Leduc is a great writer.
You treat it badly.
You were less.. picky with Genet.
- May be he should remove
eroticism and...
keep Faffeciivité.
Make a story é
share with these two schoolgirls..
If the author consented
é surround some shade
its operating techniques.
- You can not afford
a woman to speak openly
about his sexuality.
This is your look that is dirty.
- What is Sartre?
- Like me.
What Leduc is a great writer.
- And this passage Pavortement?
Qa never happen.
Censorship sanction.
- It must be that these
things called the Solent.
Grasset and Albin Michel does not want.
Or with drastic cuts.
With Gallimard, we save on Pavortement
passage.
You will be the 1st é speak out.
- What do you advise me?
- Yield.
- And if I resist?
- I know what you feel.
We catch up one day.
Violette, look at me.
You talk about female sexuality
as no woman has done.
With poetry, truth and more.
One day they will thank you for ga.
- I was mutilated.
This is awful.
Stomach hurts.
Music Drama.
- Did you sleep?
This is important, sleep.
've Avoided making noise
turning pages.
She screams.
She sobs.
Dramatic Music.
- Hello.
- I'm sorry, was banned visits.
- She sleeps.
- I'm furious.
- He was given electric shocks
despite my opposition.
Excuse me, I need to talk to Dr. Fouquet.
- Do you want me to accompany you?
- This is useless.
- There
d0 have significant expenditure.
I want to participate.
-There is no question.
- I am grateful
friendship you wear it.
From your constant help.
- You can not be friends with
Violette.
- You know as well as me.
Oest a duty that I made.
Excuse me, I'm in a hurry.
Soft music.
He currently also letters.
You will read when you can.
Listen ga.
"We must jump into Rev /
ages as in fire.
" Violette Leduc is not afraid of anything,
"Has mercy on nothing.
" His character is possessed
a frantic need to love
"which transforms into executioners
beings she likes.
" She dares this
no woman has ever said,
"kill these things,
" torn from the womb Angels."
Violette.
You did halfway
I do not lick you as ga.
Spiritual.
- Loyal é half a century
of literary tradition,
awarded the Goncourt
will their annual award.
The 9. including Francis Carco,
Dorgelès Roland, Pierre Mac Orlan,
Philippe Armand and Hériat Salacrou
crowned The Mandarins by Simone de Beauvoir
which remained invisible.
Music spirited ante.
Less shy Jean Reverzy
winner Renaudot
faced obligations
glory by signing...
- It was drélement well,
this clinic.
Mme de Beauvoir has paid all ga?
Saw the price of the room.
've ever slept that price web.
Not even for my wedding night
Ernest.
Lean on me, go!
Take pressing your mother.
My God!
This shambles!
Oh!
I wanted to spend doing housework,
maisj'ai caught the train for 11 h.
You should undress and lie
down a little, my Violette.
And the same trash not emptied.
You should go to bed.
- "Miss, we confirm
payment of your monthly
" amounting to 25,000 F that day.
Accounting ".
- I can here more
sick of living here.
- Qa is nothing é
revenge on things
! =. . = - Well, thou shalt give Michel é.
Oest finished, I will write more.
- Tomorrow fauras changed my mind.
Go to bed.
- No No.!
.! write more.
- Swallow.
Hop.
Your friend Mr. Guérin came several times
for your sleep therapy.
With large bouquets as ga
!.. Your friend Genet also.
You were féchés.
Mme de Beauvoir came once a week.
Sometimes with Sartre.
That is ugly!
A beautiful woman
live with an ugly man.
Finally!
We had attentions
for my little darling.
The flowers are wilted.
But there ales gifts.
I put them in your suitcase.
You want to see?
You will not cry when I made this trip
to be with my little sweetheart.
- You will shut up!
Once and for all,
is what you gonna shut up?
- Why are you evil?
Qu'es't-what I do to you?
- You've made me!
Veiled the problem.
You made me
when you did not want me
neither my father nor anyone!
I am a bétarde!
Veiled the problem.
And nobody wants me.
Nobody wants me.
Cris.
She cries.
Dramatic Music.
- Veiled.
Worrying Music.
- Violet'te,
what a nice surprise!
How do you feel?
42a Go
have my mother on the back.
- You're leaving?
- No, I'm moving.
Not have Finstinct property,
maisj'ai purchased near Montparnasse.
My Mandarins sell well.
- I know.
Bravo for the Goncourt.
- Thank you.
- Ms. Beauvoir?
What is being done for the office?
- We meet somewhere?
I come.
- I'll help you.
Let me help you?
For once I can be useful.
And the curtains?
Forgot to pick up the curtains.
- I'll make more.
Take ga if you are interested.
- I said not to ga ga.
- I left things, the old stove...
Do not hesitate.
- I do not demand Pauméne.
- Finally, Violet.
Do not get upset,
we are more web.
- We're PLUS?
We are 0U, then?
You know, 0U we are?
You are right.
See you later.
I'm going.
By the way...
The pension...
- Do not worry, they will pay.
I am committed.
- Gaston Gallimard,
é pay pension Leduc.
You take me for a fool.
- I do not know what you're talking about.
- I know you dest.
Drama Music
jealous, bitter, unhappy,
veiled this queje
é am because of you.
I remain attached é you.
You tell me that I will succeed.
I believe you, I obey you.
I finished in a clinic
drugged, crazy, no future,
while you earn the success.
Get out of my life!
- It's you who gave me
this place!
Give me another one.
- I can not!
- Take your pen,
will change the course of things.
No otherwise.
The cries do not advance,
Pécriture yes.
- I have nothing more to say é.
- Repeat from the beginning,
since birth.
- Qa change what?
- All
since you no longer are the very.
Your eyes on you has changed!
Music Drama.
- You fire?
Why you gallop?
- I'm in a hurry.
- My name is René.
What do you do?
- I came to take the air.
And you?
Me?
- What's your name?
- Violet'te.
Oest here our paths separated.
Qa amuses you follow the crones?
- I want to see you again.
A knock.
Musiquejazz
- how you came?
- What question? Subway.
Oest good home, ga smells good.
- Roast beef.
- Who's in the pictures,
an actress?
- This is Simone de Beauvoir.
Qa anything to you?
- I read about it.
Articles.
- This is my friend.
- It was not the big head?
- A table!
- Oh, oh!
- I can?
- Yes, but no frills, eh?
Moaning.
This is baroque.
This is a man
sex in a woman's hand.
Yet dest root of the world
= = On strike.
- Who is it?
- It's me, Violet.
Phoned the bistro e thugs.
I wanted to remove.
I've finally finished.
I do not want to disturb you. Veiled.
Qa is 1000 pages.
Did as you told me.
've Kept the essentials.
These gentlemen of the expedition
charcuteront.
Come on, we'll see.
From all aforesaid, I do not care.
- I'll read it very quickly.
Excuse me, I feel not very me.
- I do not wanna bother you.
- Violet'te.
Please, we'll have a drink.
Qa will do us good.
- This is jolly good home.
This is great.
- Tenez.
- Thank you.
- I buried mom yesterday.
- Really?
- In the strictest privacy.
I did not want anyone.
Account Appointments,
dest me crying.
He had warned me.
I'd come to support you.
- It went so fast.
Poor woman.
I am steeped in remorse.
Say that I made him afraid.
One day...
I too am web.
'm Know, this idea disgusts me.
- Provided ga never happens to me.
Losing my mother.
I do not survive it.
- OR are you getting your
love with your magon?
He married dest so complicated.
He sends me his brother
that I sleep with him.
What to do?
- His brother please?
- No.
But time passes.
And I am alone.
Always alone.
Nothing changejamais.
I'm a desert monologue.
- I'll read it now,
ga will do me good.
- I can stay a little?
- For The Bétarde,
I will write the preface.
Qa running in my head for a while.
I put all our chances thugs.
- My case is not unique
'. fear of death
and I'm sorry cfétre world
I did not travaiflé
I did not study
I have cried, I have cried.
Iarmes and cries
mbnt took a long time
I will go as I arrived.
Intact.
Officer
my fault that mbnt tortured.
Jkaurais wanted unborn statue.
I am a Hmaoe manure under my
virtues are qualities,
courage, meditation, culture,
arms crossed, I'm broke me
é these words ie.
Music ante gusto.
- They reproach me so.
From not having loved
called love.
Qdils call love
qwest But this they know 7.
And qdest-oe know that Yen .7.
To each his love.
And her need for love.
Maybe mine
a need for love
=. = Who can all e is set.
In a body.
And that remains the song.
What I throw to you.
What I nbserais not.
If I lacked love
4964 the reform of marital
is underway.
The woman is entitled
é a bank account
manage her own property.
D'e > <ercer profession
without the permission of her husband.
Simone de Beauvoir, hello.
- Hello.
You just preface
The Bétarde Violette Leduc.
It embodies happiness and poetry.
Combat a woman for her freedom.
It seems that the company is on the eve é
profound changes
altering irreversibly
women's relationship é literature.
Tell us a little more
on your relationship with the author.
What was fundamental Pécriture
démancipation in its process.
- Every writer draws é sincerity.
Each has its own
which resembles no é no.
I do not know more than
integrates Leduc.
The Bétarde clearly shows
a life is resuming
a destiny freedom.
Tirelessly she questions
and recreates what she discovered.
In the late 50s, on my advice,
Violet'te
Leduc began to tell his life.
I had to publish my memoirs.
I encouraged é do so.
She laughed to herself,
as if she did not deserve my trust.
I undeceived etj'ai insisted.
She was overwhelmed with loneliness,
disappointments and poverty.
I did not believe or é or é
solitude his inner poverty.
One day, she discovered Provence.
The gentle landscape and wild
é suited this girl from the North.
Sensual, curious, emotional,
she found in this setting serenity
which allowed him to understand,
isolate the motjuste,
construct a work that
finally met the public.
She mingled
real life and dream life.
Dreams, é his surprise,
were no longer used
to shut out the world, but to reveal
é readers.
I do not know
finer salvation through literature.