VIOLENT COP
What are you doing, mister?
I'll go home.
Me, too.
Hello.
What is it?
Your son home?
Police.
Upstairs?
Excuse me.
What for?
Let us alone.
Don't worry.
Yeah?
Don't bother about me.
Give yourself up tomorrow.
What did I do?
I did nothing.
Nothing?
Then I did nothing, either.
Ass!
As your new chief,
I'd like to say this:
Police are sacred.
Keep it in mind.
Be proud of your job.
Have self- respect...
Azuma.
The kid gave himself up.
But you should've caught
him in the act last night.
Azuma.
Our new boss wants you.
I'm Kikuchi, the rookie.
You saw it?
Coincidence.
You kept silent?
What could I do?
Nothing but breaking in his house
and forcing him to talk?
I'd like that, but
behave yourself for a year,
while I'm chief.
I'm no fool.
I know who lives here,
and the kind of cops
we need.
You've got to be smart.
That's all.
It tires me.
Because you act wild.
Was he mad?
No.
I'll go to the hospital.
Akari?
She's going to be released.
Thanks.
If there's anything
I can do...
Come see
my wife sometimes.
Thanks.
Let me.
I'm Kikuchi, the rookie.
Coach me.
I want the document later.
A festival.
Let's go.
Did she say that?
She's a liar.
She's pregnant.
Take care of her.
So I told her not to dance.
You told me
to get an abortion.
I didn't.
Who's the father, anyway?
You. Who else?
You're a couple.
Be nice to each other.
Not a couple.
I live with her because
she begged me to.
All you want is my money.
Why else would
anyone lay you?
Don't be mean to her.
Why did you send
for me, anyway?
Why don't you go bugger
a thief instead?
What's that?
What's what?
A gigolo must take
care of his girl.
Or work yourself.
Let her go, but not him.
Drink?
No.
How's Akari?
It's like you had
your own daughter.
I'll have mine soon.
Where to?
Home.
I'll walk you home.
Care for a drink?
What'll it be?
Anything.
Two Wild Turkeys.
You come here often?
Sometimes.
How's business?
So-so.
Your pal?
Name's Azuma.
What do you do?
We sell guns.
Guns?!
Welcome.
Dope?
Money first.
Why don't you give me
a little discount?
Why?
We can't keep this
business forever.
After all, it's us
who take risks.
Then go to someone else.
That's a good idea, but...
Kiyohiro.
Let me make a profit.
I know where you get it.
Safe and sound.
Police?
Exactly.
Then, no other way.
Don't ask for
too much, punk.
You must know your limit.
Kikuchi, lend me money.
5,000 yen?
Good.
A bet?
No! Gambling is a crime.
No.
This one's no good.
How is it?
Your machines never
let me win.
They do.
No. Few customers.
Usually the house is full.
Where are they?
What're you doing?
No bets.
You know how to play?
No. Sorry.
I'll give you back
what you lost.
No! It can send me to jail.
Give it to him.
No! I can't take it!
You aren't doing funny
business anymore, are you?
"Funny?"
Backdoor.
No more gun-smuggling.
This, at best.
Azuma.
Never mind.
Which way?
Tell him.
I can't.
Follow that prowl car.
Azuma. So soon!
I did it.
Azuma, the cab fare.
I'm broke.
Will you pay him off?
Carry money.
Kikuchi, it's 1,760 yen.
Azuma, it's 1,760 yen.
He was stabbed
with a knife.
He was convicted for dope.
A pusher?
Yes. I'll ask the man
who found his body.
Mori.
Kikuchi.
Help them.
Honma.
Give me a loan.
Welcome home.
Who's there?
A friend of mine.
Coffee?
No.
Akari, which way is
the nearest station?
Bus?
Never mind.
Come.
No thanks.
By bus?
No. I'll take a taxi.
Bus.
Taxi.
Don't bother about me.
Name?
Mine?
Say your name.
Yamada.
Where from?
Chiba.
To lay my sister?
No. I work around here.
Where?
Shinagawa Machinery.
Since when?
Yesterday.
Where did you pick her up?
A discotheque.
Damn punk!
Will you marry her?
Get a go-between.
Go-between?
Engagement first.
You won't dump her?
No.
Wait! Sorry.
We won't use it.
Maybe we will.
It happened before.
It was a round-up. Your
bullet hit a neighbor's kid.
I aimed to.
I've been wondering...
How come you became a cop?
Scouted.
Come on!
Sorry.
Hello.
A cop and a greenhorn.
A cop and what?
A greenhorn.
What do you mean?
The greenhorn.
He meant me.
Of course.
You and who else?
Cut it out.
Look over there.
His woman called us.
The murdered
dope- pusher's customer.
Let's go.
Come on.
I'll stay here.
Dangerous.
No smoking.
Him?
Who?
That's what I meant.
Azuma! He got away!
A cop needs an ambulance!
Send an ambulance!
It's an accident!
Emergency!
Come!
Go quick!
No beeping.
Don't tell him
where we are.
Sorry.
He's gone.
You can't find him here.
Turn.
Would a criminal run here?
Sorry.
Find an alley and go in.
Turn right.
One way.
Never mind. Turn!
Stop!
Turn when I say "Turn."
It's an emergency.
You must listen to me.
Who said to come here?
He's gone.
There!
Go get him!
Let me drive.
One way.
This way.
There!
I know.
You're going to
run over him.
Why did you hit him?
He might be dead.
Does he look dead
to you, stupid?
Go back.
Did you have to
run over him?
Write an apology.
How?
The usual.
Did you write an apology?
Yes, in your name.
Oh, no!
Alone?
Drugs?
What kind?
Special.
A bargain.
How much?
Let's talk in the toilet.
Let's go.
I hear you have a sister.
Yes.
She was in a hospital.
What was wrong?
Her head.
Not again!
Stay there.
Hashizume!
Yes.
What is it?
You tell me. What is it?
What's that?
Dope. You're pushing it,
aren't you?
No.
He had it.
You still push dope?
I told you not to.
Stop acting, punk.
Emoto died.
So what?
I don't know.
Who sells you the stuff?
Who?
Go home.
You know who.
Iwaki, your pal.
What did he do?
He sells it.
You, too?
No arrest?
No.
He meant lwaki of
the vice squad?
Did he talk?
So?
Thanks.
Dope?
What?
Stop acting.
We'll sell it and run.
What?
What are you saying?
Don't give me that.
Why are you here?
Dope!
What can punks
like you do?
Go ahead. Try.
Nito will kill you.
A cop named Azuma is
checking on you.
Azuma.
Come.
You can fish here.
Did you have fun?
No. I stayed home.
Feel better?
This is not the sea.
What do you want?
Iwaki's your old friend?
I think so.
Has he changed lately?
Why?
The press wants to know
about him.
I must do something.
Why not ask him?
He lost contact.
Not at home. He's missing.
Do you know?
No, I don't.
Nothing's definite.
Don't worry. I'm all right.
Thanks.
I'm sorry to have
troubled you, Azuma.
Any message?
No.
I don't know.
I can't read papers.
What's he doing?
He should call me.
May I ask you a question?
Was it suicide?
You were his best
friend, weren't you?
I'll go home.
Brother.
Hello.
Let's go home.
No?
No.
Maybe there.
Up there. That one.
"Narcotics."
Let's find them.
Wait.
Ryuji, come here.
You know him?
The guy hurt in the
toilet-- his pal.
His address?
We don't know.
No news?
Nothing.
No?
Thanks.
I haven't seen him lately.
His address?
I don't know.
Somewhere around here.
If he comes again, call us.
I think I saw him.
Criminal?
No, not that.
He's a dick.
Have you seen this guy?
No.
He was around here.
If you see him, call us.
He's here.
Sir?
I told you to kill only
Emoto and lwaki.
Didn't I?
Yes, sir.
Why did you
kill Hashizume?
Don't act unless ordered.
Yes, sir.
You may go.
Shinkai, do we have anybody
who can take care of him?
Was he here?
I don't know.
I'm new here.
You asked for it.
Hashizume was killed.
By whom?
Kiyohiro.
No one else.
Kiyohiro? What is he?
Nito's henchman.
Did he kill lwaki, too?
He's crazy.
He'll do anything for Nito.
Nito told him to kill?
Not only that.
He likes killing.
You'll be next.
Only after you, idiot.
I'm Nito.
Won't you come in?
A restaurant with
dope-pushers and killers?
Pardon?
You know what I mean.
Kiyohiro?
Kiyohiro? Who is he?
Your assassin.
If you want to question me,
get a warrant first.
Our gift.
I'm afraid it doesn't
become your tie.
I'll return your favor.
Come for dinner next time.
Use the backdoor.
Arrest?
So you tailed me?
Bedroom.
Good taste.
Dope?
Do I have dope?
Where?
Here.
Shame on you!
Get dressed.
What're you doing?
Nothing.
Who's in there?
That's a dirty trick.
It won't work on me.
You killed lwaki?
He killed himself.
Then, kill yourself.
If you want to
kill me, go ahead.
Aim at me.
You're nuts
like your sister.
You're fired!
You framed him,
Iocked him up, and
tortured him.
That's enough.
You're fired.
You even shot at him.
You're wild! Stupid!
Write your resignation!
Now!
If you make more trouble,
I'll be finished.
You should get the ax,
but I'll save your honor.
Just quit the force.
Consider what you've done.
Your investigation is
useless. Iwaki killed himself.
Give her a thrill. You're
not screwing a Dutch wife.
It's her fault.
She doesn't move.
She's keeping cool.
Where did he find her?
A bakery.
Who knows?
Why don't you let me do it?
You know how
to screw a girl?
I'm bi, you know.
She needs a shot.
Don't waste it on her.
Give it to me.
You took too much junk
and went goofy.
What? How mean!
This stuff is expensive.
No! Let go of me!
Hold him.
Water?
Junk is too good for you.
I'm not your woman. Why?
She's dumb.
We wasted a shot on her.
You attacked
the detective?
Why?
He's on your tail.
Someday he'll finish you.
It's you who's
going to finish me.
How can I save your ass?
How can you?
I want to kill you.
Never see me again.
An ex-cop wanting
an illegal gun?
Here's one.
What for?
Never mind.
Let's be friends.
You suspect me,
but you're wrong.
I'm innocent.
He's nuts. We're through.
Please! Give me a shot!
Beat it!
Her brother's coming.
He'll kill you.
You raped her. Don't run.
If you do, I'll kill you.
Either way, you're
going to die.
No kidding!
Dope...
Everybody's crazy.
You replace Iwaki?
I'm much smarter.
Produced by
KAZUYOSHI OKUYAMA
Screenplay by
HISASHI NOZAWA
Music by
DAISAKU KUME
Photographed by
YASUSHI SASAKIBARA
English Subtitles by
TADASHI SHISHIDO
Starring
TAKESHI
ITTOKU KISHIBE
MIKIKO OTONASHI
TAKESHI HIRAIZUMI
SHIRO SANO
MAIKO KAWAKAMI
HAKURYU
Directed by
TAKESHI KITANO