<THE VIRGIN STRIPPED BARE
BY HER BACHELORS>
You'll have to wait outside.
Will it be long?
/I'm almost done.
Okay.
Hello?
It's me.
Soojung.
Where are you?
I just got up.
You mean just now?
I'm not feeling very well.
Where are you?
I'm already here.
Are you sick?
I'm sorry.
Can't we do this another time?
Soojung. ..
Soojung, you know this wasn't easy.
If you're not really sick, please come.
Do we really have to do it today?
Of course.
Soojung, You're making
things really difficult.
Where are you?
In the hotel?
Yes.
I'm in the room.
What number?
Room 308.
Grab a taxi. I'll wait.
-The 3rd Painting Exhibition-
-Growrich Gallery-
Interesting? Not much, yes?
I liked it.
Not interesting at all.
I thought it was fun.
We're right in front of
Kyongbokgoong Palace.
Our palaces are quite small.
Shall we go?
Where to?
How about lunch?
Did we eat?
Didn't we?
You can't remember
whether you had lunch or not?
Anyway, let's have something.
Let's go.
You should start painting again.
What?
And what about you?
I have a studio
and I go there once a week.
And your brother,
why doesn't he trust you?
He thinks there's only one way
to live, just his way.
Nobody can get through to him.
I think I know what you mean.
No, you don't, Youngsoo.
No one can get through to him.
Even though you know he's wrong,
it's no use, no use.
I know what you mean.
Excuse me, the toilet.
What's the matter?
It's probably his stomach.
Are you two close?
I've known him for about 5 years.
We don't get together often
but we're fond of each other.
He's a very gentle person, this kid.
The way you talk about him,
you seem very close.
What did I say?
I've never seen you be nice
to someone for this long.
What are you trying to say?
What is her name?
/Soojung.
Her last name?
/Yang.
Can you please move?
We're shooting here.
Thank you.
Hello. What a coincidence!
Hello.
You must be here with the crew.
Yes.
Can I see those gloves?
These gloves?
These gloves are really mine.
How did you get them?
These gloves are yours?
I found them on that bench.
I came back but. ..
I didn't think I would find them . ..
I must have left them
on the bench during lunch.
Well, how lucky.
I can't believe that you, Soojung,
brought them to me.
You remember my name.
Of course. Do you remember
my name by any chance?
Yes, of course.
I have a pretty good memory.
I have good memory, too.
Well, I have to go.
It was nice meeting you again.
/It was nice meeting you, too.
Oh, I'm seeing Youngsoo later on.
I see.
Well, so long.
/Good-bye.
And thank you for the gloves.
/That's alright.
The independent way is the way
to make the best films.
The industry way isn't right for me.
I'm ready to struggle.
Then I can help out.
Yes, of course.
But this is a bit embarrassing
for me to talk about, isn't it?
You shouldn't be.
It would be good if you could help.
It would be great if I help out, right?
Can you really?
Just direct as well as
you paint, okay?
It'll be great for me, too.
Is this codfish?
No way. Codfish wouldn't
be this cheap.
But isn't this place called Cod house?
This is crayfish.
I have to go to the bathroom.
Codfish isn't so cheap.
New chopsticks, please!
They're right here.
Oh, there they are.
Where did you get
the chopsticks before?
From there.
Let me pour for you.
Do you drink a lot?
/What?
Drinking. ..do you drink a lot?
Yes.
I used to drink up to 5 bottles of soju,
and 3 bottles of whiskey.
Really? You drink that much?
Not anymore.
Youngsoo, are you okay?
Are you going to Sadang-dong?
Youngsoo, get in.
Be careful.
Are you alright?
To Sadang-dong, please.
/Soojung, will you be alright?
I'll take you home.
I'm okay.
Please go.
/I'll take you home.
You are an odd one, aren't you?
I'll show you something funny.
Come.
What is it?
I know it's really cold,
but it'll be fun.
What is it I'll enjoy?
There's this strange guy
who lives with this girl. ..it's really funny.
Come on.
They're not here.
You're really funny.
Soojung. ..
Stop! Stop it!
I'm sorry.
Are you hurt?
No. ..
I don't know how you think
about me, but I would really
like to start a serious relationship.
But, we don't know each other well.
I'm really serious.
I'm not just saying this.
If you can trust me, maybe you
could start a relationship with me.
I'm asking for the last time.
No.
I see.
Then, I should apologize.
I'm sorry. Please forgive me.
I will.
Thank you.
I'll return this right after
I'm back from location scouting.
Sure.
Are you sure I can borrow this?
Of course.
/Very nice. ..
I should get one of these.
They're not available in Korea.
I bought this in Japan.
You go to Japan, right Youngsoo?
Why would I go to Japan?
Hey, Park!
If you're not going to shoot,
why did we have to come so early
in the morning and wait?
If you think editing will take
more time, you should have
at least given us a call.
We've been here waiting
from the break of done.
I thought the editing
would be over by then.
We have to leave early if we want
to save a day. You should know that.
You always end up spending
3 days to edit, and you know it.
And you still make us come
so bloody early in the morning.
Come on, tell me when you've
taken less than 3 days, huh?
Okay.
At least, buy us some lunch.
The crew have been
waiting all day, you know.
Let's do it next time.
I have visitors today.
It's 1 6 to 9.
It's my serve.
Oh, don't we have to check
on the staff before they leave?
Okay. We can do that now.
Let's quit playing.
You're good. Why did
you say you're not good?
I'm not good.
This isn't funny.
Why do you say you're
not good when you are?
Hello?
/Hello, is this Park?
Oh, Kwon. You didn't
come back so I left.
I told your assistant before I left. ..
I don't want to hear any of that.
So, are you coming tomorrow, or not?
I waited the whole day today.
Besides, something's come up
and I'm out of town tomorrow.
I don't care what your plans are.
Are you coming tomorrow, or not?
We're shooting tomorrow.
Are you gonna be here, or not?
What about Driver Kim?
/Why should he come?
He's the boss' driver, not the driver
for the crew. Why would he come?
You're really not up to this job.
Why don't you just quit?
Okay. You're fired. Now you won't
have to come tomorrow. Satisfied?
What? You, son of a bitch.
What's that? Bastard.
You better not move an inch.
Stay right there, you bastard.
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
You know how it is.
We're always behind schedule.
So I was a bit tense, and I said
some things I shouldn't have.
I'm really sorry.
Let's shake hands and make up.
I'm sorry.
/We don't have to shake hands. ..
I'm really sorry, Park.
My mistake. I shouldn't have.
Come on. Give me your hand.
Is everything okay?
Are you okay?
You know, one can't do
everything one wants in life.
This is pretty heavy.
You carry the camera in your pocket?
I just put it in here a while ago.
How did it go with Park?
Well, you know. ..I was too thoughtless.
It's his job we're talking about.
It was my temper,
but it was my mistake. My fault.
So is he coming tomorrow?
Oh, I forgot about that.
By the way, Youngsoo,
it only takes 30 minutes to recharge.
To Sadang-dong!
To Sungbook-dong.
Yeah, you go.
Soojung, get in. I'll drop you off.
Me? No, I'm fine.
It's the opposite direction.
It's okay. It'll only be
a slight detour.
Bye Youngsoo.
Get in.
Bye.
Bye, Youngsoo.
How about if I be your girlfriend
only when you drink?
Would you?
I liked that.
Did you like it?
I'll show you something.
When I was young,
I used to stick my head out.
Back then, my parents and
I drove to the airport almost everyday.
On the way to the airport,
my brother and I used to fool around. ..
Our car was a foreign car, too.
I guess we were well off, back then.
Please, make yourself at home.
Would you like something to drink?
/No thank you.
Are you sure?
/Yes.
Excuse me while I take a shower.
Would you like to take a shower?
No, thank you.
Just a second.
This is my first time.
What?
I've never done this before.
Really?
Yes. I've never done this before.
I'm a virgin.
Quite funny, isn't it?
/No.
Not at all.
Isn't it funny?
You don't like to wear a bra?
I don't like to in the winter,
because it's uncomfortable.
I see. I guess in the winter,
it doesn't show.
Excuse me.
Can I get you anything else?
I think we're okay.
So it seems you come often these days.
That's your car out there, right?
Yes.
It's a very nice car.
Well. Have a nice time.
It's just a fork.
I would if I had a girlfriend.
I think you're being too picky.
Yeah, you're too picky.
It's not easy.
What's not easy?
Well, you know.
I thought you were the simple type,
but I guess not.
I guess I'm kind of chicken.
I think it's in our family blood.
Then how did your older brother manage?
He and my sister-in-law go way back.
They met when she was in high school.
They went to the same church,
and when she was in high school,
he decided that she's the one.
So we can say that he raised
a child, then gobbled her up.
What?
Well, I think it's fate and. ..
/I'll take her. Come on.
I think she might have been offended.
What do you mean?
She also met her husband
when she was in high school, remember?
Oh, right.
And I said that he raised a child,
then gobbled her up.
She must really be offended.
Oh, no.
Anyway, happy birthday.
Thanks for coming.
Come on. We're in public.
To be frank, the type of woman
that's attracted to you,
would probably be half crazy or decadent.
But, what you need is a woman
that's disciplined and secure.
That's why it is very hard
to find a right woman for you.
That's enough.
No. I mean it. See, you wife here. ..
Someone's at the door.
I'll get it.
/Okay.
Long time no see.
Jaehoon, you're here.
Hi.
The numbers of the apartment
buildings are so mixed up.
Come in. Come in.
She's a writer and works with me.
Hello.
Come on in.
How come it's so dark?
Where are the lights?
/In the back.
Please sit down.
I've brought some baked sweet potatoes.
/Thank you.
So, it seems you've had
quite a few drinks, already.
How have you been?
/Fine.
What about dinner?
/This will do.
Can you hand me the chopsticks.
/Try some of this.
Youngsoo, how's your movie
coming along? Going well?
Fuck.
Why do you always have to
call me by my name, Youngsoo,
when you never call their names
when you talk to them?
Have you ever really cared about me?
Soojung, come here.
Come over here.
Move over, damn it.
Come on. Get over here.
Pour a drink for your boss,
the producer. Come on.
Youngsoo!
/I'm just kidding.
Get away.
Soojung. Loosen up.
Just enjoy yourself.
You don't have to act so innocent.
Drink up. Go with the flow.
Drink up. Drink up. Drink up.
Are you saying I didn't drink?
I did drink a lot.
You did?
Okay, then I'll drink this.
This is for me?
He's a thief. How can he steal
his own friend's camera?
You don't know if he stole it?
He said he lost it.
What do you mean he lost it?
It's so obvious. Just because
there's no proof, we can't
just forget about it.
It's not obvious.
How funny. How really funny.
Soojung, so are you saying
that he's not a thief?
We don't know. How can you. .. okay.
Producer Kwon made a mistake.
He drank too much tonight,
and he was out of line.
Let's just leave it at that.
Are you saying that I'm accusing
a completely innocent person?
I'm not talking about him
being drunk tonight.
I'm talking about his integrity.
His integrity. You know!
He was out of line
because he doesn't know about us.
Him not knowing has
nothing to do with it.
What about him touching you,
like your legs?
Is that also because
he didn't know about us?
Stop it!
We didn't tell him,
so it's our fault, too.
Funny. Very funny.
An innocent mistake
because he didn't know, huh!
Soojung, are you in love
with him or something?
How very funny, mister!
Was it so wrong for me to ask you
to keep our relationship a secret?
Were you that offended?
How can you not know
how I feel about you?
Okay.
No, its not okay.
I don't want our relationship
to be taken as a fling.
I don't want other people
gossiping about us, either.
Or him staring at us with
a knowing eye.
This is really important to me.
You know? Our relationship is.
Alright, okay.
Let's just keep it between us.
Soojung, you don't know
what I really want.
I really want our relationship
to be really meaningful.
I've never felt like this before.
I was even considering marriage.
Even marriage. ..
How can you not know how I feel?
Me, to consider marriage.
Do you know how hard it is for me
to consider marriage?
For me to consider. ..
/Don't make it difficult, then.
Make your life easier.
Let's stop seeing each other, then.
Why should we see each other
if it has to be so difficult?
Am I wrong?
Soojung! Come here.
Come here.
Enjoy your meal.
Can I see you today?
I have to go somewhere today.
I see.
How are you?
Okay.
Are you going somewhere far?
No. A friend has just moved to Ansan,
and invited some friends.
Ansan?
Where's Ansan?
It's close if you take the subway.
She moved to Kojan,
which is right before Ansan.
Kojan?
Do you know how to get to Kojan?
Look for yourself.
You look very nice in a skirt.
What is this?
Beethoven's 6th symphony, "Pastoral".
Oh, and thanks for this CD player.
Not at all. Do you like it?
My mother asked me who gave this to me.
Is that so?
I told her it was a gift,
and she said it must be
from someone who's very generous.
Is that so?
Is that how you hold your chopsticks?
Why?
You're supposed to hold one still
so it doesn't move.
Then, hold the other one
at the end of the three fingers.
Like this?
You move them back and
forth with these two fingers.
Very good.
If you're not used to it yet,
just do it your way, for now.
I should correct
something if it's wrong.
No.
/Why not?
Let's do it next time.
Again?
I'm really getting tired of this.
Let's do it next time.
Next time, when?
This is all you want to do.
You got my breasts, didn't you?
I really want to do it.
Let's do it next time.
Not today.
I'm having my period.
Period?
It doesn't matter. I don't mind.
I do!
Let's do it when I'm clean.
Are you really having your period?
Of course.
Show me, then.
/It's true!
Let's go somewhere nice.
How about Cheju Island?
Yes. Let's go to Cheju Island.
Okay. Let's do it in the most
expensive room in Cheju Island.
Look at that grin.
Soojung. ..
I love you.
I love you, too.
It's me.
Soojung?
Where are you?
At home.
I just got up.
You mean just now?
I think I'm sick.
Where are you?
I'm here at the hotel.
Are you sick?
No. It's just that
I'm not feeling very well.
Hello?
It's Soojung.
What are you doing?
Can you talk on the phone right now?
Where are you?
Myong-dong.
What are you doing there?
Do you think you can come?
Let me see. Not today.
The whole family is getting
together at my mother's.
I see. Well, then okay. ..
Is something wrong?
Well. Then, so long.
Do you want me to call later tonight?
No, that's okay.
You should be with your family.
Alright, then.
Calling control room.
Control room. Control room.
The cable car has been suspended
because of a power outage.
Tell the passengers
so they don't panic.
Alright. When will it work again?
We're calling the power utilities
now so bear with us for a while.
We'll use the emergency engine
if it takes too long.
I think the baby had a scare.
/Yes. I think so.
Sorry, but can you hold her for me.
Okay, see you later.
Bye!
Come here.
My baby. Sweet heart.
Let's go.
/My baby.
What's that?
Did you eat?
No.
Let's go see some paintings.
What's the matter?
Paintings?
You mean a painting exhibit?
Yeah.
Now?
Let's go.
I'll buy you a drink.
We're right in front of
Kyongbokgoong Palace.
Our palaces are quite small.
Why should it be bigger?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Kim, you can leave early today.
We're going to eat somewhere
here, so I won't need a ride.
No, sir. I'll wait.
I'll be waiting here, sir.
You will?
Then get something to eat.
Yes, sir.
Shall we go?
Okay.
/Let's go this way.
Then why don't you move
out of your brother's house.
Get your own place.
Youngsoo, I respect my brother.
He's a good person.
There's a lot to learn from him,
in a practical way.
Excuse me. ..
I have to go to the toilet.
I guess he had too much to drink.
Do you drink a lot?
Excuse me?
Drinking. .. do you drink a lot?
Yes. I used to drink up to 5 bottles
of soju, and 3 bottles of whiskey.
Really? You drink that much?
These days I can't handle that much.
Soojung, are you sleeping?
Are you sleeping?
Soojung, wake up.
Do you know what time it is?
Don't you get any sleep?
Just once.
Not now. I'm tired.
Just once, please?
Try to control yourself.
Don't you have any self control?
I'll be quick, please?
Hurry up, then.
Slow down.
Gently. ..
Where are we going?
How about Kyongbokgoong Palace?
Do you know how far that is?
Let's go to Yongsan Park.
It's close by.
We've used Yongsan Park too many times.
Isn't there some other place?
Then, let's go to the riverside.
We won't find any people there
at this time of day.
Let's go to Kyongbokgoong Palace.
We'll find people there.
I'm Youngsoo's. ..
Hello.
Soojung, what brought you here?
You remember my name.
I'm here with the crew.
I see.
You must come here often
since you're right across the street.
Yes, I think I told you that I come here
almost everyday for lunch.
Are these yours by any chance?
Let me see.
Really! They're mine.
/They are? This is incredible.
I found them on that bench,
and wondered whether they were yours.
Really, what a coincidence.
These are really yours, right?
/Yes.
This is so funny.
Don't lose them again, okay?
Thank you.
How much?
1 0,000 won.
We had one portion of ribs
and Makgulli.
/1 0,000 won.
I was late. I joined the group later.
Okay, 8000won.
/How many?
Four.
Any minors or not?
/None.
Then come inside.
/Thank you. Bye.
Something's got into her.
She's drinking a lot tonight.
I'm a strong drinker, you know.
Then we should drink up.
Then give me a big smile.
What?
Oh, I said give me a big smile.
What am I supposed to be?
/Just give him a big smile.
A big smile.
What's blood?
What?
I said what's your blood?
Blood?
He's talking about your
blood type, blood type.
um, B type.
/I'm A type.
What's B type supposed to be like?
Well, it's not that.
I just wanted to ask.
I should have told you.
He can be a bit muggy. ..
I have to go to the toilet.
Some napkins please!
It's okay.
You're wet.
Napkins!
There are some napkins here.
I'm not that wet.
Thanks for the gloves.
Right after this movement,
attach this.
Should I connect them?
/Yeah, next.
How many do we have left?
I think two.
Are there any more down there?
No.
Then, two.
What?
Don't you have a lot of women?
What women?
Is it because of sex?
This kiss, I mean.
How do I get into the office?
What office?
Oh, Unicom Seoul.
Can't you see it's right over there.
Over there.
I've tried touching.
I really like kissing.
I think kissing is nice.
But I've tried once.
He was a close friend.
We were talking about this.
So one day we decided to do it.
We weren't even drunk,
but we went to a motel.
But it didn't work.
Why not?
I don't know.
Well, it hurt so much. ..
And it didn't feel right.
Like we shouldn't be doing it.
So we stopped.
What about the guy?
Him?
He was just a good friend.
And we tried it another time.
But it still didn't work.
Director Kwon, you have a visitor.
I guess I'm late.
Oh, it's you. I have to finish up.
You want to wait?
What did you shoot?
/It's nothing.
Can you get some coffee for the guest?
No, I'm fine.
It'll only take a minute.
I'm almost done.
Hello.
/Hello.
Take off your glasses, you bastard.
Do you think that you'd be
enjoying all this if you weren't
the nephew of the owner?
Okay. That's enough.
Son of a bitch.
You bastard. You get this job just
because you're related to the boss,
And what did you stay to me?
You think people call you director
cause they respect you?
You loser.
What did you say to me? I'm fired?
/I was just. ..
You bastard.
I could kill types like you,
and nobody would give a shit.
Where's the bitch?
The fucking bitch.
You two did it, didn't you?
Bastards.
If I catch you two fooling
around in the editing room,
I swear I'm gonna kill both of
you right then and there.
To Sadang-dong!
To Sungbook-dong.
Yeah, you go.
Soojung, get in. I'll drop you off.
Are you sure? Alright, then.
Bye Youngsoo.
/Yeah, bye.
So, this is how it turns out.
Are you crying?
What's wrong?
/Nothing. I don't know why I'm crying.
What is it?
I've never kissed like this before.
I've only had crushes.
Really?
What?
Kissing?
Crushes?
Come here.
Hi.
Did you go someplace?
I had to get some medication.
Why?
I'm not gonna tell.
Why didn't you go to work today?
You weren't there yesterday, either.
Did you call the office?
Yes.
I'm gonna go back.
What kind of medication did you get?
I told you I'm not gonna tell you.
I want to suck your
whole body. Every inch.
I want to sleep with you.
Really?
Yes.
I want to do it, too.
Really?
Let's do it somewhere really nice.
Do you want to go to Cheju Island?
Yes.
It's just a spoon.
Hey, big brother, what are you doing?
Mommy made chicken.
What's this?
I ate too much.
Why are you drawing that?
Get out.
You're not making films anymore?
Kodak doesn't develop 8mm's anymore.
Then there's no use for all of this?
You can't make films anymore?
Get out.
Okay.
That's pretty.
Are you going out with Jaehoon?
Why?
Well, nothing.
Just. ..you know. ..
The assistant got the phone,
and he asked for you, not me.
I thought you two were
doing a film together.
I'm not gonna beg to him.
1 00 million won isn't
pocket money, you know.
No matter how rich you are.
Yeah, shit, he's loaded.
He's loaded,
but he isn't returning my calls.
You. .. are you two really going out?
I guess it's true since
you're changing the subject.
You can tell me. Come on.
It just happened.
It hasn't been long.
Are you alright?
It's cold.
I'll show you something.
It's really funny.
Mr. Kwon!
It's cold.
Look at me.
Look at my face.
I had a big crush on you.
You did?
Okay. I'll stop.
Really. ..
I undressed your panties, right?
I undressed your panties,
and could have, but I didn't, right?
Yes. Let's stop.
That was a scare, wasn't it?
You know you were about to rape me.
Rape?
Rape, my foot!
I should have stopped after
I took off your panties.
These are hard to take off.
Hey, what are you doing?
I'll get it. Move.
Come over here.
How do you open this?
Pull, and turn it.
Are you guys picking a lock,
for heaven sakes?
Long time no see.
Oh, Jaehoon, you're here.
Come in.
/Hi. Hi, Youngsoo.
Come in. Come in.
She's a writer and works with me.
Hi.
/Hello.
Take this.
/Thank you.
Sit down.
/How come it's so dark?
Where are the lights?
I've brought some baked
sweet potatoes.
Sit down.
/Thank you.
This is nice.
How have you been?
/Fine.
What about dinner?
This will do.
I'll pour you a glass of wine.
Can you hand me the chopsticks.
Thank you.
Soojung, how's life treating
you these days?
Are you enjoying it?
What about you Mr. Kwon.
How is it with you these days?
I'm wearing long underwear.
Shit! underwear.
You told me to quit,
that I'd be able to find another job.
That's what you said, right?
Yes.
If I quit. ..
Let's do a film together.
Together.
Then, don't quit.
That's not what you said before.
How can you say that so casually?
Soojung Yang, why should I?
I'll tell you one.
/Okay. Just a minute.
Soojung, your phone is ringing.
Guess who laughes 1 0 minutes
in the morning and cries
1 0 minutes before going to bed?
Hello?
It's me.
Jaehoon?
Yes, this is Jaehoon.
This is a surprise.
I'm here at Kojan Station.
Really?
Yes. I just came. I wanted to see you.
How did you get here?
Are you really at Kojan Station?
Yes. I didn't bring my car,
I took the subway.
I didn't know a subway ride
could be so nice.
I'm not very far from there.
Be careful.
Oh, be careful.
It's okay.
Actually it's more dangerous
if there's no cracking sound.
Then, the whole chunk of ice
can crumble in all at once.
The water would be so cold.
It's okay.
There's too much cracking.
I told you this means that it's safer.
Look at this.
It's gum wrapping paper.
It says "Kiss" gum.
Yeah, it really does.
Give me a kiss.
Thanks for coming.
Do you want to slide?
I'm heavy, you know.
Junga!
Get up.
I called the wrong name, didn't I?
Soojung, are you angry?
I'm sorry, really.
What got into me. ..?
It was just a slip of the tongue,
What? I'm not Junga now?
There aren't any taxis here,
let's try over there.
Where are you going?
There might be some taxis on
that big street. Let's go.
What do you think you're doing?
Where have you been?
I've been. ..
Do you know how worried sick I was?
Were you worried?
Do you know how I ran all over
the place like I was crazy?
Really, like I was crazy.
I really thought I would go crazy.
What is there to be so angry about. ..?
Did I commit such a major crime?
Don't shout.
/What?
You're telling me not to shout?
Do you know that I'm going
crazy because of you.
Okay, I did. ..
So I called someone else's name.
Is this as if I committed murder?
Why are you making me go crazy?
Okay. You don't have to die for it.
Are you satisfied?
Did I mean to call her name?
No, Soojung.
Right?
This is driving me crazy!
Soojung, what's
so important about a name.
Okay. It's my fault.
Soojung. ..
Is it hard to learn to play?
No.
How long would I have to
take lessons to play that?
Maybe learn up to Czerny 1 00.
Or maybe, an easier text might do.
You seem to enjoy
having the piano here.
This is the kind that
Stevie Wonder plays.
Stevie Wonder plays this piano?
It gets recorded inside.
Automatically?
What are you doing?
Are we going or not?
/We're going.
Let's go then.
Hello?
/Hello?
Jaehoon?
Oh, you answered.
Nobody else is here.
Why is your cell phone turned off?
The batteries are dead.
Oh, I see.
You know, about our date. ..
Yes. Why?
Can we postpone to tomorrow?
Tomorrow? How can we go to
Cheju Island in just one day?
Well, not Cheju, we can do
that some other time.
Let's meet in Wooie-dong.
I know a quiet and nice hotel there.
Why?
Just. ..
I just want to.
Tomorrow's a Sunday, right?
Yes, and that's also another reason.
You don't want to?
Do we have to go all the way
to Cheju Island?
Do you think I'm obsessed
with Cheju Island, or something?
Soojung?
Okay. Let's meet tomorrow.
Is that okay? Great.
Yes.
1 6 to 1 0
<NAUGHT SHALL GO ILL
WHEN YOU FIND YOUR MARE>
You're here.
Come in.
So, is this the room?
Open them like this.
This side, too.
And bend you knees.
Hold still.
It hurts.
I'll make sure it doesn't hurt.
Really, it won't hurt.
Don't move.
Relax.
Relax your body.
Really, I'll make sure
it doesn't hurt, I promise.
It really hurts!
Just a little more.
A little more.
A little more. Hold still.
It hurts!
That's it.
Ow! It hurts!
I'll be gentle.
Very very gentle.
This is Soojung, right?
Yes. It's me, Soojung.
What should we do?
Really.
Is it supposed to be so much?
I don't know.
It is a lot.
What should we do?
Should we take it with us?
Do you want to?
What should we do?
You have to use cold water.
Really?
Why go to all that trouble?
What?
Why don't you just take it
home with you, then?
I thought you didn't want me to.
You don't like me washing
out your blood?
We can't just leave
our trace like this.
Do you want me to stop?
No.
Go on.
I want to take it with me.
But don't you think that's
being too superstitious.
Okay. I'll do it.
Come here.
Are you hungry?
A little.
You've lost blood,
so we should eat some red meat.
What?
Are you a good cook?
I don't know.
I'm not good at anything,
so you take care of it.
Really?
What should we do?
Do what?
I'm so happy and tingly that I don't
care if I'm not making any sense.
You really don't mind
me not being good?
I don't mind.
You're my. .. I've found my other pair,
so I really have no problem.
Me neither.
I will correct all the faults I have.
I swear on my life that I will.
I promise, Soojung.