(click)
(microphone thumping)
WOMAN:
At the end of high school,
I fell in love with
a substitute English teacher.
It was quite a scandal.
Corin didn't start out
a bad guy though.
We were together
about 10 years
and we had two kids.
And then he fell in love
with someone in a Starbucks
and moved to
Palo Alto, California.
Kind of severed relations
with the three of us.
My parents,
if I were defending them,
which I'm not,
had said back in the day
that he had an "impatient eye."
They didn't like him.
Week I left,
things... escalated.
My parents cursed at me,
which was, like, crazy unusual.
And it ended one afternoon
very badly.
I left at 19.
Haven't spoken
to my parents
in 15 years.
Whatever.
That's just the history.
Recently, my parents
looked me up on the Internet.
Asked to meet
their grandchildren.
Spend a week with them.
I looked my parents up.
They have a counseling Web site.
(chuckles)
People love 'em.
Ironically,
they counsel people,
which is a hoot.
Whatever.
I told the kids.
They said they wanted to go.
I told them I didn't
want them to go. They said
they were gonna go anyway.
They're brats.
What can I tell you?
And my 15-year-old
wants to make a documentary
about this.
GIRL:
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Go back.
Describe the events
on the day you left
your parents' farm at 19.
I did something
I don't choose to tell you.
If they choose to tell you,
that's their right. Okay?
GIRL:
I wanna do this
for you.
MOM:
Listen, they're good people.
Ask them.
Can I be done with my part?
I still gotta
get you guys packed.
떰 (speakers:
chorus vocalizing)
I'm on the text
with two separate girls.
It's important
you put the word
"separate" in there,
in case we thought
they were conjoined twins.
MOM:
Explain "on the text."
GIRL:
In communication.
Nothing more.
No, they're on deck.
You are 13!
There's no deck to be on.
GIRL:
I've seen him in the shower.
That's eerily accurate.
You don't even
have boobs!
Stop, both of you!
I need to text.
(laughs)
It's one week.
Your phones won't work
all the way out there.
You'll be home Saturday.
GIRL:
Are you holding
my camera properly?
Swerve, girl.
Okay?
Oh.
(bell tolling)
(track bell ringing)
(no audible dialogue)
GIRL:
Our mother, Loretta Jamison,
is dating an eligible
and rather rakish-looking man
named Miguel Diego Torres.
He's in love with her.
We've decided
to promote this union
by giving them time.
They're going on a trip.
Mm-hmm.
A Royal Caribbean cruise.
Your basic beach cruise.
We're visiting
our grandparents,
whom we have never seen.
We don't know
their temperament
or their proclivities.
Yeah.
And we don't even know
what they like.
They--
They could be scrapbookers.
They could think
boy bands are cute.
- Ticket?
- GIRL:
Two for Masonville, PA.
Our grandparents
are meeting us.
You a, uh, film prodigy?
You know, I used to be
a pretty good actor.
GIRL:
Oh, my, uh--
my camera light's blinking.
"I am disgraced, impeached
and baffled here."
Battery pack is low.
"Pierced to the soul with
slander's venomed spear--"
Unfortunately,
I'm just gonna have to
shut the camera off.
(microphone rumbling)
(door closes)
Since our father left,
my-- my brother's had
a preoccupation with germs.
The psychologist
we saw for a month said it was
his way of controlling things.
(door opens)
떰 (imitating beats)
(rapping)
Girl, I'm chillin' again
I'm feelin' again
I'm like Iron Man
and Batman
I'm a hero again
Oh
You think I'm little,
but last month I grew
an inch and a quarter again
You think you're
too good for me,
but that's really a joke
'Cause, see,
that doesn't bother me
'Cause I'm not
a sensitive bloke, oh
Now, in the end,
you'll be in my bed,
we won't be just friends
You'll write
inappropriate texts
and hit "send"
We share a Starbucks
Frappuccino blend, oh
And see, this isn't
just philosophy
It's based on science,
you see
Mr. Singh, my pediatrician,
just confirmed for me
You tall skanks,
I'm going through puberty
Ho 떰
Ooh!
Whoo!
Pound.
Whoa.
Maybe I can rap at the end
of your documentary.
GIRL:
Right.
Because that's how
all Oscar-winning
documentaries end--
with songs of misogyny.
GIRL:
This is where
our mom grew up.
When she left,
she thought she was with
the man of her dreams.
(bell tolling)
WOMAN (laughing):
Oh!
Hi.
(laughs)
MAN:
Becca, right?
Yeah?
BECCA:
Oh!
This is
Marja Bella Jamison.
Uh, my-- my nana.
She's a good cook.
And, uh, we--
we have the same eyes.
And this is Fredrick
Spencer Jamison.
My-- My Pop Pop.
He's a farmer now,
but they also volunteer
as counselors.
BECCA:
How do you feel about
your new grandparents, Tyler?
It's all good.
I mean, they don't even know
who One Direction is, so--
Nana, d-did you
make these pretzels?
Yes, I did.
(Pop Pop laughing)
NANA:
Thank you so much.
(kisses)
Yes.
NANA:
Here we are.
(car doors
opening, closing)
(Pop Pop sighs)
BECCA: Tyler, look!
It's Mom's tree swing.
Okay, on camera,
tell us what Mom told you.
She used to wait out here
on this when her friends
would come over.
BECCA: This is
the perfect cinematic image
to open the documentary.
Go near it.
Wait!
Wait, don't touch it.
Just let it
organically swing.
(hinge creaking)
BECCA:
We're entering the home
that Mom grew up in.
(Nana, Pop Pop
talking, faint)
Look!
There's the clock
that she told us about.
(ticking)
Do you play sports?
I don't like sports.
He used to.
What do you do?
Why are your pants
so low?
I rap.
It's a form
of modern poetry.
If you give him a topic,
he'll extemporaneously
rhyme on the subject.
His stage nom de plume
is "T-Diamond Stylus."
Go ahead.
Nana, give him anything.
Is food okay?
I like food.
Yeah.
Of course.
How about...
pineapple
upside-down cake?
Yeah.
Sure. Why not?
Okay.
(chuckles)
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Got it.
The girls, they like me
They think I'm sweet
like candy
One girl looked at me
like I was a Hershey... bar
Her name was Angie
And a few tall girls,
they just looked at me
blankly
So here's the thing
you gotta understand
about me
I got more rhymes
than a beehive has bees
So it didn't surprise,
confuse or make me say
"For heaven's sake"
When a Hawaiian girl
with a balance disorder said
"You remind me of a pineapple
upside-down cake"
Ho! 떰
POP POP:
Whoa!
(both laughing)
Yes, sir!
Yeah?
BECCA (whispering):
Mom's room.
POP POP:
It's not fancy.
I call the main bed.
BECCA:
No pre-calls!
No, no, no! I got here first!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
Rock-paper-scissors?
Okay.
TOGETHER:
Rock, paper, scissors!
Shoot!
Do it again.
Rock, paper, scissors.
Shoot.
(chuckles)
Have a nice rest
all the way over there.
(Tyler sighs)
You guys are good kids.
This is gonna be a great week.
By the way,
there's mold in the basement.
We don't want you guys
to get sick. Yeah.
I-I got, like, no bars!
None.
BECCA:
Just keep unpacking.
No, don't--
don't look at the camera.
There we go.
This is so beautiful--
Stop looking at the ca--
Just unpack
like you normally would.
But I'm not here, okay?
Just be-- be--
(chuckles)
Be natural.
Is this natural enough?
BECCA:
You're such an idiot.
These are the people
in Nana and Pop Pop's life.
You have to burn them
a little.
Not too much.
Just a skosh.
NANA:
Here, chick-chick-chick.
(chickens clucking)
(Nana talking, indistinct)
So where are they now?
Outside,
by the chicken coops.
How are they?
Don't answer that.
I don't care.
Are they being nice?
Have they said anything
nasty about me?
Don't answer that.
Ugh. This is like
a divorce settlement.
They get you for one week
every 15 years,
and we try to be civil.
Mom, we talked
about this.
We made a decision. You go.
We're having a great time.
Yeah. You should go. Okay?
You won't be so grumpy
when you get back.
Oh!
(laughs)
Jacques Cousteau over here
wants to go buy swimsuits.
We're headed for the dock
in a few hours!
Hey, Miguel.
(muffled greeting)
(sighs)
I can't believe
I'm doing this!
A Walmart sales associate's
gonna be on the world's
largest cruise ship!
I hate
you spoiled brats.
TOGETHER:
We hate you too.
(laughs)
We're looking
for visual tension.
Things that pull the frame,
things that force us to imagine
what is beyond the frame.
Record only
what is happening to you
as a participant,
and we'll discuss
what mise-en-scene is
tomorrow.
So, I'm, like,
co-director now?
"B" Camera Operator
will be your official title.
This is the first camera
that Mom found
in the damaged goods bin.
Just try to be formal,
as in classicism,
moments that are--
(groaning)
TYLER:
Hi, Pop Pop!
Hi, Pop Pop.
Pop Pop!
What's in the shed, Becca?
Okay.
I've decided to use
female pop singers' names
instead of cursing
from now on.
Why?
I think it would
sound better.
Like, if I stubbed my toe,
I'd say, "Ah, Shakira!"
(sighs)
You're strange.
(door opens)
Is everything okay?
Yeah.
W-We're great, Pop Pop.
I have not seen your nana
this happy in years.
(Becca chuckles)
Becca, T-Diamond Stylus,
we're old people.
Bedtime here
is 9:30.
Yeah.
See you
in the morning.
9:30?
9:30.
Oh, my God.
(laughs)
9:30. Okay.
This is gonna be fun.
No Wi-Fi
and 9:30.
(groans)
(water running)
BECCA:
I want more cookies.
She was right about
the burnt walnuts.
So go get some.
Well, it's past 9:30.
I don't wanna wake them.
TYLER:
Just be quiet.
They're old. They--
They won't hear anything.
BECCA:
I've wanted to spend time
with you for so long, Nana.
TYLER:
Seriously, that--
that makes me wanna cry.
BECCA:
You can teach me all
of your cooking secrets.
Are you consciously aware
that that's my intention?
I hate sappy movies.
I find them torturous.
That smells so good, Nana.
I think
it looks good.
떰 (chorus vocalizing)
I've decided to use
Mom's favorite
musical soundtrack.
It's so over the top.
It'll be her presence
in the documentary.
Counterpoint
to the quiet drama.
떰 (dramatic orchestral)
This'll be
ironic scoring.
TYLER:
You're gonna be alone
your whole life, aren't you?
Like Miss Porter,
the gym teacher.
Oh, and, um--
떰 (man rapping)
By the way,
how is this helpful?
Oh, snap!
That's a little candy
for the ladies.
I can't sleep.
I need Nana's cookies.
I'm gonna turn
a personal addiction into
a positive cinematic moment.
Mom, I'm retracing the steps
of how you might have
snuck out of your room
and stole Nana's cookies.
(shrieking,
groaning)
(groaning)
(gasps)
(vomiting continues)
Tyler?
(retching,
moaning continue)
Tyler, wake up.
T-Diamond.
Nana's sick.
(retching,
moaning continue)
- And that's the camera.
- Hmm.
So, then you put the videos
on the Internet.
So I have four
freestyle videos.
One of them
has 347 hits.
You're both
so talented.
Do you know who
Tyler, the Creator is?
No.
Well, I-- I got
that kind of sound.
Mmm.
People say.
Come, Becca, darling.
Eat.
(chuckles)
(horse snorting)
BECCA:
Pop Pop.
(grunting)
(wood splitting)
Pop Pop?
(Becca gasps)
You need me?
(horse whinnies)
Your grandmother is fine.
She had a little bit
of a stomach flu last night.
Must have been
a 24-hour thing.
I-I knew it was
something like that.
She's an old lady, Becca.
She gets sick sometimes.
Yeah, of course.
BECCA:
Tyler!
Pop Pop said he'd take us
into town this afternoon
to shoot some of
Mom's old hangouts.
Tyler!
Raaar!
(screams)
You can play
hide-and-seek down here.
There's, um-- There's
lots of visual tension.
Mom's hide-and-seek place.
You better hide,
my ethnically confused friend.
One Mississippi.
Two Mississippi.
Three Mississippi.
Four Mississippi.
Five Mississippi!
Ready or not,
here I come!
I see you,
you little pudge.
I'll have to use strategy.
He's faster, but I'm--
I'm smarter, by at least
two standard deviations.
Here I come!
(screams)
(Becca panting)
(chuckles)
Right past me.
(panting)
Becca?
(growling)
Here I come, Tyler.
Here I come.
(Tyler gasping)
(Tyler screaming)
(whispers):
Tyler? Tyler?
TYLER:
Oh, my God-- Ohh! Oh!
Stop! Stop!
(high-pitched giggling)
(laughing)
I'm gonna get you.
I'm coming to get you,
Becca!
(gasps)
(Tyler groans)
(growls, laughing)
(sighs)
I'm making
chicken pot pie.
TYLER:
What the hell was that?
(gasps)
(knocking)
BECCA:
Can I help you?
Hi.
Uh, I'm Doctor Sam.
I work at the hospital where
your grandparents counsel.
You must be Becca.
Are you making a movie?
I used to be an actor
back in my day.
"Life's but
a walking shadow,
a poor player that struts
and frets his hour--"
Did you wanna talk
to Nana and Pop Pop?
Yes. Are they around?
No, th-they're
taking a walk, I think.
You just missed them.
Okay.
Well, uh, tell 'em
I stopped by.
They were supposed to
volunteer a few days ago.
I tried calling.
I just wanted to make sure
everything was okay.
I think the volunteer stuff is
getting too stressful for them,
although they won't admit it.
Oh, they're fine.
Well, glad to hear it.
Tell them there's
a lot of excitement
down at the hospital.
I, uh-- I can't wait
to tell 'em.
I know they love gossip.
I'll tell them.
Nice to meet you.
12:15 PM. Tuesday.
Tyler Jamison,
known to most ladies
as T-Diamond Stylus,
investigates
what is in the shed.
This is
an isolated farm.
People sneaking around.
Is it dead bodies?
(lock slides)
(hinge creaking)
(door closes)
(thumping)
I'm gonna go to the shed.
Ugh.
Smells like ass in here.
(flies buzzing)
I'm--
I-I'm moving closer
to the suspicious pile.
(buzzing continues)
Oh, shit!
(groaning)
Oh, goddamn it!
(groaning continues)
Ohh! Sarah McLachlan!
Tyler.
What the hell, Nana?
Your Pop Pop
has incontinence.
He hides his accidents
in the shed,
and then I think
he burns them
out in the field.
He's such a physical man,
he gets ashamed.
You must be disappointed
in your grandparents.
I'm sorry
we ruined things.
We're really trying.
I'll make you
some bread pudding.
Are we okay?
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm good,
Nana.
Good.
(door slams)
My mom's a classic
narrative character.
She says things like
"Things don't work out for me,"
and then makes it happen.
(footsteps)
She needs the elixir,
or all of her relationships
will fall apart.
TYLER:
Becca!
Pop Pop, we play this game
where you have to
point to a building,
and you have to say
who lives there
and what they secretly do.
Becca,
do that police station.
A police officer
named Jerry
works there,
but he never
comes in to work,
he never answers
the phone,
because all he
really wants to do
is be a Latin dancer.
(all laugh)
TYLER:
Ooh, okay, I'll go.
That huge brick building
back there is a sneaker factory,
and a woman named Sally
works there--
Oh, that's Maple Shade,
actually.
Yeah, M-Mom said
you guys volunteer there.
Yeah, every Tuesday
and Thursday.
They're good people.
There's just nobody there
to take care of 'em.
I have to find
my Maple Shade badge
and we'll visit.
Join us on a journey into
young Loretta Jamison's past.
This was young Loretta's
high school.
Young Loretta and her friends
used to hang out at this sign.
We will now go around
to the back
to catch a glimpse of young,
mischievous Loretta's locker
through a window.
BECCA:
Pop Pop,
was Mom a good student?
We have to go.
That fellow
keeps staring at us.
H-He's--
He's not, Pop Pop.
Damn it,
he keeps stopping.
Pop Pop?
Pretending
like he's not watching.
What are you doing?
Pop Pop, stop!
Hey.
Hey!
Stop following me.
No, no, no,
don't--
He's following me!
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
I'm not following you!
I don't know who you are!
Stop following me,
you cross-eyed--
Pop Pop! Pop Pop!
You're hurting him!
Get off me!
Hey.
What's
your problem?
Tyler.
He doesn't know you,
Pop Pop.
Oh, man.
Yeah, my mistake.
I'm fine.
I'm-I'm--
I'm sorry.
TYLER:
That was crazy.
He's as strong as a wrestler.
BECCA:
He's old.
They get confused.
Don't freak out.
Old people get paranoid.
And he's a country guy.
All he does is chop wood.
TYLER:
Hey. You still don't
want to talk about it?
(thumping, creaking)
(thumping,
creaking continue)
What is that?
(rhythmic thumping)
TYLER:
Okay, we think there's
someone outside the door.
It's 10:47.
(thumping, squealing)
Open the door, Becca.
No way.
Okay, keep recording this.
(loud thump)
Come on. Let's see
what's out there.
(thumping, scraping)
No, something's wrong.
I'm opening the door,
Becca.
I'm opening the door now,
I don't think
you should.
Here I go.
I'm gonna open the door.
Well, open it then!
Why do you keep
talking about it?
(thumping continues)
(groans)
(thumping,
scraping continues)
Jesus, Becca,
I'm blind.
Pop Pop?
I gotta tell you
the truth.
She has
a diagnosed disorder.
Apparently,
many elderly people
have it.
Why was she throwing up
like that?
Well...
sometimes
she gets it in her head
that she ate something,
and it's inside her--
(sighs)
and trying to crawl out.
It's called sundowning.
It's a kind of dementia.
It's triggered by nightfall.
BECCA:
This is real?
It's like somebody
talking in their sleep,
is how I was explained it.
It's probably best
that we just call it a rule
that you two shouldn't
come out of your room
after 9:30 PM.
Deal?
Is that a deal?
Yeah, yeah.
It's fine.
I'm sorry about this.
You must not be
happy now.
It's okay,
Pop Pop.
I'm okay.
We're just here
till Saturday.
A-Are you
going somewhere?
Yeah.
I've got to catch the train
to go to the costume party.
Pop Pop, I think you're
mixing up something.
Huh?
Oh, man.
Wh-What a--
What a bunch of
confused old fools
your grandparents
turned out to be.
It's all right.
Huh.
It's okay.
(sighs)
Don't worry about it.
Yeah.
Okay?
Okay. Yeah.
It's okay.
Right. Yeah.
NANA:
Good morning,
Cecil B. DeMille.
He was a great director.
I made you
cheddar biscuits, dear.
Was the old coot getting ready
for the costume party again?
BECCA:
Yeah, he was.
He's crazy.
I'm just doing
some chores in the barn.
I'll be in in a minute.
Something happened
to your computer.
I spilled
some biscuit batter on it.
I tried to clean it
with cleaner.
I'm sorry.
TYLER:
She's weird during the day,
and then gets
even weirder at night?
I'm telling you it's okay.
I downloaded the definition
of "sundowning."
You wouldn't understand
half the words I'm reading.
The word "YOLO" isn't in it.
It's got to do with
neurological reactions
to sunshine and moonlight.
It's literally
a chemical reaction.
"Sundown Syndrome--
a term
for disorientation,
agitation,
a general worsening
of mental symptoms
classically described
in the elderly
at dusk or nightfall."
It's normal
old-age problems.
People are scared
of old people
for no reason.
What about the computer?
The only thing messed up
is the computer camera.
There's something else
going on.
She used oven cleaner,
and now
the tiny camera on the screen
doesn't see anything.
You don't find that
odd at all?
She made a mistake.
Just come to accept
they're old people
and things
won't be as weird.
We're on the upper deck.
Miguel has entered
a hairy chest competition.
He's getting oiled.
(laughs)
It's so weird
I can't see you.
I think I can
clean it off.
Tyler,
why are you quiet?
Nana and Pop Pop
are acting strange.
Ow.
What kind of strange?
Becca,
did you hit Tyler?
No.
Kids--
Pop Pop wears diapers
and he keeps them
in an outhouse,
and Nana
walks around at night
without her clothes,
and Pop Pop
thinks strangers
are following him.
(exhales)
I knew we were gonna
have this call.
They're old, Tyler.
I've discussed this
with him.
Old people have trouble
with their bodies sometimes.
They also
aren't very self-aware.
They can get paranoid too.
- How strange are they acting?
- They haven't been mean
one second.
Nana crawled after us
under the house.
Playing hide-and-seek.
You guys played hide-and-seek
under the house?
I used to love that!
- Carrie Underwood.
- T, just bear with it
for a couple of days.
My parents
were strange back then.
Mom was a hippie.
She used to sunbathe
in the backyard
without warning back then.
I'm already
partially blind.
I used to get
so embarrassed.
They're just weird people,
honey.
What level of problem
is this?
One.
See?
I miss you guys.
[ Hooting, Cheering ]
Oh.
The hairy chest competition's
about to begin.
I can hear
the cougars clapping.
I gotta go.
Wish I could see
your faces clearer.
Hi, honey.
(water running)
Nana, could I ask you
about Mom?
(dishes clattering)
Maybe you'd be okay
to talk for a minute
in an interview?
(sighs)
Would you mind
getting inside the oven
to clean it?
I'm sorry?
I'm too big.
I can't reach back there.
The kitchen's
got to be clean.
The oven's off.
Yeah, sure.
(chuckles)
Get farther in there.
All the way in.
Okay.
I'll star in your movie.
If you could
be any animal,
what would you be?
Is there a right answer?
No. These questions
are intended
to get you loosened up.
Oh.
A grizzly bear.
(Becca laughs)
I think
we're warm.
Mom told me
that you and Pop Pop
were very much in love.
Where did you
first meet Pop Pop?
In a garden.
And what did you
think of him?
Oh, he was handsome.
He has a very strong
personality.
This is great.
Uh, we'll come back
to that.
Right now,
I want to talk about
something else.
I know it happened
a long time ago,
but what happened
on the day Mom left?
She won't tell me.
Did she do
something?
Nana?
Nana.
(whimpering)
Nana!
Don't answer
that question.
No more questions
about Loretta Jamison.
Maybe I can ask about--
I don't want to star
in your movie.
Okay.
It's Wednesday night.
Three nights left.
T-Diamond Stylus
is gonna find out
what exactly
is going on.
What are you doing?
I'm putting the camera
out tonight.
It's like we're living
with a werewolf.
You can't record her.
Swerve.
Look, I know you won't
understand this
because your brain
isn't fully developed yet,
but you can't do this.
Why?
It's exploitative.
I have cinematic standards.
(laughs)
No.
No one gives a crap about
cinematic standards, okay?
It's not the 1800s.
Have you seen
reality TV?
Housekeepers of Houston
has, like, a billion viewers.
Look, if one of us isn't
participating in the event,
we can't record it.
It's just what's ethical.
No offense to Ryan Seacrest
or whoever came up with
The Housekeepers of Houston.
You think
you're so great,
don't you?
I hope things
don't get weirder.
'Cause I'm at my limit.
(thumping)
TYLER:
Show the clock.
This is what Pop Pop
was talking about.
(thumping continues)
The werewolf is real.
Wait.
She's sundowning.
(running footsteps)
We're participating in this.
You're not being
Housekeepers of Houston.
Wait.
If you're gonna open the door,
just open it for a little bit.
(running footsteps
continue)
(hinge creaking)
(footsteps running)
(Tyler gasps)
She's supposed to do that?
It's just like someone
talking in their sleep.
You used to
talk in your sleep
till you were seven.
Dad used to come in
and quiet you down.
(thumping)
Hey, Becca.
Who am I?
BECCA:
T.
(whispers):
There's a family
of foxes.
You're going to
miss it.
We're coming!
Just stop.
Hey, why is Nana
staring into the well?
Come on. Let's go.
Come on.
Enough of that.
I don't know.
Come on.
Mise-en-scene.
You know,
y-you're not as dumb
as your performance
on the standardized tests
would indicate.
Oh-- Oh!
Forgot I had
something for you.
When you think of Dad now,
in California,
do you still
like him?
I don't know.
Stuff happens.
No, but Dad is hilarious.
Dad's funny.
He sent the funny card
of the fat lady
on the boardwalk.
Do you remember that?
What do you mean,
"stuff happens"?
People leave
'cause they find something
they like better.
So you don't
feel bad?
No.
You're not
being truthful.
Well, you can believe
what you want,
but this is how I feel.
Make me
believe you.
So, I'm on the Titans
pee-wee football team,
and it was third down.
It was at the end,
and we were leading.
So if we stopped 'em,
we probably win the game.
Give me context.
How old are you?
I'm eight.
So, I'm free safety,
which means that I'm supposed
to tackle the guy if he makes
it pass to people on the line.
So their running back
punches the hole--
Okay, am I supposed to be
following these terms?
Are these phrases supposed
to mean something to me?
Just listen.
So their running back,
who's big,
makes it past the line,
and I'm the only one
left to tackle him.
All I gotta do is tackle him,
put my hands around him
and tackle him, but...
I just stand there.
They call it "freezing."
And I could hear
everyone yelling.
Coach Daugherty. Dad.
All my teammates.
He gets the first down
and runs and runs,
and the other team
is celebrating,
and I'm still
standing there.
Same place.
Then the assistant coach
came and got me,
and Dad patted me
on the shoulder and then
went to the car, and he--
he never told me
he was angry or anything.
You think Dad didn't
say anything and left
because you didn't
tackle another eight-year-old
in a game five years ago?
Well, when you
say it like that,
it sounds stupid.
BECCA:
Why are we here?
She was staring
at something.
So, what did you find?
It's only water.
So, I just read these
in order?
"If you could be any animal,
what would it be?"
I feel like a douche,
Becca.
Shut up.
I would be a dolphin.
It's an intuitive
and highly intelligent
creature
with great power and poetry
in its movements.
How come you like
the pizza delivery guy,
even though he has
all that ratchet acne?
Please answer
the question.
He's kind.
He has kind eyes.
How come you don't
look at yourself
in the mirror?
Okay, fine.
What's this now?
Besides when you're editing,
y-you don't like
looking at yourself.
You never
look at yourself
in the mirror.
You comb your hair
with your back
to the mirror.
And I see you
brush your teeth.
You look down
the whole time.
Your sweater's
inside out.
Did you know that?
Did you see that
in the mirror
this morning?
Is that correct?
It doesn't
feel so good,
does it?
Are you changing
the focal length
of the lens?
No. I don't even know
what that is.
Are you zooming?
No.
So, do you admit that
you don't look at yourself,
or are you gonna
keep lying?
When do you think
I started doing that?
TYLER:
You know when.
That's not true,
asshole.
TYLER:
You think you're worthless.
Admit it.
(crying)
He gave me a card
when he left.
A card.
Old footage of us as kids.
Was thinking of using it
in the doc.
I refuse to use anything
that has my dad in it.
That would mean
I forgive him.
(footsteps)
TYLER:
Nana?
Becca's blind.
I know I'm right.
There is something
going on here.
TYLER:
Maybe there's something
down in the basement.
They don't want us
to go down there.
They're throwing shade.
Speak English.
They could be hiding
something down there.
There's mold down there.
That's why they don't
want us to go down.
Just stop, okay?
Just let me put
the camera out.
Hi. I'm Stacey.
Is Mr. and Mrs. Jamison
around?
BECCA:
No. They just
stepped out.
It's just me
and my brother here.
Mr. and Mrs. Jamison were
counselors at Meadowbrook.
I was in the rehab
program there.
They used to sit by my bed
when I wasn't in good shape.
All night sometimes, so--
Anyway, this is
a blueberry cobbler
for them.
They were supposed
to stop by on Saturday,
but they never showed.
I know Mrs. Jamison hadn't
been feeling herself,
so I thought I'd just
stop by and check in on 'em.
They hear
all that scuttlebutt
down at Maple Shade?
Uh, I don't think so.
BECCA:
Stacey, it's okay.
Just be natural.
I'm just-- I'm just getting
portraits of everybody.
Just be natural.
Okay. Never mind.
Pop Pop?
(whispers)
(screams)
(gasps)
We're even.
(Becca laughs)
Been editing montages
with music,
but I need some
everyday footage
of our grandparents,
so I've decided to spend
Thursday afternoon
following them around.
(Nana laughs)
떰 (woman singing
in foreign language)
Hear that?
She's laughing
as she's watching TV.
Maybe Mom and her
watch the same shows.
(laughs louder)
(laughing continues)
Nana?
Nana, are you okay?
Good afternoon.
I heard you laughing.
I have the deep darkies.
Nana? Nana!
Nana, Nana, Nana, stop!
Nana, stop!
떰 (continues)
Nana,
what's happening?
You have to laugh
to keep the deep darkies
in a cave.
(panting)
BECCA:
Pop Pop.
(shotgun hammer cocks)
Pop Pop,
I think Nana's--
I was just cleaning it.
What is that?
You want somethin'?
I was just
cleaning it, really.
I th-- I think
Nana's not feeling well.
Thank you, Becca.
I'll check on her.
BECCA:
We're putting
the camera out tonight.
(whispers)
What do you think?
(wind howling)
떰 (Hip-hop beat)
Whoo-hoo!
Ladies!
MIGUEL:
That's right.
I'm bad. I'm bad.
She seems like she's
better off without us.
Side to side.
Here we go.
We're doing this
so Mom can have a life, dummy.
Now roll. Now roll.
Give me some real
Doug E. Fresh now, people.
Here we go.
From the top.
(clock chiming)
BECCA:
Good night!
POP POP:
Is everything
okay?
BECCA:
We're fine.
You sure?
You both seem
to be acting funny.
We're terrific.
Just terrific.
Thanks for asking.
Okay.
BECCA:
Good night.
What am I gonna do?
What happened?
Th-There aren't
any tissues left
in the bathroom
and I had to touch
the toilet handle.
There's something
on my hand though.
Let me see.
You can't see it,
but I can feel it!
Shh, shh, shh.
Tyler. Tyler.
It's disgusting.
Nothing's com--
Nothing's coming off.
Let me have a look.
I can feel it.
There's no tissues left, Becca.
Tyler, there are tissues
underneath the sink.
Where? What?
It's okay.
It's too late. It's--
No, it's not gonna come off.
I think it is.
Rubbing it isn't gonna
make it come off!
Shh, shh, shh. It's okay.
It's all right.
I can feel it though.
I'm definitely
getting at it. Look.
(sighs)
It's-- It's
definitely coming off.
You sure?
There.
See?
Yeah.
So look next time,
all right?
It's okay.
I didn't know
they were there.
(sighs)
(slamming)
(rapid footsteps)
(shrieks, growls)
(panting)
(clicking)
(door slams)
Becca?
(doorknob rattling)
Stay in bed.
(slams)
Mom will be home
late this afternoon.
We're ending
this trip tonight.
We stay away from them
unless I say.
Pack your bags.
I still need them
to give Mom the elixir.
Becca,
what's the elixir?
BECCA:
Just pretend
like you're playing.
Is everything
all right?
We're just playing.
Uh, do you wanna do
the interview?
TYLER:
What? What are you doing?
I thought we were staying
away from them, Becca.
You're gonna interview him?
Mom told me you worked
in the coal industry
for a long time.
I did work in a factory.
I know.
Worked at night.
Saw a white thing
running around.
A white thing?
Yeah, it used to run around
the factory at night.
Only I saw it.
I started to tell people
about it and they--
they didn't believe me.
Had yellow eyes.
Then they fired me.
And nobody
talked to me.
Mom didn't tell me that.
Oh, she doesn't know.
Happened after she left.
Pop Pop,
you seem down.
Well, it's just, uh,
the end of your trip.
I know it's all
coming to an end.
Why don't you just ask Mom
if you can visit?
Are you really
still angry?
(sighs)
She can't get over this.
She still thinks
you're mad at her.
TYLER:
That whole "white thing" story--
the hairs on my arm stood up.
It's definitely some sort
of late onset schizophrenia.
They're both in bad shape.
Great.
(thumps)
Our Pop Pop
has schizophrenia
and our Nana
becomes Michael Myers
when the sun goes down.
(wind howling)
That's Stacey.
(chattering, faint)
TYLER:
What? Why is she angry?
She must be telling them
that they need to get help.
(chattering)
POP POP:
Come in the back.
(horse nickers)
I got it all off.
I didn't see
Stacey leave.
Did you?
Nana said okay.
BECCA:
Thanks for doing this.
We're leaving soon,
Nana.
I'm sad it's all over.
This is the last time
I'll get to ask you questions.
It's like-- It's like
the big end to my film,
and like you said,
"You're the star."
Oh.
(chuckles)
Tell me anything.
Whatever you wanna talk about.
I know a story.
It's about water.
Great.
There is a pond
that has
little creatures in it.
These creatures
are from another planet,
but no one realizes it.
These creatures spit
into the water all day long.
Their spit
can make you sleep,
but not die.
When people go underwater
in the pond,
they go
into a deep sleep.
A really beautiful sleep.
The creatures
from another planet
have many people
at the bottom of the pond,
storing them up.
They are going
to take them back
to their planet
of Sinmorfitellia one day.
That's just a made-up story.
It's not real.
Wow. That's--
That's some story.
And the creatures
have antennas,
but they are
invisible antennas.
Can we talk about Mom?
You don't ever
wanna see her?
No. Never.
On the day she left,
she must have done something.
(sobs, whimpers)
Okay, okay.
Let's-- Let's pretend
we're telling another story.
And the story
concerns a young girl...
who thinks she's in love
with an older man,
and they decide
to run off together.
Now, the parents of the girl
warn her that this won't work
and they refuse to let her go.
And then one day, the girl gets
into a horrible fight with them
and leaves forever.
Now, the parents
in this story don't know it,
but she misses them a lot
and she suffers greatly.
And then
the worst thing happens.
The man, he breaks
the girl's heart
(voice cracks)
and leaves forever
and leaves their
two small children behind.
(sniffles)
So, Nana--
Nana, in this story,
what do you hope
will happen to the girl?
In this story,
is she very sad?
She's inconsolable
at times.
She tries everything
to be happy.
Medications, and goes
to therapy for four years,
but still remains a little sad.
I don't like this story.
What do you think the parents
in this story should do
if they saw the girl again?
Nana. Nana, pretend you
were in this story
and she was your daughter
and she left.
What would you say
when you finally
saw her again?
I would tell her...
"I forgive you,
little girl."
(sniffles)
(sobs)
"I forgive you,
little girl."
BECCA:
That's the elixir.
What are you doing?
This is how
children play, okay?
Hey.
Mom should be home.
Let's go and Skype with her
while they're in the back.
Okay.
BECCA:
This will be
the denouement.
(line ringing)
LORETTA:
Hey, kiddos!
Did you get
my videos?
I know.
I look like an apple.
(chuckles)
Trip was great.
Miguel and I
had a little fight
this morning.
He wanted to get
short-stack pancakes.
I told him
he was gaining
a little weight.
Can you believe it?
Things don't work out
for me.
Mom?
Yeah?
Mom, you need to come
and get us right now.
What?
What happened?
Mom, get in the car
and come right now.
Do you know
how long that would
take by car, Rebecca?
Mom, trust me.
There's something wrong
with Nana and Pop Pop.
I'm telling you,
you need to come
and pick us up tonight.
Becca, you're scaring me.
My heart is in my throat.
We're okay now.
Just come.
Where are they now?
Uh, they're out--
they're outside
by the chicken coops.
They won't see you.
Becca--
BECCA: They've been acting
so strange, Mom.
We've been
recording them.
Becca, T-T--
I kept telling Becca
something was wrong, didn't I?
Becca, Tyler--
And Nana walks around
at night with a knife.
And Pop Pop had
a gun in his mouth.
Tyler--
I think he was trying
to hurt himself.
Becca, Tyler,
babies,
I need you
to listen to me
very carefully.
Becca, Tyler,
just listen to me.
We are.
Those aren't
your grandparents.
What are you
talking about, Mom?
Where are Nana
and Pop Pop?
You've been staying
with those people
the whole time?
(shuddering)
Masonville
Police Department.
(line ringing)
Come on, come on.
(ringing continues)
(knocking)
What are
you guys doing?
(ringing continues)
We'll be right in,
sweethearts.
(automated recording)
This is the Masonville
County Police Department.
Our officer, Jerry,
is currently
out on dispatch.
Please leave
a message--
(beeps)
Police
aren't answering.
Damn it!
Stupid hick town.
Okay.
I'm gonna keep calling
from the car, I promise.
Get you
and your brother out.
- Try to get
to a neighbor.
- Just stay calm, T.
I'm coming.
We're in a house with--
(door opens)
After we clear up,
I have a fantastic idea.
We should play
a board game.
Families
play board games.
It's our
last night together.
(door closes)
Becca, you'll help me
clean up, right?
You can record it
with your camera.
BECCA:
Okay.
Yeah!
(chuckles, sniffles)
(thunder rumbling)
Maybe we should go outside
and film some evening shots
of the house.
Okay. Sounds good,
Sister.
Could you clean
the oven for me, Becca?
Hmm.
(chuckles)
Get all
the way inside.
TYLER:
Becca?
She's done it before.
We really should
film something outside.
Do this first.
I'll be quick.
Oh, this will
just take a second.
(grunts)
Nana?
I can clean those.
Nana, please
open the door.
Oh, that's okay.
Please open it.
NANA:
There she is.
So, what was
the big fuss?
(thunderclap)
Let's make it...
(dice rattling)
a perfect
family night.
(laughing)
(thunder rumbling)
Your Pop Pop
is very competitive
with board games.
Be warned.
POP POP: If you wanna
move that over here,
that's fine.
NANA: If we use this table,
there's not room
for the cookies.
T-Diamond Stylus and I
are gonna do one
last interview outside
and be right back.
NANA:
You can sit over there.
Figure out
what the teams are.
(Nana, Pop Pop chattering)
BECCA:
Go, go, go. Hurry.
Brought a coat. I'm coming.
TYLER:
Okay, open it.
BECCA:
Who is that?
(gasps)
Picked teams.
It's young versus old.
(thunder rumbling)
(rattling)
(dice hit table)
POP POP:
Stop rolling all the dice
on every roll!
You're losing the game
for us.
No, I'm not.
We don't have
to keep score.
I'm a Yahtzee master.
Doesn't everyone
in the cafeteria call me
the Yahtzee master?
떰 (stereo: soul)
What cafeteria?
You wanna win at Yahtzee,
listen to me.
You're not
a Yahtzee master.
That takes 10 years.
(dice hit table)
See?
He's using strategy.
A Milton Bradley-approved
strategy.
I don't know what I'm doing.
- This game is made
by Hasbro, Pop Pop.
- That's a lie.
It used to be made
by Milton Bradley.
Who cares, Becca?
Finally!
I'm having
so much fun.
(laughs)
(sighs) Wow.
My-My battery's
running low.
I'll be right back.
You keep playing
with them, T.
Just keep playing.
I'll be right back.
(spitting)
(rattling)
(stomach rumbles)
(farts)
떰 (continues)
Becca?
(whispers)
Katy Perry.
What time is it, Nana?
Isn't it getting late?
(shrieks)
Yahtzee!
Becca!
BECCA:
I'm going down
into the basement.
I think they have
my grandparents here.
(light switch clicks)
(gasps)
Pop Pop.
Nana?
Are you down here?
(hinge creaking)
Things are not
working out tonight.
(stereo: needle
sticking in groove)
It's half past 9:00.
I have to get your Nana
to her room.
You wait here.
(thunder rumbling)
(panting)
Nana?
Pop Pop?
"Maple Shade
Psychiatric Hospital"?
(gasps)
Should the three of us
finish the game?
(gasps, whimpers)
(gasps)
My name is Becca Jamison.
If you find this footage--
(screams)
My name is Mitchell.
They kept telling us
you were so great,
how you're gonna visit,
how you're gonna be
a family.
That was a bad thing
they did.
They knew Claire
had put her two children
in those suitcases
in the pond.
She deserved this week
as a grandma.
Claire's kids
are on Sinmorfitellia.
(whimpers)
You're gonna join them.
(screaming)
No!
(grunts)
(screaming)
The only way
to Sinmorfitellia from here
is through the well.
Stop!
Wasn't it
a perfect week?
(whimpers)
I promised her
it would be.
The white thing
with yellow eyes is real.
It waits for us.
I saw it out in the field.
It was laughing at us.
(grunts)
떰 (stereo:
man singing aria)
They're murderers,
Tyler!
Becca!
BECCA:
Get out of here!
Run!
TYLER:
Becca!
POP POP:
We're all dying today, Becca.
No--
(door slams)
(lock clicks)
(grunting)
(grunts)
떰 (continues)
(sobbing, whimpering)
(groans)
(whimpers)
POP POP:
You...
have a magic spell
on you.
(whimpering)
(water runs, stops)
(belt buckle clinking)
(pants unzip)
(shoe hits floor)
(shoe hits
floor)
(whimpering)
Help! Help!
(grunting)
(pounding)
(whimpering)
(whispers)
I never liked you.
(moaning)
BECCA:
Claire?
I'll tell you a story.
(moaning continues)
(gasps, whimpers)
(thunder rumbling)
(clattering)
(whimpers)
(rumbling continues)
떰 (continues)
I have to go to the train
to go to the costume party.
It's a company party.
That's not now.
I know that.
(moans, cackles)
(gasps, whimpers)
(snarling)
(shrieks)
(whimpers)
(moaning)
You have a problem
with germs, don't you?
(whimpers)
(thunderclap)
(whimpering)
(growling)
(moaning, wheezing)
- (growls)
- (gasps)
(Becca screaming)
(growling)
(Nana gasping)
No!
(screaming)
You are blind.
I am the exposer.
I am a seer.
I see the veiny,
deformed...
face of the world.
(thunder rumbling)
(Becca whimpering)
(yells)
(object thuds)
(grunts)
(thuds)
(knob clatters on floor)
(whimpering)
We can all be
saved tonight.
Your magic spell
will be lifted.
(thuds)
No!
(grunts, groans)
Becca!
(Becca gasps)
Have you been
watching me?
BECCA:
Run, Tyler! Run!
(Tyler yelling)
Eyes on the runner!
Watch his hips!
(yells, grunts)
Stay low!
Wrap the arms!
Tyler?
(yelling)
(sirens blaring, faint)
Tyler!
No!
Any other
crazy bitch-ass
fucking people here?
(sirens continue)
Come on out!
(yelling)
떰 (chorus vocalizing)
떰 (lush orchestral score)
떰 (vocalizing continues)
LORETTA:
Becca! Tyler!
Babies!
(all crying)
I'm here.
MAN:
Is this everybody?
Come over here.
떰 (vocalizing continues)
We need an ambulance!
Hurry up!
Over here!
MAN #2:
Yo, Jimmy,
watch that front door!
떰 (ends)
BECCA:
Mom, honestly, you know
you don't have to do this.
I wanna do this for you.
I used to sing.
My mother used to say
that she wasn't listening,
but I know she was hiding
behind this big clock
down the hall,
a kitchen towel
over her mouth
to hide her smile.
She thought
I had a better voice
than Olivia Newton-John.
Olivia Newton-John was,
like, her Elvis.
My father
was a gentle man.
We'd take these
long walks together.
We'd never say a word.
I used to wake up early
when I was a child,
work on some project.
(sniffles)
My father thought that meant
I was gonna do great things.
Anyway, as I said before,
the day I--
the day I left
turned really badly.
My parents cursed at me.
I moved to the door to leave
and my mom stepped
in front of me.
I hit my mother.
And then my dad hit me,
and then we kinda
stood there in shock,
and then I left.
They reached out to me
soon after.
I refused
to take their calls.
(chuckles)
I know you were trying to
get me forgiveness, Becca.
You didn't have
to do that, honey.
It was there
whenever I wanted it.
(sniffles)
Please,
don't hold on
to anger, Becca.
You hear me?
(mouths word)
Okay.
(sobbing)
(sniffles, sobs)
(no audible dialogue)
Happy birthday
to you 떰
Blow them out!
Okay, okay!
Yay!
Yeah!
(rapping):
I may be thirteen,
may not live in the hood
May not carry no chrome,
may not be allowed
a cell phone at dinner
But I'm young
and can do 18 push-ups
and I speak the truth
My sister tried
to make a film about
old people feeling dismay
But it didn't
turn out that way
She had to scream and kill
and got vomit in her face
Chunks in her hair
from a stew
But she washed them out
with Herbal Essence
Body Envy Shampoo
So here's a few things
T-Diamond learned
from visiting elders
Adult diapers
come in many a name
There's Attends and Depends
and Medline and Prevail
But they all the same
They keep your mess
from spilling out
And they keep it contained
So here's the truth
I got messed up with a killer
who's truly insane
I will try not to refrain,
try to overcome my pain
'Cause one day
it will get me my fame
Like 50 Cent getting shot
and being lame
You see
I got a diaper shoved
in my face for half an hour
I thought it was over
I thought I'd be
under the ground
Growing four-leaf clovers
Some dude going over me
with a mower
But that's not
what happened, you see,
'cause I went all mental
I was like Mel Gibson
at the end
of a Lethal Weapon rental
I'm straight now
I'm not gonna lie
For three weeks
that diaper left me
like a basket case
I had to use two
whole Dove bars on my face
And one last thing
and I don't mean to sicken
But the truth is
Shit doesn't taste
like chicken 떰
Oh!
Shania Twain, bitches!
MAN:
No man can hold me down
떰 (hip-hop)
Yeah, I walks on fire
I walks on water
I walks on sand
and I walks on land
Can you hear me now?
Hey, can you feel me now?
Yeah, I walks on fire
I walks on water
I walks on sand
and I walks on land
Can you hear me now?
Hey, can you feel me now?
No one can hold me down 떰
떰 (violin)
떰 (violin continues)
떰 (ends)