Kurusu Rena... Someday, she has a VISION,
an ability to see the reflection of the murderer.
Christina!
They keep calling Kurusu Rena with "Christina" when they kill people.
I can't kill three persons!
Asano Kazuma, a detective on his off-duty period, and Rena has draw near into the mystery of the VISION.
What is this?
Chapter 5. Body contact
Christina...
Thanks everyone!
Well… This is the best!
- Ah Mr. Niitsu, thanks for your hard work!
- Thanks for your hard work.
That was great, right Yukino?
I had a lot of fun.
I'm glad that I can get a chance to perform on stage and I think it's not that bad.
- Hey Rena, don't you think so?
- How if you also become a member of group idol?
Well…  It will look nice with the three of you.
Should we make a new group with the three of you?
- Then, I'll be the leader!
- Eh!?
I don't want to do it next time.
If you still want to do it, then you two do it.
Oh! So it was finished. Thanks for your hard work.
- Thanks for your hard work.
- You look good with the costume.
- What?
- You never change the displeasure face expressions of yours.
You are always easy to get pissed off.
You never care the important things, do you?
What are you doing now is a good thing.
Even you object it now, it was happened, wasn't it?
Of course, I know that it's not my decision if you are going to do it or not.
Rena… I'm your ally, right?
That's why… Do this job, ok? This is a good job.
That talks again.
Rena, please believe in me.
I have resolution for the job.
What's with you?
Note: freeter in Japanese: someone in their 20's who is moving from job to job, mainly part time jobs which pay small wages.
The murder scene is in here. The victim is 27 years old,
a freeter who always chase after the group idol.
Note: freeter in Japanese: someone in their 20's who is moving from job to job, mainly part time jobs which pay small wages.
Both his room and his computer full with the idol pictures.
We still analyze the computer now.
He attached this thing on the computer screen.
It was written on here.
This is Kazuma's job.
Then, what about this mark?
The smartphone was dropped one kilometer from the murder scene.
Look at the display.
- This is Rena.
What is she doing?
- Last night, she was appeared on live performance as pinch hitter.
Ahhh~
But the pictures on that time,
didn't take by the smartphone's owner.
It seems like he also picked up the pictures from Internet.
This is the bloodstains left on the murder scene,
and this is where there was a tire track suddenly brakes.
In other words?
- In other words?
Why am I always the one who give all the explanation?
In other words, he killed the victim in here.
The murderer was in a hurry escaped with a car,
he was driving too fast, and he hit someone in here.
Maybe he was too scared to get caught so he escaped and take the corpse in his car.
At that time, his smartphone was dropped.
Ah I see.
Just "I see"?
You should give your opinion, a detective on his off-duty period, Asano Kazuma!
Is the smartphone's owner discovered?
- He still can't be found.
How about the data inside his computer?
- It is also full with group idol's pictures.
However, there are no pictures of him and also no communication traces.
We still investigate it now.
It means we still can't find any clues about him.
That's right.
Listen! The murderer wanted to dedicate himself to Christina,
and he killed two persons already.
One more person… I'm sure he has one more target already, but who is his next target?
Why did the murderers take the corpse in his car purposely?
Err… Revealing…
- Why?
Hey, why is it? - Err…
Why? Why? - Hey!
Why are you questioning and why am I only answering?
How can you do that? If I don't know about those things,
then you should think about it too, Idiot!
I understand now, you don't know anything.
I think I got criticize.
Are you awfully on rebellious period today?
Hee… Since I'm done with the toilet, I'm going to Rena's place.
If I get something, I will report.
- Kurusu Rena is going to shooting location in countryside.
Shooting location in countryside?
Let me hold your bag.
- Eh? Why?
Just let me hold it.
- What's for!?
While working, you must put your effort in it.
I only want you to concentrate in your work.
That's good, right?
- What?
Hey! As I said before, what is the most necessary thing we do in this place?
What is it?
Yes, it is for job.
Finally, you got it.
I'm relieved.
Ah! Today is just a minor work but the photographer is really famous.
He is young but he is known as the best first class photographer.
Heeee…
- Don't just "Heeee…"
Ah! Good morning!
Good morning!
- I am looking forward to work with you.
- I ask your favor.
So, if it's success, this will be a gate to major work.
I hope you understand.
Note: CM is Japanese TV commercial.
It will looks like we are going to shoot CM on Tokyo,
need going to overseas suddenly, eating delicious food.
In spare time of photographing we are playing,
and when we are back, we will receive a lot of fee.
Mr. Kiyosue's dream is so small.
- How come is it a small dream?
Good morning!
- Good morning.
- I'm looking forward to work with you.
Hey! Is that person a photographer?
Eh where?
- There.
- Let's go
- Ok.
Hello~
Eh? Mr. Kiyosue?
Rena is in preparation to do an important work.
Now, I'm heading there.
Can you tell that to Rena?
I heard there was a case.
Because of that, I was conveyed to Mr. Sakisaka,
that I want him to stop coming here and there to investigate Rena without any reason.
He doesn't have a right to do that thing, right?
- Yes, I also think that.
In every cases happened until now, there is no evidence that Rena and Christina are to be tied together.
This case has not yet solved.
You don't understand what will be happen if we leave such guy alone, right?
Even Mr. Kiyosue was attacked once.
Anyway, cancel it for today.
She is doing an important work right now.
I will always be with her.
So don't worry.
- I'm not like that police,
I'm worried about her personally, so I'm going over there.
If it's the reason, you don't have a right to stop me, right?
I have. I really have a right to stop you.
Bye~
What's with that guy?
Eh!? Aaaaa!
I've such a bad luck this time.
There is no doubt that freeter's murder is his acquaintance.
We will search those guys who have caused any trouble with the victim.
We should emerge the case by look for the information.
Sakisaka Inspector.
- What?
How should we report about "Christina" message?
We have no choice besides grasp of the theory.
The murderer didn't write Kurusu Rena name.
Isn't it, Mr. Sakisaka?
Note: The X-Files is an American science fiction drama television series.
Two FBI agents investigate the strange and unexplained while hidden forces work to impede their efforts.
In Japan, there is no such thing like the X-file.
What is that?
- It's ok. No need to talk about it.
Note: The X-Files is an American science fiction drama television series.
Two FBI agents investigate the strange and unexplained while hidden forces work to impede their efforts.
Akiyama, please go to get some information from her share house mates, Maria and Takami Yukino.
Then if you can, go to Kurusu Rena's room and look her belongings for a while.
Huh!?
By doing that it is counted as an illegal investigation, right?
It's not, if you just look it for a while.
- It's locked though.
But it's still possible, right?
Be careful on your way.
- Yes.
The mail has come. Is it from Christina?
Sorry for waiting.
- Yes.
How is this?
I'm sorry… Since the main staff will arrive late because of traffic jam,
can you wait a little longer?
Then please wait here.
I'm sorry.
- No problem.
Is there someone?
Are you seen something again?
Oh!
- Hey!
What's with this?
- Hey, what are you doing?
Please let go of me.
You are coming here again so you can steal some news!
I'm sorry. I accidentally near here.
Liar! Hey! What's this camera for?
You come here often to peeping photos and steal it in our photographing schedule.
If you are doing it again next time, I will report it. Remember my word!
Please forgive me.
I won't do it next time.
Sorry. I'm really sorry.
I will be careful from now.
You're so careless.
You didn't notice me.
Are you one of the photographer's staff?
Yes... It seems the main staff hasn't arrived yet.
I'm sorry but can you wait for a little longer?
I see... I'll wait.
Can I take your picture?
Now?
But if you don't want, let it be.
The photographer is really famous.
He is young but he is known as the best first class photographer.
It's ok with me.
I'm glad.
Then, let's do it outside.
- Ok.
Are you alright?
- Yes.
Thank you.
- No problem.
This is the pictures of acquaintance's colleagues with the murder victim.
They might come to live performance several times.
But I don't know who he is arguing with.
Is it enough?
Yes.
- Excuse me.
What is your true purpose?
- Hmm?
Your purpose to come here.
Even you are shown these pictures to Yukino,
it's not that simple to find the murderer.
I ever thought that many Models are stupid, but actually they are not.
Err… anyway…
Can't you enter Ms. Rena's room?
Do you think I will cooperate with you to do such thing?
We also have an appropriate reason. It's a house searches.
That thing is troublesome.
If you keep silent, you can't remain disagree too.
And I may not be able to proof her innocence.
You're really smart. You made decision really fast.
The police are really worst.
Ok…
Do they still not come yet?
- Yes… They still not call you.
So what are you doing in your free time?
- I do my job.
It's a little too late. I will ask them.
Why is the call not answered?
I feel like I was being sentimentize.
Sakisaka Inspector.
- Yes?
A little while before the case, seems like there was a big quarrel between those guys who were chased after their idol.
We can't get in touch with those three persons.
Their pictures are here.
Is there a murderer in this picture?
- Yes, there is a high possibility he is in this picture.
So, which one?
Let's see…
- "Let's see"?
You are really type of person who have your own opinion without saying it,
you're not obstacle and pleased with your superior, while keep work.
That thing…
It's Japanese people type, right?
Let's go!
Ah! When you come in? I didn't notice at all.
I come in as usual.
- Please don't frighten me.
That's right, I'm sorry.
- No need to apologize.
Have you ever had a feeling of loneliness before?
Eh?
- Even you're not alone but you feel lonely.
I'm sorry for asking strange question.
I felt it before.
I felt loneliness as well, but as usual thing come and pass through, I get used to it.
Geez… Finally, I arrived.
Yes?
- I think I know the murderer.
He left Kurusu Rena's picture in computer.
That's the last night live performance's photo,
and it is the same picture in the smartphone which was dropped.
He's a guy who does this for Christina's sake.
Did you contact Rena?
No, I didn't… Her manager is Mr. Kiyosue, right? He told me not to contact her.
So you didn't contact her.
Ah! Can you send the murderer's picture?
Yes, I can.
Hey Rena!
- What?
This will be a victory or defeat.
If you can manage it well, you will success after this.
I'm counting on you, Rena.
Since my future also depend on you.
Are you worried?
- No, no… I'm not worried.
I ask your favor, Ms. Rena.
- Yes.
I ask your favor.
- I ask your favor.
I'm sorry for the lateness. I'm the photographer, Kondo.
Eh?
Did something happen?
Are you the photographer?
Are there two photographers?
Huh?
You are the photographer, right?
No, I'm just an assistant.
- Christina.
- Eh?
I can't fulfill your wish anymore.
But... I want to meet you.
No! Stop it!
Rena!
- Are you alright?
Hey! What's happened?
There is someone, right? Is it this man?
How come?
- So, he is.
That guy is the murderer.
- The murderer?
Is he killed someone again?
- Yes.
But it's strange. There is no such thing…
Because this person...
touches me before.
- Eh?
This person also holds me.
I ask you to calm down, Rena. You can't continue shooting if you don't calm down!
Christina.
Please come here.
Where are you going, Rena? You're in the middle of shooting.
He called me.
That person called me.
Rena! What's the matter?
He is different from the previous criminal.
- He is trying to tell me something.
Hey! What's happened?
Someone hurry bring her back!
Goodbye Christina.
Rena...
There is something inside…
Who is the owner of this car?
Stop it!
Hey! stop it!
Shut up!
- Stop it!
It's not like what did you think.
Hey!
Ah...
No!
I don't know why it's happened!
I don't know… I really don't know!
Hey wait!
He is attempted hit and run accident, and abandoned the corpse.
Kondo who killed Tanaka using his car, are going to filming location at the hill...
and trying to hide Tanaka's corpse.
Christina...
He discovered Christina, and killed a man.
Unexpectedly, he got hit by a photographer who has scheduled to shooting Kurusu Rena,
then he died.
That coincidence is amazing.
In this world, that coincidence also happened once in a while.
I have encountered something like that too.
The murderer who had been missing for five years,
was sleeping next to me in the sauna.
So, did you find something from Rena's room?
Please look at this.
This is Kurusu Rena's picture when she studied abroad in Melbourne.
I have checked it but the pictures are mixed.
Mixed?
- Yes.
Heee~
There is a person inside the trunk of car.
- Yes.
I'm sure before we discovered his body,
he still alive.
They are starting to hire a new photographer.
I see.
Let's go back.
Ah! If you don't have a problem, I will send her back.
Eh?
Let him send me back.
I see… Ok, then.
Hey Rena... I didn't tell you about the case,
because I only want you to do your job well.
I know that.
I see. Then be careful.
Ok.
Should we go now?
Hey.
If something happened, you should come, ok?
Come to my place, properly.
Promise me.
By any chance, are you confessing to me?
You are stupid.
Thank you for praising me.
Let's go!