Hey, you! Switch the engine off!
No, don't accelerate!
Stop the engine!
As a boy, I had a list of favorite jobs.
My top 10.
On top, it said in red letters, "Pilot."
And in second position?
Coffin-maker?
I can't remember.
The other nine were of no importance.
Watch out!
When it comes back, you have to duck!
Okay.
Beautiful flight.
Wow, Grandpa!
Straight into the kitchen window!
It's like a real piano!
Did you say, "Thank you"?
Thanks.
The boy needs a real piano.
Mom, when do I get a real piano?
Vitus, get dressed. We have to go.
You'll have to ask your dad.
Okay.
Dad, when do I get a piano?
You'll have to ask your godmother.
Okay.
Watch out! Don't touch anything.
This thing can hear
five times better than a human ear.
Bats can hear 10 times better.
Yeah? Really?
Put these on.
I hear even less now.
Wait a minute.
You're right. There are no batteries.
But when this thing is finished,
everything will be put into a microchip,
which will be built into this here.
Then you'll hear as well as a cat.
I'm going to call it Cat-Ear.
Actually, Bat-Ear would be better.
I would like that, too.
Speaking of Bat-Ear,
I've got something for you.
And in fact, it works.
Press here, and it lights up.
Look at the red light.
There are two little microphones.
And then this.
Now you can hear like a bat.
Come to the window.
It's great, isn't it?
I wouldn't do that, Olga.
Soon he'll be telling you what to do.
Vitus, hurry up and get dressed!
Actually, I'll need that back.
When's your appointment?
Not till the afternoon.
Damn, I can't find my transparencies.
Does this have to happen now?
It's paradoxical!
No, it's typical.
Dad, what does "paradoxical" mean?
- "Paradoxical" means...
- Leo.
I'll tell you later.
But I want to know it now.
Two minutes.
Okay, two minutes.
Just a quick question.
Could I work 70% instead of 30?
Okay, but what about Vitus?
We have a very expensive child.
We have a babysitter now,
the daughter of our gem.
Monti's daughter?
Great.
No wonder a lot of people
would rather do without a hearing aid
and give up some quality of life
than carry a snail shell behind their ears.
You know that we generate 90%
of our turnover with these snails.
I know that, but if Phonaxis
wants to become a global player...
Young people should wear
our hearing aids as fashion items, then?
Maybe in fluorescent colors?
Yes, that's exactly what I think.
We have to beat the competition,
which isn't sleeping, either,
with highly intelligent
and pretty hearing computers.
That means, don't hide your hearing aid,
but show it off and present it like jewelry.
On the table, you can see my prototypes,
the Cat-Ear and the Bat-Ear.
The design might need a few changes,
but this is all about the idea, isn't it?
Sounds like you want to lead
the project yourself.
That's exactly what I think.
Why should I believe in you?
You even dropped out of university!
Because, otherwise,
I'll go to the competition.
Thanks for the presentation.
You'll be hearing from us.
The other day, he read
about global warming to the children.
He told them they would all have to die.
The children started to cry.
And then I get
the phone calls from the parents.
Why don't you tell Vitus to read
The Wolf and the Seven Little Kids to them.
Actually, that's my job.
Vitus should be at school, not kindergarten.
And besides, he's very cheeky.
Instead of calling me Mrs. Pfenninger.
He calls me Obelix.
But that's a compliment.
He loves Obelix.
I'll take him with me.
Come on, let's go.
- Bye, Obelix.
- Bye.
I've had enough.
They're getting soggy.
- I love you.
- I know.
Don't wipe off the lipstick
so people can see that you're taken.
- Bye, Vitus.
- Bye.
See you in the foyer at 7:30.
Listen, Vitus, you don't have
to go to kindergarten anymore.
Cool.
While I'm at work,
a babysitter will look after you.
But I'm not a baby.
Then just call her a girlfriend.
Isabel is coming tonight.
We're going to a concert, okay?
I'll have to practice tonight.
You can practice all day.
- Can I?
- Of course.
Nobody's ever got to the top as fast as you.
Ah, Isabel.
Hello, Mrs. von Holzen.
Call me Helen. Please come in.
Okay.
Vitus has a shower every evening.
So now you know where to find everything.
And, once again, never disturb Vitus
- while he's practicing, okay?
- Okay.
Take care. Bye, Vitus!
Vitus?
I'm reading.
Can I come in?
Be quiet. I want to read.
Did you know
that it was me who made the bat?
I gave it to you for your first birthday.
It's called Abraham.
- Abraham?
- Abraham.
That's a beautiful name.
Oh, my God, it's so big.
Do you mind if we pick some flowers?
It's all right, my little darling.
I just need to pick some flowers.
See? You just have to ask politely.
Why are you picking flowers for my mother?
Because she reminds me
of your grandmother.
Can you show me a photo of her?
She was too beautiful for a photo.
Oh, no, we've just missed the train.
We'll take the next one.
The walls are freshly painted. New furniture.
Have you suddenly become rich?
What do you mean by rich?
Would you like to wear one of my suits?
If I'm not good enough
for your dinner party,
feel free to cancel the invitation.
You've brought some lovely flowers.
Yes, they're from a very special shop.
You're even more charming than your son.
Well, that's not really hard.
- Where's Vitus?
- In his room.
Are you getting dressed up?
I'm not into costume parties.
Let's get away, Grandpa.
That's impossible. You're the host.
Have a pleasant evening.
Cheers!
You have a nice place here.
A typical 1930s house.
It's going to be pulled down soon.
That's why the rent is low.
To go public at the right moment
could be a stroke of genius.
You want to go public with Phonaxis?
I have a feeling
that our Cat-Ear
will attract lots of speculators.
It's either boom or bust.
I do feel optimistic.
But I'm still against going public.
The stakes are too high.
Mr. von Holzen,
you are our savior or our ruin.
I hope I'm not either of them.
Nick, take a look at that buffet!
Yes, just help yourself.
Thanks. We know how it works.
Why does he hate me?
Because your wife is more beautiful.
True.
You'll talk him round.
I'm not musical at all.
My godson, however,
is all the more musical.
- Really?
- Yes, it's incredible.
That's interesting.
My husband wanted to become a pianist.
Really?
It was a long time ago.
Oh, excuse me.
Do you play the piano?
No, our son does.
Oh, a talented family.
But surely not these difficult notes.
Yes, he has a good teacher.
He's been taking lessons for six months.
For six months?
You don't believe that yourself!
He doesn't play like a maestro.
Leo?
Would you play something for us? No?
Come on, only one piece.
We'd all be delighted.
What does he play?
Robert Schumann's Wild Rider.
Vitus.
What a sweet little chap!
You can sense that he's musical.
Beautiful.
Extraordinary.
A real wunderkind.
I've never seen anything like it.
He's only six, but we do hope...
Well, he didn't get it from me.
They've told us that his IQ
is so high it's incalculable,
but I don't know much about it.
I'm too stupid.
I've been telling Leo
that we're raising a real talent here.
Do you remember
the horoscope that I did for Vitus?
You carry a huge responsibility,
especially as his mother,
- if you know what I mean.
- Yes.
All of the world's great pianists
were so-called wunderkinds
in their childhood.
No exception.
You really have to foster his talents.
The earlier, the better.
He should go straight to the conservatory.
You don't just owe this to your son
but also to music.
Now the world knows
we have a real wunderkind
and a cheeky little monkey.
Maybe Knaak was right.
We have to foster his talents.
What he doesn't learn now, he'll never learn.
We shouldn't put pressure on him.
Otherwise, he might do the opposite.
It won't work without a little pressure.
Vitus needs that.
Same as you.
You're right in principle,
but an academy is for adults.
The boy doesn't even go to school yet.
But didn't you...
However, I have recognized his talent.
We will accept him.
Did you hear that, Vitus?
I'll teach you myself.
That's unbelievable!
Thank you very much.
Are you a concert pianist yourself?
He's in good hands with me.
Are you happy, Vitus?
Of course, he'll keep on taking lessons,
but not with you, I'm afraid.
Don't you understand...
Now, listen!
He's our son,
and you're just not good enough for him!
And I'm sorry, too, Mrs. Piantoni.
Just send me the bill!
Goodbye, Mrs. Piantoni.
Where is he, by the way?
In his room. He doesn't want to eat.
He wants to stay with Mrs. Piantoni.
"I love her," he said.
Vitus?
I've got something for you.
Come out here.
Vitus, hold the spandrel.
Why shouldn't it fly?
You know
all about aerodynamics, don't you?
The bulge creates an air cushion,
and it flies.
All we need is
some silky skin like the bats have.
Very good. Silky skin!
Yes, silky skin.
Do you want to learn how to saw?
- Okay.
- Come here. I'll show you.
Hold here
and follow this line here.
And now you.
But I'm not allowed to play with this.
We're not playing. We're working!
Come on!
Hold the work piece,
and go!
Yes.
Are you completely mad?
What if he hurt his hands?
Just imagine the disaster!
Listen, Helen,
we are building wings.
Wings? What for?
To fly, of course.
That's what they'll look like.
Vitus, promise that you'll never play
with such dangerous things again.
We're not playing. We're working.
I'm the boss here.
But I wear the trousers.
I wish you a very happy birthday.
Many thanks.
When you come here next time,
we will fly.
Oh, no, you can't do this to me.
Okay.
No, I'm very proud of you.
Yes, me, too.
We'll eat without Daddy.
- Bye, Isabel.
- Bye.
See you.
Vitus?
Bye-bye.
We're going to Sonja and Walter's.
Your dinner is on the table.
We'll be back around 11:00, okay?
Yes, I know.
How long are you gonna stay in your room?
Until I'm an adult.
Can you help me?
It's much too heavy for us.
If you want, you can come with me.
Until we're adults?
Okay.
Really? That's extreme.
Do you want to know how bats reproduce?
No, thank you.
What do you want to be when you grow up?
I don't know yet.
You know so much, but not that?
I want to become a rock singer.
Sounds good.
They left the light on.
What?
Isabel?
Isabel, get up!
Come on, I'll take you home.
Isabel, what did you two do?
No idea.
Come with me.
Baby.
I'm back.
What's got into the girl?
- Did you ask her?
- No.
How could she give alcohol to Vitus?
Come here.
You've filmed them?
Yes, I used a sensor.
My dress, my jewelry!
We need a new babysitter.
Okay, but she's a good dancer.
Think it over.
Sorry, but I've already decided.
And what about your career?
Maybe this is my career.
Even the experts say now or never.
You're so quiet.
Are you ill? Is something bothering you?
I've been waiting all day.
Okay, then, let me guess.
You're in love?
Not me,
but I know
who I'm gonna marry when I'm grown-up.
Really? And who will that be?
Come on, tell me!
But it's still a secret.
Isabel?
Mommy, when is Isabel coming?
Vitus, I have a surprise for you.
You have a new babysitter.
Me!
I don't need a babysitter!
And Isabel is my girlfriend.
Listen, Isabel won't be coming anymore.
She's too young to have
such a huge responsibility.
Come on, let's practice the piano.
No, I want Isabel back!
Are you crazy?
Hello, who is it?
- Post, express delivery.
- I'm coming!
Vitus!
Vitus, you can't do that!
Open that stupid door at once!
Vitus, open the door!
Damn it all!
I'll give you one more chance!
Or else I'll get
the caretaker with his crowbar.
I'll count to 10! One, two, three,
four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten!
Look, the professor
coming to school by taxi.
Poor guy!
That smart-ass
could at least wear normal clothes.
Shitus will do that when he reaches puberty.
The interest is 1.258%
and is being continuously credited.
How much money will be on
his account after 322 days?
Without the calculator, please.
Ah, someone knows the result already.
Vitus?
No, sir, but I could calculate it for you.
Then go on.
If the account neither has credit nor debit,
the interest would be
216.6.
So, after 322 days,
there'd be 19,466.6 on the account.
Correct.
But your arrogant behavior
is an insult to my intelligence.
Excuse me, sir,
but if I'm insulting your intelligence,
there are, after all, two people in here
who have some intelligence.
Okay, that's enough.
Pack your bag and get out!
Okay. Okay.
The school has phoned again.
What has he done this time?
They want to talk to us.
Talk to us?
Is Wednesday at 3:00 okay?
Next week? No chance.
Leo, it's important.
Yes, I know.
It's a shame your husband's not here.
I think so, too.
You can speak Swiss-German.
We really have to find a solution.
Your son sabotages every lesson.
He doesn't miss a single opportunity
to make the teacher look stupid
in front of the whole class.
My teachers refuse to carry on teaching him.
But you cannot throw out a child
just because he isn't challenged enough.
Yes, you are right.
That's why there are
special schools for the highly gifted.
Vitus is wasting his time here,
and we are wasting our time.
My husband and I
are against such zoological gardens.
A special-needs school
is out of the question.
Well,
in that case, I'll enroll Vitus
for the high school graduating exams.
At the age of 12?
Yes, why not?
Good.
Very good.
Hold your horses.
The left hand has to hold the pace.
- Hold back a bit, know what I mean?
- No.
Syncopation: tenuto!
That's boring.
Let's try the second last bar,
and try to play it a little bit boring.
Would you like another slice?
Yes, please.
Here.
Thanks.
Do you want to do your final exams now?
I don't know. Why should I?
You could go to university.
You earn a lot as an engineer.
You could still play piano as a hobby.
The Institute of Technology at 13?
Well, okay, it is a bit early.
You could do
a traineeship with us for two or three years.
You could invent something, like your dad.
Have you seen this before?
It's the "mother of hearing aids."
Worldwide.
In fact, it's the further development
of the Cat-Ear and Bat-Ear.
It's a kind of Rolls-Royce.
With this, Phonaxis
has increased its turnover tenfold.
If I had bought some shares then,
we'd be rich now.
But we are rich!
I mean really rich.
Shall I tell you a secret?
The boss will be retiring soon.
There's a rumor that I'll be his successor.
Cool!
You'll be the CEO of Phonaxis!
Knock on wood.
Ah, where were we?
Yes, you have to plan your career.
Let's have a look at it together.
Von Holzen.
Hi, Klaus.
What about the chips?
I'm kind of busy, but go ahead.
Is that... Is that right?
Yes? Okay. Okay.
Bat scientist, architect, chemist...
Don't you fancy any of these?
Maybe cabinetmaker,
and you could take over my workshop.
- No.
What about banker? Taxi driver?
I got it.
Pilot.
You don't even want to become a pilot.
It's getting difficult now.
Maybe butcher? Vet? Surgeon?
You are a hopeless case.
I'd like to be someone else.
Like who, for example?
I don't know. Whoever. Just normal.
As normal as me?
No, more normal.
Well, then just become normal.
But how?
Hold this!
If you can't decide,
you'll have to part with things you like.
Get it?
You've only practiced for two hours!
If I have to play "holding back,"
I can also practice "holding back."
Don't talk nonsense.
Okay.
She lives in a castle?
Look!
She's coming towards us.
Is that her?
Yes, that's her.
Gina Fois, the living piano legend.
She looks like an old bat.
Vitus!
So you're Vitus.
Nice to meet you.
Have a seat.
What are you going to play for me?
I'd like you to play something for me.
Me?
That's very flattering,
but I'd rather listen to you
playing Scarlatti's sonata in E minor.
No.
Okay, I'll play something for you,
but it's your turn first.
I don't feel like it.
Do it for me.
Why is it always for you?
Don't worry, madam.
It's more important for a pianist
to have good parents than good teachers.
Vitus, you should play neither
for your mother nor me.
Just take your time
until you feel like playing,
playing the piano for the sake of the music.
Cold rationality and a warm heart,
that's what makes a great pianist.
That's why I want to become a vet.
Can I visit Grandpa for the weekend?
No way!
Do you have any idea how many youngsters
would like an opportunity like this?
They come here from all over the world
just for one single piano lesson, and you?
Vitus?
Has it come?
Come on, sweetheart.
We're here!
He was lucky.
We couldn't find any injuries,
not one bruise.
Extraordinary, considering the heavy fall.
There are miracles, though,
especially with children.
- The wings carried him for a bit.
- Yes.
But he isn't an Icarus, luckily.
He's still unconscious.
At the moment, the initial diagnosis
is concussion of the brain.
What do you mean, "At the moment"?
There are injuries
which only show up after a few days.
With brain injuries, you can never rule out
long-term implications.
I'll show you some pictures.
You're taking a long time.
Sorry.
Well, I have plenty of time.
Check!
And what is this?
Dad brought it.
It's for my exams.
Vitus, what are you doing?
This isn't our car.
Come on.
The following, Mrs. von Holzen.
We have tested
his speaking and reading skills,
his memory and his sense of perception.
We got normal levels.
What does "normal levels" mean?
Please, take a seat.
Normal according to his age group.
He's even slightly above average,
especially in his logical thinking.
- And the IQ test?
- Yes?
- Did you do...
- Yes, but, at the moment,
the test is irrelevant,
but if you really want to know,
it's around 120.
120?
It used to be 180. How is that possible?
I know.
It's difficult to say.
Even for specialists like us,
the brain remains a mystery.
There's no real explanation
for extraordinary abilities.
If I can give you some advice,
give yourself and Vitus some time.
Time, time, time.
He'll make some progress.
You just want to cheer me up.
Many thanks.
I cannot understand your disappointment.
After all, you have a healthy
and normal child.
I have to give
worse news to a lot of parents.
Listen, everybody!
Silence, please!
Daniel, please!
This is your new schoolmate, Vitus.
He has changed schools,
and he's with us from now on.
Vitus, you can sit next to Jens.
Hi, Vitus, what's up?
Hi, Jens.
Like this. Loosen up.
Now make a fist.
Yes, that's right. And again.
Play the run, and take your time.
"Es!" Doesn't it hurt your ears?
At least your fingers
should be able to remember.
Sorry.
Music comes from the heart,
from your fingers, from your soul!
All you hurt was your head.
Sorry, Mom.
Don't you feel lonely sometimes?
Yes, I do.
Loneliness is the worst,
but I'm doing something about it.
- I write love letters.
- To whom?
Up to now, I've only written to Annemarie,
but now I'm getting more generous.
I'm also writing to the beautiful woman
who sat opposite me in the train
and to the glistening lake,
to the lovely figure skater on TV
and to the cool shade under the pear tree.
- And then?
They fly beautifully.
Fabulous.