-Landlady. -Yes? - I'm thinking of making a deal. We should discuss it upstairs.
Make some tea and bring some flower cookies for our guest.
Please.
After you.
Timing and Subtitles by the Gone With the Shirt Team @ VikiPlease do not reuse or reupload our subtitles.
When a Snail Falls in Love-Episode 20-
Jin Dun,
you felt really weird, right?
The smuggling and drug dealing you organized.
How did they get discovered by us?
Do you remember the Ye Lanqing kidnapping case from 13 years ago?
You colluded with Hu Zhishan and killed Ye Lanqing with dynamite.
A policeman from the rescue operation went missing.
That policeman...
He knew it was a trap but he still came alone.
Don't Chinese police like you
value your own lives?
We do value our lives.
But we value our responsibility more.
Some things are more valuable than being saved and living like a dog.
Can you understand?
Big Hu!
Someone like Zhao Xiaolu, only someone with a very close relationship can earn her trust like that.
Therefore, I think the biggest possible answer is a couple relationship.
Plus this person is very arrogant.
-Hello? - Director Zhan!
This is Xu Xu. I have some very urgent information I need to report to you.
We can't trust General Po, he might be the Golden Python.
The safety of the suspects and witnesses on this train can't be guaranteed.
I don't have enough time to explain right now.
Okay, I understand.
Don't make a move yet. Try to stabilize him. The border police will be there very soon.
- I can't hear you, Director Zhan. - Persist for another half-hour and then the border police will arrive.
Hello?
How long ago did Po's train depart?
Where are you?
Miss, the general wants to meet you.
I need to talk to my colleagues.
I am sorry, the general wants to meet you now.
Please.
Stop, general's order. This is a secure area.
You guys are not allowed to enter.
- Are you blocking us? - Yes. Please.
Where are the two, my colleagues?
What is going on?
We are just taking her back to her room.
Xu Xu?
Secure area. It's the general's order.
Not long after Ye Zixi entered Ye Corporation,
I found out she was flirting with Zhang Shiyong.
I thought I could do something since they were together.
The fact that Ye Zixi wanted the Ye Corporation's stocks
was obvious like it was written on her face. But Zhang Shiyong was different.
I think his ambition and greed hid his intelligence.
He was constantly trying to dig up more information about that 1.9 billion account.
He also sent people to spy on me.
I needed to prepare a backup plan, right?
So I sent someone to gather information and found this man called Yang Yu.
He was looking to create trouble for Zhang Shiyong.
So you ordered Jin Maitian's people to contact Yang Yu and create trouble for Zhang Shiyong.
You were disappointed when Yang Yu didn't get him, right?
That's right. I wasn't surprised by the outcome though.
That time, I just wanted to teach Zhang Shiyong a lesson.
But Zhang Shiyong used the cops to threaten me.
You can come in now.
Sit.
Inspecter Xu, please sit.
General Po, do you need anything from me?
I heard that you are good at psychological analysis.
You can analyze the identity of the other party.
Who told you that I'm good at psychological analysis?
Was it Tisa... or our commander?
How were they talking about me behind my back?
You don't need to know that.
All I'm interested in is your analysis of me.
I'm sorry. My expertise is used for solving cases, not for fun.
Chinese people always love to brag.
Looks like you are also no different.
You don't need to goad me.
It's not hard to analyse you.
Fine.
If your analysis is right,
I'll give you this handgun as a gift.
From now on, we are friends.
Guns are regulated in China.
I have no use for it even if you give me one.
How about this?
If my analysis is right, give this one to me. Is that okay?
This?
This is not valuable.
In China, we believe in affinity.
It means that just by looking at an object, you feel that you two are fated.
For you, this item might just be an ordinary decoration.
But I feel that it has a lot of vigor in its style. This must have been made by you personally.
Ye Zixi. You used Ye Lanyuan's trust.
After stealing the international financial report, you deliberately leaked it, framed Ye Zixi and then
personally killed her.
She is too intelligent.
She was in my way. I must get my hands
on that 1.9 million.
There really was no other choice.
Ji Bai,
do you want to know what your childhood friend, your little sister Ye Zixi
said before she died?
Silly girl, let me ask you a question.
Who do you want to contact the most at this time?
Yang Yu? Zhang Shiyong?
Or Ji Bai?
She just stared at me and I returned her gaze.
She didn't want to die. She wanted to find her Third Brother. She was very afraid.
A stream of blood... from her chest that was as white and creamy as white cheese...
Gudu... Gudu... it flowed out like that...(T/N: 'gudu' = transliteration of blood spurting out)
Firstly, you're a firm and resolute person.
You base your actions on your own principles, and not what others determine as right or wrong.
That's why your troops are both fearful and respectful of you.
In their eyes, you're both Heaven and Earth (their god).
Secondly, you lust after power, and determined to boot.
That's why at just over the age of 40, you're able to have such standing in the military.
Thirdly, you have a slight tendency to be violent and sadistic.
You can see this from the way you shot and killed the criminal the other day.
But not all kinds of sadistic action can bring you pleasure,
even, at some point, you'll resist the desire to be violent.
You're now the general of an army.
If you completely indulged yourself, you'd definitely have all sorts of channels
and more violent methods to satisfy your sadistic desires.
But in Myanmar, I didn't hear of any such criticisms.
That's why I think that even though you're unable to get over your addiction for sadism,
but you've always held yourself back.
General Po, regarding this, I'd like to show my admiration for you.
Fourthly, you don't have women around you.
That's why I reckon that you have a steady partner.
Fifthly, judging from your office decoration style,
you're someone who likes extravagance and flamboyance.
I guess that you must feel bitter towards the Commander.
You're competing with him.
You need to be careful of this cop.
She's very formidable. It's like she can see through everyone's disguise.
General Po, is my analysis accurate?
You really are an interesting girl.
This makes me like you a lot,
and want to talk to you longer,
but I have something to do now. I can't let you leave now.
Take her away.
How was it? You saw that Xu Xu?
Let the headquarters know, my train is spoiled,
and needs to do an emergency change of route and go to another station.
Received!
What's happened?
The plan to send you to Laos,
I'm afraid we won't be able to wait until the return journey to do that.
We're going to do it now?
Stay here.
Ji Bai,
right now, you think that you've won and you're feeling very pleased with yourself, aren't you?
Let me tell you. The schemes that I've come up with,
the people who I've killed, the money I've earned,
also the heroin that I've sold,
do you even know how much I've sold? You guys don't know.
One day, you'll send me to the execution grounds.
Pow!
And everything will disappear into dust.
All these will turn into mysteries. I'm willing to bet
that you don't know about the other things I've done.
You're not as smart as me.
You're not smart either.
You unscrupulously did so many things,
only because in your heart, there wasn't any happiness or warmth worth protecting
or cherishing in your heart.
I've been in the police for ten years. If I were to list all the degenerates who I've caught, like you,
it'd be much longer than your list of people you've killed or misdeeds you've done.
You've now become a name on my list.
Therefore, your list ends as of today,
whereas my list will continue on.
Timing and Subtitles by the Gone With the Shirt Team @ VikiPlease do not reuse or reupload our subtitles.
[Xu Xu has been taken away by Po.]
Stop there! Don't run!
Boss,
are you okay?
It is General Po's army.Go find Da Hu and Hou Zi.
We need to ensure the suspects' safety. Xu Xu has been taken away.
I need to go find her.
Stop. What are you doing here?
What? Pardon me?
Can you speak English?
I am looking for my colleague, Xu Xu.
The train is running, the army is in control. This is General Po's order.
General Po?
Yeah, General Po with me.
We are friend, good friend.
Stop, don't move.
- You see, you know? - I am going to shoot. I said stop.
Teacher!
Teacher, I am here!
Back off!
Don't move! Stop! Nobody moves
without General Po's order. Nobody move.
Teacher.
Po is the Myanmar official who has been backing Zhao Xiaolu all this time.
I already contacted Director Zhan and asked for support from the border police.
What happened to you?
I feel dizzy.
Sit down. Sit down.
Back off. Back off.
Let's go.
Hurry up.
They are over there.
Our leader has contacted your commander Juewen.
Po betrayed the army. He is not a good officer.
Commander Juewen is on his way here and he will work with the Chinese army to take this bad guy down.
Commander Juewen is on his way coming here and he will work with the Chinese army to take this bad guy down.
Everyone else, put your weapon down and cooperate with the investigation.
You will not be found guilty if you don't know anything.
Help the Chinese police, Po betrayed us.
Yes, sir.
Put your weapon down.
Down. Put your weapon down.
Put it down.
-What is going on? -Let's go check it out.
The train changed direction. If it continues travelling east, we'll arrive at Laos' border.
Po wants to escape.
No, the one who needs to escape is Zhao Xiaolu.
When will we meet again?
When all the Chinese are gone,
I will escort you back.
She is on the train, too.
Bring that policewoman to me. Don't let her contact anyone.
Go in, go in.
Track them down, track them down.
They are somewhere here.
No, no way.
-We don't have time. Hurry up.
- No, no way.- Hurry up.
Give me your hand.
Find an open area. Figure out a way to contact the headquarters and tell them the location of this train.
Can you finish this mission?
Teacher.
Contact the border army as soon as possible.
We have a chance if you go.
If we stay, the only result is we will both die.
I don't want to go. I won't go.
I don't want to leave.
I am not going.
Ji Bai!
Timing and Subtitles by the Gone With the Shirt Team @ VikiPlease do not reuse or reupload our subtitles.
♫  How I wish to say that we are not in the wrong. ♫
♫  Just that the world is a circle. ♫
♫  So round. After going one round, then we realise. ♫
♫  With time, I have finally understood. ♫
♫  Between us, day by day.  ♫
♫ Those stories that happened. ♫
♫  weren’t discovered in time and everything happened with fear of regrets. ♫
♫  Your indistinct face seems to have vanished in the distance ♫
♫  yet still tugs at my heart.  ♫
♫  The breeze past my ears reminds me this is not an illusion ♫
♫  Seeing everyday as a remembrance, then you will know how intense this love is ♫
♫  Before the rain ceased, I suddenly wish to see your face once more. ♫
♫  Your sweet smile  ♫
♫  has foolishly stopped at happiness’ destination. ♫
♫  The breeze past my ears reminds me this is not an illusion ♫
♫  Seeing everyday as a remembrance, then you will know how intense this love is ♫
♫  Before the rain ceased, I suddenly wish to see your face once more. ♫
♫  Your sweet smile  ♫
♫  has foolishly stopped at happiness’ destination. ♫