Wake up Grace!
Our super engineer
Boss, the deadline is noon today!
Where are your drawings?
Sleep is a luxury you can't afford!
It's all your fault!
Those little fingers in your robot...
are impossible to power...
they're too small to fit the wires.
But you're the miracle worker! You're Grace!
You'll find the solution! See you at noon?
See you, bye!
You taught me well Courage is the best solution
All problems can be solved
How can a man whistle and brush
his teeth at the same time?
He's brushing his dentures!
Mom
Which is the smallest island in the world?
Asafety island on a busy road!
You're good
Mom, how about this one?
Why do birds fly south in the winter?
They don't like the cold?
Nope!
Why do birds fly south? Because...
they can't drive?
You're so silly!
Why do birds fly south? I know
the flights are fully booked.
Wrong! All the other parents get it right away!
You must too!
But there're two of them... and I'm all alone!
I'll give you double the time then, bye!
Bye
Don't forget to pick me later.
I won't!
Bye
Tinker!
Bye Bye
Hello! Ada, I've got it!
What do you have in mind?
If we use a photo sensor
then reaction speed will be fast.
We won't need so many wires...
problem solved?
Wow! What inspired you?
Took a beautiful photo ofTinker just now...
the way the sun lit up her smile
Good! Gotta go! We'll talk later! Bye!
Sure! See you later!
Bye Bye
Ma'am! Help me!
I know nothing...
I know nothing. Ma'am, please help me!
Maria!
Pleasehelp...
Please don't kill me! Please...
Don't kill me! Ma'am
Help! Help!
Sis!
You wanted to drive your son to the airport
Don't promise if you can't.
We can go ourselves
Yes, I know
Sis, I'm at work.
Don't you think I want to be there...
I was really busy just now...
Bob, you've got to take responsibility.
Yourwife's gone. When will you grow up?
We're off to Australia, and you may
not see yourson fora long time.
Sis, I was really working!
Please tell Kit to come to the phone
OK! But you've go to the airport
and say goodbye properly
I'll check-in first, but I won't wait long.
Kit, it's your dad.
Hello
Kit
Daddy is on the way to the airport
You go with Auntie Jeanie first.
I'll see you there
You're lying again!
You never keep your promises
You said mommy won't leave she left anyway!
Daddy swears I'll be there!
Trust me once more, please?
Take yourtime, so daddy can catch up with you?
Let me speak to youraunt
Remember. A promise is a promise!
Yes! I know! I'll be there! Thanks! Bye!
There's nothing left!
Broke again?!
I've given you everything!
There's nothing left!
If I find anything... you're dead!
Stop! He's gone! He doesn't live here any more
What are you staring at?
What are you doing? I'll kill you!
Stop! Leave me son alone!
He ran away, go find him!
Bitch, listen to me. I'm not leaving
until I get what your husband owes.
Now that he's gone, you'll have to pay up!
You know the rules
Mommy
Let's go! Mommy
Just give me something? Anything of value left?
I can't go back empty-handed
How did it go? Did you collect?
No. She is dead broke
Where are my keys?
I've got to get to the airport
Here.
Give me some cash?
I'll need to leave town right now.
What happened?
Long story. This guy is after me
I bought a gun for protection.
Money!
Just my luck, no battery.
Hey, the gun is in your
Thank you for calling. Ourcustomer hotline
is busy right now, please call again later.
Sir, you're such an experienced
detective, any ideas?
The whiff that cures all pain;
the smell of heaven!
Cocaine
This is definitely drug related.
Wait...
The car was set on fire at 3 am. Last night!
West winds last night,
that's why the trunk is completely burnt.
You believe me?
Sure!
Sucker! I'm just bluffing
Hey, what do you think you're doing!
Look! It's Supercop Fai! Salute!
What a coincidence! Fluke Zhang!
Who do you think you're!
I'm Detective Zhang to you!
Look at the stars, Tristar Zhang.
Let me introduce everyone
This is Supercop Fai, my old supervisor
He had many stars back then, now
he's directing traffic.
What are you doing here?
Guarding the crime scene
This is evidence, take it back to my office!
Sir, traffic is separatejurisdiction.
I don't mind if I get to go home on time!
Sir, give me an evidence bag
Thanks!
Your initials
Stripping your medals definitely
improved yourtemper!
Serves you right...
for all the hard times you gave me
You begged for it back then
What are you waiting for? Go!
I'm off
Let's go!
Yes, sir!
Hello? Hello
Hello! Mister, help!
Help me! I beg you not to hang up!
Miss, please stop with the prank calls,
thanks! Bye!
Mister, please!
My name is Grace Wong.
I've been kidnapped
I don't know where I am
It was very difficult to make this connection
I beg you not to hang up
Miss, maybe you should call the police instead?
Your kidnappers seem nice enough
They even grant you access to a phone
I'm telling the truth.
They smashed the phone.
It was very difficult to rewire
to get a connection
If you hang up,
I may never be able to call again.
Please, I beg you to please don't hang up.
Stay on the line
Miss, this is not funny, please stop, bye!
Hello Kit
Daddy, my flight is at 310pm
I'll see you at the check-in counter
Remember, don't be late!
I won't let you down
I promised to be there, right?
I'll see you at the check-in counter right?!
3:10pm?
Yes, don't let me down again.
Yes! Yes! Bye Kit!
Hello Hello?
You're still on the line?
Please hang up! This is annoying now
Mister! I've been kidnapped...
and I've seen theirfaces
They're going to kill me!
You're my last chance...
Listen
I know you're a kind-hearted man.
Just give me five minutes
Just hand your phone to a policeman nearby
I'll talk to them.
OK, five minutes!
Thank you!
Tell me, what's your name?
Call me Bob
Thank you, Bob.
Turn off your engine! Officer, I'm
Your driver's license and ID please!
This woman
Turn of your engine! Now!
This woman on the phone says
she has been kidnapped.
She asked me to file a police report.
Here's my ID Talk to her
I'm police constable badge number 2004
How can I help you?
Officer, my name is Grace Wong.
My address is 125 Fulan Road
Console to PC2004
Roger, console send.
They're coming, please don't hang up!
Accident at the intersection of Eastwind
and Literary, go to location!
Got it! Going overthere now.
Miss, hello! Can you repeat that?
Hello? Hello? Hello?
Nothing?
Hello? Hello...
Stop mucking around!
She asked me to help!
Wreckless driving and false report...
I can lock you up forthat!
Sorry, officer. Sorry.
Drive careful
Yes, sir.
Hello?
Hello? Hey
Hey!
There's a police station ten minutes
away if you need to file a report
Thanks officer!
Where is it?
Hey! What game are you playing! Hello! Hello!
What? I don't understand
Where is your brother?
I don't know.
Well, you must know your brother's good friend
Grace!
Joe!
Where is Roy? Where is Roy?
I don't know.
What did they do? Why are you doing this?
It's very simple.
They've made a mistake They've been nosey.
Call him.
Stop it! Don't hurt him! Stop!
Call your brother!
Hi, I'm Roy
leave a message.
You know where he is.
I don't
I really don't know where he is
You leave me no choice!
You're crazy! You're a monster!
You've killed him! Why did you kill him!
Monster! Why?!
Your daughter is getting out of school soon?
No! Don't touch her!
Adorable kid
Please, I beg you!
Don't touch her
Tell me where is it, or
find your brother.
I'll pick up your little girl from school now...
Officer!
He's gone. Are you OK?
Was that a gun shot?
They killed Joe.
You're the only one who can save us now.
Bob, I beg you
to go get my little girl.
Your daughter?
How farare you from Hongji Primary?
Not too far I think
Go fetch her now, they're going after her
Let me go to a police station and get help
They've got guns!
I need to get to the airport
They've left already
If you don't go, she'll die...
she's only six
In that case... I'll give it a try!
Thank you
Wait, let me look at the map
Bob, you OK?!
I'm alright.
I'm on my way.
Who are those guys? What happened?
What do they want with your brother?
What did he do to them?
I know he is innocent.
He just graduated from university.
We're just a normal family
I don't understand what's going on...
What about your husband?
Maybe he messed with the wrong people?
My husband is dead.
I'm from China, and moved to
Hong Kong to open a design firm.
Just a second, I've got anothercall
Hello? Hello?
Daddy, we're on the way now.
Auntie wants me to tell you
that we'll be at aisle B.
Aisle B! I know.
Don't forget! A promise is a promise!
OK, OK! A promise is a promise
Bye
Hello? Hello?
I'm here at the school. Wait
Which floor is she on?
Up the stairs to the second floor, turn right!
Which classroom? What's her name?
Primary 1A, her name is Tinker Fong
Hurry
One more minute and they're out
Mister!
I'm the headmaster, how can I help you?
Excuse me, I'm looking for
Tinker Fong of Class 1A
You're not supposed to be up here
Why don't you come downstairs and registerfirst?
I knowbutbuttalk to her mother!
This is an emergency.
Parent or not, we've got to followthe rules.
Come with me This is very serious!
Sir
sir, just come with me downstairs.
Come with me to registerfirst.
Sir, sir, what are you doing?
Sir This is very important
TINKER FONG! Hey! Sir!
Youjust have to trust me, this is very important
Sir, stop harassing ourstudents!
Have you seen Tinker Fong?
She went downstairs
TINKER FONG!
Don and Michael...
come here! We've got trouble!
TINKER FONG!
What does she look like? How do I recognize her?
She's 12m tall. She has a ponytail.
There are bunnies on her hairclip
There are bunnies everywhere
Tinker Fong!
Hey! Hey!
Hey help!
Hey! Stop! I've called the cops already.
Didn't you see two foreigners
just kidnapped that little girl?
Stop it! Security, over here!
I'm so sorry.
They've got your little girl
You're bleeding. Stop!
Please save her!
I'm on it! I'm right behind them.
Mom! Mommy! Mommy!
Are you OK?
I'm... OK!
You know how to drive or not?!
You're the one who needs a lesson!
You don't know howto drive!
You're kidding?!
You the one who crashed into my car!
You cut into my lane without warning!
Shut up! Shut up!
My bumper is totally dented!
Just call the cops! There's nothing more to say
Cops? You think I'm scared?
Give me a second
Sorry! Sorry!
Excuse me! Excuse Me! I'm sorry!
You! Where do you think you're going?
Stop! Are you nuts! Stop!
Help!
Oh shit!
You want to kill someone?!
Someone is hurt, call the cops!
What? What's that? Stop!
Stop!
Stop! Stop!
Hello? Are you OK?
Bob! Hello!
Answer me, Bob!
Bob! What's going on?
Hello?
Hello! Bob!
Bob! What's going on?
Hello?
Bob! Hey!
Are you OK?
What a mess...
a big, bloody mess!
This guy is coming after me.
I bought a gun for protection...
Mister? You hurt? You're OK! I'll help you!
I'll call an ambulance for you!
My head is spinning
Come! Slowly!
Hey, calm down! He has a gun!
Bob!
Hello! Bob!
Hello?
Bob, did you lose them?
They... couldn't have gone far!
I'm going now...
Wait!
I've got to see my son!
Bob! Bob!
Can you still see them?
I'm going towards the same direction!
What now?!
Hello?
My phone is running out of battery!
What to do?
(Cellphone CustomerService Center)
Wait! Wait!
I've got to see my son! It'll be fine!
I need a carcharger!
Mister, sorry! Mister, excuse me!
Can I go first? I'm in a hurry!
Everybody here is in a hurry Get in line!
Get in line!
Ticket A108 to counterthree please
Please, can I
have a car chargerforthis mobile phone?
Of course, sir! What's your name sir?
I'm out ofbattery I don't have timehurry up!
Can I take a look at your phone?
Forthis model, we have a few car chargers
made in USA, Japan orChina
Which one would you like?
USA!
Ok! Please wait!
US made... plain or patterned?
What's the difference?
Patterned ones have patterns! Many patterns!
With patterns
Good choice! Please wait!
There's Batman, Tweety, or Bugs Bunny,
which one would you like?
Batman!
Let me see, let me see!
Batman - with lights or no lights?
I'll punch out your lights
if I don't get this soon.
Lights then!
Oh, one with lights is out of stock!
No lights?
Let me check
Calm down, I'm getting it now
Don't you have work to do?
You stood me up last night
I never confirmed
You did! You said you were
having dinnerwith me tonight!
I said I'd see! Get out my way!
What's there to see? Look at me!
We'll talk afterwork.
Stop torturing me!
All these girls want to go out with me
but I just want you!
Really?
Are you getting the chargerfor me?
I'm coming. I'm coming I'm getting it now.
Take care of the customerfirst.
Everyday you say tomorrow, just say yes!
I dunno. Ljust can't decide
Yes you can! Charger!
Coming, comingjust a moment!
Just say yes! I don't care! Dine with me tonight!
I'll see how I feel!
There's nothing to feel, you feel good!
Pleasejust promise me, say yes
I said I'd see!
Thanks!
How much is it?
$199!
Keep the change.
Hello?
I've got the charger...
but lost the car. Wait Taxi!
Taxi! Taxi! Taxi!
(Out of service)
Stop! Stop!
Darling, where do you want to go...
for dinner?
How about hotpot?
Hotpot?
Yes, but the smell gets into yourclothes
How about something else?
You chose, I always let you chose
Hello? Stop! Stop your car!
How about sushi? Hello! Bob!
Whateveryou want darling
Hello? Hello?
Hey!
What? A phone? Hello?
Bob?
Bob? What are you saying?
I'm not talking to you!
Mister, please give the phone to Bob
Are you nuts?! I have no idea what you're saying.
Are you yelling at me?!
Darling, I'm not yelling at you.
I'd neveryell at you...
Is this some promotional gig?
This is a new mobile model!
No, please don't hang up we're...
we've got a gift for you
Do you see a man running after yourcar?
Oh yeah!
That's it! He has a gift for you
Stop the car, he'll give you the prize
Definitely my lucky day!
Stop!
What's the prize?
Let me see
Are youjoking?
You chased me a few blocks
just to give me a charger?
Give me the phone!
Are you nuts?!
Hey! Which TVstation is this?
Where's the camera?
Hey you! Get out of my car!
Your staff got into my car!
I'm gonna file a complaint!
I'll sue yourcompany and you!
The phone is a prize! It's mine!
Give it back! Who are you yelling at?!
Sweetie, I'm not yelling at you.
This man jumped into my car, I'll tell you later!
Darling, why don't you call the cops for me!
It's Bob.
Hey! Hello?
I've never hang up on my girlfriend like this!
You explain to her!
Call her now! Explain to her!
She'll kill me! Now!
Oh! You call the shots now.
I'm sorry
Drive carefully!
I've just paid up...
Hello?
It's Bob...
I've heard it all. Thank you.
I'll try to find them...
I can only try to catch upno promises
Don't watch that stuff!
Porn gives you STD!
You fixed my mobile yet?
Yes! A lunatic
Don't drop your phone into the sink again...
attacked the principal...
of a local school today and bit his hand...
tell us what happened Mr Yu
The man is deranged
He said a student is being kidnapped.
I told him I'm calling the cops
He bit me and ran away
The suspect then went to a mobile service center
Mr Tong, can you tell us what happened?
He was very agitated at the time
He was really worked up.
He took out his gun and fired a shot
He paid $500 for a charger...
that costs $199...
and told me to keep the change
The suspect turns out to be a
generous robberwho overtips!
Support Center
Hey, Lau? It's me!
Please check a phone numberfor me
The address is 125 Fulan Road
Sure, no problem
The number is...
Thanks!
Hello! How are you?
Yes?
Ma'am, is your name Grace Wong?
Yes, how can I help you?
I'm PC2004
We spoke earliertoday?
I just want to make sure you're alright
I'm fine. I don't think we've spoken today.
Are you sure?
Of course! I'd remember if I've talked to you
I'm sorry Somejokerwas
Never mind Actually, I'm off duty.
I shouldn't be here.
I shouldjust get to the market
Is there a wet market around here? Maybe I can
ask my wife to come and meet up with me
I don't do the shopping myself...
Your maid...
only men and maids go to
the markets these days...
my wife can't cook either
I'm sorry to disturb you. I'll run along now
Don't worry, you're just doing your job.
Bye Thanks!
Bye
We have a problem! A cop came to check on us.
We need to hurry!
Got it.
Grace, I'm really sorry I
I think I've lost them.
I'll call the cops foryou...
They're back. Don't hang up...
Tinker! Tinker!
Let hergo.
She's only six. She won't say anything
She won't tell anyone.
I don't have time forthis. Give me what I want
Where is it?
What are you looking for?
I'll kill yourdaughter if you don't tell me
I really don't know
Three-Two-
I beg you...
I beg you... let us go...
I think something happened to my brother
He should be home by now
I beg you...
Since you know nothing, then I'm really sorry
Kill me! Let my daughtergo!
Don't kill a child... please...
Yeah
We just got a message, Roy had fallen
down the hills He is in Hospital.
Queen Margot.
Queen Margot Hospital
When I find your brother,
I'll arrange a proper reunion
Tinker!
Hello?
My brother is at Queen Margot Hospital
they're on theirway already.
Bob, please save him!
Again, I'll try.
I'll give it a go!
Thanks!
I'm almost there What's your brother's name?
Roy Wong 18 years old.
Honey, why are we shopping here?
Achange of scenery boosts romance!
When I retire, I want to open a cafe...
I'll cook
you'll be the cashier
what do you think?
Terrific!
We can finally put your culinary talents to use
Ma'am
How much is this salted fish?
$68 per kilo.
Good choice!
This is most delicious!
My name is Grace Wong.
I'm fine. I don't think we've spoken today.
$68 please.
Do you want anything else?
What's bothering you?
Why don't you see if we need something else.
I have to make a call.
Can you give me a discount if I buy more??
Sure, sure!
Lau, it's me.
Can you give me that number again?
Sure, hold on.
The number is 37499035.
Thanks!
This is Grace. I'm not available right now
please leave a message afterthe tone.
Thanks
She is a Mandarin speaker, Mandarin...
If something is bothering you...
go take care of it
What about you?
I'm not a kid. I can take care of myself.
OK, finish the shopping.
When I come home, I'll cook dinner!
OK.
Thanks darling.
Go.
Ma'am
excuse me... I've a question
I'm looking fora patient name Roy Wong
When was he admitted?
This morning
This morning, Roy Wong, please wait.
Yes, he was...
really agitated
He then took out a gun
and snatched a carcharger!
Did he take any cash?
Can you please hurry?
Just give me a moment.
As a professional customer service agent,
my instinct tells me that he's crazy
The suspect turns out to be a
generous robberwho leaves a tip!
Stop! Don't move!
Don't move!
Stop!
Don't move! Hands in the air!
Don't move! Police!
Hands in the air!
Stop!
Hey! What do you think you're doing?
Don't move!
Stop!
Put your hands behind your head!
Don't move! Hands in the air!
Senior Inspector
We're Interpol, sorry about the misunderstanding
What's going on?
Interpol?
They're Interpol
I'm really confused now. Who are the bad guys?
Interpol? That's impossible!
You've got to find my brother We'll know then
Hurry!
Get up, let's go
What are you doing?
We're friends.
My leg... ouch! My leg!
You're in great danger
Some Interpol or kidnappers
are looking foryou...
Excuse me miss
May I help you?
Where is bed numberone?
Here, talk to your sister
and you'll understand...
Hello?
Roy?! Hello!
What!
You're not Roy!
Man, she's looking for Roy!
I don't have a sister.
How can you not have a sister?
You're not Roy Wong? Roy...
Just my luck...
I'm so sorry. I made a mistake.
Total my car last night
Overthere
Thank you
Definitely not my day
I don't have a sister...
I've a brother
So what if I don't have a sister...
Yourfriend died horribly
Do you want tojoin him?
Where is it?
I don't know.
Do you want your sister and niece
to end up like yourfriend?
Take me to it!
What are you doing? He can't leave yet.
We're Interpol He has information we need.
The police will explain later.
They've got him
Sis!
Roy!
Are you OK? Where is Tinker?
I don't know. They took her.
Are you OK? Roy! Sis! Sis!
Give me the camera and I'll let your sister go.
I don't know where it is.
I fell and passed out
I need to retrace my steps to find my backpack
Go find it. No funny business.
Now!
Go!
Bob, are you there?
Where is my brother?
They're going up the hill
I'm not sure what they're doing
Are there a lot of people flying planes?
Yes!
He likes flying planes here
Whateverthey're looking for,
it's got to be nearby
You've got to get it first
If they find it, that's the end.
I think it's here
Watch out! My plane is new!
No worries, I'm a pro!
Watch out! We're going to crash.
Found it!
Don't move! Come here!
Stand back
Here! Get down!
No! Please don't! Help!
Help! Someone fired a gun!
Honey! I'll love you foreternity...
and protect you always
Hey, hey!
What do you want?
Hey! Hey
Once I get to safety, I'll call you
Bob! Hello!
Hello?
Grace, hello?
Bob?
Hello?
Hello? Hello...
Bob!
Faster!
Help! Help!
Someone help!
Help! Help! Anyone there?
Help me! Help!
(Clear out, leave now)
Police! You're shooting at an officer.
Surrenderyourweapon or I'll have to shoot you
The numberyou dialed is invalid
Please try again.
What are you doing? You little BITCH!
You still wanna play?
Do you want to play?
Sorry, if you don't want to die, don't move!
TinkerTinker
Tinker
Call out to me Tinker!
Mommy
Tinker!
MommyMommy!
Mommy
TinkerMommy is coming!
Tinkerdon't crymommy is here!
Tinkerdon't cry
Mommy
MommyMommy!
Mommy loves you!
Mommy has come to rescue you!
Let's go! Quick!
Hurry mom!
Let's go!
Mommy! Mommy they're coming!
Mommy! Let's go!
Hey! Focus on the planes, not me!
What is that?
Tong, pack up the drugs and
dispose of the bodies!
Hey! You!
They saw us! Run!
Hurry! Run! Faster...
(Missed call from Grace)
Who were you talking to?
Astranger. Honest
You told him to intervene!
Please let them go
You can do whatever you want with me.
If you leave now, you still have time
Did you think you can win?
I never play to lose.
I won't kill you
I'll kill those you love.
Forthe rest of your life
you can remember how your
daughterand brother died...
The phone is smashed...
I can't reach him anymore
If a loved one dies,
perhaps you'll do the right thing
Roy! Roy!
No! No!
Tinker! No!
No... please!
I don't know how to find him!
I really don't know how to find him!
Hello?
Hello! I want to speak to Grace NOW!
And you are?
Your father!
It's none of your business
Tell Grace to come to the phone.
It's you You're the one who took my camera?
I don't want to talk to you!
I want to talk to Grace! Now!
You want your video?
The one shows you killing these people?
Let me talk to Grace.
You're not calling the shots here!
Give me the camera or I'll kill them all
You're not calling the shots either
Tell Grace to come to the phone...
or I'll take the video
to the police right now.
Hello?
Mister, wait a second.
Bob, it's me.
Grace? Are you OK?
Thank you
Not yet I'm in a lot of trouble also
The cops are looking for me
I'll tell them to go to take you to the airport
I'll think of something by then.
Got it!
I need a favorfrom you.
If anything happens to me
please tell my son
that for once in my life
I've done what I set out to do.
What next, Mr Hero?
Go to the airport now. I'll call you
The doorwas pried open
We found jewelry on the victim
Wow, what happened?! Killing an Interpol agent
How do you plan to explain this?
Sir, someone kidnapped the ownerof this house.
She's probably in great danger
Who do you think you are?
You're not a detective anymore
In fact, you're under investigation!
You've seen the place
Obviously something is wrong.
You WERE my supervisor
Stop telling me what to do.
There must be more of them.
Are you one of them?!
You two broke in to rob the house
Killed the maid
Your partner got greedy so you killed hertoo?
That's my theory
Forold time's sake,
I'm not locking you up, PC2004...
Even if you've nothing to do with this
An off-duty cop trespassing on private property
You'll lose your last medal
You don't have anymore to lose
Take anotherstatement
Make sure it's satisfactory
Yes, sir.
Commander Wong is here.
Fool, why not keep him waiting until midnight?
(Abrupt change, go to airport now)
Hello?
Kit!
Daddy! Where are you?
Listen...
I need to rescue someone. I'm on my way
Wait for me! You understand?
You're lying. You're not going to make it
It's almost time!
I'm on my way...
I'm coming... at rocket speed...
Let me talk to him
No show again?!
I'm giving you five more minutes.
Next time, you'll have to fly out to see him
Bye!
(Message from Michelle)
(I'm off to the airport.
Where should we meet up?)
(Terminal One)
Yes!
Hello?
Little Zhang, Master Fai here...
I thought I told you to file a statement?
Where are you?
Listen...
I've solid leads that link the burnt car...
missing house owner,
and dead Interpol agent
It's none of your damn business
Get back here right now
You believe me?
You know who's behind all this?
Not yet, but I'd find out soon enough
You believe me?
You've got evidence?
Yes Do you believe me?
I believe you What do you want?
Asalute for Master Fai!
Master Fai
You're an asshole.
Airport. Hurry Don't screw up
I'd call you if I need you
Hello?
You watch your mouth!
If it wasn't me, you'd have nothing.
I think he took the camera.
60397043
You betterfind him!
See you at the airport.
Robin, wait for my order
Kit!
Hello
We're here. Where are you?
Hostages?
Of course we brought them
How do you want to do this?
Go to Parking Lot 2, I'll tell you what to do
No problem.
Drive them to parking lot numbertwo.
Give me the camera and I'll let them go!
I want to speak to Grace
Friend, listen... there's nothing in this for you
You know who we are...
there's no way you can win
It's time! We've got to go!
Let's do a deal
Tell me how much and I'll see what we can do.
Let's talk about this face-to-face.
Let's meet!
OK boss, I've got them here in the parking lot
We're here. What now?
I'll tell you after I speak with her!
OK.
Hold on
Bob? It's me We're at the parking lot
Hello? Hello?
Hello?
Are you here yet?
Yes! You found them yet?
Not yet its confirmed that the suspect is here.
Did you bring a full team?
Relax! Don't do anything without my order!
Tong, you were closest to him
What does he look like?
I was behind him
Chinese, dark hair, glasses,
brown jacket, 1.8 metertall.
What's up?
Sorry
Hello?
Satisfied? You spoke with her.
Now give me the camera and I'll release them.
I'm calling the shots!
I'll tell you what to do!
You can see the car.
Tell them to turn towards the exit
Roll down the window and I want to see them
Turn the cartowards the exit,
roll down the windows
Search the departure area.
He has a view of the parking lot
Copy! Copy that!
Get out of my way!
Turn the car around
He's on the move Try the opposite direction
Happy now?
Stop jerking me around.
See the patrol car parked straight ahead.
Let them go.
Once they get inside, I'll give you your video.
No deal
Goods must changed hands at the same time.
I'm calling the shots!
If you don't let them go, I'll take the video
to the TVstation and get it broadcasted!
Let them go!
Let them go.
Tong, I've got him.
He is heading back towards the escalator,
in the lobby!
Help!
Miss, what's wrong?
Officer, help!
Let go!
Help!
Agun!
Let go! Let go
Police! Run!
Out of the way!
Get down! Down! Now!
Get out of the way!
Get out of the way! Get out of here!
Hey! Fluke Zhang!
Drop yourweapons!
Drop yourweapons! Drop yourweapons!
What are you doing?
We're Interpol He's our suspect.
We found the drugs.
We know you killed the dealers
and stole their goods!
Drop yourweapons!
Lock them up and take them to the car!
Sir, I've the video showing
they killed those men!
There are three hostages in the car park.
We've rescued them, don't worry
Master Fai, thank you.
Lucky bastard!
Yes! Yes!
Jack, take Fai here to the first aid
station and get him cleaned up.
Yes, sir.
Try not to cut me off the next time...
you see me drive by
Everything's fine now
Where's the evidence?
I hid it in the men's room
Sorry, police at work, no entry.
Sir!
How's are the hostages doing?
Dunno
Officer, what's happening?
Officer Officer
It was none of your god damn business
Why did you have to interfere?
Miss Wong, please wait.
Detectives are on theirway
Shut up! Stay still!
Must be hard reporting to Zhang?
Which precinct are you from?
When did youjoin the force?
Forgot to give this to Zhang...
Hey, it's evidence
Go, just go
(Taking care of witness & evidence now.)
(Rendez-vous at lobby men's room.)
Terrible manners
Help!
You know the game...
Russian roulette?
You lose, you die!
Help!
Help! Help!
Fluke Zhang, why did I trust you!
Get down!
Go!
Want to be a hero huh?
Here's the truth
I'm the one who serves truejustice!
I kill drug lords
They deserve to die!
Show yourface!
Call me a fluke?!
Why can't youjust let things be?
Damn!
This is the heroic death you're looking for
Die!
You recognize this?
The video of you serving justice!
Stop!
Guess this takes us to overtime
I lose, give it to me.
I'm sending this to the police. I'm
I'm taking you down with me
Time's up!
No!
Mommy
Bob?
Miss, are you alright? We're cops!
Call an ambulance!
Yes, sir.
You, guard the scene. The others come with me
Thank you
Keep the press out of the way!
It's you! Stand up!
You're under arrest for robbery!
Turn around!
Your hands behind your back
Hey...
Hey, Fai! What are you doing?
He's one of us One of the good guys! Let him go.
Yes, but I've got to follow protocols...
What protocols?! Let me handle it...
But
But what?! He's a good guy! Go now!
Sorry sir.
Thank you
Thanks for believing in me
No need to thank me. Just doing my job!
See what you've done
looks like I'd be on along medical leave
Good business for my doctor
Look, I should thank you
Years of pent-up anger
all purged now
Feels great
Looks like my stars and medals are coming back
Thanks for sending the video to the police
You go bask in the limelight
I need to run home to cook my wife dinner
let's not meet again
Hey, one more thing... what do you do?
I'm a debt collector...
Batman is a more suitable calling!
This is a live broadcast from the airport
According to our sources,
this man has been secretly...
helping the police since early afternoon
It's daddy!
It's daddy! It's daddy!
Look! It's daddy!
Hello?
Bob! Thanks forsaving me and my family
Thank you
I made a promise
You won't take my call again, will you?
If you're calling for help, no thanks!
If you want dinner,
I'd consider
Kit! Kit!
Daddy! Daddy!
Kit! Daddy!
THE END
Subtitles by: