[ Birds Twittering ]
[ Twittering Continues ]
[ People Conversing,
Indistinct ]
[ Children Laughing,
Chattering ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
HURRY UP !
HEY, WAIT !
WAIT FOR ME !
[ Continues Shouting ]
HURRY !
[ Insect Buzzing ]
[ Meows ]
[ Woman Screaming ]
NO !  AAH !
[ Woman Weeping ]
[ Baby Crying ]
[ Crying Continues ]
YOUR DAUGHTER, SIR.
[ Crying ]
[ Murmuring ]
[ Crying Stops ]
YOU'LL BE WITH
OUR SON IN HEAVEN.
[ Sobbing ]
GOOD AFTERNOON.
GOOD DAY TO YOU,
DOCTOR.
FATHER'S HOME !
CATHERINE,
QUIETLY, PLEASE.
FATHER !
CATHERINE.
[ Grunts, Chuckles ]
I SEE YOUR INSTRUCTION OF
BEHAVIOR BEFITTING A YOUNG LADY
GOES ON, BUSINESS AS USUAL.
OH, PLEASE DON'T BE ANGRY
WITH AUNT LAVINIA, FATHER.
SHE TRIED TO STOP ME,
BUT MY HEART BEAT MY BREAST...
WITH SUCH
A VOLUPTUOUS SWELL.
TO HAVE A DAUGHTER
WITH SUCH HIGHBROW TASTE...
IN DRESS AND LITERATURE,
AND AT SUCH A YOUNG AGE, WELL.
AND IT IS YOU I HAVE TO THANK,
DEAR SISTER.
COME, FATHER.
YES, YES.
HERE YOU GO.
[ Choking ]
OH, FATHER,
I'M SO SORRY.
IT WAS A RASPBERRY.
ON THE CONTINENT, PEOPLE PUT--
WE'RE IN NEW YORK.
AND IN NEW YORK,
PORT IS UNADORNED.
IS IT TOO MUCH TO ASK
THAT THERE BE ONE THING
NOT OVERDONE IN THIS HOUSEHOLD ?
- [ Choking ]
- SURPRISE !
[ Together ]
HAPPY BIRTHDAY, DR. AUSTIN.
SURPRISE.
[ Party Chattering ]
[ Choking Continues ]
EXCUSE ME, I--
[ Clears Throat ]
MY WINE WENT--
WENT DOWN THE WRONG WAY.
[ Woman ]
COME ALONG, DEAR.
THAT SHOULD BE LOVELY.
[ Chattering Continues ]
NOW DON'T BE NERVOUS.
WE'VE REHEARSED THIS
A THOUSAND TIMES.
SHH, PLEASE.
SIT DOWN.
SWEETHEART ?
[ Chattering Stops ]
* [ Piano ]
* THERE--
[ Clears Throat ]
-  [ Off-Key ]
* THERE--
- [ Whispering ]
[ Whispering ]
NOW COME ON.
* [ Piano ]
[ Off-Key ]
* THERE--
[ Whimpers ]
[ Trickling Sound ]
[ Whispering, Giggling ]
[ Giggling Continues ]
OH, AUSTIN.
SIT DOWN.
COME WITH ME.
SHH !  SHH !
MAUREEN !  MAUREEN, THERE'S BEEN
AN ACCIDENT.  DO SOMETHING.
ALICE, WOULD YOU LIKE
TO RECITE SOMETHING FOR US ?
DO YOU WANT YOUR CAKE ?
GOOD NIGHT, CATHERINE.
GOOD NIGHT.
GOOD BIRD.  GOOD BIRD.
[ Man, Children
Chattering ]
AH, GOOD AFTERNOON,
DOCTOR.
GOOD AFTERNOON.
FATHER'S HOME !
CATHERINE, UNLIKE
THE FOURTH OF JULY,
THE OCCASION
OF YOUR FATHER COMING HOME
IS AN EVERYDAY OCCURRENCE.
PLEASE DO NOT JANGLE
MY NERVES SO ARBITRARILY.
CATHERINE !
[ Stomping ]
GOOD AFTERNOON,
DR. SLOPER.
GOOD AFTERNOON, FATHER.
[ Panting ]
DID YOU FORGET THE PARTY
AT AUNT ELIZABETH'S ?
MY DEAR CHILD, THE WORLD
WAS CREATED IN SIX DAYS.
SURELY WE MORTALS CAN PREPARE
FOR A GATHERING IN THREE HOURS.
[ Laughing ]
FATHER, THERE IS
SO MUCH TO DO.
PLEASE, I BEG YOU,
ALLOW ME TO ATTEND MYSELF.
I FEAR WHAT WILL HAPPEN
IF I KEEP YOU FROM YOUR
PREPARATIONS A MOMENT LONGER.
[ Laughing ]
CATHERINE !
[ Door Opens ]
HOW LONG COULD IT TAKE FOR ONE
WOMAN TO MINISTER TO HERSELF ?
NOW, AUSTIN, CHOOSING ONE'S
FIRST EVENING GOWN ALONE...
IS A GREAT EVENT
FOR A YOUNG GIRL.
PLEASE... BE GENTLE.
IF A PRELUDE IS NECESSARY,
IT MUST BE BAD INDEED.
SO THIS MAGNIFICENT CREATURE
IS MY CHILD.
I'LL GO CHANGE.
YOU'VE TAKEN UP
ENOUGH TIME ALREADY.
COME ALONG.
YAH !  YAH !
GOOD DAY,
MRS. THORNBRED.
GOOD DAY.
OH, IT'S UNCLE AUSTIN.
UNCLE AUSTIN.
[ Chattering ]
[ Girls ]
UNCLE AUSTIN !  UNCLE AUSTIN !
LAVINIA.
OH.
OH, ELIZABETH.
HELLO,
AUNT LAVINIA.
WHAT A HAVEN OF PEACE
AND TRANQUILITY.
OH, DEAR BROTHER,
THAT'S A SURE SIGN
OF GETTING OLD.
IT DOES SEEM THAT
THE YOUNG GET MORE RAUCOUS
AS WE GET OLDER.
IT'S DELIGHTFUL.
ANYTHING SHORT OF HIS OWN CHAIR
IN HIS FRONT ROOM
SEEMS VIOLENT TO AUSTIN.
LAVINIA HAS NOT
COTTONED ONTO THE FACT
THAT SHE'S A SHEEP.
* [ Men Singing ]
LOVELY, DEAR.
OH, I DON'T THINK
FATHER APPROVES.
WELL, DON'T LET THAT
TROUBLE YOU UNDULY, MY DEAR.
IF THERE'S ONE THING
I'VE LEARNED OF MY BROTHER
AFTER ALL THESE YEARS,
IT'S THAT HE'S GENERALLY
NOT THE APPROVING SORT.
COME.  MARIAN IS
EAGER TO SEE YOU.
* THERE THEY ARE
THERE THEY ARE
THERE THEY ARE *
* [ Continues ]
OH, SEE HOW
SHE BEAMS ?
THEY MUST BE
VERY MUCH IN LOVE.
DEAR CHILD, HE'S A STOCKBROKER.
HE'LL MAKE A FINE HUSBAND.
THAT IS ALL
MARRYING REQUIRES.
I OFTENTIMES THINK
IT'S EASIER TO BE BASIC.
ONE'S NEEDS
ARE SO SIMPLE.
A POLKA !
WHY DO THEY DO THAT TO ME ?
MARIAN,
CATHERINE'S HERE.
CATHERINE.
A NEW DRESS ?
[ All Chattering
Simultaneously ]
ONE MUST TAKE CARE
OF OTHER'S NEEDS
BEFORE ONE'S OWN.
CAN YOU IMAGINE ANYTHING
MORE DISAGREEABLE ?
[ Elizabeth ]
CONGRATULATIONS, MY DEAR.
MAY I ?
[ Chattering Continues ]
IF I WANTED TO BE A PIONEER,
I'D SETTLE IN MINNESOTA.
ISN'T SHE PRETTY ?
I THINK IT'S BEASTLY
WE CAN'T DANCE.
I KNOW.
[ Man ]
SO WE'LL BUY A NEW HOUSE
EVERY THREE OR FOUR YEARS.
WE'LL KEEP MOVING UP.
IS IT TRUE IT'S
ALL THE RAGE IN PARIS ?
-  MORRIS.  MORRIS.
- WHAT IS IT YOU WANT ME
TO DO NOW MARIAN ?
YOU MUST TAKE CATHERINE
OUTSIDE TO DANCE.
IF YOUR WIFE-TO-BE IS THIS
DEMANDING OF ME, DEAR COUSIN,
CAN YOU IMAGINE--
[ Man ]
OH, YES, I CAN.
SOMEONE HAS TO DEMAND OF YOU.
IT MAY HELP TO BUILD
SOME LONG-AWAITED CHARACTER.
YOU SEE WHAT YOU'VE DONE ?
YOU'VE MADE POOR MISS--
MISS--
[ Giggling ]
ANSWER HIM, PLEASE.
HE'S CONCEITED ENOUGH
TO BELIEVE HE HAS
MADE YOU SPEECHLESS.
THIS IS CATHERINE SLOPER,
MARIAN'S COUSIN.
THIS IS MORRIS TOWNSEND.
SHALL WE ?
COME.
* [ Chamber Orchestra ]
[ Laughing, Chattering ]
ONE, TWO, THREE,
FOUR, FIVE, SIX.
IF I CAN HAVE YOUR ATTENTION
UP HERE, I PROMISE YOU
I'LL TAKE CARE OF DOWN THERE.
[ Both Grunting ]
OH, FORGIVE ME.
I'VE BEEN OFF THE DANCE FLOOR
FOR FAR TOO LONG, IT SEEMS.
HERE. LET'S TRY
THIS DANGEROUS SPORT.
HERE.
PLEASE SIT DOWN.
OH.
I'LL GET SOME
REFRESHMENTS, SHALL I ?
OH.
* [ Continues ]
OH, GRACIOUS.
- MY DEAR, WHAT ARE YOU DOING,
HIDING IN THE BUSHES ?
- NO--
YOU MUST COME OUT WHERE
THE YOUNG MEN CAN SEE YOU--
NO, NO, NO.
OH, MY.
I D-- I DON'T BELIEVE
WE'VE BEEN INTRODUCED.
MORRIS TOWNSEND.
COUSIN TO ARTHUR.  I BEGGED
MISS SLOPER TO TAKE PITY ON ME.
I'M AFRAID, AS A DANCER,
I MAKE A VERY GOOD HORSEMAN.
WELL, MR. TOWNSEND, I CAME
LOOKING FOR MY NIECE...
BECAUSE THERE WERE
SEVERAL YOUNG MEN
SEARCHING FOR HER FRANTICALLY.
SHE'S BEEN IGNORING
HER DANCE CARD SHAMELESSLY.
HOWEVER, IF SHE'S PROMISED
TO KEEP YOU COMPANY,
I'LL TRY TO KEEP THEM
AT BAY A LITTLE LONGER.
NOW, I'VE MET THE MOST CHARMING
WOMEN HERE TONIGHT, BUT THEY
ALL COME FROM THE SAME FAMILY.
IT'S REMARKABLE.
[ Gasping ]
I'M GOING TO PRETEND
I DIDN'T FIND YOU, CATHERINE.
BUT YOU MUST NOT MONOPOLIZE HER,
MR. TOWNSEND.
OH, NO.
WELL, I SEE OUR TIME IS LIMITED.
I MUST MAKE THE MOST OF IT.
I DON'T WANT TO EARN
THE ENMITY OF EVERY MAN HERE.
PLEASE DON'T MOCK ME,
MR. TOWNSEND.
I'VE OFFENDED YOU.
NO.  NO, I--
MR. ROBBINS.  HE'S--
HE'S--
DO YOU SEE ?
AND, UH, MR. ALMOND.
HE'S-- HE'S MY--
[ Laughing ]
HE'S MY UNCLE.
A WOMAN WITHOUT GUILE.
WHAT A RARITY.
[ Laughing ]
GUILE ?  ME ?
NO.
I MEAN, A WOMAN
OF SUCH UNCOMMON GRACE HAS--
HAS NO NEED OF GUILE.
PLEASE DON'T BANISH ME.
YOU SEE, I'VE BEEN AWAY
FOR A VERY LONG TIME.
AND IF YOU LEAVE ME, I-- I'LL
BE FORCED TO MAKE MY OWN WAY...
IN-- IN THIS STRANGE AND
I'M QUITE SURE DANGEROUS WORLD.
I KNEW
I HADN'T BEEN MISTAKEN.
YOU ARE INDEED GRACIOUS--
FAR BEYOND WHAT I DESERVE,
I'M SURE.
YOU ARE SO BEAUTIFUL, I--
[ Laughing ]
OH, THANK YOU.
[ Moans ]
OH, ALLOW ME.
[ Sighs ]
MISS SLOPER.
MISS--
- WHO'S THAT YOUNG FOREIGNER
TALKING TO CATHERINE ?
-  THAT'S NO FOREIGNER.
BUT YOU'RE RIGHT
IN THINKING HIM ONE.
- HE LOOKS QUITE BRILLIANT.
-  HE'S ARTHUR'S COUSIN, AUSTIN.
SEVERAL TIMES REMOVED,
OF COURSE.
YOU SEE, THERE ARE TOWNSENDS,
AND THEN THERE ARE TOWNSENDS.
THE YOUNG BRANCHES,
ELDER BRANCHES, OF COURSE.
INFERIOR BRANCHES ?
WELL, THAT'S THE WAY IT IS
WITH ALL ROYAL LINES.
[ Marian ]
ARTHUR.
EXCUSE ME.
YOUR MOTHER
WANTS TO SEE US BOTH.
AUSTIN, YOU MUST
CHOOSE YOUR OPPONENTS
WITH MORE DISCRETION.
UH, GO FIND
ALICE, GIRLS.
OTHERWISE, THERE'S
NO SPORT TO SLAUGHTER.
* [ Violin ]
THANK YOU.
GOOD-BYE, MY DEAR.
MISS SLOPER,
YOU DROPPED THIS.
[ Austin ]
THAT CHARMING YOUNG MAN
WAS UNCOMMONLY TENDER,
LAVINIA,
WHENEVER YOU CONVERSED.
HE HAD
SUCH A DEVOTED AIR.
MY DEAR BROTHER,
THE DEVOTION WAS NOT TO ME.
IT WAS OF CATHERINE
HE SPOKE.
SO HE'S IN LOVE WITH
THIS REGAL CREATURE, THEN ?
OH, FATHER !
HE DIDN'T SAY THAT.
BUT HE ADMIRED HER DRESS.
IT MUST BE LOVE, OR HE THINKS
SHE HAS 80,000 A YEAR.
I DON'T BELIEVE HE THINKS
OF THAT.  HE'S TOO REFINED.
HE MUST BE
TREMENDOUSLY REFINED.
YES.
YES, HE--  YES.
MISS SLOPER--
[ Surprised Shout ]
OH !
I'M SORRY.  I'M--
I'M SO SORRY.
YOUR MUSIC.
[ Sighs ]
[ Chuckles ]
MY-- MY CLUMSINESS IN YOUR
PRESENCE IS BECOMING LEGENDARY.
EX-- EXCUSE ME.
I'M SORRY
TO HAVE BOTHERED YOU.
YEAH, I WAS-- I WAS JUST
SO HAPPY TO SEE YOU AGAIN.
AND I-- I'M SORRY.
YOU KNOW, I DON'T
ALWAYS KNOW HOW TO--
PLEASE ACCEPT
MY APOLOGIES.
MR. TOWNSEND--
OH !
SORRY.
OH, MY !
YOU'RE SO BLESSED
TO HAVE A TALENT FOR MUSIC.
OH, I HAVE NO TALENT.
JUST, UM, APPRECIATION.
YEARNING.
OH, CAN IT BE
THAT I HAVE FOUND A TWIN ?
YOU-- YOU SEE, MUSIC IS SUCH
AN INTENSE LOVE OF MINE...
THAT MY WEAKNESS
IN THE EXECUTION OF IT IS
THE CAUSE OF GREAT PAIN...
AND, AT TIMES,
GREATER EMBARRASSMENT.
Y-- YOU SEE, I REFUSE
TO ACCEPT THAT I AM SO
UNTALENTED AT SOMETHING...
THAT TOUCHES ME
SO DEEPLY,
I-- I SIMPLY BELIEVE
THAT I'VE NOT YET...
DISCOVERED THE KEY
THAT WILL UNLOCK THE GIFT.
I KNOW.
REALLY ?
YES.  THAT--
THAT'S THE EXACT THING.
EVERY NIGHT I INCLUDE
A MENTION OF IT IN MY PRAYERS.
[ Laughs ]
I THOUGHT
THAT I WAS ALONE.
OH.
DO YOU SUPPOSE
IT'S POSSIBLE THAT WE COULD--
I-- I LIVE WITH MY SISTER
AND-- AND HER FIVE CHILDREN
WHILE I SEEK EMPLOYMENT.
AND OUR SITUATION
DOESN'T ALLOW...
FOR SUCH FRIVOLITY
AS MUSICAL INSTRUMENTS.
BUT DO YOU SUPPOSE THAT IT WOULD
EVER BE POSSIBLE THAT WE COULD--
YOU ARE BRAVE.
I AM NOT, SO MUCH.
I SO WANT TO FIND FAVOR
WITH YOU.  PLEASE--
[ Gasps ]
PLEASE-- PLEASE DON'T BELIEVE
THAT I AM SO MUCH A FOOL
AS I APPEAR WITH YOU.
I CAN'T SEEM--
I CAN'T SEEM TO--
HERE'S ANOTHER.
GOOD DAY.
MR. TOWNSEND ?
[ Clears Throat ]
WE WOULD BE PLEASED TO EXTEND
THE USE OF OUR PIANO.
IS TOMORROW TOO SOON...
FOR OUR SLOPER-TOWNSEND
MUSIC SOCIETY TO COMMENCE ?
NO.  NOT--
NOT TOO SOON.  YES.
* [ Piano ]
* [ Continues ]
[ Whispers, Indistinct ]
[ Whispering ]
YOUR AUNT IS LEAVING.
YOU'LL HAVE TO EXCUSE ME,
MR. TOWNSEND.
I HAVE THE MOST
FORTUITOUS HEADACHE.
OF COURSE.
EXCUSE ME.
AUNT ?
HMM ?
I CAN HARDLY BE AN AUDIENCE
TO YOU AND MR. TOWNSEND FOREVER.
I'VE NEGLECTED MY DUTIES
SHAMELESSLY THESE PAST WEEKS.
BESIDES, MOST YOUNG LADIES CRAVE
TIME ALONE WITH THEIR BEAUX.
HE IS NOT MY BEAU.
MR. TOWNSEND'S INTEREST
IS IN THE PIANO.
ACCOMPLISHED AS MR. TOWNSEND
MAY BE IN MANY AREAS,
HE'S NO FREDERIC CHOPIN.
AND EVEN MR. CHOPIN WOULD BE
HARD-PRESSED TO TRAVEL...
FIVE TIMES A WEEK FOR FOUR WEEKS
ACROSS TOWN IN AN OMNIBUS...
TO PRACTICE ON AN INSTRUMENT
SO IN NEED OF TUNING.
BESIDES, I HAVE
THE YOUNG MAN'S CONFIDENCE.
HE'S COME A-COURTING.
[ Giggles ]
TAKE MR. BYRON'S ADVICE:
"BE WARM, BUT PURE.
BE AMOROUS, BUT BE CHASTE."
NO, NO !
GO.  GO.
ARE YOU AFRAID
TO BE ALONE WITH ME ?
HMM ?
MM, MM, NO.
JUST DOES NOT SEEM
QUITE PROPER.
IS PROPER
SO IMPORTANT TO YOU ?
IS A STROLL
IN THE PARK PROPER ?
WILL THAT
MAKE YOU HAPPY ?
YOU KNOW,
I ASK FOR NOTHING MORE.
EH, WE-- YOU DO.
[ Chattering ]
GOOD AFTERNOON,
DOCTOR.
GOOD AFTERNOON.
HOW DO YOU DO ?
AFTERNOON.
LOVELY DAY, DOCTOR.
THEY'RE RATHER HUMBLE,
I'M AFRAID.
[ Catherine ]
NO, THEY'RE LOVELY.
OH, BUT THEY PALE
IN COMPARISON TO YOU.
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughs ]
MAUREEN SAID YOU WANTED
TO SEE ME, AUSTIN ?
WOULD YOU CARE
FOR SOME PORT ?
OH, MY.
[ Laughs ]
THERE.
THIS IS MY FAVORITE
TIME OF DAY,
WATCHING THE SUN GO DOWN...
AS THE CITY WINDS TO A CLOSE,
SO PEACEFUL AND QUIET.
IT QUITE LULLS ONE...
INTO A SENSE
OF RESTFUL TRANQUILITY.
[ Laughs ]
ABSOLUTELY FALSE, AS IT HAPPENS,
BECAUSE DARKNESS IS FALLING,
AND MY DAUGHTER IS RUNNING WILD
IN A PUBLIC PARK WITH A MAN;
A VIRTUAL STRANGER TO ME, BUT
BY ALL APPEARANCES NOT TO HER.
OH, AUSTIN--
ARE YOUR DUTIES
TOO NUMEROUS, LAVINIA ?
LET US TAKE THEIR NUMBER,
SHALL WE ?
WELL, THERE'S, UH,
CHAPERONING CATHERINE.
AND THERE'S, UH--
WE-WELL, THAT'S IT.
SHOULD I PERHAPS
HIRE YOU AN ASSISTANT ?
I-- I WOULDN'T WANT
TO TAKE ADVANTAGE...
OF OUR FAMILIAL BOND
BY OVERWORKING YOU.
[ Door Opens ]
[ Catherine Stomping ]
OH, FATHER, ISN'T THAT
A BEAUTIFUL DAY ?
PERHAPS IT'S TIME
I MADE THE ACQUAINTANCE
OF YOUR YOUNG MAN.
YES !
[ Lavinia Chuckles ]
SO IN SHORT, I WOULD SAY
THAT IF A GONDOLA DOESN'T COME
EQUIPPED WITH A GONDOLIER,
WALKING IS A VERY GOOD PLAN,
UNLESS, OF COURSE,
YOU LIKE TO SWIM.
[ All Laughing ]
OH, MORRIS, MORRIS,
TELL-- TELL DR. SLOPER...
ABOUT THE TIME IN SWITZERLAND
WHEN YOU TOOK IT INTO YOUR HEAD
TO SCALE THE ALPS.
I'M SURE THE TELLING WOULD
BENEFIT FROM A GOOD CIGAR AND,
UH, SOME EXCELLENT PORT WINE.
WHAT DO YOU THINK,
MR. TOWNSEND ?
OH, I-- I THINK A STORY
CAN'T HELP BUT BE IMPROVED
BY SUCH ACCOUTREMENTS.
SINCE YOU BOTH KNOW THE STORY,
IT CAN'T BE THAT MUCH
OF AN INCONVENIENCE.  SHALL WE ?
YES, OF COURSE.
EXCUSE ME.
[ Whispering ]
AUNT.  NO, NO.
[ Men Murmuring ]
[ Silently ]
I'M SURE YOU HAVE ANY NUMBER
OF DELIGHTFUL STORIES
THAT WOMEN ARE ENTHRALLED WITH.
NOW IT IS YOU WHO ARE
BEING KIND.  [ Chuckles ]
[ Chuckles ]
THERE.
THANK YOU.
I HEAR YOU'RE LOOKING
FOR A POSITION.
WHAT ARE YOU FIT FOR ?
NOT VERY MUCH,
I'M AFRAID.
I HAVE ONLY A GOOD RIGHT ARM,
AS THEY SAY IN MELODRAMAS.
IN ADDITION TO YOUR GOOD RIGHT
ARM, YOU HAVE YOUR SUBTLE BRAIN
AND AMAZING PHYSIOGNOMY.
WELL, I DON'T KNOW
HOW TO ANSWER IN THE FACE
OF SUCH GENEROUS OBSERVATION.
YOU ADVISE ME, THEN,
NOT TO DESPAIR ?
I SHOULD BE SORRY TO ADMIT
THAT ANY ROBUST,
WELL-DISPOSED YOUNG MAN
NEED EVER DESPAIR.
WERE YOU KINDLY INTENDING
TO PROPOSE SOMETHING
TO MY ADVANTAGE ?
IT OCCURS TO ME
I SOMETIMES HEAR OF POSITIONS
OUTSIDE OF NEW YORK.
MM.  I'M AFRAID
I COULDN'T MANAGE THAT.
YOU SEE, I'M-- I'M MY SISTER'S
ONLY LIVING RELATIVE.
SHE'S A WIDOW,
AND I'M PROVIDING AN EDUCATION
FOR HER FIVE CHILDREN.
I AM SURE YOU MUST BE
A GREAT COMFORT TO HER
IN THE CIRCUMSTANCES.
AS, UH, HONORABLE AS THAT IS,
IT IS HARDLY A CAREER.
MM.  IT WILL NOT
MAKE MY FORTUNE,
IF THAT'S WHAT YOU MEAN.
ARE YOU BENT
ON MAKING A FORTUNE ?
ON THE CONTRARY, I'M SIMPLY
LOOKING TO TURN AN HONEST PENNY.
I SHALL KEEP THAT IN MIND.
IF MY SITUATION BECOMES
DESPERATE, I SHALL PERHAPS TAKE
THE LIBERTY OF REMINDING YOU.
BE ASSURED, I WILL NOT
LOSE SIGHT OF YOU.
NOW, I'M-- I'M QUITE IN THE MOOD
OF AN ALPINE ADVENTURE.
AND LEAVE OUT NONE
OF THE DETAILS THAT I'M SURE
YOU DID FOR THE LADIES.
[ Men Laughing ]
WHAT CAN THEY BE TALKING ABOUT,
ALL THIS TIME ?
I FEEL ONE OF MY HEADACHES
COMING ON.
IF YOU WISH TO RETIRE,
I WILL MAKE YOUR EXCUSES.
[ Door Opens ]
OH.
[ Whispering ]
DID IT GO WELL ?
HE'S AN EXTRAORDINARY MAN,
YOUR FATHER.
HE'S THE TYPE OF MAN
I WOULD WISH TO BE.
I KNEW
YOU TWO WOULD GET ALONG.
AND WHAT IF WE HADN'T ?
I SHOULD LIKE YOU TO TELL ME
THAT IT WOULDN'T HAVE MATTERED.
BUT OF COURSE
IT WOULD HAVE MATTERED.
IT WOULD HAVE MATTERED GREATLY.
YOU WOULD NOT HAVE WELCOMED
THE OPPORTUNITY
TO CONTRADICT HIM.
I NEVER CONTRADICT HIM.
YOU WOULD HEAR ME ABUSED
WITHOUT OPENING YOUR LIPS
IN MY DEFENSE ?
MY FATHER WOULD NOT ABUSE YOU.
HE DOES NOT KNOW YOU
WELL ENOUGH.
[ Both Laughing ]
I'D LIKE US TO PLAY
FOR YOUR FATHER, CATHERINE.
NO.
DON'T YOU KNOW YET THAT
TOGETHER WE HAVE SANCTUARY ?
COME.  COME.
IT'S ALL RIGHT.
* [ Piano ]
[ Murmuring ]
* [ Italian ]
* [ Continues ]
* [ Joins In ]
* [ Ends ]
BRAVO.
HE THAT WILL NOT
APPLY NEW REMEDIES
MUST EXPECT NEW EVILS.
[ Women Giggling ]
[ Whispers ]
WOULD YOU GO ?
[ Shrieks ]
[ Door Closes ]
CATHERINE, I'M--
FORGIVE ME, I'M TREMBLING
LIKE A SCHOOLBOY.
I NEVER IMAGINED
I'D BE TAKEN LIKE THIS.
I MUST-- I MUST CONFESS
I ACQUIRED A CERTAIN...
VENEER DURING MY TRAVELS.
BUT, UM, I'D HEARD TALES
OF THIS-- THIS THING,
BUT I SUSPECTED
IT WAS AN IDEA...
ORIGINATED BY
MERCENARY NOVELISTS.
YOU KNOW,
I FIND MYSELF--
I FIND MYSELF PERFORMING
THE MOST USELESS TASKS...
IN THE HOPE THAT I'LL FIND
A MOMENT'S RESPITE
FROM THINKING OF YOU.
I-- I'M QUITE OVERCOME.
[ Chattering,
Applauding ]
OH, MISS, MISS.
LET ME HELP YOU.
[ Bell Jingling ]
OH, YOU MUST BE
MORE CAREFUL, DEAR.
ON THIS MOST HAPPY
OF OCCASIONS,
I WOULD LIKE TO CONGRATULATE
MY DAUGHTER AND MY SON-IN-LAW.
-  MY GREATEST HOPE FOR YOU BOTH
IS THAT YOUR YEARS TOGETHER...
- MADAM ?  SIR ?
- THANK YOU.
-  WILL BE AS HAPPY AND
AS BOUNTIFUL...
AS YOUR MOTHER'S
AND MINE HAVE BEEN.
[ Man ]
WELL SAID.  WONDERFUL.
ABSOLUTELY WONDERFUL.
I'LL DO MY BEST
FOR HER.
[ Arthur ]
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
THREE CHEERS.
LOVE AND PROSPERITY.
TO THE COUPLE.
HEAR, HEAR.
AUSTIN, DON'T YOU THINK
HE'S CHARMING ?
SO YOU TOO BELIEVE
THAT HE'S PAYING ATTENTION
TO MY DAUGHTER...
FOR HER UNCOMMON BEAUTY
AND WIT.
WOULD THIS BE AN INOPPORTUNE
TIME TO REMIND YOU...
WAS VERY WELL ENDOWED MONETARILY
WHEN YOU HAD OCCASION
TO MARRY HER ?
- YOU'RE CERTAINLY NOT
SUGGESTING, ARE YOU--
- I SUGGEST NOTHING.
FOR YOU NOR MR. TOWNSEND.
I MERELY STATE FACTS.
HE'S ALTOGETHER TOO FAMILIAR,
TOO SELF-ASSURED.  HE'S--
RAVISHING, POSSESSED OF
A RAPIER WIT AND A VELVET CHARM.
WHILE YOU, DEAR AUSTIN--
[ Groans ]
NOW, IF YOU ARE REALLY INTENT
ON GATHERING INSIDE INFORMATION,
MRS. MONTGOMERY,
THE MUCH-MENTIONED SISTER.
[ Girl ]
CATHERINE, DO YOU WANT
TO PLAY WITH US ?
YES, YES, COME ALONG !
CATHERINE, WAIT.  MARTHA,
I'D LIKE YOU TO MEET CATHERINE.
MY DEAR CATHERINE,
I AM SO PLEASED TO MEET YOU.
[ Giggles ]
MORRIS HAS TOLD ME
SO MUCH ABOUT YOU.
MARTHA--
I AM CATHERINE.
I HAVE HEARD
MUCH ABOUT YOU TOO.
MAY I PRESENT
ALICE ALMOND, MY COUSIN ?
HOW DO YOU DO ?
[ Bell Jingling ]
OH, CATHERINE, LOOK.
WE'RE MISSING THE RING.  COME.
WILL YOU EXCUSE US ?
[ Jingling Continues ]
- I'M--
- THANK YOU, MARTHA.
YES.
[ Laughing ]
OH, THAT'S A LARGE PIECE.
WATCH THE GLASS.
[ Arthur ]
WELL, I'M A BROKER,
NOT A WAITER.
[ Marian ]
OH, HERE, HERE.  I'M SORRY, I--
[ Arthur ]  THANK YOU.
I HOPE THERE'S ENOUGH.
[ Girl ]
FOR ALICE.
OKAY, ALICE.
[ Marian ]  HERE WE GO.
[ Arthur ]
WHO'S GOING TO FIND THE RING ?
-  [ Marian ]  ANYONE ?
-  [ Woman ]  YOURS IS ON
THE BRINK OF PROPOSING !
KEEP LOOKING.
I MET THIS--
WHO'S NEXT ?
THANK YOU.
[ Marian ]
CAROLINE.  CAROLINE.
[ Squealing ]
OH !
IT'S CATHERINE,
IS IT ?
[ Applause ]
* [ Chamber Orchestra ]
[ Applause Continues ]
INTRODUCE ME.
[ Elizabeth ]
MAY I PRESENT MY BROTHER,
DR. SLOPER ?
[ Marian ]
OH, MY BROTHER--
MISS PENNIMAN,
Y-- YOUR HANDKERCHIEF.
BEWARE THE IDES OF MARCH.
WE MUST MEET AND PLAN.
DANGER IS AT HAND.
HERE YOU ARE.
WHERE DID THAT COME FROM ?
THE CAKE.
YOU CAUGHT
THE RING IN THE CAKE ?
WELL, I HOPE
THAT'S A GOOD OMEN.
YOUR FATHER
IS INVESTIGATING ME.
HE DOESN'T TRUST ME,
I'M AFRAID.
I DON'T SEE HOW
YOU COULD KNOW.
I FEEL IT.
I'M VERY QUICK TO FEEL.
MORRIS.
WHEN MY MOTHER
AND MY BROTHER WERE TAKEN,
I BECAME FATHER'S LIFE.
[ Sighs ]
HE MUST FEEL...
CERTAIN THAT HE HAS DONE
HIS DUTY TOWARDS ME.
IF I WERE BEING
PURSUED BY THE POPE,
HE WOULD INVESTIGATE HIM TOO.
IF YOU WERE BEING PURSUED
BY THE POPE, HE SHOULD INDEED
HAVE CAUSE FOR DISMAY.
[ Laughing ]
[ Laughs ]
IT'S MY SIZE.
[ Whispering ]
I LOVE YOU.
[ Chuckles ]
HOW CHARMING.
YOU'VE, UH, TRAVELED
EXTENSIVELY, MRS. MONTGOMERY ?
[ Laughing ]
OH, MY BROTHER.
HE'S COLLECTED SOMETHING
FROM EVERYWHERE HE'S EVER BEEN
FOR ME.
ARE YOU CLOSE TO HIM ?
OH, YES.
WE WERE ORPHANED FROM AN
EARLY AGE AND REARED EACH OTHER.
WHAT SORT OF GENTLEMAN
IS YOUR BROTHER ?
[ Grunting ]
EXCUSE ME.
THANK YOU, THERESE.
IT'S DIFFICULT TO TALK
ABOUT ONE'S BROTHER.
IT SEEMS TO ME IT IS NOT
WHEN ONE HAS GOOD THINGS TO SAY.
OH, YES, EVEN THEN, WHEN SUCH
A GREAT DEAL DEPENDS UPON IT.
AND FOR YOUR BROTHER,
A GREAT DEAL DOES DEPEND ON IT.
I MEANT FOR MISS SLOPER.
PLEASE SIT DOWN.
OH, THANK YOU.
- WHAT DOES HE TELL YOU ?
- THAT HE IS IN LOVE.
YOU CAN'T BE THAT OBTUSE.
IT'S MY BELIEF YOUR BROTHER
LIVES OFF YOU.
NOW HE MEANS TO LIVE OFF
MY POOR CATHERINE, AND SHE'S
TOO SIMPLEMINDED TO SEE IT.
IF THAT IS TRULY
WHAT YOU BELIEVE,
THEN YOUR PATH IS A SIMPLE ONE:
DON'T LET HER MARRY HIM.
YOU HAVE DAUGHTERS ?
YES.
WHEN YOUNG MEN COME A-COURTING,
YOU WILL BE CONCERNED
WITH THEIR MORAL CHARACTER.
CATHERINE IS ILL-EQUIPPED
TO LOOK AFTER HERSELF.
I CAN'T STAND BY AND SEE HER
MAKE SO GREAT A MISTAKE.
IF I'D THROW HIM BACK ON YOU,
THE LEAST I CAN DO
IS HELP WITH THE BURDEN.
I SHALL TAKE THE LIBERTY
OF PLACING IN YOUR HANDS...
AN AMOUNT
FOR YOUR BROTHER'S SUPPORT.
NO WONDER YOU HAVE SUCH
A GREAT CONCERN ABOUT MONEY.
YOU BELIEVE
IT CAN BUY ANYTHING.
MAMA !
YOU'LL FORGIVE ME
FOR TELLING YOU:
IT'S EASY TO SAY
WHEN ONE HAS NOT EXPERIENCED
PURCHASING POWER.
PEOPLE TALK GREATLY ABOUT IT:
PLAIN, STUPID GIRL...
WITH A LARGE FORTUNE...
MARRYING A HANDSOME,
WORLDLY MAN WITHOUT A PENNY.
DON'T THEY, DOCTOR ?
IMAGINE THE INDIGNITY.
WHY, PEOPLE MIGHT EVEN THINK
THAT YOU HAD BEEN TAKEN
FOR A FOOL.
IT'S MORE
THAN A MAN IN YOUR POSITION
SHOULD EVER HAVE TO BEAR.
YOU DO ME
A GRAVE INJUSTICE.
DO I ?
TIME WILL TELL THE TRUTH OF IT.
EXCUSE ME.
[ Austin ]
MR. TOWNSEND, I HOPE
YOU WEREN'T WAITING TOO LONG.
YOU CAN ONLY APPROXIMATE
HOW LONG THESE THINGS TAKE.
OH, NO.  IT'S A WONDERFUL THING
TO HAVE A PROFESSION.
AH, BUT IT'S NOT ONLY
A THING ONE HAS.  IT'S A THING
ONE MUST APPLY DAILY.
YES, BUT THERE IS
TREMENDOUS SATISFACTION
IN THAT APPLICATION.
AS MUCH AS IN SCALING AN ALP
OR RIDING IN A GONDOLA ?
WELL, I'M SURE I WOULDN'T KNOW,
NEVER HAVING HAD A PROFESSION.
SO WE'RE AT AN IMPASSE,
AS THEY SAY,
FOR I'VE NEVER SCALED AN ALP
FOR BEING OCCUPIED WITH
APPLYING MY PROFESSION.
I WISH TO MARRY
YOUR DAUGHTER, SIR.
SHE IS SIMPLY
ONE OF THE MOST DELIGHTFUL...
AND CHARMING INDIVIDUALS
I'VE EVER ENCOUNTERED.
MR. TOWNSEND, YOU MUST BE
VERY SUSCEPTIBLE.
AS CATHERINE'S FATHER,
I HAVE, I TRUST, A JUST...
AND TENDER APPRECIATION
OF HER MANY GOOD QUALITIES.
BUT I DON'T MIND TELLING YOU,
I'VE NEVER THOUGHT OF HER
AS DELIGHTFUL OR CHARMING...
AND NEVER EXPECTED
ANYONE ELSE TO EITHER.
WELL, I'M SURE I DON'T KNOW
WHAT I'D THINK OF CATHERINE
IF I WERE HER FATHER.
I CAN'T PUT MYSELF
IN THAT PLACE.  I SPEAK
FROM MY OWN POINT OF VIEW.
AND YOU SPEAK VERY WELL.
KEEP TALKING, SIR, FOR
I FEEL SURE YOU'LL BE TELLING ME
NEXT OF HER BEAUTY AND WIT.
DR. SLOPER,
I DON'T PRETEND TO KNOW...
WHAT ALCHEMY
IS AT WORK HERE,
BUT THE FACT IS, I'VE NEVER BEEN
HAPPIER THAN THESE TEN WEEKS.
TO INTRODUCE MAGIC
TO A MAN OF SCIENCE
IN THE COURSE OF A DIALOGUE...
SIGNALS THAT COMMON GROUND
HAS LONG DEPARTED.
WELL, THEN-- THEN LET ME SPEAK
A LANGUAGE YOU WILL UNDERSTAND.
I'VE LIVED LONG ENOUGH TO LEARN
CERTAIN TRUTHS ABOUT MYSELF.
ONE IS THAT MY VANITY
REQUIRES AN AUDIENCE.
NOW, THIS IS NOT THE MOST
ATTRACTIVE OF TRAITS, AND WOMEN
ARE QUICK TO ACKNOWLEDGE THIS.
NOT SO, CATHERINE.
I TIRE MYSELF
BEFORE SHE TIRES OF ME,
WHICH IS SAYING A GREAT DEAL.
WHAT YOU SEE,
AND MY STORIES,
ARE ALL I BRING
TO THIS UNION.
AND SHE MAKES ME FEEL
LIKE THE MOST IMPORTANT BEING...
EVER TO ROAM THE PLANET.
DO YOU KNOW WHAT IT'S LIKE
TO BE THE MOST IMPORTANT PERSON
IN THE WORLD TO SOMEONE ?
PERHAPS YOU DO.  PERHAPS
THAT IS--  PERHAPS THAT IS WHAT
BRINGS US TO THIS TO THIS PLACE.
CATHERINE IS SO GOOD...
AND HONEST AND-- AND TRUE.
SHE-- SHE LIVES
IN A PLACE WHERE EVERYTHING
IS SHINING AND CLEAN...
AND WHERE EVERYONE HAS
THE BEST OF INTENTIONS.
I NEVER IMAGINED
SUCH A WORLD.
AND NOW I WANT
TO LIVE THERE WITH HER.
YOU ARE
A REMARKABLE INDIVIDUAL.
AS A DINNER COMPANION,
AS A STORYTELLER,
AS A MAN OF THE WORLD...
AND, IN FACT,
AS A SUPERIOR HUMAN BEING,
I TAKE OFF MY HAT TO YOU.
BUT THE ABSENCE
OF EMPLOYMENT, MEANS,
A PROFESSION,
ANY VISIBLE PROSPECTS...
PLACE YOU IN A CATEGORY FROM
WHICH IT WOULD BE IMPRUDENT...
FOR ME TO CHOOSE
A HUSBAND FOR MY DAUGHTER.
BUT-- BUT IT'S NOT
FOR YOU TO CHOOSE.
IT'S FOR CATHERINE TO,
AND SHE HAS CHOSEN ME.
YOU'VE SPENT A LIFE IDLING.
NOW YOU'VE DECIDED IT'S TIME
YOU FOUND A POSITION--
A POSITION IN THE PARLOR
OF 21 WASHINGTON SQUARE AS THE
HUSBAND OF A WEAK-MINDED WOMAN.
YOU SEE, YOU NEED NOT BE
CONCERNED WITH MY EYESIGHT.
BUT THAT IS NOT
WHAT CATHERINE SEES.
I HAVE 26 YEARS...
AND THE DEEP WELL OF HER RESPECT
AND ADMIRATION TO DRAW FROM.
I'LL SUPPLY HER
WITH A PAIR OF SPECTACLES.
WELL, DO NOT FORGET THAT I, TOO,
DRAW FROM THAT SAME WELL.
[ Chortling ]
THIS IS TOO AMUSING.
YOU MEAN TO DEFY ME.
A MAN WHO SPENDS HIS LIFE--
YOU CALL IT IDLING; I CALL IT
SEARCHING-- SEEKS SOMETHING.
FOR ME, IT WAS HAPPINESS.
BY HAVING GONE TO THE ENDS
OF THE EARTH IN PURSUIT OF IT,
WHAT DO YOU SUPPOSE...
ARE THE CHANCES OF GIVING IT UP,
HAVING DISCOVERED IT
ON HIS DOORSTEP ?
PLEASE EXCUSE ME.
I AM LATE FOR LUNCH.
[ Eager Sigh ]
[ Door Closes ]
[ Austin Murmuring ]
[ Women Whispering ]
[ Whispering ]
WOULD YOU JUST GO AWAY ?
OH !
[ Man ]
COME ON, MA'AM.
YOU'VE HAD YOUR LOOK.
HMM.
[ Men Shouting ]
COME ON, DIGS !
NO TIME FOR TAIL WAGGIN' !
-  EASY, BOY !
-  [ Barking ]
- [ Screams ]
WE'LL GO THROUGH THIS WAY.
YOU MAY DISROBE NOW.
OH, MR. TOWNSEND.
I REFUSE TO CARRY ON
A CONVERSATION WITH THAT...
CONTRAPTION.
I HAVE MY REPUTATION
TO THINK OF.
THEN WHY CHOOSE AN
ESTABLISHMENT THAT FAIRLY
REEKS OF LICENTIOUSNESS ?
I'D HEARD IT WAS RELIABLE
FOR THINGS CLANDESTINE.
DO YOU HAVE ANYTHING FOR ME ?
HE WILL NEVER CHANGE.
TO DO SO WOULD BE
TO SURRENDER.
I KNOW HIS HARD,
INTELLECTUAL NATURE.
HE'S IMPERVIOUS TO PITY.
HE WILL BE VANQUISHED ONLY
BY THE ESTABLISHED FACT.
WELL, IT'S A FACT THAT
I WANT TO MARRY HIS DAUGHTER.
I PRESENTED IT TO HIM,
AND HE DIDN'T SEEM
IN THE LEAST VANQUISHED.
MARRY CATHERINE FIRST.
MEET HIM AFTERWARD.
YOU MEAN I SHOULD
CARRY HER OFF ?
ELOPE ?
WELL, DON'T YOU SEE ?
HE THINKS YOU LIKE
THE MONEY.
IF YOU MARRY HER,
KNOWING THAT SHE'LL BE
DISINHERITED,
HE HAS NO CHOICE
BUT TO SEE THAT
YOU'RE HONORABLE.
WOULD YOU REALLY WISH
THE LIFE OF A PAUPER
ON YOUR NIECE ?
SHE HAS 10,000 A YEAR
FROM HER MOTHER.
SHE'S USED TO MORE.
YOU KNOW, MY HUSBAND,
THE GOOD REVEREND,
ONCE MARRIED A YOUNG COUPLE...
IN THE SAME DISTRESS.
THE FATHER WAS RECONCILED
AFTERWARD.  EVERYTHING
WORKED OUT BEAUTIFULLY.
WELL, UNFORTUNATELY, WE DO NOT
HAVE REVEREND PENNIMAN TO MARRY
US.
NO, BUT YOU HAVE ME.
I CAN'T PERFORM THE CEREMONY,
OF COURSE, BUT I CAN
BE IN ATTENDANCE.
WE MUST USE
A SUBTERRANEAN CHAPEL
WITH LITTLE LIGHTING SO--
IS THIS WHAT YOU
CALLED ME HERE TO ASK ME ?
I THOUGHT YOU MIGHT
WISH TO SEE SOMEONE
CLOSE TO CATHERINE...
TO SEND HER WORD,
A MESSAGE...
A LOCK OF HAIR.
SHE KNOWS MY HEART.
AS I DO.
I KNOW IT TO BE GOOD
AND CONSTANT AND TRUE.
YOU CANNOT KNOW THIS,
BUT I WENT TO GREAT
PERSONAL PERIL TO COME HERE.
AUSTIN THREATENED TO THROW ME
TO THE ELEMENTS AND WORSE
IF I CONTINUED TO HELP YOU.
HOWEVER, I CANNOT SIT BY...
AND SEE YOU IN DISTRESS.
MY NATURE DEMANDS
THAT IF I CAN BE
OF ASSISTANCE...
IN MATTERS OF THE HEART,
I MUST BE.
I'M THINKING ONLY OF YOU,
MORRIS.
I RACKED MY BRAINS
TRYING TO THINK OF WAYS
TO HELP YOU.
I PAY THE PENALTY
WITH MY HEADACHES.
[ Couple Moaning In Ecstasy ]
MY PERFECT CIRCULATE
OF PAIN.
BUT I CARRY IT AS A QUEEN
CARRIES HER CROWN.
-  [ Moaning, Shouting ]
- WHAT ARE THEY DOING IN THERE ?
YOU KNOW,
I HAVE NO IDEA.
[ Gasps ]
OH, MY GOODNESS !
[ Exhales Sharply ]
[ Twittering ]
AH, SWEETS.
PRETTY THING.
PRETTY--
[ Morris ]
CATHERINE !
[ Sighing ]
[ Fire Crackling ]
[ Knocking ]
YES ?
FATHER...
YOU TOLD ME IF I HAD
ANYTHING TO SAY ABOUT
MR. TOWNSEND...
YOU WOULD BE AVAILABLE
TO LISTEN.
I WISH TO SEE HIM.
- TO BID HIM GOOD-BYE.
- HE'S NOT GOING ANYWHERE.
WOULD YOU LIKE TO MAKE
YOUR FATHER VERY HAPPY ?
IF I CAN.
YOU CAN AND YOU WILL.
IT DEPENDS ON YOUR WILL.
IS IT TO GIVE HIM UP ?
YOU ARE HAPPIER THAN I.
I HAVE NO DOUBT
YOU'RE UNHAPPY NOW.
BUT IT'S BETTER TO BE UNHAPPY
FOR THREE MONTHS AND GET OVER IT
THAN BE UNHAPPY FOREVER.
BUT THE ONLY THING THAT
WOULD MAKE ME UNHAPPY FOREVER
WOULD BE TO BE WITHOUT HIM.
YOU SUPPOSE I KNOW
NOTHING OF MEN ?
THEIR VICES AND FALSITIES ?
HE'S NOT VICIOUS.
HE'S NOT FALSE.
YOU MAKE NOTHING
OF MY JUDGMENT, THEN !
I-- I CAN'T BELIEVE IT.
I DON'T ASK YOU TO BELIEVE IT.
TAKE IT ON TRUST.
BUT... WE CAN WAIT
A LONG TIME.
[ Chuckling ]
OF COURSE.
YOU CAN WAIT UNTIL I DIE.
YOUR ENGAGEMENT WILL HAVE
ONE DELIGHTFUL EFFECT
ON YOU.
IT WILL MAKE YOU
EXTREMELY IMPATIENT
FOR THAT EVENT.
IF I DO NOT MARRY
BEFORE YOUR DEATH
I WILL NOT HAVE TO.
THERE'S ONE THING
YOU CAN TELL HIM
IF YOU SEE HIM AGAIN.
TELL HIM IF YOU MARRY WITHOUT
MY CONSENT, YOU'LL NOT GET
A FARTHING OF MY MONEY.
WELL, I-I, UH--
NOT, IN THAT CASE,
TO HAVE A FARTHING OF IT.
YOU ARE AN UNGRATEFUL,
CRUEL CHILD.
IF YOU SEE HIM AGAIN,
YOU'LL HAVE GIVEN YOUR FATHER
THE GREATEST PAIN OF HIS LIFE.
[ Sobbing ]
NO !
OH !  I'M TO TAKE IT
TO MR. TOWNSEND
AND WAIT FOR AN ANSWER.
OH.  YEAH, I'LL
TAKE IT FOR YOU.
OH, N--
MISS SLOPER MADE ME SWEAR
NOT TO GIVE IT TO ANYONE
BUT HIMSELF.
SHE DID NOT INCLUDE ME
IN THAT NUMBER.
GIVE IT HERE.
ARE YOU QUESTIONING
MY TRUSTWORTHINESS ?
I--
I-I WILL JUST GO ASK
THE YOUNG MISS
IF IT'S ALL RIGHT.
YOU'LL JUST GET
MY BONNET.
THANK YOU.
[ Door Opening ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Gulps ]
HAVE YOU CALLED ME HERE
TO LOOK AT ME ?
AS GRATIFYING
AS THAT IS,
AFTER THREE WEEKS--
THREE WEEKS OF SILENCE,
I AM IN NEED OF
HEARING YOUR VOICE.
I DID WANT TO LOOK AT YOU.
[ Chuckles ]
MY FATHER HAS ASKED ME
TO GO AWAY WITH HIM...
TO EUROPE FOR SIX MONTHS,
AND I HAVE AGREED.
HUH.
SO, IT'S DONE.
YOU'VE GIVEN ME UP
FOR HIM.
NO, MORRIS.  NO.
LET ME EXPLAIN--
EX-EXPLAIN WHAT ?
THAT I AM...
AN UNDESIRABLE MATCH
BECAUSE I AM POOR.
OR THAT HE BELIEVES
THAT I AM A MERCENARY.
HE TOLD ME TO TELL YOU...
THAT IF I MARRY YOU WITHOUT
HIS CONSENT, I SHALL NOT INHERIT
A PENNY OF HIS FORTUNE.
[ Slams Fist ]
PLEASE TELL HIM
THAT I DON'T GIVE A DAMN
FOR HIS MESSAGE,
AND THAT I DON'T WANT
NOR NEED HIS MONEY.
- MARRY ME.
- WITHOUT HIS CONSENT ?
CATHERINE...
YOU CAN'T PLEASE US BOTH.
YOU HAVE TO CHOOSE.
I HAVE.
I HAVE CHOSEN YOU.
HE IS TAKING ME TO EUROPE
TO TEST OUR DEVOTION.
NO.  NO, HE'S
TAKING YOU TO EUROPE
SO THAT YOU'LL FORGET ME.
NO.
PEOPLE THINK
TERRIBLE THINGS, MORRIS.
THEY DON'T KNOW
WHAT IS BETWEEN US.
THEY SEE YOU,
AND THEN THEY SEE ME AND--
FATHER DOESN'T UNDERSTAND.
[ Sighs ]
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
FORGIVE ME, BUT I CANNOT--
I CANNOT FORSAKE HIM SO.
[ Crying ]
PLEASE... PLEASE...
WAIT FOR ME.
PLEASE, WAIT...
FOR ME, MORRIS.
[ Whispering ]
I'LL WAIT FOR YOU.
[ Relieved Sigh ]
BUY YOUR WEDDING GOWN
IN PARIS.
[ Laughs, Sniffs ]
SOME-SOMETHING
BEAUTIFUL.
SOMETHING BEAUTIFUL
THAT'S WORTHY OF YOU.
* [ Band ]
[ Crowd Shouting Joyfully ]
FATHER !  FATHER !
-  FATHER !
- MADEMOISELLE !
[ Continues In French ]
[ Man, French ]
VOILA !
[ Man Continues,
French ]
UN, DEUX, TROI.
[ Crowd Exclaiming ]
[ Panting ]
* [ Woman Singing
In French ]
* [ Continues ]
* [ Ends ]
- CATHERINE, WE OUGHT TO P--
-  [ Catherine ]  AGNES.
PACK.
WE'RE LEAVING FOR GENEVA.
[ Whispering ]
AGNES... HELP ME
GET OUT OF THIS.
"WHOM IT--"
OH, NO, NO, NO, NO.
OH, THIS I--
THIS IS PREPOSTEROUS.
HE'S GONE TO FAR.
HE WRITE-- EH--
HE WRITES THEY ARE TO SPEND
ANOTHER SIX MONTHS.
ANOTHER SIX MONTHS ?
OH.
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN ?
WELL, IT COULD BE
ONE OF TWO THINGS.
WELL, NO, UH, THREE.
WE-- NO !  I'VE JUST
THOUGHT OF ANOTHER.
LAVINIA.
[ Sighs ]  NO, IT MUST BE THAT
SHE'S PERSUADED HIM OVER TO YOU,
AND THEY'RE BOTH SO HAPPY
THEY'VE DECIDED NOT TO
BREAK THE JOURNEY.
OR, OR HE PROMISED THAT
IF SHE REMAIN FAITHFUL
FOR YET ANOTHER SIX MONTHS,
IT MUST BE LOVE
AND HE WILL GIVE
HIS BLESSING.
OR, OR, OR IN EXCHANGE FOR
HIS CONSENT, SHE'S GIVEN HIM
ANOTHER SIX MONTHS.
IT WOULD, AFTER ALL,
BE THE LAST TIME HE HAS
HER COMPANY SO FREELY.
OR ?
OR... SHE HAS REFUSED
TO GIVE YOU UP,
AND HE'S HOLDING
HER HOSTAGE--
IN SOME
NON-ENGLISH SPEAKING,
DENSELY POPULATED NATION...
WHICH CIVILIZATION
HAS YET TO REACH--
UNTIL SHE SEES REASON.
OH.  NOW, THERE.
THERE, THERE.
DON'T DESPAIR.
COOK HAS PREPARED
YOUR FAVORITE.
LAMB CASSOULET.
WITH THE NEW POTATOES ?
OF COURSE.
BY NOW, WE KNOW NOT
TO SERVE A MEAL WITHOUT
YOUR FAVORITE POTATOES.
[ Coachman ]
HUP !  HUP !  HUP !
[ Horses Whinny ]
[ Coachman Continues ]
FATHER ?
SHOULD YOU LIKE TO BE LEFT IN
SUCH A PLACE AS THIS TO STARVE ?
[ Gasping ]
THAT'LL BE YOUR FATE.
THAT'S HOW HE'LL LEAVE YOU.
NO, THAT'S NOT TRUE, FATHER.
YOU SHOULDN'T SAY IT.
WHAT WERE YOU THINKING OF
WHEN I CAME UPON YOU ?
YOU WERE GLOWING.
YOU WERE THINKING OF HIM,
WERE YOU NOT ?
THE STORY OF HIS
ALPINE ADVENTURE.
THAT ONE OVER THERE, I IMAGINE.
HIS YOUNG, BEAUTIFUL TORSO
DANGLING IN MIDAIR, WITH ONLY A
ROPE BETWEEN HIM AND MORTALITY.
WELL, WE'RE ALL YOUNG
AND BEAUTIFUL ONCE.
IT'S TRANSIENT.
WHAT WILL YOU HAVE
WHEN THAT'S GONE ?
THAT'S HIS ONLY TALENT.
THAT, AND HOODWINKING
DIMWITTED YOUNG LADIES
OUT OF THEIR INHERITANCES.
I LOVE HIM,
AND WHEN WE GO HOME
I SHALL MARRY HIM.
HE SHOULD BE
VERY THANKFUL TO ME.
A YEAR AGO YOU WERE
RUSTIC, LIMITED.
NOW YOUR VALUE IS TWICE
AS GREAT WITH THE KNOWLEDGE
AND TASTE YOU'VE ACQUIRED.
WE HAVE FATTENED
THE SHEEP FOR HIM
BEFORE HE KILLS IT.
HOW OBSCENE...
THAT YOUR MOTHER SHOULD
GIVE HER LIFE SO YOU COULD
INHABIT SPACE ON THIS EARTH.
OH, YOUNG MAN, WHERE IS
THE BOAT FOR MERCY ?
IT'S ALREADY DOCKED, MA'AM.
RIGHT THERE.
MM ?  OH, THANK YOU.
[ Austin ]  THANK YOU, OFFICER.
OH, WILL THE, UH, LUGGAGE
COME ASHORE TODAY ?
YES, SIR.
[ Lavinia ]
CATHERINE !
THANK YOU.
OH, MY !  YOU LOOK
SO GLORIOUS.
[ Chuckles ]
OH... HE WANTED TO
ALLOW YOU REST AFTER
YOUR JOURNEY.  OH !
EUROPE MUST'VE
AGREED WITH YOU, AUSTIN.
YOU LOOK ALMOST CIVIL.
I'LL GO AND ATTEND
TO THE LUGGAGE.  MAUREEN,
YOU'RE NOT MARRIED YET ?
[ Maureen ]
OH, DOCTOR !
HE-HE WANTED
TO COME MEET YOU.
BUT I CONVINCED HIM...
AUSTIN WOULD THINK HIM
PRESUMPTUOUS.
BESIDES, HE HAD PRESSING
BUSINESS AT HIS OFFICE...
THAT REQUIRED
HIS IMMEDIATE ATTENTION.
OH !  IT WAS TO BE A SURPRISE,
BUT HE GAVE ME LEAVE
TO TELL YOU.
[ Laughing ]
ISN'T WONDERFUL ?  YOUR FATHER
CAN FIND NO FAULT NOW.
AND HE'S NOT
A SUBORDINATE, EITHER.
HE'S A PARTNER
WITH BUSINESS CARDS
AND EVERYTHING.
[ Giggles ]
I'VE SEEN
A GREAT DEAL OF HIM.
WELL, HE ISN'T
EASY TO KNOW.
I SUPPOSE YOU THINK YOU
KNOW HIM, BUT YOU DO NOT.
WELL, NOT AS I DO.
YOU WILL KNOW HIM
AFTER YOU'VE LIVED
WITH HIM FOR A WHILE.
I HAVE LIVED WITH HIM,
AND I MAY SAY, HE'S FULL OF--
OH, HE'S JUST FULL OF
REMARKABLE CHARM AND ENERGY;
FULL OF PASSION,
AND-AND--
WHAT IS IT ?
HE-HE WROTE ME
OF YOUR KINDNESS.
I-I THANK YOU FOR IT.
DID YOU FAIL TO BRING
YOUR FATHER AROUND ?
THE PURPOSE OF MY JOURNEY
WAS NOT TO BRING FATHER AROUND,
AS YOU SAY,
BUT RATHER, TO SPEND
SOME TIME WITH HIM
BEFORE I LEFT HIS HOUSE.
IT IS DONE.
YOU ARE THE SAME ?  YOU-YOU
HAVE NOT SWERVED THE LINE ?
I AM THE SAME, ONLY MORE SO.
I AM HOME TO MARRY.
WITHOUT YOUR FATHER'S CONSENT ?
WITH OR WITHOUT IT.
IT MAKES NO DIFFERENCE.
YOU HAVE BECOME BRAVE.
PERHAPS IT DOES MAKE
A DIFFERENCE TO MORRIS.
[ Laughs ]
WHY ARE YOU
SO CONTRADICTORY ?
A-A YEAR AGO YOU
WISHED ME NOT TO WORRY
ABOUT DISPLEASING FATHER.
NO, I THANK YOU FOR
YOUR CARE OF MORRIS,
BUT, UM, I AM HOME NOW--
TO MARRY.
COME, LET'S GO.
YOU KNOW HOW FATHER
DISLIKES DILLYDALLYING.
[ Dogs Barking ]
[ Knocking At Door ]
[ Morris Gasps ]
[ Whispering ]
CATHERINE, I ADORE YOU.
[ Indistinct Thudding ]
I HAVE BEEN MISSED.
YOU WILL MARRY ME
TOMORROW.
TOMORROW ?
[ Panting ]
NEXT WEEK, THEN.
TO MAKE ME WAIT LONGER
MAY WELL JEOPARDIZE
YOUR VIRTUE.
[ Moans ]
[ Breathlessly ]
YOU ARE SHAMEFUL.
TO-TO REMOVE A MAN FROM
THE OBJECT OF HIS DESIRE
FOR A DAY IS BRUTAL.
TO DO SO FOR A YEAR
CARRIES A PENALTY SO HIGH,
ONE SHOULD NOT INCUR IT.
OH, MORRIS.
MM ?
I'LL MARRY YOU
ANYTIME YOU SAY.
[ Thud ]
HUH ?
[ Maureen ]
UH, GOOD AFTERNOON, DR. SLOPER.
UH--  OH.
[ Austin ]
SOMEONE IN THE PARLOR ?
UH, MISS CATHERINE...
AND MR. TOWNSEND, SIR.
[ Laughs ]
OH, HOW IS YOUR FATHER,
CATHERINE ?
MY FATHER DOES NOT...
FIGURE ANYWHERE
IN THIS EQUATION.
HE-HE'S UNCHANGED ?
YES.
OH, MY POOR, DEAR GIRL.
I DON'T MIND IT NOW.
YOU MUST LET ME
TRY HIM.
NO, MORRIS.
HE'LL NOT BE BROUGHT 'ROUND.
YOU WILL ONLY MAKE HIM WORSE.
N-- YOU SAY THAT ONLY BECAUSE...
I MANAGED SO BADLY
THE LAST TIME.
YET, I'VE HAD,
I'VE HAD A YEAR
TO THINK ABOUT IT NOW.
I HAVE NEW TACT.
IS THAT WHAT YOU'VE BEEN
THINKING ABOUT FOR A YEAR ?
THE IDEA
STICKS IN MY CRAW.
I-- I-I DON'T LIKE
TO FAIL.
WELL, HOW HAVE YOU FAILED
IF WE MARRY ?
NO-NOT ON THE MAIN ISSUE,
OF COURSE, BUT ON
THE REST OF IT--
MY REPUTATION,
MY RELATIONS
WITH YOUR FATHER,
UM, MY RELATION
WITH OUR CHILDREN--
OH... WE SHALL HAVE
ENOUGH FOR OUR CHILDREN--
ENOUGH FOR EVERYTHING.
HMM.
BESIDES,
I BELIEVE YOU WILL SUCCEED
BRILLIANTLY IN BUSINESS.
MM, IT ISN'T OF
THE MATERIAL COMFORT
THAT I SPEAK.
IT'S OF MORAL COMFORT;
OF THE INTELLECTUAL
SATISFACTION.
I HAVE GREAT
MORAL COMFORT NOW.
YES, OF COURSE
YOU HAVE.
Y-YOU HAVE IT WITH ME
IS DIFFERENT.  I--
I STAKE MY PRIDE ON
PROVING TO YOUR FATHER
THAT HE'S WRONG.
AND-- AND NOW THAT I AM
THE HEAD OF A BUSINESS,
I CAN DEAL WITH HIM
AS AN EQUAL.
PLEASE, CATHERINE.
PLEASE... PLEASE,
LET ME GO AT HIM.
NO, MORRIS.
NO.
I HAVE GOOD REASON.
WHAT IS IT ?
MY FATHER DESPISES ME.
CATHERINE, THA--
THAT ISN'T TRUE.
DO NOT DO THAT.
IT IS A GREAT...
THING TO BE SEPARATED
FROM YOUR FATHER.
ESPECIALLY WHEN--
BUT IT IS DONE.
TAKE IT ON FAITH.
IT--
WE MUST NEVER
SPEAK OF IT AGAIN.
[ Baby Crying ]
OH, HEAVEN'S SAKES,
DON'T BOUNCE.
ARTHUR !
MAY I HELP THERE,
PLEASE ?
GO.  TAKE A WALK IN THE PARK.
BOTH OF YOU LOOK AS IF YOU
HAVEN'T SEEN THE LIGHT OF DAY
FOR SOME TIME !
NO, WE HAVEN'T.
SHE'S SO FRETFUL.
PERHAPS I SHOULD STAY.
DO BE CAREFUL, PLEASE.
BE CAREFUL TO SUPPORT
HER HEAD !  MAMA !
I RAISED EIGHT CHILDREN.
I THINK I CAN BE TRUSTED
FOR AN HOUR.
ONE MORE MINUTE AND I WILL
WITHDRAW MY OFFER...
[ Children Giggling ]
[ Maid ]
AWAY WITH YOU, NOW !
TO CARE FOR ELIZABETH.
[ Man ]
MARIAN, YOUR HAT.
WE'RE GOING.
BYE, NOW.
THANK YOU.
YOU'RE WELCOME.
MARIAN.
[ Elizabeth ]
THE YOUNG.  NO ONE KNOWS
MORE THAN THEY DO.
ESPECIALLY NOT
THEIR PARENTS.
HOW IS
DEAR CATHERINE ?
AS STUBBORN AS A MULE
AND TWICE AS STUPID.
TRIED EVERYTHING,
BUT SHE REMAINS
STUCK LIKE GLUE.
SHE GAINED NOTHING
FROM OUR EUROPEAN TRIP,
EXCEPT A YEAR OLDER.
[ Chuckles ]
I CAN BARELY SIT IN
MY OWN PARLOR ANYMORE.
HIS ESSENCE PERMEATES IT.
I CAN FIND NO REFUGE FROM MORRIS
TOWNSEND IN MY OWN HOME, AND I
HAVE LAVINIA TO THANK FOR THAT.
SHE IS NOT A WOMAN
TO BE LEFT ALONE.
SHE HAS TO HAVE ENTERTAINMENT.
HE WAS AVAILABLE.
ALL THE BETTER.
WITH LAVINIA IN THE BOAT,
YOU MAY BE ASSURED IT'LL SINK.
HEALTHY BABY.
LAVINIA HAS A CAPITAL WAY
OF DESTROYING ALL
SHE SETS OUT TO HELP.
[ Chuckling ]
I BELIEVE SHE FANTASIZES...
THAT THE ATTENTION OF
THAT ABOUNDING MALE ENERGY
IN THE FRONT ROOM IS FOR HER.
WELL, LET'S ASSUME FOR A MOMENT
THAT YOUR THEORY IS CORRECT...
AND HE IS MERCENARY.
WHAT DOES IT MATTER ?
YOU'VE WORKED ALL YOUR LIFE
TO AMASS THIS FORTUNE...
KNOWING THAT CATHERINE
WOULD BE THE ONLY ONE
TO LEAVE IT TO.
SHOULDN'T SHE HAVE
SOME HAPPINESS WITH IT,
EVEN IF IT DOES MEAN
SHE HAS TO BUY IT ?
THERE IS NO EVIDENCE TO SUGGEST
THAT HE WILL NOT MAKE
A FINE HUSBAND.
DID NOT RAISE MY DAUGHTER
TO HAVE SO LITTLE DIGNITY.
WHAT FANTASY IS BEING SHATTERED
BY HER MARRYING THIS MAN ?
BY YOUR OWN ACCOUNT
SHE IS DIMWITTED, UNATTRACTIVE,
WITH NO SOCIAL SKILL OR GRACE.
WHAT DREAM DID YOU HAVE
FOR THIS PRIZE ?
WHERE DID
MORRIS TOWNSEND
FALL DOWN ?
[ Whispering ]
MAY I HAVE SOME CAKE ?
YES, YOU CAN.
- WELL, AUSTIN ?
- WELL...
I THOUGHT SHE'D END HER DAYS
AT WASHINGTON SQUARE
IN THE BEST OF COMFORT.
OH, I SUPPOSE THAT IN SOME YEARS
TO COME, SOME MAN MIGHT
HAPPEN ALONG, AND--
A WIDOWER, PERHAPS,
WHO WOULDN'T MIND
HOW SHE WAS TOO MUCH,
WHO WOULD BE INTENT
TO LIVE OUT THE REMAINDER
OF HIS LIFE WITH HER.
THE AFTERNOON SUN
LIGHTS THE WEST SECTION
OF THE PARLOR;
CATHERINE,
HEAD BENT OVER,
EMBROIDERS...
WHILE THE WIDOWER
SMOKES HIS COB PIPE
AND READS THE NEWSPAPER.
WELL, DON'T YOU SEE ?  THAT'D BE
SO PERFECT FOR CATHERINE.
SHE REQUIRES SO LITTLE.
ALL THIS TIME I THOUGHT IT
WAS BECAUSE YOU DIDN'T THINK
HE WASN'T DESERVING OF HER.
WHAT HAVE YOU DONE ?
SHE WILL NEVER LET GO.
* [ Piano ]
PLEASE, DON'T STOP.
WHEN I CAME INTO THE HALL
JUST NOW...
I WAS REMINISCING
ABOUT ALL THE TIMES
I CAME HOME TO MY DAUGHTER,
ALMOST KNOCKING ME DOWN
THE STEPS IN HER EAGERNESS
TO GREET ME.
DO YOU REMEMBER ?
I REMEMBER HOW DISTASTEFUL
YOU FOUND...
SUCH CLUMSY DISPLAYS
OF AFFECTION.
WHEN I HEARD YOU...
I... THOUGHT OF
YOUR DEAR MOTHER.
ARE YOU TO MARRY HIM ?
YES, FATHER.
I WOULD LIKE...
A DEFINITE NOTICE
OF WHEN YOU SET A DATE.
WHEN A POOR MAN IS ABOUT
TO LOSE HIS ONLY CHILD,
[ Knocking ]
HE WOULD LIKE
AN INKLING BEFOREHAND.
THANK YOU.
WELL, WHEN IS IT TO BE ?
IT OCCURS TO ME
IF I LIVE WITH YOU,
I OUGHT TO OBEY YOU.
IF THAT'S YOUR THEORY,
IT'S CERTAINLY MINE.
BUT IF I DON'T OBEY YOU,
I OUGHT NOT TO LIVE WITH YOU--
TO ENJOY YOUR...
KINDNESS AND PROTECTION.
WHAT A DISTASTEFUL IDEA.
IT MUST BE MR. TOWNSEND'S.
NO.  IT IS MINE.
WHY DO YOU
SPEAK TO ME THUS ?
I'VE DONE NOTHING BUT TRY
TO PROTECT YOU FROM--
FROM ?  FROM WHAT, FATHER ?
LOVE ?
AFFECTION ?
CARING ?
RESPECT ?
IT SEEMS YOU'VE
ALREADY DEPARTED.
[ Relieved Laugh ]
*
AH, IT'S SUCH
A BEAUTIFUL DAY.
I WAS A LITTLE WORRIED
WHEN YOU SENT FOR ME TO MEET
YOU HEAR AND NOT THE HOUSE.
BUT NOW I SEE THE REASON.
WHAT MANNER OF MAN
DO YOU THINK I AM...
TO COME WHERE
I AM NOT WELCOME ?
Y-YOUR FATHER DOES NOT WANT ME
IN HIS HOUSE AND I DON'T WISH
TO BE THERE.
[ Sighs ]
OF COURSE.  HOW--
HOW INCONSIDERATE OF ME.
OH, LET US NOT SPEAK
OF MY FATHER TODAY.
I AM EXCEEDINGLY HAPPY.
I'M GLAD YOU ARE HAPPY.
ARE YOU... NOT WELL ?
YOU SEEM RESTLESS
AND YOU LOOK PALE.
I'M AFRAID
YOU ARE OVERWORKED.
[ Scoffs ]
YOU OUGHTN'T TO WORK SO HARD.
WELL, I DON'T WISH
TO OWE YOU EVERYTHING.
I SUPPOSE YOU THINK
ALL THE EFFORT
IS ON YOUR SIDE.
NO.
NO, I KNOW HOW DIFFICULT
THE SITUATION HAS BEEN
FOR YOU.
BUT IT HAS HAD THE ADVANTAGE
OF MAKING US ONE.
WE WILL BEAR
THINGS TOGETHER.
THERE ARE SOME THINGS
WE CANNOT BEAR TOGETHER--
SEPARATION,
FOR INSTANCE.
WHY DO YOU SPEAK
OF SEPARATION ?
WILL YOU PROMISE
NOT TO MAKE A SCENE ?
A SCENE ?
DO I MAKE SCENES ?
I MUST GO AWAY
ON BUSINESS.
YOUR BUSINESS IS
WITH ME NOW, MORRIS.
YES !
THAT IS WHAT
THE WORLD SAYS.
WHERE ARE YOU GOING ?
TO NEW ORLEANS
TO BUY COTTON.
I'LL GO WITH YOU.
DO YOU REALLY THINK
THAT I WOULD TAKE YOU
TO A NEST OF YELLOW FEVER ?
THAT I WOULD EXPOSE YOU--
IF THERE IS YELLOW FEVER,
WHY SHOULD YOU GO ?
WELL, TO MAKE $6,000 !
OR WOULD YOU DENY ME
THAT SATISFACTION ?
IF YOU CAN GO TO
NEW ORLEANS, I CAN GO !
[ Sighs ]
WHY SHOULDN'T YOU CATCH
YELLOW FEVER QUITE AS
EASILY AS I ?  I'M STRONG.
WHEN-- WHEN WE WERE IN EUROPE,
WE WERE IN MANY UNHEALTHY PLACES
AND I NEVER CAUGHT ANYTHING.
WELL, WHAT WILL BE
THE USE OF $6,000
IF YOU DIE OF A FEVER ?
WHEN A PERSON IS GOING
TO BE MARRIED, YOU SHOULDN'T
THINK ABOUT COTTON.
YOU SHOULD THINK ABOUT ME.
YOU COULD GO TO NEW ORLEANS
SOME OTHER TIME.
THEY-THEY-THEY'LL ALWAYS
BE PLENTY OF COTTON.
YOU SAID YOU
WOULDN'T MAKE A SCENE.
I CALL THIS A SCENE.
I HAVE NEVER ASKED
ANYTHING OF YOU BEFORE.
OH, BECAUSE I HAVE NOTHING
TO GIVE !  THANK YOU !
I NEED NO REMINDER.
YOU THINK TOO MUCH
OF MONEY, MORRIS.
YOU DARE SAY THAT TO ME ?
I-I THINK OF MONEY BECAUSE
I MUST FIND WAYS TO KEEP YOU
IN THE COMFORT...
TO WHICH YOU
ARE ACCUSTOMED.
I CAN'T FORGET THAT
I AM THE REASON THAT
YOU ARE DISINHERITED !
MORRIS... ARE YOU GOING
TO LEAVE ME ?
YES.  YES, J--
FOR A LITTLE WHILE.
FOR HOW LONG ?
D-- UNTIL YOU'RE
REASONABLE AGAIN.
I SHALL NEVER BE REASONABLE
AGAIN IN THAT WAY.
TRY TO BE CALMER...
THE NEXT TIME I COME.
IS IT TOMORROW ?
I DON'T KNOW !
MORRIS !  MORRIS !
COME TOMORROW.
I'LL BE BETTER TOMORROW.
I'LL SHOW YOU
HOW GOOD I CAN BE.
I WILL COME WHEN I CAN.
I DON'T HAVE
THE LUXURY OF SLOTH.
I WORK FOR MY LIVING.
[ Horse Nickers ]
[ Woman ]
COME ALONG.  DON'T DAWDLE.
OH !
MY DEAR, WHAT CATASTROPHE
HAS BEFALLEN US ?
WELL, TAKE MR. SHAKESPEARE'S
ADVICE: "GIVE SORROW WORDS;
THE GRIEF THAT DOES NOT SPEAK
WHISPERS THE O'ER-FRAUGHT HEART
AND BIDS IT BREAK."
I KNOW NOT OF WHAT SORROW
YOU SPEAK.
COME, COME, MY DEAR.
YOUR EYES ARE NOT
REDDENED WITH JOY.
[ Indistinct Whispering ]
YOUR PRIDE
IS MY PRIDE.
YOUR SUSCEP--
SUSCEPTIBILITIES ARE MY--
I SEE YOUR SIDE.
BUT I ALSO SEE
THE SITUATION AS A WHOLE.
YOUR FATHER MUST BEAR
THE BRUNT OF YOUR ANGER.
MORRIS DID
EVERYTHING HE COULD.
OH, HE WAS PATIENT.
HE ALLOWED AUSTIN
TO ABUSE HIM.
HOW MUCH CAN
A YOUNG MAN OF HIS TALENTS
BE EXPECTED TO TAKE ?
NO, CATHERINE.
WE MUST STUDY RESIGNATION.
RESIGNATION...
TO WHAT ?
- TO A CHANGE OF OUR PLANS.
- MY PLANS HAVE NOT CHANGED.
OH.  HE HASN'T
TOLD YOU ?
TOLD ME WHAT ?
WELL, WHAT HAS HAPPENED
BETWEEN YOU THEN ?
YOU HAVE SPOKEN
TO MR. TOWNSEND
ABOUT OUR SITUATION ?
[ Chuckles ]
YES !
I HAVE CONFERRED WITH HIM.
IS IT YOU, THEN,
WHO HAS CHANGED HIM
AND MADE HIM SO UNNATURAL ?
HE DOESN'T BELONG
TO YOU.
YOU HAVE NOTHING TO DO
WITH WHAT IS BETWEEN US.
[ Crying ]
HOW COULD YOU BE SO WICKED...
SO CRUEL ?
NO, FATHER WAS RIGHT.
YOU DO--  YOU SPOIL
EVERYTHING YOU TOUCH.
I WAS AFRAID OF YOU
ALL THE TIME WE WERE ABROAD.
I HAD NO REST WHEN THOUGHT
YOU WERE ALWAYS...
TALKING TO HIM.
YOU ARE A MOST
UNGRATEFUL GIRL.
DO YOU THINK
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE
WHO HAS LOST ?
I THOUGHT OF
THE YOUNG MAN
AS MY OWN--
[ Gasping ]
MY OWN SON.
I'M SURE
WE NEVER TALKED
OF ANYTHING BUT YOU.
YES.
YOU TALKED ABOUT ME AND TALKED
ABOUT ME UNTIL YOU MADE HIM SICK
OF THE VERY MENTION OF MY NAME.
IF YOU TRULY LOVED HIM...
YOU WOULD WANT
MORE FOR HIM.
[ Knocking, Creaking ]
- IT'S TIME ?
- CATHERINE IS DOWNSTAIRS
IN THE PARLOR.
[ Door Creaks, Shuts ]
[ Children Arguing,
Indistinct ]
[ Boy #1 ]
NO, HE SAID I COULD.
[ Boy #2 ]  GET OUT OF THE WAY !
[ Woman ]  JAMES !
YOU SHOULD NOT
HAVE COME.
I'M PAST THE POINT
OF PROPRIETY.
I APOLOGIZE, MISS SLOPER.
I HAVE GIVEN UP
EVERYTHING FOR YOU.
I CAN'T BE THE CAUSE
OF YOUR LOSING
ALL THAT IS DEAR.
BUT ACTUALLY,
I-I HAVE NOTHING.
I WILL WRITE TO YOU.
THAT IS BEST.
I DO NOT WISH YOU
TO WRITE ME.
BE THE MAN
YOU PROFESS TO BE.
LET ME HEAR YOU SAY
YOU ARE ONLY INTERESTED
IN MY FORTUNE.
SAY IT...
SO I WILL NEVER SPEND
A SLEEPLESS NIGHT...
THINKING IT WAS SOMETHING
I DID OR DID NOT DO.
- AT LEAST GIVE ME
THAT SMALL COMFORT.
- YOUR FATHER WILL COMFORT YOU.
HEAVEN DELIVER ME
FROM MY FATHER'S COMFORT.
HE WILL REINSTATE
YOUR RIGHTS WHEN HE SEES
THAT WE'RE NOT TO MARRY.
SAY IT.
DON'T PUSH SO.
SAY IT !
[ Shouting ]
SAY WHAT ?
THAT-THAT I WANTED YOU
WITH YOUR MONEY ?
IS-IS THAT SO IMMORAL ?
[ Chuckles ]
WOULD YOU-- WOULD YOU WANT ME
WITHOUT MY ATTRIBUTES ?
YOU HAVE MONEY,
I HAVE-- I HAVE THIS.
IT WAS A FAIR EXCHANGE.
[ Door Shuts ]
[ Whispering ]
CATHERINE.
MORRIS !  MORRIS !
MORRIS.
[ Panting ]
ALL THAT IS MINE,
YOU CAN HAVE.
I'M INDUSTRIOUS.
I CAN COOK AND I CAN SEW.
I'LL LIVE SO SIMPLY.
[ Sighs ]
YOU KNOW...
10,000 A YEAR--
THAT'S A FORTUNE.
OH, YEAH,
BUT NOT WHEN ONE
WAS EXPECTING 30,
AND SPENT TWO YEARS
OF ONE'S YOUTH
IN PURSUANCE OF IT.
I KNOW, BUT--
I KNOW, I KNOW !
I KNOW WHAT I AM.
I KNOW WHAT I LACK.
BUT I'LL BE A LOVING,
GOOD AND UNDERSTANDING WIFE.
YOU'LL NEVER SUFFER
A MOMENT'S TROUBLE FROM ME.
MY FATHER--
I'LL GO TO MY-MY FATHER,
AND I'LL BEG HIM.
OH !  [ Sobbing ]
YOU CANNOT LEAVE ME
TO THAT HOUSE.
WHAT DO YOU WANT
ME TO DO ?
JUST-JUST TELL ME
WHAT YOU WANT ME TO DO.
[ Screaming ]  FOR GOD'S SAKE !
WHAT DO YOU THINK I AM ?
I'M NOT GOOD ENOUGH FOR YOU !
NOT NEARLY GOOD ENOUGH.
WHAT DO YOU WANT ME TO DO ?
I WANT YOU TO LOVE ME.
WELL, MARRY ME, THEN.
[ Sniffling ]
WHY ?
MORRIS !
[ Sobs ]
[ Horse Whinnies ]
UUH !
DO YOU WANT THESE ?
YES.  THANK YOU, GRETA.
IT'S GINGER.
ARE YOU PREPARING
FOR A MARRIED LIFE
IN WHICH SERVANTS HAVE NO ROLE ?
THE COOK IS FRIGHTENED
OF ANYTHING NEW.
IF I WANT ANYTHING THAT EVEN
WHISPERS OF THE EXOTIC,
I MUST SHOW HER.
IT OCCURS TO  ME THAT YOU'RE
NOT... TREATING ME WITH ALL
THE CONSIDERATION I DESERVE.
HOW SO ?
WE'VE BEEN BACK FROM OUR TRIP
ALMOST THREE MONTHS.
YOU MUST HAVE SET
YOUR WEDDING DATE.
I ASKED THAT YOU GIVE ME NOTICE.
I HAVE NOT LEFT YOUR HOUSE.
PERHAPS NOT IN BODY,
BUT YOU MAY AS WELL BE UNDER
THE CONJUGAL ROOF...
FOR ALL THE BENEFIT
WE HAVE OF YOUR SOCIETY.
[ Catherine ]
WELL...
[ Clears Throat ]
I WILL TRY TO BE
MORE SOCIABLE.
I THINK YOU OUGHT TO.
YOU STRIKE ME YOU'RE
A VERY LUCKY YOUNG LADY.
IT WOULD BE A CONVENIENCE
TO KNOW WHEN I CAN EXPECT
AN EMPTY HOUSE.
FOR WHEN YOU GO,
YOUR AUNT MARCHES.
IS IT TOMORROW ?
NEXT WEEK ?
I SHALL NOT BE LEAVING.
HE'S BACKED OUT ?
I HAVE BROKEN OFF
MY ENGAGEMENT.
I HAVE ASKED HIM
TO LEAVE NEW YORK
FOR A LONG, LONG TIME.
HOW DOES HE TAKE
HIS DISMISSAL ?
I DON'T KNOW.
YOU MEAN YOU DON'T CARE.
YOU'RE VERY CRUEL,
AFTER ENCOURAGING HIM...
AND PLAYING HIM
FOR SO LONG.
I AM MY FATHER'S DAUGHTER.
[ Chopping ]
ALMOST.  TWO MORE.
YES, AND... VERY GOOD !
HAPPY BIRTHDAY !
YEA !
ALL RIGHT.
SIT DOWN, EVERYONE,
ON YOUR SEATS...
LIKE LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
NOT ANIMALS IN THE ZOO.
[ Child Giggles ]
PUT YOUR NAPKINS
ON YOUR CLOTHES,
PLEASE.
[ Laughing ]
LET ME HAVE
MY GODCHILD.
[ Boy ]
NOT ME.
HE IS MY DARLING.
[ Laughs ]
YOU HAVEN'T
EATEN ALL DAY.
CAN YOU BELIEVE
MY DAUGHTER IS
EIGHT YEARS OLD ?
DOESN'T SEEM LIKE YESTERDAY
WE WERE HERE FOR THE PURPOSE
OF MY ENGAGEMENT ?
[ Sighs ]
IT SEEMS VERY
LONG AGO TO ME.
ANOTHER LIFETIME.
SUPPOSE WHEN I
THINK ABOUT IT
IT DOES TO ME TOO.
THEY WERE GOOD DAYS,
THOUGH, CATHERINE;
FULL OF PROMISE,
EXPECTATION.
OUR WHOLE FUTURE
LAY BEFORE US.
CATHERINE...
THE COMFORT OF BEING
AN IDIOT IS THAT PEOPLE
PARDON YOU READILY.
- HMM.
-  FORGIVE ME.
DR. LUDLOW.
WELCOME.
GOOD EVENING,
MARIAN.
* AND LIGHT FAIRIES
* BABIES, FOXES
* ELVES SO MERRY
* COME TO SEE ME NOW
* THEN GO, PLEASE GO
* AND DANCE WITH THEM
* SO GO, PLEASE GO
* ALL NIGHT AGAIN
* [ Continues, Indistinct ]
IS NOT THAT
A PERFECT PICTURE ?
* WILL BE WAITING THERE
YOU KNOW,
YOU REALLY SHOULD TRY IT.
[ Laughs ]
WHAT ARE YOU SUGGESTING
WE TRY ?
MOTHERHOOD.
[ Laughing ]
WELL, MARRIAGE FIRST, OF COURSE.
AT LEAST, TO LEAD IN.
[ Chuckling ]
ALAS, IT IS NOT I
WHO POSSESS THE COLD FEET.
I'M GOING TO GO
AND GET SOME PORT.
I LEAVE MY FUTURE
IN VERY CAPABLE HANDS.
[ Cooing ]
[ Man ]  DO YOU WANT ONE ?
HE'S SO CHARMING,
CATHERINE.
IT SEEMS EXCEEDINGLY RUDE
TO REFUSE HIM.
HE'D MAKE A GOOD HUSBAND.
[ Woman Screaming ]
GET HELP !
[ Man ]
KEEP BACK.
GIVE THE MAN SOME AIR.
[ All Chattering ]
CATHERINE, CATHERINE !
[ Choking ]
CATHERINE !
[ Man ]
HE'S NOT BREATHING.
[ Crying ]
FATHER ?
WHO WOULD EVER HAVE BELIEVED
THAT DOCTORS MAKE
THE WORST PATIENTS ?
I WOULD.
YOU NEVER CHANGED THIS ROOM.
IN THIS ROOM,
I COULD ALLOW HER PRESENCE.
DO YOU SUPPOSE
YOU'LL MARRY JOHN LUDLOW ?
NO.
I DON'T SUPPOSE
I SHALL.
IS IT, BY CHANCE, BECAUSE
YOU PLAN TO MARRY TOWNSEND
AFTER MY DEATH ?
I WILL NOT LISTEN
TO TALK OF DEATH.
I'M DYING.
THERE'S NOTHIN'
TO TALK ABOUT.
AS A PHYSICIAN,
I UNDERSTAND THESE THINGS.
IT WOULD GIVE ME
GREAT SATISFACTION...
IF YOU WERE TO PROMISE
THAT UPON MY DEATH
YOU WILL NOT MARRY TOWNSEND.
I VERY SELDOM THINK
OF MR. TOWNSEND.
ALL THE EASIER
TO KEEP YOUR PROMISE.
I CAN'T PROMISE.
YOU'RE VERY OBSTINATE.
I DON'T THINK YOU UNDERSTAND.
PLEASE EXPLAIN, THEN.
I CAN'T EXPLAIN.
AND I CAN'T PROMISE.
THE WILL OF RECORD DIVIDED
DR. SLOPER'S ESTATE IN SIX WAYS.
MRS. PENNIMAN IS TO RECEIVE
$2,000 A YEAR
FOR THE REST OF HER LIFE.
AND MRS. ALMOND,
THE SAME AMOUNT.
TO HIS COUSINS,
BETHANN AND ROBERT LAWSON,
HE'S LEFT
A ONE-TIME GIFT OF $500.
MAUREEN O'DONNELL
IS TO RECEIVE...
$100 A YEAR
IN ADDITION TO HER SALARY...
AS LONG AS SHE REMAINS
AN EMPLOYEE
AT 21 WASHINGTON SQUARE.
CATHERINE SLOPER IS TO RECEIVE
THE BALANCE OF THE ESTATE,
VALUED SOMEWHERE
UPWARDS OF $300,000.
AS I'VE SAID,
THAT IS THE WILL OF RECORD,
WRITTEN SOME TEN YEARS AGO.
HOWEVER, SEVERAL WEEKS
BEFORE HIS DEATH,
THE DOCTOR
RECORDED THE CODICIL.
"THE AMOUNTS
ACCORDED TO ALL...
"REMAIN UNCHANGED
WITH ONE EXCEPTION:
"IN THE CASE
OF CATHERINE SLOPER,
"HER PORTION
HAS BEEN REDUCED TO THIS HOUSE
ON WASHINGTON SQUARE.
THE BULK OF THE ESTATE GOES
TO VARIOUS AND SUNDRY MEDICAL
INSTITUTIONS AROUND THE CITY."
HE WROTE AN EXPLANATION
OF THIS CHANGE,
WHICH, I'M SURE, YOU'LL WISH
TO READ IN PRIVATE, MISS SLOPER.
PLEASE, READ THE CODICIL,
MR. WEBBER.
THIS IS SOMETHING BETWEEN YOU
AND YOUR FATHER, MISS SLOPER.
WOULD YOU PLEASE EXCUSE US ?
NO.
WE HAVE SOME FAMILY MATTERS
TO ATTEND TO.
BY THE VERY NATURE
OF THE GESTURE...
AND THE FACT--
PLEASE, EVERYONE, SIT.
AND PLEASE READ IT TO ME,
MR. WEBBER.
"SHE IS AMPLY PROVIDED FOR
ON HER MOTHER'S SIDE,
"NEVER HAVING SPENT MORE THAN
A FRACTION OF HER INCOME
FROM THIS SOURCE.
"SO THAT HER FORTUNE
IS ALREADY MORE THAN SUFFICIENT
TO ATTRACT...
"THE UNSCRUPULOUS ADVENTURERS
WHO SHE HAS GIVEN ME
REASON TO BELIEVE...
THAT SHE PERSISTS IN REGARDING
AS AN INTERESTING CLASS."
- YOU MUST BREAK THE WILL.
-  NO, NO, NO.  I--
[ Giggles ]
I LIKE IT VERY MUCH.
CATHERINE, IT'S--
IT'S A TRAVESTY.
NO, NO.
I THINK, UM,
IT'S RATHER FLATTERING.
I THINK IT'S THE PERFECTLY
FITTING CONCLUSION...
TO THE SAGA OF FATHER'S
ALL-IMPORTANT FORTUNE.
I LIKE IT...
VERY MUCH, INDEED.
LET'S HAVE, UM,
SOME TEA, SHALL WE ?
OH, NO, NO.
PERHAPS SOMETHING STRONGER.
AUNT LAVINIA, LET'S
BREAK OUT THE GOOD PORT.
WELL, IS IT NOT
CUSTOMARY TO CELEBRATE
THE READING OF THE WILL ?
[ Giggling ]
COME ON, EVERYONE.
JOIN ME, PLEASE.
[ Giggling ]
* THERE ONCE WAS A PLAIN
LITTLE PIECE OF STRING *
* ALL ALONE
AND WITH NOTHING TO DO *
* EACH NIGHT IT WOULD WISH
MORE THAN ANYTHING *
* FOR A SOMEONE
TO TIE ITSELF TO *
* THEN ONE DAY A FINGER
CAME WANDERING BY *
* AND THE PLAIN LITTLE STRING
QUICKLY CAUGHT HIS EYE *
* THE FINGER SAID
JUST COME ALONG WITH ME
* I CAN TELL YOU
HOW HAPPY YOU'LL BE *
* I HAVE A BROKEN STRING
ON MY FIDDLE
* I CANNOT PLAY A THING
ON MY FIDDLE *
* AND MUSICALLY SPEAKING
YOU'RE JUST WHAT I'M SEEKING *
* WITH YOU
I'LL BE ABLE TO PLAY *
* YOU'VE MADE A MISTAKE
SAID THE LITTLE STRING *
* I HAVE NEVER
MADE MUSIC BEFORE *
* THE FINGER SAID
I'LL TEACH YOU HOW TO SING *
* AND YOU WON'T
BE ALONE ANYMORE *
* HE PLAYED ON THE STRING
AT A FANCY DRESS BALL *
* AND THE SOUND
THRILLED THE DANCERS
AND FILLED THE HALL *
* SO SOMETIMES A PLAIN
LITTLE PIECE OF STRING *
* MAKES THE PRETTIEST MUSIC
OF ALL *
-  GOING-HOME TIME.
- [ All ]
AWW !
WELL, IT MUST BE
NO ONE WANTS THE BISCUITS
THAT GRANDMA'S BAKED.
[ All Chattering ]
EDITH, IS YOUR MOTHER
WORKING LATE AGAIN TONIGHT ?
MM-HMM.
[ Girl ]
WAIT FOR ME !
WELL, YOU MUST HELP ME
CLEAN UP THIS MESS !
I NEVER CAN SEEM
TO MANAGE IT ALONE.
THERE'S ALWAYS
SO MUCH TO DO.
WHAT HAVE YOU GOT THERE ?
MY BOOK.
WHAT IS THAT ?
WHAT'S THAT SAY ?
"UPS--"
UPSETTING.
[ Murmuring ]
- THAT'S RIGHT.
"PONDO, THE DOG, WHO WAS--"
- [ Gasps ]
OH, MY DEAR !
OH, MY DEAR, THIS WILL NOT DO !
IT WILL NOT DO AT ALL.
[ Gasping ]
WHAT ?  AUNT ?
YOU KNOW, THE MOST-- THE MOST
EXTRAORDINARY HAPPENSTANCE.
[ Laughing ]
OH, I HAD THE GOOD--
NOW PROMISE ME--
OH, PROMISE ME--
PROMISE ME YOU'LL BE CIVIL.
PROMISE ME, CATHERINE.
PROMISE ME.
THANK YOU.
AUNT, UM, COULD YOU TAKE EDITH
IN FOR SOME MILK AND BISCUITS ?
OH, YES.  COME ALONG NOW.
WHAT'S YOUR NAME ?
EDNA ?
EDITH.
COME ON.
[ Sighs ]
THERE HAVE BEEN CHANGES.
HMM.
HOW HAVE THE YEARS
TREATED YOU, MORRIS ?
BADLY.
BUT, UM--
[ Crockery Clatters ]
I SUPPOSE YOU WOULD SAY
THAT'S AS IT SHOULD HAVE BEEN.
YOU LOOK VERY WELL.
I HAVE--
I HAVE VENTURED--
I SO MUCH WANTED TO--
I WAS DETERMINED THAT--
WILL YOU NOT SIT DOWN ?
NO, I THINK
I HAD BETTER NOT.
FOR MANY YEARS
IT HAS BEEN...
MY DEEPEST DESIRE
TO BE FRIENDS AGAIN.
WELL, WE BOTH KNOW
WE WERE NEVER FRIENDS.
OH, CATHERINE,
YOU DO ME AN INJUSTICE.
YOU TREATED ME BADLY.
NOT IF YOU
THINK OF IT RIGHTLY.
YOU HAD YOUR LIFE
WITH YOUR FATHER,
WHICH WAS WHAT I COULDN'T
MAKE UP MY MIND TO ROB YOU OF.
YES.  I HAD THAT.
THE PAST CAN BE PUT BEHIND US
IF YOU WILL ALLOW IT.
I WILL NOT ALLOW IT.
YOU HURT ME TOO BADLY.
I FELT IT VERY MUCH.
I FELT IT FOR YEARS.
IT MADE A GREAT CHANGE
IN MY LIFE.
BUT I CAN'T
TALK ABOUT IT.
WHY DIDN'T YOU
MARRY, THEN ?
LAVINIA TELLS ME...
THERE HAVE BEEN CHANCES.
I DIDN'T WISH TO MARRY.
YES.
YOU HAD NOTHING TO GAIN.
I HAD NOTHING TO GAIN.
WHAT EVER ELSE HAPPENED,
I DID--
I DID LOVE ONCE.
WELL, ACTUALLY.
DO YOU HATE ME ?
NO.
BUT PLEASE
DON'T COME HERE AGAIN.
GOOD-BYE, THEN.
* [ Piano ]
* [ Continues ]
* [ Woman Singing, Italian ]
Encoded by VYTO
Support us by visiting P2PDL.com