[TV] Good Morning.
Welcome to Seattle Today.
I am the captain
of the Pinafore
- And a right good captain too
- You're very, very good--
It's almost ready,
you guys.
- We'll be right down.
Occasionally say
I'm never, never sick at sea
- What never
- No never
- Well hardly ever
[ TV ] I'm gonna be talking
about traveling with children.
[ Scream ]
Michael!
Emma,
stay right there.
What's the matter?
Claire, stay here.
Mommy?
Hey!
- Ooo, I'm sorry. Sorry.
- Hey, hey, hey.
- [ Michael ] What are you doing here?
- Mommy?
It's okay, sweetheart.
- Honey, this gentleman says
the Better Ways Society sent him.
- Um... better day.
Sorry.
Better Day Society.
The Better Day Society
helps place...
the mentally disabled
with employment.
I live there.
- Of course!
You're here to build the fence.
- Y eah.
I tried knocking.
Solomon, right? Rene Peterson told us
about the work you did.
I'm Claire and this is
my husband, Michael.
- Yeah, we met outside.
- And this is Emma.
Hello.
It's nice to make
your acquaintance, Emma.
[ Claire ]
I'm gonna throw some shoes on.
See if our guest would like
anything to drink.
My mom says to ask
if you want anything.
I'd like a
brand new bicycle...
with a big basket...
on the handlebars
and some gears.
That sounds neat.
Y eah.
Okay, um...
okay, I see.
Um...
you wanted
to take away this.
Y eah.
The new fence
should contain...
the area here and
the gate should be there.
Um...
do you want the fence
to keep people in...
or...
keep people out?
Well... both.
But mostly
to keep people out.
Okay.
One...
two...
three... five...
nine.
[ Chuckling ]
Just kidding.
I got the tape measure.
See?
Is everything all right
out here?
Right... as rain.
- Mrs. Bartel?
- That's me.
The doctor
will see you now.
-This is your first exam with Dr. Mott?
-Y es, it is.
The doctor who delivered
my little girl retired.
Dr. Mott was kind enough
to take me on midterm.
- He's one of the best.
Expecting his own, you know?
- Oh, really?
- Take everything off, put
the gown on, open at the front.
- Okay.
- Doctor.
- Mrs. Bartel!
- Hi.
- I'm Dr. Mott.
- It's nice to meet you.
So...
how are we today?
Just great.
The baby's kinda
kicking up a storm all day.
This is your second.
You're a pro at this.
I see you have
a history of asthma.
- Any problems?
- No, none at all.
- Why don't we take a look? Feet up.
- Oh, okay.
I didn't think it was usual to give
pelvic exams after the third month.
We won't again
until the 36th week,
but... I want to make sure
my new patients...
have a full exam
on their first visit.
It's Mrs. Miller. She's calling
again for the test results.
Why don't you go ahead and
give them to her. She's all clear.
- If she has any questions,
I'll call her back.
- Yes, doctor.
[ Nurse ]
Would you hold, please?
Oh, Maria,
when you're in the lab,
would you call in the results
of yesterday's virupaps?
Yes, doctor.
- Sorry about that.
- It's okay.
Why don't we start
with the breast exam?
Weather's been beautiful
these days, hasn't it?
It has. Yeah.
I love taking walks
after the rainstorm.
It's very important
to be able...
to give yourself
your own breast exams.
Relax.
Mrs. Bartel, we need to
schedule your next appointment.
[ Wheezing ]
- Claire?
- Oh, Michael!
- Honey, what's the matter?
- Michael.
[ Crying ]
Just hold me.
Honey, what's wrong?
Claire?
It was the way
he was touching me.
He wasn't examining me.
It was like...
he was getting off
on it.
I mean...
what if I accused him
and I was wrong?
Do you think
you're wrong now?
No.
Then we have to file
a complaint.
- Michael, I don't think I can do that.
- Claire, listen to me.
If we don't
report this,
he's gonna do the same thing
to somebody else.
You have
to trust yourself.
I don't think I can,
Michael.
I think you can.
We'll go through it
together.
[ TV ]
Even with food and supplies
flown into the area daily,
the aid is not reaching
many of the refugees.
Dr. Victor Mott, Seattle
gynecologist and obstetrician,
was brought up today on formal charges
by the district attorney's office.
The scandal began last week when one
of Mott's pregnant patients...
went to the state medical
board claiming...
she had been sexually molested
by the doctor during an examination.
Since the patient's initial accusation,
four more women have come forward...
alleging that they, too,
had been sexually molested.
Citing the possibility of criminal
misdeeds, the state medical board...
- turned the case over to
the district attorney's office.
- [ Gunshot ]
Dr. Mott was unavailable
for comment.
[ Man ]
The suicide provision
is quite clear;
However, we may be able to get
the insurance company to return
a small settlement.
Mrs. Mott, although your
husband had sizable assets,
- they've been frozen by the state.
- Frozen.
This is normal procedure
when the estate...
is probably going to be sued
by a number of sources.
You are free to stay in the house
until you have your baby,
but you should begin
to make alternative plans.
I'm very sorry,
Mrs. Mott.
Can I help?
Get an ambulance here
right away!
[ Mrs. Mott ]
My baby.
[ Groaning ]
- We'll need blood.
- [ lndistinct ]
- Four units cross matched now!
- Undo the belt.
- I want vital signs!
- Pediatrics is standing by.
- My baby.
- Now lift.
She's hemorrhaging. We gotta get this
baby out or we're gonna lose them both.
- I feel it kicking.
- You can?
- Ow! Ow!
- Keep her still.
I can't stop
this blood.
Call anesthesia.
I'm gonna operate.
Chest compressions are reducing.
We're losing him!
No!
Hold her down.
- He's gone.
- No.
- Anesthesiologist is on the way.
- We're prepping her for surgery.
Increase the drip
to 90.
Her pressure
is 80 over 40.
- She didn't touch it.
- Emergency hysterectomy.
She's been so depressed,
she won't talk. Let me try.
[ TV ]
...against the late
Victor Mott's estate.
The suits were filed by four of the
women who claim they had been molested.
You have got to eat.
The investigation was dropped
when Dr. Mott was found dead...
from a self-inflicted
gunshot wound.
Claire Bartel has not filed a suit
although she was the first...
to accuse Mott of molesting
her during an exam.
I'll leave your food.
Her accusation prompted the other
women to come forward.
I'm coming up
to the back door.
I'm getting close
I am now entering...
the back door.
- Good morning, Solomon.
- Good morning.
- [ Crying ]
- Thank you.
[ Emma ]
You can't catch me, Daddy.
Hi, little baby.
- Get back here. I gotcha!
- [ Crying ]
Sorry, Mom.
Oh, don't cry,
baby.
Oh, yes,
that's a big boy.
Thank you, Solomon.
Don't cry, sweetheart.
Remember the rule at
the Better Day Society?
They said it's best if
you didn't handle the baby.
[ Solomon ]
I'm sorry. I forgot.
- I only wanted to help.
- I know you did.
Thanks.
Ooo-ooo-ooo.
They're replacing the small greenhouses
at the botanical gardens.
- I thought I might get
one of the frames.
- Let me guess.
You want to build
your own greenhouse.
Y eah! The frame's there,
the hardware's there.
All I'd have to do is erect it
and replace the glass.
Honey, don't you think
you're taking on too much?
Have you given any more
thought to hiring a nanny?
Honestly, I wouldn't
feel comfortable...
having any of the girls
I've interviewed take care of Joey.
Claire, it's not like
when we had Emma.
You don't need to do
everything yourself.
What about Solomon?
He could be our nanny.
Honey, I don't think
that Solomon...
would make
a very good nanny.
Why not?
Remember we had the talk about
what a special person Solomon is?
- Y eah.
- Well, there are just some things...
that he can't do.
What's gonna happen
to Solomon...
when Solomon
finishes painting the trim?
[ Michael ]
Well...
when he finishes painting,
we'll have to find something
else for him to do.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Hurry up, sweetheart.
- Bye, Mom.
- Bye.
Mrs. Thompson?
Mrs. Thompson!
[ Squeaking Brakes ]
Thanks.
- Thanks for stopping.
- No problem.
- Here you go, sweetheart.
- Thanks, Mom.
Thanks. I think it's gonna rain later.
That was really nice of you.
- You're welcome.
- Well, thanks. Thank you.
Excuse me, do you know
where the Bartels live?
Well...
I'm Claire Bartel.
- Oh, hi. I'm Peyton Flanders.
- Hi.
- I was coming about the nanny position.
- Oh!
- All right. You wanna
come up to the house?
- Yeah.
I can't believe I forgot
I had an appointment.
I'm usually so good
about these things.
Actually, I didn't have
an appointment.
Oh. Did the agency
just tell you to stop by?
- Well, no. I'm not with an agency.
- Oh.
The truth is, I've only
worked with one family.
They're moving and I didn't
know what I was gonna do next.
I was with their
little girl in the park.
Nannies talk and I heard
that your family needed someone.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't
have just showed up.
- I've made you uncomfortable.
- Oh no, it's fine.
You're here
so come on in.
- Are you sure? Okay.
- Yeah, yeah.
Usually I have a set
of questions I ask, like...
- are you old enough to drive?
- Thank you.
Oh, here.
Don't lose this.
My husband's been after me
to fix this thing.
Well...
[ Chuckle ]
how did you come
to be a nanny?
Well, um...
a few years ago
I was pregnant.
I lost the baby and my husband
within days of each other.
The miscarriage prevented me
from having more children.
It was a very
difficult time.
A mutual friend set me up
with a family looking for a nanny.
It turned out to be... a wonderful
experience for both of us.
I adore children.
I love being with them,
taking care of them.
For me it's...
the next best thing
to actually being a mother.
Well, I'm building
my own greenhouse.
And... although I'll just be
right in the backyard,
I'm anticipating
being very busy.
[ Crying ]
That's Joe.
Oh!
I'd love to meet him.
The nursery is across
from the master bedroom.
[ Solomon ]
Claire? I need to ask you something.
I'll be right back.
Excuse me.
[ Crying, Cooing ]
[ Claire ]
Try to open the window from the inside.
If you can't, wait
'til Michael comes home.
Solomon, this is Peyton.
Peyton, Solomon.
- Nice to meet you, Solomon.
- Oh, hello.
[ Gasp ]
Oh, I'm sorry!
I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- That's all right. It was an accident.
Anyone can have an accident.
Okay.
Ohh!
He's beautiful.
He's very hungry.
I've taken up
half your morning.
No problem,
I really enjoyed it.
I should be going. I'm gonna
leave a letter of reference.
I can show myself out.
You don't have to get up.
Peyton, would you like to
have dinner with us tonight?
I'd love for you
to meet the family.
I'd love to.
Say around 6:30?
I'll be here.
I'm in charge of
the salad dressing.
And now you're in charge of setting
the table, sweetheart.
Daddy's gonna be home
any minute.
If you don't mind my asking,
what does your husband do?
Michael's a
genetic engineer.
He works for a research
outfit called Biotechnics.
Daddy is a
mad scientist!
[ Honking ]
It's Daddy!
Here, let me help
with that.
Thanks.
Gimme a kiss.
Thank you very much.
- You helping Mom out, huh?
- Shh.
What are you
shushing me for?
[ Whispering ]
Oh, Joey's asleep. Thank you.
Shh.
- [ Michael ] Hi, beautiful.
- How are you?
- Peyton, this is my husband, Michael.
- Hi.
[ Michael ]
I gotta tell you guys,
- that was one of
the all-time great meals.
- It was delicious.
I was in charge
of the salad dressing.
That's right. She did.
She made it all by herself.
When Mom finishes
the greenhouse,
- I'm in charge of the strawberries.
- Really?
- That sounds like a very important job.
- It is.
[ Whispering ]
She seems terrific. What's the catch?
There is no catch.
I think she's great.
I don't think she'll be a nanny
forever, but we can get her
to commit for a year.
- [ Michael ] Let's grab her up.
- Yeah? Okay.
[ Gasp ]
Oh my God!
[ Crying ]
- What happened?
- He had this in his mouth.
- Mommy's earring.
- It must have fallen out
when I was holding him.
He's okay.
I'm sorry
I frightened everybody.
- I'm glad you caught it.
- I'm glad you got there on time.
[ Doorbell ]
- Hi.
- This is for you.
- Oh, thank you.
You didn't have to do that.
[ Chiming ]
Oh, that's
very pretty.
They say a wind chime
helps a baby sleep.
Why don't we get
you settled downstairs,
- then we'll hang it up
outside the nursery.
- Okay.
This is a little bit dark,
but your room gets more light.
This is...
the laundry room.
And this is your room.
- Ah... it's perfect.
- You like it?
[ Alarm ]
[ Chiming ]
[ Cooing ]
There we go.
Mom, look!
We did it.
Oh boy!
Let's see.
- Emma, you can certainly shovel!
- Thank you.
How pretty!
It looks just like
your house.
Y eah, I know.
We put it out every year...
[ Claire ]
when the martins come back.
Who are the martins?
They're large swallows.
The same family comes back
every year to visit us.
Yeah!
I would come back too.
That is a beautiful
bracelet, Claire.
You like that?
I got that at an antique show.
- You can borrow it anytime.
- Well, thank you.
This must be
a special occasion.
I always feel sexy and glamorous
when I wear this dress.
It's a present
from Michael.
Okay...
which shoes should I wear,
red or black?
- Are you wearing a jacket?
- Yeah. Well, no.
- Maybe not.
- Then I'd go with the black.
You think so?
[ Claire ]
Yeah, I guess you're right.
- [ Doorbell ]
- That's them. Now I'm really late.
- Where are you guys?
- Oh, we're running late.
-Where's Marlene? She want to come in?
-Nah, she's on the phone.
Oh damn.
- What is it?
- It's just a stain.
It's perfume oil.
I must have perfume oil
on my hands.
-Don't move. I'll go get some club soda.
-Thanks.
Marty, this is... Peyton.
- Hello, Peyton.
- Hello. Nice to meet you.
- I need to get something for Claire.
- Okay.
[ Marty ]
Whew!
Maybe we should
go ahead and have kids.
I just want to inform everybody that
this place will not hold our table.
- Hello, Marlene.
- Hello.
What's with you?
What do you mean?
Nothing's with me.
Nothing my ass.
Hi, I don't
believe we've met.
-I'm Marlene Craven. You must be Peyton.
-Nice to meet you.
- Poison.
- Excuse me?
- The perfume. You're
wearing Claire's perfume.
- Oh.
Well, Claire
needs me upstairs.
You look great.
- You don't think that's funny?
- No.
There she is.
- Hi. Sorry.
- Hi.
[ Marlene ]
You look great!
Honey, I thought you were going
to wear that dress I bought you.
Is there something wrong
with what I'm wearing?
That's not what I meant.
Um... boy you look good!
[ Marlene ] You look beautiful.
Let's go. I'm starving.
You have the number
where we'll be.
I do. Have fun.
Bye.
[ Scream ]
Zombies.
The living dead.
This is great! Mom never
lets me watch these movies.
That's why we have
to keep it a secret.
Do you know what
a secret is, Emma?
Yeah, something
you can't tell anybody...
- No matter what.
- That's right.
Now we have our own little
secret club. That's our sign.
It was fun meeting your
Aunt Marlene and Uncle Marty.
They've known your mom and dad
a long time, huh?
Aunt Marlene grew up
with daddy.
They used to be boyfriend
and girlfriend when they were little.
Is that right?
Do you have
any boyfriends?
- No, I hate boys.
- You do?
If I tell you something, you
promise not to tell anybody?
I promise.
Secret club.
Well...
this mean kid at school,
his name is Roth,
he's been really mean
to me.
But he said if I told,
I'd be dead meat.
He said that to you?
- Did your mother do anything about it?
- She tried...
but she couldn't help.
You never, ever...
Iet an attractive woman take
a power position in your home.
- It's very bad business.
- A power position.
You heard what I said.
What's that saying?
- "The hand with the baby..." that...
- Hey, Marl?
How much did you get for
the Fletcher house last week?
Three...
and change.
All I'm saying is
you have to watch your back.
I'm serious!
There's too much pressure.
A woman can feel like a failure if
she doesn't bring in 50 grand a year...
and still make time for
blow jobs and homemade lasagna.
Marlene's not
much of a cook.
Marlene, I think I'm
gonna bum one of these.
You're such
a bad influence.
He only smokes
around you now.
- One isn't gonna kill me.
- Oh, I got it.
"The hand that rocks
the cradle...
is the hand
that rules the world."
You wanna look
at the baby?
Ahh, look.
Hi!
Ahh, look, honey.
- Boy or a girl?
- Boy. His name's Joe.
- How old?
- Three months.
He is beautiful.
- Thank you.
- He has your eyes, you know.
Do you really
think so?
Absolutely!
Do you have
any other children?
Yes, he has a sister.
Her name's Emma.
She looks more like
her father though.
We have one more too,
don't we, sweetheart?
- Peyton.
- Hi, Emma.
Tell me, which one
is he? Where?
Take that!
- The one with the blue
and gray striped shirt?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay.
[ Arguing ]
- Watch it, Trippy!
- Sorry, Roth.
Ouch! My arm! My arm!
I got a message for you, Roth.
Leave Emma alone.
If you don't, I'm gonna
rip your fucking head off!
Ow!
I get it, ma'am.
Let me go!
Don't forget it.
[ Girl ]
Awesome! Wow, that was cool.
Ha-ha ha-ha-ha.
Secret club.
Good morning.
What's the matter?
You're not hungry,
sweetheart?
Shh-shh-shh.
Claire, I thought...
maybe you could use
a cup of coffee.
Oh, thanks.
- Peyton?
- Yeah?
Have you noticed anything
different about Joe?
No, I haven't.
Why, is something wrong?
No. I was just wondering.
I'm real tired. Michael was up all
night finishing his E.P.A. proposal.
- I got up at 4:30 to help him type it.
- I hope it works out.
- Good morning.
- See you tonight.
- You're not gonna have pancakes?
Nah, I've got to go to Federal Express
before I go to the lab.
Let me. That's the last thing
you need to worry about.
You have the time?
My proposal has to go out today.
Okay. Thanks.
I love you.
- Bye-bye.
- Bye, Michael.
[ Peyton ] How long have you
been volunteering here?
Gee, about seven years.
These days, I mainly take care
of the morning maintenance.
- Hi, Claire.
- Hi, Stan.
Kinda like a big
botanist family here,
- right, Stan?
- Y ep.
We sit around talking
about root rot,
drainage properties of shredded bark
and other topics like that.
[ Peyton ] Is your greenhouse gonna be
something like this one?
Oh, well, hopefully.
On a much smaller scale.
I've always loved
growing anything.
When I was little,
my parents thought I was crazy.
They thought I should've
been born on a farm.
[ Cooing ]
Hey!
Ohh!
Hello.
Hello!
Do you have relatives
in Seattle?
Oh no.
No, I don't.
My husband
was my only family.
He's the only one who ever...
really understood me.
He took care of me.
He was murdered.
Murdered?
They never caught
who did it.
But I firmly believe...
what goes around,
comes around.
Is there a
bathroom here?
- Yeah, down through there
on the right side.
- I'll be right back.
Come here,
little one.
Do you need
to be changed?
[ Wheezing ]
Come here.
Michael's proposal. I can't find it.
It was in your purse.
I saw you put it in there!
- Claire, are you all right?
- Asthma. I'll be okay.
Asthma.
Michael, it...
just disappeared.
I retraced my steps. I spoke to
the manager in the restaurant.
He said he'd call
in the morning.
What did they say
when you called again?
They said they'd
consider it next quarter.
- But they said they'd consider it?
- Claire, come on.
We've been over this.
Look, everything
is gonna be okay.
- Michael, I'm so sorry.
- I know you are, honey.
I know you are.
Maybe I left it
at the botanicals.
I'm going to
get back to work.
I'm sorry.
[ Crying ]
- Michael, I'm worried about Joe.
- Why, what's wrong?
Well, it's
his eating habits.
He's not nursing
the way he used to.
How long has this
been going on?
- It's not all the time,
but... a couple of weeks.
- Did you call the doctor?
- Y eah.
- What'd she say?
She said it's fine as long
as he keeps gaining weight.
- Well... I'm sure he's fine, honey.
- Okay.
Someone named Peyton
is here to see you.
- Peyton's here?
- She's waiting in your office.
She's our nanny,
Gilbert.
Uh-huh. Okay.
Let me in on where
you do your hiring.
Hi.
Shh!
He's out cold.
I'm sorry to bother you
here at the office,
- but I just wanted
to talk to you in private.
- Everything all right?
Oh, yeah. Everything's okay.
I just had an idea.
It's Claire's birthday
coming up.
I thought maybe it would be nice
to throw her a surprise party.
She's been feeling
kinda low lately,
- especially with this thing
with your proposal.
- That's a good idea.
- especially with this thing
with your proposal.
- That's a good idea.
- Y eah?
- Y eah.
Oh... do you think,
do you think Marlene
would want to help out?
Help out? You kidding me?
She'll take over.
Well, maybe it's best not
to tell her it's my idea.
Why not?
I wouldn't want her to
think I was competitive.
You know?
About Claire's friendship.
You understand Marlene
pretty well already.
Well, good...
so I'll be going.
Okay, good.
I'm real glad you came by.
- Bye.
Oh!
Solomon!
I want to show you
my sculpture.
Ah...
okay.
Is... that the head?
Or is
that the foot?
No, that's part
of the fur.
Oh!
Okay, I see.
That's a piece
of art.
- I knew you'd see it.
- Y eah.
Y eah.
- Hi, Emma.
- Hi, Peyton.
Hi, Solomon.
Emma, why don't you go inside.
I've got to talk to Solomon.
- Okay.
Are you a retard?
No.
Did you like
looking at me?
Did you like...
Iooking at me?
Don't fuck with me,
retard.
My version of the story
will be...
better than yours.
I won't let
you hurt them.
They're my friends.
I won't let
you hurt them!
Oh boy.
Solomon!
Would you step inside
for a minute?
Okay.
Surprise!
It's for you,
big guy.
I was in charge
of picking it out.
Ohh.
You're my friends.
Oh my.
Oh.
[ Claire ]
Should've seen his face when we gave
him the bicycle. Emma just adores him.
Claire, there's something
that's been bothering me.
I feel a little awkward
bringing it up.
I've been noticing
some behavior that...
I feel might be
inappropriate.
I'm sorry. What
do you mean, inappropriate?
Something about the way
he touches her.
I'm sure you
must've misunderstood.
You're right, Solomon would
never do anything like that.
Besides, it would be obvious
if Emma were keeping a secret.
- I'm sorry.
- Oh no, please. It's okay.
[ Solomon ]
She's coming around.
Whoa! Whoa!
I love you very much,
sweetheart.
You know that
if anything happened,
good or bad,
you can tell me and l
would love you just as much.
Do you know that?
Yes.
We shouldn't have
any secrets, Emma.
Secrets between people who
love each other aren't good.
What's the matter,
baby?
Nothing.
You don't have to say.
Why can't I see
through this glass?
It's fiberglass,
a different kind of glass.
We put real glass in the ceiling
to let the sunlight through.
And this lets the air in so it
doesn't get too hot in the greenhouse.
Claire, Joe's intercom
conked out.
I couldn't find any
batteries in the kitchen.
- Do you think Solomon's
got some in his cart?
- Well...
he's got everything else there.
Let me take a look.
Do you see
what you've done?
[ Wheezing ]
[ Claire ]
Sweetheart?
Come away from
the window, honey.
Emma?
Come sit down.
Peyton.
[ Crying ]
But I don't
understand.
Why did they take
Solomon away?
I guess your mommy didn't
like Solomon very much.
I wanted to help Solomon, but I was
afraid she'd try to send me away too.
I hate her.
I bet your mommy
wasn't mean like mine.
I didn't have
a mommy.
She died when
I was very little.
Your mommy died?
Then who took care
of you?
I had to take care
of myself.
Peyton, if something
happens to my mommy,
would you
take care of me?
Of course I would.
And your daddy too.
I'd take care
of all of you.
- Last of the boxes.
- Yeah.
[ Sigh ]
Emma's gonna be okay,
Claire.
But she's so different
around me lately.
She's not
my little girl.
She's so angry...
and guarded.
I think...
maybe she blames me
because I didn't protect her.
I don't think so,
Claire.
Shh.
Marlene wants to get together tonight
to make out a guest list.
I'm not sure this party
is a good idea now.
- What do you think?
- I think we should go ahead with it.
Everyone could use
some cheering up,
especially Claire. You know how
she's been blaming herself.
Y eah, I think
you're right.
Guess I just
needed to hear it.
[ Cooing ]
[ Marlene ]
Thanks for lunch.
I especially liked the part where
we picked up the fertilizer.
- Oh, you liked that?
- Oh, yeah.
[ Peyton ]
Hi, you two.
- Hi. Oh, can I take him?
- Oh, sure.
- Hi, sweetheart. Hello.
- [ Crying ]
- Let me help.
- He's getting so big.
- [ Crying ]
- He's like a different kid
every time I see him.
[ Crying ]