Previously
on "Wayward Pines"...
You didn't think Wayward Pines
ran itself, did you?
Hey. Who are
all of these people?
Volunteers.
We were changing the world,
and, as a result...
Oh!
...we, ourselves,
were beginning to change.
Testing cryonic suspension was
both dangerous and illegal.
- They're all asleep.
- Yes.
This isn't a little town,
Ethan.
This is
a new civilization.
You have to
tell them the truth.
People are fragile.
They need time to adapt.
Young minds are fearless.
Welcome
to the First Generation.
They're less ingrained
in the old world.
They can accept the truth.
There's a new threat.
We don't know
who they are,
but they're gonna take down
the fence.
If they succeed...
They're not
going to succeed.
It's ready.
Ethan.
It is imperative
you tell no one about
what you've seen
and what you've heard.
I believe
the survival of humanity
may well be
in our hands.
Ethan.
When did you get back?
Have you been sitting here
all night?
Please tell me
you found something.
We have got to get back
to Seattle.
I cannot get ahold
of anybody.
Mom's surgery is
on Wednesday.
Theresa, Theresa.
There is no Seattle.
What are you
talking about?
Look.
When we were pulled
from those car wrecks...
...we weren't taken
directly here.
We were put into
some kind of a...
suspended animation.
What happened to
your arm?
You're gonna think I'm crazy.
But there's these creatures
out there...
monsters.
I saw them
with my own eyes.
Cities destroyed.
This...
this fake little town
is all that's left.
Ethan, what did they do
to you?
What did they do
Did they take you back
to the hospital?
No.
I need you to
try to remember
if they did
anything to you,
- if they injected you with something.
- You don't believe me.
- Are you sure?
- I wasn't at the hospital!
4,028?
Now, what... Okay,
what does this mean?
That's the date.
Ethan.
What's wrong?
It's the starter.
This might take a while.
You guys should walk.
Okay.
Sure.
Let's go.
Oh. Sorry, sorry.
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
_
Good morning,
Mr. Burke.
Can I help you
with something, Pam?
No, but I think I can help you
with something.
Really?
Oh. Franklin Dobbs.
Do you think he's involved
with these subversives?
I don't know.
But when I find out the answer
to that question,
you'll be
the first to know.
Until then,
I've got to do my job,
so if you don't mind...
No, I don't mind.
Go ahead. Do your job.
I'm just here to help.
I would do anything
for my brother.
Even work hand-in-hand
with you.
So, how about it?
You can't do this alone.
You need some help.
I can be
a very good friend.
How about giving me access
to the surveillance system
so I can see
what Franklin's been up to?
S... I kind of thought
we had moved past
this whole
"walk your kid to school" thing.
I just wanted to spend time
with you, if that's all right.
Everything okay?
Yeah.
You ever miss Seattle?
I don't really think
about it.
Really?
Not even camping
with your cousins
or playing with Stanley?
Stanley.
We're not supposed to
think about the past.
Right.
Good morning.
Good morning,
Dr. Jenkins.
Hey.
I like it here, Mom.
I have friends.
I like school.
You'd probably like it,
too,
if you gave it
half a chance.
Okay, well, I'm glad things
are working out for you.
Good morning, guys.
Nice to see you,
Theresa.
Hi.
Hey, Ben.
Mrs. Burke.
Amy, will you help Ben
find a biology textbook?
There's a big stack of them
behind my desk.
Yeah, sure.
Come on.
You know,
I have not set foot
inside that school
or your classroom.
Is there a tour
or a parent/teacher
conference coming up?
School is for children,
Theresa,
not their parents.
Your job is to feed them
and keep them safe.
Let us do the rest.
Oh, that's my cue.
Nice to see you.
Yeah,
it looks really bad.
I want to thank you
for coming down, Franklin.
As the new Sheriff
in town,
I'm making a point
of getting to know
all the shopkeepers
on Main Street.
Never really had
a "get to know you" meeting
with Sheriff Pope.
Franklin, we don't talk
about the past here.
You know that.
Lighten up, Franklin.
I'm just messing
with you.
Oh.
But, listen, I did have
something of a personal nature
that I'd like to discuss
with you.
Gophers.
- Gophers?
- Yeah, that's right.
They're destroying
my lawn.
And I remember looking
through your file one day
and it said that
you worked in, uh...
explosive demolition.
Hmm.
Afraid I c-can't help you,
Sheriff.
Yeah,
I should really be
getting back
to the shop.
So...
Open your books to page 17.
Go ahead and look
at all the pictures.
Giggle if you want.
For obvious reasons,
your textbooks
will remain here in class.
Parents tend to be uncomfortable
with these sorts of images.
Even biology can be
misunderstood.
The point is,
procreation is
a beautiful and blessed thing.
And here in Wayward Pines,
that really is
your most important job.
Ben, Amy.
Would you step up front,
please?
Come on, quickly.
Ahh. Behold,
the male and the female.
Two bodies,
beautifully designed
to fit together
effortlessly, seamlessly.
Two perfect puzzle pieces,
like hand in glove.
Yes, yes, it's embarrassing
to talk about.
But what if...
what if Ben was a bee
and Amy was a flower?
Well, that wouldn't be funny
at all, would it?
Wayward Pines needs
a new generation.
And one day,
not too long from now,
you all will have the honor of
parenting the first generation
of 100% originals.
Now, take a look
around the room.
This is a small town.
Right?
Chances are, your mate...
your co-parent
is sitting right here
in this room.
And it's part of my job
as your teacher and counselor
to help you
find each other.
You two may sit down.
That was weird.
Ah, there you are!
Nurse,
could you give me
a moment alone
with Dr. Jenkins, please?
Thank you.
Wonderful news.
You know, I'm doing my annual
fertility consults this morning.
And already,
two new pregnancies.
Imagine.
Two new members
of our First Generation.
That is wonderful.
David, what is it?
Why are they
trying to undermine us?
Is it inevitable,
this... passion
for self-destruction?
Have you eaten today?
Pam...
is it happening again?
You always
get like this.
You worry so,
and you forget to eat.
Then once
your blood sugar drops,
the whole world
looks gloomy, hmm?
Ethan Burke will ferret out
these troublemakers.
Sheriff Burke
will get us through
this present difficulty.
That's very generous
of you.
Oh,
you believe in him.
I believe in him.
Dr. Jenkins?
Wayne Johnson is here.
Oh.
Thank you, Nurse.
Back to work.
Great news
about the pregnancies.
Oh, indeed.
Just be careful.
- All right, great.
- Okay.
- For sure.
- Yeah. Byebye.
Morning, Ethan.
Friend of yours?
Oh, Franklin?
Yeah. I mean,
you know, it's a small town.
Yeah, you guys have been
seeing a lot of each other.
I'm gonna need you
to come with me
so we can talk more...
privately.
Sure, what about?
About the damn bomb
in my truck, Harold.
I-I don't know anything
about this.
Okay.
Well,
let's go to my office,
and you can tell me about
what you don't know.
All right, let's go.
Don't make me subdue you
again, Harold.
Next time,
I won't be so gentle.
It's okay, folks.
He tripped and fell.
Let's go.
Franklin made the bomb,
and you or somebody
who works for you
planted it
in my truck.
I swear, I don't know anything
about a bomb in your truck.
But you know about the other
bombs that Franklin made...
the ones that are
still out there.
'Cause that's what this is
all about, isn't it?
You want to take down
the fence.
Don't you
want to get out?
Just go somewhere,
anywhere?
There is no somewhere,
no anywhere.
I want names...
...of everybody
in your group,
starting
with your leader.
Who is he?
Or maybe it's a she.
There's no one else.
- Really?
- I acted alone.
- You acted alone?
- Mm-hmm.
So that means that
you did plant the bomb
in my truck,
and you were lying about it
when you denied it,
but you're telling me
the truth now, is that it?
Great.
Okay.
Give this to Kate.
You can go now.
Um, I don't understand.
I confessed.
Yeah, I got it.
You can go.
Morning, beautiful.
Sorry I'm late.
I wish I could blame it
on the traffic.
But somehow, I don't think
that'll fly.
Good morning.
You seem like
you're in a great mood.
Hey.
Crispy like a cracker.
I passed by that lot
this morning, Plot 33?
And I think
I found something.
There appears to be
a substructure of some kind
underneath the soil.
It felt like metal.
Oh, well,
a water tank, maybe.
Y... But it's buried in
an empty lot, Bill, that...
Life's full of mysteries,
all chock-full
of head scratchers.
I wouldn't think about it
too much.
Besides, you really shouldn't
snoop around out there.
And why is that?
The secret to
a safe and happy town
is everyone minding
their own business.
People need to do
what they're supposed to.
And not do
what they're not.
Right.
Now, uh, I need you to go down
to the hospital a bit
and pick up some files
for me.
If... if you're not
too busy.
I got your note.
I came
as soon as I could.
Good. Come on in.
Here, sit down.
Don't worry.
I disabled
all the surveillance in here.
I thought you didn't care
about that.
It's not for my safety.
Coffee?
I heard about the bomb
in your truck.
You have to believe me.
I-I don't know who did that.
Good.
But you can figure out who did,
can't you?
Because
you're their leader.
What if I was?
Come on, Kate!
Of course you are.
Look, Harold was
an accountant.
If there's anybody leading
a resistance in this town,
it's not Harold,
so who else is involved
in this group?
This group is the only thing
that's kept me sane here.
How long
have you been active?
It evolved over time.
We started
as something else.
Just a few of us
trying to connect.
We'd meet in secret,
just to be real
with each other.
Uh...
Kate Hewson,
um, Seattle.
I miss the ferry boats,
oysters,
hiking Burroughs Trail.
My friends.
I'm, uh... I'm...
I'm Franklin.
Uh...
It's all you, man.
Harold Ballinger, St. Paul.
Um...
I have a fiancée.
How come you didn't
tell me any of this
when I first got here?
Ethan, I've been trapped here
for 12 years.
Try and imagine
what that's like.
And then you show up.
And a week later,
you're Sheriff?
All right, look,
it stops now.
Why would I stop trying to
escape this prison?
Look, the world
that you and I knew,
the world outside the fence,
that no longer exists.
It's not 2014.
It's not... It's not even
the 21st century anymore.
What... What do you mean,
it's not
the 21st century anymore?
Hey.
- Good class today.
- Oh, thanks, Amy.
Yeah.
You and Ben look so nice
together.
How is that working out?
It's great, actually.
I really like him.
Like, a lot.
Oh, I'm so glad.
As a teacher,
it's so fulfilling
when an assignment
turns into something more.
Yeah, he's sweet.
Kind of shy.
I don't think
he's had much experience.
You might be
his first real girlfriend.
I was thinking of
maybe asking him out
later tonight.
Go some place secluded
and romantic.
Mm.
I just... I feel like
I'm ready for us
to be more... intimate.
He's not
pressuring you?
Ben?
Oh, God, no.
I just hope I don't
have to pressure him.
I'm so happy for you.
Enjoy this moment.
There's nothing like
being young and in love.
So, let me
get this straight.
Whoever's
behind all this,
the people up there
pulling the strings,
you work for them now?
Hand over whoever it was that
planted the bomb in my truck,
surrender your arms
and explosives
by tomorrow morning,
and everything
stays between us.
You can't take down
that fence.
Okay.
You were right.
They got to Ethan.
We have to advance
the timetable.
He knows about us,
knows about Franklin.
Exactly. We have
a very narrow window.
And we're not gonna get
a second chance.
We have to
tell everyone.
We execute tonight.
Ballinger Toys.
Oh. H-Hello, Pam.
Of course.
Uh, it slipped my mind
completely.
We've been backlogged
with orders and...
I-Is it... is it possible
to reschedule?
Of course, I-I understand
the importance.
Uh, we'll be right over.
All right, then.
It's our annual
fertility consult.
Of course it is.
There's no point
in making her suspicious.
So...
We have a married couple...
young, fertile,
in their prime...
and yet, somehow...
not pregnant.
Yeah.
I don't understand it.
Your lab work is all good.
- There's no problem with the sperm count.
- Good.
And you.
Periods regular?
- Everything is in working order. Hmm.
- Hmm.
Well, thanks so much
for coming in.
You know,
I've always thought
so highly of the two of you,
ever since
I introduced you.
Hmm.
I mean,
what a blend of genetics.
The perfect Wayward Pines
couple.
Hmm. Don't let me down.
Pharmacy, pick up 512.
How much time do you need
to gather the team?
Whatever
you can give me.
And get with Ted
and set the backup plan
in motion.
Wait.
Do you think
we need both?
We're only gonna get
one shot.
Kate.
Do you have a minute?
I'm very worried
about Ethan.
- Come on.
- Okay.
Did he tell you
the story
about it being 2,000 years
in the future?
How the world
is destroyed,
and we're
the only humans left?
What is going on?
I don't know,
but I think they have some way
of brainwashing people
up on that mountain.
- Now, I...
- Kate, there's more.
The week
after I got here,
I finally found a phone
that worked.
I called a secure line
belonging to the Service,
and Agent Hassler
left me a message.
- Adam Hassler?
- Mm-hmm.
What did he say?
That I was entering
a government experiment.
That I should lay low,
blend in,
and that I may be
severely tested,
possibly
by another agent.
You think
that Ethan is...
I don't know,
but I can't rule it out.
Theresa,
you know Hassler.
He is nothing
if not a straight shooter.
How much of this
have you told Ethan?
I haven't, and I'm not sure
it's a good idea to.
I really have to go.
You're a good person,
Theresa.
And I wish we had met
under different circumstances.
I'm so sorry.
Ethan,
we're worried about you.
You're worried
about me?
Yes.
What, you think this
is all in my head?
What do you think?
You think, uh,
I was brainwashed?
I saw stuff out there, Theresa.
I'm not making this up.
Everything I told you
is true.
But you're telling me
that everything is gone.
Except us.
And I want to keep it
that way.
So please, tell me.
What else did she say?
She told me not to tell you
anything,
and then she left.
She was very emotional
when she said goodbye,
like it was
a permanent goodbye.
Where's Ben?
He's at school.
Okay,
I'm gonna go get him.
I think
they're planning something.
Hey,
so I was thinking.
How about later tonight,
you and I sneak out
for a walk in the woods?
Isn't that
against the rules?
Well, there are rules,
and then there are rules.
There's a sweet spot
I've been meaning to show you.
It's like a little meadow
up in the trees.
How will we get there?
I have a plan.
Meet me after dinner?
Corner of Birch and 9th?
Yeah, sure.
It was fun
in class today, huh?
I don't understand
why people get so nervous
talking about biology.
Yeah, I... Yeah,
I know, right?
It's just nature.
Ben!
One second.
What?
Look, I'm gonna need you
to come home.
I'm kind of busy
right now.
Oh. Hi!
I'll explain it to you
in the car.
- Say goodbye.
- Come on, Dad.
Amy, I-I'm terribly sorry,
but Ben's got to come home.
- Okay.
- H-He'll talk to you later.
Go ahead.
Say goodbye.
Sorry.
I got to go.
It's okay.
Meet me later.
I just need to know,
did you put that pipe bomb
in the Sheriff's truck
this morning?
Damn it, Ted.
The last thing we need is
him breathing down our necks.
We're not murderers.
Why not?
They murder.
You've been to
your share of reckonings.
Do you want me to do this
or not?
Second camera
just went out at Cell 33.
No, it's Kate.
She's trying to throw us off.
In about 10 minutes,
the guards circle around.
And once that fence is breached,
there's no turning back.
They'll be on us...
fast.
Where are
the blind spots?
There's one at Zone 41,
right at the fence.
Almost there.
So if anyone's
having second thoughts,
now is the time to go,
all right?
Okay, that's it.
Everybody stay
right where you are!
- Down on the ground!
- Ethan!
I'm not letting you
blow up that fence.
Get down on the ground.
Okay, Franklin,
disarm that bomb.
Don't do it.
Disarm the bomb,
or she's dead.
No.
No, Franklin.
I trusted you.
Let's go.
Come on, on your feet.
We had a deal, Kate.
They did something
to you, Ethan.
You just don't know it.
You'll see very soon.
We will be back in Seattle,
overlooking that bay.
Seattle? No, forget it, Kate.
That's not gonna happen.
You've got to convince these
people to stop this insanity!
It's not gonna stop.
It's just begun.
Where's your husband?
There's another bomb.
There's a backup.
Where's Harold, Kate?
Where's Harold?!
It should be here
any second.
It's always right on time,
right at 8:00.
We can catch it
right up to the pines.
Uh,
we could just walk.
It's more fun this way.
Just relax, newbie.
I've done this
plenty of other times.
I need you
to locate Harold.
Harold Ballinger.
Last seen at the Biergarten
less than an hour ago.
Who's that?
That's...
Ted Laufer.
He drives
the delivery truck.
Where is
the truck now?
Well, he takes the same route
every day.
Finishes up on 16th,
heads up Main to access one,
drops off the truck,
and picks up another one.
And where does he switch
the two trucks?
At the fence.
What's that?
Here he comes.
We got to slow him down.
Get up.
Are you okay?
Amy.
Amy, what are you
doing here?
Ben.
Ben!
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com