Just a moment!
Here's the Archbishop of Palermo
Saverio Cincotta.
This is his third Conclave.
Cardinal Masao Takada...
archivist and librarian
of the Holy Roman Church.
We can see Sidi Kamara,
followed by Koma Mbosou.
As you know the African continent
has never... Here's Ricardo Aguilar.
Who could be
the first South American Pope.
And the cardinal from Sri Lanka,
Don Somasiry.
We'll try approaching
Cardinal Massucci for a word.
Cardinal, could we have a statement?
Obviously they can't
answer our questions.
And now, we can see
the Syrian Patriarch of Antioch...
Simon Al Shuriani, Prefect of the
Congregation of Eastern Churches.
Here's who we're all waiting for:
The Vatican spokesman,
Marcin Rajski is approaching us...
- maybe to ask us.
- Thank you very much.
- We must ask you to leave now.
- He asks us to leave...
but thanks the press.
- Maybe a long shot of the Sistine Chapel.
- No, thank you.
He thanks us very much...
but our work ends here.
We can't get that shot.
Here, we know them all,
Cardinal Dean Gregori...
the favored of the Conclave.
As of this moment
the 108 cardinal electors...
will be isolated from
the rest of the world.
Gregori, what do we do?
- Has the power failed?
- What else could it be?
- Please, stay calm.
- Any candles?
- They're not allowed. - Why?
- They ruin the frescoes.
Do they know outside
that we're in darkness?
Of course they do...
and they're already fixing it.
- Who's that? What happened?
- It's Cardinal Brummer.
I fell.
It's nothing, I'm already getting up.
- Are you alright?
- Yes, thank you.
- Is everything alright?
- I said: Yes!
Are you okay, Brummer?
- I didn't hurt myself.
- Your back, ankle?
- I'm not hurt at all!
- Are you sure?
Please, try not to move around.
Let's return to our seats.
Pick things up...
Not me, Lord, not me!
Not me, Lord, don't choose me!
I'm not up to it.
Not me, Lord, please.
Not me.
Not me, Lord.
No, I said no!
Gregori.
Bikila.
Aguilar.
Gregori.
- Where does Gregori stand?
- 13.
Gregori 18, Bikila 11.
- Bikila.
- Gregori 21.
- Aguilar 18.
- Gregori and Bikila 15.
Bikila.
- Aguilar.
- Just a moment!
Gregori.
Lucci.
The smoke's black,
the Pope still hasn't been elected.
The smoke is white!
The thousands of faithful here
in St. Peter's Square...
joyfully applaud the news.
But the bells aren't ringing.
Maybe the smoke only looked white.
I can hear my colleagues
saying the smoke is black.
The smoke, actually...
Yes, the smoke is black.
Yes, it's black, nothing doing.
The smoke will last a while
because, as well as the ballots...
their personal notes
will be burned too.
Nothing regarding the Conclave
can filter through to the outside.
Aguilar.
Gregori.
Lucci.
Bikila.
Another black smoke signal.
The cardinals in the Conclave still
haven't managed to elect a Pope.
A second vote will be cast
this afternoon.
We don't know if the favorites are
still Gregori, Aguilar and Bikila.
Melville.
Aguilar.
Cevasco.
Melville.
Aguilar.
Do you accept your canonical election
as Supreme Pontiff.
as Supreme Pontiff?
Yes.
- Holiness...
- What are you doing?
- What happens now?
- You can just give a blessing...
or, as our deceased
beloved Pope did the first time...
address the faithful with a speech.
Dear brothers and sisters...
Nuntio vobis gaudium magnum,
habemus Papam!
Eminentissimum ac reverendissimum...
Help me.
I can't do this.
I can't do this!
Holy Father...
you mustn't worry.
By bestowing this charge, God also
gives you help to accomplish it...
and the strength to sustain the
weight of this great responsibility.
Would you like something hot?
Herbal tea?
You could retire to your apartments...
and when you're ready,
I'll take you to the balcony.
No.
The Conclave has indeed
elected the Holy Father...
who, aware
of this great responsibility...
feels the need to retire in prayer.
This unusual gesture
is also an act of humility...
which we are sure
you will want to respect.
Please.
I believe I express the sentiments
of my colleagues worldwide.
We respect His Holiness' will...
all we ask is his name. Only that!
Tell us if it's one of these 8.
Aguilar? Gregori?
- Bikila? - We believe...
- Todorov?
We believe within a few hours...
the Pontiff will introduce himself
to the faithful from the balcony.
At that point you also will meet him...
and we will celebrate
the new Pontificate together.
Thank you.
- Do you feel any pain?
- No.
- Headache?
- Yes... no.
How is your blood pressure usually?
- Good.
- I was sure.
I was sure.
- Good morning!
Good day!
Good morning!
We're going to Borgo Pio
for breakfast.
What?
There's a place where they make
delicious cream-filled doughnuts.
Then I'd like to take them
to the Quirinale Museum.
There's a wonderful
Caravaggio exhibit.
I don't think you can.
Why not? Our task is done.
How could you think
of leaving the Vatican at this time?
The Holy Father will recover very soon
and we must be at his side!
Yes, but we won't go far.
We'll take our cell phones,
so you can contact us at any time.
I'd like to remind you
of John Paul the First's precedent...
who, after his election and
appearance on the balcony...
made us stay an extra day.
Here it is.
Alright, if it's only for a day...
No cardinal shall have
contact with the outside...
until the election is over...
and publicly announced.
Could I at least get a cappuccino?
Not too hot!
- What will we have?
- Orange juice.
A cappuccino, very little froth.
The Holy Father
has been seen by a physician...
who said
he's in good physical condition.
But the Holy Father isn't improving.
Given the gravity of the situation...
the cardinals
said they're in favor of...
Professor Brezzi,
may I present Cardinal Gregori.
I know you, your picture
was in the papers.
He was the front-runner, right?
The cardinals are in favor
of trying psychoanalysis...
despite the natural skepticism you can
well imagine. - Yes, I can imagine.
I think it's unnecessary to remind you...
- the concepts of soul and subconscious cannot possibly co-exist.
- Okay, we'll see.
What's his name?
I don't recognize him.
Who did you elect? What's his name?
- Call him Holiness.
- It's a little too much!
In a therapeutic situation,
a name can give life...
to the relationship...
Okay, it doesn't matter,
we cannot know his name.
I'm off, I'll leave the two of you.
- Where can the Pope and I meet?
- Here.
Good morning.
- How do you feel?
- I'm sorry, I don't know what to say.
Don't worry.
Fine, we'll begin now.
Thank you all!
Right...
well...
All that's happened recently...
your election and everything...
we'll lay it aside for the moment.
I'd like us to begin with retracing...
reliving your emotions...
Wait.
- I suppose I can't ask...
- Absolutely not.
I was sure that anything about sex.
A mention of his mother?
Right now, it might reawaken
distant episodes, memories.
- Exactly.
- Exactly?
No.
And what about facing unfulfilled
fantasies and desires?
- No.
Something regarding his childhood?
With great discretion.
With great discretion, fine.
- Dreams, yes, though.
- It depends on the dreams.
- However, no... it's best not to.
- Best not to...
Perfect, thank you.
Perfect.
Change of program!
We'll start with
all that's happened recently.
I just can't go on.
Have you ever felt like this before?
I don't know.
I don't think so, but I don't know.
Listen...
- Any problems with your faith?
- No.
- You're sure?
- Yes.
God sees abilities in me
I don't have.
Where are these abilities?
I look for them and find nothing.
You've been chosen,
let's say, by God...
for your qualities...
for your goodness.
So how can you possibly suddenly...
Was the doctor asked
if he's a believer?
No one asked.
- Are you?
- No, I'm not.
- Not good.
- But I'm afraid that's how it is.
Anyway, let's go on.
Excuse me, you can stay
it's fine, but in silence please!
Your spokesman...
Your spokesman told me
that while they all waited for you...
- to go onto the balcony...
- Know what happened to me?
- As they were coming towards me, some singing...
- Yes.
Some crying...
We were all very emotional.
Little by little,
they began disappearing.
They began disappearing?
No...
all the people I once knew
were suddenly gone.
Everything vanished.
I can't remember anything.
- Do you want to be Pope?
- I'm already Pope.
It was decided by the cardinals.
It was decided by God.
Was this meeting of ours useful?
I don't know.
You see, Pope,
with all these people around...
looking at me...
checking me, I just can't work.
Maybe a colleague
who doesn't know he's the Pope...
could meet him away from here.
We must do something right away.
That's why we came to you.
- Because you're the best.
- A curse!
Everyone always says:
"You're the best".
My wife, also a psychoanalyst,
always said:
"Darling, you're the best".
But she left me,
she couldn't stand the comparison.
- Is your wife good?
- The best after me.
She's prepared, sensitive...
but she's obsessed
with parental deficit. - Interesting.
She tells everyone,
really everyone...
when we all were small children,
infants...
when we were just a few...
when we were just a few months old,
something happened...
that we have to deal with
for the rest of our lives.
So the fear of being abandoned...
and the fear that something
might happen to us...
- Where are we?
- It's your room.
- My room?
- I'm here if you need anything.
You'll be quite comfortable.
Now I see!
Don't worry, we're sworn to secrecy.
You don't think I'd go around...
If you'd like to phone home.
I'll stay here, listen,
and then I'll take your phone.
No, my kids are in school now.
I have to call them this evening.
Talk to them!
- Why take my phone?
- It's forbidden to communicate with the outside.
I'm sorry.
Meet with the cardinals,
those you're closest to...
and start thinking of
a new Secretary of State...
or perhaps reconfirm
the previous one.
Or, if you're up to it...
you could go out on the balcony...
to say hello to the faithful,
or just give a blessing.
I didn't follow a word you said.
Help me.
I can't do this!
Rajski, what's
the reaction of the faithful?
How are they taking this uncertainty,
what do they know.
No one knows anything, but we
can't keep it secret much longer.
All together we can convince
His Holiness to go out on the balcony.
Locked up in here,
maybe you don't realize.
This is a very big deal!
Don't do that.
That attitude doesn't help.
You see, we don't know what to do.
No one ever thought
anything like this could happen.
- Good evening.
Good evening.
Come in.
Good evening, how are you?
Fine.
- Good night.
We can't do this!
Mom, help!
Mommy, help!
No!
No! Why?
We can't do this!
No!
- Good night.
Two are positioned
on the Bingo Hall on this square...
another three
on the roof of the Eden Theater.
If we go through Piazza Adriana...
one of you substitutes
the newsagent...
two dress as traffic cops...
and we'll put another eight
on the Castel Sant'Angelo walkway.
For security reasons, the route
will be decided at the last minute.
I remind you that the cardinals...
We'd rather the cardinals know
nothing about this operation.
However, we'll be back
within a couple of hours...
and all this
will never have happened.
Hello, how's it going?
Rajski, I wrote it all here.
The first eleven patients
must be contacted immediately...
we had appointments
for today or tomorrow.
- Please, tell them gently.
- Don't worry.
I haven't missed a day in six years.
Tell them I'm sick
and it will take...
How long will I be sick?
That never opened again...
leaving the world holding its breath.
The faithful sang and prayed
in the square all night...
I saw someone moving
behind the drapes.
I'm sure it was two cardinals.
I feel something will soon happen.
You just heard a nun talking.
These rumors still haven't
been denied by the Holy See.
Meantime we're receiving statements
from Heads of State worldwide.
"We feel great anxiety",
said Sarkozy.
"But the entire Catholic world trusts
the Vatican to find a rapid solution".
- It's shameful.
- The President of Brazil is flying to Italy...
to be close to the Holy See.
Second floor, apartment 3.
So, you've always lived alone?
- Why do you ask?
- It will help me get to know you.
You say you're not married,
you have no children.
- Any important ties of affection?
- No.
Has this been a problem for you?
I don't know,
that's how my life has been.
I can't do anything anymore,
I'm always tired.
Have you talked to anyone
about this difficulty?
No one.
But everyone knows by now.
I can't do this.
But the others
have great trust in me.
- The others?
- I'd like to do so much.
So many things need to be changed.
I'd like...
- So, you work.
- Yes, but... no.
What do you do?
- What do I do?
- Yes.
- I'm an actor.
- An actor!
Nice!
- But an actor...
- Theater.
I've always loved it.
The tours...
traveling from one city to another...
the rehearsals...
the opening nights,
when you read the reviews together.
Nice.
But now I'm tired.
How did it go?
I think it will take
three sessions a week.
- For how many weeks?
- I'd say a couple of years.
That's a lot.
I know.
I need to walk a little.
No! No!
A sustained heaviness.
My head's too full,
but I don't know what of.
It's like a kind of
psychological sinusitis.
Is this what you call depression?
It happened to me so suddenly.
Faster!
What have we done...
What have you done!
Perhaps you suffered
because your mother...
when you were a small child...
paid more attention to someone else.
You know what we call that?
Parental deficit.
- What?
- What should I remember.
Yes.
What should I remember?
My first three months,
my first three years...
I don't remember a thing.
Sir!
Are you sick?
Do you need help?
- A little water?
- Yes.
How are you feeling? Any better.
Better, thank you.
If you wait, I'm through in an hour.
- I'll take you to a bus stop.
- There's no need, really,
I'm fine now.
- You're still very pale.
- I said I'm fine now!
Didn't you hear me?
- If you want...
- Stop, I'm fine, I told you!
- Good evening.
- Excuse me, do you have...
- The bathroom's out of order.
Pardon me.
- May I make a phone call?
- The phone's only for work.
Sir?
- You can use mine.
- Very kind of you.
- Thank you.
- It's a short call.
- Hello?
- I'm Melville.
Holiness! How are you?
Tell me where you are,
we'll come immediately.
- No.
- Where are you?
I don't know.
- Are you all right?
- I feel better.
- We're worried about you, you should come back!
- Be patient.
I need time.
I have to remember
a lot of things about my life...
- things I've forgotten.
- Please...
Do it for me, I made such a fuck...
an unforgivable mistake!
Help me please, come back.
Not now.
I'll call you soon.
- I'm not sure I can do it...
- Don't worry.
It's very simple but rather important.
Stop here please.
Here.
Move these drapes
in the morning, very early...
so they'll all see
the Holy Father is in his apartments.
Do it a couple of times a day...
and once before going to bed.
But be careful,
all they must see is a shadow.
Remove your beret, of course.
- Can I turn on the TV?
- Yes, occasionally.
Remove your doublet too.
I'll have them bring you something white.
Good night.
"For my days vanish like smoke..."
".. my bones burn like glowing embers."
"Hear how these Bible passages..."
"..seem to echo
the situation of the Holy Father."
"My heart is blighted
and withered like grass."
"I forget to eat my food."
"Fear and trembling come upon me..."
"..and anguish overwhelms me".
In the Bible, the only book
you put in my room...
I might add...
in the Bible,
it talks about depression.
Yes, but this cannot
concern the Holy Father.
It is you, due to your temperament
and professional bias...
who sees depression everywhere.
But in this book
are all the symptoms of depression:
Feelings of guilt, weight loss,
suicidal thoughts.
"I feel better".
The Holy Father just told me
these exact words:
"I feel better".
He had a good day, he prayed...
he had something to eat
in his apartments...
and his mood seemed encouraging.
You're pleased
the Holy Father feels better?
- Australian cardinals, good evening.
- Good evening.
- How's the jet lag?
- Much better, thank you.
- What is it?
- "Living with the Etruscans".
- Is it worth a visit?
- It's a beautiful outing.
I've never been there
but it's beautiful.
- Good evening.
Everything we need is
here in the Vatican, right?
The famous service station
where gas costs less...
shops...
Gym facilities.
- Gym facilities?
- Sure. - Just great.
The pharmacy with medicines
you can't find in Rome.
Well, well...
We who are fortunate
to think we understand things...
but recently it's been hard for
the Church to understand things.
The beginning of Peter's mission...
in the history of salvation...
in the history of God's people...
Why?
What's changed?
I can't live without you.
We've often been afraid...
to admit our faults.
Yes, I'm talking to myself.
I'm looking for the words
for a speech I have to make...
before a crowd of people.
I'm a little worried.
If I take my usual sleeping pill
before bedtime...
when I wake up at 3,
I take this other one?
- No! - Why?
- These medicines don't go together.
Sleeping pills.
This is the family of tranquilizers.
These are mood stabilizers...
This is a major tranquilizer.
This is strong!
Who takes this?
- Who takes this?
- I don't know.
Anyway, if you take a sleeping pill...
it should have a short half-life.
O'Neill, let's say you wake up
tomorrow wanting to do sports.
- I don't do sports!
- Follow me on this.
If you do sports tomorrow,
you'll still be fuzzy from this...
- Good evening to all.
- How is he?
Better, his appetite's back.
His Holiness ate everything.
Two types of prosciutto,
all the vegetables.
He devoured the fruit...
and even had a small dessert.
Now he's resting in his apartments.
Like it?
I have a parental deficit.
But I don't know what it is.
- Good evening.
Excuse me, could I have a room?
- How many nights?
- I don't know.
- For tonight?
- Yes. Special rates?
No.
- Poor man.
- Why?
They say he's dead.
Now they'll elect another,
but without letting on.
- They said it on TV?
- They can't...
but it's obvious.
The Holy Father
is in his rooms, in prayer.
But the moment
we've been waiting for...
Nuntio vobis gaudium magnum...
The Pope!
Brummer!
What is happening?
- The Pope!
- He feels better.
Nina, coming from backstage:
"It's clear we can't continue".
"I can leave, goodbye."
She kisses Arkadina
and Polina Andryevna...
- Please, excuse us.
- "May I introduce Boris Alexeyevich."
Nina, confounded:
"A great joy, I've read your books."
Arkadina, sitting Nina beside her:
"Don't be confounded, dear,
he's a celebrity."
"But he's a simple man,
and is himself confounded."
Dorn, irritated:
"Jakov, my brother, raise the curtain."
"When I was young I wanted to be
a scholar, but didn't become one!"
"I wanted to be an orator, but my
speaking would make you nauseous!"
"I wanted to marry but didn't!"
"I wanted to live in the city."
"I wanted to live in the city..."
".. but I end my life living
in the country. And that's it."
"To express dissatisfaction
with life at sixty-two, is petty."
"How obstinate!"
- "Can't you see I want to live?"
- "That's frivolity."
"The laws of Nature dictate
that every life must end."
"You reason as a satiated man.
You are satiated..."
"..so you're uninterested in life."
Medvedenko: "Let's go home, Masha!"
- "Let's go home, Masha."
- Masha:"Go by yourself."
- "Go by yourself".
- Medvedenco: Your father won't give me horses."
- "Your father won't give me horses."
- Stop, why repeat my lines?
- My sister...
- You have no sister!
- It's not true.
- My sister played Chekhov for many years.
I know it by heart.
- "The Seagull".
- Masha.
Masha, confidently:
"He will, ask him for them."
"He will."
"Father, will you let
my husband have a horse?"
Shamrayev: "Not possible!"
Not possible!
Medvedenco: "I'll walk home."
And at last, he exits.
We'll see you soon.
You had three points,
plus one, is four.
- We made just one point?
- Yes!
You had to take 5 and 4 with 9!
- With a 7 on the table?
- You don't know how to play.
You should have left the 7
and called "spariglio".
- But we made a point.
- And they got two points...
with the last trick.
When it's not your hand,
you must call "spariglio".
- You're always distracted!
- No, I'm focused.
- No, it's no way to play!
- I'm very sorry.
It's the second time we've lost.
- Whose deal is it?
- Excuse me, I can't take anymore.
- You're offended?
- No, I have a headache.
- Would you like to play?
- I don't know what they think.
- Know what "spariglio" is?
- I've been told lots of times.
I think I understand,
but I can't follow this technique.
Let me play my own way.
"Evgenij, which of us
looks younger?"
- "You, of course."
- "You see! And why?"
- "Because I work, I feel..."
- Because I work, I feel.
You're always in the same place,
you don't live.
"I have a rule:
Never look to the future."
"I never think about old age or death."
"I feel like I was born so long ago..."
- "I drag my life like an endless train".
- Excuse me.
"Often I've no desire to live."
Here Dorn should come in.
- Did you visit Dario? How is he?
- The doctors say it's not serious.
- But he won't make the opening night.
- Pardon...
That's it? Did you call Baldineti?
Yes, but he's on tour,
Guerrini's not here or Zagoni...
and not even that tall guy
with a moustache, De Biasio.
- What'll we do about Dorn?
- I can give the lines.
I've given it some thought, I guess
I'll just have to do it myself.
- Oh, great.
- Just for the first few days!
I really miss my wife.
A period of being apart gives you
the chance to measure the value of love.
- What do you know?
- No, guys, I miss her...
meaning, we're separated.
She's a psychoanalyst too.
She left me because I'm the best
and it bothered her.
She's good too, but she's
obsessed with parental deficit.
Interesting!
But these are formulas.
I could simplify and say...
the Holy Father
feels vulnerable at the moment...
but at the same time,
narcissistically exceptional!
- How dare you?
- I mean the man...
- not the Pope.
- They're the same thing!
I'm not so sure... Queen.
Does your wife have a new life?
Yes, she's been with a guy
for a few years.
He's a good person, but she can't
bring herself to tell our kids.
He's a psychoanalyst too.
All these psychoanalysts!
Is there such a need?
But I have a good relationship
with my wife.
- I'm glad. - Yes.
- I'm glad too.
Point!
I confused them with my chatter.
Actually, the Conclave
is still technically operative.
Yes, we all heard
the spokesman for the Holy See...
but I don't think he reassured
the hundreds of millions of faithful.
Might we say this is
an unexpected event?
You know I used to eat here
with Salvo Randone?
Do you know who he was?
He's the one who, with Gassman,
would do Othello one evening...
and lago the next, they'd swap parts.
We need to be patient.
Haven't you formed an opinion
about what might have happened?
I don't think there's
a mystery behind all this.
A search for serenity, in silence,
before approaching the waiting world...
- is a Pontiff's prerogative.
- It's not nonsense:
Wine and tobacco
deprive the personality.
Loving without hope.
Entire years waiting for something...
Last night I went into the garden
to see if our old theater was still there.
- And it was there.
- It's dark in the garden.
They should tear down that theater.
It is there, bare.
After a good cigar or some vodka...
Let's remember that the Pope
is the Lord's first servant.
- But he's also the last.
- The first, but also the last.
So, the first and also the last.
This leads us, as a consequence?
As a consequence this leads us...
- This leads us...
- This leads us?
No, I'm improvising!
The truth is I'm totally confused.
I ask the viewers' forgiveness.
Forgiveness from all of you.
- Sorry.
- No, no problem!
I remind you, formally,
the Conclave still isn't over...
- I know.
- The cardinals are still isolated...
far from the glare of the media.
Europe, I haven't decided
if you're in two or three teams.
North America, Asia, South America...
Oceania, Swiss Guards...
No! The tournament's unbalanced
with the Swiss Guards!
- You like winning, right?
- Yes.
You're right,
no team of Swiss Guards...
but I can't remember your name,
Cardinal.- Pescardona.
During the Conclave...
the bookmakers,
especially the English...
have odds for all of you.
Let's see Pescardona...
Pescardona, Pescar...
- You were given 7 to 1!
- What's that? Good?
It sure is!
The Holy Father was given
just 90 to 1.
- That's wonderful!
- You don't understand.
I'll explain.
If you'd bet 10 Euros on him,
you'd have won 900.
- Not bad?
- Then there's Cruz 72.
Gregori well, the favored.
- Here he is! - Good evening.
- We were talking about you.
You were given 3 to 1.
Was he disappointed
not to be elected?
No one here is disappointed.
- Lucky you!
- Brummer, what were my odds?
Brummer you say?
Brummer...
Brummer.
If you all agree,
I'll choose the teams' captains...
from the bookmakers' favorites.
The captains can be Aguilar...
Aguilar, Cincotta, Stenton, Bikila...
You didn't give my number!
If I didn't, there's a reason!
What do you think?
Your number's not here.
Your number doesn't exist.
Since you insist:
You were given no odds at all!
You weren't considered!
You insisted, happy now?
- No.
- I'd say not!
But you insisted!
Flatten these corners, all the way.
To the side...
it has to be flattened right
to the end or we'll get hurt.
Go, like that... come back!
There's a hollow here.
Go back...
Now this part here.
You have to flatten it,
one, two, three times...
if not, when we jump
we could get hurt.
Like that, overhand.
Overhand.
Next in line.
Next.
- The Korean way. - What's it like?
- Underhand with a spin.
Okay, no spin there...
In the first heat is: North America,
Asia, Europe A, Eastern Europe.
Why can't we have
an all-Italian team?
No, you Italians play
either on the Europe A team...
or on the Europe B.
Please, don't spoil the grid,
I worked on it all night.
Or I'll leave and you can do
the tournament by yourselves!
Why don't we play Prison Dodgeball?
- What?
- Prison Dodgeball.
- Prison Dodgeball?
- Yes.
Cardinal, it hasn't been played
in 50 years!
In the second heat is:
South America, Africa...
- Europa B e Oceania.
- But there are just three of us!
Oceania is just three? Too bad!
That means
you get experience this time...
then, if you're good to
the faithful in the coming years.
There will be more of you at
the next Conclave, 4, 5, 6...
Do you see why it's better
to do a round-robin tournament...
and not a direct elimination?
- Professor, we don't understand.
- I can tell.
But it's okay, just don't get mad.
I won't get mad.
And with more games we give the Holy
Father more time to get back on his feet.
Never underestimate the support...
he receives in feeling
surrounded by this energy...
this fighting spirit.
I'd even tend towards
a double round-robin tournament.
Double round-robin, no!
We'd die!
Come on, Giulio!
It's true!
Mommy knows him, it's okay.
I thought about it, it's true,
I've never really felt well.
But I've done many things in my life.
- Yes.
- I've even done some good.
Why can't I do anything anymore?
Can we talk later?
I'm taking the kids to school.
Talk to you later.
Yes, me too.
Was that your boyfriend?
No way!
It was Leonardo, my colleague.
- Giulio told me you have a boyfriend.
- Not true, I didn't tell you anything.
You're an idiot!
- You say it every night, I can't stand it!
- Mouth!
Your classmates say so too:
You're a big mouth!
- You're stupid!
- Stop it!
Or I'll drop you right here!
You're a stinky girl!
Bird-brain!
That's enough!
- Creep! - But he...
- Enough.
I want no more.
- Did you hit girls when you were little?
- Sure.
See?
This black dragon,
with trees covered in lava.
Here's the two-headed dragon phase...
like he was divided.
The two volcanoes:
One good and one bad.
- This is him in the dragon's jaws.
- That's nice!
- It's monstrous!
- No, look.
Do you think he knows
Carlo and I have problems?
What do you think,
should I leave my husband?
Please, pay no attention to me.
I'm not sitting here,
I'm in my apartments.
Yes.
- It's not true I'm an actor.
- No?
I wanted to be, but I didn't
make it into the Academy.
- I failed the audition.
- I'm sorry. - Thank you.
They were right, I was no good.
But they took my sister.
See, very strong,
he gets four points.
That was a wide-angle shot.
He's trying to shoot...
Point for South America!
Point for Europe B!
We're not the casual,
senseless product of evolution.
- Point for Africa!
- We're each the fruit of a thought of God.
No, Gregori.
That's the terrible
beauty of Darwinism.
Terrible: No sense in life.
No consolation.
Point for Europe B.
Europe B 10...
Oceania 0.
This other one is more exciting
because it's more competitive.
South America to serve.
Africa - South America: 8 - 6.
Oceania 0...
Europe B 11.
Point for South America!
South America to serve.
Point for Europe B. Oceania!
The Holy Father!
Too bad, it was such
an interesting case for me!
But now I know who he is,
I can't do anything for him.
Who knows how he feels?
Let's get back to it!
Europe B and
South America to serve.
Point for Africa!
Ball!
Serve!
Change!
- Change!
- Change.
Ribeck, Schindler, you seem tired.
Scipioni and Bollati, you're in!
- Me? No...
- Yes.
I don't feel like it.
Cardinal Cruz, again!
Time out!
I've told you when you are there...
raise your hands!
- I can't do it.
- Of course you can!
Serve.
- Europe B and Africa to serve.
- We can win!
Concentrate.
- Anyway you're lucky, you won't go to Hell.
- Good news.
Point for South America!
No one will, Hell is deserted.
Point.
A comeback! A comeback!
Point for Oceania!
Europe B: 16. Oceania: 1.
Let us welcome the word
that God gives us today.
His words are for those of us...
who carry in our hearts
desires, dreams, plans...
but also worries...
problems and fears...
of all the things, maybe
what frightens us are these new times...
the unprecedented situation,
the waiting...
the length of which is unknown...
but which asks us for a new heart...
a new answer which God himself
suggests in these words:
Humility, the wisdom
to recognize that we need God.
We need His forgiveness,
His patience.
We need to show our wounds to Him...
because He is the only one
who can heal them.
Holy Father,
we're behind in everything.
You haven't yet indicated
the start of the new Pontificate.
We understand how you feel...
but you remember,
how, in years past...
our beloved Pontiff
even when he was seriously ill...
continued his pastoral commitment.
Of course, we can't allow
more time to pass.
In fact, I brought you
several sketches...
for the Pontificate coat of arms.
Here they are.
Do any appeal to you?
- This one.
- This one? - No, this one.
It's simple, I think it's right.
- Are you sure?
- No.
Holiness, you were right.
You had to reflect, be by yourself...
but now I beg you,
do an act of obedience to the Lord.
Come back to us.
A billion people are waiting for you.
Can't we make me vanish?
I disappear.
All this never happened,
no one has ever seen me.
No one will ever see me again,
I promise you.
Let me go away, please.
Guys, you must be kidding!
Stop, you can't do this to me.
We have to play the two semifinals!
Then the winners...
The Holy Father is watching us.
It's not right to leave him
without a winning team.
It's not right!
Pescardona, are you saying
it was all useless?
South America is in the semifinals,
you're the tournament's revelation!
You're in the semifinals.
- Let's play this semifinal!
- Professor, there's no more time.
Why?
Good morning.
Thank you for responding
to my invitation...
but the situation
has become very serious.
I can no longer be silent.
No doubt I made a mistake...
and I take full responsibility
for what I've done.
I tried, for the good of all,
to resolve a very difficult situation.
But in so doing, I lied to you.
The Pope hasn't been here with us
for three days.
He has gone.
I know where he is.
I ask you to forgive me.
It's my fault so much time
has passed.
The moment has come for all of you
to make a decision.
Forgive me once again.
Is anyone against this proposal?
Thank you.
In favor?
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Food poisoning, really nothing.
Food poisoning, a negligible episode.
- What did they put in that omelet?
- I don't know. - Food poisoning.
- Nothing serious.
- Thanks. - Thank you.
- Why do you wear black all the time?
- I'm in mourning for my life.
- I'm unhappy.
- Why? You're healthy.
Your father, although
he's not rich, is quite well off.
I'm more miserable than you.
I'm paid 23 rubles a month...
I'm paid 23 rubles a month
and they take pension deductions.
Still I don't wear mourning.
Quiet!
Money doesn't matter.
Even a poor man can be happy.
Yes, in theory, but not in reality.
But not in reality.
There's me, my mother,
my two sisters, my little brother...
and 23 rubles...
23 rubles in all.
We need to eat and drink!
And tea?
And tea...
And sugar? And tobacco?
Tobacco!
- Now me?
- No!
Treplyov, listening:
I hear footsteps.
Enter the uncle, Treplyov embraces.
"I cannot live without Nina."
"I am madly happy!"
He runs to meet Nina who enters.
Then with passion:
"My enchantress, my dream!"
"I'm not late, am I?"
Treplyov, kissing her hands:
"No, no..."
Nina: "I've been in a fever all day."
"I was afraid my father, but then..."
".. he and my stepmother went out..."
"..then I urged my horse!"
She squeezes Sorin's hands:
"I'm so glad! So glad!"
In these days...
In these days
you must have asked yourselves...
why doesn't our Pope
come to say hello?
He mustn't worry
if the Lord chose him...
He couldn't have made a mistake.
Yes, I was chosen...
but this...
instead of giving me
strength and consciousness...
it crushes me, confuses me.
In this moment the Church needs
a guide who has the strength...
to bring great changes...
who seeks an encounter with all...
who has, for all,
love and understanding.
I ask the Lord's forgiveness
for what I am about to do.
I don't know if
He will be able to forgive me.
But I must speak to Him
and to you with sincerity.
In these days I've thought
very much about you...
and I realize I am not able...
to bear the role entrusted to me.
I feel I am among those
who cannot lead...
but who must be led.
In this moment I can only say:
Pray for me.
The guide that you need
is not me.
I can't be the one.