Subtitles by OnDemandKorea
(This program is about 2 MCs)
(who are praised and survived)
(in a jungle of variety shows.)
(This is a documentary about these two)
(going on a trip to find dinner.)
In a heart of the mountain...
A sound of wooden bell coming out
from a temple...
Why did two sinners come to this temple?
Kyung-kyu!
We're in Gangnam!
We're in the middle of Gangnam!
Samsungdong.
That's Bongeun Temple!
(Now that he mentioned it...)
(It's right in the middle of a city.)
I heard it's 1,200 years old.
1,200 years?
Yes.
That's pretty cool.
Those Chinese characters mean...
Receiving luck.
No, receiving grace.
A temple where you receive grace.
It sits on an amazing land.
Why?
It's great.
This whole area is really expensive.
That's COEX!
KEPCO used to be here
but they sold the site to Hyundai
for 2 billion dollars.
This place...
Is incredible!
This place is priceless!
Before Kyung-kyu starts feeling greedy,
they head into a 1,200 years old temple.
A lot of foreigners.
Ask them something.
Should I?
Belgium.
(Tourists from Belgium.)
(To visit Bongeun Temple.)
How do you like it?
(He was doing so well at first...)
(Frustrated.)
What do you think about Bongeun Temple?
Can you tell them it's 1,200 years old?
It was made over a thousand years ago.
(Got his numbers confused.)
(It became 10,000 years old now...)
1,200 years ago.
This temple?
1,000 is one thousand!
(Finally understands.)
Are you guys friends?
She's my cousin.
Have a nice day.
Thank you.
(A Buddhist farewell.)
Kyung-kyu.
Do you realize something?
Nature this way.
There's a mountain
But look this way.
Look at all those buildings!
That's a forest of trees.
That's a forest of buildings.
An awesome sight of an old temple
in the middle of tall, modern buildings.
This temple is a time machine
that can travel 1,000 years.
And this is where today's guests are.
They must be here somewhere.
It's about time they come out.
Really?
We have incredible guests.
We have to stay alert.
Really?
You might face harsh internet comments.
I gave you enough hints.
You'll like them.
Really?
Wait.
Is that our guest?
(She's just praying...)
You need to read the news...
Today's guests...
Are one of your favorites.
You said the name all the time!
(Let's see...)
It's already on the news!
(he just yells the most famous people)
(that he knows.)
BTS!
(Even in front of Wanna One...)
(Are they really here today?)
(No way...)
Is it really BTS?
Are they here?
(They go inside to look for the guests.)
(Careful.)
Over there.
I think that's them.
Should we go in?
(Who could it be?)
(Walks in quietly.)
(They're concentrating on calligraphy)
(in a quiet, 1,000 years old temple.)
(Let's see...)
(Shows respect to the monk first.)
Hello.
Sir, we're looking for our guests.
Food?
Guests.
A friend to eat with today...
Welcome.
We're doing calligraphy.
(Practicing hard.)
Have you ever watched our show before?
I'll start from now on.
(Please do!)
Please take a seat.
But these guys...
Are they your students?
Today's their first day.
Sir...
Do you know who they are?
I think...
They were BTS?
(An unexpected exposure...)
People in other countries call them BTS.
They were even on the Billboard.
Really?
They won a huge award just now.
They're my favorite idols.
Really?
(Nice to meet you.)
Then could you sing...
What was it...
Pop?
Hip hop?
Could I listen to you guys sing?
(Jung-gook starts first.)
(Good job.)
(Jin's turn.)
(That's my BTS.)
They're good songs.
If they're really popular,
you guys will succeed today.
Don't worry.
And good luck.
Thanks for your time.
Hi.
(They're finally here.)
You got lucky this time.
I know who they are.
Who?
Jin, Jung-gook.
Do you know all 7 of us?
Why would I know that?
Kyung-kyu have been waiting for them
to come to our show.
An idol that took the world by a storm.
Jin, their oldest member
Jung-gook, the youngest, are here.
Where will they go test their fate today?
Samsungdong, Gangnam-ku, Seoul.
Samsungdong is the focus
of trades and finances.
It's the focal point of buyers
from all over the world.
With a lot of expensive houses
and apartments,
it's one of the wealthiest areas
in Korea.
With BTS that conquered the world,
can they conquer a meal too?
Let's Have Dinner Together ep. 50
Rice, Sweats, Tears.
BTS!
(Kyung-kyu's favorite idol is here.)
BTS is here!
Us too!
(Jung-gook and Jin are today's guests.)
They're back with a new song!
Where do you live?
Manduk in Busan.
Manduk?
Yes.
Choryang!
Choryang?
He's their mascot!
Really?
You don't know the big 3 in Busan?
Lotte Giants.
I know Giants.
Haewoondae.
I know that too.
Lee Kyung-kyu, old man.
(Let's get going guys...)
Swag!
That's COEX, the biggest convention center
in Asia.
It's huge!
What exactly is COEX for?
Isn't it a movie theater?
It's a trade center...
I'm sure it has a movie theater!
They hold conventions.
A lot of exhibitions too.
That's the Tehran Street.
Isn't that a big road?
Why do you think it's called
Tehran Street?
Star Craft?
(That's Terran...)
Tehran is Iran's capital.
Iran's capital.
When the mayor of Tehran came to Seoul,
we changed its name to celebrate
that moment.
It was in the 70s.
Since then, it's become Tehran Street.
(Iran has a Seoul Street too!)
That's a cool story!
(They're walking on Tehran Street now...)
Jin loves dad jokes!
What kind of dad jokes?
How do you say don't fart in English?
Don't fart in English?
Don't Gas.
He's loving it!
(Stuck Kyung-kyu's chords.)
What happens when you pass the limit?
Pass your limit?
Two!
(That's it!)
Writers are laughing too!
(Unbelievable but funny...)
There's nothing special to what he says!
It's just 2!
Do you have about 500 of these?
Only about 400.
400?
Jin never closes his eyes.
He's good at staring contests.
Ready!
Staring contest!
Jin vs. Kyung-kyu!
Who ever blinks first loses!
Ready...
Are you ready?
Go!
(A staring contest in Samsungdong...)
(He's been spinning his eyes for 30 years.)
(But Jin's the best within all idols.)
(The match of the century.)
(Shocked.)
(Surprise attack.)
His eyes move so fast!
(Can't hold Jin's eyeballs attack...)
I won!
(The fall of the master...)
What high school is that?
Gyeonggi High School.
That's Gyeonggi High School?
A lot of smart students went there.
It was a prestigious school.
(Bang Si-hyuk, a producer who made BTS)
(graduated from this school.)
This is known as the
Gyeonggi High School Intersection.
I remember that bus stop!
(In the middle of tall buildings.)
The entire place was a field before!
Here?
There was nothing here!
When he was in college!
Really?
There were absolutely nothing here
except for rice paddies and fields.
(Gangnam that Kyung-kyu remembers...)
Just 40 years ago,
it was full of rice paddies and fields.
Gangnam was not a wealthy neighborhood
that it is today.
After 1960,
because of a rapid increase in population,
the old town area was muddled
with over population,
the government decided to develop this area
to expand the city.
The result...
Saw Gangnam become the most expensive
area in Korea and is making Kyung-kyu
regret his past choices.
That's when...
Do you know what his biggest regret is?
He studied.
I was in college.
If I bought real estate here
with my tuition...
I could've built my own university!
This is a disaster!
This place is golden now!
It used to be a field!
That's why everyone's rich here!
Wouldn't it get even more expensive?
Wouldn't it get more expensive?
Buy it now!
Just in case it does go up!
I'll go talk to the mayor
and make a BTS Street!
From over there to over there!
Thanks!
A lot of our fans heard that.
Let's go make BTS Street!
(They start walking around again.)
Is this Samsungdong too?
Yup.
(They have to find a residential area...)
I don't think I saw houses here.
Me neither.
I only passed business districts.
Let's go talk to a real estate agent.
We need to familiarize ourselves to here.
Exactly.
This is important to Jin.
How much is this building?
You and Jin have a lot in common.
This place smells nice.
You're working on a Sunday too?
(They shot on Sunday this time.)
Can we sit down?
Sure.
Where are we?
That's where this office is.
If you take a look around here,
this read area,
that's a designated residential area.
Designated residential area?
Buildings can't be higher than 2 stories.
They're mostly houses.
(This is it!)
House size are between 251 and 561
square meters.
The smallest one is 251 sq. meters?
Some are smaller...
But most of them have yards.
In Seoul?
Most people who live there
are either celebrities or CEOs.
Really?
Do you know any celebrities who live there?
Jun Ji-hyun, Song Hye-kyo.
Yoo Ho-jeong and Lee Jae-ryong.
Is it because it's close to Daechidong?
Exactly.
There are a lot of great
private educations there.
That's why a lot of people live here
and Cheongdamdong.
What's special about houses in Samsungdong?
They're expensive.
If you only count the houses,
Samsungdong is the most expensive place
in Gangnam.
More than Cheongdamdong?
Yup.
Normally, Gangnam's houses cost
$40,000 per sq. meters.
But now, it's way more than $40,000.
Some are $50,000 or $55,000 even.
Some houses here cost $60,000.
Monthly rent?
No, per sq. meter.
I thought the rent was $60,000.
Are you losing it?
What's the age group here?
Not a lot of young people.
People here are mostly old.
So we won't find a lot of people
who eat alone?
Not much.
But there are some townhouses here too.
(Just behind Gyeonggi High School...)
(There are a lot of townhouses
or condos too!)
No studios?
There are some.
Really?
They're not in this residential area.
It's a bit far.
What kind of people live here?
People who work nearby.
I see.
The rent is around $700
with $1,000 deposit.
Do you think we'll succeed today?
It might be tough...
A lot of people go out on weekends.
People go out to eat.
It's 5:30 right now.
Let's hurry.
We'll get going then.
Thank you.
This was expected.
Having a meal here will be difficult.
Will they be able to open the doors
in Samsungdong?
This is the residential area.
Is this the place he told us about?
Yes.
I've never been here before.
Me too.
I didn't know this even existed!
I only saw tall buildings.
I would love to live in a quiet place
like this.
It'll be peaceful here at night.
This place is huge but it's so quiet.
Maybe everyone's out.
(Quiet.)
There's no one walking around even!
(Quiet and empty streets.)
Look, there's no one there.
Is it because today's Sunday?
It's like this on weekends too.
Oh, people go to work.
Maybe it's the mountain
next to Bongeun Temple...
But there are a lot of trees here.
This kinda feels like Yangpyeong.
Or a country house.
The air seems fresh too.
So quiet.
And they really do have yards!
That's a huge persimmon tree!
They all are.
They're starting to ripe!
(Autumn is coming.)
They're turning yellow from the bottom.
Those dates are becoming ripe too.
(Met traces of Autumn in Samsungdong.)
Ho-dong!
Finger print scanner!
That's so cool.
I've never seen it before.
Really?
Our house is like that too...
(Really...?)
So this is the generation gap.
Well, this is my first time...
Even cell phones have them!
(Old vs. New)
Some even uses face recognition!
(Changes the topic.)
Donkatsu delivery!
It has New York in its title.
Don't fart in English.
(Old but creative.)
(Used dad jokes to bridge)
(the generation gap.)
You guys haven't eaten at home in a while?
I really miss home cooking.
How long has it been?
Thanksgiving from 2 years ago?
(Jin's eyes start to wander.)
I live close by.
I went 3 days ago.
(He doesn't miss it that much.)
It's really close from here.
You have to be honest.
(Not all idols miss home cooking.)
(Look at this.)
Retina scanner!
This is what you'll do later.
(Ring a bell...)
(Approaches quietly.)
(He just rang?)
Did you just ring it?
You can't do that yet!
I'm not supposed to?
Not yet!
Go say sorry if someone answers.
Sorry...
Did someone pick up?
No one's home.
We didn't start yet!
(Well that was a first.)
Think before you act!
I don't care if you're BTS!
(Sad.)
You told me to ring it...
You said, you have to ring it.
I said, you will have to ring it.
Try to think first.
You're 5 years older than me!
He's 5 years older than you?
Yes.
Is he frustrating?
(Needs water to calm down.)
You guys must be good friends.
We are.
Do you call him hyung?
I say Jin hyung.
He just doesn't use honorific.
I do.
But I hit him too.
While using honorific?
This is a dance for our unreleased song.
If we stand like this in a formation...
He slaps me.
I was so dumbfounded.
Even our choreographer laughed.
That's because it looks so soft.
Back of his neck?
(Jin's neck attracts violence.)
We've been slapping each others' necks
a lot these days.
Doesn't that look like a castle?
Samsung.
(Sung = Castle.)
These all are estates, literally.
(Houses fenced in with high walls.)
I think it was a same developer.
They look identical.
You're right.
(6 identical houses in one street.)
Just like townhouses!
They are townhouses.
(Built by Hyundai.)
Look over there.
That's the Namyang Houses.
It looks like a complex.
There are streets inside too.
Wouldn't they have managers Yoo?
Hi.
What's that space for?
What?
A' studio?
What kind of people live around here?
Someone really famous.
Who?
I can't.
Can you whisper it to me?
Who?
It was supposed to be a secret...
(Confidentiality.)
I wanted to act like I was surprised...
Bye!
(Samsungdong is a popular areas)
(among celebrities.)
Kyung-kyu,
someone we know might
open the door.
I know!
We might run into our friends.
That's why that lady told us
to not say anything.
But I want to tell someone badly.
We can just cut her out!
Or you could just give us hints.
Then try to guess.
Lee Min-jung!
(If Lee Min-jung's a hint...)
She told me not to reveal
who the other one is!
She didn't say don't mention Lee Min-jung.
This is Min-jung's house!
Do you know who lives here now?
What happens if we go there?
We know who lives there
so you can't ring the doorbell.
He's probably out of the country.
He's my friend!
(Your honor, I didn't say any names.)
I'm starving.
We didn't eat properly today.
Please...
(Please give us a meal...)
Kyung-kyu.
Let's choose teams.
I want to go with him...
But he says so many weird things!
It's uncomfortable.
Me?
You rang a bell when you shouldn't!
You told me to go ring it.
That's why I did!
You two are perfect for each other.
They'll be a great team.
They both complain a lot.
With BTS...
Let's Have Dinner Together!
The time for BTS to open doors
is finally here.
Let's break our limit today.
Let's succeed in two houses.
We're going for 2 houses!
Do you think we'll succeed today?
(Will they be able to eat today...?)
(Who's first?)
Who's going first?
Should Jin go first?
Jung-gook should do it!
Rock, paper, scissors!
(Jung-gook won!)
I'll go first.
(Not cool...)
(Jin's first attempt.)
(His first ring.)
(Nervous...)
(More nervous...)
Show your face!
Yes?
Hello.
I'm Jin from BTS.
Do you know who we are?
Do you know BTS?
Yes.
You do?
(His eyes are about to pop.)
How can I help you?
You know BTS?
Yes.
(He's more surprised that she knows.)
If I man...
How old are you?
I'm old.
Why?
I'm truly honored that you know who we are.
Thank you.
Please continue.
Did you eat yet?
Our grandma lives here
so we eat early.
I see...
(They ate already!)
(Disappointing.)
She knew who we are!
She knew BTS.
She knew BTS...
We're taking the world by storm!
(Confident after being recognized.)
World wide BTS!
(Self congratulations is in his DNA.)
Can you express that happiness
by dancing?
(Fire.)
Jung-gook!
Is it my turn?
We go right after one another?
(Jung-gook's first attempt.)
Good!
(Readjusts his location.)
He has to show his face on the monitor.
He's so good looking!
No one's home?
(Tries to use his looks.)
I don't think anyone's home.
Try one more time.
(Can't use his looks if no one's home...)
(No answer yet.)
(Jung-gook's first attempt failed.)
Let's succeed by the end of this wall.
That'd be great.
Jin!
(Jin's second attempt!)
Does Jin mean truth?
Nope!
Aren't you nervous?
I'm really nervous.
(Silly.)
I look terrible...
Wait.
He needs lights.
He's BTS!
But still...
Who cares about lighting?
I'm beautiful!
(Stop talking nonsense.)
(A match made in heaven.)
(Think before you speak!)
(Rings the bell.)
(Please...)
Jin's going toe to toe against Kyung-kyu.
(No answer again...?)
Yes?
Hi.
Do you know BTS?
No...
We're singers...
Did you eat yet?
Yes, we all ate.
I see...
Do you know Let's Have Dinner Together?
Of course!
That's what we're doing right now.
Hi.
I'm Lee Kyung-kyu!
Why did you eat so early?
We're old...
If you didn't...
Do you think you would've invite us in?
Of course!
(Thank you for the kind gesture.)
Thank you for your time.
Thanks.
(It's Jung-gook's turn again.)
(Kyung-kyu rings the bell.)
We'll do it!
We need to get ready first!
(Nervous.)
(Even if you are ready...)
(It's no use if no one's home.
We even prayed to Buddha...
(Please...)
No one's home.
Hello?
(Empty house twice in a row.)
(Not only do doors in Samsungdong)
(look incredibly thick...)
It's shut as people went out to eat
on a Sunday evening.
The lights are on!
(Jin tries to ring...)
Do you live here?
Hi.
Do you know BTS?
This is BTS.
Hi.
Are you coming back or leaving?
Leaving.
Did you eat yet?
I'm on a diet.
(First person on a diet in this show!)
It would've been nice if we ate together.
With this many people?
No, only two would've gone in.
So you don't normally eat dinner?
I do.
Why is the light on inside?
My kids are inside.
(Her kids are at home)
(and she's going to the gym.)
Who else is in there?
We could eat with them...
But she won't be home...
Are they young?
No.
One's in college.
Then can we try?
You can go to the gym.
Do you think they ate?
They didn't eat yet.
Do you want to eat at our yard?
Of course!
I don't care if it's a basement.
I could eat on the roof too.
We can eat here too!
Did you just succeed?
Just be quiet for a second.
She's on her way out.
She said she's not leaving.
(Debating about what's going on.)
Miss.
I'll have to cook!
(Success?)
(Did we do it?)
(They're getting their hopes up now!)
Didn't Jung-gook ring a bell?
(Damn it.)
His fans are watching!
(Then let me!)
How many kids do you have.
3.
Can I put some makeup on and change?
Of course!
(Take your time.)
Then would you like to eat with
Kyung-kyu and Jin?
Sure!
(Success!)
(Totally jealous.)
(She goes into her house first.)
Could you ask your kids
if they're okay with being filmed?
Thank you!
We'll get going.
We don't have a lot of time.
Congratulations!
See you next week!
We might end up going with you.
Congratulations Jin!
See you next time.
See you tomorrow Jung-gook!
(They leave with heavy hearts)
(and heavy steps.)
Did they get in?
The only thing he sees when he turns,
is disappointment...
(Waiting outside.)
What if her kids don't want to do it?
Then we have to go somewhere else.
(They need everyone's approval)
(to succeed.)
She's coming.
Is it okay?
Only my son wanted to do it...
(A bolt from the blue.)
Then we have to go.
We need everyone's permission.
The little ones ran away.
We can't have that.
Thank you.
Thank you for even talking to us.
Wish us luck!
Good luck!
Thank you.
So close, but no cigar.
They have to wander in the dark again.
Jung-gook!
Huh?
What's wrong?
You just said, see you next week.
Her son didn't want to?
No.
She has 3 kids...
Only her son wanted to do it...
(So close.)
(I thought it was too easy.)
(He's too disappointed to a point)
(it became funny.)
The sun is setting.
Let's hurry.
Most people finish eating by 7.
(Goes down to the camera.)
Are you getting a good vibe?
Stop overreacting.
Wake up!
That scared me.
(Hilarious.)
Hello.
I'm BTS.
Do you know BTS?
No.
Hello?
Hi.
I'm Lee Kyung-kyu.
Did you eat yet?
I ate a long time ago.
You did?
We'll close the door for you!
Thank you!
Sorry?
I'd like to pay for your meal.
Money?
It's okay
Thank you for your kind gesture!
She wanted to give us money?
Wow...
Go get the money.
Yes, money.
That would've been nice.
(She was worried that they'll starve.)
So we can buy food with it?
(Jung-gook's turn.)
(Will he be able to talk to someone?)
Hearts!
Love!
They're spreading love.
Excuse me!
Hello?
(No one's home again...)
(Let's hurry.)
Someone's out!
Who is it?
Ma'am!
I'm Kang Ho-dong!
We're doing a show when
we can talk all sorts of things
in Samsungdong!
Let's Have Dinner Together?
(She knows!)
I'm starving!
For our guest today,
I brought...
Do you know BTS?
I'm too old to know what it is.
I ate already!
You did?
(Failed...)
Why did you eat so early?
We always eat early.
How early?
4:30.
That's lunch!
You didn't eat dinner yet.
Our breakfast is at 5.
Breakfast is at 5?
Then when do you eat lunch?
12.
Just like in a military.
Aren't?
Old people don't get hungry.
Do you think we'll succeed today?
Everyone probably ate by now.
Only old people live around here.
(Most people eat early here...)
Then we'll have to get going.
Sorry we have to go!
Wish us luck.
(They're picking up speed.)
We even brought our own spoons!
We ate already.
You did?
Did you eat yet?
Yup!
We eat late.
But people here eat really early.
Dinner's early in Samsungdong...
As they hurry more,
the walls grow taller.
This isn't as easy as I thought it'd be.
(Ho-dong and Jung-gook's attempt!)
One team has to succeed at least.
(Desperate hands.)
We should change the rules.
(A trick in order to succeed.)
Let's allow houses that already ate.
There are 3 houses here.
Who is it?
Do you know BTS?
Yes.
Hi!
I'm Kang Ho-dong!
Ho-dong!
Yes?
Me?
Kang Ho-dong!
Do you know me?
Of course I do!
(Who could it be?)
I'm...
Who is she?
Do you know me?
Of course I do!
(Who could it be...)
Ho-dong, I'm Kim Nam-ju.
(They rang Kim Nam-ju's house!)
Kim Nam-ju!
We didn't know you lived here!
We really didn't.
We're shooting
Let's Have Dinner Together!
I saw a bunch of lights pass by
and was wondering what it was.
I was so surprised when my doorbell rung.
Did you eat already?
I already ate with my kid.
Did you ever watch our show before?
Of course!
Why did you have to come today...
I seriously would love to offer
you guys a meal.
That sucks.
Who's home right now?
Just me and my 2 kids.
Do they like BTS?
My daughter loves them.
Jin, say hell.
(Identifies himself.)
Hi Kim Nam-ju!
Hi!
Where did Sung-woo go?
Seung-woo stepped out for a bit.
He's not home right now.
That's fine!
Please tell him we said hi!
Sorry!
Come to our show next time!
If you pass our house again,
you can definitely come in.
We literally just ate.
I'm so sorry.
This is such a weird coincidence!
Jung-gook wants to say bye
to your daughter!
Hi.
Hi!
See you next time!
Bye!
We'll get going then!
Sorry!
Thank you!
(They almost ate at Nam-ju's!)
I'm sorry but...
We're going to Lee Min-jung's house.
(Still can't believe what just happened...)
I'm starving.
We'll try first.
Yes?
Hi!
Ma'am!
This is BTS.
She's coming out.
(Can they find someone who didn't eat yet?)
Hi!
Is this Let's Have Dinner Together?
Yes!
Did you eat yet?
Yes.
It would've been nice to eat together.
I'm Kang Ho-dong.
(Let's go.)
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry that you can't even come in...
That's okay.
Good luck in the future!
Thank you!
Thanks for welcoming us.
Hi.
We're from JTBC.
Let's Have Dinner Together!
Yes!
I watch it every day!
We're on air on Wednesday.
Where do you live?
Way over there.
Did you eat yet?
Of course I ate.
(Shows her disappointment.)
It would've been nice to talk to you
while eating together.
I already ate.
(Should've come sooner...)
That house has lights on!
Lights are on!
(Jin takes the lead.)
Who is it?
Hi!
Do you know BTS?
I don't.
We're an idol.
We're shooting a show called,
Let's Have Dinner Together.
(The most important question!)
Did you eat yet?
I'm eating right now.
Hello?
I'm Lee Kyung-kyu!
We bring our own spoons...
If you let us in,
this is a show about eating together
while having a conversation.
Did you watch Let's Have Dinner Together?
No.
I see...
Who are you eating with?
By myself.
Then how about...
Eating with me and BTS?
Would you like to eat with us?
I don't think I can...
I see.
Thank you!
This is hard...
She's alone right now.
We only have 30 more minutes.
We have to run.
We're done eating.
(They all ate already...)
The clock keeps ticking.
Now it's time for Blood, Sweat and Tears.
I've got a bad feeling about this.
I can smell the convenience store.
Jin.
We only have 20 more minutes.
As long as I'm with you, I don't care.
I don't think you understood my question.
(He doesn't care what the question is.)
We're running out of time!
(With no teams succeeding yet,)
(they have to start running.)
7:42.
(Hopeless...)
Car! Car! Car!
There's a car!
(No more hesitations.)
Kyung-kyu.
That sounds like a song.
Why does it sound like that?
(Even bells are giving the trouble now...)
There's no time to have fun with it!
I'm starving.
Let's go to the apartments!
We only have 15 more minutes.
They hopelessly walk into apartments
with one foot in the convenience store
already.
Okay, here we go.
(Please...)
Who is it?
Hello?
I'm...
(He's stuttering.)
I'm Kang Ho-dong.
We're done eating.
You already ate?
Yes...
Our deadline's at 8.
We'll get going.
(Turns on his boosters.)
We'll go next door!
10 minutes to go.
Everyone for themselves.
(They split up into 2 teams)
(for a better chance!)
Who is it?
Hi.
Do you know Let's Have Dinner Together?
I'm sorry...
It's okay!
It's fine!
Thanks!
We only have 7 minutes!
7 is a lucky number!
Exactly!
I'm sorry...
We just ate!
(Unlucky 7.)
Come back to our show later...
For a revenge.
We don't have any time left!
We only have 4 minutes.
But we already ate...
You did?
2 minutes!
Should we go to Bongeun Temple
for temple food?
These doors are bullet proof.
Will they both fail for the first time?
1 minute.
This is our last chance.
(Failure here means they're going)
(to the convenience store!)
(Ring the bell together!)
(They only have 1 more minute too.)
Hi!
(Their last hope.)
Do you know BTS?
Yes!
Really?
Nice to meet you!
Did you eat yet?
No!
You didn't eat yet?
Are you about to?
We're getting ready for dinner!
Where's your mom?
Dad's home!
You can come up!
Ask your dad first!
Dad!
Please...
Hi!
Who is it?
This is BTS.
What?
And I'm Kang Ho-dong!
Kang Ho-dong is here!
BTS!
Hi!
Let me explain what we're doing.
Please...
Do you want me to explain what we're doing?
You're wearing rubber gloves...
You're even holding a spoon!
You didn't eat dinner yet?
No idea.
(What does her rubber gloves mean?)
(Doing the dishes after a meal?)
(Or before a meal?)
We don't care what you have...
This is our last house.
We're out choices now.
This is our last chance.
Don't get nervous.
Let's shake hands.
Can I ask you an important question?
Please...
You should ask.
Did you eat dinner yet?
Can we come up?
The time has run out.
Can they make one last miracle
and have a meal in Samsungdong?
He said you can!
We can?
(It's a miracle!)
(Ecstatic.)
I can't believe we ran into them!
(Will miracle happen here too?)
Did you eat yet?
We're cleaning up right now...
(No way...)
(No...)
(Ho-dong and Jung-gook failed.)
We love BTS.
My son does too.
I'm sorry...
Can the camera get your hand?
Were you doing the dishes?
I just started doing the dishes.
It would've been nice if she was
getting ready for dinner.
We just finished...
You'd be still eating
if we came 5 minutes early?
3 minutes.
3 minutes?
(Disappointed...)
Would you have eaten with us
if we came 3 minutes early?
Of course!
Because it's Sunday...
We had Korean BBQ.
How was it?
Good.
(Sad...)
And we just went to a bakery...
And bought cake.
Cake as well?
Then had a glass of wine.
(What was the point of our whole day...)
(This place was heaven...)
This meal...
Is a perfect course meal
with LA style galbi, cake and wine.
It could've been theirs
if they came 3 minutes earlier.
Do you know who this is?
Probably not...
I know BTS...
(She knows!)
Thank you.
She says BTS not Bangtan.
They're popular in Japan.
How did you know that?
I go there often for business trips.
Didn't you have a concert in Osaka?
That's right!
I saw a bunch of people in a line
so when I asked,
they said, we're waiting for BTS!
(Embarrassed.)
Only if we came 3 minutes early...
we could've talked about this
while sitting down.
I love one of their songs,
Blood, Sweat and Tears.
I love it.
(I could've sang it inside...)
When I listen to that song...
Spring Day and Not Today.
(Singing in a hall because of 3 minutes.)
(Touched.)
(I want to eat...)
(The crowd is going nuts!)
Thank you.
I want LA style galbi.
I'm so disappointed!
Attention!
Say thank you.
Thank you!
They missed a meal by 3 minutes...
Now they head to the convenience store.
So close...
That could've been a dramatic finish.
It really was close.
What happened to the other team?
(Arrived at the front door!)
Hi!
I'm Lee Kyung-kyu.
Thank you for inviting us in!
Invite...
My kids did!
You didn't yet yet?
I didn't...
But my wife isn't home.
We can eat whatever's lying around.
I'm a good cook!
He is!
Then come inside!
Thank you!
Thanks to the little girls by the window,
they finally got the door opened
and went inside to have a meal.
Hi!
I love Let's Have Dinner Together!
BTS!
Who's that?
My oldest daughter.
(Shy.)
How many daughters do you have?
Jenny!
That's a pretty name.
Who's Jenny?
She's too shy. She can't come out.
She's a huge fan.
A fan!
We all are!
Jenny!
Come here.
Introduce yourselves.
What grade are you in?
We're all in 6th grade!
Elementary school?
You're all friends?
Except her.
What grade are you in?
2.
Who's your daughter?
Jenny.
The little one here, and the oldest one.
What's your name?
Min-ji.
Min-ji and Jenny.
Min-ji and Jenny love BTS.
A dinner with their friends.
(Can't believe BTS is here!)
Calm down.
First time seeing him?
Yes.
Isn't he handsome?
Very!
Why are you eating so late?
We're having a pajama party today...
What party?
Pajama party.
You walk around in pajamas?
It's kind of a sleep over.
That's called a pajama party?
But for an old man, Kyung-kyu,
there's something more important
than a pajama party.
What are you making?
I'm making rice for now.
Kimchi stew!
(Love it!)
Do kids come here often...
To stay over?
Yes, all the time!
I've never heard of a pajama party before.
They wear pajamas and just play
in a room.
Do you have to take care of them?
My wife does normally.
But she's traveling right now.
Travel?
You're a good husband.
If I may, what do you do for a living?
I'm in an education business.
Education business?
You own an academy?
Yes.
Kids in that age...
Love BTS.
I know...
If you said no, you would've been
in trouble.
Hi...
You're my wallpaper...
Can I see it?
(Shaking.)
(Fact checked.)
That's embarrassing.
Thank you.
Min-ji!
Did you call your friend?
She was supposed to come over...
We don't have enough rice.
Tell her to go home.
(You're too mean...)
I'm her phone's wallpaper!
Really?
She had my face on her phone!
It's true!
(Proud.)
She has Jin as her wallpaper!
Guys.
You guys need to thank me.
I brought him here.
Thank you.
Didn't I say hi first?
(Embarrassed.)
Change your wallpaper
to me later.
(No thank you...)
I'll even take a picture with you.
Thank you...
(A fart broke the ice in the room...)
He has healthy intestines!
He knows how TVs work!
For the first time in our show...
Someone farted.
Do you know how to say
farting in English?
Thar's not right!
What's don't fart in English?
How do you say don't fart in English?
I have no idea.
He told me that earlier today.
Then he really farted!
(Perfect timing!)
That was the first time.
Who's his sister?
I am.
Did he follow you to the pajama party?
No, he'll go home soon.
(That's cold...)
Why don't you guys introduce yourselves?
I'm in grade 6, class 3 in
Bongeun Elementary.
Kim Jenny.
I'm in grade 6, class 1.
Kim Ho-jung.
Are you a good student?
I'm not...
What do you wanna be later?
Korean classical music.
Really?
I want to listen to it later!
She can play a pipe!
She wants to do it too.
(It was Jenny's dream too!)
Next!
Fart!
(His turn to introduce himself.)
I'm in grade 2, class 4.
Kim Ho-jun.
Kim Ho-jun!
Grade 6, class 5.
Jo Su-min.
What do you wanna be when you grow up?
I haven't thought about that yet...
You didn't?
You're only in 6th grade.
I'm in grade 6, class 4.
Lee Ji-Ahn.
What do you wanna be?
A perfumer.
(She wants to make perfumes.)
You want to make your own perfume?
I'm in Gyeonggi Women's High School,
9th grade, Ko Ye-rang.
9th grade, I'm Kim Min-ju.
I...
Want to do my own business!
(Cracks up.)
Fashion?
Nice.
(While they're having fun inside...)
(They're distraught by disappointment.)
It's not over yet.
Look for a convenience store?
I'm disappointed.
Talk about this...
And that!
That's what we should be doing...
But the last family really did welcome us.
I guess that counts too.
I guess so.
We got love instead!
The love and warm heart...
Were enough to fill me up today.
But I can't get galbi out of my mind...
(Where is he going?)
(He lost his mind due to hunger.)
Put some garlic in it.
(This is how scary hunger is.)
That looks delicious.
wonderful!
(After a tough acting...)
(Comes a deep sigh.)
Let's sit for 1 minute.
We walked so much today.
(Exhausted.)
I'm starving.
Both teams failed for the first time?
(They don't know about Kyung-kyu yet.)
Should we call them?
What?
Ho-dong called me.
Wait.
(Found Jung-gook.)
(2nd chaos.)
(They can only see Kyung-kyu.)
(Unaware of their success.)
(What?)
They got in!
Why aren't you inside?
Is this real?
(Totally real.)
Hi!
You guys succeeded?
At 8!
Did you eat yet?
It's being cooked!
He's cooking by himself.
That's unbelievable.
Go to the convenience store
and call me back when you eat ramen!
Jin, since you're the only one to succeed,
good luck on promoting your song!
Good luck Jin!
Our episode in Samsungdong...
Only a half successful!
Enjoy your meal!
(Good luck Jung-gook!)
They succeeded...
We don't have all the time in the world
for convenience stores.
Our deadline's at 9:30.
We have an hour left.
Let's go.
Let's go find one.
(Can they find people to eat with?)
I don't know where we are.
I don't think there are any here.
Over there!
Let's watch from over here.
This way.
(Tries to scout from across the street.)
3 men?
(Having a conversation.)
Should we go?
(Ho-dong approaches them first.)
Hi.
Are you eating?
We're about to go eat.
You're going right now?
Isn't it too late?
We just got out of work.
Now?
Are you guys coworkers?
Okay, have fun!
(Searching for convenience stores.)
(Found another one.)
(Anyone eating...?)
(No one.)
Let's just wait.
Someone will come, right?
We have until 9:30...
Let's hide here.
(Stake out by one of their tables.)
We can eat only when people come.
That looks like rice.
Is that an ash tray?
My dad used to smoke...
And quit.
How old is he?
He was born in 1971.
(Pause.)
(What's wrong?)
I'm your uncle.
(He's old enough to be most idols' dads.)
1 year?
(He's older than Jung-gooks dad by 1 year.)
My dad did get married early.
He's younger than my mom.
By how much?
By 2 years.
Do you know their love story?
Mom hit on him first.
(That sums everything up.)
She said she did because dad
was good looking.
Mom is...
Proactive?
Yes.
She's energetic.
Until his parents' love story was over,
no one came...
Do you need my help with anything?
It's okay.
I really like cooking.
I'd like to help.
Should I make some egg rolls?
Sure...
Just a second.
You cracked the eggs already?
(Washes his hands firs)
Cooking at someone else's house...
(Is awkward.)
Do you know what a surprised car is?
A surprised car?
Canola oil.
Sorry...
Your daughters said you're a great cook...
They had high praises...
But you might be disappointed.
I haven't had home cooking in a while.
(It's been whole 3 days...)
(Tuna.)
While stew with tuna and ham
are cooking just as kids would love it...
One man is deep in thought.
How many eggs did you use?
5.
That's a lot to cook at once.
I normally use 3 at a time...
(5 eggs...)
(What am I gonna do...)
(Let's go!)
(Rolled.)
(Spread out again.)
(It's being cooked with some fancy skills.)
(He really was good at cooking.)
(His passion is on fire.)
(Careful.)
(Jin's egg rolls are ready!)
You're really good.
This is my first time cooking on TV...
It's my first time too.
Fish is almost cooked...
Delicious Kimchi in beautiful red...
And Kimchi stew looking spicy as well...
To top it off,
pepper paste fish.
These two men's cooking
is heating up the kitchen
as much as the pajama party.
(Meanwhile, in the living room...)
How long did you live here for?
3 years?
3 years...
Where did you live before?
Seochodong.
Seochodong?
How do you like Samsungdong?
Quiet...
Don't a lot of old people live here too?
There's nothing here!
Not even convenience stores...
Really?
Not that many.
There were no pedestrians either!
Yup.
Why am I...
Interviewing them?
I'm not their teacher...
This is our first time having
this many students on our show.
Elementary, middle school...
Don't I look like a principle?
When Jin was here, they were so excited.
After he left, they calmed down.
I think they feel like
they're talking to a teacher.
(Only Jin disappeared...)
(Silence.)
Can I go help?
Sure.
(They go help set the table...)
(He even plates the egg rolls beautifully!)
(But the fish disintegrated...)
(Stew is complete.)
(They quickly move to get ready.)
9 people?
(Works hard.)
Both of his daughters' friends are here.
This rice has to feed a lot of people.
Unused bowls have to come out as well.
He expertly hands out rice.
Take this.
(Kids take the food then places)
(them on a table.)
(Table set!)
(Can't forget to take a picture!)
This meal was made by a super dad and Jin
for girls in Samsungdong.
It's delicious and nutritious.
(Dinner theater first!)
(Today has an audience too!)
Okay.
When I say ready...
Say action!
Ready!
Action!
Let's eat.
Thanks for the food.
(Very awkward...)
Did you work hard
at the art academy?
I stopped going...
I can't because of school exams...
Really?
(Embarrassed.)
So only Jenny is studying?
She didn't go either.
I had tutoring...
Her tutor came here.
Jenny...
Is your middle school application
start tomorrow?
Get ready.
Get prepared.
You never study.
She always plays with her phone.
BTS is coming back soon...
(What?)
(He feels guilty...)
I have to watch BTS with my phone...
(Loss for words...)
(Finished before things get serious.)
I feel bad now...
She doesn't study because of us...
I feel so guilty...
She doesn't study because of BTS!
Take a seat.
All we need is rice!
(Finally a time to eat!)
Give him a round of applause!
I made the eggs.
Try some.
Thank you!
Enjoy!
Thank you for the food!
(They all go for the egg rolls!)
(Hesitates.)
(This is...)
(Jin's egg rolls...)
She's like...
I can't eat this...
(Wants to cherish it forever.)
(They should freeze it to keep it forever.)
(Jin, who was hungry,)
(is happy.)
Hey guys...
You're the only fans who get
to eat with Jin.
It's not in a big group either!
I always liked cooking.
I've been saying I want to cook
for the fans for a while.
And I finally got to today.
It's an honor.
(It's an honor for us...)
Did you really make this?
This Kimchi stew.
Yes.
It's delicious!
Thank goodness.
It's really good.
I really missed home cooking.
We always deliver.
It's really good.
(Heartbroken...)
I saw him cook eggs...
He's really good.
(Shy.)
They met this family
When things were bleak.
Kyung-kyu is loving this meal...
It's delicious.
(And...)
And Jin finally gets to enjoy home cooking
after 3 whole days.
Did you make this too?
(Can't get their eyes off of him.)
What's this?
Bean pepper fish!
Watching Jin fill up himself...
These girls doesn't know how to
control themselves.
And...
He got to feed the culprit
that prevents his daughters from studying.
Sorry, I have a cold...
(Heartbroken 2...)
It's not serious.
(Worried.)
My head!
Are you okay?
When he said he had a cold...
(Jealous of an idol...)
(Keep it up!)
These kids...
Love  BTS.
How is it as a father?
Well...
I don't think it's bad.
Really?
It'll be a problem if they don't study
and go to see their show everyday.
My youngest daughter said...
She'll pass her next exam
if I invited BTS to our house.
She promised.
(A deal was struck.)
When we were outside?
When you said no,
she promised she'll pass her exam?
(She promised just to have a meal!)
Someone came to our signing event...
Said she's 1st in her class...
She said, she'll come back as
1st in her school,
if I cheered her on.
Then she really got 1st in her school.
You could be the reason
for kids not studying.
But you could also make them study.
Exactly.
(Under a huge pressure now...)
Do you cook like this often?
I don't get to eat often at home lately...
Busy?
Kids leave early,
I come back late.
We don't get to eat at home often.
Then where do you eat dinner
during the week?
Their mom cooks at home normally...
But since she's not here today...
We had chicken for a few days...
We got tired of it for a few days.
So decided to eat rice?
I missed home cooking.
(It's a destiny!)
Perfect timing.
Exactly.
Why did you allow a pajama party?
They do it often.
(They hold pajama parties often.)
They come over a lot.
My wife's friends come over a lot.
My wife is from Geojedo.
When her friends come to Seoul,
they stay over at our house.
How did your daughter
start on a classical music?
She likes music.
When she sleeps at night...
She listens to BTS all the time!
(Feels guilty.)
What an honor.
When I go in my car,
she changes the CD
and plays BTS as soon as she's in the car.
(Jenny's with BTS 24 hours a day.)
She promised her mom that
if she gets 100 on her exam,
she wanted a BTS CD.
Did you get it?
She didn't get 100 yet.
I did!
Isn't that a really good score?
It is!
People who like BTS,
are all nice.
Our fans are all nice.
I'm a huge BTS fan!
(Everyone unites under BTS.)
Do you know our members' names?
I only need you and Jung-seok.
Jung-gook...
(He doesn't even remember)
(what he did yesterday.)
Do you know all 7's birthdays?
Yes!
Really?
When's V's birthday?
12/30.
They do know!
Jung-gook?
9/1.
And?
9/12.
3/9.
(They're on top of their stuff.)
How do you know all that?
When's Jin's birthday?
12/4!
My birthday?
How would they know that?
No?
7/3!
(1/365 chance to get it right.)
Your dad's birthday?
8/14.
January?
(Quickly closes her mouth.)
(Gotta laugh it out...)
(Embarrassed.)
(Let's go play in the room.)
Kids who finished the father's cooking
leaves...
The two daughters
and their father remains.
What's hard about raising daughters?
Isn't this the worst time?
When they're on puberty?
My wife and I are different in that sense.
Because they're girls,
they go through things only girls
go through.
They need their mom for that.
Exactly.
There are things I can't do anything about.
That's what's tough for me.
But my wife is really good with that.
She talks to them a lot.
Are both of your daughters...
Past puberty?
The older one did.
Jenny's just getting started.
Just slightly.
How?
Because of her puberty...
When I tell her to study,
she says, wait!
Wait for what?
(Embarrassed.)
(She's becoming more independent.)
Does she know
that she's on puberty?
It happened to my daughter too.
But I had male menopause.
I won.
Are you comfortable with your dad?
I...
She likes dad more.
More than mom?
Yup!
You're gonna be in trouble!
Mom's scary...
Mothers do nag.
(Her dad is like her friend.)
Yes...
Dad or BTS?
BTS.
(Didn't even think for 1 second.)
(Guilty as charged...)
She said BTS...
But he's really good looking.
(Thank you.)
No wonder kids like them.
I spent the whole day with him.
He's really nice too.
He's a great person.
I am very nice.
(Compliments himself.)
I know I'm the one who said it.
But it's true.
Okay.
Time to give compliments.
They're both the same...
They're really nice.
They listen to their parents well.
That's the best.
Why don't you
thank your father for letting
BTS into his house tonight?
We could've gone somewhere else.
Thank you for saying yes.
(Her shy gratitude makes him laugh.)
(Happy.)
This dad tries to understand his daughter's
puberty and love for BTS.
Meanwhile...
They didn't find anyone to talk to yet.
Right about now...
Today's Sunday...
People sleep early on Sundays.
If it was during the week...
People could be getting off work late
and stop by on the way back.
To get something quick.
Exactly.
Someone's here.
Act natural.
Hope he comes here.
(Pretends to not look...)
He's buying beer.
Beer?
(Beer and ramen would be perfect.)
It's so good right before sleeping.
But he's leaving.
He wants to drink right before he sleeps.
Wait.
(Someone goes in with a kid.)
(Takes a peak.)
Coming here must mean they live here.
They're leaving...
(Most people go home.)
(When he was about to complain...)
Someone's here!
(This customer is alone.)
Maybe he'll eat alone!
A lone wolf type.
Lone wolf...
(His filter doesn't work out of hunger.)
Someone who eats alone,
watches movies alone,
and does a BBQ alone.
(Choosing carefully.)
You're unstoppable!
Buy ramen!
Ramen!
He's leaving...
(He didn't buy anything.)
(20 minutes left.)
Isn't this a TF?
A total failure.
I want to call someone
and act like a stranger...
(To have a meal.)
(He's that desperate.)
What are your concerns?
Concerns?
I used to be the Knee Drop Guru.
Do you know what that is?
Of course I do!
You watched it?
(What's Jung-gook worried about?)
When I was in a puberty...
I came to Seoul alone...
When I meet someone for the first time...
I don't feel completely sincere
in how I act.
It feels like there's a wall.
To get close,
we need to understand each other.
But I worry about what should I do
to make this person like me?
I feel like I'm wearing a mask...
You want to be more sincere with people?
Yes.
(Told Ho-dong what he's worried about.)
You started working too early.
I think so too.
(It was his survival instincts.)
But on the other hand...
I used to wrestle...
To be the champion,
you can't just have one style.
Against a tall person,
you need to put your right leg more
to put more pressure with your weight.
Against a smaller person,
you need to try to bring him inside.
You need different styles
for different people.
That's complicated.
Depending on people you meet,
you're changing how you treat them.
That's right.
Being open to many stances...
Could be a good thing?
Exactly!
(He may look happy,)
(but he had his issues too.)
A little boy who wanted to be an idol,
broke out of his shells to the world
and took over the world by storm.
Should we say it out loud?
(Goes back being the Guru.)
Here's my solution.
Today's client...
Look over there!
That tree!
That flower!
Change their appearance every seasons.
Every sides of Jung-gook!
Is who you are!
(Touched.)
Stay positive!
I have goosebumps.
(Ho-dong's happy with his solution too.)
Everybody!
(Ceremony for solving a crisis.)
(He's too skinny...)
The guru solved the problem...
But no one's here to give them a meal.
(Worried about a meal.)
(Worried.)
15 minutes left...
(They're choosing what to eat.)
They're buying gimbap.
It's a matter of eating here
or taking it home.
Please...
(Desperate.)
(Transaction complete.)
(Please eat here!)
Can their desperate plea
become true?
(Didn't even turn back.)
That's how...
Our saviors...
Left.
I'm getting mosquito bites.
(Would they really fail?)
We have 5 minutes.
I can't stay seated.
(A car stopped in front of them.)
(What?)
(Someone's getting off...)
I heard the news!
You scared me!
(Did he see a ghost?)
(Who is it?)
(A familiar voice.)
Did you get to eat?
No?
(Kim Nam-ju's husband, Kim Seung-woo.)
(A celebrity couple for the first time)
(in our show!)
(He's confused too.)
I'm sorry..
We saw your wife!
She told me over the phone!
What are you up to?
I'm on my way home!
This is a coincidence?
I live right there!
Did you eat?
You saw us on your way back?
How could I miss you!
(Huge.)
We have 3 minutes left...
If nothing happens in 3 minutes,
we fail.
I can't buy it for you?
No...
You have to starve?
Can you give them a wave?
They're still shooting.
Just wave.
Give them a wave.
When are you coming to our show?
You need to go eat.
My wife's doing a new drama on JTBC!
So...
Call her!
That's better!
That'd be great.
I'm really sorry for not eating...
Jung-gook from BTS!
BTS!
He's the youngest.
Nice to meet you!
Your niece is a huge fan!
That's right!
Is my voice getting recorded?
Of course!
Then I'll use honorifics.
That's fine!
(See you later.)
Thank you!
Bye.
Thanks.
What did you have for dinner?
I had noodles.
There's a delicious restaurant there.
Thanks!
Bye!
Wow.
(Thank you Kim Seung-woo)
(for coming on to our show.)
Instead of a meal,
they got to meet Seung-woo.
It's too early to say we failed.
We still have 2 minutes.
2 minutes?
2 minutes is an eternity.
(But he feels the hunger...)
We went to a convenience store
in Neungdong.
No guests came.
(We even ate with a dog...)
(Don't give up yet.)
(Someone's here!)
(Someone came with a minute left!)
I feel like this is it.
This is our last chance.
I'm looking forward to eating...
He's at the food section!
Ramen!
He got ramen!
(Another miracle?)
Please...
I can't believe this is happening.
Its 9:30!
Wow.
(Unbelievable.)
(He goes to the cashier!)
(Please eat here!)
He's paying.
He should open it anytime now.
Eating outside is always more delicious!
But...
Will the last guest...
Make the miracle happen?
(Ho-dong to the rescue.)
Hi.
I'm Kang Ho-dong.
What did you just buy?
Just...
Ramen?
Why don't you eat it here?
It's for tomorrow.
Did you eat dinner already?
Yes.
Enjoy rest of your night!
Bye!
(They...)
(Completely failed for the first time.)
This is a let down...
(Deep sigh.)
They desperately wanted a meal
in Samsungdong.
They tried their best to get it...
We just ate...
But their dreams didn't come true.
In the end...
They couldn't find anyone
at the convenience store either.
The win the prize of being a first team
to completely fail in our show.
(Sad.)
Ho-dong and Jung-gook tried very hard
as a team.
We broke every single record
on a show that's 1 year old.
(Dizzy.)
(It's funny and sad at the same time.)
A record breaker.
That's what BTS is.
TF.
The first guest to totally fail.
TF...
We went to a celebrities house
completely unaware.
And a couple were both in our show!
Exactly.
It was so random!
Out of all the firsts...
The best one is...
The total failure.
TF.
Couldn't eat until the end...
I need to buy something on the way back.
You can't eat today.
I can't?
It's on effect until I fall asleep?
His goal of the day became fasting...
Meanwhile,
Jin is doing the dishes
after a great meal.
That's okay.
Our fans said they really like you.
Your fan club...
Has protected me a lot.
You yell BTS all the time.
(Shiny.)
Guys!
He's about to sing.
(Getting ready for the party.)
Take a seat.
(Gets to promote his new song.)
Tell us what kind of a song it is.
The title song for our album, DNA,
is saying our love has been connected
since the beginning.
That's what the song's about.
(Live performance begins.)
(I must be dreaming.)
(They won't be able to sleep tonight.)
(Stay cool.)
In our previous life,
in our next life...
(He's pretty good.)
(A round of applause.)
It's not released yet!
Give him a round of applause!
(DNA promotion was a success!)
(Time to take a photo.)
(Their father goes to the end.)
My kids will be happy if he's
in the middle.
(His daughters love their dad right now.)
(Gives him a spoon.)
BTS!
Guys!
(What everyone was waiting for.)
One, two, three!
With a huge welcome from the girls,
a house who offered a meal, #80
was born in Samsungdong.
We had a great time
with Let's Have Dinner Together.
Let's go Let's Have Dinner Together!
This show is so fun!
You said it was difficult!
It was before.
But it was really fun.
I feel at one with that family's peace...
I thought I was a part of that family.
Good work.
(On their way home...)
Adults used to say if you whistle at night,
snakes will come out.
My grandpa told me to not whistle.
That was our new song...
Your whistle?
(They didn't get to eat today)
(but they don't let that bring them down.)
Jung-gook, 1,2,3!
A dinner to wipe
your blood, sweat and tears...
Would you like to join us?
Subtitles by OnDemandKorea