Previously on "Weeds"...
Mama, mommy's trying to talk.
Nancy: It's for you.
To grow and to do
what you love.
It's great.
Um... Andy...
You're a man of big ideas.
What do you want?
I want my son.
I've been inside you.
Getting Stevie is not gonna be
the answer to your problems.
The spirit of compromise.
Everyone's a little happy,
everyone's a little miserable.
It's family.
Man: Cadets!
When you graduate
from this police academy,
you will be the first line
of defense.
Nancy: We celebrate the closing
of escrow on this,
the Botwin-Price-Gray
family compound,
with significant contributions
from the Wilson fund.
CFO?
That's a promotion, right?
You are gonna have
so much money.
An experiment, to be sure,
but really...
the only solution.
May we not kill one another?
[ Chuckles ]
Shayla!
I swear to God.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Laughter ]
Whoo!
[ Gunshot ]
♪ Little boxes on the hillside ♪
♪ little boxes
made of ticky-tacky ♪
♪ little boxes on the hillside ♪
♪ little boxes all the same ♪
♪ there's a green one
and a pink one ♪
♪ and a blue one
and a yellow one ♪
♪ and they're all made
out of ticky-tacky ♪
♪ and they all look
just the same ♪
♪ and the people in the houses ♪
♪ all went to the university ♪
♪ where they were put in boxes ♪
♪ and they came out
all the same ♪
♪ and there's doctors
and lawyers ♪
♪ and business executives ♪
♪ and they're all made
out of ticky-tacky ♪
♪ and they all look
just the same ♪
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
[ Heavy breathing ]
[ Muffled ] Nancy? Ohh, ohh.
Oh, Jesus. Pants?
Nancy: [ Muffled ] I should
have used the plastic glasses,
but wine always
tastes better in glass.
Don't you think?
Is everyone wearing shoes?
Silas, call 911.
Silas!
Zapatos. Zappos.
Do you think that's why
they call it Zappos?
Because "shoes" in Spanish
is "zapatos."
- Jesus. Don't move. - No, it's okay.
I'm wearing sandals from Zappos.
Silas, take out your phone
and dial!
I said no phones at the table.
- What's that noise?
- Holy shit.
My nose is tingling.
Would you help me up, Andy?
- Um, I think you should stay
right where you are. - Why?
Silas: [ Muffled ] She's been shot.
M-my mom's been shot in the head.
What? Whose mom?
Shayla, don't look.
[ Camera shutter clicking ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
Oh, motherfucker!
[ Birds chirping ]
[ Tires screech ]
[ Siren wailing ]
Aah!
[ Indistinct radio chatter ]
Do you know your name?
I do.
I know my name.
- Nancy Botwin.
- I'm not asking you.
I'm asking her.
I'm assessing.
Oh. Sorry.
Oh.
Nancy, how many fingers
am I holding up?
[ Exhales sharply ]
Over here.
Three -- three very long,
elegant fingers.
- Do you play the piano?
- No, I don't.
- Do you have a very happy girlfriend?
- Let's let him ask the questions, okay, mom?
It's okay.
I just need to keep her talking.
- But you're trying to assess.
- Hey, don't tell me how to do my job, okay?
Don't snap at my kid,
long-finger man. [ Chuckles ]
Long fingers snapped.
[ Laughs ]
Nancy, do you know
what year it is?
You don't know?
Doomsday is coming.
Not really, though.
You still haven't
answered the question, mom.
Oh, right.
Uh, what's your name?
- Mike.
You can call me Nancy.
Nancy, do you know
what's happened to you?
Yeah.
I broke a glass.
[ Inhales sharply ]
Nancy, can you count back
from 100 by 7s for me?
Uh, I -- I'm so bad at math.
I'm really good at boggle, though.
On a five-by-five,
I once spelled "pilsners,"
like the beers.
Nine letters, motherfuckers.
All right, Nancy, we're about
to get to the hospital now.
Oh, 'cause I've been
shot in the head.
'Cause you've been
[ Breathes deeply ]
Motherfucker.
I'm just gonna
close my eyes. Is that okay?
- Nancy, I need you to keep talking
to me, sweetheart. - Okay.
[ Cellphone rings ]
Nancy? Hey.
- Nancy!
- Mom? Mom?
Mom!
[ Ringing ]
[ Cellphone beeps ]
What the fuck?
Andy, let's go!
Shut up, Jill.
Shut your mouth and shut it
and shut up and shut up!
Okay, come on.
We're leaving.
She asked me
to pack things for her.
Those were her last words --
"pack me some stuff."
Andy, she doesn't need
a silk camisole and a thong.
There was blood all over her.
[ Sighs ]
They'll clean her up.
They'll put her
in a hospital gown.
Let's go.
Later you can
go through her underwear
while I go through her jewelry.
What is wrong with you?
I'm dark and dry in a crisis.
You can't hold it against me.
We all have our ways.
Doug:
Hey. Are we going?
I'd kind of like
to get the fuck out of here.
- Where's Shane?
- He took off into the woods.
He ran after the shooter.
- Fuck. That kid's got balls.
- Or did.
They might be shot off by now.
You are bad people.
Listen, the Mexican kid
is hiding in the pantry.
I really think we should leave.
Okay. All the essentials.
Here we go.
Jill?
What if she dies?
She's not gonna die, Andy.
Why not?
Because there is no God.
Whimsy: What do you see, Pill-Pill?
Phillip:
I see a mess.
Oh, I'm not surprised.
They seem like the messy types.
[ Panting ]
Oh, I didn't see you there.
We're your neighbors,
the Ardmores --
Phillip and Whimsy.
I think you need
to climb back down your ladder.
When the Brysons lived here,
they had an eyesore
of a play structure
right up against
the property line.
Their children used to climb up
and pee into our yard.
I got them with a hose
and once with a fire
extinguisher
and once with bees.
Ask him about the ruckus.
Oh, right.
What was all the ruckus?
My mother got hurt.
We live in an enclave,
you know.
This is an enclave.
We try to keep the noise level
down to a civilized level
of noise.
[ Sirens wailing ]
Sorry if we disturbed you.
I was checking the vole traps,
and I heard a bang.
- What was that bang?
- It was an awful bang.
[ Wailing stops ]
It was a gunshot.
Gunshot?!
Well, that's simply unacceptable.
Those are not hunting woods.
Those are strolling woods.
O.S. Police! Freeze!
Do not move!
Oh, my.
[ Mutters ]
You, too, old people.
Tipton.
- What did he say?
- He called us old.
This is my house.
I live here.
Put the gun down.
Put it down, Tipton.
S-sorry about that, folks.
Come on.
You need to send some men
over to Halcyon Road
and get tire imprints.
And she was shot
from over there.
That's where you need
to look for shell casings,
potential hair samples,
footprints, fingerprints,
anything you can computer-check
against known --
one of your guys
is stepping in her blood.
- Oh, shit! - Son, how would you
like a ride to the hospital?
I'm sure you'd like to see
how your mother's doing.
I'm happy to zip you
right over there
while the men here look around.
Jesus. Fine.
Please take me to the hospital
so I don't have to watch
you guys
fuck up the crime scene anymore.
I'm watching you, kid.
Good. Watch this.
We're going.
Tipton, you're in charge.
Where are they going?
Messy.
Messy types, for sure.
Can I get a coffee?
She gets coffee?
- I want flan.
- Get whatever you want.
Watch TV. Keep your phones on.
Do not wander.
Stay in the cafeteria,
or you come back here.
Okay, it's got to be
the Mexicans, right?
Sure. Mexicans.
Why not?
Does that mean
they're gonna come back --
you know, to finish the job?
Unless they have.
Would we bury her next to dad?
Can't. He's in a Jewish cemetery.
She did conversion classes
before Silas was born, remember?
She never actually
finished them, did she?
I don't know.
I know she took the classes.
Mom eats cheeseburgers
and shrimp.
We've had Christmas trees
every year.
Like most Jews.
Maybe she did convert.
- Botwin family?
- Yes, right here, yes.
- Is she alive?
- Yes. However, she is in a coma, and, uh--
I won't pull the plug.
I will.
I can do that for her.
She did it for Bubbie.
Oh, no, the coma is medically
induced to arrest swelling.
If we see the swelling has come
down, we'll bring her out
and better assess where we are
in terms of brain damage.
- How long does that take?
- We don't know yet.
You didn't use that
Michael Jackson drug, did you?
'Cause that didn't turn out
too well.
Propofol, when properly
administered and monitored,
is a safe drug.
I don't know.
I had some
for a colonoscopy once,
and, phew, crazy dreams --
monkeys fisting me.
I mean, that's kind of weird, right?
If you'd like to see her,
you can go in one at a time.
Did she say anything?
Before you put her in the coma,
was she talking again?
Yes, she was,
and that's a good sign.
What did she say?
Did she mention the name Andy?
No, she only said that I had
very pretty eyelashes.
She's right.
Your eyelashes are quite lush.
- What about the bullet?
- Oh, it's in there.
We're gonna
leave it in for now.
So, who'd like to see her?
- Both: I'll go first.
- You go first.
- That's right, yeah. Go ahead.
- This way.
Hello, Botwin family.
I'm Mrs. Taft,
hospital administration.
So sorry for your situation
and so sorry to be
clobbering you with this now,
but we are a private hospital
and blah, blah.
How will you be paying?
I have forms.
They need to be filled out.
We're not Canada.
We're not France.
We're not Taiwan, Costa Rica,
Iraq, Oman, Sri Lanka,
Argentina, New Zealand, Spain,
Ireland, Israel, Portugal,
Germany, Ukraine, China --
you get the point.
We're America.
We take all credit cards.
Who gets the clipboard?
Jill: Gee, which one of us
isn't broke?
I spy with my little eye
a tall wall street animal
with a corporate credit card.
Here you go.
And again, so sorry
for your situation,
and if there's anything
I can do -- Llewelyn?
Lleweln:
Right here.
Ah. I'm Mrs. Taft.
So sorry for your situation.
Shane!
Who did it?
Did you catch him?
What the fuck is wrong
with your children?
Shit.
I'm gonna kill her.
[ Monitor beeping ]
[ Respirator hissing ]
Hey.
Oh. Hey. Where the hell
have you been?
Where'd you get those?
Lee R. Crawford.
He has many friends.
They all hope he gets well soon.
Snack thief.
Yeah, well, my dinner
was rudely interrupted.
Yeah, I'm kind of hungry, too.
From all that running
in the woods?
[ Chuckles ]
There's tapenade
and fancy crackers.
Pull her curtain
in case someone comes in.
Mm.
Wow.
You went to town.
He's getting everything he needs
through a tube, anyways.
Did not see
this one coming, huh?
Come on. It was always
in the back of our minds.
What would you have done if you
would have caught up with him?
He had a fucking rifle.
I know how to disarm someone.
- Bullshit.
- I do. We learned it last week.
You learned what?
How to subdue and disarm
a suspect.
What the fuck
are you talking about?
I'm in the police academy.
[ Laughs ]
- That's funny.
- I'm serious.
I'm in the police academy.
I'm not in college.
That's where I go every day.
Shane...
We're... criminals.
It's the family business.
What the fuck are you doing?
I had to. It was this whole
thing with Ouellette.
The weird part is
I kind of like it,
and I think I want to be a cop.
That's bat-shit crazy.
I'm hoping they'll
let me use a croquet mallet
instead of a billy club.
Don't tell mom.
[ Chuckling ]
Jesus, what am I saying?
Who knows?
Maybe she's hearing everything.
[ Chuckles ] Hey, mom, any idea
who shot you in the head?
Any guesses?
Do you have any guesses?
Guillermo? Cesar?
Any other
random Mexican gangster?
Well, what about
that crazy lesbian, um...
What was her name?
- Zoya?
- What about Zoya? Crime of passion?
It's not her M.O.
She's an arsonist.
She would have gone
all Joan of Arc on mom.
How about
your girlfriend, Emma?
Nancy screwed her up
pretty bad.
No, I doubt it was Emma.
Warren Schiff?
I think he's in jail.
What about that chick
whose husband Nancy banged
in the trailer park?
It could be bikers, Armenians,
D.E.A. agents gone rogue.
Heylia might have finally
grown some balls.
There are
a lot of possibilities.
She's so great
at pissing people off.
Think he'll come back,
try and finish what he started?
I don't know.
Hope so.
Give me a chance
to nail the fucker.
And what if he comes back
to finish what he started?
What then?
She needs security.
There should be a guard
posted at her door.
We should have security detail
at our house.
Somebody shot her in the head.
We don't know that the shooter
was specifically targeting
your, uh, wife?
Uh, sister-in-law,
but that does not adequately
explain our relationship.
That's not the point.
The point is you're wrong.
She was specifically targeted
for many, many reasons
that you can figure out
for yourself.
She needs protection.
[ Inhales sharply ]
Sir, with all due respect --
Jill:
You think it's funny?!
You think the world needs to see
a picture of my sister like that?
You know, I heard that
they own that photo now.
They could use it
for advertising.
- They don't own it.
- Yes, they do!
You read the fine print
on that service agreement.
Take it down now.
Where's your phone?
It's at home.
Okay. Let's go.
Andy: No. No! You cannot go home.
It is not safe there.
Please! Someone's
trying to kill Nancy, not us.
- See? - Ma'am, kindly
let go of your child's hair.
Hair? This is a clump of dirt
hanging from her head.
- Ma'am.
- Will you please tell him
Nancy's shooting was not random
and she needs security?
- I need the car keys.
- Doug has them.
Shit.
Out.
[ Monitor beeping ]
What if she doesn't wake up?
Fuck you.
She's gonna wake up.
And if she's retarded?
[ Door opens ]
- Oh. Hey, Doug.
- Doug: Hey.
I brought food
from the vending machine.
It's all kind of crap, but...
These artichoke hearts?
You mind sitting with her
for a few minutes?
We want to check in with Andy,
see if there's a plan.
Sure. No problem.
Hey, Nance.
Rough day, huh?
[ Door closes ]
Mmm. I love these.
Look at all this good stuff.
You got stroopwafels, tapenade.
Ooh, olive oil crackers. Yum.
Mm-mm-mmm!
Feels kind of weird
eating off your body,
especially when
you're not naked.
[ Chuckles ] Kidding.
Tell you what --
I'm gonna move these
onto your table here.
There you go.
Oh, sorry. Got all kinds
of crumbs all over you.
Let me wipe those off for you.
You stay in pretty good shape,
don't you, Nance?
Trim. Fit.
Dana used to zumba,
but that doesn't seem like
that would be something
you'd like to do.
Also, Dana's boobs
fall down into her armpits
when she lies down like that,
but not you.
You look great.
Oh, another crumb here.
Let me pop that off there.
Whoops.
There you go.
Wow.
Boy, you are just a mess,
aren't you?
Tell you what --
I'm gonna loosen your gown
to just kind of shake it out
a little bit.
[ Sighing ] Wow.
I had this image in my head.
[ Door opens ]
There. That's better --
nice and tight, nice and tight.
[ Lid clinking ]
Is that --
have you been stealing
from our baskets?
What, this?
[ Door opens ]
Finally got the keys.
Ugh.
Apparently Doug's been banned
from the hospital.
Do you know what happened?
Never mind.
I don't want to know.
I'm gonna head back to the house
and beat my daughter in private.
Do you need anything?
Don't you want
to take a moment?
No, I don't.
Maybe when she's awake
to defend herself.
I'm mad at her.
For getting shot?
Sure.
Add that to the list.
She looks very peaceful.
Well, of course she does.
She doesn't have to deal
with all this shit. We do.
She gets to sleep.
What are you doing?
She looks dry.
Eye cream
is very important to her.
Oh, look at that.
You're doing something sweet.
I do sweet things all the time.
I'm just sort of graceless about it,
so people don't notice.
I'm mostly, you know,
a do-good person.
You're right.
You are.
You really are.
Thank you for noticing.
This is so surreal.
Is it?
For me it is.
Oh.
[ Breathes deeply ]
[ Moaning lightly ]
Wait. Wait.
What? We should stop.
We should stop, right?
This is too inappropriate.
It's wrong.
- No.
- What?
- No. We're working shit out.
- Yeah.
And we're full of emotion.
It's fine.
I just -- I have to take out
my weight.
Your what?
- I -- I had twins, Andy.
- Right.
- And I'm trying to rebuild
my pelvic floor. - Uh-huh.
I Kegel around it.
It's like doing reps
for your vagina.
Hot.
Can I see?
Mm.
Ow.
Wow.
Oh, it's heavy.
I've been doing it for a while.
I'm getting pretty buff.
Buff muff --
I like it.
Oh, you will.
[ Both moaning ]
[ Monitor beeping ]
Wow. Whatever you're doing,
it's working.
Thank you.
Do you feel bad?
I feel a little bad.
I feel great.
Thank you.
Now I'm gonna go home,
where you should go, too.
Take a break.
Take a shower.
Come back later.
She'll still be here.
Yeah.
I don't know if it's safe.
I'm not worried.
Come home
when you're ready. Mwah.
I'm gonna order pizza.
- Oh! Excuse me.
- Sorry.
[ Indistinct speaking over P.A. ]
[ Door closes ]
[ Up-tempo jazz music plays ]
Oh. Uh, that's a vagina weight.
Thanks.
[ Grunts ]
She'll want that back.
My friend's rebuilding
her pelvic floor.
Nurse!
Man on P.A.:
Pediatric oncology to 463.
You mind if I sit?
What?
No. Sit away.
- Dave.
- Andy.
Andy.
You're not hungry?
It's hospital cafeteria food.
That soupçon of depression
and grief you get in every bite?
Can't quite take it on
right now.
They do a nice tapioca.
- You can barely taste the sadness.
- Come on.
Tapioca is inherently sad --
delicious, I grant you,
but a sad, sad food.
Mm.
Do you want to talk?
About what?
Whatever you want.
Okay. Is this how people speak
to each other in hospitals,
or are you cruising me?
Which, if you are, I got to say
ordering tuna was a bad call,
but kudos to you for creativity
in terms of locale,
and I got to pass.
No, it's a hospital thing.
I like women.
Mm. Me, too.
Who are you here for?
My dead brother's wife.
She might be dying right now,
and so I fucked her sister
up against the wall of her room.
- Wow.
- Oh, you don't even know.
Her sister's been working out
with these vagina weights.
Wow.
We fooled around a while ago.
It was fine and all,
but, man, now it's like
dick massage up there.
Like, there's the in and out,
but there's also
this squeezing thing happening
that's simply delightful.
And I know it's all
in the heat of the moment,
in the face of a crisis --
I can't think of another cliché
right now --
but what if she dies?
What do we all do then?
And how come I didn't keep her safe?
And why doesn't
she love me back?
And why can't I move on
with my life, my own life,
not the one where I'm
this satellite orbiting her sun
and raising her sons?
I have nothing,
and my life is half over --
more than half, probably,
'cause I have
high genetic risk factors
for heart disease
and colon cancer.
And even if she does live, she's
been shot in the fucking head.
Who's she gonna be?
And if I've been defining myself by her
all this time, who am I gonna be?
And you don't care.
Eat your tuna,
which, I got to say,
was probably the right choice,
'cause this lasagna
is disgusting.
How do you ruin lasagna? I'm gonna...
[ Hands bang, plates rattle ]
quit talking now,
drink my Fanta.
I like Fanta. It reminds me
of spring breaks.
What?
You're sure you're done?
Ah, come on. I still got
most of my sandwich left.
I'm sure you got stuff to do.
I mean, who are you here for?
- Here for?
- At the hospital. Who are you visiting?
I'm not visiting.
Chaplain.
Well, actually, I'm a rabbi,
but I do the chaplaincy
part time.
You know, it brings in
a little extra cash,
and it expands my world view.
Have you ever sat with
a grieving Southern baptist?
Boy, they know how to pray.
Perfect.
That's perfect.
I just asked a rabbi
if he was cruising me.
It might have made sense
if I was a priest, right?
And the sister fucking.
Fucking. What is this fucking
that you speak of?
I-I've never heard of it.
Stop.
It's my job.
I listen.
I'm not judging.
No?
Well, maybe a little bit,
but I keep it to myself.
Although
the vaginal-weight thing --
that was very intriguing.
Now, how is a Jew
the chaplain in Old Sandwich?
We all trade off
at the local hospitals --
the ministers, the rabbis,
the priests.
I personally have a little
congregation in Greenwich --
temple mishkon shalom,
house of peace.
Although with the fighting
that goes on with the board --
I don't know
if I believe in God.
Well, you're not alone in that.
I feel very alone.
Which is why a lot of people
turn to God.
It's the whole concept.
It makes the world
a little less lonely,
a little less scary.
I don't know about less scary.
God comes with a lot of scary.
[ Chuckles ]
And I hear you --
especially
the old testament God.
He's, uh -- whew!
He's a gangster.
Jill said that Nancy would live
because there is no God.
- And if there is a God, she dies?
- Oh, absolutely.
With all the shit
that she's pulled? Yeah.
You and Jill
could both be wrong.
Are we? Then tell me.
You're the rabbi.
I have no idea.
Great.
Andy, you want an easy answer?
Go Jesus. Go Allah.
Go -- go -- go atheist.
I'm a Jew.
My obligation is to wrestle.
It's to engage.
It's not just to simply,
blindly believe.
I mean, that's how I see it.
Well, maybe I'll decide
when she wakes up.
Yeah.
And maybe you'll never decide.
I'm gonna say a prayer
for your Nancy just in case,
if that's okay with you.
Yeah.
Knock yourself out.
[ Door opens ]
[ Monitor beeping ]
[ Door closes ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Soft music playing ]
[ Breathes deeply ]
[ Beeping continues ]
I thought I'd feel better.
But I don't.
[ Breathing deeply ]
[ Both gasp ]
Oh! Oh!
- Ugh! God damn it!
- Sorry. Sorry.
Damn it!
Damn you fucking people!
I've had it!
I've just had it!
He's sorry.
Look at this mess.
[ Rapid beeping ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
Yeah, well... Karma.
Blue team to I.C.U., please.
Blue team, I.C.U
♪ Dear God,
hope you got the letter and ♪
♪ I pray you can make it better
down here ♪
Sync by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com