hey kid!
what are you doing here?
who are you?
jános Valuska.
what do you want here?
I'm...
I'm on an errand, I'm the...
Mr Eszter told me to...
- Mr Eszter...
- Aha.
...who on Auntie Tünde's request...
- Drink this.
- just that...
Let's hear it.
he was requested to go
and Auntie Tünde when she arrives...
Your attention please!
Our show is over for today.
For technical reasons
the appearance of the Prince
has been cancelled.
All the best then until our ticket
office opens tomorrow morning.
I thank you for your attention,
and commend our company again to you.
So, please go home.
Go!
Filthy gang! No class!
Swine!
Dirty swine! Rabble!
Rogues!
Good evening Auntie Tünde.
Uncle Gyuri sent me
to tell Auntie Tünde
that all that you asked
has been arranged,
and the organising of the whole
thing is under way,
so I'm to bring your case here
this evening, right away.
That doesn't concern us now, jános.
Are they ripping the square apart?
Or setting it on fire?
The whale, the great sensation
of the century has arrived,
a gigantic, wonderful whale, and...
wait a moment.
The whole squad advances! Attack!
Bastards!
Show no mercy!
Shoot right into them.
I've called for the tanks.
Don't!
Don't.
- what are you trying to do?
- Lie down and go to sleep.
Stop it! Get away from me!
No time for sleeping, resting!
- Out of the question!
- That's enough! Go and lie down!
Nowwait!
just wait!
Pull yourself together,
act like a man!
Stay!
Stay. Don't go!
Tünde!
I have something important
I want you to do.
Go to the police chief's home
and put his children to bed.
Tell them he's going to be late,
then go to the main square,
take a look around,
observe how many there are,
who is talking to who and what about,
then come back here
and tell us everything.
Delighted to oblige, Auntie Tünde.
I'll go and take a look around.
I'll gladly observe
and tell you everything,
who is talking to who, then.
I've just come from there,
I'd like to find out
just what this strange secret is.
- Off you go.
- Goodbye.
Now my little witch,
do you knowwho wrote this piece?
Do you like it?
just dance!
Off to bed with you!
- I don't want to go to bed!
- Off to bed!
I'm not going to bed!
- Go and get into bed!
- No!
That was just a pat.
I didn't really hit you.
I'll be hard on you.
Go to bed both of you!
I don't want to.
I'll be hard on you.
Good evening Uncle Lajos.
how's it going...
what are you doing here jános?
Auntie Tünde sent me.
She said to go to the market square,
and take a look around
to see what was happening
and tell her about everything, who's
doing what, who's talking to who.
Don't go there jános,
this is not for us...
They'll have to get the army in.
There's nothing we can do now.
I'll watch out.
Be careful, jános.
Goodbye, Uncle Lajos.
Good evening.
Sorry.
The whale...
Can't I see the whale now?
Or in the morning?
Fuck off out of here.
See how much trouble you've caused!
Even though you haven't been able
to harm anyone for a long time.
...and not from the whole,
as the Director imagines.
I don't imagine anything.
But I know
that if he doesn't calm them,
but fires them up,
then the whole thing is going
to start all over again!
And tell him this too,
that I take his impudence badly.
- Translate that!
- Why?!
So that it'll get through
that infantile skull of his
that he cannot go out, that you
aren't going to take him out,
you're not going to pick him up
and translate for him.
But he sticks to me!
I won't stand for his stirring up
the rabble with his lies.
T ell him that we have finished now
once and for all.
he never wished to go anywhere.
The Director takes him.
I engaged him to show himself,
and not to stir and incite.
I won't let him out
and let him speak. Translate that.
No point.
No one can stop him
whatever they do.
I won't stand for his tearing
the town apart with these bandits.
I am not willing to risk
the good name of the company.
The last time
was positively the last.
No way!
Ridiculous!
he doesn't recognise any superior
authority. Nothing of that kind.
In the eyes of his followers
out there, he is the Prince.
No ordinary force can hold him,
he has magnetic power!
his magnetic power is a
disfigurement! he is an aberration!
A born freak who knows nothing
about anything!
The title of Prince I bestowed on him
for commercial reasons.
Tell him that I invented him.
his followers are waiting outside!
They are losing patience.
To them he is the Prince!
- Then he is fired!
- Fine!
From now, he seeks independence.
he's taking me with him.
- You!
- Me.
I shall do what he wants,
because he means money.
You are poor.
The Prince means money for you.
will you stop poncing about!
why don't we try
to arrange something?
Tell him...
that I'll let him out,
on one condition.
That he doesn't open his mouth,
not even a single word,
and he is to be as silent
as the grave.
Tell him that.
The Director cannot lay down
any rules!
The Director gets the money,
the Prince gets his followers.
There's no point in arguing!
The Prince alone sees the whole.
And the whole is nothing.
Completely in ruins.
what they build
and what they will build,
what they do and what they will do,
is delusion and lies.
Under construction,
everything is only half complete.
In ruins, all is complete.
what they think is ridiculous.
They think because they are afraid.
And he who is afraid knows nothing.
The Director doesn't understand
that his followers are not afraid
and do understand him.
his followers are going
to make ruins of everything!
Confused drivel!
Tell that to the rabble
and not to me.
I won't listen to this any more.
I'll wash my hands of him,
I won't take responsibility
for what he does.
You gentlemen
from this moment on are free.
You can do what you want.
If they destroy the towns,
after a while, there will be
nowhere left for him to go.
Does he know that?
His followers do, tell him.
There is disillusion in everything.
They don't understand why.
But the Prince knows full well
that it is because the whole
is nothing. They are finished.
We crush them with our fury!
We punish them!
We will be pitiless!
The day has come!
There will be nothing left!
Fury overcomes all!
Their silver and gold...
cannot protect them!
We'll take possession
of their houses!
Terror is here! Massacre!
Show no mercy! Slaughter!
Arson. Slaughter!
When the clamour died down,
the Prince said this:
"What they build
"and what they will build,
"what they do
"and what they will do,
"is delusion and lies.
"What they think
"and what they will think,
"is ridiculous.
"They think because they are afraid.
"And he who is afraid,
knows nothing. "
He says he likes it
when things fall apart.
"There is construction
in all ruins... "
"A single emotion for destruction,
implacable, deadly.
"we didn't find the real object
of our abhorrence and despair,
"so we rushed at everything we came
across with wilder and wilder fury.
"we destroyed the shops,
threw out and trampled everything
"that was movable
and what we couldn't move
"we broke up with slats
of shutters and iron bars.
"we turned over cars in the streets,
"tore off the miserable sign-boards,
"destroyed the telephone centre
"because we saw the lights inside,
"and we had the two post office girls
"and we left only
"when they had fainted
and like two used rags,
"lifeless,
hands clasped between knees,
"hunched over,
they slipped off the bloody table..."
- hello there.
- hello...
- Doing OK?
- Fine.
just a moment...
Allow me to introduce
Mrs Eszter.
Privilege, ma'am.
Ma'am.
Is this where
you were thinking of?
here.
And if here?
Possible, but not really.
And...
what about here?
here!
Then will you join us, ma'am?
In the car?
Yes. I'm coming.
Follow us.
FANTASTlC:.
ThE wORLD'S LARGEST GlANT whALE!
AND OThER wONDERS OF NATURE!
GUEST STAR: ThE PRlNCE
Uncle Lajos...
- how's jános?
- Good morning.
You didn't see my Lajos?
There's been no sign of him
since last night.
I saw him in the square
last night.
I'm sure he got mixed up
somehow in that ruction.
he always has to be
where he shouldn't.
he'll never have any sense. he's
always poking his nose in everywhere.
So are you, jános.
So are you.
They're looking for you as well.
They came here
and I saw your name on the list.
You'll hang for it in the end, jános.
- I haven't done anything.
- That means nothing to them.
They recognise neither man nor god.
Get away from the town
as soon as you can.
head for the rail tracks.
They're not being guarded.
Try and hide somewhere,
and we'll see what happens.
Got that?
Yes, Aunt harrer.
If you see my Lajos,
tell him to come immediately.
It's horrible here and
he's wandering about out there.
And I've so much to do here.
Goodbye Aunt harrer.
Take care of yourself.
LAjOS hARRER jr.
BOOT AND ShOEMAKER
I've made a place for you.
You'll see it if you come out.
I'm living in the summer kitchen.
Because that woman...
and the police chief have taken it
on themselves to move in
and have taken the whole place over.
But we'll get by all right
with the summer kitchen outside.
The sofa with the green blanket
will be yours.
In the top part of the cupboard
I'll make some space for you.
The windows will have to be done.
There are draughts
and it's cold.
I'm sleeping there
for the second day now.
And, thank God, out there
you can't hear a thing.
Absolute silence.
I've retuned the piano.
Now, once again,
it's like any other.
Once again,
you can play anything on it.
And if we run short of money
it's much easier this way.
I took my grey overcoat
over to Árgyelán.
he promised he'd tailor it for you.
whenever you come out
it will be ready.
Nothing counts.
Nothing counts at all.