WHEN A WOMAN
ASCENDS THE STAIRS
Produced and Written by
RYUZO KIKUSHIMA
Cinematography by MASAO TAMAI
Production Design by SATOSHI CHUKO
Music by TOSHIRO MAYUZUMI
Edited by EIJI OOI
Costumes by HIDEKO TAKAMINE
Starring
HIDEKO TAKAMINE
MASAYUKI MORI, REIKO DAN
TATSUYA NAKADAI
DAISUKE KATO, GANJIRO NAKAMURA
EITARO OZAWA, KEIKO AWAJI
KYU SAZANKA, JUN TATARA
YU FUJIKI, MASAO ODA
KEN MITSUDA, CHIKAKO HOSOKAWA
SADAKO SAWAMURA
NORIKO SENGOKU, KIN SUGAI
Directed by
MIKIO NARUSE
An afternoon in late autumn.
Bars in the daytime
are like women without makeup.
THE LILAC BAR
Not like that!
You got married in a church,
so kiss like foreigners do.
That's right!
Hurry up.
Not like that.
Try again.
Stop teasing.
He's sweating.
I'm surprised Miyuki got married first.
She loved working here.
Marriage is what
every woman wants.
Not me.
I'm going to save some money
and open my own place.
Shall we cut the cake?
Shouldn't we wait for Mama?
Mama?
We're waiting for you.
What?
Well, please hurry.
The owner's chewing out
Mama and Mr. Komatsu.
Mr. Komatsu?
I wonder why.
It's obvious.
"You're not making
enough money!"
I guess it isn't easy
being a mama.
Sales were down last month
and the month before.
Why?
Mama's doing her best.
Isn't it because
Mr. Minobe stopped coming in?
Sorry my phone call
took so long.
Mama, do you know
where Mr. Minobe goes these days?
Yuri's bar.
The same Yuri
who worked for you.
Minobe has contacts
at big companies.
If you call him,
he'll come by.
I wonder.
Your job
is to make money for me.
If sales are down again this month,
I'll replace you.
Understand?
Don't be so prim.
Yuri goes all out.
He's trying to humiliate me!
Telling me to do such a thing!
But business has plummeted.
Even so, I won't call him.
It's not just Mr. Minobe.
I've never begged
anyone to come in.
It's not pride.
I hate doing that.
I hate liquor,
yet I drink my fill every night.
Isn't that "going all out"?
Get your own place.
Where would I find a million yen?
Mama, don't worry.
Any of the 700 bars
in the Ginza would hire you.
What's that?
I hate that sound.
I've got a bill to collect on.
Regards to Miyuki.
- Mama!
- What happened?
Suicide.
The Bluebird hostess.
The fortune-teller was right.
Fortune-teller?
I took her to a fortune-teller
who predicted misfortune,
and it hit her hard.
Something awful's happened!
I heard.
I'm sorry I'm late.
The Bluebird was
heavily mortgaged.
- I heard it was a love triangle.
- Not debt?
Her patron and her lover
had a fight.
How old was she?
Forty-three,
but she looked younger.
- Aging's hard on a woman.
- I'd better save up for the old folks' home.
Enough of that talk.
Sing, somebody!
We've got a train to catch.
Thanks for everything.
I'll go see them off.
He could at least buy
second-class tickets.
Try to think more positively.
It won't be easy!
Be grateful you got
a chance to marry.
Compared to handling drunks,
his mother will be easy.
Mr. Matsui,
take good care of her.
We're not far.
Please come visit.
Thank you.
As the office girls
are leaving work,
our work is just beginning.
This is nice.
Or is it too plain?
No, but it's a bit matronly.
Really? I'd still like it.
You sure?
Twin matches - good luck!
Stop acting
like a cheap cabaret girl.
It's vulgar.
You sure know how to eat.
You just ruined the taste.
- Other shops sell these for less.
- Ours are better.
I'll take these.
How about a discount?
You'll ruin me!
How much is this?
Don't say that.
Just come by.
We haven't seen you
in so long.
I'm Ionely. I really am.
Welcome!
Don't bother.
He's from the savings plan.
Sorry I'm late.
So it's 100 yen from Sachiko,
and 200 from Kiyomi.
It's all here, pops.
Night fell...
I hated climbing those stairs
more than anything.
But once I was up,
I would take each day as it came.
Mr. Minobe, welcome.
You're quite a stranger.
You called, so here I am.
You'd completely disappeared.
Pardon me a moment.
Mr. Minobe's here.
Did you call him?
I said it was the Lilac Bar calling,
not you.
Same thing.
He's my customer.
Don't meddle.
It's business.
Just don't.
Do you like this tiepin?
Very nice.
You're not even looking.
I bought it for you.
For me?
Put it on.
- No, give it to a customer.
- But -
Good evening.
They're cracking down.
It's harder to get the goods.
- You mean Tetsu got caught?
- Yeah.
Next time I'll be the one
sent to the slammer.
You've got it good here,
surrounded by girls,
and with a regular paycheck.
That girl's crazy about you.
- I'm not interested in the girls here.
- Really?
You can't succeed as a manager here
if you fiddle with the goods.
Maybe, but what a waste!
Welcome.
You've got new girls,
but this place is dead!
That's because it's still early.
Right, Mama?
He's hinting
it's because he's been away.
That's right.
So come by every night.
- This place is so routine.
How rude!
You can't take him seriously.
He'll always act mean
and then turn on the charm.
- Is that true?
- That's my... routine.
But seriously,
I've run a lot of companies.
Any place headed downhill
is always depressing like this.
I see.
Is Yuri's place lively?
You bet.
Not like here.
Want to see for yourself?
Please.
I could learn a lot.
Welcome!
Is this seat okay?
Mari.
Mr. Inagaki came by last night.
Yuri worked for me
until last summer.
She has a gift
for handling men.
Forgive me
for neglecting you.
Care for a drink?
My stomach's been bothering me.
- Swimming in dough, eh?
- Sure. Maybe I'll lend it out.
Can you teach me
to calculate interest?
Don't imply
that's my line of work.
- It's great you're so busy.
- Thanks.
Actually, I barely scrape by.
Liar.
Didn't you buy a new car?
A used one that barely runs.
It uses so much gas
it drives me crazy.
- Still, you're succeeding.
- See, she -
Be quiet and drink.
Mama and I have a lot to talk about.
Mama, that kimono is stunning.
Those stripes really suit you.
I gasped when I saw you come in.
Your dress is lovely too.
Enough. I'm not paying
to listen to this chatter.
Well, hello there!
Hello.
I used to see him
at your place.
A brewery executive.
He's very nice.
Mr. Minobe.
Sorry I've been out of touch.
Busy as usual?
Only at night.
Business is dead.
Always the kidder.
Excuse me.
He's president
of an appliance firm.
I taught him how to use
a radio during the war.
Now his company's thriving.
Shall I introduce you?
Yes, please.
No problem.
I'm leaving for Izu tonight
to go golfing. Come along.
I can't golf.
What would be the point?
I'll play the golf, okay?
It's too sudden.
Your place just phoned.
A guest...
Thank you.
I'll be going.
I'll be here. Phone me.
Leaving already?
I'll drive you back.
Don't bother.
Walking's faster.
Please come again.
Take care.
Mama, scouting out the enemy?
I know where you're going.
Please, go ahead.
It's my first time here.
Yuri won't stop calling.
I'll drop by later.
Really?
I'll be waiting.
What were you and Mama
talking about?
Gimme a refill.
What to do?
The time to decide was looming.
I went to work at a new bar.
Only a few leaves were left
on the sycamores.
How nice to see you!
When did you arrive from Osaka?
Last night. An emergency
shareholders meeting.
I see. This way, please.
- I had a hard time finding the place.
- Forgive me.
I lost your map card.
Welcome.
He drinks Black & White with water.
Don't forget.
- Nice place.
- Thank you.
Making more than before?
It's always money with you.
That's the most important thing.
Foreigners ask for the price list
before they even drink a glass of juice.
And they pay up front.
Did Mama give Minobe
the brush-off?
Where'd you hear that?
Besides, how would we know?
You're well trained.
Is my face red?
I may look sturdy,
but I can't drink at all.
Then why come to a bar?
I can't stand sitting at home
once the lights go on.
But aren't you married?
Not even close.
Should I call Mama?
That's okay.
I'm not her only customer.
You're so nice!
I'd like to marry a man like you.
I'm honored.
It's true.
Handsome men are conceited.
May I have a drink?
Sorry to neglect you.
Yukiko, could you go to the bar?
Have a drink on me.
Thanks.
Mama doesn't have a patron?
No, she's too virtuous.
She'll cave in eventually.
A woman's a woman.
Want to bet?
- On what?
- On who'll get her.
All her regular guests are here.
Let's see.
That old man from Osaka
has the most money...
but she likes the banker best.
Odds are on him.
What about the fat fellow?
Not even in the running.
Did you put on a little weight?
Hardly, with all my debts.
That can't be.
Nothing's harder than
running a 30-man factory.
Is that so?
You're thinner.
Am I?
It's stressful changing bars.
- But even prettier.
- Thank you.
- You like tempura?
- I love it.
I'll treat you tomorrow.
Can't.
I have to see a customer off
at the airport.
Some other time then.
I'm sorry.
Welcome!
Did Mr. Goda arrive?
Mr. Fujisaki's a regular too.
Yes.
That guest told me
to hold this for him.
There's 500,000 yen inside!
Don't fall for that.
It's true!
Silly.
He's just trying to get you
to go out with him.
It's just for show?
Leave it with Komatsu.
How about dinner tomorrow?
- What time?
- Any time.
I'll call you.
Leaving so soon?
Stay a bit.
I have to meet someone.
Keep the drinks flowing
for my men there.
How about dinner tomorrow?
Okay. I'll call you tomorrow.
Take care.
Between 11:30 and midnight,
the Ginza's 16,000 hostesses
head home in droves.
The best go by cab...
the second-rate take the train...
and the worst go off
with their customers.
Junko.
Tomoko, you'll miss the last train.
Goodness! Bye now.
You forgot this.
Silly me! It's for my son's
school trip tomorrow.
Good-bye.
- Good night.
- Good-bye.
Welcome.
- Welcome.
- Thank you.
The sign's still on outside.
I'm sorry.
She's drunk again.
I'll take her to my apartment.
Keiko,
isn't that kimono a bit plain?
Is it?
Wear something flashier.
The Carton Bar.
A call for you.
What is it?
No, we can't provide
geisha this late.
Give them some sushi,
then kick them out.
I'm busy, so I'll be brief.
I paid the 170,000 yen
your guests owed at the Lilac
so you'd be free
to work for me here.
It's just a formality, but please
put your seal on this receipt.
I'll collect the money soon
and pay you back.
I'll be going.
No need to see me out.
Did the owner leave?
I hate to ask, but could you
collect on bills again tomorrow?
She'll probably
want interest too.
I'll get a cab.
Will you bring Junko?
Back home...
I felt tired
and a little drunk.
My rent is 30,000 yen,
a lot for one person.
But for us Ginza hostesses,
an apartment's
a fashionable accessory...
just like expensive clothes
and perfumes.
Junko!
Oh, it's you.
Mama wanted to come,
but relatives
arrived from Nagoya.
She asked me
to extend her apologies.
I see.
We'd appreciate
payment soon, sir.
I've overspent this month.
I'd prefer to pay
these two bills next month.
I understand.
But they're bills
from the old bar, so...
Mama's having a hard time too.
Yes, her aunt and uncle
just came from Nagoya.
She asked me to apologize.
Me?
I'm watching her place.
But please do visit
our bar again.
Okay?
Good-bye.
The man from Osaka was furious.
Was he?
It's still easier
than saying no to his face.
You're right.
I just learned a new trick.
Mama...
who's your favorite customer?
I don't know.
I do.
Mr. Fujisaki?
I don't dislike him.
But in our business
we have to treat
every man like a lover.
You can't love just one man.
Too bad.
I could love
just one rich man.
That 500,000 yen from last night -
I can still see it.
Let's not talk shop.
Here.
Thank you.
Your omelettes are as good
as a restaurant's.
My late husband loved omelettes.
I hate to cook.
- Even rice?
- I use an electric cooker.
I thought you'd say that.
You still have to know
how to use it.
You'll have a hard time
when you get married.
I had it hard at first.
At first?
Oh, when you got married?
I've always wanted to ask:
What was your husband like?
Handsome?
There's a photograph
in the family shrine.
May I?
Isn't he good-Iooking?
He's kind of chubby.
I'm disappointed.
He wasn't really handsome,
but he was so kind.
Maybe because he was
ten years older.
I was just out of high school.
I caused him such grief
with my selfishness.
He died so soon.
I wish I'd been nicer.
But he looked so healthy.
Was it illness?
No, he got hit by a truck.
Poor man.
It's hard to forget someone
you lose so unexpectedly.
Mama...
is it true you put
a love letter in his urn?
Who told you that?
Mr. Komatsu said you told him
once when you were drunk.
It's a beautiful,
romantic thing to do.
When I heard that,
I respected you so much.
Silly girl. It's not true.
That's Komatsu for you.
It was in a novel I read.
A novel?
What a letdown!
But my husband
was such a good person.
Is that why nobody else
can win your heart?
It's not that.
It just seems so dirty.
It's not my way.
If a woman does such things,
her charm disappears.
Aren't you Ionely sometimes?
Sure.
But I have a brandy
and go to sleep.
That kind of fever soon passes.
You really have some self-control!
I clench my teeth
so hard they hurt.
Honest?
You're so gullible!
Oh, you!
A woman shouldn't be loose.
That's one rule I've followed.
I'm not a prude,
but if I let go once,
it'd be too hard to stop.
Maybe I'm just a coward.
Don't sit there thinking.
Your food's getting cold.
Hello?
Mother?
Just a second.
Junko, please get the door.
What is it?
30,000 yen?
This is too sudden.
The kimono-maker's bill
is due today.
Wait a couple days.
I'll send it with your monthly allowance.
Listen, did you make
your pickled cabbage?
Bring some when you come.
Don't catch cold.
Good morning.
How'd it go?
Let me eat first.
I'm starving.
Fujisaki finally paid,
but Mr. Goda won't pay
unless you ask him personally.
He flashed the money
but wouldn't hand it over.
I'll go see him tomorrow.
The usual inn at Tsukiji?
Won't he try to seduce you?
They try all the time,
but it can only work if I let them.
Famous last words.
You've heard of
Nobuko at Club 8?
She wouldn't even give in
to a cabinet member.
But then she fell in love
with some down-and-out guitarist.
Now she's a maid
in a love hotel.
I started as a busboy
in the Ginza ten years ago.
I've seen a lot like her.
What's your point?
Just sharing my experience.
Good marmalade.
Thanks for coming.
Yesterday I had to take
five kimonos over to Yuri's place.
Five?
Her business must be booming.
Care to buy any yourself?
I just finished paying
for my last one.
Pay whenever you can.
I trust you.
Men are so strange.
You always rush off afterwards.
It's bad manners,
especially the first time.
Can't you stay another hour?
Don't get lipstick on me.
You're like a politician.
You don't keep your word.
"The girls in my care
are precious goods
not to be touched."
That only applies
to women like Mama.
Oh, that's nice!
Fooling around with me
while going on about her.
There aren't many
like her in the Ginza.
Oh, I see.
What?
You did to me
what you couldn't do to her.
Nonsense.
Hurry and get ready.
Hand it over.
- What?
- The money.
You said you liked me.
I'm a pro.
I charge the men I like too.
It pays better than a normal job,
but I have to spend
so much on myself.
It's a vicious circle.
It makes no sense.
The owner takes it all anyway.
How old are you?
Don't ask. Old enough.
Thirty?
That's the turning point
in a woman's life.
The time to decide
whether to marry
or open your own bar.
Tell me, would you like
your own place?
You're joking.
I'll consider it,
if that's what you want.
I couldn't.
Yes, you could.
You could make it work.
How much would it take?
Give me a figure.
Even tiny bars in the Ginza
cost over a million.
Then it's no problem.
Some money I lent out
came back before it was due.
An honest fellow.
See? In cash.
Just a little windfall.
My wife will grab it
if I take it home.
And the banks only pay 6%.
If you're serious
about setting up shop, take it.
You'd lend it to me?
Well...
maybe even give it to you.
I come to Tokyo
several times a month.
It's a waste staying all alone
in a big room like this.
Maybe we could...
reach an understanding.
I don't want to force you
into anything.
Think it over.
Ask yourself if you want
to spend your life working for others.
Mama...
come closer.
Will you dine now?
No, thank you.
I'm just leaving.
I should be going.
I'll have an answer
next time I see you.
Hello?
Komatsu?
I'd like your advice.
It's not a bad proposition.
You approve?
That's irrelevant.
So you'll finally get
a place of your own.
You were a cashier
when I recruited you five years ago.
Time flies.
Now it's either marriage
or my own bar.
No respectable man
would marry me now.
I've made up my mind.
So you're giving in
to the old man
after holding out for five years.
What's so funny?
If I was going
to do it that way,
there are better men
than Mr. Goda.
I'll solicit subscriptions.
If ten men put up 100,000 yen each,
that would make a million.
I'll deduct their drinks
from what I owe them.
Now I approve!
Being a kept woman is stupid.
I'll chip in too.
You will? Thanks.
But I don't want to burden you.
Mr. Sonoda, Mr. Ito,
and Mr. Matsubara -
they're good
for 200,000 yen each.
That's 600,000.
The rest are small spenders.
But Fujisaki's a banker.
He could put up 200,000.
No, not him.
Why not?
No special reason.
You feel awkward asking him?
Something like that.
I know a good bar for sale.
- Where?
- Shall I show you?
Please.
THE CONGA BAR
The down payment is cheap.
Just one drawback:
You share the restroom
with the sushi place downstairs.
No pressure, but I've got
two other interested parties.
- We'll talk it over.
- I'll be eating downstairs.
Well?
It needs some fixing up,
but it's a good place to start.
I'll be your bartender.
- You're too expensive.
- Not at first.
But sharing the restroom
with a cheap sushi place -
would my customers come?
They'll come to see you.
Let's do a test run.
Order something.
A dry martini?
Coming right up.
Komatsu, your secret's out.
The lipstick on your shirt.
Lipstick?
Can't avoid an occasional smudge
with so many women around.
So what do you say?
Well...
We can't quite decide.
I've got nicer places.
What a surprise.
Long time no see.
I'd like to talk to you.
How about some tea?
Are you still angry at me?
Angry at you?
About what?
I want to apologize
for taking your customers.
I'm sorry.
It was the only way
to keep my place going.
Don't worry about it.
Minobe still comes?
Yes.
Maybe it's this light,
but you look thinner.
Just between us, I'm deep in debt.
It's taking its toll.
You must be joking.
I heard you bought
five kimonos for Christmas.
I don't have them anymore.
I bought them on credit,
then pawned them for cash. Clever, huh?
Isn't that risky?
I sold my car
and put away my golf clubs.
I borrowed so much to get started
that now I'm in a pinch.
Don't laugh.
What'll you do?
I've decided to die.
Isn't that a great idea?
They say sleeping pills
work quite well.
Yuri!
Just kidding.
It'll be a staged suicide.
I won't actually die.
I'll just fake it
to hold off creditors.
Shocked?
Not shocked. Impressed.
I thought,
with your place doing so well,
your view of the world
might be a little too rosy.
But you've tasted struggle too.
I respect that.
You're embarrassing me.
What a strange conversation.
Whatever happens,
don't give up.
By the way,
I'm going to open my own bar.
Really? That's wonderful!
Let's drink to that.
Women working in the Ginza
fought desperately for survival.
It was a battle
I couldn't afford to lose.
On my days off, I took my pledge book
from one company to the next.
Some men promised
more than I expected,
some less.
But I didn't want to discuss money
with the man I really cared about.
A pledge book?
Well, well.
Your money will be repaid
little by little
in the form of your bar tab.
So we have to come drink
to get repaid? Smart idea.
I'm not trying to coerce anyone.
Joking aside,
I'd like to help,
especially since it's you,
but a bank can't lend 200,000
without collateral.
However, I can put up
30,000 out of my own pocket.
I may be branch manager,
but it's other people's money.
May I speak to you, sir?
Excuse me.
I shouldn't have come.
Collecting on bills?
Depressed?
I don't feel down.
My client didn't pay,
but at least I ran into you.
How about some tea?
What a nice fragrance.
What's your perfume?
Black Narcissus.
Must cost a lot.
It's stronger here
than at the bar.
Really?
So you're opening
your own place?
Has everyone contributed?
Nothing but promises so far.
I'm counting on you too.
You're putting me in a spot.
Why?
Well...
No, I'd better not.
Come on. Tell me.
All right.
A bar is no place for you.
I'd be happier
seeing you marry a good man.
You're the first to say that.
Everyone else encouraged me.
It's not the money.
But I always feel sorry
seeing you with drunks.
I don't know how you got
into this line of work,
but you belong
in a nice home.
Don't be offended.
It's just my opinion.
Put me down for 100,000 yen.
Christmas time again.
How depressing.
I have to buy new clothes,
sell tickets.
Well, well.
Long time no see.
Kiyomi! How are you?
I'm fine,
but the Lilac is going under.
Did you hear?
Yuri did a terrible thing.
I know.
You do?
She committed suicide!
No, she was just faking.
Can she fake being dead?
Dead?
Yes. I just got back
from paying my respects.
She put sleeping pills
in brandy.
Not too many,
but with that much alcohol...
I'm sorry she was
so much trouble to you.
Not at all.
I just came
to offer my condolences.
I only sold her
a slip and some panties.
You can pay me in due course.
I'll discuss it
with my relatives.
If I'm not paid soon,
I'll be fired.
We'll do what we can.
Please.
I'm very sorry.
I should have stopped her.
No, it was just her bad luck.
One way or another,
it would have come to this.
Forgive me for saying so,
but I told her from the start
not to work as a hostess.
Besides, she was too young
to own her own place.
Even a man who works his whole life
can't be sure of success.
How much harder
for a woman on her own.
Stretch yourself too far
and you're bound to fail.
Excuse me.
I've come on behalf
of Mr. Minobe.
I'm Yuri's mother.
I apologize for all the trouble
she caused you.
I'm deeply sorry for your loss.
It's very difficult
to have to say this,
but selling the bar only covers
part of the 1.5 million
that Yuri owed Mr. Minobe.
He requests that you pay
the remaining 300,000 yen.
I have the papers with me.
We need your seal.
Must I do it today?
Her funeral's not even over yet!
I'm merely
Mr. Minobe's employee.
Why do you think she died?
You kept pressing her for money.
She thought a suicide attempt
could hold you off.
But instead...
she really died!
What do you need
200,000 yen for?
Never mind that.
Can you get it?
Ask the owner.
I can make a lot on the deal.
It's a manager's duty to help.
If you get the money,
we can go
to the hot springs together.
Forget it.
You're in love with Mama,
aren't you?
I don't normally tell
strangers' fortunes,
but since you know
the lingerie shop owner...
I see the word sake
in the back of your mind.
Is there some connection
with your work?
Yes. I work in a bar.
That explains it.
What do you want to know?
It's about starting
a bar of my own.
Pick a card.
Not for a couple of years.
You'd be rowing a boat
against the current.
Time solves everything.
Wait patiently.
You'll soon receive
a marriage proposal.
A proposal?
I came to work
and forgot about everything.
Welcome.
Don't you have
the wrong place?
You're terrible, hiding out here
and not even calling me.
This is Mr. Horiuchi.
He's with Asahi Steel.
- Pleased to meet you.
- My pleasure.
Even more beautiful
than I was told.
He's a big shot in steel.
I thought you two should meet.
I'm indebted to him.
I see.
You'd better be careful.
He's no good.
Don't go telling him the truth.
Poor Yuri.
Yes. She should have
told me about her debts.
It was only a million or so.
I could have helped.
You sold her place.
Squeezing her mother for 300,000!
That should be your condolence gift!
What's your problem?
Tomoko, get me a drink.
Straight.
Don't worry.
I'll pay for it.
You really can't hold your liquor!
Mama, the manager
wants to see you.
What?
Don't be so nasty
to Mr. Minobe.
You want me to flatter him?
Forget it.
Customers pay for a good -
I said forget it!
I quit the Lilac
because of him.
Who is he anyway?
He drives Yuri to desperation, then
comes here like nothing's happened.
I hate him!
He makes me sick!
Not tonight!
I can still smell the incense
from Yuri's funeral.
Just being next to him
is an insult to her memory!
There are limits,
even in business!
Stop being so emotional.
This is a bar.
People pay to have a good time.
So what?
Listen to me!
You get paid
to show men a good time.
If you don't like it,
take off that kimono
and work in an office
and starve!
Shut up!
Komatsu, Mama's
throwing up blood!
Blood?
Mama, are you all right?
Call a doctor!
Get a cab!
Sorry to bother you.
It was a small ulcer.
Four weeks passed.
I spent both Christmas
and New Year's
in bed,
and the following week as well.
Excuse me.
Dad.
May I ask your name?
So good of you to come.
I should have come sooner.
But the holidays were so busy
with the bar
and the place in Akasaka.
I'm sorry I caused you
such trouble.
I asked Komatsu about you.
You look well.
Thank you.
It's not serious.
I see.
I came across
some turtle soup.
I thought it might do you good.
Buy some fruit with this.
Thank you.
This is my first time
in these parts.
You can still see traces
of the old Tokyo.
This may not suit your taste.
Unfortunately Mother is out.
You needn't have.
Look what she brought.
Thank you.
Heat this for her tonight.
Even turtle soup costs
a fortune these days.
Thank you for this precious gift.
Your brother seems nice.
Yes, almost too nice.
Is that his son downstairs?
Yes. He had polio.
Really?
He has such a cute face.
Don't go far.
He's starting school this year.
There's an operation
that could help him, but...
It must be hard on you too.
What about your apartment?
- Junko's looking after it.
Don't worry about the bar.
Your health's more important.
Well, I should be going.
Taxes are coming due.
Could you do some collecting?
I'm sorry.
I've been meaning to.
Ah, it's you!
I'm not supposed to let anyone in,
but you're all right.
Nice place.
The rent must be high.
Is that a present?
Thanks.
So this is her bedroom.
It's still warm.
Put that down!
- Is Mama out?
- She's in the hospital.
And I came all this way.
Which hospital?
- I don't know.
- Don't be ridiculous.
She didn't tell me.
Why not?
Is she trying to hide something?
She's not that type.
There's nobody but you.
The nerve!
Don't mock your elders.
What are you doing here?
- Watching the place.
This is a waste of time.
I'm going.
Don't be so gruff.
You can have some tea
even if she isn't here.
Don't be naughty
or Mama will scold you.
Tea's ready.
What were you doing?
Checking to see
if Mama has a lover.
Oh, you!
You call this tea?
Tastes like medicine.
You'd be hopeless as a bride.
I don't plan to get married.
- You want to stay single?
- You're so slow. I'm disappointed.
What do you mean, slow?
I mean dumb.
You're the dumb one.
I'm going to have
my own bar someday.
That's my dream.
Dreams are nice,
but first take a long look
in the mirror.
That's rude!
Speaking of which,
Mama never replied to my offer.
Did she say anything to you?
- No.
Listen...
What are you doing?
I want my own bar.
I feel my youth
fading by the day.
Sick people always say that.
Maybe I should go to the beauty salon.
It's been so long.
Want a massage?
That's all right.
I don't have much to do.
Lie down.
I hate to impose.
Here?
How's that?
I used to give my boss massages
when we went on business trips.
Brother...
were you this kind
to your wife?
Of course.
She was my wife.
That's why she left you...
and her own son.
I'm home.
Welcome back.
The owner came by to see me.
Really?
She gave me this.
You take it.
You sure?
Thanks a lot.
How did it go?
Let me smoke first.
Don't smoke the butts.
Take these.
Thanks.
Life now really makes me
long for the old days.
Those were good times.
Your father had the fish market.
We sent you
to a good school.
What did my sister-in-law say?
That she'd never return
to a family like this.
That's how couples
are these days.
You don't have to run off.
Emiko asked about you.
"How's his job
as an insurance salesman?"
You've wound up like this
because you're too nice!
You go to court again
next week, right?
I ran into your lawyer
at the bus stop.
Why didn't you say anything?
I've troubled you enough.
It's a little late for that now.
Why'd you affix your seal
to a receipt
you knew nothing about?
Did you have to do
everything your boss said?
That's right! I'm too nice!
I'm just a fool!
They were selling
these sweet bean cakes.
They're hard to find.
Have one.
No, thanks.
They're good.
I said no.
Fine. I won't force you,
but I got them just for you.
I guess you only like
fancy things these days.
It's not that.
I'm just not hungry.
Fine.
But you really can't afford
to be so extravagant.
What do you mean,
extravagant?
Aren't you?
You keep a fancy apartment
instead of living at home.
That's not an extravagance.
Then what is it?
Tell me!
Customers come to the Ginza
for a taste of luxury.
Satisfying that craving
is what we're paid for.
Apartments beyond our means,
taxis, expensive perfumes -
it all serves that purpose.
Men wouldn't be interested
if they knew I lived
in a place like this.
Somehow it would show,
no matter what I did.
Isn't it a shame
you're stuck with us?
Why even come home?
Go to some expensive hospital.
Mother.
Isn't it the truth?
That would suit
your silk kimono better!
Mother, how many times
must I tell you?
Kimonos aren't a luxury for me!
I know - it's business!
That's right! Looking good
means good customers.
In the Ginza,
appearance is everything.
You wouldn't understand.
I'm actually quite frugal.
Flashy kimonos
would get more attention,
but I can't wear them
in the daytime,
so I buy plain ones instead.
You have no right
to call me extravagant!
I said I understood!
Then stop saying it!
Who'd ever want
to work in a bar?
Drinking till I'm sick,
being a plaything for men.
I haven't enjoyed a single day
since I started.
Even lying here, thoughts of bills
torment my dreams.
I'm miserable!
But how else could I send you
20,000 a month?
If you can find a better job,
tell me and I'll quit!
Go ahead and insult me!
I'm a burden on you!
Just leave us!
Stop it!
Just go downstairs!
It's all my fault.
Keiko doesn't have to pay
for the lawyer.
I'll just go to prison.
Don't say that.
I'll ask again
when she's in a better mood.
Take this.
That's all right.
Don't tell her.
Excuse me.
My name is Sekine.
Mr. Sekine?
No, I'd be ashamed
if he saw me here.
Tell him I have a fever.
How can I do that?
Please just get rid of him!
I see. That's too bad.
I just had business nearby
and wondered how she was.
I'm sorry
she's not being more polite.
It's all right.
Please give her this.
It must be hard on you,
but please
take good care of her.
What a kind man.
How'd he find out I was here?
What does it matter?
Fat people are usually nice.
His wife is certainly lucky.
He's not married.
You don't say.
Doesn't he remind you
of Yasuo?
He was such a kind son-in-law.
I'm going back to work next week.
But you're not -
I have to.
That's why the owner came by.
I see.
Would you talk
to your brother's lawyer first?
Money will settle it.
Help him out.
No!
I have no money.
LAW OFFICES
Despite what I'd said,
I couldn't let my brother go to jail.
I'd only been away
from the bar a month,
but I couldn't get used
to being back.
Maybe because
Junko and Tomoko were away.
Whiskey on the rocks.
Without any water?
Same thing last night too.
Mama, do you still feel worn out?
A little.
Everyone's dressed so nicely.
All under 10,000 yen.
You're kidding!
That cheap?
It's true.
Miss Kiyomi sold them
to the girls before Christmas.
She bought the clothes
Miss Yuri had pawned,
then sold them to the girls here.
She must have made 300,000.
Very smart.
Smarter if she'd saved it.
She spent it all on that guy
who sells black-market whiskey.
Mr. Komatsu's
in Akasaka right now.
I'm here as a customer tonight.
White Horse. A double.
- It's been a long time.
- It has.
That's no tone
to use with a customer.
I quit the black market.
Next time
it would have been jail.
Don't be so stuck up.
I know you're Ionely.
I've been thinking about it:
Give me a chance just once.
You won't regret it.
I'm a paying customer!
Oh, hello.
- Leaving?
- I was, but come up.
No, I'll drive you home.
You will? All right.
I'm glad to see you're better.
Thank you for calling on me.
You drive well.
I'm just a safe driver.
I don't drink.
Bars can't be much fun then.
I'm looking for a mistress.
Always joking.
I wouldn't date a woman
if I weren't considering
marrying her.
Thanks.
What?
Would you laugh
if I proposed to you?
I know.
No need to answer.
I just wanted to say it once.
Pretend I never said it.
Bye.
Oh, it's you.
What is it?
I waited here.
Better than going to your bar.
May I come in?
- Don't be so formal.
You must be tired.
What do you want?
Out with it.
The lawyer got me
a suspended sentence.
It's all thanks to you.
You needn't have come.
I already knew that.
So what is it you want now?
Money again?
It's not for me.
- Yoshio?
- Yes.
Dr. Murata said
if he operates now,
Yoshio will be walking
before school starts.
Without crutches?
Well, that'll take six months
of physical therapy.
But he can't go
to school as he is.
I know you'll say no.
It's a lot of money.
Then why come?
I'm sorry.
I've always been a coward.
I don't know why.
How much will it cost?
Never mind.
It's selfish of me.
I just thought maybe
you could ask the owner -
How much?
At least 70 or 80,000.
80,000?
It can be in installments.
Please help us.
I won't ask again.
That's what you always say.
I mean it.
I've made up my mind.
We'll cut our ties
as brother and sister.
I promise...
I'll never come here again.
This is the last time.
Please help.
For poor Yoshio's sake.
Please, I beg you!
That's right - take everything!
All of you!
Just prey on me!
Enough!
I don't want to hear it!
Come in.
May I?
Go home.
Think it over.
You sure it's all right?
I meant to give you
something earlier, but I forgot.
Here.
Open it after I leave.
Please don't go.
Stay awhile.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
May I open it?
Black Narcissus.
You mentioned you liked it.
Mama.
Why are you crying?
What's wrong, Mama?
I'll take this one.
Buying a present for someone?
I heard you received
a fine proposal.
I saw the fortune-teller yesterday.
She told me.
She's good, isn't she?
Well?
Very becoming.
Look.
I don't have the money today,
but I'll pay your hospital bill soon.
Thank you.
That's a huge help.
Don't talk like that.
We're not strangers anymore.
You're right.
I never dreamed
I'd become the wife
of a factory owner.
Hello!
You seem different today.
Do I?
Junko's waiting in back
to talk to you.
What about?
She's quitting.
At least she's giving notice.
Don't be angry.
So you're quitting?
Why?
I got Mr. Goda
to put up some money.
I'm opening a bar.
Mr. Goda?
Is that so?
Congratulations.
That's wonderful.
What a relief!
Did you find a place?
It's above a sushi restaurant.
We share the restroom,
but I don't mind.
What is it?
Nothing at all.
Congratulations.
Hello? This is she.
Mr. Sekine?
No, he's not here.
Who's calling?
Mrs. Sekine?
You're really his wife?
Yes.
Hello? Hello?
It's so embarrassing.
He may not look it, but my husband's
a hopeless womanizer.
He lures them in
with marriage proposals.
I can't count how often
I've had to straighten things out.
This time he borrowed
the neighbor's car
and hasn't been home
in a week.
I'm not even jealous anymore,
but our neighbor is angry.
He forgot his address book,
so I called
all the women in it.
He's not bad at heart.
He just loves to show off.
He lies and then begins
to think it's all true.
That's just how he is.
I'm so sorry
I had to call you like that.
A pretty woman like you -
you didn't fall for it, did you?
Fill it up.
Mama, are you all right?
I'm fine!
Welcome.
You look well.
I heard you were sick.
I'm very well.
See, it's really you that I love.
Oh, my.
Excuse me.
Mr. Fujisaki, who's she?
Introduce us.
You're drunk.
Mama, come here a moment.
Komatsu, keep an eye on her.
Leave me alone!
Let me go!
What do you plan to do?
Drink till I die.
Who's that geisha anyway?
Acting so prim!
I'll steal him back!
Stop it! I hate you!
- How's Mama?
- Mr. Fujisaki's taking her to a nightclub.
The geisha left.
She can't keep drinking.
Her guest wants her to go.
I can't stop her.
Mr. Fujisaki...
I'll go anywhere
with you tonight.
Or don't you want
a woman like me?
I understand.
But no more drinks.
Mr. Fujisaki...
I've heard you've had
a lot of women.
But I love you.
Women fall for your type.
You know that?
Yes, I know. Let's go home.
It's after 11:00.
You mustn't get sick again.
Let's go.
I'm so glad you're here.
The tax collector
is coming tomorrow.
Bring your books over tonight.
We'll fix them up.
I see.
Whiskey really
knocks you off your feet.
I'm sorry to bother you.
Do you feel ill?
- No, but I'm thirsty.
- Want some water?
Thanks.
Stop thanking me.
I drank so much.
Did I say anything?
No, nothing.
Thanks for everything.
Good night.
No, don't.
I love you!
I always have!
No, don't!
What's wrong?
I had a dream.
I was crying.
When I woke up,
I was really crying.
What was your dream?
It was about my late husband.
Even when a woman's
in your arms,
you can never tell
who she's really thinking of.
Light me one, please.
It was a strange dream.
He called to say he was
returning from a business trip.
I went to the harbor to greet him.
Strange that
he'd be coming by ship,
but that's how dreams are.
He stood on deck,
waving the presents
he'd bought me.
Guess what they were.
Potatoes, onions, and radishes.
We married just after the war,
when food was scarce.
He often brought vegetables
back from his trips.
Seeing those vegetables
in the dream made me sad,
so I started crying.
I see.
Was he a kind man?
I love you...
but I'd prefer a husband.
Someone always by my side.
I don't want to see you
just once in a while.
I'm happy now though.
Really?
You don't regret it?
No, I don't.
But I'm worried about one thing.
Worried?
When my husband died,
I placed my picture and a letter
in with his ashes.
I vowed I'd never love
another man.
I wrote that down
and asked the priest
to put it in with him.
I'm a strange woman, aren't I?
I have to go now.
No, stay a little longer.
I can't.
It's still early.
I'll make some coffee.
That's all right.
I meant to tell you last night,
but I couldn't.
I'm being transferred to Osaka.
When was that decided?
The end of the year.
I leave tomorrow.
I won't forget you.
Call me if you ever come to Osaka.
All I can do now is help
when you open your own place.
I promise you that.
Mr. Fujisaki...
I really do love you.
I love you too.
You do?
I love you...
but I don't have the courage
to break up my home.
It may be selfish of me,
but it's the truth.
I bought this stock cheap.
It's worth 100,000 now.
Maybe it will help.
I meant to leave it
last night and go.
A noble sentiment, but I was
too low to see it through.
I'll never forget
this brief time together.
Take care of yourself.
I just saw Fujisaki.
Why are you crying?
Did he jilt you?
I used to respect you.
I was amazed at how
you never gave in for five long years.
That illusion's gone.
Sorry.
I'm not that good.
Do you love him?
Why don't you answer?
I don't love him or hate him.
Besides, he's being
transferred to Osaka.
You fool! Why'd you give in
if you don't love him?
Aren't you ashamed?
Did you forget
your letter and picture?
- That was just -
- Liar! I looked into it.
I got drunk one day
and asked the priest about it.
Why'd you do that?
Why?
Don't pretend you don't know.
You know I love you.
But I never said a word.
I kept it locked up inside.
It became so unbearable
I even seduced one of our girls.
Some manager!
Last December it got
so I couldn't take it anymore.
I went to the temple
and checked.
It turned out to be true,
so I vowed never to touch you,
or let anyone else either!
But now you've turned
into a consummate pro!
Sorry to disappoint you.
But who told me
to act like a pro?
Who told me to flatter Minobe?
You told me never to go halfway,
to be a real pro!
Well, now I'm a pro,
and the customer's happy.
What's wrong with that?
No!
I love you!
Let me go!
Marry me.
I'm begging you.
Let's open our own bar.
Get out or I'll scream.
You hate me that much?
I don't hate you or love you.
That kind of marriage
would never work.
We know each other too well.
Please just go.
Go!
Please let me be alone.
You really love Fujisaki,
don't you?
I understand.
I'll never bother you again.
You'd be a great help,
but I could never
afford your salary.
I see.
Why'd you quit the Carton?
Have a fight with Mama?
I'm tired of that place.
I may go back to the Club 8.
I'll help out when you're busy.
- Thanks.
Good-bye.
Mrs. Fujisaki?
I'm Keiko from the Carton Bar,
and a customer of the bank.
You've been very kind
to my husband.
Not at all.
Congratulations on his promotion.
Thank you.
I borrowed this
from your husband.
I'd like to return it.
Is that all right?
If I need it again,
I'll borrow it directly from you.
I see.
Here's a little something
for the children.
Dear...
Thanks.
Please take good care
of yourselves.
She's beautiful.
Not at all like a bar hostess.
Mommy, what is this?
Can we open it?
Later.
It had been a bleak ordeal,
like a harsh winter.
But the trees that line the streets
can sprout new buds
no matter how cold the wind.
I too must be just as strong
as the winds
that gust around me.
Ah! Welcome!
It's been so long!
Welcome!
THE END