SARAJEVO JUNE 1950
WHEN FATHER WAS AWAY ON BUSINESS
AN HISTORICAL LOVE FILM
Chiquita
Spanish land, flowers of May
Every child loves you
While listening to castanets
I have a sombrero
You're a darling girl
Chiquita
You're the woman of my dreams
You 're my new love
But you give yours to another
I have a sombrero
You're my darling girl
Carmelita
Lead me to Barcelona
So 9 can see my love
Chiquita
9 thought 9 was the first to come
9 am a stranger
But, Chiquita
H! be yours
I have a sombrero
You're a darling girl
Franjo!
What are you lads up to'?
Are you Working
or messing around'?
When you work,
you don't mess around.
- Understood?
- Understood.
Come on, comrades!
My name is Mafik Malkoc,
but everybody calls me
"Maffky Sticky-icky. ”"
I was born November 2, 1944,
but Mama wrote I was born
on October 29,
because the war was on
and we were poor
so she could get
an extra months allowance.
My best friend is Joza.
His full name
is Serjoza Petrovic.
He doesn't mind
being called Joza,
but if someone
calls him “fatso, “
he gets mad.
WE BUY HERBS AND MUSHROOMS
Franjo the janitor
sings Mexican songs.
When my dad asked him,
"Why Mexican?"
he said, "Comrade Mesa,
nowadays, it's the safest.
Such are the times.“
Mama always tells him,
“Franjo, don? drink.
You'll ruin your health. “
He smiles and says,
"When I'm drunk,"
“my reflexes are quicker.
“Who knows what would happened
if I were sober?“
He drinks up all the money
he makes from the herbs
because he loves
90-proof, plum brandy.
But we're saving up our money
to buy a genuine, leather football.
They're going too far now.
You're a swine, Mesa.
You know that?
Why'?
You don't know?
You really don't know?
I told you I had no idea
I'd be promoted.
What's the Party got to do
with the divorce?
Shut up.
You tell me to shut up'?
You've been telling me that
for two years.
What am I, a Whore?
Shut up, you stupid bitch!
- Got a light?
- I've got nicer things.
A nice girl,
but a bit hot-tempered.
I've got just the cure for her.
You can't even
get these in Paris.
La Baiser,
the queen of lipsticks.
How much'?
Cheaper than a muzzle.
In view of the situation,
only four dinars.
Give me two.
Leave me alone.
Leave me alone!
You don't love me anymore.
- You don't!
- Just be patient!
When will you get a divorce?
When'? Never!
Say something, for God's sake!
You don't love me.
Who loves anybody
in this madhouse'?
I'll go to a rest home
and bathe when it suits me.
You only take one bath a year.
There, they'd make you
take two a week.
While others fuck about,
I have to bathe.
Mama has ordered a big clean-up.
My brother Mirza and I
are to be circumcised.
I asked Mirza
what “circumcisecf means.
He says we're done for.
They grab your prick
and cut half of it off.
Jam's dad, Viado Petrovic,
was taken away
by the men in leather coats.
He shouted so that everybody
could hear:
"I'd rather have Russian shit
than American cake!“"
Later they took away
their radio and telephone.
I asked Joza why they did it.
He said it was
something to do with Stalin.
We took all of Stalin's pictures
out of the house.
We recognized him
by his moustache.
Since then, Joza's mom
first waits for the postman every day,
then tells Joza
she's going to the market
and goes off to the council
to ask about his dad.
- How's my little Communist?
- He's great, comrade.
Here you are...
Comrades.
You've got no right.
Give it...
Give it here.
Radio Sarajevo...
We inform all citizens
that vegetables
will be available...
Where have you been'?
For the lady of the house.
Mirza!
Look in my pocket.
50 mm.
Chalk in the right hand,
slate in the left.
And for the mangy, old freeloader...
I hoped you'd be gone
when I returned.
So did I, dear son-in-law.
When will you leave
and never return?
You'll have a bloody, long wait.
I know.
Scram.
You heard me!
Go on, you pest. Get down!
You shouldn't have.
The latest craze in Zagreb.
The slate indoors,
the rattle outdoors, okay?
Okay, dad.
What are you waiting for'?
The movie.
You can't Watch it in daylight.
Harder, harder.
Our people must be prepared
for anything.
The danger of being
thrown off-balance
is a constant threat.
Every individual must use
maximum concentration
and always make sure
he has control
over every part of his body.
In order to perform
his jump correctly.
Any hasty move
can lead him into
a perilous situation.
An incorrect position in flight
can cost an individual his life
or leave him maimed for life.
Don't swing your arms
when you Walk.
You can tell if someone's clever
by the Way he Walks.
How, Dad'?
The feet should be parallel.
Whoever twists them this Way is a fool.
I don't understand, Dad.
You will when you grow up.
Communists have an inborn
aesthetic sense.
It's a fact.
If you don't know that, you're a...
Fool, dolt, nitwit, dumbbell.
Comrades!
Our physical, cultural movement,
despite the present
anti-Yugoslavian campaign,
is growing stronger day by day.
However,
the attacks of Coninform
have had its effects
on the development
of physical culture.
In our country.
Since their resolution,
our physical culture
has been subject
to blatant discrimination
by socialite countries.
- Hello.
- Hi, big brother.
Are you taking care
of my sister?
No complaints.
- How are you'?
- Fine.
Let us welcome the first Woman
in this part
of the Balkan Peninsula...
who is going to fly
a Hawk Glider:
Ankica Vidmar.
Stop by for a drink tonight.
I'm busy.
She came here to help develop
our physical culture.
A date, eh'?
Yes.
And you're not afraid?
No, it doesn't take
much courage.
I come from a family of fliers.
I just love flying.
No doubt about it.
She's modest and brave.
A model, young Communist.
Witty, isn't it'?
Don't you think?
Some people wouldn't agree.
With What'?
They don't think it's witty.
Who doesn't think it's Witty?
You know him very well.
Who'?
Your own brother-in-law.
And what does he think?
I don't know...
That they're going too far.
Three minutes left in the game.
Vukas passes the ball
from the left side.
Mitic gets it,
the Danish half in front of him.
Mific evades his opponent.
A powerful shot!
The fifth goal for our team!
Ifs 5-0, Yugoslavia!
We showed them, Comrade Mesa.
- Damn good.
- Huh?
Come on, Muzafer, have one.
- Come on.
- No.
Mrkusic, Horvat, Stankovic,
Cajkovski, Jovanovic...
Dazjic, Ognajanov, Mitic,
Hocevar, Bobek, Vukas.
Vukas broke through on the left
and passed to the edge
of the penalty area.
Hocevar coolly put the ball
into the net.
That made it 2-0, Yugoslavia.
In the second half,
our team played very well,
led by Mitic,
who scored three goals.
Hello, brother-in-law.
Hello.
You scared the hell out of me.
Don't worry about it.
Sit down.
Tell me first.
Make yourself comfortable.
I've no one to inform on.
No, I can't.
Come on, drink.
I really can't.
How's the job'?
Traveling'?
Too much.
Twice a month.
Everythings okay'?
As far as I know.
And as far as you don't know?
- Others know?
- I'll say they do.
You thought things
could be kept hidden'?
No, it's like they say:
"The State Security
knows everything."
Sit down.
Listen, she was mine,
now she's yours. That's all.
We don't arrest people for screwing.
- What?
- You heard.
You mean, I'm...
Not yet.
But God, himself, Won't save you.
“ DJ-Uro! _ Yes?
I don't need God.
I'm clean as a Whistle.
Zijo...
I'm having the children
circumcised tomorrow.
The old man's arranged it all.
A fairy calls
From atop Mount Trebevic
is Sarajevo still
Where it used to be'?
Is the tavern still
By the Moria Inn?
Are they drinking wine
Sarajevo's young folk?
Are they served
By the maid Mara'?
Is Mara wearing
Three, fine skirts?
Tighten your belt.
You've no choice.
Do you hear that,
neighbor llanka'?
The crap I take from my own son.
Fuck our Russian brothers,
when they screw us.
What have you done'?
I don't know. A mistake.
Get back there. They'll notice.
Please, go on.
Anything left, butcher?
Enough for a good screw.
Beg your pardon, ladies.
When they circumcised me,
Mrs. Petrovic,
there was enough skin left
to make you a coat.
Well done. Congratulations.
You're my little hero, aren't you'?
Uncle.
Will you buy me a football?
I sure will.
Did someone scream
or am I hearing things?
You're hearing things, Dad.
I screamed.
Are you all right'?
Yeah.
Make sure you're healed up...
when I get back.
I don't want to find
anybody still in bed, okay'?
Since dad's been away
on business,
everybody's tense...
Grandpa, mama...
Everybody who comes to our house
they all shake their heads,
tick-took, like a clock.
Mama is always sewing.
When she stops,
she starts crying.
Once I heard Mrs. Honka
say to my mom,
“Don't cry, Sena.
“He's not an informer.
He's something else.“
"What else?" asked my mother.
Mrs. Honla was silent,
just like me when I teH a He.
Dad, get up!
Get up. Malik's gone!
Quick, quick!
Wait, Sena!
Telephone'?
It's the doorbell.
Good morning.
Is my brother here'?
He's asleep.
Would you like to come in'?
Come in.
What did you bring us'?
My pain, that's What.
Can you sleep, brother?
You see I can, sister.
Well'?
I've been waiting
for you to tell me.
I thought you'd drop in.
You used to come
and visit your father.
Where is he'?
Why doesn't he write?
Listen, Sena. I'm serious.
He'll write when he can.
My brotherly advice is
mind your own business.
Don't ask anyone anything.
Don't even come
to see me anymore.
Mind the children
and your business.
- He's your brother-in-law.
- So what'?
I'm a soldier of the Party, understand?
Understand what I'm saying?
What's this'?
Some underwear.
He went in thin socks,
without a vest.
Take it home.
Can't you even
slip him a parcel?
You could when the Ustashas
caught him.
Leave it.
Take this to Malik.
The ball is on the goal line.
A big chance for our team!
Don't be an alcoholic like me.
I've made my Wife and child miserable,
And my house was sold by other...
other elements.
My life is stormy...
ruined.
Someone else killed me.
I'm still a man.
I Won't let anyone crush me.
What are you doing'?
What's it to you'?
Wait!
- It's not your money!
- It's not yours either!
- I earned it.
- So what?
- Give it back!
- Get lost!
Give it back.
I'll hit you.
Give it back!
" Get up!
- No!"
- Get up!
- No, I want a football.
Why are you hitting him'?
- What do you want'?
Give me the money!
We thought...
Fahro!
Is Father dead'?
They've taken Mesa away.
Look who's here.
Uncle!
- Can we go to a movie'?
- If you sleep.
- Go to sleep.
- Okay.
What movie will we see'?
"The Cow Jumped Over the Moon."
Now, go to sleep.
Look at the recruit!
Recruit, Dad'?
I'm an old soldier.
Sit down, son.
Where are your wounds'?
I see you've had it pretty easy.
Come on, talk.
Do the kids know?
No.
Zijo made it look like a business trip.
- They even said goodbye.
- Zijo arranged it'?
He was here at the boys' circumcision.
- There was singing...
- The neighbors too'?
If you think you're going to waste
Natasha's time...
Does Zivka know about the letters?
I didn't tell her.
No one knows?
Everyone knows.
- What do they know?
- What I saw.
What did you see'?
A oar and two men down below.
Not that.
I was thinking about Natasha.
They shoved him in like a thief.
What do you think, Dad'?
I saw nothing. I heard nothing.
They were sitting here
like normal people...
and he left with Zijo
like it was a business trip.
Did you talk to Zijo'?
No.
Why not?
It's best just to forget about it.
Attention!
At ease.
Right turn.
Forward march!
- Any word from your father'?
- No.
- Is he dead'?
What are you wearing?
Nobody wants to tell us Where he is.
I Wear it to spite them.
Sarajevo again hosts a grand army parade.
A review of the strength of our republic.
- What are you doing, boy'?
- Nothing.
Sit down! Sit down!
Bimbo! The spray!
Any film'?
Wait a second.
What do you do with it all'?
Eat it?
That's enough for this month.
Do you want a poster?
Off you go.
That'll do for this month.
Kiss me.
- Why?
- Just kiss me.
- What is it?
- A kiss!
He's alive!
Dear Daddy,
We're all so glad you've written.
And that you are well,
but I am sorry that you have to do
voluntary work in that mine.
Fm writing this on the slate you brought me
and Mama will copy it out on paper for you.
We raised the money to visit you
by selling the carpet from the living room.
Only Franjo misses the carpet.
He said, "What shall I beat now?"
But later he whispered to me,
“I'll be beating other
carpets of Mesa 's. “
I gave Mama the money
Pd saved for a football.
So don? worry. We're coming.
You can expect us for sure on April 1st.
Lots of love, Malik.
Everybody out!
Fall in! Pick up your tools!
Right face! Forward march!
- What have they done'?
- I'm just getting old.
You're not any taller or fatter.
I told you to bring Malik,
not a crybaby.
What are you, a girl'?
He's just happy to see you.
Well, good night.
What's this'?
He started sleepwalking.
I checked on him,
and he was gone.
- Why the bell?
- Just to be safe.
Have you found out Why you're here'?
Ask your brother.
I have.
What did he say'?
He told me to mind my own business.
- He married the gym teacher.
- Ankica'?
Yes, she walks around the house naked.
You could ask her of course.
No, you'd better not. Forget it.
When will they release you'?
I don't know.
I don't know anything.
- Talk about something else.
- Such as'?
How are things in Sarajevo?
Is Sarajevo still Where it used to be'?
What's Wrong?
Why aren't you asleep?
You're talking, but I have to be quiet.
Come on, close your eyes.
Can I come in with you'?
I'll stay with you until you fall asleep.
Come on, settle down.
Mama, why did we come here'?
We have to talk to this lady.
Good. Take a break.
How are you, young man'?
My, how you've grown!
Would you like some candy?
Come and sit over here.
- How are you'?
- I'm all right.
I went to see Mesa.
How is he'?
When is he coming home?
He told me to ask you.
Me'? How would I know'?
You don't know?
You do know, you whore!
You'll pay when we get home.
You know why.
I know.
9 was very sad when Joza's dad died.
It reminded me of my dad.
But I stopped being sad
when I saw no one was crying.
Joza told me his daddy
hadn't actually died
and his mom told mine,
“My Wade's dead.
I'm sick of their lies. “
She said, "I'll bury him
just to spite them."
And the priest with the beard said,
“We'll perform the service,
but we won't record it. “
Is anyone in the coffin?
I know that when someone dies
he is no more,
but he can't just vanish.
When Mama told me to shut up,
I understood everything.
I didn't even know Zvornik existed,
till Dad sent us a letter
saying he'd finished his work at the mine
where Mom and I had visited him.
Mirza showed it to me on the map,
where they're building
a hydroelectric station.
I didn't feel like going to Zvornik,
sol asked Mama
why Dad couldn't come here
instead of us going there.
She said it was a cheaper place to live
and would give us a fresh start.
Grandpa said,
“They're shoving him off again. “
Mama said they call it “resocia/izing. “
I just kept quiet.
9 was sorry to go,
but glad we'd be together with Dad again.
- Here, take this.
- I've got enough.
Take it. There are better days ahead.
Mesa will be angry, Hamdo.
Then let him send it back.
Right, boy'? Come on, take it.
Take it, Sena.
Give my regards to Mesa.
- Have you told Grandpa?
- Just a minute.
Dad. Come here.
What now'?
Fahrds letters.
Give them to Natasha.
Oh, I see.
Those two are planning to...
Oh, who's this I see'?
The generaPs up early.
Don't make fun of me.
Lucky you, dear girl.
Be a good boy now.
Let's get going.
Good luck, and, God Willing,
I'll come visit you.
I'll write as soon as We're settled.
You father was buried long ago
Buried in the damp earth
Your brother went to Siberia long ago
Long ago, clanging in shackles
The Baikal vagabond went back
To his mother
Greetings, Mama
Are Father and Brother well?
Your brother went to Siberia long ago
Long ago, clanging in shackles
In the wild...
- Where are you going'?
- To Zvornik.
The roads closed.
Wait for the ferry.
I drove here yesterday.
Ah, my friend.
Yesterday was yesterday
and today is today.
Got a cigarette?
Dad!
Doctor, this is my Wife.
This is the doctor, a great man.
Evgeni Alexandrovich Liakhov.
Your wife's lovely.
So what's wrong with me'?
Glad to meet you.
Welcome to Wetland.
You're Russian?
Yes, but I always say I'm
a native of Zvornik.
See'? I'm a Yugoslav.
I was just asking.
My mother, rest her soul,
like all Russian emigres,
used to say,
"Ubi bene, ibi patria."
Really?
Isn't it so'?
Yes.
You two ride inside.
I'll stay with the children.
Ride with your Wife.
She's so scared.
That's Why a doctor should be with her.
Come on. Hurry up.
We'll capsize, Dad.
No, we won't. The Drina's calm.
In our new economic and social system
tourism has been opened up
to working people.
Take that end.
Vvhafll we do with this'?
Throw it into the Drina.
Gentleman from Sarajevo.
That's right, boy from Sarajevo.
Get washed.
Dad, was your school big'?
Yes.
- What color was it'?
- Yellow.
- What color is my school?
- Pink.
Good morning.
You're up early, doctor.
Malik, this is Masa.
Shake hands.
- I'm late.
- For what?
For work.
We should popularize our tourism abroad.
It could play a much greater role
than before the War.
Lift your arm.
That's right. Excuse me, again.
I can never get the Waist
right the first time.
What? It's fine.
It was quite a job to
organize resin collecting,
to train the workers
to get the most resin
without impairing the quality
of the Wood.
Many workers have mastered the job.
Good bye.
Hello, hello.
How are you'?
Fine. And you'?
No rest during the reconstruction.
Jole, bring me a tablecloth!
Private room'?
- Your idea?
- Yes, the Union committee.
We'll find a room later.
Not bad.
We'll make a report on it.
Shall we knock one back'?
- During work hours'?
- I'll take responsibility.
I fell in love on September 2nd, 1951.
That day, we beat Sweden 2-1.
The goals were scored
by Bobek and Ognajanov.
9 love doing homework with Mesa.
I would love it to last forever.
Not the homework...
I hardly know what I'm writing...
But to rest my head on her shoulder.
I make a move,
my heart starts beating wildly.
I quickly put on a straight face
and go on writing.
If she noticed something,
Pd be embarrassed.
Get Daddy.
Doctor! Doctor!
Quick!
Mesa!
Hello, Doctor.
Come on up.
Come and have a drink with us.
I can't Ostoja. I'm in a hurry.
Have a drink.
I'd rather get going.
Micko, is the car ready?
Ready an hour ago.
- She hasn't a chance.
- The girl'?
They're changing her blood.
She Won't last long.
Why him'?
It serves him right,
having a child at 50.
He lost his country.
Let him at least have a child.
- You know what?
- What?
You're a bullshitter.
I just thought...
If you'd been thinking,
you wouldn't be here.
I never heard of any boss
who does the purchasing.
Neither did I, but this one does.
He does.
You think I'd give money to those fools'?
Don't lose your hanky.
What does it say here'?
Just read it.
Is that whoring around'?
Three oases of rum, 70 kilos of lamb,
500 eggs.
Is that whoring around'?
Yes, it is.
All of Zvornik goes whoring at Koviljaca.
Malik, get ready!
You're going with me.
If you don't believe me, ask your son.
Three vvhoremongers
three vvhoremongers. ..
- Don't tip us over.
- I Won't.
Just drive. We'll do the singing.
He was only joking.
All's well that ends well, right'?
Comrade Mesa!
Malik's gone, Comrade Mesa!
Malik's gone.
- What's all the shouting?
- Malik's gone.
Find him, you idiot!
Where's my son, you half-Wit'?
- I fell asleep.
- You fell asleep!
How did it happen'?
I just turned around and he was gone.
Nothing stops you, does it'?
I'd never go whoring with Micko.
Yes, you would.
He's no different.
He'd sell out his own mother.
Don't play the saint,
you bastard!
Do you take me for a fool'?
Cekic was with you.
Micko Won't give you away.
Here, see'? No hanky!
You can't lie to me anymore, damn you!
Don't go through my pockets.
What have hankies got to do with it'?
Shut up.
Did I spend two years crying for this'?
Did I leave my job for this'?
I sew like mad to give us a decent life...
a normal life.
And for who'?
For a shameless whore-chaser and a drunk.
What's happening to me'?
What have I done to deserve this'?
It'd be better if you hadn't been
released from jail.
Shut up, you bitch.
You should've killed yourself like Vladol
- Shut up, bitch.
- You scum!
Fuck you!
Screw you!
Leave me alone!
Leave Vlado out of this!
Shut up, you dumb bitch!
Take them off.
You'll get them wet,
and you'll have to wear mine.
My friend Joza can put a stone in it.
I can't.
My amid/a circumcised me.
I know.
Jews do it, too.
What's an amid/a?
He's my dad's brother. A barber.
A doctor can do it, too.
It's all the same.
It's not.
It's better if a doctor does it.
To reward me for my excellent grades,
Dad took me to a bakery and said,
“Order what you like. “
9 had four pies and was almost sick.
Dad laughed and said,
“You see, it doesn't pay to be excellent.“
9 knew he was only joking.
When 9 told him 9 was picked
to hand the Pioneers' Baton
to the mayor,
Dad stopped joking.
He stopped going on purchasing trips.
He kept pacing around the house, repeating,
"I hope to Goo' he doesn't mess it up. ”
Dear Mayor,
I present to you this baton
with a thousand greetings from Zvornik...
with a thousand cordial greetings
from Zvornik.
Louder.
Dear Mayor,
I present to you this baton
with a thousand cordial greetings.
Is your son a bit...'?
No, he's not.
He's going to present the baton.
The Pioneers of Zvornik vow again
to study and work diligently
and acquire new knowledge.
New knowledge...
For the benefit and prosperity of our...
Our...
socialist community
and keep Walking
on the...
On the revolutionary path.
Path...
that our nation is following...
led by Comrade Tito
and the Communist Party of Yugoslavia.
Good. More tomorrow.
Now, off to bed.
Take it off.
When's the fitting?
Right after the holidays.
Tomorrow, when you're with the mayor,
the words should roll off your tongue.
And don't start fidgeting.
When you run up to him, stand proudly.
Don't be shy.
Let your gestures suit your words.
But don't overdo it.
- You know'?
- I know, Dad.
Go to sleep.
Dear Mayor,
I present to you this baton...
Mesa, let's go play a game of chess.
Don't be provocative, Cekic.
What would Nikola say if he heard you'?
You'd go if it weren't for your son.
Let me hear him.
We, the Pioneers of Zvornik
vow again to diligently...
study and work...
and acquire new knowledge...
and keep Walking on the path...
followed by...
Tito...
led by the Party.
Comrades,
today, on this festive day,
the people of our district
join in a day of great national joy.
We have gathered here
to welcome the baton
through which the people of Bosnia
send their love to their greatest teacher.
It was the pin, Dad.
The pin's to blame for everything.
What pin'?
It slipped out.
- Shall I repeat it for you'?
- No.
Will you be my little Communist?
Comrade Cekic wants you to come at once.
Who wrote this speech?
You know very well who wrote it.
You didn't, by chance, change anything?
Do you think I'm crazy?
Is the Party leading Tito
or Tito the Party'?
It makes no difference.
But how would you put it'?
I believe it makes no difference.
The Party teaches us...
Tito is the Party,
the party is Tito
and Tito is all of us.
Sounds great.
Would you like a drink'?
I've got this French shit.
Well, brother, congratulations.
Are you making fun of me, Cekic'?
Congratulations for what?
Your Zvornik mandate has expired.
- It's over.
- Over.
You can go to Sarajevo
or wherever you like.
Calm down.
Sit down.
You'll play one last game with me.
Masai
I knew you'd come.
I brought the bell.
But you mustn't read it here.
Why, Mesa'?
You mustn't, that's all.
Do you promise?
Whatever you say.
Say, "I promise."
Now you're crying.
How do you know'?
Sometimes I know everything.
Your mom cries too.
Yes, she does.
She shouldn't.
That's what I keep telling her.
Give me your hand.
Do you love me'?
More than anyone in the world.
More than myself.
Stand back, son.
Masa never came back.
The doctor came to our house
wearing a black armband
on his White coat.
9 was under the quilt and 9 heard
the doctor say to Mama in Russian,
“Sister, what's the point of life? “
Thank God your troubles are over.
What do you expect from a democracy?
Don't talk about democracy.
The coffers are empty.
Don't worry. We'll make money.
We'll print our own.
Money has nothing to do with democracy.
Some politician you are.
Everything on Earth has to do with money.
I'm telling you,
if the coffers are empty,
there's no democracy.
What's that?
What about your uncle?
Have you forgiven me'?
I can forget. But forgive...
Why did you invite me then?
To talk, like two adults.
Do you still think the same'?
About what?
That I was guilty?
What I think doesn't matter anymore.
It did then.
Did you put me away for my words
or my thoughts?
- I didn't put you away.
- So who did'?
Your own tongue.
My own brother-in-law did.
During that craziness,
it was brother against brother.
You should make up with your sister.
She's your flesh and blood.
- The Pope's drinking'?
- Indeed he is!
Come over here.
- What'?
- Sit down.
Why'? I'm busy.
- What?
- You go outside.
Sit beside Zijo
and talk to him as if nothing happened.
Never.
You'll do as I say.
Never, Mesa.
Don't make me angry.
I'll die first.
Can't you sleep, brother?
Not well, sister.
Where are the parcels?
In the pantry.
Ask Ankica.
So, you're not sleeping well, brother'?
Hardly at all, sister.
What do the doctors say'?
That you can live to 100 with diabetes.
Does the brandy help?
Temporarily.
It's not easy for you.
I understand you perfectly.
Oh, Zijo, you and your fucking brandy.
Why don't you out yourself up
at your own wedding?
Mirza, come here.
My suitcase is in the pantry.
Go take it down for me.
Are you going somewhere?
Just take it down and wait for me.
The game against the Soviet Union
has begun...
It wasn't my fault, Mesa.
I just said you said,
"Who loves anybody in this madhouse."
I didn't know he'd arrest you,
his own brother-in-law.
I just said...
that you said that cartoon was overdone.
I love you, Mesa.
I couldn't Wait for you, Mesa.
Why are you crying?
I don't know.
All I need is you crying
and I'll give birth right here.
My grandfather Muzafer left our house
for a nursing home on July 22, 1952.
I don? know if it was because
he wouldn't bathe or some other reason.
9 only know he told Mirza,
"Tell them I said I'm sick and tired
of their politics."
I'm too old for that crap. “
"And he added," If you want to visit,
Travnik isn't very far.
It's all over! We've Won!
In its second attempt,
the Yugoslav team
has succeeded in qualifying
for the quarter-finals
of the Olympic competition.
Two days ago, we tied the Russians 5-5,
but today we surpassed them
in every aspect.
A richly deserved 3-1 victory.
Those names will be forever remembered
in the history of Yugoslav sport.
Beara, Stankovic, Crnkovic,
Cajkovski, Horvat,
Boskov, Ognjanov, Mitic,
Vukas, Bobek, Zebec.