Um, subject King,
just out of County,
participation mandatory,
and details to follow.
All right, turn it off.
I'm not saying shit
till you turn
the damn thing on.
So, um, what's your name?
King.
How did you get that name?
It's always been.
Is that your real name
or your street name? Or...
Just my name.
So how is...
Can I have a smoke?
Sure.
Thanks.
So, how was jail?
Oh, fuck.
Can I... can I...
Can I say "fuck"?
Yeah.
It says here, "assault,
possession, loitering..."
and that was
pretty petty stuff.
Yeah, right.
It's just survival.
A lot of kids tell you
that they party all night
with, uh, Axl Rose,
or that their girlfriend
got banged by the crips.
Or they've seen five guys
get murdered, or something.
But the truth is,
it's not hard.
It's not easy.
It just is.
You okay?
Yeah.
How long have you
been on the street?
Six, seven years.
How old are you?
Uh, 20, might be 21.
I'm not exactly sure.
That's a good question,
though.
Did you have any
brothers or sisters
growing up?
Yeah, I got a sister,
but, uh, she's gone
from home, too.
Maybe she'll show up here
in Hollywood sometime,
you know.
I'll take care of her,
or something.
I hope she's not
into drugs or anything.
She probably is.
She might be dead.
What about your mom,
your dad?
What about 'em?
Do you, um...
Not very comfortable
talking about 'em? Yeah.
Hey, what the hell?
Hey, you with the camera,
up here, I'm talking.
Drugs?
What kind you got?
Just kidding.
What kind you do?
Don't do 'em.
Hey, look,
nobody's gonna see this tape,
I mean...
I'm not shitting you.
I just want you
to be straight
with me.
I'm being
straight with you.
You do realize
that your participation
in this program
is one of the terms
of your parole?
Yeah, I also realize
that you're giving me
ten bucks a pop
for these sessions,
so, uh,
thank you very much.
Is that why
you decided to participate
in this program?
Because of the money?
Oh, it's better than
picking up trash
on the freeway.
Uh, are you... are you done?
Is that it? Can I go?
Just a minute.
Um, wh... where are
you gonna go?
Well, I've been in lockup
for two months,
where the fuck
do you think I'm gonna go?
You going back
out on the street?
Yeah.
♪ There's something
Happening here ♪
♪ What it is
Ain't exactly clear ♪
♪ There's a man
With a gun over there ♪
♪ Telling me I got to beware ♪
♪ I think it's time we stop
Children, what's that sound? ♪
♪ Everybody look
What's going down ♪
♪ What's going down now ♪
♪ There's battle lines
Being drawn ♪
♪ Nobody's right
If everybody's wrong ♪
♪ Young people
Speaking their minds ♪
♪ Getting so much resistance ♪
♪ From behind ♪
♪ We gotta stop,
Hey, what's that sound? ♪
♪ Everybody look
What's going down ♪
♪ Oh, everybody look ♪
♪ What a field day ♪
♪ For the heat ♪
♪ Thousands of people
In the street ♪
♪ Singing songs
And carrying signs ♪
♪ Mostly say,
Hooray for our side ♪
♪ I think it's time we stop ♪
♪ Hey, what's that sound? ♪
♪ Everybody look
What's going down ♪
♪ Stop, children,
What's that sound? ♪
♪ Everybody look
What's going down ♪
♪ Paranoia strikes deep ♪
♪ Into your life
It will creep ♪
♪ It starts out
When you're always afraid ♪
♪ You step out of line ♪
♪ The man come,
He might take you away ♪
♪ We gotta stop ♪
♪ Hey, what's that sound? ♪
♪ Everybody look
What's going down ♪
♪ Stop, hey,
What's that sound? ♪
♪ Everybody look
What's going down ♪
♪ Stop, children,
What's that sound? ♪
♪ Everybody look
What's going down ♪
♪ Stop, hey,
What's that sound? ♪
♪ Everybody look
What's going down ♪
♪ Everybody look ♪
♪ What's going down ♪
♪ When it's not too clear ♪
♪ Take a look ♪
Wh... what do you do for fun?
Fun?
Uh, anything we can.
Just kick back,
or hassle tourists.
Hell, we'd watch ice melt
if it was free.
To hell with the devil!
I thank the Lord
you're here tonight.
Yeah!
I pray that you find
what the Lord wants for you.
There is a purpose
for each and every one of you.
Of us!
And remember,
God does not create trash!
♪ So there I was,
Just waxing up my board ♪
Do you have friends?
No, I got a family.
It says here, you haven't
been with a family for...
My friends are my family.
Of course, you can't
trust them for shit,
but, you know,
once you know that,
it's cool.
Greg! J!
♪ While I choked
From the sulfur smell ♪
♪ I said, "Dude,
Where are the chicks?" ♪
Hey, Greg!
Hey, shut up!
♪ You should have listened
To the preacher ♪
♪ No waves to rip
A six-foot swell ♪
♪ Sorry, bud
No surfin' in hell ♪
Who threw that?
He did.
King!
King, man, shit.
Hey, did you miss me?
Why did you
do that, brother?
Because you got
terrible extensions
in your hair.
And 'cause you...
you're ju... you're shitty.
That's not funny.
Why don't you jump, King?
What's a typical King day?
A typical King day?
Mmm.
Well, hit the streets,
hook up with my friends.
You know.
Kick back. Hang out.
Stay out of trouble.
That's it. That's it.
That's it.
Hey, let him go,
you fucking pigs.
Little J.!
Now! I'm not
fucking around, man! Now!
Put that thing down!
You fucking heard me, man!
Now!
You heard me!
Come on, come on!
Come on! Let's go.
They're good people.
You'd like Little J.
He's a little shit, man,
I'm telling you.
- Skinny little fuck.
- Yeah.
He's growing, though.
It's wild.
He's hard to keep fed.
That's a tough habit.
Hey, yo, wait up.
When did you
get out, man?
Just a couple of
short hours ago.
You on the streets,
or are you at home?
Fuck them, man.
I haven't been home
since you got busted.
What the fuck were
you doing back there,
Little J.?
What do you mean?
I was saving
your fucking ass.
Don't pull a gun
on somebody again.
Get the fuck off me.
It was stupid.
It wasn't even loaded.
That's even stupider.
Give it to me.
No.
Yes.
Where did you find
this sissy piece of shit,
anyway?
In the trash, man.
It don't even work.
Ah, it figures.
What the fuck
did you do that for, man?
Your own good.
Fuck you!
I'm out of here.
I think you
pissed him off, man.
Hey, Little J.!
What?
You want that tat still?
What do you think, man?
I've been waiting
two months
for the fucking thing.
Come on, then.
So, how was jail, man?
Boring. Easy.
Did you
suck any cocks?
Just your dad's.
Whoo!
And they're going
into the stretch!
Manny goes for the whip,
makes a bid for the outside!
Whoo!
Go ahead.
Run, motherfucker!
Come on!
How do you
get by on the street?
Excuse me,
I thought we just
went all over that stuff
with the assault,
and the possession,
and the loitering,
all that petty stuff.
Right.
Give it up, motherfucker!
You guys have turkey potpie?
This is, uh, vegetable beef,
and I... I'm allergic
to anything
with lard in it. Or, um...
Do they cook the turkey
with lard?
Coming through!
Watch out! Watch out!
Well, excuse me, sir.
Come on! Let's go! Let's go!
Come on! Come on! Whoo!
Going into the stretch! Whoo!
I did bust your ass, boy.
I told you. You can't fuck
with me in this wheelchair.
See, man, that's
one of the advantages
to being a cripple.
Oh, get the fuck
out of here.
Hey, fuckin'...
You've been in County
too long, King.
How you doing?
What's up, baby?
Hey, you're looking good.
Staying out of trouble, man?
Oh, I'm trying.
I'm trying.
All right.
Let's get off
this street corner.
Hey, you got a smoke?
Yeah, you need one.
Yo, so how was it
up County, man?
What, did you read
a couple of books?
-Yeah.
-Well, did you
lift some weights?
Yeah, a little bit.
-You suck some dicks?
-Now, come on.
It's great having you back,
though, man.
You're looking good.
You still
a ugly motherfucker, though.
Drugs is the toughest habit.
And friends. Friends
are tough to keep, too.
I don't know,
what do you think?
Do you want to
tell me something?
You want to tell me
some kind of little...
Little something
about your day?
A little... a little tidbit?
A little tidbit about you?
About your day.
Well, I'm just...
Looking... looking to
get out of here and hook up.
Ow, man.
-You all right?
-Yeah.
Don't be a puss.
Fuck you.
Yo, King, man,
you gonna crash with us
in the hole tonight?
I mean, we saved
your clothes and shit.
No, I was gonna look
for Devon, maybe get some.
Has anybody seen her?
No, man, I ain't seen her.
What do you mean?
I mean, I ain't
seen her, man.
What the fuck, you guys?
Goddamn!
I told you to
watch out for my lady,
And... and so, what?
Is that... is that
too much to ask or what?
Hey, look, King, man,
um, last time we seen her,
she was with that kid,
Tommy Ray.
I think she's
in his stable.
You've seen Devon
with Tommy Ray?
Yeah, she started
swinging with him
when you got locked up.
Well, just out of curiosity,
were you gonna tell me?
Yeah.
Yeah? When?
I don't know.
Thank God you're back.
Hey, Brenda.
Who are you?
Heather.
You just get here?
Two days ago.
She's from chicago.
Trip out. Me, too.
Bullshit, you're from Phoenix.
Brenda, you know,
the next time I want you
to open your mouth,
I'll... I'll point at you.
Why don't you sit down?
You're making me nervous.
I'm King.
King?
As in what, burger?
He's the one
I told you about.
Yeah, I bet you did.
Hey, y'all,
I was thinking of
maybe going and doing
a little train hopping.
Yeah.
How'd that be?
Cool.
Greg there's got some speed,
don't you, Greg?
I was thinking maybe
we'd get, uh, some pot,
some mushrooms.
I don't know.
Let's get all fucked up.
Yeah, later.
Hey, Crasher, come here.
Come here, man.
So why do you think
so many kids come out here?
Most kids come out to L.A.
looking for Hollywood.
Told you everything
would be cool, didn't I?
Usually, it's not
what they expect.
-You're from Chicago?
-Yeah.
Crasher, I went in lockup
for two months.
I get out, and everything
turns to shit.
I took a zip gun off
of Little J. tonight.
Greg is off
tweaking his brains out.
And where the hell
is my girlfriend?
I don't know.
-Huh?
-I don't know.
Well, what the fuck
do you know about?
Don't look at me
like it's my fault.
Crasher, man,
you fucked me.
I asked you to
look out for everyone.
Yeah, well,
you shouldn't have done that.
That was a mistake.
I mean, shit, man,
nobody listens to me.
You know, you're the one
they listen to.
Shit, I'm older than you
and I don't get
any kind of respect.
Before you start pointing
fingers, you take a look
in that fucking mirror.
That's the guy
you want to blame.
You know, it's pretty lame
how you got busted that way.
You know,
and then you just,
like, disappear,
and figure, well,
I just gonna, like,
keep tabs on everybody.
Well, guess again, pal.
On Devon?
Yeah.
I'm sorry, man,
but it's not my fault.
I didn't have anyone else
I could ask.
What are you doing?
You stink.
That's you, man.
-It's not me.
-It's you.
It's not me.
Someone could be dying
in the fucking streets
and they won't
do a thing.
But if you just
so happen to jaywalk,
ten of them will come
out of the woodwork.
Shit, I got busted
last week for jaywalking.
You got busted
for being too fat.
Shut up, dickhead!
King...
King, uh, the trolls
are partying tonight
at the western squat.
King?
Why doesn't anybody
fucking listen
to me around here?
Hey, mouse.
How old are you?
Almost 18.
How come you
moved to hollyweird?
Just wanted to.
You want to be
a movie star, don't you?
No.
-Yeah, you do.
-No, I don't.
Why not?
I'm gonna be one.
Yeah, after you lose
about 100 pounds.
Brenda, I think you
have star quality.
Yeah, Julia Roberts,
eat your heart out, baby.
Yeah, sleeping
with a fat girl.
-Fuck you!
-Fuck you.
Hey, J., come on.
Why don't you
sit the fuck down.
Don't touch me.
Hey, I heard you had to
sleep with somebody
to get in this joint.
No, I didn't.
Crasher.
Have you seen Devon?
Is she here?
No, I ain't seen her,
But Tommy Ray is over there.
Is that right?
Yeah.
Tommy.
Holy shit!
Well, well, well.
It's the King
And his little
band of butt pirates.
Hey, fuck you, man.
Fuck me?
That's what I got in mind.
Who is this guy
right here?
Hey, you know, for a kid,
you got a great ass.
I could make money
With this kid.
I'm looking for Devon.
Yeah?
Well, who isn't?
Well, I ain't
seen the little cunt.
That's not quite
how I heard it, Tommy.
-Yeah?
-Yeah.
Well, don't believe
everything you hear.
That fucking bitch
was stealing from me.
She stole my radio,
she stole my rock.
So naturally I kicked
the fucking bitch out.
I mean, the last
I heard was
that, uh, she got
her face cut up real bad,
and just...
No, no, no. I know her.
She's not robbing
or stealing or thieving.
Nothing.
So what are you doing?
You calling me a liar?
Hey, Tommy Ray,
you got your whole life
to be an asshole.
Why don't you
take tonight off?
go fuck yourself, huh?
All right, all right,
Get the fuck off of him.
Get off of him.
Be cool. Be cool.
Come on,
where is she?
Hey, why don't you
do me a favor?
Why don't you
bring back your little friend
as soon as he, uh,
gets some pubic hair.
Hey, fuck you, man!
Pubic hair,
that... that's good.
Come on, Greg,
don't be needing that.
Fuck that.
And fuck Tommy Ray!
You shouldn't have
tossed my fucking gun.
I'm glad I did, too.
I feel like killing somebody.
Did your family
live in the hole
which is under
the bridge of the...
Under the freeway, yeah.
But not always there.
It depends on the weather
and, you know,
who's with us
or who's already there,
but that's basically our home.
I'll sleep with you, King.
Oh, Brenda, now that's...
Now, that's sweet.
I'm just not sure
I'm up to the challenge.
Why not, baby?
Because you're too fat
is why not, bitch!
Shut up, fool!
Fuck you, bitch.
I ain't no fool.
Yeah, you are.
You're a scrawny
little piece of shit.
Fuck, he's been here forever.
- Seven years.
-  -I'm sick of you and your trash.
If I want to
sleep with King,
I'll sleep with King.
Keep your butt
out of it.
Just shut the fuck up!
- No!
Hey, J. Stay out
of her hair,
or she's gonna
keep us up all night,
all right.
I know, I know,
I know.
Here. Here.
Hey, where are
you guys staying?
We've been
at the Bowl Motel.
- Shit, who's paying for that?
-  -I paid for it.
Well, I ain't whoring,
if that's what you're asking.
Yeah, sure you ain't.
Listen, you save your money,
this one here will
take you for a ride.
I'm gonna get a job.
And you know shit,
dick-for-brains.
I hope you do.
It's "You know dick,
shit-for-brains."
So get one.
I think either
is correct.
It's a declarative sentence,
so the juxtaposition
of the adjective
is appropriate
in either place.
Hey, nobody here
take any of Heather's money.
I'd take that personal.
Oh, okay, King,
I won't take it from her.
I don't think
that would be right.
Ok, I won't do it.
She's my buddy,
and I'm takin' care of her.
...right?
Hey, Little J.,
what's the aerosol du jour?
I don't know.
Just something
I picked up in 'Nam.
When I was down in County,
Greg came down,
but like he was gonna
get $500 to bail me out?
It's nice, though,
to have somebody
that, uh, wanted to.
Hey!
Hey, what's up?
You want some?
You should try
and get some sleep.
No.
You gonna sleep
With Heather tonight?
Not tonight.
When I went in lockup,
I couldn't sleep
for the first week.
I was used to
the fucking freeway.
Have to get
used to it again.
You having fun?
Yeah, I'm good.
I'm totally fucking tweaked.
Can I scratch that
for you?
Can we do something
tomorrow night?
Yeah.
Can we?
I'd like that.
All right,
I'm out of here, man.
Uh, King.
It's good to
have you back, man.
Thanks.
It makes me feel better,
you know?
Can I have one?
Morning.
Hi.
That's the best I can do.
That's good.
Where did you
learn that?
I don't know. I've just
been doing it forever.
How long you been
picking at your nails?
People can come
into your life,
and you can
become very close,
and then
they're gone in a week,
and you never see them again.
Hmm, how do you
feel about that?
There's nothing
I can do about it.
What were you
locked up for?
Assault
with a deadly weapon.
This bum was
trying to rob me,
so I hit him
with a bottle.
He got three stitches,
and I got three months.
One month suspended.
Brenda said you killed him.
Yeah, well, Brenda,
she says a lot of things.
I'd believe
about none of them.
Could I ask you a favor?
What kind of favor?
Oh, just a simple favor.
Maybe.
So, within your family,
do you have some
kind of code of honor?
Yeah.
Well, what... what is it?
Let's just say
we look out for each other.
Attention, please,
now arriving at gate 5,
bus number 371
from San Francisco.
...please come to
the main ticket counter.
Excuse me.
You got a light on you?
-Got a cigarette?
-Sure.
I thought I was
gonna go fucking nuts.
They don't let you
smoke on the bus.
-Yeah? Long trip, huh?
-Yeah.
Ugh!
Hey, Tommy.
You fucking bastards!
Shit!
You look good, Tommy!
- Fuck you!
- I'm gonna kill him.
Fuck you!
Shit!
Fuck! Fuck!
Fuck! God damn it!
Hey,
sleeping beauty.
Can you
fix this fucker?
What is it?
It's a piece of shit!
I don't know, man.
I could try.
Well, if you can fix it,
you got a quarter of meth, man.
Move over.
Shit, I'd do it for that.
Put on a goddamn shirt.
Oh, why don't you?
Where's the milk? Goddamn.
Fuck, I just fucking
bought this yesterday.
You know, I'm sick of this.
Nobody should be allowed
In this refrigerator
except us.
Climb in and shut
the fucking door.
No, fuck you!
Fuckin' shit!
Fuck.
You want to
slam a speedball?
No, man.
My treat.
No, fuck that, man.
No needles.
Good boy. Just say no.
I say yeah.
When's the last time
you ate?
Yesterday.
Fuck. I can't get
this stupid fucking thing.
J., no, give it up, man.
You're never gonna get it.
Yeah.
You want
another burger?
Yeah.
I'll take one, too, buddy.
Fuck you, Little Buddy.
So, you want to spend
the night with me, baby?
He likes you.
Oh, yeah?
Definitely.
How can you tell?
I can tell
by the way he's acting.
He's trying to be all cool.
I think she's right.
Besides, you're
a dead ringer for Devon.
Who's that?
His ex-old lady.
He killed her.
Really?
Yeah, just fucking stabbed
her right in the gut
and cut her up
in little pieces.
But don't tell him
I told you that.
It could... it could
get a little messy.
I won't.
He's very touchy about it.
You know, who knows
when he might strike again.
He's lethal.
Here you go.
Thanks.
Hey, Brenda,
I bought that for her.
Don't you share?
so, what's the first thing
you learn on the street?
You try not to get
too high, or too low.
You just learn
to watch your back.
Oh, shit. Oh, fuck.
I'm telling you,
this is crazy.
What happens
if you miss?
Then you die, baby.
You're not gonna die.
I mean, you might.
- J.
- What?
Here it comes!
♪ It's so hard ♪
♪ To listen to these trains ♪
♪ Outside my window ♪
♪ Here it comes again ♪
♪ And it's calling me,
Begging me ♪
♪ Follow me ♪
You guys go ahead.
I'll wait for her.
♪ And it moans so ♪
Let's go!
♪ Baby ain't comin' back ♪
♪ Well, I refuse to believe ♪
♪ It could happen to me ♪
Oh, yeah!
♪ And you ♪
Come on!
Okay. It's our turn.
Let's go. You can do it.
I can't!
Yes, you can.
If you can't,
then you got to anyway.
Let's go.
We got to go now.
♪ It got this whiskey ♪
♪ To take care of my lips ♪
♪ I got these
Long, cool steel strings ♪
Hey, Little J.!
Where's the beer?
Um, they were...
They were all out!
What do we do now?
♪ I ain't got nothing
To soothe my aching soul ♪
Whoo-hoo!
♪ Except this screeching
And screaming iron ♪
♪ To tell me
Where I ought to go ♪
♪ Well, I refuse to believe ♪
♪ It could happen to me ♪
♪ And you ♪
Whoo!
♪ Well, it's lonesome
And it's hard ♪
♪ And it's true ♪
♪ And I hear the train sigh ♪
♪ And idle ♪
So, when you guys
don't stay in shelters,
and you don't
have a curfew,
that's the kind of
thing you do at night?
Yeah, you know, just...
Kicking back, fucking around,
just trying to...
Trying to have fun.
Like kids do,
you know, like kids.
These kids are kids.
Come on, man. Fuck.
Fuck it, will you come on?
Hold on. Fuck, fuck.
God damn it.
Fuck! Come on, bro.
I'm comin'.
Fuck. Come on, come on.
It's about
fucking time, man.
Fuck.
You got a light?
I got high the first time
when I was eight.
Ever take heroin?
No. I never shot heroin.
But you did other drugs?
Well, pot, alcohol, meth,
mushrooms, acid.
I had a great trip on
Hollywood boulevard one time.
I was, like, trying to scrape
the stars off the sidewalk.
It was totally wild.
You do this?
A couple of years ago.
It's beautiful.
So, what, you've been
here about seven years?
Yeah.
In L.A.
Three or four here in the hole.
On and off.
You want to go
sit over here?
-Why?
-Why not?
You're a little edgy,
aren't you?
Well, maybe I am.
I mean, what's this I hear
about you
killing your girlfriend?
It's a joke?
Oh, hey.
Hey!
Um, I think we're gonna
go back to my van.
We got to get something
straight between us.
Why don't you
come over here
and sit by me?
What's wrong?
Nothing. I... I just
don't want to do any more.
I'm sorry, I didn't
mean to scare you.
What the hell
do you want to do?
Sleep.
Come to think of it,
I'm kind of tired myself,
I guess.
Here,
take my sleeping bag.
Make yourself comfortable.
It's okay.
No, it's okay.
I got an extra one.
It's gonna be real cold.
-Are you sure?
-Yeah.
Thanks.
I got 98.6 over here,
by the way.
Body temperature.
That's really great.
Here, bro, take this.
Fuck.
Oh, shit, man.
That's the new B.M.W.
No, don't fuck
with that, man.
That one's alarmed.
Yeah, man.
Yo, fuck,
get out of here, man!
Little J.'s
kind of an artist, though.
A graffiti artist. Yeah.
You've probably seen
his tag all over town.
It's like an "L"
with a wide bottom
that goes into a "J."
L. J.
It's all up and down Cahuenga.
Every block.
One night he said
he was gonna get every block
up to the freeway.
And he did.
Fuck! Fuck!
Ah, you little fucker!
Hey, little fucker!
Come here, come here.
Come here.
Problem?
Yeah, one named Little J.
-Fucking asshole!
-What did he do?
He almost
got us busted, man,
then he dropped
the fucking stereos
that we already fucking had!
Come here.
Leave him alone,
You're stronger than he is.
Fuck you!
I'm out of here!
Where you going?
What the fuck
do you care, man?
I give you guys everything.
My money, my fucking drugs,
and all you do is stick up
for this little faggot!
Forget about it!
Fuck you,
I'm out of here!
Fucking speed freak.
Shut up, J.
Shut up.
Go to bed.
Is she
staying with us, too?
Just go to bed.
♪ What's going ♪
♪ Hey, hey ♪
Excuse me, can you
spare some change?
A penny?
Anything, please?
Excuse me, do you know
What time it is?
Can you spare some change
so me and my sister can
get something to eat?
Excuse me, sir,
Could you
spare a little change
so my father and I could eat?
Fuck you, "your father." You
Axl Rose-looking-motherfucker.
I ain't your
fucking father, man.
Got any
spare coins, bitch?
Please,
give me some money!
Excuse me, sir,
could you spare some change
so I can give
my horse some feed?
Just a little
something, sir.
Thank you very much.
He's got
an unfair advantage.
Hello, officers.
Why don't you
cut the bullshit?
Were you down
at the bus station yesterday?
No, I wasn't at the station.
No, I wasn't.
You're on parole,
aren't you?
Yes, sir.
And I'm obeying all
the terms of my parole,
I assure you.
Let's hope so.
Why don't you get
your butt off my car?
Yes, sir.
Get out of here.
What's your name, miss?
Heather.
My mother would die
if she knew I was
being harassed by cops.
She says you have to
contribute to society.
Your mother
talks a lot of shit.
Yeah.
I'm sure
she's a very nice lady.
She's got
to be real pretty.
What's one of my lines?
Yeah,
what's one of your lines?
Buddy,
can you spare a dime?
That one
doesn't usually work.
But, no, you can say
pretty much anything.
People, you know, they can
tell when you need money.
And when I get money,
I give it to somebody
that's less fortunate than me.
So, I figure, it goes around.
Is Ted here?
- Ted!
- Who is it?
Greg.
Aspirin?
No, man.
I'm trying to quit.
So, what do you need, huh?
More meth?
Yeah, man.
That shit will drive
you crazy after a while.
Sure you don't want
to slam one of these?
No, man.
Suit yourself.
Just say no.
Here you go, man.
Hey.
Where's the cash
you owe me, huh?
Man, I'll... I'll get it.
Come back when you do.
Well, I was thinking
you could front me a bit.
Oh, no can do, bro.
Can't do that no more.
Times are changing.
Well, maybe I could make
a run for you again.
Like I did that one time.
Just get the cash you owe me
and take a shower.
You really stink.
Now, out of here.
Come on.
You do spare-changing,
and stuff like that,
but you don't
walk the streets.
What does
"walk the streets" mean?
It means I never had to
fuck anybody for money.
But you've seen
lots of kids do it.
Yeah.
You see lots of kids do it.
Boys and girls. You know,
when they're growing up,
they never think that
that's how
it's gonna turn out
and they wake up one morning,
and then, there they are,
doing it, you know.
- Hey, Kimmy.
- Hey, Little J.
Where you staying?
The Hills Motel.
How many people you got?
-Five.
-Who?
Some of Rob's
asshole friends.
How much you paying?
Seven bucks. Unless a trick
buys it for us.
-Can I use your shower?
-Yeah.
-Hello? Hi, is Dave there?
-Can I use your shower?
Yeah. Go ahead.
Go for it. Go.
All right.
Thank you.
Hi, yeah, Dave.
Hi, it's Kimmy.
Do, uh, you want to
have a date tonight?
It's that first time
that gets 'em.
I've seen 'em.
I've just never
had a first time.
Where are all
the hookers at?
Well, most of
the scuzzy ones
work downtown
or in the valley.
But a lot of them
go through those
escort services.
Excuse me, sir,
Me and my sister
haven't had something to eat
for a couple of days.
Could you help us out?
Thanks.
-King?
-Hmm?
-Have you ever...
-No. No.
Not unless you count
sleeping with some girl
just to have a place
to lay your head down,
shut your eyes.
Know what I mean?
No.
Good.
Oh, my goodness,
What's that?
So what happens
when the cops bust a squat?
Uh, well...
Usually they're pretty cool,
but I have to get
the kids out of there
'cause they'll run them
through missing person
rr runaway, you know.
They'll just
send them on home.
I wouldn't let any
of my friends go home.
It's worse there.
I swear.
And the hardwood floors
were redone about a year ago.
Kellin, can I call you back?
Someone's at my back door.
Okay, thanks, bye-bye.
Well, look who
we have here.
You've been gone, what,
two months this time?
Greg, can I ask you
how long you plan
on staying?
Greg, talk to me!
-Shut up!
-Greg!
I'm calling your father!
Fuck you!
I mean, I wouldn't let
any of my friends go home.
Hey, thanks
for the shower, man.
You look like
a drowned fucking rat.
-Hey, Rob, how old are you?
-What's it to you?
I don't know.
Just asking.
I'm 22, but I could
Pass for 17. Why?
I need to buy some bullets,
But they won't
sell them to me.
What do you
need them for?
Ah.
Let me see that.
See with your eyes,
not with your hands.
You're an asshole.
Will you buy 'em?
I mean, I got the money.
Well, maybe,
if you do something for me.
Like what?
I got this trick later,
but I don't want to see him.
I'm busy.
Maybe you can go
in my place.
No way, man,
I'm not down for that shit.
He's a cool old guy,
he won't even touch you.
You don't need to
touch him or nothing.
No.
Okay.
Sure is a sweet gun.
I mean,
what's the use of a gun
if you ain't got no bullets?
It's pretty fresh.
Okay, it's your loss.
I mean,
it sure is a shame
you don't got any ammo
for that fresh gun.
Fucking dick.
Cheap piece of shit.
Greg?
Greg,
can you open the door?
Greg.
Open the door, son.
What do you want, dad?
Your stepmom and I want to
talk to you downstairs.
Dad, we got
nothing to say, man.
Just open the door,
I want to speak
with you downstairs.
Open the door!
What do you
fucking want?
We want to talk
with you downstairs.
I don't see what there is
to talk about.
I'm 17 years old.
I can do...
What the fuck
is he doing here?
Greg, you're under arrest
for grand theft.
I didn't
steal a fucking thing!
You took the jewelry.
You get what you deserve, Greg!
- Fucking bitch!
You put him up to this!
You need help!
God damn it!
You're quite young,
aren't you?
Yeah.
I, uh, sell those.
if you ever need one,
just let me know.
Okay.
Well, uh...
Could I get you something?
Maybe a coke or some juice?
An ashtray
would be nice, thanks.
Now look, nobody
smokes in this house.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Look, I got to
get going in a while.
Why don't we take care
of business, all right?
Business?
Yeah, you know, uh...
A jerk-off or...
whatever turns you on.
Could I ask you
a question?
Yeah.
When was the first time
you had sex?
I was about, uh, about 12.
Who was it with?
This chick at school.
When was the first time
you had sex with a man?
About 10 or 11, I guess.
So, you had sex with a guy
before you had
sex with a girl.
Yeah.
Who was it with?
My uncle.
Oh.
Look,
I know you're paying me,
but what is this crap?
Did you enjoy it?
Do you want to talk,
or what?
What if I were to ask you
if I could touch your face?
Would that be
all right?
Would you mind?
No, whatever.
This is a good place
to know about.
You can come in the afternoon,
get something to eat,
some nights you can get a bed
if it's not too crowded.
They got
a lot of rules, though.
I think
I broke most of them.
You got to sign in.
I can't stay, I got to
go to this interview.
They got me being
this community service
guinea pig.
Can I be your habitrail?
Yeah, we'll see.
Hi, sorry I'm late.
That's okay.
So, what's the topic today?
Well, what do you
want to talk about?
What? Are you
out of questions already?
Hmm.
Have you seen this one?
Yeah, I saw that.
You did? How about this one?
Heads or tails?
Heads.
Cheating.
Yeah, we got that one.
I know,
I'll show you my tattoos.
Wow!
You like that?
That's great.
I got one
on my right arm, too.
Mmm.
I did that myself,
left-handed.
Wow.
My dad did this one
when I was 14.
Really?
Do you still
keep in touch with him?
What happened?
I don't know. Um...
I don't know, he's probably
dead or something.
See, uh, tattoos
weren't his only thing.
He had a taste
for all kinds of needles.
You're feeling
pretty good these days?
Yeah, I'm feeling
pretty good these days.
You got
a little cough, though.
Some days I feel good,
some days I don't,
like everybody else.
Yeah, actually I get along
with them really well.
I needed a short break
or something, I think.
Okay, you ready to go?
-Yeah.
-I see you met Stephanie.
-Come on.
-Thanks.
See you later.
Faggot.
Fucking fag.
Fuck.
So, what are
your drugs of choice?
-Um, crystal.
-Hmm.
Pot sometimes.
Coke, if I can get it.
Mmm.
When did you, uh,
start using?
When I was about 10 or 11.
It says here, uh...
the first time you ran away
you were nine.
You ran to your mother.
Why the hell did you do that?
I wanted
to live with her,
but her and I
don't get along so good.
Hmm.
What about your father,
you, uh, like him?
Yeah, he's all right.
But he got you arrested.
Yeah, well, life goes on.
Yeah, life goes on.
You know, I got to tell you,
you're... you're a very
lucky guy, you know that?
See, you've been given
a second chance here.
You could have just gone
straight to a lockup,
but you're in a rehab.
I got to be honest with you,
uh, I'm a little hesitant
to take you in.
See, you have this
habit of running away.
I mean, what's my guarantee
that you're not
gonna run from us, huh?
Well, I need help
with my problem.
Excuse me, miss,
can you spare some change?
All I want is
a little something to eat.
Skank!
How you doing, cripple?
Tommy, get your
stinking-ass breath
out of my face.
Let's take a little ride.
Hey, Tommy,
get the fuck off me.
Tommy,
Get the fuck off me!
You're infringing on
my fucking Civil Rights, man.
Shut the fuck up.
Get off me. fucking bitch.
Get off of me, man.
Calm down.
Tommy, leave me
the fuck alone, man!
I didn't
do shit to you, man!
Tommy, leave me
the fuck alone!
Get off me!
Relax, asshole,
I'm just looking for King.
Have you seen him?
I think I did see King,
I think he went
down to the corner.
You know,
your grandma is down there
spit-shining dicks again.
There's a deal
on balls today,
two for the price of one.
Hey, man,
get the fuck off me!
I asked you a question.
Didn't you hear me?
Yeah, I fucking heard you.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, asshole.
No!
Just, "Yes, sir."
Yes, sir.
That's better.
Where do I find King?
Down at the hole.
The hole.
Nice hat.
You know, Tommy,
you're a punk bitch!
Oh, yeah.
Almost forgot something.
Hello, family.
Hello, Cynthia.
We're taking away
radio privileges
until you can learn
what being a family is.
Also,
welcome a new family member.
Say hello to Greg.
Hello, Greg.
What's up?
Hey, where's King?
He's up there, man.
King. King, get up.
King, get up.
Help! Somebody help!
Help!
Leave him alone!
Leave him alone! Help!
Are you okay?
King? No!
Oh, fuck.
J....
♪ Everybody's got ♪
Hey, King?
♪ A hunger ♪
♪ No matter where they are ♪
Are you okay?
Come on.
Come on, let's go.
♪ Everybody clings ♪
Shit!
♪ To their own fear ♪
♪ Everybody hides some scar ♪
♪ Mmm ♪
♪ Precious pain ♪
♪ Empty and cold ♪
♪ But it keeps me alive ♪
♪ I gave it my soul ♪
♪ So that I could survive ♪
♪ Keeping me safe
In these chains ♪
♪ Precious pain ♪
Ah, shit.
You okay?
Yeah, it's okay.
What are you doing?
I got to see what's
keeping Crasher so long.
It's okay, I'll do that,
okay, stay here.
♪ Each road that I walk down ♪
♪ Reminds me of you ♪
♪ This whole town is haunted ♪
♪ There'll never be
Anything new ♪
♪ Precious pain ♪
Oh, god.
♪ Empty and cold ♪
Come on.
What, what is it?
We got to get
out of here, okay.
Give me your arm.
Crasher's in trouble.
♪ Keeping me safe
in these chains ♪
♪ Precious pain ♪
You have trouble
with the cops?
You got to
always watch the cops.
They're gonna bust
you for loitering,
just so they can
find out who you are.
I always tell the kids
to stay off the streets
until after school's out,
it's easier.
What do you really feel
about me coming in here,
asking you questions,
putting it on tape?
Well, I feel like
I have to, but...
I feel better about it
than I thought
I was going to.
You know that
runaway shelter?
They got this thing,
this...
This program
where they contact
kids' parents
and they arrange it
So that they can
go back home.
So?
So you can
go back to Chicago.
I think you should.
I don't want to go back.
Do you want me to go back?
I think it might
be a good idea.
You don't seem to realize
we're in a lot of trouble.
I know that.
Why are you
acting like a jerk?
'Cause you're an asshole,
that's why.
I'm not trying
to be an asshole.
I'm just trying
to live my life
the way I fucking want to.
You know,
everything is fucked up.
This world's fucked up!
It's fucked up.
And everybody's miserable,
and they're only happy
if you're miserable, too.
Lady, will you kindly get out
of my motherfucking face?
Shit!
Did you have to
be so rude to her?
Rude? Who's rude?
You are! Can you blame
the little lady
for looking at you?
I'm looking at you.
you look like a fucking fool,
you got spit
coming from your mouth.
Can you yell a little louder?
Yell a little louder,
come on, come on.
Sorry. Shit.
It's okay.
But I'm not leaving town
unless you're coming with.
Sorry, lady.
You're mad.
You're embarrassing,
get away from me.
What the fuck
are you doing here?
He's staying with us,
I told you that.
You told me fucking shit!
I did fucking
tell you three times.
He's staying with us,
he's helping with the rent!
Oh, yeah?
Chill out, man.
Shut the fuck up!
Calm down.
You're a slut.
You little slut.
Fuck you!
Seven bucks, you got it?
No, not yet.
Well, then go get it.
Did you smoke my pot?
-No.
-You fucking
better not have.
Get the fuck off me!
Shut the fuck up!
Shut up!
What the fuck
are you looking at?
♪ Saw you with
Your new friends ♪
♪ You wear them so well ♪
Excuse me, sir,
do you have any change?
♪ Broken shoes
And loose ends ♪
Hi, little girl.
♪ Gee, you look swell ♪
♪ I'm only lonely ♪
Do you happen to have
any money on you?
Some change,
or a dollar or something?
♪ Driving in my car ♪
♪ I'm only lonely ♪
Could you spare change?
Nothing?
I just want to get
some money together.
♪ I'm only lonely ♪
Any change
so I can get some food?
♪ Watching my TV ♪
Sir, I hate to bother you,
I'm just trying
to get some...
♪ I'm only lonely
Occasionally ♪
Mom, I can't,
not with him there.
No, mom,
I got to go, all right?
I just wanted to call you
and tell you I'm fine.
Bye, mom.
♪ I'm only lonely ♪
♪ After dark ♪
♪ When I watch my TV ♪
♪ I'm only lonely ♪
♪ Occasionally ♪
How do you feel?
I slept.
How did you do?
No shit?
That's like thirty bucks.
We should have been
down here the whole time.
Pretty good, huh?
I'd say it's incredible.
Now we can eat,
I'm starving.
We can get a motel room.
Shit, that's
a waste of money.
Well, I earned it,
so end of discussion.
Well, I guess
you're the boss.
-Yeah.
-Is that right?
Come on.
You okay?
Ow! Ow!
Whoo, oh, my goodness.
Oh, my goodness.
This is great!
Nine-point-two.
Listen, I... I can
wash all my stuff,
I can watch TV,
I'm in a bed,
I can watch
Laverne and Shirley.
What?
Nothing,
it's... it's just nice
to see you so happy.
Well?
Nothing, it's nice.
You're...
- What?
- Nothing.
Ok, I'm gonna go
take a shower.
-Yeah, me, too.
-You go first.
No, go ahead.
- No, go.
- After you.
No, go, you smell.
- No, you...
Come on,
you had to have known.
You stink.
Take off the hat.
A pimp named
Tommy Ray white
was killed last night.
Oh, that's terrible.
No, not really,
but we do need
some information.
I don't know
anything about it.
I'm not saying you do,
but we hope your friend
King might.
We just want
to talk to him.
Just talk, that's all.
You think you might be
able to tell him that,
next time you see him?
Yeah, sure,
I can tell him that.
I mean,
if I see him, you know.
You'll see him.
What's wrong?
Where the fuck did
Little J. get a gun?
I told him not
to fuck with guns.
Oh, man. Fuck.
Here, let me help.
Yeah.
Jesus!
Yeah, he got me,
the bastard.
I mean, what do
you think happened?
Do you think he died?
Maybe.
It's gonna be okay.
No, it's not okay.
It's not okay.
We're sitting in this motel
like nothing's wrong,
and Crasher's in
fucking jail for all I know.
Where's Little J.?
It's not okay.
I'm sorry.
It's not supposed to be
like this at all.
I'm sorry.
Oh, shit.
Have a seat up here.
I'm sorry,
I forgot.
I was just, uh...
What do you need?
Nothing.
You know,
I do have a spare bedroom
if I thought
I could trust you.
Well, I suppose you could
stay here a few days.
Would you like that?
That'd be great.
♪ Precious pain ♪
♪ Empty and cold ♪
♪ Keeps me alive ♪
♪ I gave it my soul ♪
♪ But I could survive ♪
♪ Keeping me safe
In these chains ♪
♪ Precious pain ♪
Hey, man.
What do you need?
I thought maybe I could
get a little taste, man.
You got money?
Not on me, man.
What are you
doing here, man?
I thought...
No.
♪ Precious pain ♪
Why don't you ever ask me
anything about myself?
Like what?
I just met you.
I don't know.
Like, anything.
Like why I left home,
what my family's like,
how I got here?
I know why
you left home.
Think you're
pretty clever, huh?
No.
No, really?
I bet you've known
a lot of girls like me.
No, I haven't.
So, tell me,
why did I leave home?
Man, forget about it.
No, really,
I'd like to know.
One or two reasons.
Either your father
molested you,
or your stepfather did.
You're a jerk.
Why else
would you be here?
That painting's
really spooky.
Yeah, it's freaky,
it looks like the devil.
It looks like
the Grim Reaper.
My father didn't fuck me,
my brother did.
So, a lot you know.
I'm sorry.
I am.
Open the fucking register!
-Get out of here!
-Fuck you!
Motherfucker,
sit down, back off!
Stay the fuck down!
Fuck you!
I call the police on you,
motherfucker!
Checkout time
was half hour ago.
Oh, shit.
Oh.
I think we should
get up and go
and get some more money
like we did yesterday.
It was so good
on the pier...
Listen. Listen.
That money,
that's some of the money
I had with me from Chicago.
Oh.
I didn't make anything
on the pier.
Why did you lie to me?
I don't know, maybe
I just thought I had to.
I can't stand it.
What are you mumbling about?
I don't want
you to be me.
What are you talking about?
I don't want you
to be me, mouse.
I... I see people on
the street every day,
and then I just see myself
and I don't want to see you.
I don't want to see
that happen to you.
It won't happen to me.
It won't happen
to us, I promise.
Collect call from Greg.
Hello?
Hi, mom.
Greg, Greg, where are you?
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Greg, are you all right?
I love you.
Greg. Greg.
Do you skateboard?
Yeah, well, I used to
when I lived in Boston.
How long you live there?
About, uh, 13 years,
then I moved to
New York for a while,
and then I came here.
Did you
like New York?
No.
Well, you're a long way
from Boston.
Yeah.
Why did you leave?
I broke my probation.
Yeah? What did you do?
Assault and battery.
But that's bullshit,
I never should
have gotten it.
All I did was
hit this teacher
after she tried to hit me
and she never got in
trouble for it, fat bitch.
If I saw her again,
I swear to god, I'd hit her.
Jesus Christ, man,
you look like shit.
So, your old man
got you busted, huh?
Ah, yeah.
Man, life is
a real bitch.
How long since
you slept, anyway?
I don't know, four days?
You gotta sleep, man.
Ah, it's too hard, man.
It's too hard.
You want some vodka?
No, fuck that.
I could do that all night,
that ain't gonna help.
So, what do you
want me to do about it?
You want some help?
Huh?
Yeah.
What?
Yeah, I do.
All right.
Only doing this
so you can sleep.
Starting tomorrow,
I want you to cut down
on your speed.
Cheap-ass drug, man.
Does it hurt?
Man, is it
gonna hurt?
No.
Lights out, boy.
You got the law after you.
What?
Yeah, they think
you killed Tommy Ray.
Me?
I didn't kill him.
I didn't touch anybody.
-I know you didn't.
-He didn't do anything.
I know you didn't.
I'm gonna kill Little J.
Oh, man, I can't
go back to jail. I... I can't.
What are you gonna do?
I don't know.
Well, I'm leaving.
Where are you going?
Dallas.
Yeah, Dallas.
You ought to come with me,
too. It's great there, man.
Yeah, we should.
You wanna go
to Dallas?
I'm gonna get myself
a big old lady
with some fucking gnarly,
fucking...
You know what I mean?
Maybe a couple a pit bulls?
How'd that be, huh?
Sounds good,
doesn't it?
I don't know.
Well, don't think
about it too long, King.
'Cause as soon
as I score some speed,
like I need it, I'm off
like a bride's nightie.
What's that smell?
That's you, motherfucker.
-That is you.
-That's you.
That's you.
You smell very bad.
It's you.
You're handsome devil,
but you stink.
You stink.
No, seriously, though,
man, you all ought
to come with me.
Fuck, I'll tell you what.
Why don't you
meet me back here
in, say, like a half hour?
Come on, man,
Let's go!
You're right.
Fuck this place.
I gotta get out, too.
We'll get
Little J. and Greg,
and maybe we'll come.
Yeah.
Anyway, if I don't see you,
it's good knowing you.
Yeah, you... you, too.
Yeah. Have a good life.
It's nice to
meet you, Heather.
Take care.
Later days
and better lays,
you all.
You didn't
do shit.
Yeah, well,
that doesn't matter.
I want you out of here.
I want you out of here now!
I heard you the first time!
No, don't hurt me.
Don't hurt me.
Please, don't hurt me.
Who's gonna make who
like chicken fingers, hmm?
Oh, fuck.
You gave me shit, man.
What the fuck
are you talking about?
You tried to cheat me,
motherfucker!
You gave me shit!
Dig this, man!
I don't cheat nobody!
You wanna buy it
from somebody else,
kid, you do it.
'Cause I don't want to
sell to you no more.
I'm sorry,
I'm sorry, Ted.
You just can't
handle it, man.
-I can.
-Sit down.
I'm sorry, man.
I... I didn't mean it, man.
I'm sorry.
You're practically
my brother, man.
If I would have known you
couldn't handle the smack,
I never would have given it.
I can handle it.
The fuck you can!
Look at you.
You stink, man.
What the hell is
wrong with you?
Nothing.
Nothing! Fuck that!
I'll tell you
what's wrong with you.
You're a spoiled little shit
who's ended up on the streets
and thinks he's a bad man
with an attitude.
You're nothing but a punk,
man. That's it!
A punk who can't
handle his drugs!
Fucking pathetic.
All right. From now on
it's cash only.
Maybe that'll help you
slow down a little.
You still got cash,
don't you?
All right.
What do you want?
A quarter?
No, I'll give you
a $20 piece.
That's it.
Okay.
Show me your cash.
Have you seen him?
You just missed him,
too bad for you.
He had a bunch of money,
bought me all this food.
Where'd he go?
Hey, hey!
To score some speed
from Ted.
Shit. Thanks.
Young love. Sheesh!
You just do like
we said, all right?
Okay.
Just leave it to me.
You stay in the hall.
You got your money?
Right here.
Is he here?
Ted.
Look out, Vikki.
What the fuck? Ted!
Ted, where's Greg?
Greg's here, I know he is.
What can
I do for you, man?
Just stay the fuck
out of my face.
Sure.
Greg.
Shit!
What the hell
are you doing?
-Hey, King.
-What are you doing?
What's up, bro? What?
Look at yourself.
What?
How do you feel?
It's cool, man.
It's not cool, Greg!
We're in big trouble,
all right?
Little J., Heather, and I
are leaving on a bus tomorrow.
What happened?
Somebody got shot, all right.
You're coming with us.
Where're we gonna go?
I don't know.
Someplace cheap.
We... we'll just get on a bus
and go where it's going, okay?
What do you say?
Will we be together?
Yeah, all of us.
All right?
Okay.
All right. Just get, uh,
just get your shirt on.
I can't, wait.
I'm too high for the street.
Listen, you'll do
what I tell you to do,
when I tell you to do it.
I'm too high, man.
Listen.
Look, no more drugs.
Here, take my money.
This doesn't
mean anything to me.
I can't believe
a word you're saying.
On my honor.
I just need to know
you're gonna be there.
On my honor,
I'll be there.
I'm trusting you.
I promise.
All right.
Noon. Noon.
-What? What am I...
-What's wrong?
I tell Greg...
Where are we gonna go?
What city?
We just gonna pick a city?
What's gonna change?
Maybe we'll find
a freeway underpass,
or a nice squat.
Maybe I'll just
get my shit together
and get a job!
I told Greg that
everything would be fine.
I have no right.
I can't promise anything.
No, you can't.
You can't promise
anything to anybody.
You mean the world
to them.
I just want them to see
how to look out for
themselves better.
They love you.
I...
Little J.,
are you home?
Little J.?
Where you been?
Are you okay?
Yeah. No, man.
What are...
Fuck! Man,
I didn't mean to shoot him.
I fucked
everything up for us.
I'm sorry, man.
I'm fucking sorry. Fuck!
Fuck! Fuck!
Man, I'm fucking sorry.
I didn't mean to
fucking shoot him, man.
-I know, J.
-He tried to kill me.
You saved my life.
What the fuck,
what are we gonna do?
Cool it.
J., what?
We're leaving.
We're splitting town.
You're gonna
come with us, okay?
Where? Where the fuck
are we going, King?
-Listen to me.
-What the fuck
do we have? No!
J. I'll take care
Of you, J.
Listen.
What?
I'll take care of you.
Will you come with us?
Come on, J. Come on.
Come with us.
Yeah.
Good. Come on.
Fuck!
Hey, hold up there.
Police officers.
Wanna ask you
a couple of questions.
Why?
Got a couple of
questions to ask you.
I didn't do anything.
That's all right.
God damn it!
Get up!
I didn't do anything!
What are you
running for?
Shut up! Shut up!
Jesus fucking Christ.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Look, we're not gonna
take you in.
We just wanna ask you
a couple of questions,
that's all.
Where the fuck is King?
I don't know King.
You're a fucking liar.
I never heard...
I don't know who King is.
You're a fucking liar!
He's a friend of yours.
You're lying.
Where's King?
I ain't seen him.
Oh, yeah,
what were you running for?
What do you got on you?
I swear to God.
I ain't seen him
since he's been in jail.
What's that, huh?
You're a lowlife scumbag,
you know that?
All you had to do was share
a little information,
where King was.
Now you got
a real problem.
What do you want
from me?
You're going to jail.
You have the right
to remain silent.
If give up that right,
anything you say
can and will be used
against you in a court of law.
♪ I say ♪
♪ Goodbye ♪
You did the right thing,
talking to the cops.
You save yourself.
Save yourself.
Hey,
fuck King, man.
Fuck him.
You did the right thing,
little bro.
Come to me, okay?
Good. Good.
What have you got?
They want more.
♪ Come on, love,
Come on, man ♪
No, J., you gotta roll
it over your knuckles.
You'll get it when
you get a little older.
bus number 420...
We can't wait.
We gotta go.
What about Greg?
We can't wait.
Let's go.
...is now boarding to gate G.
♪ I'm gonna ride ♪
Which way
to departures?
Shit.
Where the hell is Greg?
You guys wait here,
I'm gonna check again.
♪ Come on, baby ♪
♪ Let's get out of this town ♪
♪ I got a full tank of gas ♪
This is the final call
for bus number 420.
Service to Riverside,
Indio...
Fuck, Greg.
♪ I don't wanna be
Left alone ♪
♪ So, baby, you can sleep
While I drive ♪
♪ I'll pack my bags ♪
♪ And load up my guitar ♪
Oh, shit.
I fucking did it.
♪ Here, in my heart ♪
♪ I got some money I saved ♪
♪ Enough to get underway ♪
♪ And baby, you can sleep
While I drive ♪
Hey, King,
I did it.
Hey, freeze!
Don't move.
♪ We'll go through Tucson
Up to Santa Fe ♪
♪ And Barbara in Nashville ♪
♪ Says we're welcome to stay ♪
♪ I'll buy you glasses
In Texas ♪
♪ A hat from New Orleans ♪
♪ In the morning,
You can't tell me ♪
Put the gun down, son.
Come on,
put it down.
Don't. Little J.,
put down the gun.
Don't make a mistake, son.
Don't, don't.
Come on, put it down.
Put down the gun!
What are you doing?
Fuck that, man!
Fuck them!
Don't, man!
Don't do it.
♪ You've been looking
For something ♪
♪ That's not in your life ♪
♪ My intentions are true ♪
♪ Won't you take me with you ♪
♪ And baby, you can sleep
While I drive ♪
♪ Oh, is it other arms
You want ♪
♪ To hold you ♪
♪ The stranger ♪
♪ The lover, you're free ♪
♪ Can't you get that with me ♪
♪ Come on, baby ♪
♪ Let's get out of this town ♪
♪ I got a full tank of gas ♪
♪ With the top rolled down ♪
♪ If you won't take me
With you ♪
♪ I'll go before
Night is through ♪
♪ Baby, you can sleep
While I drive ♪
How do you see your future
on the street?
What do you mean?
Do you see yourself
always on the street?
Or do you see
yourself getting off it?
If you got a plan,
i'm willing to listen.
I'm just trying to,
You know, it's like,
what about love?
What about it?
What if you fell in
love with something?
Wouldn't that
make a difference?
Yeah. In fact,
I got somebody now.
Who?
His name's Waldo.
Big, cute black guy.
I met him in the cellblock.
Really?
Yeah, sure.
No, just some chick I met.
Tell me about her.
No.
Why not?
Because! Because
what's mine is mine.
And if I share it with you,
then it becomes less mine.
You understand?
Her name's Heather.
She's very beautiful.
So you got it out of me.
You're such a character, King.
Fuck that.
Look, can I get my $10
and get the hell
out of here, please?
Why, sure.
I think it was
a really good
session today.
Good.
Are you okay?
I'm fine.
You got a cigarette?
Uh, yeah.
Thanks.
Are you sure
you're okay?
It's been a long time.
Look, I know
you just turned 18.
I don't know your history.
But maybe you want to think
about giving home a try.
My home's here.
Okay.
He's ready.
♪ There's something
Happening here ♪
♪ What it is
Ain't exactly clear ♪
♪ There's a man
With a gun over there ♪
♪ Telling me
I got to beware ♪
♪ I think it's time we stop
Children, what's that sound? ♪
♪ Everybody look
What's going down ♪
So, what's up?
You always been
such a pain in the ass?
Yeah.
♪ There's battle lines
eing drawn ♪
♪ Nobody's right ♪
♪ If everybody's wrong ♪
♪ Young people speaking ♪
Excuse me,
you got a dime,
a nickel?
♪ Are getting
So much resistance ♪
Hey, how was it?
Suck any cocks?
Just your dad's.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Could you spare
some change
for me
and my little brother?
♪ What a field day
For the heat ♪
♪ A thousand people
In the street ♪
♪ Singing songs
And carrying signs ♪
♪ Mostly say,
Hooray for our side ♪
♪ It's time we stop ♪
♪ Hey, what's that sound?
Everybody look
What's going down ♪
♪ Paranoia strikes deep ♪
♪ Into your life
It will creep ♪
♪ It starts when
You're always afraid ♪
♪ You step out of line ♪
♪ The man come
And take you away ♪
♪ You better stop
Hey, what's that sound? ♪
♪ Everybody look
What's going down ♪
♪ You got to stop
Hey, what's that sound? ♪
♪ Everybody look
What's going down ♪
If you could
put out one thing...
Put one thing out there
about King's philosophy,
what would it be?
If you keep everything simple,
you'll do okay.
You just go where
the day takes you.
♪ Morning's hard ♪
♪ Coffee's cold ♪
♪ Pretending that the days
Mean more than getting old ♪
♪ Stale headlines ♪
♪ Others drenched in pride ♪
♪ Marching to their drum ♪
♪ With fear standing beside ♪
♪ But if I close my eyes ♪
♪ And throw back my head ♪
♪ I can see his face ♪
♪ And I hear
the words he said ♪
♪ And my memories ache ♪
♪ And my senses burn ♪
♪ Did he dream too late ♪
♪ Will we ever learn ♪
♪ I, I want to testify ♪
♪ My love still
Lives and breathes ♪
♪ And my soul
Is screaming why ♪
♪ The thoughts
Won't let me sleep ♪
♪ Don't let hearts break
And don't let children cry ♪
♪ Before it gets too late,
I want to testify ♪
♪ I take what's said
As my daily bread ♪
♪ I turn the page ♪
♪ And I turn my head ♪
♪ I pick, I choose ♪
♪ On the evening news ♪
♪ Cause by cause they fight ♪
♪ One by one they lose ♪
♪ Must I live my days ♪
♪ In these concrete ways ♪
♪ Will the fire break ♪
♪ Through the smoky haze ♪
♪ And I swear ♪
♪ Tonight I'm gonna
Find that place ♪
♪ It's not the love
That dies ♪
♪ But the understanding ways ♪
♪ I, I want to testify ♪
♪ My love still
Lives and breathes ♪
♪ And my soul
Is screaming why ♪
♪ The thoughts
Won't let me sleep ♪
♪ Don't let hearts break ♪
♪ And don't let children cry ♪
♪ Before it gets too late,
I want to testify ♪
♪ Rip through the wire
That screens in my window ♪
♪ Throw open the shades
That cover my mind ♪
♪ I'm going to touch
And I've got to believe ♪
♪ The bell tolls for me ♪
♪ I, I want to testify ♪
♪ My love still
Lives and breathes ♪
♪ And my soul
Is screaming why ♪
♪ The thoughts
Won't let me sleep ♪
♪ Don't let hearts break
And don't let children cry ♪
♪ Before it gets too late,
I want to testify ♪