Come on, then.
That's it.
Come on, where are you?
But He did come to me
and He did comfort me.
I was alone. I needed help.
In His infinite goodness,
He reached out and gave me help,
even though I'd sinned,
even though I'd turned my back on Him
and renounced His word.
Friends, He came to me, not I to Him.
And He is with me forever.
And I will dwell in His house forever.
- 'Ey up, want a kitten, Jackie?
- No, I've got one.
- Want another?
- No.
# All our sins and griefs to bear
# What a privilege to carry
# Everything to God in prayer
# Oh what peace we often forfeit... #
- Do you want a kitten?
- Do I want what, love?
A kitten, it's not dead.
That's very kind but I don't think
I can take your kitten.
We can't have 'em at home
and Eddie keeps trying to drown them
and she keeps having more, you see.
Oh dear. I am sorry.
Me dad doesn't want 'em
so Eddie keeps putting them in a sack.
Oh dear.
Jackie doesn't want it either,
so do you want it or don't you?
Charlie!
Do you see? So, if you believe in Jesus,
He'll take care of it.
Come on, our Charles!
- Now shut that!
- Our Charles is coming, Dad.
I don't care who's coming,
go back and shut it.
Shut the gate.
Shut it.
I shut it. I shut the gate, Dad.
He shut it, Dad.
- What have you been up to, then?
- Nothing.
- Do you want any help, Dad?
- No, I don't need your help.
Come here.
What have you got under your coat?
- Me pully.
- I don't mean that.
You know what I mean and don't
be so clever. What is it?
Something I found.
Are you sure I can't help you, Dad?
Go on, get on.
You don't go far, I've your tea ready.
Yes, Auntie.
Did he ask you? What d'you tell him?
- Nothing.
- Did you tell him a lie?
- I told him nothing.
- Come on, then, quick.
- Have you been at my traps again?
- No, we haven't, see.
No, well you'd better not
else I'll tell your dad, then you'll cop it.
- Cost me good money, them traps.
- We haven't been near your rotten traps.
And I'll tell me dad
that you pinch his paraffin.
Close it.
Hurry up or we'll get old trap face in here.
Let's find a place to put them.
Over there.
We'll find you a place.
Ooh, the box.
Put some stuffing in.
Right, come on, then.
There, that's a good... Come on.
Yours looks poorly.
I think it wants its mother.
- Do you want your mother?
- Shut up, yours wants...
Yours... Yours wants its mother.
What shall we call them, Kathy?
I don't know.
We'll have to think.
I'm gonna call mine Spider.
You can't call a cat Spider.
I can call it anything I like.
You're daft. You're soft in your head.
When mine grows up, I'll teach it
to hate yours and it'll eat it all up.
- Don't.
- Oh, shut up, you two.
And listen, you're not to say nowt.
You're not to breathe it to our Aunt Dolly
or she'll tell me dad.
That's it. Let's put 'em in, then.
That's it. Come on, then.
And don't keep running in
and out of here, else they'll know.
Who's going to look after them, then?
Jesus.
Don't talk wet.
Yes He will, then,
because that woman told me.
- What woman?
- The woman in the Sally Army.
I asked her to look after it
and she said Jesus'd look after it for me.
- What does she know about it?
- She knows cos she lives in His house.
How can she when He's dead?
Ooh, our Kathy.
Well, what's up? He is, isn't He?
Well fancy saying. You'll have
something terrible happening now.
Yes, you just wait till Jesus
comes and gets you.
I'm not bothered. It's only talk.
Well, come on, then.
Didn't say nothing, did I?
Only said what's true.
Can't hurt you for that.
I can't fix this any road.
Haven't I got another one?
Not clean, you haven't.
Nothing wrong with that, is there?
Well, it's shrunk or something.
That's what's wrong with it.
Anyone'd think
I didn't wash 'em properly.
'Ere. Stand still.
With you and the children, it's
no wonder poor Beatie was laid to rest.
I should think she got fed up with it
between the lot of you. I have.
- All right, don't start on that.
- All right for you. You don't do much.
- No, no.
- It's not my home. And they're not mine.
The way you'd be if you didn't have me,
I don't know.
I am only your sister, of course,
but I've got me feelings, you know.
- There.
- I can't breathe in it.
No. I expect you'll get beer
past it, though.
Come on, you two, bed.
- I haven't finished yet.
- You've finished. Come on.
Auntie said I had to eat slowly.
Never mind that. Put it in your mouth
and get upstairs.
- Night, Dad.
- Night, love.
- Straight up, now.
I have to say good night
to Auntie and Kathy.
Well, say it from there.
Good night, Auntie.
She didn't hear me.
Can I go in and say it?
Look, I'll not tell you again.
- Good night, Kathy.
- Night.
I'm going down there for half an hour.
Don't let her stay up
half the night reading.
Don't tell me, tell her.
She's your daughter.
You heard what she said.
What are you at?
Just... just off to the lavvy, Auntie.
Mind you don't leave t'door open,
banging all night.
Dusty? Dusty.
Dusty?
Dusty? Dusty?
Are you in there, then?
There you are.
Have you been looking for them, then?
Yes. Come on, then.
Let's go find them, then.
Good girl. Come on, then.
Good girl.
There you are.
Who is it?
Jesus Christ.
Jesus.
Auntie?
Nan?
Wake up, Nan.
Nan.
- What?
- I got something to tell you.
You what?
Something important.
- You've got to wake up. I've seen Him.
- You what?
Listen, you've got to listen.
I've seen Him.
Who?
Jesus.
He's in our barn. He's come back.
Kathy, are you sure?
What are we going to do, then?
I don't know.
I expect He'll tell us.
What does He talk like?
Well, He didn't say much.
He just told me who He was.
I think He was very tired.
Well, He would be, wouldn't He?
Did He say why He'd come to our barn?
Do you think it was because
of what you said, Kathy?
I don't know.
I bet it was. I told you, didn't I?
- Is He stopping?
- He didn't say.
Do you think He'd like to see me
in t'morning?
- I don't know.
- I expect so.
I mean, I didn't say anything, did I?
Funny, isn't it, Him coming to our barn?
It's like a miracle.
Come on, hurry up.
I don't think I want to after all, Kathy.
It's all right. I promise.
Promise.
'Ave we to curtsy?
I think He's gone.
- He was asleep.
- Yes, asleep in the hay.
Here, it's got to be a secret.
You've not to tell nobody.
He'll tell us. When He wakes up,
He'll tell us what to do.
What's happened, up at this time?
Have you wet the bed?
You're daft, you are, and dirty.
Oh dear. Sticks and stones'll break
me bones but names'll never hurt me.
198.
198 what?
That's how many eggs I've had
since last Easter.
Come on, don't string it out.
I want to get cleared up.
Won't a certain person
want some breakfast?
It says in a certain B-l-B-E-L
that a certain person eats bread.
Shut up, big mouth.
What are you talking about?
- Nothing.
- You are, then.
- I know what you're talking about.
- Who, then?
I'm not gonna tell you.
I'm gonna keep it to meself.
Shan't tell you anything ever again.
Eddie! Eddie, what are you doing?
- Doing?
- I thought I told you to shift that calf.
Yes, well, I was waiting on you, you see.
I told you to shift her yesterday.
It's draughty in that pen, she's worse.
Well, I was on me way to shift her.
I was waiting for you to look at her.
I've looked at her,
so shift her up to the big barn.
We'll get Weaver in to have a look at her.
And another time, don't wait for me,
just do what I say when I say it.
Right, I'll do that now, then.
Right.
What are we doing?
Are we playing with Jackie Greenwood?
One of us might be, two of us aren't.
You rotten cows, what are you doing?
Ask no questions, get no lies told.
- You rotten cows, you're nothing else.
- You watch your tongue.
It's always me. I always get it.
I'm off to hide, then.
- And no following.
- We don't want to follow you.
Well you'd better not, then.
Rotten cows.
What else?
Shouldn't we have some fishes?
- No, that's only in the miracle.
- Oh, I thought He had to have fishes.
- What about some vinegar?
- Wine. He has bread and wine.
Oh, Kathy, that's me dad's,
for after Christmas, after the Queen.
Eddie?
Eddie!
- Well, what are you doing?
- What does it look like?
- Thought the house was on fire.
- Isn't she any better?
Nah, she eats too much,
like somebody I know.
- Can I put her in t'barn?
- Trying to get my job or something?
No but me dad says
I've got to help more.
He says I'm useless and I'm not, see.
It's just that nobody lets me.
Will you let me?
Please, then I can tell me dad.
I don't know. Do you know how?
Yes, I've seen how you do it,
seen how clever you are.
Then you could go and look at your trap.
There's something in it.
I saw as I come along.
- Trap?
- Aye.
That wood pigeon,
the one you've been after.
Right. That's right.
Long as you know how.
In the trap now, is he?
Right. I'll 'ave him.
Does He always sleep?
He doesn't look well, does He?
He looks poorly.
He's got a nice face, though.
Is He like what you thought?
I'm glad He came to our barn, aren't you?
He could have gone
to Jackie Greenwood's.
Shh. Go on. Go on out of here.
Why should I?
It's my barn as much as yours.
Any road, I wanna see my kitten.
Who's that? Who's that fella?
It's not a fella. It's Jesus.
- Is he dead?
- Course not.
- That isn't Jesus.
- Well it is, then, Mr clever Dick.
Jesus wore a long dress.
Well, that was in them days.
Is it? Is it really Him?
And listen, it's a secret.
You're not to tell anyone
because we don't know yet
what He wants us to do.
And we've got to look after Him.
Oh, gentle Jesus, boom...
When you're looking
for a murderer, you've got to move fast,
especially with children around,
you've got to close in quickly.
They were slow off the mark for a start.
They should have closed in
but they didn't.
- No, no.
- It puts the onus on us, you see.
Course, your superintendent Teesdale's
a very good man.
Detective sergeant Wilcox
hasn't been to bed for three nights.
Yes, yes, Wilcox, yes.
I'm still waiting to hear from him
about the guttering that went missing.
Get out of that puddle, boy.
When you're warning them, you see,
the thing is not to alarm too much.
Not to alarm them, yes.
Six yards of guttering stolen, two
dustbin lids to my certain knowledge,
notice boards, they've walked,
wire netting.
Not to alarm them. Yes.
Right now, everybody, close your books.
- Now, put your hands up. Wait a minute.
- Miss, Miss.
Don't all shout at once.
Now, was the Samaritan
a good person or a bad person?
- Me, me.
- Miss, Miss...
Yes, Pam.
Please, Miss,
David Edwards has just come in.
Hello, David.
He looks like another person
who's been crossing the road.
Only you're not a good Samaritan,
are you, David?
No, M... No, Mrs... Miss Lodge.
You'd better go and find
Mrs Reeves and get those clothes dried.
Go on, hurry up.
Right, now let's all pay attention.
Jenny, Robert, this way.
We'll have question time now, shall we?
Has anybody got any questions?
About today's lesson?
- Or anything else?
- Miss?
Yes, Kathy?
What would happen if Jesus came back?
Well, Kathy, of course,
Jesus has never really left us, has He?
He's with us all the time.
Here, in this room,
at home,
everywhere.
- Isn't He?
- Yes, Miss.
Only I mean if He came back
in t'person, like.
Well, for one thing, He'd find a great
many changes, wouldn't He?
Now that's a good one. What sort
of changes would He find? Mm?
- Telly, Wagon Train.
- Beat The Clock.
That's right.
There wasn't any televisión, of course.
But I was meaning other things.
What else can you think of?
- ... final.
- What's that, Jackie? Speak up.
Cup final.
Anybody else?
Cup final, cloth ears.
But what would they do to Him
if He did come back?
If Jesus came back?
I'm afraid the worid hasn't changed
all that much.
There are still bad people
as well as good.
But would they crucify Him?
I suppose some of the bad people
might try.
But this time, all the good people would
have to try even harder to stop them.
We know what we'd do, don't we?
What would we do
if Jesus came back on earth?
What would we do?
Mm?
We'd praise Him, wouldn't we?
What would we do?
Praise Him, Miss.
- Praise Him.
It's stopped raining.
Do you think He stopped it, Kathy?
Yes, He could do anything, Jesus.
Do you think He could make me a nice
chocolate cake for me birthday?
- And some chocolate logs, eh?
- No, you mustn't.
Miss Lodge says you've only
to ask Jesus for love and not for things.
Oh, she talks out of t'back
of her neck, she does.
I'd like to see her face when she
knows we've got Jesus in our barn.
- Are we going to tell her?
- No, not till He's ready and better.
Then everybody'll know.
They'll all come and see Him.
- Who?
- Oh, everybody.
Shepherds, wise men, lords, ladies,
bishops and people.
The Mayor of Burnley.
There'll be thousands around
our barn before He's finished.
You just wait and see.
I'll bet you anything you like...
Come on, Charlie.
Don't be so slow.
Hello.
Are you feeling any better, then?
Oh, you've broken your wine.
We brought you that.
And the bread.
Did you?
Mm.
Sorry it wasn't very much.
I didn't bring you any dinner
but I brought you my kitten.
It's name's Spider.
We've not told anyone.
You don't want us to tell nobody,
do you, till you're better?
No. Don't tell nobody.
We know who you are.
And we're going to look after you.
We'll try and get you
some better stuff next time.
Good night, gentle Jesus.
Sleep well.
Did you come straight home
from Sunday school today, Kathy?
Yes, Dad.
- You didn't hang about anywhere?
- No, Dad.
No, well that's right.
I don't want you hanging around,
talking to people and that.
You didn't talk to anyone, did you?
No, Dad, only the vicar.
No, I mean strangers, like.
You didn't talk to any strangers?
- No, Dad.
- I don't want you talking to strangers.
There's some very funny
people about these days.
Funny men and that.
I don't want you to be bothered
with anybody you don't know.
Kathy, what are you doing?
- Nothing, Auntie.
- What have you got under table?
- There's summat going on between you.
You know summat about it, too.
What have you got in your hands?
Nothing, Auntie.
Well, eat your tea properly.
And mind what I say. I don't want
you having to do with strangers.
Just mind what I say.
Yes, Dad.
Come on, you two.
Come on.
- Did you get the stuff?
- Don't shout. Yes, I did.
Got an extra bar of soap,
some toothpaste
and an individual fruit pie.
Oh, quick, put it up your jumper.
- Do you think Auntie'll find out?
- No, I'll say I lost t'bill.
- Do you think it's wicked?
- No.
How can it be, when we're
doing it for Him? Come on, quick.
Come on.
It's you. You told them.
No I didn't, I only told Jackie Greenwood.
You told them.
I told you not to tell anybody.
I didn't tell anybody. I only told Jackie.
- What do you lot want, then?
- We've come to see Him.
- Who?
- Jesus.
Yes, Jesus.
Well, you can't, see.
Yes we can, then.
He's not your private property.
Everyone can see Him if they want.
Well,
if I tell you,
if I let you see Him,
it's got to be a secret.
You've got to promise.
It's got to be a secret society
from the grown-ups.
Do you promise?
Because if you don't,
they'll come and take Him away again,
like last time.
Do you understand?
Right.
You can't come past our house
for a start. You'll have to go right round.
Our Nan and our Charles'll take you.
You're not to make any noise
and you have to wait for me.
Do you understand? Come on.
- Do you want to see Jesus or don't you?
- Yes.
Well, shut up, then.
Here are your groceries, Auntie.
I'm just out to play.
Mind you don't get yourself
all mucked up.
You're all to wait here until I say.
And keep back out of sight.
Nan, give me the stuff.
Keep back.
I brought you these, like I promised.
Oh, your leg.
Yeah.
If you want to, you could get me
some water and a bit of cloth.
Yes, sir. I'll send our Charles.
- Charles?
- Me little brother.
Oh, yeah.
Who else knows I'm here?
Only Charles and me sister, Nan,
and the other children.
Other children?
How many are you, then?
Oh, they're not ours but they're all right.
You can come in now
but come in quietly.
- Go get some water from t'yard.
- What in?
Oh, use your loaf and find something.
Well, say hello.
Go on, say hello.
Hello.
Hello, sir.
It's got a free gift inside it.
In there.
It's an Arabian charm bracelet.
Yeah.
Very nice.
I've brought you your book.
Will you tell us a story, please?
- Story?
- Yes, please.
- What about?
- Erm, the Good Samaritan.
No, loaves and fishes.
No, the 'Oly Ghost.
- Go on, will you?
- Yes, tell us a story.
- Go on, tell us a story.
- Yes, please tell us a story.
Story. Story. Story!
Story! Story! Story! Story!
Shut up!
You mustn't make so much noise.
If you keep quiet,
I'll read you a story.
Sit down.
"Ruth Lawrence, air hostess...
"The stranger paused.
"'Yes, I have ze parcel,' he said.
"They were interrupted
"by the sound of the loudspeaker.
"'Flight 504, leaving for Hamburg."'
That's why she's worse.
Has she been sick long?
- Not long.
- Hello, young man.
What are you doing? Look at your boots.
Turn that tap off.
"Ruth Lawrence
was the youngest air hostess
"at Redbridge airport.
"She was only 17."
Dad!
- Dad!
- What?
- Are you gonna look at the calf?
- You can't come, so don't suggest it.
We've had bad luck with the weather.
Should have sown last month.
It's been terrible all round.
Good for business, though.
- Not mine.
- I'm not exactly complaining.
What are you lot doing in here?
Come on, out of it. Go and play outside.
Go on, all of you.
- Can't I stay, Dad?
- Mr Weaver doesn't want your advice.
Oh, please can't I stay?
I have been looking after her.
Oh, all right,
as long as you keep out of the way.
You're lucky not to have foot and mouth.
They've had it all over.
Come on, let's have a look at you,
young lady.
- Is she off her grub?
- No, she's keeping it down.
Come on, girl. I shan't hurt you.
Aye.
Yeah, come on.
I want to have a look at
your mouth. Come on.
Well, don't seem much wrong
with her now.
Could have saved myself your bill.
No wonder you're not complaining.
I don't know about that.
I'll have a look at her while I'm here.
She's got over it, whatever it was.
Are you gonnna keep her?
I was but I'm not bothered.
Once they're prone
to colic, you're best rid of them
but it's up to you.
There's nowt wrong with her now.
I'll get shut of her next week.
If you take my advice,
that's the best thing.
Oh, what's this?
Is this yours, young lady?
- Well, what do you say?
- Thank you.
They don't take care of nothing.
I don't know what they're up to
half the time.
It's all right.
You can come out now, they've gone.
You all right?
Yeah, it's OK.
We'll have to find you somewhere safer.
Thanks for not giving me away.
Oh, we would never
give you away. Not ever.
Why are you and all them other kids,
why are you helping me?
Because we love you.
Oh, I forgot.
I brought you this.
- What is it?
- It's a picture of you.
Course, it was taken a long time ago.
Oh, and don't worry
about the other thing.
We won't let the grown-ups find you.
You're quite safe with us.
Quite safe with us.
# The corporation dustcart
was full up to the brim
# The corporation driver
fell in and couldn't swim
# He sank right to the bottom
just like a little stone
# And all the time was whistling
There's No Place Like Home #
- What you got?
- Nothing.
Well, give it us, then, if it's nothing.
# We know something you don't know
# We know something
you don't know
# We know something you don't know
we know something you don't know
- What do you know?
- Give over!
- Tell us what you know.
- Give over.
- What do you know, then?
- Get off, man.
- What do you know that I don't know?
- Get off me.
- Get off.
- What do you know that I don't know?
- Jesus. We've seen Jesus.
- You what?
I just told you. We've seen Jesus.
- Yeah and who else? Donald Duck?
- No, honest, Patto.
- Cross me heart.
- You haven't, have you?
- Yes.
- Have you?
Have you?
- No.
- Say it, then. Say "I haven't seen Jesus."
I haven't seen Jesus.
Again.
- I haven't seen Jesus.
- Again!
I haven't... seen Jesus.
All right. Who else has seen Him?
Who else, then?
Come on, who else?
I have.
Leave her alone, Patto.
She has, Patto, we've all seen Him.
And I've seem Him as well, so you know.
- Have you got it?
- I'm just looking, just looking.
Oh.
Can't quite lay me hands on it.
Can't lay your hands on it. What's this?
- I looked over there.
- Not hard enough.
- Where'd this come from?
- No idea.
It's funny but I looked over there
when I first come in.
- Then I went over the other side.
- All right, all right.
Trouble with the tractor...
Where's mine? Where's mine gone?
- Who's had mine?
- I don't know, do I?
Jesus?
Jesus.
- What is it?
- Have you got my kitten?
- What kitten?
- The kitten I gave you.
- No, I haven't got it.
- But I gave it you to look after.
Well, I haven't got it.
It's dead.
It's dead. He let it die.
He let it die.
Has he gone to heaven, Jesus?
You've gone to heaven, haven't you?
- What's up?
- It isn't all true, in t'Bible, is it?
What? Course it is.
- It isn't. Cos He's just told me.
- Who?
Gentle Jesus. He does things for other
people but He won't do anything for me.
Cos it isn't Him.
It's just a fella.
It is Him, Charlie.
It isn't. Cos I gave him my kitten
to look after
and he let it die.
And he's supposed to look after animals
and he doesn't.
Yes, He does. It's just that...
Well, He has to let some things die,
I suppose.
It were my kitten, not his.
He can't stop everything from dying.
Nobody can.
God can't, even.
There must...
He must have had a reason.
I'll find out for you, shall I?
Shall I find out for you? Shall I?
Shall I?
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Can we have one bottle of orange
and two straws?
Thank you.
- Mr Reeves.
- Hello, Linda.
It's not Linda, it's Kathy Bostock.
Oh. Oh, yes, is it?
Kathy, that's right.
- Can I interrupt you for a minute?
- Yes.
You know how He used to cure people?
Jesus, I mean.
He cured a blind man once, didn't He?
That's right.
And He could bring people back
from t'dead, too.
Mm. Lazarus.
Only He must have let
some people die, mustn't He?
Why did He let those people die?
Mm.
Well, er...
You see, er, people...
babies are being born all the time.
And, er,
those of us who are here already
have got to make room for them,
haven't we?
Yes, sir.
The Lord giveth
and the Lord taketh away.
- That's what the Bible says, isn't it?
- Yes, sir.
God has got more than us
to think about, not only people dying.
It's what we are doing to the worid,
that's what worries Him.
You see, we hurt God much more
than He hurts us.
You don't have to go far
to see people offending God.
What about when you get children taking
guttering and lead from the church?
It's not only the value. It's God's house.
- But that's nothing to do with Jesus.
- It's going to stop.
I'm going to stamp this vandalism out.
I'm going to take very strong measures
in the future.
- Yes, sir.
- Mm.
So you pass it around.
He doesn't know, does he?
Hello.
What have you got for me today?
Erm, I got some sausage and cheese
and a custard slice.
They've all got a bit mixed up, I'm afraid.
- You didn't bring any snout, I suppose?
- Snout?
Yeah, snout.
Fags, ciggies.
Oh, no. I didn't know you smoked.
No, well, er, I never used to but...
I do now, sometimes.
Well, I'll try and get you some.
How did you get hold of this grub, then?
I just took it. Is that all right?
All right if you don't get caught.
What would your mother say?
She's dead. She's in heaven.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
Who looks after you now, then?
Me Auntie Dolly, she lives with us.
There's me, there's me dad,
our Nan and our Charles.
It's his birthday tomorrow, as you know.
Yeah.
What day is it?
- Charles' birthday? The 14th.
- No, today.
Oh...
Tuesday.
I'll have to be going soon.
Oh. Are you going a long way?
Yeah.
Will you have time to see
some more children before you go?
No. Oh, I'll have to see.
I don't know.
She's taking her time, your Kathy.
Oh, give over!
If she in't here in five minutes,
I'll get you.
Give over.
Do you think she'll be here
before I count a hundred?
Well, I'm going to count.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine, ten, eleven, twelve,
thirteen, fourteen...
Why did you let that kitten die?
Oh.
Well, I got a lot on me mind just now.
Look, would you like to do
something else for me?
Will you run me an errand?
Only, if you do, nobody's to know.
- You haven't to tell the others. Right?
- Oh, I won't.
Well, I seem to remember
there's a tunnel near here,
near a canal or a reservoir or something.
I haven't been round here for some time.
There is one, the Castlewood tunnel.
It's on t'canal but they don't use it now.
Yeah, that'd be it.
Well, there's a parcel I want bringing.
It's just inside the tunnel, wrapped
in sacking and wedged under the line.
- Do you think you could find it?
- Oh, yes, I'll find it.
That's a good lass.
Now you go by yourself
and don't open it.
- Right?
- Yes, I'll go now.
541,
542,
543,
544,
545,
546,
547,
548,
549,
550,
551.
- What's up with her?
- I don't know, do I?
You're her sister.
Thought she was taking us to see Him.
- She will.
- What, next year?
- No, tomorrow.
- You said that yesterday.
- It's your Charles' party tomorrow.
- Who's asking you?
- I was only saying.
- She'll take you tomorrow.
She'd better or I'll go and tell Him
a thing or two, so you tell her from me.
Don't ask him to the party.
I shan't.
Oi!
What are you doing down there?
- Who is it, some kid?
- I don't know. I can't see.
Hey! Come here!
Ah, it's only a kid.
Ha ha ha.
Oh, don't, Charlie.
British Bulldog. British Bulldog.
- We're going to play my game now.
- It's my party. I can play what I like.
You mind,
otherwise your party'll be over.
And I know somebody who might
find themselves in bed.
We'll play blind man's buff.
- I don't like it. It's rough.
- It isn't.
- Course it isn't.
- I'm gonna be a blind man and get you.
Oh, Dad, tell our Charles to stop it.
Now watch it, love.
You're getting overexcited.
I want to be the blind man. It's my party.
- Have you got a hanky, Dad?
- Can I? Can I be the blind man?
I don't care who's the blind man
as long as you behave yourselves.
- You can use t'duster.
- Me dad said I could be it.
- Did you, Dad?
- Oh, let him, let him.
- It's the last game so make the best of it.
- Oh, Dad.
Don't start. You've had
a good innings. Come on.
- It's too tight.
- I don't want you cheating. That's why.
I'd like another cup of tea now.
You'll have to use one of the best cups
and be careful with it.
Stop it.
- Where's that bottle of port, then?
- I don't know. Don't look at me.
- Well, it's not here.
- You must have drunk it.
It's never passed my lips. I haven't had a
drop since V-E Day and I didn't like that.
Tea's in there.
Gotcha!
Kathy. Kathy!
Kathy, have you shifted t'bottle of port
out of t'sideboard?
Mind what you're at!
Give over. Give over.
That'll do. That's enough. Now quiet.
Quiet!
Right. Now it's cake time.
If you want cake,
queue up in front of Auntie Dorothy.
- Me! Me!
- Don't drive me insane.
Hey, miss, put that down. Who's this for?
- Me. It's mine.
- Not that. I mean t'other one.
It's for Jesus.
Who d'you say it's for, love?
Who d'you say it's for?
Jesus.
It isn't Jesus.
It's just a fella.
Eddie! Eddie!
Here. Give me that quick. Come on.
He's got a gun. Now look,
you stay here and keep out of the way.
I'll be back.
You're not going there,
so make up your mind.
- I'm going to see Him.
- You're not.
- You don't know. You don't understand.
- You don't understand anything.
- You don't know who he is.
I do. I do. It's Jesus.
Look, he's got a gun, love.
He's got a gun.
You're making it up
because you want to get Him.
You can't leave anybody alone.
- I'm going to see Him and I don't care...
- Stop it, Kathy, stop it.
You're not going up there
so make up your mind.
- Oh, please.
- Come along.
Come along! Now behave.
- Kathy, behave. Come along.
- It's Jesus.
Come on. Now get along.
Go along.
Now listen, all of you.
You're to stay here and not to come out.
Just do as I say, there's good kids,
and there won't be any more trouble.
Just do as I say.
It's half-day closing. He's at t'cemetery.
Ann Green.
Who?
Excuse me.
Hello.
Yep. Right.
We've got him, Frank.
What do you think he's doing?
Jesus?
Oh, please, Jesus, please.
Jesus.
Oh, please talk to me.
I believe in you.
I won't hurt you. It wasn't me.
I love you. I love you.
Go away, kid.
Go away.
I brought you something.
Your snort.
Did you bring any matches?
Oh, I forgot matches.
Doesn't matter.
You remembered the snout.
I didn't give you away. It was Charles.
But he didn't mean to.
It's just that he didn't think.
- That's all right.
- He didn't mean to.
- Will you forgive him?
- Yeah.
Then me Aunt Dolly went for the police.
What'll you do?
Are you gonna get away this time?
It's not up to me, is it?
- It's up to them, innit?
- There's lots of other children.
I sent for them to help you. I know
they'll come. I just know they'll come.
Did you hear what I said?
- Yes, I heard.
- We wouldn't have sent for the police.
Not ever. Not ever.
They're coming now.
What are you going to do?
There must be something you can do.
You can do anything.
- Is that what you all think?
- Yes.
Yes, we all believe in you.
He's in that barn, I gather. You stay here.
I'll go up with Wilcox, a couple of men.
He'll cover the back...
- Where the hell are they coming from?
- I've no idea, sir.
Well, I want this whole area cleared.
He's got a gun, you know.
Come on, Frank.
Please, you must hurry.
Please, you must.
Will we see you again?
Will we see you?
- You bet.
- What did you say? I didn't hear.
I said yeah.
You'll hear about me again.
Do you promise?
- Promise?
- Come on, love. Out of it.
Yes, I promise.
You there, Blakey?
Gonna be a good lad?
What about it, Blakey?
What's it gonna be, then?
Gonna make more trouble for yourself?
You'll need more than that, Blakey, lad.
Has He gone?
Yes.
Yes, you missed Him this time...
but He'll be coming again.