Mr. Lee Dong Jun.
You are under arrest for forging a trial...
and forming a slush fund.
You have the rights
to consult an attorney...
I won't consult an attorney.
What I have done is...
not worth defending.
I will accept the punishment as they
are asserted by the prosecutor...
and as they are ruled by the judge.
You may choose to remain silent.
Thank you for everything.
Without you,
I would have...
lived for that seat.
Thank you so much,
Young Ju.
Look at me.
Look at me, Young Ju.
Attorney Lee Dong Jun, who has been...
the temporary CEO of Taebaek
after CEO Choi Il Hwan's arrest,
was arrested by the police
for a forged trial.
Attorney Lee is accused of declaring
Shin Chang Ho as guilty...
for charges against
Kim Sung Sik's murder...
knowing the real culprit is someone else.
The police said they will do
everything to find out...
if he received anything in return
for forging the trial.
Currently, Attorney Lee...
has admitted to all of his crimes.
This is Mr. Lee's testimony.
He testified that he forged
the outcome of the trial...
and covered up the real culprit
behind Kim Sung Sik's murder.
The entire case began when...
you, Kang Jeong Il murdered...
Murder?
Who?
Me?
Would you call it a murder
if I stabbed a dead body...
with a fishing pole?
Sadly, when I arrived at the fishing site,
Reported Kim Sung Sik was...
already dead and gone.
I told you just to take the document.
Mr. Lee, you were a judge.
I'm sure you have studied many precedents.
This is usually seen in many
hit-and-run cases.
This person is walking on the streets.
A car that was passing by...
hits the pedestrian.
The pedestrian dies on the spot.
Then a car that came after that...
hit the body of the pedestrian
who's already dead.
I'm sure...
many precedents say the
second driver is innocent.
Right?
It's just like that.
Before I got to the there,
Baek Sang Gu's subject...
had already killed Reporter Kim Sung Sik.
He put up such a fight. What can we do?
Don't worry about it.
This rain will wash away the blood.
I was afraid.
What if...
What if he wakes up?
I was so afraid...
that I stabbed the dead body...
with the fishing pole.
Are you trying to avoid
your murder charge...
with desecration of a corpse?
I am only speaking the truth.
Ms. Choi, who was at the scene...
says you murdered...
Su Yeon saw that.
From afar.
Where on her testimony does it say...
that Reporter Kim was alive
when I stabbed him?
Article 159 of the Criminal Code,
desecration of a corpse.
It says anyone who has damaged
a corpse, human bones or hair...
will be detained up to two years...
or be fined up to 5,000 dollars.
Su Yeon bribed Chief Justice.
She'll receive a severe punishment.
CEO Choi...
took the lead in covering up
the whole incident.
He'll receive a life sentence.
Mr. Lee.
You have forged an outcome of a trial.
You'll receive a severe punishment too.
This huge incident began...
with a petty crime,
desecration of a corpse.
5,000 dollars of fine.
That's pretty burdening.
Mr. Lee.
You should...
rewrite your testimony.
Su Yeon.
You'll spend a very long time in prison.
I'll visit you often.
I'll show you how I got out...
and how I live on.
I really want to...
show that to you.
This is the result of the autopsy.
On Reporter Kim's body,
you'll see wounds which were created
by a knife and a fishing pole.
However, it's unclear...
if the cause of his death was the
knife of Baek Sang Gu's subject...
or the fishing pole.
They say it's impossible
to tell from an autopsy.
Kang Jeong Il has been quite
cooperative in the investigation.
I thought he would admit to his crime...
and give up on taking any legal actions.
When he was investigated
face-to-face with Choi Il Hwan,
he made sure there are...
no evidence about how he
covered up the incident.
When he was investigated with Choi Su Yeon,
he made sure...
she did not see that Kim Sung
Sik was alive at that time.
He really is a smart lawyer.
He has been looking for a
loophole in the investigation.
The only one who can testify
Reporter Kim was alive is...
Baek Sang Gu.
He knows we cannot bring
Baek Sang Gu, so...
Let's forget about Kang
Jeong Il's murder charges.
Damaging a dead body.
You should take that, Young Ju.
- Dong Jun.
- He has committed another crime.
Murder instigation.
I'm the victim.
Kang Jeong Il ordered for you to go abroad.
Baek Sang Gu tried to kill
you on his own accord...
To prove that he did not instigate murder,
he would have to bring Baek Sang Gu.
However,
Baek Sang Gu is not here.
To catch Kang Jeong Il,
we must use his ways.
I made seasoned lotus roots.
Once he goes to prison,
he won't be able to eat
anything that I cook.
I'm sure this is troublesome,
but please do this for me
while he's still here.
May I...
also ask you for a big favor?
It's been over 30 years.
It's my first time coming
back to this hospital...
after I left this place as a nurse.
And this is my first time
asking you for a favor.
I hope you can do this one for me...
as Dong Jun's dad.
You probably checked the
autopsy result from the NFS.
I'm pretty sure you looked
for Baek Sang Gu's body,
but you don't look so good.
Presumption of innocence.
Don't be stubborn in trying to
arrest me for murder. Be objective.
Then you will get to find
out the truth, Young Ju.
Jeong Il, the statement you
wrote for the murder...
should be revised for a statement
of desecration of a corpse.
Jeong Il killed Reporter Kim.
I witnessed the crime scene.
Su Yeon.
Lower your voice.
The days you could abuse
the law are gone now.
We have an additional charge.
(Statement)
This is the victim's statement.
We are checking to see...
if you hired Baek Sang
Gu to murder Dong Jun.
We have a witness who saw Baek
Sang Gu receiving the payment...
from you for the contract killing.
(Statement)
Here is the statement.
Goodness, I would have come to you.
He was an underling of Baek
Sang Gu who was at the scene.
This must be a familiar face to you.
Jeong Il,
did you instruct Baek Sang Gu...
to kill Dong Jun in exchange
for something in return?
No way.
I...
Please take a seat.
Director Lee Ho Beom.
Was there a time you performed a
surgery on Dong Jun who arrived...
at the hospital after being stabbed?
Yes.
I will perform the surgery.
Get some sleep.
I will wake you up.
You must know informing the
police when you receive...
a patient with a stab
wound is the protocol.
I was going to report it.
But at that time, he visited me.
That is a complete lie.
I have never seen him before.
This is my first time seeing him.
This is what he said at that time.
This might come across as a bit
rude in our first meeting,
but please don't report this to the police.
This will only make things messy...
for Taekbaek, Dong Jun,
and Hangang Hospital.
He is making a false statement.
I have never set foot in Hangang Hospital.
When Baek Sang Gu acquired
the construction company,
he needed Jeong Il's help to get
a loan from a savings bank.
I have the document.
I obtained it with the intention
of destroying it to protect him.
I'm glad that I didn't
throw it out and kept it.
Every piece of evidence...
proves that you instigated murder.
I only told Baek Sang Gu to get
Dong Jun to a country overseas.
This is only instigation of violence.
Baek Sang Gu tried to
murder Dong Jun on his own.
Jeong Il, if you want to prove your claim,
bring him then.
Oh, right.
If you bring him,
it will be revealed that
Reporter Kim was alive.
I have a witness who saw you
promising Baek Sang Gu a reward.
You asked the President's doctor
to conceal the attempted attack.
The evidence you rewarded
him will be submitted.
Jeong Il,
you'll be arrested on the suspicion
of instigation of murder.
Jeong Il, you will end up...
spending a long time in prison.
I will visit you often.
I will show you how I got out...
and how I live on.
I really want to...
show that to you.
Your mom came to visit me.
Since I told lies my whole life,
she asked me to lie one more time for you.
I will ask the people at the Blue
House to decrease the sentence...
Don't.
Out of all the paths you walked on,
there wasn't a single moment I
wanted to follow in your footsteps.
I'm sorry, Dad.
Okay. I understand.
I hope...
you won't regret the path
you chose or look back,
Dong Jun.
I heard you are investigating the
police officers who partook...
in the cover-up of Reporter Kim's murder.
Police officers with low rankings
are being asked to take the blame.
At that time, I was in the briefing
with senior police officers.
Everyone disregarded the truth.
Taebaek.
Taebaek took every case related to
corruption in the defense industry.
CEO Choi of the law firm hired...
high-ranking officials who were
released after being detained...
due to the corruption
as the firm's advisors.
Please investigate the senior police
officers present at the briefing.
(List of attendees of the briefing)
This is the list of senior police
officers who attended the briefing.
There must be a reason why they
turned away from the truth.
The world is fair.
Your mom is...
beautiful and elegant.
I thought I wanted to
grow old just like her.
But her cooking is a bit...
Even our taste in food is similar.
But there's a good side of this though.
If you continue to eat my mom's food,
food from any restaurant in this world...
tastes delicious.
Your friends came to visit.
All of them were lawyers.
They wanted to be your attorney.
They didn't want money from you.
They said you were under an
inescapable circumstance.
There are some people...
who endured that inescapable circumstance.
Mr. Shin Chang Ho.
Reporter Kim Sung Sik.
I don't need a lawyer.
I think I can wait for five years.
Don't drink too much.
Go for a run in the morning.
I asked my mom for your herbal medicine.
I asked her...
to send the same one that
I had taken every month.
Don't worry.
I'll pay for it.
I have a favor to ask you.
On the day I get released,
I want to eat a meal...
made by you.
The world is fair.
When it comes to cooking, I am...
Very good?
Goodness, you have knots everywhere.
You're in a serious condition.
That's fine. Stop.
Goodness.
(Former Attorney General, Lee Tae Jun)
A few months ago,
I was the highest ranking
person in this prison.
But in the next room,
there are chief justices, ministers,
and the another attorney
general all in one cell.
All of the corrupt...
chief justices, ministers, and
the Attorney General are...
in this place,
so I guess...
the outside world is cleaner now.
Isn't that right?
Yes.
Attorney General.
Why do you always keep those
earmuffs next to you?
Oh, these earmuffs?
This guy who went away before me...
gave this to me.
He told me never to listen
to the corrupt world.
Instead, listen to the truths
which ring inside of you.
The sounds which resonate within
your heart. You know, right?
He told me to listen to that.
Tae Gon.
Wouldn't it be so wonderful
if you can live twice?
The first time, we lived in a sewer.
The second time,
you should live in a clear pond.
Yes.
You know, ponds that are so clear
that you can see the bottom.
You can see those things...
What are they called?
The precious and expensive ones.
Right, mandarin fish.
- A place like that.
- Right, exactly.
Your trial is tomorrow, right?
- Yes.
- I see.
I'm all finished.
You can get a new start.
So do it well.
- Yes, Attorney General.
- And...
when the police...
calls you over,
can you take me too?
When you eat short rib soup there,
I'd like...
a bite of jjajangmyeon too.
Attorney General, I cannot do that.
What if they stop calling me for
asking them to take you too?
And eating jjajangmyeon...
can be quite loud.
You hear this slurping sound.
You cannot do that in
the interrogation room.
Tae Gon.
I am...
confident that I can eat it
without making any noise.
Can't you do this one for me?
No, Attorney General.
The suspects which have covered up
Reporter Kim Sung Sik's murder...
will undergo their first joint trial...
in Seoul District Court today.
This trial is a separate case
from the slush fund case.
The case involves Choi Il Hwan,
the former CEO of Taebaek,
his daughter, Choi Su Yeon,
Chairman Kang Yu Taek's son, Kang Jeong Il,
Attorney Lee Dong Jun,
and the former chief secretary
of Taebaek, Song Tae Gon.
Everyone who is involved
will be at the hearing.
(Accused)
My dad...
I just followed CEO Choi Il
Hwan's orders, Your Honor.
A judge in his office...
asked the NHS a lawful question.
You have exaggerated the case...
and handed it over to the chief justice.
Are you saying you merely
followed your father's order?
I've always been good at running
errands since I was a kid.
I believe you are a grown woman
who can think and discern...
the meaning behind what your
father asked you to do.
My father makes the decision.
Everything that is written on
the bill of indictment is...
just me following my dad's orders.
I did not mean to commit a crime.
I told my daughter to do this.
It was because...
I wanted a righteous and competent judge...
as my son-in-law.
Does it make any sense that
you would force a man...
you want as your son-in-law
to forge a sentencing...
I did not write that sentencing.
Why did you do that?
Chief Secretary Song had received money...
from Chairman Kang Yu Taek.
Yesterday,
you sent me this.
I came by to give this back to you.
I heard you recently moved.
I sent it so that you can
paint the walls again.
Do you need more?
I'm sure there was some kind
of an exchange between them.
They must've written the sentencing...
and asked him to forge the trial.
Your Honor.
I really wanted him as my son-in-law.
That's why I asked my daughter
to tell those things...
to the chief justice.
However, the one who
wrote the sentencing...
and asked him to forge the trial is...
Kang Yu Taek, who wanted to cover up...
his son, Kang Jeong Il's murder.
It may look like one case,
but this is just a coincidence...
where two intentions were
merely mixed up in a case.
Yes. I did get some money
to paint my walls again.
So what?
What do you want me to do now?
I didn't do anything for him to get that.
It was just his encouragement.
Yes, it's like a bonus.
Su Yeon is saying what she did is...
merely carrying out CEO Choi's orders.
To refute her argument,
we need an evidence that she
made a move on her own accord.
You should meet Attorney Hwang Bo Yeon.
- Then what is CEO Choi...
- He's protecting Su Yeon.
He cannot escape...
the charges against
murdering Chairman Kang.
If he makes an argument...
saying you are the one who
wrote the sentencing,
he thought he could hide
that Su Yeon got involved...
in the process of the cover up.
Hey, I've never even written
anything like a sentencing before.
I was a prosecutor.
It's not easy to change
one's style of writing.
The sentencing which CEO Choi wrote is...
probably written in his style of writing.
You're right. Whenever I see a sentencing,
I can tell which judge wrote it.
After CEO Choi graduated Judicial
Research and Training Institute,
he worked as a judge for three years.
They are probably available...
on the court's internet server.
You should look for the
sentencing which he wrote.
You two are undergoing a trial
without physical restraint.
If you cooperate, it'll be
taken into consideration.
Mr. Cho.
I met with Jeong Il.
He asked me to destroy CEO Choi.
It's his last request.
I should do that much.
Ms. Hwang?
I will testify.
If I write a good letter of apology,
it'll be used in favor to
my trial, wouldn't it?
(Witness Stand)
Ms. Choi...
Choi Su Yeon...
met with Chief Justice
Jang Hyun Guk quite often.
She's even asked him for an
internal investigation...
regarding Lee Dong Jun's
extramarital affair.
How sad.
During International
Conference for Jurists,
he will come across a nightmare.
It's been a while,
Attorney Lee Dong Jun.
I handed over...
the captured images of the video
to Chief Justice Jang Hyun Guk.
What did you give to Chief Justice Jang?
Choi Su Yeon claims...
that she did the whole thing at
the dictation of Choi Il Hwan.
No woman would conduct an investigation...
into her husband's affair at
the dictation of her father.
Chief Justice Jang and Choi Su Yeon...
communicated with each
other on regular bases.
The original ruling has been
deleted from the server.
Did you check the ruling
on the server before?
Yes.
(Enter the security code.)
Jeong Il. I found it.
At that time, the draftsman
of the ruling was...
Choi Il Hwan.
Attorney Cho Gyung Ho is an
old friend of Kang Jeong Il.
His testimony has no credibility.
Mr. Lee Dong Jun.
The police secured the ruling
and asked me to examine it.
When Choi Il Hwan was...
a Daegu District Court judge in 1977,
he wrote this ruling.
Your Honor.
A person's style rarely changes.
The ruling of Mr. Shin
Chang Ho's first trial...
and the ruling Choi Il Hwan wrote
as a Daegu District Court judge...
have the same style...
of introductions and closing with
sentences to sidestep points.
They are considered as similar.
I will submit the demanding
document that Song Tae Gon wrote...
as a prosecutor as well.
Please compare the documents...
and make a wise judgment
on who wrote the ruling...
of Mr. Shin Chang Ho's...
first trial.
Without Mr. Lee Dong Jun, this
case wouldn't have been revealed.
This shows how Mr. Lee Dong Jun has
cooperated with the investigation.
I beg you will...
(Sentencing Guidelines for Perjury
and Destruction of Evidence)
Prosecutor.
For the accomplices in the same case,
we should have the same
sentencing guidelines.
If I reduce the prison terms of Mr.
Lee Dong Jun,
we will have to sentence reduced
terms to the accomplices.
I don't think...
that's what Mr. Lee wants.
Charging the accused, Kang Jeong Il...
with desecration of a corpse and
solicitation to commit murder,
I demand 15 years in prison.
Charging the accused, Choi Il Hwan...
with bribe-offering,
obstruction of business,
and murder of Kang Yu Taek,
I demand life imprisonment.
Charging the accused, Choi Su Yeon...
with bribe-offering and
obstruction of business,
I demand 12 years in prison.
Charging the accused, Song Tae Gon...
with obstruction of business,
I demand five years in prison.
The accused, Lee Dong Jun,
while working as a judge,
tried to sell his ruling for personal gain.
So he should be given a severe punishment.
I demand...
10 years in prison...
for the accused, Lee Dong Jun.
The accused, you may give
your final testimony.
I was a judge, but I didn't
live as a decent judge.
I insulted a reporter's life who
led a decent life as a reporter.
I even pursued...
a comfortable life by doing so.
I will say no more.
Please punish me severely...
and show that nobody is
free from the law...
and let the people who are
watching this trial know...
that the time of justice...
has begun.
The police announced today the
list of the 24 officials...
with a special promotion
and 48 officials...
with an award certificate
praising their hard work...
for the investigation on the
slush fund scandal of Taebaek.
The police says they deserve credit for...
standing against...
the huge judicial corruption without fear.
Well, it just...
doesn't make any sense.
Mr. Lee took care of the whole
thing, but his name isn't there.
What is the police throwing a party for?
Is it that...
the superior officials are
trying to take all the credit?
Gi Yong, I'll make the first move.
The investigation started with
the inside report from Mr. Lee.
The list of executives forbidden
from leaving the country...
and those who accepted bribes.
Mr. Lee Dong Jun submitted the
whole thing to the police.
The police said they conducted
the investigation on their own.
That's not true. What the police
have done for this case...
is follow Mr. Lee...
and take his statement.
Lieutenant Shin Young Ju who was
in charge of the investigation...
claimed that it was Mr. Lee Dong Jun
who reported all the information...
and cooperated with the investigation.
She also claimed that the
police tried to hide it...
and take all the credit for the outcome.
This case is forming public opinion that...
the sacrifice of a whistleblower
shouldn't be covered up.
Please tell me if there's anything
that is at variance with the truth.
Another truth will be reported tomorrow.
It turns out...
there has been Mr. Lee Dong Jun's
devotion for the investigation...
on Taebaek's scandal.
The ruling of his first
trial is just a day away.
Whether they will accuse
Lee of his crime...
or praise him for his devotion...
remains to be seen.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
For what you've done for my son.
I can't thank you enough.
All rise.
Be seated.
We hereby adjudicate on
Kim Sung Sik's murder...
and concealment case as follows.
Charging the accused, Kang Jeong Il...
with desecration of a corpse and
solicitation to commit murder,
I sentence him 10 years in prison.
Charging the accused, Choi Il Hwan...
with bribe-offering, obstruction
of business, and murder,
I sentence him life imprisonment.
Charging the accused, Choi Su Yeon...
with bribe-offering and
obstruction of business,
I sentence her seven years in prison.
Charging the accused, Song
Tae Gon with obstruction...
of business, I sentence
him two years in prison.
For the accused, Lee Dong Jun,
I sentence him four years in prison...
and his license to be disbarred.
(Application for National Compensation)
I plan to file an application
for national compensation.
I have two points.
They are the false charge for the murder...
and the delay the stay of execution
although his cancer was serious.
I want your help...
to write this application.
There are other good lawyers.
You are the one who knows best...
how my dad led his life...
and how he left this world.
Think of this trial...
as my dad's epitaph.
This won't be in history,
but it will be remembered for a long time.
My dad's epitaph that...
you and I will leave behind.
Please write one for me.
I hope I will be handsomely compensated.
I need the money for something.
(A few months later)
I, hereby rule on the application for...
national compensation filed by the
bereaved family of Shin Chang Ho.
I approve the requested amount,
250,000 dollars in full.
(Letter of resignation)
(3 years later)
(Law school)
Say that a patient is about to die.
In order to keep dignity
and value as a human,
the patient can refuse
life-sustaining treatments...
or can decide to stop the treatments.
It is acknowledged as part of one's
constitutional right to decide.
However, does the country have the duty...
legalizing this guarantee of
this right for the patient...
to be able to stop
life-sustaining treatments?
But this is a different matter.
I'm nervous.
Next week is my bar exam.
Will I pass?
At my law school,
we use your rulings as our textbook.
Are your rulings that great?
Well, if I say that, it
sounds like I'm bragging.
You started your studies...
with the compensation.
So...
I'm sure your dad...
will help you become a lawyer.
(Bar Exam ID, Name: Shin Young Ju)
(ID Number:11017)
(Bar Exam Pass List)
Young Ju, Young Ju!
Young Ju, this is your number, right?
What is it?
I asked the realtor guy next
door to look up your number.
Young Ju, you passed!
Starting today, my daughter is a lawyer.
It's only a test.
Mom, let's go to the real estate agency.
Let's put our store on the market...
and look for an office
space for my practice.
Why would we put our store on the market?
You need to rest, Mom.
Your shoulders and knees hurt after
peeling the garlic all day long.
I'll take care of you from now on.
Your daughter is a lawyer now.
Goodness.
(Lee Dong Jun)
(Shin Young Ju Law Firm)
I'm here.
I told them my daughter is a lawyer
when I gave the rice cakes out.
People looked at me differently.
Don't do that now.
A lawyer should read the
law books and hold pens.
I'll use the rags.
(Police Academy Graduation)
Chang Ho,
our daughter became a lawyer.
She studied with the money you left behind.
She became a lawyer...
to follow in your footsteps.
You're watching her, right?
Please continue to look over her.
(May 2021)
(Day of Dong Jun's release)
Thank you.
It was a bit expensive with the
salary of a police officer.
You have to wear it for 10 years.
For 10 years,
I'll have you check it.
You're a player.
You sound like an expert.
(Southern Seoul Prison)
This is the fourth Reporter
Shin Chang Ho Prize.
Reporter Jo Han Sik from Politics...
Division of Daehan Daily,
please come up to the stage.
The widow, Kim Sook Hee,
of Shin Chang Ho...
will present the prize.
(Awards ceremony for the
4th Shin Chang Ho Prize)
- Great job.
- Thank you.
Sure.
Reporter Jo Han Sik of Daehan Daily...
won the Reporter Shin Chang Ho Prize
for revealing the benefits...
judicial officers have been receiving...
- for their former office.
- My mom buys clothes...
once a year.
She said she couldn't wear the same
outfit for the awards ceremony.
Reporters Associations created
an award after my dad.
On the day of the awards ceremony,
my dad's name goes viral online.
My dad must be happy.
You're going to the sanitarium, right?
Yes.
Hello.
Mom.
Dong Jun.
You're here.
He came here last year.
He has serious Alzheimer's. His
disease is rapidly worsening.
His family can't take care of him,
and he didn't want to go to his
hospital, so he came here.
Did he want me...
to see him like this?
A President's doctor,
a poor ordinary person,
a person who's led a successful life,
and a person who's wrestled
against adversity...
eventually go down the same path.
They are so cruel.
They've never visited him once.
The people from Hangang Hospital.
He doesn't even expect to see them.
I guess he knows that.
After losing...
money, greed, time,
and his everything, he came back.
Dong Jun.
Let's have dinner together tonight.
Dad,
you,
and me, as a family.
This is good. Eat a lot.
Eat up.
You should gobble up jajangmyeon noisely.
Attorney General.
I ordered this from Seonwongak.
You're right. You're good at this.
By the way,
what are you doing these days?
I don't have the license, but I
have the original technology.
I work at an attorney's office.
You're so unctuous.
Is this your first time at formal trial?
You mean...
this is your first time to
stand before the court?
I've only taken care of
some cases with fines,
summary indictment, and settlements.
How does it feel to stand before the court?
I wouldn't even talk to the judge
right if he looked down on me.
Don't worry about it.
You'll do just fine.
Try to think...
I'm the judge.
Prosecuting counsel, testify.
The medical device she purchased...
is worth about 300 dollars.
But they deceived old people into
buying it for 1,000 dollars...
with some performances...
and free trial events.
And the requests for
refund has been denied.
Your Honor,
please give an order for a refund.
The events and transport
of product cost money.
Above all things, she's used
the product for three months.
It's unreasonable...
to give her a refund.
She's tried to reach you for the
past three month, but she couldn't.
If they accept every single refund request,
the company will go bankrupt.
A bankrupt company can move one,
but a bankrupt person has
to keep making a living.
It's only 1,000 dollars
we're talking about.
The money of 1,000 dollars is her
pocket money for a whole year.
Your Honor.
A bankrupt company can move one,
but a bankrupt person has
to keep making a living.
Dozens of her friends at the
senior center were deceived.
Collect their cases and
file a class action suit.
Gather the receipts of purchase...
and submit in court.
I will never...
disregard...
concrete evidence...
ever again.
(Whisper)