Based in the live of
Countess Erzebet Bathory (1560-1614)
History is a tale told by the victors.
Who are the victors?
Barbaric warriors, mad kings, and greedy traitors.
Maybe most of our histories are made of fables
fabricated by those glorious victors.
This is the story of Countess Erzebet Bathory.
Not just as history remembers her
but also how I remember her.
Countess Erzebet Bathory was born into
one of the Hungary's most illustrious families in 1560.
Your future wife...
She was promised to Ferenc Nadasky's at birth
Erzebet, come here.
They stole a horse, they deserve to be punished.
History tells us, from very early age,
Erzebet learnt to be fearless
...unfeeling...
...curious...
The seed will turn into a big tree one day.
...and pittyless
Why is it when you put someone under the ground
they do not grow like seed?
The seeds are alive, whereas people
we buried in the ground are dead.
- But if we bury them alive?
- They suffocate and die.
So we get eaten by worms.
The body melts away
but the soul passes on to heaven or hell.
You will go to heaven just like your Papa.
The soul is eternal my dear.
If it was not, I would have to raise an army
to conquer death.
He is so lovely, I want him to be my husband.
When he reachs his marrying age,
you will be old and worn.
Count Nadasky will be your husband.
I beg you not to harm him.
I love him, Mother.
The only love you shall feel is to Our Lord,
you should respect your husband.
But as for peasants and servants
you must never fornicate with them.
Your peasant will die as he deserves. And you will stay
in your room. So no ones will know of yours silly mistake.
- It is a boy.
- Leave.
But Mother, my child.
She was married to Ferenc Nadasky at 15.
Her mother died soon after.
Erzebet managed her estate masterfully.
Soon many noble families from kingdoms of Bohemia
to Poland were in debt to her and her husband.
She even lent large sums of money to the king himself.
She gave Nadasky 3 children.
The first child was born 10 years into the union.
She hardly spent any time with her husband.
In less than 50 years
the Turks has slaughtered and enslaved
half the population of Hungary.
Nadasky and his men were the only warriors they feared.
Erzebet funded a hospital for the poor.
But bad-told said, that many of them never came out alive.
Though a devoted protestant
Erzebet believed many heretic's theories.
Darvulia, who some claimed was witch,
managed Erzebet's wealth so well
that some believed
she knew the recipe for making gold.
The combination of Nadasky's military powers
and Erzebet's intelligence and unbending will
quickly made them the most feared,
respected and powerful family in the kingdom.
- Good afternoon, my King.
- Good afternoon, Dear Count Nadasky.
Your majesty, I have come to demand
my pay for this last year of war.
Of course, you are welcome to stay
for a few days if you wish
while we gather the amount.
- We're having excutions all day tomorrow.
- Um, unfortunatly, I have no time to wait.
- I must leave before night fall.
- What a shame.
Half in gold and half in talers will do.
Good day, My King.
A gift from the King.
With what he still owes us,
he should have gotten me the holy grail.
Mother, Father is back.
Please leave the room... Now.
- Leave.
- I brought you my pay. And...
Oh, thank you daddy. A bird.
- I feel a bit sick.
- It is the wine.
My head hurts.
You're burning up.
Let me get Darvulia.
She will surely have good remedy for you.
I do not need the help of Satan.
More.
You saved me, my love.
I can see the beautiful morning light.
I am sorry dear, but he is gone.
Count Ferenc Nadasky
was a good husband and father.
But above all, a great warrior.
Today he's standing joyfully with Jesus
at the right hand of God.
Soon we will be with him
at their side for eternity.
I have sent the soldiers back to war.
You will let in Cachtice while I am gone.
I must bring the children to a safer place...
..and show the Court
Ferenc's dead has not weaken me.
- Are we ever coming back, Mother?
- Of course, but for now you will stay in Vienna.
You will learn music,
French and Latin with best teachers.
And aunt Klara will take you
to see plays and fireworks.
- Fireworks?
- Yes.
- You see it is essential to pay soldiers well.
- I know, dear countess.
But the peasants who escape this slaughter
are dying of hunger.
Please, have patience and allow me to pay you later.
- It will be difficult...
- Should I assign a guardian to manage your estate?
You know I disapprove of a widow
handling her lands alone.
I can manage perfectly well.
You know, my husband had little to do
with such matters.
Well, then you can sell some land,
hire younger men and pay them less.
I am not too keen to impoverish
my estate and send children to war.
But if you demand it, I will.
I will keep the Turks out of what is left of Hungary
no matter what it costs me.
You are my best ally.
Dear Niece, I'm delighted you decided
to leave your little angels with me.
It will not be fair to keep them at Cachtice.
Your husband's death must have been
a dreadful shock to them.
Indeed. He died so fast, and in bed.
He probably caught a shameful illness
from one of those Turkish whores.
Last time my husband came home
from the battle front,
His little skin-theca almost fell off.
Not a great loss, from what you've told me.
Countess Bathory, I heard the king
owes you so much from Nadasky.
He is so poor that he cannot afford
to pay you for more than a year.
Yes, the King owes me a fortune
which is to my advantage.
Might he not perhaps take offence
in such wealth since you are a Protestant?
Our king openly tolerates Protestants.
Thank you Count Thurzo.
It is my right not to share my posessions
with the Catholic Church.
For centuries your friends in Rome
orchestrated countless...
..murders of inocents, especially women.
Your word suprise me.
Are you defending witches, Countess?
Please, this conversation is boring me!
I apologize.
I was just asking the Countess
about her admirable wealth.
Ne pose pas de cuestions si
tu connais deja la reponse.
My little niece knows six languages,
including ancient Greek.
It is possible for a woman's mind...
- ..to be sharper than than a man's?
- Of course it is.
But I have heard that their emotions are...
..always get best of them
so their intelligence ultmately, wasted.
I agree that most women are weak.
And it is in the area of heart
that the weakness seems to lie.
A man's weakness is located
in the lower place of the body.
At somewhat less noble part.
I think men and women are both equal and different.
- Equal? That is a very bold statement.
- You do not listen, Bishop.
My cousin said "and different".
We all have our strengths and weaknesses.
What are your weaknesses, Countess?
I am a woman. I love beautiful dresses and gold jewelry.
Just like you, dear Bishop.
Are you sure the woman at Cachtice
can manage your estate wisely?
Darvulia is young but she is more than wise
to maintaining my wealth.
She is the most knowledgable woman in the land.
- After you.
- Of course.
I've heard you've earned
a large amount of money recently.
Yes, a very profitable transaction.
It did cost many the life and freedom
of many Bohemian peasants.
Everything has its price.
- Turkish lines are quite near your castle.
- Indeed.
Don't you feel endangered to stand alone near the wars?
- I am not alone and the war is my duty.
- Have you considered remarrying?
Our union would make us most powerful.
Dear Gyorgy, you know very well, it would
be improper for me to marry you
You are a Count by mariage
whereas nobility has be in my blood for centuries.
I know, dear cousin. All I'm saying is
if you feel yourself need you can always count on me.
What matters is
that we are all united against the Turks.
Of course.
We must leave for the ball, Erzebet.
Dear Count, will you join us?
Unfortunately I'm leaving for Prague early tomorrow.
What a shame. Have a good journey then.
- Did he dare to ask you?
- Of course.
I knew it. He insisted of coming.
I am not fond of his manners.
He's always wearing last year's fashion.
Do not marry him.
Safe journey.
There is that French doctor I want you to meet.
He'd like to visit your hospital.
I am afraid it has become more of a mass grave
than a hospital lately.
Also, there is an astronomer who says
the earth is not moving in the circle around the sun...
..but all over the place.
Maybe that is why I've been so dizzy lately.
- Countess Erzebet Bathory.
- Enchante de faire votre connaissance
- Je tiens a rendre a l'hopital. Madam?
- Biensur quand vous voulez!
Excuse-moi.
Do you happen to know who that young man is?
Istvan Thurzo. Gyorgy's only son.
- He moved back to Vienna recently.
- He was a child just yesterday.
Yesterday? Then do not wait too long.
He might grow old and bald
before the night is over.
- Klara.
- Istvan.
We had dinner with your father,
but unfortunately he could not join us to the ball.
I would like you to meet my little niece.
I do not think I have the pleasure of meeting you before.
Oh, would you excuse me.
Please to meet you, Count Thurzo.
I knew your late mother quite well, she was lovely.
I am Countess Bathory.
- Countess Erzebet Bathory?
- Yes. Whatever you heard about me.
That everyone respects and fears you.
- Forgive me...
- I do not object to being feared.
- Do I inspire fear in you?
- Not at all.
I'm so very honored to meet you.
And I you.
- I am awfully sorry about Count Nadasky.
- It was a dreadful shock to my children.
Might be a manner to ask
but does widowhood forbid you to dance?
No.
- You're a good dancer for one who's so young.
- I'm not that young, I'm 21.
Oh, 21?
- Would you care to dance the next one?
- I need a moment to myself.
- He is to my taste.
- Much more exciting than his father, isn't he?
- Are you going to have an affair?
- Perhaps.
You must.
- Every word he speaks seems so sincere.
- Well, he might be sincere.
Ever since his mother died,
he's been very devoted to his studies in Krakow.
The Italian countess he was about to marry
died before they even met.
Now his father has found him
a new wife in Denmark.
Istvan has spent very little time at the court.
You mean he still has a chance to go to heaven?
He has not yet been corrupted by power?
A genuine and virtuous young man... How lovely.
- What are you looking at?
- Sorry.
- Do you find them pretty?
- Pardon?
- My lips.
- Yes. That is...
- Do you wish to kiss them?
- No!
No?
- Oh, yes ...
- Then why do you not?
- In front of every one?
- Do you care?
We have arrived.
- Why are you shaking?
- I do not know.
You must rest.
I do not believe I will be able
to rest until we meet again.
I have to ride back tomorrow.
May I see you early so I can spend
every moment with you before you leave?
Every moment?
It is only because I know what I feel.
- You can meet me at my aunt's villa before noon.
- Thank you.
I must go before I lose my mind.
Wait... do you have to go?
Since we will meet in the morning,
and we only have less than a day.
I know what we've done is sinful,
but it does not feel wrong in my heart.
My heart feels warmer than ever.
- Was I careful?
- You have nothing to worry about.
Kissing you feels like making love to you.
- And making love to you feels like...
- Like what?
I cannot find words to describe it.
Is it not strange to think as we're enjoying ourselves today,
warm in each other's arms
others are dying at war?
We're all in the hands of God.
Let us rejoice we are not the ones
dying in war today.
It is morning. I ought to leave soon.
Must you travel today?
I have many matters to attend to at Cachtice.
War is a messy job for a lonely woman.
I understand.
I will have my valet bring you a letter
every week until we meet again.
Be careful, they cost me a fortune in Vienna.
I have this one made for you, my dear.
I have so much to tell you.
I had an affair with a young man.
It was so lovely.
Good.
Do you have more of that ointment
to make my skin softer?
Softer for that young man?
- Lust, it will gain you nothing.
- It's not lust, not this time.
I have never felt this way.
Even when I was a girl.
- I thought you were strong.
- Darvulia, love is not a sign of weakness.
- It is the most noble feeling known to man.
- Assuming he is one.
You should see his skin.
So soft, so perfect.
Is it him you're fond of
or just texture of his young skin?
Do not be a witch!
- How old?
- 21.
- Who is he?
- Istvan Thurzo.
His father wishes for their bloodline
to be tied to mine.
Oh, you're planning on asking for his hand?
Keep him as a lover, if you wish,
but do not forget your rank.
- He is 21 while you're soon to be 39.
- He's very mature for his age.
Erzebet, young people change their mind all the time.
He can have any woman.
I am not enjoying your company
today you old hag.
I am your servant as always.
But I remind you that I am younger than you.
Enough!
Time has no respect for beauty.
Countess, a letter.
Erzebet, you know I will marry soon.
Yes, I have heard.
It hurts me to even think
I could touch another woman.
Istvan, marry her, have children...
and be my lover always.
But I will be so far away.
And I want to be only yours.
No other woman could mean anything to my heart.
- To your heart?
- Yes.
I've never felt this way.
Is it a sin to love someone in this manner?
When I am with him, I feel joy and beauty.
When I away from him,
I feel pain as if hundreds of tigers...
..tigers are tearing apart my entire body.
- His soul is in a better place.
- Who's?
- Count Nadasky's.
- Of course.
It is such an honor to have you pray
in our humble village church.
And thank you again for your generous donation.
It is nothing, father. God has given me so much.
Countess, you shouldn't be out here. It is so cold.
- I'm waiting for a letter.
- Must be a very important letter.
- Very.
- What a beautiful dress.
- What's your name?
- Pola.
Here, take it. It's yours.
Go now. Leave the Countess alone.
It has been over a week
and I have not received his letter yet.
You have to be careful of what you wish for.
Your two destinies are to be tied
in a manner that did you not expect.
It is my desire.
- And more if the magic works soon.
- Gold is not main thing that binds me to you.
And you can spend your nights with me.
I will need something of his.
Something he gave you preferably.
Just for tonight.
My beautiful love what a fool I was to worry.
Your messenger had simply been delayed.
He will meet me at the Von Varad ball in a week.
I shall leave tomorrow.
- So soon?
- I will visit the children.
Dear Countess, you look even more as splendid...
...than in the paintings I've seen of you.
- I am Count Dominic Vizakna.
- A flatterer is a secret enemy I've heard.
Is seduction merely on of you hobbies
or your life's main occupation?
Forgive me for intruding
but you seem somewhat morose.
I suppose I can not hide my emotions very well.
Can I help you feel better in anyway?
I am afraid the reason for my pain isn't cureable.
Then it can only be
that horrible sickness called "love".
Truly this person does not deserve your love
if he is capable of hurting such
a precious woman.
A nobel man is looking for you, Countess.
I missed you so.
I'm not ba able to see you for long tonight.
- I have important matters to deal with.
- This late, what is it?
- I wish to leave Vienna with you tomorrow at midday.
- Where to?
To your castle. I would like
to stay with you.
Very well I could visit my children early...
I will be with you not later than midday.
I promise.
Wait! If there is a reason for your haste,
you're not telling me,
I must know what is it.
Is it that you do not feel the same
as you did a month ago?
I do feel the same.
And the next few days will prove my true devotion.
Dear Countess, he is not worthy of your love.
- You are wrong about him.
- Will you like company tonight?
Do you not see the lines on my face?
I have no time to play, good night!
Dear Istvan. I have waited,
and you've given me no sign.
Young people often change their minds...
because they think they have all the time in the world.
Often death takes us
before we have had the chance to taste love.
Because when love was right in front of us,
we were too busy looking for it elsewhere.
Please tell me I was not fooled,
and your feelings were true.
- You have no right to keep me in this room.
- You've disobeyed me and met with her again.
- She has being waiting for me since yesterday.
- I've found out about your foolish plan to escape with her.
She has countless minions,
you are just one of many, my son.
I do not believe she feels the same about me
as she does about her other lovers.
You got what you wanted from her.
- Everything that is conquered, is destroyed.
- Conquered?
If the goal was to honor Countess Bathory,
yes, the goal was reached, more than once.
But unlike you, I do not see
anything destructive in the act of love.
We are not talking about a land to conquer
or a competitor who must be bested.
We are talking about a kind woman
and a very noble feeling we share.
The same noble feeling that you share
with Baroness von Kraj?
You know very well that I have not seen von Kraj
since I met Erzebet.
I do love her, father.
Love is a myth to keep the minds
of young peasants and virgins occupied with a dream.
- It has no place in our world.
- In your world!
I do not understand you though.
It would be beneficial for you if I married Erzebet.
So you could grant me a tiny portion of her land?
She never marry you.
Your blood is not noble enough.
- You are leaving today for Denmark.
- I will not.
Would you like to know how grieved the Countess is?
She is already in the company of Count Vizakna.
- You know his reputation?
- That is a lie.
They met two days ago and not left each other since.
You have already been forgotten.
If you are wise, everything that
is mine will be yours one day.
Have a good journey.
Guards ...
This man will stay with you
until he decides not to disobey me again.
My father had arranged my marriage
to the daughter of a wealthy Danish trading partner.
I was married to Hanne Aagesen against my will.
It was only years later, on his death bed,
that my father confessed to me
some of the truths about Erzebet.
But I arrived so late to decide,
that I could only understand
a few words between his screams.
I heard just enough to realize that what is known
about the Countess is made of many lies.
In fact, almost all I know about her
from that day on, I was told.
Count Vizakna is waiting for an answer.
I am so honored you have agreed
to spend time with me.
and supprised you wish to ride.
- Which part of the kingdom were you born in?
- In the castle of Bekov.
There are amusing rumors about that castle.
A noble family that only lives at night
and eats newborns so I've heard.
It is because of a skin condition
that afflicts most of my family,
we are not fond of sunlight.
But do not worry. I do not feed on newborns.
Have you read that book about Turkish customs?
They drink the blood of boys
to take on their strength.
I have not read it,
but I am not surprised to hear such infamy.
Your young friend was in such a hurry the other night.
Yes, I have not heard from him since.
I'm concerned he may have gotten hurt or...
I saw him just this morning
near San Nicholas with a friend.
He seemed quite well.
- A friend?
- Yes.
- A woman?
- No.
She was too young to be called a woman.
- Probably his little sister.
- He has no little sister.
- Oh.
- Maybe you're right about him.
I did not even get a word of apology.
Making me wait all day.
You old witch!
Your repulsive look scared my horse.
Powerful now, but soon you will look like me.
- And then you shall see.
- How dare you. Out of my sight!
Countess, you can not let someone
who insults you in this manner go unpunished.
- Did someone bring a letter when I was away?
- No, Countess.
This dress makes me look old and worn.
I wish to change, now.
I wish to pray and fast until he answers my letter.
Leave me to myself.
Dear Lord, why are you punishing me?
How can you give me this beautiful love
and take it away from me so fast?
Water alone will not keep you alive very long.
Erzebet, it has been 3 weeks.
If you let yourself die,
what will happen to your lands and children.
I do not know.
I do not understand how a strong woman
can fall for such a weak young man?
He is not weak. He is pure and kind.
Before I met him, my life was meaningless,
and I had no idea.
News from Cachtice.
- The Countess is ill.
- Ill?
- Some say she's got mad, she is heartbroken.
- Istvan?
Their silly love affair might in
fact serve us in some way.
I thought it will be wise to take hold of these.
Although it was an no small cost.
Soon my son would dwell fully in melancholy.
He is naturally like his mother.
He has inherited so little of my character.
But I want this proof of her lunacy... at any cost.
I shall kill him!
He just played with me. Who is he?
A son of a whore in a brothel?
He wrote about a young married woman.
The Baroness von Kraj.
Only 17 and very pretty.
He says he loves her more
than anything in the world.
That his heart could only be hers.
He writes that he's sorry that he mistook
his feelings of admiration and respectful love.
That I reminded him so much of his late mother!
Look!
Smooth and flawless.
Even if she smells like horseshit,
any man will choose her over me.
Erzebet, forget about him. I beg you!
How?
A man dressed in black is at the door, asking for you.
- A young man?
- Count Dominic Vizakna, he says.
- Should we let him in?
- Of course.
I wish to see him alone.
- What brings you here so late?
- I do not like to travel during the day.
You frighten my maids.
All my soldiers are at war.
We are careful about who we let in here.
I have brought you that book on
Turkish customs I was telling you about.
Traveled a long way to bring me a book?
It concerned me to hear nothing from you
since that afternoon.
I've been quite busy.
The truth is I could not wait any longer
to see you again.
Let me show you other ways of using this belt.
And on someone who might find it
more suited to his taste.
When my father first told me of the nature
of her liason with Dominic Vizakna
I could not believe
she was capable of such decadents.
- Did you truly enjoy that?
- Yes.
- How can you?
- You do not know...
..because you do not have a taste for recieving pain.
- Did you enjoy inflicting it though?
- I'm not sure.
I wish to be your servant... always.
I'm not young and foolish. I mean what I say.
I wish to be alone.
I came to tell you I do not like the man
that visited you in the night.
I was such a fool to believe in Istvan's love.
I was just too old to be loved.
That is not true.
Maybe I should never have shown
my face to him in the daylight.
Look at me. I'm rotting.
- She was right.
- Who?
The old witch in the park.
She put a curse on me.
Or is it that your ointments are no longer effective?
Make something that works!
Erzebet, I will not have you talk to me
in this manner.
What are you looking at?
Come and brush my hair.
It's bad enough my face has wrinkles.
Now you want me be bald like an old man?
Look at what you've done!
Leave! Leave!
No one knows what she saw in the mirror,
if it was because the soft morning light
merely illuminated her face in an unusual manner,
or if her reason had weakened.
Thank you, my Lord.
You can stay at the castle.
We'll take care of you until you're healed.
This is for you from the Countess.
The countess is a good woman.
I did pull her hair a bit too hard.
Dorothea, Susanna needs you down in the kitchen.
- How old are you, my child?
- 16.
- Where is your family?
- In Novaky.
- That's quite far. Do you see them often?
- I visit once a year.
Are you a virgin?
- Yes, Countess.
- Of course.
Feel better.
- Her wound is completely healed.
- I told you to remove the scab every time.
I did, but it healed anyway.
Darvulia, come have a closer look.
- I do not see any difference.
- Nonsense.
Helena, Dorothea what you see?
- It looks smoother to me.
- Yes, yes, absolutely.
Yes, it is the Lord's answer
to my prayers.
Not only the look,
but the feel of my skin is incredibly different.
As if I was younger.
I believe it is because she is a virgin.
The purity of her blood seems
to be the reason why it is working.
It is a true miracle.
It is for your own good.
Did I kill you?
Almost.
I felt the cold breath of death
and I saw two doors opening to a bright light.
You mean heaven was opening
its doors to you?
I doubt you will go to heaven
with your inclination for these games.
In fact I am sure to go to hell
so why not do exactly what I wish during my time here.
I am so fond of you that I could not stay away
from you for more than a week.
To my behavior to that old woman,
I thought you might have being frightened of me.
On the contrary. That old witch deserved to die.
You were too kind.
For a while I thought she had
put a curse on me.
I looked so old and worn.
You look exceptionally ravishing tonight.
- Tonight more than the other night?
- Yes, more than the day we met.
More than our afternoon in the park.
Tonight it seems the sun itself
is glowing from under your skin.
Now that I look closely,
It is quite magical.
Tonight you look no more
than 20 years of age.
I know.
Countess ...
What is happening?
You are giving me something beautiful.
Something I had lost.
But when will it stop?
When you are empty, my child.
It is God's will.
It is said that it is how the murder started.
To achieve her mad pursuit
of eternal youth and beauty,
she needed fresh blood, more and more.
God, is it wrong for one to stay beautiful and young?
All around you is beauty.
If only Istvan could see me today.
You seem to be only one
that can not see the blood is working.
Fortunately, Dominic was there to notice...
..how different I've looked ever since I started.
I will not trust a word comes out from his mouth.
Will you stop this before it is too late.
I tried to stop,
but I already felt less alert.
I applied the blood again and I felt an
incredible strength invading every part of my body.
The blood is not making you any younger.
On the contrary, you're starting
to smell of death.
- Leave.
- Your vanity will be your undoing.
And you impudence will bring yours.
- Leave and never come back.
- No, I care too much.
Is it true that you have shared
love only with women?
That makes you a virgin then.
There have been so many maids dying
at the castle lately.
They were clumsy little geese.
Some cut themselves while cocking and got sick.
Others fell down the stairs.
- Here.
- Thank the Countess for me.
We shall stop bringing the girls to church.
I know the Countess wants to give them
proper burials, but above all...
..the Countess want fresh blood.
Quite an invention.
I want make sure the witches around here
are bled before they are burned.
I have heard that the moisture in the body
keeps them from burning in the inside.
It is said that cage allowed her
to bleed the girls...
..more effectively with very little blood wasted.
The murders quickly multiplied.
Witnesses said she used up to ten girls a month.
I wrote Erzebet many letters
but never received one from her.
After I was assured of her affair with Count Vizakna,
I stopped writing and resigned
myself to my fate.
What a stunning jewel, matches your beauty.
A token from King Matthias
for my army's many victories.
- Must be exhausting to deal with war.
- Indeed. And it is costing me a fortune.
It is a shame that a beautiful woman
has to worry about such matters.
After all, it is said that the Queen
of England lost her looks just...
..because of her war with Spain.
- Do you care for me?
- No.
You are not beautiful enough.
Your features are almost like those of a Turk.
Oh, unlike Istvan?
- Do not say his name.
- Would you like me to kill him for you?
- Is he back?
- He is visiting Vienna, with his wife.
So, should I, be his death?
No.
- What are you looking for?
- I thought the Countess has sent you away?
I come her at night to watch over her.
Make sure no harm is done to her.
- You are a rat. I know who sends you.
- I am just here to please the Countess.
No, you are here to flatter
her worst side - her cruelty.
You are quite a beauty.
I did not know witches could
have such pretty features.
- Do not touch me with your poisonous hands!
- Not poisonous, soft and loving.
If you come back, you will die.
I will die? How would I die?
Will you ask Satan for his gracious help?
Countess Bathory is the one who keeps you
from being burn at the stake.
But now it's clear that she is more fond of me
than she's of you, so
Let us see who dies first.
Seasons passed
and Erzebet spent less and less time at court.
She would visit Vienna only to see her children.
She claimed that she was busy with the war,
but slowly the rumor spread
that she stayed at Cachtice.
Because her evil practices.
Witnesses later claimed that the dead girls
were left in the wood around the castle.
And most of the bodies were never found.
Erzebet allegedly kept percise record of every murder.
Her journals were presented main proof
against her at the trial.
Even though she denied ever
having written them.
My Lord, perhaps what I am doing is wrong.
The blood has been giving
me rashes of late.
Maybe peasant blood is too rough for my skin.
Darvulia has called for you. She is very ill.
Poisoned by her own venom no doubt.
I do not wish to see her.
Many girls have gone.
I found a body last year in the forest,
no blood left in her.
There are demons in there.
Maybe it's Bathory herself.
You have to do something.
Be sure you give it to the king himself.
My lord, the demons are here.
How can you let this happen, my lord?
I gave you so much.
He betrayed the Countess.
The King must not be informed.
Stop that messenger, Janos. Hurry.
Count Vizakna left early,
and one of you journals is missing.
He will not come back
now that he knows.
We should send someone out to kill that villain.
It would be wise.
I came to tell you Darvulia has died.
She left a letter to you.
My love, do not let another stranger
into your castle.
You have given them the weapons
to destroy everything you have built.
I shall miss only one thing from your world
which is no longer mine.
Your soft kisses.
I have loved you always.
Erzebet, you have gone too far.
Everything that is alive must die,
and you will too.
No matter what you do.
There is beauty in letting
time do its duty.
I wish to leave for Vienna to visit my children.
You killed our priest, you demon.
Back to Cachtice!
Make sure the general gets it soon.
We need soldiers to protect us.
An angry crowd can be more vicious
than a pack of wolves.
Where is Janos?
He has been gone for weeks.
You sent him to get
girls from far away.
Give me a mirror.
The blood is making me sick
but without it I am dying.
Bring me a virgin. Even a boy.
No, no boys. God created them in His image.
Countess.
This is the the only girl we could fine.
She is not too healthy, but she is a virgin.
- How old are you, my sweet?
- Twelve, I think.
- You do not know?
- I was found, Countess.
- So you have no family?
- No.
They feed me when I clean up the pig sty.
Come.
Pola, I remember you.
I wish to tell you something.
Pola, run away. Run, leave this castle.
Run, or I will kill you.
Pola!
After my father's death, I found records of...
...large sums of money sent to Dominic Vizakna.
As well as a letter
mentioning women of lower nobility who...
..disappeared around that time.
- Who are you?
- I am Kasia from Rosenheim.
My parents find you and punish you for this.
- How old are you?
- 15.
- Are you a virgin?
- Yes, of course.
And you?
I'm 22 and I am married.
I am the Baroness von Kraj.
Janos, I kill you.
You have brought a married woman.
She is of no use to me.
And her husband will be looking for her.
I would like to know
why we have been brought here by force?
I will punish the traitor myself
who got us into this.
- Did you say "Kraj"?
- Yes.
Kraj, how lovely to meet you.
You are right. My husband will be looking for me.
Not if I have a letter of farewell brought to him,
confessing you run away with your lover.
Istvan Thurzo, is it not?
You are mad. I have not seen Istvan in years.
But I remember a rumor...
about an illustrious countess,
who has fallen madly in love with him.
And gave herself to him so easily.
Could you possibly be Erzebet?
Collect the blood before it is wasted.
It was no manners to pull us out of bed
in the middle of the night.
I did not want to wait too long because...
..of the smell.
We are not sure how many have perished this way.
Maybe hundreds over the past years.
Not a drop of blood left in the poor girls.
Your mother has been using her hospital
to justify the numerous deaths.
- I wish to visit my mother and see for myself.
- This is just one of many.
Would you wish to see more?
Most of them are in much poorer shape.
- I am not going.
- But you are a man, you must.
- I am not going either.
- Well I'm not going alone.
Your Majesty...
There are reports that girls have been...
..disappearing near Countess Bathory's castle
for a few years.
Many peasants have come all the way to Vienna
claiming that hundreds have died.
The girls were tortured before their death.
- I see nothing wrong in that.
- And bled to death.
Many are claiming Countess Bathory is assisted
by witches and blood-thirsty demons.
Witches and Demons?
The Countess Bathory involved in witchcraft?
Possibly.
Her strength always seemed unnatural.
Her army mysteriously invincible.
Probably driven by some spell? It's fascinating.
A priest was found dead as well.
If the Countess is proven to be guilty of using witchery,
You will be cleared of debts to her
and can seize her estate.
Sign this and I shall send the men
to investigate murders in Cathtice.
Every month, I signed dozens of death warrants
for those witches.
And it becomes worse than the plague.
When will it stop?
When men become wise.
Which will not be soon.
The King has heard of the murders
and suspects Bathory of witchcraft.
We must send our men today.
Her children signed the agreement.
They are eager to get their share.
The Harpy will be charged with murder.
I assured her children that witchcraft
would not be mentioned at her trial.
So her estate can not be seized
by the King.
It will allow her to bequeath her possessions
to whomever she wishes.
The king was going to hear of her
doings soon enough
and her children would have been
completely destitute.
She has little choice but sign this...
..in order to protect her children.
The agreement entitles you to take over her land...
..and the extrordinary army she and her husband
have raised over the years.
I see you have doubts. But the truth is
that hundreds of young women have died.
Peasant girls first, but noble women have
vanished now also right near her land.
- You used to know one of them.
- Yes. But why send me?
As I recalled, you were once quite close
to Countess Bethory.
As I recalled, you were not very pleased about it.
- Why not send him?
- She would kill me.
I believe you are the one
to take care of this matter, my son.
And she is very cautious.
It is easier for you to approach her.
- Can I say no?
- No.
You saw some of the girls
I found near her castle.
My body still bears
the scars of her lunacy.
- Would you care to see?
- No.
She is a murderess.
I want everything taken care of
before the King can get to Cachtice.
This is for you my son.
After this, you will be
the most powerful man in the Kingdom.
- After you.
- Of course.
We are leaving today.
Do not feel remorseful.
She begged me to kill you,
not so long ago.
- Why did you not?
- She did not offer to pay me.
It is strange to think that the hand that...
..once stroke her will soon strike her.
I will only strike her if she is guilty.
You know which sin is worst?
Murder or greed?
We will soon find out.
In hell.
Beware of her. She is mad.
And she will try to kill you.
Stop!
Dismount.
I wish to see her doings with my own eyes
before we arrest her.
They will stay here until we send for them.
Do not fear, she only has few men protecting her.
It is not fear of facing a murderess that upsets me.
The excitement of seeing her again
mixed with the sorrow of losing her forever.
Horsemen, 2 horsemen riding towards us.
Dorothea, my white dress. Hurry.
You answered my prayers.
Dear Count Thurzo, what a surprise
after all this time.
What has it been? Three years?
- Five.
- How quickly time flies.
Yes.
Let me ask you, how have you been, my lady.
I have been quite busy with this awful war.
So, what brings you here?
I was riding to Krakow when...
..my companion pointed out your beautiful castle.
I thought maybe we could stay one night...
or even a bit longer.
I apologize about the flies.
My men left a horse rotting outside the castle...
..and we have not been able
to get rid of them ever since.
- So you're married now?
- I was married for four years.
My wife died one year ago bearing our first child.
It died soon after.
I am so sorry to hear that.
She was the daughter of a
powerful Danish merchant.
My father needed a new trading allies.
I am truly happy about your visit, Dear Istvan.
I can not tell you how often I've wished
for this day to come.
Why did God have us
born 20 years apart?
It will not stop me from loving you.
Come to my room.
I have had a long journey.
Let me rest first. Then I shall come to you.
I was so afraid you would say no.
Why did you have to break my heart
with that abominable letter?
What did I write in any of my letters
that could have possibly upset you?
The one and only letter
I received from you...
..confessing your love for
the Baroness von Kraj.
Kraj used to be mine but after I met you,
I never saw her again.
And I certaily never sent such a letter.
My father, he must have written it in my name.
How could I have doubted you?
I only trusted my valet to deliver
the many letters I wrote to you.
Begging you to forgive me.
But I was sent away by force.
Let us be stronger than your father's desperate...
attempt to destroy our beautiful love.
It's not too late. Come.
No.
Why not?
Your hands are so cold.
Why are you shaking, my love?
It is the joy of seeing you again.
Do you know how long I've been waiting for you?
I almost lost my mind.
There is nothing more painful
than feeling betrayed by someone you love so deeply.
I always promised myself to take revenge
but when I saw you riding from afar
all my anger vanished, all I felt was love.
No matter how much I cared for her,
another part of me believed
what I've had heard and seen.
There was too much evidence, too many witnesses,
for me to believe that she could be innocent.
Have you lost your mind?
You're here to find out about the cruel murders,
not to spend the night with her.
I'm so fond of her.
I do not believe she could hurt anyone.
Do not let that sorrow charm you. She will eat you alive.
Perhaps if her heart had not been broken,
she would have not become who she is.
God made her this way - or the devil more like it.
Her evil was forged this way from birth.
- What if I disobeyed my father and escaped.
- You didn't.
So we will never know.
Let us find out who she really is.
Let's find out someting not good...
Master, you do not want to see this.
A pile of rotting corpses, dismembered children.
Their eyes eaten by worms.
The devil himself could not be more effective.
Countess Bathory, you are under arrest.
The accomplices have confessed to all the murders.
The girls were bled to death in the cage.
Erzebet's servants' confessions were made under torture.
The Countess herself was absent for her own trial.
It was decided to hide her uncontainable madness.
And thus to protect her name.
Death by strangulation is what the shrews deserve.
As for that creature, decapitation.
He can hear but not speak.
Countess Bathory is condemned
to be walled up inside her bedroom for life.
A small openning will be left
to provide food and water.
No mirrors will be left in the room
in order to punish the Countess for her vanity.
Many witnesses've testifed to the murders and atrocities...
..committed by the Countess and her accomplices.
Bodies were found around Cathtice castle.
Some were partially eaten by the Countess.
Also found were the journals written
by the Countess Bathory herself...
..documenting the murders in detail.
As well as letters from Darvulia,
the witch, heretical books,
and finally the cage she tortured the girls in.
Even if it seems the Countess may not
have practiced witchcraft,
We do have one witness who has confirmed that...
..he saw her copulating with the devil himself.
All evidence will be destroyed
per the decision of Count Thurzo
in order to keep the Countess' name
as untained as possible.
By signing this document, the Countess...
..bequeaths all her possessions
to Count Gyorgy Thurzo.
Cachtice will be seeded to her children.
The king is now cleared of any debts
to the Bathory Nadasky family.
Now, if the devil allows you to... sign this.
You have orchestrated this masterfully, I must say.
You have murdered innocent women.
- Hundreds.
- Lies.
How many innocents have been sacrificed
in your pursuit of wealth?
Your arguing persistence in denying
the truth only confirms...
..that you are now bereft of reason.
Unfortunately not. I will go to my grave completely sane.
Your tale merely confirms
that women are mad and vain.
And should not be given the right to rule.
Your fable will be keep the populace occupied
for very long time.
They will be terrified of the blood-thirsty myth...
..that you made of me, and forget about
the evils that are indeed very real.
Oh cousin Erzebet, if it's not for me
you would've been burned at the stake.
My gratitude for sparing me a quick death.
And if it were not for you,
I would have never felt love.
Eternal love.
Is it not strange to think
as I stand here today, sentenced to die alone...
so many lovers are warm at each other's arms.
Proceed.
God, you have abandoned me.
In war hundreds are killed and tortured.
And they are left there to rot
and feed the vultures.
And yet, we glorify our warriors.
We give them laurel wreaths and honors.
But till I get installment.
I can not be humiliated this way.
Give me a illness that will kill me fast.
I can not do it myself. I must go to heaven. Amen.
God perhaps you are trying my faith.
Perhaps you are punishing me
because I loved him more than I loved you.
Man has created God in his image,
which gives him dominance over everything else.
Birds, lions, trees and women.
I wish I've been born a man,
I would have killed thousands in battle...
..taken over countries, burned witches.
I would've been a hero.
That is it. You are nothing but a myth.
The Greeks created gods for everything...
..because they could not figure out
why the sea, why love, why death.
Now we have created you to appease
and feed our fears and ignorance.
Because we have so many questions and so few answers.
I have used you and prayers to forgive myself
for my horrible sins.
A proper burial or feeding the wolves
is the same thing.
Holy water is just dirty water.
Why am I so scared to die?
Because I do not belive in you
or in the eternity of the soul.
When I die, I shall rot.
And nothing will be left of me.
Love is the dagger that stabbed me in the back.
If you are not a myth, absolve me of my sins
and give me blood to keep me young.
I thank you, my Lord.
- No coffin?
- It was a very cold winter, there's no wood left.
Sort her legs.
I don't want touch her, she's been dead for weeks.
Earth to earth, ashes to ashes, dust to dust.
History is a tale told by the victors.
And that is what is left of her.
A tale of a mad murderess and a blood-thirsty devil.
Was she really guilty of all the murders? If any?
Or did my father fabricate most of the evidence?
There's nothing in this world you can be certain of.
All I know is whatever she was,
whatever crime she might have been guilty of.
I loved her deeply, and I believe she loved me.
But history does not concern itself with that,
for truth has been sealed behind the brick wall.
And time will soon bury us all.