[ Man's voice ]
You know what really gets to me?
I could swear to God he was smiling.
The problem is, the bastard
had nothing to smile about.
Whatever.
I'm on solid ground here.
[ Rumbling ]
[ Revving ]
[ Wind howling ]
[ Glass clinking ]
[ Panting ]
[ Gasping ]
[ Grunts ]
Aw, shit!
[ Exhales ]
[ Brake sets ]
[ Creaking ]
[ Wind howling ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Rhythmic thumping, faint ]
[ Exhales ]
[ Alarm beeping ]
[ Engine off ]
Fuck!
[ Liquid sloshing ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Man's voice ]
I hear what you're saying,
but I'm sorry,
there's no way--
no way anyone can prove I was drunk.
No.
Tipsy, maybe.
But, uh, drunk?
No. No, no.
[ Chuckles ]
Unprovable.
Without proof.
Next question?
[ Groans ]
Oh.
[ Wind howling ]
[ Tree creaking ]
[ Panting, Shivering ]
Shit.
[ Keys jingling ]
[ Engine starts ]
[ Air blowing ]
[ Bird screeches ]
[ Shovel hitting snow ]
How'd you sleep?
[ Speaking french ]
That was some real fucking
decency you did for me.
You're welcome.
- Did you eat?
- Yeah.
There's cereal, if you want some.
How 'bout I make us
a-- an omelet?
[ Chuckles ]
I'm sorry. I've only
got the cereal.
Help yourself.
[ Inhales, Exhales ]
[ Static, Tuning ]
♪♪ [ Pop ]
[ Women ] ♪ Give me all your loving ♪
♪ And you'll set me free ♪
♪♪ [ Continues, Indistinct ]
♪ Just give me all your loving
and you'll-- ♪
[ Engine stalls, Resumes idling ]
♪♪ [ Continues ]
[ Engine off ]
[ Low rumbling ]
[ Sighs ]
♪♪ [ Instrumental ]
Those things are freaky.
Yeah. My wife made 'em.
No shit.
The eyes.
Not the dolls.
No shit.
♪♪ [ Woman singing, Faint ]
- You mean like a hobby?
- No, no.
She did it for a living.
Pretty good pay.
No shit.
Hmm.
So where's the wife?
You divorced?
Mmm.
Cancer.
Oh. My condolences.
Was she Mexican?
No. Why?
Mexicans love crafts.
Have you ever been to Mexico?
The Yucatán?
No.
Oh, man.
Mexico.
México.
[ Chuckles ]
Ah.
There's three states
on the, uh, Yucatán Peninsula--
Yucatán, Campeche and Quintana Roo.
[ Exhales ]
Quintana Roo.
- Can I?
- Sure.
Quintana Roo is so nice, man.
It's-- It's, uh--
It's paradise down there.
You know, when you're hungry, there
are-- there are buffets everywhere.
Bar is always open.
They take care of you, you know?
You know, if you wanna go to
the pool, you go to the pool.
If you wanna swim in the sea, you
go and swim in the fuckin' sea.
Merci.
Quintana Roo, man.
Uh, a couple of years ago, my wife
and I got some of them fake tattoos.
I even had a, uh--
[ Chuckles ]
I had a-- a butterfly
on my lower back.
[ Speaks French ]
Like a stripper.
Yeah.
Like a fuckin' stripper, yeah.
[ French ]
[ Crunching ]
Really tastes like chicken wing.
Bruce, I wanna ask you something,
and I hate to ask this.
But would you mind
if I crash here again tonight?
I'll be gone tomorrow.
I promise.
But I need--
You know, I need to get
my shit together, you see.
Yeah, that's cool.
Thank you.
Cheers, man.
Cheers.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Engine starts ]
[ Shaky inhaling ]
Jesus.
[ Lighter flicks ]
Fuck!
[ Grunts ]
[ Engine cranking ]
Shit!
[ Bruce's voice ]
Normally, you'd be absolutely right, sir.
This is nice.
Thousand miles from another human.
No television, no one selling me shit.
Get my head straight.
Getting some important thinking done.
Planning for the future.
I hate it here.
[ Coughing ]
[ Door rattling ]
Are you open?
Hi.
Um, look.
You can sit where you want.
[ Water running ]
[ Bruce grunting ]
[ Panting ]
[ Water stops ]
Thank you.
Can I get two hamburgers,
please, and a large coffee?
[ Speaking French ]
And a piece of pie while I wait, please.
Uh, you want the pie before the burgers?
Yes.
Oh, and medium rare.
- Sorry?
- The burgers-- medium rare.
Oh! Yeah.
The road is closed, so how
did you get here anyway?
Uh, I-- I walked over.
- In the snow?
- Yeah. I have a friend that lives down the road.
No power, no gas.
[ Chuckling ]
Mmm! Mmm. Mmm.
Mm-hmm. Mmm. Mmm.
- Can I get a beer, please?
- Yeah.
[ Wind howling ]
[ Chattering, Indistinct ]
There you go.
You want cheese?
I do.
Uh, but, uh, I-I need to go.
Thank you.
Okay.
It's gonna be bad tomorrow.
What?
Really cold.
Here you go.
[ Clears throat ]
Well, good night.
[ Door closes ]
♪♪ [ Man singing in French ]
[ Speaking French ]
Oh.
[ Clears throat ]
I'm--
Oh, boy.
Ten bucks.
♪♪ [ Continues ]
[ Radio: announcer speaking French ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Panting ]
Oh, shit.
You fuckin'--
[ Gas can hits ground ]
[ Engine starts ]
[ Pop-top opens ]
[ Bruce's voice ]
You know what, muchacho?
I did a good thing.
Mm-hmm.
Perhaps, uh, the best thing I've ever done.
That's what he wanted, right?
[ Chuckling ]
You know?
I know.
[ Bells clanging ]
You got gum?
Mm-hmm.
Huh.
One dollar.
Take her easy.
Um, I'm gonna get goin'.
Mm-hmm.
See you around, huh?
See you.
[ Vehicle alarm beeping ]
♪♪ [ Rock: Man Singing,
Muffled ]
Hey, man!
Hey!
What's going on?
[ Speaking French ]
You a Cochrane fan?
Okay.
Hey. Hey!
I can't really do that.
You know, they got a phone
over at McGarrigle's Grill.
Maybe you should go and,
I don't know, call a suicide hot line.
Yeah, just-- just-- just give me my
hose back and walk away, man, okay?
It's a cool car.
Is she really for sale?
[ Low rumbling ]
[ Helicopter whirring ]
Oh!
[ Helicopter whirring continues ]
All righty.
Bastards.
[ Grunting ]
Aah!
Aah.
Donkey shit!
Come on!
[ Engine starts ]
[ Engine idling ]
It's too loud.
Good evening.
Hey!
Good evening, Officers.
Oh--
Paul Blackburn, you say?
Ooh.
What a name.
It rings familiar.
[ Wind howling ]
No, I wouldn't say I knew him well.
Uh, went out a few times, had some beers.
Um, well, I wouldn't consider
myself to be a close friend, no.
No, no. No.
How's that?
Oh. Yeah, he mentioned
somethin' about a wife.
He did.
What's that?
You say he had two young children?
[ Choked up ]
I wasn't aware of that.
How-- You know, uh,
how old they were?
Oh, he--
No, I get emotional whenever I'm thinking about,
you know, children and--
[ Gasping ]
I'll help out anyway I can.
Oh, man.
You're fucked up.
You are fucked up.
Beginning of the end.
Jesus.
Talk too much.
Ah, Paul. You fucker.
She drives nice.
[ Engine idling ]
- That's your house?
- Yeah, it is.
You wanna come in for a beer?
[ Sighs ]
Why are you doing this?
I don't know.
[ Bruce's voice ]
Life can turn on a dime.
One day,
you're married and happy,
and the next day, you're alone.
[ Panting ]
[ Inhales deeply ]
[ Groans ]
Fuck!
Shit.
Yeah. Mmm.
Mmm.
Yeah!
Oh.
Hmm.
Come on!
What's with all these fuckin' branches?
[ Vehicle approaching ]
Shit.
[ Man ] Well--
[ Engine stops ]
[ Chattering ]
Go, go, go, go!
[ Speaking French ]
[ Chattering in French ]
Shit.
Hey.
Hey, hon.
What's for supper?
What's for supper, hon?
Well,
wh-what would you like?
Oh, I don't know.
Some pie.
I've got some pie.
You got a smart mouth.
You sure do have a nice, round bottom.
Like to give it a goin' over.
I'd like you to.
[ Rubbing ]
[ Exhales ]
[ Moans ]
[ Rubbing stops ]
[ Paul ]
She was a very talented woman.
This is really, really nice.
Mmm.
Yeah.
Yeah, she was really good at it.
How much would they sell for?
Mmm.
Probably $10 each.
Wholesale.
Ten bucks each?
Hmm. And how many boxes
like these do you have?
A shitload of 'em.
I don't even know.
Wow, Bruce, you should cash in.
You're sitting on a gold mine here, man.
Mmm.
You know what you do?
You should sell 'em online.
No middle man.
Well, I... sold my wife's computer
last year after she died, so--
Well, listen, I've been doing this for 15 years.
I-I-- I was the--
I was the top
I.T. consultant in town.
World Wide Web,
e-mails, 2.0.
I can do anything.
This is a niche market.
So you know what you do?
We set up a Web site.
I can do all the tech work.
And we just try it, man.
You and I.
I don't know. It's--
I don't know if I really want to sell them.
Well, that's okay.
I mean-- I was just-- It's nothing.
If you're not ready,
that's okay. No problem.
You know what?
You and I, tonight, are going out.
[ Clicks tongue ]
My treat.
Yeah? Where?
Well, it's Saturday night.
I'm sure we can meet a couple of ladies.
Look at us.
I mean-- [ Chuckles ]
Look at us!
[ Woman speaking French ]
Hi.
Just stay calm, okay?
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Okay?
I'm-- I'm not a bad guy.
I'm not a bad guy.
[ Whimpers ]
I'm sorry.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Okay?
I-- I was... cold.
I was-- I was cold.
I was tryin' to be warm.
That's why I'm in here.
So--
Fuck.
That's a bad word.
Don't-- Don't-- Don't learn that word.
[ Woman ]
Simone!
No, don't--
Shit.
Simone?
[ Panting ]
Fuck.
Good morning.
[ Chuckles ]
Hey, uh--
Is that your house?
It's-- It's nice.
Um--
I'm lost. I'm, uh, with
a winter camping group.
Were you just in my shed?
Yes, I was.
Thank you.
I was just trying to warm up.
There is no camping anywhere around here.
Well, yeah, you know,
we're, uh--
Oh, yeah, it's--
We're around here somewhere.
But I-- I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to scare your daughter.
This is private property.
Are those mine?
No. No, no.
They're mine.
I got some just like that.
I think those are mine.
Yeah-- You know,
they're pretty popular.
So anyway, I'm gonna--
We're just right over that ridge, so I'm gonna...
get back to my group.
Your camping group, huh?
Yeah.
Yeah, we're Christians.
[ Chuckles ]
Listen, man, I don't know who you are,
but if you ever go near my kid again, man,
you're gonna fuckin' regret it.
Do you understand that?
I was just tryin' to get warm.
I didn't mean to scare her.
Have a nice day.
God bless you.
[ Beeping ]
[ Engine off ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Whistles ]
Shit.
[ Grunts ]
What was that?
Did you just hear something?
[ Groaning ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Exhaling ]
[ Exhales ]
[ Customers chattering ]
♪♪ [ Blues rock ]
♪ One-eyed Jack ♪
♪ He drive a pink Cadillac ♪
♪ A powder-blue suit ♪
♪ And pea-green shoes ♪
♪ Had a famous reputation ♪
♪ For singin' the blues ♪
♪ He got a picture of his mama ♪
♪ Round his neck ♪
♪ In a solid gold locket ♪♪
♪♪ [ Continues ]
♪♪ [ Jukebox:
Country ]
Yeah, I think this summer I
might go out to Georgian Bay.
Do some fishing.
You fish?
Yeah.
Nah--
I mean, not good.
- But it's really an excuse just to get away.
- Oh.
[ Speaking french ]
I should get the car fixed.
♪♪ [ Jukebox continues ]
You know what, Bruce?
Let me thank you for everything.
Sure.
I need to ask you something.
I need some cash.
A loan.
I'll pay it all back.
But I'm in pretty deep shit.
How much?
Fifteen.
1,500?
Thousand.
15,000?
Shit.
Paul, I--
I'm broke.
I'm sorry.
What happened?
[ Speaking french ]
Big debts. Debts.
Huge gambling debts.
Debts like you wouldn't believe.
I'm-- I'm--
I lost everything.
And I can't go home now.
You gotta tell your wife.
I can't.
I can't go and-- and face her
and tell her it's all gone.
She doesn't deserve that.
Well--
So y-y-you're sure
you can't help me?
You're not, uh--
I don't understand it.
Aren't you retired?
No.
I can't work.
How come?
Had an incident about six months ago.
I was drunk and...
crashed a plow into a Chicken King restaurant.
That was you!
[ Laughs ]
That was me.
Thirty days in jail, a fine.
Lost my license for three years.
I can't drive the plow.
It's how I make a living.
Can't drive a car.
I can't-- Fuck.
I can't even drive a lawn mower, so--
Okay.
Um--
Aw, shit.
Gigi, um--
My wallet's at home.
I'll get it
the next time. Okay?
I'm gonna dance, man.
♪♪ [ Jukebox: mid-tempo rock ]
♪ Hey, hey, hey ♪
[ Customers hooting, laughing ]
♪♪ [ Continues ]
♪♪ [ Continues, man singing in foreign language ]
♪♪ [ Fades ]
[ Tapping ]
[ Paul's voice ]
Bruce, I wanna ask you something,
and I hate to ask this, but...
would you mind if I crash here again tonight?
You know, I-I--
I need to get my shit together, you see.
Mmm.
[ Spits ]
[ Engine idling ]
[ Grunts ]
Au revoir, fucker.
[ Grunting ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Groaning ]
Why did you do that?
Huh?
Peek-a-boo.
I see you, fucker.
[ Chuckles ]
A-B-C-D-E-F-G...
H-I-J-K-L...
M-N-O-P--
Mmm.
[ Grunts ]
[ Urinating ]
Oh.
Sorry, man.
Oh, no.
No worries, Bruce.
[ Sighs ]
[ Paul's voice ]
Why are you doing this?
I don't know.
Seriously.
Why am I being kept here?
[ Laughing ]
[ Bruce's voice ]
You have to understand something, Officer.
I didn't mean to...
kill Paul.
It was an accident.
Th-The truth be told,
uh, he was killing himself.
Yes. No, I-I-I stopped
an act of suicide.
I did. Oh, I did.
I was involved...
in his accidental death, yes.
But I wasn't the only one.
I wasn't the only one. No.
No, no, no.
No, you're not gonna
trick me with that. No.
No.
That was another party.
But, uh,
you'll just have to...
sort that--
sort that through.
Just out of curiosity, have you spoken...
with the individual?
Have you?
Oh, I think it'd be...
quite fruitful,
uh, for you to, uh, extend your investigation...
beyond--
I didn't do anything wrong.
[ Clanking, Banging ]
[ Banging, Clattering ]
What are you doing?
Nothing.
I was just looking.
No, I was just-- I was
just looking at the--
at things.
- Were you stealing?
- No.
No. Come on.
Come on.
No, I was just--
I was--
No, I--
No, I was just looking.
Do you mind if I look?
No.
[ Grunting ]
[ Groans ]
[ Liquid sloshing ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Coughs, Groans ]
[ Flames crackling ]
[ Bruce's voice ]
You know what really gets to me?
I could swear to God he was smiling.
[ Dripping ]
[ Bird screeching ]
[ Coughs, Groans ]
[ Coughing ]
The pink lady.
She made me cough, no?
[ Coughing, Sniffling ]
[ Coughing continues ]
[ Glass shatters ]
[ Grunts ]
[ Ice creaking ]
[ Ice cracking ]
[ Water gurgling ]
[ Cracking, Louder ]
[ Man ]
Hey, what are you doing?
You're gonna go right through
if you keep doing that!
What's he doing, Doug?
This machine.
Was tryin' to get it started.
The lake's already melting, man.
Let me give you a hand.
No, no.
[ Water gurgling ]
It's all right.
I-- I got it.
I'm good.
[ Bruce ]
Thank you.
Appreciate it.
Get back, Michelle.
Wait!
Get back! Get back!
Get back, Michelle!
Get back!
[ Snowmobile slams ]
[ Ice cracking, louder ]
[ Loud cracking ]
[ Water splashes ]
Go, go, go!
Go! Go!
[ Water splashes ]
[ Bruce grunting ]
[ Lightbulb screwing into socket ]
[ Exhaling ]
[ Vehicle approaching ]
[ Engine stops ]
[ Zipper unzips ]
[ Urinating ]
[ Sighs ]
[ Phone ringing ]
[ Ringing continues ]
[ Engine starts ]
[ Insects buzzing ]
[ Breathing ]
[ Breathing continues ]
[ Bruce's voice ]
You know,
they say every guilty person is his own hangman.
They also say...
tomorrow will be a better day.
You know what I say?
Goddamn, it's freezing.
[ Man ]
♪ All I need ♪
♪ Is some sunshine ♪
♪ The siren called ♪
♪ Beyond the tree line ♪
♪ With another one for the caves ♪
♪ And in the tarn beyond those birches ♪
♪ There's a spirit that I crave ♪
♪ And from the island ♪
♪ People watched you ♪
♪ You set that Viking ship ablaze ♪
♪ We reached the moon falls ♪
♪ I see a cauldron ♪
♪ And found the spirit ♪
♪ That I crave ♪
♪ All I need ♪
♪ Is some sunshine ♪
♪ You've fallen barefoot ♪
♪ Past the tree line ♪
♪ Beaten, bone-eyed,
butchered, swayed ♪
♪ A thousand whitefish ♪
♪ Floating belly up ♪
♪ They're the spirit that I crave ♪
♪ And we threw ourselves right into it ♪
♪ Where lay the bodies had been claimed ♪
♪ We dove a third ♪
♪ A fourth, a fifth ♪
♪ Bane to the spirit that I crave ♪
♪ All I need ♪
♪ Is some sunshine ♪
♪ Want a good thing ♪
♪ Want a good thing ♪♪
♪♪ [ Voice fades, instruments continue ]
♪♪ [ Saxophone, Isolated ]