According to the report
on Takeda's condition,
"One.
Recognition of self and others
as human beings is very low.
The ability to understand
this situation is poor.
Two.
Takes words at face value,
poor concept of the abstract."
- "Mother died recently...
- Three.
- I'm not really sure...
- Has no concept of his future...
- I got word from her retirement home...
- He cannot express his dreams...
- 'Regret to inform you of the loss...
- There is a lack of imagination.
- of your mother.' This says nothing.
- Four. Tendency to delve.
- It probably happened yesterday.
- Repeatedly pursues interests."
Her retirement home is 80 kilometers
from Algiers in Marengo.
I could arrive this afternoon
if I take the 2:00 bus."
Good night.
Do you live nearby?
Yes, about 10 minutes.
Can I sit next to you?
Yes.
Why did you stop making movies?
I heard you made a lot of great films.
I also heard
you don't like discussing the past.
Won't you tell me?
You're a strange one, Mr. Ikeda.
Do you think so?
Just look at your clothes.
Is it too feminine?
Maybe.
I used to dress up as a woman.
Ms. Hisada.
Are you on your own?
Apparently.
I mean, when is your boyfriend
coming back?
Next Monday.
Are you lonely?
What do you mean?
Motosugi seems to like you.
He's very well built.
Do you have a girlfriend?
Not at the moment.
After the film,
I want to take a trip abroad.
For the first time.
On your own?
I guess.
All by your lonesome?
There's no one to go with.
Am I odd?
Who knows?
Professor...
When I was 16,
I had a bit of a run in
with my English teacher.
A fifty something American man.
He forced me back to his apartment.
Made me do a blowjob.
That was my first
and last time with a man.
I dream about having sex.
But it's always with a girl.
I'm not gay, you know.
Machu Picchu, the city in the sky
with its holy valley.
Sounds fantastic, eh?
I would prefer going to Greece.
It's a long way from South America.
I'll say it is.
I'm glad I study here.
I met you, for one thing.
Do you know what
the students call you?
I wonder.
- Venice.
- Venice?
Some lecturers call you Aschenbach.
From "Death in Venice"?
I've heard of the director
and the actress, but continuity girl?
It's late. You should go.
Okay.
Goodnight.
THURSDAY
We need extras for our film.
Okay, my best three murder movies.
Hitchcock's "Psycho,"
Jean-Pierre Melville's "Samurai,"
Fritz Lang's "You Only Live Once."
Here's my best three.
Coppola's "Godfather,"
Tarantino's "Pulp Fiction,"
the name escapes me, but
"The Good, the Bad and the Ugly."
Morning.
Are you okay?
Didn't sleep a wink.
Thinking about the storyboard?
Yukari.
What's up with Adele?
Adele... I mean Yukari
came over at 3:00 this morning.
Surely you were in bed.
Trouble is, Aya was in my bed.
That's tricky.
Bummer.
So what did Yukari do?
Poor, poor me!
I feel wretched!
I'm pitiful!
For fuck's sake get inside!
Yukari!
What did Aya do?
When I got back,
she was snoring in bed.
- Never could figure out women.
- Too right.
First one way, then the other.
We walked all over the neighborhood
until morning.
I'm pooped.
I've had just about enough,
what with thinking about the film.
No shit.
"Nozomi, from the rear seat. Subdued.
Nozomi: '... umm, I'm that ugly?'
Yamazaki: 'What?'
Nozomi: 'Should I have a nose job?'
Yamasaki:
'Are you out of your fucking head?'
Nozomi: 'I'm sorry.'
Nozomi, monologue:
'He laughed at me, this fat pig.
Makes me uncomfortable.
He wants me to get out.
Maybe my outfit was too loud.
I want to be alone.
I can't take it any more..."'
- Good morning.
Okay, break's over.
Back to rehearsal.
Motosugi.
Take a look at this.
"1:32 P.M. Traitor! I'll kill you!
2:15. I love you.
Good luck with the movie.
3:44. I am 'Adele'.
I'll follow you everywhere.
4:27. I'm not 'Adele'.
Don't leave me. I'll wait at home."
Mr. Matsukawa!
We've fixed the location
for the old woman's house.
Thanks.
We can use the furniture there.
Professor.
- Good morning.
Morning.
Everyone seems so deflated.
Making movies is a tough business.
After the movie comes job hunting.
Would a production company
want me?
Not sure.
You'll go post grad?
Not sure. I don't like the movies
they make these days.
You should. There's a lot to learn.
This is a good college for film.
I'm going to take a look.
"THE BORED MURDERER"
Help me, someone!
Help!
Just as well we insured her.
Why did he murder her?
Playing too many computer games?
The culprit is a computer...
Too many games...
Computer's fault...
Computer's to blame...
The murder scene
is too scary to watch.
Definitely a computer...
The computer is the murderer...
I tried the murder scene
with hatred in my eyes.
But I get the feeling that's wrong.
I agree.
He should have
a more normal look about him.
You can't kill someone
with a normal look.
Right, Nakane?
What?
Let's ask Professor Nakajo.
I say it should be hatred.
Takeda is feeling hate.
Let's do it again.
With hatred.
Which look is better?
Beats me.
He could try both.
One look in each eye?
Separately?
Yes.
You're like Groucho Marx!
I can't see!
It's Oyama.
Come in.
You wanted to see me?
A word please, Motosugi.
What?
Take care of this.
Did you call Yukari last night?
Not me.
Kamimura told you
about Naoki and Aya, right?
Yep, I heard.
Should I not have called her?
So it was you.
Need a piss.
I want an explanation.
I didn't call Adele.
I called her friend.
Why?
And I know you sent that poem
to Aya as well.
You must like her.
No I don't.
Well why did you make that call?
I know what Naoki is like.
He's very open,
and also the thing with Aya.
All the responsibility lies with him.
I'm sick of the whole thing.
Kiyoko, I think you like Naoki.
I know it.
You should see your eyes
when you look at him.
Is that why?
That's right.
Grow up!
Aya, are you okay?
Shouldn't I be?
Watch your step.
Adele has really become "Adele."
I'm staying at Naoki's
until the film is made.
I can go to the set by bike
and save on travel expenses.
Sounds like a plan.
Yep, that's what I'll do.
Let's eat first. I'm hungry.
Yeah. What do you want?
- Let's have ramen.
- Yeah, ramen!
On top of that, inside is a tomato!
- A tomato?
- Yeah.
Your hair looks great.
Really?
I was waiting for you.
I need to talk.
I like you.
We don't have to have sex,
but hug me.
Please!
For my role.
Good night.
Night.
We start the day after tomorrow.
You should rest.
Don't need it.
I'm young.
I'm worried about team spirit.
Sorry for the trouble
Yukari and I are causing.
She's a bit odd.
Kind of passionate.
I won't be seeing her after the film.
For sure?
100%.
So, you don't like her?
I didn't say that.
So, you like her.
I wonder.
Which?
Not sure.
Aya says she's staying
at your place.
She's just...
No feelings about Aya.
That's my place.
I've never been to your place.
Do you want to come in?
I have tea.
Sounds good to me.
I wonder if I like you.
I know I like you.
You do?
Yeah.
But you have a girl in every port.
In every port?
That's right.
Perhaps.
You slept with Aya last night.
True.
I have a lot to do so...
I should leave?
True.
Good night.
FRIDAY
Professor, this is Rei Umemiya.
Pleased to meet you.
I'm Nakajo.
I'm afraid I have to go
to a rehearsal now.
Okay.
I'll see you later.
See you then.
Thanks for this, Mr. Oyama.
Not at all.
What about your mother?
No clue about her.
Don't you want to meet her?
She married again,
moved to Osaka.
Meeting her again
has never crossed my mind.
I never think about her.
My dad and my grandfather
raised me.
But they didn't get along.
I'm researching
about Michel Houellebecq.
I've read his work in translation,
but I'd like to try the originals.
I want to improve my French.
And I want to write a novel.
Which courses do you have
with Mr. Oyama?
Is that what he told you?
Well, yes.
We aren't together in any class.
Then, your clubs are the same?
I'm in the Dance club
and Latin Classics club.
But he...
I was thrilled to have the chance
to talk with you today.
You can tell me about films
and all your experiences.
You could teach me so much...
a man of your capacity.
I'm a little old-fashioned.
I like that.
Sorry.
Oyama used to seem
so mature before.
"Before" you say.
Excuse me.
Okay, rehearsal.
And, action!
My grandfather used to pick me up
from kindergarten.
Not your mother?
She left when I was one and a half.
Sorry, I didn't know.
It's okay. I haven't seen her since.
Mr. Oyama.
Sorry.
We're married.
Are you shocked?
Somewhat.
I wanted to meet you.
To see you up close.
When did you marry?
Last year.
We were seeing each other
for one and a half years.
He has an olfactory malfunction.
Olfactory malfunction?
I can't smell my food.
I make all of his food,
and look after him.
Your marriage is in trouble?
Not in the least.
But he's becoming
more like a student.
I was researching the Middle East.
But recently he's into the supernatural.
It was a natural progression...
Our scheme has been uncovered.
We can't hide it now.
I said,
if she could seduce you,
I'd take her to France.
She wants to meet
Michel Houellebecq.
I'd like to see Paris again,
and if we went together, well...
But if you know we're married,
she can't seduce you.
Or could I?
I wonder.
I don't think so.
Takeda!
Terrible news!
Aki has been killed.
A motorbike accident last night.
He couldn't make a curve,
and hit a truck head on.
Oh?
The funeral is tonight.
We could go.
I'm not going.
But you were good friends
in class in first grade.
What's the point in twittering
to her friends
at her funeral?
Everyone's going.
I'm not.
Why not? Come on!
Come on!
No, I won't.
I'm not going.
Give it more power.
I'm not going!
Look.
You take over.
Come down now, Ikeda.
What the...
My foot!
Ouch, ouch, ouch!
Oh no! Oh no!
Ouch!
Where's the director?
Gone for a piss?
Let's take it from the top.
Come here a minute.
Naoki has fallen!
Over the edge!
Professor...
Professor!
- Professor.
Old Venice has turned
into Aschenbach.
Professor.
SATURDAY
This the movie web page?
"High drama on movie location
as director miraculously
cheats death in fall.
Shooting delayed.
Future of movie in balance."
Do you think Naoki fell,
or did Yukari push him?
Nobody saw,
so we don't know.
She really loved him.
Serves Naoki right, I think.
You wouldn't say that if he was dead.
Yes I would, wouldn't I?
How should I know?
I have an announcement.
We went to the police station.
We heard what Yukari had to say.
As she was walking on the edge,
she was contemplating s... s...
Suicide. She was all set to do it
when Naoki arrived.
It only took a moment.
She wanted to see what would happen
if she pushed him.
It was an instant response
and she remembers nothing after it.
I wonder if she was normal
at the time.
As opposed to abnormal.
I think...
We'll never know.
If she was normal,
that's abnormal,
and vice versa.
But she wanted to try.
Like an experiment.
That's it.
I think I'll experiment too!
You two. I saw you!
I just saw you kissing my Kiyoko.
You bastard!
He's coming!
- Talking to your self...
- I'm scared!
Come here!
An experiment.
Like a game!
I'll kill you!
They're here!
It's an experiment!
I'll kill you!
Cut it out!
Be quiet!
Stop fooling around.
We have our meeting
with the professor!
MONDAY
Welcome back.
What's up?
That accident?
No.
Is the movie going to go ahead?
It starts tomorrow
with me as the director.
Good for you.
Is something troubling you?
In the new schedule,
the murder scene is first.
I see.
So, what's the other news?
How was the mountain weather?
Excellent.
We had fantastic views
from the summit.
Unbelievably beautiful.
Didn't have any altitude sickness?
Look at me. Fit as a fiddle.
Hiroshi.
You know...
What?
While you were
in the mountains,
I kissed two other men.
The cinematographer
and the male lead.
Are you angry?
I might give you a smack
after the movie.
I'm really sorry.
I'm sure it meant nothing.
It's that damned movie's fault.
You can't blame the film.
Two guys, yeah?
I wanted to see how it would be
if I kissed them.
And how was it?
Horrible.
I'm sorry.
I'll never do it again, really.
I'm really sorry.
TUESDAY
I bet these are two old folks.
So I'm going to murder her.
What a shame.
Who are you?
My head!
Please, stop it!
No, no, no!
Help!
Let's roll!
- Stand by for a roll!
Scene 25, cut 2, track 1.
And, action!
Cut!
Okay!
Next set up!
Help me!
I don't want to die yet!
Please, don't make any noise.
It's harder than you think to kill.
How can I make her die?
So this is death.
You there?
Hey, you in there?
Cut!
Once more please.
Make sure you center the actor
and pan slowly.
You in there?
Are you there?
Chieko, where are you?
Cut!
That was good.
I have money.
I can give you 100,000.
You're from
Junsei High School, right?
I promise I won't tell
anyone at the school.
School? School?
Chieko!
Where's Chieko?
Chieko...
Cut!
Okay?
Okay.
That's a print!