I can't come now.
I'm cleaning this up.
How are you doing up there?
You about done?
Lift up.
Hey, give me some slack,
will you?
- What the hell is this thing anyway?
- What do you mean, "What is it?" It's art.
Hurry up, you turkey.
Do you think you might possibly be finished
before the dedication tomorrow?
- Catch.
- I can do it.
Hey!
Okay, people.
I don't want any of you to forget
there is no extra credit for this.
Don't turn into an angry mob.
Now, listen. I want the term
papers in by Wednesday...
...and tell Becky
I want it legible. Okay?
Police the area.
- I gotta go.
- Okay.
- You really did it.
- Yeah?
Yup. I'm really proud of you.
- That's really something.
- Yeah?
- You really made a...
- Yeah.
...big pile of sticks.
I used you as a model.
I gotta go.
All right, I'm cooking tonight.
What do you want?
Just a salad or something,
you know.
How about baked Alaska?
- How about a lobster Newburger, baby?
- Give me a break.
- How about M&M's?
- M&M's sound good.
- I'll see you later.
- See you tonight.
Fly ball to second.
This will put it away and that's it.
Total of five runs, 10 hits
and two errors for the Mariners.
Eight runs, nine hits
and two errors for the Red Sox.
Charlie Snow inviting
you to see...
Watch your head, Joe.
Gurney coming through.
Open it wide. Come on.
How you doing now?
Take it easy.
You all right now?
Stay back.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Watch it. That's jagged.
- unit 612. We've got
a possible broken neck here.
Trauma, double fractures, lacerations.
The man is cyanotic. BPis 160/90...
Move it. Out of the way.
To the right. Off to the right.
Lisa, I need your help.
Ventilate this guy.
- Dorothy, 1 gram of Solu-Medrol.
- One gram Solu-Medrol.
- Two units of plasma.
Type and cross-match.
Possible pneumothorax.
I can feel at least four fractured ribs
in this guy. And fractured pelvis.
- Who's the anesthesiologist?
- Levinson.
Tell him 15 minutes.
Get him into X-ray, stat.
- Right tibia, left tibia fracture and fibula.
- You hang in there, pal.
- Come on, you gotta fight. Fight.
- Move him out.
You have a fractured right rib puncturing
the right lung, so a pneumothorax.
We have a fractured left tibia and fibula,
right tibia and fibula.
- God, what didn't he break?
- I think this is gonna be our problem here.
- Shit.
- He's never going to dance again.
We'll have to very gently
fuse this spinal column together.
I can do that. I think the best
we can hope for, though, is a quad.
- I want him alive, Tony.
- I'll do the best job I can.
- Get started?
- Yeah.
- How you doing on your side, baby?
- Oh, pretty good.
Okay, now one more knot to go
and we are in terrific shape.
Over easy, please.
One, two, three...
Good.
- Hi.
- Thought I recognized those shoes.
- Well, I wore them just for you.
- Dizzy? You want anything?
- I'd like a martini.
He wants a martini. Alrighty.
Now how's that?
- Gin tastes like water.
- It is water.
I thought everyone
in Intensive Care got gin.
Well, intravenously.
- Hey, honey?
- Yeah?
You know that dinner dance
next Saturday?
I think we ought to tell
them we'll be late.
Okay.
You want to come along, Miss Sadler?
Yes, ma'am.
Good morning, Mr. Harrison.
- Good morning, Mr. Harrison.
- Morning, Rodriguez.
- Here's a new face for you.
- Hello, new face, hello.
Rodriguez, I thought you were gonna
bring me ugly old hags.
Going down.
Orthopedics, Gynecology,
Nurses' Station...
...Rubber Goods, Water Sports.
- Get the pillows out from under his arms.
Watch it.
Arms over chest.
Down with the sheets...
...and the spread.
- Neatly, neatly. - Why don't you
say something nice to her?
You need a haircut.
That's nice.
Ready? And...
...good.
- Now...
- Hello, darling.
- My little flesh pudding.
- Align the legs.
Up. Over.
- Hear the one about the
plastic surgeon? - No.
He melted in front of the fire.
- You get it in the end, don't you?
- Terrible.
- Thank you very much.
- Now rub.
I see any bedsores,
it's gonna be you and me.
Used to dream of situations like this.
- Being injured? - Being massaged
by two beautiful women.
Lay off or I'll keep
my student nurses out of here.
- You think you can manage?
- Yes, ma'am.
Well, be careful.
We don't wanna have him on the floor.
Oh, God. Somebody have
me on the floor.
I was once had on the floor, Rodriguez.
It was incredible.
You are impossible.
Make that improbable.
- So what's your name?
- Mary Jo Sadler.
- Most of my friends call me Joey.
- That's nice.
Don't let Rodriguez hear you say that.
You're supposed to answer:
"Miss Sadler," with a smile that is filled
with warmth but not a hint of sex.
- Sorry.
- Don't be sorry.
I'm gonna call you Joey when we're alone
and you're caressing my backside.
- I'm rubbing your heels right...
- Don't spoil it. I can't feel a thing anyway.
- Am I your first back rub, Joey?
- Yes, you are.
- I graduate in two weeks.
- Really?
- Anybody home?
- Joey, quick!
Get under the bed.
It's the other woman.
- Hi.
- Are you going to class?
Rehearsal.
- Does he ever stop?
- Stop? I haven't laid a glove on her.
- I don't know. It's my first day with him.
- Oh, you'll learn. I'm Pat.
- I'm Miss Sadler.
- And for you.
- Beautiful.
- Well, good morning.
- Good morning.
- How are you this morning?
- Okay.
- And how are we doing here?
- Fine.
Miss Rodriguez, you promised me
you wouldn't send cute ones in here.
Should've seen the one in here
last night.
After lights out, she snuck me out.
We went skateboarding.
Only trouble was,
I was the skateboard.
No, no, no!
- Are you finished, Miss Sadler?
- I...
Pillows. Right.
And...
one...
okay, could you straighten my hand out?
And bend the hand down...
...palm down into the pillow?
That's it, that's it.
Now smooth the fingers out.
That's it. Perfect.
Now... Now, bend the thumb
a little bit in.
That's it, that's it.
That's it. Now relax the
hand just a little bit.
That's it. Thank you.
I gotta keep going. Give me a kiss.
Love you, okay?
I got some steps to work out
before the rehearsal.
- How's your knee? - It's okay,
if I warm it up really carefully.
Kallis is coming again.
He's interested in the large nude.
Kallis always was interested
in large nudes.
Try and make him behave, Rodriguez.
Nice meeting you.
- Bye. Tomorrow.
- Bye.
Alrighty.
- Are you comfortable, Mr. Harrison?
- Rodriguez, you give great sheet.
- Go to sleep or something.
- What's the "or something"?
Stay awake.
- How long has he been like...?
- Six months.
- Will he ever be able to...?
- Nope.
John, Mr. Harrison's ready.
You better do him now.
Well, he ain't going nowhere, man.
- What you say, man?
- Uh-oh, a black man with a razor.
Okay, fleet-foot,
let's see you tap-dance.
Okay, here we go.
Man, but this is boring, you know.
Shaving dudes all day.
They won't let me near the girls.
All you could get near is the ones
with the mustaches.
- Bitchy, bitchy.
- Envy, envy.
- Listen, from where I'm laying...
- Yeah?
...if I could get off at all,
even by myself, that'd be great.
- I hear that, man. I hear that.
- John.
Shake it out. Dr. Emerson's making
his rounds this morning.
If I shake it any harder, man,
it's gonna fall off, you know?
- So how's the punk band coming?
- Oh, great, man.
I even added a xylophone
to the band.
Punk xylophone?
How the hell does that sound?
Man, great.
We be jamming and I ain't jiving.
Listen.
Hey, man, this knee needs tuning up,
you know.
Hey, John, John, John.
This isn't your day.
- What's going on here?
- He was testing my reflexes.
Yeah, you see, Dr. Scott,
this man's toe bone connected...
...to his knee bone.
And I'm just connecting myself...
...to another patient.
- Goodbye.
Well, we're all bright
and chipper this morning.
Oh, it's marvelous,
the courage of the human spirit.
Nice to hear the
human spirit's okay.
How's the heart?
- Then they went to the lobby...
- Selling tickets.
- You heard that one?
- Yes, you told me twice yesterday.
- Our relationship must be on the skids.
- You're looking great today, Mr. Harrison.
Take a deep breath for me.
Hold it. Let it out.
Okay, I think we can start stepping
up your physical therapy now.
To what purpose?
So that you can feel more comfortable
and start leading a more normal life.
- More normal, huh?
- Yes, more normal.
Meaning I can resume
my basketball career?
No, I think you're a little
too short for basketball.
- Cute.
- Thank you.
I see Dr. Emerson is making rounds
again this morning.
- Yes, he is.
- Is he gonna do it...
...in the normal fashion
or is he gonna walk on water?
Look up for me, please.
That isn't fair, you know.
You're very lucky to have him.
He's the best one around.
I'll remember that in my prayers.
Okay, see you in a few minutes.
- With Emerson?
- Right.
I won't hold my breath.
Miss Rodriguez, Mr. Harrison seems
a bit more agitated this morning.
He's beginning to realize
what he's up against.
That's what I thought. Okay, I'm
upping his valium to 5 milligrams.
- Valium, 5 milligrams. TID?
- Right. Thank you.
What, in your enlightened opinion,
Mr. Hoffman...
...was Mr. Holmes suffering from?
- I'd say pneumonia.
No, it wasn't pneumonia.
All third-year students say pneumonia.
It wasn't pneumonia
and it wasn't arthritis. Hello, Jim.
How long?
About 12 minutes.
- What did you do?
- Palpated radial artery.
- Gave him D5W, bicarb and epinephrine.
- Why didn't you transfer him to ICU?
Well, his vitals were stable at 6:00.
He just went sour real fast.
This was Andrew Dryer, age 56.
Out of surgery yesterday.
Cancer of the colon and liver.
What's your name?
- Everett, sir.
- Well, Mr. Everett...
...how do you feel about this?
- Feel, sir?
Yes, feel. You feel sick
when you look at this?
- No, sir.
- Why not?
- I'm used to seeing bodies, sir.
- Oh, I see.
You been here, what? Three years?
Cut up cadavers with the best of them.
Death holds no fear for you...
...does it, Mr. Everett?
- Sir... - Let me tell you.
This makes me sick.
It ought to make you sick too.
Look there.
That's the enemy.
The enemy has won.
Mr. Dryer was 56 years old.
And I want you, Mr. Everett...
...and I want all of you
to feel sick when you see a body...
...that hasn't reached its allotted
three-score years and 10.
That's if you want to be doctors.
Not just money-grubbers.
Shit.
Oh, sorry.
Dr. Arlene Franklin,
sixth floor waiting area, please.
Did you say something to me, man?
I think she likes me.
- Hello, hello.
- Hi.
Is that something to
put into my face?
It's coffee.
- No, it's not.
- Yes, it is.
- It is.
- It's not.
- It's caca.
- No, it's not.
- Oh, really? - It's good for you.
You have to drink it.
- Looks like somebody already drank it.
- Take a sip.
- I don't want any of it.
- It's not that...
Oh, shit, I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry. It was my fault.
- It's all right, I can clean it up.
- I'm sorry.
- I'll just change the sheets.
Don't panic.
How someone who can't move a muscle
can screw up a whole bed is...
- It's just eating its way through my P.J.'s.
- I have to pull you towards me.
- Oh, God.
- I feel like Charlie McCarthy.
- Oh, God. - How did the
quadriplegic cross the road?
- Oh, I don't know.
- It was stapled to a chicken.
Joey! Joey!
- Help! Nurse!
- Oh, God, oh, God...
Nurse, help!
Somebody help! Nurse!
- Help!
- John! Got him.
- Somebody help!
- I got him.
- What happened?
- I don't know.
- Get him on the floor.
- Got him?
All right. Ease him down.
Let's just set him down.
- Take it easy, now, watch it.
- Watch your head, man!
- Give me a clean sheet.
- I just spilled the coffee.
- Okay, get ready to lift him.
- It wasn't her fault.
It wasn't her fault.
It was just an accident.
Get ready for a lift.
- What's going on here?
- Get out of here.
They're just changing the sheets.
That's all for now.
See you tomorrow.
- Turn him on his back.
- Easy, man, watch the head, now.
- Easy.
- Watch him. You got to be gentle.
On the count of three.
Okay, one, two, three.
Roll the body.
- Slowly. Slowly.
- Easy now.
Out of the way.
- You dizzy?
- No.
Pillow, please.
- What happened here?
- He almost fell out of bed, doctor.
Really?
- How do you feel?
- Great.
It's always good to get out
of bed now and again.
Let me take a look at you.
Now move your head.
Gently.
- Does that hurt?
- No.
- Are you okay?
- Oh, yeah.
- You'll be fine.
- Are you kidding?
Have the chart, please?
Miss, can I have the chart, please?
Just breathe normally.
- I see you upped his valium.
- Yes, I did this morning.
The dialysis seems
to be holding him stable.
- Just continue the schedule, all right?
- Four hours every other day.
- Right.
- Okay.
Well, Mr. Harrison,
we seem to be out of the woods.
Now, if we can keep you in that bed,
off the accident list, we'll be fine.
When do "we" get discharged?
- Pretty soon now, I expect.
- Really? Discharged? Or transferred?
This unit is for the critically ill, which,
I'm happy to say, you no longer are.
I'll send you to a rehab.
You'll be comfortable.
I get it. You just grow the vegetables here.
The vegetable store is somewhere else.
- I don't think you understand.
- I think I do.
What chance do you think I have...
...of my ever being just
partly dependent on nursing?
- That's difficult to say with any certainty.
- I am not asking for a guarantee.
I'm asking for a professional opinion.
You think I'll ever walk again?
No.
- Regain the use of my arms?
- No.
Or my...
or my hands?
No.
- Thank you.
- What are you thanking me for?
Your honesty.
We were wondering when you'd ask.
Why didn't you tell me before?
We didn't think you'd hear us.
Look, I know it's difficult...
...but it's surprising
how we can come to accept...
You mean, things like
falling out of bed?
Dr. Scott has prescribed something
which I think will help.
- Yes.
- Fabulous.
Get Mrs. Boyle in here.
Let's start some meaningful therapy.
- Right away.
- Isn't that a great idea?
All right, Harrison.
I'll stop in on you later.
Be sure to phone first.
- I may not be in.
- See you later.
Miss Sadler,
let's get a clean gown on him.
What'd you give him,
5 milligrams of valium?
Yeah, TID.
I think we may have to up it to 10.
- You might be right.
- I want him transferred out...
...one month, tops.
I have to go to a board meeting.
- Okay. - Talk to some
tight-ass tick-tocks...
...about inflation. - I hope
you have a wonderful time.
I'd rather have my
prostrate examined.
- Excuse me, Mrs. Cole?
- Hold on. Yes, doctor?
- Have you given Mr. Harrison his valium?
- No, not until noon.
- Give it to him now.
- Now?
- Yeah.
- Hold on, let me call you back.
Oh, wait, just a sec.
On second thought, let me have it.
I'll give it to him myself.
Dr. Norton, report to Hydrotherapy,
fourth floor. Dr. Norton.
- Hello again. - Hello. I was
just practicing lying here.
I brought you something
to help you relax.
- What for?
The fall? I'm all right, I'm just angry.
I don't blame you. I'm changing the nurse.
She's not experienced enough...
- Don't do that.
- Why not?
Because it wasn't her fault.
It was just an accident.
At least I should have someone
around here I could talk to.
Here, I think this will help you.
- Don't do that. Don't give me that.
- Why not? Lt'll make you feel better.
Quieter, you mean.
Look, Mr. Harrison...
...your body cannot handle
all this excitement.
- Now, I think you need this.
- Why?
- If I wanna be mad, I'll be mad.
- It's a very small...
If I wanna make noise,
I'll make noise.
Just because you are upset
you can't do anything for me...
...does not mean I'm the one
that has to get tranquilized.
- However, it is prescribed...
- You haven't heard a word I said, have you?
Now, you listen to me, Dr. Scott.
The only thing that I have left
is my consciousness...
...and I don't want that paralyzed
as well.
You understand that?
- Yeah. I hear what you're saying.
- Good. Very good.
So if you want any tranquility,
you eat the pill.
You want me to...?
Eat it.
- We'll see.
- Good. That's what I always say.
If you're ever in doubt whether
to take a tranquilizer...
...sleep on it.
Okay.
Right.
That's bullshit.
When he came here all shaken to hell,
he didn't protest the Iv saline.
When he was gasping for breath...
...he didn't say,
"I don't want any Solu-Medrol. "
No, but those were inevitable
in emergency situations.
So is this. Look, Clare...
...we'll have to help him
to accept his condition.
Then maybe his consciousness
will be of help to him.
But how does a depressant drug
like valium...
...really help him
to accept his condition?
Listen. Ken Harrison
is an intelligent...
...sensitive, articulate,
wonderful person.
Yes, he is.
But he's not gonna prescribe
for himself.
- Will the owner of a blue Cadillac...
- Okay.
...licence PWB112...
...parked in Emergency,
please move it immediately?
This is Dr. Emerson.
I'd like you to prepare valium.
Ten milligrams, IM.
I'll be right up.
Dr. Jackson, outside call.
They've sent in the godfather.
Why are you giving my staff
such a hard time?
Dr. Emerson, I must insist...
...that you do not stick that needle
in my arm.
You don't even know what's in it.
Well, I assume that it is one of
a series of measures taken...
...to keep me alive.
That's right. You, pal,
are a valuable life.
I don't think so.
I've decided I don't
want to stay alive.
- You can't decide that.
- Why not?
Because you're depressed.
Does that surprise you?
No. In time, you'll learn to accept.
Until then, let us help you.
Do not stick that fucking thing
in my arm.
Goddamn you!
I specifically refused you
permission to do that.
It was necessary.
Now, I want you to sleep.
I don't wanna goddamn sleep.
I wanna goddamn think!
When you were sculpting...
...and things weren't coming out right,
did you quit?
- No, I didn't.
- Well, neither do I.
Is that what I am to you, huh?
Emerson?
Wait a minute.
Wait a minute!
Is that all I am?
Is a lump of clay?
Will you come on?
I told you my feet hurt.
And I've ordered three times
already. Don't forget.
Oh, my God.
My chocolates.
You like this one?
It's nice.
How's this?
That's lovely.
- Oh, that's it. That's it. Don't move.
- This one?
- Well, hurry up.
- Stay there. Don't...
Rewind. You gotta go back.
You like that?
Show me the one that's two steps
after it.
- With the elbow?
- Yeah.
That's nice.
- Sadler, you wanna do
some rounds? - Yes.
Okay, let's go.
- And good morning to you.
- Good morning.
Back with the sheets.
And spread.
And voilà.
The night nurse said you had
a good night's sleep.
Well, I had some help,
if you remember, from Emerson.
Like being hit on the head
with a soft baseball bat.
But your eyes look
bright this morning.
- I've been thinking.
- Ready? And...
You do too much of that.
What other activity would you suggest?
Jogging, perhaps?
Hey, Rodriguez, you remember
that lawyer...
...that came here a few months ago
from the insurance company?
- His name was something Hill?
- Yeah, I remember.
- You think you could call
him for me? - Sure.
Since I'm gonna be around here for
some time, I think money would help.
Good thinking in there.
His card is in my top drawer.
You'll call him?
Knock, knock. Hi, everybody.
- Hi.
- Great day, huh?
I had to park about four miles away.
Oh, you look pretty dry.
- Would you ladies excuse us,
please? - Yes.
I got some new music for you.
- How are you today?
- Fine.
You don't seem the same.
You come here every day.
It's remarkable.
What's so remarkable about it?
- I love you.
- Oh, I know.
And I'm honored by
that and moved.
What's wrong with you today?
I want to ask you a question.
We make cute little jokes about
nurses and hints of sex...
...you know?
Now, obviously, I haven't slept
with anyone for over six months.
Have you?
No.
Why not?
Not interested in other men.
I love you.
Without self-pity,
I am no longer someone to love.
I am an object that has to be
taken care of for the rest of his life.
- I don't know why you're doing this.
- I have to be on a dialysis machine...
...four hours a day.
- None of that matters to me.
Matters to me.
Pat, I know you love me...
...and when I was Ken Harrison,
I loved you...
...but that was a long time ago.
At least six months and one spine ago.
I am not the man that loved you.
Now, you have been loyal
and you have been loving...
...and you have been self-sacrificing.
I don't want any
part of it anymore...
...and I want you to walk out
of here and not come back.
- Hey. - I just want you
to find a new life.
Find a man and get married
and have babies.
What am I to do?
Go to the Salvation Army?
Patty, if you were laying here...
...and I was standing
where you are...
...I'd leave you flat.
You would, would you?
I may still love you,
but I'd leave you.
Well, you have got
a lot of balls...
...to lie there and make decisions
without me about our future.
Everything we've ever
done together...
...everything we've had together,
or been to each other...
...everything you've given me...
...that's part of me now,
and I won't give it back.
I can't give it back.
Do you know that every time
that you walk into this room...
...you remind me of the way
things were?
Every time I look at you...
...I see what I cannot do...
...and what I will never do again.
And I can't stand it.
I know you love me, Patty.
But if you don't wanna torture me,
you'll go now, please.
Don't do that.
You know, I always say
that if a man can't use his hands...
...he's got to be a real dumb
son of a bitch to cry, you know?
I mean, it's just another way
of getting your gown wet, man.
I'm all right now, John. Thank you.
Well, I didn't do nothing except
save meself the trouble...
...of carrying a wet gown
all the way to the laundry.
Dr. Greenberg, please call
Physical Therapy.
Stop it. Don't do that.
- I can't help meself, me dear.
- Oh, God.
Now I have to get these
instruments sterilized again.
Don't say things like that.
Just the thought of it
makes me crazy, you know.
Everything to you here
is a big joke, isn't it?
Can't take a place like this
too serious, you know.
I mean, one floor people dying
of poison air and water...
...the next floor, ladies having
belly tucks.
Clean shit.
Well, look what they've done
for Mr. Harrison.
Yeah, and how much does it cost
to keep him alive?
- Thousands of dollars a week.
- That's not the point.
Well, the point is, in Africa...
...people die of the measles,
you know, little babies even.
Only cost a few pennies
to keep them alive now.
There's got to be something
crazy somewhere.
- Well, that's wrong too.
- Check.
So how about going out with me tonight?
We could discuss it some more.
- I don't think... - Come on.
We could get something to eat.
Later, my band is rehearsing.
It would be fun. We're sounding good.
I have an anatomy final.
It's a real killer.
Anatomy, is it? Well, your problems
are over, you lucky girl.
You see, I'm an expert on anatomy.
I could come over and show you
the hard parts.
- Yeah, I'll bet you could.
- John.
- Are you out of work?
- This man in this place? Never.
I was about to start scrubbing
the ceilings...
...don't you know?
Miss Sadler, your job is to lower
the temperature of the patients...
...not raise the hopes
of the orderlies.
Yes, ma'am.
- So who's my blind date?
- Hey, it's a real nice lady, man.
- Don't tell me, she's lots of fun.
- It's Mrs. Boyle.
Mrs. Boyle?
- Yeah.
- Do I have to see her?
Well, Dr. Emerson asked her
to stop by, you know.
Well, then I will see her.
If I refuse...
...he'll dissolve her in water
and inject her into me.
Excuse me.
- Mr. Harrison.
- I used to be.
- Kate Boyle. John.
- Come to cheer me up?
- I wouldn't quite say that.
- No?
Would you like to go over
to that corner?
- Sure.
- John?
Anything you say.
- How's it going, Ken?
- Pretty good. Stick around.
This lady's gonna cheer us up.
We could use that around here.
She's gonna saw us in half
or do a belly dance.
Not exactly.
- Well, if that's not what you do...
- If you need me, I'll be over there.
...what exactly do you do, Mrs. Boyle?
- Come to see if I can help you.
- Really?
There is a rumor going around that
you don't want any more treatment.
- Good.
- Why good?
Because I didn't think
anyone around here heard me.
I heard you, and that is why
I want to know...
...why you don't want
any more treatment.
Because I don't want to go on
living like this.
Why not? I mean,
it's a lousy break...
...but you'll be surprised at the things
you'll be able to do with training...
...and a little patience.
- Such as?
You're gonna be able to operate
a reading machine...
...and I think, an adapted typewriter,
maybe even a calculator.
Gee and wow. The three R's.
Doesn't exactly make for
an abundant life, does it?
Do you realize that Monet was almost
blind when he painted the Water Lilies?
And that Renoir's hands were so crippled,
they had to tie brushes for him to paint?
- And that...?
- No, no, no. Don't go on, please.
Please don't go on. I know,
you're going to read to me...
...from the Reader's Digest
"My Most Unforgettable Lame. "
You're an artist.
Sculpting isn't the only art.
Have you ever thought about
dictating into a tape recorder?
You could write a book about sculpture,
a novel, poetry.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Do you think you change your art
like you switch your major in college?
I'm a sculptor. My whole being,
my entire imagination...
...speaks to me through...
Spoke to me through my fingers.
I was a sculptor.
And that was what
my life was all about.
Now, you people seem to think...
...that it's about survival,
no matter what.
Now, if I'd wanted to write
a goddamn novel, I would've done it.
If I'd wanted to dictate poetry,
I would've done that.
How do you know you won't
wanna do that unless you try?
Because trying isn't important.
The work is important.
The work.
And not the credit and not the...
The reward.
And it is the work...
...that I will never do again.
How do you know you won't find
new work?
Look, just give it a chance.
Let me bring the reading
machine tomorrow.
One try. You might
surprise yourself.
Are there many books
for that machine?
Yeah. Quite a few.
You think I could make a request
for the first one?
Anything.
How about...
...Sculpting With No Hands,
Self-Taught?
Okay. You win.
I can see that you are not ready
for this discussion...
...so I will just come
back when you are.
You know, you are amazing,
you know?
All you goddamn people
are the same.
Every single time that I say something
even a little bit awkward...
...you just pretend I haven't said
anything at all.
It's amazing.
Why can't you try to relate to
your patients like human beings?
You know what's happening?
You're getting very angry.
- I can understand your anger...
- Oh, Jesus. You're doing it again.
Just listen to yourself.
I've just said something offensive
about you...
...and you have turned
your professional cheek.
If you were a human being...
...or if you were treating me
like a human being...
...you would've told
me to screw off.
Now, can you understand that is why
I don't wanna go on living?
And I am more convinced
of that now...
...after your visit, than I was before.
How do you like them apples?
The very exercise of your so-called
professionalism makes me want to die.
What's happening?
- I can't breathe.
- Okay, what's wrong?
Just go away, please. John.
- I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Please, just relax. - John.
Is there a nurse?
Is there a nurse, please?
I'm sorry.
Is there a nurse here, please?
Relax. Watch out, Mrs. Boyle.
Let the nurse take care of it.
It happens all the time.
Watch out! Relax, man.
Relax your body.
Get the hell out of the way!
Back! Nurse Rodriguez!
Nurse Rodriguez,
he can't breathe now!
- Call Dr. Scott.
- He can't breathe, man!
You'll be all right, John.
- Open your mouth.
- All right.
- Come on. Come on.
- Jesus Christ, fix him now.
Hold him, John. Hold him.
- Hold your head.
- Hold him.
Breathe in. Breathe in.
- Just take it in.
- Okay, just relax. Relax.
- He's gonna be all right, yeah?
- Relax. Okay, yeah. He'll be all right.
- He's going to be all right. Okay.
- Okay.
Feel okay? Yeah?
Yeah. Yeah, he feels okay.
Just get him on the bed.
Hey, man's in bed with his wife,
you know.
Turns to the lady and says:
"Why don't you never let me know
when you're having an orgasm?"
She looks over at him and says:
"Darling, it's because you're never there. "
Two, three.
- I think you got a smile, John.
- Yeah.
- You got a smile. I hear a laugh.
- "It's because you're never there. "
- One and...
- Yeah. Yeah.
All right. This hospital will
kill no quad before its time.
I called Mr. Hill.
He said he'd be here tomorrow.
Didn't know exactly when.
Well, I'll be in all day.
Is everything okay in here?
- This must be Grand Central Station.
- Is there any obstruction?
No, just a spasm. He'll be fine.
- Hello there.
- Hi.
Is your breathing okay now?
What was all the fuss about?
I had a run-in with Mrs. Boyle.
I know I should've just smiled
and nodded.
The last thing I wanna do is to
get Emerson down here again...
...with his pharmaceutical nightstick.
Yeah. I'm sorry about that.
Well, I don't suppose
it was your fault.
- I'll be on the floor if you need me.
- All right. Thanks.
Mr. Harrison...
...do you think perhaps
I could give you some advice?
Why don't you take the pills?
The dose is so small,
it's like taking nothing.
They're not gonna dull your consciousness,
not like the injection will.
You have beautiful breasts.
- What did you say?
- I said, you have beautiful breasts.
What an odd thing to say.
Why? I know you're a doctor,
but you're not gonna tell me...
...that you only regard them
as mammary glands.
- No. I know.
- You're perfectly safe.
I'm not gonna jump out of bed
and rape you.
- Yeah.
- Did I embarrass you?
No, you didn't embarrass me.
- You just surprised me a little bit.
- And embarrassed you.
- Yeah, just a little.
- Why?
I admit it's unusual for a man to
compliment a woman on her breasts...
...when only one of them is in bed.
One of the people, that is.
- Not one of the breasts. No.
- Not one of...?
That...? It's not the reason,
is it?
Look, I... I don't really think this is
helping you to talk like this, do you?
Because I can't do anything
about it, you mean.
Well, yeah. Right.
You know, I've noticed you
walking around this room...
...bending over me, examining
my body. It's amazing.
It's amazing how relaxed
a woman can be...
...when she's not in the presence
of a man.
Yeah.
Look, I'm sorry.
I mean, I'm sorry if I have provoked
you in any way...
...because, believe me,
it was not intentional.
No, no. You haven't provoked me,
as you call it.
But you are a woman.
And even though I only have a piece
of knotted string between my legs...
...I still have a man's mind.
Now, the other things I've noticed
is that I now engage...
...in sexual banter
with young nurses.
I'm constantly searching
for the double-entendre...
...in the most innocent of remarks.
Every time they leave the room,
I just go cold with embarrassment.
- Is that disgusting?
- No.
- Pathetic?
- It's sad.
I'm serious, you know,
about wanting to die.
Ken, come on.
Believe me,
you'll get over this feeling.
- How do you know?
- I know from experience...
...from watching other patients
who are worse off than you are...
...who go through the same thing.
- We all respond the same? We vegetables?
It's probably very difficult for you
to know what you want right now.
Well, Dr. Scott, I do,
with a free and working mind...
...and it is your moral obligation
to accept my decision.
No. Wait a minute.
Not according to my morals.
Why? Why are yours better than mine?
I'll tell you why.
Because you're more powerful than me.
I am in your power.
Well, I think you should try
to get some sleep now.
You've had a tough day.
I'm afraid I have to get going.
I was just in the middle
of another patient.
Oh, I thought you
were just passing through.
- Dr. Scott.
- Yeah.
You still have beautiful breasts.
Well, thank you.
That's it. That's it. Let's go.
Come on.
Good. Way to fire it.
Playmaker, let's go.
All right, good.
That's in, that's in, that's in.
Mr. Hill.
- How are you?
- Oh, I'm better.
I had a terrible cold last week.
I was, you know,
flat on my back for...
You know, I couldn't move...
You know, those guys are very good,
just like a real team.
No, their dribbling sucks.
Well, I've got all the
papers here, and...
I don't wanna talk about
the accident.
I can understand that, Mr. Harrison,
but I'm afraid that we really must.
No, no, no, I don't wanna...
I didn't ask you to come here
because of the insurance claim.
Mr. Hill, do you think you could
wheel me over to that table?
Thank you.
You have to undo the brake
under my right elbow.
Okay.
Let me ask you a question.
You don't work exclusively
for the insurance company, do you?
No. I'm with a... A small firm.
So there's no reason why you couldn't
represent me independently?
No. Is this all right?
- That's just fine. Thank you.
- All right.
I'd like you to do something
for me, if possible.
All right.
I'd like you to get me
the hell out of here.
Well, I'm afraid I don't understand
what you mean.
It's really very simple. I'd like to be
discharged from this hospital.
- To another hospital?
- No.
Well, they wouldn't keep you here
any longer than necessary.
You wouldn't think so, would you?
Mr. Hill, I can't exist
outside this hospital.
They have to keep me here
in order to keep me alive.
And they do seem rather intent
upon doing just that.
But I have decided that I do not
wish to go on living like this...
...and so I would like to be discharged
so that I could die.
And you want me
to represent you?
Tough luck.
Astonishing request.
My sculpture isn't very
orthodox either.
You mean,
just lie there somewhere...
...and die?
- And die, yes.
- Well, what's the hospital say?
- They don't know about it yet.
But do you realize
what you're asking me...?
I do realize that I am not asking you
to make any decision...
...concerning my life and death.
I am only asking you to represent
my position to this hospital.
Now, lawyers,
as a matter of course...
...represent criminals who they
know to be guilty, don't they?
Yeah.
So...
...don't you think I have the same
rights as any ax murderer?
Mary Jo! Wait!
She's such a lovely girl, you know.
We'll go for a little extra ride,
Mr. Forman.
I'm going to Gynecology.
Gynecology. He'll love it.
Where are you going?
Now, why won't you
go out with me?
Oh, God. I can't.
You know, negative thinking
never got nobody nowhere.
Oh, yeah? Well, I'm busy.
Besides, I hardly know you.
Right. That's why I think
we ought to go out, you know.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
- Well, ask me next week.
- Next week?
Yeah. After exams, okay?
Okay, it's a deal.
And I'll ask you this
afternoon as well.
Now, wasn't that fun?
You want me to kill my patient?
No. I'm simply presenting
Mr. Harrison's...
...wishes in the matter.
- Would you sign this, please?
But you do represent
Harrison in this matter?
No, I told him I had to talk to you
before I made that decision.
Releasing Harrison to anything
but a full-service hospital...
...is tantamount to murder.
- No, murder's a legal term.
Murder's a legal term, doctor.
I'm merely representing
my client's needs and wishes...
...if I choose to represent him.
- You believe in capital punishment.
- Oh, come on.
- That's what you're recommending
here. - No, I'm not.
I'm not recommending anything yet.
Yet? Look, Mr. Hill.
We've spent six months and a lot of
money trying to save this man's life.
Good morning. We're not gonna
throw that down the drain.
That is not the issue, doctor.
We're talking about a man's right
to determine his life...
...not the quality or expense
of your treatment.
Mr. Harrison would like to be discharged
from this hospital.
- Will you do that?
- No.
Why not?
Because it's my sworn duty
to preserve life, not to destroy it.
I'm not gonna let this man die
through any legal chicanery.
- He is a voluntary patient here.
- This interview is at an end.
I do not see any legal basis for you
to hold him here against his wishes.
Just try to understand one thing.
Mr. Harrison is not capable
of making any rational decision...
...about his life or his death.
He's in a state of depression...
...and using his situation
for your personal gain...
...is the lowest form of banality.
In your opinion, then, Mr. Harrison
is mentally unbalanced?
- Correct.
- In my opinion he is not.
Jesus Christ! You're not a doctor.
Well, would you object to my bringing in
a qualified psychiatrist...
...who would examine Mr. Harrison?
We have several on staff who would
be happy to examine Mr. Harrison.
I'm sure you'll understand
if I ask my own psychiatrist...
...whose opinion you are not
so sure of in advance.
Goodbye, Mr. Hill.
Well, thank you for your time, doctor.
Four, five...
You weren't in the SS when you
were a kid, were you, Michael?
- Come on, you're doing great.
- I'm doing great.
- Come on.
- There we go.
- Gently, gently, gently.
- Hello.
- Hello again.
- Hello, hello, hello.
- Hey, did you find anything out?
- Quite a bit.
See if you can find Dr. Jacobs.
Ask him to call me.
And get me the hospital
administrator, stat.
Dr. Emerson does not feel that you are
in a healthy enough mental state...
...to make a rational decision, especially
one of this seriousness and finality.
Now, I'm not qualified to decide
whether or not he's right.
Well, what will help you decide?
I'd like to have you examined
by an independent psychiatrist...
- That's fine.
- I will accept his view of the case.
- Fine. Has Emerson agreed?
- Yes. He already has.
That's great.
That's a good beginning.
Probably, he'll want the hospital
psychiatrist to examine you too.
I imagine you'll end up
with two conflicting views.
I would imagine so.
- And where would that lead us, exactly?
- Well, that's hard to say.
Emerson was very adamant.
He'll probably use
the Mental Hygiene Law.
Now, that means that if he can
get two psychiatrists...
...to sign statements saying
you're mentally unbalanced...
...he can commit you here and
give you any treatment he wants.
Can he do that?
And I have no say in that?
Some. You can then request a hearing
and see how it goes from there.
Well, let's get this show
on the road, okay?
Let's wheel in your shrink, all right?
Dr. Jacobs,
please call extension three.
Now, are you going
to represent me?
I don't know. I'd like to get
the shrink in here first.
I'll be in touch.
Okay. Well, call him
11:00 on Wednesday.
- Oh, Sandy, thanks for sparing
the time. - Never too busy.
How do you feel?
You want a cup of coffee?
No, thanks.
Just keeps my heartburn awake.
Who's your problem?
I have a 32-year-old man.
Auto accident, severe trauma...
...C4 transect, nephrectomy,
dialysis, usual C4 comps.
He wants to be discharged,
to go off dialysis to go home and die.
Would he?
Without dialysis he'd
be dead in a week.
I gave him steroids,
I balanced his electrolytes...
...I stabilized his dialysis.
We just about have
a viable human being again.
Clare. Sandy Jacobs, Clare Scott.
- Good to see you, Sandy.
- You too.
I was just telling Dr. Jacobs
about Ken Harrison.
- What about him?
- He's got a lawyer.
Threatens to sue
unless we discharge him.
If I'm gonna keep him alive...
...we'll have to commit him
under Mental Health.
Okay, even if I agree,
you're still gonna need another consult.
That's no problem, is it?
Depends if he's
clinically depressed, right?
Look, if I walk in, he says,
"Hey, I'm a teapot," you're in.
Depressed? What the hell do you mean?
He's suicidal.
I can name
several prominent psychiatrists...
...who wouldn't accept suicide
as evidence of insanity.
And I can name
several prominent psychiatrists...
...who in themselves
are evidence of insanity.
I'll accept that.
Okay, I will talk to
your suicide for you.
Good. And do me a favor
for the second signature.
Try to find an old bastard like me who
believes in something better than suicide.
I will... Listen, there is
an old bastard at St. Joseph's.
Staunch Catholic.
Thanks, Sandy. I appreciate it.
So will Harrison when he realizes.
Right. Doctor.
So you're committing Ken Harrison
as mentally incompetent?
I don't believe this, Michael.
- I know it stinks.
- Yeah.
But he'd be dead in
a week if we don't.
I don't understand this.
Wait a minute.
Where do we get the right to commit him?
Isn't this his decision?
- Aren't we talking about his life here?
- But goddamn it, it's our responsibility.
Now, I can't accept
the fact that a man...
...of Harrison's intelligence
would choose suicide.
I know what you mean, Michael,
but apparently he has.
Therefore, I say he's unbalanced.
Just because we don't agree with his
choice, doesn't make him crazy, does it?
I mean, look at him.
Does he look crazy to you, Michael?
Look at him lying there. Come on.
I mean, Christ, he's got no privacy at all,
he's got no sense of dignity.
I'll tell you, if that happened to me,
I don't know if I'd have the courage to live.
How about you? Can you stop
playing doctor for one second and tell me...
...would you wanna live like that?
- Don't give me that right-to-die routine.
- We're doctors. We're committed to life.
- Don't lecture me, all right?
When a patient is brought here
in his condition...
...I don't stand around wondering
whether his life is worthwhile.
I don't have time for that.
I try to save it.
- I'm a physician, not a judge.
- Interesting. You're behaving like a judge.
Clare. Clare.
I'm sure it's not necessary
for me to say this...
...but if Harrison should suddenly sour
and die on us I'll order an autopsy...
...and I'll act on whatever's found.
You fucker.
Here we go, off to dialysis.
Oh, dialysis.
Why don't we go to a bar?
Skip the damn dialysis.
Hey, come on, now.
Come on, man.
You know I can't do that.
I need this job.
This job's gonna pay
for me xylophone, you know?
- Yeah?
- Band sounds good, you know.
We can make a record even.
- Oh, yeah?
- Yeah.
Listen:
Hello, baby.
Hello, old man.
Old man?
Good morning, Roberta.
Lissa, anybody ever tell you that
you are absolutely gorgeous?
Got your hair cut, didn't you?
I'm not gorgeous.
I have a mirror.
And?
I'm not gorgeous.
Mirrors speak with forked tongue.
Harrison speaks the truth.
- Guess what.
- What?
I'm being cut down to once a week.
You're kidding. That's great!
Oh, Lissa, that's fabulous.
- You know what that means,
don't you? - What?
That means that soon you're gonna
be cut down to once every two weeks.
And then you'll be cut down
to once every none weeks.
God.
You got a hell of a life
ahead of you, kid.
Well, you get better, Ken.
Oh, I am. I will. I have to.
I signed to play shortstop
with the Red Sox this spring.
Fantastic.
Actually, I signed to wear
red socks for the shortstops.
Actually, I'm dating a shortstop
who was wearing red socks.
- Bye, Ken. See you.
- I have to stop red mark on my socks.
And I got my red socks.
"Bye, Ken. "
Lissa, you ever been to a disco?
See you, Lissa.
Mr. Harrison.
The very same.
I'm Sandy Jacobs.
You're a psychiatrist.
Does it show?
Thank you, nurse.
I'll watch him now.
- Okay. I'll see you. I'll be outside.
- Thank you, Roberta.
You for me or against me?
Oh, did that sound like paranoia?
You would hardly expect me
to make an instant diagnosis.
Well, did Dr. Emerson send you?
Would you describe yourself
as suffering from paranoia?
Nope.
What would you say paranoia was?
Well, I think it would depend
on the person, myself...
...but generally speaking,
I think it's someone...
...who believes that what they think
is right and will brook no denial.
Now, if this person were a sculptor...
...we would, indeed,
diagnose this condition as paranoia.
If, however, the person were a doctor,
we would call it professionalism.
You don't like doctors.
You like your patients?
Some.
I like some doctors.
What is it about doctors, then?
Oh, I...
I don't think many of them realize
that many of their patients...
...can and want to understand
what's wrong with them...
...and they're capable of making
decisions about their own bodies.
And what they need,
of course, is information.
Well, a doctor doles out information like
a kosher butcher doles out pork sausages.
That's true, but wouldn't you agree
patients need medical knowledge...
...in order to make good decisions?
- Absolutely.
I would be very grateful for any information
so that I might make the proper decision.
It would, however, be my decision.
Now, let's just say, for example...
...that you came into my studio and you
took a look at my pieces and you said:
"Well, I think I'll take the mother and child,"
and I said, "No, no, no.
You don't know a damn thing
about sculpting. You get the flamingo. "
You'd think I was nuts.
But we are not talking
about a piece of sculpture.
We're talking about your life.
That's right. That's exactly right.
My life. Think about it.
And your obvious intelligence
weakens your case.
I'm not saying that you
would find life easy.
I'm saying that you have resources
an unintelligent person doesn't have.
No, no, no. Wait a minute.
That's not fair. That's Catch-22.
If you're clever enough
and sane enough...
...to put forth an invincible
argument for suicide...
...that demonstrates
that you ought not to die?
You know, you've got a nasty little
tidiness compulsion there.
I was an only child.
But enough of me.
Well, what about your parents?
Are they living?
No. No. I have no living relatives,
which really isn't bad...
...considering birthdays
and Christmas.
You know, presents?
After all, how many
hats can you wear?
Listen, I'd like to do some tests.
Tests? What kind of tests?
I'll tell you right now,
my time in the 100-yard dash is rotten.
And I'd like to confer
with Dr. Emerson.
Confer. That's when two doctors
support each other's mistakes, right?
- You seem very angry.
- No shit.
What are you gonna do?
Put me down as being in the manic phase
of a manic-depressive cycle?
No, I certainly would not do that,
Mr. Harrison.
Your lawyer, Mr. Hill,
asked me to see you.
- If anything, I'm on your team.
- My team?
Dr. Barrows, do you understand
the trap that I am in?
Can anyone prove
that they're sane?
Could you?
I'll come and see
you another time.
No, you will not
come and see me...
...because each
time you see me...
...the more I will get angry
and frustrated and depressed.
Please just leave me alone!
Hello?
Pat?
Anybody here?
Oh, God.
Hello?
- Hi.
- Sorry I couldn't meet you.
- That's okay.
I rehearse and study and perform,
and take care of the studio...
...and arrange Ken's
business affairs.
His work's gone up a lot.
- Did you get a look around?
- Oh, yeah, I did.
It's pretty amazing.
He has an incredible talent.
Yes. He had.
Here's your key. Thank you.
The place is really great.
- I'm gonna have to close it up.
- Really?
Turn Ken's work over to a gallery.
They're just better equipped
to take care of it.
I wanna thank you for
agreeing to this meeting.
You'll have to excuse my rush.
I'm late. I have a date.
Well, just go ahead.
I'll just take a couple minutes.
Pat, I could really use your advice.
I'm looking for some possible way
to help out Ken Harrison.
Some way to get through to him.
You mean, the late Ken Harrison.
- What do you mean?
I mean, he's not... - Yes, he is.
He may not be to you,
but he is to me and to himself.
Understand me, doctor.
I loved the late Ken Harrison.
- And I grieve for his death but...
- I'm sorry. I don't understand this.
I can't believe you're just
giving up on him like this.
Giving him up?
Ken Harrison is gone, doctor.
You wanna see Ken?
Look around you.
- Take a better look.
- Yes, I know. He's...
He's special. That's why we've gotta
find a way to change his mind.
Look, Pat, I know that if we can just
get him to wait a couple of months...
Dr. Scott.
I respect Ken's wishes
because I respect Ken.
Why can't you do that?
Why don't you respect him?
I do.
Then just let him do
what he wants to do.
Let him go.
Wake up, bimbo, it's feeding time.
I can't wait.
- Dinner is served...
- Oh, not leftover Thanksgiving.
- Chicken.
- Oh, how creative.
Chicken instead of turkey, I see.
Why are there no bunny rabbits
on my bib?
I want bunny rabbits on my bib.
- I want bunny rabbits...
- Shut up.
Eat. You eat.
Be a good boy.
Oh, great.
I'm eating the drumstick and
you're licking your fingers.
- You must be starving.
- I'm...
Why don't you eat the drumstick
and I will lick your fingers?
How about the peas?
Wanna try the peas?
I hate peas. They're all clones.
No, I'm not ready for the peas.
I'm not ready...
- Come on.
- Wasn't totally ready for the peas.
Come on, don't be gross.
I want you to make a circle
with your thumb and your forefinger.
My thumb and my forefinger.
Like that.
Oh, I know what you're gonna do...
- Bull's-eye.
- Right on the mark, baby.
Here, I'll put the peas back in
where they came from.
Watch out.
I'm a quadriplegic, you can't hit me.
Yes, you can.
I think the evidence is against me.
But I don't think that we're
talking about euthanasia.
Well, I'm sorry,
because I think we are.
Well, what would you think
if by a sudden miracle...
...Ken gained the use of his arms
for 30 seconds...
...and swallowed a bottle
full of sleeping pills?
What would your reaction be?
Look, I told you I'm a doctor and I
have a responsibility to my patient.
- Yeah... No.
- Okay?
You, as you.
You mean, how I would
really feel about that?
I don't know. I guess...
I guess a part of me might
be a little relieved, why?
Would you try to save his life?
With stomach pumps and all that?
I...
I don't think I would.
Great. So we're not adversaries.
No.
Well, so I've got a bottle of Rémy
at my place...
...waiting for two non-adversaries
to open.
- No, thank you.
- It's very close.
No, it would be...
A nightcap after a good dinner.
No. Thanks very much but I gotta...
I gotta go.
Oh, it couldn't possibly be two hours...
I thought I'd change
your position early.
I didn't expect to see
you here tonight.
Yeah, I had some work
to finish up in the office.
- You look real nice.
- Well, thank you.
- You been out?
- Yeah, I went out to dinner.
Good company?
You're fishing.
You're right.
Actually, yes,
it was very good company.
I had dinner with your lawyer,
Carter Hill.
Well, well, well.
The horny little bugger.
- Didn't take him long.
- It was just a dinner.
I know I asked him to represent me
but this is ridiculous.
It was just a dinner.
Did my surrogate
self behave myself?
Yes, you were a
perfect gentleman.
I want you to get another surrogate.
Could you, please?
Why?
Do you really mind?
No.
Ken, I might've done something that
you're not gonna be real thrilled about.
Something bad.
- Man.
- Yeah.
This I gotta hear.
Well, I went to your studio.
You went to my studio?
What for?
I don't know.
I guess because I wanted
to know more about you.
Know more about me?
No woman had ever examined me
so thoroughly.
I'm really glad I got a
chance to see your work.
I think you're...
Well, you're okay.
- You're good.
- Thank you.
So I was just thinking maybe you'd
wanna have a couple of pieces here.
- Well, look, I'll make you a deal.
- What?
You can take any pieces
that you like...
...free of charge.
What do you say?
You know,
I'm very glad you just said that...
...because I just happen to have
here with me one of your pieces.
An art thief on top of it all.
Yeah.
It's just so amazing.
- You do have excellent taste.
- Well, thank you.
And it happens to be
my favorite piece in the studio.
- I think it's the best thing in the studio.
- It's beautiful.
It's by Michelangelo.
What? This...
It's a realization from
the Sistine Chapel.
- You see, God, who gives life to man...
- Oh, shit.
This is Michelangelo.
Well, it's obvious.
Is my face a little red right now?
- Look, I'm sorry.
- Don't be sorry.
Really. Don't be sorry.
Actually, come to think of it...
...I wouldn't mind looking at that
now and again.
Ken, I'm...
I'm getting this very strange feeling
that you're really enjoying all this.
I'll tell you something, Clare...
...this is the first time in months that I've
begun to feel like a human being again.
And isn't that the whole point, Ken?
I mean, isn't that what
all this is about?
I'm sorry, I just can't believe
you're really fighting for death.
I just don't buy that.
You're right,
in that I had to be sure...
...that I really wanted to win
what I was fighting for, you know.
That I wasn't just doing it in order
to prove to myself that I was still alive.
And are you sure?
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
Clare, could you fix
these pillows for me?
Sure.
Clare? Clare.
Life for me is over.
I cannot do the things I wanna do.
I can't even say the
things I wanna say.
So for me...
...it might as well be over.
You do understand that, don't you?
Yeah.
- So...
...tomorrow, on with the fight.
- Right.
On with the fight.
- Good night.
Clare?
You driving home?
- Yeah.
- Use your seat belts.
Good night.
- I'm gonna lose my job.
- You're not gonna lose your job, baby.
Not for doing something like this.
Hey, come on. Cool it.
Be quiet, we're almost there.
Okay, now.
- You got to be ready, now.
- Yeah, okay.
- Okay.
- Okay. Let's go.
What are you doing?
- You're not supposed to be on duty tonight.
- There's duty and there's duty.
- What are you doing?
- Hey.
Keep that blabber
shut closed, okay?
- Where are you going?
- Dialysis.
- Hi, Ken. How you doing?
- Pretty good.
- But where are you...?
- Dialysis.
Now that I know we're
not going to dialysis, where...?
Hey.
For one time
in your life, man, shut up.
- What took so long?
- I came as fast as I could.
Now, shut up, woman.
One, two...
one, two, three, four!
Shake, shake.
Shake, shake, shake.
Hey, man.
Yeah, we was jamming, man.
Hey, Ken, I want you to meet the
members of the Rebel Rockers, man.
- Here on keyboards is G.T., man.
- Hey.
- We got Red Locks here.
- How you doing?
Right there, man, Teodoro.
And toking on some ganja,
Rossan, right here.
Herbal inspiration.
Is that an illicit narcotic I see?
- No, this is herbal.
- Herbal, schmerbal.
- Get it over here.
- On the steel drums there, man...
...is Michael, you know.
- What about Sonora?
Sonora?
Check it. One love.
- I think he like that, man.
- Hey, John.
- I think he like it, now.
- John, wait.
- Play that song you did last night.
- All the rockers, you want to rock, man?
Yo. Hey. One, two...
one, two, three, four!
Stop.
Wait, everybody stop.
Listen, stop, somebody's coming.
Stop.
- Stop it. Somebody's coming.
- Somebody's coming.
Forget the doobie
and get the microphone, man.
Hurry, man. Hurry, now.
Get the ganja, man.
Get the ganja.
- Come on back. Let's go.
- Hurry it up. Get the door.
- Oh, shit, man. I forgot my cymbals.
- Okay. What is?
What the hell is going on here?
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
Isn't this dialysis?
Okay, one, two, three.
- All the way over.
- Come on.
Rodriguez.
Rodriguez, my beloved saint.
Couldn't you spare me three
or four thousand aspirin, please?
- How about one Tylenol?
- How about two Tylenol?
I got my lawyer coming this morning.
So, what were you doing
in the basement?
I was on my way to dialysis.
Your breath smells
like my whole neighborhood.
Who is that?
Who is that? It couldn't be a doctor.
They all wear Italian loafers and silk socks.
Carter Hill.
The man who sues, eats,
and chases girls for me.
- How you doing?
- Oh, I'm all right.
- How are you feeling this morning?
- Just wonderful.
Okay. Back over.
Turn him slowly. He gets dizzy
because of lack of circulation.
Yeah, I don't get to circulate
very much anymore.
So, what's your decision?
So, how are you feeling
this morning, Mr. Harrison?
You slept well last night, did you?
Like I got hit in the
head by a spade.
Oh, cute, man, cute,
for a cripple.
I'm...
I'm going to...
...represent you.
- All right.
- When is the hearing? Why?
- I haven't applied for it yet.
- Two reason... Excuse me.
- Sadler, get the Tylenol, please?
- Why not?
- Two reasons.
Commitment judges usually find
for the hospital...
...and I...
I think I have something better.
Really?
That sounds interesting.
Miss Rodriguez.
Could it be that Dr. Emerson
suggested to you that you...
...hang around
while my attorney was here?
I'm just here in case you
get excited or something.
Rodriguez, it's you that excites me.
Where are you going?
Get away from there, you slut.
You Puerto Rican flesh pudding,
I love you.
Thought I was gonna get lucky
there for a second.
So, what's better?
I wanna go for
a writ of habeas corpus.
Habeas corpus? I thought
that had to do with criminals.
Usually it does.
It is against the law to deprive anyone
of his liberty without due process.
And if that happens, he can apply
for a writ of habeas corpus...
...which means, "give us the...
...body. "
That's right on the nose, in my case.
And if sufficient cause can't be
established to detain the individual...
...the judge will order him released.
- How long will this take?
- Not long. A couple of days.
- And will I have to go to court?
- I doubt it.
I would think that any judge would allow
the hearing to take place right here.
Well, well, well.
All's well that ends.
Well, I'm off to find the judge.
See you soon.
Be an unusual case
for you, won't it?
Making a plea for
your client's death?
Look, I'll be honest with you.
This is a case I could bear to lose.
Well, if you do,
it's a life sentence for me.
You're new, aren't you?
Yup.
- What's your name?
- Stella.
Stella?
Well, Stella, you're very kind.
Most of the nurses just yank
you around till they wake you up...
...and then they disappear
for about two hours.
You're trying to be released, aren't you?
Be taken off your medication?
Everybody knows about it, huh?
Oh, yeah. Sure.
Aren't you afraid?
Yeah.
- This what you wanted, now?
- Oh, yes. If you'll put it behind this desk.
Don't I get a special breakfast
or anything?
Not for some miserable jive-ass
moaning on about wanting to die.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
Hey.
Aren't you gonna wish me luck?
No.
Hey, I wish you luck.
Judge Wyler.
Thank you.
Please sit down.
This is an informal hearing, which
I'd like to keep as brief as possible.
Mr. Kenneth Harrison?
Yes, Your Honor?
Mr. Harrison, I've decided in consultation
with Mr. Eden and Mr. Hill...
...not to subject you to examination
and cross-examination.
- Your Honor, there may be things I want to...
- Mr. Harrison, if I have any doubts...
...I'll question you myself.
Dr. Emerson, we'll start with you.
- Will you take the oath, please?
Mr. Eden? - Thank you.
Raise your right hand.
Do you solemnly swear that the testimony
you are about to give will be the truth...
...the whole truth, nothing but the truth?
- I do.
Be seated.
Dr. Emerson,
what is your position here?
I'm chief of medical services.
Would you give the court
a medical history of the treatment...
...Mr. Harrison has received here?
Following an automobile accident
on the evening of April 27th of this year...
...Mr. Harrison was admitted
to this hospital in shock...
...and suffering from a fractured left
tibia, fractured right tibia and fibula...
...fractured pelvis. Four fractured ribs,
one of which punctured the right lung.
A dislocated fourth cervical vertebrae,
which crushed the spinal cord.
He suffered internal damage
to the spleen and kidney...
...for which we performed a splenectomy
and double nephrectomies.
He remained unconscious for 30 hours.
As a result of treatment here...
...all the bones and ruptured tissue
have healed...
...with the exception of the spinal cord.
That, together with the mental trauma,
are all that remain of the initial injury.
Will there be an improvement
in the spinal cord?
No.
- Kidney function?
- I regret not.
And the mental trauma?
It's impossible to violate the body to
the extent of Mr. Harrison's without
suffering severe mental aberration,
depression, even loss of reality.
In your view, is Mr. Harrison
suffering from such mental aberration?
He's depressed.
Clinically depressed?
Yes, clinically depressed.
Thank you, doctor. That's all.
Mr. Hill? Just one second, please.
Doctor, is there any way you can
demonstrate this clinical depression...
...any tests or measurements
you can show us?
No.
Then how do you distinguish
clinical depression...
...which might preclude the ability
to make informed and logical decisions...
...from a perfectly sane, justified
feeling of depression...
...as a result of existing conditions?
By relying on my 18 years as a physician
dealing with both types.
- Are you a psychiatrist, Dr. Emerson?
- No.
Have you any degrees, credentials...
...or have you any specialized
training in psychiatry?
No.
No further questions.
- Mr. Eden?
- No further questions.
Thank you, doctor. You're excused.
Dr. Robert Barrows.
Dr. Robert Barrows
to the stand, please.
Dr. Barrows,
what position do you hold?
I'm the consulting psychiatrist
at the Monroe State Mental Hospital.
Then you must see a large number of
patients suffering from depressive illness.
Yes, I do.
All right.
You've examined Mr. Harrison?
Well, we know that,
or else why would he be here?
- Remember the word "informal. "
- Yes, Your Honor.
Would you say that Mr. Harrison
is suffering from a depressive illness?
- No, I would not.
- The court has heard evidence...
...that Mr. Harrison is depressed.
Do you dispute that?
In my opinion, he's reacting in a perfectly
rational manner to a very bad situation.
No further questions.
- Mr. Eden?
- Doctor.
Are there any objective results that
you could produce that would prove...
...that Mr. Harrison is capable?
There are clinical symptoms
of endogenous depression.
Disturbed sleep patterns, loss of appetite,
lassitude, and many more.
Even if they were present, they'd be masked
by Mr. Harrison's physical condition.
Then how can you be sure that this is,
in fact, a reactive depression?
By experience.
By discovering when I talked to him
that he has a remarkably incisive mind...
...and is perfectly capable
of understanding his position...
...and deciding what he wants
to do about it.
Do you think he
made the right decision?
Your Honor, is this relevant?
- No, not really.
- I'd like to answer that, if I may.
Go ahead.
No.
I think he made the wrong decision.
- Oh, shit.
- Mr. Hill.
When I said "informal," I didn't mean
uncontrolled. Now be quiet.
- I'm sorry. I...
- Thank you, doctor.
That's all.
Dr. Jacobs, the consulting psychiatrist for
the hospital, wasn't able to be here today.
I have a sworn affidavit.
He agrees with Dr. Emerson's position.
- Have it entered in the record.
- Yes, Your Honor.
Mr. Harrison, you feel like
answering some questions?
Yes, I do.
I'll try to keep them
uninflammatory.
- You're too kind.
- Not at all.
No, I meant that. I think I'd
much prefer a hanging judge.
Either way I decide,
I am a hanging judge.
Now, Mr. Harrison, the medical director
and the consulting psychiatrist...
...claim that you're not capable of
making an informed, intelligent decision.
That's right. They're wrong.
- What does that mean?
- It means they're good doctors.
And they won't let a patient die
if they can help it.
Do you think you're suffering
from depression?
Well, I am completely paralyzed.
I think I'd be insane if
I wasn't depressed.
But wanting to die
must be strong evidence...
...that your mental state has gone
beyond simple depression.
- I do not want to die. - Then what
the hell is this case all about?
Make that read,
"Then what is this case all about?"
There was a "hell," and I
think he said "shit" before,
so maybe you ought to cross...
Sorry.
I do not want to die, because as far
as I am concerned, I am dead already.
I merely want the doctors
to recognize that fact.
I cannot believe that this...
This condition...
...constitutes life
in any real sense of the word.
Legally, you're alive.
I think I could challenge even that.
Any reasonable definition
of the word "life"...
...must include the idea
that it be self-supporting.
Now, isn't it true that
in heart transplant cases...
...it's legal to take someone's heart
if they can only be kept alive...
...by the use of respirators
and other medical hardware?
There also has to be
no brain activity at all.
- Yours is certainly working, Mr. Harrison.
- Certainly working and certainly sanely.
- That's what we're here to decide.
- Your Honor...
...I am not asking anyone to kill me.
I'm only asking to be discharged
from this hospital.
- Which will kill you.
- And that's exactly my point.
I'll spend the rest of my life
in this hospital...
...with everything in it geared
just to keeping my brain alive.
And I'll never have
a possibility whatsoever...
...of being able to direct
a good goddamn thing.
Now...
...as far as I'm concerned,
that's an act of deliberate cruelty.
Wouldn't it be more cruel
for society to let people die...
- ... when with some effort it
could save them? - No...
...because the cruelty is not a question of
saving someone's life or letting them die.
The cruelty...
...is that the choice is removed
from the person concerned.
I would like to be able to decide
what happens to my own body.
A man who is desperately depressed is
not capable of making a reasonable choice.
Well, as you said, Your Honor,
that is the question to be decided.
All right.
All right. You tell me. You tell us.
You tell me why it is a reasonable choice
that you decided to die.
- All right.
- No.
All right. All right.
The most important part
of my life was my work.
And the most valuable asset I had
for that was my imagination.
Now, it's just too damn bad that my mind
wasn't paralyzed along with my body...
...because my mind, which had been
my most precious possession...
...has become my enemy,
and it tortures me.
It tortures me with thoughts
of what might've been...
...and what might be to come,
and I can...
...feel my mind...
...very slowly breaking up.
Now, you take women, for example.
I used to... I used to love
what they were...
...and how they thought
and how they smelled and...
And now I, I dread it
when they come into the room...
...because I loathe the way
they make me feel.
You know, I am filled with an
absolute sense of outrage...
...that you, who have no
knowledge of me whatsoever...
...have the power to condemn me
to a life of torment...
...because you cannot see the pain.
There's no blood,
there's no screaming.
So you can't see it?
Your Honor...
...if you saw a mutilated animal
on the side of the road, you'd shoot it.
Now, I am only asking for the same mercy
that you would show that animal.
And I am not asking anyone to commit
an act of violence.
Just...
...take me somewhere...
...and leave me.
And if you don't...
If you don't...
...then you come back here in five years
and you see what a piece of work...
...that you've done here today.
In hearings for a writ
of habeas corpus...
...an immediate
decision is mandated...
...but I propose to consider
the issues carefully.
Therefore, I request everyone
to please remain here...
...unless a medical emergency
preempts your presence.
Marjorie.
Yeah, I'm still at the hospital.
I wonder if you'd look
up something for me.
A Florida decision.
About two years back.
I think it was Saikewicz.
You look up the holding
and read it to me, please.
I'll hold on.
See this quarter, man?
See the quarter, now?
Oh, you don't see it no more, huh?
Which hand is the quarter in now?
Right hand.
He's gonna take the right hand.
Will everyone please
return to your seats?
There are precedents aplenty
for both sides of this issue.
In re: Karen Ann Quinlan,
the supreme court of New Jersey...
...recognized the preservation of a personal
right to privacy against bodily intrusions.
In Belchertown v. Saikewicz,
the court held that the right
to refuse medical treatment...
...in appropriate circumstances
extends to both
competent and
incompetent persons.
And the law holds that a deliberate
decision to embark on an action...
...which will eventually lead to death
is not ipso facto evidence of insanity.
If it were, society would have to condemn
many men to dishonorable burials...
...rather than posthumous medals.
Yet...
...we do have to remember...
...Mr. Harrison's mind is affected...
...and we must, in this case, be careful
not to allow Mr. Harrison's intelligence...
...to blind us to the fact that he may
be suffering from a depressive illness...
...which would diminish his ability
to make an informed decision.
We must ignore Mr. Harrison's cogently
argued plea to be allowed to die...
...if we believe it to be the product of a
disturbed or clinically depressed mind.
However...
...I am satisfied...
...that Mr. Harrison's a brave
and thoughtful man...
...who is in complete possession
of his mental faculties...
...and I therefore order
that he be set free.
That's it, gentlemen.
Peggy, let me get that.
Hey...
...you got your hanging judge.
I think not.
Thank you.
Thank you very much,
Your Honor.
I hope so.
Thank you.
- Goodbye.
Where will you go?
I'll get a room somewhere,
I suppose.
- There's no need.
- Don't start it again!
You can stay here.
We'll stop all treatment, no dialysis.
Even stop feeding if you like.
You'll be in a coma in a few days.
Dead in a week, two at most.
But you won't be alone.
There'll be very little discomfort.
No last-minute attempt
at resuscitation?
Only if you ask for it.
Thank you.
It would obviously be easier
for me if I stayed.
Okay, I'll take care of that.
Why are you doing this?
Because you might
change your mind.
Oh, don't.
Please.
Better not, I think.
Okay.
Dr. North, you are
wanted in Emergency.
Dr. Keys, please call
Dr. Fairbanks in X-Ray One.