Intangible FS & DoReMii present
Huan Huan Ai - Why Why Love
Episode 15 - FINALE brought to you by Intangible FS!
Visit us at http://intangiblefs.livejournal.com.
This is the finale, thank you for your support and patience with us ~
Get this free at d-addicts.com
Over the mountains, over the oceans.
Over the obstacles, facing the dangers.
I still have to catch up, I still have to fly.
I am not afraid no matter how dangerous it is on the way.
Before dawn, I have to be ready.
Going forward on the roads. Being able to see my destination.
I won't regret. I am definitely right.
I want an exciting tomorrow.
Because of you, I will not back away.
I want to see my achievement progressing slowly.
Because love can make a dream fly.
No matter how much longer the road ahead of me is, I will overcome it all.
Everytime I close my eyes,
I can only think of you, smiling at me.
I have surpassed it. Everything went smoothly.
Just need one more step, and I can reach my destination.
Translators: jolene & xaralind
Timers: Jessica_27 & imaricharm00 & Miaka FY
Editors: soph_iie & Randomguyyy & lemon-twist
QC'ers: npaujmirae & Tiffiany_45 & sweetsweet
Final QC'ers: xCHELLy & sweetsweet & Tiffiany_45
Episode 15
- FINALE -
Everything that has happened today
was just a big joke.
I cannot do it.
The person I love most
is only you.
Jia Di.
Did you have a nightmare?
Don't be scared.
Mom's here.
Mom!
Don't be scared.
I'm here to tell you
that the reason for me leaving the country,
specifically New York,
was to handle the investment problem in the company
together with Uncle Yang.
Now your father's company
is fine.
Thank you.
I didn't know
that you have always been caring
and helping with my family matters.
So...
You don't need a stabilizer anymore.
Please let go of Huo Da.
So in your heart,
I am that kind of person.
You can't be serious? You really love Huo Da?
The only person I love is you.
I love him,
so he chose me.
So it's like that.
Then, please tell
the person inside
that Jia Di was waiting for him the whole night,
wondering the same question over and over again.
If she cannot stop loving Huo Da,
what can she do?!
I also want to know
what I can do.
What else can I do?
Who is it?
General Manager.
Auntie,
I'm here to look for Jia Di.
Thank you.
General Manager is with you now,
so I'll go out to handle other matters.
Okay, go do your thing.
I'm fine.
Bye bye.
Everyone must think that I'm really thick-skinned.
I split myself in half.
One half of me
also thinks that.
Then what about the other half?
The other half of me
believes Huo Da would not do that.
I don't know how to explain it,
but I just believe in him.
Actually,
there's also a part of me that
still believes
that Huo Da will make you sad and cry,
but the other half of me
also believes in him, like you do.
Anyway,
no matter what, I will still believe that you,
even if the situation worsens,
will be able to carry on.
Even if
I can only chase after his shadow,
I will not give up.
I will use all my strength to run foward.
I will definitely catch up to him.
NT $7000?!
You want to steal?
What Master and his Angel?
Who are you?
No manners at all!
I am your Master.
Hurry and get over here!
It's the Devil!
I'm dead!
Starting tomorrow,
she's the angel,
you're the master.
To me,
this is a fun game.
The goal of this game is to
try my best to
harass you, bully you.
Leave my things here.
Take your things and leave,
thief!
And you...
are really horrible, really horrible, really horrible!
Look carefully!
The things I'm taking now,
are all mine!
Eating with the right person
is not torture,
not forced,
it's happiness.
You're such a pitiful loser that you won't
understand it in a lifetime!
Empty exchange coupons,
or the ones that I haven't thought of yet.
Can all these
be used as my rent?
Lend your handkerchief to me.
I don't have such girly things like handkerchiefs.
But...
I can lend you my hands.
Do you believe when people die,
they'll become stars?
I believe so.
When I want to cry,
the stars in the sky
are just like my dad's eyes.
It's just like he's saying to me,
Jia Di, you have to keep going!
Don't cry. You have to be brave.
You only know how to make me mad
and upset.
Crying for a person like you is such a waste!
But how come I still don't want to lose you?
If...
I have 100 dislikes of you,
later on, without noticing,
they'll automatically exchange for 100 likes.
I want to continue dating you.
You're really moving...
to go live with that fox?!
Hey!
You're leaving just like that?!
It's really unfair to treat Jia Di this way!
You're despicable!
This kind of method
is the most despicable I've ever heard!
Go apologize to her!
Hey!
You've really changed your heart?
If you still take me as your brother,
then listen to me!
Huo Da stays!
How come you've turned into this kind of person?!
What do you take Jia Di for?!
That princess wants your brother; not you.
Then, you went for Jia Di.
Princess couldn't get your brother, so she came back for you,
so you're dumping Jia Di!
You're an ass!
Cold-blooded!
Heartless!
Bo Zi,
have you yelled enough?
If you have,
can I go now?
Asshole!
Yan Shu,
sorry.
I've let everyone misunderstand you.
I'm terribly sorry.
During this time,
the most unfair thing is
I want to try my best
to make Jia Di and everyone else hate me,
but
I've brought you down with me.
It has nothing to do with you,
yet you have to carry this burden.
How can it be not related to me?
Huo Da,
In your time of pain,
I am who you chose to trust.
It is a very
treasured feeling.
Yan Shu...
Even though misunderstanding is a must,
it's not important.
The thing that's most important right now
is taking you to the hospital.
What you owe me is the truth.
Wait until you recover,
then repay me.
Before going to the hospital,
I still have something to do.
Please come in.
What is it?
Huo Da wants you to meet him.
He has something to tell you in person.
If you don't want to listen,
I won't force you.
If it wasn't for Jia Di,
I wouldn't want to speak with you
nor see you at all.
I know.
I've been wanting to know
out of curiously,
why did you have to do that?
Because you've always loved Jia Di.
I've never denied to that point,
but that definitely isn't
the reason you hurt Jia Di.
I don't want to hurt her either.
I know that you don't want to intentionally hurt Jia Di,
so don't mess with Yan Shu anymore.
Return to Jia Di,
and everything can still be resolved.
But my heart
cannot leave Yan Shu.
Then what were you doing before?
Wanting to deceive her, because you were lonely?
Or was it a fun joke to you?
Probably all of the above.
Huo Da, you're too selfish.
If you love Yan Shu,
why did you make Jia Di love you?
What you want to ask is
how come I had to ruin the relationship between Taiwan Ah Xin and you.
Is there meaning to that question anymore?
It's not important what I want.
What you should do is apologize to Jia Di!
Is she alright?
Could she be?
She cried uncontrollably,
then used all her strength to eat,
and then prepared to start anew
and get you back.
She's really old-fashioned.
Other girls would have given up already,
yet she's still there and so strong-willed.
That's her cutest
and most captivating point.
Before,
when there wasn't Yan Shu,
I was also very captivated.
But just awhile back,
when Yan Shu got in a car accident,
there was a chance for her and me to reconcile.
Jia Di or Yan Shu?
I'm not sure.
Because your decisions
will hurt both of them.
You have already hurt Jia Di,
but what if you have regrets?
Are you going to hurt Yan Shu then?
So
there must be a conclusion.
This time, we'll leave it to fate.
Pick one.
What is it?
Taiwan Ah Xin's clever exchange coupons had her
forced to live at my place,
and the exchange coupons that she used to pay the rent.
I have already written down the exchange item.
Pick.
What's it say on it?
One is
an exchange coupon to give her happiness.
What about the other one?
An exchange coupon to wish her happiness.
~Give her happiness~
Since fate has given us the answer,
you have to give her happiness.
It means that
I wish her happiness.
I give you guys my best wishes.
Can she still be happy
without you?
Tong Jia Di's happiness is your responsibility.
Can you do it?
She loves you.
There won't be me in the future.
Only you.
You're so handsome,
and you're serious about her.
I believe Jia Di knows.
Huo Da, don't regret thia.
I will use all my ability to pursue Jia Di.
Very good.
You and Jia Di.
Yan Shu and I.
It must be all God's preperation.
Jia Di really loves you!
Let me see the other exchange coupon!
Take it out.
~Give her happiness~
You have seen through me.
Yes. I've deceived you.
Both of them are the same.
You would've definitely picked
the 'Give her Happiness' exchange coupon,
and I could smoothly
push Taiwan Ah Xin to you.
Cut all ties between her and me.
Is Huo Da worried
that no one will replace him in taking care of Jia Di?
You have to act so despicably
just to ditch Jia Di?
Just go along with the play.
Isn't it more touching?
At least like this,
I won't have to face the crying Ah Xin.
She gets more annoying by the minute.
I've toleranced enough of
her childlike behavior!
Huo Yan! Stop!
From now on,
I will use all my capabilities to protect Jia Di.
Don't forget...
Give her happiness.
Why did you do that?
Why did you give Jia Di to Huo Yan?
Are you preparing for the aftermath?
Are you giving your last words?
You believe you're going to die for sure?!
Are you giving up?!
I don't want to give up either.
But God
seems like He has given up on me.
Death...
is something that I've never thought about.
Before, when I've experienced a few crashes,
not once was I scared.
But this time,
I'm really scared.
Scared that unknowingly,
I'll be tricked by God.
No way. It doesn't matter how scared you are,
you still have to fight.
I won't allow you give Jia Di's happiness
to Huo Yan.
You have no right to wave the white flag to Hell.
Let's go. Take me to the hospital.
Your call will be directed to voicemail.
Leave your message after the beep.
Jia Di, mom's back!
Jia Di!
Sister-in-law!
I'm telling you...
Right now,
I'm changing my career to insurance.
I think
that this plan
will suit you.
Also, right now it's on sale.
I'm telling you,
I'm not in the mood to talk to you about this.
If you want to drink something, get it yourself.
I need to use the phone.
How come no one's picking up?
Jia Di wouldn't be in trouble, would she?
Hello?
Hello, General Manager.
I am Jia Di's mom.
Is Jia Di with you?
Auntie,
Jia Di is not here.
I thought she was resting at home,
but when I came back
she wasn't here.
Yesterday, Huo Da hurt her so badly,
where would she go?
I called her cellphone just now,
but she didn't pick up.
Then... I know she's a very earnest child,
so she won't do silly things,
but... I'm still very worried.
Auntie,
I think I know where Jia Di is.
Mr. Huo,
have you been sleeping well lately?
Not that well.
Not that well. Okay.
What about eating? Normal?
I don't have much of an appetite.
Wear it.
Don't catch a cold.
Auntie is very worried about you.
She told me to find you.
Don't forget.
There are still a lot of people
who will be sad if you get hurt.
They don't seem to be back yet.
I want to stay here and wait for them to come back.
I want to know why he changed so drastically.
You may see things
that might make you even sadder.
At least I can work harder, right?
Maybe we just didn't have a good talk.
Or maybe he has something to tell me,
but I spent too much time arguing with him.
So I didn't give him a chance to talk.
At least like this,
I won't have to face a crying Ah Xin.
She gets more annoying by the minute.
I've tolerated enough of
her childlike behaviour!
Don't wait anymore.
I'll take you back.
I want to wait for him.
Based on Huo Da's personality,
if he doesn't want to turn back,
I'm scared that you'll be hurt even deeper.
You're scared that the Devil will think that I'm too scared to stand up,
will use an even more despicable attitude towards me,
and push me away, right?
Actually, I know
that if he speaks one more harsh sentence
I won't be able to take it.
But in my heart,
there has always been a voice
telling me
that when the Devil's very harsh on the outside,
it means that his heart is at its most vulnerable.
Since you know that you could
be hurt until you can hurt no more,
and becoming shriveled up and blank space,
you won't give up?
All I really wanna know is why.
I just want to know why.
Even if he doesn't return to me,
it's all right.
I know that you'll get hurt,
but is watching you get hurt the only thing I can do?
Is my character's position only like that?
Exchange coupon for a 'Gold Fist.'
If one day, Jia Di gets tired,
you can exchange with the 10th Guy.
Exchange what?
Now that his fist has recovered,
his hands are strong,
he can exchange with you, 'Heaven-sent hands.'
I have said before
that every part of me will believe in you.
Even if you hurt deeper,
you'll be able to bring yourself up again.
But don't just depend on one person,
I have my 'Gold Fist' that will also support you.
10th Guy,
thank you.
I'm so lucky to have you as my friend.
Miss Yan Shu!
Please let me see Huo Da.
No way.
I won't let you see Huo Da anymore.
Since he has chosen me already,
I don't want to be by myself.
Jia Di.
Don't wish me happiness,
but please face reality.
Don't come anymore.
Don't be like this.
Why are you still angry with me?
Isn't this the ending you want?
I'm not like you.
I rather see her happy
than force her to stay by my side.
Whatever.
Come back tomorrow.
Jia Di,
if you continue, you won't be able to take it.
You think your determination
can break through his steel heart?
I believe that one day, he'll soften.
Yang Yan Shu,
don't think of anything else.
You can only be be Huo Da's accompaniment.
When things get cleared up,
you and Huo Da
probably will have lost our loved ones.
Even if it turns out like that,
you can't weaver.
Sister-in-law, this insurance...
How come General Manager
hasn't brought Jia Di back yet?
It's been so long already.
Sister-in-law,
isn't Jia Di dating that second young master?
How come she's with that General Manager?
Who's with who?!
It's because the Devil had a change of heart
and went back to Yang Yan Shu again.
It's better this way!
What's so good about that?
It is good!
Look, no matter who Jia Di chooses
she has to choose the General Manager
and not a sick person!
Sick?
Hello, Auntie.
Sorry,
I can't convince Jia Di to go home.
Please let me talk with Jia Di.
Jia Di,
your mom is asking for you.
Mom,
I know what I'm doing is very stubborn,
but please don't stop me.
Jia Di,
don't wait anymore.
You won't be able to see him.
He's sick.
He has Wilson's Disease...
Jia Di!
If there's another person who's always in my heart, how can I continue dating you?
Even if I do have a future wife in my heart
It won't be Taiwan Ah Xin.
I can't do it.
Everything that happened today has been a joke.
To prevent hurting Jia Di,
I definitely cannot marry her.
Because since beginning, the one that I love most is you Yan Shu.
I want to be with you.
I want to be with you in your most dangerous moments.
In your darkest moments,
I want to be with you waiting for daylight.
Devil
I saw him in so much pain.
It was only a nightmare,
don't be afraid.
He must be really scared all alone.
Hello?
Really, you've found the Devil?!
Okay, got it!
Mom!
The General Manager said that he found the Devil.
I have to go find him quickly.
Jia Di,
he must of had his reasons for not telling you he was sick.
He's afraid of seeing you sad.
I know I'll definitely be really sad, but...
You don't understand.
You don't know how much that kind of sadness hurts.
When your father was sick in hospital,
I also thought I was really strong and really brave.
But then I realized that
I was more and more afraid of walking into the ward.
I was afraid of seeing him get thinner and thinner.
Seeing him talk less and less.
I was afraid of seeing him getting closer and closer to death.
Getting further and further away from me.
So I won't stop you from going to see him,
but you must be prepared.
A person doesn't fight a disease alone,
he does it with all those who love him.
If you want to see him,
you must be stronger than him.
I will be very strong.
Mom.
Huo Yan.
Yan Shu,
when you were little, you used to help Huo Da cover up everything.
Helping him write repentence letters.
Pretending to be his parent and calling the school when he got in trouble.
It's not like I didn't know.
But this,
how could you hide it from everyone,
and help him lie to us?
Don't blame Yan Shu.
It's because of me that everyone hates her now.
It's all my fault.
It was me who asked her to bear these grievances.
I'll leave now.
You two can talk.
You're a General Manager, but do you want to become a Private Investigator instead?
Don't laugh.
You mean you want me to cry?
Hiding your disease, lying to everyone.
Don't laugh.
Please don't tell Jia Di.
So this is the way you protect her?
I'm not that great, I just don't feel like...
seeing her cry.
Then there's no problem.
No problem?
She's Tong Jia Di,
the bravest girl.
Have you forgotten?
The first time you met, she was willing to believe in you,
and risked her life to help you finish that stunt.
Don't worry about her.
She won't cry.
You picked an exchange coupon to give her happiness.
You can't be so unreliable.
Giving her happiness
is your responsibility!
I can't give it to her.
Even until the day I die,
I can't make her happy.
The one who's going to die isn't you.
Of course you can say it so easily!
Go give her happiness.
Go love her.
Go.
I asked you to go love her.
Don't let her go through so much pain for me.
Listen...
When you were cruel to her,
she didn't give up on you.
She still chose to believe in you.
Where did your courage go?
Are you the type to just give up?
Listen to me.
If you really love her, then for her sake, you must live on.
Yan Shu,
I'm sorry
and...
thank you.
I was only helping Huo Da
to get Jia Di to give up on him,
to let him not have any last regrets,
and willingly stay in the hospital for treatment.
I didn't want to hide it from you and Uncle Huo.
I'm sorry,
I blamed you wrongly
and said those things to you.
All the grievances in face of death are nothing.
I just hope that Huo Da will live.
He definitely will.
We have to believe.
With you here to face it with me,
of course I can believe.
Actually,
I really wanted to tell you the truth.
Especially after seeing Jia Di waiting outside my house.
Jia Di already knows about Huo Da's illness.
A person doesn't fight a disease alone,
he does it with all those who love him.
If you want to see him,
you must be stronger than him.
I'm so happy that God gave me this chance to let me have what I wanted.
I didn't want to leave you with pain.
What right do you have to make that decision by yourself?
It was you who barged into my circle.
I always let you do what you wanted,
but only this time I won't let you.
I'm probably going to die.
You don't have to die.
I will!
Everybody will die.
There are a lot of people who have already left us.
My dad,
your mom,
Auntie Qin,
but their love won't leave us.
So, even if you're going to die, you can't push me away.
In this world there are so many unexpected deaths.
I don't want us to lose the chance to love each other because of fear.
I don't want to lose you.
Then live on.
I will live.
I will.
Me too.
Every minute and every second, I will do my best to live on.
Dad...
Why am I stuck here?
Why am I not at the racing grounds,
not in school, not at the Huo departmental store.
Why am I here?
Everyday it feels like I'm waiting to die.
You're waiting to recover.
Only now do I know
why my dad is always angry with me.
Why, whenever Huo Yan sees me, he will lecture me.
Why?
The person I used to be
was really too wasteful.
I always thought that
I still had
a lot of time ahead of me to waste.
But now, without expecting it,
in a moment, I suddenly seem to have
no more time left.
You finally realized
one of the three biggest sins in my life is to waste.
Don't worry,
you've already confessed,
Heaven will forgive you.
He'll give me another chance, right?
All my wastefulness in the past,
He will fix it.
Right?
Definitely.
Your son has Wilson's Disease.
His liver is about to die from the damage,
and we still can't find a donor.
So his life will most likely be in danger.
I hope you understand.
What happened?
One who falls sick should be around my age.
Why is it my son?
Why is it like this?
Director.
You...
How do you feel?
Don't be scared.
I will get you the best doctors.
If this hospital isn't good enough, I will have someone find another one.
We'll definitely find the best hospital and doctors.
Here is great.
No matter how much money we spend,
we have to save him.
I know.
What else...
What else can I do?
Dad...
I'll do whatever needs to be done.
Don't worry.
Of course I'm worried.
My son is sick, yet I can't do anything.
So what if I'm Huo Zheng Hao?
So what if I'm a force to be reckoned with in business?
In the end, I'm still a helpless father.
Dad,
I read...
mom's diary.
She said...
She loved you.
So
giving birth to me
was mom's greatest satisfaction.
For that reason alone, it's worth it to live on for her.
It's me.
I didn't take care of your mother's well being.
I was mom's greatest satisfaction.
But...
my contributions to you are so bad.
I forced you to retreat,
gave you high blood pressure,
embarrassed you,
lost you money,
that...
...was all me.
The one who helped you earn money,
who gave you pride,
I also feel so thankful for you.
Good thing...
you brought Huo Yan back.
That
was all done by him.
It doesn't matter if there's Huo Yan,
my expectations for you are the same.
But you...
I only know how to make you angry.
I'm angry,
but I can't truly be angry at you because...
I know
I let your mother down.
And all my actions,
without fail,
remind you of that fact.
Yes.
So...
So I don't know
how to face you.
Dad...
Even though we think differently,
your willingness to say it
makes me very happy.
At least,
in your world,
I'm not just the empty air.
You are my son.
Huo Yan too.
You both are.
I cannot lose either of you.
I promised your mom...
To leave the best for you.
Dad...
Thank you.
Mom,
next time I go to the hospital, I'll be back late.
Go to bed, don't wait up for me.
Don't worry about me.
Is Xiao Da okay?
I believe he'll get better.
I believe he'll get better too.
So you were acting mean on purpose?
Devil,
why are you so pitiful?
So, all along,
we've been wrongly accusing you?
And I also said all of those words, cursing you to the eighteenth level of hell.
I didn't mean it!
Devil,
your love for Jia Di is really too great!
I'm really touched.
You're too exaggerated.
Could you please not tell Bo Zi and the rest?
Why?
Bo Zi said that he wanted to cut all ties with you.
I'm going to go tell him right now.
I don't want to let this affect them.
I don't know if it's right to say this, but I feel since there's a problem,
why don't you explain it clearly to everyone?
The Devil just left like that. He really isn't a good friend.
Stop talking about that person!
From now on, we aren't brother's anymore!
Bo Zi...
I just can't stand the way he treats Good Family's Virgin Girl. It's really low.
I forbid you to talk about him like that.
What?
Aren't you unhappy with him too?
Bo Zi...
I don't want to hide it from you guys anymore.
The Devil...
He's about to die.
What?
I want to donate my liver!
Me too!
Big mouth.
Devil,
you're sick? Why didn't you tell us?
Aren't we brothers?
You're so selfish!
Really a bastard!
Keeping secrets?!
Being that kind of friend really pains us.
Yeah! Aren't your problems our problems?
What is it with not telling us anything?
Letting us misunderstand you, does it feel really good?
You're too noisy!
Stop nagging!
Now we're together, listen to me.
I want to donate my liver!
I want to donate too!
We know how you feel,
but a liver transplant
can only be from a relative.
What relatives?!
He's my brother!
Why can't I donate?
Stop crying you little girl!
The situation now is very depressing.
His liver is just about to fail from the damage.
You mean...
If we still can't get a liver, the patient will be in serious danger.
I hope you are prepared.
The situation now is very depressing.
His liver is just about to fail from the damage.
You mean...
If we still can't get a liver,
the patient will be in serious danger.
I hope you are prepared.
Jia Di,
don't be discouraged.
I'm not discouraged.
I still have a lot of things to do.
Please...
One will do... just one.
Good, thanks.
Even in the hospital
Jia Di still uses her Taiwan Ah Xin spirit
to try her best and not let Huo Da lose his fighting spirit against the illness.
Only she knows how to pass through Huo Da's walls.
Uglier, okay?
It's to make him laugh.
One, Two, Three.
Thanks!
Director,
I am Tong Jia Di.
Is that really my dad?
He always has a poker face,
but to make you happy
he's done such an embarrassing thing.
Huo Yan has told me about what's going on between you and him.
I know
I don't live up to the expectations the Director has in his heart,
but
I really want to thank you for allowing me to be with Huo Da.
Thank you for taking care of Huo Da
as well as Yue Hua
and Huo Yan.
Chairman,
it's something
that is totally unsuitable for your status and position,
but
it will make Huo Da happy.
Will you try it once?
I never thought that my dad
would actually have some talent for making faces.
Next time when you miss everyone
and feel bored in the hospital,
you can look at the photographs.
Then you won't be so lonely.
Taiwan Ah Xin,
thank you.
Do you know
how much I miss everyone
while I'm in the hospital?
I miss the days
when I could fool around with everyone.
How do you feel today?
It feels worse and worse everyday.
When I open my eyes in the morning
I rejoice...
because Heaven has let me live one more day.
Don't say such disheartening words.
Yan Shu,
all along you're the most practical
and the most calm.
Everyone who knows I'm sick says
now that medicine is so advanced
and I'm so young,
I'll definitely be able to make it.
Everyone seems to have been hypnotised
saying the same words.
Now it seems like
I'm the only one accepting reality.
I could be dead tomorrow,
but no one wants to say it.
Jia Di has done so much
for me.
The more she does now
shows
how much
she is unable to face reality.
She has confidence in you.
This body is mine.
I clearly understand.
Now all I think about
is how to
lessen the sadness
after I leave.
Though at that time,
I won't be able to see her anymore.
But
once I think about her impending pain,
I already...
feel really heartbroken.
No matter what answer God gives you...
I'll be fine.
Just obediently go for your treatment,
what's the use of caring about other things?
You don't have to worry about me at all.
Have you forgotten
that I am the undefeatable Tong Jia Di?
I'll be going back now.
I'll go after her.
Let her go.
She wants to cry.
She needs to vent her emotions.
In front of me
she keeps acting strong.
She's already under so much pressure.
I don't want her to suppress herself,
but to thoroughly and freely cry.
Jia Di!
Even though he walks towards life's end,
to be able to have a love like this,
I still envy Huo Da.
Did you go do
the test for the liver transplant?
You can't.
You know you aren't suitable for it.
The results aren't out yet.
For all you know I have Hepatitis B.
You don't have to wait for the results.
You have to promise me now
that you definitely will not do
the liver transplant operation.
Other than dad,
I am the only one who is a family member.
So what?
Your heart
cannot take the stress of the transplant operation.
Yan Shu,
we all know
that Huo Da doesn't have time to wait.
This
seems to be Jia Di's old house.
We really have to be thieves?
The Devil asked us to.
It really wasn't anything good.
I'm very useless.
If I remember correctly,
Jia Di said,
at that time,
she and her dad
hid it under the big tree in the garden.
There's a guard dog inside!
It's a dog...
There are thieves!
Don't bite me...
Help!
Mr Huo,
after doing the match test,
you are the only one suitable
to do the liver transplant.
However,
I don't recommend that you do the operation.
I think you know very clearly
that you have a history of heart problems,
and unsuitable for organ donation operations.
Your body
must be able to handle the extraction of your liver.
The risk is too great.
When your whole body is put under anaesthesia
during the operation,
once your heart stops
or other side effects happen,
your life will be in danger.
I am willing to sign that I have understood
and will bear all medical risks,
as well as all the legal responsibilties.
As long as I can save him.
Doctor,
can we have the operation as soon as possible?
Mr. Huo,
I request you wait another 3 days.
If during that time
another donor appears,
then you don't have to risk your life.
After all, this is an operation
that the hospital should not be undertaking.
Dad,
I have already persuaded the doctor
to let me help Huo Da
and go for the liver transplant.
This operation
is as good as you risking your life.
If the operation is not successful,
please don't blame the operating team.
They have already tried their best.
I asked them to use my liver,
but they said that I was too old
and contracted Hepatitis before.
I couldn't be the donor.
I know.
The both of us want to save Huo Da,
but if the operation isn't done soon
there won't be enough time.
I can't let you go.
But I...
I can't let you not go.
I will do my best
to force myself to live on.
But if it really is not successful,
I have something
I should say to you first.
Dad,
thank you for taking care of me.
God,
it's my fault.
I let their mothers down.
If there was retribution,
it should be put on me.
Why
do you have to let both my sons suffer?
Does this mean that
I have to use one son
in exchange for the other?
Devil,
what do you want the box for?
Because Taiwan Ah Xin told me
this was the agreement between her father and her.
This box of secrets
was supposed to be
for her future boyfriend.
I'll tell you something,
I have an old box at home.
It contains all my secrets.
What secrets?
I can't say!
My dad said,
only when I meet someone I like
can I open the box to let him know.
I'm afraid that, in the future,
I wouldn't have a chance to see it.
So...
I had to ask you to become thieves.
Sorry.
Don't talk rubbish!
I don't want to give this privilege
to anyone else.
Thank you
for fulfilling my wish.
Thank you.
Uncle Tong,
I am Jia Di's boyfriend.
But...
I'm afraid that I won't be able
to give Jia Di happiness.
I'm unable to replace you
by continuing to cherish and love her.
Thank you
for leaving behind these precious memories.
Allowing me to love
the Jia Di in the past,
which I was unable to be a part of.
The future Jia Di
is still the same.
Really kind,
very strong.
Even her faces
are still the same as when she was little.
Really cute.
Uncle Tong,
do you also want to see
Jia Di in a wedding gown?
Jia Di, as a mom?
Those moments...
for all I know, I'll be seeing them
in Heaven with you.
Let's write down
things that we want to exchange.
After 10 years, we'll meet here again
and see each other's secret.
This last blank exchange coupon.
What I want to exchange is
to meet you in our next lives.
If there really is a next life...
Jia Di,
you can only exchange it with me.
~Don't get stolen from me~
~Be with me forever~
Jia Di,
no matter what answer
God gives...
I will still be really thankful
that in my wasteful life,
he let me meet you.
I won't be scared.
If...
you leave me first,
I will remember
the stars represent you saying "I love you".
The light breeze is your yearning.
The warmth on my skin from the sun
is that...
you opened your arms to embrace me.
Mr. Huo Da,
we have already arranged
for you to do the organ transplant.
Really?
I finally got one after waiting?
Who is it?
It's your brother.
Mr. Huo Da,
we have already arranged
for you to do the organ transplant.
Really?
I finally got one after waiting?
Who is it?
It's your brother.
Mr. Huo Yan
agreed today
to the liver transplant operation.
I refuse.
I know you hate me,
but no matter what reason do you have...
you have to listen to me this time.
I DON'T WANT TO!
You don't have time to wait anymore.
Stop talking nonsense!
I don't need you to make
such a huge sacrifice for me.
You want me to watch you die
as a bystander, doing nothing?
If it was you, would you be able to do it?
For me,
you are doing this at the risk of your life.
If you die,
because you wanted to save me?
Is it worth it?
It's worth it.
So what does that mean?
You want me to live the rest of my life
in guilt that I caused your death?
Using your life in exchange for mine,
then I'd rather die!
I am the only person on this earth
with the power
and the capability to give you a liver.
This also proves one point
that on this earth,
I am your brother.
We are family
joined by the blood running through our veins.
This sort of blood relation
is something no one can replace.
You can't deny that.
You are my brother.
I want to save you.
Even if I have to give up everything, I will still do it.
I'm actually not
afraid of owing my life to you.
If it's between the both of us
and only one can live,
I hope it's you.
Even though
I really don't want to admit it,
I really
admire you a lot.
So you should believe
that my decision is right even more now.
No way.
I must do this.
I have to do this.
So...
Leave the outcome to fate.
Just promise me,
if only one can live between us,
the one who survives
must live for the both of us.
And together
live a full life.
Brother...
The operation is tomorrow.
Don't get snatched away from me.
You must get better.
Unless I get possessed by a pig,
I will never,
in my whole life, like a guy like you.
Huo Yan, you...
Don't worry.
I've never done anything for my brother.
To be able to use a part of my body
to save his life,
it's worth it.
You must hang on.
I'll pray for the safety of both of you.
We will live on together.
Miss Yan Shu,
Huo Da will be fine.
That's why I'm more worried about Huo Yan.
What do you mean, I don't understand.
Huo Yan has had heart problems since he was young.
You have to be under total anaesthesia.
If his heart stops during the operation,
his life will be in danger.
Doctor Chen.
There are some pacts
that seem as though they have been burned into life with gold.
They make one perservere for the rest of their lives.
My pact with the Devil was for 10 years.
But...
Maybe I was influenced too deeply by him.
In my mind,
the thought of breaking that pact kept appearing.
Even though the time is not right,
but I really want to know
what was the secret was
that he left for me.
Taiwan Ah Xin,
even if you haven't dated before,
you should have watched romance films.
At this point, the female lead
should already be running up
to hug the male lead.
Life is a period where you use your own life
to meet other's.
By meeting the Devil,
my life was never the same again.
It's impossible for me to only be in my circle,
because in everyone's story,
there's also someone else's story.
Taiwan Ah Xin and Devil's story
is also Bo Zi and Xiao Nan's...
Stupid Bo Zi!
What are you doing?
Don't run away!
Sorry!
Stop there!
What are you doing?
Help!
- Don't run away!
- Another beautiful circle.
Their lives' stories
are each launching into a new journey.
This place is your favourite
in all of Taipei.
I don't know when,
but it also became mine.
In the past,
the Huo Family as well as the Huo Department Store
were like a prison made of gold
in my eyes.
I only saw it locking me in
and never saw its beauty.
It's you who reminded me
it's your own knot that untied.
People always like going after what they don't have.
Once I finish my studies,
I must really relax.
Once my business is up and running,
I must go out of the country for a holiday
to enjoy myself, and broaden my horizons.
Once I earn money,
I must be fillial to my parents
and let them have many good days.
Once I buy a house,
I will stop my hurried pace
and enjoy life.
And what I said was,
once I leave this family,
I will find my true self.
That idea was really stupid.
In the past, I thought
the one who was wasting life was Huo Da,
but actually it was me.
Good thing you came out of the operation unscathed.
Now we don't have to wait until
our lives are perfect
to know how to enjoy the best things in it.
Because it's not in the distance,
but in what you already have
and how you cherish it.
Then I'll be leaving now.
The beautiful and strong Yan Shu,
you'll definitely be able to find
the happiness you deserve to cherish and possess.
This time it is really goodbye.
Huo Yan,
everything I once gave to you
are the happiest times in my life.
Mom,
why didn't you call me to tell me when you were going to set up?
There's no need.
Didn't I say that I was on leave today?
I'll do it...
You don't have to wait until life is perfect
to enjoy the sweet things in life.
If your closest family is able
to be united,
support each other,
and face difficulties together,
that is the warmest moment.
Didn't we say that only after 10 years
would we open the box?
I didn't mean to sneak a peek!
What did you write inside?
Why are you still standing there?
Chase after it, it's my secret!
Secret!
Come back!
Jump a bit higher, I can't reach it!
Secret!
It's there!
Here!
It's here!
My secret!
Spring is aproaching us slowly.
I start to imagine the feeling of happiness.
In the field in front of the merry go round.
Love starts to blossom.
Thinking of you, I become breathless.
My lips curl into a smile unknowingly.
Are these the symptoms of blissfulness?
I become breathless, again.
Dreams that cannot be moved.
Even if there is no applause, I won't be hurt.
I won't let go of my belief.
My heart pumps furiously when I'm next to you.
Thinking of you, I become breathless.
My lips curl into a smile unknowingly.
Are these the symptoms of blissfulness?
My heart starts to pound.
I become breathless, again.
Thanks for watching the show!