Ghosts are real.
This much I know.
The first time I saw one,
I was 10 years old.
It was my mother's.
Black cholera had taken her.
So, father ordered
a closed casket,
asked me not to look.
There were to be
no parting kisses.
No good-byes.
And the lord said unto me,
- no last words.
- "Take thy place beside me."
That is, until the night
she came back.
My child.
When the time comes,
beware of crimson peak.
It would be years
before I again
heard such a voice...
Or understood
its desperate warning.
A warning
from out of time...
And one that
I came to understand
only when it was too late.
Barley mead and ale!
I got sweet and bitter!
Apple, sir?
Straight out of the oven
this morning!
Edith.
Alan.
When did you get back?
Two weeks ago.
I thought
eunice had told you.
No, I ha--
i hadn't heard.
Oh. She made
a conquest in London.
What are you
doing here?
I'm setting up
my practice upstairs.
I'm to meet Ogilvie
at 10:00
to see if he wants
to publish my manuscript.
- You do know it's only 9:00.
- I know, but I couldn't
wait any longer.
And I want to make
some corrections
anyway, so--
if you have any free time,
please come and visit.
We met him at the
British museum last fall
when we were visiting Alan.
- Mother.
- You wouldn't believe it.
He's so handsome.
And he has crossed
the ocean with his sister,
only to see eunice again.
Mother,
he's here on business.
It seems
he's a baronet.
What's a baronet?
Well, an aristocrat
of some sort.
A man
that feeds off land
that others work for him.
A parasite with a title.
This parasite
is perfectly charming,
and a magnificent dancer.
Although that
wouldn't concern you,
would it, Edith?
Our very own
Jane Austen.
- Though she died
a spinster, no?
- Mother, please.
That's all right.
Actually, Mrs. mcmichael,
I would prefer
to be Mary shelley.
She died a widow.
Alan.
Ah, miss cushing.
You're early.
Just a little.
A ghost story.
Your father
didn't tell me
it was a ghost story.
Oh. It's-- it's not.
It's more a story
with a ghost in it.
Mm-hmm.
The ghost
is just a metaphor.
A metaphor?
For the past.
Well,
lovely handwriting.
Nice, confident loops.
Miss cushing,
may I offer
a word of advice?
He told me
it needed a love story.
Can you believe that?
Ogilvie's old-fashioned.
He said that just
because I'm a woman.
Everyone falls in love, dear,
even women.
I don't want to write
a love story like that.
Well, my darling,
i was hoping to make this
a celebratory gift.
I'm a builder, dear.
If there's
one thing I know,
it's the importance
of the right tool
for the job.
It's beautiful.
But actually, father,
i was hoping to type it,
in your office.
Type it?
I'm submitting it to
the Atlantic monthly,
but I realize now
that my handwriting
is too feminine.
It gives me away.
Without a doubt.
But what you must appreciate
is the way that the molding
is incorporated into
the overall design
of the clock.
It'll take me all day,
but it does make it
look rather handsome,
don't you think?
Yes.
Good morning, miss.
Forgive the interruption.
I have an appointment
with Mr. Carter
Everett cushing.
- Goodness.
With the great man himself.
- I'm afraid so.
"Sir Thomas sharpe,
baronet."
He'll be here shortly.
Thank you.
You're not late,
are you?
He hates that.
Uh, not at all.
In fact,
I'm a little early.
Oh, I'm afraid
he hates that too.
I'm sorry.
I don't mean to pry,
but, uh,
this is a piece of fiction,
is it not?
Yes.
Who are you
transcribing this for?
It's to be sent
to New York tomorrow,
to the Atlantic monthly.
Well, whoever wrote it
it's, um,
rather good,
don't you think?
Really?
It certainly
captured my attention.
I wrote it.
It's mine.
Ghosts?
Well, the ghosts
are just a metaphor.
Really--
they've always
fascinated me.
You see,
where I come from,
ghosts are not
to be taken lightly.
Sir Thomas sharpe.
Welcome to
our fair city.
Sir.
It's my pleasure.
I see you've already met
my daughter Edith.
The sharpe Clay mines
have been royal purveyors
of the purest Scarlet Clay
since 1796.
In its liquid form,
it is so rich in ore
and so malleable
that it can produce
the strongest bricks
and tiles.
Excessive mining
in the last 20 years
has caused most
of our old deposits
to collapse.
This is a Clay harvester
of my own design.
It transports
the Clay upwards
as it digs deep.
I have absolutely
no doubt
this machine will
revolutionize Clay mining
as we know it.
Turn it off, please.
Have you tested it?
Full-scale?
Not yet, sir.
We're very close.
But we hope that with funding--
so actually,
what you have is a toy
and some fancy words.
Mr. cushing, i--
you've already tried
and failed
to raise capital
in London,
Edinburgh, Milan--
yes, that's
correct, sir.
And now you're here.
Correct again, sir.
The men at this table,
all of us,
came up through honest,
hard work.
Well, maybe not all of us.
Mr. ferguson here is a lawyer.
But even
he can't help that.
I started
as a steel worker,
raising buildings
before I could own them.
My hands, feel them.
Rough.
The reflection of who I am.
Now, you, sir,
when I shook your hand--
you've got
the softest hands
I've ever felt.
In America
we bank on effort,
not privilege.
That is how we built
this country.
I'm here with all
that I possess, sir.
A name, a patch of land
and the will to make it yield.
The least
that you can Grant me
is the courtesy of your time
and the chance to prove
to you and these fine gentlemen
that my will, dear sir,
is at the very least
as strong as yours.
I need a corset.
No, you don't.
You look very handsome.
Do I?
Yes, you do, young man.
I do wish
you'd change your mind
and come along tonight.
Mrs. mcmichael has gone
to a lot of trouble.
Little lord fauntleroy
will be there.
You mean Thomas sharpe?
Sir Thomas sharpe,
baronet.
Apparently, he's taken
an interest in young eunice.
I saw you spying
on us, child.
Was his proposal
so outrageous
as to merit such
a harsh answer from you?
It wasn't his proposal,
my love.
It was him.
There's something about him
that I don't like.
What, I don't know.
And I don't like
not knowing.
What I saw was
a dreamer facing defeat.
Did you see his suit?
It was beautifully tailored,
but at least a decade old.
I can see
that you observed
far more than I did.
And his shoes
were handmade, but worn.
That'll be
young Dr. mcmichael.
He's brought
his new motorcar
to collect me.
Come and see it.
Say hello to him.
He's just opened
his new practice.
And he's always been
awfully fond of you.
Shh.
I know that, father.
Good evening, Marie.
Good evening,
Dr. mcmichael.
Mr. cushing.
Alan.
Hello, Edith.
My, don't we
look smart, Alan.
Oh. It's just something
i threw together.
It's Edith
who should be the belle
of the ball this evening.
Don't you agree, Alan?
As I recall,
Edith takes a dim view
of social frivolity.
You lads
enjoy the party.
Don't let him drink
too much.
Hey.
So, she's not coming.
Stubborn
to the bone.
Where does
she get that from?
I'm not complaining.
I like it.
"Allerdale hall."
Father, did you
forget something?
What is it?
What do you want?
Beware
of crimson peak.
Excuse me, miss.
Are you
all right, miss?
Whatever is it?
Please help me up.
There's a sir Thomas sharpe
at the door.
Thomas sharpe?
He's dripping wet
and most insistent
on coming in.
Well, that's absolutely
out of the question, Annie.
Please, just tell him
to go away.
I tried.
And?
He wants to talk to you.
Miss cushing.
Are you all right?
You seem a little pale.
I'm not all too well,
sir Thomas, I'm afraid.
Father isn't home.
Oh, I know.
I, uh-- I waited in the rain
for him to leave.
Oh.
I know he's going
to the reception
at the mcmichael house,
uh, which is
my destination too.
But that's
in bidwell parkway, sir.
This is masten park.
You're very, very lost.
That I am.
And I desperately need
your help.
My help with what?
Miss cushing, the language,
for one thing.
As you can plainly see,
i do not speak a word
of American.
Tell me, why would you
want to stay here?
All alone.
Alan, this is
sir Thomas sharpe.
Sir Thomas,
Dr. Alan mcmichael.
Best man in town
if you're
feeling poorly.
I've heard so much about you
from mother and my sister.
Although, I must confess,
i had a little trouble
understanding your title.
- Baronet?
- Edith kindly
explained it to me.
Edith, this is
lady Lucille sharpe.
My sister.
I'm delighted
to meet you, miss cushing.
You've managed to delay
my brother quite a bit.
Now's the time.
Poor eunice
was growing desperate.
She claims
no gentleman in America knows
how to dance a proper waltz.
Come with me.
Interesting development,
don't you think?
Indeed.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please make some space.
The baronet would like
to demonstrate for us
the waltz.
European style.
Mrs. mcmichael,
i wanted to apologize.
Edith,
we weren't expecting you.
I know.
And I'm sure there's
no place for me--
don't worry, my child.
Everybody has their place.
I'll make sure
you find yours.
The waltz.
Not a complicated dance,
really.
The lady takes her place
slightly to the left
of the leading gentleman.
Six basic steps,
and that's all.
However, it is said
that the true test
of the perfect waltz
is for it to be so swift,
so delicate and so smooth
that a candle flame
will not be extinguished
in the hand of the lead dancer.
Now, that requires...
The perfect partner.
Would you be mine?
I don't think so.
Thank you.
But I'm sure eunice
would be delighted.
I daresay.
But I have asked you.
Why are we doing this?
I've always closed
my eyes to things
that made me uncomfortable.
It makes
everything easier.
I don't want
to close my eyes.
I want to keep them open.
Mr. Holly.
Mr. cushing.
I like the club
the first thing in the morning.
I have it all to myself.
A great way
to start the day, sir.
There's a young gentleman
and his sister
I want you
to investigate for me.
Something not quite right
about them.
I want results
as soon as possible.
You have not been using
the drops regularly.
Edith, come in.
And I must insist
you do so.
Take this to the druggist
and ask him
to prepare it exactly.
And resume the dose.
Toxicology of the eye.
Morphology of the optic nerve.
Principles
of optical refraction.
And Arthur conan Doyle.
Fancy yourself
a detective?
Well, not really,
but he is an ophthalmologist
just like me.
Come. I think you're gonna like
what I have to show you.
Ghost photography
is easy to fake.
However, with glass plates,
it is, by definition,
impossible.
I got these in London.
They're genuine.
The image is captured using
a coating of silver salts,
invisible to the naked eye.
It's called a latent image.
Now, it's my belief
that houses, places,
be it by chemical compound
in the earth
or the minerals
in the stone,
can retain impressions
or a person
that is no longer living.
But not everyone
can see them.
The man that just left,
amongst other ailments,
is color-blind.
Now, that man
will never perceive
the colors red or green.
He only accepts
their existence
because the majority
around him does.
Perhaps we
only notice things
when the time comes
for us to see them.
You've never spoken to me
about these interests
of yours, Alan.
You've never given me
the chance.
Edith, I understand
your fascination
with the sharpes,
but in your own best interest,
proceed with caution
is all I ask.
You've been gone
a long time and, well,
I've managed somewhat.
No, Edith,
I think
every time I read it,
it gets better and better.
And I don't mind
the love story at all.
Just a chapter or two.
Well, I like it.
Let me know
what you think.
I'll finish it now.
Is it a butterfly?
No.
But it
will be soon.
Oh, I hadn't seen them.
They're dying.
They take their heat
from the sun,
and when it deserts them,
they die.
That's sad.
No, it's not sad, Edith.
It's nature.
It's a savage world
of things dying
or eating each other
right beneath our feet.
Surely there's more
to it than that.
Beautiful things
are fragile.
At home, we have
only black moths.
Formidable creatures,
to be sure,
but they lack beauty.
They thrive on the dark
and the cold.
What do they feed on?
Butterflies,
I'm afraid.
Are you sure
about this?
I don't think
she's the right choice.
She's too young.
She's just a child, Thomas.
Lucille,
I've explained all this.
I will need the ring.
The ring's mine.
I earned it.
I will want it back.
Then you'd better hope
I'm successful.
This is the last thing
we have to sell.
You're not selling it.
We...
Are buying something
with it.
Mr. Holly.
Is something the matter?
Mr. cushing.
It is not often
that I am the bearer
of bad news,
but when I am, I insist
upon delivering it myself.
Don't open it here.
Now is the time.
Edith,
may I have a word?
Just one moment.
Let me get my father.
Father.
Everybody's waiting.
I'll be there shortly.
Miss cushing.
Edith.
I really have no right
to ask this, but, uh--
sir Thomas.
May I speak with you
in my study, please?
You and your sister,
if you would be so kind
as to fetch her.
Child, please tell our guests
that we will join them
presently.
Now, lady Lucille.
Sir Thomas,
the first time we met,
I imagine it was hard
for you to realize
that I didn't like you.
You made
that clear enough, sir,
but I had hoped
that now with time--
your time,
sir Thomas, is up.
Could you speak plainly,
Mr. cushing?
Plain I will be, missy.
Plainer than you
might like to hear.
In the past few days,
your brother
has deemed it fine enough
to mix business with pleasure
by repeatedly engaging
socially with my daughter.
My only daughter.
Sir, I'm aware that I have
no position to offer,
but the fact is--
you are falling in love
with her.
Is that it?
You play the part well.
The other day,
my daughter asked me
why I didn't like you.
Honestly, at the time,
i had no good answer.
But now I do.
That document there
gave me my answer.
That's the first
honest reaction
I've seen from you.
- Does she know?
- No.
But I will tell her
if that's what it takes
to send you on your way.
Sir, I know you
will find this
hard to believe--
you love her. I know.
You're repeating
yourself.
Now, you-- you seem to be
the more collected one, dear.
It's overly generous,
i know.
But if you want
that check to clear,
there are two conditions.
There's a train
for New York City leaving
first thing tomorrow morning.
You and your brother
better be on it.
Do we understand
each other?
We do. What is
the second condition?
That concerns
my daughter.
Tonight you must...
Thoroughly break
her heart.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we have
an unexpected announcement.
Sir Thomas.
Thank you, Mr. cushing.
Ladies and gentlemen,
when I first came to America,
my heart was brimming
with a sense of adventure.
Here the future actually
seemed to mean something.
I have found
warmth and friendship
among you all.
But for now, farewell.
May we meet again.
Perhaps
on a different shore.
My sister and i
depart for england
just in time
for the winter.
- To lasting friendship.
Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
Edith.
You're leaving us.
We must
return home immediately
and attend to our interests.
And with nothing
to hold us in America--
i see.
Your novel.
I read the new chapters.
I'll have them delivered
in the morning.
That's very good of you.
Thank you.
- Would you still like
to know my thoughts?
- If we must.
It's absurdly sentimental.
The aches
that you describe
with such earnestness.
The pain, the loss.
You clearly haven't
lived at all.
In fact, you only seem to know
what other writers tell you.
That's enough.
You insist on describing
the torments of love when you
clearly know nothing about them.
I'm not done yet!
What do you dream of?
A kind man?
A pure soul
to be redeemed?
A wounded bird
you can nourish?
Perfection?
Perfection has no place
in love, Edith.
I advise you to return
to your ghosts and fancies.
The sooner, the better.
You know precious little
of the human heart
or love or the pain
that comes with it.
You're nothing
but a spoiled child.
How's the water
today, Benton?
Piping hot.
Just the way you like it, sir.
Very well.
Be kind enough to order me
some ham and eggs.
I'll start with coffee,
if it's hot,
and a sip of port.
Right away, sir.
And the times?
If you'd be so kind.
No. No.
Please.
Miss?
What is it, Annie?
Your manuscript
was delivered this morning
by sir Thomas sharpe,
but I didn't want
to wake you early.
It's all the same, Annie.
Thank you.
Just leave it there.
The letter too?
Yes, the letter too.
Dear Edith.
By the time you read this,
I will be gone.
Your father
made evident to me that in
my present economic condition,
I was not in a position
to provide for you.
And to this I agreed.
Annie!
He also asked me
to break your heart.
My coat!
To take the blame.
And to this I agreed too.
By this time, surely I have
accomplished both tasks.
But know this.
When I can prove
to your father
that all I ask of him
is his consent
and nothing more,
then, and only then,
will I come back for you.
Yours ever, Thomas.
Thomas and Lucille sharpe.
Uh, room 107 and 108.
But-- but wait.
Wait!
Miss! Wait!
Thomas?
Thomas.
Uh, they, uh--
they checked out
this morning, miss,
in time
for the early train.
Are you
all right, miss?
Edith.
Lucille has gone.
Your father
bribed me to leave.
I cannot
leave you, Edith.
In fact, I find myself
thinking of you
even at the most...
Inopportune moments
of the day.
I feel as if a--
a link exists between
your heart and mine.
And should that link
be broken either
by distance or by time,
then my heart
would cease to beat
and I would die.
And you--
you'd soon
forget about me.
Never.
I would never forget you.
I'm afraid you'll have
to identify the body, Edith.
There's no other way.
Wait!
I came
as soon as I heard.
Edith,
don't look at him.
I'll give you
a positive identification.
That is not possible.
I was his
physician, ferguson.
You know that.
And I am his lawyer,
Dr. mcmichael.
I'm sorry.
This is not
a legal formality.
It's obligatory,
I'm afraid.
How did it happen?
Apparently,
he was alone.
The floor was wet.
Uh, no one really knows.
May I, sir?
Help me turn him.
Don't touch him
like that.
Stop!
Don't touch him like that!
That's my father!
Forgive me. I was--
he's turning 60
next week.
He's afraid of looking
his age, you see.
That's why
he dresses so well.
Why he likes
taking long walks.
His hand feels cold.
Why is it so cold?
Shh, shh.
I'm here for you now.
I'm here.
Whoa!
Ah, young
master sharpe.
- Hello, Finlay.
How have you been keeping?
- Never better, sir Thomas.
Finlay,
this is my wife.
I know, my lord. I know.
You've been
married a while.
A while?
What is he talking about?
I'm not sure what
he was talking about.
- His family worked
for ours for centuries.
- Who is this?
You never told me
about him.
- Oh, he has a collar.
Is he a stray, you think?
- That's impossible.
There's no other house
for miles,
and the town's
half a day's walk away.
Oh, the poor thing.
He's famished.
- Can we keep it?
- As you wish.
Now, your ladyship,
may I have the honor?
Take the lady's belongings.
I will grab master's.
Take the horses
for their feed
after we finish here.
Goodness.
How many rooms
are there?
I don't know.
Would you like
to count them?
What do you think?
Does it look
the part?
It does.
Although it's even colder
inside than out.
I know.
It's a disgrace.
We try to maintain
the house
as best we can,
but with the cold
and the rain,
it's impossible to stop
the damp and erosion.
And with the mines
right below,
well, the wood is rotting
and the house is sinking.
- Take it upstairs,
young master?
- Oh, yes, please.
This one goes
to the dressing room.
Let me show you.
But how do you
manage this house?
Just you and Lucille?
It's a privilege
we were born into
and one we can
never relinquish.
But we manage somehow,
my darling.
My workshop's
in the attic.
I can't wait
to show you.
Please, Finlay,
would you take my bags
to the attic?
I'll be up shortly.
Lucille?
Look, these curtains have
been closed for too long.
Would you bring that
over here?
Hey.
Where did you get this?
Thomas, I saw a woman
in the elevator.
A woman?
You mean Lucille?
No, it wasn't Lucille.
Must've been a shadow.
That contraption has
a mind of its own.
The wires are affected
by the damp in the house.
Connects to the Clay pits,
you see.
And never, ever
go below this level.
What's this thing doing here?
Lucille.
Thomas.
- Welcome, Edith.
- Thank you.
Well, I went
to the post office.
Your machine parts
are here
from Birmingham.
You'll need Finlay
to fetch them.
Excellent.
Is something the matter
with you, Edith?
Something startled me,
that's all.
A shadow.
All that lives in
this house are shadows
and creaks and groans.
So you better
soothe that boundless
imagination of yours.
I just need a proper
welcome, that's all.
From now on,
i want this house
to contain
nothing but friendship
and love and warmth.
Warmth would be
an excellent start.
Thomas,
your bride is frozen.
Of course.
Forgive me.
Let's go upstairs,
start a fire at once.
I'll run you
a hot bath.
The pipes
will run red at first
because of the Clay,
but soon
the water will clear.
Oh, Lucille,
when it's convenient,
would you mind
getting me a copy
of the house keys, please?
You don't need one.
I'm sorry?
There are parts of the house
that are unsafe.
It will take you a few days
to familiarize yourself.
Then, should you
still feel you need them,
I'll have copies made.
Come on, Edith.
Come with me.
Let's take you upstairs.
I thought you said
the dog was dead.
I left it out there
on its own.
Thought it would perish
in the cold.
How has it survived
all this time?
On scraps,
i suppose.
As we all do.
Well, you needn't worry.
We won't have
to do that anymore.
Won't we? Her money's
not here, is it?
Not yet.
- You have to trust me.
- You chose her.
Why?
All right.
Okay, ready?
Fetch.
Come on.
To my hand.
Come on. To my hand.
Good boy.
Come on.
Fetch.
Hi. Where's your ball?
Did you
lose your ball? Hi.
Where'd it go?
Hey, where's the ball, eh?
Hi.
This will make you
feel better.
What is it?
Firethorn berries.
They're very good
for you.
You don't like it?
It's a little bitter.
I'm afraid nothing gentle
ever grows in this land.
You need a measure
of bitterness...
Not to be eaten.
What was that?
That's
the east wind.
When it picks up,
the chimneys
form a vacuum,
and with the windows
all shuttered up,
the house--
well,
the house breathes.
It's ghastly,
i know.
Now, come here.
I'll have a bath,
i think.
And if you do happen
to fall asleep,
i won't wake you.
"To the hills
we raise our eyes."
I'm sorry.
I interrupted you.
That music,
what is it?
An old lullaby
i used to sing to Thomas
when we were young.
I can imagine
the two of you in here
as children.
You playing music
and Thomas coming up
with wild inventions.
We were not allowed
in here as children.
We were confined
to the nursery.
In the attic.
Mother played
the piano sometimes.
We'd hear her
through the floor.
That's how we knew
she was back in the country.
Mother.
She looks quite--
horrible?
Yes.
It's an excellent
likeness.
I like to think
she can see us from up there.
I don't want her to miss
a single thing we do.
Are all
of these books yours?
Mother collected
most of these.
Have you heard
of a fore-edge
illustration?
No.
There are images hidden
in the book's fore edge.
Carefully dissimulated
until you bend the pages.
So... secrets
everywhere.
Well, this can't
shock you
now that Thomas
and you--
he was very respectful
of my mourning.
Nothing happened.
We traveled
in separate cabins.
How considerate.
In time,
everything
will be right.
It's a pity
to liquidate
all this so quickly.
So soon.
Too soon,
don't you think?
All a matter
of opinion,
it seems.
I will need
these crates
shipped.
And to make sure
we get our invoice,
you will send them
to me.
"Thomas sharpe,
baronet."
Come on, doggy.
Come on.
Hmm. You like
my workshop, Edith?
It's wonderful.
Did you make
all of these?
I used to carve toys
for Lucille.
And make little trinkets
to keep her happy.
Were you alone
here in the attic
all the time?
Father was
always traveling.
The family fortune
didn't lose itself.
Papa really had
to put his back into it.
It's wonderful.
You're so different.
From who?
From-- from everyone.
What is it?
I thought
i heard a noise.
We were hoping
you were here.
I found him wandering
the hallway.
- Made us some tea.
- Oh, you're too kind.
Don't mention it.
We needed the company.
Thomas?
Uh, not for me,
thank you.
Drink your tea.
It'll warm you.
Thomas.
Thomas?
How did you get in there,
you silly doggy?
Wax cylinder recordings.
No, wait.
Enola.
Keep her steady, Finlay.
Yes, sir.
We need more coal,
Finlay.
Yes.
Thomas! Thomas.
Thomas, listen,
i need to talk to you.
Now's not a good time.
Lucille is inside.
She can show you the house--
i don't want
to talk to Lucille.
I wanna talk to you.
Very well. What is it?
Listen, has anyone died
in this house?
Edith, the house
is hundreds of years old.
I'd venture many souls
have come and gone.
But I mean specific deaths,
violent deaths.
- Master sharpe?
- Now is really not a good time.
Try it again, Finlay!
This way.
There.
Should feel better soon.
My hands are getting rough.
Your father would approve.
My machine will never work.
Never. Why do I keep
deluding myself?
Why did i
bring you here?
Who did you marry?
A failure.
Don't say that.
You're all that I have.
The men leave at nightfall.
We'll be racing
against the snow.
Soon we won't be able
to make any progress.
That's when you'll
find out why they call
this crimson peak.
What did you say?
Crimson peak.
That's what they call it.
The ore in the red Clay
leach up from the ground
and stain the snow.
It turns bright red,
so "crimson peak."
So you asked
to see me.
Perhaps it all
ended for the best.
Edith seems to
have found happiness.
Don't you agree?
I wouldn't know.
I haven't heard a word.
I have.
She has asked me to transfer
all her assets to england.
Seems to be investing all of it
in that Clay machine of his,
and I have no recourse
but to obey.
There's something
about all this, ferguson.
The manner
of cushing's death,
the impact on his head.
The last check cushing made
was to sir Thomas sharpe.
If I may confide.
Before cushing died,
he hired a New York man,
a Mr.-- Mr. Holly.
Now, he digs up
these unsavory facts.
The fact that this Holly
got involved in all this
just gives me pause.
Thomas?
If you're here with me,
give me a signal.
Touch my hand.
Leave here now.
Thomas! Thomas!
Edith.
His blood will be
on your hands.
- Edith!
- Thomas!
Thomas, come quick!
Edith, what's the matter?
A woman in the corridor, there!
There was such a hatred
in her eyes--
and intelligence.
She knows who I am
and she wants me
to leave.
Nonsense, my dear.
You're not going
anywhere.
You had a bad dream.
You were sleepwalking.
No!
I'm afraid I shall go mad
if I stay.
My darling,
you're imagining things.
Tomorrow,
why don't we go out?
Uh, to the post office.
I think some fresh air
will do you good.
No.
I have to leave.
I have to get away
from here.
Edith, this is
your home now.
You have
nowhere else to go.
What is she doing?
How could she know
about mother?
I have no idea.
I haven't told her a thing.
What's she trying to do?
I don't know.
She's in quite a state.
Tomorrow,
I'll go to the depot,
pick up the machine parts
and take her with me.
Let her get some fresh air.
Yes.
Get her out of here.
Once she signs
the final papers,
i want this over with.
This is a valve controller
i had fabricated in Glasgow.
This could make
all the difference.
Think lucky thoughts,
Edith.
The sharpe mines might reopen
if this thing cooperates.
Mr. sharpe?
- Ah, excellent.
- Thank you.
You're lady sharpe, then?
Forgive me, mum,
but there's
a few letters for you.
Two of them
are certified letters
from your solicitor.
Um, and another one
comes all the way
from Milan, Italy.
I don't know anyone in Italy.
Respectfully, your ladyship,
it's apparent that you do.
Edith,
the storm's picking up.
We ought to leave soon.
Otherwise we won't
make it back to the house.
If you need to
stay the night, sir Thomas,
we've a small room downstairs.
Why not?
And you're sure this is
their forwarding address?
Thomas and Lucille sharpe?
Yes, in cumberland,
england, sir.
Thank you.
- Dr. mcmichael.
- Mr. Holly.
At your service, sir.
Did you bring the copy
of the information?
Took some time to obtain
that newspaper clipping.
It's damn gruesome,
if you ask me.
It's a shame the only
relevant information
i could pass to Mr. cushing
were the civil documents,
but it was enough to impede
any further relationship
between sir Thomas
and miss cushing.
Prevent them from marrying.
Why was that?
Because, you see,
sir Thomas
is already married.
This fellow cavendish--
your hero--
there's a darkness to him.
I like him.
Does he make it
all the way through?
It's entirely up to him.
What do you mean?
Well, characters
talk to you.
They transform.
They make choices.
Choices.
As to who they become.
Well--
this is rather dismal,
I'm sorry to say.
But at least it's warm.
Oh, I like it much better.
Better than what?
Better than the house.
Why don't we leave?
The house is all we have.
I left everything I was behind.
Everything I had.
We could live
anywhere you want.
Anywhere?
London.
Paris.
Paris is beautiful.
Milan.
Have you ever been
to Italy?
Yes, I have. Once.
The past, Thomas.
You're always looking
to the past.
You won't find me there.
I'm here.
I'm here too.
Finlay, help me carry the valve
controller to my shop.
Lucille?
Lucille, we're back.
I was making breakfast.
It was burning.
I moved it.
Where were you?
We, uh--
we got snowed in.
You didn't come home
last night.
We spent the night
at the depot.
You slept there?
What's wrong
with that, Lucille?
He's my husband.
This is all a game to you!
I was frantic!
What are you talking about?
You two-- alone--
in the storm.
I didn't know
if you had an accident.
I was all alone.
I can't be alone.
Are these from America?
I don't feel well.
I'll make you tea.
That dreadful noise.
The more the house sinks,
the worse it gets.
We must do something
about it.
My dear Edith,
please be advised
that the first transfer
of your father's estate
has been completed.
Now, the final transaction
for the remaining sum
will require your signature
on the document enclosed.
Yours very truly,
William ferguson.
Enola.
It's working, Finlay.
Right, master.
A gramophone player.
Milan.
Edinburgh.
You've already tried
and failed to raise capital
in London, Edinburgh, Milan,
and now you're here.
Isn't it beautiful?
It's been working perfectly
for an hour.
Oh. We've done it.
We've done it, Lucille.
I can't wait
for Edith to see it.
Edith?
- I did this with you.
- Yes, of course, you did.
Yeah.
We did this together.
Lady sharpe?
No one else.
We'll need more coal
to test the steamer.
Would you mind, Lucille?
Sparing a bit more coal?
Uh, you just need
to give him the key.
He'll fetch it.
Lucille?
Edith?
I want to apologize
for my behavior
this morning.
I was concerned that--
you didn't drink your tea.
I don't feel so well.
Would you mind bringing me
some cold water?
Of course.
Have you had a chance
to read your letters?
Yes. Just some papers
for me to sign,
from my lawyers
to finish the transfer
of funds.
I should
let you rest.
You'll feel better soon.
Let's see
what we have here.
This is Pamela upton
testing
the wax cylinder recording
bought in this most
jubilant year, 1887,
for my beloved
Thomas sharpe.
Thomas, speak into the horn.
Say something.
It's a beautiful machine,
Pamela,
but no, thank you.
I'd rather not.
Say something, Thomas.
What do you want me
to say, exactly?
Say... that you love me.
Margaret mcdermott.
Ding dong, bell.
Kitty's in the well.
Who put her in?
Little Johnny thin.
Who pulled her out?
Little Johnny stout.
Oh, what a naughty boy
was that who tried
to drown poor pussycat.
Enola sciotti. E.S.
We had plans to leave,
but I can't.
All they want
is my money
to work on that
infernal machine of his.
That's all
they care about.
I will hide
these cylinders away
in the linen closet.
Should anyone find them,
let it be known
that they did this.
I must stop recording now.
I can hear them coming.
A baby.
To whoever finds this,
know that they
are killing me.
I'm dying.
The poison
is in the tea.
Find my body.
Take it home.
I don't want to die.
I have to get out of here.
You're awake.
We found you at the bottom
of the stairs.
Do you feel better?
I need to go to town.
See a doctor.
Yes, of course.
But I'm afraid
we're snowed in.
No.
Then you must eat.
You must get stronger.
I tended mother in this bed.
Father
was a brute.
He hated mother.
Broke her leg.
Snapped it in two
under his boot.
She never quite healed.
She was bedridden
for a long time.
But I...
Cared for her.
Fed her,
bathed her,
combed her hair,
rubbed liniment on her scars.
I made her better.
I'll do the same with you.
I'll make you better.
May I have a moment alone
with my wife?
You'll be out of this bed soon.
I promise.
Don't drink that.
Never.
Lucille, she's very sick.
She's dying.
Of course she's dying.
She knows everything.
She stopped
drinking the tea.
Doesn't matter.
I put the poison
in the porridge.
Lucille, stop it!
Do we have to do this?
Must we?
Yes.
You have no idea
what they'd do.
I would be taken from here.
Locked away.
You would be hanged.
We stay together.
Never apart.
You couldn't leave me.
You wouldn't.
I can't.
I know.
Whoa!
There's a gentleman out there
asking for directions
to allerdale hall.
At this hour?
Yeah.
Surely not.
Can't get there
on that horse.
It's exhausted.
Can I hire one from you?
We're closed
for the winter.
Can I get there on foot?
It's well over four hours
following the road.
Then I'd better get going.
Sir!
Meet me there
after the storm.
I know who you are.
Your name is enola sciotti.
Tell me
what you want from me.
Shh.
- It's all out in the open now.
- No need to pretend.
This is who I am.
This is who he is.
- I knew it.
- Don't do it, Lucille!
Someone's at the door!
You're not his sister!
That's delightful.
Aaah!
- I am.
- Don't do it!
Aaah!
Hello, Edith.
Try not to move
or talk just yet.
You're heavily sedated.
I needed to sedate you
to set your leg.
You're going
to be fine.
Forgive me
for dropping in unannounced.
Heaven-sent,
as it turns out.
I should have
sent a wire, but...
I thought you'd enjoy
the surprise.
It's a miracle.
We didn't know
what to do.
She's so ill.
Delirious.
Then she fell
down the stairs.
She spoke to me.
Who spoke to you?
My mother.
She was delivering a warning.
Crimson peak.
Delirious, you see?
Poor thing.
Yes. I see.
Here. Try to drink.
No, not that.
Not that.
You will stay here
with us, won't you?
Wait for the storm
to pass.
If you insist.
But now I need
a moment alone
with my patient.
We'll leave you then,
doctor.
Edith, listen to me.
I'm here
to take you away.
You hear?
I'm taking you
with me now.
Somebody has to stop him.
Lucille, please.
What are you doing?
I just want to know,
brother.
Is it going to be you
this time?
Show me
you can stand up.
All right.
Shh.
I won't let them
harm you.
I'm gonna
find you a coat.
Don't go.
I'll be right back.
Things are getting
a bit emotional,
i see, doctor.
She's exhausted.
She's showing signs
of anemia.
I'm gonna take her
to a hospital.
That won't be necessary.
I'm afraid it is.
You've been
poisoning her.
Edith.
Front page.
The cumberland ledger.
Lady Beatrice sharpe
was murdered
in the bathtub.
One brutal blow
almost split her head
in two.
No suspect
was ever arrested.
There was no one else
in the house at the time.
Only the children.
The truth was too horrible
to consider.
- Doctor, stop it.
- You did this.
No.
Sir Thomas, you were
only 12 at the time.
After questioning
by the police,
you were sent
to boarding school.
As for Lucille, at 14,
her story is less clear.
A convent education
in Switzerland,
the news account says,
but I think a different kind
of institution.
Sir Thomas
is already married.
He married
a miss Pamela upton.
Margaret mcdermott
and enola sciotti-- e.S.
- Edith, you don't know.
- Edith and I are leaving.
You stay there.
Edith. Edith.
- You should do this.
- Get your hands dirty.
Come here, doggy.
Little shit.
If I don't do it,
she will.
But listen to me.
You're a doctor.
Show me where.
No! Alan!
You're monsters!
Both of you!
Funny.
That's the last thing
mother said too.
Lucille has taken Edith
to sign the papers.
The moment
she signs those papers,
she is dead.
I have to go.
I'll bring her down here.
I'll find a way.
The mine shaft is open,
you understand?
Get out up there.
Can you hold on?
Go.
You thought
you were a writer.
With your ghosts.
What are you waiting for?
You have nothing
to live for now.
Sign.
All the women we found--
London, Edinburgh, Milan--
America.
Yes, America.
All had what was necessary:
Money, broken dreams
and no living relatives.
No one ever looked
for them.
Mercy killings, really.
Is that what
I'm going to be?
What about
the Italian woman?
Enola.
You killed her baby.
I did not.
None of them
ever fucked Thomas.
Don't you understand?
It was mine.
It was born wrong.
We should have let it die
at birth, but...
I wanted it.
And she told me
she could save it.
She was determined.
She lied.
All this horror--
for what?
The money?
To keep the mansion?
The sharpe name, the mines?
The marriages were
for money, of course.
But the horror--
the horror
was for love.
The things we do
for a love like this
are ugly, mad,
full of sweat and regret.
This love burns you
and maims you, and...
Twists you inside out.
It is a monstrous love,
and it makes monsters
of us all.
But you should have seen him,
as a child, Thomas.
He was perfect.
So from all
his small infractions,
from my mother's cane,
i protected him.
I took so many beatings.
And when she found out
about us--
well,
the only love
Thomas and I ever knew
was from one another
in these rotting walls.
Hiding.
- That's not true.
- You suffocate him.
Sign your name!
Sign your bloody name!
My father,
who killed him?
Such a coarse,
condescending man.
He loved you.
You should have
seen his sad face
when I smashed it
at the sink.
You! Don't come near me!
Listen to me,
please, Edith.
You get away!
Edith, please.
Listen.
Mcmichael is still alive.
He's still alive.
You lied to me!
I did.
You poisoned me!
You told me you loved me!
I do.
Edith, please.
Please trust me
one more time.
You can leave
if you want,
or you can wait here
for me.
I'm gonna get those papers back.
I'm gonna finish this.
You burnt them.
Lucille.
Yes, she will live.
You're not to touch her.
You're ordering me?
We can leave, Lucille,
leave allerdale hall.
Leave?
Think about it.
We can start a new life.
Where?
Anywhere.
It doesn't matter.
Where would we go?
We can leave it behind.
We let the sharpe name
die with the mines.
We let this edifice sink
in the ground.
All these years
holding these walls together.
We would be free.
Free, Lucille.
We could all be together.
All?
Do you love her?
This day had to come.
We've been dead for years.
Do you?
You promised.
You and i
in this rotting place.
Look at who we are,
what we've become!
Do you love her more than me?
You promised you
would not fall in love
with anyone else.
Yes, but it happened.
Lucille.
Thomas?
Thomas.
Shh. She's coming.
I'm going to get us
out of here.
I will get help.
You have to trust me.
I'll come back for you.
I promise I will.
Shh. Hide.
Before they put me away,
I kept a little souvenir--
from mother.
Edith?
I won't stop
till you kill me
or I kill you.
Help me.
There's no one
here to help you.
Yes, there is.
Look at him. Turn around.
Thomas.
Lucille.
I won't stop...
Until you kill me
or I kill you.
I heard you the first time.
Ghosts are real.
This much I know.
- Lady sharpe!
There are things
that tie them to a place,
very much like they do us.
Some remain tethered
to a patch of land,
a time and date,
the spilling of blood,
a terrible crime.
But there are others--
others that hold on
to an emotion,
a drive,
loss,
revenge...
Or love.
Those--
they never go away.